Ripped by dj-oRi
Listen to me.
What are we talkin'about, really?
Getting high? No.
We're talking about a journey, man.
A subconscious safari. A mental
expedition, okay? A mind trek.
This planet has been raped,
pillaged and fucked, all right?
And the mind is-is the only
uncharted territory.
And this shit is the ship. It's the Nina,
the Pinta and the Santa Maria,
and you are fuckin' Magellan.
[Laughing]
Oh, fuck! I spilled some!
So what do you say,
my Serbian motherfuckin' friend?
Do you wanna take a trip,
or do you wanna sit on your ass?
Okay, Napoleon,
let's see what you got.
[Laughing]
- Robi.
- [Dog Snarling]
- [Barking]
- That dog is really creeping me out.
It's a big fuckin'dog.
It makes my girl very uneasy.
I don't really like dogs.
- [Barking Continues]
- The pooch was not invited.
You don't talk about my fuckin' dog,
okay? I'll handle it.
- [Barking Continues]
- Can you tie it up or something?
He'll do what I say.
Once I show him who's boss
with a few treats and some smacks.
[Shouting Commands In Serbian]
- [Dog Whimpering]
- [Man Continues In Serbian]
- [Laughing]
- Good boy. Here's treat.
- [Laughing Continues]
- He knows who's boss, yes?
Shit, man!
Hey, hey, I got a dog too.
Yo, Tony.! I love this guy.
He works his ass off for piss.
All right, once I show him who's boss
with some few smacks and some treatsies.
- You got that? You got a smoke?
- No, no. I'm fuckin' out. I told you.
- Are you giving me some static?
- No.
Huh? You giving me the hairy eyeball?
You Irish fucking pig!
Fuck, man! See? Whoo!
I got my dog too.
[Speaking Serbian]
- Here you go, dog.
- [Continues In Serbian]
- Are you guys in? Are you in?
- Fuck you!
[Continues In Serbian]
- What's your fucking lackey saying?
- He say that he knows your dog.
- My dog?
- He say that your dog testify
at his brother's trial three years ago.
- Oh, shit.
- He also say that your dog
is not even a fucking dog.
He's a dirty, fucking pig!
And I believe him.
[Screams]
God!
- Fuck! Call for backup! Call for backup!
- Unit 17 requesting backup.
- Fuck!
- Fourth floor, one suspect.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm all right. Come on!
Good dog. Good dog.
Shit! Shit!
All right, Coral,
take that back stairwell there.
Got it.
Tony, come on. Come on.
Oh, shit. Okay.
You take this hallway on the right.
All right.
I'll take the left.
Gotcha.
Can you believe
that cocksucker shot me?
Shit.! Shit.!
[Gunshots]
Tony! Tony?
Ah, shit! Ah!
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Officer down!
I repeat: Officer down!
Suspect on north stairway!
I'm going after him!
And where the fuck is my backup!
Freeze! Shit!
[Coral Grunts]
Shit. Shit. Shit. Help me!
I'm a police officer! Help me!
Call an ambulance!
Shit! Shit! Call an ambulance!
Shit!
[Gun Cocks]
[Gunshot]
[Phone Ringing]
Hello? Yeah. Shit, yeah.
No. No, no, I'm up. I'm up.
I'll be right there. All right. Bye.
[Groans]
Mornin', buddy.
Come here, shithead.
Come here.
Good morning.
Ohh!
[Sighs, Sniffs]
[Man On Radio]
It's cold, people. Detroit's gonna have
a white New Year's this year,
because we're getting hit
with yet another storm.
No shit!
Sports comin'up.
"In the lane, snow is glistening"
"A beautiful sight
We're happy tonight"
This kind of sex
is evolutionary instinct, gentlemen.
Example: Tiger Stadium.
Bleachers empty, except me and a friend.
We always get it on
whenever and wherever we can.
No one saw us
except for the left fielder.
Let's just say he enjoyed the show,
and I didn't mind the audience.
Impulsive sex is in our genes, boys.
Don't deny yourselves.
I gotta go jump in the snow
to cool my shit off.
- Have a good New Year, I.
- You too, babe.
That animal was your type, Iris.
Probably an ex-con.
- You two should hook up.
- Fuck off, Carlyle.
We were just talking about acting
on impulses with no guilt.
Don't get angry, I.
You only bed criminals.
Everyone knows that.
Which is unfortunate for me,
because I am in love with you.
I don't bed criminals.
I fuck bad boys. Big difference.
I just hope I don't have to become
a fuckin' ax murderer to prove I'm worthy.
- [Laughing]
- What the hell is this? Fun and games?
- Buzzkill.
- Does anybody work around here anymore?
Hey, Sarge. You're late.
Happy New Year.
Hey, you're pissing me off. Get outta here
before I give you something to do.
You boys don't wanna get stuck
with us here tonight.
Bye, boys.
I'll see you guys at the new precinct.
Happy New Year, Iris.
Later, Iris.
Stuck. That's not
very nice, boss.
You're right. I apologize.
You're lovely and amazing,
and it's my honor
to spend New Year's Eve with you.
You're a sarcastic prick, aren't you?
We are going to have a good time
tonight, boss.
We officially shut down at midnight,
but all calls are being diverted,
so we might as well be closed now.
We could start gettin' fucked up
real early!
All right, but not too early, all right?
We still gotta pack this shit up.
Not much.
All the computers are gone.
Most of the gear.
Now, come on, Sarge.
It's my favorite holiday.
I even put on my very special,
sexy holiday boots.
Even though we're here,
I wanna do it right.
How could you possibly
do it wrong?
"We will conspire"
"As we dream by the fire"
"To face unafraid"
"The plans that we made"
"Walkin'in a winter wonderland"
[Man Preaching]
Never take for granted
the greatest power of all...
the power to choose.
Consider the choices
you have made in the past.
And when they led you astray,
faith in times of opposition...
will lead to your salvation,
or often the easy way
will lead only to temptation.
Think of consequences...
and cherish your power
to choose the righteous path.
You figure I'd be more liable
to tell the truth with God watchin'.
If you believe in God, Mr. Portnow.
You don't? I never met a brother
who didn't have faith.
I've stood in front of dozens of men...
who were all staring death in the face.
Every single one of them
begged for God's help.
After seeing all those pleas
go unanswered,
I... lost my faith.
So what's the what?
My answer... is this.
No.
I guess we're done here.
What'd you think? I was gonna let you
walk outta here with the crowd
for protection? Get the fuck up.
- Walk in front of me.
- "[Pipe Organ]
[Grunting]
"Amazing grace"
"How sweet the sound"
"That saved a wretch"
"Like me"
"[Continues, Indistinct]
[Woman Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
- Police.!
- [Congregation Screaming, Shouting]
[Sirens Wailing]
Hold it right there!
Freeze, Bishop! Drop your weapon!
Drop it now, motherfucker!
We're here at the new Precinct 21,
where one of the city's most powerful
crime figures, Marion Bishop,
is being held in the alleged murder
of an undercover police officer.
Move back!
Bishop, notorious
for his brutal execution methods,
earns untold millions
from his various criminal operations...
in the Detroit area.
Bishop's crew.
Yeah?
[Grunts]
Now is not the time.
I'm Lieutenant Holloway.
Marcus Duvall, Organized Crime
and Racketeering squad.
This is my team.
I know who you are.
Sorry about your man.
Where is this son of a bitch?
I don't spend one night,
not one night, inside,
and we both know why.
You do whatever you have to do
to get me out of here.
Do you understand?
That guy's a cop killer.
Judge hands down bail,
I swear to Christ I'll...
- [Door Opens]
- No arraignment 'cause of the holiday.
Bishop spends two days inside
until he has a chance to make bail.
Don't worry, Cap. We got him.
We ain't gonna fuckin' let him go.
Happy New Year!
[Laughs]
Come on, man.
There's only three of us here.
Yeah, well, one of us is Irish.
My God, look at this thing.
It's gotta be older than me.
You'll never take me alive, G-man!
[Laughing]
Look at this room.
Boy, there's gotta be evidence in here
from some of my first busts back in the day.
Uh, they got rid
of all the Civil War stuff.
Oh, ho!
Hey, that's so funny.
Don't quit the day job, all right?
Sarge?
Yeah?
Friday appointment's here.
Are you kiddin' me?
Any feelings of anxiety lately?
Yeah. Two words. The Lions.
They give me a lot of anxiety.
Please stop avoiding
my questions, Sergeant.
Are you still taking
the painkillers?
Come on, Doc.
I mean, even you have got to be getting
a little bored of these conversations.
Why don't we talk
about the real reason...
that you would come down here
on New Year's Eve...
in the middle of this storm.
Okay. Uh, let's see.
We had an appointment.
I think the real reason...
is you're in love with me.
Huh. Interesting.
I can see it in your eyes.
That's why you come
wearing these fancy clothes.
It's very flattering,
but I think you should stop
denying it, you know?
I hear... No, I hear you.
You're right. You're right.
You're right.
My face obviously betrays me.
I didn't get dressed up like this
because I'm going to a New Year's Eve
party later tonight.
Oh, no. No, Sergeant.
This was all for you.
A form of seduction.
Is it working?
Wonderfully.
[Timer Beeps]
I'm glad.
Okay, well, we'll have to finish
this conversation another time.
[Sighs]
What is this thing here?
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
That's mine.
All right, relax.
I don't care about the file.
So, uh, you got a desk job
at Precinct 21, I see.
You don't quit, do you?
How do you feel about it?
How do I feel about it?
It's no big change.
So I guess the new year's
not bringing anything different for you.
How's your leg, by the way?
I noticed you weren't limping anymore.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It's just an observation.
Five years of undercover work,
and now this. Wow!
Good-bye.
You must be itching
to get back on the streets.
Good-bye. Happy New Year.
Happy New Year to you.
I'll see you at the new precinct.
God, you know, I cannot wait.
I'd walk you out, you know,
but I just have so much...
I know the way. Thank you.
So much to do.
Jake, you should see this.
[Woman Reporting]
And now Lieutenant Marcus Duvall...
that's Officer Ray Portnow's superior...
is coming out of...
Hey, that's Duvall.
Good cop. Good man.
[Reporter Continues]
Crime kingpin Marion Bishop
in custody.
That man is in hell right now.
[Reporter]
...responsible for the slaying,
the fifth in Motor City this year alone.
Hey, you okay, Jake?
[Reporter Continues, Indistinct]
Everybody in the bus.
You know what a bus looks like.
New Year's Eve in a house
of a thousand doors. How about that?
Huh? You'll be sittin'
in that cell of yours.
You're gonna want some "cham-pag-ne,"
and you're not gonna get any. No.
No "Dick Clark's
Happy Rockin'New Year's Eve."
Losers.
I ain't no loser, baby, a'ight.
I'm just tryin' to exist 'cause my people
lack the power to consume
what the media emphasizes in society.
So I'm forced to take shit
that ain't mine.
Beck, your eyes are red.
You been snortin'? You been drinkin'?
Your eyes look glazed.
You been eatin' doughnuts?
That's funny.
Think that's funny,
motherfucker?
What'd you read that in?
A comic book?
[Shouting, Indistinct]
Get in the fuckin' back.
[Siren Wailing]
Round 'em up!
"You're nobody
till somebody loves you"
Well, we won't need that anymore.
"[Singing Continues]
All right, boys and girls.
We must raise our glasses in a toast.
A toast to this old shit-hole
before they tear it down.
I got a terrible feeling
I'm gonna miss this place.
Not as much
as I'm gonna miss you two.
What are you talkin' about?
I have news, boys and girls.
Old school here is retiring.
You're kidding.
I'm packin' it in.
- Just like this place.
- Congratulations, Jasper.
Why didn't you tell us?
I just got the word officially.
Anyway, here's to this old shit-hole.
Here's to me,
and here's to my new life.
Huh?
Cheers.
"[Continues]
And now, little lady,
may I have this dance?
To celebrate
my retirement, huh?
Come on. Oh.
Don't go away.
Maybe you'll learn something.
"The world still is the same"
"You'll never change it"
"As sure as the stars"
"Shine above"
"You're nobody"
"Till somebody loves you"
One more. There you go.
"So find yourself someone..."
"[Rock]
We never should've left in this shit.
Ah, shit. You mean their captain
didn't want these scumbags in there?
Wanted to give his men
more time off for the holiday.
Marion Bishop. Marion Bishop.
Chief, head cheddar
and whatnot, baby.
You know, I heard... I heard about you
getting shot five times, man.
Five fuckin' times! What was it...
your left shoulder, your stomach,
upper back, lower back, right hip?
Ain't that a bitch?
You didn't wanna die, though, right?
'Cause you're a persistent
motherfucker. You're like
the black Rasputin and whatnot.
Serious, man.
[Laughing]
Um, let me introduce myself.
My-My name is Beck.
I'm an entrepreneurial motherfucker
like yourself, slash lawyer, slash...
Got any openings, man?
Throw me a bone or somethin'?
[Indistinct Shouting]
- [Tires Screeching]
- Yo, pump the brakes! Don't slam 'em!
- Shut the fuck up!
- Hey, Ray Charles!
Slow this motherfucker down, man!
Officer Balls and Officer Cock.
Psst. Psst. Eye contact, man.
Eye contact. Let
me tell you somethin'.
The Constitution requires
that the state provide secure...
- Sit down.
- Incarceration. I'm-I'm just sayin'
that I'm feelin' pretty fuckin' unsafe.
- Shut the fuck up.
- Transport 1121, this is Dispatch.
Transport 1121, Dispatch. Go.
[Dispatcher]
We're gonna have to reroute you
to Precinct 13 until the storm breaks.
No problem.
What's goin'on, Dispatch?
There was an injury accident
on the Parkway 101.
We're gettin'everyone off the road.
You'll stay at 13 until further orders.
They've already been advised.
Copy.
Thirteen. What a piece of shit.
I don't care.
I'll be glad to get out of this.
[Jasper]
Well, how about this
for a New Year's present?
That scumbag Bishop
is hand-delivered to us!
- I'm gonna get some righteous payback
from that skel for Ray Portnow.
- What are you doin' here?
What? I've heard so much
about this Bishop guy over the years.
I wanna see him.
I thought you gave up bad boys.
Get back inside.
It's not the new year yet, Sarge.
You must be Roenick.
No offense, Officer, but I'm
pretty fuckin' perturbed about this.
We're closing down.
We're short-staffed.
Central said we park here overnight
until the road's clear.
You got a problem with that, call in.
I tried. I'll give it another shot.
Jake, come on. You're not gonna send
these guys back out in that weather.
Nah. Now, look.
We'll lock 'em up,
and we'll let 'em be. No problem.
All right, fine.
But they're your responsibility.
I don't wanna hear jack shit
about them or from them.
- Let's go inside.
- Bring 'em in.! Come on. Bring 'em in.!
Interesting cast.
Yeah, we got a female gangbanger...
who swears she never
committed a crime in her life.
This guy here specializes
in counterfeit merchandise.
Need a fake Rolex, he's your man.
Some junkie who robbed a deli.
- Allegedly.
He's still ridin' on a high right now.
And the star of the show.
He needs no intro.
You know his credits.
Sarge, when it rains, it snows.
Got another freakin' guest.
How's your car?
Won't move. Must've walked
two miles in this damn weather.
I'm soaking. Look at me.
Well, thank God you're not hurt.
So how did you enjoy your file?
Oh, yeah, yeah. You dropped this.
Oh, really? I dropped it? That's strange,
because I was sure that you took it.
Definitely dropped it.
That's disappointing.
If you had stolen it,
it would've been the first time...
you were taking a proactive
interest in your therapy.
- You know it's a bunch of bullshit.
- So you read it.
Yeah, I fuckin' read it.
Did you steal it?
You know I stole it, all right?
And stop being so goddamn happy
about it, Dr. Sabian.
It makes me sick.
"I think he's hiding behind his injury.
He's not really hurt.
Jake Roenick no longer
considers himself a cop."
What kind ofbullshit is that? Huh?
You think I'm scared?
That's what it is, right?
If you'd read further on,
you would see that's not what I think.
All right, well, then tell me what it is
that you think, Dr. Mrs. Mind-Fuck.
What is it that
you think I'm hiding from?
I'm not gonna explain myself to you
if you're gonna act like a child.
Excuse me.
Run away. We both know
you can't handle this shit,
'cause you want to fuck me.
Sergeant, if I wanted to fuck you,
it would've happened already.
Gotta learn to control yourself,
Doc. It's affecting your work.
It's very unprofessional.
Don't try to discredit me
because you're afraid I may be right.
Right?
Yes.
About what? Come on. Tell me
what it is you think I'm hiding from,
and then I'll tell you
whether I think you're right.
Okay! I believe that the prospect
of responsibility has rendered you impotent!
Impotent?
Yes!
And that's why you're working
at this old precinct behind a desk.
I'm injured, all right?
That's why I'm here.
Bullshit!
You feel responsible for the death
of your team eight months ago,
and that's why you're here.
I didn't do anything wrong.
A board of inquiry cleared me.
That's right.
You didn't do anything wrong.
But it was your decision that sent them
down the left hallway...
and not the right,
out the front door and not the back.
And you don't want to make
decisions like that again.
Yeah. So? Maybe you're right.
What? You want a medal?
So now you're hiding
behind that desk.
And behind that liquor
in your drawer...
and those... pills
in that stupid little matchbox.
But there's still one life you're
responsible for, no matter where you go.
- Oh, let me guess. My own?
- Yeah, your own.
And if you don't start taking care
of yourself, you're never gonna be
the cop you used to be.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Exhales]
[Whispering]
Bish.
Bish. Bishop.
Bish, Bish, Bish, Bish,
Bish, Bish, Bish, Bish!
Hi.
Yo, Bish, Bish. Just check it out.
Check it out, man.
Puerto Rican guy and a black guy
in a car. Who's drivin'?
The cops.
[Groans]
You're killin' me, man.
You're killin' me.
That was... That was...
We had somethin'.
Did you feel that?
All right.
This jail shit ain't for Smiley.
This is definitely
out of Smiley's essence.
Who the fuck is Smiley?
I'm Smiley. Me. I'm Smiley.
Look, I'm facing a lot of jail time here.
I didn't do shit
to be up in this bitch.
They lookin' for my sister,
and they picked me up.
I ain't never committed a crime
in my motherfuckin' life!
"Nothin'but the best
is good enough for me"
"I like to eat lobster"
"Directly from Maine"
"[Continues, Indistinct]
Are you still waiting
for that tow truck?
- "In sunny old Spain"
- It's not gonna come.
[Iris]
Oh, shit. It's almost time, people.
"Bish, Bish, bo-Bish
Banana-fanna-fo-fish"
"Fee-fi-mo-mi-ish"
"Bish, Bish"
How you get in the life, man?
For me it was I wanted this bicycle.
I was always prayin'for it, right?
And God, in all his wisdom,
decided not to give it to me,
so I stole it, and then I asked him
to forgive me after that.
But that was the beginning, man.
I could never stop after that shit.
That was... It was over for me.
[Clears Throat]
Right.
[Continues Clearing Throat]
Okay. Twenty, 19,
[All]
18, 17, 16, 15,
14, 13, 12, 11,
10, nine, eight, seven,
Listen to them
trying to demoralize us.
six, five, four,
three, two, one.!
[Dick Clark On TV]
Happy New Year!
- [Noisemaker Tooting]
- [Laughing, Cheering]
You gonna do it?
I'm doin' it. I'm doin' it.
"Should auld acquaintance be forgot"
[Indistinct]
"And never brought to mind"
- [Woman]
Look at him.
- "[Continues, Faint]
All jacked up and shit,
sweatin' out his fuckin' ass.
Lookin' like fuckin' Mike Tyson
in a spellin' bee.
[Laughing]
Hey, you slanderin' me?
You slanderin' me?
I'll give you some free advice. Don't.
Yo, why don't you
leave her alone, you fuckin'junkie!
Leave her the fuck alone!
- Who's talkin' to you, man?
- Yeah, but I'm talkin' to you.
So what's the problem?
What was that?
You heard me.
Who the fuck you pushin', man?
I'll slap the smack outta you!
[Chattering]
Happy New Year.
[Toots]
[Chattering Continues]
- [Shouting, Arguing]
- That's it, you bitch-ass punk!
[Shouting Continues]
[Man]
I'll fuck you up.!
Hey! Hey, you fuckin' animals!
What the hell!
[Shouting Continues]
- What the fuck?
- Oh, shit.! What's that?
- Shit!
- You monkeys keep it down,
for Christ's sake.
Hey, stop yellin', you fuckin'animals.!
It's only New Year's...
Who the fuck are you?
[Gunshot]
What's goin'on down there?
- Rosy!
- I'm all right.
Are you all right?
Stay with him. Stay with him.
Open this! Get us outta here!
Get us outta here!
- Let us out ofhere, man.!
- Iris, get in here! Get in here!
- What the fuck is goin' on!
- [Shouting Continues]
Son of a bitch!
[Indistinct Shouting]
Just keep breathing!
What the hell is going on!
- [Grunts]
- Shit.
[Groaning]
Ow! Man!
- [Groaning Continues]
- Come on!
[Jasper]
Come on.! Hang on.!
Goddamn it.!
[Mumbling]
Rosy, yeah, that's right.
Love...
Talk to me, goddamn it!
Talk to me!
Keep breathing, goddamn it! Rosy!
Iris.! Iris.!
[Groaning]
- How is he? Is he all right?
- "Is he all right?"
He's dead, for Christ's sake!
That's how all right he is!
Goddamn it! Fucking Bishop!
They're tryin'to bust him outta here.!
You son of a bitch.!
[Beck]
Get us outta here.! Come on.!
All right, relax! Relax!
The threat is over!
Look, get us outta here!
Get us outta here!
Shit! Calm down!
The threat is over!
- You fuckin' kidding me, Sergeant?
- [Groaning]
I know. I know. Shh.
How's he doin', Iris?
I'm sorry about your partner.
We just moved him to an office.
Oh, shit.
He needs a doctor fast.
Why wasn't there an alarm
on your back door?
That alarm hasn't worked in months.
They're still out there.
Some kind of a truck out there
in the forest. It's not moving.
Are you kidding me?
They must have assumed
we'd call for backup.
I'm having a little problem here.
The phones aren't working.
Sure, they cut the wires.
The storm could've
taken the phones out.
Bullshit! Those are Bishop's guys
out there. They cut the wires.
Just try the radios!
Forget it.
Frequencies are blocked.
The frequencies are blocked?
That's not easy to do.
Well, they must've got professional help,
because all the frequencies are blocked.
They probably screwed up
your cell phones too.
[Phone Beeping]
I'm not getting a signal.
Neither am I.
What the hell is this!
I told you!
They're Bishop's guys out there!
They're gonna break him outta here
one way or another.
Maybe somebody heard the gunshots
and will come check it out.
There's nothing out there
but factories.
No, no. I don't buy any of that.
They, whoever they are, are gone.
They're gonna think they're fireworks.
- They don't give a shit about me,
and I'm going! Thank you.
- [Gunshot]
[Whimpering]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
What the hell is happening here?
This is a fucking police precinct,
for God's sake! Jesus Christ!
Sarge, if you're all right,
you better take a look at this.
[Jasper]
They're surrounding the place.
- It's a goddamn siege.
- [Exhales]
I am not supposed to be here.
[Screams]
- Shit!
- Cease fire! Cease fire! Cease fire!
- It wasn't gunshots.
- Bishop.!
I told you. Those are
Bishop's troops out there.
They're taking him outta here
tonight, no matter what.!
This doesn't make any sense.
This is a police precinct!
Shut the fuck up, Doc.
You said that already.
All right, look.
Everybody just listen up.
Maybe they're trying
to give us a way out of this.
Let's just give them what they want.
Let 'em have Bishop, and it's all over.
- Nobody else gets hurt.!
- Not a bad fuckin' idea.
No, we can't let that scumbag gangster,
a cop killer, walk out of our precinct!
It's not an option!
[Jasper]
I'm trying to defuse this situation.
- You got a wounded cop over there!
- I already said no!
What in God's name
are we supposed to do then, Sergeant?
- They're gettin' ready to storm the fort.
- I don't think so, all right?
I think they're just tryin'
to scare us into giving up Bishop.
They're doin' a damn good job.
[Nervous Breathing]
See, this blackout, this is the kind of shit
that deflates human smugness...
about government's
so-called miraculous technologies.
Doesn't it? Shove it up their
lyin' corporate fuckin' asses.
This ain't no blackout, junkie.
Something suspect is goin' on.
I wanna know what the funk it is.
[Groaning]
I know it hurts, but we gotta
get you away from these windows.
[Indistinct Chattering]
Jasper, you got those flashlights?
I don't know where the fuck the are.!
Everything's been packed.!
Roenick!
Get down! Get down!
[Groaning]
Jasper, get the blinds!
All right. All right.
Yeah, we're perfectly safe now.
These are just scare tactics, all right?
They don't know how much firepower
we have or don't have.
They're not gonna come in here again.
It's too risky.
[Gasping] What about us
gettin' out there, Sergeant?
l-I need help real bad.
I need it.
Let's barricade up
these doors and windows,
and I'll figure out
how to get some help in here.
What are you doing this for, Jake?
Nobody gives a shit anymore
about anything.
We can end this right now.
I can't let a murderer
walk out of here.
I can't do that.
I'll get us out of this, Jasper.
I will. I promise.
You got almost no chance
out there, buddy.
That cop in there dies if I don't try.
You keep the place locked down
until I get some help.
All right.
I'd better cover from the front windows.
I can see the truck better from there.
Keep your head down.
[Chuckles]
Schmuck.
Oh, shit!
[Grunting]
[Yelling]
[Screams]
[Screams, Groans]
Oh, shit.!
[Grunts]
[Gunshots]
I found this on our friend out there.
Fuck it. Fact or fiction?
You pulled a guy's spine out
once, didn't you?
Are you a surgeon?
I heard that bullet
you took in your belly is still
lodged in there, rattling around.
I bet you it's causing you
a lot of intestinal issues.
Right? Right, man?
Bishop, I need to talk to you.
So I just killed a man.
His name was Danny Barbero.
A cop.
A cop who works for Ray Portnow.
The man you killed.
So tell me why cops are risking
their lives to get to you, Bishop.
Why should I answer that question?
Because I'm thinking
about sending you out to the wolves
and saving my own ass if you don't.
I assume you know
who I am, Sergeant.
You're a scumbag gangster.
And one of my scumbag partners in crime
is your fellow officer, Marcus Duvall.
Marcus Duvall and his entire team.
We used to split things 50-50.
Marcus got greedy. He wanted more.
- So you killed Ray Portnow.
- After he tried to kill me.
Mm. Right.
They're here to execute me,
because if I make it to court,
every single one of them goes to jail
for the rest of their days.
How many cops
are involved in this?
I can't say exactly, but the blood money
runs through your entire department.
I bet they're all here now,
and they can't allow me
to leave this precinct alive.
They can't allow any of us
to leave here alive.
Now that we all know
it's them out there.
Sarge.
Poor guy, he never had a chance.
Anyone know ifhe had any family?
Someone's coming.!
Shit, someone's coming.!
- Someone's coming.
- Hit squad, Sergeant.
They're here for all of us.
Me?
All of us. You especially.
Fuck you, dealer.
This is all your fault.
Those are your brethren
out there, old man, not mine.
Don't compare me with your scumbag
friends out there. If it was up to me,
I'd kick your ass out the door.
- I'd like to see you come try.
- Yeah, sure. You'd love to kill
another cop today, wouldn't you?
Only you.
They'll be coming on strong now.
Why? Why are cops
coming to kill us?
They need to kill him
before he fingers them in court.
They need to kill us too,
now that we know it's them.
So... here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna take positions
all around the precinct,
and we're gonna hold 'em off
until dawn.
Iris, Alex, you know
how to use a firearm?
No. No.
Why don't you give me
one of them guns, Sergeant.
I'll help you fend off the black hats.
Oh. Oh, shit. Men are here.
Good.
What a fuckin' mess this is.
I know.
I'm lookin' at this as a matter
of simple mathematics.
If we walk
and those eight people survive,
then 33 lives are destroyed.
The lives of my men
and their families.
People I'm responsible for.
People l...
People I love.
I don't see any other way, Marcus.
The blood trail leads right back to us.
We have no choice.
If we go through this,
we are gonna have to live with this
for the rest of our lives.
But you know something, Mike?
I could live with that
more than I could live with a cell mate.
Once we step outside,
those people are no longer
civilians or cops.
We gotta put 'em all down.
Without pause, without regard.
1,024. 2,048.
Um, 4,096.
[Gasps, Sighs]
Obsessive-compulsive disorder.
The complex problems
force me to concentrate,
neutralizing any feelings of fear
I have at a given moment.
I hide behind its structure.
[Sighs]
You're gonna be all right, Doc.
[Laughs]
We don't know that.
Don't know that. You're so calm.
Thank you so much. Thanks.
You don't have to do this.
Yes, I do. I do.
If I'm gonna die,
at least I should die gracefully.
How are you keeping it together?
I just think about living.
I want to live,
as opposed to
I don't want to die.
That, and I keep telling myself
everybody's gonna make it this time.
We both know what
could happen here, Sergeant.
[Clicks]
Safety off.
Yeah. Right.
All right! Wake up!
Wake up! Wake up!
- [Beck] All right, already.
- Come on. Get up.
[Groans]
Oh, come on.
Look, uh, here's the deal.
Those men that came in here...
they're still outside.
And... I have no idea
how many there are...
or what they're prepared to do.
Don't sweat it.
There's nothin' you can do.
You can't stop Bishop's people.
Go ahead, Sergeant. Tell them.
They're not Bishop's people.
They are police officers.
What! "Po-po" popping each other?
This is the fuckingest shit I ever seen.
This ain't Smiley's fight, man.
Let Smiley go. Let me go.
I totally figured it out.
Assassination politics, right?
By the government-sanctioned thugs
abusing their authority again, man.
Who's gonna save us from your
corrupt brethren, Sarge? You?
You?
I'm gonna do my best to protect you.
All right? All of you.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
I feel real safe, man.
[Cocks Gun]
[Grunts]
[Gunfire Continues]
Fuck!
[Groans]
What the fuck is goin' on now?
[Gasps]
[Gun Clicking]
Get down!
- [Groans]
- Fuck!
- [Grunts]
- [Whimpers]
- Fuck!
- They blew out the fuckin' window!
- Cover the front.
- [Groans]
I'll be right back.
- The window, Sergeant! The window!
- Look out.! Look out.!
- Shoot him again.! Shoot him again.!
- Shoot him.! He's not dead.!
Man down. Denied entry.
[Whimpering]
You gotta get us outta here, man.
Smiley feels very fuckin' unsafe.
It's scary. I'm scared to death.
You can't use us as fuckin' live bait.
Come on. Think about it. We're hostages.
I know.
They're gonna come for us.
Come on, man. Come on.
- You can't do that. Think about it.
- Please. Come on, man.
- You can't leave us here
as fuckin'animals to fuckin'die.!
- Smiley's scared shitless, man.
Please. We're sittin'ducks here.
Come on. Don't leave us like this, man.
[Sighs]
All right, choose a weapon.
Anything you see.
Tell me again why we should help
your little skinny white ass?
'Cause if you don't, you'll die.
No resistance. Advancing
to the front door. We're going in.
[Roenick]
Spread out across the precinct.
Stop anything that approaches.
- We might make it through this night.
- Christ Almighty. What are you doin'?
- You can't trust these people.
- What the hell are you doin'? You're
supposed to be coverin' the front. Goddamn it!
- Come on.
- [Karate Yell]
- [Panting]
- [Wind Whistling]
430.
[Alex]
13,760.
[Continues Counting, Indistinct]
All right. Just hold the front.
And don't move this time!
[Alex Continues Counting]
[Gasps]
508.
- [Door Slams Open]
- [Screeches]
[Continues Screeching]
- You fucker!
- [Alex Screams]
You make me your defendant,
you son of a bitch!
Make me set bail!
[Alex Screams Hysterically]
- You all right?
- I feel better. I'm better.
I got mine, baby.
Oh, yeah.
[Panting]
Come on, you motherfuckers!
Come on! Run!
[Gunfire Continues, Distant]
[Gasping]
Come on.
Come on. Yeah.
There you go, secretary.
Jesus Christ.
All right!
They're pullin' back!
You all right?
He saved me.
There's nobody out there
in the front. Them motherfuckers
runnin' scared.
All right. All right.
I drove 'em back, baby.
I drove 'em back.
We're gonna have
a red-raw revolution on our hands, man.
All right. Good job.
Good job. Good job.
[Chattering]
Maybe they'll leave
for fucking good now.
[Bishop] They're not going anywhere.
- Put that goddamn weapon down.
- J...
Old man, you do not
wanna point that weapon at me.
- [Gun Cocks]
- [Bishop]
That is not a bright thing to do.
- [Gasps]
- Put that goddamn weapon down slowly,
then back away from it, all of ya.!
Jake, get their weapons.
Take their weapons.
Ain't this a bitch.
We saved your asses.
Now you wanna turn on us?
Yeah, well, thank you
for that, sweet cheeks.
Now, put your weapon down.
The problem is outside, not inside.
Put the gun down, Jasper.
No, no.
You know what the problem is?
That we criminals got rights, baby.
That's right. We got rights
to be protected against assault
under any circumstances.
- If you can't provide that,
well, fuck you... we will.
- You're a fuckin' psycho.
Jesus Christ, Jake!
What? Are you gonna
trust these freaks?
Huh? The first chance they get
to blow our brains out, they'll try
to make a break for it.
They need us as much
as we need them.
We all gotta start trusting each other
right now if we're gonna
make it through this night.
Put the gun down,
Jasper.
Put the goddamn gun down!
What?
- Shit.
- All right. All right.
Now, let's all introduce ourselves
to each other. It's New Year's Eve.
Let's turn over a new leaf.
All right. Let's not
all fuckin' speak at once.
The name's Smiley.
I'm a Libra, and...
[Pats]
I'll handle these jokers.
You handle your people,
maybe we get out of here tonight.
He armed his prisoners.
It's a smart play.
Must be at least eight guns
in there now.
Just a couple hours till the sun's up.
If we can't breach, what do we do?
Get the A.V. -5 here.
Are you sure about that?
Yep. I'm not takin'
any more chances.
[Sighs]
It's gonna take a while
in this weather.
Marcus? What the fuck do we do
if it doesn't arrive in time?
We'll have to think of some
other way of ending this.
You either flirting with me
or clocking my game
'cause you don't trust me.
I don't like your beady little eyes
all over my goodies,
so turn the fuck away.
You're manipulative,
weak knees and that sexy
copper complexion.
You're definitely
an Aries, baby.
You're pretty good.
Smiley thanks you.
We got something in common,
you know that?
You comin' down
off some shit, ain't ya?
Don't be ashamed, man.
Don't be ashamed.
What's your poison?
Seconal to bring me down.
Adderall to bring me back up.
You gotta get up
to get down.
Oh, yeah, baby. Oh, yeah.
All right.
That's enough. Come on.
Let's pay attention.
I want a cigarette so bad.
Stupid New Year's resolutions.
Hey, gangster,
you make any resolutions? Hmm?
What do you think,
secretary?
Oh, my God. I can't stop
thinking about sex.
I mean, I usually think
about sex a lot, but this is crazy.
Sex and death
are very closely related.
The Greeks called it Eros
and Thanatos... love and death.
Or sex as a way
of nullifying thoughts of dying.
What's your deal, gangster?
You actually been shot five times?
Six.
You really
pull a man's spine out?
It was an Adam's apple.
If you ever get
into tussles, secretary,
you grab a man
by his throat, hmm?
Dig it?
And then you squeeze.
I guarantee you he will drop.
He will not get up
for quite some time.
Oh, God. It's really quiet
out there now.
Yeah.
That's what worries me.
[Wind Whistling]
[Bishop] We're not gonna make it till
morning. Marcus Duvall will not allow it.
We've got eight people
covering six entry points.
If we work together, we will make it.
Look at it this way. That's me out there.
You think I'd let you survive
until the morning?
- We don't have a lot of options here.
- Well, we got to figure something,
'cause I'm not gonna stay here all night
waitin' to get killed.
If you use the situation
to try and escape,
it's about me and you,
'cause when this is over,
you're goin' back to jail.
- Relax, Sergeant.
- "Relax."
This ain't about me and you.
Not yet.
- Our shit's on pause, huh?
- Yeah. Our shit's on pause.
You saved my ass back there.
Why?
Everyone in here
is my responsibility.
It's my job.
That's noble.
Unfortunately,
I don't share the sentiment.
I see a cop in jeopardy,
he's on his own,
unless it benefits me
to jump in for the save.
Listen. I don't try
to be anything I'm not.
That ain't gonna change;
I don't care what day it is.
You remember that,
Sergeant.
Hey.! Someone's comin'.
Oh, God.
It's Capra, Sarge!
[Bishop]
You know this guy?
[Roenick] He's a cop. He works here.
They'll execute him.
- Capra!
- Shh!
Yeah. Drive. Drive!
[Iris]
Oh, my God. He's gonna make it.
[Bishop] He still has to get by the sniper.
[Roenick]
Come on, Capra.!
[Gunfire]
He's still moving.
They didn't get him yet.
Where are you going?
[Panting]
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Capra.! Come on.!
- [Gun Cocks]
- [Gunfire]
Come on!
What the fuck is goin' on?
Who's fuckin'
shootin' at us, Sarge?
[Roenick Panting]
Who the fuck
are all these people?
What are you doin'here, Capra?
What are you doin'here?
It's New Year's Eve.
I knew you'd be here alone.
- I came to have a drink with Iris.
- You picked the wrong night
to make your move, baby, believe me.
You know, that's really sweet.
[Gun Cocks]
That's really sweet, but, unfortunately,
I don't believe a fuckin' word of it.
Put that goddamn weapon down,
you psycho! He works here!
I don't care
that he fuckin' works here, man.
He could be a plant.
No, Jasper. Put the gun down, all right?
Let's not start that again, all right?
He comes here in the guise
of courting that lady.
It's a fuckin'ingenious plan.
They get one of their boys in here
and then take us out one by one by one.
Come on. Tell 'em.
They shot at him.
All right? They shot at him.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, but they conveniently
fuckin' missed, didn't they?
The act is a fuckin' charade!
Come on. Tell 'em.
He's fuckin' right, Anna.
[Beck]
Isn't it a fucking charade?
Do I have a gun?
Do I have a fucking gun?
I can't hurt you.
It's not fuckin' good enough,
rat-bitch. Come on. Just lock him up,
man, so he doesn't do any damage.
Come on. Come on, Roenick.
Listen to me, man.
We're not lockin'this man up.
Not in my precinct, all right?
I vouch for him.
Okay. Okay, I'm fuckin' sorry,
but your authority has been
super-fuckin'-seded.
You understand?
You're not in charge anymore.
Right, Bish? Bish, tell 'em.
He could be one of them, man,
so fuckin'easily.
You don't think
we see right through you?
Fuckin'believe that shit?
Comes in here playing that game,
playing stupid. You don't think we know?
Right, man?
Let's do the math.
Let's put him away, man,
just play it safe, you know?
Put it down.
No, no, no. Come on.
Come on, man. Come on.
Just do the math. Come on.
Motherfucker comes in like that,
playing...
[Beck Gasping]
[Gasping Continues]
Come here. Sergeant Roenick
is in charge. Understand?
"Yes."
Let's go.
Only because I respect you.
But I still say this shit
is fuckin' illogical bullshit, all right?
He may not be who he says he is.
Just mull that shit over.
Think it over. Think it over, man.
Iris, look after Capra,
fill him in on what's goin' on.
All right, Capra?
Just be cool so no one else here
gets spooked.
Everybody else,
back to your positions.
Thank you.
Don't.
That was self-preservation.
The more men we have,
the better chance we stand.
Are you sure
you vouch for this man?
I do.
Come with me.
You know, I hate to admit it,
but Smiley agrees with what
you said back there.
Smiley want a fuckin' medal?
Hear me out, man.
Look, we're out of our shackles
for what? The last time
in the next 15, 20 years?
All right, man. Get to the point.
What do you want?
Listen to me, man.
Look out that window.
That's freedom, baby.
Get what I'm sayin'?
Look, maybe this New Year's
can bring something different
for us after all.
Beck like Smiley now.
[Man]
Eight months ago he loses his team
when a deal goes sour.
Problem with drugs and alcohol
since the incident.
Burned-out cop.
Only a matter of time
before he drops his guard.
Watch the truck.
They'll eye it as a way out.
- What's the word on the A.V.?
- Storm's starting to let up,
so it shouldn't be long now.
Good.
Someone gets inside,
takes off, goes for help.
It's too obvious.
We'd need a distraction.
We also need the keys.
Your cop said he dropped 'em
in the snow.
- [Anna] I could hot-wire a car.
- I thought you never committed a crime
in your life?
- I haven't.
- Yeah.
Just picked up some shit
along the way.
Whoa. Hold on.
How do we know she's not just gonna drive
out of here and leave us all here to die?
Who the fuck are you, Miss Fuckin' Little Skirt?
Shake that skinny ass
in somebody else's face.
Okay, Anna. No offense,
but I'll feel better if somebody
goes with you.
Maybe I should go.
I promise I'll make her get help.
Scout's Honor.
It's either me orJasper.
[Bishop]
Can't be.
We need your guns.
It's gotta be...
[Alex]
Me.
- Me.
- [Bishop] You?
[Throaty Laugh]
- Shoot.
- Hey, I'll go. I'll do it.
- What? It's the only thing
that makes sense, right?
- [Anna] Whatever.
Whatever the fuck ever.
Let's just do this. Come on.
Me and... me and the doc.
Fine. Okay.
What? It's the right move,
Sergeant. I know that.
All right. All right.
I'm the doctor, right?
Right.
You can handle that?
Yes.
You can?
I don't know. I don't know.
But I have to try, okay?
No. No.
Please. I have to go.
I have to do it.
[Screams]
Shit!
Hey! Those two skels are buggin' out,
just like I told you they would.
They torched the bus
for a diversion, I guess.
Come on!
- [Roenick] Aw, Jesus.
They're gonna get themselves killed.
- They're dead already.
We can use this.
[Duvall]
Very smart.
They knew we'd expect them
to make for the car.
Free life, baby!
We did it.
Yeah. I told ya.
Happy New Year. Now, how are we
gonna get the fuck out of here?
Visual on two men. No shot.
Moving to a better vantage.
Hey. You sure
you wanna do this?
Yeah.
All right.
[Gunshot]
[Screams] Aw, shit!
- They're fucking shooting!
- Where'd they hit you, man?
My shoulder.
Let's go! Come on!
Let's haul ass now!
Okay, okay.
Go. Go.
You go.
[Yelping]
All right. Come on.
Come on, baby. Come on.
This was not the plan, man!
This was your idea.
Come on.
We're so fucking close. Come on.
I think I can still make it.
Come on, man. You can do it.
- I'm on target.
- [Gunshot]
Thirty-six, 45, 54, 63,
72, 81, 90, 99...
Come on, man.
What am I gonna do?
What am I gonna do, man?
- Don't make me go at this alone!
- [Sniper] Target two blocked.
- No shot.
- Have position but no shot.
[Continues Counting]
What the fuck's up with
that multiplication table shit?
Fuck you!
It's freakin' me out.
You couldn't hot-wire my ass!
You're a liar!
Liar?
I will bite your little white head
right the fuck off!
Forty-five, 54,
63, 72, 81, 90, 9, 18, 27, 36, 45...
What is taking so long?
I'm gonna make it for you, man!
I'm gonna do this for you!
[Grunts]
- [Engine Starts, Revs]
- Seventy-two, 81, 90, 99...
- Damn, motherfucker!
What did I tell y'all?
What'd I tell you?
You and your sergeant boyfriend
didn't believe me.
- What?
- Sergeant boy.
That's your boyfriend, right?
- No.
- Yeah.
They made it.
They're clear!
We made it.! We made it.!
Whoo!
[Gunshot]
[Horn Honking]
The skels are dead.
We don't have a goddamn chance,
do we?
Sarge. Sarge.
God-fucking-damn it, the five
of us can't hold them back.
They're gonna take out each
and every one of us. What are we
supposed to do, Sarge?
[As In Vacuum]
What are we supposed to do?
What the fuck
are we supposed to do?
I don't know.
[Man]
What do you wanna do, Marcus?
[Woman Gasping]
[Moaning, Gasping]
How many inside?
Uh... [Inhales Deeply]
A hundred.
Answer the question.
[Grunting, Gasping]
You're a brave woman.
What do you want to do
with the body, Marcus?
Bishop's men were responsible
for all this, remember?
Let's get this thing done.
Time's up, Sergeant.
Last stand.
Your gun would be appreciated.
Why did I let her go?
I know a lot about dying,
Sergeant.
There are two ways
you can handle it:
with the self-pity or without it.
Fuck you.
Get out of my office.
[Grunts]
I see you've made your decision.
[Bishop]
Sun's almost up.
Whatever Duvall's gonna do,
he's gonna do now. We need to get ready,
or we'll be trapped.
Now, who the fuck asked you?
You know, I've had all the shit
I'm gonna take from you, old man.
- Hey, fuck you, dealer.
- No.
Fuck with me.
- I should've fucked with you...
- Enough!
Bishop's right.
Jasper, you just watch the front here.
Iris, the cell block.
Capra, you're on.
Take the back stairs.
Bishop and I'll roam,
coverin'all the other entrances.
[Wind Whistling]
[Approaching Footsteps]
[Gun Cocks]
Hey.
What were you doing
by the back door? What were you doing?
What the fuck are you talking about?
I saw you.
What did you tell 'em?
Why didn't you let 'em inside?
Hmm?
What's the plan?
Aah!
- What's goin' on?
- [Bishop] You were wrong.
He's workin'for Duvall.
He removed the handcuffs
from the back door.
- What's the plan? Answer me.!
- [Yelps]
Fuck.! I'm a fuckin'police officer.!
I don't have to fuckin'answer you.!
- [Yelping]
- What's the plan, Officer?
Oh, so it's about you and me now,
huh, Sergeant?
It's not about me and you.
Not yet.
[Gun Cocks]
What were you doin'
by the back door, Capra?
It wasn't me, Jake.
- What's the plan?
- I wasn't there.
We let 'im live once.
He almost got us killed.
We let him live twice,
we deserve to die.
- You and I are friends, Jake.
You gonna do this to me?
- [Helicopter Blades Whirring Overhead]
- What is the plan?
- There is no fucking plan!
- Don't make me fucking kill you!
- What the fuck are you doin' to him?
Listen! They're coming!
[Man In Helicopter]
A. V. -5, getting into position.
Ten seconds to target.
- What the fuck
are they doin' up there?
- What do you think?
- [Gunfire]
- [Roenick] Save your ammo.
We don't know where they are.
[Clanking Overhead]
We need to make a move
outside.
- That's what they'd want us to do.
- Yeah. They'll pick us off, one by one.
[Clanking Continues]
Jake, I found a way out!
Down in the basement.
All right, Iris, Capra.
All right. Go.
Bishop, I need you.
Come on. Come on.
[Coughing]
[Gunfire]
[Gunfire Continues]
- It's an old sewer tunnel.
- Why didn't you mention it before?
I didn't think of it.
We've been a little bit busy.
I don't even know where it goes.
Of course, we can always stay here.
[Roenick]
It doesn't matter.
Goodjob, Jasper.
Okay. We need to move.
Fire department'll be here soon.
Here it is.
All right. It's all clear.
Everybody up.
Come on, Jasper.
[Grunting]
Thanks.
[Gasps]
[Gun Cocks]
- Son of a bitch! Jake!
- [Bishop] All right. Now.
Me and the secretary
are going bye-bye.
You don't follow, she don't get hurt.
You lower your weapons, gentlemen,
we can end this on a happy note.
My apologies, secretary.
Apology not fuckin' accepted.
[Man]
Hold it right there.!
Drop your fuckin'weapons right now.!
Down, motherfucker!
Down!
Goddamn it.!
Get down!
- How the hell did they find us?
- [Car Doors Closing]
Oh, my God.
It was Jasper at the back door.
You set us up, you motherfucker!
You just killed us, Jasper.
Fuck you, Jake!
Goddamn it. I told you,
"Just let 'em have the son of a bitch.
Nobody else gets hurt."
'Cause I ain't dyin'
for that piece of shit!
- Or for you either, Jake.
- I thought you were a cop.
Go in the truck, Jas.
You don't need to see this.
Bishop, you should've
taken that deal.
These men aren't cops, Sergeant.
They're criminals.
They're killers, just like me.
Ain't that right, old man?
Yeah, that's right.
That's right. You're goddamn right,
you son of a bitch!
- Not with your weapon.
- [Bishop Grunts]
[Blows Landing]
[Bishop Grunts]
Give me a clean piece.
Goddamn it!
Give me a clean piece!
Close your eyes.
- Let him finish it.
- [Gun Cocks]
Oh!
- [Jasper Grunts]
- [Man] Shit.! Get down.!
[Gunfire]
[Roenick]
The truck.! The truck.! The truck.!
[Gunfire Continues]
[Grunting]
[Groaning]
- Go!
- [Engine Starts, Revs]
[Gunfire Continues]
Get them!
[Gunfire]
[Capra Groaning]
You breathin'?
Good. Okay.
[Approaching Footsteps]
Oh, fuck. Fuck.
Just act like you're dead, okay?
[Groans]
[Panting]
[Twig Snaps]
- [Grunts]
[Yells]
Motherfucker!
[Screams]
Fuck you!
[Grunts]
You fuckin' bitch!
- [Flesh Tearing]
- [Iris Grunting]
[Gasps]
[Panting]
[Panting Quietly]
[Gun Cocks]
Hello, Sergeant.
[Gasps Quietly]
What the hell
are you still doin' here?
Marcus Duvall still lives.
For me, this is unacceptable.
So our shit's back on pause.
Is that it?
Yeah.
We have a problem.
Duvall and his men can see us.
We can't see them.
I'll draw their fire.
Their muzzle flashes
will give away their position.
Don't miss, Bishop.
Run fast, Sergeant.
[Yelps]
[Grunts, Pants]
Call Roenick.
Who's Roenick?
[Yelps, Groans]
Hurts like a bitch, doesn't it?
Call Roenick.
Tell him I'm dead.
You know me, Marcus.
I cannot tell a lie.
[Throaty Laugh]
Look at you.
When I first approached you
10 years ago, you couldn't
look me in the eye.
One of them nervous,
God-fearin' types.
Now you put a bullet in me,
no hesitation.
You're quite the changed man
this New Year's, Marcus.
Now, for the last fucking time,
call him.
[Yelps]
He doesn't have to.
Drop your weapon.!
[Gun Cocks]
- What are you waitin' for?
- Shut up!
- Put the gun down, Duvall.
- What are you gonna do? Shoot me?
- Arrest me? You gonna kill a cop?
- There's only one cop here.
Now put the goddamn gun down.
You're caught.
How many more people
are you gonna kill tonight?
As many as it takes.
You make me fuckin' sick.
Aw! Aw, fuck!
Aw, fuck!
[Groans, Gasps]
- [Gasps]
- [Sighs]
Ow.!
- [Grunts]
- Uh-uh.
So it's about that time, huh?
Looks that way, don't it?
Well, thanks.
- For what?
- You didn't call my name.
That was self-preservation,
Sergeant, and it worked.
I told ya.
I'm not gonna change.
You try to follow me,
you'll find out just how true that is.
You're not gonna
get very far.
I'll manage.
[Grunts]
Well, you take care
of yourself, Sergeant.
[Grunts]
I will find you.
No other cop. Just me.
[Groans]
Jesus.
[Grunts]
- [Iris] Sarge?
- [Officers Murmuring]
[Iris]
Sarge! Sergeant!
Yeah, Iris.
Oh, Christ. Look at you.
Shh. Shh.
It's okay. I told these firemen.
They're not leavin' us alone.
Not for a second. Okay?
All right. Help me up.
Ow! Ow.
We have some questions
for you, Sergeant.
I'd like to get this wound looked at first.
Anybody else out there?
No, man. There's nobody else.
Just me and... and them.
- [Officer]
Let me get you on a stretcher.
- No. No, man. It's all right.
I'm walkin' out of here.
[Sirens Wailing In Distance]
Oh, geez. Do you think
we have to show up
at the new precinct tomorrow?
[Groans]
Shit. This is fucking tempting.
No. Don't
break your resolution, huh?
Give me one.
I didn't make that promise.
[Whispers, Indistinct]
You know, Sarge, I didn't
even recognize you tonight.
You were like a whole different
bad-ass motherfucker back there, huh?
Mm. You think so?
Yeah.
Well, get used to it.
[Groans]
Happy New Year, Sarge.
"KRS-One 'bout
to wreck thejoint"
"Our scene opens up
at the edge of Detroit"
"Where the cops
go beyond the laws"
"Where enemies work together
by puttin'their shit on pause"
"So what does it mean
Assault on Precinct 13"
"You about to see
just what the dirt brings"
"It's working
that force I have been searching"
"Laurence Fishburne
when it's time to hurt things"
"Ethan Hawke, man
He faced all that"
"I hold my mike
likeJa held the baseball bat"
"I stay ahead
like a baseball cap"
"The ways of the world
Chris don't chase all that"
"We gettin'up outta here"
"That's the stuff, that's the stuff"
"Watch me back up the truck
You livin'with a lot of fear"
"That's the stuff, yes they are"
"You're crooked cops
you backin'me up"
"We gettin'up outta here"
"That's the stuff, that's the stuff"
"Watch me back up the truck"
"You livin'with a lot of fear"
"That's the stuff, yes they are"
"Crooked cops, you backin'me up"
"As I walk through the street
my spirit will speak to those I meet
and greet from week to week"
"I am not on my hands and feet
I command to speak as the observer
inside the physique"
"Many rappers tried to compete
of course"
"But they got smashed and trashed
in the streets and tossed"
"Sometimes I think we all just lost
Wejust flashin'across in a disastrous course"
"We don't even know the oneness
of the only force"
"Instead of a golden calf
we got a platinum horse"
"What did Moses do
with the golden calf"
"Threw the Lord at it
and it ended in a blast"
"Master, you wanna quit
we'll run faster"
"In the background, you burnin'
'cause it's nothin'but laughter"
"I tag shirts like the shirt king
Turn up the track for Assault on Precinct 13"
"We gettin'up outta here"
"That's the stuff, that's the stuff"
"Watch me back up the truck
You livin'with a lot of fear"
"That's the stuff, yes they are"
"Two crooked cops
You backin'me up"
"We gettin'up outta here"
"That's the stuff, that's the stuff"
"Watch me back up the truck
You livin'with a lot of fear"
"That's the stuff, yes they are"
"Two crooked cops
you backin'me up"
[Bishop]
Our shit's on pause.
Precinct 13.
[Bishop, Echoing]
That was self-preservation.
[Rapper, Echoing]
Thirteen.
[Bishop]
Relax, Sergeant. Our shit's on pause.
[Rapper] Precinct 13.
[Bishop]
Relax, Sergeant. Our shit's on pause.
[Rapper]
"Wow, what an ending
what a conclusion"
"They thought they was winnin'
but they really was losin'"
"He thought he was sinnin'
but he really was provin'"
"That leadership keeps it moving
steady cruising"
"Guns up, fun's up
from sunup to sunup to sunup"
"But-But-But, yo, Doc"
"We wound up
two down, one up"
[Indistinct]
"And get butterflies in they stomach"
"Brothers can't speak
theyjust shut up"
"KRS on the comeup
liftin'big pun up
Let me sum up"
"[Rapping, Indistinct]
"Brace the drummer
or breath for breath
I'll rip your lung up"
"On my trophy wall
I'm there with your tongue off"
"KRS-One, you know what it means
turn up the track for Assault on Precinct 13"
"We gettin'up outta here"
"That's the stuff, that's the stuff"
"Watch me back up the truck
You livin'with a lot of fear"
"That's the stuff, yes they are"
"Two crooked cops, you backin'me up
We gettin'up outta here"
"That's the stuff, that's the stuff"
"Watch me back up the truck"
"You livin'with a lot of fear"
"That's the stuff, yes they are"
"Two crooked cops
you backin'me up"
"We gotta start trustin'each other
if we gonna make it through this night"
"From criminal mind into spiritual mind
and even beyond and behind"
"They better be your friend or fight
or be the lazy type"
"Me, I'm the crazy type
I give them thugs some crazy hype"
"I've thrown the classics on
with them ladies, right"
"And years later
rocked with they babies like"
"I blazed a light
They may be eight million ways to die
but they's 16 million ways to fight"
"So wherever you are
in your crib or your car
or your tank too"
"Jean Francois would like
to thank you right"
"That's why, can I wrestle the mike
wishin'you peace for the rest
of the night"
"'Cause at the end of the film
you'll see what it mean"
"Turn up the track for
Assault on Precinct 13"
Ripped by dj-oRi