[man laughs lasciviously]
Come on, honey, get it all off!.
Come on, make me stand up
for queen and country.
Show us what you got! [laughs]
Come on, honey. Come on,
all of it. Yeah, there you go.
And the rest! [laughs]
Ah, come on, babe.
If one more person calls me ""babe"",...
[groans]
Mr Santo, the package has arrived.
- My special order?.
- Under lock and key.
- What about the new dancer?.
- Who?.
The blonde with the guns.
Ah, if she"s more to your pleasing.
It"s her first night. I haven"t had
a chance to feel her out.
But you"ll be pleased
with the special order.
She is as tender as Tuscan veal.
How"s the crowd, honey?.
- Wet.
- [speaks French]
- Come again.
- She"s Chinese.
Very well done. They loved you.
I"d like to talk to you
about coming back. In my office.
- l"ll be waiting for you.
- Sure thing, big boy.
[door slams, footsteps]
What are you doing here?.
Looking for a light.
Oh.
- Got one?.
- I don"t smoke.
- [blows out sharply]
- [groans]
Neither do l.
- Who are you?.
- l"m getting you out of here. Trust me.
- [man] Right this way, Mr Santo.
- Shit. Come on.
- Go!
- Ahh!
Minka!
[both breathing heavily]
Uh.
[speaks unidentified language]
[gasps]
- What are you doing?.
- Ever see Batman?
No, I can"t.
No. No! [screams]
[girl screams]
Shut up.
Goddamn it!
[gunshoi]
[girl gasps]
Here"s your little pride and joy.
Thank you. Thank you
from the bottom of our hearts.
We thought we"d never see
our little girl again. Thank you.
Cut the shit. Where"s my money?.
Honey, pay this woman.
I"m afraid there"s been
a slight problem.
I could only come up with
half the money.
Half the money?.
Fine. I"ll take half your daughter.
Wait. I"m sure
we can negotiate something.
[ Michael Hutchence: Spill the Wine]
The car plus the cash.
Not a bad night's work.
[Barb Wire] It was the Second American
Civil War. The world had gone to hell.
The year was 201 7.
The worst year of my life.
There was only one free city.
And that's where I lived
for three years.
ort Steel Harbor.
What a shithole.
[girl moans]
[man] Why don"t we start again?.
From the beginning.
I told you.
I told you everything I know.
- I told you.
- [aide] Mind scan up on screen one.
[computer] Image is present.
Image is recording.
Citizen, l... uh, I abhor torture.
But your words
just don"t match your thoughts.
There are too many details
you"re just not sharing with us.
Our little mind-reading device
doesn"t lie.
[groans]
[computer] Reset sensors.
[metallic clanking]
Now, where"s Dr Corrina Devonshire?.
She"s going to Steel Harbor,
the free city.
Can you tell me why
Cora D"s going to Steel Harbor?.
She"s meeting members of the resistance.
They"re giving her the retinal lenses.
Helping her out of the country,
to Canada.
She's with a freedom fighter named Axel.
Who has the retinal lenses now?.
Krebs. William Krebs.
How are they getting her
into the city?.
She"s had plastic surgery. Her face has
changed. You won"t recognise her.
- You"ll never find her.
- You"re so beautiful. I"m sorry.
Colonel, Executive Council on line two.
Tell him to hold.
- [klaxon]
- Subject terminated.
Colonel PryZer, any word yet
on our traitorous doctor, Cora D?
I"m not gonna pander to
that mythic-name bullshit.
Well, Dr Devonshire still poses
quite a problem to the Congressionals.
Her escape may jeopardise
our strongest defensive action yet.
I"m fully aware of that, citizen.
Dr Devonshire was privy to
the most sensitive military secrets
of the Republic.
Her DNA holds the antidote to our
greatest biochemical weapon.
She must be captured alive at any cost.
I"ll take care of your problem, citizen.
I"ll get my hands dirty for you again.
I wouldn"t be cleaning up your mess,
if you"d stopped her
from escaping Washington.
[coughs] Well, I, uh... I had no
direct knowledge of that operation.
Of course it was a vital part
of our contract to...
Save it for the UN.
Dr Corrina Devonshire, Cora D,
whatever she calls herself,
it really doesn"t matter.
She belongs to me.
She's connecting with a resistance
contact named Krebs.
He has the lenses and will help
her leave the Congressional territories.
They're meeting in the free city,
Steel Harbor.
I'll contact their
local authorities immediately.
You see, I do my homework, citiZen.
It"s them. Let"s go.
- Which one of you"s Krebs?.
- We"ll meet him later.
- Hurry.
- [she sighs]
[men grunt and groan]
I said get to the back of the line.
[groans]
[man] Gentlemen,
l"ll take those weapons.
[woman] Don"t lose the clip.
[ heavy rock song]
Dry Martinis and a Cuban cigar.
You got it.
Bubbly on the house.
- Oomph!
- Please, be polite.
- Excuse me, Curly.
- Hey, hey, hey.
I"m still waiting to hear
from Miss Wire.
I conveyed your offer to her.
$1,500 to chop off the legs
of your ex-partner?.
You must be joking.
Naturally, she declined.
Miss Wire doesn"t accept
this kind of job.
Please.
What?. My money is not
good enough for her?.
I will make my offer in person.
- I wouldn"t do that.
- Why?.
Miss Wire"s private secretary,
Camille here,
doesn"t have you in her appointment book
and she can be very mean.
- You see?.
- [DJ] Time for a couple of dedications.
To Bobby from Carlene, ""The tests came
back and everything is cool.""
From Samantha to Kyle,
""You thieving, murderous bastard.""
""lf I ever see you again, l"ll rip out
your eyes and pluck off your ears.""
Damn, but that don"t
just tug at my heart strings.
Now here's a little rhythm
for you heartsick boys and girls.
Chanel No 5, am I correct?.
- Yes, you are.
- Ah.
When I smelled it, I thought to myself,
Charlie, now this is obviously
a woman of significant breeding.
And then I thought,
I wonder if she"d like to do some.
Breeding, that is. What do you think
about that, sweetheart?.
Who are you talking to?.
Some chick.
- Where"s your mercurial sister?.
- Why don"t you try the office?.
Oh, and when you see her,
tell her I only had two.
OK, whatever you say, Charlie.
That"s my boy.
[thunder]
[siren]
Goddamn!
Customs police.
Stay put. We"ll handle this.
- Evening, Officer.
- You got your lD?.
- Something feels wrong.
- This is making me very nervous.
Look. We just stick with the plan, OK?.
- [gunshoi]
- Change of plans.
- Let"s go.
- Get out of here!
- We got "em.
- Hold your fire!
Oh, shit. Damn!
[blows whistle] Find "em now!
[coughs] l"m sorry, boss. Is this a good
moment to talk about the payroll?.
- No.
- Tonight"s fanmail.
Three offers to sell black market
dollars, another to buy the bar,
an urgent request
to contact the resistance,
and a badly scented
proposal of marriage.
No more Valentines, Curly.
Oh, stop.
Look, boss, I hate to keep
bringing this up, I really do,
but tomorrow"s payday.
What am I going to use
for money, a smile?.
Relax, Curly, I got it covered.
- Are we going out?.
- For a while.
- Just how far out are we going to go?.
- I want to get some air.
- I thought you got some air last night.
- That didn"t happen.
This isn"t happening either.
Anybody asks, l"m taking a bubble bath.
Barb, I just don"t like...
Just keep Charlie out from under
the tables. It"s embarrassing.
I will.
[radio chatter]
- [splintering bone] Ahh!
- Sweet dreams.
OK. OK, let"s go.
- Now what?.
- We find Krebs.
- Any bright ideas how?.
- Just one.
[Barb Wire] I had to do some
moonlighting to keep my bar running.
Not an easy life. A girl's got to do
what a girl's got to do.
And in this world,
you got to use everything you got.
- Hey, handsome, want some company?.
- Are you a cop?.
See a badge?.
- You got your med reg?.
- Full medical. Checked yesterday.
- How much is this gonna cost me?.
- That depends on how you want to play.
- I like to play rough.
- Me too.
[small man] Hey, nice nuts.
[Barb] Get a life.
[distant gunshots]
Apartment 472. One guest.
[computer] Apartment 472. One guest.
[computer] Retinal scan verified.
Ruben Tenenbaum. 1081 1.
How romantic.
Ooh. I have an idea.
Go change into something
a little more comfortable.
How about something
less comfortable?.
I can hardly wait.
Bingo. Mr Krebs.
- Did you wash your hands?.
- No. I was bad.
I"m so glad to hear that.
Now close your eyes and turn around.
Oops.
What the hell?.
No! I wouldn"t do that
if I were you, Krebs.
Come on, move your ass.
Shit.
Go ahead, go.
Ha!
Haaa!
- You"re not going soft on me?.
- OK. You can have him.
Good.
You"re my last bail jumper, Krebs.
Wake up, sunshine.
- Please don"t kill me.
- That was nice kicking.
You really know your stuff, babe.
What did you call me?.
Don"t call me babe.
Goddamn it.
Ah, Mr Krebs,
it"s a pleasure to see you.
You know, we were getting
very concerned.
And, Barb, it"s a pleasure
to see you too.
You"re looking
rather buoyant this evening.
- Shut up. My fee.
- 1 0,000...
- No. The price went up for this one.
- We had an agreement.
You told me Krebs was alone
and unarmed. He wasn"t.
- [Krebs] Sorry.
- How could I know that?.
Bounty hunting is an ugly,
unpredictable business.
Barb, you of all people
should know that. How much?.
20,000.
- Canadian.
- Oh, Miss Wire.
I do believe that l"m being
extorted here.
And as a duly authorised officer
of the court, I must protest.
Look at it this way, Schmitz.
Alive, Krebs represents
your investment in his bail bond...
...dead, he"s toxic waste.
20,000 Canadian, now.
It"s a pleasure doing business with you.
If it was a pleasure,
l"d charge more.
[ heavy rock song]
- Everything go OK?.
- Candy from a baby.
- Pay the help, for God"s sakes.
- In public?.
Excuse me, Miss Wire. Hi, hi.
Uh... I"m going back
to the front lines tomorrow
and I was wondering...
You look beautiful.
Would... would you dance with me?.
Come on, Barb. Give him a thrill.
OK. Come on.
- Oh...
- Yeah!
[ rock ballad]
[laughs nervously]
I can"t believe l"m actually
dancing with the Barb Wire.
Where are you from, soldier?.
Uh... Steamboat Springs, Colorado,
or what"s left of it.
Did you hear the Congressionals
just took over Denver?.
No, I didn"t.
Do you have a girl back home?.
- Yeah.
- Do you miss her?.
Yes, ma"am, every day.
Tell you what, close your eyes,
and let"s pretend
she"s right here in your arms.
Yes, ma"am.
Everyone stay where you are.
This is the police.
[Barb]
Willis, Steel Harbor's chief of police.
He was a drunk with sticky fingers,
but at least he was honest.
He admitted he was a liar and a thief.
- Check his lD.
- Yes, sir.
[computer] Retinal scan verified.
Lawrence Crabtree. 57239.
Ben Jones, eh?.
Arrest him.
- [Crabtree] Hey, come on!
- Good luck, soldier.
- Next.
- Hey!
- [computer] Retinal scan verified.
- Arrest her.
- What the hell"s going on here?.
- How lovely to see you.
- What gives?.
- lt"s a messy business tonight.
Most unpleasant. A rather spectacular
double homicide in the old harbor.
- So?.
- So we"re checking a few lDs.
We believe
this might have been resistance-related.
And as your bar is non-discriminating
to this town"s more nefarious side...
- How long is this gonna take?.
- Everything"s negotiable.
- Curly.
- Music.
You really upgraded this place from what
it was. I like the new sound system.
- Sounds expensive.
- l"ve been saving my lunch money.
I didn"t know you were open for lunch.
A little gun running, some bail jumping.
The occasional midnight detonation.
Those are the kind of jobs
that pay for new toys.
- I don"t moonlight.
- I do.
It"s very profitable.
So what"s with
the bullshit arrests this time?.
You sold half those
fake lDs yourself.
Moi?. Bullshit arrests?.
Two of my men are dead.
Granted, they were homicidal thugs,
but nevertheless, they were my men.
What makes you think
the resistance was involved?.
Why?. Do you have any other information
I should know about?.
- Of course not.
- Mmm. Of course not.
Oh, that"s sexual harassment, Chief.
Listen, Barbara Kopetski, we could play
cat and mouse all night long,
but I have more important things
on my mind.
Now, where the hell is William Krebs?.
Never heard of him.
Why are your men watching him?.
That"s classified police business.
I can tell you he was resistance
and there"s
a million-dollar bounty on his head.
So if someone knew where Krebs was,
I could make it worth their while.
Goodbye, Willis.
OK.
By the way, Barb, we"re expecting
some distinguished visitors tomorrow.
A Congressional delegation
out of Washington,
including First Directorate
Colonel Victor Pryzer.
- I might bring "em by the Hammerhead.
- Their money"s welcome.
You don"t know Victor Pryzer.
Speaking of money,
I don"t have to make any more arrests
tonight for, say, the usual 3,000.
- 1,500.
- 1,500?.
I better go down
and start checking some more lDs.
- 2,500.
- Two grand.
- Darling.
- Thirty bucks for the cognac.
Add it to my tab, Miss Kopetski.
Boom, boom, boom.
Miss Kopetski died in the war.
I"m Barb Wire.
Cigarettes and a drink
and l"ll be fine.
Give me a goddamn drink. You,
you or you, just give me my drink.
- Sir, we"re not open yet.
- I think you"ve had enough already.
Ah, blow me.
Camille, package check.
[he whimpers]
Get her off! Get her off of me!
That"s Camille. She works here.
Camille, sit.
[he groans]
- You want to see her roll over?.
- No, no, no.
Good. Camille, outside.
[growls]
- Have a nice day.
- Yes, ma"am.
Joe, see if you can get some food
down Charlie"s neck.
Willis, what"s with the monkey suit?.
You know how uniforms
impress the Congressionals.
The Delegation arrived this morning.
They could be here any minute.
- Excuse me, Barb.
- My table?.
Best in the house, as requested.
Just keep them away
from the weapons check.
We don"t want any customers from
the United Front trying to get even.
You"ll find our guests from Washington
command more respect than that.
You"re confusing respect with fear.
[loud clang]
[guns being cocked]
Speak of the devil.
They are punctual, l"ll give "em that.
You"ll join us for a drink later?.
On my tab, of course.
Fat chance.
Colonel Pryzer, Alexander Willis,
Director of Police Operations.
- Welcome to Steel Harbor.
- Wipe that smile off your face.
This burnt-out hell-hole is the last
place on earth I want to be.
If it wasn"t for
your almost complete incompetence,
I wouldn"t be here
in the first place, would l?.
Yes, well, needless to say,
we had intended to have both Krebs
and Cora D sent to Washington by now.
Due to circumstances
outside our control...
Listen, carefully.
If Cora D escapes...
...I will personally
rip your heart out of your ass
and stuff it back down your throat.
That"s not very sanitary.
[DJ] You say it"s late, and l"m here
to tell you, it only feels that way.
So sit back and enjoy someone or
something illicit if you can get it,
and listen to the music.
Gentlemen, the steaks
are excellent tonight.
Ah, Colonel Pryzer,
allow me to introduce
our hostess, the inimitable...
Even in Washington,
we"ve heard of Barb Wire.
I hope you"ll join us.
Mm.
- You attract a very eclectic crowd.
- It looks that way.
Rumour is you used to fight
with the resistance.
You shouldn"t believe
everything you hear. I"m neutral.
- l"m a businesswoman, Colonel.
- Perhaps we can do business.
I can assure you,
Barb has a very keen sense of commerce.
Then l"ll get to the point. There"s
a fugitive, a traitor in Steel Harbor.
She intends to cross into Canada,
with the help of some of
the more disenchanted citizenry.
Do I look disenchanted?.
I"m sure your business brings you
into contact with all levels of society.
I thought you were
getting to the point.
Her name is Dr Corrina Devonshire,
but you may have heard of her as Cora D.
One of those overly romanticised
resistance names.
Keeps her legend alive.
- What does she look like?.
- We"re not sure.
She had her appearance
surgically altered.
These are photos of her before.
It"s hard to find somebody unless
you know what she looks like.
Her appearance is of no consequence.
Identification can always be
made by retinal scanning.
So... the Congressionals
can count on your assistance?.
Excuse me, boss. Trouble in the kitchen.
I need you.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I have a bar to run.
- Very interesting woman.
- With most impressive assets.
Gentlemen. Here you are, sir.
Act natural?.
That"s easier said than done.
Two beers, buddy. I was looking for
Barb or Charlie Kopetski.
Charlie"s down there.
The Congressionals.
- They have my photographs.
- Let"s hope resistance are here.
- They"ll be looking everywhere for you.
- Well, who are we meeting?.
Someone I used to know.
Wait here.
Hello, Charlie.
This must be
a post-traumatic stress flashback.
I could swear I just heard
an old voice from the battlefield.
Surprised to see me?.
Do I look surprised?.
Guess you didn"t hear.
A Congressional smart grenade. It
followed me all the way to my foxhole.
I thought l"d dug it deep enough.
I guess I didn"t.
- l"m sorry.
- Yeah. Me too.
Miss, two bourbons.
[laughs] You don"t have to
buy me a drink, Axel.
I"m tight with the management here.
You got a lot of nerve coming in here.
I had no choice. Where"s Barb?.
I don"t think talking to Barb"s
a good idea.
She took Seattle
a lot harder than I did.
I need her help, Charlie. I need her to
put us in touch with local resistance.
Haven"t you heard?.
Barb"s retired.
Leave, now, before Barb sees you.
- There"s no telling what she"ll do.
- There he is.
Too late.
Three...
- Two...
- Hello, Barb.
One.
- You all right?.
- I guess I deserved that.
Get out.
- I need your help.
- Rot in hell.
I will. I remember
when you believed in something.
I remember how it felt.
Like I was kicked in the stomach.
I"m looking for a man named Krebs.
I"ve got 24 hours.
I don"t even know how I feel.
I don"t feel much anymore.
- Just trust me, please.
- Trust you. Like I did in Seattle?.
It was not what you think.
I never wanted to hurt you.
- Now"s not the time to explain.
- You"re three years late, Axel.
- Get out and don"t come back.
- Your check, sir.
Such blatant disregard for money.
Thank you for you hospitality.
I do hope you"ll think about our offer.
I"m thinking about it.
- I knew it. I shouldn"t have come here.
- That woman"s in love with you.
There are a lot of things
I need to tell you.
- Well, I hope...
- [Charlie] Axel, over here.
Charlie?.
I can help.
The blind leading the blind.
Go to the old factory district. There's
a place called Steel Harbor Metalworks.
It's a front for the resistance.
There's a stairway in the back
near the loading dock.
Watch yourself.
[guns being cocked]
[Cora] Shit.
[through voicebox] Who are you?
Charlie Kopetski sent us. It doesn"t
matter who I am, but this is Cora D.
Scan 'em.
[computer] Retinal scan verified.
Dr Corrina Devonshire. 44791.
Cora D, I admire you.
We've been looking for you.
I never thought
I'd meet the legend in person.
I'm commander here. They call me Spike.
- You"re so young.
- Maybe, but l"m tough.
We"re glad we found you.
We hope that you can help us, Spike.
It took us a while, but we found Krebs.
The lenses are gone,
not to mention his eyeballs.
He was in an abandoned
washing machine at the old VA hospital.
The Congressionals took the lenses?.
No, the Congressionals are
still looking for Krebs. We know that.
The local cops don't know squat either.
Everybody's chasing their tail.
So who"s got the contact lenses now?.
Krebs was turned over
to a bail bondsman named SchmitZ.
SchmitZ was aiming to turn him over to
the Congressionals for the bounty.
- Then he got wise to the lenses.
- Worth two million on the black market.
Without them, there"s no way l"ll get
past the retinal scan and on that plane.
Now, let"s get Schmitz.
It's not that easy.
We can't find him anywhere.
- That plane leaves in 24 hours.
- There must be someone that can help.
One person in Steel Harbor
has connections on all sides.
If anyone knows where SchmitZ is,
she does.
Trouble is, she won't help nobody
for free and we're a little low on cash.
You know I do.
Honey, don"t make me say it, OK?.
I love you. Bye.
- [laughter]
- What are you two laughing at?.
- Who was that?.
- Your mother.
- Three.
- How many?.
Put that down!
- Give me two.
- Your bet, Moe.
- l"ll bet, when I get ready. Just wait.
What"s going on?.
Attention!
I don"t know how you do things
in Washington,
but I do make the occasional arrest
without slaughter.
You incompetent.
We needed to make an interrogation.
Sorry, sir. They resisted.
Any of these men Schmitz?.
Nope.
Look who"s here.
Krebs. Cora D can"t be far.
I"ll need one of the bodies.
Preferably one without a head wound.
[stick tapping on floor]
Hey, hey, you want some company?.
No.
OK. Do you want some advice?.
OK.
Drink when you want to remember, Barb,
not when you want to forget.
[pouring amplified]
[Axel in her head]
I'll be there. I promise.
[siren, gunfire]
- [whistling shell]
- Let"s go!
- We have to go now!
- No. He"ll be here.
- Barb!
- Axel!
- Are you Barbara Kopetski?.
- Yes. Where"s Axel?.
He"s not coming.
He said he"s sorry,
but you got to get out of here.
You guys got to
get out of here, go, go, go!
That"s it. Come on, let"s go.
Come on, get in, get in.
You cheated me
out of a million bucks, Schmitz.
I should blow your head off right now.
Lucky for me, you don"t hold a grudge.
Don"t l?.
A million dollars is pocket change
to what"s going down.
I got a business proposition. You got
connections, everyone knows that.
I don"t take sides.
Exactly. You deal with everybody.
I got something to deal.
- You can"t sell Krebs on your own?.
- lt"s not about Krebs anymore.
It"s about retinal contact lenses.
They"re smuggled in from Germany.
Put these in your eyes,
you get through any retinal scanner,
Congressional or UN.
I was gonna sell "em,
but it fell through.
Krebs was resistance.
Those belong to his friends.
Do yourself a favour.
Give "em back and say you"re sorry.
Goddamn it, Barb, I can"t.
They"ll kill me and you know it.
The Congressionals broke into my office.
They slaughtered everybody.
They were looking for me.
With or without these, l"m a dead man.
Relax, Schmitz, you can only die once.
Barb...
I know I double-crossed you.
I made a mistake. It happens.
I want to trade the lenses.
- I want to trade them to you.
- For what?.
Get me out of Steel Harbor. Canada,
maybe. Get me out and they"re yours.
You want out?. Click your heels
together three times.
You could sell these.
You know how much they"re worth?.
You could get two mill Canadian, easy.
That"s enough money to get to Europe.
You could get a neuro-electrical
operation for Charlie.
I don"t buy. I don"t sell. Get out.
You"re gonna regret not dealing with me.
You"re gonna regret this
very, very much.
I"ll add that to my list.
The subject is reasonably fresh,
but we"ll only get a few seconds
of readable data.
Cognitive impressions,
closest to death first,
and then what"s left, memories, dreams.
- Record it.
- Yes, sir. Step away from the tank.
- That"s it?.
- Here it is in slow-motion, Colonel.
Issue a warrant
for the arrest of Barb Wire.
Issue a warrant?. This isn"t Washington.
I need a reason.
She"s involved.
You heard what he said.
Sometimes all you get are dreams.
Every man in Steel Harbor
dreams about Barb Wire.
- I need something more conclusive...
- When did the law ever matter to you?.
Miss Wire may know
the whereabouts of the lenses.
- We"ll search her bar.
- Retinal lenses?.
This is over a set of Bausch and Lombs?.
It"s over capturing
an enemy of the Republic.
a traitor named Cora D.
If Cora D were to exit
this charming free city,
your relationship with the Republic
would be severely compromised...
...painfully compromised.
- Do I make myself clear?.
- Mm-hm.
Your administrative fee will cover
the cost of a search warrant.
Now, find a reason
to search the Hammerhead.
As you wish, Colonel, as you wish.
I"m unarmed.
How did you get in here?. Where"s my dog?.
Hey, l"m irresistible to females.
Thanks, Camille.
Towel.
- What?. Are you gonna shoot me?.
- Why waste a good bullet?.
I told you never to come back.
I came here to do a job.
The biggest operation
I ever signed up for.
And I came ready for anything
the Congressionals could lob at me.
The only thing I wasn"t prepared for
was running into you.
You"ll get over it. I did.
- I wouldn"t have come unless I had to.
- I wouldn"t be here if l"d known.
Goddamn it!
I guess it"s bad timing for both of us.
Am I interrupting something?.
Lovely, you brought company.
Barb, this is my wife, Cora D.
How impressive. I"m sure
you"ll have very strong, smart children.
Look, I know this is awkward
for all of us,
and, Barb, all I ever wanted in Seattle
was to disappear with you.
- The war changed that.
- [Cora] It changed everything.
Good one.
I"m not surprised
you don"t believe me.
The mission took months.
I thought after so long,
I was better left in your past.
So that"s why
I didn"t get a wedding invitation?.
There"s more to this story
than meets the eye.
Remember what happened
in Topeka, Kansas?.
How the whole city was wiped out?.
I can explain.
I was chief of medical research
for the Congressionals.
I was directly but unknowingly involved
in a globally catastrophic project,
an HlV derivative known as Red Ribbon.
It can kill you in 1 2 hours.
When I learned Topeka, Kansas,
was a lab experiment,
and they planned to unleash
Red Ribbon on the free territories,
I defected to the resistance.
Axel helped me
get out of Washington.
Initially, we married purely
for identification purposes.
- We"ve been on the run ever since.
- How utterly goddamn heroic.
Now, what do you want with me?.
Cora has the Red Ribbon vaccine in
her system. The Congressionals want it.
We have to show the Truce Commission
there"s a cure to the epidemic.
We have to tell the world. We need your
help. The cause needs your help.
- What"s the cause done for me lately?.
- Barb, where are the contact lenses?.
- If I knew, you think l"d tell you?.
- We know Schmitz was here last night.
If you know where the lenses are,
for Christ"s sake just name a price.
That"s what you do, isn"t it?.
Sell yourself to the highest bidder?.
I"m out of your price range.
[soldier] Go!
- Is there another way out of here?.
- They"ll have every exit covered.
Fall in, ladies!
Give me three minutes
and meet me downstairs.
- Why should we trust you?.
- Maybe you shouldn"t.
- Check him.
- Yes, sir.
- Hey!
- Head back.
He doesn"t have any retinas, you morons.
Sorry about that, Charlie.
- We"re not open for breakfast.
- lt"s legal. We have a warrant.
It"s a little sticky.
What exactly are you looking for?.
- This is a murder investigation.
- lt"s a Congressional matter.
I can assure you, citizen, that
if we discover that you"re involved,
the consequences would be
abrupt and severe.
- Who are they?.
- I picked them up on the boulevard.
I like a good menage every now and then.
Go out through the back.
Scan "em.
This is ridiculous.
Malfunction,
malfunction, malfunction, malfunction.
Sir, the scanner"s broken, sir.
[tuts]
Idiot.
You"re wasting my time. Get out.
How long is this gonna take?.
As long as it takes, citizen,
as long as it takes.
[whistle]
- I wish you could see this mess.
- I couldn"t see it when it was clean.
What the hell were they looking for?.
- Stupid contact lenses.
- Oh, yeah?.
Schmitz was here trying
to trade them for a trip to Canada.
- I should"ve done it.
- Contact lenses?.
Yeah.
Like these?.
- What colour are they?.
- The colour of money.
Give them to Axel
and help them escape.
No. This is our ticket to Europe.
- They don"t belong to us.
- Finders keepers.
I believe in
fighting for what"s right.
Cheer up, baby brother, we"re rich.
You"re making a mistake, Barb.
- Tell me when we get to Paris.
- A big one.
- Charlie, you worry too much.
- lt"s not just about money.
I knew Charlie was still friendly
with the resistance,
but I didn't know how friendly.
[ Johnette Napolitano: She's So Free]
- What"s the purpose?.
- He"s expecting me.
Let her through.
Big Fatso.
How"s the king of the underworld?.
Well, well, well,
if it isn"t Barb the buxom.
A gesture.
Ooh. Doughnuts.
I thought l"d be hearing
from you real soon.
I have a proposition.
Oh, now, ain"t that sweet. But you know
I only like big, fat women.
[henchmen laugh]
A business proposition.
As in lenses?.
Don"t give me that surprised look like
you don"t know what l"m talking about.
You didn"t drive through the evil
empire"s heart to see about my diet.
You came here to talk about
the contact lenses, didn"t you?.
- l"m able to broker their sale.
- That"s what I heard.
I believe
you"ve already met... Mr Schmitz.
- Never looked better.
- Let"s make a deal.
Spike?.
Anybody?.
It"s Charlie, l"m here.
- [man] Spike ain"t here.
- Well, where is she?.
She knows I was supposed
to meet her here.
She sent me instead.
Yeah, well, I talk to Spike
or I talk to nobody.
If the resistance wants to know
where those lenses are, get me Spike.
Coming right down.
[machinery starts up]
- Spike.
- Charlie Kopetski.
Hold him.
You"re charged with concealing
information regarding the whereabouts
of certain lenses.
You can cooperate and talk to me.
- Or you can join your little friend.
- l"d rather join my friend.
- One million Canadian.
- Deal.
I"m not done yet.
There"s a plane I want to catch.
It"s at the old airport. On the other
side of the unoccupied zone.
Ooh, unoccupied zone.
[laughs] Bad part of town.
I want safe passage for Charlie and l
through the unoccupied zone.
That means an escort
all the way to the airport.
The zone can be unpredictable and
the toll collector"s quite difficult.
I"d have to staff
a few more men here, there.
How about half a mill Canadian?.
- 750 up front.
- Deal. You got the lenses?.
What do I look, new?.
I"ll meet you at the toll
into the unoccupied zone
an hour before sundown.
Cash for the lenses right there.
You"re five minutes late,
I sell to another buyer.
- [electrical crackling]
- [Charlie screams]
What"s wrong with the screen?.
It"s not picking up his thoughts.
[aide] He has no visual data
for that period.
Goddamn it. Where are the lenses?.
Speak now, man,
or suffer at your leisure.
The Easter Bunny took them.
I"ll talk. I"ll talk.
- This guy has them.
- What guy?.
He"s fat, wears a red suit,
white beard, name"s Kringle,
Kris Kringle.
[they both laugh]
Merry Christmas!
[he laughs]
[ Curly sings Lili Marlene in German]
[woman] He was trying to give me
just $50.
- What a mess.
- Well, this mess is all yours, Curly.
- The bar is yours.
- Get out.
I"m giving it to you.
Me and Charlie, we"re history.
What do you mean?. You"re leaving
forever?. You"re not coming back?.
Look, Barb, I have no experience
in running a bar.
- l"m just a waiter, for Christ"s sake.
- Curly, relax. You"re a natural.
Camille.
Well, this is it.
- l"m gonna miss you.
- l"m gonna miss you too, Curly.
Now, take care of Camille, OK?.
Yeah, right.
I never thought l"d see the day you
drive away in that horrible thing.
- Where"s Charlie?. He should be here.
- He went to see an old friend of his.
Someone named Spike.
Spike?. Get in.
Oh, God.
Charlie!
Oh, my God.
- What happened?.
- They"re just kids.
- [sob]
- What"s that?.
Charlie.
We heard the Congressionals
discovered this place.
- We were on our way to warn them.
- Yeah, well you were too late.
Listen, Barb, we need your help.
There"s no more time.
That plane leaves in 90 minutes. You"re
the only one who could help us now.
For Charlie?.
[Curly, coughing]
l"ll take care of Charlie.
Let"s go.
- What about the lenses?.
- They"re safe.
She won"t be able to get on
the plane without the lenses.
- Let"s have them.
- I said they"re safe.
Are you coming or not?.
Does the word ""overkill""
mean anything to you?.
- Have you ever driven in Steel Harbor?.
- No.
Then shut up.
- [Cora] What"s this?.
- lt"s a road block.
On the other side
is the unoccupied zone.
There"s a toll.
- You two stay here.
- What"s going on?.
This is our escort.
Whoo, look at her! All gussied up.
- Nice jewellery, Barb?.
- You got the money?.
No chit-chat?.
Have it your way.
- I said cash.
- Hey, I had to work fast.
It"s a gold debit card
with 750,000 credit on it.
- lt"s as good as cash.
- That wasn"t part of the deal, Fatso.
I told you, I had to work fast.
You got the lenses?.
Nice.
- [henchman] Watch "em.
- What are you doing?.
- Back off, Axel.
- Well, well, well.
If it isn"t Axel the freedom fighter
and the famous Cora D.
We got ourselves a star-studded
gathering going on right here.
- How could you?.
- How many times do I have to tell you?.
I don"t take sides.
I"m in this for me only.
Right, Big Fatso?.
That"s right.
And I like the way you think, Barb.
[Fatso chuckles]
The lenses.
[chuckles]
All right, phase two of the deal.
A safe escort to the old airport.
Oh, ho, ho. Slight change of plans.
[blows whistle]
You fat son of a bitch.
[soldier] Cover her!
Nice work, Mr Big Fatso.
I"m the man, l"m the man, l"m the man.
Barb, l"m gonna have to ask you
to drop your weapons.
You"ll love this, Barb.
Not only do I get the lenses,
but I get a million dollars bounty on
you, and a million for the good doctor
for turning you in
to the Congressionals.
Not to mention the 750,000 credit
on the debit card.
[laughs]
Don"t you just love it
when a plan comes together.
[Fatso continues chuckling]
The face may deceive,
but the eyes never lie.
Do they, Dr Devonshire?.
Washington has been in such
an uproar since you ran away.
I can"t tell you
how eager we are to have you back.
Whore.
Chief Willis, arrest these people.
I had nothing to do
with what happened to Charlie,
and l"m sorry.
- Don"t move!
- Look out, she"s got a grenade!
Take cover!
Agghh!
Floor it!
Hang on.
Ah, jeez, we"re gonna die.
Oh, God!
Goddamn you, Willis,
l"ll break you in half.
- How do I get on the plane now?.
- If we survive this, l"ll kill you.
[gunfire, ricochets]
[gunfire]
- Axel, take the wheel.
- What?.
Don"t argue. Hurry.
In an emergency, pull that yellow lever.
[Willis] How come I don"t get to drive?.
[Cora gasps]
Second toll dead ahead.
The airport"s just beyond.
[soldier] Here they come!
That"s a bus.
We can"t just break through a bus.
- Does this constitute an emergency?.
- Yes.
Ah, shit.
Hang on.
[Willis] Oh, where are you going?.!
Holy shit!
[Pryzer screams]
Hey, wait up!
Give me your gun. Willis, get "em
to the airport. Quick. I"ll stall "em.
I"ll meet you at the plane, I promise.
Goodbye, Axel.
All right, let"s go!
Take Cora to the airport.
I"m going back. Go.
- There he is. Get him!
- Let"s go!
- He"s over here.
- All right, let"s go.
Follow him!
Where are you, you bastard?.
Ah!
[Pryzer laughs maniacally]
[Pryzer whoops]
[screams]
- [thud]
- [Pryzer laughing]
- Does this one make it go up and down?.
- Yeah. Yeah, it does.
- Which one makes it go around.
- This one.
What about this one?.
[Pryzer] Ha!
How touching.
The last stand of the desperate.
Normally,
I don"t get emotional about my work,
but vaporising your stringy ass
is gonna be a real pleasure.
[Barb groans]
[Pryzer cackles]
Oh, Barb, we"re so close.
Don"t you feel the magic?.
This is just like my favourite song,
I Got You, Babe.
Don"t call me babe.
[gasps]
[PA] Attention, attention.
Prepare for retinal scan identification.
Only UN authorised and identified
personnel permitted past this point.
Infractions will be dealt with severely.
Damn, Willis, we"ve got to do something.
We could create a flamboyant diversion.
Thanks.
[PA announcement in French]
There they are.
Are we cutting it close enough?.
Put these in.
[PA] Final seating flight 647,
destination Quebec, gate two.
Hold that plane.
- Good luck, Doc.
- Thank you.
- Destination?.
- Quebec.
Step to the scanner.
[computer] Retinal scan verified.
CitiZen approved by all governments.
She"s home free. Mission completed.
- You"re gonna miss your plane.
- I thought Barb Wire never took sides.
- Keep it to yourself.
- [PA] Last call flight 647.
Goodbye, Axel.
Goodbye.
Willis.
[PA announcements continue]
Where will you go?.
Well, I hear Paris
is nice this time of year.
I do believe l"m falling in love.
Get in line.
[ Tommy Lee: Welcome To Planet Boom]
ThE EnD
Movie & Captions Conformed By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You've Liked & Enjoyed The Movie !!! "
Movie & Captioning Conformed By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You'll Like & Enjoy The Movie !!! "