(BELL TOLLING)
RIDDLER: Riddle me this.
When is a door, not a door?
It feels like drowning, doesn't it?
When the answer is at the
edge of your cortex,
but you can't seem to grasp it.
AMANDA: You're trying my patience.
RIDDLER: The answer...
When it's Ajar!
Here is an easy one.
What runs around a
city, but never moves?
No?
A wall!
What do you want, Nigma?
I'm in charge so I'll
ask the questions.
Try to keep up, wont you?
Riddle me this.
What belongs to you,
but others use it more than you do?
AMANDA: Your name.
Huh!
You've heard that one!
No, I have Google,
like the rest of the world.
Why do you talk to me
like this, waller?
Simple, I needed to
keep you babbling
long enough to pinpoint
your position.
My... what?
OFFICER: Hands in the air,
where we can see them!
AMANDA: Take him out!
Make it hurt!
(GRUNTS)
Riddle me this.
Why didn't I quit when I was ahead?
What is it? Report!
BATMAN: The riddler is mine!
OFFICER: Switch to night vision!
Secure the perimeter!
Holy crap! It's Batman!
(GRUNTS)
(OFFICERS GRUNTING)
(PROJECTILE SWISHING)
RIDDLER: Ahh!
(BOTH GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
(STRAINING)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
(STRAINING)
I know you helped him, Nigma.
Tell me where it is.
(BUZZER BEEPS)
I'm invoking priority
level, ultraviolet.
Assemble task force X.
We have another suicide mission.
(DUBSTEP PLAYING)
(PRISONERS CHEERING)
(MOTORBIKE ENGINE REVVING)
(ALARM RINGS)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GROANING)
CAPTAIN BOOMERANG: I got the hangover,
but I don't recall the party.
Oh crap! Not this again!
You too?
It's like a bloody
recurring nightmare.
Looks like we've got rookies.
(GROANING)
Who are you people?
And why am I in uniform?
No bars!
No chains!
Time for meat!
(SQUEALS)
Ow!
You try it, fish fingers, and I'll
show you the meaning of cold-blooded.
You're feisty.
Everybody! Shut up!
- I've been here before.
- (SHOUTING)
(GROWLS)
I am leaving!
Stop!
Sit down!
I'm Amanda waller.
I'm here to indoctrinate you
convicts into our special forces.
KILLER FROST: Pass.
I kill to keep degenerates
off the streets.
I won't work alongside them.
Fresh air and term off my sentence?
Feel free to keep
calling me up, love.
Task force X is an off-the-books
government strike team,
made up of convicts with
no hope for release,
serving as expendable agents,
for impossible missions.
Succeed, and I'll shave
time off your sentences.
If we don't?
You'll be dead!
Any other stupid questions?
Yeah, what's in my neck? A tracker?
Yes, and a powerful
nanotech explosive.
Run away, get yourself captured,
disobey an order,
hell, give me a right
answer too slowly,
and I'll blow your head clean off!
KGBEAST: You're lying.
You would not take all of this
trouble, just to kill us.
Try me!
(BEEPING)
(SCREAMS)
Anyone else?
I didn't think so.
What's so dangerous this time that
you had to send in the newbies?
You're going to break
into Arkham asylum.
- That's insane!
- You don't know much, do you?
Screw that!
I don't do freaky deaky's.
Yahtzee!
How do we start?
Oh, I like you, cowboy.
You're loco!
And me likey your locomotion!
- Ahh!
- What's the plan?
A week ago, while in my employ,
a low life calling himself the riddler managed
to gain access to my computer system.
He downloaded a file
containing the identities
and histories of every current, past and
potential member of the suicide squad.
Including ours?
That's right!
He's threatening to release
them all on the Internet.
You're going to get it back.
Riddler's got one copy,
and it's on a thumb
drive in his cane,
which is apparently locked away
in the Arkham property room.
In the intensive treatment building, right
under the solitary confinement cells.
Good times!
So we get someone inside.
Is it me? Can it be me?
Dibs!
She's a wild card.
Harley Quinn, has an encyclopedic
knowledge of Arkham's layout
and its logistics.
She gonna be okay that
close to the joker?
I'm fine, we're done.
He's a jerk! Whatever.
Well, I'm convinced.
You'll be snuck into Gotham.
You'll rendezvous with a power broker
who will set you up for the break in.
This is as off-the-grid as it gets.
So let's keep the body
count to a minimum.
Deadshot, rubber bullets only.
What about the bat?
He has his hands full
on another case.
In fact, we work it right, we might
be able to take advantage of him.
Waller!
What, Lawton?
Play fair and I'll shoot straight.
Jerk me around and I'll kill you!
Be a good convict, Lawton.
Don't make me blow you up.
I'm clear!
Gas them!
Harley: What?
(GAS HISSING)
(STRAINING)
I'm getting tired of this trick.
You and me both, cowboy.
Maybe, when we get into Gotham,
I can show you around.
I know some tight places.
- Not interested.
- Hmm.
I told you Harley,
if you're giving it out,
heave a chunk my way, eh.
Eh! You wish!
Shake your boomerang
at the shark guy.
- Do it, and I will bite it off.
- (CHUCKLES)
Come on, Harl, for old times' sake!
Are we gonna have a
problem this time around?
I think we might, mate.
BLACK SPIDER: No!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I don't trust vermin.
Honorless, rudderless,
undisciplined.
They'll never find your body.
Harley: Oh, ninjas are awesome!
(GRUNTS)
You think that means we're there?
(ALL SCREAM)
KING SHARK: I hate heights!
(STRAINING)
(Harley LAUGHING)
Harley: Whoo!
We're not going to make it!
Waller, please!
Ahh!
(CACKLING)
AMANDA: Remember this feeling convicts,
I hold your lives in my hands!
You crazy bitch!
Open the damn chutes!
Do it, now!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
Good one! Good shark!
Oh, Christ!
Where's Harley?
Don't worry! I fell on my head.
Great! Now, how do we get
to the rendezvous unseen?
A few more Miles.
Keep moving, then.
(GROANING)
(EXCLAIMS)
This is flipping bonkers!
Sloshing through the sewage so a guy
dressed like a bat won't spot us.
You want to head top side, slick?
Be my guest!
Nah! We're practically there.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
(MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
Cobblepot!
MAN: We're closed! Private party!
Yeah, we're the private party!
This way. He's waiting on you.
Your guests have
arrived, Mr. Cobblepot.
Right, right. Come in!
Welcome to the iceberg lounge.
I'm just finishing my supper.
Pardon me, Mr. Cobblepot.
Lawton. Oh, I never pegged
Deadshot for a team player.
Oh, things are tough all over, sir.
That's a good one!
This man is the best
assassin I've ever seen.
And I only work with the best.
I aim to please, Mr. Cobblepot.
I was told you can
get us into Arkham.
I can, indeed.
I've made arrangements to sneak
you into the crazy farm.
Follow them to...
You!
Clown!
You're still not mad about
that truck, are you, Pengie?
Wah, wah.
It feels like you are.
You cost me money, funny girl!
Her and her loony boyfriend lit my truck
a cigarette and drove it into the river!
Just for a laugh!
Does it matter that Mr. J and
I aren't together anymore?
Nobody steals from
me and walks away!
It's bad business, love!
You're right, you should kill her!
Hell, I'll kill her for you!
Oh, come on!
Except, you know what else
is bad for business, sir?
Double crossing your clients.
And I would hate for folks to say,
"Mr. Cobblepot takes your money
"and kills your operatives."
Get her out of my sight, Lawton.
There's your files.
Memorize the contents. You can grab
some shut-eye in the rooms above.
You deploy tomorrow night
under the cover of darkness.
And then, I never want to see
any of you on my turf again.
Now, get the hell out of here!
Never the charmer, aren't you?
Bite me, boomer!
(MEN LAUGHING)
Oy, Lawton!
Nice shade, mate.
We got off on the wrong foot
at the start of this mission.
Hoist a pint with us.
Can't, it's a school night.
Suit yourself. How about a
friendly game of darts, then?
ALL: Yeah!
(ALL GASP)
Lucky shot!
Right, let's see you do it.
ALL: Yeah!
Sorry mate.
Looks like that one
took a bad bounce.
Ow!
Let's call it even. Mate.
(MACHINE BEEPS)
AMANDA: Louise, it's Amanda,
I have a special
assignment for you.
Something I'd rather keep
between the two of us.
I'm listening.
Welcome back!
- Did you miss me?
- What do you want?
I got an itch I thought you
could help me scratch, cowboy.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, good start!
Oh, what the hell?
(DEADSHOT GROANS)
(CRASHING AND CLANKING)
Harley: Yahtzee!
Here's my stop.
Wish me luck, cowboy.
Yeah!
(GRUNTS)
There's got to be
one here somewhere.
(STRAINING)
BATMAN: You know where
he put it, don't you?
Uh-oh.
Where is it, Harley?
No idea, what you're talking about.
Answers! Now!
(Harley GRUNTS)
Back off, bats.
(BATMAN GROANS)
Where is it?
What's he talking about?
Who knows what these wankers
get worked up about?
I don't know, I swear.
I'm not firing blind
against the bat.
Waller, what the devil is going on?
You don't get to call me up
and demand answers, Deadshot!
What are they talking about?
Joker stole a dirty bomb and
hid it somewhere in Gotham.
Apparently, it's large enough that the
radiation would kill half the population.
Batman's torn the city
apart trying to find it.
At one point he thought
riddler might know.
The joker has a dirty bomb?
That gives me the chills.
Ice puns? Really?
Waller, this is crap.
I don't care, convict.
Do your job!
Honestly, B man, I don't know where
Mr. J puts half of his stuff.
I just wanted a chatty boo-boo doll
before they went on sale tomorrow.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Get her back to Arkham!
Will do, Batman.
Get in there, you nutty broad.
(CAR BOOT OPENING)
(MUMBLING)
I'm in the middle of lunch.
Now I've got to process this crazy dame?
Crazy, huh?
Why don't I just toss her in
her old cell, and come back.
Yeah, right. I've got like half
a dozen new forms to fill up
before you can even come in.
We got ten minutes
to plant the device.
CAPTAIN BOOMERANG:
Where should I dump her?
Put it through the X-ray machine.
GUARD: Heh, don't get
much deader than that.
This one's cold as ice.
Hey buddy, I got nothing in the
system about accepting a new body.
Yeah! Ha-ha.
(MUFFLED PROTEST)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTS)
It says, "not found."
I came from inside.
Run it again.
Nah, something's wrong.
I'm gonna to have to get security.
Junction box is up ahead.
So move your ass.
JOKER: Harley!
Is it really you?
Shit!
Don't screw this up.
Aren't you even going to say hello?
Oh, guys, you've got to see this.
Joker just spotted Harley!
Keep walking.
Tell him to shut up.
Aw, I can tell you're still sore.
At least the bruises
cleared up nicely.
What's your hurry, Harl?
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Damn it!
(SIGHS) Let's move.
(GUNSHOTS)
Maybe, she'll kill him.
I'm going to kill you!
I'll kill him! I'll kill him
myself for what he's done to me!
Women! Am I right, officer?
Can't live with them, can't
kick them out of a moving car.
You know the rules, buddy,
I got to phone it in.
She's dead!
How much trouble could she be?
Nothing goes in or out of
Arkham without being okayed.
But...
Give me a sec, I'll try to get
a hold of the watch commander.
Run it again.
I tried twice, sir.
I can't lose this job because
your system is down.
Come on, you amateurs.
(TUTTING) Sorry hon, bulletproof.
Even better, puddin'.
Why, Harley, if I didn't know better,
I'd say you're trying to kill me.
We're finished, you and me!
I got someone new
now, someone better!
(GROWLING)
Oh, hell!
This will have to do.
Never mind, just came through.
About time!
Sorry, it's an old system.
No problem.
Let's see what goodies we've got.
Oh, shit!
How the... ow!
Ahh! My goolies!
That's payback, you dumb ass.
Walk it off, captain kangaroo.
(GAS HISSING)
Come on, we're out of time.
New guy?
That's right! You're
not jealous, are you?
That's him!
I know you.
We worked together once.
No, wait, don't tell me,
don't tell me. Hmm.
Deadhead, hmm? Buckshot?
(Harley SQUEALS)
I got her!
You can have her!
Bet you buy your shirts
second hand too.
Sir, we've got an
explosion on level E.
He's still secure, sir.
Is that room service?
Tell them I never got my calzone.
Good! I need every available
security down in the kitchen.
Stat!
We're on yellow alert.
(ALL GROANING)
You're late!
Ran in to her ex. Grab hold!
KING SHARK: Put your back into it.
Hey! Nobody's supposed
to be down there!
DEADSHOT: Ah, we just snuck
down here for a little party.
(Harley GIGGLING)
What kind of party?
Crap! You're Harley Quinn!
Don't move, you crazy bitch.
(SCREAMS)
Blech!
I hate Italian food.
Has that kitchen
fire been contained?
- Yes, sir.
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Get here!
- AMANDA: Lawton!
- What?
GPS has you in the
main security hub.
What's going on?
We own it, that's what.
Now we grab the cane.
Don't get to cocky, Lawton.
You're at the point of no return.
You best keep that in mind.
That gas explosion put the whole
bloody asylum on yellow alert.
If the security cameras
make us, we're toast.
So shut down all the security cams.
That's a sure fire way
to alert the bat.
What then? Let him watch
us run around like idiots?
KING SHARK:
Play yesterday's footage.
Aw, shark-wick had
his first thought.
Shut it, boomer! Say it again.
Play yesterday's footage
of the same time.
I can do that.
And we can operate
without eyes on us.
You mean Batman's or Waller's.
Both!
The intensive treatment
building is there,
just across the yard.
Let's move!
Low profile.
Frost, move your ass.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Top priority are those towers.
I can scale them.
No time.
You do two, I'll do two.
Fine!
On my mark.
Now!
You missed!
Wait for it.
Patrol, I need a sweep of the yard!
Boom! In your face!
He got to his walky!
I'd score that a miss,
you two-bit c-lister!
That's it!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
U.S.A.! U.S.A.!
Boys, we got company!
Shark, no!
Finally, some action!
(MEN GROANING)
So much for low profile.
(Harley LAUGHING)
Status report.
I got you in the exercise yard, but
you don't show up on the cameras.
Must be something wrong
with the system. Damn it!
We're a little busy right now.
I'll call you back.
Don't yank me around, convict.
Get the cane, get out!
Yahtzee.
OFFICER: (THROUGH LOUDSPEAKER) Victor
Zsasz, we've got you surrounded.
Please! Please, don't hurt me.
Let the girl go
before it gets ugly.
The zombie is mine to liberate.
I have righteous work to do.
I'm not in the mood tonight, Zsasz.
You seem troubled tonight, sir.
It's Harley, Alfred.
She was acting odd.
Odder than usual, you mean.
Like she was happy to get caught.
Maybe she missed her puddin'?
Maybe.
More likely it's linked
to the joker's bomb.
Arkham had a yellow
alert this evening.
Everything looks to be in place.
Hmm.
That's Mochel.
He doesn't work Friday's.
Neither does Ferrick.
That's the Thursday crew.
This isn't live. They're
broadcasting old footage.
Something's wrong at Arkham!
(ENGINE REVVING)
No! No!
Enough, shark, put him down!
Ow!
Ouch!
Do I have your attention now?
Don't break cover in the middle
of an operation, unless I say so.
Don't ever do that to me.
Or what? You'll chew my head off?
Do it! I'm begging you.
You think any of you have a shot
of getting out alive without me?
That's what I thought.
We're just lucky
this was contained.
Start following orders, all of you!
Why don't you just
calm down, puddin'?
Don't call me puddin'!
Property room's down here.
Locked!
Not for long.
Now that's just pathetic!
The warden uses his birthday backwards
for practically all of his passwords.
How do you know that?
I used to work here.
Didn't I mention that!
Come on, as what?
As a psychiatrist, silly.
And, pal, anyone who
throws boomerangs,
has some real issues letting go.
Voila!
KILLER FROST:
Where do we even begin?
Everyone take a section.
Just start looking!
Bloody hell!
(EXCLAIMS)
(LAUGHS)
My acid playing cards!
I knew I left them here.
Here's that Batman costume
Mr. J used for the train heist.
Oh!
I've been looking
all over for this.
Here's where it went.
(GIGGLING)
Bingo!
Firefly. Killer moth.
Maxie Zeus.
Never heard of any of these tools.
Mr. Freeze's gun!
Score!
Thanks.
(GRUNTING)
It's Batman!
Uh-oh!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(Harley CACKKLING)
Oh.
Ah!
(SCREAMING)
(METAL CREAKING)
(GASPS)
Aah!
(GROANS)
No way!
The spoils of war.
Black spider just
kicked the bat's ass?
Mate, I'm a little choked up.
Got the thumb drive.
What?
What the hell?
We've been played.
Where's frosty?
Frost? Damn it!
Frost!
(HUMMING)
(SNORTS)
Right. Easy.
I knew waller would send someone.
I'm too clever for
her to let me live.
Nothing gets past you, genius.
I'll make this fast.
Do you even know why
you're assassinating me?
The wall says you screwed her and
to make an example out of you.
And that satiated your curiosity?
I don't ask questions.
I don't believe that.
The human mind always
has questions.
My only question is why waller didn't just
blow your head off with your nano bomb?
It's the same reason
she needs me dead.
Because I know how to diffuse them.
Wait, what?
How do you know she's
with the riddler?
She was eyeballing him
back at the monitor room.
So she's got herself a new guy.
After everything I've done for her!
Oh, we'll see about that.
I'll make five more just like her.
I'll take her skin and put
someone else in it.
Oh, that perfect creamy skin.
Pull yourself together, man!
She mocks you right to your face.
Even dared to call you...
Puddin'.
Oh, that darling girl.
She might even deserve me.
Okay, babies!
Let's cook!
Winner, winner, chicken dinner!
Oh, Harley, I take back half the
horrible things I've done to you.
They're gone!
Yeah, we can see that
Harley, but where?
It's waller.
- DEADSHOT: I'm here.
- What are you trying to pull, Deadshot?
You're not checking in!
We had a bout with the bat!
But we're past it.
I got your cane, waller.
We're just looking for an exit.
So you're all together?
Of course, why wouldn't we be?
Then why has the special crimes unit been
called in to protect the medical center?
DEADSHOT: Maybe two-face
got a pair of hemorrhoids.
We're out of here.
Please don't explode! Please don't
explode! Please don't explode!
Shut up!
Where's that medical center?
We're still on yellow alert.
You hear something?
Ah, let me check.
- GUARD: Hey, remember
that time when mad hatter...
- (THUD)
Smitty?
Smitty!
Boo!
Aah!
Smitty!
Put your hands in the air!
And boom!
(GROANING)
(COUGHING)
(WHISTLING)
I'm just going to slip into
something more comfortable.
So no peeking.
(OVER LOUDSPEAKER)
This is the special crimes unit.
Surrender and return
to your cells.
Light 'em up!
That worked well.
Then like the hanged man,
we are at the end of our rope.
Wow, I hate you!
You can thank us later, losers!
You all right?
Somewhat.
Glad you made it.
This better be good!
He knows how to turn off the bombs.
Look familiar?
I can do it, but you got to get
me into the medical center.
We got maybe five minutes before
waller figures out what's what.
We get to that room or we're dead!
Should have brought a tank.
We have one.
No heights!
You're joking?
I said no heights!
I'll guide you. Trust me.
I'm crazy, but that's just nuts!
Step on it!
Go to the right!
(ALL GROANING)
Aah!
Let's move!
(GROANS)
Did we win?
(GROANING)
Let's see now, we'll need this on.
This for back up.
Grab a chair.
Whee!
How do you diffuse
this bomb, exactly?
It's the electroshock.
It's the what, now?
I'm going to run 1000 volts through
your heads and fry your bombs.
Oh!
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
Good, put the chairs in a
circle here, around old spark.
Oh, I love electroshock!
It's a shiatsu massage
for your brain.
Lose those.
I'll keep a look out.
More cops.
Choppers too.
This will work?
Or give you a grand mal seizure.
I'm clamping you to the chairs
because you're going to wiggle.
I don't trust this fruit loop.
Mmm, 1000 volts, 5
bodies multiplied by 5,
allowing for absorption,
three second pulses.
You know what you're doing, right?
- (MACHINE BEEPING)
- Damn it!
Don't stop working. Yeah, waller.
I'm getting reports that
there's a break in at Arkham.
You're on red alert!
DEADSHOT: News to me.
What part of off-the-books
do you not understand?
Are you in the medical center?
We hit a snag.
Batman again?
Spider needed medical attention.
Spider? But he's...
No excuses Lawton, you get that!
Uh-huh.
No more crap!
No more time! No more shenanigans!
Uh-huh.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Ah!
Those scum bags are
trying to screw me.
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
(HUMMING)
I never need to do that again.
(Harley PANTING)
Are you kidding? I feel great!
Nobody screws the wall!
Uh, guys!
Do it again!
I don't know, maybe the
skin is too thick?
Best gun ever!
Boy, why'd his head explode?
Because the bomb in his neck
didn't diffuse, you asshole!
So what's his excuse?
Oh. Oh, that's rich!
Huh?
(GASPS)
Denzel, what have they done to you?
(CACKLING)
Haven't you solved it yet?
The black spider is Batman!
Aah!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING THROUGH EARPIECE)
I know that sound.
Someone's flossing their brain.
Talk! Why are you here?
Amanda waller wanted
the riddler dead.
Waller? What's she got to...
(GUNSHOTS)
I'm here, bitches!
And I've brought
favors for everybody.
(JOKER LAUGHING)
Yahtzee!
(WHISTLING)
I think this was yours, deadhead.
Finders keepers.
Puddin', you're free!
Don't you "puddin'" me!
I go away and suddenly
you've got new friends.
Even picked a new guy!
You got it all wrong, baby.
I was using them to
help you escape!
Who else would I break
into Arkham for?
Nobody, that's who.
It'll be just like old times.
Oh!
(BOTH SIGH)
Hmm.
You! New guy.
I don't like people
touching my stuff.
Go ahead! You're out of bullets!
I am not!
You are!
You're going the pull the trigger
and when nothing happens,
I'm going to punch you in the
throat and bash your brains out!
Three.
Two.
One.
Hold on, stop counting
for a second.
I know there are bullets.
See!
Mate, you just
out-crazied the joker!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
KILLER FROST:
This place is crawling with cops!
I'm going to kill waller!
Can we get out of here first?
Harley: Whoa!
Oh.
Mallet!
Its right here, Mr. j.
I was keeping it safe
for you the whole... ow!
It's time for a very big bang.
(PANTING)
Why the hell are we running?
We're sitting ducks here.
And whose fault is that,
do you suppose, leader?
I've been carrying this team
all night, you douche bag!
- Ah, fellas!
- CAPTAIN BOOMERANG: Really?
- Is that what you'd call it, eh?
- KILLER FROST: Guys.
- Guys, listen...
- Yeah, yeah that's what I
call it, you one-gimmick hack.
Great, let's split up.
I'm better off on my own.
Guys! Batman's here!
Joker, where did he go?
Don't owe you squat, bats!
Lawton,
we can settle our business later.
Now, where's the joker?
He and Harley took their
mallet and disappeared.
That's where he's hidden the bomb.
Simulus testing! Simulus.
I know you can see me, bats.
Hope you brought protection.
'Cause I'm about to give Gotham
a terminal case of tainted love
and it's really gonna burn.
And just in case you're
thinking of stopping me,
I figured I'd invite some
friends to my big blow-out.
Stop! Please!
(SCREAMING)
I need to find joker
and stop that bomb.
Good luck with that, mate.
Got to get out of here.
Yeah, but what will get us far
enough to escape that blast?
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
Well, isn't that convenient.
(SHOUTING)
Ow!
Out of my way, loser.
(OFFICERS SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
No!
(KILLER FROST SCREAMS)
Oh no you don't, Lawton.
That's my ride!
(STRUGGLING)
Only one of us is getting out
of here, and it ain't you!
(SCREAMS)
I'll get you for this, Lawton!
Get those gates closed!
Where's our backup?
Now that's what I call backup.
We've got it under control,
Batman, you can take...
And I'm talking to myself, again.
Going my way, handsome?
Cute kid!
Hope she doesn't take
being an orphan too hard?
(GROANS)
- (CONSOLE BEEPING)
- Huh?
Holy crap!
You know she's going
to kill us, right?
Where's the fricking gas pedal?
Uh-oh!
Sure he smacks me around sometimes,
but you're the one who's
always hurting me!
Now I'm going to hurt you!
Stop me, if you've heard this one.
Listen to me!
Harley, the bomb!
(TICKING)
For someone who's not Batman,
you've been a real pain in my ass.
Deuces, new guy!
Have a seat, puddin'!
Bang!
(JOKER LAUGHING)
BATMAN: Waller!
You knew when you sent your
little suicide squad into Arkham,
they'd go off script.
Oh, it's just you.
When your bombs didn't dice them,
you figured the SCU would.
All that, just so you
could kill the riddler!
Let's just say, I break a lot
of eggs to make an omelet.
And because you're a messy cook,
the riddler was able to escape.
I got careless.
My men will get Nigma next time.
There is no next time.
No?
We're the U.S. government!
Who's going to blow the
whistle on us, the convicts?
Who'd believe them?
You?
You're going to start
a blog and expose us?
I don't think so.
That's checkmate, Batman.
I'm warning you!
Enough!
Don't they need you back in
your squalid little city?
They never did find the
joker's body, did they?
Punk!
Mother...
Bang!