Subtitles & translations by AsifAkheir♪♪
At the end of the 21st century
the Earth is over-populated
polluted, and plague-stricken.
The wealthiest residents have fled
the planet to preserve their lifestyle
Max!
[SPANISH]
Come here.
Let's not make the sisters wait.
Her name is Frey.
She's new here too.
Can you read?
This is a giraffe.
They lived in Africa.
Can you read?
Yes.
[ENGLISH]
There are many robot servers,
and they serve you all day.
If you live there,
you'll never get sick, or old.
I'll take us there, one day.
- Really?
- Yes, I promise.
Frey and Max.
Forever.
[SPAN]
Max, are you stealing again?
It breaks my heart.
Why do you do it?
To save up ?
You want to buy a ticket to go up there?
That place is not for you, or me.
It's not fair, sister.
Why can't I go?
There are things that
can't be explained in life.
We just have to accept them.
But one thing I know for sure.
You're a very special person.
One day you'll do something marvellous.
You were born for it.
My little Max.
Max, muy bueno!
[ENG]
Off to work, huh?
Gotta get up early, to work that line.
Wanna make the world better?
That's real funny,
I have a job. Chistoso.
Por favor ninos!
You think I got money?
Do I look like
I have money?
How about you,
you got a little money?
Come on, whatta you got in there?
Wait a minute.
Oh, it's 5 bucks. Hey, wait a minute.
I got 5 bucks, I'm rich.
[SPAN]
I can buy my ticket to Elysium, huh?
[ENG]
Alright.
Please form an orderly queue.
Your bus has arrived.
I don't have anything.
Don't touch me.
OK. Go.
Morning, Officer.
Extensive criminal history.
Multiple felonies. What's in the bag?
Hair products, mostly.
I'm just fucking with...
Hey .. I'm just going to work, man.
There's nothing in the fucking bag.
Come on, I...
Dealing with citizen disobedience.
Just going to work, man.
Come on.
- Shit!
- Nothing in it, is there?
Complying with policy
applies to all citizens.
No shit?
You must report immediately
to your parole officer.
Thank you, Citizen.
No, thank you.
Frey, fracture in bed 2.
Max?
Frey...
I thought you were...
- When did you get back?
- Been back for a while.
- I see things haven't changed.
- No, this wasn't even my fault.
- Of course not.
Let me have a look.
- How's it?
Pretty bad break.
So you're a nurse, huh? You did it!
Yeah.
That's great.
You still stealing cars?
No, God, I don't do any of that
stupid shit anymore.
I work at Armadyne.
On the line, you know? Workin...
- Frey, they need you
up on the 3rd floor.
- Be right there.
- So, you know, now that you're back...
- Just a second.
Just sec.
Dominica, can you take over here?
- Hey, listen, because
you're back and everyth...
- Max, I'm so sorry I have to go.
Good to see you.
Stay outta trouble.
I do.
Look...
I know why you left the
neighborhood, I understand.
If I was as smart as you
I would have left too.
Have dinner with me. Just...
I'll settle for a coffee.
- No.
- Aww.
Have I gotta break
my other arm to get attention?
- Stop.
- ...'cause I will do that.
My life is complicated, Max.
I just, I... I miss you.
- My shift ends at 8
on Wednesday, OK?
- Yeah, all right.
- Coffee.
- Yeah, coffee. Right.
Get out of here.
All parolees must have
weapons inspection
Hello.
Before we start,
I'd just like to explain...
Max da Costa, violation of
Penal Code 2219.
101.1
Today at bus stop 34-B.
Yes, that's exactly what
I wanted to talk to you about.
See I believe there's been
a misunderstanding.
Immediate extension of parole
by a further 8 months.
Wait, What? No, no,
I can explain what happened.
I just made a joke.
And, you know...
Stop talking.
Police officer noted
violent antisocial behavior.
We regret that we must extend parole.
Elevation in heart rate detected.
- Would you like a pill?
- No!
Thank you,
what I'd like to do is expl...
Stop talking.
Personality matrix
suggests a 78.3% chance of...
regression to old behavior
patterns, grand theft auto...
Assault with a deadly weapon,
Resisting arrest.
- Would you like
to talk to a human?
- No, I'm OK. Thank you.
- Are you being sarcastic
and/or abusive?
- Negative.
It is a federal offense
to abuse a Parole Officer.
Understood.
- Hey, da Costa! You're late for your shift.
- Yeah man, I had a little thing...
No, no. You can't work
with that. You're out.
No, no, I'm good, man.
I can work.
It's coming off later today.
I'm fine.
- You're good?
- I'm good!
OK, I'm docking you half a day.
- Yeah, alright.
- You're lucky to have this job.
No weapons detected.
You are clear for entry.
Please keep your workstation tidy.
A tidy workstation is
an efficient workstation.
- Hey check it out, man.
I think he likes you.
- Think he got his face peeled today?
He looks good.
Attention: all workers
must reach weekly quotas.
Please report any unsafe
activity to your supervisor.
If we don't have a clear path
to up-side,
our investors are going to start
losing a lot of confidence.
What do you think
I've been doing here, on Earth?
D'you think I enjoy
breathing this air?
- No, of course, but...
- I'm doing everything possible...
to restore profitability to this company.
The company that I built.
Now, if you will excuse me,
I have to not speak to you
people any longer. Thank you.
Closing 34 !
Firing 34.
[SPAN]
Tag her quick!
[ENG]
Let's go, we don't have much time.
We have 3 transporters codes, Spider.
OK, pull'em up on screen.
Codes have been accepted.
Fire up the shuttle!
We're going up!
- Welcome.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Take a look at the garden.
- We will, thank you.
[FRENCH]
- Hello, Madame Delacourt.
- Hello.
Hi, Ivan, how you've grown.
Hi. You alright?
- Fine. Are the kids here?
- Yes, with Dominica.
I have a present for you.
Wanna see? It's in the salon.
Go get it with your mother.
-It's, by the canape.
-OK
-Bye.
[ENG]
Madam, would you care
for a refreshment?
Command: Cancel !
Sorry for disturbing you, ma'am. We have
a number of undocumented ships in-bound.
Good afternoon,
Defense Secretary Delacourt.
3 undocumented ships are
approaching Elysium airspace.
Emergency orders 6 and 7 are now in effect
Protocol 22/B39...
Attention, incoming vessels.
You have made unauthorized
entry into Elysium airspace.
- Dad!
- It's okay!
We will be forced to take
immediate action
You are in violation of
Elysium airspace.
Standard warning didn't work.
15,000 Kilometers and closing...
- What do you want us to do, ma'am?
- Activate Kruger.
Ma'am, according to Executive Order 355
we are unauthorized to use our assets on earth
I am authorizing you.
Yes, ma'am.
Agent 32--over.
We are sending the packet--over.
Welcome, Agent Kruger!
10,000 Kilometers and closing.
Sending coordinates to asset.
Three target data.
Shoot them down!
Green light, 21-B. Green light.
Missiles away!
Shit.
[SPAN]
Impacto inminente. 10...
[ENG]
Two ships destroyed.
46 total casualties.
Impact in 5...
- Last missile was a miss.
- Ridiculous!
[SPAN]
Only one made it.
[ENG]
Ma'am, the ship has breached
our atmosphere.
First undocumented ship
just touched down.
I want everyone coming out of
that vehicle apprehendeded.
Identification confirmed.
Scanning.
<Reconstruction process initiating
No!
We have 32 arrests, 13 casualties,
and 2 illegals at large, Ma'am.
Reconstruction complete.
You are under arrest.
Article 68-C Immigration Act.
- All illegals are now
in custody, ma'am.
- Yes.
Send them to deportation,
Get them off this habitat.
Secretary Delacourt, Please report
to President Patel immediately.
Secretary Delacourt,
report to President Patel.
What up, man?
¿Qué te paso?
Como siempre, the police, man
(As usual)
- Are you OK?
- Yeah, don't worry about it.
Max, I gotta talk to you.
You know...
- No!
- What do you mean no?
You didn't even hear
what I was gonna say.
- Alright, go ahead.
- OK.
- You know the house of
Doseta's up on the hill?
- Yeah, the one with all the guns.
Yeah, they have five cars.
New ones.
It's gonna be three of us.
Tomorrow, at lunch.
Lunch time?... That's the plan?
Jesus Christ.
- You have a better plan?
- Yeah, just take one guy.
Go before sun comes up.
You take two fastest cars.
Torch the batteries
on the other ones.
Fuck you. Fuck you!
I got you cojone! (scrotum)
Oh please. You're the best.
Give me one year.
- I'm not going back to prison.
- One year, please!
Look at you! You used to be
a legend, and now what?
The time is 5:50 am.
No weapons detected.
You are clear for entry.
Closing 34 !
[SPAN]
Attention, doors are not
aligned. Worker attend.
[ENG]
Hey, you're holding up the line.
No, no, I got a jam!
Attention: workers may not use
the restroom more than once per sh...
- What've you done to close up?
- No, I'm just trying to reset.
Let me look.
- The pallet's pinched.
- Yeah, It didn't move.
- Just go in there.
- No, I mean...
Look, you go in there right now...
or we'll find someone who will,
and you can go clean out your locker.
- Come on, man.
- Not. That's the deal, OK?
In you go!
C'mon people, work!
Fuck.
No, no, no, stop!
Hey!
Come on! Go work!
Too late!
Extraction!
[SPAN]
Sister, they beat me up.
I only want to live there.
See how beautiful
it looks to us down here?
Yes.
Well, now...
See how beautiful
we look to them up there.
Keep this.
Now it belongs to you.
So you never forget where you come from.
[ENG]
- What happened?
- You have been exposed to a
lethal dose of radiation.
You will experience
catastrophic organ failure.
In five days time, you will die.
What is going on?
Why has production stopped?
- He's been exposed ...
- Don't breathe on me.
- Cover your mouth.
- I'm sorry, sir.
Does his skin fall off,
or something?
I don't want to replace the bedding
in there. Just get him out.
- Yes, sir.
- Right, thank you.
Mr. Carlyle, your shuttle
is ready for departure.
Please sign this
to receive medication.
Miporol--extremely potent.
Will keep you functioning
normally until your death.
Please take one pill
with each meal.
Thank you for your service.
At 15:00 hours yesterday you shot down
two shuttles, killing 46 civilians.
Your mandate is
to deal with illegals 'quietly'.
I am aware of that.
And then there's the use of this... agent.
A Mr. M. Kruger.
15 human rights violations...
Rapes, kidnapping, torture.
The man's been diagnosed with
serious psychological issues.
We made explicitly clear to you
that we're no longer using sleeper agents.
Tell me something,
President Patel.
Do you have children?
I'm not the one
being reviewed here.
Then I will assume you do not.
Perhaps, if you did have children.
Then you would behave in a manner
that is more conducive to the
longevity of this habitat.
I understand, it is not the fashion
to think and to act as I do.
I understand that perfectly.
But when they come for your house...
or the house you built
for your children.
And your children's children...
It won't be PR or campaign
promises that keep them out.
It will be me!
I've heard enough!
This is your final warning.
Any further unauthorized actions,
and you will be removed from office.
And let's discharge this
agent Kruger permanently.
All in favour?
Good.
Effective immediately.
You want some beer?
You have been discharged from CCB.
Please return all weapons to local embassy
Fuck your 'Politikster'!
Fuck you!
Look...
Max...
Max!
What's wrong?
What happened?
Jesus, let me help you. Let's go.
Max, what happened?
- Max, what happened?
- I shouldn't have gone in it.
Gone in where?
I took a full dose, man.
Lethal dose.
You OK? Let me help.
- You're gonna be OK, Max.
- They gave me Miporol, man.
They gave me... Miporol.
I got five fucking days!
I only got five days!
You have to take this.
- They can fix this shit
on Elysium, man.
- I know.
- Gonna go see Spider.
- Max, Max!
Take the pill!
There you go!
To see Spider, you need money.
I'll give you everything I have,
but it's not enough for a ticket.
He's going to give me a ticket.
He's gonna give me a fucking ticket.
Frey, you know we've done everything
we could to help your daughter.
But I had a meeting today with the board,
and they're recommending that
we send her home with you.
How can I work here
and leave it at home?
You know it can happen
anytime, Dr. Faizel.
I know, if she has another seizure,
of course bring her back here.
But until then she's discharged.
This isn't Elysium.
We can't just heal her.
Max!
It's been a while, my brother!
How's life at the factory?
- I need to ask you a favour.
- What? I can't hear you. What?
I need a ticket. Up there.
And an ID.
Oh.
Yeah, sure sure.
Absolutely. You prefer
aisle or window?
Don't play games with me.
I'm fucking serious, man.
Listen, I'm gonna come back
and work for you.
Anything you need.
I'll fucking pay it back.
You know what?
This... is...
priceless.
This is priceless.
Yeah, let me ask you a question.
Do you have any idea
how many idiots
come in here saying
the same kinda bullshit?
I got little kids
coming here every day.
Max, if I were you, I'd get
the fuck out of here, right now
I did 3 years for you. Everything I did
for you, you're gonna get me up there.
Go ahead and shoot. I got so much
radiation in my body, right now,
you're probably getting
a little sick yourself.
- You really dying?
- I'm fucking dying, motherfucker.
See this ?...
I put the gun down.
Put the gun down!
Put the gun down! Get out of here!
Okay!
Listen, I've been looking for
someone to take a job for me.
But no one here has the balls.
You said you'd do anything, right?
Max...
- Hey.
- I'm OK.
This...
My friend.
This can be your ticket up there.
One last job for me,
You earn your way up.
What is it?
Take an Elysian asshole, right?
A billionaire who's down
on Earth for some business...
He's, he's here for, whatever.
We hijack him.
- Fuck that!
- Relax.
The guy's like much worse.
Forget his watch, forget his ride,
forget all that shit.
This, is what you take.
Organic Information,
right out of his head.
I'm talking about the bank codes,
passwords, login data...
Access to billions.
All you have to do is plug into his brain,
download the data to yours with this baby...
And bring it to me.
This is crazy, Max.
Once we verify the data,
I'll give you a one way ride,
all expenses paid.
Even throw in some snacks
and a drink.
All you have to do is walk
into a house and use the
Med-bay, and you're cured.
Sandro who will do the surgery.
You know him?
-Fuck...
-Christ!
I'm good.
Actually, you seem all weak.
And a fucked up, so...
You know what? I have...
It's crazy, let's get out of here,
Please, listen to me.
What am I gonna do?
I'll have them install...
...this!
A third generation Axo-suit.
We hook this into your nervous system,
and it'll make you as strong as a droid.
You're already under the knife, right?
Let's get out of here, please.
I want a 4 man team.
But I pick them.
I'm sending my own data wrangler.
Brain to brain, that is real tough.
OK, but I'm taking Julio, he gets
a ticket up there, same as me.
Yeah, sure.
OK, I'll go get the boys ready.
Wait!
It's gotta be John Carlyle.
The CEO of Armadyne, Carlyle?
That's the mark.
Secretary Delacourt,
Mr. Carlyle has arrived.
You are here to persuade me to
renew our Armadyne contracts, yes?
Astute as always.
Come with me.
I'm not interested
in your little ideas.
I am interested in
something much larger.
This habitat is dying.
There is a political sickness inside of it.
A tumor that needs to be removed.
You and your company are in
need of revenue that is drying up.
So...
You built the Torus.
Can you override the servers and
place a new president in power?
A coup?
Are you suggesting a coup?
Is it possible?
I could write a reboot sequence.
It'd shut down the entire system,
and at that point...
you can encode a new President, yes.
Then that is what you will do.
And you will have your contract
secured for the next 200 years.
Missile Defense Batteries, Droids,
everything we need, to protect our liberty.
all guaranteed, of course,
by your new President.
[FREN]
Go! Get to work, Mr. Carlyle.
[ENG]
This is the guy.
- He's the guy?
- This is him.
Sit down.
We're gonna cut you up good, homie.
Play nice, amigo.
Play nice.
Let's get him an ID first.
...one of them
identification codes.
Get that ready.
Arm up.
It'll merge with your DNA.
Now you fit in.
Like you were born there
Now it's time for the real fun.
[SPAN]
Lower it to me.
[ENG]
Hey, man.
Yo.
This gonna hurt?
Yeah bitch, it's gonna hurt.
It's gonna hurt good.
When we're done with you,
you're gonna be a (...) ninja.
Mariana!...
Bring down the bone saw!
This ain't gonna kill me.
You'll be airight. Not bad.
Max.
I'm here.
We got this, man.
We got this?
Yeah!
Hey!
[SPAN]
He's awake!
[ENG]
Made it, huh?
Surprised !
You can still jack off, alright?
How's everything going?
Ready to kick ass?
What the fuck did you do to me?
Gave you a way out.
Hey!
What's up, partner?
How's that suit working out for you?
That shit is tight !
Show me.
Hold this.
Is this a family heirloom?
Wait or it.
Air-bursting ammunition.
Designate your enemy...
and any round you fire will
explode around a 5 meter kill radius
And...
Safe Detonation rounds
for this bad boy.
That'll work.
Move out!
Sir...
Your shuttle is ready.
Do you read me?
[SPAN]
Yes
[ENG]
Alright, here's the deal.
We'll wait outside the factory
until we see the shuttle leave.
One of you will shoot a round
in it then we go to the
crash site and get some data.
OK, copy that.
Be back in five, boys.
Alright now, let's go!
Let's play ball !
You nervous?
- No.
- No?
[SPAN]
I'm shitting myself with fear.
[ENG]
- I'm not gonna fucking die.
- No.
Go, go, go!
Acceleration to supersonic
speed in 15 seconds.
Come on, come on, ...!
Critical engine failure.
Ma'am, we have an Elysium
citizen on Earth in danger.
Data coming up now...
Citizen identified.
John Carlyle. N8321...
I see you, motherfucker!
I have a situation here.
Kruger, do you read me?
Ah, Ms Delacourt.
How lovely to hear your voice.
There's a citizen carrying sensitive
brain data out of the city right now.
Some thieves are trying to hijack it.
What's in it?
That's classified
You don't call a recently
deactivated agent to retreive
classified fucking information!
The government doesn't know
about this, do they?
I can ask for whatever I want,
can't I?
Prepare for impact
Please remain calm.
You have sustained zero injuries
Oh, that's a real comfort.
I got one condition:
I do this, I get re-instated
Fine.
I've recommissioned 2 of your
preferred agents.
Completely confidentially, of course.
They should be at your position any second
Feed me the mission data
Come on, guys. out of the car!
Droids, there appears to be some
type of wheeled vehicle, with one
Two occupants.
They are armed and I'd like them dead.
Droid!
Jammed!
Identified, Max da Costa.
Federal Parole number 61492-8-557
It's jammed, man!
Got it!
He's reloading!
- Guys! We got the bastard!
- Go! I got you covered!
Go, go, go!
Don't fucking move.
Bring it!
Another one!
Die, motherfucker!
Don't hit the mark!
No, no! He got hit!
Citizen has sustained
a cardio-thoracic trauma.
Blood pressure is dropping
Not in the head !
No in the chest!
Hold his head, let me see.
Let me see your brain.
Come on, Come on!
- Yes.
- Is it working?
Yeah, we're syncing.
You have no idea
what you're doing.
One minute to target, sir.
We're syncing.
Come on, baby, here we go.
It's gonna work. We got it
It's a data heist, ma'am.
They're downloading now.
Guys, we've got in-coming.
Fuck me!
Come on, guys, hurry up.
That's a Raven.
That's Military.
- Alright we got this, 97...98!
- Hurry up, they're coming.
- Almost there!
- 99!
- In !
Here we go!
Shit! Data must be corrupted!
What the f..? What does that mean?
Wait. Hold on.
I can't read the data.
It's scrambled! I can't read the data.
What?
- Come on, guys! We gotta move!
- What the fuck does 'scrambled' mean?
Fuck this!
No, No! Run it again!
Another time!
- Get off me, man! I'm bailing!
- Please. Run it again.
Fuck you!
Let's get out of here.
What the fuck are you doing,
Sandro?
Let's get outta here!
Goddamit!
C'mon man
Get out of there! Let's go!
We gotta go!
Come on! Come on!
Hey, boss, we got a runner.
Fire!
That's what I'm talking about!
Fuck, man!
Target moving south-southwest
Move back!
We got another one.
Again!
This is wrong! This is all wrong, man!
Going into holding pattern, sir!
Where do you think you're going?
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
Come on!
No!
No, no!
Get up!
No!
We've got one assailant
leaving on foot, ma'am.
They have the data. Repeat:
The thieves have the data.
Apprehend the target at all costs.
Do not damage his brain.
Let's go! We got a runner, boy!
The citizen has suffered
catastrophic blood loss
leading to cardiac arrest
Time of death, 17:45.
Come on,
where are you hiding?
What's that?
Looks like a herd of pigs,
boss.
Fuck you, man!
Find him!
Go back to the crash site,
see what they left behind.
Roger, that.
Thanks ma'am. [Gracias senora]
Hey boss, I think
you better come look at this.
This is a record
of what we picked up
being transferred between
Carlyle and the criminals.
That's why
she wants it so badly.
He's got the keys to the kingdom
in his fucking head!
Now we just need to find it.
Gonna let the girls out.
13 grid, 3 to 11.
I'm authorising
a Full Containment Order.
Issue a No Fly Zone
for Los Angeles.
- All of Los Angeles?
- The murderer's still out there.
Until we apprehend him, No one
leaves the surface of that city.
What the f...?
Max.
- Hey, sweety!
- Hey.
We can go home.
Am I better?
I'm gonna get the car, okay?
Be right back.
Frey...
Max!
My God, what happened to you?
- Shit, gonna get the medics.
- No, no!
- I can't go in there.
- Max!
- I can't go in...
- Max, listen, you need a doctor, OK?
People are looking for me.
They're gonna kill me.
- I came here for you.
I need your help.
- Max!
You've got to go through
the system to get treatment.
Please help me.
I don't wanna die.
Max!
Stay awake!
- I wanna see the man.
- Mama's gonna help him, OK?
Try to sleep.
Don't sleep!
[SPAN]
You're too heavy for me. Max, help me!
[ENG]
Come on!
Max, you can do it, come on!
No, wait. Let's turn you over!
Max, Max, wait.
- Thank you.
- Who did this to you?
Okay.
I got hurt at at work.
I had to take a job from Spider
to try to get up there and get healed.
It went bad,
now I'm in trouble.
Mommy?
Hey, sweety, come here!
Who is that man?
His name is Max. Mommy knew him
when he was your age.
- It's Matilda.
- Hi!
You can go watch cartoons, OK?
I'll be right there.
I didn't know you had...
I'm so sorry, I need to go.
- Wait, Max, you can not leave.
- I shouldn't have come here. I have to leave!
Max! She's dying. She's in
the final stages of leukemia.
I told you my life complicated.
I need you to help me.
- I've no idea how to do this.
- How to do what?
- Get her to Elysium.
- I can't help her. I...
I would if I could.
How about this? Fake citizenship.
If you took her there,
- could you heal her with this?
- It doesn't work that way.
This is coded to me,
it's locked to my DNA.
The people looking for me.They...
You don't understand who these people are.
If they find me here,
they will kill all of us.
The only thing I can do to help
you is leave. I promise you.
- She's all I have.
- I'm sorry.
You have bandages.
Yeah. I got bandages.
What are you doing?
I don't want you to be sick.
You wanna hear a story?
N.., ah...
There once was a meerkat
who lived in the jungle.
He was hungry
and he was small.
So small.
And the other big animals had all the food,
'cause they could reach the fruits.
So he made friends
with a hippopotamus
OK, stop!
It doesn't end well for the meerkat.
Yes, it does 'cause he can
stand on the hippopotamus' back
to get all the fruits that he wants.
- What's in it for the hippo?
- The hippo wants a friend.
I'm sorry.
Hey, boss.
I think we got him.
Yank this fucking boat!
- Mommy, is everything OK?
- It's OK, sweety.
Clear !
[SPAN]
What is this?
[ENG]
Good afternoon.
Sorry to come bursting into
your home. Didn't mean to...
traumatize your young daughter.
Me and the boys here are
looking for a young gentleman...
who was in this very house a moment ago.
We're hoping you can tell us
where he went.
No.
I...
- I don't know where he is.
- I don't believe in ...
...committing violent acts
in front of the kids.
So I just need you to
close your eyes, sweetheart.
- It's OK.
- I really need you to tell me.
Hey?
- You remember now?
- Mommy!
Close your eyes,
keep your fucking eyes closed.
Keep her eyes closed.
Please, I don't know where he is.
He was wounded,
I helped him and he left.
Please!
D'you fucking hear that?
No loyalty nowadays, hey?
What's this here?
- This a hospital you're runninghere?
- She's sick.
She's sick? Let me have
a look at her... Alright!
- Don't touch her.
- See that? Protective instinct, here!
- I said don't touch her!
- I'm just trying to have a word with your child.
Do not touch her!
- Bring her. Come!
- Where are you taking her?
Sweety, it's OK.
It's OK, darling. It's OK.
Sit! Shut up!
Stop!
No, no, don't shoot him!
Put the gun down! Let him come!
- You got something, didn't you?
- What?
That's why they shut down
the sky... what is it?
Wire transfers? Corporate intel?
You gotta have something big in there!
No. I fucking got nothing, man!
It all got scrambled. Julio is dead.
You owe me. Let's go fucking now!
We can't!
The flight system is jammed!
Nobody is going up there.
- Until when?
- Till I don't fucking know.
- I gotta fucking get up there!
- Everyone needs to get up there.
My guys are working on it.
See if they have a hope in hell
of ever getting back online.
But, for now...
- Let's just take a look at
that head of yours.
- Get away from me, man!
Look at me, if they shut down
the whole fucking sky,
for what's in your head...
Maybe the key to opening it
could be in there too, right?
Come on.
Alright
They will hunt you to the edge
of the world for this.
What is it?
It is a reboot program for Elysium.
Whoever has this, has the power
to override their whole system.
Open the borders...
Make everyone
a citizen of Elysium.
This can save your life.
- We can save everyone.
- When can I go?
They're trying to hack through
the signal jam, but soon...
- Don't bullshit me,
when can we go?
- I dunno.
Five days... a week?
Fuck you, I don't have 5 days!
I got hours.
My guys are working on it.
You're always working on it,
You can't get me up there.
I don't know why you try
sending people up there,
they just get fucking shot down.
Not with what's in your head!
That's what I'm talking about!
We would control the system.
We would be in charge!
We can change the course
of fucking history!
Back up there...
What I have in my head,
is worth a lot to them, right?
Don't do this.
If it falls into the wrong hands,
they could shut us out for good.
Listen, man,
I'm going up there right now.
If you can find me, and I'm healed,
you can have all of this.
- But I'm not fucking dying.
- This is wrong, Max, don't do this.
Do not shoot him! Do not shoot him!
Let go!
It's okay. It's okay.
I always wanted a wife.
Just couldn't quite settle down,
you know? Too much temptation.
But you...
You make me ready to settle down.
You really make me want to
settle down, baby.
- Holy shit, sir.
- Eh?
You better come
take a look at this.
- What is it?
- Check this fucking oak (guy).
Turn us around.
-Take it.
-Right, sir.
Open the door.
Stop right there, and you're
gonna do exactly what I say.
Or I'm gonna blow my fucking head off, understand?
Yeah!
You can have everything in my head!
Just take me up there,
and get me in a med-bay.
- What I have is very valuable.
- We can fix you up.
Put you in a med-bay,
Sort all this fuck-up.
Let's go!
We'll take you up there.
Weather's nice, air's nice and clean.
Likely you'll dig it.
- Don't you fucking try anything!
- Step aboard!
Come meet the boys, come on!
Don't be shy, they won't bite.
Let me introduce you.
This is Drakie. This is Max.
What is news?
Let's fly!
Yes, ma'am, we apprehended the subject.
- Open the skies, we're coming in.
- I'll expect you in 19 minutes.
- Cancel the No Fly Zone.
- Yes, ma'am.
Hold it...
Hold it. What is that? ...
Are we back? Marcelo!
What the fuck is that? Are we back?
- We're back online.
- Alright.
Frey...
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna make this right.
- We've got him.
- Alright. Where is he?
Leaving Earth...
Heading to Elysium.
Manuel! Rico! Get weapons!
Let's get up there.
Echo leader 234, requesting
landing in sector 22.
Roger that Echo leader 234.
You are clear for entry...
[Afrikaans]
♪ Jan Pierewiet, Jan Pierewiet,
♪ Jan Pierewiet staan stil(stand still)
♪ Goeie môre, my vrou,
Good morning my wife,
♪ hier's 'n soentjie vir jou
here's a kiss for you,
♪ Goeie môre, my man,
Good morning my man,
♪ daar is koffie in die kan.
there is coffee in the can.
[ENG]
- I see you got the G-1 there.
- Hey, back the fuck up!
- Or what?
- I'll let it go.
What you gonna do? Huh?
I want what's in your head, boy.
Git'im !
Grab'im Deck!
What do you want us to do, ma'am?
I want everyone coming out of that
vehicle apprehended by Homeland Security.
Evacuate everyone on the level five
clearence out of the building, now.
I warned you of this.
An unlicenced vehicle just crashed
potentially damaging the Torus.
All because of your inability to act.
Evacuate him.
- Get your hands off me.
- This is an act of war.
That puts CCB under my control.
Now, if you'll let me do my job.
I'm sure you have
fund raisers to attend.
Let's go, sir.
Max!
Take me out of here, Max!
I'm trying!
Air quality reaching toxic levels
Get me out of here!
It is recommended you exit
the craft immediately
Run!
Fuck!
2 Illegals heading
Northeast in zone 3
You deal with those two.
I'll handle this pussy.
Welcome to the spectacular
properties from your...
Error
No!
No citizens detected
Please she's sick, help her.
She's gone into a coma.
Please !
Shouldn't we remove this thing?
Can't, till we get all the data.
It's wired into him neurologically.
The data is intact, yes?
Data looks intact.
Warning
We can still pull this data
out of him, which will kill him.
Oh, it's fine.
How long before you can download
and turn the system online?
Not long, Ma'am.
Keep everything in a restricted cloud.
Lock down all access.
Starting prep right now.
And get these two out of here.
Roger that.
Kurt you wanna go get
the boss' chicks
Yeah, good.
Give them the runaround.
Keep them busy.
Got 'im!
Let's go!
Alright. 50 exabytes, buddy.
Are you ready?
What are you taking out of him?
Hey! What're you doing to him?
What's gonna happen to him?
Hey!
Rise and shine.
- Get up!
- Max.
Max. Max.
Max!
Get in there!
Yes. Boss got fucked up, eh?
Ate that fucking grenade, eh!
His brain is fine. But he's gonna
be pissed when he wakes up.
Remember what cock-up happened
in India when he lost his hat?
Kruger.
Boss?
It's Crowe.
Where is he?
All right, all set.
Let's get the data.
I got the needle prepped.
You wanna grab this?
Grab the needle! Grab the...
- Where did they take the girls?
- The Armory.
Where the fuck is that?
Level three.
Lethal radiation poisoning detected.
You require urgent medical attention
You idiot! Do you realize
what you've done?
You crashed an unlicensed
vehicle into a suburban area.
Your orders were
to keep this covert.
Do you even remember
what that means?
Have you completely lost your mind?
You're useless to me.
If the administration
realized what we're doing.
They'd hang us both for treason.
For God's sake, Kruger!
Are you listening to me?
Yes.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm listening.
I'm sorry that we crashed the
vehicle and ruined someone's lawn.
But nobody is gonna
hang us for treason.
We do the hanging!
Put your hand on it.
keep pressure on it.
How tough you be now, eh?
Right boys, Elysium is about to
get its first proper president.
She needs some
medical attention.
I was gonna heal your daughter.
But now, I'll make sure
she's never healed.
Drakie, don't trust
any of those politicians!
Clear out this whole building!
Thank you, boss.
I'm gonna find that little gangster.
I'm gonna take what's in his head.
This place is mine now.
You want to come to
my fucking house and play?
Then play!
I'm going to annihilate
that little motherfucker
Pulverize that damn...
Hey!
What the hell was that?
All members of CCB please go to
the nearest exit and proceed calmly to...
Go, go, go!
No.
Detecting deceased
Emergency systems are now online
Please follow indicated procedures
Spider!
Do you read me, Spider?
Max, where are you.
The thing in my head, it can make
everyone a citizen here, right?
Yeah.
You know how to get it out, right?
Yes.
You're sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
OK, listen to me carefully.
Armory selected
Set.
Turn me on.
OK.
Crowe, get rid of those two.
My pleasure, boss.
My pleasure.
Where are you pikey?
Where are you?
How is it, girl?
Let's play.
- Come on, I'll be nice.
Gentle, I promise
- No. Please.
- Come on.
- Get off me!
- Want me to hurt the girl?
- No.
Then come here.
Fuck!
She alive?
For now.
Stay behind me.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
I have a plan.
D'you hear that sound?
That's the sound of me coming for you
I'll find you!
I'll hunt you down!
Frey, we have to split up.
- What?
- Listen.
You're gonna go to the
surface, OK? Take this.
Find a house,
get her to a med-bay.
- Max, it won't work.
- Don't stop. Don't stop...
She doesn't have an ID.
It doesn't work.
It will this time.
I know how to fix it.
Surface selected
- Go.
Come with me.
- I'm right behind you.
- No.
I promise.
Okay, a mother and her daughter
just went up in that elevator.
They're going to the surface
headed for a med-bay.
Send one of your guys
make sure they get there.
And we have our deal.
Right to a med-bay, man.
-Let's go.
-Go, go, go!
-This way!
Hurry up, man.
...emergency lock down...
Almost there.
What's that?
It's just a m... bitch!
That's what I'm talking about.
Fire has been detected...
Hold the door!
The Door!
...have been shut down.
- Come on! Come on!
- Go, go, go
Let's go!
Fuck. C'mon!
Let's go! You first. C'mon!
Come on! Stand up!
Stand! Stand up!
Come on!
Stand up!
You little fucker.
I'm gonna take
your fucking head off!
Dude, you should
definitely stand up now!
No!
Stay there.
Fuck!
- You think you could
get through me?
- Come on, Max! Come on!
I'm just getting started.
Come on.
Don't give up now.
Get up, come on! Come on!
You want more than this?
I know you.
You look a little bit dizzy, eh?
Did I get you?
Are you bleeding?
You must get that looked at.
Hey, boy?
You wanna heal
that little girl?
You just need to come
through me.
You got some fire in you, boy
You almost had me.
We die together, boy.
Come on, ma, let's go.
Let's go, man, let's do it.
Come on!
Ready? Let's go.
Get the guards, now!
Alright.
Sorry.
OK, we're good, we're good.
We're good.
What?
Max.
It's okay. I know.
There's no coming back from this.
No med-bay can heal you.
Alright, give it to me.
Take it.
Ready?
You just have to press
that button.
Frey?
Max?
Max where are you?
I'm gonna have to break my promise.
I can't make it back up there.
You remember what I said
when we were kids?
Yes.
I'll take us there one day.
- Really?
- Yeah, I promise.
You wouldn't believe what
I'm looking at right now.
Tell Matilda
I really liked her story.
I figured out why
the Hippo did it.
Come on!
You go first. Come on!
[SPAN]
We all have something special, Max.
Something we're destined to do.
Something for which we were born.
[ENG]
Fuck you!
Let go of me!
Come on, please.
[SPAN]
My baby. My dear.
[ENG]
Stand down, Officers.
Arrest him.
I can not arrest a citizen of Elysium.
What?
Doing a great job.
Guess who Elysium
belongs to now?
[SPAN]
See how beautiful
it looks to us down here?
Now look how beautiful
we look from up there.
Now it belongs to you.
So you'll never forget where you come from.
My little Max.
Subtitles & translations by AsifAkheir