(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER RADIO)
ENDER: Fifty years ago,
an alien force known
as the Formics attacked Earth.
Tens of millions died.
It was only through
the sacrifice
of our greatest commander
that we avoided
total annihilation.
We've been preparing for them
to come back ever since.
The International
Fleet decided
that the world's
smartest children
are the planet's best hope.
Raised on war games,
their decisions are intuitive,
decisive, fearless.
I am one of those recruits.
No, I got him.
He's poking his head out.
HYRUM: I've watched
through his eyes,
I've listened
through his ears,
and I tell you
he's the one.
That's what you said
about his brother.
Brother tested out impossible
for other reasons.
Nothing to do
with his tactical abilities.
I gotcha, I gotcha...
RECRUIT: Go around.
(RECRUITS SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
He's gonna crush him.
Come on!
You can't do that!
You've got to use
what's around you.
No, no, no. I had you
all the way through the belt!
You miscalculated
your trajectory
relative to
the incoming asteroid.
Don't lecture me, Wiggin!
You cheated!
It was a good game.
Thanks.
Hey!
Play again.
Sorry.
Tomorrow maybe?
HYRUM: You see?
He's got a talent
for strategy.
His humility could be false.
Part of a strategy
to avoid antagonizing
an ego-driven opponent.
Which makes him even smarter.
He may be a genius,
but we need someone the others
will follow. A leader.
He can't win on his own.
HYRUM: Well, let's see how
he handles rejection.
MAN: (OVER PA) Andrew Wiggin.
Andrew Ender Wiggin,
please report
to the infirmary.
Ender Wiggin,
(DOOR OPENS)
(INHALES)
Hello, Ender.
Hello.
That nasty monitor
is coming out today.
Please. Lie face down.
Am I off the program?
Did I do something wrong?
That's not really
for me to say.
Lie down.
The sooner we get this done,
the sooner you can move on.
(GASPING)
Ready?
This won't hurt a bit.
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
(SCREAMING)
(ENDER BREATHING HEAVILY)
OFFICER: A-ten-hut!
Forward march!
(OFFICERS CONTINUE YELLING
ORDERS INDISTINCTLY)
BOY 1: Where do you think
you're going, Wiggin?
(GRUNTS)
Washed out, huh?
Come on!
(GRUNTS)
BOY 2: Get him in there!
ENDER: You're expecting...
(GRUNTS)
Come on!
(PANTING)
Come on, cheat.
One on one,
for real this time.
No game.
BOY 3: He's got
no monitor now.
That's right.
No one watching you now,
Wiggin.
One on one?
Then why are your boys
holding me?
Let's go.
Come on, man.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(YELLS)
(PANTING)
Stay down...
I'm gonna kill you, cheat.
(GRUNTS)
Goddamn...
(GRUNTING)
Take it easy, Ender!
(ENDER PANTING)
You might be thinking
of ganging up on me.
But just remember what I do
to people who try to hurt me.
ENDER: He said I was cheating.
Said that was why
I was off the program,
and I kept on kicking him.
VALENTINE: It doesn't matter.
Even after he was down.
He'll never bully you again.
All I could think was,
"What would Peter do?"
I'm just like him, Val.
No. No, you are
nothing like him, Ender.
PETER: Nothing like who?
I thought you had a game?
Rained out.
What's he crying about?
I'm not crying.
My monitor's gone.
Now I'm just like you.
You mean that
Mom and Dad spent
all that money on a third,
and now he's off
the program too?
Stop it, Peter. He made it
farther than either of us.
Hey, dropout.
Remember how to play
Formics and Astronauts?
That's it! Where's Mom?
ENDER: No, don't.
I'll play.
PETER: Put the mask on.
You can be the bug.
(GASPS) Peter! You're insane!
Stay out of this, Valentine!
No! Stop it!
PETER: Alright, bug, you
started it, you attack first.
Peter! Let me in!
Come on!
(BOTH GRUNT)
PETER: Come on, fight back!
At last
we got one of you alive!
Peter! Stop it!
You know, I could kill you,
just like this.
(GASPING)
Peter... Please...
I should have been chosen.
(GASPS)
(COUGHING)
CHAMRAJNAGAR: (ON TV)
Deep space intel shows us
that the number of enemy ships
already deployed
is 10 times those we faced
during the first invasion.
The Formics are rebuilding
and strengthening their fleet.
We must conquer or die.
Turn it off, please, John.
Why? You'd rather not know
what's going on in the world?
We must never again
bear witness
to the slaughter of tens of
millions of innocent people,
as we did during
the Formic invasion.
I'd rather you talk
to your son.
Our survival demands
total commitment
to the destruction
of the enemy.
If you want, I'll go away,
so you don't have
to be embarrassed.
Ender, no one is embarrassed.
I'm a third.
I should never have been born.
No. We wanted you, Ender.
We just needed permission.
(SIGHS)
John, please say something.
It's a tough program, Ender.
When they brought me
to this country,
there was less competition.
And still, I didn't make it.
You have nothing
to be ashamed of.
Nothing.
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
AUTOMATED FEMALE VOICE:
Sensor alert.
Front door.
Please state your name.
Colonel Hyrum Graff,
Director of Training,
International Fleet.
This is my colleague,
Major Anderson.
May we?
GWEN:
Why'd you keep kicking him?
You'd already won the fight.
Did you enjoy it?
No.
Then why? Speak up, son.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Knocking him down
was the first fight.
I wanted to win
all the next ones too.
So they'd leave me alone.
Ender, you should have asked
a grownup for help.
Nonsense.
He can fight his own battles.
Colonel,
he was obviously being bullied
and he defended himself.
Son...
I'd like to offer you a place
in our program.
But you took away my monitor.
The final step
in our evaluation
is always to see what happens
when the monitor's removed.
And he passed?
He put a child
in the hospital.
HYRUM: It's not what he did.
It's why he did it.
It was tactical.
A strategy to stop
future attacks.
Ender, you don't
have to do this.
Ender and I should have
a private conversation.
Absolutely not!
With all respect, sir,
you really can't stop me.
The Formics
might have wiped us out
the last time, you know.
A brilliant commander is
the only thing that saved us.
Mazer Rackham...
Mazer Rackham.
We need minds like yours,
Ender.
Young people integrate complex
data more easily than adults.
Will the monitor
be reinstalled?
No.
You're graduating.
To Battle School.
Privacy rights restored.
If there is a chance that,
because of you,
the Formics might leave us
alone forever,
then I have to ask you
to come with me.
It's what I was born for,
right?
ENDER: Valentine
was too compassionate
for Battle School.
My brother Peter washed out
because he was too quick
to violence.
Colonel Graff said
I need to find a balance
between those emotions
if I were to succeed.
(PILOT ON PA
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Join the others.
Go on.
(PILOT ON PA CONTINUES
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
You're late.
Out of my control.
I'm Ender.
Ender?
(SCOFFS)
What kind of name is that?
What's your name?
Name's Bean.
Bean?
Grew up on the streets.
Not worth a bean.
PILOT: (ON PA) T-minus
10 seconds and counting.
(ALARM BUZZING)
T-minus five seconds
and counting.
Four, three, two, one...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
ENDER: Wow...
BOY 1: Oh...
BOY 2: Oh, my gosh!
(GAGGING)
I'm gonna be...
A bag! Give him the bag!
(RETCHING)
(ALL GROANING IN DISGUST)
ALL: Whoa!
Oh!
(COUGHING)
BOY 3: Are you serious, man?
Close the bag!
You all right?
Mmm.
What are you doin', Wiggin?
Nothing, sir.
Something funny?
I asked you a question,
Launchie!
Sir, the way you're floating.
Horizontal.
I thought that was funny.
Really? Why?
Because in zero gravity
there is no right side up.
You may think you're vertical
and we may be horizontal.
Is that funny?
ALL: Sir, no, sir!
Yes, it is.
Alai, do you know
what he's talkin' about?
Yes, sir.
No, you don't.
There's only one kid
on this launch
with any brains at all so far.
And that's Ender Wiggin.
WOMAN: (OVER PA)
All new arrivals
follow the yellow lights
to your accommodations.
The yellow lights.
(WOMAN ON PA
REPEATING INSTRUCTIONS)
Sir, you made them hate me.
I told them you were the best.
We need a Julius Caesar,
a Napoleon.
We hope that will be you.
Caesar was assassinated
by the people he trusted.
And Napoleon lost in the end.
Not before he conquered
the known world.
Dismissed.
Yes, sir.
He has a complicated response
to authority.
He wants to please the
overbearing father figure,
but resents a lack
of reciprocated affection.
His isolation
can never be broken.
He must never believe anyone
will help him.
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Oh, look! It's the smartass.
Thanks.
Thought I'd have to ask
to be by the door.
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
Speak your name.
Ender Wiggin.
DAP: Don't freeze
your balls, kid.
BERNARD: Attention on deck!
At ease.
Listen up, Launchies!
My name is Sergeant James Dap.
Ask me a legitimate question
and I will give you
a direct answer.
But if you are looking
for a shoulder to cry on,
use a pillow!
(BOYS CHUCKLE)
Do I look like I'm joking,
snots?
ALL: Sir, no, sir!
Good.
You are to work as a team.
You will all make
this bunk room your home.
You will keep your home clean!
There are separate showers
for both sexes.
If you're found in an area not
designated to your gender,
I will personally neuter you!
Am I clear?
ALL: Sir, yes, sir!
Class is in five!
Follow the yellow lights!
Yellow, like your
cowardly selves!
ALL: Sir, yes, sir!
Welcome to Battle School.
A great responsibility
rests upon each of you.
When the enemy first invaded,
we were not ready.
Millions of innocent lives
were lost.
That must never be allowed
to happen again.
We threw everything
we had at the invaders.
And in the midst
of that decisive battle,
a legendary hero emerged.
(MEN CHATTERING ON RADIO)
MAN 1: Eject! Eject!
MAN 2:
Break away now! Hammer 3!
Hammer 2, break left!
Bend at left, 7 o'clock.
Hammer 2 is hit!
Hammer 2 critical!
MAN 3: Hammer 1 has been hit!
(MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO)
(ALARM BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(ALL CHEERING)
HYRUM: We will never forget
what the enemy did.
But we defeated them.
And we will do so again.
Let the courage
of Mazer Rackham
be your inspiration.
DAP: Wakey, wakey,
rise and shine!
Put on your Battle Room suits!
That's the padded one with
the helmet and the weapon!
Do not attempt to fire
the weapon! Holster it!
Let's move it, Launchies!
You've got 10 minutes!
(ALL PANTING)
At ease.
This is the Battle Room.
In here,
the floor has been designed
to create an Earth-like
gravitational pull.
Step through that gate
and you're in
a zero-G environment.
(BEEPS)
(DEVICE BEEPS)
Wiggin.
Get up here.
(BEEPS)
(ENDER BREATHING HEAVILY)
What do I do now, sir?
Go on in.
(GASPS)
All right. Now, push off.
(GASPING)
(LOW GRUNT)
Whoa.
(GRUNTS)
(KIDS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(BOY 1 WHOOPS)
(GRUNTS)
BOY 2: Pull yourself. Whoa!
BOY 3: Grab my hand.
No, no! Stop! Stop!
Nicely done!
These guys
are still trying to stay up,
the way they came in.
Like you said in the shuttle,
there is no up
or down in space.
But we'll need some way
to orientate in here.
Maybe the enemy's gate
is "down."
I like it.
Like they're a bug to be
crushed under our feet.
Exactly.
What do you think this does?
We'll have to find out.
(GUN POWERING UP)
Whoa!
Well, that's harmless.
What do you think it does
when it hits the suit?
Good question.
Shoot me in the leg.
We shoot each other.
Same time.
You ready?
In three...
(GUNS POWERING UP)
BOTH: ...two, one...
Whoa! My leg's frozen!
Mine too!
I can't bend my knee.
Shoot me in the chest.
Come on! I'm getting away!
(GRUNTS)
This is amazing!
I can't move at all now.
You're out of your mind.
That's enough.
(ALL EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
(BOY 1 LAUGHS)
(BOY 2 WHOOPS)
You're flappin' around
like a bunch of drunken ducks!
If you expect to compete
with the other teams
at this school,
you've got a lot to learn.
Sergeant, explain the game.
You will train to compete
as a team against other teams.
You get one point
for a hit to a limb,
six for a torso hit,
which will immobilize
you completely.
But, if either side
gets one cadet
through their enemy's gate
unharmed,
that army will win,
regardless of points
already scored.
Am I clear?
ALL: Sir, yes, sir!
ENDER: "Dear Valentine...
So this is Battle School.
"Every day, hours of training.
"And far more homework
than we ever had on Earth.
"We train in
hand-to-hand combat.
"It keeps us in shape.
And aggressive."
And up!
And one!
(ALL YELL)
Two!
Three!
(ALL YELL)
"I feel Peter in me
whenever I fight."
Wiggin!
"I wish I didn't.
"We've been studying
Formic flight patterns
"for three months now,
"but they seem
entirely random.
"The truth is we really don't
understand our enemy.
"And no one ever
adequately explains
"how Mazer Rackham actually
defeated the entire fleet.
"The Colonel said
he expects me to lead.
"But how?
What makes a good leader?
"Everyone here
is very different.
"So many,
many things to learn.
"Always very little sleep.
"Please write back.
I haven't heard from you.
"How are you?
Is Peter behaving?
"Are you getting my emails?
I miss you..."
DAP: Attention on deck!
Evening, Launchies. At ease.
I'm pleased to see that most
of you are performing well.
As you know, competition for
Command School is tough.
Some in the higher ranks have
failed to meet our standards,
and they're being sent home.
So, I may have the opportunity
to promote some of you.
Look to your left.
Look to your right.
These are not your friends.
They are competition.
Keep up the hard work.
Attention!
Sir?
Is our email being blocked?
It's just that none of us
have received
any replies from home.
All communication is being
temporarily held back.
Why, sir?
Launchie,
it is not your place...
Your families
will not understand
what we're doing here.
And none of you need the
distraction of their replies.
I thought our privacy rights
had been restored, sir.
You have the right
to privately think
whatever you wish, Wiggin.
But there's too much at stake
to allow
your unfiltered thoughts
to leave this facility.
Yes, sir.
Keep it up, snot,
and you will never make it
to Command School.
I thought it was
a legitimate question.
What?
You said if we had
a legitimate question...
Drop and give me 20!
(HUFFING)
You think you're the smartest
kid in this school?
No, sir.
You will never be a commander!
I will never salute you!
Yes, you will, Sergeant.
Give me 20 more!
(HUFFING CONTINUES)
Get up!
You do not speak
unless spoken to!
Am I clear?
ALL: Sir, yes, sir!
Even if I have
a legitimate question?
Shut it, Wiggin!
Now go to sleep!
All of you!
You heard him.
Get some sleep.
We have only three
passing scores
on the deep space
navigation test.
Alai, Bean and Ender.
What happened here?
They probably cheated.
Your mother cheated.
That's why
you look like a plumber.
BEHARI: Zip it!
(ALL CHUCKLING)
You think this is a game?
No, ma'am.
We are preparing for war.
Yes, ma'am.
Now, the problem was simple.
How do you slingshot
your forces
into an attack position on
the blind side of this moon
using the gravitational pull
from this planet?
This is basic rocket science,
people.
Ender,
get down here and explain.
Ma'am, I think Bean or Alai
have a better handle
on this than I do.
BEHARI: All right.
Alai, come and explain.
ALAI: Ma'am,
we need to approach the planet
in the direction it's moving.
That way, we benefit
from its energy of motion.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Is something funny?
Go on, Alai.
ALAI: Of course, there's
a moon we have to pass here
and that complicates things.
Because the moon's moving in
the opposite direction to us,
we get
a gravitational braking.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Who sent this?
Who sent what, Bernard?
Nothing, ma'am.
Oh.
If you can't take it, Bernard,
don't dish it out.
Yes, ma'am.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
AUTOMATED MALE VOICE: Welcome
to Games and Recreation.
Cerebral control enabled.
(SQUEAKING)
(DERISIVE LAUGHING)
One is poison. One is not.
Choose right
and you'll go to Fairyland.
He's found the Mind Game.
Decide or I'll bite
your head off.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(SQUEAKING)
(SQUEAKING LOUDLY)
Bad luck.
(CHUCKLES)
Who authorized
his access to this?
I did.
Try again, little mouse.
To what end?
Not every battle can be won,
Hyrum.
The way he plays a game
reveals his state of mind.
If you won't let me
assess him one on one,
I need some other way
to know what he's feeling.
I don't care
how he's "feeling."
I want him to toughen up
and learn how to lead.
Well, before
we make him a leader,
let's see how he deals
with frustration.
(SQUEAKS LOUDLY)
Come on!
Oh, dear.
What you doin'?
Playing a stupid game.
No matter what I choose,
I die. It's rigged.
You're back.
One more time.
Can I watch?
Sure.
One is poison. One is not.
Choose right
and you'll go to Fairyland.
Which you gonna choose?
Neither.
Come on little mouse, come on.
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
ALAI: You killed him.
Why?
That's what they want from us.
Follow the rules, you lose.
Choose violence, you win.
I've never seen
anyone do that.
Perfect.
He's perfect.
SOTO: (ON CONSOLE)
Ender Wiggin,
you are assigned
to Salamander Army,
Commander Bonzo Madrid,
effective immediately.
Orders of Colonel Graff.
Follow the green lights.
Take nothing with you. Go now.
What are they doing?
They're promoting you.
Ender...
Yeah?
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Peace to you.
Throw!
BONZO: Come on!
Ball...
BONZO: Strike two!
Give me the ball.
It hit the wall!
All right. Strike two.
Play ball!
You lost, Launchie?
I'm Ender Wiggin.
Supposed to report
to Bonzo Madrid.
So you're the replacement?
Ender Wiggin.
Petra Arkanian.
Only girl
in the Salamander Army.
With more balls than anybody
else in this bunkroom.
Ooh! Mama Petra, she talking!
Wiggin?
Sir, yes, sir!
Ender Wiggin. Reassigned.
I ask for a replacement
for O'Reilly
and this is what I get?
A useless, skinny,
untrained snot!
I'm a quick study.
Let me be clear.
I intend to trade you ASAP.
My army is undefeated
in the last 21 battles.
I'm on track to make it
to Command School
within six months.
You can get your training
at someone else's expense.
He's all heart.
Shut it, Petra!
Easy, Bonzo...
Watch your mouth, Dink.
Here's the deal, snot.
When we go into battle,
you will not pass
through the gates
until all my soldiers
are through.
Then you will remain
just inside the gate
with your weapon
undrawn and unfired,
until the game ends.
So, I am to do nothing?
You are to keep
out of the way.
You bunk at the back
of the room.
PETRA: You know,
Bonzo doesn't like to lose.
He doesn't want
an untrained Launchie
screwing up
his perfect maneuvers.
But the Battle Room
is open 24/7.
During free time,
I could show you some moves.
(CHUCKLES)
You ready?
In three, two, one...
(GRUNTS)
(GUN POWERING UP)
Impressive.
Your turn.
Okay, you can't just keep
your thumb on the trigger.
You need half a second
to recharge.
At least you don't have
any bad habits.
I don't have
any good ones either.
I'll give you those.
Relax.
The further your target,
the longer you have
to hold the beam.
Fire.
(GUN POWERING UP)
Even longer.
It's the difference between
a tenth and a half-second.
But in battle
that's a long time.
Aim, fire, hold, recharge.
That's it.
Learn where your trigger
actually fires,
and ride the edge.
Now you're gettin' it!
In three, two, one...
Go! Let's see who'll beat me!
CADET 1: Come on, Dink!
You can do it!
BONZO: Once.
Just beat me once!
FLY: It's over.
CADET 1: Come on.
You can do it.
CADET 2: You got this!
BONZO: That's five in a row!
Who's the boss?
You the boss, Bonzo.
That's right. I'm the boss.
Let's go again.
I'm gonna make this six.
Ready?
PETRA: You'll get better
with practice.
Yeah, let's do it
again sometime.
(ENDER CHUCKLES)
Mmm-hmm. That was fun.
Where were you?
Practicing.
In free time.
You don't practice with her.
In fact,
you don't practice at all!
May I speak
to you privately, sir?
BONZO: Hey...
Wiggin!
Hey! Pendejo!
Don't you ever turn
your back on me!
If I'm gonna be useful in this
toon, I have to practice!
You will do what I tell you!
I will follow all commands
you are authorized to give.
But if you take away
my free time,
I will get you iced.
Are you threatening me, snot?
No.
Listen.
I know you want to trade me.
But no one will take me
if I don't know anything.
Let me practice.
You can get rid of me sooner.
I already gave you an order!
I know. In front of everybody.
And you don't want
your soldiers to think
that you backed down.
So, for tonight, you can say
that you won this argument.
Then tomorrow,
you can tell everybody
that you changed your mind.
You'll look generous,
I'll get to train,
we both win. Deal?
You'd better watch your back,
Wiggin.
Wake up!
Wake up, mis pendejos!
Battle with Leopard
in 10 minutes!
Hey, Wiggin!
Yes, sir!
I changed my mind.
Maybe by watching my toons,
you'll learn something
and I can trade you easier.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir!
Move! Everybody, let's move!
♪ Salamander is number one!
(CADETS REPEATING)
♪ There's no one
like us under the sun
(CADETS REPEATING)
♪ 'Cause Salamanders,
we're on top
(CADETS REPEATING)
♪ When it comes to winning,
we never stop ♪
(CADETS REPEATING)
Salamander halt!
At ease.
What's the play?
Four winds. Toon A, up,
B left, C right, D down.
You, Wiggin.
You hang back near the gate.
Bonzo, my toon'll be a man
short without him.
He knows nothing about
our formations, Dink.
He'll only get in the way.
You come out last.
Hang back and observe.
We don't need you.
Go, Salamander!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go, go, go, Salamander!
Go! Go!
(CADETS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTS)
We gotta break them up.
Fly, you lock with me.
Petra rides chariot!
Got it?
Got it!
Ready?
PETRA: Ready.
In three, two, one...
(CADETS CONTINUE SHOUTING)
I'm hit!
DINK: Me too!
Keep shooting, Petra!
Body hit her!
Take her out! Go!
I'm on it!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
Wiggin!
What are you doin'?
I told you to stay back!
(BOTH GRUNT)
Are you okay?
What are you doing here?
Bonzo will kill you.
I can't go back now.
Well, then get in the game.
We're losing.
ENDER: They've got half their
toon back near their gate.
Put your feet to mine.
Redirect me.
Play dead.
Don't draw your weapon
till you know you have a shot.
Got it.
In three, two, one...
(GRUNTS)
Smart move,
holding Wiggin back.
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GIGGLES)
Where'd you learn all this?
I had a brother.
Had?
Have.
Come on. Let's go again.
But use your arms,
not your hips.
Officer on deck! A-ten-hut!
I thought I told you
not to train with her.
I thought we'd agreed
that free time was free, sir.
At ease.
(GRUNTS)
Stop it, Bonzo!
(ENDER GASPS)
Try making me look
like a fool again
and I'll kill you.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(GASPS)
What do you want me to do?
Valentine?
(SQUEAKING)
How can you be in my game?
(WIND WHOOSHING)
(GASPS)
Ah!
(GRUNTS)
(HISSES)
(YELLS)
(PANTING)
Well done.
(GASPS)
You're a killer now.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Nightmares, Launchie?
Keep 'em to yourself.
HYRUM: You said the game would
reveal his state of mind,
not screw with it!
How did his psycho brother
end up in the game?
He's obviously feeling
some psychological pressure...
Of course he's feeling
pressure, Anderson!
This is a boot camp for kids
that are gonna have
to face a real enemy!
The game
is a thought relationship
between the child
and the computer.
Together they create stories.
Then change the story!
The stories reflect
the child's emotional reality.
I can't change that!
I don't know how these images
got into the game.
Erase the game.
(SIGHS)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(GASPS)
Doin' well.
Very well.
Top test scores in class.
Highest Battle Room ratings.
But you have a habit
of upsetting your commander.
I find it hard
to respect someone
just because
they outrank me, sir.
Puts you in a difficult
position, doesn't it?
Yes, sir.
You don't like taking orders
from Bonzo.
No, sir.
Perhaps you'd prefer
to give them yourself?
Sir?
How would you like to lead
your own army?
Dragon Army.
Sir, I've never heard
of a Dragon Army.
We discontinued the name
four years ago.
No Dragon Army
ever won a battle.
Then why not a new name, sir?
Because we already
have the uniforms.
And who will be
in this army, sir?
Misfits. Like you.
Oddballs who might
just be brilliant
with the right commander.
Your new quarters.
Your soldiers
are being notified now.
You will address them
in 15 minutes.
Do you think
they'll follow me?
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
DINK: A-ten-hut!
Officer on deck.
At ease.
Welcome to Dragon Army.
Bunking will be arranged
with youngest at the front
and veterans at the back.
Ender,
every other commander
has their seniors
closest to the door.
Well, I don't intend to be
like every other commander.
What am I doing here, Ender?
You don't even like me.
I didn't select this army,
Bernard.
But I intend to make it
the best in this school.
I think you can help
make that happen.
Am I wrong?
No, sir.
You will respect one another.
If anybody has an idea they
think is better than mine,
I wanna hear it.
I can't be expected to do
all the thinking
in this army, can I, Bean?
No, sir!
Then let's get suited up.
Training starts now!
CADETS: Sir, yes, sir!
GWEN: He's pushing them hard.
Might even make something
of Bernard.
Command School is pressing
for a decision.
Tell them we need more time.
We're out of time.
Lieutenant.
Tomorrow's game
will commence at 0300.
Yes, sir.
(ALARM BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Wake up! Wake up!
Battle with Salamander
and Leopard! In five!
BEAN: Two armies at once?
The Colonel is changing
the rules!
In a battle with the Formics,
there will be no rules.
(GROANS)
DINK: You all right?
I twisted my ankle.
How bad?
(GROANS) Not good.
Dink, get him
to the infirmary.
The rest of you, let's move!
Come on! We're late! Come on!
They already opened the gate?
Petra?
Two armies weren't enough?
They had to block
your view too?
What are you doing here?
Colonel said you needed a sub.
Guess he thought
your odds were zero
with me on the other team.
Bonzo agree to this?
DINK: Colonel Graff's orders.
He didn't have a choice.
Dink. Kneel.
What?
I have an idea. Kneel.
ENDER: Ready?
In three, two,
one!
ENEMY CADET 1: Fire now!
Shoot 'em! Fire!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
DINK: Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Look out!
(BOTH GRUNT)
PETRA: Twelve clear
on the wall!
Twelve down, 20 to go.
They could be right behind
these forward stars
or all the way back
at their gate.
Ready?
Ready.
ENEMY CADET 2: Now!
(GRUNTS)
Pull!
(GROANS)
Dumbos have a bunch of stars
around their gate
like a giant donut!
They're just
hanging behind 'em.
No one closer?
Nah.
Nice.
Let's see how
they handle a formation.
We've never done a formation.
Then they won't expect one.
We still outnumber him.
We should storm him
and crush him.
No. We hold our positions.
He has to come to us.
We can't lose.
Open fire!
(ENEMY CADETS
YELLING INDISTINCTLY)
They're drifting upwards!
On my count, row two,
push row one!
We're changing direction,
30 degrees!
In three, two, one...
Now!
Rear thrusters, row six...
Row five... Now!
ENEMY CADET 3: Come on.
Don't let them through.
ENEMY CADET 4:
We've gotta break them up!
ENDER: We're almost there!
(GRUNTS) I'm hit!
BERNARD: Hold on!
Alai, are you okay?
Yeah! Are we there yet?
Almost! Keep close!
Alai can't get hit!
BERNARD: We're nearly there!
Keep shooting!
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL GRUNT)
ALAI: We did it! Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
Eat that! Dragon rules! Yes!
ALAI: Who's undefeated now?
DRAGON ARMY CADETS: Dragon!
Still think he's not ready?
Don't be smug.
Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
BERNARD: Did you see the look
on Bonzo's face?
(DRAGON CADETS CHEERING)
We're tired of you, Ender.
You know,
your father would be proud.
Come to fight a boy
in the shower.
With your buddies.
Go watch the door.
Go!
Look...
You can say you won.
I'll say you taught me
a lesson.
No, coward.
Raise your fists.
Come out and fight! Come on!
Come on, fight! Come on!
(YELLS)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
I could break your arm!
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
(CHOKING)
Bonzo?
Bonzo!
Help!
We need help in here!
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
Everybody knows he started it.
Ender...
I am so sorry...
Major!
We should never have
allowed you to be alone...
Not now, Major!
Leave us.
Leave him.
Now.
You too, cadet.
He's gonna die, isn't he?
No... No.
Please, don't lie to me.
We're gonna send him home.
Back to Earth.
So he can get better.
I want to go with him.
I can't let you go.
You've come so far.
And I wanna talk to my sister.
The Fleet owns you, Ender.
Strategos would
never allow it.
Send me home, Colonel,
or I will resign.
Don't threaten me, boy.
I am not the enemy.
I'm not so sure.
I won't play
this game anymore.
I quit.
What are you gonna do?
Waste millions on a loser?
You wanted to see me.
You can't resign.
You have an obligation
to stay here
and convince him
to do his duty.
My father trained horses.
I've raised yearlings
since I was five years old.
I know a thoroughbred
when I see one.
We can't lose him.
My God...
You really don't see them
as children, do you?
It used to be a war crime
to recruit anyone
under the age of 15.
When the war is over
we can have the luxury
of debating the morality
of what we do.
When it's over,
what will be left of the boy?
What does it matter if
there's nothing left at all?
We're using these children
to win a war.
And if they come home,
it's my job to put them
back together again.
Thanks for what you've done.
Where's Ender?
Hello, Valentine.
Why are you here?
Did something happen?
They won't let me see him.
I need you
to take a ride with me.
HYRUM: He's gonna be happy
to see you.
Come on... You just
want him to re-enlist.
I want him to save lives.
And what about his life?
ENDER: I've been sitting
by Bonzo's bed,
waiting for him to wake up.
But he may never wake up.
Ender, he attacked first.
And I fought back,
just like Peter taught me.
I've had a lot of fights, Val.
I've won because
I've always understood
the way my enemy thinks.
And when I truly
understand them...
...you also love them.
I think it's impossible
to truly understand someone
and not love them
the way they love themselves.
But in that moment...
You beat them.
I destroy them.
I make it impossible for them
to ever hurt me again.
Ender, they want me to talk
you into going back.
I told them I won't cooperate.
I don't think
you're hiding here
just because you care
about Bonzo.
I think you're hiding
because you're afraid.
Afraid you don't know
your enemy.
Afraid you might lose.
But what if you're the next
Mazer Rackham?
You can't hide here forever.
But if you stay here,
if you don't try,
then we will all be lost.
I'll miss you.
VALENTINE: I'll miss you, too.
I need to know that you will
not block my emails again.
(SPEAKER BEEPS)
WOMAN: (OVER PA) Attention,
prepare for transporter
docking operation.
Initiating final approach.
I thought we were going back
to Battle School.
We're not.
Where are we going?
(SIGHS)
Much further.
ENDER: "Dear Valentine...
"I must now travel
to our advanced command base
"near the Formics'
home planet,
"where I'll begin
final training.
"If successful, I'll command
the entire invasion fleet.
"I wish there was another way,
but war seems inevitable.
"Stay safe. Love, Ender."
HYRUM:
Not very hospitable, is it?
We took it from the Formics
27 years after
Rackham's victory.
Flushed them out
of these tunnels
like rats from a sewer.
Drove 'em all the way back
to their home planet.
How long did they live here?
We're not sure.
This was a forward
staging post
for their invasion of Earth.
We built our base here to be
closer to their home planet,
to allow instantaneous
communication
by Ansible
with our attack fleet.
If they're on their
home planet,
do we have them contained?
For now.
If we have them boxed in,
why go to war?
For the same reason that
you kept kicking that bully
before I recruited you.
The purpose of this war
is to prevent all future wars.
Your training begins
first thing tomorrow morning.
Sergeant Dap will show you
to your quarters.
Yes, sir.
We're still re-seeding
the atmosphere.
It's breathable, but thin.
In the event of an evacuation,
two breaths every minute
from one of these
will compensate for lower
levels of surface oxygen.
Lights out in five.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GASPS)
Who are you?
Look, this may be
amusing to you,
but they'll come
looking for me.
(GROANS)
You wanna fight me?
Is that the test?
To see if I'll attack
an old man?
Well, I won't.
I'll just sit this one out.
(GROANS)
Okay. You win.
Since when do you tell
the enemy when he has won?
I surprised you once.
Why didn't you destroy me
immediately after?
I thought you were a teacher.
There is no teacher
but the enemy.
Only he will tell you
where you are weak,
where he is strong.
From now on,
I am your enemy, got it?
Yes.
Good.
(PANTING)
During training, I will devise
the strategy of your enemy.
Remember,
he is stronger than you.
From now on,
you are always about to lose.
Sir?
Do you have a name?
Mazer Rackham.
What? You thought I was dead?
Sir, I've been building models
of your planes
since I was six years old.
I have a question, sir.
On the vids,
they always cut out
right after you destroy
the one carrier.
Why?
Get dressed.
(MEN TALKING
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO)
Sir, I've already seen this.
And I wanna know
what happens after.
Just watch.
(ALARM BEEPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
After the explosion cleared,
everything was
incredibly still.
(SILENCE)
Their ships
just stopped shooting.
And then they started
falling out of the sky.
ENDER: Scroll back, please.
To just after you lost
your wing man.
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
ENDER: There.
Play back, please.
You took cover in the cloud.
You couldn't see anything,
so you must have
been using your HUD.
There. Stop.
You saw something.
What did you see in your HUD?
Did you find a pattern?
Very good, Ender.
Thermal imaging
from a satellite.
The enemy's in red.
What pattern do you see?
ENDER: It seems random.
But it's not.
There's an epicenter,
right there.
Meaning?
You took out
that one particular ship,
and the rest just
gave up?
To what animals
are the Formics
most often compared?
Ants.
Which have...
A queen...
Who directs the worker ants.
What she thinks they do.
Without her, they can't
think for themselves...
And they die.
You destroyed
the queen's ship.
I must have. Yes.
But you can't be certain?
No.
And so the Hegemon insisted
we keep it classified.
That's why they never show
the rest of the battle.
Or my face.
To the world I'm dead.
Colonel...
Your face...
You mean, why is it marked?
My father was a Maori.
Lost him in the war.
Ta Moko is a way
to connect to my past.
To my inner skin.
It was a way for me
to speak for the dead.
Sir, have you ever
seen a queen?
No. No one has.
But if the Formics
have rebuilt their fleet,
there must be more
than one queen.
Yes, of course.
On their home planet.
What happened
when you attacked here?
Did you find one?
No.
Why did they come?
Water.
BEAN: Attention!
Officer on deck!
Hey, Bean.
Ho, Commander!
Petra.
We thought you were iced.
We were gonna have
to have Dink take over.
That was never gonna happen!
Salaam, Alai.
Salaam, Commander!
Bernard.
Good to see you, sir.
At ease.
BEAN: While you've been
skinny-dipping
the Colonel's been flogging us
to death on the simulator!
All right. Take your seats.
In a matter of weeks
we may be called on
to fight a real battle.
Let's bring your commander
up to speed.
Our latest probe images
will give you an idea
of what's happening
on the enemy planet.
Like us, they appear to have
a population growth rate
that's unsustainable.
For now, they're contained
on their planet.
Time is not on our side.
Where are they?
MAZER: High surface
temperatures limit
their above-ground activity
to just a few hours a day.
What's most alarming
is the rate
at which their military power
is expanding.
But they have not yet
moved against us.
No.
They're planning to colonize
another planet
before they breed themselves
into extinction.
Our orders are to defeat them
before they pose
an irreversible threat.
HYRUM: Their very existence
is a threat.
Is that clear, Commander?
Clear, sir.
Good.
Carry on, Colonel.
We will begin with
photo real simulations
to best approximate
real battles.
You will command
overall strategy.
Your toon leaders will
each command a battle group.
You will issue orders to them.
They will issue orders
to their squadrons
of drone pilots.
(HATCHES OPENING)
(ENGINES BOOMING)
Finally,
your entire fleet must support
and protect your most
important asset.
Seventy billion dollars
of pure destruction.
The M.D. 500.
Which Petra
is trained to fire.
M.D.?
Molecular Detachment Device.
We call her
"the little Doctor."
Particle beams accelerate
from her twin barrels.
At the focus point, they reach
critical effective mass.
A chain reaction
spreads outwards,
shattering molecular bonds.
Leaves nothing standing.
That's the beauty
of the little Doctor.
No need to identify
a specific ship for the queen.
The chain reaction
takes out an entire swarm.
But I'll only get one shot.
Once the Formics
see how she works,
they won't clump
together again.
You will have to win this war
one battle at a time.
CHAMRAJNAGAR: Once our battle
fleet is detected
entering the Formic
solar system,
we will have no alternative
but to engage.
I trust we have chosen
our commander well.
There's greatness in him, sir.
And a killer instinct too,
I hope.
Absolutely.
Let's hope he's all
you claim him to be.
We'll be with you soon.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, sir.
ENDER: "Dear Valentine...
So this is Command School.
"I'm finally here.
"Being a third, I've always
been so afraid I might fail.
"That I might not measure up.
"But they made me a leader.
"And I promise you
"that I'll do everything I can
to win this war.
"I know if anything
ever happened to you,
"I would never
forgive myself."
What are they doing?
Harvesting water.
If you're going to use me,
I need to be closer.
Too risky. Let's not reveal
our best weapon
in what should be
an easy attack.
Alai, Bean,
your Dreads peel away.
Track them from below the ice
and mirror their path.
BERNARD: They're swarming!
They see us!
Deploy all drones!
Give me
four hyperbolic formations
with 90 degree offsets!
Open fire!
Bean, Alai, on my call,
fire directly up into the ice!
We're gonna shred 'em!
ENDER: In three, two, one...
All right!
Now!
(CHUCKLES)
(ALL CHEERING)
ENDER:
"As our training progresses,
"the simulations are becoming
"more and more complex,
and real.
"The pressure to win,
day after day,
"month after month,
is intense.
"We get very little sleep.
"Some days,
it's hard to keep up."
I got the breakaway!
Great work, Bean!
Squadrons 43 through 57,
split to quadrant Foxtrot,
38, 89!
Ender, watch our right flank!
We need backup for Bernard.
ENDER: I see it!
Bernard, you flank them!
Copy that.
Using 10 through 18!
Alai, peel right!
Dink, compensate
for the pull of planet G8
and go full throttle!
Bean, mop up in sector Sierra!
I got a sprinter left in Lima!
Do Sierra now!
Bernard, watch your speed!
Dink,
you are closing too fast!
You said full throttle!
Pull back now, Dink!
(SIGHS)
(ANGUISHED CRY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
We can't absorb
these kind of losses!
War isn't a game where you get
to reboot and start over!
Sir, I can't win
if I don't take any risks.
Nobody's saying
not to take risks.
Just don't try
and control everything.
Let Bean improvise
in the mop-ups.
You focus on the big picture.
Delegate more to your teams!
My teams are burned out!
How can they be effective
if they don't get any sleep?
Sleep deprivation
is part of your training!
A battle with the Formics
could last for days!
If I'd been smarter,
I could have annihilated
Petra's little Doctor
while you were
micro-managing Bean!
That can't happen, understand?
Yes, sir.
Do you?
'Cause I've trained others.
Each one so hopeful.
Each one ultimately a failure.
All right, Colonel.
He understands.
So I'm not the first?
MAZER: No.
But you will be the last.
There's no time
to train anyone else.
Son, tomorrow
Colonel Rackham will run
your final simulation.
And if I win tomorrow?
What happens?
You will be ready to face
the real enemy.
And you will be the finest
commander we've ever trained.
ENDER: One more simulation
and I may have to go to war.
What happens when
it's no longer a game?
Real war is different.
I still know nothing
about my enemy.
ENDER: What if they
could talk to us?
They can't.
Dissections show
no vocal chords.
There are other ways
to communicate.
Ender,
this is not a conversation
we should be having
at 1:00 a.m.
What if they could
"think" to one another?
What if we could
"think" to them?
We need to sleep.
We have a graduation battle
tomorrow.
Right.
We're gonna get crushed.
We won't be crushed.
We have you.
Now go to sleep.
Goodnight, Petra.
Goodnight, Ender.
You still think
he's "the one"?
We're committed.
This boy has the empathy
to think like a Formic.
To understand them,
anticipate them.
He's not ready.
You're never "ready."
You go when you're
"ready enough."
(GASPS)
DAP: Easy, sir.
It's graduation day.
(GASPS)
Good luck, sir.
BEAN: Attention!
At ease.
BEAN: Sir...
We have an audience.
HYRUM: Commander Wiggin,
the Strategos is here today to
witness your final simulation.
If you are successful,
he will endorse your promotion
to Battle Commander
of the entire fleet.
Yes, sir!
This simulation is staged
around the enemy's
home planet.
Good luck, Commander.
Thank you, sir.
Stay calm.
Shoot straight.
Here we go.
They're waiting.
Maybe they think
we come in peace.
BERNARD: I don't think
Mazer intends for us
to find a diplomatic solution.
What's he waiting for?
Just give him a minute.
Ender, what do we do?
BEAN: Ender...
The enemy's gate is down.
Petra. You're up.
They're spread too wide
for a chain reaction.
She's right.
Just let him follow
his instincts.
All battle groups
deploy drones.
Protect your carriers.
Alai!
You're squadron five! Engage!
This is suicide.
Oh, crap...
They're swarming.
Clumped enough
for you now, Petra?
Once I fire I need
time to recharge.
ENDER: Understood.
Just go for the center.
Fire now!
She did it...
Yeah...
(BEEPING)
Give me false color.
We're not done yet.
But we are so screwed...
No, we're not.
Charged, Petra?
No. I need two minutes.
All fighters fall back
and surround Petra's ship!
BERNARD: Copy that.
ENDER:
I want rings within rings.
Layers upon layer.
Every fighter we have!
Ender, you're gonna leave
our transporters defenseless!
If we're gonna win
this battle, Dink,
it's all or nothing now!
When the outer layer is hit,
the wreckage will continue to
drift with us, like a shield.
Do it now!
He's abandoning
his entire fleet.
He's in command.
There's no stopping him now.
PETRA: Ninety seconds, Ender!
ALAI: No, no... No!
I'm losing my carriers!
My Dreadnaughts are out!
I don't care
about Dreadnaughts!
Just protect Petra!
Like we protected Alai
when we fought Bonzo!
I hope you know
what you're doing.
Ready, Petra?
PETRA: In 60 seconds!
What am I aiming for?
The planet.
What?
If we destroy the planet,
we destroy the queens.
Game over.
Ender, my targeting sensor
needs a clear line of sight!
ENDER: We will clear a path!
All fighters maintain
a clockwise rotation!
Focus all firepower forward!
Ender, we're entering
their atmosphere!
ALAI: We need to slow down!
BERNARD: We can't!
We're one unit now.
PETRA:
We're not equipped to handle
the heat of passage
through an atmosphere!
Our drones
are our heat shield.
Keep falling.
Let gravity do the work.
The shield won't hold forever!
We don't need forever.
PETRA: Thirty seconds!
I still don't have
a clear shot.
BERNARD: We're burning up!
Bean, on my count,
accelerate your fighters
from the nose of the formation
in a continuous stream.
Yes, sir!
Like bullets from a rifle,
you will clear
a visual for Petra!
We will drill a hole
through this swarm!
Petra,
you will only get a second.
That's all I need!
In three, two, one...
Now, Bean!
DINK: Shield integrity's
at 5%!
Now, Petra! Now!
PETRA: Seven seconds!
BEAN:
They've broken the shield!
Fire, Petra!
We're out of time!
(MACHINE POWERING UP)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
We did it! Yeah!
DINK: Yes!
(APPLAUSE AND CHEERING)
(TEAM LAUGHING)
ALAI: Great job, Ender!
Yes! Thank you!
BERNARD: Good game, Ender!
ENDER: Good job, guys!
BERNARD: (LAUGHING) Yeah!
How about that?
Game over.
(INAUDIBLE)
What's he saying?
MARTIN:
Restoring Ansible connection.
ENDER: What is this?
Why are we watching
these images?
(GASPS)
Ender...
HYRUM: Thank you.
Brilliant.
Absolutely brilliant.
Thank God for you, son.
Why are these images
in the program?
Ender...
We won.
What do you mean, "we won"?
I beat him.
He runs the simulations.
He said it was a game!
MAZER: It was them
or us, Ender.
There was no other way.
With this victory,
you've won all future battles.
You destroyed them.
For all of us.
(STRATEGOS APPLAUDING)
DAP: Stand down.
(ENDER WHIMPERS)
HYRUM: Move, move, please!
Move!
DAP: Make a way.
(SOBS)
Ender...
Stay away from me!
You lied!
Son, we were afraid
if we told you, you might...
What?
Refuse to play?
I've killed an entire species!
They would have done
the same to us.
No! They waited.
What were they waiting for?
Who cares?
We lost 1,000 men
on the transporters
you abandoned!
I abandoned them
in order to win!
Yes! And they died proudly!
For us!
They might not
have died at all!
If I'd known it was real,
I would have...
What?
Called for "a dialogue?"
They can't even speak.
Watched them!
What were they thinking?
Were they building an army
for a second invasion?
Or... Or simply preparing
to defend themselves...
Ender, stop...
...from us?
They came to Earth
to establish a colony.
We chased them away.
And in 50 years,
they never returned.
Makes no difference now.
I will bear the shame
of this genocide forever.
No. You will be
remembered as a hero!
I will be remembered
as a killer!
It was us or them.
And you're sure we've killed
every last one of them?
I saw their whole
planet destroyed.
How do you know
there isn't another colony?
Or another queen out there?
There isn't!
We won!
That's all that matters.
No.
The way we win matters.
(GRUNTS)
Don't hurt him.
(GROANS)
Go on.
We need to let him rest.
PETRA: May I stay with him?
Just so he's not alone.
Please?
Yes, of course.
DINK: Come on.
Just let him rest.
ENDER:
What if they could talk to us?
What were they thinking?
Valentine!
What if we could
"think" to them?
Valentine!
Ender!
Ender, wait!
What are you doing, Ender?
ENDER: I know what she wants!
Ender!
AUTOMATED MALE VOICE: Warning,
you are leaving an
oxygen-balanced environment.
Ender, stop!
It's not safe!
Ender!
(PANTING)
Breathe. Just breathe.
ENDER: In the mind game,
I saw this place.
What are you talking about?
The Formics accessed
the game through me.
Their thoughts. My dreams.
All mixed together.
They were trying
to communicate.
What are you doing?
Go back.
No.
Please...
I have to do this.
(INHALING)
ENDER: "Dear Valentine...
"I now know my dreams
were never my own.
"They came from her.
"She was always trying
to communicate with me.
"I know the Formics
better than any living soul.
"I stole their future
from them.
"Now I must find a way
to make amends."
(PULSATING)
(FORMIC SKITTERING)
(GASPS)
(SHUDDERS)
You're dying...
Is it a queen?
I will find a new home.
I promise.
ENDER: "I miss you, Valentine.
"You won't be hearing
from me for a while.
"I need to find out
"if I'm as gifted at peace
as I am at war.
"They've awarded me
the rank of Admiral
"and left me
to my own devices.
"Which suits me fine.
"I'll travel the universe
"and carry with me
a precious cargo.
"Because I have
a promise to keep."