WILL: I don't have time.
I don't have time to
worry about how it happened.
It is what it is.
We're enetically engineered
to stop aging at 25.
The trouble is, we live only one more year
unless we can get more time.
Time is now the currency.
We earn it and spend it.
The rich can live forever.
And the rest ofus?
I just want to wake up
with more time on my hand
than hours in the day.
Hey, Mom.
You got in late last night.
I put in some overtime.
Where'd it go?
On you.
They drink it in New Greenwich.
Happy 5oth!
Fifty?
That's right.
Twenty-five for the 25th time.
Oh, I was sure I'd have a grandchild by now.
Here we go.
Bela's daughter is always asking about you.
Who has time for a girlfriend?
Besides, what's the hurry?
What do you got?
Three days. Not even.
We owe half that in rent.
Eight for the electric and
we're still late on that loan.
I can make extra on the side, you know.
- I could...
- What, start fighting?
Nobody wins.
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
Remember, I'm not here tonight.
I got two days' work in the garment district.
- I know.
- Meet me at the bus stop tomorrow.
- After I pay off the loan, I won't have long.
- I'll be there.
Will...
I just wouldn't know what to do if I lost you.
I'm late.
Let me give you 3o minutes
so you can have a decent lunch.
I love you.
Happy birthday, Mom.
When you get back,
we're going to celebrate.
GIRL: Will!
Will!
You got a minute?
What are you talking about, Mya?
You have a whole year.
Not a year I can use yet.
Come on, Will. I've got bills to pay.
Here, take five minutes.
Get out of here.
Four minutes for a cup of coffee?
Yesterday, it was three.
You want coffee or you want to reminisce?
Two coffees.
- How many shifts you got today, Borel?
- Just the two.
Really excited about it.
If you had any of your father in you,
we could make a fortune.
I don't fight.
There's another one. Broad daylight.
Whoa, what is this? Where's the rest?
Never met the quota.
My units are up from last week.
So's the quota. Next.
That's a joke, right?
- Next.
- MAN: Move it. You're taking forever.
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING IN THE BAR)
You in, Will?
I don't have time to gamble anymore.
Oh, thank God.
Because ever since you stopped playing,
I started winning.
You still owe me an hour.
You seen Borel?
- Will!
- Hey, man.
Your wife's looking for you.
You're not gonna believe it.
This madman's been buying drinks all night.
He's got a century!
Come on, let me get you home.
Soon as I finish this drink.
Hey! You!
You!
More everything!
Do you want to come home with me?
You can take us both home.
Excuse me.
You need to get out of here.
Somebody's gonna clean that clock.
Yes!
I mean, they aren't going to rob you.
They are going to kill you.
They can't take that much time
and let you live to tell about it.
Yes.
I don't think you understand.
You should not be here!
(MUSIC STOPS)
BOREL: Will. Will!
Minutemen!
Minutemen! Walk away, Will.
Those gangsters aren't playing around.
Wait, wait.
He's asking for it. Let's go.
He's not one of us.
You think he'd help us?
Don't worry. I won't do anything stupid.
Go.
The name's Fortis.
And that, sir, is a very nice watch.
Do you mind if I try it on?
I think it would suit me.
FORTIS: I'll tell you what.
I'll fight you for it.
Come on.
I'm an old man. Turned 75 last week.
I need a moment.
(VOMITING)
You ready to go?
Ready to go.
Let's get you out of here.
Get him!
Stop. What are you doing?
I can take care of myself.
Yeah, it looked like it.
I know what I'm doing.
Run. Run!
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
WILL: Come on!
Here!
Hurry!
Move!
Where the hell are you going? Get in here!
(KICKING DOOR)
I know who took him.
I know who he is.
Who he was.
(BOTH PANTING)
(SIGHS) Damn it, damn it.
(CHUCKLES)
What the hell are you doing here?
Flashing all that?
You out of your mind?
Henry Hamilton.
Will Salas.
Ugh. (COUGHS)
God.
Drink more, it gets better.
(EXCLAIMS)
Not much better.
You'll be safe till morning.
I'll get you out of here.
You're from New Greenwich.
Does it show?
Nah.
Looks like you could use some help yourself.
No, thanks.
How old are you?
In real time?
Twenty-eight.
I'm 1o5.
Good for you.
You won't see 1o6, you have too many
more nights like tonight.
You are right.
But the day comes when you've had enough.
Your mind can be spent,
even if your body's not.
We want to die.
We need to.
That's your problem?
You've been alive too long?
You ever known anyone who's died?
For a few to be immortal, many must die.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
You really don't know, do you?
Everyone can't live forever.
Where would we put them?
Why do you think there are Time Zones?
Why do you think taxes and prices go up
the same day in the ghetto?
The cost of living keeps rising to
make sure people keep dying.
How else could there be
men with a million years
while most live day to day?
But the truth is
there's more than enough.
No one has to die before their time.
If you had as much time
as I have on that clock,
what would you do with it?
I'd stop watching it.
I can tell you one thing.
If I had all that time,
I sure as hell wouldn't waste it.
(SIGHS)
Get some rest.
Don't worry. I won't take it in the night.
And I won't take yours.
(EXHALES)
It does get better.
(COUCH SPRINGS CREAKING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(BABY COOING)
- Oh, hey, Will.
- Hey, Greta.
Is Borel in?
Yeah. Borel?
Look at that.
A shame we gotta wait 25 years.
We could use that year right now.
Borel?
I'm here.
You'd better get her inside, Greta.
Look at this.
Where did you get that?
The guy at the bar.
They were going to kill him.
He gave it to me.
He timed himself out
before I could stop him.
No one gives anybody 1oo years.
He didn't just give me this.
He gave me the truth about it.
You can't let anyone see that.
Hey.
You know that time will get you killed.
How long have we been friends?
What, 1o years?
Here.
A decade.
You've been like a brother.
Where are you going?
Where this won't look out of place.
I finally got the time to take my mom
to New Greenwich.
Greta, I'm going out!
COMPUTER VOICE: Loan payment received,
two days. Thank you.
Dayton.
Two hours.
It's always been an hour.
Now it's two. Price went up.
Since when?
Since today.
My son is meeting me.
He'll pay the difference.
I can't do that, policy.
Please?
It's a two-hour walk.
I have an hour and a half.
Then you'd better run.
Stop! Please stop!
Wait! Please! Please, no!
Wait! No! Please!
(EXCLAIMS)
Mom?
Will!
- Will!
- Mom!
(GROANS)
No, no, no, no!
(CRYING)
No!
Mom, Mom, Mom!
(CRYING OUT)
MAN: Thirteen zeros.
Unlucky for all.
The last time anyone saw him alive,
there was over a century on that clock.
Around here, they'd kill you for a week.
What was he doing in this Time Zone?
JAEGER: What I was thinking
was he might have brought this on himself.
Interesting. How long
you been keeping time, Jaeger?
Five years.
Let me know what you think
when you have been doing it for 5o.
It doesn't matter why he came here.
What matters are the hundred years
that came with him.
Gotta be a witness.
Trust me, no one saw anything.
What would you like us to do, sir?
What we always do. Follow the time.
Hey, Ray. I'll give you 1o minutes
for an hour.
When are you gonna
get out of the game, Leila?
You gotta be pushing 6o.
Thanks for letting everyone know.
Am I in the right place?
We don't normally make
pickups in this Zone.
I was lost.
COMPUTER VOICE: Please deposit
one month.
Please deposit two months.
There are more of these than I remember.
That was a year.
Welcome to New Greenwich.
What are you really doing here?
I'm going to take them
for everything they've got.
I'm going to make them pay.
Please, miss. You can't be too careful.
Are you sure?
What's a night here cost?
Two months for a standard room.
Give me a suite.
Do you need help with your bags?
No.
- He's fast.
- He's going to have to be.
The camera doesn't show us
how the body got into the river.
What do we really know?
(SIGHS) What do we know?
We know that most thefts in Dayton
amount to hours or days.
This was a century.
I don't see any more in circulation.
He could have capsuled the time.
You can't hide a hundred years
in the ghetto.
They can sense when a man has
a month more than he should.
The time left town.
(EXHALES)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
That'll be eight and a half weeks.
Take a week for yourself.
Thanks.
You're not from around here, are you?
You do everything a little too fast.
Not everything.
What's that place across the street?
The casino.
Can anybody go?
Not dressed like that.
Good luck.
Sir, you were right.
If you turn back the clocks
the day of Hamilton's death,
and look at the time checks,
someone spent years crossing
four different Time Zones from Dayton...
To New Greenwich. The cameras picked up
on his suspicious behavior.
He's conscious of the surveillance,
he doesn't have a bodyguard, and he runs.
But if he has time, he doesn't need to run.
It's a hard habit to break.
You're looking for a match?
His name is Will Salas.
You know him?
No.
I remember his father.
(GREETING GUESTS)
Good evening.
I assume my time is as good as anyone's.
Indeed it is. However,
there is a voluntary donation
for non-members. Most give a year.
What's your game?
Poker.
Right this way.
What's the limit?
There is none.
I don't believe we've had the pleasure
of your company before, Mr...
Salas.
Will Salas.
Philippe Weis. You must come from time.
You could say I'm gambling my inheritance.
You don't have a guard, Mr. Salas?
I assumed I was amongst friends.
Bet you 5o years.
You must be young.
When you've been 25 for 85 years,
like I have,
knowing only a random act of violence
can take your life,
you learn to appreciate what you have.
And you seem to have a lot to appreciate.
I call.
Of course,
some think what we have is unfair.
The time difference between Zones.
I've heard that.
But isn't this just the next logical step
in our evolution?
And hasn't evolution always been unfair?
It's always been survival of the fittest.
Raise you another two centuries.
This is merely Darwinian capitalism.
Natural selection.
Absolutely.
The strong survive.
And I think your hand is weak.
I call.
It appears you're all in, Mr. Salas.
Thirteen figures.
Well played.
That was some risk.
It wasn't a risk.
No offense. I knew I was going to win.
(PHILIPPE CHUCKLES)
Confusing times.
Is she my mother, my sister
or my daughter?
You're hoping she's not my wife.
Things used to be simpler once. So I'm told.
Very beautiful.
Daughter.
Though she does look
a lot like my wife. Sylvia?
Will Salas.
Congratulations, Mr. Salas.
You've taken years off my father's life.
Which is normally what you do.
Isn't that right, my darling?
We're having a party tomorrow night.
Perhaps you'll give him a chance to
win back some of those years.
I'd love to.
Carl will tell you where I am.
Good night, Mr. Salas.
Sylvia, stay with your guards.
Fifty-nine years.
Plus tax.
(SIGHS)
The price includes delivery.
Delivery?
To wherever you're going to display it.
Display it?
Hell, I'm going to drive it.
(ENGINE ROARING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Will Salas.
Allow me to introduce
my mother-in-law, Clara,
my wife, Michele, and my daughter, Sylvia.
I believe you two have already met.
Nice to meet you all.
PHILIPPE: I'll come find you later
for our game.
I look forward to it.
Having fun, Mr. Salas?
Please, call me Will.
It's okay, Constantin.
Do you always have a hired hand
standing right next to you?
No. I usually have two.
That doesn't make it very easy
to get to know you.
I think that's the idea.
Your idea?
My father's.
I understand.
You all have a lot to lose.
So do you.
What do you do, Will?
I haven't quite figured that out yet.
Yes, why bother? What's the hurry?
Right. Why do today what
you can do in a century?
I know one thing we can do.
Dance with me.
(SLOW JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Do you really come from time?
Why would you doubt that?
I saw you run.
Reminds me of people
who come from the ghetto.
Sometimes I envy them.
You don't know anything.
Oh, no? The clock is good for no one.
The poor die and the rich don't live.
We can all live forever as long as
we don't do anything foolish.
Doesn't that scare you? That maybe
you'll never do anything foolish?
Or courageous or anything worth a damn?
Come with me.
JAEGER: This was tonight.
He's only an hour ahead of us.
Look at that.
I've never seen anything like it.
What are you doing?
We don't go in.
You're insane.
You have this in your backyard.
You never go in.
And I'm insane?
Well? What are you waiting for?
Sylvia, come on!
What happened to doing something foolish?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I don't know you.
We could change that.
I get it.
You're out here, all alone,
with a stranger.
You can't be too careful.
Maybe you can.
Sylvia!
I have to go back.
To what?
You should go back.
- Have you seen my daughter?
- I have.
She's with her guards.
Right behind you.
Thank God.
Now,
how about that game?
(DOOR OPENING)
(GUESTS GASPING)
It's all right, everyone. What's this about?
I'm sorry to have to
break up the party, Mr. Weis.
I just need a word with your friend.
My friend?
Very well.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm Timekeeper Raymond Leon.
I'm Will Salas.
I know.
What are you doing in this Zone?
It's not illegal, is it? To change Time Zones?
No, it's not illegal.
It's just rare.
Where did you get that?
I won it.
Gambling.
All of it?
No.
A man named Henry Hamilton
gave me over a century.
He said he didn't need it anymore.
He timed himself out.
Henry Hamilton was
worth thousands of years.
He could practically live forever.
You expect me to believe that
he was immortal and he wanted to die?
I don't expect you to believe it.
But it's the truth.
It was a gift.
I'm not a thief.
But, hey, if you guys
are looking for stolen time,
maybe you should arrest everyone here.
Oh, I see.
You're talking about justice.
Well, I am a Timekeeper.
I don't concern myself with "justice. "'
I only concern myself
with what I can measure.
Seconds, minutes, hours.
I keep time.
And that time is in the wrong hands.
That time will be held, along with you.
We'll leave you two hours
for booking and processing.
Why are you investigating a suicide?
There's mass murder
in the ghetto every day.
That is fascinating.
Huh.
I heard another man talk like that.
It was over 2o years ago.
You're probably too young
to remember your father.
We'll arrange safe transport.
This is New Greenwich, after all.
Sylvia? Do as I say and go with the guards.
Oh, for God's sake, Father.
There's an army in this house.
If we can't stop one man from killing us,
we should kill ourselves.
(GUESTS SCREAMING)
(SYLVIA PANTING)
Stop him!
Move! Get out of the way!
- (GRUNTS)
- (CRIES OUT)
Put it down or I'll blow her head off.
Thanks.
(SIREN WAILING)
You're going to kill us!
Please just let me out!
(EXCLAIMS)
What are you doing?
Do you even know how to drive?
What's there to know?
(EXCLAIMS)
- Oh, shit.
- (HORN HONKING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Give me some time.
I guess you really are
from the ghetto, after all.
What the hell do you know about
where I'm from? Give me some time.
Or you're gonna kill me,
like you killed Henry Hamilton?
Lend me an hour.
I'm not giving you a second.
I should have listened to my father.
Please, take me home. Please.
- I can't do that.
- Why?
You're keeping me alive.
Keep that covered.
Anybody sees it, you're definitely dead.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Now that worked too well.
You guys wasted a gorgeous car.
Look who it is.
Who it was.
He's done in minutes.
He'll wake up dead. That'll be a shock.
Too bad. I would have preferred to
kill him more beautifully.
The girl's still breathing.
She's got a decade.
Holy shit.
The man he stole from me
had more than a century.
What? We'll divide it later.
It's like an angel fell from the sky.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Fortis!
Leave it!
(EXHALES)
Look at me.
You okay?
No.
(CHUCKLING)
Why are you laughing?
We're not dead.
Yeah, we're not alive for long, either.
Where did my time go? I have a half hour!
Ah.
You're lucky.
- Minutemen.
- Does everyone in the ghetto steal?
That's rich, coming from you.
- Please help me, Will.
- Let me guess,
now you like the idea of sharing.
Come here.
Hey, don't worry.
It's not the first time I've been this broke.
Well, it's a first for me.
What are we going to do?
Whatever we have to.
Come on, we got to go.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Dispatch, wire me my per diem.
COMPUTER VOICE: Time transfer.
Cutting it close again, sir.
Well, I'm still walking around.
Judging by the lack of dead bodies,
I have to assume they are also.
They got jacked. They couldn't have
left here with more than minutes.
He's back in his old neighborhood.
So, where do you want us to start looking?
We don't. He'll come to us.
(BOTH PANTING)
Borel?
Borel, open up. It's Will.
Greta.
Where's Borel?
He's dead.
Dead? What?
You gave him a decade.
He drank himself to death
with nine years on his clock.
Jesus Christ.
Greta, I'm so sorry.
(BABY CRYING)
Goodbye, Will.
Will, we have minutes.
Try not to act like it.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Shut up!
We're going to die, Will!
Do you want to die?
Shut up!
I hope those are real. Run.
WILL: Stop! Wait!
SYLVIA: Please, wait!
MAN: Come back in an hour.
That won't be possible.
Here!
I'll give you two days for them.
They're diamonds.
You can take the 48 hours,
or you can be a pretty corpse.
We'll take it.
(SIREN WAILING)
WILL: Don't make a sound.
SYLVIA: Give me my time.
Let's go.
I guess I got my wish.
I did do something foolish.
Your name's on a lot of buildings.
It's my father's name.
How much is he worth, anyway?
Eons.
What do you think he'd pay to get you back?
You have no shame, do you?
COMPUTER VOICE:
Please deposit one minute.
Dial.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello.
Mr. Weis, please give the phone
to the Timekeeper.
Hello, Will. How much do you want?
A thousand years.
(SCOFFS)
You'll never live to spend it.
Then distribute it
to the Time Lines in Dayton.
Do it by sunrise tomorrow
and she can go home.
Will...
I'm afraid for you, Will.
You keep talking like him,
you're going to die like him.
My father died in a fight,
trying to take a man's time.
Oh, no. His crime wasn't taking time.
He was doing something
far more dangerous.
Please don't make your father's mistake.
(DEVICE BEEPS)
Dayton. Pedre Plaza.
I know it.
A thousand years to the Time Lines.
A thousand years.
It's nothing.
It's for our daughter.
No, it's for them.