CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
NEW LINE HOME ENTERTAINMENT
Computer: ACCESS DENIED.
ACCESS DENIED. ACCESS DENIED.
ACCESS DENIED.
MAINTENANCE LINE.
ACCESS GRANTED.
[MOANS]
[GAVEL BANGS]
YOU CAN'T TAKE
THE CHYRON CHIP
AWAY FROM ME.
IT IS MY IDEA,
MY DESIGN,
MY PATENT.
DR. TRACE, YOU HAVE
TO DEFEND YOUR PATENT
FOR THE CHYRON CHIP.
THE INVESTORS HAVE FINANCED
THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE CHIP.
BY LAW, IF THEY
CAN'T BE REPAID,
THE PATENT
BELONGS TO THEM.
YOU CAN'T
GIVE IT TO THEM.
THEY WILL
POLLUTE THE VISION
OF EVERYTHING
MY CHYRON CHIP
STANDS FOR.
HERE'S AN OPENING.
LET'S BREAK ON IN!
BREAK IT IN!
WE'VE GOT A LIVE ONE
OVER HERE.
GET THE GURNEY.
GURNEY OUT.
WE HAVE TO REPAIR THIS
SHATTERED MAXILLARY FRACTURE,
OR WE'RE GONNA LOSE HIM.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO GET
THIS DAMN ARTERY CLAMPED OFF.
WE'RE LOSING
THE VITAL SIGNS.
GET ME RD 40.
HEART STOPPED.
WE NEED THE DEFIBRILLATOR.
CLEAR.
1, 2, 3.
[DEFIBRILLATOR BLASTS]
PATIENT IS A MALE,
LATE 20s.
MULTIPLE AMPUTEE,
SMOKE LESIONS
ON THE LUNGS,
AND THIRD-DEGREE
BURNS
OVER 80%
OF HIS BODY.
TRANSFER FROM COUNTY?
MM-HMM. THEY AMPUTATED
BOTH OF HIS LEGS
AND RECONSTRUCTED
HIS FACE.
WELL,
WHAT'S THE VERDICT?
IT'S HARD TO TELL.
THERE'S SO MANY
DIFFERENT PATHWAYS
FOR THE INTERFACE.
ONLY ONE WAY
TO FIND OUT.
HELLO, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
PETER PETER
PUMPKIN EATER.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
IT MEANS
HE CAN HEAR US.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
WHAT YOUR IS NAME?
Both:
PETER PETER PUMPKIN EATER.
MAYBE HIS NAME'S
PETER.
[SIGHS]
I'LL TRY THIS.
[TYPING]
HAD A WIFE...
BUT COULDN'T KEEP HER.
HAD A WIFE,
JOBE.
HELLO, JOBE.
JOBE...
TELL ME
ABOUT YOURSELF.
EMPTY SPACE.
IT'S ALL JUST
EMPTY SPACE INSIDE.
LIKE IT'S BEEN ERASED.
I WANT YOU TO
TRY AND VISUALIZE
ALL THE PEOPLE
AND PLACES
THAT YOU'VE HAD CONTACT
WITH IN YOUR LIFE.
JUST RELAX
AND LET THE IMAGES
COME TO YOU.
JOBE. HEY, JOBE.
HI, PETER.
LOOK WHAT I GOT.
IS THAT
THE NEW COSMIC MAN?
YEAH.
IT'S GREAT.
WOW. THANKS, BUDDY.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, JOBE.
MAKE A WISH.
[GIGGLES]
EXCUSE ME.
JOBE...
I'M JONATHON WALKER.
I, UH,
RUN THIS PLACE.
I NOW OWN THE PATENT
TO THE CHYRON CHIP,
AND YOU CAN BUILD
THE CHIP FOR ME.
[HYPERVENTILATING]
JOBE,
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE AFRAID OF.
VIRTUAL REALITY
WILL REHABILITATE
YOUR MIND
AND EVENTUALLY
YOUR BODY.
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I PROMISE.
JUST CONCENTRATE,
OK?
WE'LL TRY
SOME MUSIC.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
WARNING.
INPUT EXCEEDS MAXIMUM.
WARNING. INPUT
EXCEEDS MAXIMUM.
[ALARM BUZZING]
ACCESS GRANTED.
[SIREN]
HEY, MATT! MATT!
COME HERE.
HAVE YOU SEEN
PETER?
NO. SORRY.
HEY, JONATHAN!
SERVICE HAS BEEN
TEMPORARILY INTERRUPTED
ON METRO FIVE.
[NO AUDIO]
Woman: GET DOWN
ON YOUR KNEES AND REPENT!
MAN DESTROYS MAN!
SAVE YOURSELF BEFORE THE END!
SAVE YOURSELF
BEFORE THE END!
GET DOWN AND PRAY
FOR FORGIVENESS
BEFORE THE FIRE
AND THE DESTRUCTION!
[BEEPING]
THANK YOU.
YOUR VIDEOPHONE
ACCESS CODE IS APPROVED.
[GIGGLING]
YEAH!
OH, THAT WAS AWESOME.
HERE. LET ME SEE.
COOL.
HERE.
AAH!
TRAVIS!
CRAP.
MAN, ARE YOU OK?
MAN, ARE YOU CRAZY,
PETER?
YOU KNOW
YOU CAN'T HURT ME.
WHAT'S UP, SIS?
HOW LONG,
TRAVIS?
RIGHT NOW.
DID YOU GET IT?
ASK PETER.
JUST SHOULDER SURFED IT
ON THE WAY OVER.
OH, MY GOD.
YOU'RE A SAINT.
THANK YOU.
COME ON,
LET'S GO INSIDE.
Peter:
LET'S DO IT.
Travis:
I'VE GOT US PATCHED
INTO THE FIBER OPTICS.
YOU'VE GOT
THE ACCESS CODE?
MAN, WE'RE SET.
WHAT'S UP, SHAWN?
HEY. WHAT'S UP,
TRAVIS?
HOW ABOUT A TASTE
OF REMOTE PRESENCE,
MY FRIENDS?
ALL HOOKED UP
AND READY TO GO.
ALL RIGHT! HEY, LET'S USE
THE CYBERCYCLES DISK.
NO WAY, MAN.
I'M FLYING.
I AM FLYING,
MAN.
HEY, ME, TOO.
Shawn: I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR THIS ALL DAY.
[BEEP]
PLEASE ENTER
VIDEOPHONE ACCESS CODE.
TRAP-DOOR ACCESS
TO CYBERSPACE GRANTED.
YEAH!
PLEASE STAND BY FOR ENTRY.
10, 9, 8, 7,
6...
ONE.
TRAP DOOR OPEN.
ENTER NOW.
[INDISTINCT VOICES]
YEAH!
WHOO!
AH!
[EXPLOSION]
HEY, PETER,
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[BARKS]
WHOA!
AAH!
Shawn:
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[ARTILLERY FIRING]
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHO'S DOING THIS?
[BARKS]
SHAWN,
THE CYBERCYCLES.
YEAH.
HARVEY.
HARVEY, PUT IN
THE CYBERCYCLE DISK.
HARVEY, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
PUT IN
THE CYBERCYCLE DISK NOW!
[WHIMPERS]
[BEEPING]
NO ONE JACKS OUT
TILL WE FIND
WHO'S DOING THIS.
JOBE?
YOU'RE ALIVE.
HOW CAN THAT BE?
THERE ISN'T TIME,
PETER.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
I'M DYING.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
DYING?
THE CYBERSCAPE
IS DYING,
AND SO AM I,
RIGHT ALONG WITH IT.
I'M TRAPPED HERE,
PETER.
YOU'VE GOT TO
HELP ME.
I--I DON'T GET IT.
I NEED YOU TO FIND
SOMEONE FOR ME.
BENJAMIN TRACE.
WHAT?
DR. BENJAMIN TRACE.
HE'S IN SECLUSION
SOMEWHERE.
YOU'VE GOT TO
BRING HIM, PETER.
WHEN THE CYBERSCAPE
DIES, SO DO I.
WHAT IF HE WON'T
JACK IN?
TELL HIM I'M BUILDING
HIS CHYRON CHIP,
AND I NEED TO KNOW
ABOUT THE EGYPT LINK
TO COMPLETE IT.
NO!
WARNING.
PETER!
I DON'T THINK
HE'S BREATHING.
WHAT DO WE DO?
UM, LET'S TRY CPR.
HURRY UP. WE'RE RUNNING
OUT OF TIME.
1-1,000, 2-1,000,
3-1,000,
4-1,000, 5-1,000.
BREATHE!
BREATHE, PETER. BREATHE.
1-1,000, 2-1,000,
3-1,000, 4-1,000, 5-1,000.
BREATHE!
IT'S NOT WORKING!
ALL RIGHT,
ONE MORE TIME.
COME ON, PETER.
BREATHE.
1-1,000, 2-1,000,
3-1,000, 4-1,000.
[COUGHING]
ALL RIGHT. COME ON.
GET UP. YOU OK?
IF YOU KNEW
YOU WERE IN DANGER,
YOU SHOULD HAVE
JACKED OUT, YOU JERK!
THAT WAS THE MOST REMARKABLE
EXAMPLE OF TELEPRESENCE
I'VE EVER EXPERIENCED.
ALL PERSONNEL,
CLEAR THE FLOOR.
V.I.P. ARRIVING.
ALL PERSONNEL,
CLEAR THE FLOOR.
V.I.P. ARRIVING.
ALL PERSONNEL,
CLEAR THE FLOOR.
V.I.P. ARRIVING.
I WANT TO TALK TO HALLOWAY
PERSON TO PERSON.
I DON'T WANT ANY OTHER
NONSENSE AROUND THAT.
WELL,
SENATOR GREENSPAN.
HOW WONDERFUL
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
WELCOME TO
THE VIRTUAL LIGHT
INSTITUTE.
THANK YOU.
I'D LIKE TO
INTRODUCE YOU
TO MY HEAD OF RESEARCH
AND DEVELOPMENT,
DR. CORI PLATT.
NICE TO SEE YOU,
SENATOR.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
AND THIS IS JENNIFER.
PLEASE COME WITH ME,
SENATOR.
SENATOR...
VIRTUAL LIGHT.
UNTIL NOW, NO ONE
HAS HAD THE ABILITY
TO CREATE
AN ENTIRE COMPUTER NETWORK
BASED WITHIN
VIRTUAL REALITY.
OF COURSE,
WHEN I COMPLETE
MY VIRTUAL LIGHT UPLINK,
I'LL RENDER ALL OTHER
SYSTEMS OBSOLETE.
VIRTUAL REALITY
HAS EVOLVED
FROM A SIMULATION
TO AN ACTUAL PLACE.
WATCH YOUR HEAD. THOSE
MONITORS WILL KILL YOU.
SO, IT'S LIKE A WHOLE
NEW WORLD OUT THERE.
AHA. FULL OF INTERESTING
POSSIBILITIES.
EXACTLY. WE--
I LOVE A MAN
THAT DOES HIS HOMEWORK.
DON'T YOU, DOCTOR?
BUT, SENATOR,
WHAT'S HOLDING US BACK
IS FINAL CONGRESSIONAL
APPROVAL OF OUR LICENSE.
AH. AND THIS...
AH, YES. THIS MUST BE
THE FAMOUS CHYRON CHIP
THAT EVERYBODY'S
TALKING ABOUT.
THE KEY TO
MY VIRTUAL LIGHT UPLINK.
HMM.
Platt: SINCE
THE INFORMATION SUPERHIGHWAY
HAS LEFT PEOPLE
FEELING ISOLATED
FROM THEIR FELLOW MAN,
THE VIRTUAL LIGHT
INSTITUTE
WILL BRING CULTURES
AND RESOURCES TOGETHER
IN ONE CONTINUOUS
VIRTUAL ENVIRONMENT.
AND THIS IS OUR MAIN
CONTROL ROOM,
HUB OF ALL OUR OPERATIONS
HERE AT VIRTUAL LIGHT.
I'M STILL
A LITTLE UNCLEAR
AS TO HOW ALL THIS
FITS TOGETHER.
WELL, I'M SURE DR. PLATT
WILL ENLIGHTEN YOU.
JENNIFER, PLEASE.
THE OUTER CIRCLE
REPRESENTS THE REAL WORLD.
THE INNER ONE,
VIRTUAL REALITY.
THE SPOKES ARE THE DIFFERENT
PATHWAYS BETWEEN THE TWO.
THE CHYRON CHIP WILL OPEN UP
THESE PATHWAYS SIMULTANEOUSLY,
SO A NETWORK BASED INSIDE VR
CAN BE ACCESSED BY EVERYONE.
UH-HUH.
SO, NEXT MIRACLE.
Platt: PLEASE.
JENNIFER.
WHEN YOU HOOK
INTO THE LIBRARY
OF MY VIRTUAL CITY,
YOU'LL HOOK INTO EVERY LIBRARY
IN THE WORLD.
AND ULTIMATELY,
THE CHIP WILL BRING EVERYTHING
ONLINE FOR EVERYONE.
WELL, YES, IT'S VERY
PRETTY, JONATHON,
BUT I THINK
WE'D BE PLACING
QUITE A CONCENTRATION
OF POWER IN YOUR LAP.
HMM. MY LAP
IS YOUR LAP, SENATOR.
[TAPPING]
TWINKIE.
HOW DID IT GO?
WALKER MAKES ME FEEL
LIKE THE STAR POODLE
IN HIS DOG SHOW.
AT LEAST YOU GET
TOP BILLING.
NO. WALKER ALWAYS
GETS TOP BILLING.
OF COURSE, HE DIDN'T
MENTION THE FACT
THAT IT'S YOU
COMPLETING
THE CHYRON CHIP
AND DESIGNING
THE VIRTUAL CITY.
I DON'T MIND.
I CARE HOW OTHER
PEOPLE SEE YOU,
HOW THEY
PERCEIVE YOU.
THAT'S YOUR WORLD,
DR. PLATT, NOT MINE.
MY WORLD IS IN HERE.
OUT THERE,
PEOPLE LOOK AT ME
AND THEY SEE
HALF A PERSON.
BUT IN HERE, THEY SEE
WHAT I WANT THEM TO SEE...
HOW I REALLY AM.
HERE.
I DON'T SEE
HALF A PERSON, JOBE.
THAT'S YOUR WORLD.
GOOD NIGHT, JOBE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YOU SURE DON'T LOOK LIKE
THE FATHER
OF VIRTUAL REALITY TO ME.
WHAT?
YOU'RE DR. BENJAMIN TRACE,
RIGHT?
HE'S DEAD.
DEAD?
THAT'S NOT WHAT THEY SAID
ON THE INTERNET.
ON THE INTERNET, THEY SAID
HE WAS, LIKE, LIVING HERE.
THE BENJAMIN TRACE
YOU WANT IS...
RESTING IN PEACE.
SO I SUGGEST
YOU GET ON
THAT COOL BIKE
OF YOURS AND...
GO ON HOME.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT JOBE WAS THINKING.
HE'S JUST CRAZY.
TRIPPY FOOL INVENTED
SOME KIND OF CHYRON CHIP.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
CHYRON CHIP.
COME INSIDE.
SO, WHAT'S
YOUR NAME, KID?
PETER...DOC.
CALL ME TRACE.
TRACE.
WELL, PETER,
YOU KNOW, IT'S ALL HERE,
ALL THE ANSWERS--
IN THE EARTH,
IN THE WATER,
AND IN THE AIR.
YEAH.
THE REASON I CAME
IS BECAUSE
MY FRIEND JOBE IS DYING,
AND HE SAID THAT
YOU WERE THE ONLY ONE
WHO COULD SAVE HIM.
YOU SEEM A BIT YOUNG TO KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THE CHYRON CHIP.
WELL, JOBE TOLD ME
ABOUT IT.
WHO'S JOBE?
HE WAS
OUR LAWNMOWER MAN
BACK WHEN MY MOM
WAS STILL ALIVE.
AND HE WAS
MY BEST FRIEND,
BUT NOW HE'S STUCK
IN VIRTUAL REALITY.
WHAT DOES HE KNOW
ABOUT IT?
HE'S BUILDING IT.
HE'S BUILDING IT?
YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT HE SAID.
SO ARE YOU GONNA
HELP OR WHAT?
I DON'T LIVE THAT LIFE
ANYMORE, PETER.
ALL THAT TECHNOLOGY,
IT JUST...
CONSUMES THE SOUL.
CHECK THIS OUT.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
YOU CAN FIND ME
AT THE THIRD STREET
STATION, TUNNEL 11,
IF YOU EVER
CHANGE YOUR MIND.
[DISK FAST-FORWARDING]
DR. BENJAMIN TRACE.
ONLY HE CAN
STOP THIS.
WHAT IF HE WON'T
JACK IN?
TELL HIM I'M BUILDING
HIS CHYRON CHIP.
ATTENTION, PASSENGERS--
ALL METRO BLUE LINE TRAINS
HAVE BEEN CANCELED
DUE TO FLOODING.
Woman:
HUSTLE, YOU GUYS.
THEY WANT US
OUT OF HERE.
Man:
HEY, COME INSIDE!
Man: YOU GOT 50,
MAN?
MY DOG
DOES NOT STINK.
YES, HE DOES, SHAWN.
THE FUNK
IS BURNING MY EYES.
IT DOES NOT STINK.
I LOOKED AT HIM,
AND I ALMOST WENT BLIND.
IT DOES NOT.
WE ALL KNOW HARV
USED TO BE A POODLE.
HE LOOKS LIKE A CHIHUAHUA
ON STEROIDS!
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
WHO IS IT?
PETER?
TRACE?
HI.
YOU KNOW THIS GUY,
PETER?
BACK OFF, GUYS.
THIS IS THE GUY
JOBE TOLD ME ABOUT,
ALL RIGHT?
YOU ALL
LIVE DOWN HERE?
OH, NO. THIS IS JUST
OUR SUMMER COTTAGE.
I LOVE
YOUR VENTILATION SYSTEM.
LISTEN, I THINK THIS GUY
CAN HELP US, OK?
ADULTS HAVE BETRAYED ME
MY WHOLE LIFE.
YOU KNOW THAT, PETER.
YEAH!
HEY, HEY, HEY.
LOOK, TRAVIS, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO TRUST HIM.
YOU JUST GOT
TO TRUST PETER.
YEAH!
SO YOU'RE
THE EINSTEIN OF VR?
I'LL TAKE THAT AS
A COMPLIMENT, TRAVIS.
YOU KNOW, EINSTEIN MADE
A FEW MISTAKES HIMSELF.
WHAT ARE THESE?
MAN, YOU MUST
REALLY BE A DINOSAUR.
SEE THE ELECTROPLATES
ON THE SIDES?
THEY HIT YOUR TEMPLE
AND TAP INTO
CERTAIN NEURONS,
GIVING YOU FULL
NEUROSENSORY INVOLVEMENT.
YOU CAN
ACTUALLY FEEL?
EXACTLY.
SEE, THAT'S WHY WE GOT
TO SAVE JOBE, THOUGH.
BECAUSE IT'S REAL IN THERE.
IF HE DIES IN THERE,
HE'S GONNA DIE OUT HERE.
YOU SURE JOBE
NEEDS SAVING?
WHAT ARE YOU
TRYING TO SAY?
JOBE WOULDN'T LIE TO ME.
HE'S NOT THAT TYPE
OF PERSON.
YOU SAID YOU COULDN'T
TRUST ANY ADULT.
HE'S NOT LIKE YOU.
I MEAN, HE'S LIKE A KID.
AT LEAST HE WAS
UNTIL...
UNTIL WHAT?
UNTIL MY NEXT-DOOR
NEIGHBOR
DID SOME EXPERIMENTS
WITH HIM IN VR
AND TURNED HIM FROM
A SIMPLETON INTO A GENIUS.
LOOK, WE'RE WASTING TIME.
YOU CAN ASK HIM YOURSELF IN VR.
READY?
YEAH. LET'S HOOK IT UP.
LET'S DO IT.
OK.
DOC,
HERE'S YOUR STUFF.
OH, I DON'T WANT
TO GO INTO VR.
WHY NOT?
I'M NOT READY.
IT'S, UH...
I DON'T KNOW.
SCARED I MIGHT GET
LOST OR SOMETHING.
FINE. I'LL GO IN.
OK.
[BEEPING]
10, 9, 8, 7...
TRAP-DOOR ACCESS
TO CYBERSPACE GRANTED.
PLEASE STAND BY FOR ENTRY.
ONE.
[CAWING]
WELCOME TO MY WORLD,
PETER.
YOU BRING
THE GOOD DOCTOR?
NO. HE'S WATCHING.
HE WON'T JACK IN.
JACK IN, JACK OFF.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
SCARED OF THE BOOGEYMAN,
DOCTOR?
YOU COULD
AT LEAST HUMOR ME
WITH A POINT OF VIEW,
CAN'T YOU?
IT'S A PLEASURE TO
FINALLY MEET YOU, DOCTOR.
I FEEL LIKE
WE'RE ALMOST--
I'M BLUSHING--
FAMILY.
HA HA. I DON'T
THINK SO, JOBE.
DON'T BE SO SURE.
INCEST--THE GAME
THE WHOLE FAMILY CAN PLAY!
"MY BROTHER'S MY DADDY!"
WE HAVE A LOT
IN COMMON, DR. TRACE.
WE'RE BOTH UNWANTED,
UNDERAPPRECIATED,
AND AHEAD OF OUR TIME.
YET THE DIFFERENCE IS,
YOUR TIME WAS THEN.
MY TIME IS NOW.
IT'S A SHORT RIDE,
JOBE.
ENJOY IT
WHILE YOU CAN.
OH, I PLAN TO ENJOY IT
FOR A VERY LONG TIME, DOCTOR.
YOU SEE, I FOUND
THE SECRET TO IMMORTALITY
IN THE CHYRON CHIP.
WHERE IS
THE CHYRON CHIP?
COME WITH ME NOW,
WON'T YOU?
THERE SHE IS!
MISS CHYRON CHIP!
IT'S TAKEN
YEARS OF WORK,
BUT OUR CHYRON CHIP
IS FINALLY A REALITY.
[SINGING THEME TO JAWS]
LOOK WHAT
I'M DOING, DOCTOR.
ISN'T IT AMAZING?
YOU DON'T LOOK LIKE
YOU'RE IN DANGER.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
EGYPT.
COME ON,
DON'T HOLD BACK ON ME.
IT'S A HIDDEN
NANO-ROUTINE
ENCODED INTO THE DESIGN
OF THE CHYRON CHIP.
I'M NOT GOING TO
HELP YOU.
TELL YOU WHAT--
YOU SHARE EGYPT WITH ME,
AND I'LL SHARE WITH YOU
TECHNOLOGICAL KNOWLEDGE
BEYOND YOUR
WILDEST DREAMS.
THIS IS YOUR WORLD,
TOO, DOCTOR.
YOUR WORK HELPED
CREATE IT.
MY WORK IS TO BUILD IT.
NOW, TELL ME, DOCTOR,
WHAT DOES EGYPT MEAN?
I'M NOT GOING
TO TELL YOU.
YOU'RE INSANE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
ITS POWER, JOBE.
OH, BUT I DO, DOCTOR.
AND IN THREE DAYS,
I'LL BE IN EVERY
SYSTEM IN THE WORLD.
NO.
TELL ME WHAT
EGYPT MEANS, DOCTOR,
BEFORE I GET REALLY
FUCKING PISSED OFF!
GET OUT OF THERE,
PETER.
PETER,
GET OUT OF THERE!
GET HIM OUT
OF THERE! PETER!
Shawn: THIS IS GETTING
OUT OF CONTROL!
I'VE NEVER SEEN
JOBE LIKE THAT BEFORE!
WEST COVINA LOCAL,
DEPARTING PLATFORM B,
LEVEL C.
FOR CUSTOMER SERVICE
OR CASHIER,
FOLLOW THE BLUE LINE
TO PASSAGE 9, LEVEL 4.
SAN FERNANDO EXPRESS
NOW ARRIVING,
PLATFORM D.
HEY! HEY!
WAIT!
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
NO, NO!
STOP IT! HELP ME!
I CAN'T STOP IT!
SHH. SHH.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
THAT TRAINS DIDN'T RUN
THROUGH THESE TUNNELS.
THEY DON'T!
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S HEADING RIGHT FOR US!
EMERGENCY
PROCEDURES AT ONCE!
GET OUT OF HERE.
WHAT? BUT THIS
IS OUR HOME!
GET OUT OF HERE! GO!
DISPATCH, DO SOMETHING!
IMPLEMENT EMERGENCY
PROCEDURES IMMEDIATELY!
IMPLEMENT EMERGENCY PROCEDURES
IMMEDIATELY!
DISPATCH, SHUT ALL
SYSTEMS DOWN! DISENGAGE...
COME ON! COME ON!
JADE, PETER,
HURRY UP! RUN!
GO, TRAVIS! GO!
THE GAME...
IS AFOOT.
CODE RED! CODE RED!
THE CABOOSE IS LOOSE.
PLEASE, GOD, NO!
Man: UNAUTHORIZED VESSEL
IN ZONE 4.
[TRAIN PASSES OVERHEAD]
TRACE, GO!
COME ON, LET'S GO!
GO!
AAH!
GO! RUN, RUN!
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE!
PETER, RUN!
GO! PETER!
PETER!
THIS WAY!
Shawn:
HARVEY, COME BACK!
Peter: THERE'S AN EXIT
AT THE END!
FORGET ABOUT
THAT DOG, SHAWN!
COME ON UP!
YES!
ALL RIGHT!
IT'S OPEN!
AAH!
SHAWN, LET'S GO!
COME ON!
COME ON, SHAWN!
I CAN'T GET UP! I CAN'T
LEAVE HARVEY HERE.
COME ON, SHAWN!
UHH!
COME ON, TRACE, PULL!
GET OUT OF THERE!
GOOD BOY.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
IT'S GOING TO BLOW!
[JADE SCREAMING]
AAH!
MAN.
LEVEL 5 TECHNICIAN
TO ROBOTICS, DIVISION 2.
CHANDARA
TO QUALITY CONTROL.
NOW LET'S DEAL WITH
THE TRUE BELIEVERS.
SHOW ME
ALL THE CONTRIBUTORS
TO FUNDAMENTAL
WORLD RELIGIONS
OVER THE PAST FIVE YEARS.
AND EACH USER THINKS THAT
THEY HAVE TOTAL PRIVACY.
EVERY TIME
ANYONE LOGS ON
TO VIRTUAL LIGHT UPLINK,
WE'LL KNOW EVERY
GODDAMN THING ABOUT THEM.
NOW, SHOW ME ALL
HYPOCRITICAL DEMOCRATS
MAKING OVER 300,000 A YEAR.
THAT TRAIN WAS
NO ACCIDENT, WAS IT?
NOT A CHANCE.
MAN, NOW WE'VE LOST OUR HOME
AND THE CYBERSCAPE.
Peter:
I BET JOBE DID IT,
SO HE CAN
BUILD HIS CITY.
LIKE THIS WORLD DIDN'T
SUCK ENOUGH ALREADY.
I THINK
THAT'S JUST A TASTE
OF WHAT HE CAN DO
IF HE GOES ONLINE.
IT CAN'T GET
ANY WORSE.
I MEAN, WHAT'S WITH
THIS EGYPT THING, DOC?
I MEAN, DOESN'T HE NEED
THAT FROM YOU?
IF JOBE'S WORRIED
ABOUT EGYPT,
IT MEANS HE'S ABOUT
TO USE THAT CHIP
TO ITS FULL
HIDEOUS POTENTIAL.
WHICH IS?
ENTER EVERY AND ANY
SYSTEM IN THE WORLD
AND TAKE OVER
THROUGH VR.
SO IS THERE ANY WAY
TO STOP HIM,
OR SHOULD WE JUST START
DIGGING UP OUR OWN GRAVES?
WE'VE GOT TO GET
THE CHYRON CHIP
FROM HIM
BEFORE HE
FIGURES OUT EGYPT.
THAT'S WHAT
WE'VE GOT TO DO.
Jade:
FEDERAL LIBRARY?
Peter:
WE CAN USE THEIR COMPUTERS
TO TRACK DOWN JOBE,
TO FIND THE CHIP.
THAT'S RIGHT, PETER.
YOU ARE
ILLEGALLY PARKED.
JADE?
INITIATE
IMAGE REGENERATION.
YOU'VE GOT
TO HELP ME.
ISN'T THAT JUST LIKE
A RECORDING?
NO. WE'VE GOT TO
STRIP AWAY THE LAYERS
WITHIN THE PROGRAM,
DISCOVER WHO THE SOFTWARE
THAT JOBE USED
TO ENTER VR
WAS LICENSED TO.
WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM.
I CAN'T GET PAST
THE MEMORY LOCK
TO ISOLATE THE CHAIN.
SIMPLE. JUST ENHANCE
THE MEMORY INDEX.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT HERE?
ACTUALIZE DATA.
POINT 5.
HERE WE GO.
EXECUTE WORM FUNCTION.
GET 'EM.
ENHANCE.
REDIMENSIONALIZE VARIABLES.
TA-DA!
ALL WE
HAVE TO DO NOW
IS ACCESS
DATATRONIC SYSTEMS.
I'M RIGHT WITH YOU, DOC.
OK.
THERE'S OUR
REGISTERED OWNER--PLATT.
I'M ACCESSING
PHONE LISTINGS...NOW.
OK, WE'VE GOT
43 PLATTS.
SEE IF YOU'VE GOT
A CORI PLATT.
C-O-R-I.
NO CORI, BUT WE'VE
GOT THREE C. PLATTS.
ONE'S A Ph.D.
BRING UP
THE DOCTOR.
WHOA!
SHE...
Peter:
HEY, TRACE, PULL OVER.
Jade: AREN'T WE GOING TO
DR. PLATT'S APARTMENT?
YEAH, BUT FIRST
WE GOT TO GET A TRACKER,
SO SHE CAN LEAD US
TO THE CHIP.
IT'S LOCKED.
SO, HOW ARE THEY
GONNA DO THIS?
NO PROBLEM.
MY BROTHER CAN HANDLE IT.
REALLY?
HE'S GREAT AT THIS
KIND OF STUFF.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
Peter:
IT'S UNLOCKED.
Travis:
LET'S GO SHOPPING!
UNAUTHORIZED CONTACT.
STAND BACK
FROM THE GATE.
WELL, THE EXTRA DAY
I GOT GREENSPAN TO STAY
WAS USELESS.
THAT LIBERAL IDIOT
IS ON HIS WAY BACK
TO WASHINGTON RIGHT NOW
TO RECOMMEND THAT
THEY RESCIND OUR LICENSE
TO GO ONLINE.
IF WE LOSE
THAT LICENSE...
WE'RE DEAD.
[TAPS KEYBOARD]
ACCESSING L.A.X.
RESERVATION FILE.
PASSENGER
ROBERT GREENSPAN,
FLIGHT 3701.
ACCESS NUMBER 3701
FLIGHT NAVIGATION
COMPUTER.
ACCESS DENIED.
ACCESS GRANTED.
RESET SYSTEM.
AUTO PILOT DESCENT
FROM 30,000 FEET.
WARNING--
ALTITUDE, 15,000 FEET.
EXECUTE.
WE'VE LOST
THE INSTRUMENT PANEL.
ACTIVATE AUTO PILOT.
AUTO PILOT ACTIVATED.
DESCENT RATE
INCREASING.
OVERRIDE AUTO PILOT.
WHAT?
OH!
I CAN'T!
CONTACT APPROACH.
DECLARE AN EMERGENCY.
OH!
OH, MY GOD!
[SCREAMING]
[EXPLOSION]
OOPS.
OPEN TOP-SECRET FILES.
REQUEST
DATA TRANSCRIPTS--
JOBE, VIRTUAL LIGHT.
UHH!
YOU'RE AWFULLY NOSY,
AREN'T YOU, GUILLERMO?
AAH!
CORI.
TRACE.
HI. YOU HAVEN'T
FORGOTTEN ME?
NOT FOR LACK
OF TRYING.
HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
FINE, BEN.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I NEED
TO TALK TO YOU...
ABOUT JOBE.
HE'S NOT WHAT
YOU THINK HE IS.
NEITHER WERE YOU.
HE'S VERY
DANGEROUS, CORI.
HARDLY.
AND WHAT
MAKES YOU THINK
YOU CAN JUST
SHOW UP HERE
AND ENTERTAIN
A CONVERSATION WITH ME?
PLEASE. I KNOW YOU'RE ANGRY.
YOU HAVE EVERY RIGHT TO BE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M LEAVING.
CORI.
WHAT?
LET'S GO.
YOU LOOK TERRIFIC--
MORE BEAUTIFUL
THAN I REMEMBER.
OK, HAS JOBE USED UP ALL
THE MEMORY IN YOUR SYSTEM?
EVERY PRINTED WORD,
THOUGHT,
AND DEED
IN HUMAN HISTORY
COULDN'T BEGIN
TO FILL
THE TYPE OF MEMORY
WE'RE USING.
BECAUSE OF
MY CHYRON CHIP.
I HEARD YOU DESERTED
THAT PROJECT,
JUST LIKE
YOU DID US.
I'M SORRY YOU
LOST THE PATENT.
I DON'T WANT PITY, CORI.
I WANT THE CHIP.
AND YOU WANT ME TO HELP
YOU GET IT. FORGET IT!
YOU SHOULD KNOW
WHAT JOBE IS UP TO.
DON'T PATRONIZE ME,
TRACE.
I'M NOT YOUR
STUDENT ANYMORE.
HE TRIED TO KILL ME,
CORI.
YOU MUSTN'T LET HIM
GO ONLINE.
CHECK HIS DATA FILE!
YOU'LL BE SURPRISED
AT WHAT YOU FIND THERE.
HEY,
HOW ARE WE DOING?
COOL.
THE TRACKER'S WORKING.
Peter: THAT'S WHERE
WE HAVE TO BREAK INTO
TO GET THE CHIP?
Trace:
GOT ANY IDEAS?
WE COULD HAVE JADE
TAP INTO
THE COUNTY ENGINEERING
AND PULL UP
THE BLUEPRINTS
ON THAT PLACE.
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
YOU'RE CLEVERER
THAN YOU LOOK.
THANKS.
WHERE'S DAVID?
I DON'T KNOW.
HE WAS JUST HERE.
MA'AM.
DAVID?
YES, MA'AM?
TAKE THAT DOWN
TO THE MAILROOM.
RIGHT AWAY.
ARTHUR, IT LOOKS
LIKE YOU'VE BEEN
GOING AT IT
FOR HOURS.
WALKER'S ORDERS.
YOU DON'T DO ANYTHING
ON THIS PROJECT
WITHOUT
MY AUTHORIZATION.
CAN I SPEAK WITH YOU
FOR A MOMENT?
WHAT?
I DO TAKE
MY RESPONSIBILITIES
JUST AS SERIOUSLY
AS YOU DO, YOU KNOW.
YOU DO YOUR JOB
AND LET ME DO MINE.
WHAT EXACTLY
IS YOUR JOB?
Arthur: CORI,
WE GOT A PROBLEM.
WHAT?
ALL AVAILABLE
MEMORY CAPACITY
ON THE I-1086S?
GONE.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
I KNOW THAT.
WHAT IS GOING ON?
I DIDN'T AUTHORIZE
THIS EQUIPMENT.
JOBE, WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE MEMORY?
I FORGET.
WALKER'S
BEHIND SCHEDULE.
WE'RE NOT
HE'S LOSING MONEY,
AND HE WANTS JOBE
WORKING
AROUND THE CLOCK
ON THE VIRTUAL
LIGHT.
I'M NOT GOING TO DISCUSS
THIS WITH YOU.
HE'S GOING ONLINE
TOMORROW.
OH, REALLY?
MR. WALKER.
MR. WALKER!
I THINK YOU'VE MADE
A MISTAKE, DOCTOR.
NO. I THINK YOU'VE
MADE A MISTAKE.
WHY WASN'T I NOTIFIED
THAT YOU INTENDED
TO PUT JOBE
ONLINE TOMORROW?
WELL, YOU'RE
JUST A SCIENTIST.
[UNZIPS ZIPPER]
I'M THE BUSINESSMAN.
AND JOBE
IS A HUMAN BEING.
JOBE IS
A PART OF THIS PROJECT,
A SUPREMELY
IMPORTANT PART.
AND EVERY DAY THAT
VIRTUAL LIGHT GOES UNFINISHED
IS COSTING ME MILLIONS
IN POTENTIAL REVENUE.
HE'S SHOWING SIGNS
OF INSTABILITIES.
I'M WORRIED
ABOUT HIM.
[LAUGHS]
WELL, THE MAN IS
AT A DISTINCT
DISADVANTAGE.
[ZIPS ZIPPER]
YOU HAVE
BEEN PROFITING
OFF THIS MAN'S
MISERY FOR YEARS.
HOW MANY TIMES
HAVE YOU POSTPONED
HIS PROSTHETIC LEGS?
WELL, I COULDN'T
HAVE HIM
LITERALLY GETTING UP
AND WALKING OUT ON US,
NOW, COULD I?
WHY DON'T
WE DISCUSS THIS
AFTER JOBE GOES
ONLINE TOMORROW, OK?
REQUEST FILE, JOBE.
ACCESS DENIED, CODE 7.
OVERRIDE CODE 7,
3942.
ACCESS GRANTED.
PLEASE WAIT.
FILE 248 JOBE...
EMPTY...
CONTENTS ERASED...
WHOSE AUTHORIZATION?
JONATHON WALKER.
CORPORAL,
HAVE YOU FINISHED
YOUR SECURITY SWEEP OF
ALL SECTORS ON THIS FLOOR?
Corporal:
YES, SIR, I HAVE.
DR. PLATT.
HENRY.
YOU STARTLED ME.
JUST MAKING MY ROUNDS.
IS EVERYTHING OK?
FINE, FINE, FINE.
I WAS JUST DROPPING OFF
SOME PRODUCTION
CHARTS FOR THE WEEK.
GOOD NIGHT, HENRY.
GOOD NIGHT.
AAH! OH, GOD!
OHH...
OH, MY GOD,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
DID I HURT YOU?
OH, YEAH.
WE'RE OK, MA'AM.
WE'LL BE JUST FINE.
WHOA, WAIT, WAIT!
LET ME...HELP YOU.
[GASPS]
ME AGAIN.
I WAS RIGHT,
WASN'T I?
JOBE'S EXPANDING
HIS MEMORY BASE.
GET OUT
OF THE CAR.
CORI.
[BEEPING]
AH, GOOD.
I CAUGHT YOU.
A GUARD REPORTED
SEEING YOU
IN MY OFFICE
THIS EVENING.
NOW, SURELY
YOU COULD HAVE COME UP
WITH A BETTER EXCUSE
THAN PRODUCTION CHARTS.
NO, NO, NO, NO. JOBE
IS GOING ONLINE TOMORROW,
SO I WANTED TO DELIVER
THEM TO YOU MYSELF.
I SEE. WELL...
GOOD.
BE SURE TO GET
SOME REST.
WE'VE GOT
A BIG DAY TOMORROW.
YOU'RE WORKING
FOR JONATHON WALKER?
HE'S THE ONE
THAT STOLE MY PATENT?
HE DIDN'T EXACTLY
STEAL IT.
HE WAS ONE
OF THE INVESTORS
THAT TOOK ME TO COURT.
GET OUT
OF THE CAR.
I WAS RIGHT ABOUT
THE MEMORY BASE.
I'M RIGHT ABOUT JOBE.
I DON'T THINK YOU
AND WALKER UNDERSTAND
THE POWER
YOU'RE DEALING WITH.
GET OUT.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
BETTER THAN THIS, CORI.
YOU STOLE A GUN?
NO, MAN.
IT'S A CAMERA.
CHECK IT OUT.
COOL.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S DO IT.
[GUARDS CHATTER]
Guard: YEAH, HE DID.
EXECUTE VIRTUAL
SURVEILLANCE SYSTEM LOOP.
YOUR ATTENTION, PLEASE.
A COOLANT TEST
WILL BE RUN
ON LEVELS 8 THROUGH 10
AT 0300 HOURS.
THANK YOU.
YES!
LIEUTENANT MARTIN
TO SECURITY.
LIEUTENANT MARTIN TO SECURITY.
SUBLEVEL 4.
THEY HAVE TO UNDERSTAND
THAT THOSE TUBES
HAVE TO BE HELI-ARCED
ABOUT 3 INCHES WIDE.
GUESS THEY DON'T
REALIZE THAT
THAT ALUMINUM TUBING IS
ABOUT 8 MILLIMETERS THICK.
Trace, whispering:
That's a special laser alarm,
sensitive to
anything above
0 degrees centigrade.
Come.
I've got an idea.
[BEEP]
YEAH,
IT'S DR. PLATT.
I SEEM TO HAVE LEFT
MY KEY CARD IN THE LAB.
OH, YES, DOCTOR.
I'M SORRY.
WE DIDN'T KNOW
IT WAS YOU.
THANK YOU.
YOU READY?
I DON'T THINK SO.
THIS ISN'T ONE
OF YOUR BEST IDEAS.
I WOULDN'T TRUST
ANYBODY ELSE.
YOU CAN DO IT.
STAY STEADY NOW.
GO ON. STEADY.
GRAB IT.
GRAB IT!
[WATER DRIPS]
STEADY.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
HA HA HA!
WHO IS IT?
AAH!
Platt: TRACE!
HA HA HA!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HE'LL KILL THEM!
HENRY!
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON?
Man: STOP!
BY THE WAY,
WHO ARE YOU?
STOP!
[GUARDS CHATTER]
Guard: CUT THEM OFF!
CLEAR!
Peter:
TRACE!
HALT!
SEALING OFF SECTOR 4.
SECTOR 4 SECURED.
WANT THE CHIP?
PUT YOUR GUNS DOWN.
PUT THEM DOWN,
OR I'LL SMASH IT.
PUT THEM DOWN NOW!
SLIDE THEM FORWARD.
UHH!
PETER! CATCH!
TRACE!
[GRUNTING]
PETER!
TRACE!
GET OUT OF HERE. GET!
AAH!
TRACE?
TRACE!
COME ON!
YOU HAVE THE CARD?
[BEEP]
WHAT NOW? HERE.
WHERE?
GO ON. GO.
GO.
OH!
GO!
WHOA!
UHH!
AAH!
YEAH!
[TRACE COUGHS]
WHY DID I LET YOU
BACK INTO MY LIFE?
YOU FIND ME
IRRESISTIBLE.
YOU GOT THE CHIP?
GOOD WORK.
HA HA.
YOU'RE BLEEDING.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Man: YEAH.
Woman: YES, SIR.
[SNIFFS]
WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S NOTHING.
JUST SOME DIRT.
BRING IT TO ME.
GET THAT DIRT,
YOU IDIOTS!
YES, SIR.
TAKE OFF YOUR SHIRT.
WHAT DO YOU
HAVE IN MIND?
SHUT UP.
I NEED TO STOP
THIS BLEEDING,
AND I'LL BE DAMNED IF
I USE MY SHIRT TO DO IT.
DO I KNOW YOU GUYS?
OW. OW.
I KNOW I OWE YOU
AN APOLOGY, CORI.
YOU COULD SAY THAT.
DO YOU MIND?
NO, NO.
OH, NO. NO.
YEAH.
PRETEND WE'RE NOT HERE.
OK.
SO APOLOGIZE.
I'M SORRY, CORI.
I REALLY AM.
MM-HMM.
I DIDN'T WANT
TO SEE ANYBODY.
I WAS TOO AMBITIOUS.
I WAS NAIVE.
I WAS--
YOU WERE STUPID.
THAT, TOO.
THANKS FOR
THE MEDICAL ATTENTION.
YOU'RE WELCOME
FOR THE MEDICAL ATTENTION.
[CHUCKLES]
HEY, RACE TO THE TOP
OF THE HILL.
NOT ME.
HEY, I WONDER IF THERE ARE
ANY SNAKES OVER HERE.
[BEEPING]
PRETTY NEAT, HUH?
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
SEE HOW THEY WERE
ABLE TO BYPASS
THE CAPABILITY
PROTECTION REGISTERS?
I KNOW.
IT'S AMAZING.
IT MAKES ME WONDER
IF I COULD HAVE EVER
FINISHED IT MYSELF.
THE CHIP
WAS SUPPOSED TO
MAKE THINGS BETTER
FOR THEM, WASN'T IT?
IRONIC.
STILL,
MAYBE IT COULD.
WHAT DID
HE DO HERE?
THAT'S WHERE JOBE MERGED
THE NANO-MATCHING HARDWARE.
HE COULDN'T HAVE.
THERE'S
NO TRANSMATRIX.
YES, THERE IS.
THERE ISN'T.
LOOK.
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
IT SHOULD BE THERE.
SO, YOU LOST THE CHIP.
YOU IDIOT.
DO YOU HONESTLY THINK
I'D ENTRUST SOMETHING
THAT IMPORTANT TO YOU?
VOIL.
BUT...
PEOPLE WANT A SHOW.
AND NOW THAT JOBE HAS
SOLVED THE EGYPT LINK,
THE CHIP
CAN BE ACTIVATED.
NOW GET OUT
OF MY SIGHT.
ANY PROGRESS?
JOBE IS TRACKING DOWN
THE INTRUDERS
BY ANALYZING THE DIRT
SAMPLE WE FOUND.
GOOD.
AND YOU ARE
INGENIOUS.
YES, I KNOW.
I THINK IT'S TIME
WE CALLED THE PRESIDENT.
TRY TO GET
VIRTUAL LIGHT EUROPE.
WHERE?
ANYWHERE.
UPLINK, ENGLAND,
VIRTUAL LIGHT.
NOTHING.
GREETINGS,
MR. PRESIDENT.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
AND THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US
ON THIS MOMENTOUS
OCCASION.
I'M HAPPY
TO BE HERE.
I WAS SHOCKED
TO HEAR
ABOUT SENATOR GREENSPAN'S
DREADFUL ACCIDENT.
MMM, YES.
I KNOW HOW MUCH
HE WANTED TO BE A PART
OF WHAT WE'RE
DOING HERE TODAY.
BUT LA VIE CONTINUE.
WE'LL BE JOINED BY HUNDREDS
OF OTHER PROMINENT PEOPLE
WHO WILL BE JACKING IN
FROM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY,
SO IF YOU'RE READY,
DON YOUR EYEPHONES,
AND...WE CAN BEGIN.
I'M--
JUST RELAX.
[CROWD CHEERING]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WELCOME TO VIRTUAL LIGHT.
WE STAND IN THE FACE
OF A NEW AGE.
THE FUTURE IS ONE WORLD,
ONE THOUGHT,
ONE MIND.
BEHOLD.
THE FUTURE...
IS NOW.
YEAH!
OOH!
12 HOURS TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
[SPEAKING
AFRICAN LANGUAGE]
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
[NO AUDIO]
Jobe:
IT'S ALL TAKEN CARE OF.
THE FOREIGN MARKETPLACE
WILL BE SECURE
ONLY WHEN THEY PLACE
THEIR MONEY IN YOUR HANDS.
EXCELLENT WORK, JOBE.
IT'S ALREADY STARTED
TO HAPPEN.
WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED
TO MEAN?
IT MEANS THAT JOBE
MUST HAVE FIGURED
A WAY AROUND EGYPT.
AND HE'S USING THE CHIP
TO ENTER EVERY SYSTEM
AND PROGRAM AROUND THE WORLD,
REPLACING IT WITH HIMSELF.
IT TAKES ABOUT 12 HOURS
FOR THE INTERFACE TO COMPLETE.
ONCE COMPLETE,
IT'S IRREVERSIBLE.
WALKER'S GOING
TO STOP HIM.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
WHO DO YOU THINK IS
DOING THIS WITH HIM?
WALKER'S A BUSINESSMAN,
AND JOBE IS
BAD FOR BUSINESS.
[BEEPING]
COME ON.
WELL! WHAT A SURPRISE.
I DIDN'T EXPECT TO HEAR
FROM YOU SO SOON, DOCTOR.
YOU'VE GOT TO STOP JOBE
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
TOO LATE?
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR
SENSE OF LOYALTY, CORI?
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
THE MEANING OF
THE WORD, WALKER.
IS THAT DR. BENJAMIN TRACE?
LISTEN, WALKER,
YOU'VE GOT TO TAKE JOBE
OFF-LINE IMMEDIATELY.
WELL, YOU SEE, DOCTOR, I WOULD
LOVE TO ACCOMMODATE YOU--
I REALLY WOULD--
BUT THAT'S NOT AN OPTION
I CAN EXERCISE RIGHT NOW.
LISTEN TO ME,
YOU STUPID BASTARD.
IF YOU DO NOT
TAKE HIM OFF-LINE,
YOU WILL HAVE
NO OPTIONS!
NO ONE WILL.
ARE YOU THREATENING ME,
DOCTOR?
NO, I'M NOT.
JOBE IS.
JOBE IS A LOYAL EMPLOYEE
OF THIS COMPANY.
I TRUST HIM WITH MY LIFE.
WELL, YOU'D BETTER,
BECAUSE YOU JUST
GAVE IT TO HIM.
TIME TO GET RID OF
SOME PESKY LITTLE ROACHES.
STOP.
BACK TWO SECTORS.
ENHANCE.
THEY CHECK IN,
BUT THEY DON'T CHECK OUT.
SYSTEM OVERRIDE.
Pilot: STILL
NO RESPONSE, CONTROL.
I NEED HELP HERE.
I HAVE MAYDAY.
[HELICOPTER APPROACHING]
Control:
4-ALPHA-6, GO TO NAV--
HEY, DOC,
WE GOT COMPANY.
REFERENCE
PRESENT POSITION.
HELP ME HERE!
OVERRIDE THE SYSTEM!
4-ALPHA-6--
ROGER. REFERENCING
PRESENT POSITION BRUNO.
DO HAVE BRUNO.
WE ARE LOSING
ALTITUDE, CONTROL.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
Shawn:
HARVEY! HARVEY!
NO!
LEAVE THE DAMN DOG!
GO TO FREQUENCY--
HELP ME HERE! HELP ME!
I'M IN DANGER!
AAH!
TWO HOURS TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
GIVE ME ACCESS
TO ALL CREDIT ACCOUNTS.
I'M SORRY.
YOUR ACCOUNT IS OVERDRAWN.
HUH?
THIS CARD IS
NO LONGER VALID.
NO! NO!
ATM MACHINES.
OH! OH!
[SHOUTING]
DEPARTMENT
OF WATER AND POWER.
Woman: REPORTS OF CITY-WIDE
CIVIL DISTURBANCES
HAVE BEEN VERIFIED,
AS THE POLICE DEPARTMENT HAS
GONE ON FULL TACTICAL ALERT.
BUT WITH AUTOMATED
SYSTEM FAILURES OCCURRING
THROUGHOUT THE CITY,
RESPONSE IS EXPECTED
TO BE SLOWER THAN USUAL.
ALREADY THE VIOLENCE
HAS TAKEN SEVERAL LIVES,
AND FEW SEE AN END
TO THE CONTINUING CHAOS.
OFFICIALS ARE REPORTING
A REMARKABLE OUTBREAK
OF LOOTING
AND RANDOM MAYHEM
THROUGHOUT THE CITY,
NATION, AND GLOBE.
JOBE.
HE'S FINISHED
HIS CITY.
THAT'S WHY HE WAITED, SO HE
COULD OFFER AN ALTERNATIVE.
PEOPLE NEED HOPE.
IF HE CAN DESTROY
OUR WORLD,
HE FIGURES WE'LL
HAVE TO TURN TO HIM
AS THE NEW MESSIAH
IN CYBERSPACE.
BUT YOU CAN'T LIVE
JOBE CAN.
IF HE CAN ACHIEVE
GLOBAL INTERFACE,
WE WON'T HAVE
ANY CHOICE.
EGYPT.
WHERE THEY BUILT
THE FIRST DAM.
THE CHIP
IS A DAM.
EXACTLY.
[SHOUTING]
COME TO ME,
ALL WHO HAVE BURDENS.
I WILL SET YOU FREE,
AND YOU WILL NO LONGER
BE THE BASTARD CHILDREN
OF A LOST GENERATION.
Jobe:
IT'S TIME TO TAKE CONTROL
OF THE SYSTEM!
GET AWAY!
THERE SHALL BE
NO MORE AUTHORITY
TO OPPRESS YOU.
WE CAN ALL BE
THE AUTHORITY.
[GLASS BREAKS]
JACK INTO
THE NEW WORLD ORDER.
FOLLOW JOBE.
ESCAPE THE VIOLENCE
AND GREED
THAT THREATENS
TO CONSUME YOU.
40 MINUTES
TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
COME BE ONE
WITH YOUR FELLOW MAN.
THIS IS TRUE SPIRITUALITY.
THERE SHALL BE
NO MORE AUTHORITY
TO OPPRESS YOU.
WORLD ECONOMIC MARKETS
HAVE TAKEN
SOME OF THE WORST COLLAPSES
IN HISTORY.
Man: WHAT ABOUT
THE EVENTS IN AFRICA?
JONATHON, I HAVE
SOME BAD NEWS,
AND I HAVE SOME BAD NEWS.
...THE CORE OF A REACTOR
IN KAZAKHSTAN
WENT INTO A MELTDOWN
IN THE WORST NUCLEAR ACCIDENT
SINCE CHERNOBYL.
ATTENTION, PLEASE.
ALL DATA HIGHWAYS...
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
WHERE DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE GOING?
COME BACK HERE!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
STAY HERE.
YOU CAN'T
GO ANYWHERE!
COME ON.
JOBE.
WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON?
WE'VE LOST CONTROL
OF THE ENTIRE SYSTEM.
ALL THE LABORATORY FILES
ARE DISAPPEARING.
ARE YOU MESSING
WITH ME?
NOW ANSWER ME.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
YOU HAVE NO POWER
TO GIVE ORDERS.
IN A HUNDRED YEARS,
YOUR PETTY FINANCIAL EMPIRE
WON'T MEAN ANYTHING,
BUT I'LL STILL BE HERE.
[THROWS DOWN TOY]
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
WITHOUT ME,
YOU'RE NOTHING
BUT A DEAF AND DUMB
CRIPPLE.
I MADE YOU,
AND I CAN
UNMAKE YOU.
JONATHON.
20 MINUTES TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
HUH.
YOU CAN'T DISCONNECT HIM
BECAUSE THEN VIRTUAL JOBE
WILL REMAIN INSIDE,
SO IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU HAVE TWO OPTIONS--
YOU CAN EITHER
HEAVILY SEDATE HIM,
OR YOU CAN
TAKE HIM OUT.
IF YOU WANT TO TAKE ME OUT,
JUST ASK.
[DOOR LOCKS]
OPEN THE DOOR,
GOD DAMN IT!
BASTARD!
[JOBE CHUCKLING]
ALL RIGHT...
IF THAT'S THE WAY
YOU WANT TO PLAY IT.
HA HA HA HA!
PRIME ALERT.
SECURITY BREACH.
ALL PERSONNEL, PRIME ALERT.
ALL PERSONNEL.
CODE RED.
THIS IS AN EMERGENCY.
ALL PERSONNEL WILL EVACUATE
THE BUILDING IMMEDIATELY.
THERE ARE THREE TERRORISTS
ON THE PREMISES,
FULLY ARMED AND DANGEROUS,
MOVING DOWN CORRIDOR 16.
SHOOT ON SIGHT.
REPEAT--
SHOOT TO KILL.
Walker:
THAT SON OF A BITCH.
WAIT, SIR, YOU JUST SAID
THERE WERE TERRORISTS
IN THE BUILDING.
WE'RE THE TERRORISTS,
YOU IDIOT!
GIVE ME THAT GUN.
THERE ARE THREE TERRORISTS
ON THE PREMISES.
SHOOT ON SIGHT.
REPEAT--SHOOT TO KILL.
NO!
[GRUNTS]
15 MINUTES
TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
Jobe:
GIVE YOURSELVES TO ME.
YOUR REBIRTH IN THE WOMB
OF CYBERSPACE
IS A CHANCE
FOR A NEW BEGINNING,
TO LIVE IN EDEN
WITHOUT HUNGER,
WITHOUT FAMINE,
WITHOUT TEMPTATION.
10 MINUTES TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
WE HAVE 10
MINUTES, CORI.
YOU BETTER WATCH
THE MONITORS--
AND PULL THE REAL CHIP
AT THE EXACT MOMENT
YOU DESTROY
THE VIRTUAL ONE.
TRACE.
CHECK IT OUT, MAN.
LET'S LOOK.
WOW. IF WE COULD JUST JACK
INTO THAT DOME UNNOTICED.
Cori:
WON'T WORK.
'CAUSE JOBE WILL KNOW
EVERYTHING ABOUT ANYONE
WHO JACKS INTO THE DOME.
WE NEED TO FIND
ANOTHER WAY IN.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
THESE ARE THE ROUTES
FOR THE INFORMATION
SUPERHIGHWAY
THAT LEAD DIRECTLY
INTO THE DOME.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO JACK IN, DOC.
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH JACKING INTO VR?
NO. I'LL BE FINE.
I'M NOT GONNA
RUN AWAY THIS TIME.
OK, LISTEN UP, YOU GUYS.
WE'RE GONNA FOLLOW
THIS SUPERHIGHWAY,
THROUGH THE CITY,
TO WHERE IT GOES
UNDERGROUND,
ALL THE WAY
INTO THE DOME.
WE TAKE THIS
ACCESS ROUTE HERE,
FOLLOW THAT UP INSIDE.
THEN COMES
THE TRICKY BIT.
WE'VE GOT TO GET BY JOBE,
SMASH THE CHIP.
Peter: HOW ARE WE
GONNA GET THROUGH
THE CITY?
WELL, HOW'S ABOUT
A LITTLE BIKE RIDE?
OK.
LET'S DO IT.
Trace: COOL.
OK...
DESTROYING THE CHIP
WON'T STOP JOBE.
WHAT DO YOU REALLY
HAVE IN MIND?
THE PARADOX
OF THE CHIP
IS THAT WHEREAS
IT GAVE JOBE
THE POWER
TO GO ONLINE,
IT CONTAINS
A DAM FUNCTION
TO PREVENT THE USE
OF ABSOLUTE POWER.
IF WE DESTROY
THE CHIP,
WE DESTROY THE DAM
AND EXPOSE JOBE.
WE'VE GOT TO MAKE
HIM ANGRY ENOUGH
TO DESTROY HIMSELF.
TRACE, COME ON, MAN!
WE GOT TO GO.
IF YOU CAN'T, GET OUT.
I DON'T WANT YOU
DISAPPEARING ON ME AGAIN.
AAH!
NO!
Jobe:
...THE PROMISED LAND.
THE TIME HAS FINALLY COME.
YOU SHALL WAIT NO MORE.
THE PROPHECY IS ALREADY
BEING FULFILLED,
FOR I HAVE SEEN
THE HEAVENS OPEN
AND A VOICE
FROM THE THRONE SAY,
"THE RIVERS WILL RUN
WITH BLOOD!
"THERE WILL BE CHAOS
IN THE STREETS!
"AND IN THE FINAL DAYS,
"THE MATERIAL WORLD
WILL FADE AWAY,
AND ONLY CYBERSPACE
WILL REMAIN."
IN THE WOMB OF CYBERSPACE
IS A CHANCE
FOR A NEW BEGINNING,
TO LIVE IN EDEN
WITHOUT HUNGER,
WITHOUT FAMINE.
WITH ME,
YOU WILL FIND REFUGE.
JOBE!
WE CAME
TO SAVE YOU, JOBE.
IN HERE,
I AM THE SAVIOR.
TRACE!
[GRUNTING]
I WILL CRUSH YOU!
30 SECONDS TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
YOU'RE JUST
A LAWNMOWER MAN, JOBE.
29, 28,
27...
LAWNMOWER MAN
IS DEAD!
AAH!
...GLOBAL INTERFACE.
24, 23...
BY THE WAY,
I DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT EGYPT ANYMORE.
I SIMPLY BUILT AROUND IT.
19, 18,
17, 16...
15 SECONDS TO
GLOBAL INTERFACE.
14, 13, 12, 11...
10 SECONDS TO GLOBAL INTERFACE.
YOU DESTROYED
PETER'S WORLD.
I'M GOING TO
DESTROY YOURS.
7, 6, 5,
4, 3,
2, 1.
AAH!
YOU'RE A FOOL, TRACE.
I DON'T NEED
THE CHYRON CHIP ANYMORE.
I'VE BECOME THE CHIP!
YOU BETRAYED PETER,
JOBE.
YOU'VE SOLD YOUR SOUL
FOR NOTHING.
YOU DON'T EVEN
HAVE ENOUGH POWER
TO DESTROY ME!
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
IS THAT ALL
YOU'VE GOT, JOBE?
YOU'VE GOT?
IS THAT THE BEST
YOU CAN DO?
[BEEPING]
[GASPING]
WHAT'S...
HAPPENING TO ME?
EGYPT, JOBE. EGYPT.
[GASPING AND WHIMPERING]
HEY, JOBE. COME HERE.
MAKE A WISH.
YEAH! WE'RE BACK!
WHOO!
YEAH!
OHH...
WHOO.
SWEETHEART.
HEY.
MY PAL.
WELL DONE.
HEY!
[SIGHS]
I NEED TO SEE JOBE.
OK. LET'S GO.
Shawn: WE GOT TO
DEFINITELY DO THIS AGAIN.
THERE HE IS.
CAREFUL.
PROBABLE PATHWAYS
TO INTERFACE,
40,084.
HE'S REGRESSING.
JOBE?
PETER...
PUMPKIN EATER.
WELL, ISN'T
THAT TOUCHING?
I WANT THE CHIP.
YOU CAN KEEP
THE REST,
FOR WHAT
HE'S WORTH.
WE'LL GIVE YOU THE CHIP.
GIVE US THE KID.
I REALLY DISLIKE
REPEATING MYSELF.
GIVE HIM THE CHIP.
GOOD LUCK.
OH, BY THE WAY,
DR. PLATT...
YOU'RE FIRED.
PETER!
[GUNSHOTS]
[GRUNTING]
AAH!
[SCREAMING]
I THOUGHT
I LOST YOU, MAN.
COME ON, LET'S GO HOME.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
NEW LINE HOME ENTERTAINMENT
CAPTIONED BY THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE --www.ncicap.org--