NARRATOR:
At the center of the universe...
...at the border
between the light and the dark...
...stands Castle Grayskull.
For countless ages,
the Sorceress of Grayskull...
...has kept this universe in harmony.
But the armies of darkness do not rest...
...and the capture of Grayskull
is ever most in their minds.
For to those that control Grayskull
will come the power.
The power to be supreme.
The power to be almighty.
The power to be
masters of the universe.
SKELETOR:
Report, Evil-Lyn. Speak.
EVIL-LYN:
We have sealed the gates to the city.
The castle is secure and we are closing in
on the Thenurian as we speak.
SKELETOR: Yes, yes. And He-Man?
EVIL-LYN: He continues to lead the resistance.
I assure you,
we will have him before the day is out.
SKELETOR:
I want him kneeling at my feet.
After all this time...
...Grayskull is ours.
- No.
Mine.
SORCERESS:
The power of Grayskull...
...has not yet passed to you.
- Oh.
Someone is speaking to me.
Yes. Sorceress.
My lovely prisoner.
My prisoner at last.
I've won. I've won.
The darkness is rising to embrace you.
The dark can embrace the light,
but never eclipse it.
You have not won yet, Skeletor.
He-Man is still alive.
- I can feel it.
- Really?
How sensitive you are.
Can you feel this?
[SORCERESS GASPS]
[MOANING]
Evil-Lyn, activate the holosphere.
People of Eternia, the war is over.
My forces are victorious.
The Sorceress of Grayskull
is my prisoner...
...and her powers are now joined with mine.
Let this be my first decree:
Those who do not
pledge themselves to me...
...shall be destroyed.
The new age begins.
Unh!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
- He-Man, thank the Sorceress you're alive.
- I've been looking for you.
TEELA:
Oh...
Grayskull...
- It was terrible.
- How many units are left?
Not many. All of us were scattered.
Suddenly, they were everywhere.
- Chaos.
- Someone betrayed us.
Help! Help!
- Get me out of this!
- It's all right.
Help! Help! Help, somebody.
- Help.
- All right, all right, we heard you.
- Pull the pole out.
GWILDOR: Careful. Careful.
MAN-AT-ARMS: Thank the Sorceress.
- I hear you.
Aah! Oh. Uh...
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Who are you?
I am Gwildor of Thenur...
...locksmith and inventor.
Ah! Skeletor's forces were hunting me down.
A million blessings upon you
for saving my life.
No blessing is necessary.
Any foe of Skeletor's is a friend of ours.
Now, why are you so important
to Skeletor?
Uh... Help me.
[GRUNTING]
[CHUCKLES]
I'd better show you. Please come with me.
I remember the days
we didn't have to lock our doors.
Those days will come back. Oh, yes.
[LOCK WHINES AND BEEPS]
Enter, enter.
Come on, come in. Welcome to my home.
Come on.
Come, come, come.
Ahem. Now, you ask
why is Skeletor after me? Ha!
Because of my invention.
Because of this.
Now I wish I hadn't created it.
Skeletor wants me killed
so I can't make another one.
If he knew I had this prototype...
What is it?
What does it do?
I call it...
...the Cosmic Key.
It is the most unique key in the universe.
The tones it generates...
...can open a doorway to anywhere.
- Anywhere?
- Exactly.
One simply computes gravitonic tones...
...for a specific destination...
...activates the energizer and...
And that's how Skeletor's troops
got into the city and surprised us.
Yes. Yes.
- I'm afraid so.
- You little worm.
- Don't you realize what you've done?
- Easy, Teela. He didn't know.
That's right. How could I know?
We Thenurians are a peaceful race.
Trusting in every way.
A woman came to see me.
Said she heard about my fame
as a locksmith.
She seemed, uh, interested in my work.
How could I know
she was from Snake Mountain?
- She was beautiful.
- That would be Evil-Lyn.
She tricked me. She stole the key.
Gwildor...
...can this device of yours
get us to Grayskull?
- Certainly.
- To the Sorceress?
Those were the first coordinates
I calculated before she came.
- Oh, good.
- Oh, but we can't. We can't.
If we disturb the gravitonic waves,
Skeletor's key will locate us.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
Sounds like he's already located us.
KARG:
Warlord, to the point.
No, no, no. Not that way.
This way, the secret passage.
- Hurry. Hurry.
- Go.
- In the corner, there. Let's move.
TEELA: Right.
Gwildor, where does this lead?
To the caverns underneath Grayskull.
Ionize.
Gwildor, hurry.
GWILDOR: Yes, yes.
HE-MAN: Come on.
I don't like adventures. Oh!
KARG:
Secure the room. Hurry.
Find the key. Tear this place apart.
He-Man, we made it. Look.
Ssh! I know he's here waiting for us.
- You're right. It's too quiet.
- Look. The Sorceress.
Come on.
Gwildor, hurry.
MAN-AT-ARMS: Shh!
HE-MAN: Be careful.
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Quiet.
Sorceress?
Sorceress, we'll free you.
Skeletor has imprisoned me
within this energy field...
...which only he can dissolve.
- You are in danger here. You must leave.
- We won't leave without you, Sorceress.
Gwildor, can your key open a door
to the force field?
- Of course.
- Then do it now.
- It'll take time.
- Let's get started then.
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Gwildor, over here.
I have to take a reading
and compute the gravitonic tones.
- He's taking your power.
- I can withstand him until moonrise.
Until the Great Eye opens on the universe.
- They're coming.
GWILDOR: Aah!
Gwildor, get back there. Keep working.
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Come on. Come on.
Everything comes to he who waits.
And I have waited so very long
for this moment.
- Let her go.
- I don't think so.
No.
While she remains imprisoned
within this field...
...her powers increase my own,
and when the moon reaches its zenith...
...the Great Eye will open
and all the powers of Grayskull...
...will be bestowed upon me.
Your wondrous Sorceress...
...will die.
- You dare threaten her life?
I dare anything.
I am Skeletor.
Throw down your weapons
and pledge yourselves to me...
...or you will join her.
- It's not her you want, it's me.
It's always been between us.
Silence.
[KEY BEEPING]
It's the locksmith.
- The little worm has another key.
- What?
No.
Kill him!
Cover Gwildor! Keep working.
Gwildor.
- Can that thing get us out of here?
- It will. It will. But where?
- Anywhere. Just do it fast.
- Yes, yes, yes.
[BEEPS]
It's working.
It's working, it's working.
Man-at-Arms, Teela. I did it!
[LAUGHING]
- The door. It's open. Let's go. He-Man!
- No. I won't leave her.
But you must.
Eternia needs you alive, He-Man.
You still have until moonrise. Go.
He-Man, let's move. Come on, go.
Come on, Gwildor.
Stop him.
- Gwildor, come on!
- The door! The door!
[GWILDOR YELLS]
- Gwildor!
GWILDOR: My key.
SKELETOR:
The key. Get the key.
Find them. Trace them!
I want them and that key hunted down
and brought to me.
It looked as if he was punching the keys
at random.
- There's no way of telling where they went.
- Monitor the frequencies.
Wherever they are, they'll use it again.
When they do, lock it in.
He-Man lives and possesses that key.
I must possess all or I possess nothing.
Find them.
[GWILDOR SPLASHING AND HOOTING]
[GWILDOR GRUNTING AND SPUTTERING]
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
- Are you all right?
- Brrr!
Trust a Thenurian
to find a soft place to land.
[COUGHING]
Thank you.
I could have suffocated
in that loathsome stuff.
Stop complaining. It's only mud.
That's easy to say
when you don't have clogged gill slits.
MAN-AT-ARMS: Oh, no.
- Oh, I... I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- Gwildor.
We must get back to Eternia.
So if you're through clearing your gill slits,
maybe you can tell us where we are.
We could be anywhere.
Any planet in the galaxy.
Any planet in a thousand galaxies.
I had no time to renominalize
my coordinates.
You got us here, you Thenurian wurbat,
now you get us home.
Calm down. Now, we're all in this together.
How can he get us home
if we don't know where we are?
I'm not a Torktum, you know.
I wouldn't build a device
that didn't store its home coordinates.
All we have to do
is punch the energizer switch and...
Uh...
Where is the key?
Perimeter search.
Each of us take a sector.
[RUSTLING IN BUSHES]
- What's that?
HE-MAN: Shh.
[WHISPERS]
Scan the area.
Alien life form. Big.
- Let me blast it.
- Wait.
It might be intelligent life.
[BRANCHES RUSTLING]
By the Sorceress, it's ugly.
It seems harmless.
[MOOS]
What a hideous cry.
Maybe I can communicate
with the poor creature.
Gwildor.
[GWILDOR MOOING]
Gwildor, we have very little time.
He-Man, I show 0.84 chromons
until moonrise at Grayskull.
- We'd better find the key, and fast.
- What's your plan?
When we find the key,
Gwildor will set coordinates for Grayskull.
- We'll use the element of surprise.
- Drop right into the throne room...
...fight off 2- or 3000
of Skeletor's crack troops...
...break into the force field
and free the Sorceress.
- Right.
MAN-AT-ARMS: If we're gonna split up...
...we'd better synchronize
our personal locators.
You both ready? And:
[BOTH DEVICES BEEP]
If you find the key...
...activate the sourcing signal.
- The sourcing signal.
- Good journey.
Good journey.
Moo.
Moo?
Moo!
HE-MAN: Gwildor.
- I'm going. I'm going. Moo.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
OVER JUKEBOX]
- Thanks. Come again.
CUSTOMER: Sure thing, ma'am.
MAN: Billy, get off the game
and get Daddy some napkins.
[DOOR CLOSES]
I never thought I'd feel sad
about doing that for the very last time.
Ha, ha. Don't worry, Julie.
They've got fast food in Jersey.
Thanks a lot.
I got a going-away present for you,
but it isn't wrapped.
- You didn't have to do that.
- It isn't even in a box.
It's a piece of advice,
and I pray to God you listen to it.
If you break up with Kevin Corrigan,
you will regret it for the rest of your life.
Monica, this is not
the seventh grade anymore.
Kevin's changed. I've changed.
Everything's different now.
Fine. Except for two things.
A: You still love him
and B: He still loves you.
Kevin doesn't need me
or my problems right now.
I just feel if I stayed...
Julie, I know it's hard right now...
...but you don't have to move away.
- Yes, I do.
- Your folks would've wanted you to stay.
The best thing for me to do right now
is to get 3000 miles away from Kevin...
...my house, this town and everything,
and just start out fresh.
[CAR HORN BEEPS]
- That's Kevin.
- I'm gonna miss you.
So, what time's your bus to the airport?
- Eight-thirty.
- Oh, great.
You can make my sound check, right?
Yeah?
- Yes, I'll make your sound check.
- All right.
- I brought us dinner.
- Oh, boy, Robby's ribs.
- I thought something different for a change.
- Oh, yes.
Yeah, well, it's not very romantic
for our last date.
Look, Julie, why don't you take
a later flight, huh?
Kevin, don't start that again.
We decided.
Okay.
JULIE: Kevin, I'd like to go to the cemetery
to say goodbye to my parents.
KEVIN:
Yeah, sure.
[MAN-AT-ARMS GASPS]
Don't ever sneak up on me like that.
This is my sector.
You're not supposed to be here.
An old soldier learns to follow his nose.
- Oh, father, you're always hungry.
- I'm not always hungry.
During the Siege of Kreyf, 30 days...
BOTH:
Without rations.
Father, the Sorceress.
We must find the key.
We're not gonna save Eternia
if we die of starvation.
Wait. Look.
MAN-AT-ARMS: I was doing that
before you were born.
TEELA: Not the natives, Father.
There, in the bushes.
[SMACKING LIPS]
BOTH:
Gwildor.
Holding out on us, huh?
Ah, ha, ha!
Just in time. I was going to share.
I was going to share.
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Sure you were.
[GWILDOR CACKLING]
Teela.
Mmm! Good food.
Yes, I've never tasted anything like it.
I wonder why they put their food
on these little white sticks.
Those are rib bones.
[COUGHS]
- You mean this used to be an animal?
- Mm-hm.
TEELA:
Ugh.
Ugh, what a barbaric world.
Never think while you're hungry.
I think we've wasted enough time.
We better get back to our sectors.
Gwildor.
It tasted good.
- Gwildor.
- I'm going. I'm going.
JULIE: I never told anyone this before,
but it's my fault they died.
Julie, come on.
It was a plane crash.
Those things just happen.
You don't understand.
We were all supposed to go
to the beach that day.
But I said I had to study because
I wanted to spend the day with you.
So they took the plane to Catalina instead.
Hey, come on.
Your mom and dad wouldn't want you to go
around the rest of your life blaming yourself.
- Would they?
- No.
I wish...
I wish I could change things.
[SNIFFLING]
But you can't.
That only happens in fairy tales.
[KEY BEEPING]
JULIE:
What is that?
KEVIN: Wow! Whoa, Julie, be careful.
- Kev, look at this thing.
Whoa! That is incredible. What is it?
Don't know.
Someone must have dropped it.
Dropped it, are you kidding?
Look at the size of that hole.
It's like it fell out of the sky or something.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
This is one of those
new Japanese synthesizers.
- Here, let me try it.
- Okay.
[KEY SOUNDS CHORD]
Whoa!
Listen to this. Oh, this is hot.
[KEY PLAYING MUSICAL NOTES]
We've got to turn this in to the caretaker.
No way, come on, are you kidding?
He'd just keep this for himself.
EVIL-LYN:
The Cosmic Key has been activated.
- We have a bearing on them.
- How accurate?
Within a parsec eon.
The next time they use the key,
lock in the source and open a doorway.
- Shall I prepare a full battalion?
- No. It may be a trap.
We'll send an advance group.
Assemble the mercenaries.
Have faith, Sorceress.
You won't be lonely long.
[CHUCKLES MANIACALLY]
Julie. Here, listen to this.
[KEY PLAYING MUSICAL NOTES]
- What do you think?
- Sounds great.
Okay.
I want to see what this thing can really do.
Test. Test, test. Hello, test.
Here, hold that.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to amp this baby up.
See how it sounds.
- All right, are you ready?
- Mm-hm.
Hold on.
All right, here goes.
[KEY PLAYING MUSICAL NOTE]
Wow!
I can't believe it.
Override complete.
We're locking in
on the key's source of origin.
Very good. Excellent.
SKELETOR:
You are too easily pleased, Evil-Lyn.
Have you forgotten time is of the essence?
Show me.
There. That's close enough.
- Have you assembled the mercenaries?
- Here, and awaiting your command.
I have selected your finest warriors.
Blade.
Saurod.
The Beastman.
And Karg.
Hmm.
A curious quartet.
He-Man has slipped away from me.
I want him back.
This must happen before moonrise.
Now, you are to go through to this world
to where they are hiding...
...find the key...
...do as you wish with the others,
but bring He-Man back alive.
You do understand?
ALL:
Yes, lord.
Good.
Open the door. Do not fail me.
I... I can't believe this thing.
I mean, did you see those lights, huh?
Look, we've gotta take this
down to Charlie.
- He's gotta know what this is.
- No, you go ahead.
This sounds really strange,
but I want to spend some time here alone.
Say goodbye to the place.
I'm not gonna be here for graduation.
Look, Julie,
I'll just go by Charlie's later, okay?
No, no, go ahead, I promise.
- Are you sure?
- Mm-hm.
Okay, all right.
I'll be gone 15 minutes, tops. All right?
- Don't let anybody in here except Carl.
- All right.
Hear me? Bye.
- I'll guard this stuff for you.
- All right. Bye.
[WHOOSHES]
Carl?
[KARG JABBERING]
Carl, is that you?
- Blade.
- Deserted. No sign of the key.
Scan the perimeter. No one in, no one out.
Kevin, if this is some kind of joke,
it's really not funny.
Listen, you kids can't just come in...
Don't kill him yet.
Unh!
[SCREAMS]
JULIE:
Leave him alone!
[SCREAMS]
Somebody help me.
Somebody help me!
No, no. Take her alive.
She may know where the key is.
Over there.
That way. Go around.
[JULIE SCREAMING]
[GROWLING]
- I've got you, pretty.
- No!
No!
Let go, stay away from me!
Let go!
Get her.
She's mine.
Aah!
[ROARS]
Stop her.
Somebody help!
[YELLS]
Move, you animals. Go, go, go.
Find her. Find her!
JULIE:
Help me! Help me!
Somebody help me!
Oh God, help.
BLADE:
She's in there. This way.
[YELLING]
She's in here somewhere. Find her.
[JULIE SCREAMS]
- Get away from me.
- It's all right.
It's all right.
Don't be afraid, I won't hurt you.
Now, what are you running from?
I'm running from these, these...
...monsters.
- Easy, easy.
- These creatures...
- I'll take care of it.
Look in there.
You, look up that way.
Search over there.
- You. Over there.
- No.
Search in there. Hurry.
Here, take this.
Protect yourself.
[BOXES FALLING]
She's over here.
This way.
[GROWLING]
[STEEL PINGS]
No!
[HE-MAN GRUNTING]
I've waited a long time for this.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
My sword.
Unh. Unh!
Pretty.
KARG:
Retreat. Retreat!
Follow them.
They must have a doorway to Eternia.
Are you all right?
They're gone now. You're safe.
You're safe. Do you understand?
[SNIFFLING]
Good. I know you've been through a great deal,
but I need your help.
Hey, hey, hey! Charlie.
- Charlie!
- Hey, Kev, how are you?
Hey, turn that down, turn that down.
Look, wait until you see this.
Oh, hey, I heard you were good last night
at Club Zero.
Thanks. Thanks.
We're going to be better tonight.
- I want you to take a look at this baby, huh?
- All right.
All right, here.
- What do you think?
- I've seen these before.
- You have?
- Yeah.
- It's Japanese.
- Oh, no, no, no.
I don't think so. Here, look.
Press a few of these buttons. Go ahead.
[KEY PLAYS CHORD]
Huh? Now press that red button in the front.
Go ahead.
[KEY PLAYS MUSICAL NOTES]
Far out. Fantastic.
[KEVIN CLEARS THROAT]
You know, I guess if you've seen one,
you've seen them all, right?
Thanks a lot, Charlie. I'll talk to you later.
- Come back here. Where'd you get that?
- What?
- You wanna sell it?
- No, no. Look, I don't wanna sell it.
I found this at Laurelwood.
Man, you would not believe it.
It was like... It was lying in this huge crater.
I was just hoping
you'd know something about it.
- I never saw anything like it.
- Look, we gotta figure out...
- What's that?
...how...
[KEY PLAYS NOTE]
D sharp.
Oh, Mr. Perfect-Pitch.
[POLICE SIRENS BLARING]
Whoa! All hell's breaking loose out there.
Let's see what's up.
WOMAN [OVER POLICE SCANNER]:
All units, Code 6.
Proceed to Central High School.
Fire and vandalism. Possible arson.
Repeat: All units, Code 6.
- Oh, my God.
- Proceed to Central High. Fire and vandalism.
- Julie's in there.
- Proceed with caution.
Our only hope of defeating Skeletor
is to find the Cosmic Key.
Now, those creatures were after you
for a reason, Julie.
Have you seen it?
- It's this large. It has lights on it.
- Wait a minute, I have seen that.
My boyfriend and I found this thing
that had light and music coming out of it.
That's it. Where is it?
- Well, Kevin has it.
- He's in terrible danger. Let's go.
MAN 1: Let's call it back.
MAN 2: Everything's all clear in the room.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
- Carl. Carl, what happened?
- You don't never wanna know.
Wait, listen to me. Carl, where is Julie?
What happened to Julie?
- There you go.
KEVIN: Excuse me.
- Where you going?
- My girlfriend's in there, all right?
Kid, we swept the place.
The only person we found was the janitor.
No, you don't understand.
I just left her here 10 minutes ago.
I'm telling you,
we went through there with a police dog.
The only stuff we found in there
was right there.
Dear God, that's Julie's.
Where'd you find this?
Where do you think we found it?
Listen, we got vandalism, arson,
we got a lot of bad stuff going on around here.
- What do you know about it?
- Look, I don't know anything about it, all right?
You're the cop.
Why aren't you looking for her?
- What does she look like?
- Look, she's about 5'5".
She's got short, dark hair.
She was wearing a pink sweater.
Is that all you're gonna do,
you're gonna write?
Why aren't you out doing something?
I'll do something.
I'll take you for a little ride. Let's go.
Oh, great.
- What are you doing, arresting me?
- We're gonna go look for your girlfriend.
We'll try her house first.
I bet you know where that is.
Harry, do me a favor.
Take that down to Properties,
give me a full report, okay?
Keep the coffee hot.
Looks like it's gonna be a long night.
FIREMAN:
Come on, guys, let's go. Let's put it out.
MAN-AT-ARMS: He-Man, they got away.
- Easy, Julie.
What happened?
These are friends of mine:
Teela and her father, Duncan.
- Man-at-Arms for Eternian High Command.
- This is Julie.
She knows who has the key,
wants to help us.
- Good.
- Did you have any luck?
- Not as much as you, apparently.
- We tracked them spinward, 40 metrons.
- Then they disappeared.
- They're only a scouting party.
Let's find that key
before they return in full force.
- Julie, which way?
- This way.
[METAL SCREECHES]
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Take arms. Full power.
Ready.
Native transportation. A primitive land boat.
Enter, enter.
Gwildor.
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Well done, Gwildor.
It was an inefficient combustible system,
but I fixed it.
It runs on lucrenos now.
No hydrocarbons needed.
[DEVICE BEEPING]
Why is there still resistance?
The people must know that I am Grayskull.
I depend upon you for these things.
You know that.
EVIL-LYN:
The people...
...wait for He-Man.
They believe that he will return to lead them.
For you to rule completely...
...he must be destroyed.
He-Man. If I kill him,
I make him a martyr, a saint.
No, I want him broken.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
Where is the key?
We, uh, uh...
...traced the key's signal, uh,
but were unable to take possession of it.
Is that all?
We... We fought with the Eternians,
but were outnumbered.
We thought it wise to return alive...
...and gather a larger force.
- So He-Man's free?
[STAMMERS]
You are all aware
of the penalty for failure?
Give me one more chance, Lord Skeletor,
and we will succeed.
I am not in the giving vein this day.
[SCREECHING]
Ha!
[GROWLING]
Get away.
He begs your forgiveness, as do we all.
- We live only to serve you.
- It would be a pity to waste their talents.
Save your pity for yourself, if you fail.
Take them and whatever troops
and resources you need.
- I was not suggesting that I go.
- Then you should not have spoken.
Leave immediately.
When you find the key,
send the sourcing signal.
An attack force will join you
or I will follow.
Go.
Maybe your girlfriend's here.
The lights are on.
No. They leave that on
to scare off burglars.
Oh, yeah? Let's go see.
Hey, not so fast, kid.
[DIALLING PHONE]
[PHONE RINGS]
- Hello?
- Kevin, thank God it's you.
[SIGHS]
- Um, Julie's not here right now.
- Kevin, this is Julie. What's going on?
Well, it's good to hear your voice, too,
but I've been really worried about Julie.
- Kevin, is someone there? Are you okay?
- Yeah. That's what I thought too.
Look, this is important.
I know you can't talk, just say yes or no.
Do you still have that thing we found?
Mm-hm.
Thank God.
All right, listen. Don't do anything.
I have so much to explain to you.
Just stay there, we'll be right there.
Stay put, all right?
I love you. Bye.
- Okay, if you talk to Julie, could you tell her...
- Wait a minute.
This is the police, who is this? Who is this?
- Who were you talking to?
- It was just a friend of Julie's.
- Say, you hungry?
- No.
You were talking about this thing,
weren't you?
- What... What is this thing?
- It's a synthesizer.
Yeah?
- How does this thing work?
- Just press these buttons right here.
- Like this?
- Whoa, whoa, careful, careful.
[PLAYING MUSICAL NOTES]
[LAUGHING]
Do you want to know something, kid?
I don't think this is any synthesizer.
This is where they ambushed us.
We didn't have a chance.
We'll see. Scanner.
I see only He-Man.
Where are the forces that you spoke of?
[STAMMERING]
Ah!
And a native girl.
It must have been she
who tipped the scales against you.
Outnumbered?
- Outclassed is more like it.
- The key has been activated.
Lock onto the signal.
It's close. About 10 metrons.
You wanna see what that thing does,
press the red button down at the bottom.
What? This one?
Whoa!
[KEY PLAYS CHORDS]
Holy smokes.
What are you, a magician?
How do you stop this?
[GASPS]
What's a kid like you
doing with something like that?
- Come on. It's my instrument.
- Ha, ha, yeah.
All right, look, let me heat this up,
then I'll show you, okay?
We're getting interference.
They're jamming the signal.
Locate the source of the jamming
and destroy it.
It's difficult,
like nothing I've seen before.
Destroy it now.
Whoa! Watch... Watch out.
The source of interference is destroyed.
We have a clear signal from the key.
Lock it in. We'll track it from the air.
Turkey, sit down.
- No more crapping around. What is this?
- I don't know.
Listen, I got vandalism, I got arson,
I got stuff blowing up in my face.
- You better know something.
- Look, I found it, okay?
- Found it? You don't know who the owner is?
- No.
Listen, I was gonna go put a note
down at Charlie's Music Store.
Know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna take this to the station...
...put it on the computer, check it out,
see if it's reported stolen.
Now, for the last time, kid,
where'd you find this?
Laurelwood Cemetery.
It was in a flowerbed.
Look, if you don't believe me,
go ask Charlie, all right?
- Go ahead, ask him.
- Boy...
- I just may do that.
- Hey, you can't just take that.
Oh, yeah? You just watch me.
Don't worry about your girlfriend.
We got an APB out on her. She won't get far.
As far as this is concerned,
don't worry about it.
If your story checks out, you'll get it back.
If.
[BEASTMAN GROWLING]
Get out of here! Get out of here.
Get out of here.
[GRUNTING]
What do you want from me?
No. Leave him.
You have the Cosmic Key.
Tell us where it is.
I don't know what you guys
are talking about.
- Let me persuade him.
- No.
The collar.
Please. Look, I don't know what you want.
Aah!
Now...
...you will answer my questions.
Yes.
Have you seen...
...this object?
Yes.
EVIL-LYN:
Where is it?
- It was taken from me.
- Who took it?
A policeman.
Where is he now?
I don't know. He...
He just left.
We should be able to track the key
from the air.
Yes.
Prepare the transport immediately.
Wait. Evil-Lyn, I found this.
This is the native girl
who is helping He-Man.
- This may prove useful.
BLADE: Into the transport. Move.
BLADE:
Move it out!
Move.
- Fan out.
- Moving.
- Looks like Skeletor got here before us.
- It's all clear.
- Stay ready.
- Kevin!
Kevin.
Oh, my God, Kevin, you all right?
He's bleeding.
What happened?
They asked me for the key,
but I didn't have it.
- The Cosmic Key.
- Kevin, did they take it?
No.
- A policeman took it.
- Where is he now?
What is this thing?
- What's the matter?
- Skeletor's work.
The Collar of Aldruber.
They've been questioning him.
- I'll have it off in a moment.
- He'll be all right.
Who put this on you?
A woman.
- Strange eyes.
- Evil-Lyn. She's here.
From the looks of this place,
she definitely wasn't alone.
- Right.
- Oh!
You all right?
Julie. Julie, get out of here. Now!
Ow! Damn.
- Kevin, these are my friends.
- Your friends? Julie.
Look, will somebody tell me
what the hell is going on here, huh?
- These creatures come in and beat the crap...
- Kevin, listen to me.
These people are fighting the others.
- They saved my life, now trust me.
- Trust you?
Julie, I swear to God, these...
...things come in here...
I mean, look at this place.
[GWILDOR CLEARS THROAT]
Look. Look. Native clothing.
Lots of it, all over the place.
[ALL LAUGHING]
If we dress like this,
no one will recognize us.
- What the hell is that?
- See? Ha, ha!
That's Gwildor.
Look, Kevin, I'll explain to you as we go.
We've gotta help these people
find the key.
- Are you well enough to go with us?
- Go with you?
Tell us where that policeman was headed
and we'll take it from there.
- Kevin, please.
- I wish I'd never seen that damn thing.
Okay, look. He said he was gonna
go to Charlie's Music Store, all right?
- It's at Landmark Mall.
- Can you show us the way?
- Of course.
- No.
Charlie, the kid said you know
about this kind of stuff.
You don't think this could be Russian?
Eh...
[CAR APPROACHES]
Well, what do you know?
The mountain comes to Mohammed.
Hey, how come I get this feeling
I've been looking for you all night?
I believe you have something
that belongs to us.
- Let me guess. That music gizmo there?
- By the Sorceress...
Freeze. All of you.
Choice, really choice.
What's this, a circus act?
Somebody's gonna give me
some answers here.
- Let's start with you, blondie.
- We're not your enemies.
If you'd just give us that,
we would be very grateful.
You get nothing until I get some answers.
- He-Man, He-Man. Someone's following us.
- What the hell is that?
Neutrino Drive,
18 metrons and closing fast.
- It's them.
GWILDOR: At 10.
They've locked in on the key.
- Hey. Drop your weapons or I...
- He-Man.
Gwildor, how long to calculate
the coordinates and take us home?
I don't know.
The keys have all been moved.
- Boy, are you people in trouble.
- He-Man, 0.61 chromons until moonrise.
- Teela, take these people in the back.
- Let's go.
You can't order me around.
If you'd rather stay and face
Evil-Lyn's commandos, that's fine.
Look, believe me, sir, you wouldn't.
Evil-Lyn, just as the signal indicated...
...the natives and the key
are within the structure, but...
- Yes, Karg?
- He-Man.
The Eternians have already arrived.
Beastman, full-force attack at my command.
Karg, Blade...
...follow me.
How do you feel?
I'm feeling a little hungry.
- Gwildor, you've got to hurry.
GWILDOR: I'm working as fast as I can.
There.
There's Grayskull, and that puts us...
...there, but we have to be there.
Twenty metrons forward
if we wanna break through...
...the barrier of the Sorceress' force field.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I don't understand.
Now, what are you trying to do?
The universe is music, Kevin.
Hey, this is really weird, huh?
Reminds me of
Invasion of the Body Snatchers.
The part where the pods
started taking over people's bodies.
You don't know who are pods
and who are the bodies.
Shut up. They're psychos, Corrigan.
We've stumbled onto some
loony fringe group here, some kind of cult.
Our guests are arriving.
- Gwildor, how much longer?
- I don't know. I don't know.
I'd give all the chalconite in Fribillian...
...if I could only spend two units
with a master song maker.
- You think they don't like us?
- No, they're just Ionely.
They miss us.
Go.
He-Man.
What the hell is going on out there,
World War III?
Ain't that your buddies
getting their heads blown off?
Kevin, you know how to use one of these?
Don't let him out of sight.
Guard the key with your life.
If anyone comes near it, blast him.
You understand?
They're killing each other out there.
- Is Gwildor ready?
- Not yet. The room's secure.
It sounded like you needed
a woman's touch.
Woman-at-Arms.
Give me the gun, kid.
Come on, give me the gun.
Don't you get it, Lubic, huh?
All right, this is for real.
She meant what she said.
- I said give me the gun.
- No.
Look, we've come this far.
We're not giving up until they get home.
Look, don't stop, Gwildor, all right?
Don't say I didn't give you a chance.
When this is over, you're going to jail:
Accessory to assault, resisting arrest,
endangering lives.
I guarantee, you and all your buddies.
I'm gonna put you away for 850 years.
What are you looking at, shorty?
Mark my words, Corrigan,
you're going to jail, you hear me?
Yeah, Lubic, I hear you.
Lubic, listen to me.
Lubic...
KEVIN:
Just relax, okay?
- All right, Gwildor, you need anything?
- Give me that thing.
Hey. Kevin, stop it.
CHARLIE: Watch that gun.
Come on, you're gonna get hurt.
- Mother?
- Yes, darling, it's me.
But the plane...
Oh, I'm so sorry
you had to go through that, Julie...
...but we had to disappear.
We're doing very important,
very secret work.
Oh, honey, I've missed you so much.
I don't believe it.
Mom.
Listen, darling.
Your friends are tied up
with the work we're doing...
...and they have something we want.
That shiny metal thing.
With the blinking lights.
Will you get it for us?
[KEVIN GRUNTING]
Charlie!
KEVIN:
[ALL GRUNTING]
LUBIC:
Moron kid. Watch your arm, pal...
[GUNSHOT]
I don't believe it.
I've got a lot of serious work to do.
You're acting like Torktums.
Julie. Where's Julie?
- I...
- Kevin, you won't believe this.
- They're alive.
- What's the matter? Where were you?
Julie.
Julie!
GWILDOR:
The key. The key.
Thank you, my darling.
No!
KEVIN: Julie!
- No!
- No.
- Julie.
[YELLS]
HE-MAN:
Where are they going?
Teela. He-Man. Hurry.
The key.
- That way.
- Bring Gwildor.
Hold them.
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Down.
JULIE: That woman took the key.
MAN-AT-ARMS: Let's move.
HE-MAN: Gwildor, come on.
GWILDOR: I'm going. I'm going.
Charlie, you got a gun in here?
A gun, a gun. For holdups.
- In the front room, under the counter. I got one.
- You got one? Go. Come on. Let's go.
Oh, my God. My store.
- My keyboards.
- Look at this place. Look at those guys.
This is an invasion. Give me the gun.
- Give me the gun. Give me the gun.
- All right, all right.
- Stay right there.
- No problem.
Police. Nobody move.
Holy shit.
I think I'm gonna need some backup.
Ready to transport.
I will send the signal to Skeletor.
[KEY PLAYS CHORDS]
KEVIN: What's happening?
HE-MAN: Hurry, keep moving.
The key. Someone's opening a door.
A very big door.
HE-MAN: Cover your eyes.
KEVIN: What's that?
TEELA: This way, hurry.
- Into the alleyway, hurry.
TEELA: Let's go.
- By the Sorceress. Come on.
It's him! It's him! Aagh!
Contact Evil-Lyn.
Evil-Lyn, Skeletor demands a report.
I have the key, my lord.
The natives are fools.
Weak and easily controlled.
- They are...
- And He-Man?
- He has eluded us.
- That will be all.
Air Centurians, find him.
Come on.
- Hurry.
TEELA: Air Centurians.
Down.
- Quick, he'll be back.
- All right, let's move. Come on.
- Come on.
- They're coming.
- This way.
- Hurry.
Come on.
- On the roof.
- Go, go.
Go. Go.
- They're turning around to come back.
HE-MAN: Keep moving.
Gwildor, your grappler, give it to me.
On the roof.
Hurry. Go.
- Where's He-Man?
- There.
No!
Fire.
He must not use that key.
Unh!
SKELETOR [OVER HEADSET]:
Centurian, lead him to me.
What do you say, Gwildor?
Any signal from the key?
There's got to be something.
Unfortunately, no.
Nothing.
He should be here by now.
I'm not worried about He-Man.
He knows how to take care of himself.
I'm more worried about getting us
out of here before they find us.
I only have two numbers left.
Once we get the key back,
we'll be gone within two pretons.
I think not, Gwildor.
Not the way to treat your beloved ruler.
Throw down your weapons or you die.
Gwildor...
...you minute minion...
...I have you to thank
for all these troubles. Why?
I had such grand plans for you.
I would never knowingly serve
the lord of Snake Mountain.
- Wait till He-Man arrives. He'll see to you.
- Will he?
I expect him at any moment. Take them.
GWILDOR:
Torktums.
He-Man, no! It's a trap!
[JULIE SCREAMS]
Julie!
Unh!
JULIE: No.
MAN-AT-ARMS: He-Man.
Kevin?
[GRUNTING]
Stay where you are, He-Man.
One more move...
...and your friends will not live
to see another day.
It's gonna be all right.
I give you a choice.
Return with me to Eternia as my slave...
...and save their despicable lives...
...or perish with them
on this primitive and tasteless planet.
Surrender your sword.
He-Man, no.
Teela, I have no choice. This is our fight.
- I don't want innocent people to die.
- Well said, He-Man.
How noble.
- Take care of them.
- Good journey.
Good journey.
What about them, sir?
Leave them alone.
He-Man is my slave.
As long as I let them live,
he is bound by his word.
Let them rot.
[CHUCKLING]
Let me look at her, Kevin.
- What's wrong with her?
MAN-AT-ARMS: This is Skeletor's particular gift.
- Gwildor, we need to get back to Eternia.
MAN-AT-ARMS: Lmmediately.
There's little chance of that.
The power core's melted down.
The tones are erased
from the key's memory.
There's no way home. No way.
Here. Cover her with this. Teela.
She's burning up.
We've got to get her water.
There's a fountain down below.
- Good.
- Up.
MAN 1:
Okay, move out, let's go.
MAN 2: I'll take the west perimeter.
MAN 3: Unit 3, keep coming from there.
Okay, Lubic.
- Where's the army?
- Will you shut up!
They were here, I'm telling you.
It was the damnedest thing you ever saw.
- Everybody, follow me.
- Let's go, guys.
MAN-AT-ARMS:
Let me see this.
Oh, my God.
- What's gonna happen to her?
- The poison's already in her blood, Kevin.
- The wound will keep growing...
- Only our Sorceress can heal her now.
I'm sorry, Kevin.
Look, don't be sorry,
just find a way to get us back, okay?
I mean, there's got to be a way.
Isn't there?
Gwildor?
No.
You see, Kevin...
...opening a dimensional door
is relatively easy.
But the tones, Kevin...
...the tones that were stored
in this Cosmic Key...
...were completely erased.
Skeletor knew what he was doing.
Even if I could fix it,
we could search for a thousand years...
...and never find the tones
that will take us home.
But wait a minute. The tones.
You mean the melody the key played
every time we pressed the red button?
- Yeah.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
- What is it, Kevin?
- Shh.
[HUMMING]
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING OVER RADIO]
God, I wish that thing would shut up.
Whoa. Thanks. Okay.
[HUMMING]
Wait a minute, I've got it.
[WHISTLING]
That's it. How did you do that?
I don't know, I just... if I hear a tune a couple
of times, I can usually remember it.
It had a good hook.
I was going to use it in one of my songs.
Songs?
Why didn't you tell me
you were a song maker?
Are you a master? Yes, you are. I know that.
[CHUCKLING]
That's why the fates brought us here.
The final chord, Kevin.
Twenty metrons poleward.
Pull it out of the air for us.
You've got the wrong song maker, Gwildor.
All right, I'm just a stupid keyboard player
in a high school band.
There's a million of me.
Only one of you, Kevin.
Only one of anybody.
Listen to me, boy.
In half a chromon...
...we're not going to have a sorceress
to go home to.
So if you know how to do something
with that thing, then you do it.
Gwildor, Kevin knows the tones.
Can you get us home or can't you?
[STAMMERING]
Yes.
Yes, I think I can.
I need a few things. Hmm...
A bossonic tesseract.
- Right here.
- An octode rectifier.
I have an octode rectifier.
- And something to play the tones on.
- I'll get a keyboard from Charlie's.
- Look, take care of her.
- I will.
I win.
How long?
CENTURION: Half a preton until moonrise.
- Do you hear, Sorceress?
The final moment has come.
All the forces of Grayskull...
...all the powers of the universe
will be vested in me.
Me. And you will cease to exist.
- It is not too late to undo this madness.
- Madness?
I demand the destitution,
shame and loneliness of scorn.
It is my destiny. It is my right.
- Nothing will deter me from it.
- Men who crave power...
...look back over the mistakes
of their lives...
...pile them all together and call it destiny.
[CHUCKLES]
Thank you for that bit of philosophy,
Sorceress. Here is my response.
Yes, Sorceress.
The sword of Grayskull.
Mine.
Now and forever.
Your champion.
Witness this moment, He-Man.
This moment
when the powers of Grayskull...
...will become mine for eternity.
Our lifelong battle is ending at last
in the only way it could.
CENTURION:
Holosphere standing by.
When the Great Eye opens...
...the people of Eternia
shall see you kneeling to me...
...just before you die.
- I'll never kneel to you.
- Yes, you will. Yes, you will.
Or I shall wreak
unforgettable harm upon you.
Lubic, let me drive you home
so you can get a little rest, huh?
I was in Korea.
I never saw anything like this.
[CAR APPROACHING]
- That's him. That's him.
MAN1: Not again.
MAN 2: Come on, Lubic.
- Come on, we're moving in.
[CAR APPROACHING]
I got it.
- How is she?
- The same, Kevin.
Okay, this should give us
the tones we need.
How?
Just press the keys.
Keys? What keys?
Oh, no, no, no. Here.
[STRIKES KEYS]
Excellent.
[CHUCKLES]
[GASPING]
[GWILDOR PLAYING KEYBOARD]
Wonderful.
You never told me you had sonic keys
in this world.
I just hope it helps, Gwildor.
- Thank you, Kevin.
- It's okay.
I'll have this ready in a preton.
Kevin, please don't leave me.
I promise you, Julie...
...I'll never leave you.
Never.
I love you.
[GRUNTING AND WHIP SNAPPING]
Enough.
Where is your strength? Where has it gone?
Look at your precious Sorceress.
An old crone. Weak. Withering.
Dying.
Are you ready to kneel now...
...proud warrior?
The moon rises to its apex.
Do you hear?
The alpha and the omega.
Death and rebirth...
...and as you die...
...so will I be reborn.
What are they doing over there?
We've gotta stop this fast.
- Okay.
- No.
Stay here and cover me. Spread out.
- And wait for my signal.
- Yes, sir.
These guys are mine.
People of Eternia.
I stand before the Great Eye of the Galaxy...
...chosen by destiny...
...to receive the powers of Grayskull.
This inevitable moment will transpire
before your eyes...
...even as He-Man himself
bears witness to it.
The Eye opens.
Now, I, Skeletor...
...am Master of the Universe.
Yes.
I feel it.
The power fills me.
Yes.
I feel the universe within me.
I am... I am a part of the cosmos.
Its energy flows...
...flows through me.
Of what consequence are you now?
This planet, these people...
...they are nothing to me.
The universe is power.
Pure, unstoppable power.
And I am that force. I am that power.
Kneel before your master.
Fool.
You are no longer my equal.
I am more than man.
More than life.
I am...
...a god.
[SKELETOR YELLING]
Now...
...you will...
...kneel!
Kneel!
- Are you ready, Kevin?
- Yeah.
I'm going to set the power. Now, here goes.
Now, Kevin, now.
[PLAYING CHORDS]
Freeze. Nobody move.
You're all under arrest.
Throw down your weapons and
place your hands on your heads.
- You have the right to remain silent...
- Lubic, you don't understand.
- We've gotta get back.
- Nobody's going anywhere!
[ALL YELLING]
Where are they?
Where are your friends now?
Tell me about
the loneliness of good, He-Man.
Is it equal to the loneliness of evil, huh?
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
- Holy shit.
- We did it.
- Gwildor, get down.
- Destroy them.
Take cover!
- You promised not to hurt them.
- I lied.
Farewell, He-Man.
SKELETOR:
Block him.
Get him.
Give He-Man some cover action.
Kevin, watch the rear.
You. Watch the forward position.
Will somebody tell me
what's going on around here?
- I feel like I'm in The Twilight Zone.
- Lubic, this is for real. Just get down.
Hey. Nobody takes pot-shots at Lubic.
All right, you wanna play games?
Then let's play.
Come on, you mother...
SKELETOR:
No. Don't kill him. I want him alive.
You cannot hide from me.
[LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
- Karg, prepare the battle station.
- Surely you won't leave with Skeletor still...
Yeah. Warlord, let's go.
Signal the retreat.
No.
I have the power!
You.
You will no longer stand between me
and my destiny.
But I will.
I told you it was always between us.
I ache to smash you out of existence.
To drive your cursed face
from my memory forever.
- Enough talk.
- Yes. Let this be our final battle.
Skeletor.
- It's over.
- Yes.
For you.
Aaah!
No! Aaah! No!
He did it. He-Man!
- Victory!
[SIGHS]
Victory.
Well, Lubic, look at you.
- Ha! So you're really gonna stay here?
- Are you kidding? Why would I go back?
And look what I got here. I got a castle.
I got a view, I got clean air,
I got a beautiful woman. Huh?
Some kind of retirement, huh?
Julie, keep this with you
and Eternia will always be near.
JULIE:
Thank you.
I guess this is really goodbye, huh?
He-Man...
...Teela, Man-At-Arms.
Don't. Don't say goodbye.
Say, "Good journey."
There's an old Eternian saying:
"Live the journey...
...for every destination
is but a doorway to another."
Good journey.
Take care, Julie.
- You look after her, now.
- I will.
Activate the doorway, Gwildor.
Are you sure you don't wanna go back
in your planet's history?
I could take you back in time
to the past or future.
No. Look, Gwildor, that's okay.
Just send us home.
We better get home, Gwildor.
[PLAYING NOTES ON KEY]
- Good journey, Julie.
- Good journey, Gwildor.
[GIGGLING]
Good journey.
Gwildor. Wait. Send us back...
Mom, Dad, hi.
- You're up bright and early.
- You're all right.
What's this all about?
I love you both so much.
I don't ever want to lose you.
We're just going away for the day.
We'll be back tonight.
No.
I changed my mind.
I do wanna go to the beach with you today.
Don't go to Catalina, okay?
- Don't be silly, honey. Stay home and study.
- Mom, Dad, please.
Don't get on that plane today.
I have a terrible feeling.
Julie, your father's an excellent pilot.
It's a short trip.
No.
- Julie. Julie, put those keys back.
- I love you.
Julie, where are you going?
Come back here.
KEVIN: Julie.
- Kevin.
KEVIN:
Oh. Oh...
- Don't let your parents get on that plane.
- I've already stopped them.
Wait a minute.
You know?
Yeah.
We were there.
Eternia.
I have the power!
I'll be back.
[English - US - SDH]