ANGEL: Almost got hung myself once.
Didn't care for it much.
How about you?
We'll leave you now.
Don't want anyone to see me here...
...and get the crazy notion
that I was connected with your...
...accidental death.
On the other hand...
...it's not good for a man
to be out here alone.
The mind can do terrible things.
[Angel laughs]
Enjoy the company.
[Buzzard screams]
BRET: Whoa!
[Horse whinnies]
[Hissing]
[Rattling]
[Horse whinnies]
Oh, snakes!
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa, Ollie!
Whoa, whoa, Ollie!
[Straining] Whoa, whoa!
Don't go without me,
all right, Ollie?
Lord...
...whatever I've done
to piss you off...
...if you'd just
get me out of this...
...let me know what it was,
I'll rectify the situation.
BRET: It had just been a shitty week
for me from the beginning.
It all started when I was heading
into Crystal River...
... to get some money
from the bank.
I should've known there was
bad luck on the horizon...
... when my horse got stolen...
... and I had to replace it
with less than a thoroughbred.
[Donkey brays]
My luck had to change fast.
The poker game of the century
was 4 days away in St. Louis...
... and I was still $3,000 short
of the entrance fee.
There was no way in hell
I would miss that game.
It wasn 't only
the half-million dollar pot to be won...
... though that kind of money
certainly demands attention...
... but I needed to know
how good I really was.
Once and for all.
BRET: I had to hole up here
for the night.
Business would have to wait
till morning.
BO Y: Hello, sir.
BRET: Hi, son. [Grunts]
BRET: How much?
BO Y: On a day, week or month?
BRET: Not to take care of him,
how much to just take him. Permanently.
BO Y: Pa, this man
wants to sell a burro.
PA: That burro ain't worth a dollar.
BRET: You got yourself a deal.
PA: Here's your dollar.
BRET: He doesn't eat much,
but he's a regular jackass.
And he-aw, he-aw, he always likes
to be called Arthur. [laughs]
The moment I slapped eyes
on this hombre , I smelled trouble...
... and refried beans.
Something else told me that this
was not just a chance meeting.
ANNA: I'll see your 10
and I'll raise you 10.
ANGEL: I call.
ANNA: Full house.
BRET: Is this seat taken?
[Chuckles] It is now.
My name is Annabelle Bransford.
ANNA: What do they call you?
BRET: Bret Maverick.
Pleased to meet you.
ANGEL: I like the game the way it is.
Well, I bring all sorts
of pluses to the table.
I hardly ever bluff
and I never, ever cheat.
I don't believe it.
[Laughing] Neither do I.
ANGEL: I like the game
just the way it is.
PLAYER 3: What good is an empty chair?
Indeed.
I'll bet I can change your mind.
I promise that I will lose
for at least an hour.
PLAYER 2: Sounds good.
PLAYER 3: My kind of player.
We're playing five-card draw.
ANNA: Please, sit down.
My name is
Mrs. Annabelle Bransford.
I caught that before, ma'am.
Except the "Mrs."
PLAYER 2: Ante up.
ANGEL: I'm in.
PLAYER 2: Same game.
Chips, sir?
PLAYER 1: You can lose
as much as you want.
[Bret chuckles]
BRET: 200.
ANNA: You said you'd lose for an hour.
BRET: I'm a man of my word.
ANNA: I know.
[Laughter from bar]
PLAYER 2: Place your bets.
PLAYER 2: Ante up.
PLAYER 3: It's about time.
JOHNNY: I'll see you...
...and raise you 20.
BRET: Slow down,
I'm running low on chips.
I'll see your bet and...
...I'll call.
JOHNNY: 2 pair,
aces over queens.
BRET: Lucky for me, I had 3 sixes.
Sorry.
PLAYER 1: Nice pot.
PLAYER 2: Broke your losing streak.
JOHNNY: That one shouldn't count.
BRET: Beg your pardon?
I don't think
that hand should count.
You got any logical reasons
why not?
My mind wasn't on the game.
BRET: Your mind...
His mind wasn't on the... [laughs]
What's your name, son?
Johnny.
You got a last name?
Johnny Hardin.
What's your occupation?
I'm a gunfighter.
I have to assume since you're
still alive and playing cards with us...
...that you're good at it.
Care to find out?
BRET: This hand definitely
does not count. Take it all.
Whatever you think's fair.
Do you mind if I just hang on to...
ANGEL: You always been gutless?
I think so. For as long
as I can remember, at any rate.
BRET: My old pappy used to say,
"He who fights and runs away...
...can run away another day."
What?
BRET: I don't see
what's so great about...
BRET: Whoa! Whoa!
Look, son...
BRET: Slow down there!
Where's the fire, son?
[Laughs]
BRET: Slow down. Don't shoot me.
I'm just trying to expound.
I was saying, I don't see
what's so great about being brave.
BRET: I'm a card player.
Call me a gambler.
BRET: I want to become an old gambler.
You are a gunfighter.
BRET: An exceptional one at that,
from what I hear.
If I went up against you, what
chance would I have had? Answer?
Zero.
[Click]
[Patrons gasp]
Absolutely none whatsoever.
Want to see it again?
[Patrons gasp]
[Bret laughs]
Oop! [Chuckling]
Damn thing won't stay in the holster.
BRET: Whoop!
I must have a spring in there.
Come on, let's just play poker.
BRET: Who here wants to play poker?
Who wants to see
some guy get killed?
No.
Let's play poker.
BRET: I'd rather be rich than dead.
ANNA: Was that fast?
I thought that was fast.
Was it fast? Was it?
JOHNNY: Yeah.
BRET: Now, what was it?
Stud?
I prefer draw!
[Bret laughs]
Just kidding.
[Laughing] Sorry, I couldn't resist.
[Laughter]
PLAYER 2: My ante's in.
Raise you 75.
Oh! 75.
That takes care of your bet.
And I'll raise you whatever that is.
Looks like 100.
[Sighs]
Shit! I fold.
BRET: You didn't pay to look...
ANGEL: You said you never bluffed.
I had a pair of aces!
BRET: I said I never cheated
and I hardly ever bluff.
This is one of the "hardlys."
You've been cheating
the whole game.
What do you think I was doing
during that first hour?
I was learning your "tells."
[Chuckling] Your weakness comes
when you get your hand.
You shuffle the cards back and forth
and act a little fidgety.
I just called you a cheat!
[Patrons murmur]
You also called me gutless...
...but I figured
you were just teasing.
THUG 1: Get your hands off him!
THUG 1: We get him first!
THUG 2: When I seen you
through the window...
...I believed in the Almighty.
BRET: You fellows were drinking.
A lot.
And you played bad.
Whose fault is that?
THUG 2: Yours, you bastard!
It's all your fault.
THUG 2: It's our time now.
[Patrons scream]
[Patrons murmur and laugh]
BO Y: There's going to be a fight.
BRET: Come here, son.
BRET: Hold onto this for me.
BRET: Now, if these fellows
get to whupping me...
...you can shoot me.
BO Y: Shoot you?!
BRET: Yes. See this doesn't get dirty.
Good luck!
[Exhales]
[Laughter]
[Bullwhip snaps]
THUG 1: I'm going to cut you up,
fancy man!
[Dog barks and growls]
[Bret yells]
[Applauding and cheering]
BO Y: You're pretty good.
BRET: [Gasping] Me too.
BO Y: By the way, I won 20 cents.
BRET: [Gasping]
Thanks to my lucky shirt.
BO Y: Speaking of my 20 cents...
OLD MAN: That's the way you do it!
That'll learn them assholes!
[Laughs]
All right! My shirt's damaged!
Damn!
What the hell else bad can happen?
You!
What did you say before?
You called me something.
Nothing important.
ANNA: He called you a gutless coward.
I did not.
I might've said a gutless cheat.
Cheat?! Cheat?!
ANGEL: I was teasing.
BRET: Teasing?
ANGEL: Teasing. [Chuckles]
Oh! [Laughs]
I don't like being teased.
Hey... my friend, I'm sorry.
[Laughs]
Now I'm teasing you.
[Laughing] Let's play poker.
BRET: Let me get your chair.
ANNA: That was truly amazing.
BRET: I just get lucky sometimes.
[Sighs]
BRET: Whose deal was it? Mine?
JOHNNY: Think I'm through
with you all for the evening.
JOHNNY: Good night, ma'am.
ANNA: Good night.
BRET: Good night, son. [Sighs]
Five-card draw all right?
ANGEL: Whatever.
Mind if I take 6?
BRET: [Laughing] Little poker humor.
I'm just teasing you again.
[Knock at door]
BRET: [Click] Who is it?
ANNA: Annabelle Bransford.
I shouldn't be doing this.
You're standing in the hall,
Mrs. Bransford. That's still legal.
If only I weren't a married woman.
ANNA: [Sighs] I couldn't help myself.
My very being cried out to hold you.
[Gasps]
Stop by anytime.
I know we may never
see each other again...
...so I think it's safe to say...
...you are the most blindingly
attractive man that I've ever seen.
ANNA: Goodbye.
BRET: Annabelle.
[Annabelle grunts]
BRET: How can I possibly
go on without...
...my wallet?
BRET: If you don't give back my money,
I'll have your ass in jail.
ANNA: Damn!
BRET: Don't get mad at me
because you're a miserable thief.
ANNA: I'm a very good thief.
I just been having bad luck.
BRET: I know what that's all about.
Where're you from?
Your accent could use some work too.
ANNA: Most gentlemen enjoy my Southern.
BRET: That's not in dispute.
But I'll bet there is
no Mr. Bransford, is there?
No, and there never will be,
thank you very much.
Now what do we do?
You're not going to turn me in?
I am law-abiding.
It's my duty to turn you in.
BRET: I'm afraid I'll have to...
What the hell! I got my money back
and there's no harm done.
Let's just call it square,
shall we?
Damn!
What?
You're just so irritating
and... likable.
I have to work on that, I guess.
There you go, all likable again.
[Giggles]
You know, I...
I think that had we known each other
under different circumstances...
...we'd have hated each other.
[Bret laughs]
There's no Mrs. Maverick?
I'm sure I would've remembered.
May I?
I wish we'd never met.
Goodbye.
Ow!
[Exhales]
She did it...
Son of a bitch!
BRET: Can I be of some help?
ANNA: [Screams]
BRET: What?!
ANNA: You must admit
I was better this time.
Not just better.
You were good.
ANNA: I was?
BRET: Very good!
ANNA: Thank you.
BRET: And now
it's time you do something I want.
ANNA: How dare you? I'm a lady.
Not in a million years!
Not if you or I were 100 years old...
BRET: Shut up! I don't want
to go to bed with you.
Why not?
[Laughing] Why not?
I'd be too frightened!
If I dozed, God knows
what parts of me you'd steal.
I'd wake up
with all sorts of things missing.
BRET: But I don't know
how to clean this...
...and, obviously,
you must know how to.
The laundry's closed,
I leave early and you owe me.
Easy on the starch.
ANNA: If I can't touch you,
I can touch your shirt and dream.
BRET: Want a hand?
ANNA: Yes, thank you.
[Annabelle screams]
[Bret laughs]
BRET: Thank you.
Goodnight, Bert.
[Moans] Bret!
Bret. That's my name.
Bret.
BRET: Good morning.
ROBERT: Morning.
BRET: Is Eugene in?
ROBERT: Yes, sir, but he's bus...
[Click]
Eugene?
BRET: Get up,
you bald-headed reprobate!
BRET: On your feet!
EUGENE: Don't shoot.
BRET: I need some cash.
EUGENE: I know a desert flower...
BRET: Shut up!
BRET: Put the cash on the table.
EUGENE: I don't have any.
ROBERT: Robbery!
EUGENE: Robert, no!
It's all right.
EUGENE: It's my friend Bret
saying hello.
EUGENE: Tell everybody
everything's okay.
EUGENE: Son of a bitch!
BRET: Silly bastard!
BRET: How are things going?
EUGENE: Things couldn't be worse.
I know I owe you $ 1,000.
BRET: That's what I came for.
EUGENE: Would you take 100?
EUGENE: I've never welshed on a debt.
Give me to year's end.
BRET: The end of the...?
I need that money right now.
For the All Rivers
Poker Championship.
EUGENE: How much to enter?
BRET: $25,000.
I'm $3,000 short,
but with Joseph and you...
Pork Chop Slim owed me...
...but his widow used the money
for his funeral.
EUGENE: They never found the body.
What?
They never found his body.
BRET: The widow Pork Chop conned me.
What's with people nowadays?
EUGENE: I know. You can't trust them.
Take my last 100.
BRET: I can't.
What about Matilda and the kid?
ROBERT: Bank robbery!
EUGENE: I told you...
ROBBER 1: You heard him!
Bank robbery!
[Screams and gasps from lobby]
ROBBER 1: I'll take this, gunslinger.
Empty your pockets, old man.
EUGENE: I got a silver dollar.
ROBBER 1: Do better!
My trigger finger's itchy.
EUGENE: All right, don't shoot!
[Eugene growls]
EUGENE: Take it.
ROBBER 1: What?! Look at this!
ROBBER 1: Well, I'll be!
[Robber stammers]
BRET: [Stammering]
Hundreds and thousands!
BRET: You said you were broke?!
EUGENE: I am now! He's got it.
ROBBER 1: And I'll get the rest too!
EUGENE: I don't have any more.
ROBBER 1: Pull those pockets out.
Turn around!
ROBBER 1: Hurry up! Hey!
BRET: I'm sorry.
ROBBER 1: Give me that!
ROBBER 1: Nah!
BRET: Nah!
ROBBER 1: Let's blow the safe!
ROBBER 1: Light up!
ROBBER 2: Heads down, everybody!
[Bret gasps]
[Screams from lobby]
BRET: [Grunting] I'm younger than you.
EUGENE: I should be under... [Grunts]
[Explosion]
[People scream]
[Horse whinnies]
ROBBER 1: [Grunting]
I'm getting too old for this shit!
ROBBER 1: Hi-yah! Yah!
EUGENE: You sons of bitches
beat me by a day!
BRET: [Coughing] Eugene!
You're holding out.
EUGENE: [Laughing]
Bret, that's all I got left!
EUGENE: Maverick!
[Bret chokes and coughs]
THUG 1: Hey!
THUG 1: Bret Maverick!
THUG 1: We want to talk to you, pal.
THUG 1: Where're you going?
THUG: Got you now!
BRET: Anybody see you?
THUG 1: Not a soul.
BRET: [Gasps] You come in
any later last night...
...that monster would've eaten me alive.
THUG 1: We saw that.
Anybody suspect anything?
BRET: [Laughing]
Not a thing. You were great!
THUG 1: We enjoyed it. [Laughs]
BRET: No kidding.
THUG 1: Thanks for taking it
easy on us.
Easy?
Those were my best shots.
THUG 2: The one there
rung my bell a little bit.
That's good.
THUG 3: You owe us $5 apiece.
THUG 4: $5.
BRET: Damn right, $5 a beating.
[Thugs murmur]
BRET: [Chuckling]
You won't believe this.
They cleaned the bank and me out.
I'll have to owe you.
THUG 1: Are you saying...
...you don't have our money
for taking your best shots? [Click]
BRET: Killing me won't make you richer.
THUG 4: But it'll make me feel better.
[Gasps]
You got a point there.
Let's see here.
[Thugs murmur]
I'm sorry. I forgot!
I honestly forgot.
I always keep something pinned
inside my vest...
...for such a rainy day occasion.
THUG 1: It's a good thing.
It was clouding up pretty quick.
[Bret and Thugs laugh]
BRET: That's a $ 100 bill.
THUG 1: A $ 100 bill?!
BRET: But I do need some change.
BRET: 80 will be close enough. 75...
THUG 1: Let's see what we got.
[Thugs murmur]
THUG 2: I got 17 here.
THUG 1: 17?!
THUG 2: That's right.
THUG 1: You owe me $8 for a month.
THUG 2: We'll settle that later.
THUG 1: You always cheat me.
THUG 2: I can't believe you!
BRET: Close enough.
BRET: You came out better
than you think. Nice working with you.
You keep this
under your hats, okay?
News travels fast in the old West.
THUG 2: A $ 100 bill!
That's...
...$25 apiece.
[Thugs cheer and laugh]
[Bret whistles a tune]
[Bret stops whistling]
[Exhales]
BRET: Ever since I was a kid,
I believed I had a gift.
That if I thought hard enough
about a card...
... I'd be able
to cut straight to it.
My old pappy always said
I was a damn fool.
But I knew if I really believed
and made it happen, then that...
... would be
nothing short of magic.
Of course, it didn 't always work.
What do I expect!
In fact, it had never worked.
[Sighing] You sweet woman!
[Sighs]
Lucky shirt. Yes!
[Gasps]
[Gasps and stammers]
[Gasping] Mrs. Bransford!
BRET: Wait! You!
BRET: [Stammering] I'm...
No! You...
[Mutters]
[Bell rings]
BRET: Hold up the ferry!
BRET: [Gasping]
You did this on purpose!
ANNA: You bet I did!
This is my lucky shirt.
Do your own laundry then.
My underwear comes from New York.
BRET: Got any idea
where this shirt was made?
Paris, France, that's where!
I can't go to the nearest store
to get another!
ANNA: Why don't you try
the kiddie department? [Giggles]
COOP: Remove your hands from the lady.
ANNA: When you least expect it,
your hero arrives. Mister...?
COOP: Zane Cooper.
Folks call me Coop.
COOP: Suits me just fine.
BRET: Coop!
ANNA: This creature's named Maverick.
I'm Annabelle Bransford.
ANNA: I'll be taking this coach.
COOP AND BRET: So am I.
BRET: That ought to be fun.
ANNA: Lord knows what he'd have done,
being alone with him for 2 days.
COOP: I hope you can relax
and enjoy the journey now.
My feeling is that
if there weren't any women...
...none of us would be here.
BRET: What kind of sense
does that make?
If there were no men,
we wouldn't be here either.
Are you mocking me?
BRET: Don't get ruffled.
I was agreeing with you...
...in a totally unusual way.
ANNA: What would this world come to
without gentlemen like yourself?
[Coughing from behind the coach]
BRET: A passenger!
Come ahead.
BRET: Right this way, sir.
Want a hand?
[Elderly man stammers]
ELDERLY MAN: I'm the driver.
BRET: Are you all right?
DRIVER: Why does everybody
ask me that?
Get me up there so
we can get this thing going. [Coughs]
ANNA: I think it's about time
we get to know each other.
Mr. Maverick has aspirations
to be a card player.
COOP: I'm not ignorant of cards.
Can't be in my line of work.
ANNA: And pray what might that be?
COOP: Lawman.
ANNA: I bet you're the best there is.
I can tell things about a man.
BRET: I can't quite place your accent.
Where in the South are you from?
ANNA: Ever been to Mobile?
That's where I'm from.
BRET: Mobile, Alabama?
Hell, I been there.
BRET: I'll bet we know the same people.
You start.
ANNA: I've tried so hard
to forget that place.
I endured
such personal tragedy there.
[Bret laughs and cheers]
COOP: A woman's suffering
is not a funny thing, Bertie.
BRET: [Chuckling]
There are exceptions.
[Bret laughs]
BRET: Watch your billfold.
BRET: Hey, old-timer!
BRET: The thief and the old guy
find it bumpy back here!
ANNA: How could you face them all down?
9 men, all of them armed?
A man gives his word to do his job,
he's honor bound to do it.
ANNA: Weren't you afraid?
COOP: A mite.
ANNA: Maverick doesn't believe
in bravery.
BRET: I think bravery's a fine thing...
...just overrated is all,
and doesn't suit me personally.
COOP: I just realized something.
What's that?
COOP: You're spineless.
BRET: That's right.
It's kept me alive a long time.
[Laughter from café]
ANGEL: You fellas got a problem?
THUG 2: [Laughing]
Heavens to Betsy, no!
[Laughter]
ANGEL: What's the joke?
JOHN: You, Pancho. You're the joke.
ANGEL: Explain that.
DOC: You'll have to pay us
more money than Maverick did.
ANGEL: He paid you to fall down?
JOHN: Paid us good too.
THUG 2: That's right.
A $ 100 bill.
ANGEL: That's a good day's work.
You fellas ought to see me first.
I'd a let you fall down for free.
ANGEL: Maverick is mine, anyway.
ANGEL: But this time it's personal.
ANGEL: $ 100 bill! Ha!
ANNA: Is he taking a short cut?
[Annabelle grunts and gasps]
Hey, old-timer, wake up!
COOP: Is he asleep?
BRET: It's more serious than that.
BRET: He's dead.
COOP: Dead?!
Yeah.
COOP: Get up and stop the stage.
BRET: Me? I just put a fresh shirt on.
BRET: You stop the stage!
COOP: Because this wheel's loose.
COOP: If it comes off, we're all dead.
Stop the stage.
I'll take care of the wheel.
COOP: Give me your hat.
BRET: It better fit when I come back.
Now, Bert... stop playing around
and stop those horses.
BRET: Help!
COOP: This is serious!
[Annabelle gasps]
COOP: He'll be fine. He looks handy.
ANNA: He is?
[Bret grunts and groans]
[Grunts and mutters]
[Coughs and sputters]
ANNA: Why don't you fix the wheel?
COOP: The wheel is perfect.
ANNA: Then help him.
He'll kill you when he gets back.
COOP: No, in the long run,
he'll thank me in his prayers.
[Bret yells]
[Bret screams]
[Grunts and groans]
Ow!
ANNA: What's he doing back there?
[Bret coughs and grunts]
[Bret gasps]
[Bret screams]
[Annabelle screams]
[Thump]
BRET: Sorry!
ANNA: [Screams]
COOP: Stop fooling around!
BRET: You poked me in the eye!
COOP: Get up there
and stop the horses!
BRET: Whoa, horses!
Stop!
[Bret screams]
Whoa! Stop!
Whoa!
[Bret screams]
[Grunts and gasps]
BRET: [Gasping] Ow!
COOP: Let me help you.
BRET: I got it.
[Bret grunts]
[Bret gasps and pants]
BRET: [Gasping] So...
what's with the wheel?
COOP: Oh! It's fine.
ANNA: Nothing was wrong with it. It...
BRET: [Gasping] I know.
I got a real good...
...close look at the wheels
from underneath.
ANNA: Don't you feel better
about yourself for being so brave?
ANNA: Wasn't that exciting?
BRET: [Laughing] I get it.
BRET: [Gasping] This was all
for my benefit. [Laughs]
ANNA: Yes!
BRET: To help me build character.
COOP: Exactly.
ANNA: He's bursting with pride.
BRET: [Laughing] That's funny.
You'd think I'd be mad, wouldn't you?
[Coop and Annabelle laugh]
COOP: Give me your hand.
BRET: Don't you ever try
and help me again.
BRET: [Gasping] You either.
BRET: Now back off.
Go ahead, back off!
BRET: Go away.
ANNA: Ungrateful!
[Bret gasps]
BRET: [Whispering] Help.
COOP: [Shouting] What?
BRET: Help.
COOP: [Stammering]
What did you say?
BRET: [Gasping] Please help me.
COOP: Oh! Okay, take my hand.
BRET: You take my hand.
[Bret whimpers]
[Bret grunts]
BRET: [Whimpering]
Take my other hand.
BRET: [Grunting] Easy!
COOP: Oh, watch the cactus!
BRET: [Groaning] I don't care about it.
Just get me up there.
COOP: You're doing good.
[Bret groans]
BRET: Now get your hands off me!
[Bret pants and whimpers]
COOP: Ungrateful.
COOP: Somebody ought to say
something nice about the deceased.
ANNA: We know nothing about him.
The only thing in his wallet
is names of whorehouses.
[Bret sings "Amazing Grace"]
[Coop and Annabelle joins in]
[Click, click, click]
[Screaming from road]
COOP: Trouble!
BRET: Pull up! Whoa!
[People screaming and crying]
[Groans]
M. MARY: We sing praises
unto the Lord, our God!
[People murmur]
[Dress rips]
BRET: Here.
COOP: We'll do everything we can.
M. MARY: "Though I walk
through the valley..."
COOP: Maverick!
COOP: They got hit by Indians.
M. MARGARET: Yeah, they were Injuns.
BRET: Ma'am, it was not Indians.
M. MARGARET: I seen them.
They were wearing war paint...
BRET: If it was Indians...
COOP: I said we'd take them
to Cristal City.
BRET: That's backtracking.
COOP: Just a day.
BRET: I have a game to get to.
COOP: I know what you have to get to.
M. MARGARET: Took my girl's music box.
GIRL: My favorite!
M. MARGARET: And the wagon
with our money.
BRET: Hold it.
Simmer down.
BRET: Exactly how much money?
ANNA: What kind of animal are you?
COOP: Vulture.
ANNA: Exactly how much money?
M. MARGARET AND M. MARY:
$30,000.
We were starting a mission...
BRET: If I get it back,
is it worth 10 percent to you?
M. MARGARET: 5!
5 percent.
M. MARY: No, 10 percent, Mary Margaret.
I want my wedding dress back...
...for when I find a husband.
M. MARY: [Sighs]
M. MARY: All right.
Can you do it?
ANNA: I know we can.
BRET: What's with the "we"?
M. MARY: I'll give you 10 percent,
but make those savages suffer.
BRET: I'm telling you, there are
no hostile Indians around here.
[Beating of drums from distance]
[People screaming]
M. MARY: Oh, my God!
Come on...
COOP: Drums.
Those are definitely drums.
ANNA: Right again, Bert.
BRET: It's Bret.
BRET: Hm.
ANNA: Well?
BRET: They look like dimples in dirt.
BRET: But they're shod horse tracks.
Indians don't shoe their ponies.
ANNA: They're Indians.
They probably stole the ponies.
BRET: Not everybody's like you.
ANNA: What is it with you and Indians?
BRET: Nothing. I try to shoot
one a day. How about you, Coop?
BRET: It's their fault for being
on our land before we got here.
[Bret gasps and grunts]
BRET: What are you doing here?
ANNA: We're partners. 50-50.
COOP: Sounds like 50-50 to me.
BRET: You want 50% too?
COOP: I want those ladies
to get their money.
BRET: Oh, fine!
I don't split my bounty with anybody.
ANNA: Would 60-40 be agreeable?
BRET: What'll you do for your 40%?
ANNA: I'll help. [Grunts]
[Gun fires and Annabelle screams]
[Bret gasps and pants]
BRET: Oh.
ANNA: 70-30?
BRET: 70-30?
[Bret laughs]
BRET: I don't know about 70-30.
BRET: You're not exactly
an experienced tracker.
ANNA: Some tracker you are,
following horses. Anybody can do that.
BRET: Anybody? Oh...
[Click]
...you see that hawk?
ANNA: No!
BRET: I won't shoot the hawk.
BRETT: You know what that hawk means?
ANNA: What?
BRETT: Nothing.
But you didn't know that.
ANNA: I did!
BRETT: You didn't.
COOP: Children!
BRET: Shh!
ANNA: [Whispering] What?
Smell some Indians in Montana?
BRET: No!
Now be quiet.
ANNA: [Whispering]
What is it?
ANNA: [Whispering] What do you hear?
BRET: Huh? Nothing.
BRET: I thought I'd nap before sundown.
Sneak up on them in the dark.
[Bret grunts]
[Coop laughs]
ANNA: What are you laughing at?
[Bret chuckles and sighs]
BRET: [Whispering]
Here you go.
COOP: There's 6 horses.
It's got to be them.
BRET: You got good eyes.
COOP: We got to tie these up.
ANNA: Can you teach me
to be a better poker player?
BRET: What? Now?
ANNA: You might be dead later.
BRET: You're all heart!
Poker's about observing.
Observe the U.S. Cavalry brand
and the shoes.
They're not Indian.
These are tells.
BRET: You got tells too.
ANNA: Do not.
BRET: You play with your hair at cards.
ANNA: I never...
COOP: Would you two shut up?
Just listen!
[Chime]
BRET: Sounds like a music box,
doesn't it?
BRET: Oh, hey!
There they are.
BRET: There's the music box
she talked about.
BRET: And look at that fella
in the back.
He's wearing your sweetheart's
wedding dress, Mary Margaret.
COOP: Margaret Mary.
She's not...
You're on a first name basis.
Would you two be quiet!
ANNA: Be quiet!
COOP: You're crazy!
Did you see any money over there?
BRET: No.
BRET: Nothing.
BRET: We could take them easy.
They're half drunk...
COOP: What's "we" doing
in your vocabulary? It's your show.
BRET: [Gasps] You'd just stand there
and let me face 6 guys with 6 guns?
BRET: I have 1 gun with 6 bullets.
6 guns means 36 bullets.
BRET: What if they got 2? That's
72 bullets. Maybe they got rifles.
COOP: Shut up!
You're babbling.
ANNA: You're babbling.
BRET: No, I wasn't.
ANNA: You are babbling.
Don't worry,
they're probably drunk.
Coop faced 9 men dead sober,
didn't you?
BRET: He's always dead sober.
COOP: She didn't mean that.
BRET: That's what she said.
I said the outlaws were sober!
BRET AND COOP: Shh!
BRET: [Whispering] Shut up!
[Click]
ANNA: [Gasping] Here he comes.
[Snoring]
[Gasps]
[Music box plays]
[Grunts]
BRET: What if there's trouble?
Seriously.
COOP: I'm right behind you.
BRET: You are?
BRET: No "wheels coming off" shit.
COOP: That was broken bones.
This is dying.
ANNA: [Exhales] Other way.
Dying. Right.
BRET: Give it to me.
It may be my last chance.
Hand it over.
ANNA: [Gasps] How dare you?!
BRET: I need all I can get.
ANNA: No, just take your own!
BRET: Got to be under there.
ANNA: All right, 50%.
BRET: 50%?
BRET: No!
ANNA: 50-50.
COOP: 60-40. 60-40?
ANNA: All right, 60-40.
ANNA: You're the fastest draw.
Why do you need my tiny gun?
COOP: Who said that?
BRET: It's true.
I am fast, but...
...I can't hit shit, especially when
I aim at people, so I need bullets.
BRET: You back me up?
COOP: Yeah.
ANNA: Bert.
Bret. My name is Bret.
You're Annabelle, he's Coop.
It's like you're shooting me.
ANNA: Be careful, okay?
BRET: Of course.
You, too.
[Bang]
BRET: Hey, everyone.
BRET: Wake up!
No need to get alarmed.
I saw your fire and thought
I'd come visit for a while.
THIEF 1: Who are you?
Bert Maverick.
BRET: [Laughing] No.
I'm Bret Maverick, and I'm here
to say each one of you has a gun...
...pointed at your heads.
BRET: Just whistle,
so they can hear you.
BRET: You're surrounded.
[Neither Coop nor Annabelle can whistle]
BRET: Did another wheel come off?
Clap if you can't whistle!
[Coop and Annabelle gently clap]
BRET: See? They're out there.
Zane Cooper will blow your brains
out. Probably heard of him.
I know you're thinking he's old, decrepit,
gums his food and his women.
But he can still shoot straight.
After you is Ugly Annie Bransford.
She came out backwards when
she was born, and nobody noticed.
Her parents had to tie a pork chop
to her so the dog would play with her.
When making love, she has to pretend
she's somebody else.
[Thieves laugh]
THIEF 2: You're all right, Bart.
COOP: Admit it.
That was funny.
ANNA: I didn't think so.
BRET: Some Indians
attacked a wagon train.
They said it might be whites acting
like Indians, but I don't believe it.
If you come along with me,
we'll settle this matter.
BRET: So if you could just follow me.
BRET: Get up.
Get in a line and let's go.
THIEF 3: Here's a thing
to remember!
ANNA: Aren't you helping him?
COOP: A man could get killed like that.
ANNA: Did you just help him?
THIEF 4: Shot my whiskey bottle!
ANNA: Oh, that's my gun!
[Giggles]
THIEF 4: Damn you!
ANNA: [Gasping]
Oh, isn't he wonderful?
COOP: Oh, yeah.
ANNA: Look at that!
They're all gone.
Isn't it wonderful?
ANNA: I'll be rich!
BRET: It was nothing, really.
COOP: I'll tell you what you did wrong.
ANNA: Now where's the money?
ANNA: You tell me where it is.
ANNA: There it is!
[Thief screams]
ANNA: I've never seen
such beautiful money!
COOP: Take off that dress!
ANNA: How dare you!
COOP: Not you. Him.
ANNA: Put that cash down!
ANNA: I found it!
BRET: I nearly got blown away!
COOP: I'll take the money.
ANNA: I'll count it for you.
BRET: Don't let her touch it!
COOP: Where are you going?
Stay and clean up your mess.
COOP: Be mature.
Clean up this mess.
BRET: Get back!
Put those guns down and line up.
BRET: Don't let her get
within 10 yards of that cash!
[Thieves grunt and groan]
M. MARY: I have found you.
For He said, "Seek and ye shall find."
M. MARY: And I have found you.
Oh, rejoice!
M. MARY: Bless you
for finding my wedding dress.
M. MARY: The Lord says it's good
to bear children. The Lord says...
COOP: It's a beautiful dress.
M. MARY: Thank you.
M. MARGARET: $2,500...
...$2,600...
...$2,800...
ANNA: $2,700, ma'am.
M. MARGARET: Are you sure?
ANNA: I'm sure.
BRET: She'd know.
M. MARGARET: $2,700, $2,800...
...900.
M. MARGARET: $3,000.
Here you go, the 10 percent we promised.
M. MARGARET: That leaves us
with $27,000, Margaret Mary.
M. MARY: That's not enough
to start a mission.
M. MARGARET: Don't worry.
We promised Mr. Maverick...
...$3,000 and we delivered.
The Lord will provide for us.
[Dog whines]
[Bret clears throat]
BRET: My pappy used to say...
..."Never sneeze when you hide
or smile when you lie.
And never,
under any circumstances...
...take money from women who've lost
a dog, a wedding dress and a wagon."
M. MARGARET: Hallelujah!
ANNA: I lost a wedding dress!
Bret!
[People cheer]
M. MARGARET: We have got
our money back. Saint Maverick!
ANNA: You owe me my 30%.
BRET: I'm a man of my word.
You can have 30%...
...of whatever I got.
[Annabelle spits]
COOP: I hate to interrupt,
but I got a problem.
If those renegades
weren't real Indians...
...who was beating those drums?
ANNA: Maybe it was them.
BRET: I'll take care of this.
JOE: You've come
for the money I owe you?
BRET: Anybody get that?
ANNA: You know about Indians.
Can you speak to him?
BRET: [Exhales]
I'll do my best.
BRET: Friend, go with me on this.
BRET: I'll explain later.
JOE: How long will it take?
It's getting hot.
BRET: I'll make it quick.
Scream at me now!
What's he say?
BRET: [Sighs] It seems
we've committed a terrible sin.
We're on sacred ground.
ANNA: We didn't know that.
Can't you tell him?
BRET: Yeah.
BRET: Shake your head,
fire your rifle in the air...
... look really mad, lots of words!
[Rifle fires]
[Indians yell]
BRET: His gods demand a sacrifice.
There's no other way.
COOP: Sacrifice?
BRET: Human.
BRET: You're doing great. Point your
finger and speak angry!
BRET: We can go if one of us
passes a bravery test...
...but one of us
must go with him.
ANNA: What's the bravery test?
BRET: He cuts off your hands.
If you don't make a sound, you pass.
JOE: Who 's the girl? She's pretty!
BRET: Point to her, say you want her!
JOE: Ah, I do want her.
Is she available?
[Indians yell]
[Howls]
[Growls]
BRET: I'll die
before I let him touch you!
ANNA: There's too many of them!
BRET: You're right. Don't show fear!
It makes them crazy.
BRET: One of us must go,
or there'll be bloodshed.
COOP: I'll go.
BRET: No, I'll go.
COOP: I owe you.
I almost got you killed twice.
BRET: I can't do what you can.
You get these people to safety.
BRET: I'll go, but it's okay.
Third time lucky.
ANNA: [sighing] Oh, Bret.
BRET: I liked it just now
when you called me Bret.
One thing.
What, Bret?
When you bluff, never tap
your fingernails on your teeth.
That's your second giveaway.
Even at a time like this,
you think of others.
BRET: [Gasps]
Goodbye, my lady.
BRET: You were right, Coop.
I never felt better
than I do right now.
COOP: Take care of yourself.
BRET: Now when they...
[Laughs]
[Laughing]... cut my hands off,
my lucky shirt'll fit.
ANNA: [Gasps]
Bye, Bret.
[People say goodbye]
JOE: [Whispering] What was that about?
My throat's killing me.
BRET: Tell you later.
JOE: Tell me later.
BRET: [Whispering]
I could die happy right now.
[Bret and Indian children laughing]
BRET: I'm just trying to...
Will you slow down?
BRET: I can't get my... Where'd
you get this useless piece of junk?
JOE: I won it off a Russian at poker.
Watch out!
JOE: My bicycle! Look at that!
BRET: [Groaning]
I'll stick to a horse.
[Groans] Why are they laughing?
JOE: Nobody's ever ridden it before.
BRET: [Gasps]
Ooh, hey!
You sure do pick the spots.
Yeah, I know.
Next time you people drive us off,
I'll find...
...some swampland so awful
you'll leave us alone.
[Laughter from children among teepees]
[Drums and chants]
BRET: Is that good?
JOE: Nah.
BRET: What's with the drums
and war paint and horses?
JOE: We had a lousy year.
So when this Russian archduke,
who gave me the bike...
...came and wanted to see
the real West, I said, "Okay."
He pays well.
We get dressed up in war paint
and whoop around like idiots.
He wants me to speak like
they say in books: "How, white man!"
You people are such assholes!
JOE: And he's got to hear
the war drums all the time!
Gets on my nerves.
JOE: You'll move on, you'll have
the cash. What's eating you?
JOE: [Clears throat] Bret.
BRET: What?
[Inhales]
I don't have the $ 1,000 I owe you.
[Gasping]
Oh, I knew you'd say that.
JOE: I'm sorry. You'll get it as soon
as I change my rubles into dollars.
BRET: When will that be?
The big game's only a few days...
JOE: You need $25,000 to get into that.
You're crazy.
BRET: I know that. [Sighs]
I suppose I have to win the $3,000.
With your $ 1,000,
I'll only have to win $2,000.
JOE: Wait!
You've got $22,000?
Cash?
It's not frog skins.
[Joe gasps]
I've never seen $22,000.
BRET: I've never seen 25.
This is terrible!
Can I see it?
Why not?
JOE: Can I touch it?
BRET: You can roll in it.
JOE: Where is it?
BRET: Where else?
JOE: What is this stuff?
[Spits]
JOE: Oh, ha, ha, ha! Very funny.
BRET: What?
[Bret gasps]
BRET: It's...
It's newspaper!
[Bret grunts and groans]
JOE: You all right? Was it the food?
BRET: No, no, no!
BRET: [Gasping]
I'll kill her!
JOE: What?
BRET: Annabelle!
BRET: How could she when
I was off to face my doom?
You were to cut my hands off,
she robbed me anyway!
JOE: Pull yourself together!
Everyone's looking.
JOE: I got your money.
I wanted to see how you'd react.
I was just teasing you.
[Bret laughs]
[Joe laughs]
BRET: [Laughing] Teasing?
I don't like being teased.
JOE: I'll kill you!
You'll be dead, I'll be happy.
JOE: Wait!
BRET: What?
JOE: Did you say, "dead"?
BRET: Yes.
JOE: I just got an idea!
[Speaks in Russian]
[Ring]
[Archduke laughs]
JOE: [Mutters] Big asshole.
JOE: Ah, bonjour, Monseigneur.
JOE: Comment allez-vous?
ARCHDUKE: C'est la langue
des missionaires.
ARCHDUKE: Parle anglais.
JOE: How, white man!
ARCHDUKE: Hello, Noble Savage.
I've had a terrible day.
I kill every animal in sight
and it's boring me.
JOE: Boring?
JOE: Maybe His Largeness be interested
in greatest Western thrill.
ARCHDUKE: What is it?
JOE: Come, come!
ARCHDUKE: [Whispering]
What is best Western thrill?
JOE: [Whispering]
Kill Injun.
JOE: Shh!
ARCHDUKE: Is it legal?
JOE: White man been doing it for years,
but much wampum needed.
How much?
JOE: Uh...
One thousand.
ARCHDUKE: One thousand?
Don't tie him.
That wouldn't be sporting.
No, he'll lose, but easy hit.
Dying anyway.
Smoke too much tobacco.
[Coughs]
JOE: Put out of misery.
Deal?
ARCHDUKE: Deal.
JOE: Me go find
and give him courage.
Indian law say death private thing.
You wait here.
BRET: Psst! Hey!
JOE: Bret?
BRET: Who else? Did you fix his gun?
JOE: He wouldn't let go of it.
BRET: Great!
What's in it for me if I die?
I got him up to $500.
BRET: 500? Worth the risk.
Let's get it over with.
JOE: $250 a piece.
BRET: I'm the one taking all the risk.
Why do you need $250?
JOE: Shh!
[Clears throat]
JOE: So, Arch!
JOE: Look sick.
[Bret coughs]
ARCHDUKE: Tell him to run.
JOE: No, no, no.
Wrong!
Why?
I don't want to lose the light.
JOE: Injun shot by white man's weapon
not reach Happy Hunting Ground.
JOE: Injun die by Indian way.
ARCHDUKE: I never used one of those.
JOE: Psst! [Clears throat]
JOE: Real easy, see?
[Archduke growls]
[Archduke inhales]
[Thwack]
[Archduke groans]
ARCHDUKE: No wonder you people
were so easy to conquer. Give me it!
JOE: $2,000.
ARCHDUKE: $2,000?
ARCHDUKE: $2,000. Give me that.
[Bret gasps and pants]
JOE: [Grunts] Come, come!
[Bret grunts]
[Joe screeches]
[Gun fires]
ARCHDUKE: I killed him.
[Laughs]
I really killed him!
ARCHDUKE: Will you leave him
for the vultures?
JOE: Never liked him much anyway.
Come, we get the money now.
JOE: Partner, we did it!
[Laughs]
BRET: We did it.
Yeah, "we" did it.
BRET: He could have killed me!
BRET: Arrows missing, bullets whiz...
JOE: We had to make it look real.
BRET: Real? You knew
he'd miss me by this much!
JOE: Shoot this.
BRET: You shoot it.
JOE: I'll show you something.
BRET: You get
a 5-second start.
JOE: I saved your life!
BRET: What?
JOE: Shoot it.
I'll show you.
BRET: Ow!
BRET: That's not funny.
JOE: Hurts, doesn't it?
JOE: Anybody who uses my bow
can't use their hand for half a day.
[Joe laughs]
JOE: And fresh from the mint.
All yours. You earned it.
BRET: I'd kiss you, but there's people.
JOE: Don't do that.
JOE: So... I guess
you'll be going now.
BRET: How will I explain I got away...
...with my hands still attached?
JOE: Tell them you got us drunk
and escaped in the confusion.
BRET: Nobody'll believe that.
It's stupid.
JOE: You people believe anything.
Besides, that's not $500.
JOE: I got the big dunce up to $ 1,000.
BRET: From $500 to $ 1,000?
JOE: Who's the best?
BRET: He would've gone for $2,000.
JOE: Uh, no!
That's pushing it, really.
BRET: All I need now is another $2,000.
JOE: You'll win it soon.
BRET: With my luck,
I'll lose this 1,000.
JOE: Hey, what's this?
You insult me by counting it?
BRET: I'm sorry Joseph, but lately,
even my close friends...
...have stiffed me.
JOE: Oh, hey, Mav!
What are friends for?
[Joe laughs]
[Laughter]
BRET: Yeah.
It's all there, isn't it?
BRET: I had to hotfoot it
out of there...
... as it wouldn 't be long
before Joseph had a scheme...
... to help me reinvest
my newly-acquired thousand.
CHILDREN: Goodbye, Bert.
BRET: The $ 2,000 wasn 't the only thing
I was short on.
I was really getting short on time.
BRET: Hey!
[Groans]
BRET: Hey! [Grunts]
[Click]
ANGEL: Should've paid your cowhands
a little more.
Lucky for you,
I don't mind being made a fool of.
ANGEL: If you hadn't done what you did,
I might've let you live.
[Bret groans and pants]
But now I won't.
[Chuckles]
BRET: It occurred to me, before I
blacked out, he might be teasing.
And then again...
... maybe not.
[Hissing]
[Horse whinnies]
BRET: Whoa, whoa!
BRET: [Straining] Whoa.
[Straining] Whoa!
[Groans]
All right, Lord.
That's enough.
[Stammering] I've found humility.
If you could get me out of this,
I don't mean to be...
...too presumptuous, but...
[Choking] Whoa.
[Rattling]
Let's go! [Grunting]
Go, Ollie, go!
Thank you, Lord.
All right, Ollie.
You can stop now.
[Grunting]
Ollie, you can stop!
You can stop, Ollie.
[Coughs] You can stop.
Thattaboy!
[Pants and coughs]
[Groans]
[Grunts]
[Grunting] All right, Ollie!
[Horse whinnies]
[Straining] Don't go, Ollie!
BRET: Stay there, pal.
Come on!
No!
No, no. Don't run!
[Bret mutters]
Ollie!
[Steam whistle]
[Laughter and music from steamboat]
ANNA: Bret!
Bret!
Bret Maverick! Look at you.
My hero's alive and well.
You seem happy.
Well, I am.
ANNA: How ever did you escape
from those hostiles?
I'm not exactly
a whole man anymore.
[Anna gasps]
[Bret grunts]
ANNA: My beautiful, beautiful,
perfect male. [Sighs]
I don't want to seem forward, but...
...could you loan me $4,000?
ANNA: I've only broken even
at the poker tables these days.
That means you can't enter.
Mrs. B., I'd give you
that money in a heartbeat.
The problem is,
I'm $2,000 short myself.
ANNA: And my poor, pure heart
was just set on it.
ARCHDUKE: [yelling]
This wine is for peasants!
BRET: Set on this, Mrs. Bransford.
BRET: Just stay as pure as you are
right now and I'll be back soon.
WOMAN: Hunting savages,
wasn't that dangerous?
ARCHDUKE: It's primitive,
but I like killing.
BRET: Excuse me,
but may I speak with you?
ARCHDUKE: Do you know who I am?
BRET: No, but I do know who I am.
Maverick, Indian Affairs.
BRET: It's over for you, Dukey.
Joseph talked.
ARCHDUKE:
I know no one with that name.
BRET: That's what he said of you
when I investigated the murder.
BRET: But once in jail,
he told the truth, and so will you.
[Stammers]
But, I no American.
Murder's murder, Dukey.
You face...
...at least 10 years in jail
and a $6,000 fine.
[Stammering] Six...? Wait, wait!
I have...
...six, six, six thousand.
ARCHDUKE: I have 6,000.
Please help me...
BRET: Do you know the penalty
for bribing an Indian Affairs official?
ARCHDUKE: No, please, I'm going home.
Take the 6. Fix it.
ARCHDUKE: Take, take!
BRET: All right.
BRET: The courts are overworked.
I'll give you a break.
BRET: Don't shoot any more Indians.
BRET: All right?
ARCHDUKE: No, no.
[Annabelle giggles]
BRET: Excuse me,
has there been an accident?
Miss Annabelle, can I speak with you?
Excuse me, gentlemen.
GAMBLER 1: Good luck, Miss Annabelle.
ANNA: Gentlemen.
BRET: I got something to show you.
Close your eyes, Annabelle.
BRET: You're in the game!
[Screams] I'm in the game!
BRET: Best be quiet.
ANNA: Your goodness has no end?
BRET: Apparently not.
Heaven will kiss you for this one,
Mr. Maverick.
I just realized something.
What?
You can't help it, can you?
You are irresistible.
BRET: If by some small chance
you happen to win, I'll expect my 50%.
ANNA: Then I'll be expecting
my 50% of your winnings.
BRET: Perhaps we should
consider that a loan.
[Steamboat whistles]
ANGEL: Let him go!
ANGEL: How'd you get here?
Tell me!
BRET: No, you tell me...
...why you said you'd never
let me make it to this game?
Who's trying to stop me?
It's going to be a pleasure
playing you again.
The pleasure's all yours.
ANGEL: Come on.
ANGEL: All right, all right!
COMMODORE: Hey!
COMMODORE: My, my, my!
COMMODORE:
Hit it!
[Gong clangs]
COMMODORE:
Welcome to my ship...
...the Lauren Belle.
And welcome to the first Annual...
...All River's
Draw Poker Championship.
[Crowd cheers]
Rules are simple.
We play till we drop.
Winner takes all.
The dealer can call one break
of one hour.
If you bust, you're gone.
[Crowd murmurs]
20 players means
there's going to be 19 broken hearts.
[Crowd murmurs and giggles]
COMM:
Let's make it a great contest.
An honest, great contest.
For that reason...
...I've imported one of the West's
most remarkable lawmen.
COMM:
Marshal Zane Cooper.
He'll run things.
[Crowd cheers]
Come on up here, Coop.
COOP:
Thank you, Commodore Duvall.
Now players,
anyone caught cheating...
...will forfeit his entry fee
and be banned.
See these?
COOP: They're the only 2 allowed here.
Anyone breaking rules...
...better be a faster draw than me.
COOP: And better learn how to swim.
[Clunk]
[Crowd laughs]
COOP: Thank you, sir.
COOP: Commodore.
COMM: All right, gamblers...
...step right up
and bring your money.
[Crowd cheers]
BRET: After you.
COMM:
$25,000.
HIGHTOWER:
That's correct. Here.
COOP:
Make your mark right here.
Thank you, sir.
COOP: Put your money in
and make your mark here right.
Good luck to you.
[Sighing] Here it is.
I'll take good care of it.
Count that, would you?
It's all there.
I'm sure it is.
[Commodore chuckles]
COMM:
The games will begin in 10 minutes.
[Crowd cheers]
COOP: Folks, if we had $25,000 more,
we'd have a half-million.
COOP: We're minus one entry fee.
COMM: What?!
COOP:
I believe it's yours.
[Crowd laughs]
COOP: Do I need to count it?
CROWD: [Cheering] Yeah!
COMM: I don't think so.
COOP: Even half-million.
[Cheering]
COOP: This safe was brought in
specially for this contest.
I selected the combination.
I'm the only one that knows it.
Commodore, the money's as protected
as I can make it.
COMM:
There it is. Gamblers...
...find your designated table
and let's play some poker!
[Crowd cheers]
5,000.
[Laughs]
My pot.
ANGEL: I'll call you.
GAMBLER 1:
Gentlemen...
...four kings.
[Crowd claps]
COOP: All right, young man.
Let's go.
WOMAN IN CROWD:
[Yelling] Hey!
GAMBLER 2:
You cheating bastard!
COOP:
Sit down! I'll handle this.
GAMBLER 3:
I knew it was him!
GAMBLER 1:
Don't touch my chips!
[Crowd murmurs]
GAMBLER 1: Hang on a second!
Wait!
GAMBLER 1:
Where are you taking me?
I can't swim!
[Splash]
[Crowd cheers]
GAMBLER 4:
Gentlemen, my pleasure.
MULDER:
Kings over tens, gentlemen.
Ripped my shirt!
COOP: Time to go for a swim.
Divide the chips among the players.
GAMBLER 5:
You son of a bitch!
COOP:
Sorry, old-timer, that's it.
[Crowd murmurs]
[Crowd yells]
COOP: Sir.
MULDER: If you don't mind.
COOP: At your pleasure.
MULDER: Thank you, Mr. Coop.
[Splash]
[Crowd cheers]
GAMBLER 5:
Thank you, gentlemen.
GAMBLER 6: Good game, Hightower.
DEALER: Hightower retires.
[Crowd claps]
Oh!
4 queens.
DEALER 2: Congratulations.
Chips'll be waiting at the main table.
Good luck in the final game.
DEALER 3: Full house.
COMM: That's a good hand.
That beats 1...
...2...
...3 sevens.
But not 4.
What?
[Laughs]
[Blubbers] I didn't...
DEALER 3:
Why don't you get a drink?
DEALER 3: You'll feel better
if you get fresh air.
Watch your step.
[Coop sighs]
COMM: I hate those sad losers.
COOP: Don't play if you can't afford it.
COMM: How's it look?
COOP: It looks like you,
Mrs. Bransford, the Spaniard...
...and, unless a miracle happens,
Maverick.
COMM: Maverick, huh?
COMM: When it's decided,
call a break for an hour...
...and let's set it up
at that table.
GAMBLER 7: I was going to leave you
something, but I'm cleaned out.
DEALER 4:
You're a hell of a player.
GAMBLER 7:
It's the most I enjoyed losing.
Adios.
ANNA: That's for you.
DEALER 4: Thank you, ma'am.
DEALER 4: Congratulations.
I'll have your chips set up.
GAMBLER 8:
Good luck to you, son.
DEALER 1: Leave your chips here,
I'll transfer them to the final game.
Congratulations.
[Rip]
[Clock rings]
The players can take
a one hour break.
Anyone not back at the stroke of five,
forfeit their winnings.
BRET: [Whispering] Annabelle.
ANNA: [Whispering] Bret.
BRET: Annabelle!
BRET: [Stammering]
I... though...
Good morning.
[Bret grunts]
[Screams from inside cabin]
BRET: Sorry. [Gasps]
[Bret grunts]
[Door slams]
BELLMAN: [Ring]
30 minutes, everybody.
30 minutes to the final game.
[Bret gasps and pants]
He's a good 4 minutes fast.
BELLMAN:
30 minutes...
CHIP MAN: Positions, sir?
COOP: Dealer over there.
Give me the cards.
BELLMAN: [Ring]
15 minutes, everybody.
BELLMAN: 15 minutes.
BRET: Maybe we better get serious.
CATHY: Ooh!
WAYLON: Here.
COOP: I've got it,
if you don't mind.
Madam, we have rules
about that on board ship.
That's my gun.
COOP: It's your gun?
WAYLON: Yeah, it's mine.
COOP: Do you swim?
Swim? No.
But she does and it's her gun.
COOP: And this one?
COOP: Is this hers too?
WAYLON: I'm carrying it for her.
CATHY: What?
COOP: Madam, is this your husband?
WAYLON: How about a little boat?
COOP: A little boat?
[Annabelle grunts]
COOP: Well, you look particularly
ravishing for 5 in the morning.
Nice glow about you.
Five minutes, Mr. Maverick!
[Ring]
[Ring, ring]
COOP: Dealer...
...start dividing up Maverick's
chips. Looks like he's a no-show.
[Bret grunts]
[Bret gasps]
[Gong]
BRET: Wait!
[Crowd murmurs]
BRET: Excuse me.
[Crowd applauds]
[Bret sighs]
COOP: Dealer,
you can start the game.
DEALER: Ante up, everyone.
$50.
BRET: A thousand and two more.
ANNA: I'll see your $2,000 and...
Can I bid everything I have?
DEALER: Yes, ma'am.
ANNA: That'll be $ 12,000.
COMM: Too rich for my blood.
ANGEL: I'm out.
[Bret exhales]
BRET: What the hell!
I feel like being silly. I'll call.
[Bret clears throat]
It's just a pair of sixes.
If you can beat that,
then I'm licked.
Not a totally unpleasant prospect.
[Crowd laughs]
ANNA: I'm out of the game.
I'm out.
You put me out.
BRET: I did.
ANNA: I didn't do any of my tells.
I didn't twirl my hair
or flick my teeth.
BRET: [Inhales]
You held your breath.
No, I wasn't.
ANNA: Did I hold it?
COMM: Yes.
ANNA: Did I?
BRET: See?
BRET: Sorry.
See, usually...
...when you get excited,
you breathe heavily.
How do you...
I'll just pretend I was playing
with somebody else's money.
BRET: Shouldn't be hard.
ANNA: Gentlemen.
[Applause]
COOP: You did hold your breath.
DEALER: Ante up.
[Whistle]
DEALER: You open, Commodore.
I'll open for $5,000.
HIGHTOWER: 5,000?
ANGEL: I'll see your 5...
...and raise you 5.
DEALER: 10,000 to you.
BRET: Call.
COMM: And 5 more to me.
DEALER: Cards?
2 cards, please.
DEALER: Sir?
ANGEL: 2.
DEALER: Mr. Maverick.
BRET: One card, but not from you.
Put the deck down.
BRET: I'd like a new deck,
new cut and a new shuffle.
I'm sorry, that isn't permitted.
COOP:
But you can have a new dealer.
In that case,
I'd like you to deal.
Just one from the top.
I like that.
Shows trust.
The Commodore has 4 of a kind,
Angel has a small straight flush...
...and I don't know
what Maverick has.
DEALER:
It's up to you, Commodore.
COMM: It looks like I'm sucking
hind tit, so I'll bet everything.
DEALER:
The Commodore wagers $25,000.
[Crowd gasps]
ANGEL: I'll see your 25.
ANGEL:
I guess we're even.
I'll raise you everything I've got.
[Crowd murmurs]
That's half a million to the winner.
BRET:
That should cover the Commodore.
Aren't you going to look at your card?
No need.
ANGEL: What are you playing at?
Look at it.
I'd look at my card
if I were you. [Laughs]
DEALER:
This is your portion of the pot.
What kind of poker you playing?
Look at that card!
DEALER: Cards have been called,
Commodore. Show your cards.
I have 2 small pair.
COMM: Eights...
...and eights.
[Crowd gasps and applauds]
Thank you.
Not going to look?
Well...
...how you going to know
if you can beat my straight flush?
[Crowd gasps]
[Crowd applauds]
GAMBLER 4: [Laughing]
Unbeatable!
DEALER:
Ten of spades.
Jack of spades.
DEALER: Queen of spades
and King of spades.
DEALER:
Possible royal flush.
[Crowd cheers]
DEALER:
Quiet! Quiet!
[Crowd sighs]
[Crowd cheers]
ANNA: You won!
You cheating son of a bitch!
[Screaming from crowd]
[Crowd gasps and murmurs]
BRET: [Whimpering] Ha!
ANNA: You all right?
BRET: I can't believe
I pulled that card. I...
Did I ever tell you
about the snakes...
ANNA: You're babbling.
Shh!
You're babbling.
COMM:
Your security isn't worth a damn!
Everybody's got a gun!
COMM:
Ladies and gents...
...for our presentation of one-half
million dollars to our winner...
...Mr. Maverick!
[Crowd cheers]
COOP: I want to congratulate you
on a game well played.
I wish your moment
could last longer...
...but I see all this money.
Hell, I just...
...got to take it.
What?
I'll have regrets, I'm sure,
but I'm going to take it nevertheless.
Move down the steps.
[Laughter]
This is no time to be brave,
Bertie boy.
COOP:
Down the stairs, now.
You too, Commodore.
Move it!
BELLHOP: I'll take your bag.
COOP: Get your hands off.
Get away from here!
Down the stairs. Move!
BRET:
You son of a bitch!
I worked my ass off for that.
I'll be coming for it.
I'll look for you.
BRET: Look real hard!
That's my money.
Was your money.
[Crowd screams]
COMM:
Do as he said!
[Crowd screams]
COOP: I don't want to see any faces
looking this way.
COMM: Captain!
CAPTAIN: Yes, sir?
COMM: Get my gun.
CAPTAIN:
He's headed for the lifeboat.
COMM:
Stop him!
COMM: Move!
I'll kill that son of a bitch!
COOP:
Go, go, go!
[Crowd murmurs]
Ah, ha!
COMM:
There he is.
BRET:
Let him go!
COMM: Let him go?!
BRET: The man saved my life!
BRET:
I can always win more money.
Anyway, I found out
what I came here for.
COMM: Do I have to remind you
that's $500,000 that bastard's taking?
BRET: And it grieves me,
but it's my half million.
It's only money, right?
CROWD: Right!
COMM: Only money?!
BRET: It's not worth killing a man.
CROWD: No!
I won't swear out
a warrant against him.
COMM:
Well, I'll be damned!
[Laughing]
I will be damned!
COMM:
Let's toast our champion.
COMM: Our champion!
[Crowd cheers]
[Steamboat whistles]
COMM: Fiddle that Coop!
COMM: Goodbye!
ANNA: [Sighs] Well...
BRET: Oh, here.
BRET: I meant to give you this.
I took it from you on the stage.
You should have it.
ANNA:
I meant to give you this cufflink...
...I took before you left
with the Indians.
BRET: I been looking for it.
Yeah, I have. It's all right.
ANNA: [Whispering]
Well...
...bye.
[Exhales]
You going to miss me?
You are going to miss me.
ANNA: How do you know?
BRET: You were holding your breath.
ANNA: I was not.
Maybe I was.
ANNA: Well, I...
ANNA: I guess
I better go make my stage.
ANNA:
See you in Abilene.
New Orleans, wasn't it?
ANNA: Either.
[Holds breath]
[Snap]
[Horse whinnies]
Where have you been?
I had to say goodbye
to a lot of people.
I didn't want them thinking
I was off to meet someone.
COMM: And I did a lot of twists
and backtracked a lot...
...to keep anyone from following me.
I thought
we were in this together.
You win, I do nothing.
Someone else wins, I do what I did.
You didn't tell me
Angel was in it too.
Oh.
COMM: If Angel had won,
we'd split it the same way.
COMM:
The reason I brought him in...
I telegraphed him
to keep Maverick out of the game.
He messed up on that.
Poor, dead bastard.
I don't like secrets.
COMM: You probably won't like
this one either.
I don't know,
I guess it's my greedy nature.
But I've decided...
[Click]
...not to share it with you.
Uncock it.
BRET: Sit down, gentlemen.
BRET: Let's get real cozy.
Parlay some.
[Laughing] Put your hands down.
You look ridiculous!
I admit, you had me fooled.
Not many can.
BRET: But you did save my life.
It wouldn't be neighborly to kill you.
Besides...
...everybody knows
what you are now, anyway.
All your life's work...
...it's all been wiped away.
Was it worth it?
You got nothing to show for it.
COOP: What you said is true.
I traded every decent thing I know
for that money.
You can't leave me alive.
I don't care where you go...
...one night you'll relax.
Guess who'll be waiting.
[Chuckles]
BRET: [Laughing] You couldn't
sneak up on a corpse, Coop.
Not anymore.
You're a decrepit old has-been.
Well, what're you going to do?
Maybe the fairest thing would be...
...let one of you kill the other.
I'll let you decide which.
[Commodore and Coop gasp]
COOP: Oh!
[Grunts]
COMM: Give me that!
[Commodore laughs]
COMM: That...
[Click]
...as they say,
is that!
[Gasps]
[Clunk]
COMM: Oh, shit!
[Laughs]
[Commodore grunts and groans]
[Commodore gasps]
COOP: You dirty rotten,
double-crossed...
I've never committed
a cold-blooded murder in my life.
[Pants]
But I won't.
Not till I find Maverick.
[Sighs]
[Click]
Decrepit old has-been?
Couldn't sneak up on a corpse?
COOP: You got $500,000 in that satchel
and your gun is 8 feet away.
Not smart.
Not smart at all.
Guess not.
It's plain to see
who won the toss-up.
You shoot the Commodore
in the back?
No.
Good idea, but no.
I really enjoyed
nailing that bastard.
No room in poker for cheats.
COOP: He can't touch a deck of cards,
this side of the Mississippi.
BRET:
My old pappy used to say...
..."There is no more deeply moving
religious experience...
...than cheating a cheater."
COOP: I never said that once.
You've misquoted me all your life.
BRET: Are we quibbling fine points?
COOP: I'm sick of it!
[Bret gurgles and gasps]
BRET: The things you said were so dumb
I had to improve on them.
COOP: Dumb, huh?
BRET:
Will you cut that out, Pappy!
These are a buck apiece.
You taught me to save money.
COOP: Really?
Let me have one.
BRET: Yeah, those are the good ones.
COOP: They are?
COOP:
You got a match?
MRS. D: Bret, Coop, everything good?
Enough cigars, brandy, hot water?
MRS. D: Yell if you need anything.
COOP: Yes, Mrs. D.
[Sighs]
[Click]
ANNA: I certainly hope
this shirt fits you.
It's from the best
shirtmaker in San Francisco.
COOP:
Isn't she sweet?
BRET: Hell of a shirt,
but she's robbing us.
Look! Here's a lot of money
and your gun is 6 feet away.
BRET & COOP:
Eight!
What a remarkable family.
BRET: How'd she...?
How'd you figure that?
ANNA: You don't have
the exclusive on tells.
You both have the same
height and build. You both...
...kiss the same way,
you both...
...draw your guns alike and sing
the wrong words to "Amazing Grace."
BRET & COOP:
We do not!
ANNA: Hm.
Hm.
My! Such...
...splendid similarities.
From the looks of things, the lady
better bring more hot water.
Bye!
COOP: Bret, son, you know
what we ended up with?
A $500,000 silk shirt.
BRET: Nope. We ended up with a
$ 125,000 silk shirt...
...because my old pappy used to say,
"Never put the cart..."
No. "Don't count..." No.
"Don't put your eggs in one basket."
COOP:
Now that, I said.
BRET: So I have a boot for you.
COOP: A boot?
BRET: And the other one's
twice as heavy.
[Coop chuckles]
COOP:
Ah, Bret, that's my boy!
BRET: What are kids for?
Give back the boot.
Be my guest.
BRET: Thank you.
I don't know why I left
the other half in the satchel.
COOP: I do.
BRET: [Laughing] So do I.
BRET: Lt'll be lots of fun
getting it back.
COOP: Bret.
BRET: Yes, sir?
COOP:
Something I got to know, son.
How did you come up
with that ace of spades?
You won't believe me.
I'm your father,
I'll believe you.
Magic.
Magic?
I believe you.
Thanks.
Subtitled by
GELULA & CO., INC.