[GRUNTING]
[GROANS]
No, please.
[SCREAMlNG]
Your brother's soul is mine.
Liu!
You will be next.
[GASPlNG]
Chan.
[THUNDER RUMBLlNG]
Let's go. Sixty seconds to target.
-Jaxx, is the perimeter secured?
-Locked tight.
-lt better be. l want Kano.
-Trust me, Sonya.
I trust one person on this planet, Jaxx.
You're talking to her.
[BAND PLAYlNG HEAVY METAL MUSlC]
[MEN GRUNTING]
[CHUCKLES]
Good boy.
She's here.
Right on time.
I love punctuality in a woman.
Don't you, Mr. Shang Tsung?
Now, you're sure she's gonna follow me?
You killed her partner, didn't you?
She'll follow you into hell.
Just make sure she's on that boat.
Sonya Blade must be at the tournament.
[LAUGHlNG]
[GRUNTS]
Maybe me and Sonya
should share a cabin...
...have our own little honeymoon cruise.
If you so much as touch her, Kano...
[SWITCHBLADE CLlCKS]
...you're going to need a Seeing Eye dog.
[MEN GRUNTING]
[GROANS]
Where's Kano?
Where is he?
Let's dance.
[ALL GRUNTING]
This is where you fall down.
[GRUNTS]
Where do you get these guys?
And the press says
I don't know how to do this stuff?
Cut.
-All right, reset. We're back in 1 5.
-l'm not doing it again.
-What do you mean?
-l'm not.
Johnny, it's the last shot.
Where are you going?
To my trailer. I'm gonna get a gun
and l'm gonna shoot myself...
...for being in your movie.
It'll kill me. l'll be back directing traffic.
Don't leave me hanging up here.
You're killing me, Johnny.
-l love you, I need you.
MAN: Johnny.
Excuse me, Johnny, there's, uh, someone
over there who wants to speak to you.
-Who is it?
-l don't really know.
You let somebody on the set
you don't know?
No, of course not, I--
-lt had better not be a reporter.
-Oh, God, no, l--
You want me to find out?
Oh, great.
Hey, mister, you're in my chair.
Hi, Johnny.
Master Boyd, I--
I see the, uh,
press is still giving you a hard time.
Yeah, they think l'm a fake.
Johnny, you're one of the best
martial artists in the world.
And l can help you prove it.
Prove it? How?
A tournament.
The tournament.
It's held once a generation.
The best fighters in the world are invited.
You win the tournament,
you win their respect.
They'll tell the entire world
that you're the real goods.
-So how do l, uh...?
-There's a boat.
It leaves Pier 40, Hong Kong, tomorrow.
Be on it.
Liu.
LlU: ls this the place?
-Yes.
-This is where we found his body.
-What happened?
After you left for America,
he followed in your footsteps...
...preparing for the tournament.
Grandfather, it wasn't enough
that you filled my head with that nonsense?
To save the world is not nonsense.
Men fighting in a simple contest
don't decide these things, Grandfather.
-How can you, a wise man, believe this?
-We all believe in it.
Including your brother.
[BELL RINGlNG]
[MONKS SHOUTlNG INDISTINCTLY]
GRANDFATHER: Liu Kang has been
given the dream. He is the chosen one.
No. He left our temple,
turned his back on us.
Why have you come back?
I want to represent
the Order of Light at the tournament.
For what reason?
LlU: The man who killed my brother
will be there.
MONK:
That cannot be your only reason for going.
-Or you will fail.
-Oh, yes, l forgot.
We're fighting for the fate of the world.
MAN: That's why you left the temple
and ran away, isn't it?
The great tournament
was too much responsibility.
But vengeance...
...that's so much simpler.
Lord Rayden.
You're still running away
from your destiny.
Rayden?
Grandfather, get up.
This isn't your god of thunder and lightning.
He's just a beggar.
Spare him, my Lord Rayden.
American life has enfeebled his mind.
Too much television.
So you're going to win the tournament?
-Yes, I am.
-Show me how.
Oh, don't tell me you're afraid
of a simple beggar?
[LIU GRUNTS]
If you are Rayden...
...why did you let Chan die?
-Why didn't you protect him?
-Why didn't you?
I've had enough of this.
I'm going to find my brother's killer
at the tournament.
With or without your consent.
[ALL MUTTERlNG]
He isn't ready, my lord.
-And we've lost so much time.
-l know.
But there is no one else.
[MAN SPEAKlNG INDlSTlNCTLY
OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
-Oh, give me a break.
-Hey.
-Look, don't let them get to you.
JOHNNY: Yeah, sure.
Hey, you're Art Lean, aren't you?
Man, l saw you fight in London,
you were great.
Thanks. I saw a couple of your films.
-Listen, you can't fake those moves.
-Yeah, well, tell that to the press.
Hey, pal, when the ship comes in,
could you put these on board?
You want me to carry your luggage?
Yeah. l pay money, you carry the bags.
-Or is that too complicated?
-No.
-l got it.
-Good.
Huh. Thank God l didn't ask him
to park the car.
Nothing says that creep at the club
wasn't lying his ass off.
Kano could be a thousand miles
from here by now.
What is that?
You gotta be kidding me.
-That's him.
-Hold on.
KANO:
That's it, baby.
Come to papa.
Sonya, don't get on that thing.
Hey, Sonya.
Hey, you.
All right, tough guy,
you wanna get...rough?
No, do you?
Hi. l'm Johnny Cage, and you are?
Where's Kano?
I don't know who you're talking about.
-But l'm sure I can help you find him.
-Out of my way.
Just another starstruck fan, huh?
It's an honor to finally meet you, Sonya.
Shang Tsung, at your service.
I'm looking for a murderer.
He boarded this ship.
I'm impressed.
But it is my boat, and if you'd like a tour,
I'd love to give it to you myself.
Hey, be nice to the lady.
She's just doing her job.
When I want backup, l'll radio for it.
Got that radio handy?
Scorpion and Sub-Zero,
deadliest of enemies.
But slaves under my power.
Move aside.
[SQUEALING]
-Enough.
TSUNG: Lord Rayden.
How good of you to grace us
with your presence.
Your sideshow freaks
attacked my fighters.
That is expressly forbidden
before the tournament.
-As your emperor well knows.
-My sincere apologies.
It won't happen again, I promise you.
-Hmm. I shall see to that.
TSUNG: Of course.
Until we reach the island,
where you have no dominion.
My dominions are well known to me,
sorcerer.
-Thank you.
-What tournament?
You've been chosen, Sonya.
Much to my delight.
You really are Rayden.
Come with me.
JOHNNY: We got a guy
with things coming out of his hand...
...another guy who freezes stuff.
And then a man who, as far as l can tell,
is made out of electricity.
I mean, how did he disappear like that?
What is going on? Who is this guy?
Let's just think this through.
There is a rational explanation for this.
He's Rayden.
God of lightning
and protector of the realm of Earth.
-Oh, great.
-There's your rational explanation.
RAYDEN:
Listen.
What you're about to face
is vastly more important than...
...your ego...
...your enemy...
...or your quest for revenge.
You have embarked on a sacred mission.
You have been chosen
to defend the realm of Earth...
...in a tournament called Mortal Kombat.
Defend it from who?
Your world is but one of many realms.
One of them is a forsaken land
called Outworld...
...ruled by an immortal
who has crowned himself emperor.
Now he seeks a new world
to conquer and enslave.
Now, wait a second.
If this guy is so powerful,
then why doesn't he just invade us?
To enter the realm of Earth...
...the emperor's demon sorcerer,
Shang Tsung, and his warriors...
...have to win 1 0 straight victories
in Mortal Kombat.
Heh.
They have won nine.
This will be the 1 0th tournament.
A handful of people on a leaky boat
are gonna save the world?
Exactly.
The essence of Mortal Kombat...
...is not about death, but life.
Mortal men and women
defending your own world.
Why are you telling us all this?
-What about the others?
-They are all great fighters.
But l have looked into their souls.
And yours.
One of you three will decide
the outcome of the tournament.
The fate of billions will depend upon you.
[LAUGHlNG]
Sorry.
What about Shang Tsung?
Oh, still concerned only with vengeance?
If you challenge Shang Tsung now,
you will lose your life and your soul.
He is gonna pay for my brother's death.
You're not ready.
Look. lt has begun.
It has begun.
SONYA:
Black Hawk to Cardinal.
Black Hawk calling Cardinal.
Is anybody monitoring?
[RADIO STATIC]
Jaxx, this is Sonya. Do you copy?
While you're at it,
why don't you call my agent?
Do I look like your secretary?
[YELLS]
What are you doing?
That electrical disturbance
must have blown out the transistors.
Your radio equipment's fine.
Look at your compass.
Where the hell are we?
-Do l look like your travel agent?
-Fine.
Okay. l give up.
-What's going on?
-l don't know.
But what if all the legends were true?
What legends?
LlU:
Do you need help with those?
[JOHNNY PANTlNG]
Ah, ha, ha. Ah, no more steps.
Oh, great. Can't wait to see
what the bathrooms look like.
You know,
when a woman looks at you like that...
...it usually means something.
TSUNG:
Princess Kitana.
She's a most dangerous adversary.
Watch her carefully, Reptile.
Keep her away from these humans.
[SQUEALING]
[MEN SHOUT]
TSUNG:
Welcome.
You're here to compete
in Mortal Kombat.
Tomorrow morning
the great combat begins.
Some of you will even have
the distinct honor and pleasure...
...to face Prince Goro,
our reigning champion.
You are all witnesses to one of the greatest
turning points in the history of your planet.
Treasure these moments...
...as if they were your last.
And now, for a taste of things to come.
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[YELLS]
[JOINTS CRACKlNG]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTlNG]
Flawless victory.
"Come to a little tournament," he said.
"Be good for the career," he said.
Yeah, right. Liu.
-Hey, where are you going?
-After Shang Tsung.
You can't go after him.
Don't you remember what Rayden said?
Yeah, well, he didn't say anything to me.
Shang Tsung knows where Kano's hiding.
You know, you gotta admire her.
When she sets her mind on something....
It's not her mind you're admiring.
It's true.
[GRUMBLlNG]
How many times do l have to tell you?
I don't need your help.
I can take care of myself.
We can't help it, it's a guy thing.
-Hey, where are you going?
-l'm following him.
-l work alone.
-No, Shang Tsung is mine.
JOHNNY:
Why don't we forget about Shang Tsung?
What do you mean, "forget about him"?
Did you see what happened back there?
-l wanna get to the bottom of this.
JOHNNY: Are you out of your mind?
[ROARING]
Sonya.
You go ahead, find out what that was.
-Liu and I will wait right here.
-What?
Mm!
See, me, l believe in a fair fight.
You know, one-on-one,
man-to-man, hand-to-hand.
Just like my daddy taught me.
But what I saw out there
was not very fair.
That's Kano.
Forget about Kano.
Who's the other guy?
So then he freezes this guy, right?
And then he explodes.
I could see his guts and everything. Heh.
Almost lost my lunch.
Disgusting.
What l wanna know,
if this Shang Tsung guy is so great...
...how come he's got
such a crummy-looking boat? Hmm?
Eh. Anyway, guy gives me the creeps.
Heh.
"Treasure these moments."
That was his intention.
Shang Tsung is a great sorcerer.
The wise cultivate his favor.
Those who challenge his power
become his slaves.
Yeah?
Well, l haven't seen any of them around.
You fool. You know nothing.
He enslaves souls.
He learned the black arts
from the emperor himself.
-You're some kind of royalty too, right?
GORO: I am Goro.
General of the armies of Outworld and
prince of the subterranean realm of Shokan.
Subterranean?
What's that?
Something like underground?
Yes, something like that.
Yeah? Well, l'm kind of an
underworld boss myself, you know.
-Hmm.
-Well, l mean, back home.
How lucky for them back home.
-lt's true, Prince Goro.
-Hmm?
Why else would I have chosen
such a disreputable-looking cretin?
Look at him. No dignity, no manners.
Yet in the realm of Earth,
men like him can amass great wealth...
...and almost godlike power.
Yeah.
Well, l'd like to get back to my amassing
as soon as possible, if you don't mind.
-Now, when do I get paid?
-After you've fought the girl.
But remember,
she's not to be harmed, only humiliated.
I have plans for my beautiful Sonya.
To what do we owe the honor of your visit,
Shang Tsung?
I've come to warn you that Kung Lao's
descendent is competing in the tournament.
You must handle him carefully.
I saw this Liu Kang in the hall.
He'll pose no problem.
This is no time for foolish pride.
We've never been so close
to absolute victory...
...which is why l've come to warn you
of another danger.
-Princess Kitana.
-The emperor's adopted daughter?
Why should I worry about her?
Princess Kitana is 1 0,000 years old...
...and the rightful heir
to the throne of Outworld.
But she must not be allowed to join
with the forces from the realm of Earth.
Especially Liu Kang.
-What's so special about you?
-l don't know.
The emperor will not tolerate failure.
And neither will I.
I do not fail.
Let's get out of here.
[PEBBLES FALLING]
-What? What is it?
-Huh?
We are not alone.
Wait a second, l don't remember this.
Look.
That has to be Princess Kitana.
-l think she's trying to help us.
-You're hard up for a date.
-She's trying to lead us out.
-Forget about her, she's 1 0,000 years old.
-So what?
-Liu.
Liu? Liu.
[SCRAPING]
[SCREAMS]
[SQUEALING]
-Liu, what happened?
-There's something here.
-l think it's following Princess Kitana.
-Where is she?
I don't know.
LlU: Do you know where we're going?
-l know exactly where we're going.
Kitana went this way.
I can smell her perfume.
I don't smell anything.
I smell something.
Bullshit.
[MEN GRUNT]
-We got company.
-l know.
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[ALL GRUNTING]
Just the way I like them. Dumb and ugly.
-Piece of cake.
-Piece of cake, huh?
-Well, it was easy for me.
-Oh, get over yourself.
What is it with you guys?
We're standing, they're not.
What more do you want?
[SLOW CLAPPING]
Brilliant. Absolutely brilliant.
So why don't you show me
what you plan to do about them?
[ALL SHOUT]
Ah, ah.
I don't think so. Ha-ha-ha.
I think you'll find
that this is the way out.
You guys are lucky he stopped us.
So now you've seen what you'll be facing
in the tournament.
-You mean Goro?
-And Shang Tsung.
-Will Shang Tsung fight in the tournament?
-lf he chooses to.
As a former champion,
he has the right to do so.
And he's far more dangerous than Goro.
His power comes from the souls
of vanquished warriors.
To fight Shang Tsung is to face not one,
but a legion of adversaries.
Remember that.
Tomorrow the tournament begins.
Be prepared.
From this moment on,
my island will be your battleground.
Liu Kang, you will be first.
Let Mortal Kombat begin.
[GRUNTS]
MAN 1 : Come on.
MAN 2: Yeah.
[BOTH SHOUTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
Your soul is mine.
FIGHTER:
No!
[SCREAMS]
Fatality.
Hyah.
Sonya Blade.
I have something for you, my dear.
I don't want anything from you.
On the contrary.
I have something you want very much.
You can thank me later.
[LAUGHlNG]
Hello, baby. Did you miss me?
Ooh.
Now, look at this.
This little baby brings back memories,
now, doesn't it?
What? You used it
to knife your mother in the back?
No, it put a big smile
on your partner though.
Ear...
[WHlSTLES]
...to ear.
[CHUCKLES]
[YELLS]
Give it up, baby.
-l've studied all your moves.
-Yeah? Study this.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[GROANING]
Does it hurt, baby?
Yes.
Right. Finish him.
No, Sonya. Don't.
-Oh, give me a break.
-Okay.
[BONES CRUNCH]
[CROWD BOOING]
Get over here.
[SQUEALING]
Come here.
Welcome.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
Get down here.
[YELLING]
[SCREAMlNG]
[BOTH YELLING]
TSUNG:
Begin.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
If you won't fight with all of your heart,
there is no hope.
LlU:
Why do you care if l win or lose?
To win your next match,
use the element which brings life.
-What?
-Kitana.
Remember my words.
TSUNG:
Kitana, that's enough.
You disappoint me.
Not very wise.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[YELLS]
KlTANA:
Use the element which brings life.
Water.
Is it time?
Yes.
We've let these humans win enough.
At last.
[GORO ROARING
AND CROWD CHEERING]
[ROARING]
[GRUNTlNG]
What the--?
[CRACKlNG]
[ROARS]
[GORO LAUGHS]
-Yeah, that's it, in and out.
LlU: Come on.
[ROARS]
Yeah! Goro!
-Come on, Art. You can do it. Come on.
-Make your move, Art. Use your feet.
SONYA: That's right, use the kick.
-Ugh!
[GRUNTlNG]
JOHNNY:
Come on, Art.
Get up.
[ROARING]
Yeah!
Kill him, smash him!
Get out. Get out.
[ROARS]
Yeah! Goro!
Finish him.
Time to die.
[ROARING]
No!
Flawless victory.
Your soul is mine.
No!
SONYA:
We can't win now.
How could we possibly beat
something like that?
Good question.
Goro can be killed.
Shang Tsung's power can be destroyed
by mortal men and women.
You can overcome any adversary...
...no matter how bizarre
their powers may seem.
There is always a way.
Only one thing can defeat you...
...your own fear.
So who says we're afraid?
You must first face your fears
if you are to conquer them.
You, Johnny, are afraid you're a fake...
...so you'll rush into any fight
just to prove you're not.
You'll fight bravely enough...
...but foolishly, carelessly...
...and you'll be beaten.
You, Sonya...
...are afraid to admit
even you sometimes need help.
If you are afraid to trust...
...you will lose.
Wait.
-What about me?
-Oh, you.
You fear your own destiny.
You already fled it once
when you went to America.
It has brought you guilt
for the death of your brother.
I am responsible for Chan's death.
No. Every mortal is responsible
for his own destiny.
Chan believed this. Why can't you?
-l tried.
-Despair is the most dangerous fear of all.
I know this, and so does Shang Tsung.
He can peer into your soul
and use the fear he sees there against you.
You must be prepared.
Liu!
You will be next.
SONYA:
Goro's never been beaten.
You go up against him, he'll kill you.
Well, if I don't,
then he'll finish us off one at a time.
If l challenge him now, I can finish this.
You're making this all sound really simple,
and it isn't.
Yeah, it is.
Because I can't let
what happened to Art happen to you.
Not to you.
Oh, don't you dare do this
to protect me, Johnny Cage.
Trust me. l got a plan.
Oh, l can't believe this.
You are the most egotistical,
self-deluded person I have ever met.
Yeah? Well, you forgot good-looking.
Challenging Goro, eh?
You weren't supposed to fight him now.
Are you that eager to die?
I'm not the one who's gonna die.
I see.
You're very foolish.
The true sign of a hero.
You want to protect your friends,
but make no mistake.
They too will die after Goro destroys you.
So, what's the problem?
As you wish.
As absurd as your request is,
I shall grant it.
In return, l reserve the right
to challenge the winner myself...
...or another of my choosing...
...in a place designated by me
for the final battle of the tournament.
-You got it, pal.
-l don't think so.
Too late, Lord Rayden.
The rules are quite clear.
It's-- How do you say?
A deal's a deal.
-What have you done?
-l made a choice.
This is our tournament, remember?
Mortal Kombat. We fight it.
Good.
At last one of them has understood.
[CHANTING]
Goro, Goro, Goro.
[ROARING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
-Get him!
-Goro!
[CHANTING]
Goro, Goro, Goro.
[LAUGHlNG]
Finish him quickly.
Pay me my tribute.
This puny mortal will be no problem.
I'll crush him in one blow.
All right.
Let's dance.
[ROARING]
[GROANING]
Yes. Ha-ha-ha! Sorry.
You imbecile.
Damn, that hurt.
Follow him. Finish him.
CROWD [CHANTlNG]:
Finish him, finish him, finish him.
Yeah! Goro!
[GORO ROARING]
Those were $500 sunglasses, asshole.
[YELLING]
This is where you fall down.
[SCREAMlNG]
SONYA:
No!
Let me go! Aah!
Stop!
I hereby exercise my right to challenge.
I challenge her.
You're a coward, sorcerer.
-Stand and fight.
-We had a deal, remember?
Mortal Kombat continues.
I'm simply changing the place...
...as we agreed.
SONYA:
No!
-Sonya!
-No!
-Where's he taken her?
-To the emperor's castle...
...in the wastelands of Outworld,
where l cannot follow.
We can.
Rayden, can Sonya beat Shang Tsung?
No. I'm sorry.
-You're sorry?
-There is one last rule.
He neglected to mention it.
She has to accept the challenge
or there can be no final combat.
I have nothing further
to teach you, Liu Kang.
You possess the knowledge.
All that is lacking now is the will.
JOHNNY:
You sure you don't wanna go with us?
RAYDEN: In Outworld, if you look
hard enough, you will find another guide.
Good luck.
They'll need it.
This is not good.
But l'm fine.
I can deal with this.
So this is Outworld, huh?
Well, l can see why they want
a change of scenery.
LlU:
We should head for that tower.
Shang Tsung
would have taken Sonya there.
Liu, I hate this place.
I do. l'm telling you, l hate it.
I'm in a hostile environment,
I am completely unprepared.
I'm surrounded by people
who probably wanna kick my ass.
It's like being back in high school.
What's that?
Wait.
What?
There's something else.
Oh, great.
What are you doing?
[SQUEALING]
[BOTH YELLING AND GRUNTING]
LlU:
Oh, no, you don't.
[YELLS]
KlTANA:
Well done.
You're finally learning, Liu Kang.
Kitana.
Come with me.
LlU:
What happened here?
KlTANA: The same thing that will happen
to your world...
...unless you prevent it.
My father was the rightful ruler
of Outworld.
Then his best warriors
lost 1 0 Mortal Kombats...
...and the emperor entered the realm,
killed my parents and adopted me...
...to lay claim to the throne.
It was beautiful once...
...before Shang Tsung
engineered its destruction.
How can l possibly stop this
from happening in my world?
If l did not believe in you, Liu Kang,
I would not have helped you.
In the Black Tower,
you will face three challenges:
You must face your enemy,
you must face yourself...
...and you must face your worst fear.
[DOOR OPENlNG]
I will not fight you, Shang Tsung.
I am not playing your game.
Sonya. My sweet Sonya.
There is no one else.
If you don't fight...
...the realm of Earth
will forfeit the tournament...
...and its portals will open
to our great emperor.
You're lying.
My friends will come for me.
Hoping against hope.
Such an endearing human trait.
I'm touched, really.
One last chance, Sonya.
Fight me in Mortal Kombat.
Go to hell.
Take her away.
The emperor will be overjoyed.
My friends will come.
They're already here.
-Seize them.
-Stay where you are.
Will you dare interfere
with the tournament...
...and betray our emperor?
In his great wisdom,
he knows that Mortal Kombat...
...cannot be won by treachery.
How dare you speak to me of treachery?
Your ignorance will lose for all time
the keys to the realm of Earth.
Very well.
Johnny Cage, l challenge you.
No, you'll fight me.
I am Liu Kang...
...descendant of Kung Lao.
I challenge you to Mortal Kombat.
Do you accept or yield?
I accept.
Leave us.
I will take care of this
impudent mortal myself.
-Nice dress.
-Ugh.
[BOTH YELLING AND GRUNTING]
You fool.
[DRONlNG]
What's that sound?
The source of all Shang Tsung's power.
The souls of a thousand dead warriors.
Face your enemy.
[ALL YELLlNG AND GRUNTlNG]
Is that all you've got, sorcerer?
Liu Kang.
I can see into your soul.
You will die.
Face yourself.
You can look into my soul,
but you don't own it.
Face your worst fear.
I'm not afraid of my destiny.
Face me.
Liu.
Chan?
It can't be you.
Rayden sent me.
To help you.
You're not really Chan.
Remember when our parents died...
...and you promised
that you would always take care of me?
I remember.
Now it's my turn
to take care of you, brother.
Liu, come with me.
I forgive you for letting me die.
No.
It wasn't my fault.
-Brother.
-No.
Chan chose his own path.
Every man is responsible
for his own destiny.
Shang Tsung killed my brother.
You're mine.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
The chosen one.
I am the chosen one.
[GHOSTLY VOICES MUTTERING]
-You hear your slaves, sorcerer?
VOICE 1: Finish him.
VOICE 2:
Finish him!
You have lost your power over them.
They have risen up against you.
Free them.
They are mine forever.
[BOTH GRUNT]
All those souls,
and you still don't have one of your own.
I pity you, sorcerer.
Save your pity for the weak.
Surrender. lt's over.
[GROANING]
[YELLING]
Never!
Flawless victory.
I knew you'd come.
Chan.
One day, we will be reunited.
But until then,
my spirit will always be with you.
Go in peace, my brother.
Let's go home.
[CHEERlNG]
RAYDEN:
I've been waiting for you.
What took you so long?
I guess you knew it would end this way.
Didn't have a clue.
You humans are so unpredictable.
[LAUGHlNG]
I've got to tell you something,
you guys did great.
EVlL VOICE:
Bow to me.
What is it?
The emperor.
You weak, pathetic fools.
I've come for your souls.
I don't think so.
[English - US - SDH]