[#Alexi Murdoch: "All My Days"]
[crowd screaming]
[phone ringing]
[grunting]
[groans]
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
- [ringing continues]
- Come on.
- Yeah?
- [man] Where are you, Charlie?
More importantly, where is my money?
- You're into me for 30 grand.
- All right, all right.
Jack, Jack, Jack,
I'm going to pay you.
This ain't Jack! It's Bill Panner.
You owe Jack money, too?
Charlie, you pay me first!
Bill, hey, no, we're good, buddy.
I got your money.
It's right here in my hand.
So why don't we meet up on the...
[stammering]
- Charlie, your phone's going screwy.
- Bill?
- Hello?
- I'm losing you, Bill.
Wait, Charlie,
I can't hear what you're saying.
[girl] Hey, mister.
Is that Ambush?
- Uh, yeah.
- Can we see him?
- You want to see him?
- Yeah.
All right, give me...
Give me a minute.
This...
...is Ambush. Wakey, wakey.
- [beeping]
- [whirrs]
[gasps]
- What robot is he fighting?
- Actually, he's going to fight...
Whoa, little lady.
What are you doing?
- Can we get a picture with him?
- Sure. For five dollars.
You want five dollars? Seriously?
No, I want five dollars immediately.
Come on, guys.
Hey, hey.
All right, all right, I'm kidding.
- Three bucks.
- Whatever.
- How about $2.50?
- [girl] You suck!
All right.
It's going to be one
of those towns, huh?
[announcer] Welcome,
ladies and gentlemen,
to the 2020 San Leandro County Fair.
- Yah!
- Please take your seats.
We're almost ready
to get this thing started.
[grunts]
I was told my bot
was fighting an 800-pound steer.
Hey, hey!
That is not 800 pounds, knucklehead.
[man] Charlie "the Can Do Kid" Kenton.
Time has not
been good to you, my friend.
Ricky, we got a problem here.
A big problem.
Whoa, hey, slow down there, hoss.
Come on, last time I saw you,
you were staring up at the ceiling
at the Sam Houston Center
with the taste of my right cross
all over your face.
Pow!
- Are we good to go here?
- Yeah.
We agreed that my boxer would fight
an 800-pound steer for three grand.
- Am I right?
- Yes, sir. We did.
- That bull is, like, 2,000 pounds.
- Right, OK.
Well, Charlie, I'll tell you something.
Your bot don't fight,
you don't get paid! Whoo!
- How about that?
- [man chuckles]
- Get the hell out of here.
- [bull groans]
All right, all right.
Why don't we
make this more interesting?
My bot against your bull, straight up.
- How much?
- Twenty grand, winner takes all.
- You got 20 grand, Charlie?
- In a safe in my truck.
All right, Charlie.
I'll tell you what,
twenty grand it is,
but if you lose and you welch,
I'm gonna come after you and beat you
to within an inch of your life.
And you know that I can do that
because I already done it!
What's the problem with you, man?
In life you get too close,
in the ring you
stand back like a girl. Just shake.
All right, Charlie.
Shake and pow!
Just like that once again.
You want to dance again?
You wanna dance?
Come on, cheer for this guy.
Give him some luck.
He needs some luck, y'all.
Yahoo! Let's get going!
- [bull groans]
- Don't touch that bull.
Ladies and gentlemen, I got to ask,
do we have any fans
of robot boxing here today?
- [cheering]
- [Ricky chuckles]
Now, listen, friends, I understand,
we can't all afford to go all
the way over there to Dallas
and pay $300 for one of those World
Robot Boxing League fights. I get it.
So, I decided that I would
bring a robot boxing match
right here to our little fair
here in San Leandro.
How about that?
All right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I introduce to you,
- Ambush!
- Let's do it!
[metal music playing]
All right, big fella.
[Ricky] Whoo-hoo!
He's a big fella, ain't he?
Take a turn.
Let them see how beautiful you are.
Yeah.
[chuckles] Show them some power.
[Ricky] Look at that.
He's getting all kung fu-y on us.
- Yeah!
- [Ricky] Yeah, big fella.
Ambush's opponent today,
he's last year's runner-up
in the baddest
of the bulls competition,
ladies and gentlemen, Black Thunder!
[crowd roars]
- Let's get it on!
- Let's get this thing started.
- [grunts]
- [whirring]
Is that all you got?
Yeah, brother. Bring it on.
Take him, take him.
Ambush lays the smackdown
on that prime beef.
Woo woo!
I got more for you, big fella.
We're just getting started.
OK. Jump, now!
Boo-yah!
- Dang it!
- [Ricky] Ambush, decks
Black Thunder
but when you mess with the bull,
you're going to get the horns.
You like that. I can tell.
- You like that.
- [bull grunting]
Jeez! Turn around!
[mechanical chirping]
Ricky! Ricky, stop this thing!
[crowd gasps]
[cheering]
Come on, come on.
We're still in this thing.
We're still in this. Just hop. Hop.
That's it. Come on.
Ricky, enough! Enough!
I can't hear you over the sound
of your robot being destroyed.
[laughing]
[chanting] Kill! Kill! Kill!
All right, come on. Get up.
Get up. Come on!
[groans] No!
C'mon. No, no, no!
[Ricky] Ladies and gentlemen,
let's hear it
for our warriors out here today
at the 2020 San Leandro County Fair.
Now, thank you all for coming out,
and we'll see you next time,
because there will be one.
Hey, hey! Give me that leg.
Sure. For five dollars.
Boo-yah!
Whoo! All right!
That was ridonculous fun,
now wasn't it, ladies and gentlemen?
I'm going to come by for my money,
Charlie boy. You best have it.
- Everybody say "hey!"
- [audience] Hey!
- Everybody say "ho!"
- [audience] Ho!
How about that?
How you doing there, little robot?
[muttering] My keys, damn it.
One more step
and I'll drop you like your girlfriend.
Charlie, relax.
I'm not paying you.
That was a bogus fight.
- It cost me my last robot.
- Just listen to us.
- Do you recall Caroline Fallon?
- She's my ex-girlfriend.
I haven't seen her in like ten years.
What does she want?
- Nothing. She died.
- Do you recall Max Kenton?
He's my son.
He's got to be like nine.
- Eleven.
- Eleven. OK.
[sighs] Is he dead, too?
No, he's fine.
That's why we're here.
[soft music playing]
[man] This court is convened
to address the custodial status
of one Max Kenton, age 11.
Mother, Caroline Fallon, deceased.
Father, Charles Kenton.
Debra Fallon Barnes,
you're the boy's aunt.
Yes. As I've already told you,
my husband, Marvin, is wealthy,
and we can more than provide for Max.
I appreciate that, but per Texas
state law, without a written will
next of kin retains custody.
Charles Kenton, who is aware
of this custody hearing,
and we are expecting him...
[Charlie] No, I need a new robot now.
I had a big fight
for Ambush next Saturday.
I got to show up with something.
Noisy Boy is for sale?
In his day, Noisy Boy was a killer.
How much?
That's a good deal.
What's wrong with him?
I can live with that.
Well, I don't have it have it.
Charles Kenton waived all
of his rights to custody
right after the boy was born.
I can more than provide for Max.
Whoa.
Please be Charles Kenton.
Uh... Charlie, yeah.
[stammers] I'm here to sign some paper
that releases my rights
to the custody of my son.
That's why I'm here.
Do I need to be here?
Charlie.
Do you even remember me?
- Debra, Caroline's sister.
- Yeah, sure, Debra. How are you?
- Mr. Kenton.
- Yeah.
Please take a seat.
Your Honor, may I please go
and see my nephew now?
Yes, you may.
- How about you, Mr. Kenton?
- What?
You can spend some time with him,
if you'd like.
- With the kid?
- [Debra] Yeah, the kid.
- Max. Your son?
- All right, all right.
You've been working with those robots
for so long, you've become one.
Honey, you wait right here.
I'm going to be back.
You take all the time you need,
sweetheart.
Your Honor,
I'd like to, at this juncture,
step out and call my attorney,
if that's all right.
[judge] Please.
Come on. Come on.
There you are.
He'll be in a foster home.
No, they find good families.
Young, energetic. Yeah.
Thanks, Michael. I will. OK.
- [phone beeps]
- Oh, hey.
Hey, um...
- Marvin Barnes. I'm Debra's husband.
- Right, yeah.
You know,
Debra really wants to adopt Max.
And...
- I'm up for it, but...
- Seventy-five grand.
$75,000?
- You're serious?
- Mm-hmm.
The thing is...
...we're supposed to go
to Italy this summer
with my oldest friend and his wife.
Two months in Tuscany and all over.
Just the four of you. Sounds nice.
We'll be back in New York
by the end of August.
In August. A hundred.
- $100,000?
- You heard me.
- You're crazy.
- Not nearly as crazy as your wife
if you tell her I just signed
over that kid to the state of Texas.
The way I see it, there's a real way
everyone gets what they want here.
So here's what you're going to do.
You're going to tell your wife
I'll only sign over custody to her
if I get to spend the summer
with the kid first.
Just tell her how guilty
she made me feel
for being such a terrible absentee dad
how I want to make good with junior,
a little fatherly bonding, whatnot.
She'll buy it, you get to be the hero,
and everybody wins.
OK. But not a word about the money
to Debra, you understand?
I understand.
I'll give you 50 grand tonight
when we drop off Max
and the other 50
when we get back in August
and you deliver him to us in New York.
Pleasure doing business with you.
Your Honor, I'm really happy
we all took the time
to make the best decision for everyone.
- Happy?
- [Charlie] Yeah, it's me.
I'm buying Noisy Boy.
I got the money.
Take him to Tallet's Gym
and I'll meet you there.
Hello?
Bailey?
Some guy is here
with the robot you're buying,
and I gotta tell ya, Charlie,
- it smells like disaster to me.
- Nice to see you, too, Bailey.
- Might I also say how cute you look.
- Give it up, Charlie.
God, I need a shower.
You want to take a shower?
- Come on.
- Let me make something clear.
A creepy dude with a robot in a box
has been sitting outside my gym
for two hours.
Now, putting aside the fact
that you're doing
what I'm guessing is a black market deal
on my doorstep,
how are you gonna pay him
when Ambush just got destroyed?
The money is on its way.
Just, you know, distract him.
- I have been. It's exhausting.
- You're the best.
- Yeah? Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Is that why
you're buying a $45,000 robot
when you owe me six grand in rent?
- Because I'm the best?
- Three.
- No, six.
- Whoa.
No, listen, Charlie. There is a guy with
real money who wants to buy this place.
Come on, like you're really
going to sell your dad's gym.
If you don't make rent,
I can't make payments
and I won't have a choice.
Your father would climb out of his grave
and kick your ass if you sold this place.
My father would climb out of his grave
and kick your ass.
[sighs]
Bailey.
- Don't.
- Don't what?
Don't do that. Don't... that...
Hey.
- Don't what?
- Don't do that thing.
- No, you like that thing.
- No.
- Yeah.
- No, I don't like that thing.
I used to. Once. Briefly.
Now I like money more.
- I don't believe you.
- I don't care.
[clears throat]
Marvin.
Your money has arrived.
Marv.
Fifty grand, as promised.
- Now, here are all our numbers
- Right.
- and contact info over in Europe.
- All right.
So that's everything there.
So Marvin tells me you want
this time with Max.
- Yeah, yeah.
- You did the right thing
giving me custody. I think
Caroline would have wanted that.
Yeah.
Now, have him back in New York
on August 27th.
That's a deal.
- OK, well, let's go get Max.
- OK.
OK? Let's get Max.
It's OK. You want me to go on the
other side here and I'll get Max?
Hey, Max.
See you, pal.
[Debra] Max, we'll see you
at the end of the summer, honey.
I'm Charlie.
It's been a long time.
You know, I'm your...
- You screwed me.
- Nice mouth.
Do you know where they're going?
- Italy?
- Yeah, Italy.
- So how did I get stuck here with you?
- Relax, kid.
You got a whole life
of fine living ahead of you.
Charlie, dude's pissed.
He's going to take off.
- Yeah, OK.
- Did Marvin give you that money?
Here, just close the deal.
I'll be right there, OK?
- OK?
- Hey.
Hey.
- I'm Bailey.
- Max.
Max Kenton.
- Wow, OK, so this is your...
- Yeah, it's him.
Don't worry about it, OK?
I'm standing here looking at you two...
Just go and put Noisy in the shop,
please? Thank you.
[sighs]
So listen, you're going to stay here
with her while I'm on the road.
How much did he give you, huh?
You're coming
at this the wrong way, kid.
No, tell me. I want to know.
50,000. OK?
He gave me $50,000
to sign you over to her.
Will you shut up now?
You sold me?
Sounds worse than it is.
- Really.
- It's just to take care of you.
Give me half the money
and you won't have to.
- Where are you going to go?
- Give me the money. I'll be fine.
I told your aunt I'll get you
to New York at the end of the summer.
Now you're concerned for Aunt Debra?
You sold me for 50 grand.
You owe me half!
I don't have it!
I spent the money on a robot.
It's gone! OK? Gone!
I'm through here.
All right, what do we got?
Noisy Boy has arrived.
That's a lot of airline stickers
and customs tags.
- Yep, he's been all over the world.
- London, Japan, Brazil, São Paulo...
Hasn't seen North American soil
in over two years.
Maybe that's why you got such
a good price, genius.
[Charlie] Decided to stay, huh?
This is Bailey. She'll be looking
after you for a few weeks.
- What?
- By the way,
I need you to look after the kid
for a few weeks or, like, eight.
- I want half that money.
- Are we back to this again?
Is there a real robot boxer in there?
Noisy Boy's in there.
Have you ever heard of him?
Of course. He fought Rubicon
for the WRB belt in 2016.
- [chuckles]
- [beeps]
Holy crap, he looks amazing.
Well, his composite armor
has been replaced.
Let's see if the insides look as good.
I've watched that fight
with Rubicon like 20 times.
He should have had him
in the third round
but Rubicon got lucky
with a huge right and ended it.
[beeping]
[Charlie] Relax, kid. he's on our side.
- Not funny.
- Kind of funny.
You know he
has voice recognition, right?
- No, he doesn't.
- He didn't in the League.
When Noisy fought in Brazil,
they must have put it in.
Brazilians are crazy about
that talk-to-your-robot crap.
Right, left, uppercut!
Doesn't work.
I knew that price was too good
to be true. We got screwed.
Give me a second.
Let me see if I can fix it.
God, look how good he looks, too.
Give me two seconds.
Let me look at something!
Why didn't you ask the guy
to have a look at it?
Relax!
[speaks Japanese]
Whoa, whoa.
What was that? Was that Japanese?
[speaks Japanese]
Let me see if I can reset him
to English. Hang on.
- How the hell do you know Japanese?
- Video games.
[Charlie] You play video games
in Japanese?
Japanese bootlegs are always better.
- Give me that.
- OK, so he's reset to English,
and I found his command matrix.
They have pre-loaded a bunch
of combinations.
- They should be listed here.
- Right.
Uh... Top salvo!
- [laughing]
- What did I tell you?
Gravity One Downtown!
[chuckling]
I was due for some good luck!
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
Bailey, help me put him in the truck.
I am going to go and get your money.
- Give me the keys.
- I'm coming with you.
- No, you're not.
- Why not?
Because I don't want you with me, OK?
I'm either coming with you, or you're
fishing for your keys in the sewer.
Your choice.
What's it going to be, old man?
[jingles]
Oh, my God. That was close, wasn't it?
Don't do that again.
- Don't, don't, don't.
- That's scaring you, isn't it?
- Don't do this again? Whoa, whoa!
- Get in. Just get in, will ya?
Give me the keys first.
No, you can wait
till I get in the truck.
Thanks, Big Pops.
[Max] Sweet ride.
[Charlie] Put on your seatbelt
and don't talk.
[engine starts]
[# Eminem: "'Till I Collapse"]
I'm taking all bets!
Keep up. Stay close.
Hey, hey, hey!
Charlie Kenton is in the house!
All right, all right.
- [man] Come on, man!
- Hey, Finn.
- Is that Noisy Boy?
- The one and only.
- That's Noisy Boy!
- [cheering]
Noisy's been in Japan.
Softer bots over there.
You sure you want
to fight him tonight?
What do you got, Finn? He can take any
bot in this place. You know it.
[laughs] You can have
any undercard you want.
- Five thousand guaranteed.
- Come on, man.
A thousand
every round your bot survives.
- Fight till the death!
- [crowd cheering]
No. Give me the main event.
- Come on, Charlie.
- Finn, this is Noisy Boy.
An original Tak Mashido bot.
He was a World Robot League boxer.
Come on!
You want to fight Midas?
Fifty thousand guaranteed,
winner takes all.
Fifty? Really, 50?
Now you're talking.
[Max] Listen, listen. No, look.
- Listen!
- Give me a sec.
We should take an undercard fight,
make a little cash
and get the hell out of here!
All right, first, there is no "we."
Second, he's going to crush Midas,
and I'm going to make real cash!
We'll take Midas!
[crowd cheering]
[metal music playing]
Yeah!
Tonight, our main event
features the gold-blooded killer!
This pimped-out punk
is programmed for pain!
I give to you the mighty Midas!
Whoo!
Against a bot
who ran with the big boys in the WRB!
He's been on an exile tour overseas,
but now he's back home
and he's ready to make some noise!
Take your first look in a long time
at Noisy Boy!
Crash Palace,
who's ready for some destruction?!
Let's make some money! Come on!
[Finn] We have Midas against Noisy Boy.
Noisy Boy against Midas.
You've been waiting all night
for this matchup, Crash Palace!
[bell rings]
Scimitar right!
Did you see that?
Easy money, easy money all night.
All night long!
Come on! It's not over yet. Let's go!
Skull salvo! Firefight!
- Yeah! Go, Noisy!
- Undercard, huh?
Shockfist!
Get in there. Shogun Trinity!
Let's finish him. Gravity Slam, Uptown!
This son-of-a-bitch is crazy!
Get up!
Full Metal Feud! Bring it!
Southpaw! Pain Revolution!
I got something for you.
Don't you run from me!
You can't run from me!
Get up!
That's illegal!
This is the underworld, kid.
There are no rules!
[Finn] Now we're seeing
the Midas touch.
No. Hands up!
Get back in that corner, bitch,
and take this whooping like a man!
He's getting killed in there!
It's a headset! You talk into it
and you tell him what to do!
Panic Shield!
That's it. One-Two Overlord!
[grunting]
No, no. Shatter Punch!
- Five Recall!
- Get some!
Jeez, damn it.
Jab, jab!
Right roundhouse! Roundhouse!
[Finn] Did he just spit
his juice in Midas's face?
No, you did not spit in Midas's face!
- It's party time now, Crash Palace!
- Use your left!
[Finn] Noisy's trying to do something
with his one arm!
But Midas pins him,
and Daddy goes to work!
No, no, no! Get up!
Get some!
He's got...
Just gotta get to the bell.
Move! Get out of the corner!
[crowd chanting] Midas! Midas! Midas!
Somebody's ready
to serve up a decappuccino!
I got something for you!
You ready?
[Finn] Good night!
That's a home run for Midas.
And so long to Noisy Boy.
[screaming]
[crowd chanting] Midas! Midas! Midas!
Well, that sucked. You hungry?
I saved what's left
of Noisy's voice recognition board.
Other than that, he's trash.
I got to get a new robot together.
I need to find a mainframe. What?
- I hate hamburgers.
- What kid hates burgers?
Fine, more for me.
Here, drink this.
You never should have taken that fight.
Really? Really? Thanks, genius.
Do you even think about the stuff you do
before you do it?
You had no idea how to fight that fight.
Those combination codes, you didn't
know what half of them even meant.
You threw them in there cocky
and half-assed.
Of course he lost.
You never gave him a chance.
- He wasn't that good.
- Noisy Boy was a great robot.
Was. Was a great robot back
in the League, back in the day.
But look around you, kid. This place...
This place is where once great robots
go to die.
So throw him away.
That's what you do, right?
Anything you don't need
you just throw away.
Wow.
It's been a long night.
If you want to sleep indoors tonight,
shut up and get in the truck.
Don't look at me like that way.
Get in the truck!
Well, they gave me 400 for his head.
You stay put.
I'm going to go look for some parts.
- I'm coming with you.
- Huh?
That drink has my heart pounding.
If I sit in this truck by myself,
my head will explode.
Whatever. Just keep up.
[thunder crashing]
Crap.
Stay back, stay back, stay back.
All right, keep up.
These searchlights are automated,
but you got to time them right,
so stay close.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Keep up. It's all right.
All right. Come on, come on.
- We're going to get caught.
- Come on.
Easy, easy. Easy, easy.
Quick, quick. Down in here! Go, go, go!
Robots are on the east side.
We got to be quick in here.
Once we're through here,
there's no more searchlights.
Quick! Go, go, go!
- Here it is.
- What are we looking for?
Anything. Anything I could use
to put a fighting bot together.
- Hey, look.
- What?
It's so small.
Yeah. That's before your time.
That's a Generation One,
the very first fighting bot.
They wanted them to look like us.
The more human, the better.
Crazy how quick everything changed.
Here, put that in the cart.
What changed?
A good question.
Boxing, human boxing.
- It just faded.
- Why?
Because the money moved on.
People wanted more carnage,
more show.
You had the whole Brazilian
underground,
the Gracies, the Machados,
jiu-jitsu, Muay Thai,
and 1,000 styles in between.
Full-on ground-and-pound.
- Look at this.
- What's that?
- I don't know.
- Not bad. Good spot, kid.
You still had human fighters,
human bodies
so you couldn't
give the people what they really wanted:
true, no-holds-barred violence.
So the next logical step:
get the humans out of there
and let the machines kill each other.
Do you miss it?
- Boxing. Do you miss it?
- Careful.
What? I want to know.
Careful, you're on a cliff.
Whoa!
That's a long way down.
If you fell, you'd definitely...
[Max screaming]
- Charlie!
- Max!
Charlie, help me!
Charlie!
Max! Max!
Max!
- Try not to move!
- I'm on some sort of robot arm.
Wait! Just easy, easy.
Give me your hand. Nice and easy.
Very slowly. Good. OK, don't look down.
Look at me. Look at me.
That's it! I've got you, Max!
You don't have to be scared. I got you!
- It's so far!
- It's OK. I got you.
Give me your other hand.
Nice and slow.
Just give me your other hand
very slowly.
Reach back. Come on. Reach!
All right, look at me.
We're going to do this together.
You and me.
Just look at me.
That's it. That's it.
One... two... three!
[screaming]
That's it. I got you!
I got you. I got you. I got you.
- I got you. I got you.
- [Max panting]
You're safe. You're safe.
All right, I got you.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Come here. Easy. Easy.
You all right?
- You all right?
- Yeah.
I told you it was dangerous.
Careful. We're still on the edge here.
Charlie, I think there's
a whole robot in there.
So what? Let's go. Come on.
I'm taking him with me.
He saved my life.
He did not save your life.
I saved your life. Let's go.
Could you just bring the cart to the
edge? I'll use the winch to get him out.
You want that piece of junk? You get
the cart yourself. I'm through here.
[wheels whirring]
This is what's left of Noisy Boy?
That's it.
His head does make a nice addition
to the front of the Crash Palace.
- [scoffs] It's not funny.
- Let's get a robot, you and me.
Yeah, good idea. You're broke.
I'm almost there myself.
- You destroyed the best shot you had.
- We'll put one together.
You're brilliant at this.
There's good stuff here.
- No, there's nothing here.
- There is. Look.
Charlie, all your junk is... it's junk.
You're not even
in the game anymore, Charlie.
- It's all garbage.
- I heard you. It's garbage.
Don't get loud with me.
- You're your problem, Charlie.
- What's that supposed to mean?
I have been here for you a long time.
In the ring, out of the ring,
and the whole ugly spiral down,
and I'm tired.
My father invested everything
he had in your fight career.
We loved...
He loved you like family.
And this is his home.
I'm just trying not to let it die.
That's my plan.
What's yours?
[sighs]
You're done, right?
You're finally done?
Because I sure as hell am, Charlie.
I got nothing left.
All right.
Maybe there's something here.
This robot the kid brought
in last night.
Would you look at it for me?
Please?
Bailey?
I've never seen
anything like it before.
He's Generation Two, but barely.
I found a power cell that fits him,
and I hooked him up
to this old G-2 remote that I had, so...
You can at least move him around,
Charlie, but he's crap.
Maybe I can get a sparring gig for him,
make a few hundred bucks.
- Charlie, stop.
- [Max] It's my robot!
It took me half the night
dragging him out of there.
- He's mine.
- He's yours? Yeah.
But the parts we're
putting in him are mine!
You idiots should see if he powers up
before you start fighting over him.
What happened to you?
Hey.
[beeping]
[beeping fades]
[electronic whirring]
Whoa. Whoa.
Watch out. Stay back.
Looks like he's got a shadow function.
That's pretty rare.
He can mime your movements
and store them in memory, Max.
[Charlie] You think there's
anything here we could use?
- [Bailey] Not much.
- There's a bucket...
There's a bucket
I use to wash the truck sometimes.
Use it and clean him up.
He smells like crap.
Wash yourself off, too,
while you're at it. You stink.
I switched him to remote.
It's pretty basic.
Just use the toggles here
to steer him and walk him.
- You play video games, right?
- Of course.
Same idea, only this one's
a thousand-pound robot.
Cool.
"Atom."
[Max] His name is Atom.
Can we get him a fight?
I don't think he
was ever a boxing robot.
He's a G-2, built in early 2014.
He was a sparring bot.
They must have built robots
like this one
that could mirror the fighting style
of any other robot.
OK, so can we get him a fight?
Are you not listening?
He's a sparring bot.
Built to take a lot of hits, but never
dishing out any real punishment.
You could always sell him off for parts.
Can't you get him a fight?
"Why can't you get him a fight?
Get him a fight."
God, you don't quit, do you?
You want me to put him in some
bottom-rung scrap-fest to the death?
I saw how scared you were
at Crash Palace.
The places that would
let you fight this robot
would make you pee your little pants.
Excellent. Get him a fight.
[mechanical chirping]
Stubborn kid.
Surprise, surprise.
[beeping]
[mechanical chirping]
[whirrs]
Let's take a walk.
[Max laughs]
[Atom whirrs]
Can you understand me?
Don't worry.
Your secret's safe with me.
[whirrs]
[Max] You've known Charlie a long time.
Too long.
We both kind of grew up in this gym.
My dad, he trained him.
That's them. That's Charlie.
- [Max] What was he like?
- [Bailey] As a boxer?
As anything.
He was something.
He was lean, tough.
No quit, no fear.
Come here.
I want to show you something.
I have this newspaper article
from Phoenix 2007
when Charlie fought Nico Tandy,
the top contender.
- You were at the Nico Tandy fight?
- I was.
Charlie was just supposed
to be a warm-up fight, an easy win.
Nico wasn't
even supposed to break a sweat
but nobody told Charlie that, so he just
kept coming and coming at him.
Check this out.
[Bailey] That's Charlie.
First, Nico couldn't believe the balls
on this nobody.
But Charlie kept coming,
and that's when Nico looked scared.
- Really?
- Really.
He was toying with Nico.
The top contender,
number two in the world
and Charlie was dancing with him.
Pop! Pop! Bam! Pop!
Charlie was floating inches
off the canvas that night.
He was like a ghost.
Nico couldn't even see him.
I could.
He was beautiful.
So what happened?
Did Charlie beat Nico Tandy?
No, Nico Tandy put me on my ass
in the 12th round. Twice.
Second time for good. Lights out.
You were ahead on the scorecards
going into the 12th round.
Nico Tandy rung my bell
and went on to be the undefeated
world champ for the next three years.
- So he knocked you out?
- Yeah, so did a lot of guys.
You knocked a lot of guys out, too.
24 and 19.
It's not exactly a career.
But every fight a knockout.
- Yeah.
- Win or lose, fight's not over
- till someone's on the mat.
- Till someone's on the mat.
- Your old man taught me that.
- Damn straight he taught you that.
- [Max] Who else did you fight?
- Go get your stuff together.
I don't need to.
Did you fight for the title?
Yeah, you do.
We leave in an hour. Go.
Wow. Here.
Keep it.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
I like that kid.
He likes you.
- What I said yesterday was...
- No, nothing more to say.
I'm heading off to Atlanta tonight
to see if I can get a partner
or raise money to get a new bot.
That's what you wanted, right?
Me gone?
Yeah, that's what I wanted.
OK.
[mechanical chirping]
[cell phone rings]
[ringing stops]
Hey. Hey.
Look.
The champ is here. Zeus is here.
Yeah.
[announcer] Zeus! No one has ever
gone two rounds with this monster.
Two rounds!
The champ puts his Real Steel world
championship belt on the line tonight.
He just may have a real fight
on his hands.
Zeus, greatest robot boxer
of all time. Ever.
End of story. Good night!
- So cool. It's so cool.
- What?
[Charlie] Come on.
All right, listen up.
I got to go find Finn.
- I want you to stay in this area, OK?
- OK.
[man] Out of the way. Champ coming
through. Zeus coming through.
Move, move.
Champ coming through.
[whirring]
[reporters clamoring]
[whirring continues]
Farra Lemkova, daughter behind
the father-daughter Zeus team.
They say your father's the money
and you are the mind behind Zeus.
You're very kind,
but I assure you,
the mind behind Zeus
belongs to the great Tak Mashido.
[all clamoring]
What did it take to lure the reclusive
genius, former boy wonder
and arguably the most
important bot designer
in the history of the sport
out of retirement?
Why don't you ask him yourself?
[all clamoring]
Is this Tak Mashido's greatest creation?
Zeus is autonomous and constantly
evolving during a fight.
With his adaptive operating system
he recognizes patterns
and rewrites his fight code
instantaneously.
For myself and Joe Sixpack out there,
are you saying that Zeus...
I'm saying that no matter
what happens in that ring,
the result of any fight is inevitable.
What Zeus sees...
...he kills.
Sweet.
[all clamoring]
[Zeus whirrs]
[Finn] I'm never
going into business with you.
[Charlie] I just need a break here,
Finn. C'mon.
You got that old bot truck out there.
- You always got something in there.
- I got an old G-2 sparring bot,
ain't worth the paint left on it.
What am I supposed to do with that?
The Zoo. Take him to the Zoo.
They fight there tomorrow.
Even I wouldn't be caught dead
at the Zoo.
I just need a little loan. Something...
What?
- You're serious, Charlie?
- A loan.
Something. A couple hundred. Few
hundred. Whatever you got.
You know I'm good for it.
I know you,
and as much as I like you, dude...
...you're a bad bet, brother.
Right, yeah.
[bell ringing]
[crowd cheers at a distance]
- Get back.
- All right. All right.
[electric zapping]
Did you see that?
That's what's left of Axelrod.
Where you been?
I told you to stay put.
You should have seen him.
Zeus was, like, amazing!
- Amazing, huh?
- Unbelievable, yeah.
He was just peppering Axelrod
with punches, but so fast.
It was incredible.
Axelrod didn't even land a punch.
He didn't even survive the first round.
Is that what you think boxing is?
Zeus beating up some piece
of steel that they feed him?
Axelrod's not just some piece of steel.
And that is what boxing is now.
Deal with it.
And I love it, and I'm in it now.
You're in it now, are you?
You and your G-2 sparring bot?
He's more than that. And if you'd
just get us a fight, you'd see.
You're in luck, kid.
There's a lovely place called the Zoo.
Tomorrow afternoon,
you'll get your fight.
- Great.
- And it will be the end.
I told you I hate hamburgers!
It's a burrito!
[Max] Right uppercut.
Left uppercut.
Bend your knees.
Rise up with both hands.
Again. Bend your knees.
- You been up all night?
- Yeah. I cleaned him up.
I'm using shadow mode
to program some fight moves
and sync them to the remote.
Yeah. I saw that double-up punch
you were showing him.
That's... That's lethal stuff.
Let's do this.
Jeez. Let's do breakfast first.
[rock music playing]
You know you're
bringing him home in pieces, right?
We'll see.
[man laughs]
Let me deal with this.
Charlie Kenton. This is Max.
Kingpin. Call me Kingpin.
- All right, Kingpin, so...
- How much a round?
What's this, we on a field trip?
All right.
He can fight my robot Metro.
I'll give you a 100 bucks
for one two-minute round.
- Take it.
- Three hundred.
One hundred. Baby boy, I'm going to
give you $100 just to get in with Metro.
How about 500 for two rounds?
[laughing] Two rounds.
Two rounds, son, he ain't
going to survive one round.
- What if he does?
- He ain't.
Let's just say he does.
If he's still
standing after one round...
- ...I'll give you 1,000 bucks. Shut it!
- A 1,000...
But if he dies in there,
which he will, junior...
...I get to keep what's left.
Take the 100.
Deal.
We're on. We on!
Let's go!
[Charlie] You should have taken the 100.
- [Max] I got us a thousand.
- [Charlie] Yeah, if he wins.
[# The Beastie Boys:
"Here's A Little Something For Ya"]
[crowd cheers]
[groans]
You want me to drive?
He's my bot. I got this!
This ain't a video game, kid.
This is for real. Right here.
You said he's coming home in pieces.
What difference does it make?
All right.
I got this.
Let's get it on!
Let's get it on
like Ping-Pong in Hong Kong!
Give me a bell! Give me a bell!
[metal music playing]
Don't watch Atom.
Watch your opponent. Watch him.
Watch out for that foot.
He's looking to pin you.
I told you to watch for that foot plant.
Come on.
Here comes the sledgehammer.
Did you see that?
- Come on! Get him!
- Don't yell at him, control him.
Slip right. Back step.
Duck. You're welcome.
- Shut up! You're not helping!
- Actually, I think I am.
No, no, no, no, no.
Backhand. You got speed on this guy.
Just keep moving. Bob.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Slip out of that corner.
Keep moving! Bob and weave!
That's it! Now you're listening to me.
He can take a hit. I'll give you this,
kid. Your bot can take a hit.
You better slip that headlock 'cause
this ain't gonna end well for you.
I'm trying!
Thirty seconds!
Thirty se... Half a minute.
Half a minute!
Keep moving! Just move!
C'mon, you've got 20 seconds!
That's a thousand bucks. Twenty
seconds. Let me... Let me take over!
- No...
- Just move, then. Move!
Come on.
Get up, Atom. Get up, Atom.
Count with me! Count with me!
One!
Get up, Atom!
He can't hear you... You know you're
talking to a machine?
[crowd chanting] Four! Five! Six!
Get up, Atom!
All the way up! All the way up!
- No!
- Yeah!
Yes! Yes!
[indistinct]
I'm going to fix it!
I'm going to fix it! Come on, now.
- This 1,000 bucks...
- Yeah, 1,000.
...double or nothing
he can't make another round.
- Yeah, thanks anyway.
- Deal. Double or nothing.
Baby boy said it!
We're back on! We on!
Are you crazy?
You threw away a 1,000 bucks!
He can barely stand up in there.
Look, I really need the money.
I know. Let's work.
Ah, Jesus.
- Watch that. Watch that.
- I got that.
[grunts]
- [whirrs]
- Huh?
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Yeah!
- I got it.
- That's a system failure!
- I don't got it.
- He's going down.
- Yes!
- No!
Start... Hey, hey! Start the count!
Start the count!
One! Two! Three!
[all chant] Four! Five! Six! Seven!
Eight! Nine!
Ten!
You did it! We did it! Wow!
[Max] Yeah!
Time to go. Come on. Grab your robot.
I know, I know!
I know! I know!
Kingpin, pay up.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know, I know, I know.
- We owned!
- Let's go. Come on, come on.
- Yeah?
- Have I got a fight for you.
Saturday night.
Guaranteed four grand.
Seven if he wins.
Four grand?
You're on. Let's go!
Bailey, it's me. He won.
Can you believe that?
The kid's robot actually won.
I know.
Oh, yeah, oh, happy?
Oh, my God. Yeah.
He's been bit.
He's been bit real bad.
Yeah. Anyway, I...
...I just wanted you to know.
[mechanical chirping]
[Max] Jab.
Jab, jab, hook.
I think you have to move your feet.
Your feet. Feet.
[hip-hop music playing]