At the beginning of
the 21st century
the Umbrella Corporation
had become
the largest commercial entity
in the U.S.
Nine out of every ten homes
contain its products.
its political and financial
influence is felt everywhere.
In public, it is the world's
leading supplier of...
computer technology, medical
products and healthcare.
Unknown even to
its own employees,
its massive profits
are generated by...
military technology,
genetic experimentation
and viral weaponry.
All Umbrella staff must
wear their identity tags...
at all times.
All radiation badges...
will be collected
at 5 this afternoon.
Thank you!
God!
Some people.
- Don't show me.
- Why not?
Because I'm busy.
It's nothing. Fire drill.
- What is that?
- Fire drill.
- Shit!
- What's going on?
- Get the computers covered! Move it!
- I'm trying!
Move the experiments!
Shouldn't the doors open
or something?
It's supposed to take us
to the nearest floor.
Hello?
What's happening?
Line's dead.
Is that a dill? Come on!
- What's the problem?
- The doors won't open.
- The ones at the back?
- Locked as well.
There's no fire here!
No fire!
- there's no fire here! No fire!
- The code doesn't work!
- What's wrong with you?
- The door won't open!
- And this water isn't going anywhere.
- What?
It's a sealed room.
- Help me with the door!
- Fuck the doors!
We have to get out of here.
What's going on?
Has this happened before?
We have to get out of here.
- Take it easy.
- You take it easy!
Quiet!
Quiet.
What is that?
Oh, my God!
Halon!
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop!
Let me see.
We have to get out of here.
We have to get out of this building.
Here, give me a hand.
That's as far as they'll go.
They're caught on something.
That's wide enough.
I can squeeze through.
I'll get help.
I'm stuck. You'll have to push.
That's it. A bit more.
What was that?
Oh, Christ!
It's the brakes!
- Get out! We have to get out!
- I can't move!
I can't move!
Oh, my God!
- Push her out of the way!
- Pull me back inside!
Pull me back inside!
Today all your dreams come true.
Today all your...
Hello?
Who are you?
Don't touch me.
Get away from me!
Down!
What are you doing? I'm a cop!
I told you. I'm a cop.
You're breaking my arm.
Report.
Report now.
What?
I want you report, soldier.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Sir, the house's primary
defences were activated.
She's probably suffering
side effects.
- What are you doing with us?
- What about the cop?
Matthew Addison.
I'm not getting a match.
Who are you?
I just transferred. They probably
don't have me on file yet.
The locals are inefficient.
It's possible.
Should I secure him here?
No. We take him with us.
You can't do this.
Blow me.
Prep for entry to the Hive.
- Power's down.
- So fix it.
I'm on it.
Are you done yet?
Jumpy!
Stand clear!
- You got a problem?
- How's that door?
- Sealed shut.
- Let me.
Jumpy?
Lie still.
Lie still!
Watch this light.
Follow it.
- How many fingers?
- Three.
Good. Tell me your name.
I don't know.
He's fine.
Memory loss, like the other one.
Let's open that door.
I want to know who you people are
and what's going on here.
Now!
You and I have the same employer.
We work for the Umbrella Corporation.
The mansion above is an
emergency entrance to the Hive.
You were security operatives
placed three to protect that entrance.
What about this?
Your marriage is a fake.
Just your cover to protect
the secrecy of the Hive.
And what is the Hive?
Show them.
Accessing schematic
of the Hive.
Raccoon City,
nearest urban centre.
The mansion, where we found you
and gained access to the train...
which, in turn,
brought us to the Hive.
The Hive is located underground...
deep beneath the streets
of Raccoon City.
A secret research facility
owned and operated
by the Umbrella Corporation...
The Hive houses over 500 technicians,
scientists and support staff.
They live and work underground.
Their research is of
the highest importance.
Its nature is classified.
Our position on the map
is indicated by heat signature.
Why can't I remember anything?
The Hive has its own defence
mechanisms, all computer-controlled.
A nerve gas was released
into the house.
Primary effect of the gas:
Complete unconsciousness
lasting up to four hours.
Secondary effects can include
acute memory loss.
- For how long?
- Subjective. An hour, day, week.
So, this place was attacked?
I'm afraid things are a little
more complicated than that.
Sir, we've breached the Hive.
J.D.
Got it.
Halon has dissipated.
Easier to work underground,
thinking there's a view.
Looks like we're taking the stairs.
Status.
Red Queen's locked on to us.
She knows we're here.
Who's the Red Queen?
State-of-the-art
artificial intelligence.
The computer
that controls the Hive.
This will slow us down.
Our route to the Queen takes us
straight through these labs.
Rain, J.D.,
see how bad the flooding is.
Kaplan, find an alternate route.
What happened here?
Five hours ago,
Red Queen went homicidal.
Sealed the Hive
and killed everyone here.
Jesus.
When we realized what happened,
we were dispatched to shut her down.
- Why did she do it?
- We don't know.
But outside interference
is a possibility.
Jesus!
You okay?
Here.
- No, I'm fine.
- It's cold in here.
Are you...?
Do you remember anything from...
before this?
No, nothing before the train.
And you?
Nothing.
I found an alternate route
but it will cost us time.
If we double back, cut through
Dining Hall B, we're right on track.
Sir, no go.
The whole level's flooded.
All right,
we're behind schedule.
So let's move it.
Come on.
Poor bastards.
Kaplan?
Dining Hall B.
That's what's on the map.
Maybe you're reading it wrong.
Maybe the Corporation
keeps secrets here,
something you're not
supposed to see.
J.D., you and Rain keep the prisoner
here and secure the exit.
Halon levels are nonexistent.
I think the system malfunctioned.
There may be survives. Give me
a search line but keep it tight.
Move it.
- I said keep it tight.
- Sorry.
I'm not sure I want to remember
what went on down here.
I don't blame you.
- What the hell do they keep in these?
- How do I know?
What's taking so long?
Red Queen's defences are in place.
She's making it difficult.
Let's pack it up.
You. Stay here.
The lights are automated.
Nothing to worry about.
- Transmitter in position.
- Roger.
Running a bypass.
Checkmate.
Move up.
What is that?
That will shut the Queen down.
Delivers a massive electrical charge.
Forces the mainframe to reboot.
Kaplan!
A dormant defence mechanism.
We must've tripped it.
- Put it back to sleep.
- Working on it.
- Open that door.
- I'm trying.
Hold your positions.
Stay calm.
What's that?
- Get them out!
- Something's happening in there.
- Come on.
- Help them!
Down! Get down!
- Something's killing them!
- Don't do this!
Medic! Medic!
- Open the door!
- I'm trying!
You're going into shock.
Stay awake!
Almost there.
It's coming back!
- Open it!
- I'm trying!
Try harder!
It's coming back!
Oh, God!
- Do it!
- Almost there.
Come on!
- Shit.
- Got it.
All right.
Let's do it.
- Do what?
- We have to complete the mission.
No way I'll go down there.
Her defences are down.
Déja vu, anyone?
Keep going.
Give me a hand.
Get out!
You can't be in here.
Don't listen. She's a holographic
representation of the Red Queen.
Get out!
Modelled after
the programmer's daughter.
She'll deceive us, confuse us.
I wouldn't advise this.
Disabling me will result
in loss of primary power.
She'll say anything to stop us
from shutting her down.
I implore you.
- Implore away.
- Please?
Please?
You're all going to die down here.
That pulse forces
the circuit breaker
to shut down her mainframe
for 30 seconds.
After that, if I don't have
her boards, he can reboot.
They're late.
I'm on it.
J.D., we got a survivor!
We're here to help.
You seem to be in some sort of...
Get off!
Get off of me!
Get her off me
before I stab her ass.
You okay?
She bit me, man.
She took a chunk right out of me.
Stay back.
I'm warning you, stay down!
She's crazy.
Come any closer and I'll fire.
I mean it!
Damn you!
I shot her five times.
How was she still standing?
Bitch isn't standing now.
- What was all the shooting?
- We found a survivor.
- And you shot him?
- She was crazed. She bit me.
She's gone.
She's gone!
Bullshit!
She fell right here
but she's gone!
Look at this.
There's blood, but it's not much.
Looks coagulated.
Yeah.
It's not possible.
Why not?
Blood doesn't do that
till after you're dead.
Can we go now?
Not till the rest of
the team get here.
There's no one else coming.
- What the fuck you talking about?
- Wait.
Quiet.
- Fuck!
- Don't come any closer!
They're behind us!
Jesus!
They're everywhere.
They're all around us.
I said stay back!
Why aren't they dying?
Watch the tank!
The tank!
- Let's go!
- Hurry up!
- Wait!
- Come on! Move!
Come on!
Move.
I can help you get the virus.
I have security codes...
surveillance plans, the works.
Shit.
- We lost the others.
- Keep moving.
- You waited?
- Didn't know the code.
Come on.
- Shit!
- Come on!
- Hurry up.
- Shit!
- Come on.
- What's taking so long?
- I'm trying!
Come on.
- Move! What's the code?
- Hurry, I'm running out of ammo!
0-4-3-2... No, fuck!
- What?!
- 0-4-3...
- What is the code?
- 0-4...
0-3-1...
9-6-5.
- Got it?
- See how easy that was?
Shit!
Grab my hand, man!
Don't let go!
Where are the bodies?
Where did they go? Fuck!
Whatever they are,
there's too many.
Whatever they are?
It's pretty obvious what they are.
Lab coats, badges...
Those people used to work here.
All the people
working here are dead.
That isn't stopping them
from walking around.
Where did they come from?
Why didn't we see them on the way in?
When you cut the power, you unlocked
the doors. You let them out.
We're never goanna make it
to the surface.
You are security operatives...
placed there to protect
that entrance.
Lisa.
I've got one in the breech.
And an extra mag.
I can help you get the virus.
I have access to security codes...
surveillance plans, the works.
But?
- But there will be a price.
- Name it.
- Who was she?
- My sister.
Corporations like Umbrella...
think they're above the law.
But they're not.
There are hundreds of thousands of us
who think the same all over the world.
Some of us provide information.
Others give their support.
Some take more direct action.
Like you.
If your friends had been
more thorough,
they would've seen
through my false I.D.
Then all the red flags
would've gone off.
Quantico, NSA, ViCAP,
all the rest.
There's no way I could've
infiltrated the Hive.
So you sent your sister.
We needed something concrete,
anything to expose Umbrella
to the press.
Proof of the research
going on down here.
What kind of research?
The illegal kind.
Genetic.
Viral.
My sister was going to
smuggle out
a sample of the virus
they were developing.
How was she going to
make it out?
She had a contact within the Hive,
someone I never met.
They had access to security codes,
surveillance, everything she needed.
So why didn't she make it?
Maybe she trusted the wrong person.
Maybe they set her up.
Kept the virus of themselves.
Do you have any idea what the T-virus
would be worth on the open market?
Worth all this?
Yeah.
To someone.
- Don't shoot!
- Close that door!
- They're right behind us!
Get off!
Son of a bitch!
You okay?
Yeah.
Right behind us.
What about this door?
They’re waiting there too.
And that way?
Dead end. There's no way
out of the Queen's chamber.
So we wait.
Someone doesn't hear form you...
they'll send backup or something.
Right?
What? What's wrong?
- We don't have much time.
- Those blast doors we passed...
on the way in from the mansion,
they seal shut in under an hour.
If we're not out by then,
we're not getting out.
What are you talking about?
They can't just bury us
alive down here.
Containing the incident is
the only fail-safe plan they had...
against possible contamination.
And you're telling us this now,
when we're trapped...
half a mile underground?
We have to find a way
out of this room.
What are you doing?
- Where are you taking those?
- I'm turning her back on.
- That's not a good idea.
- She'll know a way out of here.
That homicidal bitch killed my team.
That homicidal bitch may be
our only way out of here.
Considering the way
she's been treated,
I'm sure she's real happy
to help us out.
That circuit breaker you were
talking about. Can you bypass it?
- Yeah?
- So do it.
Circuit breakers disabled.
This time, if I hit the switch,
she won't shut down. She'll fry.
The charge must've damaged
her boards.
There you are.
Things, I gather,
have gone out of control.
Give me that switch right now.
I'll fry your ass!
I did warn you, didn't I?
- Tell us what's going on down here.
- Research and development.
What about the T-virus?
The T-virus was a major
medical breakthrough.
Although it clearly
also possessed...
highly profitable
military applications.
How does it explain
those things out there?
Even in death, the human body
remains active.
Hair and fingernails
continue to grow.
New cells are produced.
And the brain holds
a small electrical charge
that takes months to dissipate.
The T-virus provides a massive jolt,
both to cellular growth...
and to those trace
electrical impulses.
Put quite simply,
it reanimates the body.
It brings the dead back to life?
Not fully. The subjects have
the simplest of motor functions.
Perhaps a little memory.
Virtually no intelligence.
They are driven by the basest of
impulses, the most basic of needs.
- Which is?
- The need to feed.
How do you kill them?
Severing the top of
the spinal column...
or massive trauma to the brain
are the most effective methods.
You mean shoot them
in the head.
Why did you kill
everybody down here?
The T-virus escaped
into the air conditioning system.
And an uncontrolled pattern
of infection began.
The virus is protean,
changing from liquid to airborne
to blood transmission...
depending on its environment.
It's almost impossible to kill.
I couldn't allow it to escape
from the Hive.
So, I took steps.
- Steps?
- You must understand...
those who become infected,
I can't allow you to leave.
- We're not infected.
- Just one bite...
one scratch from these creatures
is sufficient...
and then you become one of them.
A check of my systems indicates
my main drive circuit breaker...
has been disabled.
May I ask why?
Insurance.
We need a way out of here.
If you refuse to help,
we flip the switch.
Understand?
After you.
What the hell is this place?
The utility tunnels.
They run underneath the Hive
of water, gas and power lines.
- Been in here before.
- Keep moving!
- Going found in circles.
- This is the route the computer gave.
- I don't know why you listen to her.
- Enough!
We have no choice
but to keep moving
because those things
are behind us, got it?
That mesh won't hold.
Keep moving.
Jesus Christ!
- Hold it!
- There's too many of them!
Fuck!
Up on the pipes.
Up on the pipes!
Quickly, everyone, up on the pipes!
- Let's go!
- Come on, there's a way up!
Keep them back!
Go on up, move it!
Look out!
Get over here.
There's too many of them!
Go, go, go!
Go on!
I can manage!
Go!
JD?
What?
We have to do something
about your wounds.
I'm fine.
I said I'm fine.
You like that, don't you?
You like the way it tastes,
don't you?
Like the taste of that?
She was right.
- We're all going to die down here.
- No.
We're getting out.
All of us.
You okay?
God!
Get away!
- Hold on!
- Come on!
Help him.
- I can't.
- What are you waiting for?
I can't focus.
I can't see!
- Go up!
- Climb up there!
You got to keep going!
- Come on!
- Go!
- You can do it! Move!
- You got it!
- Stay there.
- We'll get you.
We need to cut this wire and throw it
to him. Then we'll get him.
Hold on.
That's lucky.
I want you to go.
- I'm not leaving you.
- Yes, you are.
You can't kill all of them.
I'm not going anywhere.
I want you to go, now!
Please, just do it.
Just do it now!
Please!
Go!
You'll have to work
for your meal!
Come on.
Give me your arm, okay?
Over my shoulder.
Ready?
Here we go.
When I get out of here...
I think I'll get laid.
You might want to clean up first.
Wait.
Are you okay?
Blue for the virus,
green for the antivirus.
- There's a cure.
- What are you talking about?
There's a cure.
The process can be reversed.
There's a cure!
You'll be okay.
I was beginning to worry.
This is where they kept
the T-virus.
How do you know all this?
Because I was going to steal it.
I was your sister's contact.
- You betrayed her.
- I don't know.
- You caused all this.
- I can't remember.
- The truth.
- I don't remember the truth.
I don't understand.
It's gone.
It's gone. It's not there.
I can't.
I just can't. It's over.
I can help you get the virus.
I have access to security codes...
surveillance plans, the works.
But there's a price.
Name it.
You have to guarantee me that
you'll bring this corporation down.
Today all your dreams
come true...
Spence?
Thank you!
We can still make it out of here.
Come with me.
We can have everything
we've ever wanted.
Money's out there waiting.
You wouldn't believe how much.
Is that how you thought
all my dreams would come true?
Please.
I wouldn't want to shoot you.
Might need the bullets.
Back off!
I won't take any part in this.
Okay, but you can't just
wash your hands of this.
We work for the same company.
You knew what they did.
I was trying to stop them.
You really believe that...
people like him will ever
change anything?
Nothing ever...
changes.
Where...
Where is...
the antivirus?
It's on the train...
where you found me.
Couldn't have been standing
more than their feet from it.
I so nearly made it out.
I didn't realize that
bitch of a computer...
had defence systems outside the Hive.
In or out?
In?
Or out?
I don't know what we had.
But it's over.
Back...
the fuck off!
I'm missing you already.
Your boyfriend's a real asshole.
He shot the locking mechanism out.
I can't believe that son of a bitch
is going to get away with this.
I don't think so.
I've been a bad, bad girl.
Oh, my God.
What the fuck is that?
One of the Hive's
early experiments.
Produced by injecting the virus
directly into living tissue.
The results were unstable.
Now that it has fed on fresh DNA...
it will mutate...
becoming a stronger,
faster hunter.
Great.
If you knew it was loose,
why didn't you warn us?
Because she was saving it.
For us.
Isn't that right?
I didn't think any of you
would make it this far.
Not without infection.
Why didn't you tell us
about the antivirus?
This long after infection,
there's no guarantee it would work.
But there's a chance.
Right?
I don't deal in chance.
Fuck it.
No pressure, guys.
You require
the four-digit access code.
I can give you the code. But first,
you must do something for me.
What do you want?
One of your group is infected.
I require her life for the code.
The antivirus is right there
on the platform!
I'm sorry,
but it's a risk I cannot take.
She's right. It's the only way.
You'll have to kill me.
Otherwise,
we all die down here.
The glass is reinforced,
but it won't hold forever.
Do it.
- Get up.
- Just do it.
- Please.
- Do it!
You don't have long to decide.
- You have no choice.
- Kill her now!
- Get off!
- You don't have any choice.
- Just do it now!
- I can't!
- Kill her now. Do it.
- Please.
- Kill her. Kill her now!
- Just do it.
Kill her!
Cap?
The bitch wouldn't open the door,
so I had to fry her.
Move!
What the fuck was that?
It's a long story.
Start it up.
I'll get the virus.
I'm missing you already.
we're in business.
Full power!
We're leaving!
I don't want to be
one of those things...
walking around without a soul.
You won't.
When the time comes...
you'll take care of it.
No one else is going to die.
Here.
Rain.
I'm not dead yet.
I think I'll have that back.
I could kiss you, you bitch.
What the hell's going
on back there?
- Get us the fuck out of here.
- Any faster, we'll come off the rails.
Open the doors!
Now!
I failed all of them.
I failed.
Listen to me. There is
nothing else you could've done.
The Corporation's guilty here,
not you.
And we finally have the proof.
And that way,
Umbrella can't get...
away with this.
I mean, we can...
What is it?
You're infected, but you'll be okay.
I'm not losing you.
- Help!
- Help him! What are you doing?
He's mutating.
I want him in the Nemesis Program.
Get off!
What's happening?
I want her quarantined.
Close observation...
and a full series of blood tests.
Let's see if she's infected.
Take her to the
Raccoon City facility.
Then assemble the team.
We're reopening the Hive.
I want to know
what went on down there.
Just do it.
Who's in there?
Let me out!