** [ Fanfare ]
[ Narrator ]
Young people from all over the globe...
are joining up
to fight for the future.
- I'm doing my part.
I'm doing my part.
I'm doing my part too!
[ Laughter ]
They're doing their part. Are you?
Join the Mobile Infantry and save the
world. Service guarantees citizenship.
The Bugs send another meteor our way.
But this time, we're ready.
Planetary defences are better than ever.
Klendathu, source of the Bug
meteor attacks...
orbits a twin star system
whose brutal gravitational forces...
produce an unlimited supply
of Bug meteorites in the form
of this asteroid belt.
To ensure the safety
of our solar system...
Klendathu must be eliminated.
We break net now and take you live
to Klendathu...
where the invasion has begun!
[ Man ] D XQ uplink on.
Two, one... you're on!
We've just landed here on what
cap troopers are calling Big "K"...
with the Sixth Mobile
Infantry Division.
- It's an ugly planet, a Bug planet...
- [ Roaring ]
a planet hostile to life
as we know it--
Aaaah!
Help me!
- Go!
- We've got to keep moving!
[ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Gunfire ]
- [ Roaring ]
- Die! Die!
- Come on!
- Go! Go! Go!
- Keep moving!
- Get out of here now!
- [ Troopers Yelling, Indistinct ]
- [ Roaring Continues ]
Run! Run!
[ Screaming ]
Kitten! No!
Aaah--
[ Gasping, Groaning ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Man ]
Rico.
Rico!
Pay attention.
Sorry, Mr Rasczak.
Let's sum up. This year,
we explored the failure of democracy...
how the social scientists brought
our world to the brink of chaos.
We talked about the veterans,
how they took control...
and imposed the stability
that has lasted for generations since.
You know these facts.
But have I taught you anything
of value this year? Hmm?
You. Why are only citizens
allowed to vote?
It's a reward-- what the Federation
gives you for doing Federal Service.
No. No.
Something given has no value.
When you vote, you are
exercising political authority.
You're using force.
Force, my friends, is violence...
the supreme authority from which
all other authority is derived.
Uh, my mother always said
violence never solves anything.
Really?
I wonder what the city fathers
of Hiroshima would say about that.
You.
They probably wouldn't say anything.
Hiroshima was destroyed.
Correct. Naked force
has resolved more issues...
throughout history
than any other factor.
The contrary opinion,
that violence never solves anything...
is wishful thinking
at its worst.
People who forget that
always pay.
Rico, what's the moral difference,
if any...
between a civilian
and a citizen?
A citizen accepts personal
responsibility for the safety
of the body politic...
defending it with his life.
- A civilian does not.
- Exact words of the text.
But do you understand it?
Do you believe it?
- I don't know.
- Of course you don't.
I doubt anyone here
would recognize civic virtue...
if it reached up
and bit you in the ass.
[ Bell Rings ]
- [ Students Chattering ]
- [ Chuckles ]
Not here.
Come on. Let's see
if they posted the math final.
- Rico. We gonna take Tesla?
- We're gonna kill 'em.
[ Woman On P.A. ] Remember,
all graduating seniors must go--
First thing Fleet Academy looks at
is your math scores.
Wish me luck.
- [ Beep ]
- [ Student ] Way to go.
- Good job.
- [ Chuckles ] Your turn.
Hold on.
I want to talk to Marco.
- His sister's at Fleet. Marco!
- Hi, Carmen.
- [ Carmen ]
What'd you hear about Roxie?
- [ Marco ] She made pilot.
[ Beep ]
Thirty-five percent!
Very nice.
- Look at that!
- [ Students Laughing, Applauding ]
Thirty-five percent,
ladies and gentlemen.
- Big numbers.
- Carl!
Sorry.
[ Students Continue Chattering ]
So, you haven't done it yet,
have you? Don't lie!
I'm not in any hurry.
Others are waiting.
- [ Giggling ]
- Did you read her mind?
Don't have to.
It's pretty clear what she wants.
Yeah, but I want Carmen.
Aw, you got it bad.
Hey, don't forget about this afternoon.
He's always late when he
walks you home to fish for a kiss.
[ Laughs ]
Get out of here.
- Marco's sister made pilot!
- So will you.
I mean, imagine flying
a half a million tons of starship.
You gotta have nerves of steel.
Yeah, you do.
Let's see how yours hold up.
[ Woman ]
You may begin!
[ Grunts ]
[ Groans ]
- Ohh.
- Oh, come on. It's just a bug.
- Better put your goggles on.
-Just a bug. Ha!
We humans like to think we are
nature's finest achievement.
I'm afraid it just isn't true.
This Arkellian Sand Beetle
is superior in many ways.
It reproduces in vast numbers...
has no ego, has no fear...
doesn't know about death...
and, so, is the perfect,
selfless member of society.
But humans have created art,
mathematics and interstellar travel.
[ Gulps ]
True, but before you
let that go to your head,
take the example of the Arachnids...
a highly evolved
insect society.
By human standards
they are relatively stupid...
but their evolution
stretches over millions of years.
-And now they can colonize planets...
- Here. Take this.
by hurling their spore
into space.
[ Rico ]
Yeah, I think we got it.
- There's the heart...
- [ Gulping ]
and here's the stomach.
[ Laughing ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Dizzy ]
Nerves of steel, huh? [ Laughs ]
[ Computer Beeps ]
[ Sighs ] Don't think about it.
Just go on instinct.
Try to visualize it.
I see the ace of spades.
[ Computer Beeps ]
Uhh.
Statistically speaking, you should have
accidentally guessed right by now.
[ Yawns ]
Try another.
So, my psychic abilities
are zero and I'm unlucky.
- [ Computer Beeps ]
- No, luck's not a factor.
No one really knows why some people
are sensitive and some aren't.
Who knows? Maybe it's
a new stage of human evolution.
That's why they do
these kind of Federal studies.
Cyrano!
Ah, shit. Time out.
Aw, he just wants some attention.
You don't play with him any more.
Cyrano!
- Go bug Mom, Cyrano.
- [ Chitters ]
How do you make him do that?
Oh, I gave him the impression
there's a grub crawling up my mom's leg.
He's on a mission
to go eat it.
- [ Mom ] Oh! Get off my leg.
- [ Chittering, Metal Clanging ]
[ Mom ]
Oh! Carl!
I sure hope you don't do
anything like that to me.
Don't be afraid.
Can't do human. Yet.
[ Crowd Screaming, Cheering ]
All right!
Yeah! Yeah!
[ Announcer ]
The score is now 41 to 38.
Tigers lead with 2.:46 remaining
here at the Buenos Aires Sports Arena.
- Time out.: Giants.
- Are you all right?
- Much better now.
- Good.
[ Crowd, Team Cheering ]
Hey! Your helmet!
So, what are you doing
after the game?
[ Laughs ] Well, everyone's
going to the dance. Aren't you?
- I don't know.
It's my last night as a civilian.
- Number 12, let's go!
Ship off to Tereshkova tomorrow.
- You're going to the Fleet Academy?
- Uh-huh.
- That's where I want to go!
- [ Man ] Come on, number 12!
Let's play ball.
Don't get any ideas
about my girlfriend!
All is fair in love and war.
- Giants! Giants!
-Johnny! Yeah!
Hut! Hut!
[ Cheerleaders Cheering ]
- Woo!
- Take that!
[ Announcer ]
Just under 22 seconds remaining.
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- Yeah!
[ Dizzy ] All right, let's go.
Irving, Latham, cover the rook.
Perry, fake left.
Ricoli, you go long.
Rico, flip six, three hole.
Got it?
Hey! Rico!
- Hey!
- What?
You're drifting!
Flip six, three hole on one. Got it?
Just throw me the ball, Diz.
- Ready? Break!
- [ Team Grunts ]
[ Diz Shouting ]
Two! Six!
- Climb left!
- Screen!
Hut!
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- Yeah! Go! Go! Go!
All right!
- [ Buzzer Sounds ]
- [ Cheering Continues ]
- Yeah!
[ Blows Whistle ]
He's in there! It's over!
** [ Marching Band ]
[ Shouting ]
Who said you could
grow up so fast?
Mom, don't get mushy.
This came for you today.
I presume, at your request.
A lot of my friends
are doing Federal Service.
Well, you're not
thinking of applying?
Have you lost your mind?
I'd rather take ten lashes in Public
Square than see you ruin your life.
It's a term of service.
It's not a career.
I just want
to get out on my own...
see the galaxy
for a couple of years.
Johnny, people get killed
in the Federal Service.
Who gave you this idea?
It's that teacher, isn't it?
What's his name?
You know the one I'm talking about.
Mr Rasczak.
Rasczak?
[ Chuckles ]
Silly name.
There should be a law against using
a school as a recruiting station.
No. Rasczak doesn't
do that at all.
He sort of discourages you.
Well, that's good, 'cause you're going
to Harvard and that's the end of it.
It's my decision not yours.
- Oh, is that how it is?
- Wait, you two.
Dad and I have a surprise for you
that will settle this.
- Can you guess what it is?
- No.
You wanted to see the galaxy?
How about a trip
to the Outer Rings?
Zegema Beach. Huh?
- I've always wanted to go there.
- Good. Then it's all settled.
[ Rock ]
* Into it, into your head *
* Save it
Sell one *
* Mix it
Hang these *
* Leftover waste--**
Sure. Don't go away.
[ Rico ]
I'm just gonna go see Mr Rasczak.
Hey, Rico.
You wanna dance?
Actually, Diz,
I promised Carmen--
Aw, come on. Too bad for her.
She's not around.
It's sad-- after tonight, most of us
probably won't see each other again.
So, you still gonna play for Rio?
Yeah, looks like.
Unless Tokyo lets me start.
Well, anyone who gets you is lucky.
Johnny, how come
we never got together?
Can't we just be friends, Diz?
Sure.
- Okeydokey.
- Nice seeing you.
Look, Diz,
I want to talk to Mr Rasczak.
Well, you'd better hurry up
if you want to catch him.
You're the best.
Hey.
[ Chuckles ]
- Mr Rasczak!
- What is it, Rico?
I want to thank you. Your class
was the best one I had this year.
Well, it's really not my job to please.
I just hope you learned something.
I want to join up. I think
I got what it takes to be a citizen.
Good for you.
Go find out.
Well, my parents are against it.
I know it's my choice.
I was wondering.
What would you do if you were me?
Figuring things out for yourself
is the only freedom anyone really has.
Use that freedom.
Make up your own mind, Rico.
* [ Light Salsa ]
* Ah-oh *
* But I have not been
to paradise *
* Ah-lay-oh *
* No, I have not been
to paradise *
* Watch the days go by *
* All is well *
[ Carmen Laughing ]
Don't exaggerate.
You have really
beautiful eyes.
Johnny!
- This is Zander.
- Yeah, we know
each other from the game.
- No hard feelings?
- Oh, none at all. We won.
Come on, Carmen.
It's the last dance.
Well, maybe I'll see you
at the Academy.
Yeah. Who knows?
Good luck.
- [ Sighs ]
- Zander's going for pilot too.
You two have so much in common.
Johnny Rico.
Are you jealous?
Well, maybe.
You don't have to be jealous.
* No, I have not been
to paradise *
Hey, hey!
Break it up, you two!
There's a place
for that sort of thing.
[ Sighs ]
I've been thinking,
and I'm gonna do it, Carmen.
I'm gonna go for Federal Service.
That's great! Carl and I
are signing up tomorrow. Come with us.
I will.
* Walk about
Watch the days go by *
My father's not home tonight.
* All is well *
* Talk about
Watch the days go by *
* All is well *
* Twenty-third century guys *
* All is well **
[ Recruits ]
...of my own free will...
after having been duly advised
and warned...
of the meaning and consequences
of this oath...
enrol in the Federal Service
for not less than two years...
and as much longer as may be required
by the needs of the Federation.
Thank you.
Fresh meat for the grinder, eh?
- So, how'd you kids do?
- I'm gonna be a pilot.
Well, good for you.
We need all the pilots we can get.
- Hey, did you get Starside R&D?
- No.
- I don't believe it.
- I got Games and Theory.
Games and Theory?
That's Military Intelligence.
Way to go, Carl.
Next time we meet,
I'll probably have to salute you.
Hmm.
What about you, son?
- Infantry, sir.
- Good for you.
Mobile Infantry
made me the man I am today.
[ P.A. ] All recruits report
to the Federal Transportation
Hub within 2 4 hours.
- Welcome to the adventure
of Federal Service.
- [ Laughing ]
Let's make a vow.
No matter what,
we'll always be friends.
I'll go for that.
Well, chances are
we'll never see each other again.
We'll be millions of light-years
away from each other.
But, uh, yeah, sure.
Why not?
You'll resign.
That's all there is to it!
It may look bad, but if that's
the worst you suffer, then that's fine.
- I won't quit.
- I'm telling you, you will.
You're not going back.
You're going on vacation!
I am not going on vacation!
I want to be a citizen.
My decision.
I made it.
You walk out that door, you are cut off,
young man. You understand me?
All right! That's it!
You are cut off!
Johnny, why won't you
change your mind?
Does citizenship
mean that much to you?
Well, yeah. Sure.
I hope so.
I hope you don't ruin your life
over some silly little girl...
who wants to look handsome
in a uniform.
- Don't talk about Carmen that way!
-Johnny!
[ Woman On P.A. ] Your attention,
please. Outbound troops 13-A--
[ P.A. Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Man ]
Do you have everything? Great.
[ Carmen ]
Johnny.
- You're late.
- My dad had to help me pack.
Suddenly, he's afraid he's never
gonna see me again or something.
It was sweet,
but it took forever. Ohh.
Anyway, I guess
I'm ready to go.
Yeah, me, too.
I'm wearing everything I own.
I'm sorry your parents were mad.
Who cares?
The Federation'll give me everything
I need for the next two years, right?
You talk to Carl?
Yeah, he left this morning.
Couldn't say where.
Oh, it's exciting going away.
But I'm scared.
Aren't you?
[ Sighs ]
I'm gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss you too.
I love you.
[ Woman On P.A. ] Outbound group 94-A,
Tereshkova, all sections--
That's me.
Just say it once.
Try it on for size.
I love you.
- Don't forget to write.
- I won't.
** [ Fanfare ]
Fully automatic Morita.
Who wants to hold it?
- Me! Me!
- [ Narrator ] Citizen rule.
People making a better tomorrow.
- Pow!
- Mine!
- Gimme!
[ Laughing ]
A murderer was captured
this morning and tried today.
Guilty.
Sentence.: death.
Execution.: tonight at 6.:00.
If you think you're psychic...
maybe you are.
Federal studies are being
conducted in your community.
Every school kid knows
that Arachnids are dangerous.
[ Screeching ]
However, Mormon extremists
disregarded Federal warnings...
and established Port Joe Smith deep
inside the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.
Too late, they realized that
Dantana had already been chosen
by other colonists--
Arachnids.
[ Cadets ]
One, two, three, four!
[ Man ] Most of you will not live
to be in the Mobile Infantry.
The trouble is, you are not
good enough the way you are.
Hands at your side!
Chin up! I am your senior
drill instructor, Career Sergeant Zim.
Suck in that gut!
Feet together!
To think this had to happen to me.
What a bunch of apes.
No, strike that!
You don't rate that good!
Never in my life have I seen--
- [ Chuckling ]
- Do you think I'm funny?
- Do I make you laugh?
Do you think I'm a comedian, son?
- I'm sorry.
The first words and the last words out
of your stinking holes will be "sir"!
- Do you get me?
- Sir, yes, sir!
See that armoury?
Run around it!
- [ Groans ]
- Run, I said! Run! Run! Run!
- Bronski, keep pace!
- Move!
[ Zim ] Now, any time
you think I'm being too tough...
any time you think
I'm being unfair...
any time you miss your mommy, quit!
You sign form 1240-A,
you grab your gear, you take
a stroll down Washout Lane.
- Do you get me?
- Sir, yes, sir!
Pathetic! I wonder if there's a handful
of guts in the whole bunch of you.
Now...
who here thinks they got
what it takes to knock me down?
Sir, I guess maybe I do, sir!
[ Growls ]
Aaah!
- [ Bone Snaps ]
-Ah, God! [ Groaning ]
- You all right, son?
- Sir, yes, sir!
It's my arm.
I reckon it's broken, sir.
Medic!
Pain is in your mind!
- Who's next?
- [ Dizzy ] Sir.
Recruit Flores
reporting for duty, sir.
You specifically requested transfer from
Fort Cronkite to this training unit?
- Sir, I heard it was the best, sir!
- It is the best.
But what makes you think
you're good enough?
Now, that's the kind of gal
who makes squad leader.
That's my job
you're talking about.
- Huh!
- Come on!
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasping ]
You know, I'd like to kill
that Sergeant Zim.
Whoa! Improper attitude! They'll
kick you out for talking like that.
Bye-bye. There you go,
down Washout Lane.
Yup. Either you got
what it takes or you don't.
- Hey, there is a line!
- Wait your turn, Ace.
Hey. At ease, little soldier.
It's all the same muck.
Get in line like everyone else.
[ Laughs ]
You got some guts for a rich kid.
I guess you and me
could be buddies.
What d'ya say?
- I'm honoured.
- Hey!
Of course you are!
Everybody should have a friend like me.
- Come on, Ace!
Back of the line, man.
- Back, back, back, back!
- What a jerk, man.
- Tough guy.
Whoo.
Hey, Rico.
Want to sit together?
No, thanks, Diz.
What's your malfunction, Rico?
You are.
I joined up to get out on my own,
and you had to tag along.
You think I joined
the Mobile Infantry because of you?
You saying you didn't?
Hi.
[ Rico ] Forget about it, Ace.
You don't stand a chance.
What makes you even think you're going
to make squad leader, Rico?
Something I've got you don't.
- You rich kids are all the same.
- It isn't about that.
- It's about who's the best.
- [ Dizzy ] Hey!
[ Both Grunting ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Zim ]
First squad!
Sir, I don't understand.
Who needs a knife
in a nuke fight anyway?
All you gotta do
is push a button. Sir.
Cease fire!
Put your hand
on that wall, Trooper!
Put your hand on that wall!
Aah!
[ Groaning ]
The enemy cannot push a button
if you disable his hand.
Medic!
Hand me that towel, will ya?
Ah, well. We all have
one thing in common.
We were all stupid enough
to sign up for Mobile Infantry.
Breckinridge, what's your excuse?
My family's all farmers.
I hate farming.
Mobile Infantry?
It's like pure picnic by comparison.
All right, so they grow 'em big
and dumb on the farm planet, huh?
- [ Man ] And pretty!
- [ Woman ] I like big.
- Djana'd, what about you?
- Oh, I'm goin' in for politics.
And, you know, you gotta be a citizen
for that, so here I am.
- Ah, you want some responsibility.
- Yeah.
Shujumi! C'mon.
Let's keep it going.
I got into Harvard,
but my father says, "Forget it."
It's gonna cost an arm
and a leg, you know?
So, if I serve,
Federation pays my way! Ha-ha!
I want to have babies. It's a lot easier
to get a licence if you serve, so--
I'm going career.
Officer's training. All the way.
Ah, future sky marshal.
All right, Rico, your turn.
- Who asked you to be so nosy?
- What, I'm the bad guy?
I'm gonna be a writer.
A writer's got a right to be nosy.
Hey, Flores.
You know Rico from Buenos Aires.
- What's his story?
- Oh, uh...
he's here because of a girl.
- [ Cheering, Catcalls ]
- Oh, Rico! Lover boy!
[ Kitten ]
He's gettin'me excited!
He's gonna blow!
Is it you?
[ Rico ] This is where we live.
Not much, but it's home.
Right there, that's my bunk,
where I dream about you every night.
Boot's pretty tough.
Sometimes, I think I won't make it.
But then I think about
what you're doing, and I try harder.
[ Hooting, Hollering ]
- [ Farting Noise ]
- [ Rico ] Do you mind?
We try harder, baby!
We try harder!
Who knows? They might even
make me squad leader.
- ** [ "Taps" ]
- Uh-oh. Well, I better pack it in.
[ Screaming ]
- Write me!
- * I love you Carmen *
- I love you!
- I'm gonna kill you guys!
* So much **
Uhh. Bye!
Write me!
[ Door Opening ]
Orbit in five, Ibanez!
First one there gets to fly.
[ Both Giggling ]
- Locking it down.
- [ Man ] Wait! Wait!
Oh, no! Not Ibanez again!
She's crazy!
Ready! Go!
Yeah!
Deploying wings.
How come you're
in such a good mood? Huh?
'Cause today I get to fly that.
Pilot Trainee Ibanez
reporting for duty, ma'am.
- Take the number two chair, Ibanez.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Identify.
- Ibanez, T-3-2-5-A, clear.
[ Laughs ]
What are you doing here?
I'm the guy who's gonna teach you
to fly this crate.
Ah. Assistant instructor.
Should I call you "sir"?
Only when I give you an order.
Prepare for departure.
It's amazing, us running into each other
like this. Maybe it's fate.
Maybe not. I heard about this crazy girl
coming through the Academy.
Solid math, a little wild
on the stick but a natural.
When it turned out to be you,
I just made sure that
we would run into each other.
[ Woman On P.A. ] Rodger Young,
cleared for undocking and departure.
All right, Ibanez.
Take her out.
Yes, ma'am.
[ P.A. ]
All systems go.
[ Engines Roaring ]
In simulation,
my supervisors could never keep up.
Well, this isn't simulation any more,
so take her out easy, Cadet.
Yes, sir.
[ Computer ]
Five metres from object.
Three metres from object.
Clear.
- Don't exceed port speed.
- Or what?
Or they revoke
your flight status... and mine.
Your career is in my hands.
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
Prepare for warp.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Number One, design for Jupiter orbit.
[ Man On P.A. ] All crew, all sections.
Stand by to cut in C-drive--
[ Zander ]
Stellar drive in...
- five, four...
- ready, steady, go!
- three, two, one.
[ Grunting ]
Aah!
I'm goin' in! Move!
Man, they're defended!
No way in!
[ Laughing, Hooting ]
- Flip six, three hole.
- What?
We run a flip six, three hole play,
and you can score.
- Cover me!
- You got it.
Now!
- Thanks, buddy!
- Bastard!
Yeah!
The kid's got some moves.
Give him a squad.
See what he can do.
[ Cadets Laughing, Chattering ]
[ Pool Balls Clattering ]
Someone's got to teach you guys
how to play some pool here.
Look at him. You ever seen anybody
so pleased with himself?
Well, Zim must've had to choose someone
to be his brown-nose.
I couldn't have done it
without you, Diz.
Friends?
Friends.
[ Bronski ]
Mail call! Levy!
- Yeah, that's me.
- Shujumi!
- Here.
- Rico.
- Breckinridge.
- Nyla.
- Yeah, here I am.
[ Nyla ]
Oh, great. My dad.
[ Bronski ]
That's all, folks.
Hi,Johnny. I'm sorry I haven't
written you sooner, but--
- Oh, Rico! You don't
deserve that! Ho, ho!
- Shh!
They've really got us going. They must
have made you squad leader by now.
And if they haven't,
tell 'em to talk to me.
See? All it takes
is the love of a good woman.
Now, that is a woman!
Look at that.
Isn't it beautiful?
I love it out here.
[ Sighs ] That's also
the problem, because...
I think I'm gonna go career.
I want a command,
a ship of my own and, you know...
I don't think that's gonna leave
a lot of room for you and me,Johnny.
I know that's not
what you wanted to hear...
but, uh...
I have to follow my heart.
I'm sorry.
Write me. All right?
Write me, so that I'll know
we'll always be friends.
[ Sighs ]
Funny how they always want to be friends
after they rip your guts out, huh?
Yeah.
Well, that's what I deserve.
What are you talkin' about?
I joined up for her. I wouldn't
even be here if it wasn't for her.
What are you talkin' about?
You made squad leader on your own.
And, hey, you still got me
to kick around.
[ Zim ]
Fun and games are over, children!
You will be firing live ammunition
in a simulated combat environment.
You will exercise extreme caution
on my assault course!
- Do you get me?
- Sir, yes, sir!
Rico, take 'em out.
First fire team with me.
Next team in ten seconds!
Maximum score has been 2 80.
I expect you to do better.
- [ Buzzer Sounds ]
- Go!
[ All Yelling ]
[ Rico ]
Stay low! Keep moving!
Shujumi, stay down!
Hey! Goddamn it, Breckinridge!
Clear my line of fire!
It's my helmet.
It's all screwed up.
- You're gonna blow the score!
- Man!
- Dumb shit!
- Diz, stay put! What's the problem?
Damn thing keeps getting in my way!
How come whenever
something goes wrong,
it's always you, Breckinridge?
- It must be 'cause I'm big and dumb!
- Yeah, right!
Ohh!
Medic!
[ Zim ] Rico! You are relieved
of squad command!
[ Man ] Rico, did you give the recruit
permission to remove his helmet?
Sir, yes, sir. Breckinridge
reported a helmet malfunction,
and I asked him to show me, sir.
Are you rated to repair
the M-3 tactical helmet, Rico?
Sir, no, sir!
Then why did you order your man
to remove his helmet
during a live fire exercise?
Sir, I needed everyone
in my squad operational, sir!
I wanted to win, sir!
[ C.O. ] Sergeant, we've already lost
two recruits over this incident.
Think there's any possibility
of salvaging this man?
Yes, sir, I do.
All right.
We'll try administrative punishment.
Prisoner, halt!
Bite down on this, son.
It helps. I know.
[ C.O. On P.A. ]
For incompetence of command...
for failure to abide
by safety regulations
during a live fire exercise...
for negligence which contributed
to the death of a teammate...
Recruit TraineeJohn Rico is sentenced
to administrative punishment.
Ten lashes.
You may carry out the sentence.
[ Bronski ]
One!
- Two!
- [ Muffled Groans ]
Three!
Four!
Five!
- Six!
- [ Groaning ]
Seven!
- [ Whip Cracks ]
- Eight!
- Nine!
- [ Whip Cracks ]
- Ten!
[ Man ] All sections secure. EBX is
high-normal. Switch to slave on my mark.
- Mark.
- [ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Thanks. You read my mind.
Oh, third watch
always seems to last forever.
I don't know. Depends on who
you're spending it with.
Something's wrong.
- There!
- No.
I replotted the course.
It's more efficient this way.
Three weeks aboard a starship
and you think you can lick my navs?
[ Laughs ]
Check it.
You know, I was talking with
Captain Deladier and, uh, she said--
Don't change the subject.
Am I right?
[ Sighs ]
Yeah. Yeah. You're right.
So, what did the captain say?
She thinks we should
team up officially...
and crew for her.
- You and me, huh?
- We're good together, Carmen.
We're way ahead of the curve
in every department.
I can anticipate you.
You know what I want.
No. What do you want?
[ Low Rumbling ]
There's a gravity field out there.
- Run a scan. Sensors on.
- There.
- [ Carmen ]
Gravity at 2-2-5 and rising.
- Report!
Captain, we are in the path
of an unidentified object
moving toward us at high speed.
Profile suggests
an asteroid, ma'am.
- [ Computer Beeping ]
- [ Zander ] Impact.:six seconds!
Emergency evasion!
Three...
two...
fire!
Close compartment 21!
Where'd it come from?
It came out of the
Arachnid Quarantine Zone, ma'am.
Number Four, contact Fleet.
Tell them there's a loose
asteroid headed their way.
Communications are down, ma'am.
They're gone.
- Damage assessment!
- Hull's compromised.
We're lucky to be alive, ma'am.
Luck didn't have anything
to do with it.
We have a hell of a flight team.
[ Sighs ]
It really stinks, you goin'.
Yeah, well, the Mobile Infantry'll
just have to get along without me.
[ Bag Zips ]
I don't get it, Rico.
You took your licks. If they didn't
want you, they would've kicked you out.
Hey!
I joined up for the wrong reasons.
I got a guy killed.
I figure that kinda proves
I don't have what it takes.
Rico, your call's goin' through.
Take it there.
Hello?
Oh,Johnny!
- Hi, Mom.
- B-Bill, pick it up. It's Johnny.
-Johnny?
- Dad.
- Where's your uniform?
- Bill!
It's just good to hear from you.
How are you, son?
It's not really
working out here for me, Dad.
I was thinking-- I was hoping
it would be all right if I came home.
Well, of c-- of course.
You should come home immediately.
I'm sorry.
I've been an idiot.
Don't talk like that.
Just come on home.
We'll talk things out.
We love you, son.
- My, what's that?
- Looks like rain.
- This time of the year?
- Sure is dark--
Your transmission has been terminated
due to atmospheric interference.
Please try your call again later.
I'll see ya.
Hey.
You take that stroll down Washout Lane,
you're only proving one thing.
What's that, Diz?
That you don't have what it takes
to be a citizen.
[ Shouting ]
- * Sound off *
- * Stand by *
[ Shouting, Singing Continues ]
Stand by!
Left, right, left!
[ Shouting Intensifies ]
Hold it!
What's happening?
Bombed!
Lost the whole city!
Hey, what's goin' on?
Wh-What's going on?
Hey, Kitten, what's goin' on?
War! We're goin' to war!
[ Narrator ] The devastation
we are seeing is unparalleled.
Judging from early estimates,
millions dead, a city in ruins.
Is that Geneva?
Goddamn bugs whacked us,Johnny.
[ Narrator ] The meteor was shot
out of orbit by Bug plasma...
that derived from Klendathu,
the Arachnid's home planet.
Nothing lives
in what was once called...
the Latin paradise.
Oh,Johnny, that's us.
[ Narrator ] Buenos Aires
has been wiped off the Earth.
It's home.
[ Narrator ] The Federal Council
met moments ago and voted unanimously...
for mobilization to destroy
the Arachnid threat.
- I'm serious. I'll go anywhere.
- Forget it, Zim. We need you here.
I want combat, sir!
The only way you're gonna see
combat is if you bust yourself
to private. Get me?
Yes, sir. I get you.
- Sir!
- What do you want, Rico?
-I wish to reconsider
my request to drop out, sir.
-You already signed your 1240-A.
- It wouldn't be legal.
- Major, I know it was wrong.
I didn't learn from one mistake,
and I made another, sir.
You made your decision, son.
Sir, my family-- my whole family
was in Buenos Aires, sir.
Is this your signature, Rico?
Sir, yes, it is, sir!
Doesn't look like it to me.
Carry on, Private.
Yes, sir!
[ Narrator ]
Out of the ashes of Buenos Aires...
comes first sorrow...
then anger.
The only good Bug
is a dead Bug.
In Geneva,
the Federal Council convenes.
We must meet the threat
with our valour, our blood...
indeed, with our very lives...
to ensure
that human civilization...
not insect...
dominates this galaxy
now and always.
[ Applause ]
Sky Marshal Dienes announces plans
for an offensive against Klendathu...
the source of the Bug meteor
that destroyed Buenos Aires.
Every day Federal scientists
are looking for new ways to kill Bugs.
Your basic Arachnid warrior isn't too
smart, but you can blow off a limb...
[ Screeching ]
and it's still
86% combat effective.
Here's a tip: Aim for the nerve stem
and put it down for good.
[ Narrator ]
Everyone's doing their part. Are you?
- Aah! Aah! Aah!
- Die! Die!
The war effort
needs your effort...
at work, at home,
in your community.
We now break net
and take you live...
to Fleet battle station Ticonderoga...
deep inside
the Arachnid Quarantine Zone...
where the men and women
of the Federal Armed Services...
prepare to attack.
[ Man ] D-X-Q uplink
on two, one. You're on.
No one here in the A.Q.Z.
knows exactly when the invasion
of Klendathu will occur...
but everyone's
talking about it...
and the talk says tomorrow.
Here's a bunch of M.I. kids that
look like they could eat Bugs for lunch.
[ Chuckles ]
Yum-yum-yum.
So, Trooper, you're not too worried
about fighting the Arachnids?
Hey, shoot a nuke down a Bug hole,
you got a lot of dead bugs.
I just hope it's not over
before we get some.
Some say the Bugs were provoked
by the intrusion of humans
into their natural habitat...
that a live-and-let-live policy
is preferable to war with the bugs--
Let me tell you somethin'. I'm from
Buenos Aires, and I say kill 'em all.
- Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
- Oh, yeah!
Big, bad Bugs, huh?
Hey, guys,
we oughta get tattoos.
- Let's all get cut together.
- What do I want a tattoo for?
- What, your skin's too pretty?
- Hey, Johnny!
Johnny Rico!
Carmen?
- Oh.
At ease. Guess I oughta
lose the hat when I'm off duty.
Hi, Diz.
Carmen.
My mother was right about you.
You look great in a uniform.
You look pretty good yourself.
So, what do you hear?
You know about anyone
who made it out of B.A. alive?
Most of the time,
I don't think about it...
like it happened
to someone else.
Then it hits me,
and I can't stop crying.
Well, we're still alive.
Gotta be happy about that.
You don't look very happy
to see me.
Should I be?
Johnny.
It's different now.
We're at war. I think what I did was
probably the best thing for both of us.
Everything copacetic, Lieutenant?
Zander, you remember Johnny.
Zander and I are a flight team now.
Yeah. Best in the fleet.
I get it.
This is the part
that's best for both of us.
Don't do me any more favours.
-Johnny, wait--
- Forget it, Lieutenant.
He's Mobile Infantry.
See, when you're
trained to kill...
it just doesn't pay
to be polite.
You got something to say
about the Mobile Infantry?
I think you heard me.
You wanna make something
of it... Private?
Not with an officer, no, sir.
The M.I. doesn't admit
stupid troopers.
- Well, let's disregard rank.
- Zander, please.
[ Trooper ]
You go, Rico.
Everybody hear that?
Rank is not an issue here!
- Don't do this.
- Come on. What's he gonna do?
[ Crowd Shouting ]
[ Groaning ]
Aaah!
Come on!
Jarheads!
I'm gonna kill you!
I'll kill you!
-Johnny, don't! Quit it!
- Come on!
He's not worth it!
Come on! Come on!
Forget it, Rico! Mobile Infantry
and Fleet don't mix. Come on.
Come on. Let's go.
Jarheads.
- [ Kitten ] Whoo-hoo!
- [ Ace ] Mobile Infantry rules!
- Yeah!
- Oh, God, that hurts!
Hey, well, I got somethin' that might
hurt just a little bit more, buddy.
- Aaah!
- Ohh!
- [ Laughs ]
Oh, yeah!
We're gonna fight, and we're gonna win!
[ All Yelling, Hooting ]
This is the captain speaking.
All personnel
prepare for drop.
We are at "T"minus three
and counting.
We are going in
with the first wave.
Means more Bugs
for us to kill.
You smash the entire area!
You kill anything that has more
than two legs! You get me?
We get you, sir!
- Plasma, ma'am, from the planet.
- Bug batteries.
According to Military Intelligence,
it'll be random and light.
- Drop status?
- Drop is... 35 percent complete, ma'am.
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
[ Groaning ]
[ Exhales ]
Remember your training...
and you will
make it back alive!
[ Retching ]
[ Exhaling ]
Whoooo-hoo!
This isn't random or light.
Someone made a mistake.
That's it.
We're empty, ma'am.
Someone made
a big goddamn mistake!
Break for high orbit!
[ Grunts ]
Aaah!
[ Shouting ]
Go! Go! Go!
Fall in!
Rockets up!
Rocket crew, move up!
- Nuke 'em! Levy! Rico!
- Heat 'em up!
- Set.
- Fire!
- Follow me!
- Let's go!
- [ Shouting Continues ]
- [ Gunfire ]
First Platoon, left flank!
Spread out!
First and second squads,
follow me!
Shoot cover!
Left, with me!
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Screeching ]
Fire!
Aaaah!
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Screeching Continues ]
Here they come!
- Ace, what are we doing?
- Uh, I-I don't know.
I don't know.
Kill them!
Kill them all!
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
You want some?
Here's some! Yeah!
Here's some of this!
[ Screaming ]
- Oh, my God!
- Shujumi!
No! No! No!
[ Screaming Continues ]
Help!
Help! Get it off!
No! God!
Let's get out of here!
Fall back!
[ Whimpering ]
[ Screaming, Groaning ]
[ Screeching ]
- [ On Radio ] Retreat!
All units, prep for retrieval!
- What's goin' on?
- Repeat! All units,
all battle stations!
- You got some?
- It's a general retreat!
Back to the boats!
- Come on! Let's go!
[ Shouting ]
[ Correspondent ]
We'vejust landed here on what
cap troopers are calling Big "K"...
with the Sixth Mobile
Infantry Division.
It's an ugly planet,
a Bug planet...
a planet hostile to life as we--
Aaaah!
Help me!
[ Screaming Continues ]
Cut right!
Come on!
Go, go, go!
Get outta here now!
- [ Bugs Screeching ]
- [ Shouting Continues ]
-Watch your step!
-Watch your flanks! Watch your flanks!
[ Bug Roars ]
[ Screaming ]
Kitten! No!
[ Groans ]
[ Screeching ]
Aaaah!
[ Groans ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Aaaaah!
[ Narrator ]
Crisis for humankind.
Fleet officials
admit they underestimated
the Arachnid's defensive capability.
Accepting responsibility
for Klendathu...
Sky Marshal Dienes resigns.
His successor, Sky Marshal Tahat Meru,
outlines her new strategy.
To fight the Bug...
we must understand the Bug.
We can ill afford
another Klendathu.
[ Narrator ] Federal scientists
struggle to explain...
the intelligent military actions
of the Arachnids.
When a colony
reaches a certain size--
300 generations or something--
it gets smarter.
Insects with intelligence?
Have you ever met one?
I can't believe
I am hearing this nonsense.
-Just wait a moment--
- This is the most ridiculous
conversation I have ever had--
Maybe there is some kind of bug
that we haven't seen yet--
a leadership caste
of hive brains.
Brain Bugs? Frankly, I find the idea
of a Bug that thinks offensive!
Ticonderoga, this is Rodger Young
requesting approach vector.
[ On Radio ]
Affirmative, Rodger Young.
One-zero-zero-niner-five-two.
Welcome back.
My God.
How could this happen?
We thought we were smarter
than the Bugs.
- [ Shouting, Chattering ]
- Gimme somethin'! Please!
It hurts!
[ Nurse ] A-positive!
We're gonna need two litres!
Be right with you.
[ Groaning ]
Help me.
God!
It's strange.
There's almost no wounded at all.
Bugs don't take prisoners.
Oh, no.
[ Trooper ]
Look!
- Carmen--
- [ Sobs ]
- Heh-heh. There he is.
- Let's wake him up.
- Hey,Johnny! Hey!
- [ Chuckling ]
Hey, Rico!
- [ Dizzy Pounding Glass ]
Hey, Johnny! Wake up!
- How you doin', fish boy?
Hey, look!
You're dead!
Killed in action!
- Three more days and you're out.
- Three days.
- Good as new. See you later.
- Bye.
So, what do you hear
about our new unit?
Roughnecks killed more Bugs
than any other outfit on Big "K."
Yeah, well, I hear their lieutenant
is a real nut-buster.
Who's top kick?
[ Weapon Cocks ]
You want the job, huh?
I wouldn't mind.
I would.
Just doin' my part.
Orders.
Yours?
Where you been besides Big "K"?
Outer Ring. Zegema Beach.
Zegema Beach.
I always wanted to go there.
Good luck.
It's not there any more.
So, I hear your lieutenant
is a real nut-buster.
No one talks about
the lieutenant that way.
- He saved my life.
- Mine too.
- Same for me.
- Me too.
Well, sounds like
he's quite a guy.
Who do you think
saved your ass?
[ Sergeant ]
Stand by.
Attention on deck.
This is for you new people.
I only have one rule.
Everyone fights.
No one quits.
You don't do your job,
I'll shoot you.
- Do you get me?
- We get you, sir!
Welcome to the Roughnecks.
- Rasczak's Roughnecks!
- [ All Grunt ]
At ease.
Listen up!
Got a new sky marshal
and a new battle plan.
Gonna clean out the systems outlying
Klendathu one planet at a time.
Tomorrow we hit
Tango Urilla.
After Fleet glasses the planet,
M.I. mops up.
Carry on.
[ Screeching, Roaring ]
All right, spread out!
Fire teams!
You locate a Bug hole, nuke it.
Watkins, take out Flores and Rico.
Copy that.
Move out!
[ Birdie ] First Platoon,
we're going for that ridge.
- Levy, you're with me.
- No, I'm with " A "squad.
I'm goin' with Rico.
Shut up and follow me!
[ Shrieking ]
[ Groans ]
[ Shrieking Weakly ]
Huh? You like that?
Monkey-sucking sack
of maggot puke!
It's dead, Watkins! It's dead!
Ain't much to look at
after you scrape 'em off your boot.
Bug hole. There.
[ Weapon Firing ]
[ Screeching, Roaring ]
Nuke 'em, Rico!
- [ Beeping ]
- Fire in the hole!
[ Birdie On Radio ]
We're under heavy attack, position M-4.
- Get over here!
- Move!
- You got a Bug problem, ma'am?
- Aw, stow it, Trooper!
Tanker!
- Oh, shit!
- Come on. Move!
Get down!
[ Screaming ]
Come on!
[ Grunting ]
- [ Beeping ]
- Aaaah!
[ Troopers Shouting,
Hooting, Cheering ]
[ Trooper Shouting, Laughing ]
- Come on.
- [ Grunting ]
[ Rasczak Grunts ]
Call for retrieval.
- Medic!
- Nice moves.
Where'd you learn
how to do that, soldier?
Back in school, sir.
Don't you remember?
I was captain of the team.
- Rico.
- Sir.
I need a corporal.
You're it until you're dead,
or until I find somebody better.
Thank you, sir.
- All right, saddle up!
- Way to go, Corporal!
Hey, I need a squad leader.
Oh, no. No.
I've been there. I blew it.
I'm just here to fight.
What about it, Diz?
Looks like I'm your girl, sir.
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Together ] Ooh-aaah!
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Laughing ] Catch ya later.
Go.
Listen up!
I expect the best,
and I give the best!
- Here's the beer!
- [ Cheering, Whistling ]
- Here's the entertainment!
- [ Shouting, Cheering Continues ]
Have fun!
That's an order!
[ Trooper ]
This one's for me!
- Whoo!
- Thank you, Lieutenant!
-** [ Violin.: "Dixie" ]
- Rico.
You kill Bugs good.
Thanks.
[ Cheering, Shouting Continue ]
You knew the lieutenant
before the war. What was he like?
-** [ Continues ]
- He was a teacher.
Kind of like he knew it all.
He always had this little smile.
Yeah, well,
he don't smile much any more.
Well, I guess your bottle fills up
real quick when your kids get smeared--
- Come on, Corporal.
- Oh, no. I don't do that any more.
- I remember when you
used to dance. Come on.
- Do I have to pull rank?
Excuse me, sir.
** [ Continues ]
Rico.
You once asked me for advice.
You want some now?
- Yes, sir.
- Lieutenant, H.Q.'s on the com.
Never pass up a good thing.
** [ Continues ]
- Watkins. Beer?
-** [ Ends ]
[ Applause, Cheering ]
** [ Slow Ballad ]
[ Giggles ]
So, Rico, what are you doin'
after the dance?
[ Grunts ]
[ Whispers ]
Come on.
[ Chuckles ]
What's so funny?
You know, just the way
things work out.
We finally got together, Diz.
I love you,Johnny.
[ Rasczak ]
Rico!
We're moving out.
There's been a distress call
from General Owen on planet "P."
- So get your shit wired
and report in ten minutes.
- Yes, sir.
Who's that with you?
Flores, sir.
Make it 20 minutes.
[ Rico ]
Yes, sir.
[ Giggles ]
Twenty minutes?
We can do it.
Whisky to Outpost.
Do you copy?
This is Roughneck Two-Zero
on tack three. Come in, please.
Whisky, Outpost. This is
Roughneck Two-Zero on tack three.
- Make contact with General Owen?
- No, sir.
Not even the transponder signal.
It's these canyons.
Go to higher ground, Sergeant.
Whisky, Outpost.
- This is Roughneck Two-Zero on--
- [ Screeching ]
[ Sergeant Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Sugar, your weapon.
Help me! H-- Aaah!
[ Screaming Continues ]
I'd expect anyone in this unit
to do the same for me.
- Rico.
- Sir.
You're acting sergeant.
Move 'em out.
You heard the lieutenant!
Saddle up!
[ Groans ]
Gee, someone really
humped the bunk.
- Watkins.
- Sir.
- Secure this compound.
Police these bodies.
- Yes, sir.
- Give me three up on the tower, now!
-Aye-aye!
O.P. there!
Siren Two, police up these bodies!
Whew. Stinks in there.
- Rico!
- Yes, sir.
We need retrieval.
This place crawls.
Get somebody in a communications tent
and get me an uplink.
Yes, sir.
Diz, check it out.
[ Rasczak ]
Command group with me.
Ah, shit.
Lieutenant.
Dirty Bugs came in
right while they were having chow.
Ugh.
Yeah.
This is where they got in.
Lieutenant.
I think you're gonna
want to see this.
What do you got, Flores?
[ Ace ]
God, I hate this place.
What's that look like
to you, Rico?
Looks like a Bug
was in his brain, sir.
[ Squish ]
[ Gasps, Swallows ]
They sucked his brains out.
[ Crash ]
[ Rattling, Crashing ]
Open that.
Aaaah! Aaah!
Officer on the deck!
- Pick up the general.
- [ General ] Cohen?
- Is it safe?
We gotta get out of here!
- General.
Sir!
[ Exhales ]
Thank God for you.
- All of you.
- [ Muttering ] Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
You're all gonna be heroes,
every last one of you.
Close that hole.
Yes, sir.
I had to evade capture.
- The security of the Federation
was at stake.
- Fire in the hole!
[ Explosion ]
I have operational knowledge
of what we're up to out here.
- Flores, I need that uplink.
- Working on it, sir.
- Damn it.
- [ General ] See?
They get in your mind.
Look. They did it to Farley.
They got into his mind.
They make you do things.
They made Farley
call headquarters.
The distress call was a trap.
They're just like us.
They want to know what makes us tick.
They wanna know us
so they can kill us.
Roughnecks, this is Lead.
Prepare for attack.
Where's the retrieval boat?
Mayday. This is Roughneck Two-Zero
to battle group. Do you read?
Oh, God!
We're gonna die!
Don't you understand?
We're all gonna die!
[ Groaning ]
Control yourself, General.
I can't. I can't.
I wish you'd just shoot me.
- [ Weapons Cocks ]
- [ Whimpers ]
Lieutenant! He's just
a little out of his mind, sir.
Bugs! Bugs!
- Die! [ Whimpers ]
- All right.
Warm it all up!
Everything you've got!
Come on, you apes!
You wanna live forever?
[ Trooper ]
I got Bugs!
[ Shouting ]
[ Screeching ]
- [ Trooper ] Magazine!
- [ Weapons Cocking ]
Fire at will!
Yaaaah!
Incoming!
Ohh! Ohh!
Aaaah!
No! Aaah!
[ Troopers Shouting ]
Rico!
Where's my communications?
- Diz, status on the uplink?
- Give me a minute!
We don't have a minute!
- Battle Group,
this is Roughneck Two-Zero.
- This is Rodger Young. Go ahead.
We are under attack, sir.
We need retrieval now!
- We have planet "P"as clear.
- This place crawls, sir.
We need pickup now!
- What's your position?
- Come down on this transmission.
- The outpost? That's crazy!
- I hope you have a crazy pilot! Out!
[ Yelling ]
Lieutenant!
Boat coming down, sir!
Fall back into the compound!
Fall back!
Hold here!
Hold what you got!
Aaaah!
Running low!
- [ Chamber Clicking ]
- I'm out!
Here! Make 'em count!
Make cover fire!
Fall back!
Move! Move! Move!
Fall back to the boat!
Haul ass!
[ Rumbling ]
Yaaaah!
[ Grunting ]
Aaah! Aaah!
- Oh, my God!
- Ohh!
[ Screaming ]
- Get him clear!
- Aaah!
Rico-- Aaaah! Rico!
- You know what to do!
- Yes, sir!
[ Weapon Cocks ]
Do it, Rico!
Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
Dizzy!
No! No!
[ Screaming ]
- No!
- [ Coughing, Groaning ]
Ace, help me!
Hold her down!
[ Screaming ]
Move! Get her into the boat!
- [ Coughing ]
- Come on, Diz. Don't die on me.
Get her out!
Let's go! Let's go!
[ Trooper ]
Go, go, go!
Let's go!
Get aboard!
Tower, let's go!
Let's move it, Tower! Run!
Lift off!
[ Gagging ]
Johnny, I'm dying-- dying.
No. You're gonna be
all right, Diz.
[ Gasping ]
It's all right...
because I got to have you.
[ Quiet Sob ]
[ Panting, Gagging ]
[ Coughing ]
Johnny, don't let me go!
J--J--
[ Coughing ]
Don't let-- Don't let--
[ On Radio ]
This is Battle Control.
Proceed on vector
five-niner-two-two-seven.
I think you should know...
your friend Rico is back there.
Get on the com and tell Fleet
to blast that rock.
On whose authority, Corporal?
That would be mine, sir.
I assumed command of the mission.
Rodger Young,
we have an official request...
by the Mobile Infantry...
to commence bombardment
of planet "P."
I thought you were dead.
I'm not, but a lot
of my troopers are.
Negative on your request. The sky
marshal has other plans for planet "P. "
Welcome back.
M.I. does the dying,
and Fleet just does the flying.
Hold on.
Something's up.
Fleet's mobilized
for a big operation.
Attention on deck!
Once, somebody asked me...
if I knew the difference
between a citizen and a civilian.
I can tell you now.
A citizen has the courage
to make the safety of the human race...
their personal responsibility.
Dizzy was my friend.
She was a soldier...
but more than that...
she was a citizen
of the Federation.
Present arms!
Order arms!
Left face!
- Officer on deck.
- Carry on.
Burial detail, dismissed.
At ease.
How are you, Carl?
Carmen, good.
Johnny, I'm sorry
it had to be your unit on "P."
That mission had
a very low survival probability.
The Bugs laid a trap for us,
didn't they?
Elegant proof of intelligence,
isn't it?
I thought there might be
a Brain Bug on "P."
You knew, and you sent them anyway?
We couldn't afford to launch
an operation if there wasn't one.
You don't approve.
Well, too bad.
We're in this for the species,
boys and girls. It's simple numbers.
They have more...
and every day I have to make decisions
that send hundreds of people
like you to their deaths.
Didn't they tell you, Colonel?
That's what
the Mobile Infantry's good for.
I hope you're ready for more.
We're going back to "P"
to capture that Brain.
The Roughnecks
are always ready, sir.
I hear they need a new lieutenant.
Want the job?
I'll take it, until I get killed
or you find someone better.
[ Sighs ]
Well?
Take care of yourself,Johnny.
I'll see you again.
Officer on deck!
Who are all these kids?
We got reinforced.
Most of them
are fresh out of boot.
We're the old men, Ace.
This is for all you new people.
I only have one rule:
Everyone fights.
No one quits.
You don't do your job,
I'll kill you myself.
- Do you get me?
- We get you, sir!
Welcome to the Roughnecks.
- Rico's Roughnecks!
- [ Soldiers Shout ]
Today we're gonna pay
a visit to Bug City.
We're lookin' for a Bug
no one's ever seen before.
Some kind of smart Bug.
[ Whooshing ]
And it probably knows we're coming.
Saddle up!
- Saddle up! Hyah!
- [ Shouting ]
Go, go, go, go, go!
Evasive action.
Get us clear for warp, Number Two.
Clear in five, four...
- Initiating star drive in five--
- three--
[ Yelling ]
[ Screaming ]
This is Rodger Young.
We're going down.
- Repeat. This is Rodger Young.
- Get out!
Abandon ship! Come on!
- Aaaaah!
- Zander!
- Here!
- We've got to get to
the rescue deck!
Come on!
[ Grunting ]
Aaaah!
- Captain!
-Aaaah!
[ Groaning ]
Abandon ship.
That's an--
[ Sighs ]
She's dead, Carmen!
She's dead!
[ Screaming, Shouting ]
- Here!
- [ Shouting Continues ]
Follow me!
Ready?
- Hit it!
- [ Engine Starting, Accelerating ]
Life pod Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
Scanning for a landing zone.
Checking terrain. Here!
- Can you handle that?
- Piece of cake.
[ On Radio ]
We've lost the Rodger Young.
Flight Command, we have confirmation.
The Rodger Young is down.
Aww!Johnny!
[ Grunts ]
Johnny!
Rodger Young just burned up.
It's on the rescue net.
[ Radio Chatter, Static ]
Any survivors?
Well, they're gettin'
tarred up there pretty bad.
Life pod Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
Is anyone receiving?
- [ Carmen ] Is anyone receiving?
- Affirmative!
- This is Roughneck Two-Zero.
- You're breaking up. Say again.
- Carmen?
- Say again! I'm losing you!
Carmen!
Prepare for landing!
Retro in three, two, one.
Fire!
Carmen. Carmen.
- Hey. You okay?
- Uh-huh.
Get out. Get out.
[ Hushed Screech ]
[ Radio Static ]
Are you receiving? Over.
This is Roughneck Two-Zero.
Carmen! Are you receiving?
Johnny, is that you?
Yeah, it's me!
What's your position and situation?
We're in Bug City,
20 metres underground, position:
south 42, east 118.
- Situation is--
- [ Hissing ]
[ Rico ]
I repeat, south 4 2, east 118.
[ Roaring ]
[ Rico ]
Carmen!
Situation is extremely hostile.
I need a squad to pull 'em out!
Direction!
Three clicks, south by southwest.
Look out!
[ Roaring, Snarling ]
[ Screaming ]
Aaaaah!
[ Radio.:Static ]
What do you wanna do?
You heard the lieutenant!
Rescue party!
Third squad, come with me!
Cancel that!
You know as well as I do
she's already dead.
Sorry, buddy.
Roughnecks, let's move.
All right.
[ Screeching ]
Aaaaaah!
[ Groans ]
Why didn't they kill us?
They want us alive.
We should go this way.
"A" company's that way.
Yeah...
but Carmen's down there.
Hey, I hate to be rude, buddy...
but word has it she's dead.
- She's still alive.
- How do you know?
I don't know how I know, but I know.
Listen, you got command,
but goin'off mission...
that's a serious offence.
Yeah. I think
they hang you for that.
Roughneck Two-Zero,
proceed on mission.
I need two volunteers.
[ Sighs ]
[ Screeching ]
Aaah!
[ Groaning ]
[ Roaring, Gurgling ]
One day...
someone like me...
is gonna kill you...
and your whole fucking race.
Aaaah!
[ Groaning ]
[ Panting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Slurping ]
Aaaaah!
[ Roaring ]
You know what this is?
[ Makes Exploding Sound ]
- [ Roaring ]
- Sure you do.
You're some kind of big, fat,
smart Bug, aren't ya?
[ Roaring ]
Come on.
This is Roughneck Two-Zero.
Brain Bug sighted
moving west of grid five.
- Run!
- [ Roaring, Screeching ]
[ Screaming ]
No!
- Give me the nuke!
- You tryin' to be a hero, Watkins?
I'm tryin' to kill some Bugs, sir.
Get outta here!
- [ Beeping ]
- Get outta here!
Move!
Come on! You like that?
You like that?
Come on!
You want some more?
You like that? You like that?
Come on! Come on--
- Aaaah!
- Down! Down!
Come on, Carmen.
[ Shouting, Cheering, Faint ]
- [ Trooper ] We did it!
- [ Trooper ] Come on!
[ Cheering, Shouting Continue ]
- What's goin' on? Come on!
- They got it!
[ Grunting ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Officer ]
Quiet!
[ Shouting Quiets ]
[ Growling ]
What's it thinking, Colonel?
[ Whimpering ]
[ Rumbling, Gurgling ]
It's afraid.
- It's afraid!
- [ Cheering, Shouting ]
[ Weapons Firing ]
Whoo!
Yeah!
[ Carmen ]
Carl! Carl! Hey!
Well, look who's here.
You made it. Good.
It was you, wasn't it?
You told me how to find Carmen.
Well, that's classified.
You know, whenever the three of us
are together...
I feel like things
might just work out.
I hope you're right, Carmen.
We've got one of their Brains now.
Pretty soon we'll know how they think,
and then we'll know how to beat them.
One day it will all be over...
and everyone will forget
that this was the moment.
This is when it turned.
And it wasn't the mighty Fleet.
It wasn't some fancy new weapon.
- [ Cheering Continues ]
- [ Zim Laughing ]
It was a drill instructor named Zim
who captured a Brain.
Come on! Come on!
Zim.
He got him! Yeah!
Zim! Zim got the Bug!
Zim got the Bug, man!
- Good job, Sergeant.
- Thank you, sir.
That'd be Private, sir.
Carry on, Private.
- Yes, sir!
- [ Cheering Continues ]
[ Narrator ] What mysteries
will the Brain Bug reveal?
Federal scientists are working
around the clock to probe its secrets.
- [ Drill Whirring ]
- [ Roaring ]
Once we understand the Bug,
we will defeat it.
[ Loud Roaring ]
We have the ships.
We have the weapons.
We need soldiers.
Soldiers like
Lieutenant Stack Lumbrezer...
Over the target area now, Captain.
[ Narrator ]
and Captain Carmen Ibanez.
This is the captain speaking.
All personnel prepare for drop.
[ Narrator ]
Soldiers like Private Ace Levy
and Lieutenant John Rico.
Come on, you apes!
You wanna live forever?
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Narrator ] We need you all.
Service guarantees citizenship.