Marcus.
How are you?
Ask me in an hour.
I thought I'd try...
one last time.
You should have stayed
in San Francisco, Dr. Kogan.
By signing
this consent form,
you'll be donating your body
to a noble cause.
You'd...
have a second chance...
through my research
to live again.
You know
what I did.
My brother and two cops
are dead
because of me.
I'm not lookin'
for a second chance.
But I'm not the only one
with a death sentence, am I?
Do you think
I'm gonna kill your cancer
this permanent?
I'm not worried
about myself.
I'm worried about
the future of the human race.
I'll sell it to you.
For what?
A kiss.
So that's what
death tastes like.
You are doing something
very noble.
I'm guilty.
Just cut me up
until there's nothing left.
That I walk through the valley
of the Shadow of Death.
I will fear no evil.
For thou art with me,
thy rod and my staff,
they comfort me.
Do you have
any last words?
Bag Art,
this is Black Hawk Six.
Missile imbound to
Skynet target.
TTO 11 seconds,
taken close.
- Come on, come on!
- Move, move!
- Help, go back!
- Right here!
Connor is on the ground.
This mission
is a quick in-and-out.
Command deems the information
on those computers
should be
at the highest priority.
Connor, there's no sign
of the machines.
They're gone.
Way too quiet.
It's almost like
they were waiting for us.
What the hell's
that smell, man?
Whoa!
You're seeing this?
Olson.
Objective located.
There's something else
you'd have to see.
We got what we came for,
Barbaros.
The clock's ticking.
Spread out,
secure the perimeter.
I got a big gap
over here.
Why didn't we know
about this?
Sir, I think this is
what Command's looking for.
I'm in
their source code.
These people are being taken
up north to San Francisco.
Some sort of R&D project,
for a new Terminator.
Send it to Command.
It's uploading,
I need two minutes.
Wait, wait, wait.
Go back. Go back!
Stop!
- T-800.
- A new Terminator.
Thought you said
it would be...
It's worse.
Connor, get your nose
out of that.
None of your business.
You're not
leading this mission.
Alright, let's cut
these sorry bastards loose.
Come on, let's go!
- Jericho, come in.
- What's that?
Come in, Jericho.
Connor,
get your ass top-side.
Remind those men
they need to answer me on the radio,
even if they're dead.
Connor!
Connor,
get those men to respond.
Olson,
something's wrong up here.
Top-side, come in!
Help out enemy aircraft,
I'm in pursuit.
There are human prisoners
aboard there.
Get after 'em!
Data transferred to plane.
Connor, we're joining you, top--
Bravo Ten, Bravo Ten.
Do you copy? Over.
Eagle White to Bravo Ten.
Bravo Ten, do you copy? Over.
Bravo Ten, Bravo Ten,
do you copy? Over.
Here.
Bravo Ten, identify.
Over.
Connor!
We'll send units
to the extraction point.
How many survivors
are outside? Over.
One.
Copy.
Return to base, sir?
RGB?
Negative.
Take me to Command.
Sir.
Command!
Roger, re-routing.
Request
has been denied.
Command doesn't want
to give up their position.
Radio cogs, over.
Are they down there?
Request
has been denied, sir.
Need to go home.
It's straight from the top.
You open up that ramp!
And you tell them...
I need divers for a log-in.
Now!
This is crazy.
John Connor,
prophesied leader of the Resistance.
Soldier, you put every man
and woman in this sub
in jeopardy
with your little frogman stunt.
What the hell
are you doing here?
What did we find
down there?
You'll be pleased down
the need-to-know basis.
Well, I need to know,
because my men died
down in that hole.
What did we find
down there?
We found the solution,
Connor,
that can end this war,
once and for all.
We know the machines use
short-wave transmitters
to communicate.
Our intel has located
a hidden signal
under
the primary channel.
It allows for direct control
over the machines.
Skynet's a machine,
and like all machines,
it has an off-switch.
Does it work?
Will it work?
Yes.
Have we field-tested it?
No.
Give it to me.
I'll do it.
I'll test it.
Connor,
you can stay Comm unit.
Have a nice one record.
Alright.
Leave Connor in top-side.
Prepare for lock-out.
Connor,
we do this right...
The war is over.
Remount our offensive
in 4 days.
Connor...
These are the codes
for the signal.
Good luck.
Why four days?
A kill list was intercepted
from Skynet.
It says everyone in this room
will be dead by week's end.
You are number two
on the list.
Well,
who's number one?
I don't know.
A civilian.
Kyle. Reese.
Barnes...
My brother...
He didn't make it, did he?
This is tape number 28.
It's Sarah Connor to my son, John.
What's most difficult
for me
is trying to decide
what to tell you
and what not to.
Should I tell you
about your father?
Will it affect
your decision
to send him back in time
to protect me,
knowing that
he is your father?
And he'll be younger
than you,
only a teenager,
when you meet him.
Kyle. Person could go crazy
thinking about this.
But if you don't send Kyle,
you can never be
and Skynet will win the war.
You want
to talk about it?
Kyle is out there
somewhere alone
and Skynet
is hunting him.
What about the signal?
What do you think?
If it works,
it's incredible.
Yeah.
- We have to be careful.
- I agree.
But we have to try.
Okay.
Alright then,
start with something small,
something
more familiar with.
We should try
to capture a Hydrobot,
bring it in for testing.
Yeah.
What is it, John?
Kill Kyle Reese,
reset the future.
No John Connor.
Hey!
Come with me
if you want to live.
What is that?
She doesn't talk,
but you need to start.
Where did you
get that jacket?
The other guy
didn't need it.
You see that red?
It stands for blood.
It's a symbol
of the Resistance.
You're obviously
not a Resistance fighter,
so take it off.
Take it off!
You point a gun
at someone,
you better be ready
to pull the trigger.
I'm going to ask you
one more time.
What the hell was
that thing?
A Terminator.
T-600.
What day is it?
What year?
2018.
What happened here?
Judgement Day happened.
I gotta get outta here.
You can't go on foot.
Machines will cut you down.
You need speed.
I need a car.
Look, there's some by
Griffith Observatory.
- I don't know now.
- Take me.
Get down!
That was
a Hunter Killer.
Thanks to you,
they know we're here.
What's your name,
kid?
Kyle Reese.
Come on.
We burn down the transmitters
so it can't talk to any of its pals
that it can still recieve.
Turn it on!
You got it?
Hold it down!
Hold a bit...
Turn the signal up.
Get me a strap.
- Holy shit.
- Could you believe it?
Just strap it tight.
The signal
has to be continuous.
If there's
any interruption...
Let's rig up
a portable shortwave.
I need to test it on
something larger in the field.
Alright.
Destroy this thing.
So where are the cars?
You don't want
to go out after dark.
Hunter Killers have infrared.
Hunt better at night.
We'll all go
tomorrow morning.
What is that?
Two-day old coyote.
Better than
three-day old coyote.
Hey, hey!
- Grab it.
- What?
Grab it.
Magic.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
This radio work?
No.
My dad
tried to fix it, but...
He could never get it
to work.
Hold that.
Where is everybody?
They're gone.
So why are you
still here?
'Cause we're the Resistance.
L.A. branch.
Welcome
to the headquarters.
Resistant to what?
Machines.
Skynet.
Just the two of you?
Yeah.
How come you're not wearing
one of these?
'Cause I haven't
earned mine, yet.
I hope
he's listening to this.
We've been fighting
a long time,
and we've all lost
so very much,
so many loved ones gone.
But you are
not alone.
There are pockets of Resistance
all around the planet.
We are at the brink...
Do you want to see
a magic trick?
Hold that up.
Press the button.
If we had to finally scope
when it is less than 100 meters.
We've had
a lot of firepower
but the T-600's
are heavy,
and so,
their primitive design.
Who is that?
If you can help
or no...
- I don't know.
- then you have one option.
Their motor cortex...
is partially exposed
to the back of their neck.
A knife
to this area will disorient
their tracking device
but not for long.
Above all,
stay alive.
You have no idea...
how important you are
and how important
you will become.
The machines
are advancing even faster
than I told you
they would.
I've seen it
with my own eyes.
They were inventing
new Terminators.
New ways of killing us.
Skynet is planning
something big.
But the Resistance
is planning something bigger.
This is John Connor.
If you're
listening to this,
you are
the Resistance.
John Connor.
We gotta find
this guy.
So...
You get it working?
- Almost.
- Good.
Look, I figure
we head east, right?
We go
through the desert,
then we can connect
with the Resistance there.
I'm heading north.
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
The machines control
the whole Northern Sector
upto San Francisco.
That's Skynet's central.
I have
to find someone.
There's a lot
that you don't understand
about Skynet, okay?
It's just too dangerous
for us to go there.
What about
the L.A. branch?
Come on, man.
We need to get out of L.A.
[ Song: Rooster
Band: Alice in Chains ]
What is that?
Something my brother
used to listen to.
Star, get out.
Don't look at me
like that, Star.
Get out.
Get out!
You're leaving?
You're gonna leave us?
Ah, I get it.
Do you want to know the difference
between us and the machines?
We bury our dead.
But no one is coming
to bury you.
Aerostat!
- It's a scout of a Terminator.
- Go! Drive!
The Aerostat
heard the music.
Keep the steering.
I've never driven
before.
Hold the wheel.
This thing
is pissing me of.
Get it!
Hold on!
If the idea
was to stay alive...
I'll drive.
We're seeing a lot of
enemy movement in L.A.
Any of our people
in the area?
No one on the ground.
Two A-10s in the air.
Williams and Mirhadi.
Send the birds down.
Guide them
to a safe area.
Roger, Coyote 6-7
in console.
Ten miles to bring.
Lima-Alpha, 1-2-5-7-9-0-3. Over.
- Copy that.
- Roger, Wild Eagle.
Final copy.
Hey,
there's someone here.
Get down, now!
- Get down! Now!
- Move!
- Drop your weapons.
- Let's see your hands!
I never thought
that you guys--
- That's it, drop it!
- Move, man!
What?
Is there a problem?
Hey, we saw
your Resistant sign.
The old lady put it there,
not me.
What do you want?
We're looking
for fuel.
The dark season's coming.
We only got enough
for ourselves.
You point that gun
at somebody,
you better be ready
to pull the trigger.
Put your guns down,
everyone.
Look, we just came
to find the Resistance.
That's all.
The Resistance?
What a joke.
Fighting those machines
is impossible.
We keep our heads down,
they ignore us.
You keep your heads down
and they'll come for you eventually.
We help you
and maybe they will.
These people
aren't gonna help you.
Let's go.
You're not going
anywhere.
Not until this one
gets something to eat.
Bring me a basket.
Here you go.
Come on, help yourself!
Eat up.
Are you alright, son?
It's our food.
Our fuel.
It's not your choice
to make!
- Are you okay?
- What?
Are you okay?
Star, Star!
Damn!
You brought them here!
You brought them here.
Hey!
- Stop, stop!
- Come on, wait.
- Hey!
- Go! Go get 'em, go!
- Head for the tunnels!
- Truck!
Marcus, Marcus!
We can't
just run for it.
Run!
Shoot it!
Go, go, go!
It didn't work!
Shit!
Hell, yeah!
Mototerminators!
Shoot that
son of a bitch!
Marcus,
turn right up here.
Hold on!
Where is the other one?
Get up here!
Come on!
Star,
give me the gun.
I got it.
Yeah!
Hang on!
- Drop the ball!
- Uh, alright.
Star, go!
- Star!
- No!
Kyle!
Marcus!
Get back!
Marcus! Marcus!
I got my eyes on
two targets.
We've got two bogeys
at 270º.
They've never come
this deep before.
They're looking
for something.
H.K. is down.
We've got an H.K.
porching our six.
Come over by.
Breaking off.
Evasive maneuvers
now!
Taking fire. I'm hit.
Portside damage.
It's got a lock on you.
Break off.
Eject, Williams, eject!
Punching out.
There's your transport,
headed northwest,
bearing 2-8-9
towards San Francisco.
First,
test the signal...
and pray it works.
You okay?
Get my knife.
It's in my left boot.
What's your name?
Blair Williams.
What's yours?
Name's Marcus.
You can let me down now,
Marcus.
- That thing, where'd it go?
- The transport?
Skynet.
Where the hell
are you going?
After it.
Hate to break it
to you but...
If you've got friends
on that thing...
They're good as dead.
The same is you
if you keep walking in that direction.
They've only been dead a while
and I am getting used to it.
Why don't you come with me
to my base?
Connor might know why.
Listen, if you've got a problem
with the machines,
he's definitely the guy
you wanna talk to.
- How far is your base?
- It should be 1 or 2 days hike.
And it's that way.
What are you saying?
Speak English!
I was telling him...
It is not true,
the part the machines killing us.
They're gonna kill us.
They're gonna kill everyone.
We are
in a cattle cart,
on our way
to the slaughterhouse.
Calm down.
You're not helping.
The most important thing
that we can do right now
is stay alive.
In here
and in here.
Alright?
Just stay alive.
Over there.
Find something
that can burn.
We'll be
at my base tomorrow.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
What you got there?
Just some antibiotics.
Antibiotics are hard
to come by these days.
Listen,
I don't have much, but...
you're welcome
to whatever you need.
We've been watching you.
Looking for this?
Come on, guys.
Machines are the enemy.
- We're on the same side.
- No, no.
See, I've got a couple of friends
on my side.
Maybe they can
carry you home...
when I'm done with you.
You might want
a chamber around.
Kill me,
you ain't gonna win this war.
Ow! Oh, God!
I'm a little cold.
Relax.
I just want
some body heat.
You have
a strong heart.
God,
I love that sound.
Thank you...
for saving me
back there.
I don't meet a lot
of good guys these days.
I'm not
a good guy.
You are.
You just
don't know it, yet.
Do you think people
deserve a second chance?
Yeah.
I do.
This is it.
Skynet's Valley of Death.
We've never been
this deep before.
We've got to be sure
this thing works
in their territory.
On the bigger machines.
That will bring them in.
H.K.
They're coming.
Turn it up!
It works, man.
The signal works.
It's beautiful!
- Commander Ashdown.
- Connor, tell me it works.
It works.
That is affirmative.
The signal works.
Good.
The attack commences tomorrow
at 0400, worldwide.
Your unit will be in support
of a bombing in Skynet's central.
What is the extraction plan
for the prisoners?
Extraction plan?
There is
no extraction plan.
We're gonna level
the place.
Negative!
I told you.
Skynet Central
is filled with human prisoners.
This is war, Connor.
Leadership has its cost.
You, above all,
should know that.
Ashdown, come in.
Ashdown, Connor.
Ashdown, Con...
Damn him!
Star! Get back!
Get back!
You have
to calm down, now.
I gotta get
out of here!
Blair.
What?
This is us.
The mines are magnetic.
If we head due west
at this point of entry,
we're good.
I'll go first.
Let's go, Marcus.
I'm starving.
For thou art with me,
thy rod and my staff,
- they comfort me.
- Father.
This is the beginning
of something
wonderful.
- The son of a bitch is here.
- What do we've got here?
He stepped
on a landmine.
Start a large four IV.
Keep it open.
- I'm okay.
- Patient needs more morphine.
- What's his name?
- Marcus.
He's got
a prosthetic limb?
What?
Okay,
pulse is dead.
Let's see
what we've got here.
Barnes?
The Devil's hands
have been busy.
- What is it?
- It's real flesh and blood.
Though it seems
to heal his off quickly.
The heart is human,
but very powerful.
The brain too,
but with a chip interface.
- He done enough?
- It has a hybrid nervous system.
One human cortex.
- One machine.
- What the hell would have they done?
Who built you?
My name is
Marcus Wright.
You think
you're human?
I am human.
No!
No! God!
Where were you
manufactured?
I was born...
August 22nd, 1975.
I know you.
I heard your voice
on the radio.
- You're John Connor.
- Of course you know me.
You were sent here
to kill me.
Kill the leadership.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Then why are you here?
Blair said you could help me
find who I'm looking for.
Now let me down.
If I let you down...
you'll kill everyone
in this room.
Just you, Connor.
'Cause I ain't
give a shit about you.
I didn't even know your name
until two days ago.
No?
You and me...
We've been at war,
since before
either of us even existed.
You tried killing my mother,
Sarah Connor.
You killed my father,
Kyle Reese.
You will not
kill me.
Kyle Reese is on a Transporter,
heading for Skynet.
If I wanted
to kill him,
I would have done him
in L.A.
Where did you
find that thing?
You sent Mihradi and me
to provide cover for some civilians.
He was
one of them.
Was there
a teenage boy?
I honestly don't know.
They were taking him
to a Transport.
- He was the only one left.
- Not he, Blair. It.
"It was the only one left."
Don't be naïve.
It saved my life.
Kate, what's gonna
happen to him?
Disassembled.
You mean killed.
It may have information
on Skynet.
I know
he's not the enemy.
I've been shot at
by the enemy.
That's not him.
That machine saved you
only to gain access
to kill all of us.
We're gonna be okay.
Don't worry.
For my brother.
No!
Connor wants
to see you.
What for?
Like he's going to tell me,
Barnes.
Let me see that.
You want me to tell Connor
you're not coming?
No.
Watch him.
I told you everything
I know, John.
Skynet is ruthless
and unpredictable.
They will use the best part of you
against yourself,
and they will have methods
I can't imagine or predict.
That I can't
help you with.
And when
you're unsure,
which just always
follow your heart, John.
I love you.
Goodbye.
There's nothing on the tapes
about machines with organs.
That thing in there...
I thought I knew
our enemy.
But that thing...
That makes me feel like
I know nothing.
I looked in its eyes,
and it believes,
absolutely believes,
that it is human.
It believes everything
that it says,
and it is telling me
that Kyle Reese is in Skynet.
If that is true...
The Command is about
to bomb my father
and the rest of those prisoners
and I cannot stop them.
Thank you.
Come in!
Wassup?
Blair says you needed me.
Get in!
Kill them!
Barnes!
What about Blair?
She made her choice.
Get down!
Let's move.
- Put some light out there!
- We're back in the minefield.
I have a plan.
- Blair, you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay!
- Get your team back!
- There they are!
Run! God--
Now what?
M-My plan stopped
at the jeep.
Okay.
Do you have
the shot?
I'll draw the fire.
You take out the light.
I got a target!
Behind the wall.
- Don't move.
- Go!
Down!
Keep your head down!
Go, go, go, go!
Come on!
- You alright?
- Let's get you out of here.
There they are!
On the ground!
Stay on the ground!
Report 47.
Coming straight down.
I'm going in.
- Do not move!
- Keep your eye on them.
Who's there?
Alligator, this is Scarface 5-1,
we have eyes on the machine.
Contact--
Take my gun!
Check the river.
You see him?
Move!
God!
I'm going down!
Fall!
Give me your hand!
They know what you are,
even if you don't.
Enough!
That gun ain't
gonna stop shit!
Nobody shot you
in the heart,
and I see that thing
beating a mile a minute.
Kyle Reese...
He's in Skynet.
You do that, he's dead.
I can get you in.
How?
Look at me.
That's why
I don't trust you.
I'm your only hope
you have.
I need to find
who did this to me.
So do you.
Connor!
Make your choice.
You kept being...
You tell me
where I can find Kyle Reese.
- Yeah?
- I will.
Contact me on that.
Let me know
he's still alive.
What are you?
I don't know.
Hey,
he's over here.
Where is he heading?
You alright?
Any sign of him?
He's gone.
What'd you do?
I saw a man,
not a machine.
How's your leg?
I'll live.
Let her go!
Connor.
Command for you.
This is Connor.
Connor,
are your men ready?
Negative.
Nobody is ready.
We are not,
you are not.
We must abort the attack.
The game has changed.
What are you talking about?
All our elements
are past the release points.
They are in
assault position.
Then delay the attack.
At least, delay the attack.
I have a chance
to infiltrate Skynet
and rescue
those prisoners.
Give me
that opportunity.
No, absolutely not.
This is not the time
for a rescue mission.
What you ask for,
will undermine the whole operation.
Skynet has Kyle Reese.
And that is his fate.
No, it's our fate.
I have to save him.
He is the key.
The key to the future,
to the past.
Without him,
we lose everything.
No!
You stay the course!
If we stay the course,
we are dead!
We are all dead!
As of this moment,
soldier,
you are relieved
to your command.
You are no longer
a part of this Resistance.
I didn't catch
that last statement.
Neither did I.
This is John Connor.
If you're listening
to this,
you are
the Resistance.
Listen carefully.
If we attack tonight,
our humanity is lost.
Command wants us
to fight like machines,
they want us to make
cold, calculated decisions.
But we are not
machines.
And if we behave like them,
then what is the point...
in winning?
Command is going to ask you
to attack Skynet.
I am asking you
not to.
If even one bomb
drops on Skynet before sunrise,
our future will be lost.
So, please.
Stand down.
Give me the time
to protect our future,
that all of us,
are fighting for.
This is
John Connor.
Thank you.
What should I tell your men
when they find out you're gone?
I'll be back.
[Song: You Could Be Mine
Band: Guns N' Roses]
I'm coming for you.
Come on, Marcus.
Okay.
Signal broadcasted
with full thrift, sir.
Good.
Commence
bombing of Skynet.
We have a green light
for the attack.
This is Bakersfield.
That's a no-go
on your last. Out.
Eugene.
Standing down.
This is Reno.
Negative on your last.
Eugene, Reno, Bakersfield,
they're all standing down.
They will not attack,
unless Connor gives the order.
Kyle Reese?
Go!
Get to your transport!
Is Kyle Reese here?
Welcome home, Marcus.
We knew you'd be back.
After all,
it was programmed in you.
Oh, and you executed
that programming beautifully.
What am I?
You are
an Infiltration Prototype.
The only
one of your kind.
We resurrected you.
Advanced CyberDyne's work...
amended it.
You're dead.
Calculations confirmed
the Serena code
on this face
isn't easiest for you to process.
It can be others
if you wish.
Marcus...
What else could you be...
if not machine?
A man.
The human condition
no longer applies to you.
Accept what you
already know...
That you were made
to serve a purpose.
To achieve what no another machine
has achieved before.
To infiltrate,
find a target,
and then bring that target
back home to us.
We've been at war since before
either of us even existed.
You tried killing my mother,
Sarah Connor.
You kept being...
You tell me
where I can find Kyle Reese.
Yeah, I will.
Kyle Reese!
Move! Move!
Get to your transport.
Kyle Reese!
You, move!
In times of desperation,
people will believe
what they want to believe.
And so, we gave them
what they wanted to believe.
A trick,
in the form of a signal,
the Resistance thought
would win the war.
And they were right,
it will end this war.
Except that it is the Resistance
that will be terminated,
not Skynet.
Get the attack through
Skynet's Central back online.
I want our aircraft in the sky,
immediately!
Sir, sir, we got a bogey
with a very large radar signature,
closing in
on our position.
Losenko?
We have destroyed
ourselves.
Skynet tracked
our signal.
We led them
straight to us.
Our best machines have failed,
time and again,
to complete a mission.
Something was missing.
We had to think,
radically.
And so we made you.
We created the perfect
infiltration machine.
You, Marcus.
You did what Skynet
has failed to do for so many years.
You killed John Connor.
Kyle!
Hey!
Don't fight, Marcus.
Remember
what you are.
I know what I am.
I'm better this way.
You will not be given
a second chance.
You cannot save
John Connor.
Watch me.
We got a message
from Connor!
He's in Skynet.
Needs air support.
Let's go!
Scram for the aircraft.
Star!
Star, go!
Star! Star!
Star! Go back!
Come on!
Come on.
What's your name?
Kyle Reese.
Stay with me!
Back!
Get back!
Come on, Star,
move!
Move!
T-800s.
There's so
many of them.
Be careful!
- What are these?
- Fuel cells.
Life source
for the T-800.
Nuclear.
Enough
to level this place.
Cover us.
Get ready.
Run!
Star, come on!
Let's go!
Come here!
- Come on!
We got to get
to the transport!
Where are you going?
- I gotta end this.
- No, no!
I'm not gonna
leave you!
- You didn't.
- Who are you?
John Connor!
- Hang back now!
- Hey!
Hey, John Connor's
in there.
Where?
- You show me there.
- Hey, hey!
What?
John Connor's
in there.
Come with me!
Connor!
I need help!
Help!
Connor, it's Kyle!
You son of a bitch!
Come on!
Let's get
out of here.
John...
We can't make it
back to base.
Center's down
and they never say so.
Medevac, urgent.
Severe chest trauma.
Call the surgical team.
We're locked.
It's Connor.
How long?
His heart...
can't take it.
He's going to be okay.
He's going
to be okay, Kate.
Kyle?
Take it...
You earned it.
Kate...
Take mine.
Marcus?
Everybody deserves
a second chance.
This is mine.
What is it
that makes us human?
It's not something
you can program.
You can't put it
into a chip.
It's the strength
of the human heart.
The difference
between us and machines.
There is a storm
on the horizon.
A time of hardship
and pain.
This battle
has been won,
but the war against
the machines races on.
Skynet's global network remains strong,
but we will not quit,
until all of it is destroyed.
This is John Connor.
There is no fate, but what we make
Terminator Salvation.[2009].R5.DVDRIP.XVID.[Eng]-DUQA