AFTER NEARLY FIVE YEARS
OF APPEALS,
DINO MORETTI,
REPUTED LIEUTENANT
OF THE FRANCO
CRIME FAMILY,
WAS RELEASED
FROM PRISON TODAY
AND ACQUITTED
OF ALL CHARGES
IN CONNECTION
WITH THE MURDERS
OF POLICE OFFICER
FRANK CASTLE
AND HIS FAMILY.
MORETTI HAS LONG
MAINTAINED HIS INNOCENCE,
CLAIMS HE HAS NO IDEA
WHO IS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE 125 MYSTERIOUS
GANGLAND MURDERS,
OFTEN ATTRIBUTED
TO A SHADOWY FIGURE
KNOWN AS THE PUNISHER,
WHICH HAVE OCCURRED HERE
OVER THE LAST
HALF DECADE.
LAURIE SILVERS
HAS THIS REPORT.
MR. MORETTI?
HOW DOES IT FEEL
TO BE FINALLY
ACQUITTED?
IT FEELS GREAT.
JUST GREAT.
THE GOVERNMENT
SAYS IT'S GOING
TO APPEAL.
LET THEM APPEAL
A HUNDRED TIMES.
I'LL STILL WIN.
THIS IS AMERICA.
IF A MAN IS INNOCENT,
JUSTICE PREVAILS.
ARE YOU WORRIED
ABOUT THE PUNISHER?
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING ABOUT
THIS PUNISHER,
WHOEVER HE IS.
IF HE EVER SHOWS UP
WITHIN 1,000 YARDS OF ME,
HE'LL FIND OUT WHAT
THE WORD PUNISHED
REALLY MEANS.
NOW, IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME.
AND THERE YOU HAVE IT.
THE DAPPER DON,
ALLEGEDLY HEAD
OF THE POWERFUL
FRANCO CRIME FAMILY,
ONCE AGAIN SHRUGGING OFF
ANY FEAR OF THE PUNISHER
DESPITE THE FACT
THAT OVER 125
ORGANIZED CRIME FIGURES
HAVE BEEN MURDERED
BY THE SELF-STYLED
VIGILANTE
IN THE LAST FIVE YEARS.
THIS IS LAURIE SILVERS
FOR CHANNEL 8 NEWS.
HEY, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
MAYBE I GOT
A FUTURE IN POLITICS.
ENOUGH OF THE JOKES.
BREAK OUT THE CHAMPAGNE.
I'LL GET IT, BOSS.
NO. FIRST THINGS FIRST.
YOU GUYS CHECK THE HOUSE.
MIKEY, START
THE MUSIC AROUND HERE.
?? WINNING
ISN'T EVERYTHING ??
?? IT'S
THE ONLY THING... ????
[BOARD CREAKS]
WHAT THE FUCK?
JESUS!
JOEY!
COME ON, YOU GUYS.
PARTY TIME.
JOEY.
YOU!
SWITCH ON THOSE CAMERAS!
KEEP THEM ROLLING!
COME ON, GUYS!
MOVE IT!
KEEP IT ROLLING!
LOOK, THERE'S
SOMEBODY THERE.
I GOT
THE TIGHT SHOT.
WHO IS THAT?
HOLY SHIT!
THE PUNISHER!
IT'S HIM!
MOVE IN FOR A CLOSE-UP!
ARE YOU GETTING IT?
OUT OF THE WAY!
I GOT SHIT
ALL OVER THE PLACE!
KEEP THEM GOING!
[COUGHS]
COME ON, GOD.
ANSWER ME.
IT'S YEARS
I'M ASKING YOU WHY.
WHY ARE
THE INNOCENT DEAD
AND THE GUILTY ALIVE?
WHERE IS JUSTICE?
WHERE IS PUNISHMENT?
OR HAVE YOU ALREADY
ANSWERED?
HAVE YOU ALREADY
SAID TO THE WORLD,
"HERE IS JUSTICE,
HERE IS PUNISHMENT,"
HERE...
IN ME?
MOMMY, AREN'T WE
GOING TO WAIT
FOR DADDY?
DADDY'S WORKING.
WE'LL MEET HIM
AT GRANDMA'S.
OK?
JULIE!
ARE YOU BEING
PRESSURED TO RESIGN
AS HEAD OF THE
PUNISHER TASK FORCE?
NO COMMENT.
DO YOU HAVE LEADS?
DO YOU STILL THINK
FRANK CASTLE
AND THE PUNISHER
ARE THE SAME PERSON?
ABSOLUTELY.
DON'T YOU PEOPLE
HAVE ANYTHING
BETTER TO DO
WITH YOUR TIME?
IT'S 2:00 IN THE
GOD DAMN MORNING,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
SHIT.
HEY,
GIVE ME A BREAK.
NOW, THAT WAS SMART.
VERY SMART.
THE CHIEF OF DETECTIVES.
IT MUST BE IMPORTANT.
IT IS.
I HAVE A MESSAGE
FROM THE MAYOR.
I QUOTE,
"FRANK CASTLE IS DEAD."
NO MORE TALK
ABOUT HIM BEING OTHERWISE.
YOU TOW THE LINE
OR YOU GET THE BOOT.
YOU'D GO ALONG
WITH THAT, TOO.
WE CANNOT LET
THE PUBLIC THINK
THERE'S SOME PSYCHOTIC
EX-COP WHACKING OFF
WISE GUYS
LIKE HE'S GOT
A HUNTING LICENSE.
WHY NOT?
BERKOWITZ, IT'S LATE.
I'M TIRED.
YOU'RE WARNED.
WHAT THE HELL
EVER HAPPENED TO YOU?
EXCUSE ME,
LIEUTENANT BERKOWITZ?
I'M DETECTIVE SAM LEARY.
SAM?
SAMANTHA.
I WORKED WITH YOU ONCE
FIVE YEARS AGO.
DID THE MORETTI
HEROIN BUST.
IT WAS MY FIRST ASSIGNMENT
PLAIN-CLOTHES.
I WAS THE HOOKER.
OH, RIGHT.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU,
DETECTIVE?
I'D LIKE TO BE
YOUR PARTNER.
I DON'T WORK
WITH A PARTNER.
BUT YOU USED TO.
USED TO.
PAST TENSE.
I'M NOT AFTER
A FREE RIDE.
I CAN CARRY MY SHARE
OF THE LOAD.
I'M SURE YOU CAN.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
YOU'RE NOT
EVEN LISTENING.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'M NOT EVEN LISTENING.
WHY?
I WORK WITH THE BEST.
ANYTHING ELSE
IS A WASTE OF MY TIME.
THINK YOU'RE
THE FIRST TO APPLY?
NO, BUT I'M
THE MOST QUALIFIED.
WHAT MAKES
YOU THINK THAT?
I GRADUATED FIRST
IN MY CLASS
AT THE ACADEMY.
I SCORED
IN THE TOP 1%
IN THE TARGET RANGE.
I MADE DETECTIVE
FIRST TIME UP,
THE SECOND YOUNGEST
ON THE FORCE
TO DO THAT.
IT MUST MAKE
YOUR PARENTS PROUD.
BUT WHY SHOULD
IT MAKE YOU MY PARTNER?
I BELIEVE
THAT FRANK CASTLE'S
THE PUNISHER.
KNOW WHERE
MY OFFICE IS?
YEAH.
YOU BE THERE
AT 9:00 SHARP.
MR. FRANCO,
HOW DOES IT FEEL
TO BE BACK HOME?
IN THE 30 MINUTES
SINCE I'VE LANDED,
SO FAR, SO GOOD.
HAVE YOU COME
TO TAKE OVER?
IT WAS A LONG FLIGHT.
GIVE HIM A BREAK.
AREN'T YOU AFRAID
OF THE PUNISHER?
IN EUROPE,
THEY THINK
YOU MADE IT UP
TO SELL
NEWSPAPERS.
WHAT'S BEEN KILLING
YOUR ASSOCIATES
FOR FIVE YEARS?
TOO MUCH STRESS,
I GUESS.
THANKS FOR COMING.
COME ON. VANISH.
JUST A SECOND.
CAN I HELP YOU,
DETECTIVE?
OH, YOU ALREADY HAVE,
FRANCO.
REALLY? HOW?
KIND OF LIKE
A WORM HELPS A FISHERMAN.
I'M GLAD YOU FINALLY
CAME HOME, GIANNI.
I WAS RUNNING
OUT OF BAIT.
I'LL SEE YOU AROUND.
TOO MUCH STRESS, HUH?
THAT'S FUNNY.
HOW'D YOU
LIKE IT THERE?
IT WAS OK.
LEARN GOOD STUFF
IN THOSE FANCY SCHOOLS?
SHOW HIM SOMETHING.
YOU GOT A QUARTER?
SURE.
HERE YOU GO.
WATCH HIM.
HEY, THAT'S GREAT.
I CAN DO IT WITH $10.
THAT'S EXPENSIVE FOR ME.
GIVE THIS TO LOUIE
IN THE KITCHEN.
ASK HIM TO GIVE YOU
MORE CHEESECAKE.
LOSE SOMETHING?
HEH HEH!
SO TELL ME.
HOW BAD IS IT?
HOW BAD?
IF YOU DIDN'T
COME HOME,
I WOULD BE HEAD
OF THE FAMILY.
IT'S NOT GOING
TO BE FAMILIES ANYMORE.
THAT'S OLD THINKING.
IT'S DAD THINKING.
THERE'LL BE
NO MORE WARS,
NO MORE TERRITORIES.
HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO CONVINCE ANYONE?
WITH AN ACT
OF GOOD FAITH
SO GENEROUS
THAT EVEN
FREDDY DeLEO
WILL SEE THE LIGHT.
A WEEK FROM NOW,
I'VE ARRANGED
FOR 600 KILOS
OF PURE JUNK
TO COME IN.
600 KEYS?
$500 MILLION WORTH.
EVERYONE GETS
THEIR SHARE,
PROVIDED
THEY WORK TOGETHER
TO MAKE IT HAPPEN.
ONE GROUP
ON SECURITY,
ONE AT RECEIVING,
ONE IN COLLECTING,
ONE IN DISTRIBUTION.
THAT WOULDN'T
BE TOO HARD.
AND WHAT DO WE DO
ABOUT THE PUNISHER?
ONE THING
AT A TIME, JIM.
FIRST WE CONSOLIDATE.
AND THEN WE OBLITERATE.
EXCUSE ME,
KIND SIR,
BUT I CAN'T HELP
BUT SEE IN YOU
A MAN FAR
LUCKIER THAN ME.
WHAT?
WHATEVER YOU CAN SPARE
WILL BE SUFFICIENT.
AND THIS OLD THESPIAN--
WHAT THE HELL'S
A THESPIAN?
AN ACTOR, SIR.
OH, SURE.
THANK YOU.
HEY.
WHAT'D I TELL YOU
ABOUT BUGGING
THE CUSTOMERS?
RICHIE.
THROW THIS TRASH
OUT OF HERE.
YOU CAN'T
TREAT ME LIKE THIS.
I DEMAND SOME RESPECT!
I'M NOT TRASH!
I'M A MAN!
MAYBE I SHOULD HAVE TRIED
SOME EUGENE O'NEILL.
AW.
HI THERE.
NICE WEATHER
WE ARE HAVING FOR--
YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO MEET ME HERE
FOUR HOURS AGO.
I KNOW.
I'VE HEARD IT
ALL MY LIFE.
CHECKS, RESPONSIBILITY...
CAN'T KEEP
AN APPOINTMENT.
WHERE IS THE DOPE
COMING INTO?
THE DOPE.
OH, THAT.
PIER 30.
BUT THE LOCATION'S
NOT THE BIG STORY.
WHO'LL BE THERE IS.
WHO'LL BE THERE?
EVERYONE.
THEY'RE ALL
WORKING TOGETHER NOW.
ONE BIG, HAPPY FAMILY
UNDER THE FATHERLY WING
OF YOUR OLD FRIEND
GIANNI FRANCO.
MR. P!
HAPPY HUNTING.
ALLEZ, VITE.
ILS RAPPROCHENT.
I CAN'T GET THIS
FRIGGING THING TO WORK.
[BEEP]
VERY DIFFICULT.
WELL, FUCK YOU.
FUCK YOU!
HEY, THERE'S $500 MILLION
OUT THERE, ASSHOLES.
COOL OUT!
HERE,
CHECK THE PERIMETER.
GET WITH IT.
HELLO, RED 1.
COME IN.
RED 1, WILL YOU
GET OFF YOUR ASS?
WHAT?
EVERYTHING'S OK?
YEAH.
RED 2, WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
BAD KIDNEYS.
I GOT TO PEE.
SO PEE.
EVERYTHING'S OK?
YEAH.
IT'S DEAD HERE.
THE U.S. COAST GUARD.
CUT YOUR ENGINES.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WE HAD TO PULL INTO DOCK.
OUR HULL IS LEAKING.
DOWN THERE.
HAVE A LOOK.
15 MINUTES LATE.
JESUS CHRIST.
FUCKING FAGGOT
FRENCHMEN.
HERE THEY COME.
HERE THEY COME!
YOU'RE 15 MINUTES LATE,
YOU STUPID DICKHEAD.
WHAT'S THE BIG IDEA?
HEY, GUYS,
GET BACK THERE.
600 KILOS OF DOPE.
SEVEN DEAD WISE GUYS.
ALL FROM
DIFFERENT FAMILIES.
GUESS IT'S
A DRUG DEAL GONE BAD.
GUESS AGAIN.
AAH!
IDIKO TANAKA.
SHE'S SINGLE,
IN HER EARLY 40s.
SHE HAS ONE DAUGHTER,
A MUTE AMERICAN GIRL
SHE ADOPTED AT BIRTH
WHO NEVER
LEAVES HER SIGHT.
SHE'S A GRADUATE FROM
HARVARD BUSINESS SCHOOL
AND THE FIRST FEMALE
EVER TO HEAD THE YAKUZA.
YAKU WHAT?
YAKUZA.
JAPANESE MAFIA.
THIS IS A LONG
FUCKING WAY FROM JAPAN.
WHAT ARE THEY
DOING HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
WE ARE ABOUT
TO FIND OUT.
OK.
LADY TANAKA.
MR. FRANCO.
IT IS AN HONOR.
YOUR REPUTATION
PRECEDES YOU.
AS DOES YOURS.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
NO, THANK YOU.
WHAT I HAVE TO SAY
WILL BE BRIEF.
WE HAVE BEEN TRACKING
YOUR ORGANIZATION
FOR QUITE SOME TIME.
YOUR LEADERSHIP
IS DECIMATED.
YOUR SOLDIERS
ARE INEXPERIENCED.
OUR LITTLE
DEMONSTRATION ON PIER 30
WAS AMPLE PROOF OF THAT.
YOU'RE WEAK, MR. FRANCO,
VULNERABLE...
AND WE ARE NOT.
WE COULD CRIPPLE
ALL YOUR OPERATIONS--
LEGAL, AS WELL AS ILLEGAL--
VERY EASILY.
BUT WE DON'T WANT THAT.
WITH ALL
DUE RESPECT,
LET'S CUT THROUGH
THE BULLSHIT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
A PARTNERSHIP.
DEFINE THE TERM.
YOU WILL
MANAGE AND OVERSEE
ALL YOUR BUSINESS
ON A DAY-TO-DAY BASIS.
WE WILL ASSUME
THE DUTIES OF EXECUTIVE
ADMINISTRATION,
INVESTMENTS,
AND FINANCIAL SERVICES.
COME ON!
I'M NOT THROUGH.
WHAT DO YOU PROPOSE
AS A SPLIT?
75% FOR US.
25% FOR YOU.
NO FUCKING WAY
AM I GOING TO BE
A SALARY BOY
TO SOME BUNCH
OF NIPS.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT YOU GUYS,
BUT THE DeLEO FAMILY
GIVES UP SHIT.
WE DON'T WORK
FOR NOBODY.
WHO THE FUCK
DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
WE ARE YAKUZA.
WHEN YOUR ANCESTORS
WERE STILL SHEPHERDS
SCREWING SHEEP
ON THE
MEDITERRANEAN COAST,
OURS WERE THE
CRIME LORDS OF ASIA.
I'M NOT
OFFERING TERMS,
MR. FRANCO.
I'M MAKING DEMANDS.
AND WHAT IF WE
CHOOSE NOT TO COMPLY?
STEPS ARE NOW BEING TAKEN
TO ENSURE THAT YOU WILL.
YOU AMERICANS HAVE
A GREAT CAPACITY FOR VIOLENCE.
BUT IT'S
WILD, UNFOCUSED.
YOU WILL LEARN.
GOOD DAY, GENTLEMEN.
WHAT DO WE DO?
ONLY ONE THING WE CAN.
WE GO TO WAR.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE GOING
TO DO WITH THAT,
PLAY MS. PAC-MAN
OR SOMETHING?
HOPEFULLY FIND CASTLE.
NO SHIT.
UH-HUH.
HOW ARE WE GOING
TO ACCOMPLISH
THIS LITTLE MIRACLE?
I'VE ACCESSED
INTO ALL AVAILABLE
DATA BANKS
WITH INFORMATION
ON HIM
AND PROGRAMMED
THE COMPUTER
TO FORM AN ANALYSIS
OF PROBABLE
LOCATIONS.
OH, WOW.
EVEN THE PUNISHER
HAS TO LIVE SOMEWHERE.
HEY.
YOU SEE
THIS BOARD HERE?
YEAH.
I'VE BEEN LIVING
WITH IT FOR FIVE YEARS.
EVERY TIME
HE KILLS SOMEBODY,
I PUT A PIN THERE.
I FINE-TOOTH
EVERY BUILDING,
EVERY ALLEY,
IN THIS CITY.
THE ONLY THING THAT
I'VE GOT TO SHOW FOR IT
IS THESE LITTLE
CALLING CARDS HERE...
AND A WHOLE
BUNCH OF THESE.
I'VE ALREADY BEEN
THROUGH THIS CITY.
I'VE BEEN IN IT,
AROUND IT,
ON TOP OF IT.
YOU NAME IT.
HOW ABOUT UNDER IT?
I GET THE RED.
I HATE YELLOW.
THE RED'S GROSS, JENNY.
I THINK IT'S
TOTALLY HOT.
HI. I'M PETER BEAR.
I REALLY CARE.
AND TO SHOW YOU
IT'S TRUE,
I HAVE THINGS
TO TEACH YOU.
LIKE WHAT, PETER?
OHH!
COME ON!
WAIT UP!
ROGER?
HELLO?
COME OUT.
COME OUT,
WHEREVER YOU ARE.
OH!
BUBBLE, BUBBLE,
TOIL AND TROUBLE,
I BETTER GET OUT OF HERE
ON THE DOUBLE.
AAH!
WITH YOUR FLAIR
FOR ENTRANCES,
YOU SHOULD
CONSIDER A CAREER
IN THE THEATER.
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
WHAT WOULD I
BE DOING,
TRAMPING AROUND
THE SEWERS OF THIS
GREAT METROPOLIS?
SIGHTSEEING.
HEH HEH. VERY FUNNY.
I BRING YOU NEWS,
YOU GIVE ME GRIEF.
YOU KNOW, THEY ALL
THINK YOU'RE DEAD.
THEY'LL KILL
EACH OTHER NOW.
TURN THE LIGHTS OFF
WHEN YOU LEAVE.
VERY CLEVER.
AND WHAT
WILL YOU DO
WHILE THE
CARNAGE ENSUES?
TAKE A VACATION.
YES, I HEAR
THE SEWERS OF PARIS
ARE LOVELY
THIS TIME OF YEAR.
AND WHAT ABOUT
THE CHILDREN?
WHAT CHILDREN?
THE CHILDREN
OF THE NEW BOSSES
ARE NOW COUNTED
AMONG THEIR LOSSES.
THEY'RE BEING
HELD FOR RANSOM
BY THE JAPANESE.
SO THE BOSSES
WILL HAVE TO PAY UP.
PAY THEY WILL
AND ALL FOR NAUGHT.
THE CHILDREN
WILL BE SOLD BY
THE SLAVE TRADE--
THEY'VE BEEN BOUGHT.
MY GOD, MAN,
DON'T YOU SEE?
THIS IS THE RESULT
OF YOUR FIVE-YEAR
KILLING SPREE.
YOU WEAKENED
THE FATHERS
TO SUCH DEGREES,
THEY COULDN'T
PROTECT THEIR
OWN FAMILIES.
I PUNISH THE GUILTY.
AND AS A RESULT,
THE INNOCENT
NOW SUFFER.
YOU MUST DO SOMETHING!
YOU MUST DO SOMETHING.
ENOUGH OF
THIS FUCKING
BRAINSTORMING.
LET'S SNATCH
HER DAUGHTER,
TAKE HER
TO THE MEETING
WITH THIS
IN HER MOUTH,
THEN WE TALK.
BEFORE YOU
GO SNATCHING ANYBODY,
LET ME TELL YOU
A STORY
ABOUT OUR MISS TANAKA.
THE ONLY PERSON
SHE WAS EVER CLOSE TO
WAS HER TWIN BROTHER.
THEY GREW UP IN
A TOKYO ORPHANAGE
AFTER THE SECOND
WORLD WAR.
THEY WERE INSEPARABLE.
THEY LIVED TOGETHER
THEIR WHOLE LIVES.
ONE DAY HE STUCK
THE YAKUZA
FOR A LOT OF MONEY,
WHICH HE HAD NO INTENTION
OF PAYING BACK.
NOTHING HAPPENED TO HIM
BECAUSE OF HER.
THEN OTHER PEOPLE STARTED
GETTING THE SAME IDEA.
BEFORE SHE COULD BECOME
HEAD OF THE ORGANIZATION,
THE OTHER LEADERS DEMANDED
AN ACT OF ABSOLUTE LOYALTY.
YOU KNOW WHAT SHE DID?
SHE WENT HOME,
COOKED HER BROTHER
A BEAUTIFUL MEAL,
WAITED UNTIL
HE HAD FINISHED,
AND THEN SLIT
HIS THROAT.
JESUS.
WHAT ARE
YOU SAYING?
WE DON'T DEAL
WITH HER?
WECAN'T
DEAL WITH HER.
YOU'RE SAYING
THERE'S NOTHING THAT
CAN SAVE OUR KIDS.
THERE IS, BUT IT'S LYING
AT THE BOTTOM OF THE HARBOR.
WELL, I'M GOING
TO THE MEETING.
YEAH.
YEAH, I'M GOING, TOO.
I'M NOT.
GOOD.
THE MONEY
FOR THE CHILDREN.
THE SLAVE BUSINESS
IS VERY PROFITABLE.
COME ON. DON'T CRY.
WE'RE GOING TO BE OK.
WE'RE NOT. IT'S BECAUSE
OF MY FATHER I'M HERE.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
THEN WHY ARE
WE HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
WE'RE BEING HELD
FOR RANSOM
BECAUSE OUR FATHERS
ARE RICH GANGSTERS.
BUT MY FATHER'S
NOT A GANGSTER.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
YOUR FATHER'S
THE BIGGEST GANGSTER
AND A COWARD.
MY DAD SAID
HE'S RESPONSIBLE
FOR THIS MESS.
BULLSHIT!
YOU'RE BULLSHIT!
WHY ARE YOU
FIGHTING?
EVERYTHING IS
GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT.
I WANT TO GO HOME.
AND YOU WILL.
WHEN?
SOON.
SHH.
NO MORE TEARS.
HERE.
COME WITH ME.
LEAVE HER ALONE.
OW!
UHH!
COME IN.
THANK YOU.
HI.
HERE'S YOUR USUAL.
AAH!
EVERY DAY
THE CHILDREN
ARE GONE,
IT'S GOING TO
COST YOU MONEY.
TAKE THAT MESSAGE
TO YOUR PEOPLE.
TAKE THE MONEY.
RUN. GO! GO!
HOLD IT. HOLD IT.
WHO ARE THESE
TWO HAPPY CAMPERS?
THEY WON'T
SAY ANYTHING.
BE STILL.
I SAID, BE STILL.
YOU'D THINK HE WAS HIDING
SOMETHING UNDER THERE.
MAY I?
BE MY GUEST.
WHAT THE HELL
IS THIS?
TROUBLE.
GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
[BEEP BEEP]
I'LL GET IT.
OK.
LIEUTENANT?
YOU WON'T BELIEVE THIS.
TRY ME.
THE KIDS OF THE
NEW FAMILY HEADS
HAVE BEEN SNATCHED.
THEY'VE NAMED THE PUNISHER
AS THE PRIME SUSPECT.
THEY'RE WRONG.
IT MAKES SENSE.
I KNOW IT DOES.
BUT THEY'RE WRONG.
DO YOU HAVE A REASON
FOR SAYING THAT?
I'VE GOT TWO REASONS
FOR SAYING THAT.
MY CONTACTS TELL ME
THE KIDS ARE HERE.
YOU SURE
THIS IS IT?
I'D STAKE
MY REPUTATION ON IT,
IF I HAD ONE.
DO YOU GOT A SPARE?
WHAT?
ONE OF THOSE.
IF THEY'RE HOLDING
THE KIDS HERE,
IT'S WITH
A FUCKING ARSENAL.
YOU MOVE LEFT
INSTEAD OF RIGHT,
YOU'RE DEAD.
THE CRITICS SAID
THE SAME THING
ABOUT MY HAMLET.
STAY HERE.
WATCH YOUR BACK.
THAT WAS A VERY EXPENSIVE
QUESTION YOU ASKED
AT OUR PLACE
THE OTHER NIGHT.
IT COST US NEARLY
$2 MILLION IN CASH.
HOW MUCH PAIN
DO YOU THINK THAT BUYS?
IS THE QUESTION
TRUE/FALSE OR
MULTIPLE CHOICE?
NEITHER.
UHH!
WHO SENT YOU?
BATMAN.
DO YOU GET THE IMPRESSION
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU?
DO YOU THINK
I GIVE A SHIT?
YOU HANDLE YOUR PAIN
VERY WELL.
LET'S SEE HOW WELL
YOU HANDLE THE PAIN
OF OTHERS.
NOW WILL YOU TELL ME?
YOU'RE A VERY
STUBBORN MAN.
I HAVE AN APPOINTMENT.
I WILL LEAVE YOU
IN THE HANDS OF MR. ITO.
HE WILL KEEP YOU ALIVE
MUCH LONGER
THAN YOU CARE TO BE.
GOODBYE.
HEY.
HAVE A NICE DAY.
WAIT.
COME HERE.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
I'VE GOT
SOMETHING TO SAY.
SAYONARA.
I DON'T WANT
TO STRETCH THIS OUT,
SO TELL ME
WHERE THE KIDS ARE.
DESERTED WAREHOUSE.
AVENUE "A."
TAKE CARE OF
THE LITTLE ONES.
THANK YOU FOR
YOUR COOPERATION.
YOU COULD SPEND
YOUR WHOLE LIFE DOWN HERE
AND NOT FIND ONE CLUE.
WE COULD GET LUCKY.
THE ETERNAL
OPTIMIST, HUH?
LOOK WHO'S TALKING.
FIVE YEARS
WITH NO LEADS.
NOW YOU'RE TRAMPING
AROUND THE SEWERS
ON A COMPUTER'S HUNCH.
HOW COME?
HOW COME WHAT?
HOW COME YOU
NEVER GAVE UP?
I KNOW WHAT
IT'S LIKE TO BE
GIVEN UP ON.
WHO GAVE UP ON YOU?
EVERYBODY.
EXCEPT HIM, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO, WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU KNOW HOW YOU GO OUT
FOR A DRINK AFTER WORK?
IN MY CASE IT WAS
THE DRINK BEFORE WORK,
THE DRINK DURING WORK,
AND FINALLY THE DRINK
INSTEAD OF WORK.
THEN IT BECAME
A PROBLEM.
NOBODY WANTED
TO DEAL WITH IT,
ESPECIALLY ME.
BEFORE I KNEW IT,
I WAS BUSTED DOWN
TO COLLECTING
EMPTY SHELL CASINGS
ON THE FIRING RANGE.
OUT OF SIGHT,
OUT OF MIND.
THEN ALONG COMES
FRANK CASTLE
WITH A SHINY NEW
DETECTIVE BADGE,
AND HE SAYS
HE WANTS TO LEARN
FROM THE GUY
WHO WROTE THE BOOK
ON BUSTING BAD GUYS.
ME.
HE TOOK ME
INTO HIS LIFE,
HELPED ME GET
MY ACT TOGETHER,
AND SHOWED ME HOW
TO BE A COP AGAIN.
SO WHAT'S A LITTLE
SEWER SHIT
FOR A FRIEND?
YOU KNOW, WHEN
WE GET OUR KIDS BACK,
I'LL RIP HER
FUCKING HEART OUT
WITH MY BARE HANDS.
I SWEAR.
NONE FOR ME.
I'M ON MEDICATION.
HEY,SALUD.
HERE'S TO
THE SAFE RETURN
OF OUR CHILDREN.
SALUD.
HERE WE GO.
SO, MR. FRANCO DECIDED
NOT TO ATTEND.
A WISE DECISION.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YOU FUCKING BITCH!
AAH!
WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR?
YOU'RE GOING TO
KILL US, DO IT!
I ALREADY HAVE.
CHAMPAGNE.
[CRYSTAL VIBRATES]
THE GLASSES.
THIRSTY, MR. DeLEO?
SINCE YOU HAVE
REFUSED THE DRINK...
PLEASE,
ACCEPT THE CHASER.
AAH!
BLACK COFFEE, ED.
THANKS.
HEY, THAT'S MY BUS!
HEY!
HEY, THAT'S MY STOP!
YOU MISSED MY STOP.
SORRY.
THANK YOU.
DON'T MENTION IT.
THE KID'S READY.
THE BOAT SAILS
IN AN HOUR.
I WANT YOU
TO MEET JIMMY.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
WAKE UP!
PSST!
UHH! UHH!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
I'M HERE
TO TAKE YOU HOME.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
COME ON.
LET'S GO.
RUN. RUN.
INTO THE BUS.
MOVE IT.
THEY TOOK TOMMY AWAY.
WHAT?
DOWN THE CORRIDOR.
CATHY. WHERE'S CATHY?
GET IN THE BUS.
COME ON.
STAY IN THE BUS, OK?
STAY HERE.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
TOMMY.
WHERE'S CATHY?
I DON'T KNOW.
COME ON.
I CAME DOWN
FOR MY DOLLY.
RUN TO THE BUS,
CATHY.
LET HIM GO!
SHOOT HIM!
GET DOWN!
WHERE'S TOMMY?
THEY'VE GOT HIM.
I'LL GET HIM BACK.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO.
HOLD ON!
STAY DOWN!
I'M SCARED.
YAAH!
SHIT! COPS!
HOLD ON!
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
COME ON, KIDS.
COME ON. OVER HERE.
HURRY. HURRY.
IS MY MOMMY HERE?
HURRY!
HELLO, FRANK.
HOW YOU BEEN?
BUSY.
OH, I KNOW.
I KNOW YOU HAVE.
I'M IN CHARGE
OF THE BODY COUNT.
WHAT THE HELL
HAPPENED, FRANK?
FRANK IS DEAD.
ALL RIGHT?
OH, I SEE.
SO YOU DECIDED
EVERYBODY ELSE
HAD TO BE DEAD, TOO.
IS THAT IT?
NAH.
IF YOU'RE GUILTY,
YOU'RE DEAD.
COURTS DECIDE
WHO'S GUILTY,
NOT COPS.
THEY HEREBY SWEAR
TO UPHOLD THE LAW.
REMEMBER?
I'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU
FOR FIVE YEARS, MAN.
WHY THE HELL DIDN'T YOU
COME TO ME FOR HELP?
I DIDN'T NEED YOUR HELP.
YOU'RE SICK.
YOU KNOW THAT,
DON'T YOU?
NO, I'M NOT.
THEN WHAT THE FUCK
YOU CALL 125 MURDERS
IN FIVE YEARS?
WORK IN PROGRESS.
GOD DAMN YOU! LOOK!
IT'S NO FUCKING JOKE HERE.
THEY ARE GOING
TO ELECTROCUTE YOU,
AND THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO ANYTHING ABOUT.
TALK TO ME, MAN.
LET ME IN!
THEY WERE MY FAMILY, TOO.
LET ME IN,
GOD DAMN IT!
LET ME IN!
I SEE.
YOU WANT TO DIE.
IS THAT IT?
WELL, FUCK YOU.
GO AHEAD AND DIE.
THE FRANK I KNEW
DIED FIVE YEARS AGO.
FUCK YOU!
OPEN THIS DOOR.
HA HA HA HA!
NO! PLEASE DON'T!
AAH!
IN A FEW MOMENTS,
FRANK CASTLE,
THE EX-POLICE OFFICER
WHO'S WAGED A ONE-MAN WAR
AGAINST ORGANIZED CRIME
FOR THE PAST FIVE YEARS,
WILL BE ESCORTED TO COURT
TO FACE AN UNPRECEDENTED
125 FIRST-DEGREE
MURDER CHARGES.
THERE'S STILL NO NEWS
AS TO THE WHEREABOUTS
OF TOMMY FRANCO,
THE SON OF CRIME BOSS
GIANNI FRANCO.
WHERE'S BERKOWITZ?
HURTING.
WHAT HAPPENED
BETWEEN YOU TWO--
WHAT DO YOU CARE?
HEY, I CARE.
I'M HIS PARTNER.
HE CARRIED THE BURDEN
FOR A LONG TIME
BY HIMSELF.
HE NEEDED HELP,
AND YOU WEREN'T THERE.
I WAS THE NEXT BEST THING.
HE RESIGNED
FROM THE FORCE
AFTER SEEING YOU.
HE LIVED
FOR THE DAY
HE FOUND YOU.
THAT'S ALL HE HAD,
AND NOW YOU'VE
TAKEN THAT AWAY.
HE'S YOUR BEST FRIEND.
WHY DO YOU WANT
TO TAKE HIM DOWN
WITH YOU?
YOU WERE HIS LIFE
BEFORE THIS EVER HAPPENED,
AND YOU'VE BEEN HIS LIFE
EVER SINCE,
AND YOU FUCKING WELL
KNOW THAT.
HOW LONG DO YOU THINK
SOMEONE CAN LIVE
AFTER YOU'VE
CUT OUT THEIR HEART?
A LONG TIME.
LIKE YOU?
IS THAT WHAT YOU
WANT FOR JAKE?
TO LIVE LIKE YOU?
CALL HIM.
WHAT?
I SAID, CALL HIM.
NIGHTY-NIGHT, ASSHOLE.
LET HIM BE.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR FAMILY
WASN'T SUPPOSED TO.
IF I COULD UNDO IT,
I WOULD, BUT I CAN'T.
I SWEAR THIS ON THE LIFE
OF MY SON THOMAS ANTHONY.
I WANT HIM BACK.
I CAN'T DO IT MYSELF,
OR I WOULD.
I NEED YOU, CASTLE.
I'LL GIVE YOU
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
I'LL DO
ANYTHING YOU WISH.
SAY SOMETHING.
FUCK YOU.
LET ME PUT IT
ANOTHER WAY.
A LIFE FOR A LIFE.
I'M NOT GOING
TO ASK YOU TWICE, CASTLE.
WELL?
OK.
OK, I'LL DO IT.
BUT UNDERSTAND...
WHEN THIS IS OVER,
YOU'RE DEAD.
THE ELEVATOR
STOPS AT 40.
THEY'RE ON 41.
WE NEED A KEY TO GET THERE,
WHICH THE LOBBY GUARD HAS.
FIVE MINUTES.
PUSH THE FIRST BUTTON.
WHAT'S THAT
GOING TO DO?
BLOW OUT THE LIGHTS.
SIR, JUST IN CASE,
IT'S BEEN AN HONOR
TO HAVE KNOWN YOU.
LIKEWISE.
CASTLE, HERE'S
SOME BODY ARMOR
FOR YOU.
JUST IN CASE.
HERE. JUST IN CASE.
HAVE IT YOUR WAY.
15 MINUTES.
YOU HIT
THE SECOND BUTTON.
WHAT'S THAT GOING
TO BLOW OUT?
EVERYTHING ELSE.
HEY.
I GOT TO
TAKE A LEAK.
BE MY GUEST.
THAT'S FINE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE BOSS WILL SAY
ABOUT A YELLOW STAIN
ON THE SEAT.
HEY, HEY, MAN!
THAT'S SKIN BACK THERE.
TAKE IT EASY.
UM...
WHAT?
ARE YOU GOING TO HANDLE
THE EQUIPMENT FOR ME?
IN FRONT.
CAN I ASK YOU
A QUESTION?
WHAT?
IS AN IQ TEST
REQUIRED FOR THIS JOB?
NO.
I DIDN'T THINK SO.
HEY, MAN,
I GOT THE PIZZA.
PSST.
CAN I ASK YOU
A QUESTION?
WHAT'S THE REASON BEHIND
YOU KILLING ALL THOSE GUYS?
THERE'S A LIMIT
TO REVENGE.
WELL, I HAVEN'T
REACHED MINE YET.
WHICH WAY?
NOT THAT WAY.
YOU GO THAT WAY.
[SIREN]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT
THIS POOR, OLD SLOB.
GET ON THE CASE.
DO THE JOB.
TAKE CARE OF THIS GUY.
I'LL OPERATE
UNDER MY OWN STEAM,
THANK YOU.
HERE. HOLD THIS.
TOMMY!
DAD!
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
TO GET AN ELEVATOR?
IT'S HARD TO SAY.
ELEVATORS ARE VERY
TEMPERAMENTAL THINGS.
SO DO COPS WHO HATE
BEING JERKED AROUND.
10 MINUTES.
HOW LONG?
HEY, HOW LONG?
UH, FIVE MINUTES?
AH, MR. FRANCO.
HOW NICE
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
LET HIM GO.
YOU'VE GOTTEN EVERYTHING
YOU WANTED.
NOT QUITE YET.
TAKE ANOTHER STEP,
MR. FRANCO.
WELL, YOU
CAN'T WIN HERE.
YOU KILL HIM,
I KILL YOU.
AND WHO LOSES MORE?
CERTAINLY NOT ME.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
ON YOUR KNEES.
ON YOUR KNEES!
PUT THE GUN
IN YOUR MOUTH.
YOU HAVE MY WORD
HE WILL LIVE.
HOW DO I KNOW
YOU'LL KEEP IT?
YOU DON'T,
BUT SOME CHANCE
IS BETTER THAN NO CHANCE.
ALL THE WAY IN.
PULL THAT TRIGGER,
MR. FRANCO.
NOW! NOW!
THIS IS PART
OF YOUR EDUCATION.
YOU WATCH.
GOODBYE, MR. FRANCO.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
LET'S GO.
TOMMY?
DAD.
TOMMY.
LET ME HAVE
A LOOK AT YOU.
CARE TO WALK?
YEAH.
OK. COME ON.
WAIT OUTSIDE, MY SON.
I'LL SEE TO HIM.
I CAN HELP HIM.
WAIT OUTSIDE, TOMMY.
I MUST
COMPLIMENT YOU, CASTLE.
YOU'VE DONE SOMETHING
I NEVER DREAMED POSSIBLE.
YOU'VE WIPED OUT
THE COMPETITION.
THANKS TO YOU,
THERE'S ONLY ME.
IN FIVE YEARS' TIME,
MY NEW ORGANIZATION
WILL BE THE MOST POWERFUL
CRIME SYNDICATE ON EARTH,
AND THAT BOY
WHOSE LIFE YOU SAVED
WILL INHERIT ALL OF IT.
AND THE ONLY THING
HE WILL HAVE TO FEAR,
I'M ABOUT TO ELIMINATE.
YOU GAVE ME BACK MY SON.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M IN YOUR DEBT.
SEE YOU IN HELL,
CASTLE.
DAD!
TOMMY!
DAD, STOP!
STOP!
DAD, GET OFF HIM!
[GUNSHOT]
DAD?
DAD.
I'M GOING TO KILL YOU.
GOOD.
MAYBE IF YOU
GET IT OVER WITH NOW,
YOU WON'T GROW UP
TO BE LIKE HIM.
COME ON.
DO IT.
WHAT THE HELL?
[WHISTLES]
WHOA.
ALL RIGHT.
SPLIT UP.
FRANK?
YOU'RE A GOOD BOY,
TOMMY.
GROW UP
TO BE A GOOD MAN.
BECAUSE IF NOT...
I'LL BE WAITING.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHICH WAY DID HE GO?
FRANK!
I STILL TALK
TO GOD SOMETIMES.
I ASK HIM IF WHAT I'M DOING
IS RIGHT OR WRONG.
I'M STILL WAITING
FOR AN ANSWER.
AND UNTIL I GET ONE,
I'LL BE OUT HERE.
WAITING.
WATCHING.
THE GUILTY
WILL BE PUNISHED.