Subtitles By NaV
Don't shoot me.
Who is that?
There's your money, release the hostage
How much in there? -
Three -
You're too late. We want five million dollars
Wha'da ya know, a greedy pirate
Last chance, take it or leave it
We want the money... now!
Goal in front of me-
No!-
A little low
I'll kill him, I swear I will kill him
Drop your guns!
Fat chance -
Yeah, that'll happen -
Last chance, let the hostages go
or you're outta there
Bring the money here to me, Cocoa face
I'll take the four on the left
Why don't you take the two on the right
leave the rest alone
I'll kill them all, I don't care
You should take the two on the right,
you're not that fast anymore
The only thing faster is light
We'll see
Bullets are faster than the blades
Bring the money here! Now!
Want money?
. Go and Get It
(cell phone: buzz-buzz!)
What's that?
Insects
Excuse me?
Kill him!
I call that a tie -
Come on, you're dreams -
These guys are arrested development
A little compassion, folks
Ya' know, I don't think you hit one of 'em
I don't see any knives actually
How you guys doin?
What the hell is he doin?
Hanging a pirate -
Don't be rediculous
Gunner! What are you doing?
Hanging a pirate
He's seriously demented
This is not good -
You're on your own -
'Preciate it, it's good to have friends
Gunner
Yeah?
This is not the way we work
Let him go
Why? He'd do it to us
Gunner, last chance)
. Let him go
or we let you go
It's good to hang pirates
We don't kill like that
Yeah? Not polite enough?
Let him go, Gunner -
How are you a partner? -
Very Good
My partner here kicked me with steel tipped boots,
can you believe that?
You deserved it
This will require stitches -
Maybe -
I hate stitches
Everyone does
Let him go, Gunner
Let him go
He's cool? -
Be careful, go -
Gunner, you cool?
Yeah
Nah, keep it
You appreciate a good blade
You alright?
Yes
Life just got to him
It'll get to all of us
Coming
Who is it?
Someday you'll find a man who'll be
happy just to watch you sleep
Hi, didn't know you were back
Hey, babe
I have just arrived
... hi -
.... Why, you look quite... -
I wish you would have called
I've never been a good caller
I hav'nt heard from you in over a month
Really?
Won't happen again, sorry
But, I do have a surprise
The first blend, a special
And
I have something else for you
Bought something
Surprise
It's a good color, but
It's hard to see in this light
It looked real shiny when I bought it in the shop
Grace
Is everything okay?
Yes?... -
Who's he? -
He's a friend
Kinda late.
You gotta name?
Friend. She just told you
Lee, come on...
Don't leave like this.
Lee, I'm sorry
I thought that things were good between us
I felt like you never cared about getting in my life,
or letting me into yours. Stop!
Sure I did
No, I have known you for over a year and a half
. And do not even know what your business is
What's wrong? When I am here
I am with you and that is what counts
What matters is, when you're here
. You're not really here
... You're a good man and I love you but
Grace! -
I hate his voice -
Did you say something? -
Don't let him come down here -
You do not understand what I'm saying,
you have to understand
I understand
You take care -
Lee -
He's no good, Louise
Hey, brother, don't you ever sleep?
. OK
... This is my friend
What is your name? -
Cheyanne -
Cheyanne, Arapahoe, Charikee, Pony
You wanna drink? -
I'm fine -
Why don't you run up them stairs and get me
one of them super good brews
6 olive Martini, baby -
Anything for you, baby -
You got it
She got a crush on me-
Like the last 50 -
Welcome back, my brother,
Damn, you look good
Yes, well, my friend
Let's finish this bird up
Yeah, brother. It's taken you a couple of
years to do a couple of letters
We had to get rid of Gunner
Yeah, well, he went crackistan on you ass
you gotta cut 'em loose
Yeah, you wanna fill in?
Let me tell you something
Remember where we were last time?
Where were we? In that mud & blood -
Nigeria -
Yes, your hand was all shot to shit
And you were bleedin all over the place,
and I was bleedin and ...
Since that time, I promised myself
I don't wanna die all alone full of
holes in the mud and the blood
I wanna die with something that counts.
I wanna die with a woman.
I wanna die, ya know, with someone who cares about me
Don't wanna die for a woman, I wanna die
laying next to a woman. That's what I want
It is Christmas time -
. Yes, I can smell him from here -
Mr. Christmas, how ya doin, brother?
I'm good, Toole
Take a look at this, what do you think?
Eh, it still looks like a black chicken
Black Chicken? -
Black Chicken? You done? -
Yes, I'm done -
It's a damn raven -
Oh, man!
Good to see ya, bud
You know what?
For you
I have a great idea
Why don't you let me doodle like a
... I do not know
A Charlette's Web on your head
Something different, something exciting
Because you a perfect dome muscular heads
... I can put a
web on the top of the head...
Maybe a pregnant Charlette coming out of your ear
peeking around
Making sure them bugs don't come inside...
Her long legs dangling down your neck?
Yes, sexy, right? -
. Very sexy -
This will give you a little mystery,
a little character
and very...sexy
That will make you stand out
He's thrilled, though
Ok, tell you what
I feel a little lucky tonight
I'm feeling very acurate
Maybe another time
Come on, take him on
Come on, Christmas, bring it, baby
I am a coward in his place
He never beat you in your life -
Come on, Christmas, no disgrace in losing -
Yes
Good
Well, I've go 3 pieces of work
Two a walks in the park
And one to hell and back
I need some time alone -
Hey, cheer up.  Make the meeting -
General!
Now we can see inside of him
And I see lies
He wasn't stealing from you, he was stealing from us
Both
Want to rate respect?
Smoke those two
Let's just keep it simple, if the money's right
we don't care where the job is.  Got it?
Let's quit jerkin' off...
Get down to business, see who's hungry.
I know your real name's probably not Barney Ross
You don't need to know my name
The only thing you need to know is that the job's real...
and the money's real.
And since we're in this beautiful place
Just Call me Mr. Church
Ok, Church, what can I do for you?
In a minute. Still waiting for one more guy.
Who?
You know him? -
Yeah, we used to be on the same team together-
What's my oldest worst friend doin' here?
Both your names came to the top of the list.
Is this a problem?
Yeah, should'a shot 'em when I had a chance.
Big Barney Ross!
Bigger Trent Mouzier
What are you doing here?
Praying for work?
Could be
Have you been sick?
You've lost weight
Really? Well, whatever weight I lost you found, pal.
You guys aren't gonna start sucking
each other's dicks, are ya?
Let's get down to business,
To see who wants to work
Ever hear of an island called Valiena?
No
Yes
It's a little island in the Gulf -
That's right-
You should read more
Thanks
There are resources on that island that my
people are very interested in
But a general by the name of Garza has overthrown
a hazardous government
That's right
My people are having a problem with this fanatic Garza
So you want Garza gone -
I want him dead -
All it takes is a little army. Only an idiot would do this job
How much?
Well, like I said...
I'm busy anyway, so give this job to my
friend here. He loves playing in the jungle
Right?
Right -
That's right -
Why don't we have dinner?
Sure, when?
In a thousand years
Too soon
What's his fuckin' problem?
He wants to be governor
I gotta recon this island first
I have a contact for you on the island
Good riddance
I got the feelin' that everyone else has passed
on this job, so our fee is... five million
5 million?
I want half up front, the other half in an offshore account,
you got a problem with that?
No
What I have a problem with
is people who try to fuck me over
So if you take this money
And you don't deliver
or you try to fuck me with some kinda weird
cockamamie scheme of yours
Me, and my people
are gonna come get you and your people
and chop you up into little fucking dog treats
You gotta problem with that?
Let's talk
Valiena -
Yeah, Valiena -
They got work there?
Come on
I ain't got shit for you, Gunner
Don't replace me
I'm good
I'm still good
You're still using. I can't trust you anymore, man
You can't trust me? -
Yeah -
You can't trust me?
Be careful
You threatening me, Gunner?
No
I am a nice guy
So, going over the info this guy Church gave me, there's
probably about six thousand people on the island
How many soldiers?
Perhaps a few hundred
Wouldn't take much more than that
to control a space that small
Great. They got a small army
And what have we?
Four and a half men
Not so funny
I need a raise. -
Why?-
I need the money for my son
I want to send him to a better school
When did Yen Yang get a family?
I have no idea -
You no ask -
I no tell
Anyway...
The pay share will stay the same.
That's the way it's gonna be.
Now, the target on the island, a guy named
General Garza
What's the problem? -
Who gives a shit what the problem is? -
We have problems here is enough for us
That we can not get rid of them
. First get rid of us
Totally, when's the last time you seen your analyst?
This morning -
Yeah? What you talk about? -
Avoidant Personality Disorder
You think too much -
You know, Tollwell? -
You're an unusual guy. And you're always gonna
have unusual problems, right?
Unusual? You are talking about my ear
Oh, come on, don't start with the ear again.
Not the ear story again
Not again, we all know the ear story
We all know
Let's just concentrate on the job -
Hey, no. Shit, no. You guys started this -
We all know I wrestled in college
Right
A common injury associated with that sport
is trama to the ear
a clot
Which, if left unattended, causes a contraction in the cartilage
and forms cauliflower ears
And your point is? -
It ain't easy being green -
In any case
Me and Christmas are gonna head down to Valiena
and scout the island to see if we should take the job
How much pay?
I need more money for my family
What family?
My family
Listen, that girl wasn't your type
Her lost, right? -
I should've broke that bastard's jaw-
Maybe if you were lucky he could've broke yours
Impossible
You know,Christmas
I understand, but
Let's just say you were with her for a couple of hours,
and it's nice and it's hot and heavy
But after that, think about it...
What do you do for the rest of the day?
She probably did you a favor
You have more time to feel sorry for yourself
You are a great bastard
Good morning
Good Morning -
Speak English? -
Big plane, huh?
Yeah, we use it to tranport injured animals -
Why are you here? -
Ornithologist
We are photographing exotic packs
You're nervous? -
Nervous? -
Why? -
You look nervous -
Do I look nervous?
Yeah, your skin looks a little dry, I think
you should fly with the windows closed
It's the altitude
It is the altitude, it'll get to you
What is the address?
Yes, it's in my head
Wanna share it?
Canteen Gloria
Spanish
Who are you? Zoro?
Army
Come on, in there
You rollin'?
Yeah
Get the suit. Tighten up on the suit
Got it
Look at these clowns, hand picked monkeys
What's wrong with this picture?
Everything
Let's get out of here
What's the point? I mean, you think you know
someone, and you truly do not.
Aren't you the guy who said "The man who can best
get along with women is the man who can
get along without them"?
That's bullshit
Truthfully, she wasn't your type
I wasn't finished -
Look, enjoy your freedom -
Yeah, you wait 'til it happens to you -
It has -
Contact's late
Alright, let's go
Chill
You ever been rejected?
You're really pushing the boundaries of
our relationship, you know that?
Is that our contact?-
Could be-
I'll bet she's all about it -
Stay focused -
You the contact? -
I'm Sandra -
What are your names?
(Buda)
(Pest)
Follow me, please
Buda...Pest...nice.
You do all these?
Yes
Take one
A gift -
I don't take free gifts, ah... -
How much do you want for it? -
Nothing taking money for something is not a gift -
Taking nothing for something is-
Oh-
Is it like this all the time?
This place was a beautiful place
Then, one day, they came with money and
General Garza sold his soul
And the people who fight back are killed
You said "THEY came with money".  Who's they?
Some Americans
That's all I know
But one day all this will change
You really believe that? -
Yes -
The best day will be the one when we can say
our lives are our own again
Do you have family, Sandra?
My mother died when I was small
And my father is gone too
Sandra, how close can you get to the palace?
The palace?
Why?
I just wanna...check out the view there
There is no view
Why don't we just go there anyway, ok?
Where is my growth?
Where is your manpower?
Do you know how long it takes
for a cocoa field to produce?
Of course you don't, let me tell you
We are 8 weeks behind schedule
Kick your peasants' asses,
get me my product
When you talk like this to me in front of my men
It's no good
I am your lifeline.  I am the one who
coordinates all this confusion
I am making you rich
And being wealthy is very good
It allows people to be the real ass-wipes
nature intended them to be
Sometimes
Things are just not worth the money
Sure they are
Sandra, are we close?-
It's just over there-
Pull over please
Where are you going?
Where am I going.
Well, I suppose you could say
I love to see the world from different views
Do not lose my hat
We should get goin'
He's very emotional
What are you looking for?
Sandra...
How do I know you're not setting us up?
What does "setting us up" mean?
You don't look like the kind of person we deal
with all the time. How did you get involved in this?
An American came here. He asked
my friend to show you around.
He was afraid, so he asked me to
And you're not afraid.
I'm afraid
But he said that maybe you can help the Valiena
I don't think so
Listen
If I were you, I'd leave
Just leave
You should leave
Do not say anything, let me speak
Run!
Get her -
Got her -
Are you crazy?!
You could have killed me! -
You're Welcome! -
Alright, speed it up!
We are on the way
We get out of here it's a miracle
She's coming with us, right? -
She'd better -
How can we leave? -
We have a plane -
No, I can not leave
Well, you don't have no choice -
Yes, I do -
They'll find you in an hour -
Maybe, but I'm staying -
Stay for what?
There's nothing here
Not to you
Look, you stay here, you're dead.
She's leaving with us
I got the guys inside -
Give me a 60 second lead -
You got it-
Go. Go. Go.
Come on
Get in
Get in! -
No, no, I can not -
Let's go -
I can not.  I belong here -
There is no time -
Go. You Go -
You look nervous
Run!
Run, you burfbag!
Where is the girl? -
Gone. She won't leave -
Won't leave? Don't know of anybody
who would want to stay
I don't believe this shit
Climb, baby, climb
Goin' back?
Yeah -
Ride & die -
Ride & Die,
let's do it
Great job
That was a statement?
How did two, obviously professionals, pass
right through security personal
kill 41 soldiers and get away?
With help, that's how
Everything is under control except for
one detail
A daughter
Who wants her father and company dead
and gone. Bad Shakespear
Some how the Company parasites got to her.
Look, she's your daughter, and that's tragic
But blood or not, she goes
To hell with the price of lemons
You don't kill your family -
Come around my house during the holidays, pal-
Nice bird
First of all, I do not feel comfortable talking business
with a giant carrying a shotgun
Pretty boy wouldn't give it up
Not if you wanna know where they are
What do you know?
I was one of them
Why are you turning on them? -
Personal problems -
We settled on 50 -
No, math wiz -
We settled on a hundred grand,
up front in my pocket
This guy thinks he's a real bad ass
This case is a bloody joke
Life is a joke, shitface!
If you don't want that Fu Man Chew knocked back into
the 60s, you better keep your gum chewin'
trap shut, and show some respect
Bring it
Hey! Be nice
Need a face lift, pretty boy?
Back off, Peyton -
I'm gonna kill him -
We need him
Back off!
This is what I think is happening. This guy who calls
himself Church is really a front for the CIA
So, we're working for the Agency -
Yeah -
Church hired us to take out the General but the
real target is this guy - James Monroe
He used to be with the Agency, but got greedy,
went rogue, and teamed up with the General to keep
the whole drug operation for themselves
And that's a big cash plus. But Church and the Agency
can't afford to send in the Navy Seals or Special Forces
to take out one of their own
That would be a bad head line, so they hire us to kill 'em
Then they're back in business
And we're taken out-
Nobody's gonna miss us-
Is it still 5 million?
We'd never live to spend it.
I'm telling Church the deal's off
Sound about right?
It's about right -
I agree -
Where is he?
Who the hell is this?
Some punk
Do not worry about it
We got your back
If he comes over here
we'll bust his ass
What do you want?
Your life
I was thinking about taking it -
Is that right? -
But I don't do so well in tight spaces,
so going to prison worries me
You shouldn't have bruised her face -
Really? -
Would have like to have kept it the way it was
Well keep the bitch 'cause I'm done with it
I'd still like to deflate your real balls
Friend
Now you know what I do for a living
I'm not perfect, but you should have waited
I was worth it
So your daughter paints too
This is how it starts!
Let's go, there's nothing -
This is all how it ends! -
What's the matter, Barney? Don't you ever sleep?
Nah. What happened to your girlfriend?
Ha. Another one bites the dust, brother
I was going to paint this for her and uh...
you know what? I'm gonna finish it
Then I'm just gonna smash the shit out of it
Want be alone?
Not really
So what's up?
On the island, there was this girl
Yep, usually are
Yeah
She showed us around, she was the target's daughter
When she had a chance to leave...
she didn't do it
Ump, she had some guts
Why can't I get that out of my mind?
'Cause she stands for something
We don't, man, we don't stand for shit.
We used to, but...
That dried all up like this is gonna dry all up
It's your paint is gonna dry
What dried up?
Just belief. Just belief in the soul. Just...
I don't know, the human parts, brother.
You remember that time we were up in Bosnia?
We took down them Serb bad boys?
All our guys were gettin' chopped up all around us and...
there was blood everywhere
I never thought I was gonna make it out of there,
and I know you didn't...
and you didn't either -
Yeah -
Kinda feelin' like...dead too, ya know?
My head's all very, very black place.
Didn't believe in shit
Just goddamn directly to black
I remember I got this bottle of this local shit they have
over there. That Silvits...I think that's what it was called
And I ain't feelin' no pain now
... and I come up on this, uh...
I come up on this overland bridge, and I see this
.... I see this
I see this woman standing there, ya know?
... and she's uh...
I stepped out, and she saw me,
and she's just lookin' right...
right in my eyes. And I was lookin'
her right in her eyes, and...
I knew what she was going to do
She looked at me, and I knew
she was gonna jump
You know what I did, man?
I just turned around and I just kept walkin'...
Until I heard that splash
And she was gone.
After...
after taking all of them lives...
she was one that...
I could have saved
but I didn't, and uh...
What I realized later on was uh...
if I'd have saved that woman...
I might have saved what was
left of my soul, ya know?
A wise dead man once told me that a real man...
never strikes a woman
You push some, if you have to
but you never strike
It's the way I was raised
This man, however,
does not share that moral dellima...no
.... This man
...well
So the question is, Sandra...
Why were the Americans here?
Again
What did the American tell you?
What are they after?
Continue
I'm going back to Valiena -
Yeah? Something's changed? -
What is the plan? -
There is no plan -
We need a strategy -
I'm going, and you're not -
What? -
I said I'm going and you guys are not -
Are you out of  your mind? -
It's personal business -
You don't owe that woman nothing -
Didn't say I did -
If you want to kill yourself, fine. Your call
Listen, I don't want to kill myself.
You guys take care. I gotta do this
I gotta do this
Hey, hey!-
What?
Don't lay this guilt crap on us.
We don't deserve it
Hey, this is my choice, there's no guilt
There's no guilt
Take care
Yeah, fuck it, his choice
Yeah...
I said I'm going alone
I'm going too
Come on, Yang, get out
Just drive
Do not lose your nerve
Don't talk to me, cockroach
Why are you doing this?
Friends die together
Hey! Give me the good luck ring. Come on
Don't make me hurt you, Yang. Come on
Speed better than luck
Whatever...
It's difficult
What is?
My life is difficult. I need more money
Why's that?
I work harder than the rest -
No you don't -
Yes I do
Because they're taller
Everything's harder for me
When I get hurt, the hole is bigger
Because I'm smaller
When I travel, I need to go further -
I know, because you're smaller, right? -
Yes
My life is harder than you think
I need more money
I know, you told me
For your family, right?
I don't have family
I know
Maybe one day I will
Get out there! -
Why me? -
Because you're smaller
Oops
Do that again, I'll kill ya!
Gunner!
Aww! Beautiful!
That's good
What are you doin'?
You're dead, junkie!
Insects
Shit!
What are you wearing? Size 3?
Bring it, Happy Feet
My turn!
Gunner!
Shit!
You shot me
Don't say that. You were gonna kill him
I was just gonna scare him
Don't put that on me, you never liked him
Am I dying?
Shot you a couple of inches above your heart
I'll take that as a "yes"
Gunner, who sent you?
Who hired you?
Who cares?
Do yourself a favor, don't let go until you
cooperate for once in your miserable life
That better make me right
You got it
Who sent you? Who sent you?
Is the girl still alive? -
Come closer -
You know, it's not easy being your friend
That's true
Man, we'll die with you.
Just don't ask us to do it twice
I know the lay out.
I'll tell you about it on the way
What the hell happened to you?
It's too sad to talk about it
Let's fly
You know, the enemy will
always be terrified of noise
Especially shotguns
With this big boy spittin' out 250 rounds a minute,
you tell me who's tolerating that
Absolutely zero
So let me get this right: Gunner tries to kill you,
you shoot him, at death's door he gives you
the whole layout?
It was something like that
I would have win -
I know you would have win -
You know what?
I trust you
Want you to meet my girlfriend
(Oomayah Kaboom)
You lost me there
When Oomaya's primer strikes, she gets off
a reentry warhead that arms itself
And when that happens, anything that gets in my
lady's way becomes instant red sauce and chowder
And if that doesn't work...
Her sister will
You should meet my doctor
Too late
It's 3:36. We have 20 minutes to take this
place down. I'll take the cellar
We've got company
I've got him. You guys take off
Is there a reason you've taken the soldiers this
man has trained and made them look like fools?
They look like warriors
Warriors loyal to me
I thought the people of Valiena hired
these mercenaries to kill me
But then I think, maybe this is your plan
Because you can not control me
And torturing Sandra
Works for you
You want to kill her to make me suffer
A man can never kill a child
But you can
Bring Sandra here
Bring her now
Or I will kill you
Go get her!
It's me
I won't hurt you
How are you here?
I just am
Can you move?
Yes
Ok
Time's up. Where's Barney? -
What's the call? -
If he's not come in 10 minutes, we're gonna
assemble the same way we came in -
No way! -
This's what he wants -
Ten minutes! -
Let's go
Stop! Don't!
No, don't kill him!
It's not his fight, it's mine! -
Get here out of here! -
Seal the building
Stand him up
If you didn't have this kevlar vest
your insides are gonna be like fuckin' mush
Well ain't that a shame?
You know you're a lucky man
Well, I ain't feelin' lucky, man
You are a lucky man
He told me to keep you conscious
Did he?
Alright. First...
you're a real tough guy, aren't you?
What? -
Are you a real tough guy? -
Look at me you piece of trash
How many men you got?
Just your mother!
This is your last time
You give me the right answer
I'll cut you a break
You give me the wrong answer you will die
a damned slow death. Do you understand me?
Yes -
Do you understand me? -
Yep-
Who sent you?
Breathe, can't breathe
Loosen up
Who sent you?
Your hair dresser
GO, MAN, GO!
Come on!
Shit!
Remember this shit at Christmas!
Damn, that thing's loud! -
What happened to you? -
Got my ass kicked
Alright, come on!
Get my rifle, let's go!
What's this?
Everything bad that has happened you bring
Take your money!
I only see death with you.
Take it all and go!
I'm not goin' anywhere -
You are done here -
You can't succeed without me
I am the leader!
You're a puppet in a hat!
Shut up! -
No! -
NOW!
Get back!
(Throw down your weapons!)
(There's no way out!)
Shit's gettin' old!
Your lucky ring stinks
I know
Let's backtrack -
Building's rigged. This is the only way out-
Chopper's ready in 5 minutes-
We're not leaving yet-
What's he saying? -
He's saying we're dead with an accent -
We ain't dead
Blow the building -
Not yet -
We will kill this American disease
Blow the building! -
She's down there! -
The money!
Blow it!
She's out!
Blow the fucking building!
I'm out!
Let's go, come on!
Cut Monroe off!
Come on!
Hey!
It's too heavy -
Give me it -
What do you want me to do?
Throw it as high as you can
Blow up the dump
Got it
Monroe!!
Drop the weapons, or I'll
put a bullet through her eye
Don't test me
No No -
Shut up or I'ill kill you -
The Agency's parasites hired you, didn't they?
I'd have paid you twice as much...
to go fishing
You have to think I'm pretty freakin'
stupid to surrender to the Agency
Why would I do that?
I created this
I made it all happen
And they wanted me out. Why?
Because I saw the big picture
Stop walking
And what about me and you?
We both the same...
we're both mercenaries
We're both dead inside
Why the hell did you come after me?
I didn't come after you, dipshit.
I came for her
Call it a tie
Yeah, I guess so
You're not as fast as you think
I'm beginning to sense that
Same account number as mine. It'll
help get things going around here.
No, I can't
You've done so much -
Yeah, well, so have you -
Gift for a gift
You take it
Will you come back?
I promise I'll always be around
Take care, Sandra
Take care
Bye
What?
Truthfully? -
Yeah -
I never really thought she was your type
Come on, let's see what you've got
Ghostdiver!
Ohhhh! You...go...You...go!
So, you're back from the dead
How ya healin?
Good
Considering you could have kill me
I forgive you
OK
I would have win
Of course
Hey Garner!
Whatever doesn't kill you makes
you stronger, brother. Therapy
Man's got a point
You know what?
I'm gonna do you a favor, Toole
I once knew a man called Toole
I love poetry
to me was the epitome of cool
He was good with a knife
Bad with a wife
That hurts -
But to think he could beat me -
Dreaming
He'd defeat me
Cool Toole
You gotta be a fool
Please give your comments on opensubtitles.org
user name nav_sx