.. [ Choir Singing Liturgy ]
[ Baby Coos ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Whispers ]
[ Dialing Phone ]
[ Speaking Serbian ]
- Da ?
- Da.
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Men Speaking Russian ]
[ Russian Continues ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Car Door Slams ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Man Shouts ln Russian ]
[ Engine Chugging ]
[ Goat Bleats ]
[ Cow Lows, Dog Barks ]
[ Engine Chugging ]
[ Chugging Fades ]
[ Rumbling ]
[ Electronic Tone ]
[ Heavy Footfalls ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Man Speaking Russian ]
[ Men Speaking Russian ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Shouts ln Russian ]
- [ Speaking Russian ]
- [ Beeping ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Rapid Beeping ]
[ Brakes Squealing ]
[ Chattering ln Russian ]
[ Explosion ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ People Shouting, Moaning ]
[ Baby Crying ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Panting ]
What happened ?
I don't know, Dr. Kelly.
Please come with me, ma'am.
[ People Chattering ]
[ Man ] I've got estimates on
cloud size comin' through on line six.
- What've we got ?
- NORAD's got R4 going over sector 9877.
It's been localized.
Sixty degrees longitude, fifty lat.
- What about N.P.I.C. ?
- Ground blast 40 minutes ago
in the Ural Mountains.
Two trains collided.
One was carrying warheads to Cherbynsk.
- Nice hair. Very au naturel.
- Jesus.
Nuclear forces are going from
DEFCON four to DEFCON three.
Secured faxes comin' in now.
N.M.C.C.'s concerned the Russians
are gonna use this incident...
to veil troop movements
into Chechnya and Georgia.
That's not our problem.
Estimates from Livermore ?
Five to seven hundred
kilotons.
Mark Appleton's looking for you.
He's upstairs.
- All current data on my desk ?
- Yes.
- I'm gonna need a minute.
- Radiation pattern projections in ?
- Yeah, but those aren't confirmed.
- Get them confirmed.
[ Man ] Russia. What a fucking mess.
God, I miss the Cold War.
Get Essler down here now.
I need a translator.
Essler's gone.
He quit to run J.P.L.
- Who did we appoint ?
- My memo's sitting on your desk.
- Who the hell's in charge down there ?
- [ Kelly ] Mark ?
Mark ?
Excuse me.
Sorry. Forget Chernobyl.
This is-- This is huge.
Dr. Julia Kelly,
Acting Chair, Nuclear Smuggling Group.
- You know Terry Hamilton,
National Security Advisor.
- Yes, sir.
- We met at last year's Christmas party.
- I'm briefing the president.
I need to explain how,
with our own START team there,
a goddamn accident
like this could happen.
It wasn't
an accident, sir.
I'm sorry ?
We believe that train was
carrying SS18s.
- SS18s pencil out at One Point Safe.
- What's she saying ?
It means if you fire a bullet
directly into the warhead,
there's less than a one-in-a-million
chance of the bomb going off.
The warhead has to be ignited
by its own nuclear trigger.
Would you hold this, please ?
Here we have the satellite imagery.
This is the two trains approaching,
and here's the collision itself.
Now check out
the field of regard.
These two shots are at the same height
because they occurred at the same time.
Look at the blast.
It's two degrees higher,
after the satellites passed over.
Elapsed time
between shots ?
Between the train wreck
and the detonation, 4 minutes.
Somebody set that nuclear weapon off.
This was a terrorist act.
Full N.S.C. briefing
at 9:00 a.m.
The Russians' accident story will stand
for now. No leaks to the press.
Nobody shows up on Nightline.
Doctor-- ?
Kelly.
I'm putting your group on point
until I find a replacement.
Yes, sir.
Oh.
Get me the latest satellite overviews,
and keep the updates coming.
Okay, uh, State, we're gonna need
talking points for the president.
We're also gonna need to know anybody
that might want to detonate a nuke
on Russian soil.
General, I'm gonna need
a military liaison...
with intel background
and Russian contacts.
- You've got it.
- Oh, and, General,
make sure he's willing
to take orders from a woman.
[ Woman ] Colonel Devoe,
let's deal with the events of May 18.
You were arrested
in a bar brawl...
in a Moscow disco
called Night Crawler ?
Yes, ma'am,
that's correct.
And you were in the company
of a prostitute...
and a Russian
army colonel named...
Dimitri Vertikoff ?
Yes, ma'am,
that is also correct.
Dimitri and I went into this bar
to try and buy some nerve gas...
off this ex-K.G.B. guy
that we had heard...
was selling black market
surplus munitions to lraq.
The fight started because, well,
we'd run up a bit of a bar tab--
I believe the exact
amount was $5,200 ?
Mm-hmm. Well, we had dinner,
and I bought a couple of rounds.
Uh, Colonel Vertikoff
identified the K.G.B. guy,
and we were able to stop the nerve gas
from getting to lraq.
So how do you repay
a man like that ?
- Sports utility vehicle ?
- That's exactly right.
Dimitri has a teenage daughter.
She likes to go four-wheeling.
I know this Ford guy in Maryland who cut
me a great deal on these Explorers.
- I like the Bronco better myself.
- Colonel, let me get this straight.
You spent taxpayers' money
to buy and ship...
a Ford Explorer
8,000 miles...
to the teenage daughter
of a Russian colonel ?
Yes, ma'am.
Think of it as
exporting goodwill.
[ Men Chattering ln Russian ]
Your Russian is awful.
Speak English.
- [ Speaking Russian ]
- It was stupid, understand ?
Your friends made this deal,
but this is my operation.
Don't make me start thinking
of why I don't need you.
- They will never let us through.
- Of course they will.
Section 21-A,
Nuclear Disaster Protocol.
One, secure area.
Two, control debris.
Three,
evacuate casualties.
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Chuckles ]
Huh ?
[ Kelly ] But they would have
the technical knowhow...
and should not be ruled out.
And moving on, we come to
Shamil Basayev, a scientist.
He claims responsibility
for having placed...
a canister of radioactive cesium
in a park in Moscow last June,
but his underworld ties suggest he could
be part of a much bigger operation.
Uh,
Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev,
Chechen leader since the
Russians assassinated Dudayev.
He has threatened to attack
Federation nuclear power plants.
There are other possibles on
our terrorist list,
as outlined in section 4
of your packet.
Our reaction to the crisis
is as follows.
We have initiated
an intelligence directive...
with the Nuclear Smuggling
Group acting as hub.
D.I.A. and N.R.O., heads up.
You'll continue responsibility
for primary SAT imagery--
Excuse me, ma'am. I'm sorry.
I don't mean to interrupt.
- Yes ?
- Um, these terrorists,
have they asked for anything,
a list of demands ?
Russians out of Chechnya ?
That sort of thing ?
No, but it's not unusual
for days, even weeks to go by...
before a claim
of responsibility is made.
- Yeah.
- Air mob command--
Uh, excuse me again, ma'am.
I'm sorry.
Uh, that's a satellite shot of the two
trains just before they collided.
Dr. Kelly, perhaps you should discuss
Special Op possibilities ?
Right. General Garnett has Special
Operations command at full alert.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. I'm sorry
to keep interrupting.
You see these blobs right here
at one-meter resolution ?
Those are people jumping off
the passenger train before it crashes.
Now take a look at that train.
That's the one with the nuke.
Nobody's jumpin' off that.
Why not ?
They were already dead.
[ Man ]
How many warheads were on that train ?
-The Russians haven't confirmed.
-So we have no idea of potential yield.
Are you suggesting
this was a robbery ?
I'm suggesting that
whoever did this...
had access to Russian satellite
positioning intel.
That leaves out
your Chechen rebels.
[ Murmuring ]
I would like
to point out...
that 1,500 people
were killed last night.
You don't do that unless you're trying
to make a very profound statement.
Do you know how much a functioning nuke
is worth on the open market ?
Minimum $200 million, cash.
$200 million makes for
a very profound statement.
Now, I'm sorry, ma'am.
The detonation was a smoke screen.
This was a hijacking, and whoever
stole these things...
got off the bus
a long way back.
[ Murmuring ]
Well, we will certainly be
considering your theory.
Thank you very much.
Well, it's just an opinion.
Whoever has current data on the blast,
I need it on my desk A.S.A.P.
[ Woman ]
You got it.
Ken, try to get Russian Missile Command
on the phone, please.
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Whistles ]
- First reports in say the
explosion was seen 500 miles--
- Anything on D.I.A. ?
- We should have Russian intel
within the half hour.
- Great.
Sue, I need the START observers' report.
Not just the summaries.
- Not just the abstracts.
The whole thing.
- I'm all over it.
- And where the hell
is my military liaison ?
- Right here.
Lieutenant Colonel
Tom Devoe...
reporting as ordered, ma'am.
My enthusiasm sometimes
gets the best of me.
I hope that I didn't
offend you in there.
No. Of course not.
- Coffee ?
- Sure. I'd love some.
It's over there.
[ Ken ] Russian Missile Command's
holding on line six.
And I would like to reiterate
our commitment to helping you
come up with some answers.
- Yes.
- I--
- No, I understand, General.
- I brought you some coffee.
I'm gonna--
Uh, that's right.
Well, we need to know
exactly who was on that train.
Uh, no, I am the man in charge.
I report directly to the president.
What do you want me to say ?
I don't see what
that has to do with anything.
Yes, well--
I see.
No. I understand.
I think I have--
I know I have a couple--
All right.
- Well, if you would be able
to get back to me...
- Excuse me.
with the names of the men who were on
the train and the number of warheads,
Go to the--
- that would be wonderful.
- In my office.
- And how long do you think
that will take ?
- [ Chuckles ]
Well, uh,
I'll be expecting
your call.
Thank you.
To repeat, CNN has confirmed
the detonation of
a nuclear device in Europe.
[ Overlapping Chatter ]
[ Kelly ] We got confirmation.
There were ten warheads on that train.
- Departure orders. Forty men on board.
- This is meaningless.
- It's in Russian.
- [ Speaking Russian ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
- Princeton.
- Mmm.
The blue-blooded backbone
of our country.
- My father's a mailman.
- Well, you'd never know.
Ilin, Kodoroff, Kulik,
Levindovsky, Lu--
- Kodoroff ? Aleksander Kodoroff ?
- Yeah. You know him ?
Yeah, I know him.
Goddamn it !
I don't know about the rest of these
guys, but General Aleksander Kodoroff...
doesn't ride around on
a nuclear transport train.
Get me N.M.C.C. Intel,
please.
- It's like lvana Trump on a subway.
- Can you get my files ?
- Have that enhanced off the Urals.
- [ Man ] Yes, sir.
- Sergeant.
- Sir.
We know Kodoroff's under
investigation for corruption,
probably gonna be indicted.
Gave a speech nine days ago
in Saint Petersburg.
Mostly nationalistic bluster,
bemoaning the loss of empire...
- and unity of the Slavic peoples.
- Yeah, yeah.
Family history, phone records,
bank statements.
Urinalysis from a Moscow traffic stop
last month: .367.
- I'm amazed he could turn the key.
- That's a few cocktails.
Saw his dentist on Tuesday,
had dinner with some
very attractive people on Friday.
We haven't been able
to l.D. them yet.
Jesus, Costello,
you're slippin'.
- Oh, I'm gettin' old, sir.
- You're not old.
General Garnett's old.
[ Chuckles ]
If you don't mind me askin',
sir, is Kodoroff involved ?
- We don't know. He was on the train.
- You see, that's funny.
- Why's that ?
- Because the General's got
this Finnish mistress.
- She lives in Helsinki.
- Laina.
- Guy calls her every day
like clockwork. Never misses.
- So ?
Well, the thing is,
if this Kodoroff guy was on that train
and he's so dead,
who's bouncin' calls to Laina
in Helsinki off some satellite
over southern Russia ?
If that's a secure phone, I need it.
Excuse me, General.
[ Dialing Phone ]
Sir, if a top-ranking
Russian general is involved,
any intel we get from Moscow
is either compromised--
Palkawunic Vertikoff
Pajaloosta.
- Or a flat-out lie.
- You're right.
Dimitri, Tom Devoe.
- What do you want ?
- Are you busy ?
I'm with two women.
Call me back some other time.
How're you guys
holdin' up ?
I think the only virtue is,
people are forgetting Chechnya.
[ Chuckles ] Yeah. Listen, D, I've got
the troop manifest from that train.
Alek Kodoroff got vaporized
out there, did he ?
- Yeah. What a shame.
- Yeah.
So how is it he's calling Laina
from a bird over southern Russian ?
How's he doin' that, D ?
Hey, D,
are you still there ?
You must be wrong
about that, Tom.
Our figures indicate the fallout
should have dissipated by then.
Let me fax you what we've got.
Your number ?
Hold on. Fax number, please.
Hang on.
[ Devoe ]
All right, 0-0-1-7-0-3...
- 5-1-1-6-8.
- Six-eight.
I'm going to hang up now.
Bye.
Listen, D--
That scared him.
- Is this the fax ?
- Yes, sir.
[ Newscaster ] lnformation
on the nuclear weapon incident...
in Russia's Ural Mountains
is still sketchy at this hour,
but we do have a few new facts
about the magnitude of the disaster.
Seismographs around the world
detected the blast,
and we have reports that the explosion
was seen as far away as Lithuania...
on the Baltic Sea.
Initial projections indicate
the nuclear fallout...
will affect all of Russia
and northern Europe.
There's still no word
on casualties.
There's word that President
Clinton will issue a statement
on this tragedy in 30 minutes.
Vienna, 2:00 p.m.,
Bacherplatz.
Why Vienna ?
- Kordech.
- Maybe.
Kordech is a front for
the Russian mafia in Vienna.
And it's
a trucking company.
Whether it was an accident
or a deliberate act of terrorism
remains a question.
I need NORAD's sector 9877
intel from the Urals,
updated fallout patterns...
and troop movements
from NATO humint.
Honey-roasted. Think anybody'll mind
if I stole a couple of bags ?
My old man will get a kick
out of the Executive Seal.
Go ahead.
Knock yourself out.
Would you call Langley ?
We're still waiting on the
psych profile on Kodoroff.
He's an asshole.
I'll save you a trip.
Thanks. I'll settle for
the official version.
Okay. Officially,
he's an asshole.
He'll do anything for money,
which is the good news,
'cause it makes him
fairly predictable.
I'd say he's been
anything but predictable.
He took an order for an
expensive, hard-to-find product,
and he intends to
make good on delivery.
Supply and demand.
Your area of expertise,
right, Colonel ?
At least, that's
the word on the Hill.
You've been
checkin' up on me.
I like to know
who I'm working with.
I'd like
to know something.
You moved from Lawrence Livermore
to the White House.
So, first you build the bombs
to blow up the entire world...
and now you wanna
save it.
Make up your mind.
Which is it gonna be ?
Well, I believe
this week we're saving it.
- [ Chuckles ]
- So, it's really that simple ?
It is to me,
that simple.
And when you've been the boss for more
than two weeks, you'll know that.
Three weeks.
You've done some checkin' yourself.
Well, I like to know
who I'm workin' with.
Doctor, you can run your charts
and your theories all you want.
In the field,
this is how it works.
The good guys-- that's us--
we chase the bad guys,
and they don't wear black hats.
They are, however,
all alike.
They demand power and respect,
and they're willing to pay
top dollar to get it.
And that is our
highly motivated buyer.
- What about other motivations ?
- Not important to me.
Whether it's important to you or not,
there are people out there...
who don't care about money
and don't give a damn about respect,
people who believe the killing of
innocent men and women is justified.
For them it is about rage,
frustration, hatred.
They feel pain, and they're
determined to share it.
That does me no good.
Now let's deal with the facts at hand.
Twenty-three hours ago,
General Aleksander Kodoroff...
stole ten nuclear warheads.
He's just a delivery boy.
I'm not afraid of the man who wants
ten nuclear weapons, Colonel.
I'm terrified of the man
who only wants one.
[ Children Shouting,
Chattering ln Serbian ]
[ Chattering ln Serbian ]
[ Speaking Serbian ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Chuckling ]
Hey, look who's the secret agent.
Nice hat. You don't
stand out at all.
Dress shoes
with khakis ?
- Look at you.
- Leave me alone.
- Let me tell you:
whatever happens, deny it.
- I'll try that.
These are CD's.
They are for Tasha.
You will not like them.
How is she ?
Sixteen, and in love with
a 20-year-old motocross racer.
- She said to say hello.
- Send her my love.
Is Kodoroff involved
with Kordech ?
Dr. Julia Kelly,
Colonel Dimitri Vertikoff.
- Dr. Kelly heads
the Nuclear Smuggling Group.
- With the White House.
That's good.
I think we can do
business, Dr. Kelly.
- Let's take a walk.
- Okay, let's take a walk.
.. [ Woman Singing ln German ]
[ Patrons Chattering ]
[ Dimitri ] They sit here and drink.
We might as well join them.
My group's been monitoring
Kordech for years,
- but it's always been
a mafia/ex-K.G.B. operation.
- Until recently.
You have to see that in
the context of my country.
Alek Kodoroff comes from
a generation of officers who
grew up in a crumbling system.
Those pictures in your head
about Russia--
bread lines, shitty little apartments,
ancient cars--
Kodoroff and his friends made sure
that it never applied to them.
But now, even that system is crumbling.
[ Popping Sounds ]
This was Kodoroff's way out,
his big score.
So you brought us here because you
can't investigate Kordech yourself.
No, no. I can't investigate
without alerting Kodoroff.
Half the men
used to be in my unit.
Mr. Dietrich Shumaker schedules
all Russian shipping for Kordech.
- You have an appointment at 4:00.
- Good.
- Let's go see a man about a truck.
- Cheers.
[ Groans ]
That's gasoline.
[ Chattering ]
[ Horn Honking ]
- Do you have them ?
- Yes. We have to begin immediately.
[ Speaking Serbian ]
You just have to remember the plan.
I'm Anthony Haden--
- I'm Patty Carson.
- Right.
We go in, we get the information
and then we get out.
You call me Tony.
Here we go. Hi.
I'm Anthony Haden.
This is my associate, Patty Carson.
- I think Herr Shumaker's expecting us.
- Please follow me.
[ Computer Beeping ]
[ Receptionist ]
Make yourselves comfortable.
Thank you.
Trucking business
must be pretty good.
Wonder what chateau in the Loire Valley
these came from.
Mr. Haden ?
Welcome.
Thank you very much
for seeing us.
This is my associate,
Ms. Carson.
-Nice place you have here.
-My personal taste runs to the ltalians,
but the German and Austrian late Baroque
was heavily influenced by the ltalians.
- Several of our paintings are ltalian.
- Mm-hmm.
- That's a Tiepolo.
- Mm-hmm. Oh, yeah.
I'm a big Leroy Neiman fan.
Are ya familiar at all with his work ?
- No, I'm afraid not.
- No. Oh. Tsk.
- Please, come in.
- Sure.
To my office.
- Oh, now, this is nice.
- Thank you.
Have a seat.
- How can we help you ?
- I just wanted some information...
about, uh, trucking
in Russia.
I might not be the right man
if you need to rent equipment.
You're the head
of transportation, right ?
The head ?
- No, I just do the scheduling.
- Right.
You're the guy who gets things done.
Smart. Put a German on it.
Yes, well.
- As I said, how can I help you ?
- What we wanna know is...
if I wanted to rent a vehicle to steal
and transport nuclear weapons...
from somewhere, let's say,
inside the Urals,
would you be the guy
to talk to ?
Would you be that guy ?
No, I'm afraid not.
I believe
our meeting is over.
All right, well,
thank you for--
- Do you like Ford Explorers ?
- We have to go, Mr. Haden.
- Range Rovers, Land Cruisers ?
- We really have to go.
- Mr. Haden, may I ask you
to leave the room ?
- [ Wrist Cracking ]
- [ Kelly ] No ! No !
- Should've taken the money, Hans.
[ Kelly Screaming ]
- Get up and get behind that desk.
- You broke my nose.
Not a word. Get the duct tape
out of my briefcase, now.
I'm not gonna shoot you unless
I have to. If I have to, I'm
gonna feel real bad about it.
- Now sit down. Give me the duct tape.
- Here.
- I need the password.
What's the password ?
- Hang on.
- The password.
- [ Gasping ] No.
All right. Hang on.
All right, Hans.
- Oh !
- We'll do it your way.
How's the backhand ?
[ Cocking Gun ] Password.
- Hasselhoff.
How do you spell ''Hasselhoff'' ?
Come on.
Way to go, Hans.
Very brave.
- I'm in.
- [ Devoe ] All right, I need...
the trucking invoices
for the last seven days.
All right.
[ Murmuring ]
- This is your plan ?
- Yep.
- This is your big plan ?
- This is my plan.
[ Devoe ]
Let's go. Hurry up.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Almost. Just logging off.
- Stay on. Who cares ? Leave it on.
- Got it !
Good.
- [ Muttering ] Oh, shit.
- [ Chuckling ]
All right.
Hang on. And...
thank you very much,
Herr Shumaker.
[ Beeping ]
[ Speaking German ]
- Go. Go !
- Come on ! Come on !
Hurry !
- You get it ?
- Got it. You all right ?
- No, I'm not. Brilliant idea:
just smash his face in.
- That is how things get done.
- That's thinking. No warning.
- A couple of bribes, it never
happened at all, right ?
Check the seats.
They go all the way back.
- Oh, yeah.
- Cool.
- Embassy car.
- Of course. C.D. player,
bulletproof glass.
Everything.
Oh, shit.
We may have a problem.
This is going to cost us.
What do you have ?
- Eighty.
- That's enough. I'll be back.
Hold this.
- So you think he set us up ?
- Who ?
- Your friend.
- No.
How can you be
so sure ?
Because he's my friend.
- He needs more money. Give me.
- [ Gunshots ]
- [ Gasping ]
- No !
[ Kelly ]
Oh, my God ! Oh, my God !
[ Devoe ]
Down !
Out ! Out !
[ Tires Squealing ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Click ]
Get up front. Get up front !
Up front ?
- They're behind us.
- How many of them ?
- Two. Two-- Three.
- Reach into that briefcase.
Pull out an extra magazine.
[ Horn Honking ]
- Where is it ?
- In the briefcase. Reach in !
Goddamn it !
Seat belt.
No, don't !
Come on. What's wrong with you ?
What's wrong with you ?
What are you doing ?
Wait ! Shit.
[ Pedestrians Screaming ]
[ Engine Stalled ]
[ Shouting ln German ]
No ! No !
[ Gasping ]
- Come on.
- The invoices.
- Come on. Come on !
- The invoices !
- Come on, goddamn it !
- No !
Go, go, go ! Go !
Dimitri has a...
a daughter, Tasha.
Sixteen.
She lives in Rybinsk.
I remember
when she was three.
Sh--
She's beautiful. Sh--
Doesn't make sense, you know ?
[ Sighs ]
You don't...
kill a Dimitri Vertikoff.
There are certain rules.
Killing him isn't useful.
Is it ever ?
I never watched
anybody die before.
[ Beeping ]
Welcome. You've got mail.
Oh.
I e-mailed Shumaker's files to my
A.O.L. account before I logged off.
Did it work ?
Uh... yeah.
We're looking for a vehicle hired
in the Urals on about June 29.
- Right ?
- Yeah.
- No, the truck's too small.
- Yeah, yeah. Saint Petersburg,
one direction.
Point of origin: Chelyabinsk.
Registration number: 7056BM.
Destination:
lmisli 44E.
That's Azerbaijan.
It's just south of Russia.
That's five miles
from fuckin' lran.
Kodoroff crosses that border
and those nukes are gone.
We got a payment number.
Looks like a bank-routing code.
There's no names of any clients yet.
''44E.'' Does that mean anything to you ?
- What ?
- Shumaker put a private memo
at the bottom of the invoice.
- It can't be copied, and it
wouldn't show up in any--
- This is Devoe.
We have a target vehicle.
It's a cargo truck.
Registration:
7056 Bravo Mike.
- It's traveling south from Chelyabinsk
to lmisli in Azerbaijan.
- 44E.
I am requesting
a high-priority tasker.
Any birds-- any birds--
find this truck.
We've got nukes
heading for lran.
What the hell is 44E ?
[ Men Arguing ln Serbian ]
[ Men Exclaiming ]
- [ Speaking Serbian ]
- Da.
I am a Serb.
I'm a Croat.
I'm a Muslim.
You will look at what
I have done and say,
''Of course. Why not ?
They are all animals. They have
slaughtered each other for centuries.''
But the truth is...
I am not a monster.
I'm a human man.
I'm just like you...
whether you like it or not.
[ Soldiers Chattering,
Sergeant Shouting Drill ]
Hey, Rich.
How you doing ?
- We haven't seen you
since the great scud hunt !
- That's right.
- Captain Santiago, sir.
- Hello, Captain.
This is Lieutenant Beach.
He'll be running the operation
from the ground, sir.
- Gentlemen, tell me you found him.
- Damn close, sir.
Giving them an average speed of
65 clicks,
if their destination of lmisli
is correct...
and if they're taking a direct
route, we've got 'em somewhere
about here, in Dagestan.
Still in Russia, below Mahackala
on the Caspian Sea.
We've snuck a peek at everything
within a 200-square-mile area.
We haven't turned up your truck.
We think they're probably stuck
here, in Kumuh.
- There's a hell of a
traffic jam down there, sir.
- Trucks are too close together.
- We can't get an angle on the plates.
- What's going on down there ?
Renewed fighting between
Armenia and Azerbaijan.
Roads are clogged with refugees
fleeing north.
Ken ? Ken ! Get me a copy
of Kodoroff's intel phone records.
- What are you thinking ?
- I need an outside line here.
Somebody give me
an outside line, please ?
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
Filthy fucking refugees.
- Azerbaijani, Georgian, Kazhakstani.
- [ Honking Horn ]
Eh, don't curse them.
I don't care what bitch
gave birth to them--
Moslem, Serb.
I don't hate them
for who they are.
I hate them
because they are poor.
[ Car Phone Ringing ]
[ Speaking Russian ]
- [ Speaking Russian ]
- Hey, Alek, how's the ride down there ?
- Who is this ?
- Doesn't traffic drive ya nuts
when you're in a hurry ?
- Who the fuck is this ?
- It's Tom Devoe, Alek.
How the hell you been ?
I gotta know. You still humpin' that
Finnish stewardess with the bad skin ?
Tom. Are you still trading stolen cars
on the black market ?
Hey, Alek, you watched CNN
during Desert Storm.
Remember all those television shots from
the nose cone of the G.B.U. missiles...
slammin' into those trucks ?
Remember
that picture ?
How it kept gettin' closer
and bigger on the screen ?
You could just about see the faces
of those drivers, and then...
zap, the picture went dead; we didn't
get to see what happened next.
Well, guess what, Alek.
You will,
you son of a bitch.
Shit. Get out of the way.
[ Honking Horn ]
[ Horn Honking ]
- [ Beeping ]
- I guess that upset him.
- Can you get an angle ?
- In a minute.
He rear-ends some guy, that can't
detonate that nuke, can it ?
- As long as no one opens
the primary, they're safe.
- Come on.
Come on, sweetie.
Come on.
It's coming.
- 70-56 Bravo Mike. That's it.
- How long until the satellite
passes out of range ?
- One hour, 46 minutes.
- Get in contact with Russian command.
Give them the exact location
of the truck. Ken ?
Boom.
- We have to go now.
- We only have them under
surveillance for another hour.
- It doesn't matter what the
State Department says, sir.
- Yes, sir, absolutely.
- No, I understand, sir.
- Fine. Thank you.
- Yes. Yes, sir. Will do.
- Thank you, sir.
- Okay, go. You go.
- No, no, you go first.
I was talkin' to the chairman
of the Joint Chiefs.
He says the State Department
is draggin' their feet.
I was talking to the president.
- He says it's a Russian problem;
they have to manage it.
- No, we have the advantage now !
The Russians say
they are handling this.
The Russians couldn't find snow
in the middle of fuckin' winter.
When that satellite is out of range,
those nukes are gone.
It's only jet fuel.
- Get up into NATO.
- Good for you. Let's go. Rich ?
- No, wait. Wait. Colonel.
- Santiago !
With Russia insisting they're
handling this,
you will not take action
without authorization.
What do you think I am, some
gung-ho stupid son of a bitch ?
No, I don't think you're stupid.
I think you're a talented soldier
with sloppy impulse control,
and I don't want you provoking
an international incident
because of a personal agenda.
My personal agenda
is my business.
Now you are not
in Washington anymore.
You are in the real world.
In the real world,
there are nuclear arms
heading for lran.
So whether you agree with me
or not, get me authorized !
[ Speaking Serbian ]
Cobra Three, this is Tango Six.
What have we got ?
[ Kelly ] Russian command
has been notified of
the target vehicle's location.
Proceed to position
and await further instructions.
- Ken, does N.R.O. have
anything up there for us ?
- They got us on standby.
Take this down.
How much time are we looking at ?
We can track 'em for another
45 minutes.
Let's alert IFOR
at the Bazta checkpoint.
They'll have to pass
through there.
Put that away.
[ Speaking Russian ]
Stop.
[ Soldier Speaking Russian ]
[ Reporter ] There's been a tragic
setback in the ongoing effort...
to secure lasting peace
in the former Yugoslavia.
So far, no one
has taken responsibility...
for the killing of the Bosnian-Serb
finance minister, Zarko Preljevich,
who was assassinated
in a Sarajevo churchyard.
Word of Preljevich's
violent death...
has sent shock waves through
the international community.
The well-liked moderate
was considered a crucial player...
in the upcoming peace talke scheduled
to begin this week in New York.
Reporting live from Sarajevo,
this is Jean Rogers for CNN.
Forty-four ''E.''
Forty-fourth parallel
runs through...
Sarajevo.
Where's that bank routing number ?
The one off the Kordech invoice ?
- You better get over here.
- Check it against banks in Sarajevo.
- What's going on ?
- A Russian roadblock.
They're all dead, ma'am.
I think
they're all dead.
[ Devoe ]
Cobra Three, they got 'em ?
Negative, Tango Six. How much longer
do we have them on satellite ?
Less than ten minutes.
Alert the Russians
of the truck's current position.
Tell them they have
men down out there.
Wallace, stand by to track
if they go to Bravo.
[ Devoe ] We've now reached
the Federation airspace, Cobra Three.
Running out of time.
Suggest we go.
Negative, Six.
Do not proceed without authorization.
- Do the Russians have
troops in the area ?
- Negative.
[ Devoe ] Cobra Three, we're gonna
lose 'em on satellite. We have to go.
Get me a secure phone link
to N.M.C.C. Negative, Six.
Do not proceed without authorization.
You will not proceed.
When we lose the satellite,
do we have other eyes in the area ?
[ Kelly ] Sir, we have the target
vehicle approaching the lranian border.
Requesting permission to enter Russian
Federation airspace and take it out.
Dr. Kelly, in your estimation, is this
our only remaining course of action ?
Based on available intel, the Russians
having no forces in place,
our analysis of
the satellite sigint--
I'm not asking for analysis, Dr. Kelly.
I'm asking for a decision.
- Must advise we go, sir.
- Dr. Kelly, if there are
nuclear weapons on that truck,
and the Russians
can't interdict,
are you willing to risk a war
to stop it ?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, I am.
Six, this is Cobra Three.
We have a go.
Avoid foreign casualties.
Secure the target vehicle.
Detain anyone found inside.
Copy, Cobra. Six to task force.
We're cleared as briefed.
Let's rock and roll !
This is Red Dog Pack to Three.
Execute. Execute.
Why aren't they finished
back there ?
[ Speaking Russian ]
Russian control tower,
this is Air Force 53762,
a flight of three U.S. Air Force
helicopters in pursuit
of stolen nuclear weapons.
Request a weapons-hold status.
[ Speaking Russian ]
You must return to Turkish airspace,
U.S. Air Force.
Your intrusion is not authorized.
You have crossed international line.
They've locked onto us.
A second battery's
locked onto us.
This is Air Force 53762. We are
in pursuit of stolen nuclear weapons...
on their way to lran.
Repeat: Put your weapons
on hold.
Reverse course immediately,
or we will begin to fire.
This is Red Dog Three.
We're lit up like a Christmas tree.
This is Air Force 53762.
Those weapons could be going to
Chechnya or Georgia.
We repeat:
Put your weapons on hold !
[ Speaking Russian ]
Here they come !
[ Devoe ] Number One is down.
Cobra, we have a downed aircraft...
two miles east
of checkpoint four.
- Number Three, acknowledge.
- This is Red Dog Three.
Do you see the aircraft ?
Do you see any survivors ?
Negative. The whole fucking forest
is up in flames.
Number Three, duck behind the hill.
Behind the hill.
- How many men on that chopper ?
- Nine.
[ Devoe ]
Cobra Three, we're out of range.
Target is two miles out.
Here it is.
What's he doing ?
- Will it work ?
- It can be activated by a single man...
and will render a nuclear yield
of one to two kilotons.
- Why is he doing that now ?
- Because that was the deal.
One warhead for us, to do
with as we wish.
After I get my money.
Helicopters !
All right, gentlemen, whatever you do,
do not shoot any civilians.
Do you understand ?
Amerikanski.
[ Gunfire ]
Take out the road !
Rig me a heavy lift line !
Those fuckers
you can shoot !
Let's get him out !
Pull up !
[ Screaming ]
Where are they goin', Alek ?
Where are they goin' ?
Fuck you !
- Get it down ! Lower it !
- Heavy line ! Let's go !
- Grab it and get out !
- Drop a cable ! Drop it !
Bring it down !
More ! More !
Come on ! Get on !
Hook on !
[ Grunting ]
- More !
- Lower it ! We gotta lower it !
[ Shrieking ]
Go !
- [ Men Shouting ]
- We're clear ! We're clear !
All right, sweep 'em. Open 'em up.
Let's go ! Let's go !
- You all right, sir ?
- Yeah. Open 'em up. Let's go !
[ Devoe ] Give me the radio.
Cobra Three, are you there ?
Six, what happened ?
One assault aircraft is gone.
Nine men are dead.
- Santiago !
- Kodoroff is dead, and we have
recovered...
- eight nuclear warheads...
- Someone's holding on over the side !
- in their containers.
- That's not enough warheads.
- What ?
- [ Kelly ]
That's not enough damn warheads.
- For once, you could
say something nice.
- It was an SS18-- ten warheads.
One detonated, eight with you.
That leaves one unaccounted for.
Colonel Devoe ! There's
somebody alive down here !
Hold on a minute.
Take this. Motherfuck.
Goddamn it !
We got a live one, Colonel.
- Do you speak English ?
- Yes, l-- I went to Harvard.
Go, Crimson !
Help me up, please.
- Where's the other warhead ?
- Please, bring me up.
Listen to me very carefully.
You are gonna die unless you
tell me where the warhead is.
- I don't know. He took it. He's gone.
- Who ?
I don't know his name ! He's, uh,
with the ones who arranged this !
- Kodoroff ?
- No, Kodoroff just handled the money !
It was the other one !
He-He made me dismantle
the primary, make it mobile.
- How ?
- It's in his backpack.
Help me up, please ?
- I'm goin' back to the rig.
- Help me up.
- Just hang on. We'll bring you up.
- Okay.
Kelly ? A guy
got away with a bomb.
[ Kelly ] Copy, Devoe.
All right, come on back.
We got it. The bank account
on the Kordech invoice ?
Registered to an address in Grbavica,
a Serbian suburb of Sarajevo.
Good. Get this information to IFOR.
Tell them to proceed with caution.
Where are you going ?
- [ Boy Chattering ]
- [ Siren Wailing ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Speaking Polish ]
[ Speaking Serbian ]
Tsk.
- Are you all right ?
- I've been better. How 'bout you ?
I've been better. We traced the money
back to a man named Vlado Mirich.
IFOR found a tape in his apartment.
They're uplinking it to us now.
They say it has some sort
of terrorist message on it.
Colonel, the guy you caught
is Dr. Amir Taraki.
Pakistani. Ph.D. in astrophysics.
Educated at Harvard.
That's right. We educated
half the world's terrorists.
- You need to tell me
exactly what he said.
- All right.
He removed the primary from the warhead,
and he put it in a backpack.
The primary is packed
with plutonium.
Detonated, it could still
take out ten city blocks...
- IFOR tape is transmitting !
- and kill 100,000 people...
in a densely populated area
like Sarajevo or Tuzla.
[ Mirich ] You will look at what
I have done and say,
''Of course. Why not ?
''They are all animals.
They have slaughtered
each other for centuries.''
But the truth is...
I'm not a monster.
I'm a human man.
I'm just like you...
whether you like it
or not.
For years, we have tried
to live together...
until a war
was waged on us.
On all of us.
A war waged by
our own leaders.
[ Mirich On Videotape, Continuing ]
And who supplied...
the Serb cluster bombs,
the Croatian tanks,
the Muslim artillery shells...
that killed
our sons and daughters ?
It was the governments of the West who
drew the boundaries of our countries--
sometimes in ink,
sometimes in blood--
the blood of our people,
and now, you dispatch
your peacekeepers...
to write
our destiny again.
We can never accept this peace
that leaves us...
with nothing but pain--
pain the peacemakers
must be made to feel.
Their wives,
their children,
their houses
and churches.
So now you know.
Now you must understand.
Leave us to find
our own destiny.
May God have mercy
on us all.
- [ Click ]
- IFOR can shut down Bosnia. He's
never gonna get into Sarajevo.
- He's never gonna get into Tuzla.
- He's not going there.
We weren't meant to find this until
after he had detonated the bomb.
Now, ''pain the peacemakers
must be made to feel.''
The peacemakers aren't in Bosnia.
They're in Europe and the U.S.
- They're signing a new treaty
this week, right ?
- Tomorrow at the U.N.
- What is the address ?
- Over by the river, east side.
Forty-fourth Street.
Forty-four ''E.''
He's goin' to New York.
- What've you got, Ken ?
- The only way we can
close the airport...
is with a Federal Nuclear Emergency
Response Plan.
- It has to come from her.
- All right. I'll give it to her.
I wanted to know...
who they were.
Oh.
All right.
Secure line to N.M.C.C.
This is Dr. Julia Kelly.
I am issuing a presidential directive...
for a Federal
Nuclear Emergency Plan.
We have a possible weapon
of mass destruction...
coming into the United States by
unknown terrorist or terrorists.
- Check in the rear.
- Yes, sir.
Commencing diplomatic evacuation.
Perimeter is secure.
Repeat:
Ladies and gentlemen, may I
have your attention, please ?
I'm with the U.N. We've been
informed of a serious threat
to the treaty signing.
We have to get you off this plane
to insure your safety.
If you would all please stand up now.
Everyone, stand up.
Thank you.
Move to the exits...
at the rear and front of the aircraft
in an orderly fashion.
- Glad you could make it. Coffee ?
- No, thank you, sir.
- I popped a couple of ''stay-awakes''
on the plane.
- Dr. Kelly ?
- I'm fine.
- How many ''stay-awakes'' did she take ?
This is Mark Carey, Energy.
Over here, Special Agent in Charge,
David Branigan, F.B.I.
Welcome to New York.
We're running N.Y.P.D. and
Agency response out of here...
in coordination
with D.O.E.
- Evacuation plans ?
- FEMA and National Guard are on alert.
- What about NEST ?
- Energy has containment teams...
on alert in Battery Park
awaiting instructions.
We're running
casualty scenarios.
Initial blast would throw 60 rads
of prompt radiation out three miles.
That's most of lower Manhattan
and Queens-- 2.5 to 3 million
people, 50% survival rate.
We're gonna need to monitor localized
wind patterns, and we're gonna need...
radiation detectors,
ground and air.
- Intel report from IFOR.
- Let me see that.
All right, Vlado Mirich,
Bosnian-Serb, radical.
Been missing for about a week. Father
fought with Tito. No wife or children.
Has a half-brother who was
a classical pianist in Sarajevo.
Mirich's been arrested three times
for smuggling and black-marketeering.
- It's gotta be him.
- No, no, something doesn't fit.
- What ?
- The man in the tape.
He's no black-marketeer,
and he's not a nationalist.
Remember, he said, ''l am a Serb,
a Croat and a Muslim.'' He's
holding everybody responsible.
- This background doesn't fit.
- Sir, I'm checking all
incoming passenger manifests.
I've got a V. Mirich on SwissAir
Flight 1204 from Zurich to Kennedy.
- [ Devoe ] Arriving when ?
- Touchdown seven minutes ago.
[ Devoe ] Call JFK.
Get Security. Send 'em a picture.
- [ Kelly ] Reroute
to Kennedy Airport NEST.
- [ Ken ] Done.
Excuse me.
Excuse me !
Cover all the exits. Nobody gets out
of here. You understand me ?
- Nobody gets out !
- [ Agent ] Who's Devoe ?
- SwissAir Flight 1204, nonresidents.
- Station 20.
This way.
[ Kelly ]
He's not here.
- He's not here !
- We got a possible identification
at desk seven.
It's the far corner.
Excuse me.
Vlado Mirich ?
Yes ?
Who the hell is this ?
- [ Speaking Serbian ]
- Uh-huh. All right.
Passport's fake. Claims he bought it
on the street in Sarajevo.
- He wants a lawyer.
- We've been able to detain eight men.
Tried to enter today using passports
issued by the former Yugoslavia.
- None matches your description.
- Where the hell is he ?
- Even with the treaty signing ?
- That doesn't include the delegations.
- The what ?
- They don't go through customs.
- Give me that.
- Altogether, there must have
been a couple hundred of them.
-[ Alex Trebek On TV ] ...Julius Caesar.
-[ Contestant ] Marcus Brutus.
- [ Trebek ] Right.
- Half-brothers, 800.
[ Trebek ]
Answer: Another Daily Double.
[ Game Show Continues, lndistinct ]
No, ma'am. Let me explain.
We are talking about a possible
terrorist situation.
We need to detain
the entire delegation.
These are diplomats, here as
guests of the State Department.
I can't order them around.
- Then I need their names
and room numbers.
- We're looking for Vlado Mirich.
- I need what floor they're on too.
- This isn't Vlado Mirich.
This is Dusan Gavrich.
He's an alternate with
the Bosnian-Serb delegation.
Their minister was assassinated
last week. Mr. Gavrich
is attending in his place.
The brother.
[ Beeping ]
[ Firearms Cocking ]
[ Poodle Wheezing ]
[ Elevator Beeping ]
Go. Go !
Oh, shit. ''Diplomatic papers.''
They never even searched it.
Still warm.
Please. Move.
.. [ Bach ]
[ Gunshots, Screaming ]
Nina ! Nina !
- [ Gunshots, Pedestrians Screaming ]
- Nina !
Nina ! Nina !
[ Speaking Serbian ]
[ Screaming ln Serbian ]
Help me !
Help my child !
Please help me !
[ Speaking Serbian ]
[ Horns Honking ]
East 44th Street.
- D.O.E., you have anything yet ?
- Choppers are up.
Couple of +2 spikes reported, but
nothing approaching target levels.
The backpack's gonna be
leaking radiation.
They should be able to locate him
within a three- to four-block area.
Set up roadblocks here.
We're gonna close off Second Avenue.
Funnel him down 43rd
to the U.N. We deploy snipers
between First and Second...
- Command Center.
- and take him out.
General, we have to close down
the east side of Second Avenue...
from 55th to 42nd and the north side
of 42nd from Sixth to the river.
- [ Kelly ] Let's go.
- [ Devoe ] We're gonna be
in position at the U.N.
Instruct all field agents,
all snipers:
Subject cannot be aware
of the hunt.
[ Police Whistle Blowing ]
- [ Horns Honking, Whistle Blowing ]
- Move it.
Something big at U.N. today.
Traffic bad all morning.
[ Kelly ]
Chopper Hunter One, anything ?
- That's a negative.
- H.Q., Kelly. We're gonna work
our way south into the funnel.
Suggest stopping anyone
with a backpack north of 55th.
- [ Branigan ] Roger. How soon
will you get to the U.N. ?
- What are you talking about ?
This is
a national emergency.
- [ Pedestrians Shouting ]
- Get over here and spread 'em.
Hold it ! Up in the air ! Put your
hands on your head. Don't move.
Who are the fascists now ?
Du kleine Ficke !
[ Horns Honking ]
- [ Tires Squealing ]
- Come on !
Come on.
- [ Horns Honking ]
- [ Man ] Let's go !
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- Come on !
Okay, guys, let's move it out.
Go ! Go !
Come on.
Let's move it.
[ Whistling ]
Go !
[ Horns Honking, Drivers Shouting ]
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- [ Officer ] All right,
move back on the sidewalk.
- What the hell is this ?
- We have instructions to secure--
- It looks like Desert Storm !
Get these men outta here !
- He sees us, we're all dead.
- Colonel.
- N.Y.P.D. is shutting down
off-ramps to clear it.
- Where's the containment trucks ?
- It's gridlocked out there.
- Where are they ?
- [ Pilot ] We picked up
a diffused radiation source...
somewhere between Third and Second,
54th and 46th.
- Can you be more precise, D.O.E. ?
- Not at this altitude.
On my way.
You keep an open channel.
When we locate him, move out
with the NEST team.
[ Chattering ]
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
H.R.T. Command, put me direct
with your closest shooter.
- Hunter One, copy.
- Leader, this is One.
[ Devoe ]
Expect he's comin' your way, One.
[ Hunter One ]
Roger that. Do we have a green light ?
[ Devoe ]
Affirmative.
- [ Officer #1 ] Thank you.
- [ Officer #2 ]
Get outside the barriers, folks.
Good. That's good.
No, you may not walk that way.
Please turn around.
- Thank you. Round the barrier.
- Over to the left, please.
I think he's somewhere between
First and Second, probably below 46th.
All positions,
do you see target ?
No, sir.
Not me.
Come on.
Come to Papa.
This is Four. Target acquired.
Three hundred meters.
Not clean.
Too many friendlies.
Four, this is Leader.
Take the shot.
[ Hunter Four ]
There's a child, a family.
Acknowledged. Take the shot.
Shoot him.
Come on.
Four, this is Leader.
I repeat: Take the shot.
Take the shot !
Shoot him !
- Oh, God.
- Goddamn it ! Somebody shoot him !
- [ Sighs ]
- This is One. I have target acquired.
Four hundred yards, inbound.
No shot. Should open at 43rd.
[ Siren Wailing ]
F.B.I. !
-I need to get the hell through.
-You and the rest of New York.
Take it easy, all right ?
Just get outta here.
Dispatch, this is 1501.
I need backup on 43rd Street...
as soon as
you can get it for me.
Leader, this is Hunter One.
Waiting for target to clear.
You with the backpack,
get your hands up.
- Get out of the way.
- Get your hands up.
I'm a diplomat
with the United Nations.
I must be allowed to pass.
Leader, I may have lost him.
He stopped.
- What ?
- He may have stopped.
He went behind some trees.
He's gotta be there.
Reacquire. Move if you have to.
- What've you got in
the backpack, buddy ? Cuffs.
- You got it.
- [ Gunshots ]
- [ Pedestrians Screaming ]
- Can you engage, Number One ?
- Negative, sir. Somebody shooting.
Corner of 43rd and Second.
Is he down ?
ls he down ?
[ Hunter One ] Negative.
They're southbound, toward 42nd.
Stay in contact with the
containment trucks...
and have them ready to move
on my command.
- Where are you from ?
- Philadelphia.
Give me the keys.
[ Siren Wailing ]
Hey ! Out of the way !
D.O.E., you have him ?
He's eastbound on 42nd.
- Get out of the way !
- [ Siren Wailing ]
Go ! Make way !
[ Woman Screaming ]
Move it !
[ Cabbie ]
Hey, off o' the car !
[ Screaming ]
[ Speaking Serbian ]
Oh !
- East of Second, off 41st.
Give me backup now !
- He went down there !
- There !
- Stay behind me !
- [ Gasping ]
- Drop your weapon, and
show me your fuckin' hands.
We got him.
Alley off 41st.
[ Yelling Gleefully ]
[ Yelling ]
- [ Grunting ] You all right ?
- Yeah.
[ Gasping ]
[ Radio ] The signal just quit. You're
right there. He's gotta be indoors.
[ Panting ]
Oh, Vlado.
[ Speaking Serbian ]
- [ Woman ] I saw them !
- [ Man ] Up those stairs ! ln there !
[ Speaking Serbian ]
[ Door Opening, Bell Ringing ]
Move !
Move, move, move !
- [ Screaming ]
- Move ! Move !
- Move !
- [ Students Shouting, Screaming ]
- Anybody have him ?
- [ Radio ] Negative. Nothing to
the south end. Same to the north.
- D.O.E., what have you got ?
- Still picking up a diffused
energy source...
somewhere in the area.
We're circling back now.
He knows he'll never make it
to the U.N.
He doesn't have to.
He's got a nuclear weapon.
All he has to do is sit down behind a
Dumpster and take out half of Manhattan.
He doesn't wanna die behind a Dumpster.
He wants his death to mean something.
- [ Radio ] Still not getting
a clear reading.
- Keep circling.
Fan out. We've established
a new perimeter. He's gotta
be within 200 yards.
- Look for blood, door to door.
- [ Radio ] There's no sign, Colonel.
He probably
ducked into a building.
- Keep looking !
- Will continue circling
a six-block area.
.. [ Choir Singing ]
Devoe !
Listen.
.. [ Choir ]
[ Speaking Serbian ]
[ Shouting ln Serbian ]
- Go ! Go !
- [ Children Screaming ]
[ Priest ]
Hurry along. Come on. Come on.
- [ Screaming ]
- Father, take these children
out of here ! Move it !
[ Priest ] Come on, girls.
Quickly. Quickly, girls.
[ Faint Noise ]
Come on. Come on.
Give me your hand. Give me your hand.
Let's go. Go.
Go, go, go, go.
[ Indistinct Noise ]
[ Gasps ]
You cannot stop this.
Never !
Okay.
Okay, just,
just, just stay still.
Stay there.
Stay still.
It's okay.
You don't wanna die
like this.
Tell me about the bomb.
Is it on a trigger ?
Is it on a timer ?
ls it activated ?
Come on.
Talk to me.
- We can decide on a way out of this.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Cocks Pistol ]
- No !
Who decided
for my wife ?
My child, murdered.
Huh ?
For what ?
[ Whispering ]
For breathing ?
For smiling ?
And now, I am left.
Who decides for me ?
Mr. Gavrich,
what is it you want ?
[ Speaking Serbian ]
- I--
- I want it to be...
Iike it was.
Sir, it's not our war.
- It is now.
- No !
- Son of a bitch.
- Where the hell is NEST ?
- [ Beeping ]
- Get NEST in here !
- It's on a timer.
- All right, listen. The bomb's
on a timer, all right ?
Ken. Ken.
Where the hell are they ?
- I don't know. I'm on it.
- Ken, tell me NEST is here.
[ Ken ] Affirmative. We've cleared
43rd. They'll be there in four minutes.
They're not gonna make it.
They're not gonna make it !
All right.
Okay. You're gonna have to do this.
Understand ? Look at this.
Tell me what you see.
- Take a look at this
and tell me what you see !
- Yeah. Uh,
an SS18 primary
with a plutonium core.
A bomb inside a bomb. It has
a capacitor-relay detonator,
double pull, double throw.
Uh, the only way of knowing
is to open it up.
What ?
- What ?
- Let's move it into the chapel.
Get it off him. Get it off !
Hang on. We got a trip wire right here.
We're gonna move the man with the bomb.
All at once.
Here we go. Ready ? Go !
Let's go !
Let's go ! Careful !
Get the gate !
- Why in here ?
- It'll help contain the radiation.
You need to get out of the
church. Evacuate as many people
from this area as you can.
- Okay. I, uh, I need
something for the screws.
- Here.
- Anything. Quick !
- Go, go.
Devoe, get out of here.
Okay. I'll be in the truck.
[ Laughs ]
[ Gasping ]
Shit.
The plutonium core is surrounded
by explosive panels.
Uh, give me the knife.
I need the knife back.
If we can separate
one of the panels,
uh, we may be able to blow up
the outer bomb...
without the core
going to nuclear yield.
You're gonna blow this up.
You're gonna blow up the bomb ?
You know what you're doin', right ?
You've done somethin' like this before.
Defused stolen nuclear primaries
jerry-rigged by Pakistanis ?
No.
[ Beeping ]
Oh !
[ Gasping ]
- [ Blade Snapping ]
- Ah, damn !
All right.
Uh, I need your gun.
Give me the gun. I need the gun.
Go.
Easy, easy, easy, easy !
It's all right.
- [ Devoe ] Fourteen, thirteen, twelve,
- I know.
- eleven, ten,
- It won't let go !
- nine, eight--
- Move !
Come on ! Seven !
Come on ! Six, five !
Go, go, go, go !
[ Beeping ]
[ Rapid Beeping ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
Julia. Come here.
Come here. Are you okay ?
- [ Gasping ]
- Hey ! Are you okay ? Hey !
- Come here. Come here.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
Come here.
Hey.
- You okay ?
- I think so.
- [ Man ] Get in there with the ladder !
- All right.
[ Crying ]
Yeah. All right.
Hey, listen. You're okay.
All right ?
- You're okay.
- Sir, we need you to go with these men.
- Yeah. Go, go, go. Go.
- We have to get you to
a radiation checkpoint.
- Julia !
- I'm bleeding.
Julia.
Julia !
[ Horn Blowing, Siren Wailing ]
So, they give you
any new medals ?
Yes, they did.
- Well, you worked very hard for them.
- Thank you.
So we've got kind of a tradition
over at military ops...
whenever combatants
come back from the field in one piece.
Uh, we buy each other
a beer.
- You made that up.
- Yes, I did.
Well, um,
I got ten more to go.
I'll wait.
Subtitles by
Captions, lnc. Los Angeles