[Instrumental music
with industrial effects]
[Sirens scream in distance]
[Sirens wailing]
[Gunshot echoes]
[Siren screams]
[Flashbulb popping]
[Muffled voices on police radio,
background]
KELLY: Come on, Doc.
REPORTER:
Reporting live from the home...
... of Dr. Richard Kimble...
... a respected vascular surgeon
at Chicago Memorial Hospital.
Details are sketchy...
... but we understand Dr. Kimble's wife,
Helen, was found murdered this evening.
Area Six detectives are bringing
Dr. Kimble out.
We assume that they're gonna be taking
him to a police station, probably Area Six...
... where they hope he can shed some light
on what happened here this evening.
Now, as I indicated,
she was found shortly before midnight.
We know that she made apparently
a 911 call to police...
... indicating that she was being assaulted
by an intruder.
Details are very sketchy.
We do know that he and his wife Helen...
... were at the Four Seasons Hotel
earlier tonight...
... a fundraiser
for the Children's Research Fund.
[Dance music, background]
Rich, remember Cara?
RICHARD: Nice to see you.
CARA: Nice to see you.
RICHARD: Straighten that arm
or you're gonna slice.
PAUL: Golf pro teach you that?
RICHARD: My wife.
CHARLES: Before I forget...
...thanks for the loaner.
Keys are downstairs.
RICHARD: Any gas in it?
CHARLES: Yes. Enough.
Alec, Richard Kimble.
RICHARD: How are you?
ALEC: Dr. Kimble!
RICHARD: Knock it off!
There's nothing to see here.
And you, come with me.
Thank you.
I was just down to my last joke.
RICHARD: You look really beautiful tonight.
Thanks, honey.
I know you hate these things,
but God, I love looking at you in a tux.
I feel I look like a waiter or something.
[Car phone ringing]
- Dr. Kimble?
- Yes, it is.
Sorry to bother you, sir...
... but Dr. Stevens is in Emergency Surgery
and needs your help.
Call him back and tell him
I'll be right there.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you. Good night.
I'll wait up for you.
HELEN: [Echoing] I'll wait up for you.
RICHARD: Talk to me. What have we here?
STEVENS: Thanks for coming.
STEVENS: A 58-year-old.
Just pulled his gallbladder. Bleeding.
SURGEON 1: Big time. It's in the liver bed.
RICHARD: What are his coags?
STEVENS: They're all messed up.
STEVENS: PT's 36 and the rest
are off the wall.
RICHARD: Where is he from?
STEVENS: Lentz's name is on the chart.
We paged him, but no answer.
RICHARD: Here guys. Let me in there.
Give me some room.
RICHARD: Give me a clamp.
RICHARD: Give me suction.
ROSETTl: Have you been getting
any threats at work?
Co-workers, hospital staff, anyone?
No.
KELLY: Anything unusual going on...
...phone calls, people hanging up?
Maybe people coming to the door?
Tradespeople?
Not that I know of.
Back to this fight
with this guy with one arm.
Did it happen upstairs or downstairs?
Upstairs.
And he had which? A right or a left arm?
With a gimmick on it?
Right arm.
Is it one of those with the hooks, or...
No, he had a cosmetic hand.
The security system in your house,
it's a pretty good one.
KELLY: Anyone else have the coding?
Our maid.
She knows the code and has a key.
Those scratches on your neck...
...did the one-armed guy do that?
Helen scratched me
when I was trying to move her.
Before or after you had the fight
with the one-armed man?
I told you.
You own a gun, Doc?
Do you own a gun?
[Flashbulb pops]
Yes, we have a gun in the house.
Is it registered in your name?
RICHARD: Yes.
ROSETTl: Where do you usually
keep that gun?
ROSETTl: The one that you own.
RICHARD: It's in Helen's table.
RICHARD: Bedside table.
ROSETTl: Do you keep much jewelry
in the house?
His fingerprints are all over the lamp...
...the gun and the bullets...
...and the good doctor's skin
is under her fingernails.
KELLY: She's got the money
in the family, hasn't she?
Helen comes from a wealthy family, yes.
Is she insured?
Yes, she is.
ROSETTl: Who's the beneficiary?
I am.
The sole beneficiary?
Yes.
KELLY: Financially, you won't be
hurting after this, will you?
I mean, she was worth
quite a bit of money.
Are you suggesting that I killed my wife?
You're saying that I crushed
her skull and shot her.
RICHARD: How dare you!
When I came home,
there was a man in my house.
I fought with this man.
KELLY: The one-armed man.
RICHARD: He had a mechanical arm.
ROSETTl: Plastic? Rubber?
RICHARD: You find this man!
You find this man!
ROSETTl: How tall?
He took everything from me.
Oh, Jesus.
ROSETTl: What did he weigh?
RICHARD: Oh, God!
ROSETTl: What color was his hair?
ROSETTl: What color were his eyes?
[Richard cries]
ROSETTl: We can't help you
if you don't help us.
Book him.
PROSECUTOR:
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
...you will hear iron-clad proof
of Richard Kimble's guilt.
PROSECUTOR:
Indisputable scientific evidence...
... that on the night of January 20...
...Richard Kimble did in fact viciously...
...attack...
...and brutally murder his wife.
But you'll hear more than that.
You will hear a voice from the grave.
The voice of Helen Kimble
identifying her killer...
... her husband, Richard Kimble.
Detective Kelly...
...tell us what you observed at the home
of the victim on the night of the murder.
No forcible entry was found.
KELLY:
From the beginning of the investigation...
... it didn't appear to be a break-in.
Nothing was missing.
Honey, I'm home.
RICHARD: Who won the game?
His prints were on the gun and bullets.
FORENSIC EXPERT: No other sets were
found, other than the housekeeper's...
... and the deceased's.
Mrs. Kimble's skull fracture caused
a massive hemorrhage to the brain.
It took less than 5 minutes for her to die.
[Busy signal buzzes]
[Helen wheezing]
[Phone beeps as dialed]
Your Honor, we would ask to play
Helen Kimble's 911 emergency call...
... previously identified by
a Chicago Police Department dispatcher.
OPERATOR: Emergency 911.
Please help me.
OPERATOR: What's the problem?
HELEN: He's...
[Gasping] He's still in the house.
OPERATOR: Did I hear you right?
OPERATOR: Someone's in your house?
HELEN: He's trying to kill me.
OPERATOR: Could you repeat that, please?
OPERATOR: Ma'am?
HELEN: He's trying to kill me.
OPERATOR:
Is your attacker still in the house?
OPERATOR: Ma'am?
HELEN: Richard...
Richard...
Is he trying to kill me?
[Dial tone hums]
JUDGE: Mr. Kimble...
...having considered all the factors and
aggravation and mitigation in this case...
...and found the offense was brutal
and indicative of wanton cruelty...
...it's judgment of this court, you will be
remanded to Illinois State Penitentiary...
... where you will await
execution by lethal injection...
...on a date to be set forth
by the Attorney General of the State.
May God have mercy on your soul.
[Gavel bangs and echoes]
[Slam echoes]
GUARD 1: Carlson.
CARLSON: Here.
GUARD 1: Partida.
PARTIDA: Yeah.
GUARD 1: Copeland.
COPELAND: [Yells] What?
GUARD 1: Copeland, you be nice now.
GUARD 1: Kimble.
Yeah.
Let's go, gentlemen.
JAIL OFFICER: Four prisoners coming out.
[Electronic buzzing of gate]
Let's go, gentlemen.
GUARD 1: Kimble, you're here.
GUARD 1: Carlson, right over there.
Partida, up front left.
Copeland, you're back here with me.
GUARD 1: Come on,
make yourselves comfortable.
GUARD 1:
You know the routine, gentlemen.
GUARD 2: I'm tired.
GUARD 1: 20 miles from Menard.
We'll be there in about 40 minutes.
GUARD 1: I'll be glad to get rid of this load.
Let McKenzie take care of them.
GUARD 2: Always got some
good eating there. I'm starving.
GUARD 1: Me, too.
GUARD 1: Had enough prison chow.
GUARD 1: Old Ed, he don't care.
His old lady's got him on a diet.
GUARD 1: Right, Ed?
[Carlson coughing and choking]
[Gasping and wheezing]
Somebody get in here, quick!
PARTIDA: He's getting sick!
Let's go, move! Move!
GUARD 2: He's foaming at the mouth.
GUARD 1: We're almost at the prison.
He's choking!
Wait!
[Loud blast]
[Multiple gunshots]
[Tires screeching]
[Rifle clicks]
[More gunshots, tires screech]
[Coughing and gasping]
Oh, shit!
Kimble!
Kimble, get over here.
You're a doctor, do something!
Unlock me!
You'll be okay.
[Train horn bellows]
What the hell is that?
GUARD 1: Shit!
Help me!
The hell with you.
Help me with this man!
COPELAND: Kiss my ass, Doctor.
[Train rumbles]
[Thunderous crash]
[Metal squeals]
[Violent explosion]
[Flames crackling]
Now you listen.
I don't give a damn which way you go.
Just don't follow me. You got that?
Yeah.
Be good.
[Richard breaths heavily]
[Sirens scream,
scattered voices over police radio]
[Propellers pelting overhead]
My, my, my.
What a mess.
It's a circus.
COSMO: You got my bag?
SAM: Point of impact right here.
The first engine uncoupled,
and the train jumped the track.
About 100 yards?
You must get new boots.
COSMO: I told you not to wear the heels.
Wear two coats.
POOLE: Next train wreck.
Why do we always mother her?
COSMO: Because she loves us.
BIGGS: How'd you like to be the driver?
SAM: I bet he did a Casey Jones.
TROOPER: Hold it, sir.
Hi. Who's in charge?
Sheriff Rollins.
Just follow the TV lights.
SAM: Sheriff Rogers.
ALL: Rollins!
Look down there and take Newman.
BIGGS: Come on, Noah.
Time to go to work.
GUARD 1:
The bus rolled over several times...
... before settling down
at the bottom of the hill.
I don't know if I passed out or what...
... but when I looked up,
the train was bearing down on us. Fast.
I don't know how. It's still kind of hazy.
Somehow I grabbed him
and pushed him out of the bus.
You're brave, you could've been killed.
GUARD 1: I know.
He's my partner.
He would have done the same for me.
Excuse me, I'm Deputy U.S. Marshal
Samuel Gerard, I'd like to...
I'll be with you in just a minute.
ROLLINS: One more time,
just for the record...
...these three are dead.
And this one?
Everything happened so fast.
I don't think he made it.
You came a long way for nothing.
With all due respect, Sheriff Rollins...
...I'd like to recommend
checkpoints on a 15-mile radius...
...at l-57, l-24 and over here on Route 13...
Wait. The prisoners are all dead.
Checkpoints will get a lot of people frantic
and they'll flood my office with calls.
Well, shit, I'd hate to see that happen...
...so I'll take over your investigation.
On what authority?
The governor...
...the U.S. Marshal's Office...
...5th District, Northern Illinois.
All right, you want jurisdiction
over this mess. You got it.
Okay, boys, gather around and listen up.
We're shutting it down.
Wyatt Earp is here to mop up...
That's very funny, Wyatt Earp.
BIGGS: Sam.
Look here!
We're always fascinated when
we find leg irons with no legs in them.
Who held the key, sir?
Me.
Where're those keys at?
I don't know.
Care to revise your statement, sir?
What?
Do you want to change
your bullshit story, sir?
GUARD 1: He might've got out.
SAM: He might've got out.
You said he was part of the wreckage!
SAM: Set up operations by the fire truck.
Listen, everyone!
A fugitive has been on the run
for 90 minutes.
Average foot speed over uneven ground,
barring injury, is four miles an hour.
That gives us a radius of six miles.
What I want out of each and everyone
of you is a hard target search of every...
...residence, warehouse, farmhouse,
hen house, outhouse...
... and doghouse in that area.
Checkpoints go up at 15 miles.
Your fugitive's name is Dr. Richard Kimble.
Go get him.
[Sound of rushing water, birds chirping]
[Truck door slams]
[Propellers pelt overhead]
[Sirens screaming,
scattered voices over police radio]
[Dramatic instrumental beat]
COSMO: Please don't give me shit.
I got three very unhappy dead people.
Put him on.
Stevens, it's Cosmo.
COSMO: I'll have a satellite
telephone hookup in two seconds.
Chester Police just found a blood trail...
...two miles southwest.
Match that blood against the prisoners'.
BIGGS: Right.
Renfro, get a fax I.D. On Kimble
to every local hospital.
And follow that with troopers.
Newman?
- Yeah?
- What are you doing?
I'm thinking.
Think me up some coffee
and a doughnut with sprinkles on top...
...while you're thinking.
RESCUE WORKER: [Yelling]
We got a live body!
SAM: A live one?
[Scattered yelling]
RESCUE WORKER: Come on. Hang in
there, brother. We'll get you out of here.
RESCUE WORKER 2:
Get that ambulance down here! Come on!
[Ambient hospital noise]
Is this what you want?
That's it.
I'm going to make some copies.
Good morning, Mr. Johnson.
I have your breakfast for you.
We're thirsty today, aren't we?
NURSE: Eat up before this gets cold.
It really does get dry in here, doesn't it?
NURSE: Here you are.
NURSE: Now, you eat something,
Mr. Johnson.
You need your strength.
Doc, we're looking for a prisoner
from that wreck. He might be hurt.
What does he look like?
Six-one, 180, brown hair,
brown eyes, beard.
OFFICER: Seen anyone like that around?
Every time I look in the mirror, pal.
Except for the beard, of course.
OFFICER: Doc!
Yeah?
Thanks.
[Siren wailing]
RICHARD: I'll give you a hand.
TECHNICIAN: Thanks, Doc.
It's...
How is he doing?
Good, considering we dug him out
from under a train.
Tell those attending he's got a puncture
in the upper gastric area.
How could he tell that
by looking at his face?
[Tires squeal]
Background just came in from Chicago.
SAM: About time. What've we got?
"Richard Davis Kimble, vascular surgeon."
What the hell is that?
POOLE: Somebody that makes
more money than you.
"Convicted of first-degree murder
of his wife.
"Pleaded innocent."
Says a one-armed man did it.
POOLE: Lots of friends.
Doctors, hospital staff.
We'll start there. I want phone taps.
First, his lawyer.
You'll never going to get that.
Call Judge Rubin.
Tell him I want phone taps.
Why'd you yell at me?
I'll tell him who if I'm in a good mood.
COSMO: Why not yell at her sometimes?
We got a call from the hospital.
The wounded guard swears
he saw Kimble there.
That's hot.
And an ambulance is missing.
Where the hell is he going
in an ambulance?
[Bells ringing at crossing]
[Siren wails]
Ambulance just spotted...
...two miles west of Doverville,
heading north, State Highway 53.
COSMO: Running out of map!
[Chopper hisses]
Get your maps out, Renfro.
Check, sound check. Get your maps out.
I want to know all routes
in and out of that town.
[Sirens echoing]
We're headed north on Route13,
toward the Barkley Dam.
Son of a bitch!
Don't lose that ambulance.
[Propellers pelting loudly]
Visual location of an ambulance headed
north on Route 13 toward Barkley Dam.
We'll pass through a viaduct.
Get on the horn. Bring Biggs and Newman
in from the south side of the viaduct.
He's hauling ass.
[Sirens scream, tires screeching]
Is there a tunnel between here and there?
We have Biggs and Newman?
Look on your map
to know how to get there.
[Chopper humming]
[Car horns beeping]
We got him!
Watch out! Watch out! Watch out!
MAN: What's going on?
SAM: Get back in your car, sir!
BIGGS: Newman! Rock and roll!
Put a light in there!
SAM: Put a light in there!
SAM: Biggs, what do you got?
BIGGS: I got nothing.
SAM: What do you got?
BIGGS: You gotta be kidding me!
SAM: Ah, shit!
COSMO: Seal off the tunnel! Seal it off!
[Water gurgling]
We got a gopher.
COSMO: Shit! I just bought these shoes.
SAM: Shut up, Cosmo.
BIGGS: Which way, Sam?
[Muffled bang]
[Grunts]
I didn't kill my wife!
I don't care!
[Water roaring]
Put that gun down!
SAM: Put that gun down!
SAM: Now!
Hands up!
Over your head!
SAM: Turn around!
Richard, do you want to get shot?
Pay attention!
Get down on your knees!
Right now!
COSMO: Sam!
No!
What happened? Where'd he go?
He did a Peter Pan right here off this dam!
SAM: Right here!
Down! Boom!
Holy shit!
Can we go home now?
No.
Holy shit!
[Chaotic yelling]
SAM: There's no way out of here!
BIGGS: We must go up.
BIGGS: Go up the stairs! Up, up!
SAM: Have that water turned off.
Come over here.
Put two patrol cars on that bridge
down there, four patrolmen.
SAM: Have them glass this river
upstream and down.
I want a helicopter 100 feet off this river.
Make him aware of these wires.
Are you out of your mind? He's dead!
That'll make him easy to catch.
I want hounds on both banks
of this river for two miles...
...upstream and downstream.
You've got a search-and-rescue team?
Get them down here and drag
the bottom of this spillway.
Why isn't the water turned off?
POOLE:
Somebody from County's working on it.
[Sirens blaring]
[Gasping and breathing heavily]
COSMO: Bring in the helicopters now.
SAM: We're out of here!
TROOPER:
I don't think there's anything to find.
SAM: Find it anyway. You've got lights
and generators coming tonight.
[Shivering and hyperventilating]
TROOPER: I won't tell you
how to do your job...
SAM: Put the helicopter on the bridge!
...but only one person in a million could
survive that fall. The guy is fish food!
Get a cane pole.
Go catch the fish that ate him.
SAM: Get Stevens.
Tell him we're on the way in.
[Grunts]
[Chopper pelting overhead]
[Dogs barking]
RICHARD:
That man took everything from me!
We can't find the guy.
GUTHRIE: We can't find the guy.
RICHARD: You find that man!
[Echoing] You find that man!
COSMO: The generators and searchlights
are there now.
They'll continue the search into the night.
Good. Call Kentucky
and thank them for the dogs.
Remember, opera ain't over
until the Big Dog howls.
[Thunder rumbles]
[Car horn beeps]
Need a ride?
BIGGS: Check it again.
All right, we got him. He shacked up
with some babe over in Whiting.
POOLE: She left work tonight
and took him home.
NEWMAN: About two hours ago,
her boss said.
BIGGS: They spotted her car
outside her house.
Does she run with anyone?
No one we could find. No family either.
Tell the police not to move till we get
there. We'll go first thing in the morning.
Your cousin still got his truck?
Call him. Tell him we need it.
[Coughing and wheezing]
SAM: Be drunk, Newman.
BIGGS: Stay close.
HENRY: Right on your ass, buddy.
SAM: Newman, I don't want you
getting lost. You stick with me.
[Gun clicks]
U.S. Marshals! Everybody down!
[Woman screams]
Hold it right there! Show me those hands!
Keep them up!
COPELAND: Get your ass in there.
COPELAND: I got your man!
I got your man, you hear me?
WOMAN: [Pleading] No, no!
COPELAND: I want out of here!
I got your man!
COPELAND: I'm going to blow
his brains out! I want out of here!
Do you hear me, Cops?
Do you hear me?
I want out of here!
[Woman screaming and protesting]
COPELAND: Listen! We can work this out!
NEWMAN: Yes, we can.
COPELAND: Shut up! Shut up!
NEWMAN: I'm listening.
COPELAND: Do you hear me?
Listen, and I'll tell you what I want.
I just want a car out front.
[Loud gunfire]
Don't shoot.
SAM: It's over.
[High-pitched screaming]
Shut up!
[Scattered voices]
I can't hear anything. My ear is...
I can't believe you did that.
You think I should've bargained
with that guy.
Yeah.
I do.
You could have missed.
You could have killed me.
How bad is that ear?
Terrible. I'll have permanent damage.
Let me see it.
Come here.
Can you hear what I'm saying now?
Yeah.
[Whispering] I don't...
...bargain.
You hear that?
Yeah.
Good.
[Siren screeches]
[Train bell rings]
Walter, this is Richard.
Richard, Jesus! Why did you run?
Running only makes you look guilty.
I wasn't worried about appearances,
Walter.
Tell me where you are,
so I can meet you and you can surrender.
I won't surrender. I need help, money.
You're asking me to harbor and aid a
convicted felon. I can't help you that way.
My advice both as your friend
and legal counselor is to give yourself up.
Now tell me, where are you?
St. Louis.
Give me an address.
I'll get there as soon as I can.
Mr. Copeland was a bad man.
He was going to kill one of my kids.
Well, sir, you can blame me.
I'm the one that shot him.
WALTER ON TAPE: Give yourself up.
Now tell me, where are you?
RICHARD ON TAPE: St. Louis.
So he's not dead.
Let that be a lesson to you.
Don't ever argue with the Big Dog.
Big Dog is always right.
[Biggs barks]
POOLE: Yeah, you been right before.
RICHARD ON TAPE: Walter, this is Richard.
WALTER ON TAPE: Why did you run?
It only makes you look guilty.
RICHARD ON TAPE: I wasn't worried
about appearances.
WALTER ON TAPE: Tell me where you are,
so I can meet you and you can surrender.
RICHARD ON TAPE: I won't surrender.
I need help, money.
I might be crazy,
but that train sounds like an EI.
St. Louis doesn't have one.
How do you know it's an elevated train?
I lived under an El for 20 years.
Explain the difference between the sound
of an El and a train on the ground.
You must have ears like an eagle.
Play that back.
I want to hear the sound of an EI.
What cities have Els?
New York has got an EI.
POOLE: Philly.
BIGGS: We do.
Milwaukee has got an EI.
Hold it! Where the lawyer says he's guilty.
There's a bell in the background.
There's a guy on a P.A.
Can you drop everything but him?
I'll try. Hold on.
Right there.
What's he saying?
Sounds like, "Next stop." Do that again!
"Next stop..."
"Merchandise Mart."
Son of a bitch! Our boy came home.
That bell is on the Wells Street bridge,
six blocks away.
I knew it was an EI.
Yeah, Big Dog. You're never wrong.
BIGGS: I'll call the C.P.D.
POOLE: This is his Chicago file.
Andiamo, bambini.
Sammy, when I die,
I want to come back just like you.
Happy and handsome?
STEVENS: I'll notify the press.
SAM: No press.
STEVENS: Right, no press.
CHARLES: Hi, Billy.
BILLY: How's it going, sir?
CHARLES: Good, and you?
BILLY: All right.
CHARLES: Here you go, Billy.
BILLY: Have a good one, sir.
Spare change? Dollar, mister?
No, thank you very much. I don't want it.
Oh, my God. Richard!
How are you, Charlie?
CHARLES: Jesus, you're back.
I need some money.
Sure, sure. Get in.
No, I can't. Just whatever you got on you.
You're hot, pal. If not now, you will be.
Have you got a place to stay?
I mean, how can I help you?
[Siren screeches]
COP: You've got a green light. Move on!
I'll call you.
SAM: So why did Richard Kimble
kill his wife?
He did it for the money.
For the money? He's a doctor.
He's already rich.
She was more rich.
Is this the entire
Chicago Police Department file?
KELLY: That's everything.
SAM: I want to do all the interviews again.
The list of hospital staff is it in the file?
Sure is.
Thank you.
You don't want to use the media?
We want him to relax. Make himself
comfortable. Try to re-enter his life.
[Polish accent] Here's the apartment.
You can see here is heater.
You will have warm.
Here is kitchen. Sink.
Over there is bathroom.
And here is the room.
Is nice bed.
Plenty space.
You can look at.
[Speaking in Polish]
LANDLADY: So you like the place?
It's okay with you?
It's perfect.
KELLY: All right, people.
As this morning we were notified
by the U.S. Marshal's Office...
... that our old friend Dr. Richard Kimble
is alive and well and back here in Chicago.
You all know in what high regard
we hold this scumbag.
So I'm personally donating
a bottle of 12-year-old Scotch...
...to whoever puts the collar on this quack.
Dick Rosetti is passing out bulletins.
NURSE: Help you?
RICHARD: Gracias.
[Digital beeping]
[Man singing in Spanish, background]
SAM: You went
to medical school together?
Yes, we did.
SAM: The class of '73.
You know Morton Feinberg?
CHARLES: I do.
SAM: He's a real nice guy.
When did you see him last?
CHARLES: Who, Richard?
I saw Richard this morning.
COSMO: You saw him this morning?
CHARLES: He stopped me in my car.
I gave him money.
Where was this?
Outside my tennis club.
Did he ask for help?
I volunteered. He wouldn't accept that.
How much did you give him?
Couple of bucks. Just what I had on me.
COSMO: He won't get far on that.
SAM: Why'd he come back to Chicago?
He didn't tell me that, sir.
I'm sure he's trying to protect you
from having to lie for him, but...
[Sighing] Dr. Nichols...
You really want to be
his friend and help him?
Help us bring him in unharmed.
Why?
So he can go back to prison?
If you want help, gentlemen,
you've come to the wrong man.
Richard is innocent.
You'll never find him. He's too smart.
BIGGS: We're some smart guys.
What about us? We're smart. We are.
How smart could he be, really?
Is he as smart as you are?
Smarter.
[Flashbulb popping]
SURGEON: Peripheral vascular surgery.
SURGEON: Fixing the arteries
as they come out of the heart.
SAM: How long have you known Kimble?
SURGEON: 10 years. Since I've been here.
What kind of medicine did he practice
here at the hospital?
I want you to know that
I believe Kimble to be innocent.
Would he come to you for help?
If he came to me, I would help.
But he wouldn't come to me.
That's not his style.
A warrant remains outstanding
for Chicago surgeon, Richard Kimble.
COSMO: This is where the one-armed guy
he struggled with fell down the stairs.
COSMO: If I fell down these stairs,
I'd be a goner. I'd be dead.
COSMO: What a waste!
RICHARD: When I came home,
there was a man in my house.
[SIow distorted sound of heart beating]
[Heart beats quickly and stops]
Richard.
[Tires screeching]
COP: Police!
[Scattered yelling from outside,
voices over police radio]
COP: Police! Where is he?
COP: Get him! Get him!
COP 1: Freeze!
COP 2: Where are you going?
[Landlady yelling in Polish]
COP: You like stringing out
12-year-old girls, huh?
LANDLADY:
What are you doing with my baby?
COP 2: Your baby's a drug dealer, lady.
COP 3: Come on, ma'am.
LANDLADY: What they doing to my baby?
[Richard gasps]
[Siren echoing]
ORDERLY 1: It will be crazy here tonight.
Did they get a count?
ORDERLY 2: A lot of kids.
ORDERLY 1: They bring them all here?
ORDERLY 2:
All coming down here to County.
[Knocking on door]
RICHARD: I've come to do those blinds.
I'll get the door.
I'll start in here, huh?
[Sirens echoing in distance]
[Machinery beeps]
[Sound of typing, periodic digital beeps]
KELLY: Let's go over it once more.
What time did he arrive at the house?
About 10:30 in the morning.
KELLY: And he was alone?
KID: Yeah, he was alone.
ROSETTl: You got a good look at him?
KID: Yeah, a real good look.
You better be straight with me.
This is the guy staying
in your mother's basement?
That's what I'm telling you.
[Chaotic yelling, hospital noise]
NURSE: Just breathe. Stay calm.
I need a doctor over here!
ATTENDANT: Watch the bag!
Watch the bag!
[Child sobbing and wheezing]
COP 1: Hello, Marshal. It's right there.
[Landlady speaking excitedly in Polish]
[Scattered chaotic conversation]
BO Y: My chest hurts.