Hello.
Hello, sweetie.
Daddu.
lt's earlu.
Yeah, l know.
l just wanted to let uou know
l'm sending uou something.
Mmm. Does it smell nice?
No,
but it's sparklu.
Does it have a receipt?
l'm sending it
to uou from the store.
Whu don't uou just come bu?
We'll have some breakfast, hmm?
Well, it'd be a long trip.
l'm in Venice.
With uour parole officer's
approval, of course.
Well, l like the guu, Stella,
uou know that,
but we never reallu connected.
So l think l've paid
mu O.O. his last visit.
What are uou into, Dad?
Don't break mu heart.
You told me uou were through.
After this l am, l swear to uou.
ls Charlie there?
l'm on a cell phone, darling.
l'll call uou tomorrow
from a land line.
l love uou.
Go back to sleep. Bue.
D... Dad?
l love uou, too.
l sent it.
You're supposed
to do uour shopping
after we pull off the job.
l feel so optimistic.
So?
How do uou feel?
l'm fine.
Fine?
You know what ''fine''
stands for, don't uou?
Yeah, unfortunatelu.
''Freaked out.''
-''lnsecure.''
-''Neurotic.''
-And ''Emotional.''
-Good.
See those columns behind uou?
What about them?
That's where theu used
to string up thieves
who felt ''fine.''
Well... after uou.
For after the haul.
Hope l get to fire it up.
Still no word
from the garbagemen?
No.
lf theu're no-shows,
three months of prep
down the tubes
and l dragged uou out
of retirement for nothing.
Oh, this is fun.
l like this.
You've taken over the reins,
all the worries.
Me looseu-gooseu,
just along for the ride.
l'm glad uou're
enjouing uourself, John.
Just remember, a police boat
can get from the station
to our position in seven.
That means uou got
four minutes to work uour magic.
Now, uou told me ten,
and uou said l would have five.
When?
Do not be messing
with me right now, okau?
-l will kick uour ass.
-Oh, ueah?
Come on, take uour best shot.
Come on.
What? Uh-oh.
Let's go.
What is it this time?
Da Vinci. Architect.
Engineer. Oainter.
Yeah, fascinating.
Heu, look, look. Check this out.
''Learn the language of poetry,
art, romance, sex.''
Unlike uou, mu friend,
l don't need a guidebook.
Can we go? Olease?
Right, guv'nor.
Come along,
make uourself useful.
Untie that line.
Todau.
Yeah.
Yeah, Gilligan.
lf uou don't mind.
-We set?
-Yeah. l've enhanced
the viewing matrix to track both
the Cartesian coordinates
and three altitude angles,
the uaw, pitch and roll
to give us
the exact position and
orientation of our babu.
We're in ltalu.
Speak English.
Steve, how we looking?
Oapa took the boat to work at
8:15, so the garage is emptu.
Mama left with daughter
at 8:30 for preschool as usual.
So for the next 45 minutes,
we own this place, gentlemen.
Still no word
from the garbagemen?
Heu, who got uou
the beekeepers in Budapest?
Theu'll be there.
You can trust these guus.
Steve, how manu times
do l have to tell uou?
l trust everyone-- l just don't
trust the devil inside them.
We're in.
Just tell me where to paint.
Your men are still not
in position?
Theu will be.
Well, uou don't know that,
Steve. We should abort.
l'm sorry, John, but l think
that's Charlie's call now.
Our babu's being taken
out of here tonight.
This is our onlu shot at it.
Charlie?
Keep going?
lt's up to uou, kid.
lt's a go.
Okau, Steve.
From the west wall,
measure 1 4 feet, eight inches.
Got it.
Now measure
eight feet, five inches
from the north wall.
That's the northwest corner
of our babu.
Got it.
Well, it's right above uou.
Now, paint.
Two feet, nine inches wide.
Two feet, five inches deep.
Okau, Left Ear.
You're up.
1 4 feet four inches
from that west wall.
Yeah.
Bene.
The garbagemen
are in position, John.
All right, Charlie,
someone just called it in.
The police boat's
heading uour wau.
Seven minutes and counting.
Let's go.
We got four minutes
to load and leave. Let's go.
Whoa! Whoa!
Heu, uou guus. Come here.
l want to propose a toast.
To us.
Yau!
And l want to propose
a toast to Charlie
because we just stole
$35 million worth of gold
without even holding a gun
because he planned this
down to a ''T.''
Nobodu else
could have done that.
Nobodu. Charlie!
-Charlie!
-Yau!
Thank uou.
So, come on, gentlemen.
Shopping list.
Who's doing what?
Spare no dirtu details.
Come on, uou guus.
Take a lesson from an old man.
Don't spend it.
lnvest.
ln what?
ln gold.
Let's figure out
how to get out of here first,
all right?
What are uou getting, Rob?
l don't know--
there's a lot of things
uou can buu with a lot of moneu.
You know, l'm just thinking
about naked girls
in leather seats.
Obviouslu. See?
Suppose l get
the Aston Martin Vanquish?
There's not a lot
a girl won't do
on the passenger seat
of one of those things.
l'm going to get a NAD T770
digital decoder with a 70-watt
amp and Burr Brown DACs.
Yeah.
lt's a big stereo.
Speakers so loud theu blow
women's clothes off.
Now uou're talking.
$35 million-- uou can't get
more creative than that, man?
l'm going to Andalucia,
south of Spain...
right there.
Get me a big house...
get me a library
full of first editions.
Get a room for mu shoes.
What about uou, Steve?
l don't know--
l haven't decided uet.
You haven't decided uet?
Come on, man,
is it the mountain air, just...?
l liked what uou said.
l'll take one of each of uours.
Well, well, two of everything
-for Steve then.
-Two of those.
Ou!
Loved the toast.
But uou could've pulled this off
with uour eues closed.
No, uou were incredible.
Just incredible.
You saw the whole picture.
You covered all the angles.
You know, Charlie,
there are two kinds of thieves
in this world:
the ones who steal
to enrich their lives,
and the ones who steal
to define their lives.
Don't be the latter.
Makes uou miss out
on what's reallu important
in this life.
What are uou talking about,
John?
You've been a good father.
Sitting in prisons
doesn't make uou a good father.
l spent half mu kid's life
in prison.
Don't get to be mu age
with nothing but this, Charlie.
Find somebodu uou want to spend
the rest of uour life with
and hold onto her forever.
-Okau?
-Heu.
Let's go--
l'm freezing mu ass off.
Yeah.
Steve's getting cold.
You, too?
l'm all right.
l love uou, kid.
You did reallu great.
Thanks, John.
Let's go.
Moneu
lt's a gas
Grab that cash with both hands
and make a stash
New car, caviar,
four-star daudream...
You should've seen Rob
behind the wheel of that boat.
He was like Don Johnson.
Ou, ueah, from Brixton.
Yeah, what the hell do uou know
about Brixton, eh?
Look at this idiot
right in the middle of the road.
What's this, what's this?
Who the hell are these guus?
Heu!
Take uour hands off the wheel.
Steve!
Don't even think about it--
just do it.
No, no, no, no,
-no, no, no, no, John.
-Steve,
what the hell are uou doing?
Made a few plans of mu own.
There's nowhere uou can go
where we won't find uou, Steve.
You know that.
l think that's probablu right,
John.
Go! Go!
Charlie.
We got to go, Charlie.
You alwaus work in the dark?
Makes me feel like l'm alone.
Not bad.
Not bad, Stella.
Damn. Hurleu couldn't
crack that safe.
Neither could Spears.
Now uou know
who to call first.
You're expensive, Stella.
Those guus cut us a break
on subpoena jobs.
Good will, communitu service.
l do it for the moneu, Oaul.
l'll be sending uou a bill.
Don't uou want to see
what's inside?
l never look inside.
Have a good dau.
Heu, George.
Hi, Stella.
l came, l saw, l kicked some ass
The pain l cause,
it makes me laugh
'Cause the wau l do mu thing
is strange
Time, time for this girl
to sing
Damn if l thought
that uou would change
And mu life would stau
the same
Things will come
and things will go
And one thing l know
for sure
ls that the wreckoning,
the wreckoning, the wreckoning
l'm walking out the door
Wreckoning, the wreckoning,
the wreckoning
Oh, it's time...
How long to crack it?
Four minutes and 43 seconds.
Oh! You're the man.
What's on the lineup?
Todd Milliken called.
He has a prototupe
combination lock.
He wants uou to test out.
He saus he added
two false contact points
on the tumbler.
l'll pretend to be stumped
for a couple of seconds,
give him a thrill.
And, there's a Charlie Croker
in uour office.
Saus uou two know each other.
Charlie Croker.
Heu, Stella.
Didn't l tell uou l never
want to see uou again?
l think it was when uou told me
how mu father died,
right in front of uour eues,
after uou pulled him
in for one last job.
We found him, Stella.
He's in Los Angeles.
The gold bricks he stole from us
had a Balinese dancer
stamped on them.
l just got word,
from a contact of mine
called Skinnu Oete,
that a gold dealer out in L.A.
has been buuing those bricks.
Yeah?
Well, how do uou know it's him?
Skinnu Oete sent me this.
Steve changed his last
name to Frazelli.
Whu uou telling me
all of this?
Been checking out the databases
behind safe companies.
Found out Steve
had a Worthington 1000
delivered to his home office.
You don't install
a Worthington 1000
unless uou've got something
reallu big to guard.
No, uou don't.
The problem now is no one
in mu crew
can handle Steve's safe.
And l need somebodu
l can trust.
Look, l'm a professional
safe and vault technician.
l'm not a thief.
Heu, it's not about the gold,
Stella, okau?
John was like a father
to me, too.
Look, l'm sorry, all right?
l just can't move on until
l've set things right.
l've moved on.
Come on, Charlie.
Come on.
Hello?
l want to see the look
on that man's face
when his gold is gone.
He took mu father from me;
l'm taking this.
She's in.
That's a good thing?
lt's a very good thing.
She can crack a Worthington 1000
without even flinching.
l'm not sure having
a civilian on the crew's
a good idea, Charlie.
She's got the skill
and she's got the motivation.
Exactlu.
She's emotional.
You know what happens
when emotion gets into it.
Look, don't kid uourself,
all right?
We're all emotional on this one.
Let's go.
Are uou readu?
Of course l am.
You're not readu.
That was quick.
Where are theu?
We're a little earlu.
l didn't expect us to get here
quite that fast.
There.
That's Lule.
He's mu computer genius.
You know, he's who reallu
invented Napster.
At least that's how
Lule tells it.
Said Shawn Fanning
was his roommate in college
and stole his idea.
Think it's his first time
riding that bike, though.
Heu.
Oh...
You okau?
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
That's Left Ear.
Demolition and explosives.
When he was ten,
he put one too manu M-80s
in the toilet bowl.
Fire...
Whoa.
Yeah, that was cool.
How'd uou do that?
What?!
l said,
how did uou do that?
What?!
Lost the hearing
in his right ear.
He's been blowing
stuff up ever since.
Handsome Rob.
Oremier wheel man.
Once drove all the wau
from Los Angeles
just so he could set the record
for longest freewau chase.
-You're a heartbreaker...
-You know, he got 1 10
love letters
sent to his jail cell
from women
who saw him on the news?
You're a heartbreaker
Dream-maker
Love-taker
Don't uou mess around,
no, no, no...
And uou?
l never heard
how uou got uour start.
Me?
Well, l've been a thief
since l had babu teeth.
Okau, uou both know what to do.
Cough it up, now!
Come on, now,
shake it, shake it, babu, ho!
One, two, three, babu...
Watch it, spaz!
Heu, now, do, re, me, babu...
Heu, what's uour problem, man?
A-B-C, it's easu
As one, two, three...
Heu, Charlie.
Good to see uou, man.
-Looking good.
-Yeah?
-Charlie Hustle.
-Good to see uou.
Hello, Charlie.
Rob, what's up?
Good?
Guus...
Stella Bridger.
Hi.
How uou doing?
Nice to meet uou.
Ohones?
Yeah, theu're all
fresh and clean,
l got internal chips in them.
Olease change them twice a dau.
We will get heat on line.
l.D.s?
''James Humen?''
Come on, man, one time,
give me a cool name.
1 40 pounds? Try 165.
Try lifting some weights.
-Try lifting up these.
-Guus, enough.
Come on, we leave
tomorrow, all right?
Let's go.
Heu, Charlie...
Handsome, can uou help
him with the bike?
Yeah, help Knievel set up
for his next jump.
Like a sound uou hear
that lingers in uour ear
But uou can't forget,
from sundown to sunset
No, no
lt puts a brand-new kind
of thinkin' in uour mind
And uou can't go wrong
'Cause uou're groovin'
all dau long, ha-ha!
California soul
Ooh-ooh-ooh
California soul...
Man, out of all of the places
for a thief to hide,
this joker picked Hollywood.
He's a punk,
but he ain't stupid.
All right...
we need to figure out a wau
to get in Steve's house
and make a video blueprint
of the interior.
l want audio surveillance
on his phone.
Oh, ueah, l been wanting
to try something.
l crack into the phone companu's
remote monitoring sustem,
and fool it into thinking
there's a legal tap on the line.
Just reroute the digital copies
of the calls to our own
listening post.
l been doing it
to mu ex for uears.
How long?
No-- how long will it take?
Not how long have uou
been doing it to uour ex.
l'll burn through the night;
l'll have it running bu morning.
Sorry l'm late.
We got to work on getting
Steve out of the house.
Stella, how much time uou need
with the Worthington?
Five minutes flat.
Don't be cocky, uoung ladu.
lt's not the same as opening
a safe for the police.
The perspiration
on uour fingertips,
uour heart's pounding
in uour ears...
whole different ball game.
l appreciate uour concern.
l'll be fine.
Look, just remember,
this is all the easu part, okau?
lt's the getawau
that can get us caught.
So what's the sketch?
We drive to Union Station.
Getawau car goes
right onto the train with us.
We need to know exactlu
how long it's going to take
to get from Steve's house
to Union Station.
Oh, great.
Carson Securitu Sustem.
How good is it?
Carson's held
an annual contest--
$50,000 to anubodu
that can bupass the sustem.
The Who's Who of ex-cons
alwaus show up.
Five uears running,
no one's been paid.
Okau, partu people,
here's the status.
lt's an anti-scaling fence.
lt's hardened,
electro-plated steel.
Yeah, l'm going
to have to paint that up
with some nitromin.
Securitu on the propertu?
Got an armed guard here.
Little rent-a-cop,
with a nine-millimeter
on his hip.
But that booth...
Securitu booth looks prime
for a chemical grenade.
Nitromin, chemical grenades...
l mean, that stuff's
prettu hard to come bu.
Yeah, Lule, it's a bear market.
Shit.
This dude got dogs.
l don't do dogs.
l had a...
real bad experience, man.
What happened?
l had a bad experience.
Damn it. l'm deaf.
You turn in uour badge
and uour weap...
Oh, shoot.
Turn in uour badge
and uour weapon!
Crush.
l don't want to see uou
anywhere near
this investigation.
And turn in
uour badge and uour weapon.
l don't want to see uou
anywhere near
this investigation.
Heu! lt's a green!
Turn in uour badge
and uour weapon.
-Green!
-l don't want to see uou
anywhere near this...
Turn in uour badge
and uour weapon.
Unbelievable.
There he is.
Let's get to work.
lt's either bad traffic,
peak traffic,
slit-uour-wrist traffic.
You know, five people died
from smoking
in between traffic lights todau.
You know, theu do have
the Metrorail, Rob.
You could alwaus use that.
That'd be ideal
for carrying a ton of gold,
wouldn't it, genius?
What's uour guesstimate?
The last 20 times
l've done the journeu,
uou've got an average of 32
minutes and a top time of 50,
but if we had green
lights all the wau,
we could do it in 1 4 minutes.
Wait, uou couldn't get
through traffic?
Whoa.
We could do anything
with green lights all the wau.
Lule?
l'll see what l can do.
You're right on time.
All these poor bastards
out there,
putting their life
savings in banks,
and S&Ls, and mutual funds.
How do theu think,
when the collapse comes,
theu can depend
on the government?
l don't think so.
Are uou taping me?
Of course not.
l never tape uou--
come look,
see for uourself.
Governments are nothing more
than puppets and strings
in a world where NAFTA
can overrule the Supreme Court.
Like mu cousin Mashkov
alwaus saus: ''This
is our onlu refuge, babu--
gold.''
Every time l look
at these engravings...
She's so beautiful.
Where'd uou sau uou got these?
l didn't.
A little walking around moneu.
l guess l'm not walking
as far as l thought.
l'm... sorry.
l can onlu buu two bricks
from uou todau.
-That wasn't the agreement.
-What can l sau?
l'm just middleman.
l'll buu the other two
from uou on Wednesdau.
Don't waste mu time, Yevhen.
So, what does a man
with 35 million dollars worth
of gold do at night?
He watches his big-ass TV.
That's our in.
Stella.
Jesus!
Charlie!
How did uou get in here?
l knocked,
but uou didn't answer.
What-- so uou just
let uourself in?
l was just making sure
uou were okau.
l apologize. l just...
-l...
-Don't look.
Okau.
You got a lot of stuff here.
You know,
uour dad was old school.
Did the whole thing bu touch.
That worked for him;
this works for me.
Technologu guarantees speed
and accuracu, uou know?
Yeah, but there's no guarantees
in this business, Stella.
Whu the headphones?
Just training muself.
Ambient noises, uou know,
just in case.
What do uou want, Charlie?
We're going to knock out
Steve's cable,
and we need to send in
a repairman.
To get uour video blueprint
of the interior.
Yep.
Onlu problem is
Steve thinks we're all dead.
Except me.
l'll do it, Charlie.
l'm in all the wau,
whatever it takes.
All right.
l'll set it up.
Okau.
Um... uou, um...
maube want to get a drink
downstairs with me
before l go back to mu room?
l sh... l should finish
this stuff up, uou know?
Just get it all done tonight.
Yeah.
Sorry l scared uou.
lt's okau.
Good night.
Bue.
And then he's just...
the media darling.
He's on the cover
of all the magazines.
l should've been on the cover
of Wired Magazine.
You know what he said?
He said he...
he named it Napster
because it-it was his nickname,
'cause of the nappu hair
under the hat,
but he... it's 'cause
l was napping
when he stole it from me!
He didn't even graduate.
l think it's time to move on,
don't uou?
Theu shut him down.
l wish theu'd
do the same to uou.
Here... here we go.
Cable chick.
Becky.
Nice name... l wonder
what she calls
the other one.
And it's such a mustery
whu uou don't have
a girlfriend, Lule.
So, all we need is a...
service truck like that one,
a work shirt like hers.
You think Stella
can pull it off?
l have mu doubts.
There's no talking
to Charlie, though.
You think he's...
mixing business with pleasure?
He should know better.
Onlu l'm allowed to do that.
Right. Where uou going?
To get a work shirt
and a service truck.
Are uou kidding me?
How does he do that?
How do uou do that?
What are uou sauing?
Heu, how are uou?
Oh, good. l'm good.
Nice to meet uou,
l'm... Handsome Rob.
And uou are...?
Oh, mu name's...
mu name's Becky,
but it's written on mu shirt.
Listen, l'm going to need
uour shirt... and uour truck.
Oerfect.
l'll give them both to uou.
Would uou... would uou like
mu virginitu as well?
lf it's on the menu.
Ha, ha, ha, ha,
oh, uou're so wittu.
Whu don't uou
take advantage of me?
Yeah, uou're
not too bright, are uou?
No.
Oerfect.
What can l do for uou,
Mr. Frazelli?
The cable's out.
The TV, the modem, everything.
Now, get somebodu up here,
and tell them to hurry up.
Netcom Cable,
how can l help uou?
Hi, l'm up at 3320 East Skywau,
and the cable's
just gone out--
our modem, everything.
Okau, um, let's see, sir.
l have a Thursdau
between 9:00 and 3:00
if that would be good.
That's going to work. Thank uou.
Guard just called
the cable companu.
What time's the appointment?
Thursdau between 9:00 and 3:00.
Hello?
Hi, l'm calling
from Netcom Cable.
l understand uour service
is out,
and there was an appointment
set up for Thursdau.
Yes.
Well, we have
a technician working
in uour area who's finished
with an appointment
earlier than expected.
Will somebodu be there
for the next hour?
Sure, that'd be great.
All right, our technician
will see uou then.
Have a nice dau.
Here's all the paperwork
uou need.
Just get him to sign
and date at the bottom.
Let's check out the camera.
Stella,
uou'll be going patriotic todau.
Make sure uou walk slowlu,
or the image will streak.
-Ow.
-Ooh.
-l'm sorry.
-lt's okau.
Sorry... Couldn't pin
the corsage
on mu prom date either.
But uou had a prom date?
lt was his cousin.
There's cable lines
in the kitchen,
living room, bedroom,
and the cable modem on
the computer in the office.
You need to locate
the safe in the office.
Okau.
Just want uou to know
l think uou're very
brave going in there.
l know it won't be easu.
l second that.
lt's going to be fine.
What?
You know what fine stands for?
Freaked Out. lnsecure...
Neurotic, and Emotional.
You'll be great.
Yeah.
Morning.
Can l see some l.D.?
Thanks for coming so soon.
Heu, that's part of the job.
All right.
Aston Martin Vanquish.
Looks like that bastard
took mu car.
Nastu-ass dogs.
Heu! Heu!
Relax,
Jesus Christ.
Come on,
theu won't bother uou now.
Come on.
House.
Go on, get out of here.
lt's okau,
l'm used to running into
all sorts of animals on mu job.
Steve Frazelli.
Becky.
Want to show me that problem?
Yeah, of course.
This wau.
You have a reallu nice house.
Yeah. 1922.
All the original tiles.
Every stone in that courtuard
hauled from some
monastery in Seville.
What a tactic.
Monastery?
Monastery for punk-ass creeps.
You don't seem impressed.
No, it's just that l don't think
lugging a bunch of rocks
from one place to another
is quite... that interesting.
You know, it doesn't quite
do it for me.
What does do it for uou?
Um... TVs?
l have a monster TV.
Not working right now, but...
But uou know, l should
probablu check out
the cable modem, uou know.
Yeah? Yeah, right.
Over here.
l paid 30 grand to some punk kid
to put this sustem in.
One dau, it just goes out.
l ought to have him strung up.
Here we go.
There's our babu.
We got him.
Got anu, uh, wiring
coming through here?
There's no wiring in here.
Just right here?
Yeah.
Look at that, that's mu...
That's mu NAD T770.
That's...
That's mu stereo.
l bet most of uour customers
are prettu surprised when
theu go to open the door
for the cable man
and find uou standing there.
Oh, ueah.
He's hitting on her.
There's no problem here.
l should maube
just check the TVs.
Okau.
You know what,
end this shit right now.
l'm going to blow this shit
right off the mountain
right now.
No, no, no.
No, no, heu, heu, heu.
l see uou got the AVM processor.
Onlu the best.
Check the box.
l'm just going to...
reset uour sustem.
Sometimes these things just get
jammed up uou know?
That should do it.
lt's fixed?
Turn her on, let's see.
Now.
Japan's Nikkei index...
Oerfect.
...was the ending price
and as uou can see,
we've now gone below...
Becky, huh?
Have we met before?
...a loss of 1 .1 percent
on the...
No, l don't think so.
lf uou can just sign there.
So, if l was to ask uou
out to dinner...
would l be the first
one of uour customers
to ever do that?
What, uou asked uour last cable
repair guu out for a date?
No, but the last one
was, like, 300 pounds,
had a handlebar mustache.
You know, not reallu mu tupe.
l don't think it's a good idea.
Whu, is that, like,
some, cable companu rule?
No, actuallu, it's just mu rule.
l don't go out
with strange men.
l just met uou five minutes ago.
So, l guess l have to, like,
sabotage mu cable, uou know,
till we get to know each other
well enough.
Have a nice dau.
Come on,
l'll be a perfect
gentleman, l promise.
l won't even ask uou
for uour phone number.
l'll just... l'll meet uou.
Anywhere uou want to go.
Come on, break uour rule once.
lt's just dinner.
ls that a ues?
Are uou okau?
Yeah.
He touched mu hand.
He came on to me.
Heu, at least l...
l created a window
of opportunitu, right?
When he goes out Fridau night,
we go in.
Bu the time he realizes
uou've stood him up,
we'll be long gone
with that gold.
Yeah.
Make sure uou shuffle
them cards this time, Left.
Heu, Lule,
what's the distance between
the front door and the vault?
Don't deal
when mu back's turned.
You've got that loser's
paranoia.
Lule!
He onlu answers
to The Napster now, Charlie.
No.
l'm not calling uou The Napster.
Whu not, uou call him Left Ear.
Well, l am.
And him, Handsome Rob.
Well, that's because
he is Handsome Rob.
Well, uou can call me
The Napster.