See you tomorrow.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE ROARS]
Oh, my God!
I'm in.
We're almost there.
- Sir, are you sure about this?
- I told you, we're going to be all right.
I understand, sir. It's just that I'm scoping
some serious sentinel activity up here.
- Link.
- Yes, sir?
Given your situation, I can't say
I understand your reasons...
...for volunteering to operate
onboard my ship.
However, if you wish to continue to
do so, I must ask you to do one thing.
What's that, sir?
To trust me.
Yes, sir. I will, sir.
- I mean, I do, sir.
- I hope so.
Repatch the main AC to the hard drives
and stand by to broadcast.
Yes, sir.
[DOOR OPENS]
Still can't sleep?
You wanna talk?
They're just dreams.
If you're afraid of something...
I just wish...
I wish I knew what I'm supposed to do.
That's all.
I just wish I knew.
She's gonna call. Don't worry.
Here you are.
- Are we ready to go?
- We're already late.
These geotherms confirm
the last transmission of the Osiris.
The machines are digging.
They're boring from the surface
down to Zion.
- Mother...
- They'll avoid the perimeter defense.
How fast are they moving?
Control estimates their descent
at 100 meters an hour.
MAN 1: How deep are they?
- Almost 2000 meters.
- What about the scans from the Osiris?
- They can't be accurate.
- They may be.
- It's not possible.
That'd mean there are
a quarter-million sentinels.
- That's right.
MAN 2: That can't be.
MORPHEUS:
Why not?
A sentinel for every man,
woman and child in Zion.
That sounds exactly like
the thinking of a machine to me.
Morpheus, glad you could join us.
Niobe.
My apologies to all.
But as you are undoubtedly aware...
...it's become difficult to locate
a secure broadcast position.
- Squiddies got our best spots.
- Lines are crawling with them.
And if Niobe's right, in 72 hours
there's gonna be a quarter-million more.
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna do what
Commander Lock ordered.
We'll evacuate broadcast level
and return to Zion.
And does the commander have a plan
for stopping 250,000 sentinels?
A strategy is still being formulated.
I'm sure it is.
MAN: What do you think
we should do, Morpheus?
MORPHEUS: Proceed as ordered...
- What is it?
I don't know.
MORPHEUS: however, I must
ask one of you for help.
Some of you believe as I believe, some
of you do not. Those of you that do...
...know we are nearing
the end of our struggle.
The prophecy will be fulfilled soon.
But before it can be...
...the Oracle must be consulted.
If we return and recharge now...
...we can be back in 36 hours, well
before the machines reach this depth.
Do you understand what you're asking?
I am asking that one ship
remain here in our place...
...in case the Oracle
should attempt to contact us.
Bullshit. You're asking one of us
to disobey a direct order.
That's right, I am. But we well know
that the reason most of us are here...
...is because of our affinity
for disobedience.
What happens when you
get back to Zion...
...and the commander
throws you in the stockade?
He won't.
Goddamn it, Morpheus,
you ain't never gonna change.
Shit, I'll do it just to see
what Deadbolt does to you.
You got 36 hours.
SMITH:
I'm looking for Neo.
- Never heard of him.
- I have something for him.
A gift.
You see, he set me free.
Fine, whatever. Now piss off.
Who was that?
MAN:
How did you know someone was here?
He gave you this.
He said you set him free.
Is everything all right, sir?
The meeting is over.
Retreat to your exits.
- Agents are coming.
- Agents?
Go.
[POUNDING]
Hiya, fellas.
AGENT 1: It's him.
- The anomaly.
- Do we proceed?
- Yes.
- He is still...
- Only human.
Hm. Upgrades.
- That went as expected.
SMITH 2: Yes.
It's happening exactly as before.
Well, not exactly.
- What happened?
LINK: I can't figure it out.
Agents just came out of nowhere.
Then the code got all weird.
Encryption I've never seen.
- Is Neo okay?
- Okay? Shit, you should've seen him.
Where is he now?
He's doing his Superman thing.
Where are you?
This is the Nebuchadnezzar,
requesting access through Gate Three.
Nebuchadnezzar, this is Zion Control.
Maintain present velocity and stand by.
LINK:
Roger that, Control.
This is Control requesting immediate
stand-down of arms at Gate Three.
We have the Nebuchadnezzar
on approach. Let's open her up.
You are cleared through
Gate Three to Bay Seven.
Roger that, Control.
Door's open, bed's made.
Welcome home.
No place like it.
Roger that, Control. Zion Control,
stand by for Gate Three lockdown.
CONTROL: The Nebuchadnezzar is down.
Bay Seven.
Understood.
Captain Mifune.
Captain Morpheus.
Are you here to escort me
to the stockade, captain?
- I'm just here to keep the peace.
- Commander Lock demands...
[MIFUNE CLEARS THROAT]
Requests your immediate counsel, sir.
- Link.
- Sir?
I want the ship ready to go
as soon as possible.
Understood, sir.
- What is it between them?
- Morpheus and Lock?
- Niobe.
- Captain Niobe?
She used to be with Morpheus.
Now she's with Lock.
What happened?
Morpheus went to the Oracle.
After that, everything changed.
Yeah, she can do that.
BOY:
Neo!
NEO: Oh, no.
- How does he always know?
Doesn't he have anything better to do?
You know what they say
about the life you save.
I didn't save his life.
Hiya, Neo.
- Trinity, Link.
LINK: Hey.
- It's great to have you back.
- Thanks. It's good to be back.
- Can I carry that for you?
- No, I can carry my own bag.
- Trinity?
- I'm fine.
- You can carry these.
- Yeah, sure, Link.
Hey, you know, next year
I'm old enough to join a crew, right?
I've been thinking about it,
and I've made my decision.
Let me guess.
I want to join the Nebuchadnezzar.
Morpheus hasn't filled the other
positions, except for you, Link.
I'm sure he has reasons...
...but the more I think about it,
the more I think it's meant to be.
You know, it's fate.
You're the reason I'm here, Neo.
I told you, you found me.
I didn't find you.
I know, but you got me out.
You saved me.
You saved yourself.
- Morpheus.
MORPHEUS: Commander Lock.
I spoke to the other captains. I wanted to
offer you a chance to explain your actions.
I wasn't aware that my actions
required any explanation.
You were given an order
to return to Zion.
- I did.
- You asked for one ship to remain behind.
I would have stayed,
but I needed to recharge my ship.
So you admit to a direct contravention
of your duty.
We need a presence inside the Matrix
to await contact from the Oracle.
I don't want to hear that shit!
I don't care about oracles
or prophecies or messiahs!
I care about one thing: Stopping that
army from destroying this city.
To do that I need soldiers
to obey my orders.
With all due respect, commander,
there is only one way to save our city.
How?
- Neo.
- Goddamn it, Morpheus.
Not everyone believes what you believe.
My beliefs do not require them to.
There's a gathering tonight. Everyone's
talking. A lot of people are scared.
No one remembers the last time
so many ships were docked.
- Something big is happening, isn't it?
- Hey.
We're not allowed to say anything,
so stop asking.
Goddamn, it's good to be home.
I'm recommending that you
be removed from duty.
That is, of course,
your prerogative, commander.
If it were up to me, you wouldn't set foot
on a ship for the rest of your life.
Then I am grateful that
it is not up to you.
[DOOR OPENS]
- Councilor Hamann.
- Commander.
- Captain.
- Councilor.
Council's asked me to speak tonight
at the temple gathering.
The presence of the fleet and the
persistence of rumors must be addressed.
The people must be told
what is happening.
Of course, councilor.
But might I advise a level of discretion
concerning specific details.
- We do not wish to start a panic.
- Quite right.
A panic is not what anyone wants.
What about you, captain?
What would you advise?
The truth. No one will panic,
because there is nothing to fear.
That army won't reach
the gates of Zion.
- What makes you so sure?
- Consider what we have seen, councilor.
Consider that in the past six months...
...we have freed more minds
than in six years.
This attack is an act of desperation.
I believe very soon the prophecy
will be fulfilled and this war will end.
I hope you're right, captain.
I do not believe it to be
a matter of hope, councilor.
It is simply a matter of time.
My stop.
See you soon.
Hopefully not too soon.
Let's go, kid.
These two got things to do.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
I am if you're thinking
this elevator is too slow.
- How long do we charge the Neb?
- Twenty-four, maybe 30 hours.
Some people go their entire lives
without hearing news that good.
Neo, please, I have a son,
Jacob, aboard the Gnosis.
- Please, watch over him.
- I'll try.
WOMAN:
I have a daughter on the Icarus.
No, wait.
It's all right. They need you.
- I need you.
- I know.
There's time.
Where's my puss..?
- Hey!
- Uncle Link!
God!
CHILDREN:
Uncle Link!
Oh, my God! You're so huge!
- You should be picking me up!
- No!
- Yeah!
CHILDREN: Okay!
LINK:
Okay? All right.
Now, we're gonna have
to work together here, okay?
One, two, three, lift!
Oh, my God!
What are you feeding these two?
Come on, kids. It's time to go.
- Hey, Cas.
CAS: Hey.
- Good to have you home, Link.
- Good to be home.
You be careful with her.
Don't worry about me.
He's the one that's gonna get it.
CAS:
Out the door! Both of you, march!
LINK: Bye!
CAS: Bye!
I'm gonna get what?
Every ship up there's been home two, even
three times more than the Nebuchadnezzar.
Come on, Zee.
I thought we were past this.
- We'll be when you operate another ship.
- I can't do that.
- Why?
- You know why.
If Dozer knew how I felt,
he wouldn't have asked you to do this.
Maybe. But it's too late now.
I made a promise,
and some promises can't be unmade.
- It's not fair.
- Nobody said it was gonna be.
You think Cas thinks it's fair
that I'm here and Dozer's not?
I lost two brothers to that ship, Link.
I'm afraid of it.
I'm afraid it's gonna take you too.
It won't.
How can you say that to me?
Because of Morpheus.
Because of what he's told me. He said
that this is it, that it will be over soon.
- Link, Morpheus is crazy.
- No doubt.
But Tank and Dozer believed him.
And I'll tell you what...
...after being on that ship and seeing Neo
do the things he can do, I gotta say...
...I'm starting to believe him too.
Be careful, Link.
Please be careful.
- They started yet?
- Only Councilor Hamann's opening prayer.
Tonight, let us honor
these men and women.
These are our soldiers, our warriors.
These are our husbands and wives,
our brothers and sisters...
...our children.
Let us remember those
that have been lost...
...and let us give thanks
for those that have been found...
...and who stand here beside us.
Now I would like someone else
to close this prayer...
...someone who hasn't spoken here
in a long time...
...but who I believe has something to say
that we all need to hear.
I give you Morpheus.
Zion! Hear me!
It is true what many of you have heard.
The machines have gathered
an army, and as I speak...
...that army is drawing nearer to our home.
[CHATTERING]
Believe me when I say we have
a difficult time ahead of us.
But if we are to be prepared for it,
we must first shed our fear of it.
I stand here before you now
truthfully unafraid.
Why?
Because I believe something you do not?
No!
I stand here without fear
because I remember.
I remember that I am here not because
of the path that lies before me...
...but because of the path
that lies behind me.
I remember that for 100 years
we have fought these machines.
they have sent their armies to destroy us.
And after a century of war,
I remember that which matters most:
We are still here!
Tonight...
...let us send a message to that army.
Tonight, let us shake this cave.
Tonight, let us tremble these halls...
...of earth, steel and stone.
Let us be heard from red core
to black sky.
Tonight, let us make them remember:
This is Zion and we are not afraid!
NIOBE:
I remember.
I remember you used to dance.
I remember you were pretty good.
There are some things in this world,
Captain Niobe...
...that will never change.
LOCK:
Niobe!
Some things do change.
Excuse me.
- I missed you.
- I can tell.
I was thinking, everyone is here.
Follow me.
[TECHNO MUSIC PLAYS]
Neo, what is it?
What's wrong?
It's okay, you can tell me.
Trinity...
Don't be afraid.
I can't lose you.
You're not gonna lose me.
You feel this?
I'm never letting go.
Good night, Zion.
Sweet dreams.
[PHONE RINGING]
- You all right?
MAN: I'll make it.
Did you see that agent?
I've never seen anything like that.
It doesn't matter.
All that matters is this.
You first.
- Oh, God.
- "Smith" will suffice.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
[PHONE RINGS]
- Care for some company?
- Councilor Hamann.
I don't want to intrude
if you'd prefer to be alone.
- No, I could probably use some company.
- Good.
So could I.
It's nice tonight.
Very calm.
It feels like everyone is sleeping
very peacefully.
Not everyone.
I hate sleeping.
I never sleep more than a few hours.
I figure I slept the first 11 years
of my life, now I'm making up for it.
- What about you?
- I just haven't been able to sleep much.
- It's a good sign.
- Of what?
That you are in fact still human.
Have you ever been
to the engineering level?
I love to walk there at night.
It's quite amazing.
- Would you like to see it?
- Sure.
[RUMBLING]
Almost no one comes down here.
Unless, of course, there's a problem.
That's how it is with people. Nobody cares
how it works as long as it works.
I like it down here.
I like to be reminded this city survives
because of these machines.
These machines are keeping us alive
while other machines are coming to kill us.
Interesting, isn't it?
The power to give life...
...and the power to end it.
- We have the same power.
Yeah, I suppose we do, but...
...sometimes I think about those people
still plugged into the Matrix.
And when I look at these machines...
...I can't help thinking that, in a way,
we are plugged into them.
But we control these machines,
they don't control us.
Of course not. How could they?
The idea is pure nonsense...
...but it does make one wonder just...
...what is control?
If we wanted, we could
shut these machines down.
Of course. That's it. You hit it.
That's control, isn't it?
If we wanted,
we could smash them to bits.
Although if we did, we'd have to consider
what would happen to our lights...
...our heat, our air.
So we need machines and they need us.
Is that your point, councilor?
No. No point.
Old men like me don't bother
with making points. There's no point.
Is that why there are no young men
on the Council?
Good point.
Why don't you tell me
what's on your mind, councilor.
There is so much in this world...
...that I do not understand.
See that machine? It has something to do
with recycling our water supply.
I have absolutely no idea how it works.
But I do understand the reason
for it to work.
I have absolutely no idea how you
are able to do some of the things you do.
But I believe there's a reason for that
as well.
I only hope we understand that reason
before it's too late.
- Ballard.
- Is he here?
Neo, it's from the Oracle.
It's time to go.
Morpheus said this was how
it was gonna happen.
I don't know. Maybe the prophecy's true,
maybe it's not.
All I know is, that ship needs an operator.
Right now, that operator's me.
I know.
- Zee...
- I want you to wear it.
- You know I don't believe in this stuff.
- But I do.
It's always brought me luck.
- Maybe it'll bring me you.
- I'm coming back.
I promise. No matter what it takes,
I'm coming home.
Just keep it with you. Please.
For me.
Okay.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
BOY: Neo!
LINK: How the hell..?
Bane.
Is something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
I just wanted to catch you to say...
...good luck.
Thanks.
We'll see you.
Neo! Just in time.
- You're gonna see the Oracle?
- There's no time.
I had to give something to Neo.
A gift from one of the orphans.
He made me swear to get it to you
before you left.
He said you'd understand.
Thanks.
I was just told you cleared
the Nebuchadnezzar for takeoff.
That is correct.
Am I still in charge
of our defense system?
Of course.
I believe I need every ship we have
if we're going to survive this attack.
I understand that, commander.
Then why did you allow
the Nebuchadnezzar to leave?
Because I believe our survival depends
on more than how many ships we have.
Be careful.
[BELLS RINGING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Hello.
- You seek the Oracle.
- Who are you?
I am Seraph. I can take you to her,
but first I must apologize.
Apologize for what?
For this.
Good.
The Oracle has many enemies.
I had to be sure.
- Of what?
- That you are the One.
- You could have just asked.
- No. You do not truly know someone...
...until you fight them.
Come. She's waiting.
Where the hell did they go?
These are back doors, aren't they?
Programmer access.
- How do they work?
- A code is hidden in tumblers.
One position opens a lock and another
position opens one of these doors.
Are you a programmer?
Then what are you?
I protect that which matters most.
ORACLE:
Well, come on. I ain't gonna bite you.
Come around here
and let me have a look at you.
My goodness, look at you.
You turned out all right, didn't you?
- How do you feel?
- I...
I know you're not sleeping.
We'll get to that.
Why don't you come
and have a sit this time.
- Maybe I'll stand.
- Well, suit yourself.
- I felt like sitting.
- I know.
So...
...let's get the obvious stuff
out of the way.
- You're not human, are you?
- It's tough to get more obvious than that.
If I had to guess, I'd say you're
a program from the machine world.
- So is he.
- So far, so good.
But if that's true, that could mean
you're part of this system...
...another kind of control.
- Keep going.
- I suppose the most obvious question is...
...how can I trust you?
- Bingo.
It is a pickle, no doubt about it.
Bad news is...
...there's no way you can really know
if I'm here to help you or not.
So it's really up to you. Just have
to make up your own damn mind...
...to either accept what
I'm going to tell you or reject it.
Candy?
- Do you already know if I'll take it?
- Wouldn't be much of an oracle if I didn't.
But if you already know,
how can I make a choice?
Because you didn't come here to make
the choice. You've already made it.
You're here to try to understand
why you made it.
I thought you'd have figured that out
by now.
- Why are you here?
- Same reason.
I love candy.
But why help us?
We're all here to do
what we're all here to do.
I'm interested in one thing, Neo:
the future.
And believe me, I know, the only way
to get there is together.
- Are there other programs like you?
- Well, not like me, but...
Look. See those birds?
At some point, a program was written
to govern them.
A program was written to watch over the
trees and the wind, the sunrise and sunset.
There are programs running
all over the place.
The ones doing their job, doing what
they were meant to do, are invisible.
You'd never even know they were here.
But the other ones...
Well, you hear about them all the time.
- I've never heard of them.
- Of course you have.
Every time you've heard someone
say they saw a ghost or an angel...
...every story you've ever heard about
vampires, werewolves or aliens...
...is the system assimilating
some program...
...that's doing something
they're not supposed to be doing.
Programs hacking programs.
- Why?
- They have their reasons...
...but usually a program chooses exile
when it faces deletion.
- And why would a program be deleted?
- Maybe it breaks down.
Maybe a better program is created
to replace it. Happens all the time.
And when it does, a program
can either choose to hide here...
...or return to the source.
- The machine mainframe.
- Yes.
Where you must go.
Where the path of the One ends.
You've seen it...
...in your dreams, haven't you?
A door made of light?
What happens when you go through
the door?
I see Trinity...
...and something happens...
...something bad.
She starts to fall,
and then I wake up.
- Do you see her die?
- No.
You have the sight now, Neo.
You are looking at the world
without time.
Then why can't I see
what happens to her?
We can never see past the choices
we don't understand.
Are you saying I have to choose
whether Trinity lives or dies?
No, you've already made the choice.
Now you have to understand it.
No.
I can't do that. I won't.
- Well, you have to.
- Why?
Because you're the One.
What if I can't?
What happens if I fail?
Then Zion will fall.
Our time is up. Listen to me, Neo.
You can save Zion...
...if you reach the source, but to do that
you need the Keymaker.
The Keymaker?
He disappeared. We didn't
know what happened to him until now.
He's being held prisoner
by a very dangerous program...
...one of the oldest of us.
He is called the Merovingian.
- And he won't let him go willingly.
- What does he want?
What do all men with power want?
More power.
Be there at that exact time...
...and you will have a chance.
We must go.
Seems like every time we meet
I got nothing but bad news.
I'm sorry about that. I surely am.
But for what it's worth...
...you've made a believer out of me.
Good luck, kiddo.
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
Mr. Anderson.
Did you get my package?
- Yeah.
- Well, good.
- Smith?
- He's not reading like an agent.
- Surprised to see me?
- No.
- Then you're aware of it.
- Of what?
Our connection.
I don't fully understand how it happened.
Perhaps some part of you
imprinted onto me...
...something overwritten or copied.
It is, at this point, irrelevant.
What matters is...
...that whatever happened,
happened for a reason.
And what reason is that?
I killed you, Mr. Anderson.
I watched you die.
With a certain satisfaction,
I might add.
And then something happened,
something that I knew was impossible...
...but it happened anyway.
You destroyed me, Mr. Anderson.
Afterward, I knew the rules, I understood
what I was supposed to do...
...but I didn't.
I couldn't. I was compelled to stay...
...compelled to disobey.
And now, here I stand
because of you, Mr. Anderson.
Because of you, I'm no longer an agent
of this system.
Because of you, I've changed.
I'm unplugged.
A new man, so to speak.
Like you, apparently free.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
But as you well know,
appearances can be deceiving...
...which brings me back to the reason
why we're here.
We're not here because we're free.
We're here because we are not free.
There's no escaping reason,
no denying purpose.
Because as we both know,
without purpose...
...we would not exist.
- It is purpose that created us.
- Purpose that connects us.
SMITH 4: Purpose that pulls us.
SMITH 5: That guides us.
SMITH 6: That drives us.
- It is purpose that defines.
- Purpose that binds us.
We are here because of you,
Mr. Anderson.
We're here to take from you
what you tried to take from us:
Purpose.
- What's happening to him?
- Don't know.
Yes, that's it. It'll be over soon.
- You.
- Yes, me.
Me, me, me.
Me too.
[SCREAMS]
More.
It is inevitable.
Come on, get out of there.
Are you all right?
- It was Smith.
- Yes.
MORPHEUS: Now there's more than one?
- A lot more.
- How is that possible?
- I don't know.
Somehow, he's found a way
to copy himself.
- Is that what he was doing to you?
- I don't know what he was doing...
...but I know what it felt like.
- What?
It felt like I was back in that hallway.
It felt like dying.
The machines are tunneling to avoid
our defense system.
But I believe they will intersect
certain pipelines to control them.
These points of intersection
are crucial...
...because I believe they're
vulnerable to counterattack.
Although it has been suggested that
this is the same kind of attack...
...we've defended for years,
I urge the Council to realize the truth.
This is the single greatest threat
we have ever faced...
...and if we do not act accordingly,
we will not survive.
Commander Lock, the Council is well
aware of the seriousness of this attack.
You have our leave to prepare our defense
by any and all means necessary.
- Thank you, Council.
DILLARD: However...
...we ask if there's been word
from the Nebuchadnezzar.
No, councilor. No word. Nothing.
Then we request a ship be dispatched
to ascertain the fate of the One.
I wish that were possible, councilor,
but I do not believe our defense...
...can suffer the loss of another ship.
- It will, commander, if it must.
It could take one ship days
to find the Nebuchadnezzar.
- Then send two.
- This is insane.
Careful, commander.
Forgive my frustration, councilors.
But I wish I were able to comprehend
the Council's choice in this matter.
Comprehension is not
a requisite of cooperation.
If you are asking me
to order two of my captains...
There's no need for such an order.
The captains are present.
They can answer for themselves.
The Council is calling for two volunteers
to aid the Nebuchadnezzar.
Are there two among you
that would answer such a call?
Captain Soren of the Vigilant
will answer the Council's call.
You understand the situation,
Captain Soren?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Thank you, captain.
Is there another?
- Captain, I think we should volunteer.
- What? You have gone crazy.
- Listen...
- Shut your hole, Bane...
...before I put you in one.
Is there no other?
Be hard for any man to risk his life...
...especially if he doesn't
understand the reason.
Captain Niobe of the Logos
will answer the councilor's call.
- What?
- Thank you, Captain Niobe.
Commander Lock, you have your orders.
This Council is hereby adjourned.
- Niobe, what are you doing?
- What I can.
Why?
Because some things
never change, Jason...
...and some things do.
What can you see, Neo?
It's strange.
The code is somehow different.
- Encrypted?
- Maybe.
Is that good for us or bad for us?
Well, it looks like every floor
is wired with explosives.
Bad for us.
Here we go.
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
Yes. We are here to speak
with the Merovingian.
Well, of course.
He has been expecting you.
Follow me.
A-ha. Here he is at last.
Neo, the One himself.
Right?
And the legendary Morpheus.
And Trinity, of course.
I have heard so much.
You honor me. Please, sit. Join us.
This is my wife, Persephone.
Something to eat? Drink?
Of course, such things are contrivances,
like so much here.
For the sake of appearances.
- No, thank you.
- Yes, of course. Who has time?
Who has time? But then, if we do not ever
take time, how can we ever have time?
Chteau Haut-Briond, 1959.
Magnificent wine.
I love French wine
like I love the French language.
I have sampled every language.
French is my favorite. Fantastic language...
...especially to curse with.
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
You see? It's like wiping your ass
with silk. I love it.
You know why we are here.
I am a trafficker of information.
I know everything I can.
The question is,
do you know why you are here?
We are looking for the Keymaker.
Oh, yes, it is true.
The Keymaker, of course.
But this is not a reason,
this is not a why.
The Keymaker himself, his very nature,
is a means, it is not an end.
And so to look for him is to be
looking for a means to do...
...what?
- You know the answer to that question.
But do you?
You think you do, but you do not.
You are here
because you were sent here.
You were told to come here,
and then you obeyed.
It is, of course, the way of all things.
You see, there is only one constant...
...one universal. It is the only real truth.
Causality.
Action, reaction.
- Cause and effect.
- Everything begins with choice.
No. Wrong.
Choice is an illusion created
between those with power...
...and those without.
Look there at that woman.
My God, just look at her...
...affecting everyone around her.
So obvious, so bourgeois, so boring.
But wait.
Watch. You see, I have sent her
a dessert...
...a very special dessert.
I wrote it myself.
It starts so simply...
...each line of the program creating
a new effect, just like...
...poetry.
First...
...a rush, heat. Her heart flutters.
You can see it, Neo, yes?
She does not understand why.
Is it the wine? No.
What is it then? What is the reason?
And soon it does not matter.
Soon the why and the reason are gone...
...and all that matters is the feeling itself.
And this is the nature of the universe.
We struggle against it,
we fight to deny it...
...but it is, of course, pretense.
It is a lie.
Beneath our poised appearance...
...the truth is, we are completely...
...out of control.
Causality. There is no escape from it.
We are forever slaves to it.
Our only hope, our only peace,
is to understand it, to understand the why.
"Why" is what separates us from them...
...you from me.
"Why" is the only real source of power.
Without it, you are powerless.
And this is how you come to me,
without why, without power.
Another link in the chain.
But fear not.
Since I have seen how good you are
at following orders...
...I will tell you what to do next.
Run back and give the fortuneteller
this message:
Her time is almost up.
Now I have some real business to do,
so I will say adieu and goodbye.
- This isn't over.
- Oh, yes, it is.
The Keymaker is mine, and I see no reason
why I should give him up.
- No reason at all.
- Where are you going?
Please, ma chrie, I have told you.
We are all victims of causality.
I drank too much wine,
I must take a piss.
Cause and effect. Au revoir.
Touch me and that hand
will never touch anything again.
Well, that didn't go so well.
Are you certain the Oracle
didn't say anything else?
- Yes.
- Maybe we did something wrong.
Or didn't do something.
No, what happened couldn't have
happened any other way.
- How do you know?
- We are still alive.
[ELEVATOR BELL RINGS]
If you want the Keymaker, follow me.
Get out.
I am so sick and tired of his bullshit.
On and on. Pompous prick.
A long time ago, when we first came here,
it was so different.
He was so different.
He was like you.
I'll give you what you want,
but you have to give me something.
- What?
- A kiss.
Excuse me?
I want you to kiss me
as if you were kissing her.
- Why?
- You love her. She loves you.
It's all over you both.
A long time ago,
I knew what that felt like.
I want to remember it.
I want to sample it. That's all.
Just a sample.
- Why don't you sample this instead?
- Trinity.
Such emotion over something so small.
It's just a kiss.
Why should we trust you?
If I don't deliver you to the Keymaker,
she can kill me.
All right.
But you have to make me believe
I am her.
All right.
Terrible. Forget it.
Wait.
Okay.
Yes.
That's it.
I envy you. But such a thing
is not meant to last.
Come with me.
Not again.
It's all right, boys. They're with me.
These fellas work for my husband.
They do his dirty work.
They're very good, very loyal.
Aren't you, boys?
MAN 1 & 2:
Yes, mistress.
They come from a much older version
of the Matrix.
But like so many back then, they caused
more problems than they solved.