(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(GUN COCKING)
(CALLS TO ATTENTION)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GRUNTING)
- Keep this sucker steady, Toll!
- I'm doing my best!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Here we go!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ARTILLERY FIRING)
Come on, you bastards!
Eat shit!
- Better duck!
- Oh, shit.
- (CHEERING)
- Yeah!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- (SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- (DISTANT GUNFIRE)
BARNEY: Cover up!
(WHOOPING)
Break!
- Watch your head, Insect!
- Shut up, Gunner!
(LAUGHING)
Gotta love it!
Hooah!
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
- BARNEY: Incoming chopper!
- (MACHINE GUN FIRING)
We gotta get this thing out of here!
You got any ideas?
- That's what I'm asking you!
- Well, I'm asking you.
(GUNSHOTS)
Clear!
(REVVING ENGINE)
(GRUNTING)
I got this.
Yeah!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Toll Road, get him up.
Trench?
Oh, this is embarrassing.
Yeah, it sure is.
CHRISTMAS: What's he doing here?
Saving this Chinese billionaire.
Oh, yeah? That's funny. So are we.
Well, then we have a scheduling problem,
don't we?
Cut me loose, Frankenstein.
BARNEY: Don't get nuts, Gunner.
Do it.
(GRUMBLES)
- Where's your team?
- Waiting.
I need a weapon. Something big.
- Yours.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
My big weapon's hangin' right where it is.
Is this it?
Yes, it's here.
BARNEY: Caesar! I need you in here.
Come on, Caesar. You got a backup.
If I don't get this back,
your ass is terminated.
In your dreams.
- Trench, we got a way out.
- Thanks. I got my own.
Let's get you out of here, pal.
Hey, look. I hate to break up the bromance.
We're 20 seconds late!
Get Moneybags up.
A "thank you" would be nice.
- I hate owing you.
- Well, you do, big boy.
Let's go, Yao.
- Did you win?
- Of course I win.
Let's go!
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
I'm out!
Now you put on your lucky ring?
One wet wall coming up.
I got your gang bang right here!
What?
(GROANS)
CHRISTMAS: I got your back!
Keep movin'!
TOLL: Here we go!
- Why always me?
- Are you hit?
Yeah, twice. (GROANS)
- Better you than me.
- That's nice. Nice.
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- You order room service?
- Not really. (SIGHING)
This is gonna be a piss-poor ending.
(CONTINUE SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
That loaded?
We can only hope.
(GUNSHOTS)
(GRUNTS)
Sorry, sir. I had to adjust for a wind shift.
No problem. Hit the last position.
Moving out. Over.
HALE: Let's go, go, go!
Yeah!
(GUNSHOTS)
Let's go! Come on!
BARNEY: Okay, hold on, ladies.
Cavalry's here.
HALE: it's about time you got here!
- Wake up Santa.
- On it.
Shit!
The guy is good. You're good.
BILLY: Appreciate it, sir.
BARNEY: (ON RADIO) We'll swing around
and pick you up, kid.
BILLY: I won't be late, sir.
(SCREAMING)
TOLL: Go!
All right, guys. Put your toys away.
Target in sight.
- Soup's hot!
- Fire!
- You missed.
- You're aiming!
Fire!
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
That was a statement. Hit it!
- Drop the skis!
- TOLL: Come on, get rid of this weight.
Climb, baby.
Climb, baby!
(INSTRUMENTS BEEPING)
Climb!
It ain't gettin' up!
Lucky ring.
(LAUGHING)
CHRISTMAS: We are approximately
20 miles out of Beijing.
BARNEY: Not that I wanna hear it,
what's the oil pressure?
- CHRISTMAS: Faulty.
- Oh, great. And the altimeter?
Would you believe?
It's stuck on 10,000 feet.
- Hydraulics?
- What hydraulics?
Congratulations.
You own another piece of junk now.
- Hey, can we talk when you're not too busy?
- Sure, anytime.
Kid's amazing.
Really. So am I. You're just used to me.
(CHUCKLING)
Get the client ready.
What is going on?
Looks like you're taking
a shortcut home, pal.
Parachute good?
Parachute? Why you got a parachute?
Can you believe they changed
our landing permit until tomorrow?
Yeah, but it's okay.
He'll get home a little earlier.
Fifteen seconds.
Opening the hatch!
Yang, get Moneybags home safely.
So when are you coming back?
Maybe soon, maybe never.
Maybe try a new life.
Then who am I supposed to pick on?
You will find another minority.
Yang.
Smile.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
See you later, alligator.
(SPEAKS MANDARIN)
(YELLING)
That's real Chinese takeout.
(CHUCKLING)
Floor it. I'm homesick.
You got it.
(CLASSIC ROCK SONG PLAYING)
LACY: Yes! I love this song!
Whoo!
Juliet. Two.
Christmas, my friend.
Please tell me you ain't
going through with this.
Of course I am. Look at that girl.
Who wouldn't marry her?
She cheated on you.
- It was a half-cheat.
- Which is?
The other side of a half-truth.
- The facts are murky.
- Murky.
I hate to break this to you, pal,
but your girlfriend over there
has a world-class cheating gene.
- I should stab you in the heart.
- Too late.
Hi, cheers.
You know, I used to think
you had a black heart.
Black is too colorful.
- Hey, babe.
- Hey.
- Hey, Barney.
- Hey, Lacy.
Promise next time not to keep
my baby away so long?
Cross my heart.
If he had one.
Look who's lost in space.
Got a pen?
CHRISTMAS: Hey.
You got anything
that doesn't have skulls on it?
Matter of fact, I don't.
Einstein's theory of special relativity.
Only I made it better.
- (BLOWS NOSE)
- (CHUCKLING)
Believe it or not, before Gunner
became chemically unbalanced,
he went to MIT, had a Master's degree
in chemical engineering.
This idiot actually had a brain,
you believe that?
Well, what happened?
He quit to be a bouncer.
I wanted to get close to this girl
who danced at this disco.
Yeah, I can't believe she dumped you.
- Wouldn't you?
- I would, yeah.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(LOUD ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
- Can we talk outside?
- Yeah, sure. Let's go.
How do I put this?
Just be straight up. Honest.
I feel, uh...
I'm not sure what I feel.
This life, it's not for you, is it?
I thought it was.
You gave me a chance to be one of you,
and you've got my respect forever.
And you've got my respect, too.
What are you gonna do?
Well, I'd like to finish out the month.
Then I wanna go meet up with my girlfriend.
Where's she from?
She's French.
Believe it or not, I met her in Afghanistan.
She was a nurse.
(CHUCKLING)
That comes in handy.
Yeah. And you'd like her.
You know, she's the kind of person
you wanna do things for.
That's why I took this job,
'cause the money's great.
Now I can afford to get her
everything she deserves.
It's one of those things that just feels right.
You know when you can be with someone
and you don't even have to talk.
You already know what they're thinking.
You ever had that?
Sure.
I don't want you to think that
I'm deserting you.
No, listen.
If I had to do it all over again at your age,
I'd be doing what you're doing.
Why don't you freshen up that beer?
All right.
(ENGINE REVVING)
MAN: Barney Ross.
What do you want from me, Church?
Not too good in the memory category,
are you, Barney?
You made a deal with me.
You gave me your word.
And you end up blowing up half of Vilena,
punching holes and a bowie knife
through a fellow CIA agent,
even if he was a dirtbag.
But what breaks my heart
is that you stole $5 million from me.
And for all this male pattern badness,
I could've put you in the deepest,
darkest hole in Gitmo.
No sunlight.
- But I kept you out.
- Great.
Because I knew the day would come
when you were gonna pay me back.
Today is that day.
Keep talking.
A Chinese plane got shot down
over the mountains
near a hell-hole called Gasak.
Yeah? Who shot it down?
Take a guess.
Onboard that plane is a safe carrying
something you don't need to know about.
All you need to know is
you can't let it fall into the wrong hands.
Now, you're gonna go in there,
and you're gonna get the contents
of that safe before anyone else.
You're gonna bring it to me.
It should be a walk in the park for you.
And then we're even.
We'll get to that.
The safe in that plane is very high-tech.
The access code changes
every 120 seconds.
You use the wrong code, it blows.
- So we need to get you in...
- Wait, wait.
"We." Who's we?
Who are you working with?
That's none of your business.
Let's just call our host The Corporation.
All right? I'm sending along a pro
who specializes in this type of situation.
Her name is Maggie Chang.
A woman.
That usually goes along
with the name Maggie, yeah.
Forget it.
She can handle herself.
But let me be clear.
If anything happens to her,
she gets a hangnail,
she gets hurt, she gets roughed up,
she doesn't come back in exactly
the same condition she went in,
you and your little gang of psychotic mutts
will never be seen again.
And that, I promise you.
I don't make a very good babysitter.
(CHUCKLING)
Don't sell yourself short.
You're gonna make a very good babysitter.
Be there at 7:00.
Hey. I'm Maggie Chang.
- You're Barney Ross?
- Yeah.
Mr. Church told you about me?
Said you wanna tag along?
Help, not tag along.
Nice motorcycle.
Where we're going is new.
We don't know what to expect.
Is it custom?
I think it's a mistake, you coming along.
Build it yourself?
Yeah, I built it myself.
Are you playing games with me, Maggie?
No. Are you playing games with me?
Church told me what you said.
I'm combat proficient.
I don't need a babysitter.
So, when do we leave?
0500.
Nice meeting you.
(REVVING ENGINE)
(SIXTIES MUSIC PLAYING)
(GUNNER CLEARS THROAT)
She's into me.
She hates you.
(EXHALES LOUDLY)
Watch this.
(GUNNER CLEARS THROAT)
(CONTINUES CLEARING THROAT)
(COUGHS)
Um...
(CHUCKLING)
You know, if something happens to her,
it's coming back on us.
Did you ever think to ask me
for my opinion?
I told you 10 times before, I didn't have a
choice, unless you don't mind going to jail.
Yeah, well, Church intimidated you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, is that the woman
you can never fully trust calling again?
You know, I will stab you one day.
Hey, baby.
Yeah, of course I'm thinking about you.
What else is there to think about?
(SCOFFING)
Hopeless.
Hey.
You were in the Army, right?
I can tell.
Yes, ma'am. Three years.
Last tour was Afghanistan, Kunar Province.
Didn't like it any more?
Uh... Long story.
- I would like to hear it.
- All right.
I was trained as a sniper,
and an instructor, too,
but I actually wanted to mix it up,
get in on the action.
Uh, this one time, we're stuck out
in this hell-hole valley.
About 30 Taliban opened up
from these houses in the hills above us.
And they got about eight of us
pinned down bad.
So I called in for artillery support.
But, "No way," says the captain.
Didn't wanna endanger the locals.
So we scattered. Some crawled to a ditch,
some to the dry riverbed and the rest bailed.
But we were still stuck in the kill zone.
And we battled for,
I don't know, three hours.
And finally, an Apache gunship chopper
showed up to provide air cover.
Scattered the Hadjis, but...
Smoke clears and four of my squad are dead
in the ditch and two in the riverbed.
Yeah, I was mad and sick,
all dead for nothin'.
You know the most screwed up thing of all
is when I got back to base that night,
I found out that they had shot
this stray dog that I adopted.
Commander's orders to get rid
of all animals on the base.
I mean, you'd think we had enough damn
shooting for one day, you know?
And, anyway,
I figured it was time to move on.
I heard these guys were looking
for someone, and here I am.
You got that transponder?
- Yes. Apparently, 15 kilometers northwest.
- Okay.
(CHRISTMAS' CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello, darlin'.
CHRISTMAS: Hello, darlin'.
I'm a little busy. Can I...
Let's move. We're in and out of here fast.
HALE: The sooner, the better.
- Billy the Kid.
- Yeah?
Today's your lucky day.
You get to take point.
My pleasure, sir.
Impressive.
Hold on.
Remember when you could do that?
No, do you?
I could blow him away if I needed to.
Really? Look down.
Look down. You see what I see?
Short legs.
1 ,000 bucks you can't catch him.
Go on, Flash.
I'm a little busy.
Are you?
BILLY: (ON RADIO) Found the wreck
at the bottom of the hill, sir.
Slow it down, Billy.
You're making us look bad.
- BILLY: Say it again, over?
- You heard.
- BILLY: Roger that. Slowing it down.
- (CHUCKLES) We appreciate it.
Rest of the plane's over the hill, sir.
Good work, Billy.
HALE: Looks like somebody had a bad day.
You guys go to the right.
(GROWLING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (WHIMPERING)
BARNEY: Take off, Rover.
All right, Billy.
You get a vantage point up there.
Ask him.
What you doing, Gunner?
I'm making a bomb. You mind?
- A maniac with brains.
- Scary.
Phosphate rock, it's got a density of 1 .852.
Melting point, 44.2 centigrade.
Guys, I want some gunpowder, fast.
Do it. The man's a chemical engineer, right?
And a Fulbright Scholar. Pour it in the pipe.
There's fur in their hands.
These guys were alive
- until the wolves got to them.
- (WOLF HOWLING)
Be careful.
(HOWLING GETTING LOUDER)
Is this it?
Yes, it's here.
BARNEY: Caesar! I need you in here.
Caesar, grab a hold of this thing.
I think it's spring-loaded.
Lee, hook it on.
Now, on the count of three, let's pull it back.
Ready?
One, two, three.
(GRUNTING)
- We can't hold this.
- You have to.
(MEN STRAINING)
(GROANING)
BARNEY: Come on, Maggie!
- Something's wrong.
- BARNEY: What?
The explosive timer's triggered.
- How long?
- Fifty-four seconds!
If we leave now, we'll make it.
- Maggie, let it go!
- No, I can do it!
- BARNEY: Come on, Maggie!
- (GRUNTING)
Maggie, what's going on?
She tripped the detonator. Stay back!
I'm losing my grip!
You do, she's cut in half.
- Come on, Maggie!
- Got it!
(ALL PANTING)
Yeah, lucky I was here.
Just thinking that.
I'm sorry. It's important I get this.
You've got guts. No common sense.
But guts. Come on.
It's all right. We got it. Let's go.
You're strong.
Billy, come on down. We're out of here.
GUNNER: What happened?
HALE: That woman is crazy,
but I got a good pump.
CHRISTMAS: Aren't you curious
about what's inside the case?
No, I just wanna get Church off our back.
Billy the Kid!
Where the hell is he? Billy!
(GUNS COCKING)
VILAIN: Drop your weapons!
TOLL: No way.
It ain't happening.
No?
Are you sure?
I'm sorry, sir. They were waitin'.
- Drop the weapons now.
- Don't do it.
(COCKING GUN)
He's a strong soldier.
Let's see how strong he is.
Do it.
- No!
- Oh.
(MUFFLED GROAN)
Don't do nothin' he says!
(GROANS)
Don't talk.
You should not speak.
I'm gonna kill him.
When I fire, his head will be gone.
Three seconds.
Don't give your weapons.
You don't owe me anything!
VILAIN: One.
Two.
Don't do this! They'll kill everyone!
He's gonna kill him.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Drop them!
(GROANING)
I'm impressed.
Very good use of intelligence.
Everybody stay calm, we'll be done soon
and then we'll be on our way.
Bring me that knife.
What's this symbol?
I like symbol.
This is the symbol of the goat.
The pet of Satan,
they say.
- You have a case that belongs to me.
- Does it?
Yes, like your lives.
It was lost. He doesn't have it.
Last time, the case, or you will force me
to cut
his heart out.
Do it, you piece of shit.
Wait!
(GROANS)
Let me have it.
Hey.
You talking to me?
Pick it up.
- Hand it to me.
- Go get it yourself.
- What was that?
- You heard.
Now pick it up,
hand it to me nicely,
or you'll get what he got.
Do it, Lee.
You'll be all right, Billy.
Respect is everything.
Without respect, we're just people.
Common, shitty people.
I'm sorry, sir.
It's not your fault.
Now what?
We're both fighting men.
And I respect that.
And fighting men,
they don't deserve to be killed like sheep.
But
respect
must be taught.
Lie down with your face
on the ground until we leave.
Don't challenge me.
Get down.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
Up.
Are you afraid of me?
No. I'm not.
You should be.
- I'm dying.
- Don't talk, Billy.
Cut his hands loose!
The letter.
I'm so sorry.
BARNEY: I believe you.
What was in the case?
A computer. Blueprint of a mine.
A mine. What mine?
The Russians stored nearly 5 tons
of weapons-grade plutonium.
The mine was abandoned after the Cold War.
No one knows it's there.
The blueprint shows
where the plutonium is stored.
We want to stop it
before it gets in the wrong hands.
I guess that didn't happen, did it?
This kid died so some dirtbag
can make bombs.
I'm so sorry.
Not as sorry as I am.
Let's take care of him.
"Dear Sophia.
"I wish I could find something different
to do besides just missing you,
"but I can't.
"The team's treating me good.
We got each other's backs.
"I want you to know that wherever I end up,
I'll be wanting the very best for you.
"And if some miracle happens,
and I come back again,
"I hope I'm still your man. Much love, Billy."
Why is it that
the one of us who wants to live the most,
who deserves to live the most, dies?
And the ones that deserve to die,
keep on living?
What's the message in that?
What's the plan?
Track him, find him, kill him.
RADIO DISPATCHER: CZ-1492, come on.
Requesting a response immediately.
Who's this bozo?
RADIO DISPATCHER: CZ-1492, this is
a secure air wave. Do you read?
What's this about?
MR. CHURCH: What's taking so long,
Barney Ross?
This should have been a walk in the park
for you guys. Where's the case?
Don't have it.
I warned you what would happen
to you mutts if you pulled this shit again.
A good man died trying to get that case.
- I'm sorry about that.
- BARNEY: Are you?
Yes, as a matter of fact, I am.
But this sort of situation comes
with the territory, wouldn't you say?
And so does payback.
You know, Church, you're the kind of guy
that pulls the strings,
and everyone else does your dirty work
'cause you never had the guts
to do it yourself.
We're done.
(RADIO CUTS OUT)
Sir, we got a problem.
The digging has slowed down.
Too many are dying.
They're exhausted.
(MEN COUGHING)
He's tired.
Anybody else tired?
Get more workers.
We've already taken most
of the men from the villages.
Get all the rest.
Women, children, all of them.
Show me.
Now we know where it is. Right. Right.
Okay. I know what to do.
Good, I want the plutonium out
in three days.
Three days?
I have people ready
to pay four million a kilo now.
Three days.
No more.
Understood.
You're smart.
Imagine if 6 pounds of pure plutonium
is powerful enough to change
the balance of the world.
So, imagine what 5 tons would do.
It's very interesting. Yeah?
- Something's happening.
- What?
The transmission stopped.
They're underground.
Putting it down right here.
BARNEY: Come on, let's hustle, hustle.
We gotta move.
Christmas. Come on, Lee. Do you
even know what the hell you're doing?
Five minutes.
- Don't get your knickers in a twist.
- BARNEY: Right.
BARNEY: Another transport truck.
Could be one of theirs.
Let's check this place out.
- (COCKING GUN)
- No shootin'.
- Classics?
- Yeah.
I've been dying to use these.
We'll beat the truth out of them.
Maggie, you tell the guys
to wait in the truck.
Okay.
- (LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
- (PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
- They're here.
- Yeah.
Speak English?
- He's slightly gigantic.
- So?
Just sayin'.
- He's really gigantic.
- I said that.
(SPEAKING BULGARIAN)
Hey!
- (GRUNTS)
- (WOMEN GASP)
Can't beat a classic.
I say we beat some info out of
these guys and get moving.
Sounds good to me.
Let's start with the midget.
MAGGIE: Calm down, boys.
I can get them to talk with much less effort.
What's she gonna do, give him a pedicure?
(MAN GROANING)
It's a little sick.
Christmas, I need you to hotwire that truck
and go back to the plane
and get the weapons.
Why don't you get
one of those cheese-heads to do it?
Stop complaining.
CHRISTMAS: I should've bounced
one of these over your skull.
- GUNNER: How'd it go?
- We're on. Let's move.
TOLL: Cheese-heads.
They call themselves Sangs.
They say they control
everything east of the mountains.
Robbery, kidnapping, assassinations.
Basically, a cartel for hire.
How do you know the language?
Easy. Put it together.
It's a cross between
Ukraine and Bulgarian dialect.
Impressed?
A little.
Christmas.
- What?
- BARNEY: Why are you yellin'?
'Cause you gave me the shit job, that's why.
I'm gonna shoot you in the face
when I see ya.
BARNEY: Where are you?
The 60-year-old death trap you call a plane.
Well, what's taking so long?
Because there's bridges out, signs missing.
I've been driving these dirt roads
for the last seven hours!
You done complainin'?
Thanks for the sympathy.
This is weird.
Just like home.
That figures.
What the hell is this place?
MAGGIE: I believe
it's an old Soviet Army base.
Probably used in the '80s. Cold War.
They most likely staged maneuvers
and practice attacks against the U.S. here.
Is there anything you don't know?
HALE: Great. Just what I need.
50-year-old pizza.
We'll bed down here for the night.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh.
This tastes like shit.
How's yours?
Can't complain about rigatoni.
Plan ahead, fellas.
That's all I have to say.
Y'all, what if you knew
you were gonna die tomorrow?
What would your last meal be?
- One choice.
- One choice?
It'd probably be cereal for you, huh?
And what the hell's wrong with cereal?
It's cliché.
HALE: You gotta be original. You know,
if you were an original, broad-thinking man,
you'd probably come up
with some special cereal, like Earios.
You know, just like your ear.
You know, pour milk on them suckers,
they just lay there and you don't hear shit.
For the record, my hearing is 20/20.
Barney?
Donuts and most food that kills ya.
That's deep, man.
(CHUCKLING) You think so?
Maggie?
Crispy aromatic duck with plum sauce.
Very sexy.
But I like Italian, too.
I'm starting to think Italian's overrated.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hey. What about me?
My favorite Swedish dinner would be
baby seal and whale ass
in the summer.
But I'd really die for some Chinese.
Then you're gonna starve to death.
(ALL LAUGHING)
All right, sweet dreams.
Hey, Barney. I'm not done eatin', man.
Can I ask you something?
Sure, go ahead.
Why are you so nervous around me?
I don't get nervous, Maggie.
What is it then?
I just like keeping a distance.
Is it because you don't want
to know any more people?
Let's just say bad things have happened
to people I've gotten close to.
Not a good way to live.
I know.
Do you think about
the young man who died?
All the time.
You don't talk about him much.
No, that's how we deal with death.
We can't change what it is,
so we keep it light until it's time to get dark.
And then we get pitch black.
Understand?
I understand.
Good night.
Good night, Maggie.
(UPBEAT MOTOWN PLAYING)
(GUNNER SNORING LOUDLY)
I swear to God, if he doesn't stop snoring,
I'm gonna shoot him.
Gunner!
(CHOKES MID-SNORE)
You rang?
I know it's a stupid question.
I don't suppose you have
any more of that coffee.
Pot only makes one cup.
Yeah. That's what I figured.
BARNEY: Listen up.
Those guys said the congregation of Sangs
are probably in this area,
concentrated east.
So that's where we're going.
We're out of here in 10 minutes.
Get ready. Do what you gotta do.
(SIGHS)
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Houston, we got a problem.
- Down!
- (GUNFIRE)
(LIVELY MOTOWN PLAYING LOUDLY)
We gotta get out of here!
- Go!
- HALE: Go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go!
Go.
Save your ammo.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Where the hell are you?
I'm almost there.
Hey, what's going on? Are those shots?
Yeah.
- CHRISTMAS: What's happening?
- The Sangs got us pinned down.
- Can you hold them off?
- Yeah, maybe with a tank.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
They got a tank.
Come on. Come on! Come on!
Oh!
Let's roll! Come on!
I'm out.
One left. Why not?
Hey, who did that?
Not me, I'm out.
Hey, what just happened?
Somebody got a little carried away.
It looks that way.
Where are the shooters?
I don't know, but if they wanted us dead,
we'd be dead.
Barney?
(WESTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
Don't freak out.
Small world, huh, Barney?
Booker? Rumor had it you were dead.
Yeah, I heard that, too.
So, how's life treating ya?
Been better.
You did all this?
I fly solo. I thought you knew that.
Yeah, I heard it, but I didn't buy it.
Well, now you do.
This your team?
Yeah. Gunner, Toll Road,
Hale Caesar and Maggie.
Booker. You're the one
people call the Lone Wolf?
I've been called that. But I have mellowed.
Not that much.
I heard another rumor,
that you were bitten by a king cobra?
Yeah, I was.
But after five days of agonizing pain,
the cobra died.
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, Booker. Great to see you, man.
BOOKER: So, how'd you end up
in this godforsaken place?
We got ambushed by Sangs
about 100 kilometers east of here,
killed one of my men, young kid.
- Yeah, sorry to hear that.
- Yeah.
The Sangs are the lowest form of scum.
Shooting them has been a good business.
Do you know who the leader is?
- Yeah, a guy named Vilain.
- Vilain.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah, he pretty much controls
everything in this area.
You're gonna need more men
if you expect to get out alive.
Can you help out?
Ah, sorry, Barney. I work alone.
I understand. Thanks for showing up.
My pleasure.
Hey, Barney!
There's a village down the road.
They're good people,
and they hate the Sangs.
- Maybe they can help out.
- Thanks.
Happy hunting.
What happened?
I'm still alive.
That's a matter of opinion. What'd I miss?
I'll tell you about it on the way.
Come on, guys. Unload these weapons.
Looks like Christmas
came way late this year.
Yeah, I love you, too.
Well, I'm happy to see you.
Finally. Somebody with class.
(SIXTIES MUSIC PLAYING)
This has gotta be the town
that Booker was talking about.
I could retire to a place like this.
Clean air, no stress, raise some kids.
You know, Maggie,
I could retire to a place like this.
(LAUGHING)
You are so full of shit.
(GUNSHOTS)
BARNEY: Out, out, out!
They're missing us by a mile.
- PILAR: Put down guns.
- That's not happening.
- (GUNSHOT)
- Whoa!
The safest place is in front of their gun.
- (LAUGHING)
- We will shoot you!
No! Wait.
These guys are here to help.
They want to help.
Even you two rejects
could get lucky around here.
- You think?
- I doubt it.
Do you mind?
Who you are?
- We're Americans.
- Since when?
Swedish.
- Blackfoot.
- Chinese.
- Retards.
- You done?
What do you want?
We're here to take care of the Sangs.
Okay. Come inside.
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
This is who we think you'd come for.
This is who we will die for.
First, they told us there'd be
good jobs, good money.
Some went. But nobody come back.
They come for more.
They say as soon as our men go to job,
the others come home.
My husband goes.
For a long time, we hear nothing.
Then the Sangs come, and they take
all of the rest of the men.
Forced them to work in the mines.
Same in the next village. And the next.
They take my sons.
Now all that is left are the very young.
And they will be back for them, too.
I know this.
We all know this.
So we hide them and we wait.
Why don't you just move on? Leave.
PILAR: This is our home.
Our lives will be the last thing they take.
Tell us why you're here now.
We're tracking them.
Can't you stay and help?
You saw the children!
Soon they'll be done,
and they'll kill them all.
We have our own business with them.
I'm sorry. Let's go.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
I don't think
they're gonna last here much longer.
I think they know that.
So we're not gonna do anything about it?
(SIGHING)
I got an idea.
And with your ego,
I think you're gonna love it.
- My ego?
- Your ego.
- What do you mean, my ego?
- You've got a big ego.
Well, check your ego out.
Oh, please. Your ego is like
the size of a dinosaur. Huge.
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
We have it. We found the plutonium.
(VILLAGERS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(TRUCK APPROACHING)
(VILLAGERS SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(BELL RINGING)
(MEN SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
(PRAYING SOFTLY)
(SPEAKING BULGARIAN)
CHRISTMAS: By the power vested in me,
I now pronounce you
man and knife.
(MEN GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(MEN GROANING)
(GROANING)
One more!
Rest in pieces.
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
- This is the last one?
- Da.
Good.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
The chambers are cleared.
No loose ends. You bury them all.
BARNEY: I see about a dozen guards,
light weapons,
a couple of badass .50 cals.
CHRISTMAS: Worse.
Anti-tank devices.
There's no way our trucks will
get through that mine field.
Look, I know this is a stupid question,
but you got any ideas
that won't get us killed?
I got a few I'm thinking about.
(PLANE APPROACHING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
- Boom time?
- Boom time.
BARNEY: Target in sight!
- Baby wants to travel!
- BARNEY: Fire!
- Rock and roll!
- Fire!
Bombs away!
(GUARD SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Tighten up!
- What's happening now?
- Chaos!
- You're not doing what I think you're doing.
- Yeah, I am.
Let's do it!
Come on, let's move!
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You're gonna need a new plane.
(GUNS COCKING)
(SPEAKING BULGARIAN)
(BARNEY WHISTLES)
- We're too late!
- What?
The plutonium's gone.
(MUFFLED EXPLOSIONS)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Come on, come on, let's get out of here!
Move, move! Come on!
- (CLAMORING)
- Go, go, go!
Move it, move it, move it!
CHRISTMAS: Go, go, go!
Go on, get out of here!
Go, go, go, go!
Pick it up! Pick it up!
(PEOPLE COUGHING)
We're gonna be here awhile.
Oh, this is embarrassing.
Yeah, it sure is.
CHRISTMAS: What's he doing here?
Saving this Chinese billionaire.
Oh, yeah? That's funny. So are we.
Well, then we have a scheduling problem,
don't we?
Cut me loose, Frankenstein.
BARNEY: Don't get nuts, Gunner.
Do it.
(GRUMBLES)
- Where's your team?
- Waiting.
I need a weapon. Something big.
- Yours.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
My big weapon's hangin' right where it is.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
Doesn't seem right.
Going out this chickenshit way?
Something like that.
Hey, it ain't over yet, kids.
I got a plan.
Everybody calm down.
Phosphate rock.
What's he doing?
Probably making a bomb.
You serious?
Not that much.
I heard another rumor,
that you were bitten by a king cobra?
Yeah, I was.
But after five days of agonizing pain,
the cobra died.
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, Booker. Great to see you, man.
Ask him.
What you doing, Gunner?
I'm making a bomb. You mind?
- A maniac with brains.
- Scary.
Phosphate rock, it's got a density of 1 .852.
Melting point, 44.2 centigrade.
Guys, I want some gunpowder, fast.
Do it. The man's a chemical engineer, right?
And a Fulbright Scholar. Pour it in the pipe.
- The big man might be onto something.
- You think?
Probably not.
You need some help with that? Let's go!
Here. Go blow yourself up.
Lighter?
I want that back.
Better get back! This is gonna be loud!
(GUNNER LAUGHING)
Get back!
Okay.
All right, let's go!
All right.
Better turn around
unless you want your heads blown off.
You better cover your ear.
Come on.
Well, the phosphorus must have been damp.
Yeah, right.
TOLL: Or you suck.
HALE: There's that.
Don't cry, Gunner.
BARNEY: You almost had an idea.
(RUMBLING)
(ROTORS POWERING DOWN)
I'm back.
How're you doin', Trench?
(ALL CLAMORING EXCITEDLY)
- Oh, I thank you. I thank you.
- You're welcome.
Bojan!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(LAUGHING AND WEEPING)
Hmm.
- We're even now, right?
- Right.
I'll be seeing you around, Trench.
Thanks a lot.
- Relax. It's not over yet.
- What?
That's right.
(CHUCKLING)
- How ya doin', pal?
- I was doing pretty good, Church.
What are you doing here?
- I heard there was a party in town.
- Yeah, but it's my party.
- Has he always been this selfish?
- Always.
Thanks.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
You wanna kick Vilain's ass or not?
Don't forget the Little Rascals!
Move it.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Move out!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Take the rest of the nukes to the hangar.
Now!
And get the plutonium on the plane.
Follow me.
We need to buy some time.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GUNSHOTS)
Go, go!
(GUNSHOT)
(WESTERN MUSIC PLAYS)
I'm out!
VILAIN: Hold them up!
Go! Go! Move!
Shit!
- Fun, huh?
- Yeah.
Oh, there he is!
Come on, Vilain.
- Let's go!
- Yeah.
Tear him apart!
(SCREAMING)
I'm almost out. I'll be back.
You've been back enough. I'll be back.
Yippee-ki-yay.
Who's next? Rambo?
Goodbye.
(SCREAMING)
Let's go.
(YELLING)
GUNNER: Maggots!
VILAIN: Start the engine!
Get that thing in the air.
I want to make some money!
HECTOR: Move!
Trench! Get in!
My shoe is bigger than this car.
Shoot something!
(TRENCH FIRING GUN)
MR. CHURCH: Come on.
(ALARM BEEPING)
Start the helicopter.
We have a special guest coming.
Let's go!
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(MEN SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Take care of him!
This way!
(PROPELLER BUZZING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Cannot beat a classic.
(COCKING GUN)
- Barney!
- What are you doing here?
I'm going in there alone.
Don't follow me, no matter what,
do you understand?
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
That door opens up, and I don't come out,
and he does, you kill him.
VILAIN: Let's make it more dramatic.
Now, that's better.
(GUNSHOTS)
I'm out of bullets.
That's your problem.
VILAIN: Not really.
You wanna kill me like a man?
Or you wanna kill me
like a sheep?
Nice knife.
So.
What's it going to be?
Man or sheep?
You wanna man up?
I'll man you up.
(GASPS MOCKINGLY)
You must want to hurt me bad.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm gonna take your life.
Come.
(GRUNTS)
Over so soon?
I want my money's worth.
- Come on, get up!
- Coming right up.
Going back down.
Taste good?
Talking to me?
(CHOKING)
Time to wrap this up.
(BARNEY GROANING)
Ironic. Here we are, you and I.
And your knife.
You're going to die. Like him.
What was his name?
What did you call him?
What does it matter?
Come on, Vilain.
Somebody's dying.
Come on!
(GROANS)
Get up, Vilain.
Get up.
Now turn around.
Turn around, sheep.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Now what?
(YELLING)
His name was Billy.
(GROANS)
You know how to carve a turkey?
(SIRENS WAILING)
- You win?
- I think so.
Well, where's the proof?
Heads up.
Nice touch.
Mmm-hmm.
It is a nice touch.
A little extreme. But nice.
Mmm-hmm.
And as much as I hate to say this,
Bamm-Bamm,
now that we got control of the plutonium,
that makes us even.
Good.
So, Maggie, you'll be coming with us then?
When you're ready.
So I just want...
Wow.
They're okay, just a little immature.
I don't have to go.
If you want me to stay, I'll stay.
And I did save the babysitter's life.
That you did do.
Maybe I'm good luck for you.
But I could be bad luck for you,
and I can't allow that.
If you ever want help, call me,
or you're dead.
I'll do that.
What are you doing here?
Moving on. You killed all my business.
I thought you were the Lone Wolf.
(CHUCKLING SOFTLY)
Sometimes it's fun to run with the pack.
Sure, you got a point.
You take care, Maggie.
Oh, I almost forgot.
As a token of my gratitude,
my violent friend,
I got you and the Little Rascals a ride home.
- Behold.
- What?
Consider it a gift.
- That thing belongs in a museum.
- (CHUCKLING)
- We all do.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Hey, fun, right?
- Yeah, fun.
Take care.
(ALL CHANTING) Beware, beware,
walk with care.
Careful what you do.
Or Mumbo-Jumbo's gonna hoo-doo you.
Mumbo-Jumbo's gonna hoo-doo you.
Boomlay, boomlay, boomlay, boom!
To Billy!
- To Billy.
- ALL: To Billy.
GUNNER: Rest in peace.
- Man, I need a massage.
- Don't look at me.
- Hey.
- What?
- From one friend to another?
You really should learn how to fight.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)