[Oars Splashing]
[Panting]
[Panting Continues]
[Horn Blowing]
[Horn Continues]
[Train Approaches]
- [Stereo: Loud Rock]
- [Woman] Roarke!
- [Screaming]
- Roarke!
I'm tellin' you for the 157th time,
turn that music off!
It's singeing my hair!
You got to find your sneakers, buddy.
- [Screams]
- Your old ones!
Hey! See if you can
find Dad's sneakers!
Dad? Come on, Mom.
- [Stops]
- Why bother?
He's just gonna cancel.
- Dad always cancels.
- Somethin' came up those other times.
I have a stomachache
in my mouth.
- Oh, God.
- You do?
Here we go. She pretends she's sick
so we don't leave her.
Oh, stop.
It's just for a few days.
With those notorious psychos,
your grandparents!
[Children Shouting, Door Opens]
[Laughing]
Oh. Whoop, whoop, whoop.
I almost got you packed.
Hi. I just can't find...
your old sneakers.
Um, can I talk to you
for a second?
Oh, you're not gonna do this,
not three years in a row.
Roarke, you take your sister
in the other room.
- Come on, Willa.
- And shut the door.
- Don't make this harder than it is.
- What are we to you, Tom?
Are we just some gaggle of obligations
pulling on you, making you tired?
Gail, Selvaggio didn't like my drawings.
They just weren't good enough.
- They're giving the project to Parker.
- So let Parker do it.
Fine, so let Parker do it.
Maggie, get off the quilt.
Maggie!
Get off the quilt!
Maggie, get down.
Good girl.
Gail, how did this
become such a big deal?
Oh, it's not as big as
the Selvaggio deal, clearly.
But it is your son's
birthday again...
and he thinks you don't
want to spend time with him.
You understand that part?
I do not treat you
like a baby.
I treat you like a slob.
There's a difference. Oh!
[Laughing]
- Hi, Mom.
- Ohh.
Oh, look at you.
It's so good to see you.
- Hey!
- It's good to see you too, Grandpa.
You have to sign, buddy.
Hey! Oh, boy.
Oh, yeah.
- You look good.
- Where's Tom?
- Well...
- He didn't want to come.
No, no. He's working.
He's really busy right now.
- Mags!
- [Barking]
Maggie!
[Sighs]
I think my marriage is over, Mama.
Oh, Bean.
Damn.
Well, he, uh...
just can't seem to make
time for us anymore.
He's let himself get
so beaten up by his job.
He hates it, but he spends
every waking minute over there.
He hasn't been home
one weekend since Christmas.
I don't know what it is
that he's trying to prove...
but I'm really sick
of the whole thing.
I'm sick of the whole fight.
Everything has become
unbelievably hard.
Huh. Honey, forgive me,
but you don't know what hard is.
That's because
you give yourself an out.
In our generation,
we had no out.
That was the pact
of marriage.
Do you think
if I gave myself an out...
with your father, given his
orneriness and his deafness...
that I wouldn't
have taken it years ago?
Mom.
Here, let me take that one.
- Roarke.
- Yeah.
- Go buy me a map and get the tags.
- Okay.
The ranger said I had to get tags.
I thought this was all I needed.
This just confirms
your reservation.
There you go.
Here's your three tags.
If a ranger asks,
show them to him.
- Can I buy those two first-aid kits?
- Sure. Make it 50 bucks even.
Some of the Band-Aids are missing.
- Guy tore his ear up on a fishhook.
- Ouch.
Thank you very much.
Here.
And could I have a map?
I wish you were too, Pop.
Remember the trip down
the Snake River when I was twelve?
That was the greatest.
Thanks.
[Grunting]
Whoa, there, partner.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I just got
to get new feet.
Until you do,
you better slow on down.
- You went to that concert?
- What?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
- Great show.
- So you saw Jane's Addiction.
Wish I could've seen them
before they broke up.
- Uh-huh.
- So, you goin' down the river alone?
No. Me and a couple
of my buddies.
- Who are you goin' with?
- My mom.
Oh, yeah?
This is a pretty tough river.
She used to be a guide here.
She wants me to go down the river
before it gets polluted.
What about your daddy?
He had to stay home and
do one of his stupid drawings.
Too bad.
- [Air Pumping]
- Is that your mom?
Yeah.
I'm Wade.
What's your name?
- Roarke.
- Good to meet you, Roarke.
Mom! Mom!
This is Wade.
- He's goin' down the river too.
- Hi, Wade. I'm Gail.
Great idea, showing Roarke the river
before they ruin it.
[Chuckles]
Wade!
- Come on! We gotta go!
- Be right there.
He tells me you used
to be a guide here.
Oh! About 150 years ago.
You must know the river
pretty well, then.
- Well, I used to.
- How far you going?
End of the line, Bridal Creek.
Oh, yeah? Us too.
- Oh, great.
- Come on, Wade! We're dyin' here!
[Chuckles]
I wish I were going with you guys.
[Laughing]
Well.
Here you go, Roarke.
Keep the sun
out of your eyes.
Wow! No way!
- What do you say, Roarke?
- Oh, yeah. Thanks.
Well, uh, see you
on the river, I guess.
I don't know.
We're gonna be goin' fast.
- [Man] Let's go, Wade!
- I'm comin'. I'm comin'.
[Man #1]
I said the right oar!
- [Man #2] Okay, the right one!
- Yeah! Take it!
Get off my damn foot!
[Gail] lt'll be a long haul
with him at the oars.
Guy in back
knows what he's doing.
Frank used to be
a guide on the Colorado.
- Push with both oars!
- [Roarke] It's Dad!
[Willa]
Daddy!
Is this where you sign up
for river rafting lessons?
I got a dry jacket
and a pair of reef walkers.
The guy at the camping store
said that's all I'll need.
[Laughs]
What happened to Mr. Selvaggio?
I brought him with me.
Let's go boys.
One... two... three.
Let's do it!
Jump on!
- [Willa] Bye-bye, Mommy!
- See you at Bridal Creek!
Whoa!
[Chuckling]
Whoa! That's it!
I love you too!
Roarke.
Roarke!
It's beautiful.
- Yeah.
- Really.
[Sighs]
Okay, sweetie,
put your helmet on, please.
Mom.
You don't have to wear it all the time,
but we got some rapids comin' up here.
- Just give me a hand, damn it!
- It's coming up!
You all right?
[Gail]
If you're gonna sit there in the back...
you should sit on
the floor in the center.
- I can't see from there.
- Well, then, sit in front.
I like it here.
Okay.
[Roarke]
Here we go!
Woo-hoo! Heh!
[Laughing]
Wow, this is great!
[Shouting]
[Roarke]
Yes! Hold on, Maggie!
[Roarke Whooping]
Look out for that rock!
Ohh!
- [Laughing]
- Whoa!
That was great!
But where's Dad?
[Laughing]
He's swimming.
- [Gail] Point your feet down!
- Point your toes, Dad!
Could you just stop laughing
for a second and help me into the boat?
- [Laughing Stops]
- [Moaning]
- Ohh!
- Oh!
[Moaning]
Is this the biggest one, Mom?
The biggest one's
the Gauntlet.
That's a five-plus.
That's off the scale.
- When do we do that one?
- Well, we don't do that one.
That's after the take-out
at Bridal Creek.
- You can't go down there.
- Have you ever done it?
- Mom is saying it's too dangerous.
- For you, maybe.
Roarke. Honey,
I went down the Gauntlet...
when I was 18 years old
with two other guides...
experienced guides.
And we were just lucky.
But there were two other people
that summer who did not get so lucky.
One guy got killed,
and the other one is paralyzed for life.
Don't worry. We're gonna hit
some threes and some four-pluses...
and we will risk death
a number of times on this trip.
So you're gonna scream,
you're gonna be so happy.
- Hey, look, Mom, there's Wade!
- [Gail] Hello, the shore!
- [Wade] Hello, the boat!
- Is everybody okay?
- Yeah, I just got a cramp!
- We're trying to work it out.
Hey, who's your friend, Gail?
Oh, this is Tom,
uh, Roarke's father.
Oh, no. You didn't tell him
about us, did you?
[Laughing] No.
Hey, Roarke!
Don't tell those fish we're comin'!
[Gail] All right,
let's bring a little line in, okay?
We're gonna aim for that ripple
right over there. See?
Ten, two, ten, two...
ten, release!
Then let go of your line.
Why don't you ask your dad
if he wants to come over?
Hey, Dad, you wanna try this?
Not now!
Thanks, buddy!
[Roarke] Do you think
he even knows he left Boston?
Yeah, he knows.
But he took two planes
and a charter just to get here, so...
let's give him a break.
- Try it again.
- Why are you suddenly on his side?
I'm on everybody's side.
I'm the mother.
- [Gasps] You got it! That's it!
- Look, Mom!
You got a nice one, buddy.
He's a beauty.
Let's get him.
There he is.
Come here.
Come here, sweetheart.
Look, Daddy.
Oh, it's a monster.
You know,
this is the first time...
we've all had dinner together
since Mom's birthday.
Hello, the Gail, Roarke
and Tom family!
This is the Wade raft
passing you by!
Hey, Wade!
I caught two fish today!
First time I ever fished!
Must be that lucky hat!
Hey, Roarke, if that hat's so lucky,
I want it back!
Hi.
- He's down.
- Mm-hmm.
- [Sighs]
- Well, had a big day.
It's kind of warm.
That's the way I like it.
Did you finish
your sketches yet?
No. No, I didn't.
And it's not a sketch, Gail.
- You know, it's very important.
- Very important, I know.
- So, tomorrow...
- What?
Could you just pretend
to like it here a little bit?
For Roarke's sake,
if not for mine.
I don't do too bad at pretending
to like your stuff, so...
Is that what you do?
Pretend to like my stuff?
- No. You know, that's not what I mean.
- You don't have to.
And just don't.
And don't do me any favors, either.
I don't.
I won't.
Gail.
- Listen, don't you ever realize...
- Let's just stop, okay?
You never...
Oh, please!
[Gail Laughing]
[Screaming]
- [Laughing]
- [Roarke] Whoa, it's cold!
Whoo!
[Maggie Barking]
[Roarke Whooping]
Wow!
Hey, look, Mom!
Graffiti!
Oh, wow!
Those are pictographs.
They were made by people...
who lived here thousands of years
before white men came.
So those are their hands?
Those markings might've been
made by a boy your age...
while he was
on his vision quest.
See?
Are you sure there's
fish around here, Mom?
Over there, honey.
Right in the current.
- [Maggie Whimpers]
- Hey there!
We've been waitin' for you.
I should've suspected something
when he had us camp at the walk-out.
Frank and Terry'd been
arguing most of the day.
Frank used to be married
to my sister...
until she realized
what a butthole he was.
Anyway, Frank said things
he shouldn't have said.
And this morning,
we woke up and he was gone.
Why didn't you guys just follow him out,
walk out with him?
That would have been
the smart thing to do...
but I didn't want
to give him the satisfaction.
And what he was doin' with the oars
didn't look that hard...
so we just headed downriver...
and we saw this.
That's when we decided
to wait for you guys.
- Wade said you used to be a guide here.
- Yeah. Roarke, come over here.
Is there any way
we could walk out of here...
- like go up the canyon and...
- Uh, well, you might...
but once you got up
to that canyon rim...
and headed back to the ranger station,
there's a huge gorge.
You'd have to walk around it.
Even if you had the equipment
and knew what you were doing...
and where you were going,
it'd take you five or six days.
Looks like we're stuck.
Well, we...
- I could get you as far as Bridal Creek.
- Yeah.
We... wouldn't want
to be a burden.
Well...
it doesn't look
like you have much choice.
All right.
[Gail]
Anyway, it's not as bad as it looks.
- You just got to stay to the right.
- Maggie!
There's a bad hole on the left.
Don't hit that.
No.
[Roarke]
Come on, Mags! Time to go!
Honey, would you go up
and get her?
Stay to the right, and if you
do go swimming, which you won't...
point your feet downstream
and hold on to your jacket.
Just let
the current take you.
Don't command the river.
Let the river command you.
Hey, I don't live my life like that,
and I don't think you do, either.
[Chuckling]
Maggie!
Maggie! Come!
[Whistles]
Come on, girl!
- [Maggie Barking]
- Maggie!
- [Whimpering, Digging]
- Maggie, come.
What do you got there, girl?
- [Digging, Whimpering Continue]
- You all right, girl?
[Roarke]
Maggie, come!
- [Barking]
- Come, Maggie!
[Barking]
Dogs.
Yeah.
- Buckle your life jacket. Stay right.
- [Wade] All right.
- Just relax.
- Relax, huh?
Yeah. Relax.
- I want you to be the best you can be.
- Best I can be.
Let me get down there first.
I'll be waitin' for ya.
All right!
Come on, Maggie! Here we go!
Tom, better put the map away.
We're gonna go through
our first whoop-dee-doos.
- You might want to take a secure seat.
- What?
- Here we go!
- Hold on, Roarke!
[Roarke Shouting, Whooping]
[Roarke Laughing, Shouting]
[Groaning]
Here we go!
[Whooping]
[Roarke Laughing, Shouting]
[Shouting]
[Shouting, Laughing Continue]
- Oh, great!
- Oh, boy.
[Roarke Shouting]
All right.
Here we go.
She said stay on the right,
remember?
- You remember, right?
- Oh, man.
[Wade]
She wasn't playing around.
Whoo!
Go right!
Get us over, Wade!
Oh, shit!
Oh, my God.
- The right, Wade! To the right!
- Shut up!
Oh, my God!
They're on the wrong side!
Get over!
You gotta turn!
[Terry Shouts]
There's a rock here!
Wade!
[Screaming]
Get in the front!
We're gonna pick 'em up!
[Gasping]
Wade's lost his jacket!
Wade can't swim!
He's back there! He can't swim!
Pull him in!
Get in the back.
We're goin' to him!
[Tom]
There he is!
[Terry]
Wade! Hold on, buddy!
[Roarke]
Wade!
[Tom]
He went under!
Wade!
[Roarke]
Where is he?
He's still under!
- Get the throw bag, Roarke!
- Hold on, Wade!
[Terry]
Right there!
- [Gasping]
- [Gail] Here's the rope! Over here!
- [Terry] You okay?
- Wow, Dad!
[Terry]
Come on, man. We got ya.
- Tom!
- Hey, Wade!
You almost drown!
Wow! One of these days
I have got to learn how to swim.
You okay? Nice job.
I'm okay.
Oh, I got that.
I got it.
Okay.
I want to thank you, Tom.
You saved my life.
Oh, don't worry about it.
You didn't have
to hit me, though.
Yes, I did.
[Indistinct, On Radio]
[Gail] Just turn it around.
Get it straight up and down.
- Pull out some.
- All right.
[Gail] Point that thumb
where you want the fly to go.
- Ten and two and release.
- [Continues On Radio]
[Man On Radio]
At the top of the news:
The car believed to have been used in
the robbery of the livestock auction...
at the Flathead County Fairgrounds
Sunday was found abandoned...
on a back road
near the Canadian border...
in the robbery that netted
nearly a quarter of a million dollars.
- A security guard was killed.
- What? What'd I do?
My dad's been telling
my mother for 30 years...
that they're going to rob
this cattle auction.
- And finally somebody did it.
- Cattle auction?
He's gonna be very happy.
Yeah, on the radio.
- They just...
- Wow.
You guys known each other
a long time?
Me and Wade go way back.
We just met Frank in Tulsa.
L... I thought Frank
was married to your sister.
- Oh, yeah. She lives in Tulsa.
- Oh.
So what do you do when you're not
trying to drown yourself on a river?
- I'm a skier, ski bum.
- Oh, yeah?
What about you?
What do you do?
I teach history
for a school for the deaf.
Tom is an architect.
I could tell you were a teacher.
- Little bossy?
- No, no.
- Ladies sure do like Wade.
- Yeah?
[Gail]
Let's try again.
- Ten, two, ten, two.
- Yeah, sure do.
You keep trying to bring
your left hand up.
Hey, Tom.
[Acid Rock Emanating
From Headphones]
I don't like those guys.
I think we should leave
them behind tomorrow.
They're all right.
They're just those kind of guys...
that just never
got over their adolescence.
There's lots of them up here.
Why are you defending him?
Who? Wade?
- I'm not defending him.
- Yes, you are.
You sound like you're jealous.
I'm not jealous...
even though you did
drape yourself all over him.
I did not drape myself.
That is the way you teach
somebody to fly cast, honey.
Oh, Gail. He knew exactly
what he was doing.
Well, you know, they did get in over
their heads and they lost their guide.
If something happened to me, and you
and Roarke were alone on the river...
I would want somebody
to help you.
I'm sorry.
Maybe I am being a jerk about Wade.
But that still doesn't change
that I just think... something's off.
- [Barking]
- Go get it, Maggie.
Bring it here. Come on.
- [Humming]
- [Roarke] Good girl, good girl.
- [Maggie Barking]
- [Roarke] Go get it, Maggie.
- Hey, Gail.
- Hey.
- I found a hot spring.
- Yeah, isn't it great?
If you feel the water down here,
it's really warm.
- Oh, man. People.
- [Roarke] Go get it, Maggie.
- Yeah.
- Good, good girl.
Listen, I was wonderin', uh...
What's the river like
below Bridle Creek?
Oh, it's really spectacular down there.
It's unbelievable.
Then how come people
don't go down there?
Well, you're not allowed
to take rafts down there anymore.
It's just... Rapids are unrunnable.
It's treacherous.
I bet you ran it though,
didn't you?
[Laughing]
I did. I did.
I was 18 and completely insane.
- [Laughing]
- I bet you'd like to do it again, right?
- [Maggie Barking]
- Hmm, no.
No, everything's different now.
I have kids and...
- And a husband.
- Yeah, and a husband.
And what if you didn't?
But I do.
[Roarke]
Go get it, Maggie.
Hey, Ro! I got another one
for your collection.
- Hi, Wade!
- Hey, buddy.
But I got the cigarettes too, so we had
ten cartons of cigarettes and no beer.
- I couldn't believe it.
- [Chuckling]
Maggie.
Maggie, no!
Maggie, no.
Go lie down. Good girl.
So, Mom, what's this vision quest
thing you told me about?
Vision quest is, um...
is when a boy or a girl
your age...
from one of the tribes
that used to live around here...
would go off for about
four or five days...
all alone without
food or anything...
and they'd go to one of their
sacred places, like where we were.
They'd wait there for a vision
of their guardian spirit...
to appear to them.
They believed that
that guardian spirt would then...
watch over them and
protect them all their lives.
If you'd had a successful vision quest,
you'd do two things.
First, you'd send up
a smoke signal.
Smoke signal.
Yeah. That's so your folks
would know you're okay.
And then draw an image on the rocks
just like the ones we saw today.
[Humming "Twilight Zone" Theme]
I'll be right back.
[Gail]
Happy birthday to you
[Together]
Happy birthday
dear Roarke
Happy birthday to you
- [Gail] Did you think we forgot?
- Yeah.
[Chuckling]
It's from your dad and me.
- Mom! Hey, look, guys, rollerblades!
- Are those the right ones?
- Promise me you won't break your leg.
- Nope.
And this is from
your baby sister.
It's a... plastic camera.
- It's a waterproof camera.
- Roarke.
- This is from Maggie.
- Yeah, sure.
I think it might be something
you can use on the river.
- Look at it! It's a Swiss army knife!
- Great.
Thanks, Dad!
Look, it's got everything!
- Even the price.
- Yeah.
- [Terry] How much is it?
- Who wants some cake?
- 79.95.
- [Wade] Hey, save me a piece!
Hey, Wade.
Look what I got.
Oh, man, that's great.
Terry and I don't have anything
that fancy, but... this is from us.
Gee, uh, thanks, you guys.
This is...
[Gail]
What is it?
- What do ya got there, bud?
- What is it, honey?
It's $200!
Now, that's so in case you want to see
a concert or buy some CDs or whatever.
That's your money.
It's too much money, Wade.
He can't accept that.
Hey, you guys are savin' our lives.
This is our way of showin' appreciation.
- Can I, Dad?
- It's too much money, Roarke.
Thank you very much for the gesture,
but he can't accept it.
- Roarke, give the money back to him.
- No!
- He gave it to me. It's mine.
- Roarke.
Give the money back to him
right now.
- [Roarke Murmuring]
- What did you say?
I said, you didn't even
want to come on this trip!
Gee. I'm sorry, Tom.
I was just tryin' to be nice.
I talked to him.
He's okay.
You don't have to
beat yourself up over this.
- You know, you did the right thing.
- Oh!
It's very weird that...
Giving him that money.
I pretty much ruined
his birthday party.
Damn it. Same old story.
Want to know what I think?
I think you spend so much time at work
because you don't like being around me.
Gail, it's not about that.
You set such high standards
for yourself.
Everybody around you. I'm just trying
to come up to your expectations of me.
I'm trying to make you
proud of me again.
Oh, God.
[Sobbing]
Oh, God, I'm sorry...
if I made you feel
you had to do that.
So... what does it mean?
What are we gonna do?
I think there's only
one thing we can do.
Are you making
a pass at me?
I don't know. Is that what it's called
this far outside of Boston?
This far inside
of marriage, you mean.
I think we're sufficiently alienated
for this to qualify...
as a pass.
[Roarke]
Mom!
- I'm going to put him to sleep.
- Mm-hmm.
And I'll bathe.
[Footsteps Departing]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Thunderclap]
[Rain Splattering]
[Whimpering]
It's okay, Maggie.
I'll be out in a minute.
- [Thunder Rumbling]
- [Maggie Growling]
[Growling Continues, Barking]
- [Barking]
- [Gasping]
[Barking Continues]
[Gail] They're so creepy, but I don't
want to make a big deal or scare Roarke.
I just think we have
to get away from them.
Listen, tomorrow, we'll, uh,
act like nothing's happened.
And then we'll just find
a way to leave them behind.
- Okay?
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
[Thunderclap]
Bam! Uppercut right to his jaw.
Teeth went straight through his tongue,
bit it clear off. Blood showered.
It's lyin' on the ground.
Yak-yak-yak-yak! It's still talkin'.
One more bag
and we can go.
- Okay, Roarke. Come on, honey.
- Shut him up, though.
- Hey, give me that.
- Stow your fishing rod. Let's go.
- Come on, Maggie!
- [Barking]
I don't want to go with you.
I want to spend the day with my friends.
Roarke! You get your little heinie
back here right now.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's my fault, Gail.
I told him we could practice our fly
fishing together. Ten, two, ten, two.
Wade, you're not experienced enough
to take him down the river.
If we get in trouble,
you're going to be there, right?
- [Acid Rock]
- This way our music won't bother you!
All right.
Yeah, but, Roarke,
at lunch you come back with us.
- What?
- [Acid Rock]
Gail, stop looking at them.
Sweetheart, sit down.
Sit down and relax.
Nothing's going to happen.
He's going to have a great time.
He'll listen to his music.
When we stop for lunch, we'll get him.
Then we'll lose them.
Gail, look at me.
Everything's going to be all right.
- Hey, Roarke.
- Yep.
Can you keep a secret?
- Terry, hand me the green bag.
- Wade.
Hand me the green bag.
If I show you something...
- promise not to tell anybody?
- Sure.
- Not even your mom and dad?
- I promise.
Wow.
What are you...
That's right.
[Laughing]
First, ya take out the empties.
See that?
Three, five, seven.
In go the new ones.
A full load.
Can I hold it?
I don't think your mom
would like it very much.
My mom wouldn't care.
Really.
- All right.
- They're right there.
Be careful.
It's loaded.
- Bang. Bang.
- Hey!
- Hey.
- Come on, man.
All right, all right.
Better give it back now. Come on.
- Thanks, Wade.
- Hey, what are friends for?
[Wade]
Don't forget. It's our secret.
Hey, what were you
and the guys talkin' about?
- Hmm?
- Things. I'm goin' fishing.
Listen, if you want to catch
anything this time of day...
you're gonna have to go
around that big rock.
There's a little eddy there. There's
some big fish waitin' for ya, honey.
I'll call ya
when lunch is ready.
Take it up to that flat area there.
There's a spring if you want to wash up.
[Roarke]
Come on, Maggie.
Be careful on the rocks.
Just stay close to the shore downstream.
- Okay!
- Don't go where I can't see you.
[Water Splashing]
I'll be right back.
Terry?
Help me with this, Terry.
Did you get the drinks, Tom?
No, I didn't.
I'll go get them.
Oh, this looks pretty great.
Oh, boy.
Ah, that's great.
You ought to try it.
I'll get a towel.
Oh!
Wade!
Oh, man!
Come on!
Wade!
We're gonna make it.
Roarke. Roarke. Reel it in, honey.
We're gonna find another place.
You said this was
a good place.
- Just reel it in.
- It's stuck.
- Break it, damn it.
- What are you doing?
- I'll explain later. Get in the boat.
- No!
I don't want to ride with you!
I hate you!
- Roarke! Get in the boat!
- What about Maggie?
- Maggie! Maggie!
- Roarke!
[Wings Fluttering]
- Come on, Maggie. Come on, girl.
- [Wade] Hey.
What are you guys doin'?
We were just gonna go on ahead
and be by ourselves for a little bit.
Oh.
Yeah. It is our vacation and we haven't
been alone together all that much.
I thought you guys
were runnin' out on us.
[Gail]
No. Uh-uh.
I think that's exactly
what they were doin', Terry.
You're right. We were.
L-lt's just not working out between us.
Why's that? Because your son
wants to be with me instead of you?
Roarke. Come here.
Look, I'm taking my family
and we're gonna go down the river alone.
That's what we're gonna do.
I'm sorry.
We'll send somebody back to get you.
Who died and made you stud dick
all of a sudden, Tom?
[Gail] You go get in
the boat right now.
Wade, rangers come down here
all the time.
You could hook up with one of them
and get to Bridle Creek ahead of us.
And what if I said
I'm not gonna let you go?
What would you do?
- What would you do, stud?
- [Maggie Barking]
- Hey! What is he...
- Just let him talk to him for a second.
- I don't want to fight with you.
- Oh.
- Wade!
- [Maggie Barking]
I tried to be nice to you.
I tried to be nice
to your family.
And what do you do?
You try and run out on me.
I'm drownin', Tom.
- You wanna hit me?
- [Gasping]
[Maggie Barking]
I'm pullin' you down, Tom.
Whoa!
[Grunting]
- Hit 'im, Dad! Hit 'im.
- [Maggie Barking]
Okay, we're even.
You hit me, I hit you. It's over.
Now, I'm takin' my family
and I'm leavin'.
- No, you're not.
- Look out, Dad! He's got a gun!
Roarke.
- Don't! Damn it! [Grunting]
- [Maggie Barking]
It's not gonna be that easy.
Get off of her!
- Get off me!
- [Grunting]
- [Growling]
- Get! Get!
- [Maggie Whimpering]
- [Groaning]
Don't, Wade! Stop!
He's my dad! Stop hitting him!
- [Maggie Barking]
- This is not fun anymore.
- [Gail] Oh, God, no!
- Wade!
Wade, please!
God, please, don't...
I need your wife
to get me down the river.
- I need your son to control her.
- [Maggie Barking]
- You and the dog are expendable.
- [Barking Continues]
- Right now, I think I'll get rid of...
- [Barking]
- The dog.
No! Run, Mags, run!
Run, Maggie, run!
Run! Run!
You got guts, Roarke.
But you shouldn't have
broken your promise about the gun.
Friends don't do that.
I thought you were a nice guy.
I am a nice guy.
Just a different kind
of nice guy.
Damn, Terry.
Looks like we lose our deposit.
[Wade Laughing]
All right!
Now that I'm head of the family,
here's what we're gonna do!
We're gonna haul ass down this river.
No more fishing. No more sightseeing.
And unfortunately,
no more skinny dipping.
- By the way, Gail...
- [Clicking]
You're gonna get another chance
to run the Gauntlet.
- We're not stopping at Bridle Creek.
- What?
That's right. Come on, let's get
this shit up the hill and outta sight!
Roarke.
Were you takin'
pictures of me?
Give me that camera.
[Sighing]