(COINS JANGLE)
How is everything, Mr. Sabian?
- Great, as always.
- Good.
You get home now, Eva.
It's getting late.
Stay safe.
Yeah. You, too, Mr. Sabian.
MAN: (ON TV)
Traffic is building rapidly downtown,
as citizens rush to get home
before commencement.
If you're not Purging, we advise you
to get off the streets
as quickly as possible.
It'll soon be a war out there.
Prognosticators estimate
that more people
will partake in this year's Purge...
Sabian's gone. That's it.
What is she waiting for?
Why doesn't this bitch let us go?
Hey, calm down.
We got plenty of time.
You girls up to anything fun tonight?
I might kidnap Eva this year.
Hope that's okay with you, mami.
MRS. CRAWLEY: It's getting late.
Hope to see you
all tomorrow. Stay safe.
Okay, stay safe.
CARLOS:
Finally. Stay safe, Mrs. Crawley.
Eva.
Need a ride home?
I'm fine, Carlos.
Stay safe.
Bye, Carlito. Stay safe.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
If he asked to take me home,
I'd accept that ride, girl.
He's a dog.
Oh, I like that dog. I would
walk the shit out of that dog.
But that dog doesn't want
anything to do with me,
he wants to sniff your ass.
- (CHUCKLES) You're disgusting.
- It's true.
You're really gonna ask her tonight?
I have to.
I can't afford his
medicine much longer.
All right, good luck. (SIGHS)
Stay safe.
Stay safe, sweetie.
(SIGHS)
(WHISPERING) Okay.
MAN 1 ON RADIO: Both the people and
the government wanted the Purge.
MAN 2 ON RADIO: The New Founding
Fathers came into office...
MAN 1 ON RADIO: Were voted into office
by a country who wanted change...
MAN 2 ON RADIO: This new regime
took advantage of the nation's fear.
(TURNS OFF RADIO)
I'm glad we took the back roads.
The highways are probably
a mess right now.
(SIGHING)
Yeah. We'll be there in no time.
Yeah.
What are you looking at?
Nothing. Just, you know, stuff.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
You sure?
You don't need to keep asking me.
My name is Donald Talbot.
Our regime was voted into
office nine years ago.
And the first order of business
was to deal with the
epidemic of crime
that was plaguing this nation.
The answer was the Purge.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
You need some protection tonight?
You need something?
Hey, man, we running out of...
Hey, that Purge tonight,
y'all know what time it is.
Hitting them in the face
ain't gonna work no more.
You need something powerful.
How you doing, buddy?
Use your hands, man. Just use
your hands. Don't even worry about it.
Hey, sweetheart, how you doing?
How you doing?
You gonna need something
for protection tonight?
- No. No, I'm good. I'm good.
- UZI? Beretta?
Look, on the cheap-cheap.
Or a blade to cut your man's throat?
Whatever you need.
We take any kind of payment.
(DOGS BARKING AT DISTANCE)
Eva!
- Hey, Diego.
- What's up, girl? How you doing?
- Good. How you doing?
- Yeah? Everything's great?
No, it's not great. I'm tired...
Oh, it could be better.
Take me up there with you tonight.
Get a little protection.
You know what I'm saying?
- Come on, now.
- I'm cool, Diego. I'm good.
You sure you don't
want no protection?
- Huh?
- No, thanks, Diego.
(CHUCKLING) I'm the man for
the job. You know what I mean?
CARMELO: We've lost our
souls to attain this peace.
We no longer worship
at the altar of Christ,
Muhammad, Yahweh.
We worship at the altar
of Smith & Wesson.
We, the people, know not what we do.
Horseshit.
Where'd you find this lunatic?
I saw his protest posters all
around the neighborhood.
He lives here, Papa.
He's just like us.
Now, shush. Please listen.
He's not a lunatic. (CHUCKLING)
The Purge is not about
containing crime to one night,
and cleansing our souls
by releasing aggression.
It's about one thing. Money.
- Who dies tonight? The poor.
- (SIGHING)
We can't afford to protect ourselves.
That's enough.
I can't listen to this crap.
He's as full of shit as they are.
No, he's right. Come on.
They're keeping the population down
by getting rid of people
like us to save money.
- Talk is cheap, Cali.
- Mmm-hmm.
He may be right, but he
won't do anything about it.
EVA: Home.
(KEYS JANGLING)
(EXHALES)
Hey, Daddy.
Don't "hey, Daddy" me.
Where have you been?
We're less than two hours
until commencement,
- and you're out gallivanting.
- (SIGHING)
Gallivanting? I was
picking up your medicine.
Even worse.
A waste of time and money.
Christ, Eva, I told you
not to get this stuff.
EVA: I'm tired of listening
to this every day.
It does nothing... I'm not taking it!
- You're taking your medicine.
- I'm not taking it! No, I'm not!
- Yes, you are!
- I'm not taking it. You're taking it back.
Oh, my God, really?
(STAMMERING) Can we stop?
Look, Papa, maybe it doesn't do
anything, but can you just take it?
For me?
(SIGHS)
Okay.
(SIGHS) We'll lockdown and then
we'll eat after commencement.
Count me out.
I'm gonna take a long nap,
and don't bother me.
I'm gonna try to sleep through
this godforsaken holiday.
Look, I'm sorry I'm so grumpy, girls.
I hate this night.
Please, forgive me.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
EVA: You drive me crazy.
(SNIFFLES)
Uh...
Make sure you lockdown everything.
I'll take care of my room.
I love you both.
Very much.
I know.
That was weird.
It must be the night.
Yeah.
(SNIFFS)
I'm gonna take a quick shower,
and then we'll lockdown.
Okay, wait. How did things
go with Mrs. Crawley?
- Did you get the raise?
- (EXHALES DEEPLY)
God, what a bitch.
Well, did you at least
make a good argument?
Did you say everything
that we practiced?
I'm sorry, baby.
Yeah.
- (LIZ MUMBLING)
- (MACHINE BEEPING)
I want to tell her, Shane.
Hey, did you hear me?
I said I wanna tell your sister...
Yeah, I heard you.
I just don't feel like telling her.
Why?
Because as soon as you say
it out loud to another person,
then it's irreversible.
Do you have the keys?
- Yeah.
- (KEYS JANGLING)
Handy?
Right here.
Can you unlock the car, please?
It's unlocked.
No, it's not.
There.
(BELLOWS)
Let's just get in the car.
What the fuck was that all about?
I don't know. He didn't tell me.
You know, we don't have a whole lot
of time before commencement, Shane.
All right. (STAMMERING)
We'll be fine, I promise.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Yeah.
I've been calling.
Why didn't you pick up?
What do you want?
(SIGHS)
You can't go out there.
You know how dangerous it is...
You need to go. You need to leave.
It's late.
Don't do this.
It won't make you feel any better.
Go with your new husband,
and your new family.
Leave.
(WHISPERING) Just stay safe.
(SIGHS)
You, too. (SIGHS)
(WATER TRICKLING)
CARMELO: Whatever happened
to "Give me your needy,
"your tired,
"your huddled masses
yearning to breathe free"?
The redistribution of wealth upward
through killing has to stop.
We must pick up arms.
This year, we will fight back!
Jeez, that guy freaked me out.
Did not see him coming.
I thought we decided
it was irreversible.
No, you often decide
things on your own,
and then pretend that
they were a joint decision.
You often agree with me,
and then a week later say,
- "I don't remember doing that."
- (SCOFFS)
So, you're calling me a liar?
And you're calling me a bully.
Just say you changed your mind,
not that we didn't come
to a joint decision.
This is the exact...
See, this is exactly why
we need to tell your sister
that we're separating.
You're right, it'll make it real,
but I think we need to make it real.
Maybe I don't wanna make it real.
- (BANGING AND SQUEAKING)
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What the hell is that?
The power steering's gone.
What do you mean
"the power steering's gone"?
(STAMMERS) I don't know.
There's something wrong with the car.
- Can you pull over?
- I'm trying.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Shit.
Try it again.
(CLICKING)
It's dead.
(TIRES SQUEAL)
(ENGINE REVS)
WOMAN: (ON RADIO) The sixth Annual
Purge will begin in 45 minutes.
(SIGHS)
Just in case.
Yeah.
Hey.
We're gonna be fine.
Just like every year.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
I'll pay three times as much
if you just come out here...
No, no, no. I don't care about
the car. We just need a ride.
- It's... Hello?
- Whoa, whoa! Hey!
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
(BOTH SHOUTING)
- Stop!
- Shit.
Please!
- Shane, we can't be stuck outside.
- I know. I know.
We're downtown. Everyone
comes downtown to Purge.
Hey, hey. Don't worry.
We'll figure something
out, I promise.
(LIQUID DRIPPING)
Is that coming from our car?
Oh, shit.
(BIKES APPROACHING)
(WHISPERING)
He cut those wires, Shane.
Yeah.
(PANTS) We need to run.
Yeah, go, go.
NEWSREADER: News 13 wishes anyone
who is not participating in this
year's Purge a safe evening
and for those releasing the beast,
a successful cleanse.
Good luck.
- (BEEPING)
- Should I get Papa?
(SIGHS) He hates this. Let him sleep.
FEMALE VOICE: This is not a test.
This is your Emergency
Broadcast System
announcing the commencement
of The Annual Purge
sanctioned by the US Government.
Weapons of Class 4 and lower
have been authorized
for use during the Purge.
All other weapons are restricted.
Government officials of ranking
10 have been granted immunity...
Commencing at the siren, any and
all crime, including murder,
will be legal for 12
continuous hours.
Police, fire and emergency
medical services
will be unavailable until
tomorrow morning at 7:00 a.m.
when the Purge concludes.
Blessed be our New Founding Fathers,
and America, a nation reborn.
- May God be with you all.
- Let's go this way. Let's just go.
(SIREN BLARING)
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(BLARING CONTINUES)
(DOG BARKING)
(YELLING)
(DOOR BUZZES)
(THUDDING)
(MAN GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(MAN WHOOPING)
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Do you think they're still after us?
- I have no idea.
- Okay.
- Let's just get out of here.
- (MAN YELLING)
- Oh, God!
- Let's get out of here. Go!
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
LIZ: Where do we go?
Here, get in this. Get in this!
We'll just hide in here. Come on.
(BOTH PANTING)
- Go.
- (SCREAMS) Oh, God!
Let's just get out of here.
Come on, come on. You're good.
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(ENGINE STARTS)
SHANE: Fuck, it's them.
We gotta move, we gotta move.
We gotta move.
(DISTANT GUNSHOT)
(CUTLERY CLATTERS)
I'm gonna go get Papa for dinner.
He said don't bother him.
Yeah. I just wanna see if he's awake.
CALI: Mom!
- What? What is it?
- Mom, come here!
What's wrong?
Where's Papa?
Look at this.
PAPA RICO: "Dearest Eva and Cali,
"my greatest heartache is seeing
the two girls I love so much
"struggling in this world.
"I am dying, you know this.
"I'll be a martyr for a
wealthy family tonight.
"They paid me for this service.
"$100,000 will be transferred
into your accounts, my darlings.
"Take their money.
- "Survive the night and live a safe life.
- (INDISTINCT)
"I love you."
ALL: Blessed be America,
a nation reborn.
I don't understand.
It's how the wealthy Purge, baby.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
They buy poor and sick people,
and they take them in their homes
and they kill them
where they're safe.
(WHISPERING) Oh, my God.
It's just like Carmelo said.
Why would Papa do that? I don't
understand why he would do that.
(SNIFFLES)
Okay, he must have left something
that could tell us where he went.
- Cali. Cali.
- (SNIFFLES) Like his phone.
We should call his phone.
We could stop him.
- EVA: Cali...
- CALI: Okay, that's fine.
We can do something about this.
I don't know what,
- but we can still do something about it.
- Cali, stop.
Just stop. He's gone.
- He's gone.
- (SNIFFLES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SNIFFLES)
(SOBS)
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(LOUD THUDDING)
(DOOR BUZZES)
(EXHALES) What is this?
Who are they? It looks like an army.
(WHISPERING) I have no idea.
- (EXPLOSION)
- (BOTH GASP)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
- It's them.
- No, it can't be them.
They haven't even come inside yet.
That was right in the other room.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DOOR OPENS)
DIEGO: Eva!
I'm here to protect you.
Protect you from me. (CHUCKLES)
(WHISPERING) Mom, where's the gun?
It's in the kitchen.
(SNIFFLES)
(WHISTLING)
Where you hiding, bitch?
Don't you know that you gotta be
polite to people in this society?
Because if not,
this is what happens tonight!
Diego, don't come back here.
We have guns and we will shoot you.
Cali?
That you?
Oh, I got a little bonus.
- (WOMAN SCREAMS)
- Got a little package deal.
But I'll tell you what, tonight
I'm gonna release the beast,
on the both of you
fucking lame bitches!
It's my right,
granted to me by the
New Found Fathers!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CHUCKLING)
You thought your little
weak-ass protection
was gonna keep me out or what, huh?
Let me tell you something.
Not with the barricade buster.
Saved up a lot of pennies for
this bitch, let me tell you.
Diego, don't you hear those
people in our building?
Now you shut the fuck up!
The only thing you gotta be concerned
with is who wants to go first.
- (SOBBING)
- Huh?
Who?
Leave my daughter alone.
CALI: Mom, don't.
- You can do what you want to me, Diego.
- (CALI SNIFFLES)
I will. Trust me when
I tell you, I will.
You better prepare yourself tonight,
'cause tonight,
it's motherfucking on, bitch.
That's right, because
it's Diego's night!
It's my night to motherfucking Purge!
My fucking time!
(MAN PLEADING)
(GUNSHOTS FIRING)
(MAN GRUNTING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(HOOTING)
Every fucking day,
you pass me by in the hallway,
like I ain't shit!
Well, now, that shit fucking
changes! I change shit!
I beg you, please!
- Oh, fucking beg, bitch!
- Please...
You fucking beg! Beg!
- Please! I'm saying please!
- (CALI SOBBING)
Beg, yeah.
- Don't touch my daughter, please.
- (CHUCKLING)
EVA: Please, leave her alone.
- Let me hear you say please.
- She's got nothing to do with it.
- Please.
- (THUDDING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What's that? Huh?
- Is it your father?
- I don't know.
- Is that your father?
- CALI: Please, please.
I like that.
(GROANING)
- (THUDS)
- (GASPS)
Come on, motherfucker!
You want some, too?
Come and get it!
- Where you at?
- (GUN COCKS)
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHISPERING) Is it him?
(STIFLED SOBBING)
(BOTH GASP)
GUNMAN 1: This is what
he was looking for tonight.
Let's bring these two downstairs.
GUNMAN 2: Big Daddy, we have
two for your personal Purge.
Bringing them down now.
(SCREAMING)
Get off me!
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Cali!
(EVA SCREAMING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(SCREAMING)
CALI: No! No!
EVA: Cali!
Oh, God, no! Let go!
No! (GRUNTING)
Get the fuck off me!
- EVA: Please!
- (GRUNTING)
Leave my daughter alone!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(INDISTINCT)
EVA: Please, don't.
Please, please, please.
(CALI GROANING)
(EVA AND CALI STRUGGLING)
Just drive. Just drive. Just drive.
(GRUNTING)
Get off of me!
Mom!
(POUNDING)
Just fucking drive.
Please! Let my daughter go!
Cali!
No, fucking...
Mom!
(GUN COCKS)
(STRUGGLING)
(PANTING)
(DOOR BUZZES)
- I don't know.
- They were right behind us.
What the fuck is that?
- Shit.
- What do we do?
SHANE: Here, get in. It's open.
No!
Get off!
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
What is going on out there?
We're safe, we're safe.
We're in here. We're good.
(SIGHS)
- Let's go.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
- SERGEANT: Hey! Out of the car!
- LIZ: No, no, no!
Please! Please, don't!
Get out of the car, or I will shoot!
We're not Purging! We don't
have any weapons! Please.
- I will shoot you!
- LIZ: Please don't shoot!
- SERGEANT: Move out of the car now!
- SHANE: No, we're not armed!
- SERGEANT: Get out of the car!
- LIZ: We can't! They're after us!
Wait, wait, wait. We have to go!
We have to go, please!
We don't wanna hurt anybody!
- LIZ: Please, don't...
- Shut up! Shut up!
Hands up, and shut your mouth!
- Please. Please.
- LIZ: Hands are up!
SHANE: Thank you, thank you.
SERGEANT: Get in, get in, get in.
- Shane?
- What?
- They're coming.
- We gotta go!
Over there, too!
There's people over here, too!
You gotta move, you gotta move!
Please, go! Please.
SERGEANT: Shut up!
LIZ: Drive!
(GASPS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS)
SHANE: He's shooting at the
motorcycles. They're turning!
They're not following us.
They're gone, they're gone.
They're all gone.
- Are you sure?
- SHANE: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, there's no one there!
Are you okay, baby?
Yeah, I'm fine. Are you?
(SIGHS) Yeah.
Sir, are you okay?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You. What was that army
doing in your building?
- Why were they after you?
- I don't know.
Why were they after you?
I don't know! I don't know.
- Why are you in the streets?
- Our car just broke down.
We're not out to Purge.
We don't wanna hurt anybody.
- Are you armed?
- No! No!
What about you?
What were you doing outside?
Oh, God.
Look, Mom... Mom, it's okay.
We're safe now.
(WHISPERING) No, we're not.
Sir, where are we going?
Honestly, anywhere but
here is fine with me. Just...
(ENGINE SPUTTERS)
God damn it.
Maybe nowhere.
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
Whoever's in that truck was
using armor piercing bullets.
The car is dead.
So, that's it. We're stuck
outside on Purge Night.
What are we gonna do?
Can we just hide in here?
We have seven hours until morning.
There's hunters out there with dogs.
Sooner or later,
they're gonna find you.
But you do what you want.
- You're on your own now.
- Huh?
- What?
- Whoa!
Whoa, what do you mean,
we're on our own?
I should never have gotten involved.
It's none of my business.
Okay, but you did, so it is
your business now, all right?
So, what are we all going to do?
Take this. It's loaded. Take it.
- Take it.
- You're just giving us guns?
Where are you going?
I got somewhere to be
before the sun comes up.
I can't take you with me,
you'll slow me down.
So, you're really just
gonna leave us here?
(SIGHS)
Stay off the streets.
Find somewhere to go.
Please, take us with you.
We are not the kind of people
who will survive tonight.
SHANE: Let him go, all right?
He doesn't wanna help.
- Shane, shut up!
- SHANE: Let him...
Why did you save us if you were
just gonna leave us here to die?
Please, help us!
EVA: Wait! I can get you a car.
I have a friend in the
city not far from here.
I've worked with her for years.
If you get us there safely,
you can take her car and
do what you have to do.
Where does she live?
Third and Bryant.
- Will she give me her car?
- Mmm-hmm.
Are you sure?
Mmm-hmm.
Make sure.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
Hey, it's Eva.
Listen, we're in trouble.
That was a real dick move, you know?
Walking away and then coming back.
EVA: Thank you so much. Thank you.
Okay, we'll be there really soon.
And listen, I need your car as well.
I'll explain when I
get there, is that okay?
What are you looking for?
Snipers.
Thank you so much. Okay.
Uh, she lives with her parents.
They're happy to have us.
If you can get us to her place
safely, the car is yours.
Can she help us, too?
Yeah.
Thank you.
She'll give me the car?
All right, I'm gonna help you get to
your friend's, but I want that car.
I know.
All right, you listen to
what I say. You stay close.
You slow me down, I cut you
all loose, you understand?
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. Let's go.
(GUNSHOTS)
WOMAN: I'm doing God's work.
He uses an earthquake, a virus.
(GUNSHOTS)
Population under control.
The masses nourish and flourish.
I am that virus tonight.
I am a one-woman fucking plague
and you're all in my path!
I am the Holy Trinity.
Oh, I am the Holy Trinity.
I am the Father Fucker,
Son of a Bitch, and Holy Shit!
When I move, you move, understand?
Stay close, don't stray.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
And my MP-9 silver-tipped
Auto Magnum.
The right arm of the free world
and the left hand of God!
Go!
In flaming fire, I take the heads
of them that know not God.
We're gonna go down Fifth.
Your friend's building is close.
Go through the business district,
stay away from the gangs downtown.
(MAN SCREAMING)
LIZ: Wait a minute.
(BIKES APPROACHING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(MAN SCREAMS)
Stay back, stay back.
No! Please, don't!
(SCREAMING) No! No!
What are they doing?
Where are they taking him?
It's not our business.
Those are the guys
that were after us.
SERGEANT:
It's okay. It's not our problem.
We're gonna have people in front of us,
and we're gonna have people behind us.
As long as we move, we'll be fine.
We're gonna cross Banks.
No, no, no, that's the long way.
It's gonna be much quicker
if we go down here.
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
LIZ: What is this?
Get it off of me, I'm stuck!
It's a trap. It's a trap.
We don't have time.
- Move away, I gotta shoot it.
- What?
SHANE: What? You're gonna what?
I'm gonna shoot it. Move!
- LIZ: What?
- Okay.
(SCREAMS)
Shoot it! Shoot the cable!
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Shoot it!
Shane, hurry up!
SERGEANT: Get up, get up!
(GROANS)
- Move!
- LIZ: Okay, let's go!
(GUNSHOTS)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: There are six
hours remaining in this year's...
(STATIC AND SHOUTING)
CARMELO: The NFFA pigs are wrong.
They're fucking wrong!
Profit-making is not the
essence of democracy.
Wake up, people. Wake up!
It's time to take a stand.
Tonight, we write our
message in blood.
Their blood!
It's so quiet here.
SERGEANT: The business district's
always quiet on Purge Night.
The banks move their money,
so no one's ever down here.
Let's go.
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
(WHISPERING) Stop.
We don't even know your names.
I'm Liz, and this is Shane.
Hi.
Eva. My daughter, Cali.
It's nice to officially meet
you on this shitty night.
Yeah.
Is anyone else kind of
curious about this guy?
I'm just glad that
he's out here with us.
Yeah, me, too.
But we all got stuck out here,
and he chose to be.
That means he's Purging.
(WHISPERING) Hey. Let's go.
Are you saying that
we shouldn't trust him?
He saved our lives.
All I'm saying is that he's out here
armed to the teeth,
on Purge Night, voluntarily.
That means he's trying
to do something nasty.
I can hear you.
Sorry. Just go.
Hey, are you doing okay?
(WHISPERING)
Yeah. Yeah. It's gonna be fine.
I'm gonna go talk to him.
Cali.
Cali...
- What's your name?
- Shh.
You're good with guns.
I'm guessing you're either
a cop or a criminal, huh?
And I'm guessing you're either a
pain in my ass or a pain in my ass.
You're out here to do it, aren't you?
To Purge? That's what you
have to do later on, right?
What are you gonna do?
Stop.
New rules. You shut up.
All of you, shut up.
I'm gonna stop talking because
you're being an asshole, okay?
Not because you told me to shut up.
Cali.
Hey, hey, hey.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
SHANE: "Here hangs stockbroker
David Neustadter. He stole our pensions.
"Now, he's gone."
Maybe David deserved it.
Just a bad joke.
What the hell is that?
Is that tear gas?
Smoke canister.
Stay close, stay close, stay close.
- Help me!
- (SCREAMING)
Grab him! Get off her!
Get off her!
(GRUNTING)
We were just doing our duty.
Is she okay?
- He scared the shit out of me.
- All right. You're okay, though.
(LIZ BREATHING HEAVILY)
SHANE: Just breathe.
Just breathe. Just take a breath.
CALI: Look at his uniform.
This is one of the bastards
who came into our building.
And that looks like their truck.
All right, stay here. Stay here.
MAN: (OVER PA) Truck 3, come in.
Come in, please.
- Come on.
- Come on, let's go, let's go.
Just stay together. Let's go.
Oh, Jesus.
MAN: (OVER PA)
Truck 3, please respond!
Go check the cab,
see if this thing's working.
- Stay alert. Stay alert.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
Go ahead. Go. Go, go, go.
CALI: This is some high-tech shit.
Yo, somebody spent a lot of money
trying to do some heavy-duty Purging.
Look at this. They're accessing
the city's traffic cams.
Looking for targets, I guess.
Traffic cams are controlled
by the government.
How did they get into these?
I mean, who are these people?
Maybe you just answered
your own question.
Look at this. Seventh Street.
Is that your building?
Yeah, but why is it all red?
You're being targeted for something,
along with all these other buildings.
Here, here. All over the city.
EVA: All around the projects.
Maybe you were right, Cali.
Look, I'm telling you,
this is the New Founding Fathers.
- The government...
- SHANE: The truck is fucked.
- No good?
- No, the engine's all blown out or something.
Hey, look at this.
That's Carmelo's mark, Mom.
I told Papa he was the real deal.
His group took these fuckers out.
SERGEANT: Everybody got a weapon?
Hey, grab this.
Take the weapon. Go. Go!
- Go!
- Oh, shit, there's another one.
Looks like an army. Come on.
Get down, let's go.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(SQUEAKING)
(SCREAMS)
(MUFFLED GASP)
Take this.
Shh.
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Come on.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Hey.
Why did you stop at our building?
Why did you help us?
Didn't we establish
a no-talking rule?
People are getting
killed all over the city.
Why did you stop for us?
I saw you. You were
putting up a hell of a fight.
(CHUCKLES)
You reminded me of someone.
Who?
Look, Purging, no matter
what the reason, is wrong.
Killing doesn't help anything.
It doesn't heal someone.
Enough. Enough.
Go back with your mommy.
Go.
(SIGHS)
There's no air in here.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(EXHALES)
Come over here. Put this on.
- I don't need that.
- Put it on, I said.
- I said I don't need it.
- Put it on.
Put your arm through here.
Now, hopefully, you won't need it.
Let's move.
(CLANGING)
- EVA: What was that?
- SERGEANT: Shh.
(GRUNTING)
SERGEANT: There's no threat.
They're just trying to
make it through the night.
Keep moving.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Hey, are you okay?
I just wanna get out of here.
(VEHICLES APPROACHING)
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
Oh, shit!
Move!
SHANE: Go! Come on!
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
Run! Move!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GROANS)
Move!
(ALL PANTING)
(SHOUTING)
(GRUNTS)
Get up! Get up! Come on!
Get up, get up, get up!
Mom, we have to go right now!
SERGEANT: Move it, move it! Move!
(EVIL LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
Go, go!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMING)
Up, up, up!
(SCREAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
We're not gonna make it. Fuck it.
Shane!
- What are you doing?
- SHANE: Get down!
- What do we do?
- Just shoot! Just shoot!
(GROANS)
Shane!
(SERGEANT PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
- Oh, my God.
- I'm fine, I'm fine, I'm fine!
Just keep shooting.
Just keep shooting. Go! Go!
(GROANS)
(MAN SCREAMING)
- All right. You're okay.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
Stay here. Give me this.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry.
I was just so scared.
(ALL PANTING)
You're bleeding.
- I cut it on the platform. It's fine.
- We'll help you. Just tell us...
I said, it's fine!
Get up. Get up.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
EVA: What's taking them so long?
Help! He's been shot!
I have no idea how bad.
(SHANE GROANS)
- SERGEANT: Open up.
- LIZ: We're gonna be fine, okay?
Call your friend. Tell her we're close.
We're gonna get him up.
Okay. Look at me.
Look at me, Shane. Yeah?
One, two, three. Get him up.
- LIZ: Let's go!
- (GROANING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
There are four hours and 30 minutes
remaining in this year's Purge.
- SERGEANT: Go! Just don't worry!
Go! Come on, come on!
- (PANTING)
Keep moving!
Go! Don't slow down! Keep moving!
It's right up ahead.
Come on!
Cali! Slow down!
(GRUNTING)
Hey, look, that's her building!
She said to meet around the back.
(WHIRRING)
MAN: (OVER PA) We have a target match
on the civilians who attacked Truck 2.
EVA:
She said, "Meet us around the back."
Tanya! Let us in!
It's Eva and Cali!
Holy shit! You guys look like hell.
Come on, come on, hurry up.
Get in here. Hurry up!
- EVA: Thank you.
- I don't like being out here. Come on.
(LOCK CLICKS)
SERGEANT: All right.
- Bullet went right through.
- (SHANE GROANS)
I can't believe you guys
went through all that stuff.
It's just insane!
Get him to the hospital first
thing after this is over.
- Yeah.
- You'll be okay.
It's gonna hurt like a son of a bitch,
but you're gonna be okay.
- (EXHALES DEEPLY) Thanks.
- I can't thank you enough.
That's what you get for being a hero.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
- I need the car.
- I know.
Come on, everybody. Eat, drink!
TANYA: Yes, I recommend drinking.
It's the best way to get
through the evening.
And the food is delicious.
My mother's a wonderful cook.
My sister's a testament to that.
What the hell does that mean?
TANYA: That she's a good cook!
You know, you didn't have to go this far.
Just having us here was really enough.
You guys have had a terrible night.
Get some food in your system,
and we'll get through this together.
LORRAINE: Excuse me.
Cali?
TANYA: I can't believe
nobody's drinking with me.
What about you, tough guy?
Want a drink?
No, thanks.
Okay.
You're really going back out there?
- (DOOR OPENS)
- TANYA: Mmm!
Relax! It's my father and my
brother-in-law. He's the super.
They were just checking
the building. It's all good.
Everyone, please don't
mind my husband's clothes.
He's not Purging.
He just thought it was a crazy idea
to go out and see what's
happening tonight.
Yeah, I chickened out.
No way I was going out there.
- I don't know what the hell I was thinking.
- (LORRAINE CHUCKLES)
Thank God he came to his senses.
I mean, look at him.
He would've been the laughingstock
of the neighborhood.
That's not very nice, Lorraine.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
for it to be mean.
It's not mean, it's just true.
(GUN COCKS)
How's everything, Daddy?
It's all good, baby.
The building's locked down and good.
It's quiet.
I see you had a rough
go of it, my friend.
- Oh, yeah.
- BARNEY: Relax.
Make yourself at home.
You're safe here.
We are anti-Purge in this household.
(CHUCKLES) Speak for yourself, Daddy.
What does that mean?
I could think of a couple situations
where Purging could be the answer.
- Like when?
- TANYA: I'm not telling.
I'm just saying,
don't piss me off, bitch.
- KATHERINE: Uh, please excuse my daughter.
- LIZ: No, it's fine.
And, please, if there's anything
else you need, just ask.
I could use a clean shirt.
BARNEY: Down the hall,
second door on the left.
Top drawer of the bureau.
What's mine is yours.
Okay. Excuse me, too.
I'm gonna go to the
little girl's room
'cause this wine is
going right through me.
KATHERINE: Come on,
everyone, please eat and drink.
Come on. Honey?
(TANYA COUGHS)
REPORTER: This is News 10 reporting on
a lively Purge Night across the country.
We have riots in East Los Angeles,
as well as record
participation in Pittsburgh.
(WHISPERING) He wasn't lying.
This shit hurts.
Aw, I'm sorry.
(SIGHS)
You scared the shit out of me.
I thought I was losing you.
But I still think we
should tell your sister.
(STUTTERS)
You're an asshole.
- I'm sorry.
- That's not funny.
- No, I got shot.
Oh, are you gonna use this
excuse for the rest of our lives?
- Well, at least the rest of the night.
- (CHUCKLING) Okay.
All right, people, let's change
the atmosphere up in here.
No more Purge news.
No more nothing depressing.
Let's put on some music, and let's
just liven it up a little bit, right?
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- Come on, you want to dance?
Why not?
Liven up the party, come on.
Let's dance. (CHUCKLING) Let's dance!
Okay, I gotta go. I need the car.
- (WHISPERING) I know.
- You trust these people?
Because your friend likes to drink,
and she's taking pills back there.
Yeah, she's pretty wild.
But we'll be okay.
She's a good friend.
What? You don't wanna do it? What?
Lorraine, do you care if we dance?
She doesn't even care.
She's not even paying attention.
Now he's... Look at him.
- (CHUCKLING) He's asleep.
- He is.
I don't know how to thank you.
Okay, if you can just tell her
I need the car right now,
that would be really great.
I know what you're doing tonight.
You're going out there to
kill someone who wronged you.
You believe in this night, don't you?
I think you should just
take care of your daughter.
She's special, and you're very lucky.
And I need the car.
There is no car.
What?
I'm sorry, they don't have a car.
But we needed you.
And I needed the car.
I did what I had to.
I did it for my daughter.
I was doing this for my son.
And I trusted you.
You have no idea what you might
have taken away from me tonight.
- Hey.
Look, I know you're
angry with my mother,
but I really think you
should just stay here.
Just wait out the
night with us, okay?
Look, I heard you say that
you're doing it for your son.
Now, I don't know him,
but I'm sure he would not want you to do
whatever it is that you're going to do.
- Bye, Cali.
- Please, come on, you're safe here.
- Get out of my way.
- Please, just...
I gotta go. Goodbye.
- Stay here. It's fine.
- Get out of the way.
Get back!
No! (SCREAMS)
RODDY: Lorraine!
KATHERINE: What are you doing?
Tanya! Tanya!
(GRUNTING)
RODDY: Lorraine!
What've you done?
What are you doing, Lorraine?
Jesus Christ, she's dead.
RODDY: You killed your sister!
She's your sister!
Lorraine! What are you doing?
You know what I'm doing.
I read all your emails,
you cheating motherfuckers.
You both deserve to die!
(SCREAMS)
Okay, Lorraine! Lorraine, stop!
- No!
- Get back, get back. Back up, back up!
I'm sorry, okay? I'm sorry.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Lorraine.
If you shoot me,
you shoot this woman.
Just let her go!
RODDY: You don't wanna do that!
Lorraine, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean anything.
I didn't mean it. She hasn't
done anything to you.
Okay? So, cut this out!
Fuck you! This is my right,
granted to me by my government.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Leave him alone! He's mine!
Door, now. Go.
(SCREAMS)
Door! Go!
Door, door, door!
Now!
Move, move, move!
(GROANS)
- SERGEANT: Go, go!
- (CALI PANTING)
I can't believe Tanya's dead.
What do we do now? Where do we go?
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Are you gonna leave us now?
What?
(VEHICLES APPROACHING)
You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
- Shh!
- How did they find us?
Stay here.
Don't move!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Do you think he's gonna come back?
What do we do if he doesn't?
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
BIG DADDY:
Come on, guys. Let's go, okay?
We don't have all night.
I want this building surrounded.
He's here.
I know it, and I want him.
Understood?
He shot me.
He shot half my team.
I want him dead.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHISPERING)
Come on, come on, come on.
BIG DADDY:
And I want the two women he saved.
They're mine.
I want them alive.
Please come back.
They found us.
Move fast, now. Come on.
Move now. We have 30 seconds.
Over the fence, fast. Now. Go!
Next. Come on, come on, come on.
(FENCE JANGLING)
(GRUNTING)
Look at me. You go, you get
over that fence, you run.
You don't stop.
You run for your life.
Do you understand?
You don't fucking wait for me.
Go. Go, go, go!
Fuck!
(WHIRRING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(SERGEANT BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOBBING)
How did you find us?
No, Cali, no.
We got lucky.
I mean, we was roaming
around out there all night.
Just picking up the people who got
away from those badass trucks.
(CHUCKLES)
We get their scraps.
Why haven't you
just killed us already?
We're not Purging tonight.
We don't need to kill anyone.
We just need money. Right, bro?
Money!
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
- (BRAKES SCREECHING)
- MAN: Whoa!
All right, let's go.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Come on, come on, let's go, let's go!
LIZ: No, no, no!
Who the fuck are they?
What the fuck are you doing to us?
I need my money, man.
Let's go, let's do this.
- What are they doing?
- (SERGEANT SHUSHING)
- MAN: It's all there.
- Yeah!
Let's go! Let's go, move!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GRUNTS)
- MAN: Get in there!
- CALI: No!
- EVA: Cali?
- Mom!
Get up the stairs, now.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
MAN: Get up! Get up!
Get on your knees.
Get down! Get down!
- Get on your knees.
- (GRUNTS)
On your knees!
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
- Where are we? What is this?
- Shh.
MAN: If you move or speak,
you will be shot.
WOMAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
the next batch has just arrived.
Let's take a look, shall we?
(DOOR BUZZING)
(PIANO PLAYING)
Quite an impressive lot, isn't it?
Ladies and gentlemen, since this
is the last Purge of the evening,
the entry price will be $200,000.
Mr. Lockhart!
And his wonderful wife, Lauren.
Fantastic.
The Hanover sisters!
Ah!
I've been waiting all evening
for your participation.
Fantastic.
And I assume you brought
your signature blades.
All right, one spot left.
Anyone else?
Mr. Hearst! Oh, wonderful!
And will your handsome
sons be joining you?
- (WHISPERING) What do you say, guys?
- Yeah, let's do it.
Ladies and gentlemen, this will
be Charles and Tom's first.
I am so happy that you have
this to share together.
Oh, and one last reminder.
The weapons rack is stocked
with the latest and the greatest.
And my personal favorite
is the Mauser Elite
SSX Double Barrel.
It has a delicate trigger,
and smoothest discharge.
It is so precise,
- it's as if God handcrafted it himself.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
Well, that will do it.
Purgers, please suit up.
Good luck.
Good luck. We'll see you shortly
on the hunting grounds.
Get up. Come on!
Get up! Get up! Get up!
MAN: Quit stalling!
Come on!
- Move your ass!
- CALI: Okay!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Move it! Go!
- Move it!
- Get in there!
Stay close to me.
Follow me. Move.
Get down.
Get down, get down.
Wait.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
SHANE: What is this?
We're being hunted.
SHANE: What?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
ALL:
Blessed be the New Founding Fathers
for letting us Purge
and cleanse our souls.
Blessed be America, a nation reborn.
All right, they're here.
(INAUDIBLE)
(GUNSHOTS)
SERGEANT: They're coming,
and they got night vision.
I gotta take one of them down.
If we can't see, we're dead.
We should come with you.
- No, no, no. I need you to stay here.
- Don't go. I'm scared.
I'm coming back,
I'm coming back. Stay here.
(SCREAMING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (MAN GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
MAN: No! (GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL PANTING)
- Are you okay?
- Fine.
We only get two sets of
eyes now, okay? Put those on.
I took out four of these fuckers.
There's three left.
It's loaded. You point and you shoot.
Someone's coming right at us.
Light him up.
(MAN GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(BOTH PANTING)
SERGEANT: They're going.
LIZ: They're all gone.
- They're leaving.
- (WHISPERING) Get down, get down.
- (ALL PANTING)
- Is it over?
Stay down.
We need help right now.
They've killed five people.
They've killed five of us.
LIZ: (WHISPERING) They're gone.
What the fuck?
What was that?
There's a whole fucking army.
I don't have any more bullets.
Just hold my hand, baby.
(WHISPERING)
They're not gonna let us out of here.
You make them earn it.
I'm sorry for everything.
(PANTING)
- I love you. I need you to know that.
- (MACHINE GUN FIRING)
(GASPS)
No!
No. Okay. Come on.
(SOBBING)
Come on.
Okay.
It's gonna be okay.
You're okay.
(SOBBING)
Okay, okay.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
What is that?
Oh, my God.
WOMAN: (OVER SPEAKER)
The use of explosives
higher than Class 4 is
prohibited on Purge Night.
You will be prosecuted.
(MEN SCREAMING)
The use of explosives higher
than Class 4 is prohibited...
The use of explosives higher than
Class 4 is prohibited on Purge Night.
You will be prosecuted.
The use of explosives higher than
Class 4 is prohibited on Purge Night.
You will be prosecuted.
Do not fire! We're here to help you!
Take positions over there.
We need a firing line. Let's go!
(GRUNTING)
Who the fuck are you?
MAN: Nobody special.
Just some people who don't necessarily
agree with the Purge is all.
(GUNS FIRING)
You're with Carmelo Johns.
(PANTING) Yes.
CARMELO:
Fuck the New Founding Fathers!
Fuck you!
Fuck your money!
And motherfuck the Purge!
- (GUNS FIRING IN DISTANCE)
- Carmelo!
- We're over here.
- (MAN GRUNTS)
I know you.
You once said that
the market mentality would no longer
keep the American people stunted.
"We are outraged and
we're fighting back."
- (GUNS FIRING)
- (MAN GRUNTING)
Nice to meet you, too, young lady.
There's a lot of them out here.
(WHISPERING)
Yeah, well, there's more of us.
We're more pissed off.
It's time for them
to feel what it's like.
Change only comes
when their blood spills.
You might wanna get out of here.
It's about to get nasty.
(LIZ WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
SERGEANT: Hey.
We gotta go.
Look at me.
He's gone.
Come on.
I wanna Purge.
Look, we'll take care of her.
- (GUN FIRING)
- (MAN GRUNTS)
Are you sure?
MAN: Go. We got it.
Come on.
I'm sorry.
MAN: Here, take it. (PANTING)
Get ready to bleed, rich bitches!
This is our time now!
(GUNS FIRING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Get out of the car.
Leave the keys and get out
of the car. Get out of the car!
Oh! Oh, God, no!
- No, don't shoot me. No. No, don't shoot me.
- SERGEANT: Look at me!
- Please, don't shoot me.
- You don't deserve to live, you piece of shit.
- (WHIMPERING)
- You remember me, okay? You remember me.
No!
Now, run.
- Run! Run!
- (WHIMPERS)
Faster!
CALI: Look, it's almost over.
(PANTING)
No, there's still time. I can make it.
I can make it.
MAN: (OVER SPEAKER) There isn't
much time left in this year's Purge.
Get out there and make
yourself better citizens.
God be with you all.
You want to tell us
what we're doing here?
Do you see that house on the corner?
The owner of that house
killed my son 12 months ago.
(SERGEANT SIGHS)
Nicholas
was coming home from school,
and he swerved off the road.
That bastard's blood alcohol level
was three times the legal limit,
but, you know, he got off
on a technicality, so...
Him and his wife and
his two little kids,
well, they live in that house,
happily ever after.
Two weeks ago, I came here
and I disabled his back barricade.
That's what we're doing here.
I want you both to stay in this car,
do you understand me?
I don't want you to move.
You'll be safe.
- It's almost over.
- Don't, please.
Let go of my arm.
You can just stay here with us.
- And we can drive away and it'll be fine.
- Let go of my arm.
Let go of my arm.
No, please. I know. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry about what
happened to your son.
Let go of my arm!
Stay in this car.
(RAPID TICKING)
WOMAN: (ON TV) There are five
minutes remaining in this year's Purge.
Hey.
- (MAN GRUNTS)
- (WOMAN GASPS)
No! Don't talk.
Shut your mouth.
I'm not here for your kids.
- I'm here for you.
- MAN: Okay.
Get up.
MAN: No, no, no.
- Come on, come on, come on.
Get up, get up, get up.
- (WOMAN GRUNTING)
MAN: No, please don't...
Shut up, or I'll shoot
you in the face!
- Shut up! Get down!
- MAN: Okay! Okay, okay!
You get on your stomach.
Lay down, flat.
- Look at me. Look at me.
- MAN: Okay, okay.
- Look at my face.
- Okay.
- Do you remember me? Look at my face!
- Do you know what you took from me?
- I know.
You took my boy! You took my boy!
You took my fucking boy!
- MAN: I am so sorry.
- You took my son.
You killed my son, you son of a bitch!
WOMAN: Please! Please don't do this.
Look at me. Look at my face.
Did you see him when you
hit him? Did you see him?
Tell me what he looks like.
Tell me what he looked like!
- Tell me what he looks like.
- MAN: I'm so sorry for what I did.
Tell me you saw his face!
- Tell me you saw his face!
- I saw him.
You're gonna pay for
what you did to me.
- For what you did to my boy.
- No, please.
MAN: Please!
(SCREAMING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
We found your car, Sergeant.
Your plates told us who you were.
It was easy to see where
you were headed tonight.
Hell, I would've done the same thing.
There's an unwritten
Purge rule, Sergeant.
Don't save lives.
Tonight, we take lives.
We make things manageable for us.
Unfortunately, the citizens
aren't killing enough.
So, we supplement it all
to keep things balanced.
It's important work the NFFA does,
and we can't have any interference.
We can't have heroes.
Oh, no, sir.
No heroes.
I hope you feel cleansed.
Blessed be America,
(COCKING GUN)
a nation reborn.
(GUNSHOT)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
(ALARM RINGING)
Oh, no. Oh, God.
EVA: Oh, my God.
Oh.
(PANTING) You got a car?
- Uh... Uh, yes.
- You got a fucking car?
- Go get it now!
- Yes, okay. Okay!
EVA: Okay!
Okay. Come on, Cali.
Come here and help me now, okay?
Look at me!
Do you want him to survive?
Then it's up to us. We gotta
help him now, okay? Okay?
On three, we're gonna pick him up.
One, two, three!
- (SERGEANT GRUNTING)
- Come on!
Come on!
Hurry up and get that car!
Okay.
- Hospital's not far.
We'll be there in minutes.
- (SERGEANT GROANING)
Come on, just hit it! Go, go, go!
(PANTING)
You did it.
You saved us.
So, please, just let us
take care of you, okay?
(SIRENS WAILING)
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
It's over. It's over.
MAN: (OVER SPEAKER)
Just after 7:00 a.m., March 22nd,
and The Annual Purge
has just concluded.
This is your American
morning news program.
Reports are coming in from
all around the country,
as police, firefighters and
paramedics take to the streets,
assisting victims of last night.