(SNORING)
(ALARM CLOCK RINGING)
MAN ON RADIO: Good morning.
It's 8:00 in wonderful
Coombs County,
where once again
state police have refused
to confirm or deny
more of those mysterious
"lights in the sky" sightings
by local residents.
Roving air reporters spoke
with Miss Josie Floss,
who made just such a sighting.
JOSIE: I've seen those
lights with my own eyes.
And when I called the police,
they told me it was swamp gas.
Bullshit! Ain't no swamps
in Coombs County!
I tell you,
with them illegal aliens...
Gonna be a sparkling day.
Sparkling.
ELVIRA: (EXCLAIMING)
Makes me crazy! Clara!
Clara!
My electric's gone
out again, Clara!
I'm gonna miss my soaps!
Oh, stop your yakking.
CLARA: Bill?
Bill, Elvira's
blacked out again.
Pass the word.
Have a nice day, honey.
Okay, thanks, Mrs. Boone.
You, too.
BILL: Elvira's got no electric.
She can't see her soaps,
she'll hyperventilate.
Great day for a picnic,
Maggie!
Can't wait, Mr. Boone.
Catch yourself a big one!
If I can!
Granny, I fixed your lunch
and put it in the fridge.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Have fun, child.
Sure you're gonna be okay?
I'll be fine, dear.
Now you just run along. Bye!
Hi, Mrs. Rogan.
Hi, Maggie.
Did you find that
picnic basket yet?
It's in the living room.
Oh, thanks.
Where's Alex?
Where else?
Right.
Louis.
Good morning,
space-son Louis.
(MAKES FARTING SOUND)
Earthling.
Louis!
CLARA: Jane!
(LOUIS MAKING BEEPING NOISES)
Elvira's electric
is out again,
and she's gonna get hyper
if she can't see her soaps!
Granny, tell Elvira
that Alex will be over
to patch her electric
in time for the soaps.
- I'll tell her, Jane.
- Elvira!
Louis!
CLARA: Elvira!
(MAKING BEEPING NOISES)
Louis!
Go tell Alex that I need him.
Beware, aliens.
Louis Rogan,
the cosmic cadet,
the space avenger,
is on your case.
VIDEO GAME VOICE:
Greetings, Starfighter!
You have been recruited
by the Star League to
defend the Frontier
against Xur and
the Ko-Dan Armada.
Get ready.
Prepare for blastoff!
(ENGINES ROARING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay. Let's go.
Prepare for target
light practice, Starfighter.
Mom's looking for you, Alex.
Right there!
Aim.
They're all through the center.
Shoot them, okay?
Now from the bottom up, okay.
There's one right over there.
Okay, doing good.
Right up there.
Move your head,
will you, Louis?
Uh, sorry.
(HUMMING)
(HORN HONKING)
BOY: Maggie!
Hey, you guys.
Hi. How you doing?
Come on, Alex.
They're here!
Maggie, queen
of the trailer park!
(ALL CHATTERING)
Well, Starfighter Alex Rogan
requests permission
to turn the bridge over
to my little brother,
Louis, sir!
Okay, you dorks are dead.
You are defeated.
25 cents more, please.
Oh, crapola.
BOY 1: Rogan, come on.
BOY 2: Hey, Alex,
how you doing, man?
Just a second.
BOY 3: Big Al.
Let's do it, buddy!
What are you doing?
Come on, Alex.
Hurry up!
Alex, did it come yet?
Uh, no. I don't think so.
What's it this time, Rogan?
You joining the Foreign Legion?
Yes, sir, folks.
Step right up.
Meet boy adventurer
Alex Rogan
on the last leg of his
worldwide tour to nowhere.
Funny, Blake.
You guys think I'm
gonna hang out here,
watch you shine your pickup,
go to the drive-in,
get drunk and throw up
every Saturday night,
go to City College
like everybody else?
Forget it, man. I'm doing
something with my life.
BLAKE: Mr. Serioso.
JANE: Alex!
Yeah?
Honey, Elvira's
electric is out.
Oh, Ma, that's gonna
take all day.
I was going to Silver Lake.
Honey, I know. I'm sorry.
I'm working lunch and dinner.
I'm gonna be
in town all day!
Oh, all right.
Okay, Ma. I'll do it.
Thanks, honey.
MAGGIE:
We're gonna be late.
Look. You. . .
You'd just better
go ahead without me.
No. Alex, I'll stay.
(ENGINE STARTS)
No. That's okay.
This'll take a while.
I'll catch up with you later.
Alex. . .
(BOYS WHOOPING)
(CHUCKLING)
BOY 1: Bye-bye, Rogan!
BOY 2: See you, dude!
JANE: Alex, come help me!
ELVIRA: Hey, Alex.
Could you give me a hand here?
JANE: Thanks, Alex!
MAN: What should
we do tonight?
MAN 2: I don't know.
How about cards?
Hey, that's a good idea.
But we played cards last night.
Well. . .
The missus wants to go into
town tonight and go dancing.
The fish were really biting
down thereat the stream.
It was pleasant fishing today.
Yup. It's gonna be
pleasant tomorrow, too.
Gonna be a pleasant
summer according to
Farmer's Almanac.
Yeah. I love
the Farmer's Almanac.
I've been reading it
for years.
VIDEO GAME VOICE:
Greetings, Starfighter.
You have been recruited
by the Star League
to defend the Frontier against
Xur and the Ko-Dan Armada.
Yeah. Yeah.
Get ready.
Prepare for blastoff.
Prepare for target
light practice, Starfighter.
Oh, hi, Alex.
Hey, Otis.
(EXPLOSIONS)
Where's your Maggie?
Good question.
Out having a good time,
I guess.
Oh. And you never
have a good time.
Is that it?
Oh, sure. I love patching
30-year-old fuse panels
and plunging people's toilets.
Otis, I never even
get a chance
to have a good time around here.
Things change. Always do.
You'll get your chance.
Important thing is,
when it comes,
you got to grab it with both
hands and hold on tight.
Enemy squadrons in
Sectors 3, 6, 7 closing fast.
Thanks, Jack.
You're welcome.
- Good night, Maggie.
- Good night.
(HORN HONKING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
Thought you were gonna
meet me at the lake.
What happened?
Same thing that always happens.
I couldn't get away.
(ALARM BLARING)
Where's everybody else?
Oh, they went to a movie.
Old Jack Blake just happened
to be going your way, huh?
Enemy squadron in Sector 3.
He said it was on his way home.
Blake lives on
the other side of town.
Come on, Alex.
I wanted to get back to you.
Okay?
Good show, Starfighter!
Way to go.
Alex, look!
Oh, my God.
What is that? 900,000!
900,000!
You gonna bust the record!
Hey! Hey! Listen up,
everybody!
Alex is going for the record!
Record?
Take. . . Take a hand.
OTIS: Got them!
Oh, he's gonna get that one!
(FIRING)
You can do it!
Otis?
(ALL CHATTERING)
Otis, what are you yelling about?
What's wrong?
Come on! Come on!
He's going to bust the record!
(ALL CLAMORING)
Hurry! Hurry!
Everyone get back!
Don't crowd him!
I said, get back!
Alex, you never
got this far before!
Go, Alex!
(ALL ENCOURAGING)
Good boy!
Ko-Dan command ship
entering kill zone.
Command ship!
Oh, command ship!
What's a command ship?
You can do it, Alex!
You can do it!
One more now. Come on!
That's the one!
That's the one we want!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Yeah! Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN: Good night.
Way to go, Alex!
WOMAN: Good night, kids.
Alex, you're something else.
You're wonderful, boy.
Thank you.
MAN: If I said it once,
I said it a thousand times.
That boy's gonna go places.
That's one smart boy.
Good night, Alex.
"Good night, Alex" ?
Wait a second.
Maggie? Maggie?
Hold on a second.
Where are you going?
What's wrong?
Well, I guess it just hit me.
You really are leaving
here, aren't you?
Of course, I'm leaving.
We're both gonna leave here.
- Both of us, Alex?
- Yeah.
We talked about this.
When I get to school,
I'm gonna find a place
and I'm gonna come
back and get you.
Well, what about Granny?
Granny?
Truth is, you're scared
of leaving this trailer park.
I'm not scared of leaving
this trailer park, Alex.
Hey. Listen.
Whatever happens, it's you and
me forever, right?
Right?
I love you so much, Alex.
I'll always love you, Maggs.
Diarrhea.
GRANNY: Maggie! Maggie!
Alex, I got to go in.
Good night.
- Good night.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Someday they're gonna say,
"This is where it all began."
What?
Mom, I finally broke
the Starfighter record.
Oh, that's nice, dear.
Nice? It's stupendous!
Uh, Alex,
Mr. Brenner knew that
you'd want to see this
as soon as possible,
so he brought it
by the diner and. . .
Well, I was so excited,
I opened it.
Oh, that's okay.
What is it?
It's about your loan.
You can still go to City College
with your friends.
VIDEO GAME:
Greetings, Starfighter.
You have been recruited
by the Star League to
defend the Frontier.
You have been recruited...
Greetings, Starfighter.
Get ready.
Prepare for blastoff.
(BEEPING)
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
(VOICE BECOMES GARBLED)
(BEEPING)
(AIRCRAFT DESCENDING)
Hello. Excuse me, son.
Store's closed, mister.
I'm not here for cigarettes
or bubble gum, my boy.
Can you tell me
the name of the person
who broke the record
on that game over there?
Where I might find him?
Alex Rogan.
You're looking at him.
Alex Rogan. Aha!
- Who are you?
- Centauri's the name.
I invented Starfighter,
which is why I'm here.
- It is?
- It is.
We have to talk about a matter
of utmost importance.
Step into my office.
That's it. Come on now.
Nothing to be afraid of.
Oh, yes. Say hello
to my assistant, Beta.
Howdy.
Ow!
I must congratulate
you on your virtuoso
performance, my boy.
Centauri is impressed.
I've seen them come
and I've seen them go.
But you're the best, my boy.
Dazzling.
Light years ahead
of the competition.
Which is why
Centauri is here.
He's got a little
proposition for you.
Are you interested?
(CHUCKLES)
I guess.
(ENGINE SURGES)
Hey!
What are you doing?
Listen.
Centauri wants to
keep it for a surprise.
Trust me. Oh, you're
gonna love it. Love it!
(CHUCKLES)
The amusing thing about this,
it's all a big mistake.
That particular
Starfighter game
was supposed to be
delivered to Vegas,
not some flea-speck
trailer park
in the middle of tumbleweeds
and tarantulas.
So, it must be fate,
destiny, blind chance,
luck, even,
that brings us together.
And as the poet says,
"The rest is history."
(BEEPING)
Where are you going?
Where are you taking me?
I told you. I wanna
save it for a surprise.
Hey. Are you the kind of kid
who reads the last page
of a mystery first?
Who pesters the magician
to tell you his tricks?
Who sneaks downstairs to peek
at his Christmas presents?
No. Of course you're not!
(TAUNTINGLY) That's why
I'm not gonna tell you.
Oh, God.
Besides, I just love
surprises, don't you?
Hey, look out!
- Stop!
- Oh, dear!
Hit the brakes! Hey. . .
(EXCLAIMING)
(EXCLAIMS)
CENTAURI:
Shifting into star drive
at Columba Zeta.
Hold tight.
(CENTAURI SPEAKING
ALIEN DIALECT)
(FEMALE VOICE ON RADIO
SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
(MALE VOICE ON RADIO
ALEX: Hey.
Hey, let me out of here!
(BEEPING)
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
(VOICE ON PA
SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
There's a perfectly logical
explanation for all this.
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
Hey! Wait!
Where you going?
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Hi! How are you?
What is this?
Listen. Do you speak
English? I'd. . .
This is nice but. . .
(MAKES PURRING NOISE)
(SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
(CENTAURI SPEAKING
ALIEN DIALECT)
(SMACKS LIPS)
Centauri,
what's going on here?
He's just saying
how delighted he is
that you're here.
And if there's
anything he can do
to make your stay
more enjoyable,
just give him a ring.
My stay?
What are you talking about?
Where are we?
Welcome to Rylos, my boy!
Rylos?
Wait a minute. You mean. . .
You mean like in a game?
Oh, he's quick.
He's quick. He's very quick.
He's speechless.
So long, Alex! Have fun!
May the luck of
the Seven Pillars of Gulu
be with you at all times.
Oh, someday these cheapskates
will thank Centauri. Trust me.
(EXCLAIMS IN ALIEN DIALECT)
Where the hell is June?
Yolanda, baby!
(GROANING)
LOUIS: Hi, Maggs.
Hi, Louis.
Is he up?
Yeah. He's been up
all night moaning.
Alex?
Your mother told me
about the loan.
Is there anything I can do?
Listen. I'll be next door
if you need anything, okay?
(WHEEZING)
(BEEPING)
(VOICE ON PA
SPEAKING ALIEN DIALECT)
(ALARM BLARING)
Gunstars.
I got to be dreaming.
(SPEAKS ALIEN DIALECT)
Yeah, right.
(IMITATES ALIEN DIALECT)
(MAN SPEAKING ON PA)
Listen, there's been
a big mistake.
MAN ON PA:...immediately
after situation report.
Navigation...
Welcome to
Starfighter Command.
You speak English?
No. You hear English,
thanks to your
translator device.
Hurry up.
We haven't got much time.
The briefing begins immediately.
Join the other recruits.
Wait a minute!
What are you talking
about, recruits?
(ALL MUTTERING)
I don't believe this.
MAN ON PA:
Attention. Attention, please.
Ambassador Enduran has arrived
and will now address
Starfighter Command personnel.
As you all know, we have
been on a desperate quest. . .
Excuse me. Excuse me.
ENDURAN: . . .to find
Starfighters and navigators.
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
(GRUNTING)
I should. . . I should
crush you to gorun dust!
I'm sorry. . .
It was an accident.
I didn't mean to
step on your. . .
Whatever that is.
ALIEN: (WHISPERING)
Hideous creature.
ENDURAN: If I may continue.
Our forces have. . .
You don't trifle with a Bogati.
They love to fight.
That's why they're
perfect for this war.
Did you say "war"?
But of course!
Why else do you
think you're here?
You were recruited
by the Star League
to defend. . .
". . .to defend
the Frontier against Xur
and the Ko-Dan Armada."
Eons ago,
our ancestors created
our great Frontier,
a barrier of energy
encircling the peaceful
systems of the universe,
and forever shutting out
the scourge that lurks beyond.
Fellow Rylans,
because of a dark betrayal,
our Frontier
will soon collapse.
(ALL MURMURING)
So we turn to you,
Starfighters and
your navigators.
For of all the billions
of creatures in the Star League,
only you few were
found to possess the
gift.
You, and you alone,
stand between us
and the black terror
of the Ko-Dan.
Victory or death!
ALL: Victory or death!
MAN ON PA: Now,
Starfighters, if you will
reach underneath your seats,
you will find a packet
which contains one hand...
This is a restricted area,
off-limits to. . .
(LAUGHING)
My apologies, Starfighter.
Star Navigator First Class Grig
at your service, sir!
(LAUGHING)
Hi. I'm Alex Rogan.
I was playing this
game back home,
and this guy came up to me.
Only he's not a guy.
He's an alien, right?
And I get into his car.
Only it's not a car.
It's a spaceship.
And, there's been a big mistake.
Am I to understand
you're actually declining
the honor of becoming
a Starfighter?
You got it.
Extraordinary!
For eons,
all creatures have dreamt
of being Starfighters.
- Where you from?
- Earth.
And we're not at
war with anybody,
except each other.
Earth? Earth isn't
a formal member of
the Star League,
and isn't due to be
approached until it matures.
This is all highly irregular.
Tell me.
Who recruited you?
Centauri.
There he is.
That's him!
Centauri.
I might have known.
(SINGING QUIETLY)
Up to your old Excalibur
tricks again, eh, Centauri?
Did it ever occur to you
that it is against the law
to recruit from worlds
outside the Star League?
Earth's in danger,
too, isn't it?
And, no, I did not
use the Excalibur test.
It was called a video game.
What's all the brouhaha?
After all,
he does have the gift!
This may come as
a bit of a shock to you,
but he doesn't want
to be a Starfighter.
Doesn't want to be a. . .
Are you a coward?
Are you crazy?
You didn't tell me
about any of this!
Return the money, Centauri!
Return the money?
Are you delirious?
Do you know how long
it took to invent the games,
to merchandise them,
to get them into
the stores by Christmas?
It must be terribly
embarrassing for you,
and I do sympathize.
However. . .
But I saw him fight!
He could be the greatest
Starfighter ever!
That was a game, Centauri.
A game?
(SCOFFS)
You may have thought it was a
game, but it was also a test.
Aha! A test!
Sent out across the universe
to find those with the gift
to be Starfighters.
And here you are, my boy.
Here you are!
Right! Here I am,
about to be killed!
Killed.
(LAUGHING)
You don't seriously think
it's dangerous, do you?
Don't be silly! Trust me!
Xur!
Xur?
Yes, Father, your mighty Frontier
grows weaker by the moment.
Do not call me father!
You are no longer my son!
You're an outcast!
Why have you returned?
I have returned for
the good of all Rylans.
With an armada of
Ko-Dan warships behind you?
There are some Rylans
who would welcome me, Father.
Star League justice
put down your Xurian cult.
Your followers are
few and scattered.
Star League?
A refuge for weak worlds
not worthy to be our equals!
That is for the Rylans to decide,
and not for a dangerous and
evil child such as yourself.
And yet, it is this child
who caught your master spy.
(SCREAMING)
Hear me, Rylans!
When the green moon
of Galan is eclipsed,
Ko-Dan Armada will invade,
not even your mighty Starfighters
will be able to save you.
We shall see, Xur.
We shall see!
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
You still want to go?
And miss all the excitement?
Little brat.
I invent the game,
find the kid,
drag him up there,
and he doesn't want
to be a Starfighter.
I give up!
ROBOT: Control, do you copy
our star angle difference
from parking angle?
Delta beta two at six,
delta gamma three at five.
Emperor Xur ordered me
to bring his scepter.
Let him enter.
ROBOT: Target vector
remains on scope.
Just like your Ko-Dan emperor's,
isn't it, Commander Kril?
It takes more than
a scepter to rule,
Xur, even on Rylos.
You're right, Kril.
It does take more than a scepter.
(LAUGHING)
How long must we endure this fool?
We have a break in the Frontier.
Fire the meteor gun!
My dear Ko-Dan friends!
Lest we forget,
it was your emperor who granted
me command of this Armada.
For only I hold
the secret to the Frontier.
Only I know the location
of the Starfighter base.
And therefore,
only I will give
the order to fire!
Forgive me, Xur.
You are forgiven,
Commander Kril.
Meteor gunner. . .fire.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Sergeant!
I have an unidentified
incoming object in
Sector 31, sir.
They're headed for
the base! Alert!
We are under attack!
(ON PA) I repeat,
we are under attack!
Activate automatic repulser guns.
(BEEPING)
(FIRES)
WOMAN ON PA:
Condition Red! Condition Red!
At last, it is done!
Soon the Frontier will be down
and they will bow
to their new emperor!
Or I will darken
the sky with their ashes.
Commander,
the Xurian spy reports
that one Starfighter has escaped.
Escaped?
(TOOLS CLANKING)
You sure I can't give you a hand?
You've done quite enough
already. Thank you.
Well. . .
It's only a few more
miles from here. I guess. . .
I guess I can walk it.
So long!
Bye, Centauri!
Oh, Alex!
Here!
Hey, listen. I can't take
a present from you, Centauri.
(SCOFFS)
He reduces me to poverty again
and he thinks I'm
giving him a present.
What a world this is.
What is it, then?
It's a second chance, my boy!
If you change your mind,
just tap the communo-crystals.
Keep it.
Alex, Alex!
You're walking away
from history. History!
Did Chris Columbus say
he wanted to stay home? No!
What if the Wright Brothers
thought that only birds should fly?
And did Geloca think the Yulus
were too ugly to save?
Who's Geloca?
Never mind.
Listen, Centauri.
I'm not any of those guys.
I'm a kid from a trailer park.
If that's what you think,
then that's all you'll ever be!
(ENGINE FIRES)
Hey, Maggie!
Listen to this. You're not
going to believe this.
I told you, Alex.
Me and my. . .
How did you put it?
"Strange sexual urges,"
aren't talking to you anymore.
(SNORING)
(LOUD SNORING)
Who's there!
Shh! You're gonna
wake up Louis.
Hey, you look like me!
Of course I do.
I'm the beta unit.
What the hell's a beta unit?
A beta unit is a simuloid,
an exact duplicate of you,
only not as loud.
Huh?
I was in the starcar,
remember?
We shook hands?
I became you, unfortunately.
Let me get this straight.
You're a robot?
I beg your pardon.
I'm a state-of-the-art,
top-of-the-line beta unit,
put here as a courtesy replacement
for while you're away.
Lucky me.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing back?
Are you kidding?
It's war up there!
Oh. Save the whales
and not the universe, huh?
Well, why don't you
go up there and fight?
Simuloids can't fight.
We're not allowed.
Well, tell them that
you're me! Pretend!
Be quiet, Alex.
BOTH: Sorry, Louis.
MAN: Thanks for the lift!
MAN 2: Sure thing, buddy.
See you around!
MALE VOICE:
Greetings, Starfighter.
You have been recruited
by the Star League
to defend the Frontier
against Xur and...
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(RASPING)
And, hey,
what did you do to Maggie?
Do to her?
We're sitting outside,
looking at the stars,
and she sticks her
tongue in my ear.
I screamed.
I'll apologize tomorrow, okay?
You're not gonna be here.
You're going back
with Centauri right now!
What's up, Alex?
Back to sleep, Louis, or I'm
telling Ma about your Playboys.
(FEIGNS SNORING)
You're blowing it, Alex!
What the shit?
I said, back to sleep,
Louis, or I'm telling Ma
about your Playboys!
Come in, Centauri.
Come on. Get back here.
And take your Tonka toy with you.
VIDEO GAME:
Greetings, Starfighter.
You have been recruited
by the Star League to
defend the Frontier
against Xur and
the Ko-Dan Armada.
Greetings, Starfighter.
You have been
recruited by the Star League
to defend the Frontier
against Xur...
(VOICE BECOMING GARBLED)
Where are you?
Come on, where are you?
Centauri?
MAN: Greetings, Starfighter!
(ROARING)
(YELLING)
Oh, shit!
Come on, Alex.
Don't be such a wimp!
(ROARING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Centauri, look out!
What the. . .
(GRUNTS)
Phew!
Foul stench.
Dirty creatures.
(COUGHING)
Get a good look, Alex.
You can bet your asteroids
you'll be seeing more of them.
What?
This is a Zando-Zan.
An interstellar hitbeast,
compliments of Xur.
Xur? Why is he after me?
Somehow he found out
you're a Starfighter.
BETA: So you see, Alex,
you got to go back.
You got no choice.
'Cause if you stay down here,
you're dog food.
Trust Centauri, my boy.
Because in two hours, this place
will be crawling with 10 Zando-Zans
with just one thought
on their microscopic little minds,
kill Alex Rogan.
Kill Alex Rogan.
BETA: He's right, Alex.
At least up there you'll have
a fighting chance in a Gunstar.
Exactly.
Meanwhile, down here,
they'll be going after Beta.
- Beta.
- Beta?
Of course. What do you
think he's here for?
Wait a. . .
Wait a second here, Centauri.
Alex, look out!
(GROANING)
(ROARING)
Centauri!
Beta, get a doctor!
No. No native cures.
No witch doctors.
I'm fine. Just a scratch.
Now face it, Alex.
You're a born Starfighter.
Are you with me?
Okay, let's go, Centauri.
Good luck, Alex.
You, too, Alex.
(COUGHING)
Centauri to Starfighter Command.
Come in, please.
Hey, Centauri.
MAN ON PA:
Attention all personnel.
Starcar is approaching
Docking Bay 12.
Centauri! Centauri!
Hey, hit the brakes!
- Grig! Hey, Grig!
- Alex!
They got Centauri.
He's hurt!
He's right over here.
Ah, you see?
Centauri brought him back!
Yes, I see.
Don't talk.
Does he have my money, Alex?
I have a fortune
for you, Centauri.
Now, please be still.
(COUGHING)
ALEX: It's here. It's all here.
Piles and piles of it.
All for you.
Ah. . .
At last.
Alex, I want you know,
it was for the greatest
good I brought you back.
Of course, it. . .
It never hurts to be rich.
Until the next dimension,
old friend.
I'm sorry, Alex.
Centauri?
The Frontier could
collapse at any moment.
Alex!
(EXCLAIMS)
(FLUTTERING)
(LOUD FLUTTERING)
(ELECTRONIC SQUEAKING)
BETA: Now I need an ear job.
Dying here. Dying.
(GASPS)
Alex, what the hell's going on?
Louis, you're having
a terrible nightmare.
Go back to sleep.
Louis!
Oh, no.
Am I to understand there's a beta
unit taking your place back home?
He's trying.
So it's safe to assume that Xur
thinks you're still on Earth.
Yeah.
That could work
to our advantage,
theoretically.
Ah! Now you look human!
Is this my Gunstar?
This is a prototype,
different from the other ships.
She has a greater range,
more power,
and a slight
weapons modification.
And, of course,
she's got deflective plating,
so she can withstand
several direct hits.
From here, this is
where I navigate the ship,
maintain life support
and propulsion systems.
Okay. Where do I sit?
Way up there,
in the gunnery chair.
Hang on!
Okay.
Now, climb into the gunnery chair.
Now, I'm moving you
into launch position.
There in front of you
are the two switches
for your heads-up display.
Turn them on.
While you're engaging the enemy,
the screen will reflect all
battle instruments towards you.
Hey, where did it go?
It's still there,
suspended in a xenon mist.
But it's only visible
if you look dead ahead.
Ah. Got it.
The lever on your left
is the chair controller.
As you can see,
all guns will track
with your every move.
(CHUCKLES)
Grasp the target control
with your right hand.
At your fingers is the weaponry,
the lasers, photon bolts. . .
Photon bolts and
the particle beams.
Wait a minute.
This is just like back home.
- What's this?
- Careful, careful,
that's Death Blossom,
a weapon of last resort.
Luckily, I was in here
working on it when the
hangar went up.
Now, are you ready?
All systems, go!
(BEEPS)
Ignition!
When did the hangar go up?
I told you,
when Xur attacked.
And where were the Starfighters?
In the hangar!
You mean they're dead?
Death is a primitive concept.
I prefer to think of them as
battling evil in another dimension.
In another dimension?
How many are left?
Including yourself?
Yeah.
One!
One?
(INAUDIBLE)
Hold it.
There's no fleet,
no Starfighters,
no plan?
- One ship, you, me, and that's it?
- Exactly!
Xur thinks
you're still on Earth.
Classic military strategy.
Surprise attack.
It'll be a slaughter!
That's the spirit.
No, my slaughter.
One ship against
the whole Armada?
Yes. One Gunstar
against the Armada.
I've always wanted to fight
a desperate battle against
incredible odds.
Target lights, Alex.
Target lights?
Yes. You might want
to squeeze off
a few rounds while
you have the chance.
Just work the bugs
out of the system.
After all,
it is her maiden voyage.
Steady.
Don't fight the chair.
Take your time.
Watch your gun sights.
Lead your targets.
And above all, relax!
Terrific.
I'm about to get killed
a million miles from nowhere
with a gung-ho iguana
who tells me, "Relax."
Interstellar!
(FIRING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Alex!
Sorry.
Okay, now, come on.
Ease it up.
Okay.
Oh, that's. . .
That's it. Easy.
Nice and easy. Yep.
A little bit more
and we'll get it
in there, now.
(YELLS)
Alex!
Sorry. Hi, Maggs.
Alex, are you all right?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm. . . I'm fine.
Come on. Try it again.
Did you smell anything?
Like what?
Like a Z. . .
Forget it.
I just wanted to say I'm sorry
for slapping you last night.
Oh, that's okay, Maggs.
I deserved it.
I'm sorry.
Well, maybe we can
make it up to each other
tonight at Silver Lake?
(GROWLING)
The Armada will break
through the Frontier here,
and reach Rylos in 20 klicks.
Squadrons of deck fighters
will precede the mother ship.
Squadrons?
How many squadrons?
It isn't the number
of squadrons that concerns me.
It's this communication
turret that sends out
the commands to the deck fighters,
which enables them to act
as one during the fight.
Wait a second.
We knock out the turret
to get the fighters.
But to get the turret,
we have to get through
the fighters.
We're dead.
I'll have it all figured out by
the time we reach the Frontier.
(ALARM BLARING)
What's that?
The Frontier.
Now, that's strange.
What's a cargo ship
doing this close to the Frontier?
GRIG: Hail.
This is Gunstar One.
I repeat, this is Gunstar One.
Identify yourself, please.
Alex, look out.
A Xurian ship!
Congratulations, Alex.
This is your first live target.
Live?
Within range in five klicks.
Get ready!
I've blocked its beam of frequency,
so it can't report
back to the Armada.
- Fire when ready!
- Grig, wait!
We mustn't lose them
in these caves, Alex!
Fire!
Shoot, Alex!
Shoot!
(GASPS)
You did it!
(LAUGHING)
I did it? You did it!
You almost got me killed!
(STAMMERS)
My deepest apologies, Alex.
I had hoped that by putting
you in the thick of battle,
a great Starfighter
would emerge.
But, alas.
Perhaps there was never one
within you to begin with.
I shall take you home.
You still may live a long
and fruitful life back there.
That is, until the
Ko-Dan reach Earth.
But then again. . .
(CLEARS THROAT)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, yo, Blake!
Make that sucker
blast, man!
You got it, dude!
All right!
(LAUGHING)
(WHOOPING)
So Blake comes back in
to grab his pants, right?
Sees her old lady,
and says,
"I hope this doesn't rule out
dinner on Tuesday night."
That's my man!
Alex, are you okay?
Hmm?
Yeah, sure. Why?
I don't know. You're
just acting spaced out.
You're. . .
You're not yourself.
Well, if you were me,
what would you be
doing right now?
Well, for one thing,
I'd be trying to enjoy myself.
Leaning back.
Kidding around. Laughing.
Laughing?
Well, it's a start, Alex.
Laughing.
(LAUGHING EXAGGERATEDLY)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(SNIFFING)
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
Nice place.
Reminds me of home.
This reminds you of home?
Oh, yes.
I live below ground
with my wifeoid and
6,000 little Griglings.
At least, until Xur
turns them into slaves.
Where does your kind live?
Oh, uh, houses, mostly.
That's caves above ground.
See, here.
Here's my family.
See, that's. . .
That's my folks
and my brother, Louis,
and that's Maggie.
Uh, we live in a mobile home.
That's a cave that goes places.
Only we never went anyplace.
A mobile cave that
never went anywhere.
Fascinating.
Yeah, but we have
below-ground caves
near the trailer parks.
Me and my brother,
Louis, used to play
hide-and-seek in them.
Hide-and-seek.
What is it, Alex?
Well, I was just thinking,
maybe we could hide here,
let the Armada pass by,
and then hit the turret
from behind.
Then we might take
them by surprise.
Your plan might
really have worked.
What a pity there
are no Starfighters
left to carry it out.
Yeah. Yeah.
(BEEPING)
A Xurian base!
Two more dead ahead!
Closing fast!
(EXPLOSION)
Earth course is logged
into navigational beams.
Grig?
What is it, Alex?
Maybe there is
a Starfighter left.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(BETA MUMBLING)
BETA: Ow!
What's wrong?
Should I put my tongue
in your ear now?
Don't bother, Alex.
Well, it's just. . .
I'm kind of new at
these gland games.
What are you talking about?
It's like you're
a million miles away, Alex!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(AMPLIFIED BY BETA)
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait. Darling.
Darling, forgive me.
"Darling, forgive me."
Come on!
You're my Juliet. My Venus.
(INAUDIBLE)
"You're my Juliet. My Venus."
Alex!
ALEX: All the other girls
meant nothing to me.
It was you, you, you.
WOMAN: Shut up and
talk dirty to me.
(WOMAN GIGGLING)
"The other girls
meant nothing to me.
It was you, you. . ."
Should I talk dirty to you now?
(GRUNTS)
That does it.
Oh, God.
All right. I give up.
I'm not Alex Rogan.
What?
I'm a beta unit.
I'm an exact duplicate of Alex.
He's up there
saving the universe,
while I'm down here
for target practice.
(MAGGIE SCREAMS)
See?
Alex! Or whatever you are.
Wait. Wait.
What are you do. . .
Let me go.
If that Zando-Zan reports back
that I'm not Alex,
Alex is in big trouble!
- You're staying here.
- No, I'm not.
I'm not staying anywhere until
I find out what's going on!
(HORN HONKS)
Hey, my truck!
Hey, hey, come back!
Scratch that paint,
and you're dead, Rogan!
Ready to invade, Commander.
Invade.
Commander, the Xurian ships have
not answeredour invasion code.
The Frontier is down,
the moon is eclipsed,
the Starfighters are dead.
Invade!
All squadrons ahead, half speed,
with energy probes on.
Energy probe.
Shut down, Alex. Shut down.
Power off.
(GRUNTING)
MAGGIE: Alex? In space?
- Is this for real?
- Yes! That's what I'm telling you!
It's all for real!
Well, then, don't talk.
Drive!
(GRUNTING)
(SIGNAL DRONING)
Commander Kril, we're getting
a signal on the alert frequency.
Acknowledge.
(SIGNAL DRONING)
There it is.
All right.
Now, when I give the signal,
we're gonna jump! Okay?
- What do you mean, "Jump" ?
- We're gonna ram him.
What?
Extermination Emissary
Zeta 6, one message.
Ready? Jump!
Alex!
(EXCLAIMS)
"The last Starfighter. . ."
You owe me one, Alex.
Alex!
Transmission pulsars
have stopped, Commander.
The last Starfighter. . .
Is dead!
The last Starfighter is dead!
Nothing can stop us now.
Ahead full.
To Rylos!
The command ship!
There!
The turret at the far end!
I see it.
Good luck, Starfighter.
Thanks, Grig.
For everything.
I love you, Alex Rogan.
Six.
Heads-up display. Check.
Five.
Lasers. Check.
Four.
Particle beam. Check.
Three.
Proton bolts. Check.
Two.
Chair control. Check.
One.
Let's do it.
(BEEPING)
ROBOT: Tracking alert.
Unidentified craft.
What is it?
Wait.
Gunstar!
So, the last Starfighter is dead?
This has gone far enough.
Seize him!
How dare you?
I am the Emperor of Rylos!
I and I alone
command this entire op. . .
Release me! I command you!
You will pay for this
with your lives!
All guns fire!
There it is, the turret!
Alex, now!
Yeah!
Got it!
Hurry, Alex! Fire!
The Armada's almost to Rylos!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
VOICE ON PA:
Escape pod activated.
Escape pod ignition.
The Gunstar is gone from our sensors.
Alert wing commanders.
Communication turret is destroyed.
All communication radar systems
are out, Wing Commander.
Proceed with a visual
attack formation.
Life support good.
Ammo packs at peak.
I think we've got
to use Death Blossom.
Remember,
Death Blossom delivers
only one massive volley
at close range.
Theoretically.
What do you mean,
"Theoretically" ?
After all, D. B.
has never been tested.
It might overload the systems.
Blow up the ship.
What are you worried about,
Grig?
Theoretically,
we should already be dead.
Mmm-hmm.
Open Death Blossom petals.
Switch is on.
Do not trigger D. B.
until we're within range.
Just use your lasers
until I give the signal.
Remember to lead. . .
I've been recruited
by the Star League
to defend the Frontier.
Now, are you ready?
This is it. Here we go.
Charge!
(SNICKERING)
(FIRING)
On your right!
Your left!
Evade!
Power packs are low!
We need time to recharge!
Laser power draining!
Grig, my weapons are gone!
Should I do it?
Easy, easy.
Wait till they're all
in Death Blossom range!
(EXPLOSIONS)
Fire!
We did it.
Yes, we actually did,
didn't we?
(RUMBLING)
ALEX: The command ship!
Commander, our guns are out.
Damage control is repairing them.
Forget the guns!
Ramming speed!
Grig, we need power!
Death Blossom's drained all power.
I'm working on it.
I'm trying to run boost.
All we have left is
life support power!
Grig!
All right!
Weapons on!
We have them now!
Fire. Fire!
(FIRING)
(GROANING)
Damage report!
(ALARM BLARING)
Guidance system out.
Auxiliary steering out.
Divert!
She won't answer the helm!
We're locked into the moon's
gravitational pull!
What do we do?
We die.
(EXPLOSION)
(ALEX WHOOPS)
On behalf of the Star League
and all citizens of Rylos,
I congratulate you on
your dazzling victory.
Thank you.
Thanks.
But as you know,
the Frontier is down,
Xur escaped,
and there is still danger.
So I was wondering if you
wouldn't be willing to stay on,
and rebuild the Starfighter Legion.
Wait a minute.
Rebuild the Legion?
Yes.
Of course, you'd have the help
of an old friend.
An old friend? Who?
Centauri!
I thought you were dead!
Me die and miss all
the excitement? Oh, no.
I was merely dormant
while my body repaired itself.
Now, I won't bore
you with details.
Suffice it to say,
you're on Rylos, my boy.
Stop thinking human.
That's lesson number one.
Now, lesson number two,
you've got a good thing going here.
Keep smiling.
Don't blow it.
Lesson number three,
always trust Centauri.
(ALL CHEERING)
CENTAURI: Alex, they love you!
You see, all Rylos
is behind you.
You've got to stay, Alex!
You will stay, won't you?
CENTAURI:
Of course, he'll stay.
(CHUCKLING)
That's very reassuring,
Centauri.
Grig, I leave it in
your capable hands.
I'll stay.
JANE: Alex! Alex!
MALE VOICE: Greetings...
Greetings, Starfighter.
Bunny, have you seen Alex?
Can't say that I have.
Well, ask Maggie.
She knows where he is.
She was with him.
Maggie, where's Alex?
Yeah, where's my truck?
Where's your boyfriend?
Mrs. Rogan, about Alex,
you see, he's. . .
(ALL EXCLAIM)
- What is it? What's going on?
- I don't know.
(GASPS)
Oh, my God!
(WHOOPING)
All right!
We're being invaded!
Maggie.
(MACHINERY HUMMING)
Alex?
Hi, Maggs.
Alex,
is it you?
I mean, is it really you?
Look!
My God.
It is you.
It's Alex! Alex!
Alex, what is going on here?
What is this thing?
(CLAMORING)
Is this your spaceship?
I don't know what's gotten into him.
I don't understand that.
It's so strange!
Wait. Hold it.
Hold it, everybody.
Alex, what is all this?
I've been to another planet, Ma.
Another planet?
(ALL MURMURING)
Who was it helpedfix my antenna?
Yeah, who stole my truck?
And cut my electric?
And ruined my stove?
Oh, that was. . .
That was a beta unit.
OTIS: Beta unit?
A robot.
Robot? What the. . .
Come on!
(GASPS) A monster!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(SCOFFS)
A monster!
He got them chains on him.
All right! It's an alien!
Oh, no, wait!
Hey, hey!
Granny, put away that shotgun.
What's wrong with you?
This is my friend Grig.
I want you all to
meet my friend here.
MAN: You got to be kidding!
Grig, this is Mrs. Boone.
Hello.
And this is Elvira.
Delighted.
Me, too. How you doing?
I do well.
And this is Granny.
How do you do?
And this here's Otis.
A pleasure.
Any friend of Alex. . .
And this is Maggie.
A very large pleasure.
Hi.
(CHUCKLING)
You must be Louis!
I hear good things about you.
Hear that, you slimes?
I'm famous.
(ALL LAUGHING)
And this is my mom.
You should be proud
of Alex, Mrs. Rogan.
You must all be proud of him.
He saved the Star League
and hundreds of worlds,
including Earth.
ELVIRA:
Oh, for heaven's sake!
Oh, my God!
Time to leave, Alex.
Alex?
I have to, Ma.
They need me up there.
Oh, Alex, I always knew
you'd leave someday,
but I never expected this.
Gee, can I go, too, Alex?
Can I?
Sorry, squirt.
There's only enough
room up there
for me, Grig,
and Maggie.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Alex, I don't think I can. . .
What? Come here.
Come here.
Why else do you
think I came back?
- Well. . .
- Didn't we say we'd be together?
Well, yeah, I mean,
together here or
in the city.
But. . . But up there, Alex. . .
Maggs, you got to come.
You see, I'm not. . .
I don't know when
I'm gonna be back.
(SIGHS)
Don't you see? This is it.
This is our big chance.
It's like what Otis says,
when it comes,
you got to grab on
with both hands
and hold tight.
Well, what about Granny, Alex?
You're right. I'm scared
of leaving here.
Why can't you just stay?
Maggie, I have to leave,
and I want you to come with me.
GRIG: Alex! Hurry!
Well, I got to go.
Bye.
Alex, we can't hold off
their radar any longer.
Yeah, okay.
I got to go, Ma.
Bye. Take it easy.
Bye, darling.
So long. So long, everybody.
MAN: Bye, Alex!
LOUIS: Bye!
WOMAN: Bye, Alex. Bye, Alex!
(ALL BIDDING FAREWELL)
GRIG: Alex!
Granny. . .
Be sure and write, or whatever
it is they do up there.
Alex! Wait, Alex!
(INAUDIBLE)
Get back! Come on!
Bye!
Keep your distance!
Watch what you're doing.
Keep your distance, now.
This baby really packs a punch!
(ALL BIDDING FAREWELL)
Bye.
Look at him! Bye!
OTIS: Bye.
Oh, go on.
They're gonna be happy
up there! So long, Alex!
So long, Alex!
(ALL CHATTERING)
We're gonna be famous,
aren't we, Otis?
Yes, sir!
The whole world, the whole
universe is gonna know about it!
Starlite, Starbrite,
the place where Alex and
Maggie left for the stars!
Louis! Louis!
MALE VOICE:
Greetings, Starfighter.
You have been recruited
by the Star League
to defend the Frontier against
Xur and the Ko-Dan Armada.
Wow!