[Airplanes Approaching]
[Speaking Japanese]
[Men Laugh]
[Blowing Whistle]
[Yelling in Japanese]
[Band Plays Stately March]
[Speaking Japanese]
[Both Laughing]
Sir, the Japanese ambassador
has just arrived.
He should be up shortly.
Thank you.
The Japanese are stalling, Henry.
You know that.
When Nomura took over as ambassador,
I had some hopes
of settling our differences,
but our meetings so far
have been unproductive.
He brings me proposals.
I offer compromises.
He brings me counterproposals,
and so on.
I tell you, Henry, Nomura was sent here
to buy time,
and that's what he's doing...
at our expense.
The president believes him
to be a man of honor,
that we can trust him,
that we can deal with him.
Ah, Mr. Ambassador,
we meet again.
Oh, it is always a pleasure.
I assume you know Mr. Stimson,
the head of our
War Department.
Oh, yes, of course.
Mr. Ambassador.
I do hope, Mr. Stimson,
your presence here
does not indicate
anything ominous.
Of course not, Mr. Nomura.
Mr. Nomura,
won't you please sit down?
Oh, thank you.
Well, since our last talk
a week ago,
I have received certain,
shall we say,
questions from my government
to put to you
to clarify certain matters.
[Typewriters Clacking]
Good morning, Colonel.
There it is.
This little machine enables us
to intercept every word
that passes between Tokyo
and all Japanese embassies.
The coded material
is fed into that machine.
It goes round and round
in there
and comes out here
decoded in Japanese.
All we have to do is translate it.
We're decoding this stuff
quicker than the Japanese embassy
right here in Washington.
No wonder you decided to call it
Operation Magic.
The latest intercept, sir.
Thank you.
Well, things are getting
a little hotter in the Pacific.
As long as we're
sharing this assignment,
take a look at this.
Behold the 12 apostles,
the chosen few
who have been authorized
to see the magic intercepts.
But Hap Arnold, chief of the air corps,
isn't on the list.
No.
And not one of our
overseas commanders.
[Yells]
[Man Yelling in Japanese]
Man:
Stand by.
Execute.
[The Star-Spangled Banner
Playing]
Look at that entrance to the harbor.
Sink one good-size ship
in the channel,
and you've bottled up
our whole fleet.
Well, you know as well as I do
this harbor is a mousetrap.
The fleet should have
stayed in San Diego
where it belongs.
I made the mistake
of pointing that out to Roosevelt.
Well, Jim, in the service,
we're expected to obey orders.
We're also expected
to exercise our own good judgment.
I didn't ask for the job.
Sorry, Kim,
but this was my command,
and it's become a habit to worry
about the security of the fleet.
I can't forget that the British,
flying some old biplanes,
torpedoed and sank 3 Italian battleships
at Taranto,
a harbor very much
like this one.
Well, I share your concern, Jim,
but C.N.O. Doesn't think
it can happen here.
And why not?
Well, a torpedo
dropped from a plane
would plunge to a depth of 75 feet or more
before it levels off.
I know, and Pearl
is only 40 feet deep.
I'm still worried, Kim.
[Speaking Japanese]
[Men Yelling]
[Indistinct Announcement
Over Loudspeaker]
Ten-hut!
[Airplanes Approaching]
Hey, do those planes
have to be parked like that,
way out on
the edge of the field?
Man:
Standard dispersal procedure, General,
in case of enemy air attack.
There are 130,000
Japanese on this island.
Our main problem is sabotage.
It would be too easy for enemy agents
to sneak in at night
and blow up every damn one of those
planes if they're left out there.
Make a note of that, Fielder.
We'll have to make changes.
Yes, sir.
Ten-hut!
[Intercom Buzzes]
Yes?
Admiral Halsey's here to see you, sir.
Send him in, please.
Bust me...
break me...
court-martial me,
draw and quarter me.
If you think that they're going to send
any one of my ships
on convoy duty in the Atlantic...
I tell you, Kim, I think they've gone nuts
back in Washington.
Now, how in the hell am I supposed
to fight a task force if they
send my destroyers and my cruisers
to the Atlantic?
That damn ocean is a swimming hole
compared to the Pacific.
What are we, a fighting fleet,
or are these toy boats
we have out here
so that the Japs can buy them
at Christmas?
All right, Bill.
Now, ease it off.
It's not just you.
They've asked for some of our
tankers, too.
How do they expect us to feed
these fat battlewagons
that are parked out here
in this landlocked duck pond?
You're still planning on rotating
at least half of them
at sea, aren't you?
I was.
Now, look, Kim, you've got
to make them understand
what's going on out here.
I'm going to do everything I can, Bill,
even if I have to go direct
to the president.
By God... I knew
there was at least one man
in this man's navy
who hadn't gone nuts.
[Band Plays Stately March]
[Speaking Japanese]
[Yelling in Japanese]
And we go on to say,
"It should be noted
"that Japan has never preceded hostile action
by a declaration of war.
"We have concluded
that it is a possibility
"that a fast-raiding
Japanese carrier force
"might arrive in Hawaiian waters
"with no prior warning
from our intelligence service.
"The most favorable time to the enemy
would be dawn.
"He probably would employ
a maximum of 6 carriers,
strike on a weekend.
We recommend that the air corps"...
I read it.
Yes, sir.
I appreciate the work
that you and General Martin
have put in.
These army-navy reports
are very useful to General Short
and myself.
General Martin, you don't pull
any punches, do you?
Hmm.
"We recommend that the air corps
"maintain a thorough 360-degree search
of the Hawaiian area
during daylight."
"This will require a force
of 180 B-17 airplanes."
We can't search the sea approaches
around Hawaii
unless we have the planes, sir.
180 B-17 s.
For God sakes, man,
that's more
than the total number
existing in the States.
Now, it looks fine on paper,
but that's not
a paper fleet out there.
[Airplanes Approaching]
Squadron from the Enterprise.
Bill Halsey's
working the tails off his men.
Wish we had more like him.
Makes the most of what he's got,
doesn't keep asking
for the moon.
[Loud Splash]
Well, not one bomb
anywhere near the target
for the past hour.
Your pilots can see it, I suppose.
Who's next?
It's Anderson, sir.
Well, that's more like it.
Maybe your boys are finally
getting the reins.
I hope so, sir.
Now, who's next?
Lieutenant Dickinson.
Well, you can tell Lieutenant Dickinson
for me,
he couldn't hit a bull in the butt
with a bass fiddle.
Yes, sir.
Man:
Attention!
Carry on.
Man:
Is this it?
Yes, sir. Our new radar.
It's a remarkable
scientific achievement,
capable of spotting an intruder
on the sea or in the air
and at quite a long range.
Now, listen, Colonel, as you know,
we're short on patrol planes.
We're going to have to rely
on this thing to detect the enemy.
General, radar should do the job.
Well, what's it doing here?
Why isn't it set up?
We were about to truck it up
that mountain, General.
That peak up there is the ideal spot
to put our main radar post.
At that height,
it'd be clear of all interference.
Obviously.
But, sir, we can't get permission
to put her up there.
Permission?
The National Park Service,
Department of the Interior.
All of this belongs to
the Hawaiian National Park.
Hawaiian National Park.
Yes, sir, and the Wildlife Preservation Society's
raising hell, too.
And we can't get permission?
No, sir, not unless
we want to fight them.
Fight them? You're damn good and right
we're going to fight them.
Now, you make a note of that, Fielder.
Yes, sir.
Wildlife Preservation Society.
There's no use, Al.
I spoke to General Miles,
and he took it up
with General Marshall.
The order stands.
The president is off the ultra list.
That's incredible...
Withholding information
from the president.
A security man found a copy
of one of our intercepts
in a wastebasket
at the White House.
The truth is, the brass don't trust
some of the men
close to the president.
Does anyone trust anyone anymore?
Do you even trust your own wife?
Do you?
Yes. Come to think of it,
I believe I do.
Part 2 of number 1390, Colonel.
Tokyo to embassies
in Washington and Berlin.
Thank you, Miss Cave.
The Japanese are moving south
to occupy French Indo-China.
This is big trouble.
Yeah.
Well, ultra list or not,
someone has to tell the president
about this one.
"Therefore we will impose a full embargo
on all trade with Japan."
"We do not anticipate immediate
hostile action by Japan,
"but you are furnished this information
in order that you may take appropriate
precautionary measures."
Appropriate precautionary measures.
What the hell does that mean?
Now, this is signed jointly by General Marshall
and Admiral Stark.
Till we know how the Japanese
are going to react,
we're not going to take any chances.
We go on full alert.
Both:
Yes, sir.
Stark says they don't anticipate
hostile action.
Why send a warning at all?
Damn it.
Damn it. Why can't Washington
give us the full inside story?
I'd sooner form my own opinion.
"Don't anticipate hostile action."
Well, all right,
we'll go ahead.
Increase the air and sub patrols.
Alert all senior commanders.
Yes, sir.
Maybe out of all this we can find out
how well we can function.
[Ring]
Kaminski.
This is Captain Earle.
We're going on full alert.
Yes, Captain.
Notify all ship, sub, and air patrols.
[Air Raid Siren Sounding]
What the hell is going on here?
Just what do you think you're doing?
Carrying out orders.
General Short's main concern is sabotage.
Now, all air craft
not being readied for flight
from now on will be parked together
in the center of the field,
where they can be kept
under guard day and night.
Suppose there's an air raid?
They hit one plane, and the whole shebang
goes up in flames.
Well, I'm sorry.
General's orders.
[Shouting]
[Yelling in Japanese]
Well, it's not an ideal radar site,
but at least we've got a permit.
Let's get the other
mobile units working.
That's easier said than done.
What do you mean?
Well, first we have to get all
6 units adjusted,
then link them by phone
to Headquarters.
That means equipping
an information center
and training men to operate it
so they know what to do with the information
when it comes in.
Take it easy, Verne.
You'll figure it out.
Yeah. I'll figure it out.
Well, don't just stand there.
You guys know how
to operate this thing.
We know the theory, sir.
Well, let's put that theory into practice.
Switch on.
Yes, sir.
You two stay put and keep watching
that screen.
In 2 hours, close down.
I'll send a truck back
to pick you up.
Excuse me, sir,
but what are we
watching for?
Anything unusual,
any large blip
coming from the sea.
Colonel, sir, if we do spot something,
what do we do?
Report it to Headquarters, damn it!
How, sir?
What?
How? We haven't got a telephone, sir.
There's a gasoline station
about a mile down the road.
They must have a phone.
Man: We've got 183 combat planes
on this base, General.
The way they're parked right now,
a one-eyed monkey hanging
from a 10-cent balloon
could scatter them all to hell
with just one hand grenade.
Don't blame me.
General Short gave the order.
[Knock on Door]
Come in.
Sir, Lieutenants Taylor and Welch.
OK. Send them in.
You two men get in your planes
and fly over to Haleiwa.
Yes, sir. May I ask what our orders are
when we get there, sir?
Just sit tight.
Listen for the phone.
That's all.
Both:
Yes, sir.
Haleiwa's one of several subsidiary fields.
We send those 2 up there,
2 more here.
Only way I know to disperse
a few of the planes.
If I thought I could get away with it,
I'd send them all
to the neighbor islands.
You know why we're being transferred.
Them poker games.
Been winning too often.
Yeah.
Some sucker loses his shirt,
so he bitches to the general.
That's it.
[Speaking Japanese]
Nomura has offered his resignation
several times,
but Tokyo won't let him quit.
Instead, they're sending
a second ambassador...
Kurusu... to help him out.
But do you really think
this Kurusu can do any good?
Well, I doubt it, Frank.
He's hardly the most tactful choice.
When he was ambassador
in Berlin,
he signed the Axis pact
on behalf of Japan.
You sick or something?
No.
I've been piecing together
this batch of new intercepts,
and a frightening picture
is taking shape.
Oh?
"Ambassadors Nomura and Kurusu
"recently asked their government
to extend the deadline
for suspending negotiations
between Japan and America."
You remember that,
don't you?
Yeah.
Now, according to
this latest intercept,
Tokyo wants to conclude
negotiations with us
no later than November 29,
after which, and I quote,
"Things are automatically going to happen."
Now, look at this intelligence report
from the British.
"5 Japanese troop transports
with naval escort
were sighted off Formosa,
heading south."
But we've been monitoring
the Japanese fleet,
and most of it appears to be
in home waters.
I'm not so sure.
I'd make a bet they're going to attack us.
Japan is going to attack us.
The 29th is only 4 days off,
and the 30th is on a Sunday.
We're going to be attacked
on Sunday the 30th of November.
The pieces fit together.
But can you prove it?
No, but I'm convinced I'm right.
- Oh, Miss Cave.
- Yes?
Get me General Marshall.
Oh, General Marshall's
at Fort Benning, sir.
Then get me the secretary of war.
I've got the evidence, Al...
and I'm going to make the brass around here
admit I'm right.
Huh...
Bratton's analysis makes sense.
His facts are undeniable.
Henry,
I'm washing my hands
of the whole matter.
From now on, it's in your hands
and in those
of the Navy Department.
I'll call the president.
A message declaring a full alert
will be sent out.
Sir, General Marshall
anticipated an emergency like this.
Before he left
to attend army maneuvers,
he made out this alert order.
[Speaking Japanese]
"Japanese future action
unpredictable,
"but hostile action
possible at any moment.
"If hostilities cannot be avoided,
"the United States desires that Japan
commit the first overt act"...
Wait a minute.
Read that again.
"If hostilities cannot be avoided,
"the United States desires that Japan
commit the first overt act."
"This policy
should not be construed
"as restricting you to a course of action
"that might jeopardize your defense.
"Prior to hostile Japanese action,
"you are directed
"to undertake
such reconnaissance
"and other measures
as you deem necessary,
"but these measures
should be carried out
"so as not to alarm
the civil population
"or disclose intent.
By order of General
George C. Marshall."
Not to alarm the civil population.
Hmm. What do you make of it?
Well, if you ask me, sir,
it's double-talk.
But the chief of staff
doesn't go in for double-talk.
We're going on alert.
Again, sir?
But the men are confused.
So many alerts.
Damn it, unconfuse them.
Yes, sir.
"Japanese naval forces may attack
"the Philippines, Thailand,
"the Kra peninsula, and Borneo.
This dispatch is to be considered
a war warning."
Well, there it is, gentlemen.
You now have as much information
as I do.
That's the second warning in 3 days.
"Japanese naval forces may attack
the Philippines, Thailand,
the Kra peninsula, and Borneo."
They don't even mention us.
That's correct. I think it should be
considered as significant.
Well, gentlemen,
we have a job to do.
Washington wants us to send
a squadron of our fighters to Midway
and another squadron
to Wake.
When can you sail?
Well, the Enterprise
can sail tomorrow morning.
I'll need a day or two.
We're just completing some essential repairs
on the Lexington.
Well, try to hurry things along, John.
I want you out there to probe.
I want those planes up in the air
morning and afternoon.
I want a report on any
sign of hostile ships.
Understood.
Do you want to take any of
the battleships along?
Hell, no.
They're too slow.
If we're going to probe,
let's probe, John.
If we have to run,
we don't want anything holding us up.
I think you're right.
I'm not ready to commit them myself,
not until I really know
when and where.
Do you still plan
to keep half the fleet at sea
while the carriers are gone?
No. It's too risky.
I'll have to keep
the entire fleet
here at Pearl
while you're away.
Get out.
Get back as soon as you can.
I don't like the idea of having
my battleships here
without naval air cover.
Let's get going.
- Yes, sir.
Man:
Admiral.
Kim...
level with me.
I want a clear directive.
If I run into a Jap ship,
what action do I take?
Use your common sense.
That's the best
damn order I ever had.
If I see so much
as a sampan near us...
I'll blow it out of the water.
[Speaking Japanese]
[Typewriter Clacking]
What is it this time getting me over here
on the double?
Tokyo has alerted
their embassy here
to stand by for a very long message
in 14 parts.
Look, Ruf, you scared the pants off me
and everybody else last week.
We're not going through
that again, are we?
I think you should see this, sir.
It's the latest report
on those Japanese troop transports.
Remember those 5 troop ships?
Well, they're still heading south
"with a naval escort
only 14 hours
from the coast of Malaya."
What about their aircraft carriers?
We don't know.
Intelligence was keeping track of them
until recently.
Now we've lost them.
Look, Ruf,
try to put yourself in their minds.
Where do you think I have been
the past week, night and day?
I am still convinced
they're going to attack us.
What can we do
that we aren't doing already?
I don't know about you,
but I know what I'm going to do.
Miss Cave,
where is everybody?
Oh, well, it's past 12:00, sir.
They've already gone.
Well, get them back.
On the weekend?
Yes, on the weekend.
[Speaking Japanese]
[Static]
[Hawaiian Music Playing]
This completes 13 parts?
Yes. Tokyo's holding
the final part till morning.
Wonder why.
It's almost 9:00.
Look, Harry, I'm going to make the rounds
with what we have here.
Thank God the president's
back on the list.
Have Lieutenant Brotherhood call me
the moment the missing part comes in.
Right.
You're late.
Well, I was...
Please take me
to the White House.
Well, if you'd told me
we were invited to the White House,
I would have dressed.
You know Mrs. Roosevelt.
Although she's very informal personally,
I've heard she's a stickler for protocol...
Darling, will you shut up and drive?
[Man Yelling in Japanese]
Well?
Captain Wilkinson's.
Did you see the president?
No. I saw Harry Hopkins.
And did he read the, um,
whatever it is?
No. He doesn't have the key.
I gave the pouch
to a naval aide who was there,
Lieutenant Schulz.
He took it in to the president.
And the president has a key,
I suppose.
Yes, of course he has.
And did Lieutenant Schulz
say anything?
He said thank you.
Darling, step on it, will you?
Sir, Admiral Stark can't be reached.
Should I take this
to the chief of staff?
Well, it's after 10:00.
General Marshall always retires early.
I see no reason to disturb Marshall
with something that's incomplete.
Wait till you have the final part.
Yes, sir.
If you're so concerned, Commander,
why don't we call the chief of war plans...
Admiral Turner?
His telephone doesn't answer, sir.
You don't happen
to know where he is.
No idea.
The president has already discussed it
with me.
He sent a personal message
to the Emperor,
but when the final part
of this comes in,
I'd like to see it then.
Good night, Commander.
Good night, sir.
I was starved. I bet you are.
Oh, thank you, dear.
Can't you tell me anything...
even a hint?
You'd think the world
was falling apart.
Admiral Stark
talked to the president.
What did the president say?
He sent a personal message
to the Emperor.
Gordy. Chad.
Gordy, we've got those 12 B-17 s
coming in from California
in the morning.
Yes, sir. General Martin arranged for
Honolulu radio to stay on the air all night
so the planes could
home in on the station.
Fine. You and I had better be
in that control tower
at 7:30 sharp.
Yes, sir.
Dear.
Tyler.
I've got a job for you.
Sir.
Report to the new radar center
at Fort Shafter at 0400.
At 4:00 in the morning?
From 4-7 a.m.
Our marvel of science
only operates for 3 hours.
Lucky boy.
Lucky boy!
Well, Captain, how's it feel,
first command, first patrol?
Just fine, Mr. Goepner.
In fact, I think I'll turn in for a while.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
[Loudspeaker Buzzes]
[Shouting]
[Telephone Rings]
[Ringing Continues]
Here you are.
Kramer.
Al. Al, listen to this,
the 14th part...
"Will the ambassadors
please submit our reply
"to the United States government
at precisely 1 p.m.,
December 7 th, your time?"
1 p.m.?
"Precisely 1 p.m. Your time."
I'll be right over.
Look at the time
on the president's message.
I should have had it hours ago.
As you well know, sir,
communications have been delayed
and frequently garbled lately.
Or deliberately interfered with.
Gene...
call the foreign minister.
Tell him I want an immediate audience
with the Emperor.
Bratton: "After deciphering..."
"part 14..."
"destroy at once..."
"your cipher...
machine..."
"all codes..."
"and secret... documents."
Have this translated immediately.
- Give a copy to Kramer as soon as he comes in.
- Yes, sir.
I've got to get the hell out of here.
Hey, look at this.
Finally got one.
Man:
Communications center.
It even works.
That's great.
Opana Point communications check.
Are you reading us?
Coming in loud and clear.
Where is the general?
It's Sunday, sir.
Operator, this is Colonel Bratton.
Connect me with the chief of staff...
General Marshall.
Yes, at his quarters,
Fort Myer.
[Ring]
Chief of staff's quarters.
Sergeant Aguira speaking.
Yes, Colonel Bratton.
I'm sorry, sir.
The general isn't here.
Well, where he always is, sir,
this time Sunday morning.