Doug?
Honey, are you all right?
You're dreaming.
Was it about Mars?
Is that better?
My poor baby.
This is getting to be an obsession.
Was she there?
Who?
The one you told me about.
The brunette.
Lori.
I can't believe you're jealous of a dream.
- Who is she?
- Nobody.
"Nobody"? What's her name?
I don't know.
- Tell me!
- I don't know!
You better tell me!
It's not funny, Doug.
You dream about her every night.
And I'm always back in the morning.
Let me go!
Come on, baby.
You know you're the girl of my dreams.
You mean it?
You know I do.
I'll give you something to dream about.
The chairman defended the attack,
saying that space-based weapons...
...are our only effective defense against the
southern block's numerical superiority.
And more violence last night on Mars...
...where terrorists demanding independence...
...once again halted the extraction of terbinium ore.
Kuato and his so-called freedom brigade...
...claimed credit for this latest bombing,...
...which attempted to reopen
the sealed-off Pyramid Mines.
Mars military restored order
with minimal use of force...
...and all damage to the strategic
facility was repaired within hours.
No cameras!
With one mine already closed,
Mars administrator Vilos Cohaagen...
...vowed that troops would be used if necessary...
...to keep production at full capacity.
No wonder you're having nightmares.
You're always watching the news.
- Lori.
- Doug?
- Let's do it.
- Do what?
Move to Mars.
Honey, why do you have to spoil
a perfectly wonderful morning?
Just think about it.
Sweetheart, we've been through this a million times.
You'd hate it on Mars.
It's dry, it's ugly, it's boring.
I mean, really,
a revolution could break out there any second.
Cohaagen says it's just a few extremists.
You believe him?
Okay. Forget about it.
Absolutely not. Mars was colonized by
the northern block at enormous expense.
Our entire war effort depends on their turbinium...
...and it's ridiculous to think we're going to give it away...
...just because a bunch of lazy
mutants think they own the planet.
- Maybe we should take a trip.
- Any comment sir on the rumor...
- Lori, move. Please.  - ...that you've closed
the Pyramid Mine because you found...
...alien artifacts inside?
There's a lot better places than Mars.
What about Saturn?
Don't you wanna see Saturn?
I wish we could find some artifacts.
Our tourist industry could use a boost.
Everybody says that its gorgeous.
The fact is, it's Mr. Kuato and his
terrorists who spread these rumors...
...to undermine trust in the government.
We could take of those long space cruise,
the kind with nothing to do.
- Have you found Kuato yet?
- We don't even know what he looks like.
- What do you say?
- That's it for the news.
- Stay tuned for Christine and the weather.
- I'm late.
But first, this.
- Tonight on ESPN, the fifth game of the World Series...
- Sweetheart.
- ...live from Tokyo.
- Doug.
I know it's hard being in a new town,
but let's give it a chance, okay?
Lori don't you understand?
I feel like I was meant for something more than this.
I want to do something with my life,
I want to be somebody.
You are somebody.
You're the man I love.
Bye.
Have a nice day.
You are now entering a safety zone.
No unauthorized weapons allowed beyond this point.
Would you like to ski...
...but you're snowed under with work?
Do you dream of a vacation
at the bottom of the ocean...
...but you can't float the bill?
Have you always wanted
to climb the mountains of Mars...
...but now you're over the hill?
Then come to Rekall Incorporated...
where you can buy the memory
of your ideal vacation...
...cheaper, safer and better than the real thing.
So don't let life pass you by.
Call Rekall for the memory of a lifetime.
For the memory of a lifetime
Rekall, Rekall, Rekall
Harry.
- You ever hear of Rekall?
- Rekall?
You know, where they sell those fake memories.
Oh, Rekall.
- You thinking of going there?
- I don't know. Maybe.
- Well, don't.
- Why not?
A friend of mine tried one of their "special offers"...
Nearly got himself lobotomized.
No shit?
Don't fuck with your brain, pal.
It ain't worth it.
I guess not.
Good afternoon.
Welcome to Rekall.
Douglas Quaid.
I have an appointment.
- Bob?
- Yeah?
- Doug Quaid is here to see you. Okay.
- Yeah. I'll be right out.
That'll be just one minute, Mr. Quaid.
Thank you.
- Doug...Paul McClane. It's good to see you.
- Nice to meet you.
Come on in. It's through here.
- Go and have a seat. Make yourself comfortable.
- Thank you.
Now help me out here, Doug.
- You were interested in a memory of--
- Mars.
Yeah. Mars.
Is there a problem?
To be perfectly honest with you, Doug,...
...if outer space is your thing,...
...I think you'd be much happier with one of
our Saturn cruises. Everybody raves about 'em.
I'm not interested in Saturn.
I said Mars.
Okay. You're the boss.
Mars it is.
Now, let me see.
The basic Mars package...
...will run you 899 credits.
Now, that's for two full weeks
of memories, complete in every detail.
If you want a longer trip that'll cost
you more because it's a deeper implant.
- What's in the two-week package?
- First of all, Doug,...
...let me tell you, when you go Rekall,
you get nothing but first-class memories.
Private cabin on the shuttle; deluxe suite
at the Hilton; plus all the major sights:
Mount Pyramid, the Grand Canals...
...and, of course, Venusville.
But how real does it seem?
- As real as any memory in your head.
- Come on. Don't bullshit me.
No. I'm telling you, Doug,
your brain will not know the difference.
And that's guaranteed or your money back.
What about the guy you lobotomized?
Did he get a refund?
You're talking ancient history.
Now-a-days traveling with Rekall
is safer than getting on a rocket.
Check out those statistics.
Besides, a real holiday is a pain in the butt.
You got lost luggage, lousy weather...
...crooked taxi drivers.
When you travel with Rekall...
...everything is perfect.
So what do you say?
- All right.
- Smart move.
All right, while you fill out this questionnaire,
I'm gonna familiarize you with some of our options.
No options.
Whatever you say.
Can I ask you just one question now.
What is it that is exactly the same
about every single vacation you've ever taken?
I give up.
You. You're the same.
No matter where you go, there you are.
Always the same old you.
Let me suggest that you take
a vacation from yourself.
I know it sounds wild, but it's the latest
thing in travel. We call it "The Ego Trip".
I'm not interested in that.
You're gonna love this, Doug.
We offer you a choice of alternate
identities during your trip.
Face it... Why go to Mars as a tourist
when you can go as...
...a playboy,or a famous jock,...
...or a "Secret agent."
How much is that?
Aaah, let me tantalize you.
You are a top operative, back under deep
cover on your most important mission.
People are trying to kill you left and right.
You meet this beautiful, exotic woman.
Go on.
I don't wanna spoil it for you, Doug.
But rest assured, by the time the trip is over,...
...you get the girl, kill the bad guys,
and save the entire planet.
Now, you tell me.
Isn't that worth a measly 300 credits?
It's your first trip?
Well don't worry.
Things hardly ever fuck up around here.
Good evening... Doug.
- I'm Dr. Lull.
- Nice to meet you.
Ernie, patch in matrix 62-B-37,...
...and would you like us to integrate some alien stuff?
Sure. Why not?
Two-headed monsters?
Don't you keep up with the news?
- We're doing alien artifacts now.
- It's wild.
Yeah, they date back a million years.
- Ernie?
- That's a new one.
- Blue sky on Mars.
- Been married long?
- Eight years.
- Oh, I see.
Slipping away for a little hanky-panky.
- Not really. I was always fascinated by Mars.
- All systems go.
Number seven.
Ready for dream land?
I'll be asking you some questions, Doug,
as we can fine-tune the Ego program.
You answer honestly,
and you'll enjoy yourself a whole lot more.
- Your sexual orientation.
- Hetero.
And how do you like your women?
Blonde? Brunette? Redhead?
Brunette.
Slim. Athletic. Voluptuous.
Athletic.
Demure. Aggressive. Sleazy.
Be honest.
Sleazy...
...and demure.
41A, Ernie.
Boy, is he gonna have a wild time.
- He's not gonna want to come back.
- That's for sure.
So, what do you say?
I'm not so sure, and I don't get a souvenir.
Not true. For just a few more credits more,
we supply T-shirts, snapshots of you at the sights,...
...and even letters from the--
- What is it?
- You better get down here.
I am with a very important client.
It looks like we got another schizoid embolism.
I'll be right back.
Mr. McClane, Mr. McClane.
Bob! What's wrong?
Don't let her leave!
Get off you!
You blew my cover.
What the fuck is going on here?
You can't install a simple goddamn double implant?
It's not my fault.
We hit a memory cap.
They'll be here any minute!
They'll kill you all!
- What is he talking about?
- Let me go!
Mr. Quaid, try to calm down!
My name is not Quaid.
- Let me go! Untie me now!
- Ernie, grab his leg!
- Hold him down!
- Let me go home!
Are you all right?
Listen to me.
He's been going on and on about Mars.
- He's really been there.
- Use your head, you dumb bitch!
He's just acting out the "Secret Agent"
portion from his Ego Trip!
- I'm afraid that's not possible.
- Why not?
Because we haven't implanted it yet.
Oh shit... Oh shit...
I've been trying to tell you,
someone has erased his memory.
Excuse me.
"Someone"?
We're talking about the fucking Agency.
- Shut up!
- Bob, the client's gone.
Alright! Look. Here is what we're gonna do. Renata,
cover up any memory that he's got of us or Rekall.
I'll do what I can. It's pretty messy in there.
Ernie, dump him in a cab. Around the corner.
Tiffany, you help him.
I'm gonna destroy his file and refund his money.
And if anybody comes asking,
we never even heard of Douglas Quaid.
Where am l?
- You're in a Johnnycab.
- I mean...what am I doing here?
I'm sorry.
Would you please rephrase the question?
How did I get in this taxi?
The door opened, you got in.
Hell of a day, isn't it?
- This okay?
- Right here.
- Thank you for taking Johnnycab.
- Thank you.
Hope you enjoyed the ride.
Hey, Quaid.
- Harry.
- How was your trip to Mars?
- What trip?
- You went to Rekall. Remember?
- I did?
- Yeah, you did.
- I told you not to, but you went anyway.
- What are you, my father?
- Come on, I'll buy you a drink.
- Listen, I'm already late. Thank you very much.
Okay, bring him--
Come on, move it!
Come on, let's go have that drink.
Move it!
What is going on?
What the fuck did I do wrong?
- Tell me!
- You blabbed, Quaid! You blabbed about Mars!
Are you crazy?
I don't even know anything about Mars!
You should've listened to me, Quaid.
I was there to keep you out of trouble.
Harry, you're making a big mistake!
You've got me mixed up with somebody else!
Unh-uh, pal.
You've got yourself mixed up with somebody else.
And pivot... and serve...
...and shift... and stroke...
Very good.
Perfect form.
Hi, honey.
- What are you doing?
- Some men just tried to kill me.
Muggers? Are you all right?
No, they were spies or something.
And Harry, from work, he was the--
Get down!
- Harry from work... He was the boss.
- Take it easy, Doug, okay?
- Tell me exactly what happened? Why would
spies want to kill you? - I don't know.
- But it had something to do with Mars.
- Mars? You've never even been to Mars.
I know it sounds crazy, but you see,
I went to this Rekall place after work, and...
- You went to those brain butchers?
- Let me finish.
- What did they do to you? Tell me!
- I got a trip to Mars.
Forget about Rekall, will you!
These guys were going to kill me...
- Doug, nobody tried to kill you.
- They did.
But I killed them.
Listen to me, sweetheart.
Those assholes at Rekall have fucked up your mind...
...and you're having paranoid delusions.
You call this a delusion?
- Doug, I'm calling a doctor.
- Don't. Don't call anybody.
Lori, go! Get out!
Why are you doing this, Lori?
Talk! I said talk!
- I'm not your wife.
- The hell you're not.
I swear to God!...
I never saw you before six weeks ago!
Our marriage is just a memory implant.
You think I'm stupid?
I remember our wedding.
It was implanted by the Agency.
- And falling in love?
- Implanted.
Our friends, my job, 8 years together,
I suppose all this was implanted too?
The job's real.
But the Agency set it up.
Bullshit.
They erased your identity and implanted a new one.
I was written in as your wife so I could watch you,
make sure the erasure took.
Sorry, Quaid.
Your whole life is just a dream.
Okay, then if I'm not me,
then who the hell am l?
Beats me.
I just work here.
Doug...
There's something I want you to know.
You're the best assignment I ever had.
Really.
I'm honored.
You sure you don't want to,
just for old times' sake?
Come on. If you don't trust me, you can tie me up.
- I didn't know you were so kinky.
- Maybe it's time you found out.
Clever girl.
You wouldn't shoot me, would you Doug?
After all we've been through.
Yeah. Some of it was fun.
Nice knowing you.
Don't touch her.
Nobody here.
- Are you okay?
- I guess I blew it.
- What does he remember?
- Nothing, so far.
I've got him.
Shit, he's going for the subway.
Let's get him. Go!
Let's go. Move it.
Pack your stuff and get outta here.
What if they bring him back?
Not a chance.
The subway....Go!
Get him!
He's got a gun!
- Cut him off! That way!
- Over there!
Hold it!
The escalator.
You four go up.
You come with me.
Get out of the way!
Get out! Move!
The platform!
- Which way?
- Up to the right.
Botco.
Tomorrow's fuels, tomorrow's prices.
Don't settle for pale memories!
Don't gol for fake implants!
Experience space travel the old-fashioned
way on a real-live holiday you can afford.
I want that fucker dead.
I don't blame you man.
I wouldn't want the guy like Quaid porking my old lady.
- You saying she likes it?
- No, I'm sure she hated every minute of it.
Six-beta-nine, Six-beta-nine,
we have a live transmission from Mr. Cohaagen.
Richter here. Patch it through.
- What the fuck is going on down there?
- I'm trying to neutralize a traitor sir.
If I wanted him dead, you moron,
I wouldn't have dumped him on Earth.
We can't let him run around.
He knows too much.
Lori says he can't remember jack shit!
That's now.
In an hour, he could have total recall.
Listen to me, Richter.
I want Quaid delivered alive for re-implantation.
Have you got that?
I want him back in place with Lori.
Did you hear me?
What was that, sir?
I couldn't hear you.
I got Quaid again.
Switching to another channel sir.
I've got sunspots.
I'm
- Call him back!
- I'm losing you.
- Where is he?
- Second level. Galleria.
We should've killed Quaid on Mars.
- How we doing?
- Fine.
Zooming in.
We got him!
If you want to live, don't hang up.
- What do you want?
- They've got you bugged,...
...they'll busting on your door in about
three minutes unless you do exactly what I say.
Don't bother searching.
The bug's in your skull.
- Who are you?
- Never mind.
Wet a towel and wrap it around your head.
That'll muffle the signal.
- How'd you find me?
- I'd advise you to hurry.
This'll buy you some time.
They won't be able to pinpoint you.
- Shit!
- What?
- I lost him!
- Well, find him!
Yeah, right.
Come on. Hurry up.
You look beautiful.
Now go to the window.
Go.
Can you see me down there?
- This is the suitcase you gave me.
- I gave you?
I'm gonna set it here.
Come and get it, keep moving.
- Wait. Wait.
- What?
- Who are you?
- We were buddies in the Agency back on Mars.
You asked me, if you disappeared, to come and find you.
So here I am, good-bye.
What was I doing on Mars?
Damn!
Excuse me, ma'am. But this is mine.
- I don't see your name on it.
- Somebody left it for me.
- You go find your own bag!
- Excuse me, ma'am. But I need it.
Fuck you, you asshole!
That son of a bitch got to be around here somewhere.
That guy there.
Hello, I'm Johnnycab.
Where can I take you tonight?
Drive. Drive!
- Would you please repeat the destination?
- Anywhere! Just go! Go!
- Please state the street and number.
- Shit. Shit!
I'm not familiar with that address.
Would you please repeat--
Please fasten your seat belt.
- The fare is 18 credits, please.
- Sue me, dickhead.
We hope you enjoyed the ride.
Howdy, stranger.
This is Hauser.
If things have gone wrong,
I'm talking to myself...
...and you've got a wet towel
wrapped around your head.
Now whatever your name is,
get ready for the big surprise.
You are not you.
You are me.
No shit.
Six-beta-nine, six-beta-nine, come in.
Did you find him?
We picked up an explosion at the old cement factory.
Send two units.
We'll meet them there.
All my life I've worked for Mars Intelligence.
I did Cohaagen's dirty work.
Then a few weeks ago, I met somebody--
a woman.
And I learned a few things;...
...like I've been playing for the wrong team.
All I can do now is try to make up for it.
See there's enough shit in here to fuck Cohaagen good.
Unfortunately, if you're listening to this,
that means that he is got to me first.
And here comes the hard part old buddy.
Now it is all up to you.
Great.
- What have we got?
- He's not here.
- He's gone.
- I got a weak signal over there.
Split up. Find him.
First let's get rid of that bug in your head.
Take this thing out of the case
and stick it up your nose.
Don't worry.
It's self-guiding.
Just shove real hard.
When you hear the crunch, you're there.
Just pull it out.
And be careful.
It's my head, too.
I've got a lock!
Up. Let's go.
Now this is the plan.
Get your ass to Mars.
Then go to the Hilton and flash
the Brubaker I.D. at the desk.
That's all there is to it.
Just do what I tell you,
and we can nail that son of a bitch who fucked you and me.
I'm counting on you, Buddy.
Don't let me down.
Straight ahead.
In there.
There!
Give me that.
Shit.
Get your ass to Mars--
Welcome to the Mars Federal Colony.
For your safety and comfort, domes have been
installed to protect you from the vacuum outside.
Please do not touch
exterior windows or air locks.
I insist the air volume is limited.
No smoking is allowed anywhere in the colony.
Next.
Thank you, and enjoy your stay on Mars.
Passport.
- Come on. Get out of the way.
- Make way! Stand back.
Mr. Cohaagen wants to see you right away.
Any news of Quaid?
- Not since you lost him.
- Watch your mouth, Captain.
- So how long do you plan to stay on Mars?
- Two weeks.
Look at that shit.
- What the hell's this?
- The Martians all love Kuato.
They think he's fuckin' George Washington.
Kill the bastard.
Nobody knows who he is.
Have you brought any fruits or vegetables onto the planet?
Two weeks.
Excuse me?
It's not just graffiti.
The rebels took over the refinery last night.
No turbinium is going out.
And it gets worse.
Quaid.
- That's Quaid!
- Where?
The woman!
Get him-- her!
Arrest that woman!
Grab her!
Catch!
Get ready for a surprise!
- Open the goddamn door!
- I can't!
Open it!
They're all connected.
Then a few days ago,
Cohaagen raised the price of air.
- Again?
- Nobody on Earth gives a damn what happens up here.
They just want our turbinium
so they can zap things from space.
Excuse me. What's that?
You mean the Pyramid Mine?
I used to work there,
till they found that alien shit inside.
Well, that's a rumor, isn't it?
Think so?
Mr. Cohaagen.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Richter, do you know why I'm such a happy person?
No, sir.
Because I've got the greatest job in the solar system.
As long as the turbinium keeps flowing,
I can do anything I want.
Anything.
If fact, the only thing I ever worry about is that one day,...
...if the rebels win, it all might end.
And you're fucking making it happen!
First you try to kill Quaid,
and then you let him get away.
He had help from our side, sir.
I know that.
- But I thought--
- Who told you to think?
I don't give you enough information to think.
You do what you're told.
That's what you do.
Yes, sir.
Now let's get down to business.
We've got a tricky situation here.
Kuato wants what's in Quaid's head.
And he might be able to get it,
cause they say he's psychic.
And I have a plan to keep this from happening.
Do you think you can play along?
- Yes, sir.
- Great.
Because, otherwise I'll erase your ass.
Taxi! You need a taxi sir?
I got magazines, I got music, I got whisky.
You need a cab man?
Come on!
Good afternoon. Can I help you?
Yes I would like to have a room, please.
Nice to have you back with us, Mr. Brubaker.
Would you like the same suite?
Well. Definitely.
It seems you left something in our safe.
Could you get it please?
Identification?
- I'll go encode your room key.
- Thank you.
- There you go, Mr. Brubaker. Suite 610 in the east wing.
- Could I borrow your pen, please?
- Certainly.
Thank you.
Hey, man, you need a cab?
- What was wrong with this one?
- He ain't got five kids to feed.
- Where's yours?
- Right over there man.
Hey, asshole!
That's my fare!
Eat this!
Damn you, Benny!
Welcome to Mars, man!
- What the hell was that, an accident?
- That's the rebels man.
Let's get outta here...
...before they arrest us!
What do the rebels want?
All the usual.
More money, more freedom, more air.
So, where to?
The Last Resort.
You're getting off to an early start.
- First time on Mars?
- Yes.
Well, actually, no.
Well, sort of.
Damn! The man don't even know whether
he's been to Mars or not.
Voila. Venusville.
Hey, you see anything you like?
End of the line.
We're going to have to walk from here.
I'll show you where.
- Do you want to know the future?
- What about the past?
Come on. It's around the corner, right down this alley.
They got everything.
Not bad, huh?
Read your palm? Your mind? Read your aura?
Probe the secrets of your heart?
- I bet I can guess your birthday.
- What is it?
- You're a Taurus, right?
- How did you guess?
- Tell me something; are all psychics, uh...?
- Freaks?
Afraid so, man.
It goes with the territory.
- What happened to them?
- Cheap domes. And no air to screen of the rays.
So, there it is. The Last Resort.
You sure you want to go in here man?
- Why not?
- I know this much better place down the street--
The girls are cleaner, the liquor ain't watered down--
Sure, and you get kickback.
Hey, man, I got five kids to feed.
Take them to the dentist.
Hey, Thanks! Mister!
Listen, I'll be waiting here for you.
You just take your time.
Benny's the name. Benny!
- What do you want?
- I'm looking for Melina.
She's busy.
But Mary here, she's free.
Well, Not "free" honey, but available.
Thanks.
I'll wait for Melina.
Earth slime.
Thing is, friend, Mel's real picky.
She kinda sticks to her regulars.
She will like me.
Mel!
Hello Hauser.
Still bulging, I see.
- What you been feeding this thing?
- Blondes.
I think it's still hungry.
You got a lot of nerve showing
your face around here, Hauser.
Look who's talking.
Hey Tony. Give the big guy a break.
Relax. You'll live longer.
Come on.
- Honey, take care of Tony, will you?
- No problem.
If you need any help with this one,
give me a holler.
You son of a bitch.
You're alive?
I thought that Cohaagen tortured you to death.
Well, I guess he didn't.
And you couldn't get me a message?
You never wondered what happened to me?
Hauser, thank God you're alive.
Melin-- Melina.
Melina.
- There's something I have to tell you...
- What?
- I don't remember you.
- What are you talking about?
I don't remember you.
I don't remember us.
I don't even remember me.
What, did you get amnesia?
How did you get here?
- Hauser left me a note.
- Hauser? You're Hauser.
Not anymore.
Now I'm Quaid.
Douglas Quaid.
- Hauser, you've lost your mind.
- I didn't lose my mind. Cohaagen stole it.
He found out that Hauser switched sides,
so he turned him into somebody else: me.
This is too weird.
Then he dumped me on Earth
with a wife and a lousy job and--
Did you say wife?
Are you fucking married?
- I'm sure she wasn't really my wife.
- Oh, she isn't really your wife.
How stupid of me.
She was Hauser's wife?
- Look forget that I said wife.
- No. Let's just forget everything.
- I'm sick of hearing your goddamn lies.
- Why would I lie to you?
Because you're still working for Cohaagen.
Don't be ridiculous.
You never loved me, Hauser.
You just used me to get inside.
Inside what?
I think you'd better leave.
- Melina, Hauser sent me to do something.
- I'm not falling for it.
He said there's enough in here
to nail Cohaagen for good.
- Get out!
- You've got to help me remember!
- I said, get out!
- Melina, please!
People are trying to kill me.
Really?
All right, I'm leaving.
Baby, you make me wish I had three hands.
Well I think you're doing just fine with two.
Excuse me, baby.
We'll pick this up later.
Hey, that didn't take long.
Listen! Let me ask you a question.
Did you ever fuck a mutant?
- Take me to the hotel.
- I know these Siamese twins.
Man, you don't know if you're coming or going.
This afternoon at 4:30 p.m., I signed an order
declaring martial law throughout the Mars federal colony.
I will not tolerate any further damage
to our mineral export operations.
Mr. Kuato and his terrorists must
understand that their self-defeating efforts...
...will only bring misery and suffering to the people--
Mr. Quaid?
What?
I need to talk to you about Mr. Hauser.
- Who are you?
- Dr. Edgemar from Rekall.
- How did you find me?
- It's a little difficult to explain.
Could you open the door, please?
I'm not armed.
Don't worry. I'm alone.
May I come in?
- What do you want?   - This is going to be
very difficult for you at accept, Mr. Quaid.
- I'm listening.
- I'm afraid you're not really standing here right now.
- Ya know, Doc, you could have fooled me.
- I'm quite serious.
You're not here and neither am I.
That's amazing.
- Where are we?
- At Rekall.
You're strapped into an implant chair and
I'm monitoring you at from the psychoprobe console.
Ah, I get it.
I'm dreaming.
And this is all part of that delightful
vacation your company has sold me.
Not exactly.
What you're experiencing is a free-form
delusion based on our memory tapes.
But you're inventing it yourself as you go along.
Well, if this is my delusion,
who the hell invited you?
I've been artificially implanted
as an emergency measure.
I'm sorry to tell you this, Mr. Quaid,
but you've suffered a schizoid embolism.
We can't snap you out of your fantasy...
...and I've been sent in to try to talk you down.
How much is Cohaagen paying you for this?
Think about it. Your dream started
in the middle of the implant procedure.
Everything after that--
the chases, the trip to Mars...
...your suite here at the Hilton--these are all
elements of your Rekall Holiday and Ego Trip:
You paid to be a secret agent.
Bullshit. It's coincidence.
And what about the girl?
Brunette, athletic, sleazy and demure?
Just like you specified.
Is that a coincidence?
She's real.
I dreamed about her before I even went to Rekall.
Mr. Quaid.
Can you hear yourself?
She's real because you dreamed her?
- That's right.
- Maybe this will convince you.
Would you mind opening the door?
- You open it.
- No need to be rude.
I'll do it.
Sweetheart?
Come in, Mrs. Quaid.
- What I suppose you're not here either?
- I'm here at Rekall.
I love you.
Right.
That's why you tried to kill me.
No. I'd never do anything to hurt you.
I want you to come back to me.
- Bullshit.
- What's bullshit, Mr. Quaid?
That you're having a paranoid episode
triggered by acute neuro-chemical trauma?
Or that you're really an
invincible secret agent from Mars...
...who's the victim of an interplanetary conspiracy
to make him think he's a lowly construction worker?
Stop punishing yourself, Doug.
You're a fine, upstanding man.
You have a beautiful wife that loves you.
Your whole life is ahead of you.
But you've got to want to return to reality.
Let's assume I do. Then what?
- Swallow this.
- What is it?
It's a symbol of your desire to return to reality.
Inside your dream, you'll fall asleep.
All right, let's say you're telling
the truth and this is all a dream.
Then I could pull this trigger,
and it won't matter.
- Doug, don't.
- It won't make the slightest difference to me, Doug,...
...but the consequences to you would be devastating.
In your mind I'll be dead.
And with no one to guide you out,
you'll be stuck in permanent psychosis.
Doug, let Dr. Edgemar help you.
The walls of reality will come crashing down.
In one minute you'll be the savior of the rebel cause,
and the next thing you know...
...you'll be Cohaagen's bosom buddy.
You even have fantasies about alien civilizations,
as you requested.
But in the end,
back on earth you'll be lobotomized!
So get a grip on yourself, Doug.
And put down that gun!
Good.
Now take the pill and put it in your mouth.
Swallow it!
Go ahead, sweetheart.
Now you've done it.
Now you've done it!
That's for making me come to Mars.
You know how much I hate this fucking planet!
Cuff him.
- I got him.
- Good bring him down to the service elevator.
Let's go.
Fuck you!
Doug.
Honey...
...you wouldn't hurt me, would you, sweetheart?
Sweetheart, be reasonable.
After all, we're married.
Consider that a divorce.
That was your wife?
What a bitch.
Hey, get out of the way!
I thought you didn't like me.
If Cohaagen wants you dead, you might be okay.
- Got it.
- So you come back to apologize?
Kuato wants to see you.
Come on.
- Now what?
- Jump!
No! Don't do it!
You'll crack the fucking dome!
What are you trying to do, kill us?
The dome will crack!
Move!
Taxi!
Melina! Melina!
- Need a ride?
- The Last Resort! Quick!
You guys are going in circles.
Jesus!
Come on! You drive!
You guys are in trouble?
Go! Go!
- What are you trying to do to me man?
- Shut up and drive!
Hey, I got five kids to feed!
- Shit!
- No brakes!
You idiot!
What the hell are you doing?
Christ! Now they're after me!
Give me that!
Get out of the way!
Tony!
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Thank you, Tony.
What to have some fun?
Where are they?
What are you talking about?
I don't know.
Maybe you know.
Kill them all!
Thumbelina!
Richter!
- A call from Cohaagen!
- Richter here.
- We got them pinned down.
- Stop fighting and pull out.
But they've got Quaid.
They're protecting him.
Perfect.
Get out of Sector G now.
Don't think.
- Do it!
- Yes, sir.
Pull 'em out.
Everybody pull out!
Move!
- Cohaagen's sealing off the area!
- Come on, Benny!
The first settlers are buried here.
They worked themselves to death,
but Cohaagen ended up with all the money.
He built cheap domes and watched
their kids turn into freaks.
I saw them.
And if you want to breathe,
you have to buy his air.
But maybe you can change all that.
Hey, I think my grandpa might be here.
So what can I do?
Kuato's gonna make you remember some
things you knew when you were Hauser.
- Like what?
- All sorts of things.
- Like maybe you'll remember that you loved me.
- I don't need Kuato for that.
Oh, since when?
- Freeze!
- Come on, Melina.
Kuato's waiting.
Well I didn't find him, but--
Oh, shit.
- Who's this?
- He helped us get away.
Hey, don't worry about me, man.
I'm on your side.
You're a mutant, huh?
All right, let's go.
- Have you tried ramming down the door?
- You wait here. Follow me.
It won't do any good.
- Cohaagen depressurized the tunnels.
- Then drill through to Section M.
We can't.
We're running out of air.
- We need help.
- Okay, sit tight. Melina just got here with Quaid.
I hope he was worth it.
So do I.
- I'm glad you made it.
- You don't look so glad.
Cohaagen sealed up Venusville.
He shut off all the air.
You must know something pretty damn important, Quaid.
He wants you.
If we don't hand you over,
everybody in this sector will be dead by morning.
Well then we don't have much choice then, do we?
We can't turn him in.
That's up to Kuato.
Come with me, Quaid.
Sit down.
- Where's Kuato?
- On his way.
You heard the rumors about the Pyramid Mine?
Yeah.
Cohaagen found something weird inside
and it's got him scared shitless.
What? Aliens?
- You tell me.
- I don't know.
Yes, you do.
That's why we brought you here.
Cohaagen's big secret
is buried in that black hole you call a brain.
And Kuato's gonna dig it out.
- You're Kuato, right?
- Wrong.
Kuato's a mutant,
so don't get upset when you see him.
What do you want, Mr. Quaid?
- Same as you: to remember.
- But why?
- To be myself again.
- You are what you do.
A man is defined by his actions not his memory.
Please. Take my hands.
Now open your mind to me.
Please.
Open your mind.
We should blow the thing up
before the rebels turn it on.
I say we throw the switch and see what happens.
- Don't be an idiot.
- We can't risk it.
The chain reaction could spread
to all the turbinium in the crust.
That means a meltdown,
a meltdown on a planetary scale.
Don't you think whoever
built this thing thought of that?
Who knows what the hell they thought?
They weren't human.
Maybe it's a trap.
Maybe they want a meltdown.
We don't even know if this
piece of junk will even work.
What is it?
A million? Half a million?
- About half a million.
- Half a million years old.
Well let's make sure Kuato--
Wake up! Wake up!
Come on, wake up!
They found us! Shit!
Let's go!
Wake up! Snap out of it!
Now! Come on!
They found us!
- Everybody out!
- Melina!
Get moving! Get out!
Get out!
Everybody out! Get out!
Get to the air lock! Follow me!
Benny, come on!
- Benny!
- I'm coming!
Put these spacesuits on!
We're going outside!
Benny, hurry.
Congratulations, Quaid.
You led us right to him.
How could you do this?
You're a mutant.
Hey, I got four kids to feed.
So what happened to number five?
Ah, shit man. You got me.
I ain't even married.
Now put your fucking hands in the air!
Quaid.
Forget it, bro.
His fortune telling days are over.
Start the reactor.
Free Mars.
Mr. Cohaagen would like to talk to you.
So this is the great man.
No wonder he kept out of sight.
Well, my boy you're a hero.
Fuck you.
Don't be modest.
Kuato is dead.
The resistance has been completely wiped out,
and you were the key to the whole thing.
He's lying.
You two-faced bastard.
You can't blame him, angel.
He's innocent.
You see, Quaid,
none of my people could get close to Kuato.
The fucking mutants could always sniff us out.
So Hauser and I sat down and invented you,
the perfect mole.
You know you're lying.
Hauser turned against you.
That's what we wanted you to think.
The fact is,
Hauser volunteered to become Doug Quaid.
It was the only way to fool the psychics.
Well get your story straight.
This idiot here has been trying to kill
me ever since I went to Rekall.
You don't kill somebody you're trying to plant.
He wasn't in on it.
You set him off by going to Rekall.
- So why am I still alive?
- We gave you lots of help.
- Benny here.
- My pleasure, man.
The guy with the suitcase, the mask, the money,...
...the message from Hauser.
All of that was set up by us.
Sorry. Too perfect.
Perfect, my ass!
You pop your memory cap
before we can activate you.
Richter goes hog-wild, screwing up
everything I spent a year planning.
Frankly, I'm amazed it worked.
Well, Cohaagen...
...I have to hand it to you.
This is the best mind fuck yet.
Well, don't take my word for it, Quaid.
- Someone you trust wants to talk to you.
- Who is it this time--my mother?
Howdy, Quaid.
If you're listening to this,
that means that Kuato is dead and you have led us to him.
I knew you wouldn't let me down.
Sorry for all the shit I've put you through.
But hey, what are friends for?
I would like to wish you happiness
and long life, old buddy...
...but unfortunately, this is not gonna happen.
You see, that's my body you've got there,
and, I want it back.
Sorry to be an Indian giver, but I was here first.
So adios, amigo,
and thanks for not getting yourself killed.
Hey, maybe we'll meet in our dreams.
You never know.
You bastards!
Let go of me!
- Ready?
- Auto.
- Check.
- Ready to go, sir.
Relax, Quaid.
- You'll like being Hauser.
- The guy's a fucking asshole.
Not true.
He's one of my best friends.
Besides, he's got a big house and a Mercedes.
You like Melina, right?
Well, you'll get to fuck her every night.
That's right.
She's going to be Hauser's babe.
I'll bust his balls.
Uh-uh, princess.
We're having you fixed.
You're going to be respectful and compliant...
...and appreciative, just the way a woman should be.
Mr. Cohaagen Telephone.
- Yes? What is it?
- Sir, the oxygen level is bottoming out in Sector G.
What do you want me to do about it?
- Don't do anything.
- But they won't last an hour, sir.
Fuck 'em.
It'll be a good lesson to the others.
Come on, Cohaagen! You got what you want.
Give these people air.
My friend, in five minutes,
you won't give a shit about the people.
- Fire it up, Doc.
- Excuse me, Doctor...
- ...is he gonna remember any of this?
- Not a thing.
Oh, really?
Oh, Quaid, I'm having a party tonight.
Why don't you and Melina drop by?
Remind him, Doc?
- Sure.
- See you at the party.
Keep still.
Fighting just makes it hurt.
If you don't keep still, you'll end up psychotic.
Hey, don't!
Melina, hold on!
Are you all right?
Are you still you?
I'm not sure, dear.
What do you think?
Let's get the hell out of here.
You have to make a decision, sir.
Kill him.
It's about goddamn time.
- Where are you going?
- To the reactor.
- What reactor?
- The one in the mines. Come on!
People are dying, Quaid!
Stop! We've got to get air!
The reactor makes air.
That's Cohaagen's secret. Let's go.
Where's this reactor come from?
- Aliens built it.
- Aliens?
- Are you sure about this?
- It's just up ahead.
What the hell--
Quaid!
Hey, Quaid, you remember me?
Benny! Benny's the name!
Oh, that's good!
I'm gonna drill you, sucker!
I'm gonna grind you up!
I'm coming!
I'm coming for you, baby!
What the fuck is this?
Damn this piece of Martian junk!
Hey, Quaid, I'm gonna squash you!
Benny, here!
Where the fuck are you?
Screw you!
Quaid, get over here!
What is it?
There's an opening.
I knew it.
This whole thing is one big reactor made out of turbinium.
Cohaagen knows it makes air.
The bastard won't turn it on.
Of course not.
If Mars had an atmosphere, he'd lose control.
See down there.
It's a glacier.
The whole core of Mars is ice.
The reactor melts it and it releases the oxygen.
Come on.
- Enough for everyone to breathe?
- Sure.
Enough for the whole planet.
If we turn it on in time.
Come on. Come on!
Hold on.
Now!
Son of a bitch.
Go!
He's got a hologram!
You think this is the real Quaid?
It is.
You're coming with me!
See you at the party, Richter.
Don't touch that!
Get away! Get back!
What are you afraid of?
- Turn it on.
- Impossible!
Once the reaction starts,
it'll spread to all the turbinium in the planet.
Mars will go into global meltdown.
That's why the aliens never turned it on.
Do you expect me to believe you?
Who gives a shit what you believe?
In 30 seconds you'll be dead.
Then I'll blow this place up
and be home in time for corn flakes.
I didn't want it to end this way.
I wanted Hauser back.
But no.
You had to be Quaid!
- I am Quaid.
- You're nothing!
You're nobody!
You're a stupid dream.
Well, all dreams come to an end.
- Melina, hold on!
- No.
Don't do it!
We'll all die!
Everybody will die!
Quaid!
Hold on!
I can't believe it.
It's like a dream.
What's wrong?
I just had a terrible thought.
What if this is a dream?
Well, then kiss me quick
before you wake up.