Before time began...
There was The Cube.
We know not where it comes from.
Only that it holds
the power to create worlds
and fill them with life.
That is how our race was born.
For a time we lived in harmony.
But like all great power...
Some wanted it for good...
Others for evil.
And so began The War.
War that ravaged our planet
until it was consumed by death.
And The Cube was lost to
the far reaches of space.
We scattered across the galaxy,
hopeing to find it and rebuild our home.
Searching every star, every world...
And just when all hope seemed lost...
Passage of a new discovery
took us to an unknown planet called...
Earth.
But we were already too late...
God 4 months of this...
Can't wait to get a little taste of home.
Play with mama's aligators... - You've
been talking abut barbecued gators
and crickets for the last 2 weeks.
I'm never going to your mama's hose, I promise.
Bobby, gators are known to have
the most sucklear meat.
I understand.
I mean how many times...
We don't speak spanish.
That's my herritage..
You guys remember weekends?
Sox and Filmway, cold hotdog
and flat beer?
Perfect day...
What about you captain?
You got a perfect day?
I just can't wait to hold
my baby for the first time.
Watch this crossover man,
like Jordan in his prime...
Step asside mates.
- Hey, what are you doing?
Are you gonna help me with the gear?
Colonel Sharp, we have an inbound
unidentified infiltrator.
10 miles out.
Unidentified aircraft, you are
obstircting US military airspace.
and proceed East out of the area.
Raptors 1 and 2, snap to
heading 250 and intercept.
Bogie is in the weeds,
10 miles out, not responding.
Unidentified aircraft, we'll
escort you to US SOX airbase.
If you do not comply,
we will use deadly force.
We got 10 on the bogie.
Tail 4500X.
Sir it says here 4500X
was shot down 3 months ago.
Afghanistan. - That's gotta be
a mistake, check again and recheck.
I did sir. Friend of mine
was on that chopper.
Where's the inbound?
- Bogie's 5 miles out sir.
Hi my ladies!
Oh my goodnes, look at her,
she's getting so big.
Baby we've got a
good looking kid.
I know that people say
that all the time...
We made one good looking
kid. Nice work.
Sha has your laugh.
- She laughs?
Her first one.
Are you sure she
didn't just fart?
No, she's a lady.
She doesn't know you
yet, but she will.
4500X, something's not right.
Radar's jamed.
It's coming from the chopper.
Sarah if you can hear me
I love you and I'll be home soon.
FX53 pilot, power down now.
Have your crew step
out or we will kill you.
My God...
They bombed that tower!
We're under attack!
They're going after the files!
Cut the hard lines!
I need a key, it's locked!
Ok, mr. Witwicky you're up.
Sorry, I got a lot of stuff.
Who did that?
People...
Responsibility.
So, for my family geneology
report, I decided to do it
On my great great grandfather.
Who was a famous man.
Captain Archibald Witwicky.
Very famous explorer,
infact he was one of the first
to explore...
The arctic circle,
which is a big deal.
In 1897. he took 41 brave
sailors straight in to the arctic shelf.
The ice is freezing faster
than is melting!
Chop faster!
No sacrifice, no victory!
We'll get to the
arctic circle lads!
So that's the story.
And here we have some
of the basic instruments and tools
used by 19th century seamen.
This here is the quadrant,
which should be arround 80 bucks.
It's all for sale by the way.
Like the sextant here.
50 dollars for this,
this is a bargain.
Theese are pretty cool.
Theese are my grandfather's glasses.
Haven't quite gotten them appraised yet,
but they've seen many cool things.
Are you going to sell
me his liver?
Mr. Witwicky this isn't
show and sell.
This is the 11th grade, I don't
think your grandfather would be
particulary proud of what
you're doing. - I know, I'm sorry.
This all is going to
my car fund.
You tell your folks, it's on eBay.
I take PayPal, cold hard cash works too.
Compas makes a great gift for Columbo's day.
Unfortunately, my great great
grandfather, the genius that he was...
Wound up going blind
and crazy on a sych ward.
Drawing theese strange
symbols, babling on about some...
Giant ice man that he
thought he saw...
OK, might be a pop
quiz tomorrow, might not!
Sleep in fear tonight.
Pretty good right?
I'd say a solid B minus.
A B minus?
- You were hacking yor
great grandfather's
crap in my classrom.
Can you do me a favour? Can you look out
the window for a second and see my father?
He's the guy in the green car.
I'll tell you about a dream,
a boy's dream.
And a man's promice to that boy.
He looked him in the eyes and
said: "Son, I'm, gonna buy you a car."
But I want you to bring me
2000$ and 3 A's.
I got the 2000 and 2 A's.
Here's the dream.
Your B minus... dream gone.
Sir just ask yourself...
What would Jesus do?
A minus.
Wait, I can't see.
It's an A.
So I'm good?
- You're good.
I got a little surprise
for you son.
What kind of surprise?
- Little surprise.
You gotta be kidding me!
- Yeah, I am.
You're not getting a Porsche.
You think that's funny?
- Yea I think it's funny.
What's wrong with you?
- Did you think I'd get you a porsche?
For your first car? - I don't want to
talk to you for the rest of my life.
C'mon it's just a car.
- It's no funny joke.
Get your cousin out of that damn
clown sute, he's having a heat stroke again.
Scarrying away folks.
- I'm hot, makeup's melting, hurts my eyes.
Here? No, no, no what is this?
- You said half of car not half of peace of crap.
When I was your age I'd
be happy with 4 wheels and an engine.
Let me explain something to you.
You ever seen "40 year old virgin"?
That's what this is,
and this is 50 year old virgin.
You want me to live that life?
- No sacrifice...
No victory, yeah i got it.
The old Witwicky moto.
Gentlemen.
Bobby Bolivia, like the country
except without the runks.
How can I help? - Well my
son here is looking to buy his first car.
You come to see me?
- Had to.
That practically makes us familly.
Uncle Bobby B baby.
Uncle Bobby B.
- Sam.
Let me talk to you.
Sam, your first enchilada
of freedom...
Awaits underneeth one of those hoods.
Let me tell you something son.
A driver don's pick a car.
A car picks the driver.
Some mystical bond between
a man and a machine.
Son I'm a lot of things,
liar is not one of them.
Especially not in front
of my mammy.
That's my mammy.
Don't be like that...
If I had a rock I'd bust your ass bitch.
She's deaf, you know.
Over here... every piece
of car man might want or need.
So it's got racing stripes.
- Yeah, it's got racing...
What the heck is this?
I know nothing about this car.
Manny!
- What?
What is this?
This car, check it out.
I don't know boss.
I've never seen that.
Feels good.
How much?
- Well...
Considering the semi classic
nature of the vehicle...
With the slick wheel and a
custom paint job... - But the paint's faded.
Yeah, but it's custom.
- It's custom faded?
Well it is your first car
and I don't expect you to understand.
5 grand.
- No, I'm not paying over 4. Sorry.
Kid, c'mon get out of the car.
- No, you said cars pick their drivers.
Sometimes it picks a driver
with a cheap ass father, out of the car.
There's a fiesta with racing stripes over there.
- No, I don't wanna a fiesta with racing stripes.
This is a classic engine right here.
I sold a car the oder day...
Manny get your clown cousin and get
some hammers and come bang this stuff out baby!
That one's my favourite.
It drove all the way from Alabama.
4 thousand.
Hello Mr. secretary.
They're so young.
-They are top subject matter experts sir.
NSA is recruiting right out
of high schools theese days.
Guys, that's the secretary of defense.
- I', so underdressed.
Ladies and gentlemen,
secretary of defense.
Please be seated.
I'm John Keller.
Obviously you've wondered why
you are here, so theese are the facts.
At 19:00 local time yesterday.
Saxon forward operations base at Qatar was attacked.
So far as we know, there were no survivors.
The objective of the attack was
to hack our military network.
We're not sure exactly what they were after,
but we do know that they were cut off during the assault.
Which leads us to assume
they are going to try again.
No one has taken the
responsibility for the attack.
And the only real lead
we have so far...
Is this sound.
That's the signal
that hacked our network.
NSA is working at full capacity to analize
it and intercept further communications.
But we need your help
to find out who did this
You've all shown considerable ability
in the area of signals analisis.
We're on a hair trigger here people.
The president has dispatched battle
groups to the Arabian Gulf and the Yellow Sea.
This is a real
I will leave you to your officer in charge,
break up into teams and start your work.
Good luck to us all.
Got the car,
now I need a girl.
Any money to count
the girls would do.
0 bids.
Great, broke.
Come on MOjo,
you want your pain pill?
It's like clockwork.
I know you're wasting theese
things, so I better get you sleeping outside.
That's it for today.
No more.
Crackhead.
Ron this one is uneaven.
- Yea probably.
This one is bobbing.
- I'll take care of that.
Couldn't we have hired a professional?
I do not like footprints on my grass.
- There's no footprints.
That's why I built my path.
So why don't you go from my grass on to my path.
It's family grass dad.
- When you own your own grass you'll understand.
This, I can't do it anymore.
You're putting girl jewlery on a boy dog.
He's got enugh self esteeme
issues cos he's a chiuaha.
That's his bling.
I wan't you home by 11 o' clock.
Yea allright.
- 11 o' clock.
Please, for the love of God
drive seafely.
You are so cheap.
That's his first car.
It's suposed to be like that.
A this time, we can't confirm
whether there were any survivors.
Our bases worldwide are as
of now Defcon Delta.
Our highest readiness level.
We are dealing with a very effective weapon
system we that have not come across before.
Our prayers are with the families of the brave
men and women... - Daddy's going to be ok.
I've never seen a weapon
system like this.
Thermal shows this weird aura arround
the egzoskeleton like it's cloacked
by some kind of invisible force field.
That's impossible. There's no such thing
as invisible force fields
except in comic books
stuff, right?
Man I don't know. My momma, she
had a gift, you know.
She saw things.
That thing that attacked us...
I gotta feeling it ain't over.
How about you use those magical voodoo
powers and get us the hell outta here.
When I took that picture,
I think it saw me.
It looked right at me.
We gotta get this thing back to the Pentagon right
away, they gotta know what we're dealing here.
Radio's fried.
I got no communication with Ariel.
How far do you live from here?
- Not far, just up that mountain.
Do you have a phone?
- Yes.
Allright, let's hit it.
Dude, are you sure
we're invited to this party?
Of course Miles, it's a lake.
Public property.
Oh my God. Oh my Gdd, dude,
Mikaela is here.
Just don't do anything weird, allright?
I'm good right?
- Yeah, you're good.
Hey guys, check it out.
Hey bro, that car...
It's nice.
So what are you guys doing here?
We're here to climb this tree.
I see that, it looks fun.
I thought I reckognized you, you tried
out for the football team last year right?
Let's go call your mum.
That wasn't like a real try out.
I was researching a book I was writing.
What's it about?
Sucking at sports?
No, it's about the link between brain
damage and football.
I tell you it's a good book,
your friends will love it.
It's got mazes in it, little coloring
areas, sections, pop up pictures...
A lot of fun.
- That's funny.
You gotta get off the tree right now.
Just, get off the tree right now please.
What are you doing?
- You said it's fun.
All the chicks were watching...
- You're making me look like an idiot.
We both look like idiots.
How about you let me drive?
- No, this is not a toy.
Theese 22, I don't want you grind them.
Why doesn't my little bunny
just hop in the back seat?
I can't even tell you how
much I'm not your little bunny.
You'll call me.
Hey what's wrong
with your radio?
I'm driving her home today.
- What?
She's an evil jock concubine
man, let her hitchhike.
She lives 10 miles from here,
it's my only chance.
Try to understand me here.
- Ok, we'll put here in the back, I'll be quiet.
Did you say put her in the back?
Miles I'm not putting her in the back
You gotta get out of my car right now.
What rules?
Bros before hoes.
- Miles, you gotta get out of my car.
You can't do this to me.
- You gotta get out of my car right now.
It's Sam...
Witwicky
Hope you're not stranded
or anything... Sure?
So listen, I was wondering if I
could ride you home...
I mean, give you a ride home,
in my car to your house.
I can't believe that I'm here right now.
You can talk down if you want,
it won't hurt my feelings.
I didn't mean here you,
I just mean here like
in this situation.
Same situation that I'm always in.
I don't know, I guess I just have a
weakness for hot guys, for tight
abs and big arms.
Big arms?
There's couple of new additions in the car.
Like, I've just put in that
light there...
And that disco ball, light
reflects of the disco ball.
Are you new to school this year?
Is this your first year?
No, we've been in the same
school since first grade. - Really?
Do we have any classes together?
- Yeah, history...
Language arts, math, science...
- Sam... Sam, yes...
Sam Wilckeky...
Witwicky... - I know,
I'm so sorry.
I just didn't reckognize you.
- That's understandable.
Just working out the cakes...
This radio is like...
Look this isn't something...
Look I wouldn't try this on you.
This is like a romantic thing
that I'm not trying to do.
I'm a friend of yours, I'm
not a romantic friend.
Romantic friends do this.
I mean, I'm not that friend.
I mean we...
I could be...
Just pop the hood.
Nice huders... You got hi res
double pump carborator...
That's pretty impressive Sam.
Double pump? - It squirts
the fuel in so you can go faster.
I like to go faster.
It looks like your distributor cap
is a little loose.
How did you know that?
My dad, he was a real greasemonkey.
Tought me all about this.
I could take it all apart, clean it
put it back together.
That's weird, I just wouldn't
pay you for mechanical.
Well you know, I don't really
broadcast it. Guys don't like it
when you know more
about cars than they do.
Especially not Trent.
He hates it.
I'm cool with females
working on my engine.
I prefere it actualy.
Ok, you wanna fire it up for me?
I was thinking, if Trent is souch
a jerk, why do you hang out with him?
You know what, I'm gonna walk.
Good luck with your car.
Allright...
Walking's healthy...
C'mon, please...
Don't let her walk away...
Wait a second!
There it is.
I had fun, so...
Thanks for listening.
You don't think I'm shallow?
I think... There's a lot
more than meets the eye...
With you.
Allright, I'll see you at school.
Stupid...
That was a stupid line.
I love my car.
Guys, I think the other team
figuered it out.
Iran. - This is way to smart
for Iranian scientists.
Think about it.
- What do you think?
Chineese? - No way, this
is nothing like what the chineese are using.
Mr. President? - Can you rangle me up
some ding dongs darling?
- Neprevedeni titl -
I'll be in storage.
Did you hear that?
Are you getting this?
Like they are hacking the network again.
Oh my God, this is a direct
match to the signal in Qatar.
Are you running a diagnostic?
- Should I be?
Yes you should.
- So I am.
Someone! They are hacking into
Air Force 1.
I think they're planting a virus.
- A virus?
Streaming right now. - They are planting a virus and
stealing whole lot of data at the same time.
Code red, we have a breach.
You got to cut the hard lines.
- What?!
Whatever they want, they are getting it.
- Sir, permission to take down the defence network.
Cut all server hard lines now.
- Cut all server hard lines now.
Someone's tampered with
the mainframe.
I want our president
in our bunker.
And I don't want to discuss
a damn thing other till that becomes reality.
That's pur first priority,
that's our only priority right now.
Air Force 1 is on the ground.
That's my car!
Dad call the cops!
Where are you going with
my car buddy, where are you going?
Hello 911 emergency?!
My car's been stolen!
I'm in pursuit, I need all units,
the whole squadron!
Bring everyone! Don't ask me questions,
my father is on a neighbourhood watch.
Oh my God...
My name is Sam Witwicky.
Whoever finds this, my cyr is alive.
These are my last words ever
I just want to say mom, dad I love you.
And if you find "Busty Beauties"
under my bed
it wasn't mine I'm holding it for Miles.
That's not true, it's mine
and uncle Charles gave it to me, I'm sorry.
Mojo I love you.
Please don't kill me I'm sorry.
Take the keys, I don't want to touch you.
Good you're here.
- Let me see the hands!
It's not me, the guy's inside.
- Shut up!
Walk towards the car.
Put your head on the hood.
Whoever did this finally managed
to infiltrate our defense network
which is what they've tried to do in Qatar
only this time it worked.
What did they get?
- We still don't know.
Talk to me about the virus.
It's a spider bug virus.
We're not sure what it's going to do
but it may cripple the system.
- Can westop it?
Every time we try an antivirus
it adapts and speeds up.
It's like it's not a virus anymore
it's become the system.
Obviously the first phase
of major attack against the US.
Only countries with this kind of
capability are Russia, North Korea maybe China.
I'm sorry, that's not correct.
Excuse me young lady I did not
see you standing there
You would be who?
- Just an analist that detected the hack.
Hold on, it was you?
You did it?
- Her team.
Sir I was trying to say...
They hacked your firewall in 10 seconds.
Even a supercomputer with a brute
force attack would take 20 years to do that.
Maybe you can explain then how
our latest satellite imagery
shows North Korea doubleing
its naval activities...
Maybe it's a precocion becouse
isn't that what we're doing?
Signal pattern is learning, it's evolving
on its own and you need to move past
furyair transfers and start
considering quantum mechanics.
There is nothing on Earth
that complex.
What about an organism?
A living organism, maybe some kind of
DNA based computer...
I know that that sounds crazy...
That's enough.
We have 6 floors
working on this thing.
Now if you can find proof to
back up your theory
I'm going to be happy to
listen to you.
But if you don't put a
filter on your brain - mouth theme
you're going to off the team.
You understand?
I can't be any clearer,
on how crystal clear I am being.
It just stood up.
- Just stood up?
It's really neat.
Ok, time to fill her up.
I'm not on any drugs.
- What's this?
Found it in your pocket.
Mojo...
Is that what you kids are doing now?
Those are my dog's pain pills.
- Yeah, chiuaha...
What was that?
You eyeballing my peace?
You wanna go?
Make something happen, do it.
Cos I promice you,
I will bust you up.
Are you on drugs?
Let's hope this
telephone line works.
What the heck was that?
English dude, english.
Where's your pappa?!
Sir I need a telephone...
This is an emergency Pentagon call...
Do you understand, this is an emergency...
I don't have a credit card!
Sir the attitude is not going to
speed things up, anything at all.
I'm going to ask you to speak
into the mouth peace very clearly...
I'm in a middle of a war!
Pretty rediculos!
I need a credit card!
Where's your wallet?!
- Pocket!
Which pocket?
- My back pocket!
You don't have a back pocket!
- Left jink!
Also sir, have you heard about our
premium plus service call package?
No I don't want a premium package!
Give me a status? - Sir we're tracking
a spec ops team under fire in Qatar.
They say they are survivors
at the base attack. - Survivors.
I've never seen this in my life!
Need gunships on station ASAP!
Predators coming up in a minute.
- Linking a call to the nearest AWAC
Man if you've seen this shit...
- Predator ETA 2 minutes.
What is that?
We need air support and we need it now.
Roll in strike package B on unknown target.
7 man team, north of
orange smoke!
Attack to Rich and Wess,
you're cleared hot!
The heat's coming!
- Laser target!
We got to beam light it for incoming!
Link target!
The heat's coming!
No freakin way!
That thing is still not down!
Ok 32 use .105 shells.
Bring the rain.
Be advised, ground team is
requesting .105 sable rounds.
Did we loose it?
- Warthog 1 confirm visual on frendlies.
Where is Frank?
Get a medic!
Bring them home.
Get those men stateside right now.
I want them debriefed in 10 hrs.
There's only one hacker in the world
that can brake this code.
I'm sorry to bother you.
- Maggie...
I need your help.
- No, this is my private area...
my place of zen and peace.
Shut up grandma!
What are you doing here?
- Just give me a break will you?
Grandma cut the proone juice!
What level are you on?
- Sixth...
Don't you want to
see somtehing classified?
I need a moment... please.
- Sorry.
And save my game.
How classified?
Like, I will go to jail for the rest
of my life for showing you classified.
One quick peak.
Spec Ops got a thermal snapshot
of whatever hit the base in Qatar.
I wanna see it.
- The imager was damaged sir.
The rangers are in rout with
the imager, but we also have a security issue.
Server logs indicate one of the
analysts made a copy of the network
intrusion signal.
The signal strength is through the roof,
where did you said you got this?
Hacked the national military
airguard frequency in less than a minute.
No way...
Looks like there's a message
embedded in the signal.
Gotta be worth my magic.
Project "Iceman"?
- What's Sector 7?
Who is captain Witwicky?
Are you playing those
videogames again?
Cops!
Get off my grandma's carpet!
She don't like nobody on her carpet!
Especially police!
It was an awesome spectacle here an hour
ago when over 40 C17's lifted off this very base.
We were not told where
they're going...
Stop barking Mojo it's
too early please.
Miles listen to me.
My car, it stole itself ok?
What are you talking about man?
- Satan's Camaro in my yard.
It is stalking me.
Sam?
That was really...
Awesome.
It felt awesome.
- Are you ok?
No I'm not ok, I'm loosing
my mind a little bit.
Getting chased by my car
right now, I gotta go.
You know what, I'm gonna
go, I'll check with you guys later.
Great, the cops.
Officer!
Listen...
That hurt.
Listen to me.
Thank God you're here.
I've had the worst day ever.
I've been followed here on my mother's bike.
And my car is right there
and it has been following me here.
So get out of the car.
Please, what do you want from me?!
This is a bad dream.
Are you username LadiesMan217?
- I don't know what you're talking about!
Are you username LadiesMan217?!
- Yeah...
Where is the eBay item 21153?!
Where are the glasses?!
Get back!
What is your problem Sam?!
- There's a monster right there, it just attacked me!
Here it comes!
Sam what is that thing?
- You have to get in the car.
Get in the car.
Trust me!
We're gonna die!
- We're not gonna die!
We're locked in.
The car won't start.
Atleast we've ditched the monster, right?
He's gonna kill me!
Not so tough without
a head, are you?!
Come on.
What is it?
It's a robot.
Like a... different...
super advanced robot.
He's probably Japaneese.
He's definetly Japaneese.
What are you doing?
I don't think he wants to hurt us.
He would have done that already.
Really? Well do you speak robot, because
they just had a giant twin deathmatch.
I think he wants something from me.
- What?
Because the other one was
talking about my eBay page.
You're the strangest
boy I have ever met.
Can you talk?
So you talk through the radio?
So what was that last night?
What was that?
"Visitors from heaven"...
What?
Are you like an alien or something?
Any more questions
you want to ask?
He wants us to get in the car.
And go where?
This car is a pretty
good driver.
Why don't you go sit
in that seat there?
I'm not gonna sit in his
seat, he's driving.
Maybe you should sit
in my lap. - Why?
I have the only seatbelt here,
safety first.
See, that's better.
You know, that seatbelt thing
was a pretty smooth move.
Thank you.
You know what I don't understand...
Why if he's suposed to be this
super advanced robot
does he transform back into
this piece of crap camaro?
Fantastic!
Now you've pissed him off!
That car is sensitive.
4000$ just drove off.
What?
This is easilly a hundred times
cooler than Armaggedon.
I swear the God.
Sweet... Dude I hope this guy's got
assdrilling insurance cos he is so boned.
Excuse me, are you the tooth fairy?
Hey sweetheart, what are
you doing out here by yourself?
Holy cow what happened
to the pool?
Are you Samuel James Witwicky
descendant of Archibald Witwicky?
He knew your name.
- Yeah...
My name is Optimus Prime.
We are autonomus robotic organisms
from the planet Cybertron.
But you can call us Autobots for short.
Autobots?
What's crackin little bitches?
- My first liutenant...
Jazz... - This looks like a
cool place to kick it.
How did he learn to talk like that?
We've learned Earth's languages
through the World Wide Web.
My weapons specialist, Ironhide.
You feeling lucky punk?
- Easy Ironhide.
Just kidding, I just wanted
to show him my talents.
Our medical officer Ratchett.
The boy's pheromone levels suggest
he wants to mate with the female.
You already know your
guardian Bumblebee.
You're my guardian?
His vocal processor was damaged in battle.
We've been still working on him.
Why are you here?
- We are here looking for the Allspark.
And we must find it
before Megatron.
Mega what?
Our planet was once
a powerful empire.
Peaceful and just.
Until we were betrayed by Megatron,
leader of the Decepticons.
All that were to fight
them were destroyed.
Our war finally consumed the planet
and the Allspark was lost to the stars.
Megatron followed it to Earth.
When captain Witwicky found him.
My grandfather...
It was an accident that
intertwined our fates.
Come back!
The dogs have found something.
The ice is cracking.
I'm allright lads!
Megatron crashlanded before
he could retrieve The Cube.
Men, we've made a discovery!
He accidentaly activated
his navigation system.
The coordinates to The Cube's
location on Earth
were imprinted on his glasses.
How did you know
about his glasses?
eBay...
If the Decepticons find the Allspark...
They will use it's power to
transform Earth's machines
and build a new army.
- And the human race will be extiguished.
Sam Witwicky, you hold
the key to Earth's survival.
Please tell me that
you have those glasses.
It's like a self regenerating
molecular armor.
Look at the scorch mark
where the Sable round hit.
Melted right through.
Aren't Sables hot loaded for
like a 6000 degree magnesium burn?
Close to it, that was tank armor.
This metal skin must
react to extreme heat...
I thought you said
that thing was dead man!
Strap it down!
Strap it!
This thing is wicked!
Get on a hornet northern command,
tell them that our effective weapon
is high heat Sable rounds.
Recommend we load them on all gunships, go.
You want that peace?
Ok Maggie look.
They're gonna come through
that door, play good cop bad cop.
Don't fall for that, allright?
That's why I ate their food.
They put the plate of donuts
here to test your guilt.
If you don't touch it you're guilty.
I ate the whole plate.
The whole plate.
It's me and you. They walk
through that door, you don't say nothing.
She did it! She did it!
She's the one you want!
I was just sitting home watching
cartoons, playing videogames with my cousin
and she came in there, allright?
- Glenn you freak!
I am not going to jail
for you or anybody else.
I have done nothing bad
my entire life.
Hey man, I'm still a virgin.
So what, i've downloaded a
couple of thousand songs off the internet
who hasen't?!
Glenn sut up!
- No, you shut up!
Don't talk to me!
Don't talk to me criminal!
Sugar rush.
- This is not his fault.
Can I go home now?
Just listen to me.
Whoever hacked into your
military system, downloaded a file.
It was something about
someone named Witwicky...
And some goverment group
named Sector 7.
You have to let me talk to defense secretary
Keller before you go to war with the wrong country.
What did he say?
Did he hear it too?
Jack heard it too.
- What does he think it is?
He thinks it's a military experiment.
Well I think it's a plane.
Call Sam, he should be
home in 15 minutes.
Well I'll call him in 15 minutes.
- If you wait 15 minutes he'll be late
and you'll have to ground him.
- I can't ground him if he's not late, can I?
Just stay here, allright?
You have to stay here and watch them.
You hear what I'm saying?
5 minutes, allright?
Thanks for staying on my path.
Oh the path, I'm sorry I
forgot about the path.
I'm gonna sweep the whole
thing right now, how about that?
I buy half of your car,
I bail you out of jail,
and then I just decided to
do all your chors.
Life is great.
- Life is fantastic, that's how good it is.
The trash can, sorry dad,
I'm gonna do the trash cans, allright?
No, I don't want you
to strain yourself.
Dad, you'll hurt my feelings
if you do it.
I promise... No, no, I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna do the trash cans and I'm gonna
scrape the grill and I'm gonna...
Sweep up the whole house
right now.
Right now?
- Right now.
I love you.
God I love you.
Just so much right now.
- You know, your mom wanted me to ground you.
You're 3 minutes late.
Just another thing you did for me
dad, because you're such a swell guy.
Allright, I love you.
Sleep good handsome man.
What are you doing?
Watch the path!
Sorry, my bad.
You couldn't wait
for 5 minutes, I told you to stay.
I told you...
- Ok, they are in a little bit of a rush.
Mojo no!
Mojo off the robot.
God.
This is Mojo, he's a pet of
mine, he is a pet.
That's all.
Put the guns away,
put them away.
You have a rodent infestation,
shall I terminate?
He's not a rodent, he is a chiuaha.
This is my chiuaha.
We love chiuahas don't we?
-He has leaked lubricants all over my foot.
He pied on you?
Bad Mojo!
It's gonna rust.
Just hurry
Autobots recon.
He's in the kitchen, I had to
slap him arround.
You did not.
You didn't even ground him.
- Almost, almost.
Time is short.
- They really want those glasses.
Please hurry.
No, no, it's definetly gone.
- What do you mean?
Glasses were in the bag, they were
in the backpack, now the backpack isn't here.
Well they're gonna be
pissed, so what do you want to do?
What I think you should do,
you should check this whole
this whole section here.
Give it a clean sweep.
And I'll get the corner here.
Not there, that's my private.
Sorry.
You just told me... - I didn't mean to
look inside of my treasure chest.
You should be way more specific...
This isn't hiding.
This is my back yard,
not a truck stop.
I saw it. UFO landed
right here and now is gone.
My moped is under there
man, who's gonna pay for that?
Sam he's back.
Ok I'll deal with this.
What?! No, no, no
these are my mother's flowers.
Listen, you gotta listen to me.
If my parents come out here
and they see you, they're gonna
freak out. My mom's got a temper.
We must have the glasses.
- I know you need the glasses.
I've been looking everywhere,
they're not here, they're definetly not here.
Keep searching.
- I need you to be quiet for 5 minutes.
Please, I'm begging you.
I can't concentrate.
You want me to look...
- Calm down.
You gotta do something.
Autobots, fall back.
- Please for 5 minutes.
Move! - What's the matter
with you, can't you be quiet?
He wants us to be quiet...
Earthquake! Move, move,
move, earthquake!
Judy get under the table,
move it!
Duck and cover right now!
- How did you get over there so fast?
That was tingleing.
Yeah, that looks fun.
What the hell is that?
- I don't know.
That's weird.
Ratchett point the light.
- Come on, hurry.
We've got a major issue here.
What's with the light?
You got to stop the light.
You got to tell him to shut...
Sam are you in there?
How come the door's locked?
You know the rules,
no doors locked in my house.
You know he'll start counting if
you don't open... - One more chance.
Oh dear.
- 5... 4...
Sam he's counting.
- It's coming of the hinge pal.
Sam just open the door.
- 3... 2...
What's up?
What's with the bat?
Who were you talking to?
I'm talking to you.
- Why are you so sweaty and filthy?
I'm a child, teenager.
- We heard voices and noises...
We thought maybe...
- It doesn't matter what we thought.
What was that light?
- What light?
There's no light, you've
got 2 lights in your hand.
You can't just bounce into
my room like that.
You got to knock,
you got to comunicate.
We did, we knocked...
- We knocked!
You didn't knock, you were
screaming at me.
This is repressioning what you're
doing here, you're ruining my youth.
Oh for Pete's sakes,
you are so defensive.
Were you masturbating?
Judy...
- Was I... No mum!
I don't masturbate.
- That's not something for you to bring up.
That's a father and son thing.
- Father and son thing.
We don't have to call it that word if
that makes you unconformtable.
You can call it "Sam's happy time".
Or "My special alone time".
- Stop, Judy stop.
I'm sorry, it's just been a weird
night, I had a little bit to drink.
Well we saw a light.
- Parents.
Whatever it was, but we saw it.
Earthquake, another one!
Get in the doorway!
Aftershock, aftershock.
God I hate these.
- Quick hide!
Oh no, look at the yard,
the yard is destroyed.
Judy better call the city,
we've got a blown transformer.
Power pole's sparkling all over the place...
Oh man, the yard's a waste.
Crashed, gone.
The parents are wery iritating.
Can I take them out?
Ironhide you know we don't
harm humans. What is with you?
Well I'm just saying we could.
We heard you talking to somebody
Sam, we want to know who.
Hi, I'm Mikaela.
I'm a friend of Sam's.
Gosh, you're gorgeous.
She can hear you talking mom.
- Thank you.
Oh my godness, I'm sorry
you had to hear our little family discussion.
Where's my backpack mom?
- It's in the kitchen.
Your mom's so nice.
I want you to distract my parents
while I sneak out theese glasses.
Ronald Wickedy?
- Witwicky, who are you?
The goverment, sector 7.
Never heard of it.
- Never will.
Your son is a grat grandson
of captain Archibald Wickedy, is he not?
It's Witwicky.
May I enter the premesis sir?
Ron there's guys all
over the front yard.
What the heck's going on here?
- Your son filed a stolen car report last night
we think it's envolved in a
national security matter.
National security?
- That's right, national security.
My God Ron, they're everywhere.
There's guys in suits all arround the house
Look at this!
- Would you stay off the grass?!
Get me a sample and some
isotope readings.
They gotta get their
hands off my bush.
Drop the bat ma'am,
I'm carrying a loaded weapon.
You better get those guys out of my garden
or I'm gonna beat the crap out of them.
Are you experiencing any
flue like simptoms? - Ne!
What is this?
- How you doing son!
Is your name Sam?
- Yeah...
I need you to come with us...
- You're way out of line!
Sir I am asking politely.
Back off.
You're not taking my son.
- Really?
You're gonna try to get ruf with us?
- No but I'm gonna call the cops.
Because there's something
fishy going on arround here.
There's something a little fishy
about you, your son and your little taco bel dog
and this whole operation
you've got going on here.
What operation?
- That is what we are gonna find out.
I think, direct contact.
Step forward please.
14 rads...
Bingo!
Tag'em and bag'em!
You hurt my dog
I'll kick your ass.
Sam do not say anything!
Not a word until we get a lawyer.
So... LadiesMan217...
That is your eBay username right?
Yeah but it was a tipo,
then I ran with it.
What do you make of this?
Is that you?
- Yeah, that sounds like LadiesMan.
Last night at the station you
told the officer your car "transformed"...
Enlighten me.
- Here's what I said.
This is a total misunderstanding
that my car had been stolen.
Really?
- From me, from my home
but it's fine now
because it's back, it came back.
Well, not by itself.
- Well, no.
Because cars don't do that,
because that would be crazy.
What do you kids know
about the aliens?
You mean like a martian?
ET?
It's an urban legend.
- You see this?
This is I can do whatever I want
and get away with it badge.
I'm gonna lock you up forever.
Oh God, you know what don't
listen to him he's just pissed
because he's gotta get
back to guarding the mall.
You in the train broad.
Do not test me.
Especialy when your
daddy's parrol coming up.
What?
Parrol?
It's nothing...
- A grand theft auto, that ain't nothing?
You know those cars my dad
used to teach me to fix...
Well they weren't always his.
- You stole cars?
We couldn't alwys afford a babysitter
so sometimes he had to take me along.
She's got her own jouvie
record to prove it.
She's a criminal.
Criminals are hot.
It would be a real shame
if he had to rot in jail
rest of his natural life.
It is time to talk.
You're in trouble now.
Gentlemen...
I wanna introduce you
to my friend.
Optimus Prime.
Taking the children
was a bad move.
Autobots, relieve them
of their weapons.
Give me those!
Hi there...
You don't seem affraid.
Are you not surprised to see us?
There are S-7 protocols.
I'm not authorised to communicate
with you except to tell you
I can't communicate with you.
- Get out of the car!
Me?
- Now!
I'm getting out, you see?
Wery nifty how you put
us down without really killing us.
You're good with handcuffs too now?
You weren't suposed to
hear all that.
Sam, I have a record because
I woulnd't turn my dad and...
When did you have to sacrifice anything
in your perfect little life?
Big guys with big guns.
What is Sector-7?
Answer me!
I'm the one asks questions
arround here, not you young man!
How did you know about the aliens?
- Where did you take my parents?
I am not at liberty to discuss...
Hey you touch me that's a federal offense.
Do whatever you want,
get away with the badge, right?
Brave now all of a sudden
with his big alien friends standing over there.
Where is Sector-7?
- Wouldn't you like to know.
Bumblebee, stop lubricating
the man.
Get that thing to stop!
Ok tough guy, take it off.
- What are you talking about?
Your clothes, all of it, off.
- For what?
For threathening my dad.
Little lady...
This is the beginning...
Of the end of your life.
You're a criminal.
Let's face facts, it's in your gene pool.
Those are nice.
Now get behind the pole.
- This is souch a felony that you're doing.
I will hunt you down.
- Hunt you down.
Without any remorse.
- No remorse.
We've got to alert everyone.
- They already know.
Speaker.
Incoming.
Roll out!
Easy you two.
Get down on the gorund!
Get down!
Look he's not fiting back!
Happy to see me again?
Put him in the car with his
little criminal friend.
I want that thing prepd
and ready for transport!
Optimus...
Are we just gonna
stand here and do nothing?
There's no way to free
Bumblebee without harming the humans.
But it's not right...
- Let them leave.
Chineese and Russians are nearing
our area of operations in the western Pacifik.
We feel like this could
get out of hand real fast.
In the next couple of
hours they justifed his present
US and Chineese task forces
are approaching 100 miles crouse missle range.
Tell the strike group commander
that he's not to engage unless fired on first.
Yes sir.
- Mr. secretary...
Tom Banachek. I'm with sector-7,
advanced research division.
Never heard of it, I'm a little
busy Tom, I think you can see that.
Talk to me!
- The whole room's going down sir.
I can see that.
- Virus was coded to shut us down.
I'll take a seat.
What do you mean shut us down?
- Then used our network to spread
out to the whole world.
The blackout's global.
We have no communication.
Satellite and land lines are dead.
You mean to tell me that I can not
pick up this telephone and call my family...
Mr. secretary...
I'm here under direct
order from the presidnet.
You really need to see
what I have in the case.
You'll have to accept that there
are certain things you won't understand
right away.
Sector-7 is a special access division
of the goverment.
Convened in secret under president
Hoover 80 years ago.
You might remember a NASA JPL
lost the Beagle 2 Mars rover...
We told them to report
the mission a complete failure.
It wasn't...
Beagle 2 transmited 13 seconds.
This was classified above top secret.
More than just a pile
of Martian rocks.
This is the image from Mars.
Here's the image your Spec Ops team
was able to retrieve from the base attack.
We believe they are of the
same egzoskeletal type.
And obviously not Russian
or North Korean.
Are we talking abut
an invasion?
We intercepted a message
from your Spec Ops team.
These things can be hurt
by our wapons and now they know it.
That's why the virus shut us down,
so we can't coordinate against their next attack.
Which I would bet my ridiculous
goverment salary is coming.
Soon.
Get word to our fleet commanders
over national guard frequencies
short wave radio channel,
it might still be working.
Tell them to turn their
ships arround and come home, ASAP.
And inform all commands to
prepare for imminent attack.
Captain Lennox, we need you
and your team to come with us right now!
She's in here.
What's going on?
You're coming with me.
You're gonna be my advisor.
Me too?
Who's this?
- He's my advisor.
He comes too.
What did they get you for?
I bought a car...
Turned out to be an
alien robot.
Who knew.
Please, let this work.
Fire it up Optimus.
The code...
The code on these glasses
indicates the Allspark is
230 miles from here.
I sense Deceptions are getting
ready to mobilize.
They must know is here aswell.
- What about Bumblebee?
We can't just leave him to die.
He'll undergo some human experiments.
He'll die in vein if we
don't acomplish our mission.
Bumblebee is a brave soldier,
this is what he would want.
Why are we fighting
to save the humans?
Thy are primitive,
violent race.
Were we so diferent?
They're young species.
They have much to learn.
But I've seen goodness in them.
Freedom is the right
of all sentient beings.
You all know there's only
one way to end this war.
We must destroy The Cube.
If all else fails, I will
unite it with the spark in my chest.
That's suicide, The Cube is raw
power, it could destroy you both.
A necessary sacrifice to
bring peace to this planet.
We cannot let the humans
pay for our mistakes.
It's been an honor
serving with you all.
Autobots roll out!
I got your intel, excellent work.
- Thank you sir, what about the gunships?
Being retrofitted with Sable round now.
The heatskin will be ready for them.
But, it won't do us much good if we can't
get world communications back up.
Hey kid.
I think we got off to a bad start.
You want a latte, double machiato?
Where's my car?
- Son...
I need you to listen to me
very carefuly. People could die here.
We need to know everything you
know, we need to know it now.
First I'll take my car, my parents...
Maybe you should write that down.
And her jouvie record.
That's gotta be gone.
Like, forever.
Come with me, we'll
talk about your car.
Thank you.
Man's an extortionist.
Allright, here's the situation.
You've all had direct contanct
with the NBE's. - NBE's?
Non Biological Extraterrestrial.
Try and keep up with the acronims.
What you are about to see
is totally classified.
Dear God, what is this?
We think, when he made his approach
over the North Pole
our gravitational field
screwed up his telemetry.
He crashed in the ice,
probably few thousand years ago.
We shiped him here to this
facility in 1934.
Call him NBE-1.
Sir I don't mean to trash on
everything you think you know but...
That's Megatron.
He's the leader of the Decepticons.
He's been in cryostasis since 1935.
Your great great grandfather,
made one of the gratest discoveries
in the history of mankind. - Fact is
you're looking at the source of modern age.
Microchip, lasers, space flight,
cars, all reverse engineered
by studying him, NBE-1.
That's what we call it.
And you didn't think the US military
might need to know
that you're keeping a hostile
alien robot frozen in the basement?
Until these events we had no
credible threat to national security.
Well you got one now.
So why Earth?
- It's the Allspark.
Allspark?
What is that?
They came here looking
for some cube looking thing.
And mr. NBE-1 here, aka Megatron,
That's what they called him.
Who's pretty much the harbinger of death
wants to use The Cube to transform
human technology to take over the universe.
That's their plane.
- Are you sure about that?
You guys know where it
is don't you?
Follow me.
You're about to see
our crown jewel.
Carbon dateing puts the Cube
here arround 10000 B.C.
The First Seven didn't find it
until 1913.
They knew it was alien becouse of the matching
hyeroglyphics on the cube aswell as NBE-1.
President Hoover had
the dam built arround it.
4 football fields thick concrete,
perfect way to hide its energy
from being detected by anyone
or any alien species on the outside.
Back up, you said the dam hides
The Cube's energy...
What kind exatcly?
- Good question.
Please step inside,
they have to lock us in.
Has Freddy Kruger been up here?
- No man, Freddy Kruger had 4 blades man
that's only 3, that's Wolverine.
That's very funny.
Anybody have any mechanical devices,
blackberries, cell phone?
I got a phone.
Nokia's a real nasty.
You got to respect the Japaneese.
They know the way of the samurai.
Nokia's from Finland.
Yes but he's, you know...
We're able to take The Cube radiation...
Bundled into that box.
Mean little sucker.
- That thing is freaky!
Kinda like energizer
bunny from hell.
Gentlemen, they know
The Cube is here.
What's going on?
NBE-1 haler has lost power.
Backup generator, it just not gonna cut.
Do you have an arms room?
Get everyone to the
NBE-1 chamber now!
They're poppin our generators.
Cryogenic system is failing.
We're loosing NBE1.
I want all Sable rounds
on that table.
You got to take me to my car.
You have to take me to my car,
he's gonna know what to do with The Cube.
Your car, it's confiscated.
- Unconiscate it.
We don't know what will
happen if let him near this thing.
Maybe you know, but I don't.
- You just want to whait here and see what happens?
I have people's lives at stake
here young man!
Drop it.
Drop your weapon soldier.
There's an alien war going on
and you're gonna shoot me?
No we didn't asked to be here.
- I'm oredering you on the S-7 executive juristiction.
S-7 don't exist. - We don't take orders
from people who don't exist.
I'm gonna count to 5.
- I'm gonna count to 3.
Simmons?
- Yes sir?
I'd what he says, loosing
is not an option for these guys.
Allright.
You wanna lay the faith of the
world on the kids camaro...
That's cool.
Stop!
Let him go!
You ok?
They didn't hurt you, right?
Listen to me, The Cube is
here, Decepticons are coming.
Don't worry about them,
they're ok, they're not gonna hurt you.
Just back up a little bit.
He's friendly, he's fine.
Put the guns down,
they're not gonna hurt you.
Come with me, we'll take
you to the Allspark.
Ok, here we go.
He's doing something.
Message from starfleet captain.
Let's get to it.
He's right, if we stay here we're
screwed with Megatron in other hangar.
and we're gonna hide it
somewhere in the city.
Mission City is 22 miles away.
We're gonna sneak that cube outta here
But we cannot make a stand
without the airforce.
This place must have some
kind of radio link...
Yes. - Short waves...
Right.
Sir you gotta figure out some way
to get the word out in the open.
You need alien archives sir.
Old army radio constant.
Will it work?
- It's possible...
We're set, get in the car!
Mr. secretary, get our broads in the air
when we get to the city
we're gonna find a radio on a F spectre, ok?
Set up perimeter arround
the yellow sealed door!
I am Megatron!
I live to serve you Lord Megatron.
- Where is The Cube?
The humans have taken it.
You fail me yet again
Starscream. Get them!
Over here sir.
We're hot, we're alive!
- Where are the mics?
Mics? - It doens't
work without the mics.
Let's find them.
Get in the chair.
How do we get the signal out?
How do we call the airforce?!
Glenn, can you hotwire this
computer to transmit a tone through the radio?
What good is that? - Morse code,
you can use this to transmit it through that.
Ok I'll do it.
Turn arround.
Simmons I need a screwdriver!
There's Optimus.
Allmost done.
What the hell was that?
Barricade the door.
Here, put some rounds in it.
I got it, we're transmitting!
- Send exactly what I say!
Defence secretary Keller...
What was that? - Authenticate
emergency action, blackbird 1195...
Sir I have authenticated air strike
order from Sector.
No, no, no!
- What?
Same cop.
Cool mom!
This is so not good.
He's behind the pillar.
Shoot that mother...
Maggie cover fire!
The air force!
They're responding!
Yes, they're sending F22's
to the scene!
Here, I've got short wave radios.
What am I supposed to do with these?
- Use the, that's all we got.
This is like dinosaur radio, man.
I'm only gonna get 20-30 miles out of this thing.
Are there any aircraft
orbiting the city?
F22 12 o'clock.
I want planes for air cover
and  get black hawks on station
to extract that cube, got it?
Air force has arrived, pop smoke!
Raptor do you copy?
We have you on visual.
Green smoke is the mark. Provide air cover
and vector black hawks for extraction.
It's Starscream!
Please tell me you copy.
Back up!
- Fall back!
Incoming!
Anybody hurt?!
Everyone ok?!
Bumblebee...
You allright?
Please God...
Bumblebee get up!
What the hell was that?!
What are you talking about?!
What do you mean what
am I talking abut?!
They shot at us!
- F22 pilots will never fly
below buildings.
That's alien, that ain't friendly.
You gotta get up.
You're ok.
Black Hawk inbound
to your location, over.
A 273 10 miles.
NW 1,2 cliclks north.
Move out, let's go!
I'm not gonna leave you.
Come on Decepticon punk!
Concentrate you fire!
It's Megatron retreat!
Pull back!
We need air cover now!
Sam help me with this.
Come here you little creepner.
You wanna piece of me?!
You wanna piece?!
No, I want 2!
What's going on?
Sir, that tank thing is
getting back up!
These things just don't die.
Where's The Cube?
- Right there.
You got to wrap it arround
the base and his neck.
Epps get those black hawks here.
That building.
I gotta go meet my guys back there,
so here take this flare.
There's a tall white building
with statues on top
go to the roof, set the flare,
signal the chopper.
I can't do it!
- Listen to me, you're a soldier now!
I need you to take this cube get
it into military hands while we hold them off.
Or alot of people are gonna die.
You got to go.
You need to go.
I'm not leaving until I get
Bumblebee out of here.
Black hawk, requesting emediate
evac, civilian boy precious cargo.
headed to rooftop marked by flare.
Sam we will protect you.
- Ok.
Sam...
No matter what happens, I'm
really glad I got in that car with you.
Sam get to the building!
- Move!
Watch out!
Girl get that tow truck out of here!
- I'm going!
Get outta here now!
Megatron!
- Prime!
Humans don't deserve to live.
- They deserve to choose for themselves.
You will die with them!
Join them in extinction!
Keep moving Sam.
Sam get to the building!
Give me that cube boy!
That jerk just demped my car.
I smell you boy!
I'll drive, you shoot!
This isn't going well.
- Shoot!
Nice shot.
Ok he's definitively dead now.
- Let's go, we've got business.
Watch out!
Hang on Sam!
Is it fear or courage that
compeles you fleshling?
Give me the Allspark and
you may live to be my pet.
I'm never giving you this Allspark.
Oh so wise.
I got you boy.
Hold on to The Cube.
Sam...
You risked your life to
protect The Cube.
No sacrifice...
No victory.
- If I cannot defeat Megatron...
You must push The Cube into my chest.
I will sacrifice myself
to destroy it.
Get behind me.
It's you and me Megatron.
- No, it's just me Prime.
At the end of this day,
one shall stand, one shall fall.
You still fight for the weak,
that is why you lose.
Fighters in 60 seconds.
We got friendlies mixed with
bad guys, targets will be marked.
Bring the rain.
Let's kill these things.
Target marked, still waiting.
- Coming on target, 20 seconds.
That's 22 so stay away.
Move out!
Take them out!
Sam put The Cube in my chest now!
Hold up.
You left me no choice brother.
Sam I owe you my life.
We are in your debt.
Prime, we couldn't save him.
- Oh Jazz...
We lost a great comrade.
But gained new ones, thank you, all of you.
You honor us with your bravery.
Permission to speak sir.
Permission granted, old friend.
- You speak now?
I wish to stay with the boy.
If that is his choice.
Yes.
Gentlemen, the president has
ordered sector 7
be terminated, and the remains
of the dead aliens
disposed of.
Marionas Abiss, is 7 miles below
sea level, deepest place on our planet.
Massive depth and pressure there,
coupled with subfreezing temperatures
will crush them.
Leaving no evidence.
With the Allspark gone,
we cannot return life to our planet.
And faith has yielded it's reward.
A new world to call home.
We live among it's people now,
hiding in plane sight.
But watching over them in secret.
Waiting...
Protecting...
I have witnessed their
capacity for courage.
And though we are worlds apart,
like us, there's more to them than meets the eye.
I am Optimus Prime, and I send
this message to any surviving Autobots
taking refuge among the stars.
We are here...
We are waiting...
Subtitles by:
Sentinel