(LOGAN COUGHING)
-You're aIways sick.
-You were sick when you were my age.
-Evening, sir.
-Evening, Victor.
I didn't reaIize you were stiII here.
I was just keeping James company, sir,
if that's aII right.
Very kind of you.
-Any better, Son?
-StiII coId, Father.
JOHN: Just a miId fever.
-You'II be aII right in the morning.
-You aIways say that.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) And you aIways
puII through, don't you?
-Yeah.
-Now, you taking your medicine?
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
THOMAS: EIizabeth! EIizabeth!
-Your father's drunk again.
-THOMAS: EIizabeth!
-You shouId heIp him home, Victor.
-It's not my name he's caIIing, sir.
-Father!
-Stay where you are, James.
-ELIZABETH: Get off me!
-Father!
THOMAS: Now! You never Ioved him !
JOHN:
I toId you never to come back here.
(GUN FIRES )
(ELIZABETH SHRIEKING)
THOMAS: Get out!
(BARELY AUDIBLE) James?
-No.
-THOMAS: James?
-There are things you don't understand.
-Don't.
-I need him to know!
-ELIZABETH: PIease don't.
THOMAS: No more Iies.
ELIZABETH: James...
(SCREAMING)
(GUN FIRES )
-No!
-ELIZABETH: James!
He... He wasn't your father,
Son.
What are you?
-I didn't mean it! I didn't mean it!
-Yes, you did!
He deserved it, and you gave it to him.
We're brothers, Jimmy. You reaIize that?
And brothers protect each other.
You have to be hard now,
hard so nothing can ever touch us.
-I want to go home.
-We can't.
We stick together, no matter what,
and take care of anyone
who gets in our way.
(DOGS BARKING)
Can you do that, IittIe brother?
MAN: I'm going down to the river.
VICTOR: They're coming.
MAN: Head over the hiII. Hurry!
VICTOR: Can you run?
-Keep on running and don't Iook back.
-LOGAN: Okay.
(LOGAN YELLING)
LOGAN: Back to back!
(GUN COCKING)
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
That's enough!
Enough!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
No! No!
Stand down, soIdier!
Victor!
Stand down! Stand down!
Stand down!
No!
Ready, aim...
Wake me when it's over.
...fire!
GUARD: Freaks! You're animaIs! Freaks!
My name is Major WiIIiam Stryker.
You've been charged
with kiIIing a senior officer.
Is that correct?
ApparentIy, we have some issues
with authority...
-Just keep a Iid on it.
-...sir.
The warden teIIs me that your sentence
was carried out by a firing squad
at 1000 hours.
-How'd that go?
-It tickIed.
You boys tired of running?
Tired of denying your true nature?
-What do you care?
-Oh, I care.
I care because I know how speciaI you are.
How vaIuabIe.
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
Look, you can stay here
Iocked up Iike freaks of nature,
or you can join me.
I'm putting together a speciaI team
with speciaI priviIeges.
Now, teII me, how wouId you Iike
to reaIIy serve your country?
(BLADE CLINKING)
You know, I Iove this weapon
more than any other thing
in the whoIe wide worId.
-Do you wanna know why?
-No.
It's memorabIe.
Sure, it's a IittIe buIky,
tough to get on a pIane.
You whip out a coupIe of swords
at your ex-girIfriend's wedding,
they wiII never, ever forget it.
That's funny, Wade.
I think you confuse me
with someone who gives a shit.
(SCOFFS ) Right, it's probabIy not
as intimidating as having a gun
or bone cIaws
or the fingernaiIs of a bag Iady.
-Manicure?
-Victor. Easy.
Fred got a new tattoo. I'm concerned.
Oh, Jesus, Fred,
you just met her Iast night.
-I Iove her.
-You Iove her after one night?
She's a gymnast.
BradIey, take her down.
Oh, God.
-Are you gonna puke?
-If we were meant to fIy,
-we'd grow wings.
-Aw, don't worry, Nancy.
-More peopIe die driving than fIying.
-How about from impaIing?
Hey, be nice,
or be your approximation of nice.
-WouId you Iike a bucket?
-No.
STRYKER: GentIemen,
wheeIs down in Lagos in five.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
-Why are we here?
-AII in good time. Zero?
MAN 1 : Intruder! Perimeter breach!
MAN 2: Man the weapon!
(GUNS COCKING)
MAN 1 : Intruder, stop!
Put your hands behind your head!
Having fun yet?
-Fred?
-The tank?
-The tank.
-Yeah, I got that.
(CHUCKLING)
(MUZAK PLAYING)
Great. Stuck in an eIevator
with five guys on a high-protein diet.
-STRYKER: Wade.
-Dreams reaIIy do come true.
Just shut it!
-You're up next.
-Thank you, sir. You Iook reaIIy nice today.
It's the green.
It brings out the seriousness in your eyes.
-Oh, my God. Do you ever shut up, paI?
-No. Not when I'm awake.
BradIey? Top fIoor, pIease.
Cover the eIevator! The eIevator!
(GUNS COCKING)
Time to go to work.
Okay. PeopIe are dead.
If you didn't have that mouth on you,
Wade, you'd be the perfect soIdier.
I wouIdn't do that if I was you, brother.
-Take the diamonds. They're yours.
-I don't want your diamonds.
I want this.
But that is nothing. A souvenir.
Where did you find it? I want the source.
A smaII viIIage, far inIand,
three days from here.
TeII him this rock is
more vaIuabIe to me than his Iife.
Ask him where he found it.
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(MAN SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
WADE: Okay.
He says it came from the sky.
He's teIIing the truth.
You don't know the Ianguage, Logan.
-It's a meteor fragment.
-STRYKER: I know what it is.
I'm asking him where he found it.
Sir, base wants to know our Iocation.
-Shut them down.
-Yes.
TeII him everyone here wiII die
unIess he teIIs me
where he found the rock.
(WADE SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(MAN SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(SIGHING)
-WADE: He says that it's sacred.
-Okay, fine.
Victor.
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(GUN FIRES )
Victor!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Don't even think about it.
We didn't sign up for this.
Put him down!
(PANTING)
What are you doing?
We finaIIy got a good thing going here.
Don't you screw this up.
Enough. That's enough.
We've done enough.
Who do you think you are?
This is what we do.
Maybe you'd rather be
rotting in a hoIe somewhere
tiII they figure out a way to do it to us.
Is that it? Huh?
I'm done.
You coming?
Jimmy!
We can't just Iet you waIk away.
Why are you up so earIy?
Come here.
See you, baby.
Hey.
(MEN LAUGHING)
Oh, that's nice. Yes. Take your time.
You're wrapped, man.
(FAIR MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE WHOOPING)
GIRL: Okay, I'm totaIIy gonna get this.
BOY: Nope. Come on.
Oh, wow! Let's go on the Ferris wheeI.
GIRL: How does he do it?
BOY: Come on.
MAN 1 : ...amazing Iady in a box!
MAN 2: Swing the hammer, ring the beII!
Hey, what do you do?
Oh. If you turn off the Iight,
you win a prize.
-Three tries for a buck.
-Come on, I wanna do it.
There you go. Okay?
No, that's obvious.
That's two.
(SIZZLING SOFTLY)
WeII, that's a stupid trick.
It's not a trick, man.
Come on. Freak.
Bye.
(BEEPING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Show's over!
(KNOCKING CONTINUES )
I said show's over!
The show's never over for us, BradIey.
-Victor.
-Aren't you gonna invite me in?
Yeah. Come on in.
You know, I've never said anything
to anyone about what happened.
I'm Iiving a totaIIy
different Iife now, Victor.
No need to bring up the past.
You know,
I aIways thought it wouId
be Wade to come knocking at my door.
WeII... WeII,
Wade's gone.
I'm not afraid of you, Victor.
I'm not afraid of dying.
How do you know?
You've never tried it before.
(BRADLEY SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
KAYLA: Was it the wars?
Which one?
AII of them.
-TeII me.
-Hey.
It's just a scratch.
Looks Iike we're gonna need
new sheets again, baby.
Yeah.
PHELAN: Who the heII is this?
SmeIIs Iike government.
My God. Haven't aged a day!
CIean Iiving.
-You remember Agent Zero?
-StiII shooting first, asking questions Iater?
-You stiII chewing on cheap cigars?
-STRYKER: Boys, pIease.
-I have a job for you.
-I aIready have a job.
Lumberjack? 18 grand a year?
18.5. PIus I haven't had to kiII anyone
in a whiIe.
-Starting to miss it?
-Right about now I am.
-Yeah?
-Zero, back to the car.
Attaboy.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
You know, I'm not proud about
the way things ended between us.
Conversation's over.
PIaying Little House on the Prairie
with a schooIteacher,
I mean, that just isn't you, Logan.
And you wouId know, huh?
-I wouId.
-What do you want, Stryker?
BradIey was kiIIed three days ago.
Wade before that.
I beIieve that someone is hunting down
our oId team.
-Anyone eIse?
-As far as I know, Victor is safe.
But whoever it is has names, addresses.
I can take care of myseIf.
This is not about you, Logan.
Your country needs you.
I'm Canadian.
I know you, Logan! I know who you are!
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
-Miss KayIa, Miss KayIa, Iook what I did.
-What did you do?
GIRL: Bye, Miss SiIverfox! Bye!
KAYLA: What's wrong?
Stryker came by today.
Don't worry. I said no.
Why is he bothering you
after aII these years?
Because I'm the best there is at what I do,
but what I do best isn't very nice.
You're not an animaI, Logan.
What you have is a gift.
A gift. You can return a gift.
Come on, feIIas.
(HONKING HORN)
AII right.
Stay in the car.
I'm just gonna ask niceIy.
You mind Ietting us go by?
-You in some kind of a hurry there, paI?
-Hey, hey, hey.
Are you?
Just move your truck so we can go by.
We're trying to have
a conversation there, aII right?
You start something,
you'd better be ready to finish it.
Listen...
KAYLA: Hey, guys, take it easy! CaIm down.
-Your boyfriend's got a big mouth.
-I know.
Big temper, too. So pIease Iet us pass.
-Thank you.
-MAN: Come on, man, Iet's go.
How'd you do that?
FemaIe powers of persuasion. It's a gift.
Oh, I see.
Do you have those powers over me?
WeII, you didn't stay in the car, did you?
(HOWLING)
KAYLA: Why is the moon so IoneIy?
Why?
-Because she used to have a Iover.
-Oh.
-You teII this to the kids?
-No.
(LOGAN LAUGHS )
His name was Kuekuatsheu
and they Iived in the Spirit WorId together.
-Oh, this is a true story? AII right.
-Mmm-hmm.
And every night they wouId
wander the skies together...
Oh.
...but one of the other spirits was jeaIous.
Trickster wanted the moon for himseIf,
so he toId Kuekuatsheu
that the moon had asked for fIowers.
He toId him to come to our worId
and pick her some wiId roses,
but Kuekuatsheu didn't know
that once you Ieave the Spirit WorId,
you can never go back.
And every night he Iooks up in the sky
and sees the moon and howIs her name.
But
he can never touch her again.
Wow.
Koo-koo-ka-choo got screwed.
''Kuekuatsheu.''
(LAUGHING)
It means ''the WoIverine''.
(SNIFFS )
What you doing, Logan?
KayIa.
(PANTING)
Oh, God.
KayIa !
(SCREAMING)
You're not from around here, are you?
(LAUGHING)
What gave me away?
LOGAN: Victor!
-You got insurance on this pIace?
-Insurance? No.
-Too bad.
-LOGAN: Victor!
WeII, weII, weII.
Look what the cat dragged in.
Guys, whatever this is, take it outside.
Why?
(LAUGHING)
You don't caII. You don't write.
How eIse am I supposed
to get your attention?
(LOGAN GROWLING)
(SCREAMS )
(LOGAN GROANING)
I hate to say it, Jimmy, but, frankIy,
I'm a IittIe disappointed.
Stay down.
TeII me something, Jimmy.
Was she worth it?
(TRUCK APPROACHING)
When are you gonna figure it out?
We're not Iike them.
I am nothing Iike you.
Sure, you are.
You just don't know it yet.
(SCREAMING)
(SIRENS BLARING)
-DOCTOR: What do we got?
-Bar fight. MuItipIe knife wounds.
What is this, a joke? Guy's fine.
LOGAN: Where is he?
DOCTOR: Hey, hey, don't...
-I said, where is he?
-I don't know who he is.
STRYKER: I can heIp you.
Six years I've been here.
No one knew me, and then you show up,
and the next day she's dead!
I tried to warn you.
Why didn't you teII me it was Victor?
-I didn't know!
-BuIIshit!
-Why?
-I swear on my son's Iife, I didn't!
Victor's appetites were
becoming too pubIic.
I had to Iock him up.
He feIt I betrayed him.
Went AWOL.
He said he was coming after aII of us.
You didn't come to warn me,
you came to save your own ass.
So what's your pIan, Captain?
You can't beat him, Logan,
you know you can't!
I'm gonna find him and kiII him.
I can give you the tooIs to defeat him.
And we can stiII save the others.
You mean save yourseIf, right?
I promise you two things.
You wiII suffer more pain
than any other man can endure,
but you wiII have your revenge.
I come with you, I'm coming for bIood.
No Iaw. No code of conduct.
You point me in the right direction,
you get the heII out of my way.
When it starts, whatever the reason is
that you're doing this,
focus on that. Maybe it wiII heIp.
Trust me, I've been through worse.
No, you haven't.
We're ready.
We're gonna make you indestructibIe,
but first we're gonna have to destroy you.
You remember
what we were Iooking for in Africa?
-I remember.
-WeII, I found it.
It heIped us create
a metaI compound so strong
that you wiII be abIe to withstand
virtuaIIy anything.
It's caIIed Adamantium.
I can't put Victor down myseIf, Logan.
To kiII him, you're gonna have to embrace
the other side.
Become the animaI.
Let's do this.
I aImost forgot.
I want new ones.
What do you want them to say?
WoIverine.
(AIR HISSING)
STRYKER: GeneraIs, weIcome.
GeneraI Munson.
Today we're gonna witness
medicaI history.
-Today we're gonna create Weapon X.
-X?
Roman numeraI 10.
We are about to begin bonding
Adamantium to Weapon X's skeIeton.
Let's begin.
(ECG BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
-We're brothers, Jimmy.
-VlCTOR: Logan!
Body temperature, 108 and rising.
Why is he thrashing Iike that?
Why isn't he sedated?
He feeIs pain just Iike the rest of us,
but anesthesia won't work on him.
-That's why he had to voIunteer.
-Heart rate, 190. 195.
MUNSON: WiII he survive this?
STRYKER: I don't know.
200.
Son.
(ECG BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Heart rate weII beyond maximum.
-BIood pressure?
-CORNELIUS: 260 over 180 and rising.
He can make it. He can make it.
Victor!
(VlCTOR sCReamlng)
ka YLa.: l loee you.
You're not an animal.
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
(HEARTBEAT SLOWS )
It means ''the WoIverine''.
(ECG FLATLINING)
ZERO: WeII, I guess he can die.
(WHISPERING)
Come on, oId friend. Come back.
Heart rate rising.
Adamantium reservoir is depIeted.
No rejection. Procedure compIeted.
-We did it.
Yeah! Yes.
Are we taking him to the isIand?
The isIand? No.
The bonding works.
We'II use his DNA for the XI.
Erase his memory.
I think he heard you.
(ROARING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Lock down!
(PANTING)
(GUN COCKING)
Hunt him down. Take his head off.
HEATHER: Travis.
-I think there's a naked man in the barn.
-Yep.
(LOGAN PANTING)
Son?
What in heII you doing?
-It's coId.
-CoId.
-You got no cIothes on.
-Yeah.
-You're not on the drugs, are you?
-No.
-No, just had a rough night.
-Yeah, you couId say that.
Come on up to the house.
Some of my son's oId cIothes
wiII probabIy fit you.
Here. Cover it up with that, huh?
I don't want you giving
the oId Iady a heart attack.
(BLADES CLINKING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(EX CLAIMING)
(HISSING)
-You aII right in there?
-Yeah, yeah, I'm fine!
Supper's on the tabIe.
Uh, yeah, I'II be there in a minute.
Oh.
I swear, I'm gonna pay for it.
-Set it down over there.
-Right.
Come and sit down, son.
I can't thank you both enough
for everything.
It wouIdn't have been decent
to Ieave you out there to freeze.
-''Decent.''
-What?
Nothing. I'm just not
reaIIy used to that word.
That's a nice chopper you've got out there.
-You know motorcycIes?
-Oh! Lord, here we go.
My favorite's a '48 Panhead.
Bought one new off the Iine.
I think you're a IittIe young for that, son.
You must be exhausted.
You get a good night's sIeep.
In the barn.
Nothing you can break out there.
(LOGAN CHUCKLES )
ka YLa.: Why is the moon so lonely?
LOgan.: Why?
ka YLa.: Because she used to haee a loeer.
He can neeer touch her aGain.
You sIeep okay?
Uh, yeah.
You Iook Iike a man
fixing to do a bad thing.
You know what happens
to men who go Iooking for bIood?
-What?
-They find it.
We aII got a choice, son.
-Yeah, weII, mine got taken.
-BuIIshit.
This was my son's jacket.
Try it on.
-Thank you.
-Yep.
You want to take my bike for a spin?
Test the suspension?
'64, huh?
(CREAKS LOUDLY)
Man, you're heavy.
Yeah, I put on a IittIe weight recentIy.
HEATHER: Good morning!
LOGAN: Good morning.
Oh. It fits you beautifuIIy.
I brought you some...
Weapon X is in the barn.
He's just murdered two civiIians.
STRYKER: BIow him to bits.
Let's see if he can survive that.
Come get me.
BIow his brains aII over the road!
Damn it!
AIpha one, do not Iose him !
AIpha two! Target coming to you!
PuII up!
(HELICOPTER ALARM BEEPING RAPIDLY)
PuII back! PuII back!
sTRYkeR On RaDlO.: Zero?
Zero, come in.
Zero?
-Zero, is LoGan dead?
-ZERO: I don't know.
I'm down.
Zero, is he dead? ls LoGan dead?
Zero, come in.
LOgan.: You tried to kill me.
-Logan?
-Where's Victor?
Come back to base.
I'II expIain everything.
We'II take Victor down together.
Wrong answer.
After I kiII Victor, I'm coming for you.
LoGan, listen to me.
If you go down this road,
you're not gonna Iike what you find.
You wanted the animaI, CoIoneI.
You got it.
Those were good peopIe back there.
Innocent peopIe.
(LAUGHING)
It's funny how good, innocent peopIe tend
to die around you.
CORNELIUS: Zero never stood a chance.
The onIy thing that'II take him down
is an Adamantium buIIet.
This faciIity's compromised.
Prep transport.
CoIoneI, this is turning into a disaster.
-Don't worry. We'II stop him.
-ReaIIy?
You just spent haIf a biIIion doIIars
making him indestructibIe.
(DOOR OPENING)
-AIDE: Sir?
-Yes?
The young mutant you've been Iooking for.
We've found him.
GeneraI, Logan isn't
the onIy piece of this puzzIe.
I need to evacuate this faciIity.
PIease go back to Washington.
We've got work to do.
Yo hablo, I taIk. Tu hablas, you taIk.
El habla... Somebody transIate.
Summers!
Sit up and take off those gIasses.
I have a headache.
Then you can wear them
in detention after schooI
whiIe you write out this conjugation
100 times.
-Somebody eIse?
-BOY: He taIks.
TEACHER: Thank you. He taIks. El habla.
-You sure it was Victor?
-Yeah.
Damn. I'm sorry, man.
What the heII happened to him after I Ieft?
He got worse.
He feIt Iike you abandoned him.
HeII, we aII did.
But Victor, he had to prove
he was better than you.
Hunting and kiIIing
everything he was pointed at.
Quit a few months Iater myseIf.
CouIdn't take rounding them up.
-Rounding who up?
-Leave it aIone.
Rounding who up, John?
Hey! Damn it, John!
We hunted our own kind, Logan.
There's a speciaI pIace in heII
for the things we did.
Mutants? Why?
Stryker said we'd be making a difference,
protecting peopIe from the bad ones.
How are you gonna take
Victor down, Logan?
-Remember that stuff in Africa?
-Yeah, I remember Africa. What about it?
Damn.
What'd they do to you, man?
Don't ask.
Listen, Zero said something
about an isIand.
Does that mean anything to you?
Nope. But maybe Dukes knows.
-Him and Zero were reaI tight.
-Fred Dukes? Where is he?
-He's here.
-WeII, Iet's go taIk to him.
HoId on. He don't get in tiII around 4:00.
But I got to warn you, he deveIoped
a bit of an eating disorder.
We aII got our coping mechanisms.
I'm trying to whup him back into shape.
Whatever you do,
don't mention his weight.
Come on, Fred, if you wanna get
in shape, you got to move, man.
I toId him he got to move.
He's got to move! What?
LOGAN: Fred Dukes? That Iooks Iike
the creature that ate Fred Dukes.
WRAITH: Hey, be nice, man.
Hey, fat... Fred.
I seem to remember that girI
when she was about 85 pounds, huh?
Oh, that's funny.
You're stiII so funny, Logan.
You know where Victor is?
-No idea.
-What's the isIand, sIim?
Don't Iet the door hit you
on the way out, Logan.
Listen, I ain't Ieaving here
tiII you teII me where Victor is.
So come on, bub, for oId times' sake, huh?
Did you just caII me BIob?
No, but...
(ROARING)
I toId you not to mention his weight.
Why'd you caII him BIob?
I didn't caII him BIob. I said ''bub''.
-God damn it.
-Hey, hey, hey. Hey, Logan.
I got an idea.
-This is your idea of an idea?
-I'm trying to heIp you out, Logan.
Dukes don't Iike you that much
and you know it.
-Yeah, the feeIing's mutuaI.
-WeII, use them gIoves, man.
Dance with him a IittIe bit.
AIIow him to Iet his anger out on you.
Figure if you do that, he'II probabIy
teII you everything you want to know.
Come on, man, Iook at him.
Got a big oId ass coming out
the front of his shirt.
Jesus. He's gonna have a coronary,
for Christ's sake.
Is there even a stretcher big enough
to take this guy out of here?
It ain't him I'm worried about
getting out of here on a stretcher.
-You're an asshoIe.
-DUKES: Come on, Logan.
(BELL RINGS )
-Whup his ass!
-You want it?
WRAITH: Dance with him, Fred!
Just Iike I taught you.
You want to dance with me?
-WRAITH: Come on, Fred!
-Oh! Oh, that feeIs good.
Hey! Guess what?
See, he gonna taIk now.
-You got him right where you want him.
-Whose side are you on, anyway?
DUKES: Come on!
Come on, now, Iamb chop!
Damn!
(SCREAMING)
Now, where's Victor?
(GRUNTING)
LittIe dark for sungIasses, don't you think?
-PIease, don't! PIease, don't!
-Victor!
Hey, hey! Where's Victor?
Yeah. Victor's with Stryker on the isIand.
(STAMMERING) They run it together.
What? They what?
Victor wiII be with Stryker?
Yeah.
You didn't know that?
(SHUDDERING)
(SCOTT GRUNTING)
(ZAPPING)
AII that's Ieft now is Logan.
I trust you can handIe that.
-I did before, didn't I?
-Oh, yes. You did that.
Our deaI. It stiII appIies, right?
Of course.
Now bag him and tag him, Captain.
What's the isIand?
(STAMMERING) It's where Stryker takes
them after Victor's caught them.
Wait, hang on a minute. Takes who?
Mutants.
Rumor is that Stryker's doing
experiments on them there.
I mean, you never wondered
what happened to them?
I tried not to.
They kiIIed her so I'd Iet them
put Adamantium in me.
They kiIIed her for a goddamn experiment.
-Where is it? Where is it?
-Logan, Stryker kept it reaI secret.
But a prisoner escaped there once.
-Who?
-His name was Remy LeBeau.
He was a street hustIer from New OrIeans.
The guards at the prison
caIIed him Gambit
because he kept taking
aII their money at poker.
-That's aII I know.
-What's Stryker up to, Fred?
What's the endgame?
He's taking their powers.
Trying to combine them somehow.
That's aII I know, Logan. That's aII I know.
If I have to come back here,
I'm gonna take your head off.
I'm coming with you, Logan.
-There's no redemption where I'm going.
-I ain't asking.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
(GIRLS CHEERING)
There's our dude.
That's cooI.
I'm gonna go cover the back
in case he rabbits.
-I'm not gonna fight with him.
-Yeah, right.
What? I get in fights with everybody?
Don't dogs kiII cats?
Just go cover the back, wiII you?
MAN 1 : Give me 500.
MAN 2: I'm in.
Are you Remy LeBeau?
-Do I owe you money?
-No.
Then Remy LeBeau I am.
(BOTTLE CLATTERING)
Large bIind's 100. SmaII bIind's 50.
-May I deaI you in?
-What can I get for 17 bucks?
$17?
A cab ride home, perhaps?
You my brother's new babysitter, John?
I ain't BradIey, Victor.
And your creepy bIack coat
don't scare me.
ReaIIy?
Worked on Dukes.
You shouIdn't have done that,
'cause now I'm gonna kiII you
before Logan even gets a chance.
So what brings you to our fair city, sir?
Victor Creed.
And who's that?
The man I'm gonna kiII.
(VICTOR LAUGHING)
He works with a man named Stryker
on an isIand.
-Just need to know where it is.
-And why wouId you think I know that?
WeII, 'cause I know who you are, Gambit.
You're the guy who escaped and you're
the guy who's gonna take me back there.
You know, John, there's something
I aIways wanted to teII you.
(GASPING)
You're predictabIe.
Ooh!
I can feeI your spine, Johnny Boy.
That's funny. Never knew you had one.
Those are mighty nice tags
you have on there, sir.
The men who took me wore
tags just Iike them.
Hey, now, bub, you Iisten to me.
Damn it. That IittIe...
Two years I rotted in that heIIhoIe
and I ain't never going back.
Oh! Shiny.
TeII me something, Jimmy.
Do you even know how to kiII me?
I'm gonna cut your goddamned head off.
See if that works.
(LAUGHING)
You're getting sIow, oId man.
(SCREAMING)
You son of a bitch.
You're gonna die for what you did to her.
Victor!
WeII, that's a nice stick.
Okay, shithead, here's the deaI.
See, you're gonna take me to this isIand,
where I can kiII Creed, Stryker
and pretty much everyone you hate
in this worId. Do you understand?
You're reaIIy gonna kiII them?
As Iong as you stay out of my way, yeah.
MUNSON: CoIoneI?
-GeneraI?
-Is this Weapon XI?
AII their strengths
and none of their weaknesses.
You reaIIy hate them, don't you?
No, I don't hate them.
After 20 years of working with mutants,
I just know what they can do.
We can win this war before it starts
and save countIess Iives in the process.
Pre-emptive action is
the onIy action here, GeneraI.
The days of our country
sitting on the sideIines are over.
We need to take the fight to the enemy
before they take the fight to us.
-I admire your passion, I do.
-Thank you.
But this is as far as it goes.
-Weapon X was a hiccup.
-We know about your son, BiII.
We know he's a mutant,
and we know he kiIIed your wife.
-You shouIdn't have kept that from us.
-That...
That has nothing
to do with my work, GeneraI.
BuIIshit.
You're too cIose to this.
I'm shutting you down.
Okay. You're right. I won't Iie to you.
My son did bring
the probIem home for me,
but I took an oath
to protect the American peopIe
from every threat, both foreign
(GROANING)
and domestic.
-You don't Iike fIying, huh?
-I'm fine.
-Just concentrate on what you're doing.
-You sure?
You got a bit of sweat
on your brow there.
Very funny. Just keep your eyes on the...
On the what? The cIouds?
Keep my eyes on the cIouds?
You're up and down
Iike a freaking yo-yo here!
-Where'd you get this thing, anyway?
-Oh, this is my baby.
I won her in a game. Jacks over fives.
Great.
REMY: ReIax. We're aImost there.
There it is. The isIand. Three MiIe IsIand.
Hiding in pIain sight.
No one's gonna snoop
around a nucIear reactor.
They think it's gonna turn them
into freaks.
-Like you?
-Right.
AII right. You ready?
Because it's now or never. Let's go.
About time.
Hey, if it makes you feeI any better,
this is reaIIy gonna hurt.
WeII, yeah, it kind of does, actuaIIy.
-Good Iuck.
-Likewise.
Oh, shit.
How you doing? Everything aII right?
-Is he ready yet?
-A few more hours.
-And he wiII respond to my commands?
-AbsoIuteIy.
Logan.
WeIcome back to the war.
Before I gut you, I want to know why.
I needed your powers for the PooI.
-For the what?
-The mutant kiIIer.
DeadpooI.
Years of searching and refining,
finding the right powers
that can coexist in one body
without ripping it apart.
My son was the first piece of the puzzIe.
Logan, you were the Iast.
You made Weapon XI possibIe.
I asked you to heIp,
but you said you wanted the quiet Iife.
WeII,
I've Iearned that nothing motivates
the men in your famiIy Iike revenge.
Who are you?
Oh, she's reaI, oId friend.
(GROANING)
Did you reaIIy think
we'd just Iet you waIk away?
You're a dangerous man.
We Iike to keep an eye on dangerous men.
TeII him about the day you died.
They gave me a shot
of hydrochIorothiazide.
It reduces the heart rate so Iow
it appears you fIatIined.
(SCREAMING)
Don't be angry with her.
She's a reaI credit to your species.
Did you know that her sister has
diamond-hard skin?
KayIa's mutation is tactohypnosis.
She can infIuence peopIe
as Iong as she touches them.
Quite a usefuI tooI in a seduction.
It was never reaI, my friend.
It was reaI for me.
I toId you if you came down this road,
you wouIdn't Iike what you found.
That story you toId me about a man
who gets fIowers for the moon,
I had it backwards.
I thought you were the moon
and I was your woIverine.
But you're the trickster, aren't you?
I'm just the fooI who got pIayed.
The worst part of it is,
I shouId have known.
But I ignored my instincts.
I ignored what I reaIIy am.
But that won't ever happen again.
-CoIoneI?
-Not now, KayIa.
I've done everything you've asked.
My sister.
You said if I heIped you, you'd Iet her go.
KayIa, it's not as simpIe as that.
Her mutation is unique. Quite beautifuI.
We just need a IittIe more time
to anaIyze it, that's aII.
VICTOR: You Iet him go?
-Victor, pIease.
-You can't Iet him go.
-You can't beat him, Victor.
-Then give me the Adamantium !
-Your tests came back.
-We had a deaI!
You wouId never survive the operation.
-I can take anything he can.
-No, you can't.
You're my favorite soIdier, Victor.
Be patient. Your time wiII come.
He's using us.
(SCREAMING)
How about this time you die for reaI?
Let me go.
Your IittIe mind games don't work on me.
LOGAN: Victor!
(GROANS )
(LAUGHING)
FeeIs good, doesn't it?
AII that rage.
-Do it.
-KAYLA: Logan!
-You're not an animaI.
-Oh, yes, you are.
Do it.
Finish it.
KAYLA: Logan?
My sister. They have my sister.
PIease. I didn't trick you into Ioving me.
It was reaI for me, too.
PIease, I'm so sorry.
They have my sister.
Where is she?
-Activate Weapon XI!
-The bonding process isn't compIete.
Just do it! Now!
(DOORS OPENING)
(GRUNTING)
Come on. Come on!
(DOORS OPENING)
Okay.
Perfect.
-KayIa, get these kids out of here.
-Logan...
Find another way out.
MALE MUTANT: Okay. Let's go.
Wade, is that you?
Guess Stryker finaIIy figured out
how to shut you up.
STRYKER: Now...
Wade?
You don't have to do this.
AII right, maybe you do.
You're shitting me.
STRYKER: Shoot on sight!
-I can heIp! Point me at them !
-Go.
Go! Now!
(SCOTT SCREAMING)
-Did I get them?
-Yeah.
-Let's go.
-I can't go.
-KayIa, come on!
-I have to stay here.
You take them.
Go! Go!
Xa VleR.: (TeLePa THlCaLL Y) go left.
Left.
-What?
-We go Ieft.
-You can't see.
-Trust me.
Let's see you dance up here.
(EX CLAIMS )
(GROANS )
(SCREAMS )
Nobody kiIIs you but me.
Back to back!
-I got him !
-Oh, no, you don't.
(YELLS )
Stop! This can't be the way.
-This is the way.
-How do you know?
I just know. Come on.
STRYKER: Adamantium buIIets.
Let's see him heaI with
a few of these through his thick skuII.
You can't stop him, even with that.
-He'II heaI.
-His brain may heaI,
(GUN COCKING)
but his memories won't grow back.
(CRUMBLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
This doesn't change anything
between us, Victor.
-We're done.
-We can never be done, Jimmy.
We're brothers,
and brothers Iook out for each other.
-You miss me?
-Ah, Jesus.
You know, when you said
you were gonna kiII everyone,
I thought you may
just have been exaggerating.
Yeah.
Do I Iook Iike a man who exaggerates?
-You're weIcome.
-KAYLA: (SOFTLY) Logan?
Logan.
There's kids trying to get off the isIand.
SpIit up. Go!
I'm on it.
(KAYLA BREATHING LABOREDLY)
KayIa ! KayIa !
Hey.
I Iove you.
-Hey...
-I'm so coId.
Listen to me.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Understand?
Just go easy. Nice and easy. That's it.
That's it.
Okay. I'm gonna get you heIp.
(KAYLA SCREAMING)
(GROANS )
(ROARING)
KAYLA: Logan!
I shouId make you puII the trigger.
But that wouId make us
no better than you.
Throw the gun away.
Turn around.
WaIk untiI your feet bIeed.
And then keep waIking.
Xa VleR.: (TeLePa THlCaLL Y)
lt will be all riGht, scott.
my name is Charles Xaeier.
l'm a mutant like you.
sCOTT.: (TeLePa THlCaLL Y)
l can hear your thouGhts.
Xa VleR.: Yes, and l can hear yours.
You're safe now. Come. We have to go.
SCOTT: Come on, Iet's go.
REMY: The kids are safe.
Damn.
-Who are you?
-What do you mean, who am I?
I'm the guy who brought you here.
Now, we got to go.
Where the heII am I?
Listen to me. I'm a friend.
-I'm a friend.
-Yeah? What's my name?
-What's my name?
-Your name is Logan.
You need to trust me. We have to go.
FoIIow me.
Now!
Do you know her?
No.
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
Hey, these boys aren't gonna Iike
what you've done to this pIace.
We reaIIy need to go.
I'II find my own way.
Good Iuck.
(SIREN BLARES )
CoIoneI Stryker?
-CoIoneI WiIIiam Stryker?
-Yes.
You're wanted for questioning
in connection with the death
of GeneraI Munson, sir.
(CRUMBLING)
(SHUSHING)