Enjoy the movie with a quality transcription
interpretation. bridge@gmail. com
All Rights, If I have any left... Are reserved
Kindly refer to this subtitle when reusing it
Poland, 1944
[Nazi Soldiers shouting]
[patter  of  rain]
[Dog parking]
Mamaaaaa...
Ahh.........
Over here, come here
My son
[Metal Gate Shut]
Mama...!
Over here
[Metal Gate Clank]
Westchester, NY, 1944
[clunk]
Mother...
What are you...?!
Ahh...
I thought you were a burglar.
I did not to scare you darling,
I was just getting a snack
Go back to bed.
What is the matter?
Go on, Back to bed.
I'll make you a hot chocolate.
Who are you?
And what have you done with my mother?
My mother has never set foot
in this kitchen in her life.
And she is certainly never made me a hot chocolate
XX Unless she can't ordering the maid to do it. XX
[hissing]
You are not scared of me?
I always believed i can't be the only one in the world.
the only person who is deferent...
and here you are. Charles Xavier.
Raven.
You are hungry and alone.
Take whatever you want
We got a lots of food
you do not have to steal.
In fact...
...You never have to steal again.
You must understand, Erik,
These Nazis, I do not like them
Genes are the most important thing, Right?
But what about strings of genes?
Blue eyes? Blonde hair? Sounds silly.
take the chocolate.
Delicious.
Do not you think?
I want to see my mother.
Genes are the key to the door leading into a new era, Eric
A new future for humanity
Evolution.
You know what I mean?
I am not asking for much.
a small coin, it's nothing
compared to the huge gates.
Isn't that right?
I've tried sorry doctor
I can not... I do not.
It is impossible.
The only thing i can say i favor of the Nazis is that,
their methods are producing results
I'm sorry, Erik.
[Ding-dong-ting]
Mama!
My darling.
How are you?
Now this is what we will do
I count to three ...
and you move the coin.
If you do not move the coin,
I'll pull the trigger.
Do you understand?
One ...
- Mama!
- you can do it!
Two...
It's Okay
It's Okay!
It's Okay!.
Three.
[Bang-Gunshot]
[Bell scrunching]
Excellent!
Awesome!
Ahhhhhhhhhh...
[Helmets scrunching]
[Metal objects shacking]
[Nazi Soldiers Screaming]
[Skull crushed]
No!...........................
[Whirl and clatter]
[Sobbing]
Unbelievable, Erik.
We have opened your gift with anger
Anger and pain ...
You and I ...
.... are going to have a lot of fun.
X
FIRST CLASS
Enjoy the movie with a quality transcription
interpretation. bridge@gmail. com
Geneva Switzerland 1961
Oxford University
Heterochromia.
A gentle man would at least
offered to buy me a drink first
Newman,  a pint of bitter for me
and brandy for the lady, please.
- How did you know that?
- Lucky guess.
Name is Xavier,
Charles Xavier.
- how do you do?
- Amy.
Heterochromia,
as in reference to your eyes,
which i have to say,
are stunning.
One Green, one blue.
it's a mutation.
it's a very groovy mutation.
I've got news for you Amy.
you are a mutant.
First you proposition a girl
and then you tell her  deformed.
How is that seduction technique working for you?
I'll till you in the morning.
No, no seriously there
You mustn't knock it
Mutation to this form single celled organisms
To be the dominant form or reproductive life
on this planet,
infinite forms of variations with
each generation.
All through mutations.
So let's reclaim that word.
- Mutant and proud.
- Cin cin!
Hi.
I guess I'll have to buy my own drink
I am sorry, one Cola!
Charles here was just telling me that
I am like one of the first sea creatures
That grew legs
tiny bit sexier.
[Both laughing]
I am sorry
She is my sister, Raven.
- Hi!
-  Amy! and what are you studying?
Waitressing
Aahh
O, look you have Heterochromia too.
- Sorry what?
- Oh, look at her eyes.
Hmmm, Right.
Raven get your coat please.
Don't talk to me you did that on purpose
- I did not!
- Yes you did!
Why would I do it on purpose?
You know I can't control it sometimes.
- If I'm stressed or I'm tired..
- You seem to be doing a perfectly good job right now.
[Mocking]
"Mutant and proud"
What !..
XX is that how living with pretty mutations, XX
or invisible ones like yours.
If you're a freak, better hide.
You're being ridiculous!
Look, I don't mean to
sound like an old fart.
- Which you are.
- Sometimes, but we've talked about this, Raven.
A small slip up is one thing.
A big one does not bear thinking about.
"Mutant and proud"
Mutant and proud
[Sighing]
huhh
If only...
- Would you date me?
- Of course I would.
Any man would be lucky to have you.
You're stunning!
Looking like this?
[Mumbling]
You, ah, oh , What?
Blue?
- You're my oldest friend.
- I'm your only friend.
Thank you for that.
Well?
I'm incapable of even thinking of you that way,
I feel responsible for you.
Anything else would just feel wrong
- But what if you didn't know me?
- Unfortunately I do know you.
God, I don't know what's got into you lately?
You're awfully concerned with your looks.
I'm sleepy.
Will you read to me?
I can't, I have my thesis coming up, I have to study.
Well fine, you got your thesis
it always sends me right off.
To Homo neanderthalensis,
his  mutant cousin Homo sapiens,
was an aberration.
Peaceful co-habitation, if ever it existed,
was short lived.
Records show, without exception that the
arrival of the mutated human species in any region
was followed by the immediate
extinction of their less evolved kin.
Possession of that gold is illegal.
- Do you want me to call the police?
- Let's not play this game.
- So where did you get it from?
- From a friend.
He recommended your bank.
Understood.
Do you know our terms, sir?
Yes.
And you should know mine.
This gold is all that is left of my people.
Melted from their possessions.
Torn from their teeth.
This is blood money.
And you're going to help me
find the bastards responsible for it.
[Slap]
Ahhh
Don't touch that alarm.
I want Schmidt, Klaus Schmidt.
- Where is he?
- Our clients don't supply addresses, we're not...
Not that sort of bank?
[resonance]
Metal fillings, eh, not gold.
Worried someone might steal them?
Argentina! Schmidt is in Argentina!
Villa Gesell!
I beg you!
[Gasping from pain]
[gasping in relieve]
Thank you.
I would love to kill you.
So remember, if you warn him about me ....
I will find You  .
Las Vegas, Nevada
Another day at the office
Is that Colonel Hendry?
- The NATO guy?
- Yeah.
Yes it is.
Cause that's three mob bosses,,
the Italian ambassador
the CEO of Lockheed.
They can't all be communists.
This Hellfire club's gotta be something else.
[laughing]
Do you see that?
Hello, girls!
Wow, very nice.
Wha...what are you doing?
Here's things that the CIA didn't give me.
Stay put.
- Colonel Hendry?
- Yes, ma'am.
Emma Frost,
Sebastian Shaw's associate.
And where is, Mr. Shaw?
We're having a party, and here's the entertainment.
Come with me.
[whooping and whistling]
Hello beautiful, how are you?
Hey baby, you want to find a quiet place?
I am so sorry.
I've been booked by Colonel Hendry.
Excuse me.
- Make sure, we can't get a refill, Bob?
- No.
So, I hear you blocked the proposal to position
Jupiter missiles in Turkey.
- I expect you'll reconsider.
- We've had this conversation.
You put our nukes in Turkey,
or anywhere that close to Russia,
and you're looking at war.
Nuclear war.
[Flick :button pressed]
[Whirl]
I didn't ask for favors, Colonel.
I express my expectations.
So, let me say it again.
I expect you'll reconsider.
The only thing I will reconsider,
is having another glass of that delicious champagne.
[swirl]
What the hell did you put in my drink?
Ah .... ohh
You're thinking of running, hiding?
We'd find you, Hendry
There's not a fortress in the world
that can keep us out.
Magnificent, isn't she, Bob?
Genetic mutation, the evolution of the human genome.
Where's Azazel?
Ah, we don't want the Colonel to be late.
Come here.
Missiles in Turkey send a very clear message.
We ever decided to fire them,
the Russians early warning system won't
even have time to kick in.
This better be important, MacTaggert
Whoa, whoa, whoa, slow down.
You smoking them funny cigarettes?
People don't disappear.
Colonel Hendry was there.
He was there McCone, in the Hellfire club.
Colonel Hendry?
I agree with you, General.
I've reconsidered my position.
And I now believe that we should put
Jupiter Missiles in Turkey.
Colonel Hendry is here.
So, unless he magically traveled
3,000 miles in the last ten minutes,
Listen to me, I suggest that you stop
wasting my time.
Looks like Hendry wants to start
World War III.
I have better things to deal with right now, MacTaggert.
Sir, I...!
God...
Have you lost your mind?
So, now what?
We find an expert on Genetic Mutation.
Professor of genetics, Charles Francis Xavier.
[applause]
So, how does it feel to be a professor?
Well ah, don't call me that.
You don't get to be called a
Professor until you actually have a teaching position.
- I know, but it suits you.
- No, don't say that, do say "Let's go have a drink".
- Let's go have a drink.
- Wonderful!
VILLA GESELL, ARGENTINA
- Good afternoon, my friends!
- Good afternoon!
- Hot, is not it?
- Yes...
One beer, please.
- German beer.
- Of course.
Yes, it's Bitburger. You like it?
The best.
What brings you to Argentina?
The climate, I'm a pig farmer.
I am a tailor, Have been my whole life.
My father made the finest suits in Düsseldorf.
My Parents were from, Düsseldorf.
- What was their name?
- They didn't have a name.
It was taken away from them...
...by pig farmers...
...and tailors.
"Blood and Honor".
Which would you care to shed first?
- We carried out the orders.
- Blood then.
[Screaming]
- Do not move, asshole!
- Go ahead, shoot!
[trick]
[bang : gunshot]
[Scream]  / [swish] / [Gasping] / [swoosh]
[groan]
Who, what are you?
Let's just say I'm Frankenstein's monster.
I'm looking for my creator.
[bang : gunshot]
Drink, drink, drink!
[clapping]
[laughs]
Woowwwww.....
yeahhhhhhhhhhhh
Oh, I'm so proud of  you.
- Congratulations, Professor!
- Thank you very much, it's much harder than it looks, actually..
- No, on your presentation.
- You knew my presentation?
How nice of you, thank you very much.
- Moira MacTaggert.
- Charles Xavier.
Do you have a minute?
For a pretty little beam with a
mutated MCR-1 gene, I have five.
I say, MCR-1, you would say,
golden hair.
It's a mutation, it's a very groovy mutation.
Mutation you know, took us from single
cell organisms,
to the dominate form...
You know what, this routine may go over great
with the co-eds, but I'm here on business.
- What?
- I really need your help.
All right.
The kind that of mutations that you were
talking about in your thesis
I need to know if they may already have happened.
In people alive today.
Professor?
I think that we should just talk when you're sober.
Do  you have any time tomorrow?
Something tells me, you already know
the answer to your question.
This is very important to me.
And if I can help you, I will do my utmost.
Thank you.
MIAMI, FLORIDA
- Still drinking champagne, Bob?
- I will pass.
Okay, well so much for the pleasantries.
I was wondering, who you told
about our little arrangement?
No one.
- He's telling the truth.
- Good.
Well I guess we're done here.
Let's wrap things up, shall we?
Well I knew better than to trust you.
Now you let me walk out of here
with my money.
Or I will pull this pin and we all die.
Go ahead, pull it.
I'll do it, I swear to god.
No you won't.
But I will.
[clank]
[boom]
[humming]
You're one of them?
Very astute of you, Colonel Hendry.
You want to guess what I can do?
I've got the power to absorb energy.
It keeps me young.
That's the boring part.
The fun stuff is what I can do with it
once I got it.
CIA Headquarters, Langley, Virginia
The advent of the nuclear age,
may have accelerated the mutation process.
Individual's with extraordinary abilities may
already be among us.
Thank you very much.
MacTaggert, you really think that some crackpot scientist,
is going to make me believe in sparkly dames
and vanishing men?
You just brought yourself a one way ticket
back to the typing pool.
This meeting is over.
Uh, please sit down agent, MacTaggert.
I didn't really expect you to believe me.
Given that all you could think about during my presentation,
was what sort of pie they were serving in the commissary.
It's apple pecan.
I haven't been entirely honest with you, and I'm sorry.
You see, one of the many spectacular things my
mutation allows me to do.
Is that I can your  mind.
I've seen this before in a magic show.
Are you going to ask us to think of a number
between one and ten now?
No, agent Stryker.
Although I could ask  you about your son William who
you were thinking about,
which is very nice
But I think I'd rather ask you
about the Jupiter...
...missiles America are currently placing in Turkey.
He's a goddamn spy!
You brought a goddamn spy!
I did not, I would never bring one here!
[hissing]
How's that for a magic trick?
Best I've ever seen.
I want them out of here.
And lock down until I can figure out
what to do.
My facility is off site. I'll take them.
I can't believe this.
You'd think the director of the CIA
would have a little more composure.
We should be going after Shaw right now, but...
...instead he's up there worrying about the wrong mutants.
What are we doing to do, Lavene?
Lavene?
Lavene, what's wrong with you?
Absolutely nothing, I've just frozen him for the
moment because I'd like to talk to you.
It's good, isn't it?
I'm as interested in this Sebastian Shaw as you are,
..and if you still want my help, meet me on
the third floor of the parking garage.
I've always known that there were people like
you out there.
I've been the laughing stock of this agency
for years but I knew it.
- You're going to love my facility.
- That's going to have to wait.
- Why?
Agent MacTaggert has to lead us to Sebastian Shaw,
and if we don't move now apparently
we're going to lose him.
What?
Not only can he read minds,
he can communicate with them as well.
Moria and I have just had a lovely conversation.
- Yes, we did.
- That is incredible!
But I cannot take you anywhere else,
without permission from upstairs.
- Would you like to see one more magic trick?
- Okay.
- Get in the car.
- Good idea.
[rippling]
[dipping water sounds]
Herr Doctor...
the same old Erik Lensherr.
He's here to kill you.
What kind of greeting is that?
After so many years?
Emma...
We don't harm our own kind.
Ah, now it's a party.
This is the US Coast guard.
Do not attempt to move your vessel.
Stay where you are.
They have a telepath.
I've lost, Shaw!
I've lost, I've lost, Shaw.
There's, there's something blocking me.
This has never happened to me before.
I think there's someone like
me on that ship.
- Like you?
- I'm sorry, a telepath.
This is incredible, I can actually feel
her inside my mind.
I'm very sorry, but I don't think I'm
going to be much help to you tonight.
You're on your own.
[spalshings]
[swirl]
- Oh my god.
- Jesus.
Get inside.
[chink of anchor chains]
Stop, stop, stop!
Charles! You okay?
There's someone else out there.
There!
Time to go.
Let go!
Better let it go!
You've got help him...there's
someone in the water, help him!
Let it go!
You have to let it go!
You can't, you'll drown.
You have to let go.
I know what this means to you
but you're going to die.
Please, Erik, calm your mind.
Get off of me, get off!
Calm down,
Oh just breath.
We're here!
- Who are you?
-  My name is Charles Xavier.
You were in my head.
How did you do that?
You have your tricks, I have mine.
I'm like you, just calm your mind.
- I thought I was alone.
- You're not alone.
Erik, you're not alone.
Secret CIA base.
Welcome to my facility.
My mission has been to investigate the
application of paranormal powers
for military defense.
Or offense.
This guy, Shaw, Schmidt, whatever
you want to call him.
He's working with the Russians.
We might need your help to stop them.
Marvelous.
So we're to be the CIA's new
mutant division, yes?
Something like that.
It's a supersonic. The most advanced plane
ever built.
You should see it in real life.
It's incredible.
Hank, these are the special new recruits I
was telling you about.
This is, Hank McCoy,
One of our most talented young researchers.
How wonderful, another mutant.
Already here.
- Why didn't you say?
- Say what?
Because you don't know.
I am so, so terribly sorry!
Hank?
You didn't ask, so I didn't tell.
So  your mutation's what?
You're super smart?
I'll say, Hank here graduated honors at the age of fifteen.
I wish that's all it was.
You're among friends now, Hank.
You could show off.
Splendid.
- Sorry.
- Yes, yes.
Wow
[laughing]
tadaa
- You're amazing.
- Really?
(TV): The presence of U.S. missiles in Turkey
represents an unprecedented threat
to the people of the Soviet Union.
Warned Russian Mister Gromeko, earlier today
But he was quick to insist the Russians
would not be the first to initiate any military action.
Yeah, we'll fix that as soon as
we get to Russia.
- Unless the CIA finds us first.
- I'll take care of them too.
If that telepath gets inside your head,
he won't be as much fun as I am.
Already in hand, my love.
The Russians...
...made me this.
So, what am I thinking?
I don't know.
I was thinking that you are the most exquisite
thing that I've ever seen in my life.
And that this needs ice.
Fetch me some.
There's a good girl.
[Beeping of sonar]
I, I promised myself I'd find a cure.
Ever since I was a little boy.
You have no idea what I'd give to feel...
- ...normal.
- Normal.
Charles has never understood.
He's different, but he's never had to hide.
Hank this serum that you're making,
it doesn't affect abilities, right?
Just appearance.
Normalizes it.
Yeah.
Do you think it would work on me?
I can look into it, if you'd like.
That's the least I can do after asking you to
come down here to listen to a weird request.
I have to admit,
usually when guys ask me out they're
not after my blood.
S..sorry, I didn't intend to be forward.
I was just...I was excited.
You know, the nature of your mutation.
If any genes hold the key to changing appearance,
it's yours.
Hank, you aren't being forward,
that's kinda what I meant.
- No, but I'm just sorry if you thought I was.
- And I'm sorry that you weren't.
Go ahead, take the blood.
Sorry, Does that hurt you?
Kinky!
By the way, if I looked like you,
I wouldn't change a thing.
of what I know about you, I'm surprised
you managed to stay this long.
- What do you know about me?
- Everything.
Then know to stay out of my head.
I'm sorry Erik, but I've seen what
Shaw did to you.
I felt your agony.
I can help you.
I don't need your help.
Don't kid yourself. You needed my help last night.
It's  not just me you're walking away from.
Here you have the chance to be a part of
something much bigger than yourself.
I won't stop you leaving, I could.
But I won't.
Shaw is got friends.
You could do with some.
Hank turned that radar installation into
a transmitter.
It's designed to amplify brain waves,
...so it could enhance your telepathic powers.
Help us find other mutants for our division.
last thing they wanna be found by you.
Erik!
You decided to stay.
If a new species is being discovered,
it should be by its own kind.
Charles and I find the new mutants,
no suits.
First of all, that's my machine out there.
Second of all, and much more importantly,
This is Charles decision.
Charles is fine with the CIA being involved.
Isn't that right?
No, I'm sorry but, I'm with Erik.
We'll find them alone.
What if I say no?
Then good luck using your installation without me.
I call it, Cerebro.
You.... [laugh]
- Is in the Spanish for "brain"?
- Yes.
Okay so, the electrodes connect
Charles to the transmitter on the roof.
And picks up a mutant.
His brain sends a signal through a relay.
And then the co-ordinates of their
location are printed out here.
- You designed this?
- Yeah.
- What an adorable lab rat you make, Charles.
- Don't spoil this for me, Erik.
I've been a lab rat, I know one when I see one.
Okay, right...
- Are you sure we can't shave your head?
- Don't touch my hair.
Okay!.
[Humming : Charging]
Ahh
[ticks]
It's working!
[exotic music in striping club]
With that Daddy-O, you get a private dance.
You cat's know it's double for both, right?
Ohm
No, that won't be necessary.
although I sure it would be magical...
We were thinking more, we're show you ours,
...if you show us yours.
Baby, that is not the way it works around here.
- More tea, Vicar?
- Don't mind if I do.
My turn.
[Wing Flaps]
How would you like a job, where you
get to keep your clothes on?
[ticks]
- Where to fellas?
- Richmond, Virginia.
Right, so you want the airport, the station, what?
No we were rather hoping that you would
take us all the way.
That's a six hour drive.
That will give us plenty of time to talk.
[Tick : Resets Taximeter]
What the hell does the government want
with a guy like, Alex Summers?
I hope you don't plan on putting him with others.
First guy I ever met who actually
prefers solitary confinement.
- Crazy, huh?
- What?
You like fish, I like fish too.
Maybe we should bide some time and talk about it.
I'd rather go out with the fish.
[Howls]
These fish?
- Excuse me I'm Erik Lensher.
- Charles Xavier.
Go fuck yourselves.
[sonar beeps]
- There's nothing on radar?
- Nothing.
- Sonar?
- yab.
Then we have a problem.
Beautiful, isn't it?
The reason we exist.
We are the children of the atom, my love.
We have a situation.
The telepath...
I shouldn't be able to feel him at this distance.
It's like his reach is...
...amplified.
They're recruiting.
You go on to Russia,
I'll handle them.
I can't stop thinking about the others out there.
All those minds that I've touched.
I could feel them, their isolations..  their hopes,
their ambitions.
I tell you, we've started something
incredible, Erik.
- We can help them.
- Can we?
Identification, that's how it starts.
Then ends with being rounded up.
Experimented on, eliminated.
Not this time
We have common enemies, Shaw and the Russians
they need us.
For now.
We should think of code names.
We're government agents now,
we should have secret code names.
- I want to be called, Mystique.
- Damn, I wanted to be called, Mystique.
- Well tough, I called it.
Damn wang, mysterious to you.
- Darwin, what about you?
- Well, uh, Darwin's already a nickname.
And you know, sort of fits.
Adapt to survive and all.
Check this out.
[rippling, bubbling]
Wow
[applause]
- Thank you, thank you.
- Bravo, bravo.
- What about you?
- I'm going to be...
...Banshee.
Why do you want to be names
after a wailing spirit?
You might want to cover your ears.
[laughs]
Your turn.
My stage name is Angel.
[whistles]
Kind of fits.
- You can fly?
-  Ah, hah. And uh...
[spit]
[Giggles]
ahhh, you are totally disgusting...
- What's your name?
- How about Big Foot?
Well you know what they say
about guys with big feet?
And uh, yours are kind of small.
Okay, now.
Alex, what is your gift?
What can you do?
Uh, it's not um, I just can't do it.
- I can't do it in here.
- Can you do it out there?
- Why don't you just do it out there.
- Come on.
-Come on, Alex.
- Alex.
Alex! Alex!
That's the spirit.
Get down when I tell you.
Get back.
Get back!
Whatever...
[clinking of falling statue]
Ohh, yeahh
We've got Intel that Shaw is meeting with
the Russian defense chief in Moscow.
So go ahead, say it.
I'm not here to say "I told you so",
you know why I'm here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Clearance to bring
along your mutants.
Fight fire with fire.
Makes sense.
Wait, you're okay with this?
Sending in a bunch of untrained
unauthorized freaks?
These "Freaks" are dedicated hard working people.
Plane leaves for Russia in an hour.
I'm telling you these kids
are not ready for, Shaw.
I think they're going to surprise you.
They are an exceptional bunch of young people.
What the hell?
Harder!
What are  you doing?
- Who destroyed the statue?
- It was, Alex.
No Havoc! We have to call him, Havoc.
That's his name now.
And we were thinking, you should be, Professor X
And you should be, Magneto.
Exceptional.
I expect more from you.
Country House Military Office of the USSR
We got a problem.
- What?
- I'm so sorry, this wasn't on the map.
No matter what happens, act normally.
I'll take care of this, all right.
Now listen to me..
Where are you going?
To our farm.
Open the back.
As you wish, as you wish.
Oh, easy, easy.
Take it easy, chaps.
Anything back there?
Nothing, it's empty.
- Everything's okay?
- Yes.
- Where's Shaw?
- Emma.
She's a telepath, if I read her, she'll know we're here.
Let me try something else.
Shaw sends his apologies, but
he's indisposed.
He asked me to come in his place.
But between you and I honey,
I'm a lot better company.
Please come in.
He's not coming.
- So, what now boss?
- Now, nothing. We're here for Shaw.
- Mission aborted
- The hell it is.
- Erik.
-She's his right hand woman.
That's good enough for me.
The CIA invading the home of a senior
Soviet official.
- Are you crazy?
- I'm not CIA.
Erik!
To your health.
So you must be busy planning your next move.
What with the American's refusing to remove
their missiles from Turkey.
You know I can't talk about those things, Miss Frost.
Emma.
And don't worry, you don't have to say a word.
He's going to start world war III single handed.
- We have to do something.
- Like what?
- We're moving out.
- You can't.
aahhha
I'm sorry, I can't leave him.
For good sake, Erik...
Be calm.
Forget my face. Yes.
You're beautiful, so beautiful...yes.
Pathetic.
Nice trick.
Who are  you?
Go to sleep.
You can stop trying to read my mind, sugar.
You're never going to get anything
from me while I'm like this.
So then you can just tell us.
Where is Shaw?
[Squeezing scrunching]
Erik.
Erik, that's enough.
Erik, that's enough!
[shatter]
All yours.
She won't be shifting into diamond form again.
But if she does, just give her a gentle tap.
We are the children of the atom.
Radiation gave birth to mutants.
What will kill the humans
[Cheering crowds]
will only make us stronger.
Beautiful, isn't it?
This is worse that we previously imagined.
We're taking you with us.
- CIA will want to question you themselves.
- I doubt it.
Might be other things to worry about right now.
Whoa, all right.
- Jesus, man you are killing me.
- Don't beat yourself up, we got a lot of spare time.
Oh, I didn't know the circus was in town.
Hey come on honey, give us a little, uh...
No? Come on, let's see the foot.
There it is, come on Bigfoot let's go.
Hey, hey come on, hey.
They're just guys being stupid.
Guy's being stupid I can handle.
I can handle that my whole life.
But I'd rather have a bunch of guys
staring at me with my clothes off,
then the way these one stare at me.
At us.
[bump]
[Multiple bumps]
What was that?
I don't know, but something doesn't feel right.
[more bumps]
- No news of Shaw?
- Not a peep, nothing through that back channel.
[loud bump]
[Sharp loud bump]
[snap in]
[Snap out]
What is that?
ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh
[boom]
Ahhhhah
- woahhowwwhhh
- ahhhahhhhh
We have an intruder on the main atrium.
- Where are the mutants?
- You take another step, I'm going to put you down.
Of course you will, but where do I find
the more evolved people?
Send back-up now!
Get back, get back, do not leave that room.
We're under attack.
- Look out!
- Shoot , shoot it !
[ rattle of machine-gun fire ]
Where are the mutants?
Put that man down or we will open fire.
[Clash of bazooka]
[crackle of fire]
Stay here my ass.
Let's go!
- Get back!
- We can help, we can help!
[chain reaction like explosion]
Wait, wait, you want the mutants?
They're right through that door.
Just let us normal people go.
We're no threat...
[Smashing of bones]
Where's the telepath?
- Not here.
- Too bad.
Now I can take this silly thing off.
Good evening
My name is, Sebastian Shaw.
And I am not here to hurt you.
Freeze!
Azazel...
My friends, there's a revolution coming.
When mankind discovers who we are,
what we can do.
Each of us will face a choice.
Be enslaved, or rise up to rule.
Choose freely, but know that if you are not with us,
then by definition you are against us.
So, you can stay, and fight for the
people who hate, and fear you.
Or you can join me.
And live like kings.
And Queens.
- Angel?
- Are you kidding me?
Come on, we don't belong here.
And that's nothing to be ashamed of.
We have to do something.
Stop, I'm coming with you.
Good choice.
So tell me about your mutation.
Well, I adapt to survive.
- So I guess I'm coming with you.
- I like that.
- Alex, do it!
- Get out!
Do it.
Protecting your fellow mutants?
It's a noble gesture.
Feels good.
Adapt to this.
Moscow, Russia
[sonic boom]
Hello.
Once again, my sympathies for your
treatment at the hands of the CIA.
These American's are ruthless.
Now they have their missiles placed in Turkey.
I expect you'll be planning new
missile sites of your own.
Somewhere where you know the American early
warning system won't help.
I hear Cuba is lovely this time of year.
And so close to Florida.
Missiles in Cuba?
You're serious?
We may as well declare war.
Maybe I wasn't clear enough.
You will make this happen.
Okay.
Let's see what KGB think about this.
Hello, General Armivolkoff.
It's nothing.
Raven.
We've made arrangements for you to
be taken home immediately.
- We're not going home.
- What?
- He's not going back to prison.
- They killed, Darwin.
All the more reason for you to leave.
This is over.
Darwin is dead, Charles.
And we can't even bury him.
We can avenge him.
Erik, word please.
- They're just kids.
- No, they were kids.
Shaw has his army, we need ours.
We'll have to train.
All of us.
- Yes?
- Yeah.
Well we can't stay here.
Even if they reopen the department,
it's not safe.
We've got nowhere to go.
Yes, we do.
The law says we've got to turn her over.
The law applies to human beings.
The same laws don't apply to mutants.
They're too dangerous.
Times like this, security is more
important than liberty.
- There's a war coming, John.
- Yes, but a war with who?
Excellent question.
Though I won't call it a war exactly.
That suggests both sides stand an
equal chance of winning.
Captain, no sign of any American ships.
Maintain course, full ahead.
The Russians have sent their warheads to Cuba.
We have a week before their ship hits the coast.
Our fleet can be on this line,
when the Russian missile ship arrives.
If that ship crosses the line, they will have
declared war against the United States.
We will have no choice but to retaliate
with a full nuclear response.
Do we agree?
Dispatch the Seventh fleet.
- This is yours?
- No, it's ours.
Honestly Charles, I don't know how you survived.
Living in such hardship.
Well it was a hardship softened by me.
Come on, time for the tour.
Moscow, Russia
Dear comrades.
The United States have dispatched
war ships for Cuba.
This leaves us with no choice.
Comrade First Secretary.
We must send in our fleet.
Dispatch the fleet!
[applause]
[Flash]
(TV): President Kennedy has
signed a formal proclamation.
Setting up a blockade of all missiles,
armed for Cuba.
The Soviet Union reacted by terming it
as step along the road to unleashing a thermal nuclear war.
- You're sure?
- I'm sure.
Hold it.
No, I can't I'm sorry.
I can't shoot anybody point blank,
let alone my friend.
Oh come on, you know I can deflect it.
You're always telling me I should push myself.
If you know you can deflect it, then
you're not challenging yourself.
Whatever happened to the man
who was trying to raise a submarine?
What, I can't.
Something that big, I need the situation, the anger.
No, the anger isn't enough.
It's gotten the job done all this time.
It's nearly gotten you killed all this time.
Hey, come here.
Let's try something a little more challenging.
My step-father took the possibility
of nuclear war quite seriously.
This way.
That's why he had this bunker built down here.
I thought we could use it as a practice range of sort.
You don't think I'm going to blow though the walls?
No, he had this place built to
with stand a nuclear bomb.
I think it can handle you, Alex.
You know when I do this,
bad things tend to happen.
It's because you can't control it.
It controls you.
That's why we're here, Alex.
To start your training.
[Howls]
[Laughs]
What you're doing is incredible.
You're hitting a pitch sound that at
the same resonate frequency of the glass.
That's why it shatters.
This is like any other muscle in the body.
You can control it.
"In each of us, two natures are at war."
Robert Louis Stevenson,
"Jekyll and Hyde".
Top marks.
Still it really wasn't really about good
and evil. Was it, Hank.
It was about man's animal nature,
and his struggle to control it.
To conform.
It is that struggle which is holding you back.
Jekyll is afraid of what he could be capable of.
You are too.
If you're serious about me doing this,
you might want to get back.
- Of course, should I shut the door?
- Yeah.
Whenever you're ready.
My god.
I will teach you to control this, Alex.
You're sure that this will work.
Anything is possible. I based the design...
Hank, stop talking.
Come on.
Now remember, scream as hard as you can.
You need the sound waves to be supersonic.
Catch them at the right angle,
and they should carry you.
"They should carry me."
That's reassuring.
Good luck.
And don't forget to scream.
If you want to beat me this time,
you have to set the beast free.
On your marks, get set...GO!
Oh, congratulations my friend.
Robert Louis Stevenson
would have been proud.
Impressive, Hank.
Feet like those, all you need is a red nose.
Right, Bozo?
- I'm done here.
- Thank you, Alex
Come on, Hank.
If you're using half the concentration to look normal.
Then you're only half paying attention to
whatever else you do.
Just pointing out something that could save your life.
You want society to accept you.
But you can't even accept yourself.
Sexy.
This is just the prototype.
The real will look considerably better
it'll be a whole suit.
See these sensors measure your energy output,
this panel focuses it and the excess is absorbed.
All right try hitting the one in the middle,
just the one in the middle, mind.
Good luck.
You ought to see this. Your genes are
extraordinary, you know that.
Your cells age at half the rate of a normal human.
When you're forty you will still
have the looks of a teenager.
You have the most incredible cellular
structure I've ever seen.
You truly believe I'll fly this time?
Unreservedly.
- I trust you.
- The task.
- I don't trust him.
- Say nothing.
I'm going to die!
All, look we're not going to make you do anything
that your not so...
- Here, let me help him.
- Erik!
[howling continuously]
Whaoooo!
Wahhh hooo!
What?
You know you were thinking the same.
Wonderful work Hank, thank you very much.
All right Alex, I want you to hit the X.
And try not to hit me, there's a good chap.
- You're serious?
- I'm very serious.
I have complete and utter faith in you.
- Am I still a Bozo?
- Yes, Hank. You're still a Bozo.
But nice job.
See that?
Try turning it to face us.
You know, I believe the true focus lies
somewhere between rage and serenity.
Would you mind, if I...?
[shiver]
What did you just do to me?
I accessed the brightest corner
of your memory system.
It's a very beautiful memory Erik, thank you.
I didn't know I still had that.
There's so much more to you than you know.
Not just pain, and anger.
There's good too, I felt it.
And when you can access all that.
You will possess a power no one can match.
Not even me.
So, come on. Try again.
[dish clanking]
[beaming]
- Hey!
-Well done.
The President is about to make his address.
It shall be the policy of this nation
to regard any nuclear missile,
...crossing the embargo line, that surrounds Cuba.
As an attack by the Soviet Union
on the United States.
Requiring a full retaliatory response.
Upon the Soviet Union.
- Thats' where we're going to find, Shaw'
- How do you know?
Two super powers facing off, and
he wants' to start world war III.
He won't leave anything to chance.
So much for diplomacy.
I suggest you all get a good night sleep.
...ultimately leads to war.
Tensions mount as the Soviet Missile
ship nears Cuba.
All diplomatic efforts to avert
Nuclear war have thus far failed.
As the American people ready themselves,
for the likelihood of an atomic attack.
There are widespread reports of panic wide.
Supermarkets cleared.
As shelters unused since the second world war,
are stocked for what may lie ahead.
In all its history, American has never
faced a greater threat.
The world is primed for war.
And there's no one to stop me.
Come in.
Hey.
Got a surprise for you.
I isolated the right marker in your DNA sample.
The serum works like an anti-biotic.
Attacking the cells that cause our physical mutation.
It won't affect your abilities,
just your appearance.
Do you still want to do this?
Should we have to hide?
You already do.
You're hiding right now.
Like I have my whole life.
I don't want to feel like a freak, all the time.
- I just want to look...
- ...normal.
Yeah.
Hank, don't.
You're beautiful, Hank.
Everything you are, you're perfect.
Look at all of us. Look at
all we've achieved this week.
All we will achieve.
We are different. But we shouldn't
be trying to fit into society.
Society should inspire and be more like us.
Mutant, and proud.
It behooves me to tell you,
but even if we save the world tomorrow.
And mutants are accepted into society.
My feet and your natural blue form.
Will never be deemed beautiful.
You look beautiful now.
We need this cure.
Cuba, Russia, America makes no difference.
Shaw's declared war on mankind,
on all of us.
He has to be stopped.
I'm going to kill him.
Do you have it, i need to know that ?
[chuckle]
You've known that all along
why I was here, Charles.
But things have changed.
What started as a covert mission,
...tomorrow mankind will know that mutants exist.
Shaw, us... they won't differentiate.
They'll fear us, and that
fear will turn to hatred.
Not if we stop a war.
Not if we can prevent, Shaw.
Not if we risk our lives doing so.
Would they do the same for us?
We have it in us to be the better man.
We already are.
We're the next stage of human evolution.
- You said it yourself.
- No, not.
Are you really so naive?
As to think they won't battle their own extinction?
- Or is it arrogance?
- I'm sorry !?.
After tomorrow they're going to turn on us.
And you're blind to it, because you
believe they're all like Moira.
And you believe they're all like, Shaw.
Listen to me, very carefully my friend.
Killing Shaw will not bring you peace.
Peace was never an option.
[Squeeze]
[Sigh]
[chuckle]
No.
[twang of body expansion]
[clatter of stuff on desk]
Well...
This is a surprise.
The nice kind?
Get out Raven, I wanna go to bed.
Maybe in a few years.
[Hissing: changing form]
How about now?
I prefer the real, Raven.
[Hissing]
I said the real, Raven.
Perfection.
- Could you pass me my robe?
- You don't have to hide.
Have you ever looked at a tiger,
and thought you ought to cover it up?
No, but...
You're an exquisite creature, Raven.
Only in life the world tries to tame you.
It's time for you to be free.
You know sometimes I wonder
what my life would have been like.
If you hadn't found me here that night.
Sorry what ?,
You Ed..eah...ah.
For god's sake, Raven!
Where are you clothes?
Put some, put some clothes on.
That's not what you said when you first saw me.
But I guess pets are always cuter
when they're little, right?
Raven, I don't know what's got into you lately.
I thought you'd be in a good mood.
Hank tells me he's found the
answer to your cosmetic problem.
You going to tell me what's the matter?
Or will I have to read your mind?
You promised me you would never do that.
Until recently, I never had to use my powers
to know what you were thinking, Raven.
You know Charles, I used to think
it was gonna be you and me against the world.
And no matter how bad the world gets,
you don't want to be against it, do you?
You want to be a part of it.
ahhh
Gone to the airbase, bring the crate marked X.
Hank
[squeaking of the door]
What the hell happened here?
Hank has been busy.
Do we really have to wear these?
As none of us has mutated to enjoy extreme G force,
or being riddled by bullets, I suggest we suit up.
Where's Hank?
I'm here.
Hank?
It didn't attack the cells.
It enhanced them.
It didn't work.
Yes it did, Hank.
Don't you see?
This is who you were meant to be.
This is you.
No more hiding.
Never looked better, man.
Hank!
[Roars]
Don't mock me.
Hank, put him down immediately, please.
Hank...HANK!
I wasn't.
Even I got to admit, you look pretty bad ass.
I think I got a new name for you, Beast.
[Grunts]
- You sure you can fly this thing?
- Of course I can, I designed it.
Cuba
Status of the cargo ship?
Bearing 1-8-0, 12 knots.
Three minutes to the embargo line, sir.
God help them if they cross it.
God help us all.
- Sound general quarters.
- General quarters, general quarters.
- All hands man battle stations!
- Yes sir.
Set condition, zebra.
General quarters, battle stations.
Captain, we already have our orders.
Why are you so eager for new ones?
I've lived through one war, comrade.
I'd prefer not to start another.
Battle stations, NOW!
Gun boss, target cargo ship, bearing 1-8-0.
Fleet reports all weapons ready.
There's commands From the Kremlin, sir.
New orders. As of 1025 hours, the cargo
vessel Aral sea, is hereby ordered to...
...reverse course and return to port in Odessa.
Aral Sea, come in.
They are not responding.
She's not turning around.
Aral Sea, you are ordered to turn around.
Do not cross the line.
Target ready to be fired upon, sir.
- Stand by to fire.
- Standing by, sir.
Looks pretty messy out there.
Aral Sea, you are ordered to turn around.
The crew of the Aral Sea are all dead.
Shaw's been there.
He's still here, somewhere.
He's set the ship on course for the embargo line.
That ship crosses the line, our
boys are going to blow it up.
And the war begins.
Unless they're not on board.
USS Independence,
this is, Alexander Nevski.
We have lost control of our cargo ship.
She's been instructed to stop.
Do not fire.
Repeat, do not fire.
They've signaled their
cargo ship to turn around, sir.
It's a ruse.
pay no attention, Stand by to fire.
- Standing by to fire, sir.
- On my count.
Five...four...
ahhhh
Hold on! Hold on!
[yowling]
No!
[Bang]
- What was that?
- The Russians, they have fired on their own ship.
A little warning next time, professor.
Sorry about that.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Son of a...
Give me Sinclair on the horn, I want a new set of orders.
Congratulations, comrade.
You just averted a Nuclear war.
What?
Arrest him, and put him in the cell.
What? Why?
What just happened?
They say the comrade lost his mind.
The Americans are plotting.
They're here.
That telepath is powerful.
We're moving to a back-up plan.
- That was inspired, Charles.
- Thank you very much.
But I still can't locate Shaw.
He's down there, we need to find him now.
Hank?
- Is there anything unusual on the radar scanners?
- No, nothing.
Well then he must be under water.
And obviously we don't have Sonar.
Yes we do !.
Yes we do.
They were ready for war.
We just need to strike another match
to light the fuse.
And we still have the most powerful weapon of all.
Me.
Turn the nuclear reactor to 100% output..
and make sure I'm not disturbed.
Hank, level the bloody plane!
Whoa, you back right off.
Beast, open the Bombay doors.
Remember, this is a muscle.
You control it.
You'll be in here the entire time.
We'll see you soon.
- On my mark. 3, 2, 1 GO!
- WHOA!!!
Alert the fleet, they may want to take their cams off.
[Howling]
amhh
Banshee is got a location on Shaw.
You ready for this?
Let's find out.
[Hissing]
[Plane hovering]
Remember, the point between rage and serenity.
[swirl of vortex]
Hold on guys, it's going to get bumpy.
Erik, take my hand!
[clanging, clanking, scrunching, crashing]
[Emergency beeps]
[crashing]
[All Screaming]
Down.
- Moira, Moira, are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
I read the teleporter's mind.
Shaw's drawing all of the power out of his sub.
He's turning himself into some kind of nuclear bomb.
We've got no time, the Geiger
counter's going out of control.
All right Moira, this is what we're going to do.
Get on the radio and send both fleet's out immediately.
I'm going in.
Beast, Havoc, back him up.
Erik, I can guide you through once you're in.
But I need you to shut down
whatever it is that's blocking me.
Then we just hope to god it's
not too late for me to stop him.
- Got it.
- Good luck!
- Raven, stop!
- I'm going out there.
We don't have time for this.
Anything comes in that entrance,
Sure you're taking care of it, yes?
Fine.
Beast!
If we go, you go
We believe Shaw is trying to
detonate some kind of bomb.
Erik, make for the middle of the vessel.
That's the point my mind can't penetrate.
We have to assume that, that's where Shaw is.
That's the nuclear reactor.
Disable it.
Stop, don't move.
[Flaps]
Get down!
[spitting fire balls]
[Continuous howls]
Erik you're there, you've reached the void.
He's not here Charles,
Shaw is not here.
- He's left the sub.
- What? He's got to be there.
He has to be, there's no where
else he can be, keep looking.
And I'm telling you he's not,
there's no one here, god damn it!
Erik, what a pleasant surprise.
Erik?
Erik!
So good to see you again.
[multiple fiery spits]
May I ask you something?
Why are you on their side?
- He's gone.
- What?
He's gone into the void. I can't
communicate with him there.
Why fight for a doomed race
who will hunt us down,
...as soon as they realize
their reign is coming to an end.
[Howling on soldiers]
Yeah!
I'm sorry for what happened in the camps.
I truly am.
He's back.
Erik, whatever you're doing keep
doing it, it's starting to work.
But everything I did,
I did for you.
To unlock your power.
To make you embrace it.
It's working.
I'm starting to see him, but I
can't yet touch his mind.
[Flaps]
[Speedy whirl]
You've come a long way from bending gates.
I'm so proud of you.
And you're just starting to scratch the surface.
Think how much further we could go, together.
Stop, Azazel!
[snap]
[Hissing]
I don't want to hurt you, Erik.
I never did.
I want to help you.
This is our time.
Our age.
We are the future of the human race.
You and me, son.
This world could be ours.
Everything you did, made me stronger.
Made me the weapon I am today.
That's the truth.
I've known it all along.
You are my creator.
NOW, Charles!
Are you okay?
Moira be quiet, I can only
control this man for so long.
Sorry, Charles.
Erik please, be the better man.
You have it in...
But I dont trust you.
Erik, there will be no telling what...
No.
- Charles?
- Don't do this, Erik!
If you're in there, I'd like you to know
that I agree with every word you've said.
We are the future.
But...
...unfortunately, you killed my mother.
This is what we're going to do.
No, please Erik, no.
I'm going to count to three.
And I'm going to move the coin.
One...
Please, Erik.
Two...
Three.
Aaaaaaaah!
[ringing of falling coin]
The Russians share our concerns.
And will join a strike on all the mutants.
We can end this threat for good.
We'll never have another opportunity like this.
We have an agent on that beach.
- One agent.
- She's a good agent.
She's collateral damage.
Today our fighting stops.
[Smash of bones]
Take off your blinders, brothers and sisters.
The real enemy is out there.
I feel their guns moving in the water.
Their metal targeting us.
Americans, Soviets, humans.
United in their fear of the unknown.
A Neanderthal is running scared,
my fellow mutants.
Go ahead, Charles.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Fleet commander this is X-ray Bravo-70.
Respond, over.
The beach is secure, call off the attack.
The beach is targeted and ready to
be fired upon, sir.
- Stand by.
- Standing by, sir.
All weapons set.
Hello?
Hello!
Fire.
[All sorts of projectiles and rockets launched]
[Boom] / [bang]
Erik, you said yourself, we're the better men.
This is the time to prove it.
There are thousands of men on those ships.
Good, Honest men.
They're just following orders.
I've been at the mercy of men
just following orders.
Never again.
Erik, release them.
I don't want to hurt you,
don't make me.
Stay back!
Charles, enough.
Erik, stop!
Gentlemen, it's been an honor serving with you.
Comrades, ......
[Gunshot]
[Screaming]
I'm so sorry.
I said back off!
You, you did this!
Please...
She didn't do this, Erik.
You did.
[Gasping for air]
Us turning on each other,
it's what they want.
I tried to warn you, Charles.
I want you by my side.
We're brothers, you and I.
All of us, together. Protecting each other.
We want the same thing.
Oh, my friend.
I'm sorry, but we do not.
Charles, I'm sorry, I'm so sorry, Charles.
It's all right, it's all right.
His society won't accept us.
We form our own.
The humans has played their hand.
Now we get ready to play ours.
Who's with me?
No more hiding.
You, you should go with him.
It's what you want.
You promised me you would never read my mind.
I know.
I promised you a great many things,
I'm afraid.
I'm sorry.
Take care of him.
And Beast, never forget.
Mutant and proud.
Help me out, help him.
I'm going to get you to a hospital.
- Wait, don't, Charles, don't move, okay.
All right, actually I ca.....I...I...
I can't feel my legs
I can't feel my legs.
In this week of thanksgiving.
There is much for which we can be grateful.
As you look back to where we stood,
only four weeks ago.
The unity of this hemisphere,
the support of our allies.
And the calm determination of the American people.
These qualities may be tested many more times.
In this decade.
So how many students do you think
you'll have here?
Once you get the academy up and running.
As many as I can manage, and Possibly more.
You know, one day the government is going
to realize how lucky they were,
..to have Professor X on their side.
As I suppose I am on the
road to a professor now, aren't I ?.
First thing I'll be going bald.
We're still on the government side, Moira.
We're still a G-man, just without the G.
No, you're your own team now.
It's better.
You're, "X-Men".
[chuckle]
Guess, I'll like the sound of that.
Moira, for us anonymity will be the first line of defense.
I know.
They can threaten me all they want, Charles.
I'll never tell them where you are.
Ever.
I know you won't.
My love.
I remember the attack on HQ.
Leaving to go somewhere else.
And then this morning, I woke up at home.
That's it.
All that time wiped clean from your mind.
Just gone.
He can do that.
You don't remember anything?
Sometimes I get fragments.
Like trees, sunlight.
- A kiss.
- Aw, Jesus.
Gentlemen, this is why the CIA
is no place for a woman.
[Powerful plonk, Crash]
What the hell was that?
[scrunching and snapping the door  ]
I know we've had our differences.
- Where's your telepath friend?
- Gone.
Left a bit of a gap in my life.
If I'm to be honest.
I was rather hoping you would fill it.
Join us.
Erik, I believe.
I prefer...
...Magneto.
interpretation. bridge@gmail. com
Kindly refer to this subtitle when reusing it