Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
(speaking foreign language)
Where are we
on real-time tracking?
Backdooring off a satellite
the Brits have overhead.
Hey, Kate,
friendly reminder.
I'm gonna need
your passcodes
and decryption keys
before you clear out
at the end
of the week.
Right. I'm not gonna forget.
Oh, Mariana...
What's going on out there?
Got a tip that a high-value
suspect is here in London.
Is it connected
to the president being here?
That's the speculation.
Man:
Positive I.D. On the target.
30 feet from the South wall.
Here we go.
The target's on the run!
Go, go, go, team one!
(Gasps)
It's him...
Jack Bauer.
All right, he's taken
Miller out. Has his weapon.
Armstrong, Cutler,
he's coming your way.
(Man yells)
(Coughing)
(Gunshot)
Continuing pursuit.
He'll head for the roof.
That's the best way out.
Bauer's on the move!
He's heading outside!
Well, that doesn't make sense.
Kate, please?
(Man yells)
Get out of the way! Move! Move!
Damn it! Move, move!
Target is moving west,
on his way to the river.
On your knees!
Hands behind your head.
We got him.
(Crowd clamoring)
Man: The prime minister is
putting pressure on parliament
to extend their lease,
but the vote
is too close to call.
People are just
not comfortable
with our using drones
for targeted assassinations.
(Clamoring continues)
Mr. president?
I'm thinking I don't blame them,
I'm uncomfortable
with the drones, also.
The ugly truth is,
what we're doing is working.
Worse-case scenario,
if we lose the base,
do we have anything new?
No other country in the region
is willing
to host an American base
right now.
In part because the
Chinese are making it clear
that they don't want us
in the area.
And they're spreading
their wings.
Beijing just acknowledged they
have a carrier group heading
for the Mediterranean.
For the first time in history.
It's clearly intended
to intimidate the British
over the lease.
The Chinese Navy are calling it
their "friendship tour."
Taking a page
from Franklin Roosevelt.
Sir?
Well, fdr, he sailed
the great white fleet
all over the world,
early 1900's,
called it the
"goodwill tour."
Basically
the same thing.
Just a show of force.
I have to work on my speech.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Thank you.
(Quietly):
Okay...
Uh, Mr. president?
It was, um,
it was Theodore Roosevelt.
Who?
You said Franklin Roosevelt
sailed
the great white fleet
around the world.
It was, it was Teddy.
Well, thank you, Mark.
When you're retire
as my chief of staff,
you're gonna have a real place
on jeopardy!
(Chuckles)
(Quietly):
Don't worry about me.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Give me a second. Sir.
You have a call from a local
CIA head of station.
He say what it was about?
He didn't.
This is Mark Boudreau.
Steve Navarro, sir.
My station just apprehended
a man
with a multi-agency
warrant issued against him.
You're at the top
of the alert list.
Who is he?
Jack Bauer.
Are you sure?
Yes, sir.
Where was he caught?
The old Chatham and Dominion
factory 20 kilometers
southeast of
central London.
It can't be
a coincidence.
I agree.
Jack Bauer is a traitor
and a psychopath
who killed
two Russian diplomats,
and came close to assassinating
their president.
And now after all these
years, he surfaces in London
the same time
as president Heller?
We have to consider
the possibility that he is here
to do the president harm
and there may be other people
involved.
I'll be interrogating him
shortly, and find out.
We don't have time for the
interrogations you'll conduct.
I understand there are special
activities people on site.
Well, they have a unit inside
our facility,
but they operate under
a separate charter.
We don't share intel
or prisoners with each other.
But I can have him formally
transferred into their custody?
Yes, sir.
Great. I'll get started
on that. Send me over
Bauer's case file
and keep his presence there
on a need-to-know basis.
Thank you.
No one finds out Bauer's
surfaced on our end either,
do you understand?
What about the president, sir?
I said no one.
Hey.
Congratulations
on apprehending Bauer.
That's a big one.
I hate to lose you, Kate.
It's not fair
and it's not your fault.
I'll let you get back to it.
Why didn't he go to the roof?
What? Bauer. He could have
gone to the roof
when our men were moving in.
And from there, he would've made
it to any of the other buildings
on the block and he'd
have gotten away.
It doesn't make any sense.
Maybe he didn't scout out
an escape route.
Bauer stayed off the grid
for the last four years.
He didn't do that
by being careless.
He's up to something.
Good morning.
Not for long.
Major Shepherd wants you
to call him as soon
as you arrive.
Sounded pissed.
About what?
Didn't say.
Drone holding at 19,000 feet,
80 knots.
Good luck with Shepherd.
Thanks.
(Phone ringing)
Excuse me.
Sir, it's lieutenant Tanner.
You knew your mission
was to fly cover
while I escorted
British officers to their unit.
Yes, sir. Yet, you didn't
notify their air command.
Sir, that wasn't in your orders.
Shouldn't have to be.
Get it authorized.
Right away.
Yet another dereliction of duty.
You're on base
until further notice.
Sir, I... I have a weekend pass.
My wife and I...
The pass is revoked.
Bastard.
Get that file to
the chief of staff.
And set Bauer up
in interrogation.
But I thought Special Activities
was gonna handle that.
I want to see what
I can get out of him
before that transfer
comes through,
and those people do
God knows what to him.
(Beeping)
Walk him down to interrogation.
Good grab, Erik.
Thanks.
I'd like to take a look
at the original intercept
from Prague, the one
that gave us Bauer's location.
Why?
I just want to make sure
that we're not missing anything.
Like you thinking Bauer
would head for the roof...
when he didn't?
I just, I just want
to take a quick look.
You're not cleared for that.
Look.
- Sir.
- Yeah?
Uh, I thought you should know,
Kate was asking about the Bauer op
she wanted to see the intercept
that helped us catch him.
Is that right?
Yeah, but I didn't give it to her.
I just wanted to make sure you were aware.
And that she's still
being transfered stateside?
She's still leaving at the end of the week,
and you're still on track to get her job.
That's not even what I'm asking.
Yes, it is.
And instead of shoving her out the door,
you should be learning from her.
She was a good field agent.
With all due respect, how could that be?
And considering what happened...
Now you have a lot of strong opinions,
for someone who just got here.
I'm just telling it like it is.
I mean, her own husband
selling secrets to the Chinese?
- And she didn't know?
- And no one knows that better than her
so cut her some slack until she goes.
It's just a few more days,
you can manage that, right?
Hey.
To hell with Erik.
I pulled that intercept for you,
but first there's something I want to say.
You've worked your whole life
to get here Kate.
You can't let them do this to you,
you have to fight the transfer.
I did fight, for two months
locked in a room
while they accused me
of being a part of what Adam did.
But you were cleared.
You deserve to be here Kate.
Do I really?
Because I think Adam proved otherwise.
Here.
Did you look at this?
I brought it straight to you.
Look at the message
from Prague police about Bauer.
You see the header?
Yeah.
Time stamp's out of sequence
with the rest of the traffic.
Which means the tip couldn't
have come from Prague.
That it was planted.
Exactly.
We need to find out by who.
Well, we better do it soon.
Bauer's about to be transferred
to Special Activities.
Once he's down
that rabbit hole,
he's gone.
You able to establish
a baseline?
Not a reliable one.
His reading's are so steady,
it's unnatural.
Pulse and thermal,
all completely static.
Let's see
if we can shake him up.
Steven Navarro, head of station.
Listen, you've been on my side of this
plenty of times
so I'm just gonna lay it out.
There's a long line of people
who will make sure
that you answer for the crimes
you committed four years ago.
All I care about right now
is to find out
if you're here in London
to harm president Heller.
And I'm not
the only one who cares.
There's an order coming
to transfer you to
the Special Activities division
for enhanced interrogation.
You more than anyone know
what they're going
to do to you down there.
Now, I know how many
lives you've saved.
How much the country
is in your debt.
But they're just gonna see
a man who snapped.
Who went on a revenge spree.
Killing and mutilating with no
regard to the law or conscience.
A man who's labeled
by his country a... a criminal.
A terrorist.
So, I think talking to me
is your best option.
Tell me why you're in London.
And I will do everything in my
power to stop Special Activities
from getting their hands on you.
Come on, Mr. Bauer.
Why are you here?
Jack Bauer's being transfered
down to you, here's his file.
(Grunting)
Where's the rest
of your group, O'Brian?
Go to hell!
(Screaming)
No! No! No!
Woman:
Hey, Mark?
Yes hon?
I'm almost ready.
Hey, is my jewelry box
in there?
Yeah.
Got it.
Wow.
(Quiet laugh)
Here.
You read my mind.
Maybe you shouldn't
go to the reception.
Why?
Well, with you
looking like that,
no one's gonna pay
any attention to politicians.
No, they're gonna be
distracted by your tie.
My tie?
Here.
We should probably get going.
Your father's probably
downstairs waiting for us.
How's he doing?
He's doing good.
I heard he made a mistake
in your meeting.
Well...
It's a mistake
anyone would make.
The doctors said he wouldn't
symptomatic for another year.
Well, they also said
that stress could
exacerbate his condition.
Trust me, he's handling
the stress better than I am.
I don't want you to worry, okay?
Okay.
(Knocking)
Come in.
I have an update
on the Bauer situation.
Good morning,
Mrs. Boudreau.
Just, uh, want
to let you know
your car is here.
Thanks, Ron.
We'll see you downstairs.
Okay, I'll be right down.
Sorry, sir.
Talk to me.
The transfer order's
been processed.
Special activity
should have Bauer shortly.
I'm thinking about
what happens next,
after they get what
they can from Bauer.
Well, I imagine
he goes on trial.
That may not be the best
thing for this country.
Is there
an alternative?
He could disappear.
The Russians
have wanted Bauer's head
since he murdered
their people.
I want you to explore
the possibility
of handing him
over to them.
Clandestinely.
The president should
be made aware.
(Scoffs)
The president has
enough on his mind.
Look, you weren't there.
You don't know what Bauer
did to that family;
what he did to Audrey.
She was lifeless;
she was unresponsive;
under psychiatric care...
Not expected to recover.
I had no idea.
I stood by her
for three years.
I held her hand,
I loved her,
and I want her back.
As long as she lives,
she'll never hear
the name Jack Bauer.
Understood.
Just get me what I need.
(Crowd shouting, jeering)
(Crowd clamoring, chanting)
(Crowd chanting, clamoring)
Steve:
Jack... can I call you Jack?
Your options
are running out fast.
That transfer order
is coming through.
After that, I can't help you.
Or...
I can arrange it so that
you can see your daughter again.
Did you know that Kim
had another baby?
A boy.
Any update on
the Bauer intercept?
Actually, yeah.
The intercept originated
from a local
Internet cafe,
just on the other
side of town.
Did you check the cafe
for surveillance cameras?
Snake eyes on that,
but look... here.
The cafe,
see where it is?
That's three blocks
from where we got Bauer.
Whoever planted that intercept
had to know our comm protocols,
and where Bauer was hiding.
That's a pretty short list.
Yeah, I only know
one person on it.
What if Bauer sent
the message himself?
Why would he plant a tip he knew
would get himself caught?
That's what we need
to find out.
Where you going?
Navarro needs to know.
(Lock beeps, clicks)
Steve:
What are you doing?
I need to talk to you.
It's important.
This better be good.
The intercept that gave us
Bauer's location...
it didn't come from
Prague police.
Back up. How do you know
about the intercept?
It was planted.
It originated
just three blocks
from where we grabbed Bauer.
I think Bauer may have
planted it himself.
So you're saying that Bauer
wanted us to catch him?
Which explains why he
didn't go to the roof
during the operation.
He wasn't trying to get away;
he was trying to get caught.
That intercept could've
been sent by anyone
who wanted to catch Bauer.
We need to ask him about it.
If we're right,
maybe he'll open up.
Mariana:
Excuse me, sir.
The transfer order.
Well, that's it, Kate.
It's now in
Special Activities' hands.
Sir, we can't just
let this go.
Get Erik over here.
I want him to take care of
the transfer... got it?
Mariana: Yes, sir.
(Beep)
Kate!
Damn it!
Get that door open!
That tip from Prague was
sent by you, wasn't it?
You arranged to be caught.
You wanted to be brought here
to this facility.
You're after something
or someone.
It's someone, isn't it?
Who?
Who is it?
(Lock beeps, clicks)
Steve: Kate!
Kate...
Get out of here right now.
Look, he is flat
the entire session,
but when I hit him about
faking the intercept
and wanting to be caught,
he spikes.
Let's go.
It's a reaction.
It's means I'm onto something.
Kate!
Bauer is here for a reason and
we need to find out what it is,
and what he's planning on doing.
This isn't about Bauer,
this is about Adam.
Adam?
Your husband betrayed his
country and he betrayed you
and now you're transferring
your frustration onto Bauer.
That's not what
this is about.
Believe me, I understand
how you feel.
Adam was my friend.
He betrayed me, too.
You're psychoanalyzing me
instead of listening...
Kate... let it go.
If Bauer's going
to Special Activities,
then it's a damned good bet
that's exactly where
he wants to be.
You know what?
Forget finishing
out the week.
You're leaving now.
Escort her out of here.
I'll send your
personal effects later.
You ignore this,
and you're putting
the entire building in danger.
Bauer is a violent criminal.
Kate, I really am trying
to help you.
It's for the best.
(Handcuffs clicking)
(Taser clicking, guard grunting)
(Beeps)
(Phone line ringing)
(Phone rings)
Jordan, it's me.
Where are you? I just heard
Navarro was having you escorted
out of the building.
Listen, I need you to find out
if anyone in this building has
a prior history
with Jack Bauer.
Personnel, detainees,
anybody.
Okay, I'm running
the cross-check.
I'll call you
if I find something.
Okay, thanks.
Erik: Used to study your
missions back in training.
You were really
something, Bauer.
Back in the day.
(Keypad beeping)
Dean, it's me.
I'll be right there.
(Beeps)
(Typing)
(Men grunting)
(Erik grunting)
(Grunts)
Take me to her now.
Hold on.
You know who I am.
Trigger an alarm,
and I'll blow your head off.
Now open the door.
(Grunts loudly)
Did you do this to her?
It's nothing
you haven't done.
Come on. Chloe, wake up.
Damn it.
(Panting)
(Gasps)
Easy. It's all right.
It's all right. Okay.
Jack, what are you doing here?
We got to get out of here.
Come on. We gotta move.
You were right
about Bauer.
He does have a connection
with someone
being held
by Special Activities.
And please don't ask me how
I got into their system.
Who is it?
Chloe O'Brian. She's one of
those free information hackers.
Sending this
to your phone now.
She was responsible
for releasing over 10,000
classified dod files.
Is charged with treason.
She worked with Bauer
at CTU for years.
Served time for helping him
escape the country.
Son of a bitch.
He's here
to break her out.
I'm at Special Activities.
Bauer's gone.
Erik and Brandon
are down but alive.
Listen, I want you to initiate
a level five lockdown.
Do it on my authority.
You don't have
any authority!
Just do it!
(Alarm blares)
What the hell is going on?
Why are we on lockdown?
Bauer's trying
to escape, sir.
Kate's down there
right now.
Kate?
Come on, Chloe.
You're gonna make it!
I need you to take cover
behind that wall.
(Alarm blares)
This way.
Stay down here.
Stay down.
Bauer! You're done. You're
not getting out of here!
Drop your weapon!
Drop it!
Okay, now put your hands
behind your head.
Come on. Put your hands
Do it.
Where's O'Brian?
(Beeping)
Come on, Chloe.
Belcheck.
You got her?
Yeah.
(Kate coughing)
(Gasps)
Come on. Come on.
We gotta go.
Get down! Get down!
Go!
I just love this city.
You can feel the history.
And I know that look.
What's your problem?
The mistake you made
in your meeting.
Mark said it was nothing...
That I shouldn't worry.
It's progressing a lot quicker
than the doctors anticipated.
It's terrifying,
the thought
of slowly losing yourself.
Not just the memories,
but all of it.
What do you want to do?
Right now,
I want to lock up
this treaty
with the British.
Okay.
Don't say anything
to Mark.
I'll speak to him
when the time's right.
(Electrical crackling)
Running recovery protocols.
It's gonna be at least
20 minutes before I can try
and access local cctv
to look for Bauer.
All right, let me know
as soon as we're back up.
Yes, sir.
We're laying down a search grid,
starting with a ten-block perimeter,
activating off-duty agents.
You're not gonna find him.
Thanks for the confidence.
Look at how he planned this.
He knows our protocols, he knows
the layout of this facility,
he even knows that special
activities keeps the identity
of their prisoners classified.
So what do you suggest,
we just give up?
I want everything that
Special Activities has
on Chloe O'Brian.
We track down
her known associates,
we break down the intel
for where she might go.
There's no "we."
You are not part
of this station anymore.
Can I talk to you alone, please?
Sir...
Make sure local fire and police
follow our security protocols.
And if they give you
any trouble, remind them
we've got consular status.
Sir...
Do it.
Look at what Jack did,
and he was here for how long?
Look, we need to find him.
So let me do it.
Put me back in the field.
You have to understand,
I am under a microscope here,
all right?
The president's chief of staff
is already all over me
about Bauer.
And I'm your best shot
at getting him back.
Look, yes, Adam was a traitor,
and I missed it,
but I didn't miss this.
I'm the only one
who saw it coming.
I got inside Bauer's head.
Nobody else did that.
Not Erik,
and not even you.
And if you think the chief of
staff is up your ass right now,
imagine what he's gonna do
when he finds out
that you had a heads up on this
and you dismissed it.
Kate, are you threatening me?
I can do this, okay?
I can find Bauer.
I'm asking you to let me.
Belcheck, pull over
at the end of the block.
Chloe, Chloe,
look at me.
Are you all right?
Yeah. Okay, good, 'cause
we need to move fast.
Take this phone. It's gonna be
secure for at least an hour.
They're gonna mobilize after me,
so we need to separate.
Can you get somewhere safe?
Chloe?!
I think so.
Okay, good. I will find you
on that cell phone
as soon as I'm secure.
Now we gotta go, okay?
Now come on.
You got a signal
from the transmitter
that we put
in her phone?
Yes. I still think you should
have just asked her to help.
I couldn't take
the chance she'd say no.
I thought you said
she was your friend.
I don't have any friends.
Let's go.
D-11-3, angels five,
all clear.
Mission complete.
Moving on to next assignment.
Turning South.
Wait. What? What is this?
Wait.
Oh, no, no!
My God.
(Line ringing)
(Phone rings)
Major Shepherd.
Sir, you need to get away
from that vehicle!
You're being targeted!
What are you talking about?
Targeted by who?
Something's taking control
of my drone!
It's armed a missile to attack!
What?
I don't understand it
either, sir,
but you need to get to cover
right now!
Get to cover now, sir!
Sir, move, move!
No! No!
It's done.
Sync and corrections by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com