I can't do it.
I can't testify.
Mr. Campbell, the attorney
general has put together
a grand jury based primarily
on your testimony.
You don't
take the stand,
we can't indict Joey Salucci.
We can't try him for murder.
Unfortunately for us,
the evidence
is circumstantial.
But with your witness account,
this case is a slam dunk.
Exactly, the most renown
gangster in Miami,
and I could be responsible
for putting him away.
That's a death sentence.
No, that is why the city
has arranged
for this safe house.
Eric and I are
personally
escorting you
into circuit court today.
I'm just so tired
of looking over my shoulder.
That's over
after the hearing.
That's why we have you
and your family
set up to go right
into witness protection.
Mr. Campbell,
this is incredibly difficult.
And I am very sorry.
But keep in mind that
A.J. Watkins lost his life,
and so will many other people
as long as Joey Salucci
is allowed to be a free man.
I know. You're right.
You're right.
You mind running through
my testimony with me?
Of course.
Okay, let's start
at the beginning.
You were at a club?
Yes. Spiral Bar.
Had to entertain
a couple of clients.
Did you have anything to drink?
Just a half dozen soda waters,
disguised as gin and tonics.
Keeps the mind on business.
We were there till last call.
I said my "good nights"
and hit the restroom.
And that's when I saw
A.J.. Watkins.
(club music playing)
Hey.
What's up, man?
I went into the second stall.
I wasn't there
but for a few seconds,
and it happened.
(banging and scuffling)
MAN: Hey, man.
(cocks gun)
Joey Salucci.
Know the name?
This is for Emma.
(gunshot)
And you distinctly
heard the name "Joey Salucci."
Yes. No doubt in my mind.
Right then, I knew
what I was up against.
(gunshot)
(footfalls)
What'd you do?
Thought I was a goner.
So I called 911.
(gun cocks)
Figured if anything,
someone would figure out
what happened to me.
OPERATOR:
911, what's your emergency?
(whispering):
This is William Campbell.
There's been a murder
at Spiral Bar on Washington.
Hurry. I need help.
I went out when the coast
was clear.
And the guy's body,
it was... gone.
It's very difficult
to prove murder
without a body.
That's why what you're
about to say is so crucial.
DELKO:
All right, guys,
we've got to get going.
I'm going to radio ahead
to the uniforms
at the elevator
and the rear entrance,
tell them to prepare
for transit.
All right?
Get down!
(glass breaking)
Eric?!
I'm stuck!
I can't get to you!
William?!
(panting, floor creaking)
(crumbling)
William!
Calleigh!
Grab my hand!
Grab it.
Look in my eyes.
Stay with me! Stay with me!
Stay with me.
My family.
(body thuds)
(crying)
Yeah!
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and C.S.I. PRODUCTIONS
We don't get fooled again
Don't get fooled again
No, no!
No one's being
allowed up
until the building
damage can be surveyed.
The fire department says the
structure's still unsound.
The cause of death
is obvious, but, uh,
I'll document the scene
for the case files.
You okay, Eric?
- Yeah.
Calleigh?
Calleigh is, uh...
She's okay.
She gave her statement,
and she just ran
off to track down
the crane operator.
Did we find anything?
Not yet.
Whoever did this
is long gone.
His name is
Joseph Salucci, Eric.
Campbell could've closed
the books on him for good.
It's not unlike him
to do anything to stay
out of prison.
No, it's not,
and he just used
the biggest murder weapon
in Miami.
You did everything you
could to save him, Calleigh.
MAN:
Officer Duquesne?
They said you
were looking for me.
Yeah, you the
project manager?
Yeah, Travis Blake.
Uh, how can I help you?
You can start by telling us
who operated the crane today.
Well, your guess is
as good as mine.
I know that that crane
has been idle,
because I pulled the plug
on this construction site
a week ago.
DELKO: Yeah,
why's that?
Well, housing market's
in the toilet,
bank's pulled
both of my loans.
That basically turned this
building into a ghost town.
DELKO:
The safe house
was done.
And it was
fully furnished.
Yeah, well,
that's the model.
It was supposed
to help us make sales.
I didn't sell
a single unit.
After this is done,
I doubt if I ever will.
You know a Joey Salucci?
Who?
The hard hat do a number
on your memory?
Joey Salucci, he's
in the construction business.
Or at least
that's his cover.
Joey... Joey Salucci. Yeah.
Yeah, it rings a bell. Yeah.
Yeah, I know him, why?
We're finding it
an odd coincidence that you
volunteered your place
as a safe house for our victim.
DUQUESNE: Maybe you
ran the crane today.
Do Salucci a favor,
take some of the financial
pressure off of you;
is that how it works?
That's a hell of a scenario
that you just laid out.
You got any evidence
to back it up?
Working on it.
Don't go far.
CAINE:
How are you, Joseph?
I see you're out of jail.
Show some respect, huh?
I'm visiting my daughter.
You know, you locked
me up for two years.
I could've spent
a lot of time with her
in those two years.
I come here every morning.
But it'll never be enough.
Never.
Nobody should ever
lose a child, Joseph.
Two weeks ago,
she goes to some
bonfire on the beach,
falls asleep.
She was left there all alone.
(fire crackling)
(ATV motors humming)
Come on, hurry up!
South Pointe's
the best place
to see the sunrise.
(grunts)
Oh, my God!
They say she didn't
feel any pain.
It was an accident.
Difference of opinion.
And it seems
that you've taken
your revenge at the Spiral Bar.
Never been there.
I had a witness
that can
tie you to the murder, Joseph.
Is that so?
Yeah.
I say "had," because
he's been killed, too.
It's news to me.
But what the hell, huh?
We all gotta go sometime.
Some sooner than others.
Oh, God.
(panic breathing)
Don't look down.
DUQUESNE:
Hey, Ryan,
how you doing up there?
You're about 200 feet.
I'm doing great.
In fact, cue the wind.
(panting)
I feel like a Ringling Brother.
The contractor's playing
Mr. Innocent, saying
nobody was up there all day.
See if you see anything
to the contrary.
No.
Cab's pretty clean.
System's offline.
There's a computer on board.
I'm guessing has
an internal monitoring system.
You mean like some sort
of a black box?
Yeah. It records every movement
and action of the crane.
He never said anything
about that.
(laughs)
It's probably for good reason.
You know what? I think
I can jack into this,
and, uh, bring the information
back to the A.V. lab.
(thudding)
Whoa! Whoa!
What the hell is that?!
(metallic creaking)
What was what?
(gasping)
(creaking)
No, I said...
I was saying... I was saying,
"Look at that."
It's quite a view.
I mention
what a good time I was having?
Calleigh?
I think we got
some blood up here.
Hi.
- Hi.
So, how we doing
with that blood
from the crane?
Nice get, by the way.
That sample was pristine.
Thanks.
Made it very easy
to pull up a profile.
(beeping)
Think it's ironic
that after
all that destruction,
this whole case could come down
to one drop of blood.
Yeah.
(three beeps)
Check this out.
Now, there's a face only
a mug shot could love.
Kurt Greenfield.
Mr. Greenfield,
how do you know Joseph Salucci?
Who? Bell's not ringing.
Maybe it'd help if we talked
a little bit slower.
Man was killed
by a runaway crane.
You're the crane operator.
CAINE:
We found your blood
in the cab.
TRIPP:
Salucci put you up
to murder, didn't he?
Whoa, whoa.
This about that thing
that happened downtown?
You're way ahead of me here.
Well, then try
and catch up.
Employment records say
at one time,
you worked for Salucci.
Back in the day, yeah,
but I got out of that racket.
Even look the wrong way
with a guy like that,
suddenly
you're taking a dirt nap.
Don't tell him I said that.
Now we've got evidence
of you at our crime scene.
You're looking at
a permanent
vacation, sport.
At the Gray Bar Motel.
All right, look it.
I did some work there
under the table.
But I got canned last week
when the site shut down.
So you opted
for a little payback.
No, it wasn't like that.
Ax came down so quick last week,
I didn't have time
to grab my stuff.
And I needed...
I needed my pills.
Your pills?
Uppers, man.
My cross tops.
Used to pop 'em on the job.
Only thing that keeps the lids
open on a ten-hour stretch.
Oh, look,
I wasn't in the cage
when Armageddon hit, man.
You got to believe me.
Mr. Greenfield,
I don't have to do anything.
(distant siren blaring)
You're the officers
who were with William?
Yes, ma'am. We want
to thank you both
for coming down
and talking to us.
Yeah. We wanted to tell you
face-to-face how sorry we are.
And just explain to you
what happened.
I know exactly
The state attorney
filled me in.
The only reason we
came down here is so
you could look us
both in the face,
and tell us why.
Dad said you'd
protect us
from Salucci.
(stammering):
That-that you... that you...
DELKO:
Listen, we were thorough.
We did our best.
I mean, we really felt we had
all of our bases were covered.
Even though you knew
that that wasn't possible
with a guy like Salucci.
And now my husband is dead,
and I can only assume
that we're next.
The two of you are not
a threat to him.
And the offer
for witness
protection still stands.
Do you have any idea
what this case has
done to our lives?
And for what?
I supported Will's
decision to testify,
as much as every fiber of
my being told me otherwise.
Do you want to know why?
Because it was
the right thing to do.
William was an incredibly
brave man, and...
You do not get
to talk about him,
Ms. Duquesne.
(crying):
You don't.
Not today.
Listen, we're going
to find whoever did this, okay?
Just trust us.
I trusted you
once already.
I won't make the
same mistake twice.
Mom,
come on.
Let's go home.
You okay?
(sighs)
DUQUESNE:
No.
No, I'm not.
There's something
that we're missing.
I'm gonna go back there.
Hey. Is that
the A.V. Hummer?
Yeah.
You know, I heard what happened
with the wife today.
Are you okay?
Well, I guess
if you heard what happened,
then you know I probably
don't want to talk about it.
Fair enough.
Okay. So, uh...
So, what are we looking for?
Tire treads. Somehow
our killer was able
to find the location
of the cafe house.
The site's been shut
down for a week,
so now other cars
should have been here.
Treads are fresh.
Yeah, and they ran
over the debris.
So, someone drove here
after the crane crashed
into the building.
And from the looks of it,
they didn't get away scot-free.
(camera shutter clicking)
This glass has charcoal-gray
paint transfer on it.
Hundred bucks says
this is auto paint.
(glass shattering,
debris clattering)
I'll get started
casting the treads.
Actually, there's a quicker way.
The new software allows us
to photograph the treads,
and then send the 3-D image back
to the lab,
or in this case,
the A.V. Hummer, wirelessly.
(computers chirping)
Width: nine inches.
Tread depth:
five-sixteenths of an inch.
Wheel base-- 112 inches.
I'll download the specs
to the North American Vehicle
Manufacturing Database.
Combine it
with charcoal paint trace.
WOLFE:
Gives us a BMW
645ci convertible.
Now, how many of that model
and color are registered
in the city?
Let's see.
That's
a long list.
There's only one that's a know
associate of Joey Salucci.
Mick Ragosa.
Okay. I'll put out a BOLO.
PILOT:
Air 20. Suspect vehicle sighted.
Adams and Fifth.
Repeat. Adams and Fifth.
(helicopter blades whirring)
(car engine idling, garbled
police radio transmission)
Hey, shut that off!
You Mick
Ragosa?
Yup.
Step out of the
car, please.
(car door closes)
CAINE:
There's quite a bit
of damage on your car,
Mr. Ragosa.
(sighing):
It sucks.
Happened to be driving
through downtown
when that crane
hit the high-rise.
Joseph Salucci.
What about him?
We play poker time to time.
That's it.
TRIPP:
Then I'm calling your bluff.
No way you just happened
to be at our crime scene.
Might be time to
pay a visit to Joey.
Tell him some lies about you.
You wouldn't.
Try me. It's only Monday,
and I've already had one hell
of a bad week.
Fine.
With his daughter gone and all,
the last thing that Joey needs
is another legal headache.
We got word
about the safe house,
so I followed that Campbell guy
down there.
Thought maybe
I could get him to back off.
Refuse to testify.
Suddenly,
it started raining glass.
(loud rumbling and thudding)
(tires screeching)
I barely got out of there
with my life.
Did you happen to see
who was operating the crane?
Nope.
And Salucci never
even knew I was there.
Guys been through enough
already.
Can't you just leave him alone?
Mr. Salucci needs
to go back to jail,
and I'm gonna send him there.
Is that the data
from the box
that Ryan found
in the crane cab?
Yup. There's a reason they
call this a tattletale system.
There isn't much it doesn't
know about the crash.
Like what?
For instance,
angle of the crane arm
at impact-- 72 degrees.
Miles per hour-- 11.
Time of impact--
8:22 a.m.
It's too bad
the tattletale can't tell us
who the crane operator was.
Well, it can,
in a way.
There are two manual joysticks
in the cab
controlling the crane.
Each reports data
back to the CPU.
But watch the
replay of the crash.
See that graph
over there?
(computer chirps)
Yeah. Nothing's happening.
Exactly. Meaning
that those controls weren't eve
being used during the crash.
So, the crane was being
remotely operated.
Yup. The killer
was never even
in that cab.
That just means
that it could have been operated
from anywhere.
Au contraire.
The remote operating system
only has a range radius
of 500 feet.
Let's check out the surrounding area.
Okay.
(computer chirping)
Remote would have to
be within this area.
And the killer would have had
to have known that Campbell was
in the safe house
in order to make sure
that the crane took him out.
And you can't get that eye line
from ground level.
Exactly-- he would have had
to go higher up,
so he would have had to been
on a neighboring rooftop
or something.
Let's take a look
and see
how many rooftops have
that line of sight
within the radius.
Well, there's none...
but there is a
parking structure
just down the street.
Perfect.
DELKO:
Here we go.
It's just like Natalia said.
It's a perfect vantage point
into the safe house.
So the killer stole
the remote off the crane
and then waited out here until
they knew Campbell was inside?
Yeah, and never put it back
after using it,
which explains
why we never found it
at the construction site.
So there might be a good
chance they still have it?
You ever see
one of these things?
They're pretty big.
It's not the kind of thing
you tuck under your shirt.
So maybe it'd be smart
to leave it behind?
Yeah.
Yeah, but dumb to get caught.
Maxine, Eric said
that you had the neck strap
from the crane remote?
Yeah, the remote didn't
have any prints on it.
He thought I might have
more luck with the strap.
Did you?
We'll see.
Cross your
fingers
and hope some skin cells
sloughed off our killer
while doing the deed.
(beeping)
Okay, there must be
some sort of mistake.
There's no match in CODIS,
and I thought for sure that...
Joey Salucci
and Mick Ragosa are
both in the system.
Means they didn't do it.
Okay, will you run this
against the elimination samples
from the case, please?
Sure, no problem.
(typing)
96% probability match
to William Campbell.
That's not right.
That's our victim.
It's right, unfortunately.
This is a familial match.
XY, male.
His son.
How could you do it?
Do what?
I-I'm not sure what you mean.
Don't.
Just don't.
You killed your father.
No.
No, I...
What did you do, Noah?
What did you do?
I didn't mean to, I swear.
Don't say anything else.
You need an
attorney.
I'm gonna get you an attorney.
No, Mom.
Dad risked everything
just to tell the truth.
Now I have to.
When he decided
to testify...
...he made that
decision all by himself.
No, that's not true.
He discussed it with me,
and we decided that
that's what he had to do.
But he never asked me.
The Witness
Protection Program?
I have a life here.
School, friends.
But your life is with us.
We're your family.
It doesn't matter where we live.
But it's not fair.
All this talk about
"doing the right thing."
The right thing for who?
How did you do it?
How did you operate the crane?
Everything's... on the Internet.
So I...
...swiped the remote.
O-Only thing it doesn't tell you
is what to do
when things go wrong.
(crane whirring)
Come on.
(rumbling crash)
(glass shattering)
(screams echoing)
It was out of control.
I couldn't stop it.
I only wanted to scare Dad.
So he wouldn't
testify.
So, so...
so things could be
the way they were.
You wanted a life, Noah?
You just took away all of ours.
I'm sorry, Ms. Duquesne.
SALUCCI:
What a beautiful day.
Huh?
Come on, have a
victory drink with me.
I wouldn't be too quick
to celebrate, Joseph.
My lawyers tell me
that Campbell's kid killed him.
Tragic.
Very tragic.
Very Shakespearean.
Maybe you can back off now
and leave me alone.
In due time, Joseph,
in due time.
You proved it yourself
I didn't kill the weasel.
Case closed.
A.J. Watkins.
The guy who killed
my daughter?
Didn't he, uh...
disappear a few weeks ago?
No body, no crime.
Not yet... Joseph.
(elevator bell dings)
H., I got your phone call.
What's up?
- A.J. Watkins.
Unfortunately,
still at square one.
Without Campbell's testimony,
the grand jury won't convene.
So what exactly
did Mr. Campbell witness?
Well, he was
in the bathroom.
He heard someone
threatening A.J.
MAN:
Hey, man. Joey Salucci.
Know the name?
(gun cocks)
This is for Emma.
(gunshot)
Then he heard a shot go off
and called 911.
OPERATOR:
911, what's your emergency?
So we need the 911 recording.
That's right.
While he was
on the phone with 911,
911 was listening to the room.
I just got the 911
tape from Eric.
Are we looking for
something specific?
We're looking
for something
that wasn't
in William's testimony.
A unique gun noise,
the killer's voice,
anything.
OPERATOR:
911, what's your emergency?
CAMPBELL (whispers):
This is William Campbell.
There's been a murder
at Spiral Bar on Washington.
Hurry. I need help.
Sir? Sir, are you hurt?
Mr. Campbell, are you there?
(water trickling)
What was that?
Part of the music, maybe?
I don't know.
Can you isolate that noise?
(water trickling)
Sounds like
a toilet flushing.
William wouldn't do that.
He wouldn't want to call
attention to himself.
That audio perspective
is from the next stall.
So the killer shoots
and then takes a bathroom break?
No.
Wait. The shooter was
cleaning the scene.
He was flushing evidence.
We've got to get
back to the bathroom.
Wow.
A.J. Watkins disappeared
almost two weeks ago,
and this place looks
just like night shift left it.
Yeah, well, this club
got a lot of unwanted publicity
after the shooting.
So, uh...
they closed their doors.
Bad for them, good for us.
Evidence might still be intact.
Now that is the second stall.
So that's where William
was hiding.
So this is
probably where
the shooter
disposes something.
Looks like they already
printed the toilet.
Yeah.
Well, that means we're going
to have to go to plan B.
It also means... we're going
to need thicker gloves.
(sighs)
WOLFE:
There is a chance that whatever
was flushed down here
hasn't made it into th
e city's sewer system yet.
Okay, that's it. I'm out of line.
What the hell?
People flush
the weirdest things.
Including what might be
a nine millimeter shell casing.
Hmm.
Have you had lunch yet?
All right, you
ready for this?
Yes, yes, just... do it.
(sewage pouring,
Boa Vista groans)
H., I heard you were
working on the casing.
I thought
that the, uh,
water and the sewage
did a number on this thing.
Ryan couldn't pull
a print from it.
Doesn't mean it's not
there though, does it, Eric?
What's this?
This...
is a new acquisition.
I think I've heard of this.
This is the technique where
you can detect corrosion, right?
That's correct.
It occurs...
when human sweat...
touches metal.
If you touch a casing
before it's fired,
your print literally
burns onto it.
Problem is, this level
of corrosion's
impossible for the human eye
to see.
So,
in order to make it visible,
we run a charge
through the casing,
add the conductive powder,
and....
There's your print.
You guys can't seem
to get enough of me today.
Mr. Ragosa,
in the world
of criminal prosecution,
that's not always a good thing.
DELKO:
We found a casing.
It matches the bullet
you used
to shot A.J. Watkins.
CAINE:
It turns out that
William Campbell wasn't the
only witness to the murder.
DELKO:
911 was there, too.
They heard you trying
to send the spent casing
through the city sewer system.
(gun cocks)
What the...
Joey Salucci.
Know the name?
This is for Emma.
No!
(gunshot)
(clinks)
(muted club music playing)
What'd you do
with A.J.'s body?
What body?
Right.
I didn't think so.
Good luck pinning anything
on me.
CAINE:
Stick around, Mick.
Take him.
What do you think
we should do now?
You heard the man.
Let's take him up on his offer.
I can't believe a thug
like Mick Ragosa
gets to drive a sweet car
like this.
Well, not for long.
We are so close
to finishing what William
Campbell started.
If we can prove
that this was
the car that Mick used to
transport A.J. Watkins's body--
which I have a hunch it is--
it'll be over.
I've got blood.
Why stop there?
Nice murder kit.
Wait a second.
This shovel's got trace
on the end of it.
So, Mick transported A.J.'s
body in that car.
Maybe we can use that to prove
where he buried him.
I tell you what--
I'm going to process this
myself.
Don't worry, Calleigh.
We're going to
get this guy.
H., the debris on the
edge of the shovel
is silica and quartz.
It's sand.
Yeah, which unfortunately
for us, is all too common.
What was not common, however,
was the morphology of the sand.
The, uh, the particles
were melted.
That burnt.
That's right.
And the mass spec
picked up kerosene,
which leads me to believe
that A.J. Watkins was buried
at the beach
near a bonfire.
And, unfortunately,
I can't be more specific
than that.
On the contrary,
Mr. Wolfe,
you've been very helpful.
Salucci wasn't
messing around.
He had Mick Ragosa bury
A.J. right on the spot
where his daughter
was killed.
Packed him tight, too.
Slowed decomp.
Hang on.
William Campbell said he only
heard one shot, right?
Yeah. Why?
Well, the only entry wound
is in his kneecap.
He wouldn't have died
from that injury.
Why not shoot the killer?
I don't know.
Maybe you've got the answer.
Any idea on cause of death?
Yes, actually.
Looks like our killer planted
an American flag.
Excuse me?
Red eyes, white skin, blue lips.
All consistent
with strangulation.
Actually, looks like his shirt
covered up some evidence here.
Got a thin residue
of something.
(garbled police radio
transmission)
Sometimes, even a touch of evil
can close the case.
So, A.J. Watkins
was strangled.
Yeah, Tara confirmed
that at the post.
But the killer left
something behind.
Talk to me.
Calleigh found
some pollen
on the neck
of the victim.
Uh, said it's from a fly.
Problem is, there's over
a hundred varieties.
A lily.
I called the Dade U
botany department,
see if they could narrow
it down to one.
That's not going
to be necessary, Eric.
You found pollen on a dead guy.
So what?
It's not just any pollen,
Joseph.
White lily pollen.
(scoffs)
You'd stoop that low
to desecrate her burial site.
You did that all
by yourself.
You told me you go
to Emma's grave
every day.
This is over.
You know,
you can try everything
in your pathetic little arsenal.
Ragosa's the guy.
He shot Watkins in cold blood.
It's his bullet, not mine.
Mick started the job on A.J.,
but you finished it off.
(grunts)
Where are we?
What are you going
to do with me?!
(muffled screams)
(groans)
(screams)
Judgment day, Watkins.
It was an accident.
(cries):
I swear to you.
I-I didn't,
I didn't see her lying there.
You gotta believe me!
You can make up
all the excuses you want,
it's not going to bring
my daughter back.
What do you want me to do?
I'll do anything you want!
Please!
This guy kills my only daughter.
And all he gets is a...
"watch where you're going
next time."
(groaning)
You're not
the law, Joseph.
You and I both know
there's a big difference
between the law and justice.
He had to answer for
what he did.
So do you.
# #
Subtitles by LeapinLar