SAUL:
Previously on Homeland...
Numan, it's me.
Were you able to
get the documents back,
- download them off
Carrie's laptop like you said? - Yep.
LAURA:
If I'm not allowed to speak
to Faisal Marwan immediately,
I will release the remaining
classified documents
in my possession.
_
DOCTOR:
He's in a coma for a reason.
SAUL:
He may have vital information.
Is there a procedure
for waking him up?
- What are the risks?
- Massive seizure, cerebral hemorrhage,
death.
Tell me what the target is.
Tell me where the attack
- is going to happen.
- Keep him awake, Colonel.
(croaking, grunting)
DOCTOR: - Stand back, please.
NURSE: - Sir, please.
(rapid beeping)
The Kremlin can't seriously want
this attack to go forward.
They do. And you will see to it
that it does.
What's the target?
- No!
- Last chance.
Hauptbahnhof Station,
the 5:15 to Potsdam. Please.
- (gunshots)
- No!
(gunshot)
Oh, fuck!
The attack, it's BER.
- The airport?
CARRIE: - Bibi Hamed
has a cousin, Qasim.
Guy was obsessed
with Hauptbahnhof.
- Train station.
- 5:00 is rush hour.
It's the perfect time
to hit the subway.
That's good, Carrie,
except BER is the target.
Are you sure
it's the airport, Saul?
Did he mention a specific area
within the airport?
I think I would've said, Saul.
_
(speaks German)
(creaking)
(indistinct chatter)
WOMAN:
Somebody just jumped down
onto the tracks
and went into
the tunnel.
Woman with the gunshot wound.
Where'd she go?
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
♪
(grunting)
_
(panting)
I'm an American
intelligence officer.
Do you speak English?
(panting)
The Federal Police
are on their way.
Is it here?
Is the weapon here?
What's the plan,
Qasim?
How do you know my name?
Dr. Hussein told me.
(panting)
You should go.
I didn't lock the gate.
You should go now.
Where's the weapon, Qasim?
It's clear you're having
second thoughts. Tell me.
Where is it?
With Bibi.
Deeper in the tunnel.
The plan is to disperse the gas
in front of an oncoming train.
- When?
- The next train.
(panting)
That's in four minutes.
I need to see.
(panting)
Does he have a gun?
I think so, yes.
Okay, you're gonna need
to do it then.
- Do what? - Stop him.
I won't be able to get close enough
without him seeing me first
and triggering the weapon.
Here.
Take my gun.
Take my gun, put it under
your shirt, and don't use it
until you're right in his face.
I can't.
There's no other way.
I mean, I can't kill him--
he's my cousin.
There are hundreds of people
on the platform back there,
thousands in the station.
That train will push
the gas everywhere.
(sighs)
All I can do is try
to talk him out of it.
What? Talk him out of it?
How is that gonna work?
Allah will help me
find the words.
(sighing)
Okay, then go, go.
Go now.
Bibi!
- Bibi!
- Qasim?
_
(rapid gunshots)
(gun clicking)
(Qasim choking, gasping)
_
Qasim.
It's over.
It's over. You stopped him.
(gasping)
Easy.
Easy. Help is on the way.
(gasping continues)
Shh.
That was you, too, wasn't it?
Who saved my friend,
who gave him the atropine.
(gasping continues)
Thank you.
(gasping stops)
Inna lilah
wa-inna ileihe
la ragiuun.
(sighs)
(indistinct radio transmissions)
(paramedic speaking German)
(helicopter blades whirring)
Carrie!
Thank God.
You okay?
No, not really.
(scoffs)
What happened in there?
It wasn't me, Saul.
It was Qasim.
A lot of people
would be dead right now
if it wasn't for him.
Including me.
Hey.
No, no, no, I'll be okay.
I'll be okay.
What about the others,
the rest of the terror group?
Federal Police have dropped
a net on the city.
And Allison?
What about her?
Well, I'm figuring she's the one
who sent us
in the wrong direction.
Yeah.
Tell me she is in custody.
Not yet.
She had a head start.
I want to go home now.
- I'll get somebody to drive you.
- (dialing)
(softly):
Thank you.
Jonas?
You home?
♪
(sighs)
Give us the room, gentlemen.
This charade is over.
And I'm your
self-appointed confessor.
Okay.
How old are you
now, Ivan?
50?
Two. 52.
So...
she was your
life's work.
Mind me asking whose idea it
was for her to come on to me?
On second thought,
don't answer that.
I'd rather not know.
I guess the boys
didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Chemical attack at
Hauptbahnhof's been thwarted.
Two terrorists dead,
rest on the run,
your girlfriend in the wind.
Sorry, I-I...
Now you've lost me.
I'll make it
simple.
Allison was ordered
by your bosses
to let the attack
go forward.
She tried, she failed.
She's since disappeared.
Well...
if you're telling the truth,
she has been, uh, busy.
If I'm telling the truth,
you're burned, my friend.
You're left holding the bag.
How do you figure?
Allison on her way
back to Moscow
means you're no defector.
Means she's the Russian agent
we've been saying all along.
If you're telling the truth.
I'm good.
But I'm not that good.
A story with so
many moving parts
would've taken weeks
to dream up.
You know I'm right.
Hmm.
Say...
Let's say I do believe you.
What do you want?
I want her back.
I want her punished.
And what makes you think
I even know where she is
or how they're gonna
get her out of the country?
'Cause if she were
my agent, I'd know.
- Hmm.
- 'Cause I'd know everything about her.
Down to the very last detail.
When to scold, when to forgive.
When to laugh at her jokes.
Except she's the one running me.
Ivan.
I say this respectfully.
One professional
to another.
You're playing a bad hand.
(sighs)
I understand
you were a ski racer.
Downhill?
Giant slalom was my event.
Why?
How does resettlement in
Jackson Hole, Wyoming sound?
Witness protection,
a sizable
living expense.
I'd miss the Alps.
You'll miss 'em either way.
And there's no family in the
picture, is there? Not a wife
or children?
So you've devoted
your entire life
to an institution that's now
turning its back on you.
The last illusion
of the illusionless man.
(soft chuckle)
(mutters)
What?
What's so amusing?
Nothing, nothing.
It's a good pitch you're making.
I'm... I'm admiring it.
I was gonna tell you
it's not for nothing.
- No?
- No.
Hmm.
You came this close
to painting a masterpiece.
This close.
And not many people
can say that.
But I won't
be making you another offer
like this anytime soon.
I'm being generous,
because you have
something I want very much.
Take it or leave it.
Very well.
It's a shame, though.
I would've enjoyed
talking to you again.
It was my idea.
You were an easy target, Saul.
Middle-aged,
recently divorced.
I knew if you were
sleeping with her,
you wouldn't see
other things so clearly.
Where is she, then, Ivan?
How are they planning
on getting her out of Germany?
♪
(people speaking Russian
in background)
(speaks Russian)
(doors close)
MAN:
Ah, our guest.
And my patient.
Come, this way.
(grunts softly)
Did they give you
something for the pain?
Yes, but it's wearing off.
Please, have a seat.
I am Dr. Rudolf.
And I'm going
to take care of you, okay?
How long am I staying here?
- As long as it takes for...
- (gasps softly)
things to calm
down out there.
Okay.
Until then,
I've been told to give you
the first-class treatment.
Yeah, you must be
very important.
Who are you,
Putin's long-lost sister?
I am important.
So fuck up my shoulder
and I'll see to it you never
practice medicine again.
Okay.
Laura, the BND's here
with a warrant for your arrest.
- What?
- Come on, let's get out the back way.
Wait.
What the hell
are you doing?
There's no time for that.
My air-gapped computer's
in there.
_
Laura Sutton, you are
under arrest for violating
the Foreign Residency Act.
Take her into custody.
Don't worry, I'll
try to call Jonas.
Oh, call all the lawyers
you want.
_
I know you.
You're Anders Larsen.
Sellout.
Piece of shit hacker.
_
I don't have them.
The documents aren't here.
This won't
hold up.
Doesn't have to.
You've officially overstayed
your welcome in Germany.
We're sending you back
to your good friends at the FBI.
_
Carrie.
Hi.
How long have
I been asleep?
I don't know.
(sighs)
Just got back from the BND.
They've got Laura
and they won't let me see her.
It's fucked.
I didn't know where else to go.
You heard about the attack?
Nothing happened, right?
- It's over.
- Yeah, they got the guys.
There was a big shootout
at a house in Prenzlauer Berg.
It's good to see you.
Feels like it's been forever.
Yeah, it does.
Come here.
Oh.
(both moan softly)
Take off your shirt.
(sighs)
Oh, wait. Wait. Wait.
What happened to your hand?
Nothing.
(crowd chatter)
♪
(shouting in German)
(speaking German, grunting)
(excited crowd chatter)
Eine Hamster Liebesgeschihte.
Liebesgeschichte.
A Hamster Love Story.
But she never cared
for that one. Here.
This is it.
Toff-Toff
Der Blaue Trecker.
But you have to do
all the sounds.
The tractor sputtering,
the ducks quacking.
Oh, thankfully, "quack" is the
same in English as in German.
Lucky for you.
Mm-hmm. Lucky for me.
(sighs)
I wanted to take some of
Franny's books back with me.
The danger's over then?
You're safe from what
you've been running from?
Yes, I'm safe.
We're safe.
You want to tell me
what happened today?
It's all over
the-the Internet.
A mysterious blonde woman
in the Hauptbahnhof
tunnels with a gun.
You?
Me.
Nice shirt.
Take it. It's yours.
It'll make me happy
knowing you're wearing it.
So that's it?
We're just... we're just
gonna say good-bye
like none of this ever happened?
It happened.
I was happy here.
Franny was happy.
I think you were, too.
Yeah, I was.
So why can't we just pick up
where we left off?
Would that be so hard?
- Come here, sit back down.
- No.
I don't...
I don't want to sit down.
No, I-I want another chance.
I think we could do better
this time.
Look, I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
This is not easy
for me, either.
I love you guys. I really do.
Then don't break up with us.
Let's just put everything
back the way it was.
Maybe you can't put
things back, eh?
- They won't go back.
- You don't know that.
You don't know that
until we've tried.
I can't unhear things
I've heard,
unsee things I've seen.
I'm sorry.
Stop saying that.
- Stop saying that you're sorry.
- Look, look...
I don't want to go
through life always worried
about what's around
the next corner.
And I don't want
my kids to, either.
- Your kids?
- Yeah.
What happened to Steffan
can never happen again.
- It won't.
- You can't promise me that.
- Jonas...
- Carrie, I'm doing us both a favor.
Can't you see?
It will never work
is what I'm saying.
It was a crazy idea
to begin with.
Oh, so now I'm crazy?
- I didn't say that.
- I'm not crazy, Jonas.
- No.
- I went off my meds for a reason.
- I know.
- (scoffs)
No. No, you know what was crazy?
Was that I actually
opened myself up to you
and really
let you in.
We are not talking
about the same thing.
I'm talking about loving you,
about being loved.
What are you talking about?
Hey. Hey, come on.
No, no, no. No,
I don't want that.
I don't want it.
I won't allow it.
No.
No, no.
Peter Quinn--
he was in Room 303.
He's not there.
Where is he?
- Are you his wife?
- No.
- Family?
- I am a friend, goddamn it! Where is he?
I'm sorry, you're gonna
have to calm down.
He's in the OR.
He had a brain hemorrhage.
The neurosurgical team
is operating on him now.
What, so he had a stroke?
In his case,
intracerebral and quite severe.
How long has he been in surgery?
A couple of hours now, but
he's gonna be in there a while.
Five or six hours at least.
Can I show you to
the waiting room?
The chapel.
Is there a chapel?
Yeah.
(sighs)
(sighs heavily)
WOMAN:
♪ Ich bin Klein ♪
♪ Mein Herz ist rein ♪
♪ Soll niemand drin wohnen als ♪
♪ Jesus allein... ♪
(singing in German continues)
♪ Ich bin Klein ♪
♪ Mein Herz ist rein ♪
♪ Soll niemand drin wohnen als ♪
♪ Jesus allein... ♪
(singing in German continues)
(soft groaning and gasping)
Hello.
I'm sorry.
I've-I've forgotten your name.
- I'm Dr. Emory.
- I remember.
- I'm Carrie.
- Oh.
- May I join you, Carrie?
- Of course.
So, he's out of surgery.
But the hematoma
was very large.
We had to perform a
craniotomy, drain it
and repair the bleed.
What does that mean?
Will he recover?
Well, it's too soon to tell.
Come on, Doctor.
You've seen a thousand
of these. You know.
Tell me.
It was a bad one.
And even if he does recover,
the brain damage
will be significant.
- Where is he?
- He's in post-op.
I need to see him.
Oh, of course.
(indistinct chatter)
(rhythmic beeping and whooshing)
Oh, dear God.
- (panting)
- You all right?
Did we do this to him?
(crying)
_
♪
(beep)
Good morning.
I was beginning to think
you'd forgotten about me.
(sighs)
I'm going to tell you
three things.
All true.
(scoffs)
If you say so.
One-- Faisal Marwan is dead.
He threw himself out
a fifth story window
right here in this building.
You mean you threw him
out the window.
He jumped.
That is a fact.
You killed him.
You fuckers.
No.
We made a mistake
leaving him alone,
but we did not kill him.
Still, that presents us
with a problem.
How to explain his death
to the German people.
No shit.
Which brings me
to the second thing.
Your friend Numan.
What about him?
He's in the next cell.
We have his laptop.
We've recovered
the hacked documents.
Since now they'll
never be published,
you've lost your leverage.
(sighs)
I'm happy to show him to you
if you don't believe me.
You people.
You're the one who's abused
your position here in Germany.
Yeah?
So why am I not on a plane home
like you said?
What am I still doing here?
Believe me, there are
plenty of my colleagues
not far from where we're sitting
who'd like nothing better than
to see you rot
in a supermax prison.
You think I care
what you do to me?
Ah.
But you are not the one
we're talking about, are you?
It's Numan.
What do you mean?
His asylum status here
was granted
on a temporary basis only.
Up for review
every six months.
Come on.
You wouldn't do that.
Turkey's declared him
an enemy of the state.
It is up to you, Laura.
They'll execute him or worse.
Either do exactly
as you're told,
or it's back
to where he came from.
(snoring)
(door opens)
(door closes)
♪
ADAL:
What's the prognosis?
Unchanged.
Not a good sign
he hasn't woken up.
No.
Pity.
If there's no improvement soon,
they're talking about
changing his status
to "minimally conscious."
What does that mean?
It means odds of recovering
cognitive function
drops close to zero.
Poor Peter.
That's his worst nightmare.
(grunts)
You know, we found him
when he was 16.
No, I didn't know that.
Foster home in Baltimore.
The group was looking
for a street kid.
Someone real but also...
pretty enough to turn the head
of a Hong Kong paymaster.
He was a natural
from the start.
I believe it.
Couple years later,
I sponsored him for training.
Youngest guy ever.
Here.
What's this?
You were
his beneficiary
in case anything
happened to him in Syria.
I figured
I'd give it to you now.
No telling when we might
see each other again.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(exhales)
(sighs)
(paper ruffling)
QUINN:
Carrie,
I guess I'm done,
and we never happened.
I'm not one for words,
but they're coming now.
I don't believe
in fate or destiny...
(door opens)
Talk to you for a minute?
Sure.
(indistinct chatter
in background)
How is he?
Not great.
I didn't come here
to fight with you.
Okay.
Given any more thought to what
we discussed the other day?
I have not.
But more thinking
isn't gonna change my mind.
I spoke to the Director.
He's prepared to offer you
complete autonomy, Carrie.
Design your own mission,
pick your own team.
Not interested.
Sorry.
Mind telling me why?
I think I deserve
an explanation.
I'm not that person anymore.
You just saved
hundreds of lives.
I got lucky.
Luck had nothing
to do with it.
If that weapon had gone off,
we'd be living
in a different world today.
We're already living
in a different world.
The attack wasn't the first
and it certainly
won't be the last.
You're being selfish.
Really?
"Selfish"--
that's what you think?
I think you know better than
anyone how to fight these guys.
That's the thing, Saul, I don't.
I have no idea.
Then help us.
Help me.
Come up with a new paradigm.
(sighs)
I'm gonna go back in now.
Goddamn it, Carrie.
I need you.
And I told you I'm not
that person anymore.
(door closes)
(knocking)
Come in.
(door opens)
ERNA:
It's time to go.
I hope your stay here
has been comfortable?
This house is a transit site
for human trafficking--
underage girls being
sold into prostitution.
Yes.
What is your point?
You're kidding.
I've done it myself.
It's only three and a
half hours to the border.
You'll be fine.
What if I need to pee?
You hold it in.
Next time you see sky,
it will be Russian.
(indistinct chatter in German)
WOMAN:
Und in fünf, vier,
drei, zwei, eins...
♪
ANCHOR: Welcome back,
ladies and gentlemen.
And welcome back
to Laura Sutton,
the dissident
American journalist,
who was also our guest
earlier this week,
promising to publish
more sensitive documents
if her demands were not met.
I understand you have
a statement to make.
Yes, I do.
As a reporter, I've always
valued the truth above all else,
sometimes to the detriment
of my career,
certainly to the detriment
of my relationship
to the country of my birth,
the United States of America,
where... I haven't stepped foot
in three and a half years.
In stark contrast,
Germany has provided me
with a home
and the freedom
to do my work.
I have tried
to demonstrate
my profound gratitude
by championing the rights
of the German people
and by speaking truth to power.
Four days ago, I appeared
on this program
and made some
serious allegations
about state security.
I accused the BND
of abrogating due process
and arresting Faisal Marwan
for the second time
on what I claimed
were bogus charges.
In the wake of last
week's failed attempt
at Berlin Hauptbahnhof
and in light of new evidence
I have been given access to...
I am now convinced
that Mr. Marwan is not
the innocent man
I thought he was.
In fact, it is
now clear to me
that he was a vital
and dedicated member
of the terror cell
that planned and plotted
this attack for years.
ANCHOR: Excuse me for
interrupting, Ms. Sutton,
but are you at all worried about
the damage to your credibility?
LAURA:
Of course I am.
All I can do now
is learn from my mistake
and... hope to put it behind me
as quickly as possible.
Did he come at you hard?
He did.
A promotion?
Not exactly, but...
What then?
Stock options?
(both chuckle)
Here, let me help
you with those.
No, that's okay,
let me do that.
You're being very discreet.
Are you considering his offer?
You'd tell me if
I'm too nosy, huh?
No, not at all.
Can I at least pour you
some more wine?
Well, that-that
would be good.
Thank you.
The truth is,
it was painful.
How so?
Turning him down.
Saul recruited me,
he trained me.
He's pulled so many hatchets
out of my back, I've lost count.
We were a team,
we've always been a team.
And is that what you did?
Turned him down?
Yeah.
I don't know what's ahead, but
that chapter of my life is over.
Finished.
So you're ready to
hear another offer?
I'd like to make one.
I can't go back to work
right away, Otto.
I'm sorry.
Too much has happened.
I need to take some time,
be a mom again for a while.
Understand.
But I'm not talking
about your old job.
No?
No. You've trained
your team well.
Mike can take over.
What then?
Over the years, I've hired
a lot of extraordinary people,
interviewed a lot more.
Well, you're picky.
(chuckling):
You're famous for it.
Never anybody like you, though.
That's nice of you to say.
It's not nice.
I read your application,
saw right away
how brilliant you are,
what a freethinker,
and insisted on meeting you.
I remember.
We sat down at 10:15
on a Wednesday morning.
I offered you the
position at 10:30.
I remember.
I was waiting for you, Carrie.
I was waiting for you
to walk through the door.
Okay, now I'm a little lost.
I want a partner,
someone who knows the world
for what it is
but also knows
it must be made better.
Someone to share
my life with.
Otto...
You don't have
to answer now.
Go back to America.
Spend time with your daughter.
Think about it.
I-I don't know what to say.
Say nothing.
Just think about the scope
and scale of what I'm proposing.
The possibilities.
I'll be in Washington
next month for meetings.
We can talk then.
(phone line ringing)
LAURA:
Hello.
Laura, what's going on?
They just let me go.
Numan, I can't talk to you.
What do you mean, you can't
talk to me? Why not?
It's a condition
of the deal I made.
I can't talk to you ever again.
What deal?
Good-bye.
♪
(speaks Russian)
_
♪
(shrill scraping)
(both groan)
♪
Pop the trunk.
QUINN: Carrie, I guess I'm done,
and we never happened.
I'm not one for words,
but they're coming now.
I don't believe in fate
or destiny or horoscopes,
but I can't say I'm surprised
things turned out this way.
I always felt there was
something kind of
pulling me back to darkness.
Does that make sense?
But I wasn't allowed
a real life
or real love.
That was for normal people.
With you, I thought,
"Ah, maybe, just maybe..."
But I know now that was
a false glimmer.
I'm used to those-- they happen
all the time in the desert--
but this one got to me.
And here's the thing,
this death, this end of me
is exactly what should
have happened.
I wanted the darkness.
I fucking asked for it.
It has me now.
So don't put a star
on the wall for me.
Don't say some dumb speech.
Just think of me as a light
on the headlands, a beacon,
steering you clear
of the rocks.
♪
I loved you.
Yours, for always now,
Quinn.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com