(male announcer)
In the criminal justice system,
the people are represented
by two separate
yet equally important groups--
The police
who investigate crime
and the District Attorneys
who prosecute the offenders.
These are their stories.
- I put the new budget
on your desk.
- Stay out of my office,
Caroline.
- Charles.
- Anything you have for me,
give it to Amy.
- I'm sure you understand
my position.
- You obviously
don't understand mine.
- You can't
seriously expect me to.
- What I expect
is a little consideration.
Good night,
Caroline.
- Guy going out to get pampers
for his kid
called it in from his cell.
We got a canvass started.
So far, no witnesses.
- [sighs] All right,
let's see.
- Looks like knife wounds
from the back.
- Ruined a pretty good suit.
Crockett and Jones wingtips--
obviously not
from the neighborhood.
- No wallet.
Just a business card case here.
- "Charles Whitley.
Executive Director
of the Boland Initiative."
Pretty big charity.
- Yeah, they got 100 bucks
off me last year.
Hey, check this out.
Ligature marks on his wrists.
Somebody had him tied up.
- What's this?
It's not a tattoo.
It looks like fresh ink.
- A bank account, password.
- One thing I know for sure,
it's definitely
not his lucky number.
[dramatic music]
# #
- Charles was usually
home by 7:00.
I thought he'd stopped to have
a drink with a colleague.
I fell asleep.
When I woke up
and he wasn't home...
- You have any idea
why he'd be up in Inwood?
- No.
Was this a robbery?
- Maybe.
He ever mention any threats?
Or people following him?
- No, nothing like that.
- Executive Director
at the Boland Initiative--
What did that involve?
- He oversaw
their philanthropic projects.
- Your husband, did he talk
about problems at the office?
- No, he loved his work.
He even turned down
a generous retirement package.
- He had this
written on his arm.
See?
That mean anything to you?
- It's not like Charles
to do that.
That doesn't even
look like his handwriting.
- Contusions
on his limbs and torso,
bruised ribs,
welts on the back of his legs,
all leading up
to the tercio de muerte.
- The final act
of a bullfight.
- Five stab wounds
to the right lower back.
- That's a nice cluster.
Might be somebody
with training.
- What do you make of
the numbers on his forearm?
- It was applied
with a regular pen
not more than a day
before you found him.
As for the numbers themselves,
I've seen this before.
[beep]
Survivors from Auschwitz--
The only death camp
where prisoners
were tattooed
with serial numbers.
- Maybe someone put this number
on his arm as a message.
- Anti-Semitic threats?
Charles wasn't Jewish.
- well, maybe somebody thought
the Boland Initiative
Was too sympathetic
to Jewish causes.
- That would surprise me.
We spread the money around
very equally.
- Do you spread any of it
up in Inwood?
- We have grant recipients
all over the city.
But I spoke with Charles
yesterday.
He didn't mention
going to Inwood.
- His wife said he was
offered a retirement package.
- That was pro forma.
When Charles turned 62, he was
eligible for early retirement.
We were relieved
when he decided to stay on.
- Mrs. Reeves,
your conference call.
- Oh, excuse me.
- This is all of Mr. Whitley's
personal correspondence.
- Thank you.
- I see his date book
has every other Tuesday blocked
off between 5:00 and 6:00.
- That's right.
I'd call a car for him
for a 4:15 pickup,
and off he'd go.
- Off he'd go where?
- I never asked,
and he never told me.
I just told the dispatcher
to take Mr. Whitley as directed.
- NYPD.
Can we come in?
- Oh, sure.
You must be here about
the murder down the street.
- [murmurs]
- Let me put up
some fennel tea for you.
It's great for the digestion.
- We're good.
You were here last night?
Ms...?
- Lorraine Flockhart.
Yes, I was.
- A car service sent--
oops, sorry.
Uh, a car service
said that they dropped
the victim off
at this address.
- Oh, my God!
It's Charles Whitley.
He was one of my clients.
-You were his nutritionist?
- Yes, I was.
He had a standing appointment
here for years.
- How did he seem yesterday?
- He said he was
a bit run-down, actually.
I reviewed
his glycemic index
and we made some changes
to his diet.
And then he left,
just after 6:00.
- He had this written
on his left forearm.
- Sorry.
He had his jacket on
the whole time.
- There are
plenty of nutritionists
near his office in midtown.
You sure this
wasn't about sex?
- We didn't get that vibe.
- Because?
- The woman's practically
as old as his wife.
What would be the point?
- I can't believe
you said that, detective.
- What?
- I can't believe it, either.
[phone ringing]
- Van Buren.
Yes, put her through.
- You want this closed?
- This is Lieutenant Van Buren.
Yes, that's our case.
Of course we're interested.
- It arrived at
the metro desk this morning.
No return address, no note.
This is a copy.
When I saw that Whitley
was on this, I called you.
- Let's play it.
[click]
- Bring the prisoner here.
- On your knees.
- Yes, Fraulein Vera.
- Hey, hey. It's Lorraine,
the nutritionist.
- Lick her boots, you scum.
[whip noise]
- Oh.
- Talk about
your low calorie diet.
- [grunts]
- You didn't say please.
- May I please
lick your boot, fraulein?
- Lick it clean.
And don't
get your lice on her.
[whipping noise]
[click]
- What I do
is completely legal.
Mr. Whitley got exactly
the treatment
he paid for and agreed to.
- Getting abused
as a prisoner,
the number on his arm--
that was all his idea?
- Yes. Don't ask me why.
- Maybe providing
S&M services is legal,
but making
blackmail videos isn't.
- I didn't spend 15 years
building a reputation
just to ruin it
by blackmailing a client.
- This was shot
in your office.
- Without my knowledge.
Charles came over
two weeks ago.
He was furious.
He said that someone
had sent a DVD to his work
and now they
were trying to fire him.
- So if you didn't
make the video, who did?
Maybe one of your...elves.
- They didn't know
where Charles worked.
- Okay.
So last Tuesday...
why did he come over?
- For his usual session.
- After being videoed?
- I fired my two girls.
We moved to a different room.
He needed this.
He couldn't stop.
- Somebody sends a DVD
to Whitley's boss
to try to get him fired
a month after he was
offered a retirement package.
- Which he turned down.
- Somebody wanted him
out of that job badly.
- They got him
out of that job now...badly.
- I didn't tell you
about the DVD
because I didn't want
to embarrass Charles' family.
- Do you have the DVD
and the envelope it came in?
- No, on the advice
of our council,
those materials were destroyed.
- Why?
Wouldn't you need the DVD if you
were trying to fire Mr. Whitley?
- Charles refused to resign
and he threatened
to sue if we fired him.
He was completely unapologetic.
He said he
wasn't breaking any laws,
that this was
his private hobby,
and it didn't
impact his duties here.
Our lawyers said
he had a strong case
if we tried
to terminate him.
- So you just let it drop.
What about the retirement offer?
Whose idea was that?
- I told you
that was pro forma.
- Anyone in particular
in or out of the Initiative
who wanted Whitley gone?
- No, he was respected.
That is, before that DVD
landed on my desk.
- I didn't know how to tell you
about Charles' predilection.
I asked him once
to explain it to me.
He couldn't.
- Did he tell you a video
of one of his sessions
was sent
to Boland Initiative?
- Yes, they weren't
after money.
They wanted
to hurt him professionally.
I have to call my children
before they hear
about this on the news.
- Of course.
We're very sorry.
Thank you for coming in.
- That is gonna
be one awkward phone call.
- At both ends.
What did you find
at the nutritionist's place?
- Enough leather
to outfit a biker convention,
but no spy cam.
- So it must've been
an inside job.
Take a run at
the nutritionist's little elves.
- jawohl.
- [chuckles]
- Yes! That's me.
It's not like I'm a prostitute.
It's just acting.
- It's not
what you were doing,
but how it got on the DVD.
- I told Lorraine
I had nothing to do with that,
and she still fired me.
And I'm about to be evicted
and I got, like,
$100 to my name.
- Did you just get
some work done, Vera?
- They're too high, right?
No, they're gonna look normal
when the implants settle.
- You didn't have them
on the video.
Where'd you get
the money for them?
- My savings?
- Uh-huh, okay.
So money you saved
over months?
Is that what
we're gonna find
when we check
your bank account?
- Or if we call your doctor,
is he gonna tell us
that you paid cash?
- You know, Vera,
if you paid for those
with money you got from planting
a camera in Lorraine's place,
the government can seize them
as proceeds from a crime.
They'll just
put you under a knife
and take them out.
- You can't be serious.
- As serious as murder,
which is what happened
to the gentleman in the video.
- Charlie?
Oh, my God!
- If you cooperate with us,
We can make sure
that you keep your, um...
enhancements.
- [sighs]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait, wait, wait.
- It's behind the cocoa puffs.
- Just stand over there.
- I swear I had nothing
to do with any murder!
The guy gave me 10 grand
to put that in Lorraine's place,
and that's all I did.
- Which guy?
- His name is Phil.
I met him outside of Lorraine's.
He said he was looking
for some restaurant,
and after we hooked up
at his hotel a few times,
he asked me to plant the camera
the next time Charlie came by.
He paid me and I never heard
from him again.
- Well, how do we find Phil?
- I don't know.
I went to the hotel
and he checked out.
The hotel said
that he paid cash.
- Did he have a phone number?
- It stopped working
so I threw it out.
- The hotel is the only place
you ever saw him?
- I saw him using an ATM around
the corner from the hotel,
and he looked at me like
I caught him stealing money.
So...
- Hmm?
- Are you gonna
let me keep them now?
- We'll be in touch.
- That's some
nice police work, fellas.
You found me through an ATM?
- You recognize her?
- [clears throat]
[chuckles]
I was in a nice hotel.
Expense account.
I just wanted
a no-strings-attached fling,
no crime in that.
- No crime so far.
- You know what
she does for a living?
She's a dominatrix.
A nut job.
I got a weakness
for crazy girls.
That's why
I love them and run.
- She's connected to a murder
victim named Charles Whitley.
You know who he is?
- No.
- He's one of Vera's clients.
She said you paid her $10,000
to get compromising
video of him.
- She said that?
That's the thing
about crazy girls--
they make trouble if
they don't get what they want.
- You're right about that.
How about you tell us where you
were last Tuesday around 6:00?
- And how about I don't?
I'm a security professional,
guys.
I know my rights.
- Sure.
We'll get out of your way.
Just curious...
how did you get
into the security business?
- Personal interest.
My older sister was killed
by a stalker in college.
You have a nice ride
back to the city.
- Your witness is a woman
who beats up men for a living.
If that's your probable cause,
it won't impress a judge.
- Well, Amato said he
was in the city on a job.
His boss said
he was on vacation.
- Well, Vera said
Amato gave her $10,000
to plant the camera.
Does he have
that kind of money?
- No, he's
moonlighting for someone
who wanted Whitley
out of the way.
- That's not enough
probable cause for murder,
but it may be enough
for an extortion charge.
Talk to a judge
about a search warrant.
- Hey, what do we have here?
A program to operate
remote cameras.
- Yeah,
that's standard equipment
in the security business,
big deal.
- Let's turn one on
and see what we come up with.
- Looks like the property room
at our precinct.
- Which is where we stored
the camera that Vera gave us--
The camera she says
you gave her.
You're under arrest
for extortion.
Hook him up.
- Vera set me up.
- Hey b, check this out.
- She set me up!
- It's a letter
of recommendation
for our friend here,
addressed to the Halliwell
Group, dated last year.
Check out the signature
at the bottom.
- Rita Shalvoy.
- Governor's wife.
No wonder he's so cocky.
The guy's got juice.
- Oops.
We just stepped
into a deep, stinking pile.
- According to her
letter of recommendation,
Rita Shalvoy met
Bobby Amato 13 years ago,
when his sister was killed.
- Rita was a victims'
rights advocate back then.
What was his sister's name?
- Ellie. Ellie Amato.
- Ellie's law.
- Mm-hmm.
The anti-stalking statute.
- Rita fought
to make that happen.
- You know
what a fighter she is.
And how corrupt
the husband is.
- Start by finding out
who Mr. Amato is working for.
I'll talk to Rita Shalvoy.
Just to give her a heads up
that we're charging
her friend with extortion.
- Your boss told us you weren't
working for him in New York.
You were freelancing
for someone else.
- There is no someone else.
I did a job for Halliwell,
then I decided to stay in town
and enjoy the sights.
- The sights?
From where? Zagat's guide
to S&M dungeons?
- Well, yeah, I want
to tell you about that.
- Mr. Amato--
- It's okay.
I was up in Inwood,
I was looking for a Dominican
restaurant when I met Vera.
After we hooked up, she told me
what she did for a living.
She said she was worried
about this client of hers,
this creep, she thought
he was stalking her.
I told her that my sister
had been killed by a stalker
and that I would
follow him for her
to put her mind at ease.
- An act of gallantry
toward a woman you were dating
under a pseudonym
and planning to dump?
- Did I mention that
following people is fun?
I told Vera
where he lived and worked
in case she
needed to protect herself.
Then she has
the nerve to turn on me
and set me up
with this extortion rap.
- So you're saying she planted
spy cam software
in your computer?
- No.
That would be ridiculous.
I gave her the camera
so I could watch her.
She liked to put on little shows
for me on her computer,
but then she made a video
of Whitley and framed me for it.
- You sure you
didn't leave anything out?
- No, that
just about covers it.
- Except Vera
never mentioned her worries
about Whitley to the police.
- Oh, no, she was
definitely concerned.
The guy was twisted.
And hyped up on coke.
- Drugs now.
- That's what she said.
He went to a dinner a few months
ago in honor of Jimmy Carter
and he spent the whole night in
the bathroom with a bloody nose.
That's a guy with a problem
right there.
- I'm sorry to hear
about Bobby Amato.
He's never recovered
from his sister's death.
Can I get you some coffee?
- I'm fine, Rita.
- I appreciate the heads up.
Come what may, Jack,
when this election's over,
I hope you and I are able to
find a way to be friends again.
- You know me,
I'm an optimist by nature.
But wouldn't Donald object?
- Donald's had ample
proof of my loyalty.
And with our youngest
going off to boarding school,
there's an opportunity for me
to reengage with the world.
- Well, you can't keep
a good woman down.
Back to Bobby Amato.
You wrote a pretty glowing
recommendation for him.
How well do you know him?
- I should've known
you wouldn't come
all this way
for a courtesy call.
The fight for Ellie's law
gave Bobby a purpose.
He became attached to me.
He's loyal to a fault.
- The fault being?
- [sighs]
A few years ago,
he called me.
I was on my way to Maine
to visit my mom who was ill.
Two days later,
Bobby shows up--
in Maine, car full of groceries,
ready to pitch in and help.
I had to explain why
his behavior was inappropriate.
He apologized and left.
- Sounds like you need Ellie's
law to protect you from him.
- You ever have a cat, Jack?
They'll bring you mice
they've killed
as a gift--
A kind of unsolicited
act of devotion.
Bobby's like that.
- In December,
there was a dinner
honoring President Carter--
an intimate dinner for 30
at the Shalvoys' townhouse,
and it was on a Tuesday.
- Whitley went there
straight from one
of his S&M sessions.
If he was in the bathroom
tending to a bloody nose--
- Rita Shalvoy would've known.
- She might've been the one who
told Bobby Amato what happened.
- Meaning she sicced Amato
on Charles Whitley.
- Whatever Rita's motive,
she's already laid out
a preemptive defense
for herself.
She accused Amato
of stalking her
and doing unsolicited favors.
Rita Shalvoy
and Charles Whitley.
Connect the dots.
- The invitation
to the Carter dinner
was sent to
the Boland Initiative.
Charles happened
to be free that night.
- Do you know if he had
any kind of relationship
with Rita Shalvoy?
- No, he never mentioned her.
- What about a relationship
between Rita Shalvoy
and the Boland Initiative?
- The Shalvoys have
attended some of our functions,
but there was no relationship.
- What about you,
Ms. Reeves?
Did you ever talk to Rita
Shalvoy about Charles Whitley?
Maybe complain about him?
- No, what a strange question.
- Well, you offered him
the retirement package.
You were sent the DVD.
You tried to fire him.
This campaign to get rid
of Mr. Whitley--
if it didn't come from you
it certainly came through you.
- That is completely untrue.
I knew Charles
for almost 20 years.
I never wished him any harm.
- She left her office a half
an hour after you talked to her
and took a cab
to Hudson River Park.
- She looks kind of familiar.
- Yeah, it's Thea Curry,
City Councilwoman
from District 52.
She spoke
at my niece's graduation.
Impressive.
Whatever you said to Ms. Reeves,
you got to her.
- They're lovers?
- Not to mention Caroline
Reeves is married.
- Half an hour
after she talks to us,
Caroline Reeves is crying
on Thea Curry's shoulder.
We should remind Councilwoman
Curry she has an obligation
to report any criminal
activity to us.
- I'm aware of my
ethical obligations, Mr. Cutter,
As I'm sure
you're aware of yours.
Whatever your detective saw
is nobody's business.
- Right, nobody's business,
of course.
And Ms. Reeves
is a lovely woman.
- Well, I could put
in a good word for you,
but it wouldn't do any good.
She's married.
- Isn't this the school
the Obamas
considered for their girls--
Georgetown Day School?
- I think it was.
- Are you thinking of it
for your kids?
You're moving to Washington?
- No, my husband
and I have shared custody,
and he's had job offers,
so we're just...
you never know.
- Right.
Yeah, you don't.
The people
at Georgetown Day School
say Thea Curry visited twice.
She told them that she was the
one who might be moving to D.C.,
not her ex-husband.
- So why lie about it?
- She's a smart politician.
Everyone expects her
to run for State office,
maybe even for Congress.
Of course.
It's been staring us
in the face.
New York has
an open U.S. Senate seat.
Governor Shalvoy
can appoint whoever he wants
to fill that vacancy.
- If there's something
in it for him.
- Does a bear crap
in the woods?
- Meanwhile, Thea Curry's
lover, Caroline Reeves,
tries to coax Charles Whitley
into early retirement.
- When that didn't work,
Rita's "loyal-to-a-fault"
private spy
dug up the dirt on Whitley
to force him out of his job.
- That's the horse trade.
Thea Curry becomes Senator
and Rita Shalvoy
becomes Executive Director
of a prestigious
international charity.
- The Shalvoys are running
a big game of musical chairs.
- And Charles Whitley
didn't want to give up his seat.
But it's still not clear
if Amato killed Whitley
on Rita Shalvoy's orders
or what the Governor knows
about his wife's involvement.
- We'll have to find out,
won't we?
- If Shalvoy goes down,
he takes Joe Chappell with him.
- That's not a factor
in how we prosecute this case.
- Don't look so happy, Jack.
- Rita Shalvoy described
you as a quasi-stalker
who did her favors
she never asked for.
- No, Mrs. Shalvoy
would never say that.
- She told us about the time
you brought groceries
up to Maine.
- You see what she's doing,
Bobby?
Whatever you did to Whitley,
she never asked you to do it.
We're sending you to prison.
She's greasing the skids.
- Is there a plea offer here?
- Manslaughter.
But first we hear
what he has to say.
- Mrs. Shalvoy
wanted my help
forcing Whitley out
of the Boland Initiative.
She told me about his nosebleed
at the Jimmy Carter dinner.
She said I'd have no trouble
finding something on him.
- Did she pay you?
- She gave me
a Diamond necklace.
Told me where I could sell it.
I got 20 grand for it.
I used ten to pay Vera
to make the DVD.
Two weeks after I sent
the DVD to Caroline Reeves,
Mrs. Shalvoy called me.
She said
Whitley was being stubborn,
and would I remove him?
Mrs. Shalvoy said he
was standing in her way
of doing great things.
She reminded me
of all the good she'd done.
Ellie's Law.
And how could
I turn my back on her now?
So I did what she asked.
- Did she say
anything to indicate
if Governor Shalvoy
knew what she was up to?
- No, she never
mentioned him once.
- It's hard to believe
Rita Shalvoy would go so far
off the reservation without
her husband knowing about it.
- When it
comes to the Shalvoys,
I've suspended disbelief
a long while ago.
How much of Amato's story
can we corroborate?
- Well, we talked
to the jeweler
who bought Rita's necklace
from Amato.
He resold it to a tourist
from Qatar for cash.
There's no way to track it down.
- That necklace
could've belonged to anybody.
It's gonna take more than
the word of an accused killer
to convict the Governor's wife.
- Amato offered
to wear a wire...
if we can get Rita
into a room with him.
- This woman
wasn't born yesterday.
Have Amato's lawyer
move for a bail hearing.
- I'm not
asserting a privilege,
I just don't understand
why I've been called
to testify at a bail hearing.
- I subpoenaed her to address
my client's Bona Fides
for release on bail.
She's known him
for a dozen years
and can testify to
the likelihood he'll appear.
- I don't want to hurt
Mr. Amato's chances for bail,
but I'm not
going to address that.
- Can I speak
to Mrs. Shalvoy in private?
- That's highly irregular,
your honor.
- Please, Judge,
just give him a chance
to convince her to cooperate.
- Your client has ten minutes.
- You've put me in a
really awkward position, Bobby.
- Why aren't you helping me,
Mrs. Shalvoy?
I'm going crazy in jail.
I've kept my mouth shut
until now.
- I don't know
what you're talking about.
- I don't want to hurt you
or your family.
At least help me come up
with a story.
- A story?
Are you implying you murdered
Charles Whitley for me?
- Yeah, well, I did.
- Bobby, you know
that's not true.
You may have heard
me criticize Whitley,
but I never asked you
to harm him.
- I'll tell them
about the necklace.
- The necklace.
Bobby, I've told you before,
you need psychiatric help.
Bobby,
I've told you before,
You need psychiatric help.
- She didn't come close
to an admission.
- She's too smart.
[phone ringing]
- Yes, Ida.
Tonight?
Tell him I'll be there.
I've been summoned.
- I advised Mrs. Shalvoy
that she had to report this.
She insisted on doing it
as soon as possible.
- Bobby Amato confessed
to me today
that he killed
Charles Whitley.
As fond as I am of Bobby,
I'm prepared to testify
against him.
- She'll come down tomorrow
and give a full statement
to Mr. Cutter.
- It's the right thing
to do, Rita.
Can we have a word?
- Give us a minute, Rita?
- Rita told me that Amato might
try to drag her down with him.
- Let's not insult each other's
intelligence, okay?
We both know
what this murder was about--
the Senate seat.
Seems like every day
we hear about
another corrupt civil servant.
Corrupt banker
or businessman, athlete.
Seems that behind every success
story of the last ten years,
a scandal is exploding.
We're facing a rising sea
of corruption,
and we wonder...
who will be
the next to be drowned?
Who will be saved?
And what will become
of our good works?
When will it stop, Donald,
and who will stop it?
- If you expect me...
to implicate Rita...
and jeopardize my family?
- Your family--
they're campaign props
you use to get elected.
They mean as much to you as
balloons and bumper stickers.
Your whoring proves it.
- Be careful, Jack.
I'll attribute that to
the stress of your campaign.
I know you're in a dead heat
with Joe Chappell.
I also know
a few things about Joe.
Maybe we could swing
the numbers your way.
- You're trying
to buy me off?
- Well, you worry
about your good works, Jack.
How are you
going to safeguard them
if you're not
in the game anymore?
- Rita came in
and gave her statement.
She's practically
inoculated herself
against anything Bobby
might say.
- Every time we zig,
the Shalvoys zag.
- Then go straight at them.
Convene a Grand Jury
to investigate
the selling of a Senate seat
by Governor Shalvoy.
Once we prove
the why of Whitley's murder,
we can prove the who.
- I had discussions
with Governor Shalvoy
about my possible appointment
to the U.S. Senate.
- Did the Governor
mention his wife, Rita,
during these discussions?
- He said his wife was looking
to get back into public service.
He asked if I could
help her find a position.
- So was it
your understanding, then,
that finding
Rita Shalvoy a job
was a prerequisite to your
getting the Senate appointment?
- He didn't say those words,
but that's what
I read between the lines.
- So what did you do?
- I told him a friend
at the Boland Initiative
was unhappy with
their Executive Director,
Charles Whitley.
I said that I would look into
that situation for his wife.
- And what happened next?
- My friend
Caroline Reeves
agreed to urge
Mr. Whitley to retire.
He refused.
It was then
that I called the Governor
and told him that the Boland
job wasn't opening up.
- And what did
the Governor say?
- That he'd let me know
about the Senate appointment.
A week later,
Caroline told me
that Mr. Whitley
had been murdered.
- She "read between the lines."
I'm not sure
that makes out pay-to-play.
- Should be enough
for an indictment.
- You're asking a Grand Jury
to indict a sitting governor.
He's not exactly
a ham sandwich.
- Shalvoy's giving an interview
about the vacant Senate seat.
- My only criterion
is who will best represent
the State of New York.
Right now,
I'm leaning towards someone
I've had my disagreements
with in the past,
but he's seasoned enough
to handle
the rough-and-tumble world
of national politics.
Manhattan District Attorney Jack
McCoy is at the top of my list.
Thank you.
- Shalvoy must've found out
we convened a Grand Jury on him.
He's muddying the waters.
- Not to mention
who's going to vote for a D.A.
Who's got one eye
on Washington?
You have to admit,
it's rather brilliant.
- Ida, get me Mark
in the campaign office.
I'll put an end to it
tomorrow morning
with a press conference.
- We're wanted
in the Grand Jury.
- We saw the news
during the lunch break,
And some of us wondered
if Jack McCoy
might be horse-trading
with the Governor too.
- Mr. Foreman,
Jack McCoy is not
a target
of your investigation.
- Maybe Thea Curry
was subpoenaed
because McCoy's trying to
whittle down his competition
for the Senate job.
- We'd like to hear
what he has to say about it.
- Mr. McCoy will be speaking
at a news conference
tomorrow morning.
- We want him under oath
when he tells his side of it.
- Your Grand Jury
is out of control.
- We always claim Grand Juries
are independent.
- If it leaks out that
I've been called to appear,
I might as well concede
to Joe Chappell right now.
- You need to get out
in front of this
before you find your name on the
first page of an indictment.
- My campaign director
is advising me
to assert executive privilege--
to stall
until after the election.
- Well,
if that's your plan, Jack...
I'd rather you conceded.
Mr. McCoy, have you ever
sought an interim appointment
to the United States Senate?
- Never.
I'm running for election
to remain the District Attorney.
I have no desire
to hold any other office.
- Have you ever discussed
the interim Senate seat
with Governor Shalvoy?
- Not as it concerns myself.
- Um...
- Yes.
- In other words, Mr. McCoy,
you had a discussion
with the Governor about it.
- Yes.
- And yesterday
the Governor said
he was thinking
of appointing you.
Why shouldn't we
infer you made a deal?
- I convened this Grand Jury
because the police
uncovered evidence
of political corruption
during the investigation
of a murder.
The Governor's announcement is
a ploy to hijack your inquiry.
I never sought
and will not accept
appointment of the Senate,
because I remain
committed to one thing:
To serve this city
as its chief
law enforcement officer.
And in that capacity,
I will prosecute
political corruption
wherever it occurs...
and whomever perpetrates it.
- Two hours and counting.
- I think he'll be okay.
- Don't be so sure.
That one Grand Juror was
ready to storm the barricades.
There's a mob mentality
in this country right now.
None of us can afford
to be complacent.
[bell ringing]
- Thank you.
They voted a sealed indictment
against Governor Shalvoy
for official misconduct
and attempted bribe receiving
in the second degree.
Nothing about you.
- It's just an indictment.
They still don't
have enough evidence
to convict him in trial.
- It's sufficient for
what I need to do with it.
- I will not be
sent out again, Donald.
- Whatever you have
to say to me, Jack,
you say
in front of my wife.
- Fine.
I have a sealed indictment
against you
for bartering the Senate seat
with Thea Curry.
- I'm just curious,
what did you promise Thea
in return for
her perjured testimony?
- I'd be careful.
Anything you say can be used
against you in a court of law.
- Are you Mirandizing him?
- I have officers outside
waiting to arrest you.
- Waiting?
What do you want from me?
- Corroboration
of Bobby Amato's testimony
against your wife
for Charles Whitley's murder.
- Jack.
This vendetta against me
is pathological.
- If you give me what I need,
I might be convinced that your
conversation with Thea Curry
was political back-scratching
that didn't rise
to the level of criminality.
I'll withdraw the indictment
as legally insufficient before
it even sees the light of day.
You'll keep your position,
your power.
- How can I trust you
- You can't seriously
be considering this, Donald.
- Never mind trust.
Do the math.
- Donald, I remind you
that every
conversation we've had
is subject
to the spousal privilege.
I can stop you
from testifying against me,
just as you can stop me
from testifying against you.
- The privilege
has exceptions.
- Yes, I know.
Did Bobby Amato
mention a necklace?
- The Diamond necklace--
that's how Rita paid him.
Amato sold it to a jeweler.
- If I remember
my law classes,
it's an exception
to the privilege
if I see my wife take
a necklace out of our safe
and put it in her purse.
A necklace our insurance company
has a picture of.
- Jack...
Every word out of his mouth
is a lie.
You must know that.
- Of course,
for our son's sake
I can't take the stand
against Rita.
- No, you wouldn't have to.
If the jeweler recognizes
the necklace from the photo,
that corroborates
Amato's story.
- Done.
- You bastard!
After I cleaned up after
you and that Brazilian whore,
this is how you repay me?
- Just suck it up, Rita.
You know, when I heard
that Whitley was killed,
I knew it had to be her.
She was in heat
for the Boland job.
- You're sick!
- You wanted to be
this big humanitarian
jetting around the globe,
saving the world.
And now look at you--
sad, pathetic.
- Shut up, Donald.
- Jack, he's framing me.
This is what
he's always wanted
so that he could be
with his whores.
- Rita.
- You have no idea
what it's been like
to live like this,
share a bed with him.
- Rita, don't do this
to yourself.
- He owed me.
You owe me!
- When the police
were investigating
Charles Whitley's private life,
they discovered
that his dark world
overlapped yours.
- I doubt that.
I'm not one
of those S&M freaks.
- Well, maybe not,
but you'd be surprised
how often sex workers
migrate between specialties.
High-class escort one month
may be working
in a dungeon the next.
And service people, they love
to gossip about their clients.
- That's old news.
I learned my lesson last year.
- Not well enough it seems.
One thing about people
like you...
you can't stop.
I have names, dates,
and places.
- What do you want?
- Your resignation, Governor,
with your reputation--
such as it is--intact.
Just say you're leaving office
to support your wife
and family in a time
of personal crisis.
- That wasn't the deal.
McCoy said I'd stay in office.
- I'm not Jack McCoy.
- After my wife's arrest
on these tenuous
and politically-motivated
charges,
I find myself torn between
my obligation to my family
and my commitment
to my constituents.
But after speaking
to one of the most
talented minds in the state--
Deputy Attorney General
Joe Chappell--
I realize I need
to put my family first.
I'm resigning as Governor
of the State of New York
effective immediately.
No further questions.
- One last shot at me
before the door slams
behind him.
I'm surprised, though.
- About what?
- Given the chance
to keep his job,
I thought he'd hold on
with both hands.
What'd you say
to him yesterday?
- I...
I told him
that I had this list
of his latest assignations
with prostitutes.
[paper rustles]
- I'm not sure I approve.
- Not sure?
I thought you wanted
to win this election.
- Polls open
in seven hours.
- [sighs]
May we live
to fight another day.
- Here, here.
[clinks]
Subtitles by LeapinLar