[People Laughing, Chattering]
[Man]
Okay, guys. Ready?
- [Woman] Okay.
- # We wish you a merry Christmas #
This is just what I wanted!
Yeah, you like it?
Is that the one?
Good. Good. Merry Christmas.
[Boy]
Oh! The new hockey stick!
- [Dad] Is it a good size?
- It looks fine to me.
Let me see that slap shot. Wait!
Don't knock anything off the table!
I take it that that's a cut, or what?
I am the greatest.
Uh!
[Dad]
Show me what ya got. Ho!
Ho! Hang on one sec.
Ready?
All right. Flip it up. Ooh!
[Mock Groan]
You okay?
[Mom]
Oh. You okay?
[Kiss]
Okay. You're on your own.
[Mom]
Oh, my gosh! Luke!
[Gasps]
Oh, honey!
Whoa!
Watch out for the tree though.
- [Boy] Do a trick.
- [Mom] Do a trick.
- How proud are you of him?
- Oh, my God. He's amazing.
Tell me the truth.
Did Mommy do that painting for you?
Hey. Wow, look at that.
I just got one question.
What the heck is it?
- It is abstract.
- Sorry.
- When I get signed, I'll buy you a new house, okay?
- What's wrong with this house?
Ready?
- [Glass Shatters]
- [Dad] Oh, shit.
Okay, make a wish. Make a-
- So, how old are you, Mom?
We were just wondering.
- How old am I?
[Dad] You look gorgeous.
You don't look a day over-
[Luke]
Just spit it out, Dad.
[Dad] Brendan Hume, you’ve just
won M. V.P. Our golden boy.
[Exhales]
Number one!
Number one. Number one.
- [Dad] Let's get this baby lit.
- [Brendan] Can I slap him? Will he wake up?
- No. No, no, no.
- Please. He's gonna kill us.
- [Brendan] Here's a surprise!
- Surprise!
- Happy birthday, Lukey!
[Lucas]
Fourteen.
It feels no different than yesterday
when I was 13.
Do you want your 14 punches now or-
Uh, a little later, after I wake up.
Get off me! Aw, man!
I almost had you.
# Should old acquaintance be forgot #
#And never brought to mind #
- # Should old acquaintance be forgot #
- [Toots Horn]
# And days of auld lang syne ##
[Woman]
Can you get me those faxes from London?
[People Chattering]
[Man]
All right. Thanks.
Can I bother you?
You know, just when you think
there's no order anywhere...
there's order lookin' right at you.
- Okay.
- What do you need here?
Annie said I need you to approve this.
This guy worked here at Starfish
for six years...
but, uh, his wife's dead,
no kids, no will.
I just wanna roll his pension back up
into the fund and make it easy.
[Sighs] Come on.
Don't make me file with the state.
We file with the state so that, one day,
if somebody looks back at this guy's death...
he will see that we did our job.
You're right.
We gotta cover our asses. I got it. Sorry.
No, no, no. No, we do our job...
and we do right by a guy
who worked for us, lest he die in vain.
What's that "order in the universe" thing?
Well, you- Our insurer spent
300,000 bucks on this new model-
new field data, new society.
Who is the ideal employee?
Who dies how and when?
They sent it over to show
what a great job they're doin'.
And you know what it says?
It says that people with kids
live longer than people with no kids.
People with two live longer
than people with one.
Smoking is bad. Speeding is bad.
Deaths in the family are bad.
Divorce is bad.
It's just kinda nice to see
that all that junk is still true.
- You know?
- Hey, you're the one with the perfect kids.
- [Chuckles]
- Mom, that's not fair.
- Of course it isn't fair.
But when you screw up,
it's embarrassing.
- I'm supposed to be a dean.
- It's not like I killed somebody.
Telling a teacher to shove his laser pointer
up his ass is as close as we get.
The guy's a buffoon, Mom.
I was quoting.
It was, like, an ironic "shove it."
You want an ironic probation?
We haven't even gotten to the home
punishment. This is the school end.
So, what do we do?
- Anything but community service.
- Luke, that's brilliant.
Community service is a great idea.
The assisted living leisure center's
having a dance party. They need help.
For the love of God, Mom.
The seizure center?
Okay.
The hockey team
needs a laundry boy.
You could help your brother out.
Support the team.
I'll take the dance of the dead.
I can man the diaper station.
Last time, okay? Thank you.
Brendan, you're such a kiss ass.
- [TV Playing, Indistinct]
- Hey.
God gave me the skills.
I can't help it.
- Mom, I need to go kill myself.
- Of course you do, Lukey.
- May I be excused?
- No.
I've got a cretin for a brother.
I've got a no-dick for a brother.
Okay! You stop right now.
- You should know better.
- What?
Let's be a family, shall we?
- Can I say no?
- No.
I demand emancipation.
I want a lawyer.
- Okay, I'm filing right- now.
- [Dad] I'm home.
Sorry I'm late. Did I miss dinner?
No, there's plenty.
I'll heat something up for you.
Dad, I need a ride to the city
on Saturday.
Mmm! The city?
Yeah. It's an exchange game.
And, uh, first line again.
- No kidding? That's fantastic.
- Yeah.
- Waldron must love you.
- Yeah, 'cause he's a kiss ass.
Well, good for him. We all goin'?
- No. Lukey's got soccer.
- Yeah, but I'm not starting, so you can just-
Maybe you should just kiss some more ass...
or just not suck so bad.
- I heard that could actually-
- Hey, hey, hey. Huh?
Dad, I was just kidding.
He was just being an idiot.
Don't call him an idiot.
Lucas, you have a loyal and loving brother.
- I agree.
- A loyal, loving kiss ass.
Look, can we just all please-
be civilized for once,
before I kill somebody?
- Whatever, weasel.
- Duh. "Whatever, weasel."
Luke, Luke, Luke. Plate.
- Come here, you little punk.
- Ow! Get off me!
See what you miss
when you don't come home?
Well, at least they're not throwing food.
- [Crowd Cheering]
- ## [Man Singing, Indistinct]
[Dad] You played a heck of a game, kid.
I'm proud of you.
- Heck of a game.
- Thank you.
Love the way you're handling the puck.
Shit.
So, uh, some of the guys have been talkin'
about maybe going to college in Canada.
Canada? Canada is far.
- You still have Lukey.
- Ah, there's a comfort.
Oh, no. Come on. I'm kidding. You get to
kid about your kids, or you lose your mind.
Look, you had a great game.
You've had several great games, but-
Professional hockey? Is that what
we're talking about here, Bren?
- I mean, maybe. I don't know.
- That's a risky business.
And this is coming from your extensive
professional sports background?
No. My extensive risk-assessment
background, thank you very much.
Risks, liabilities- the stuff of life, Son.
No, that's the stuff of your life, Dad.
- Your thrilling life.
- Hey, don't make fun of your father, you bum.
I'm the only one you get.
[Engine Revving]
I guess we can talk to Coach Waldron...
- and we can research schools in Canada-
- Okay.
And find somebody who can educate us
on hockey versus law school.
- Dad, Dad.
- What?
Educate us?
Look, I just wanna play some hockey.
Hey. Lights.
Dad. So, what do you say?
- L- I said we could look into it, all right?
- Okay.
- Please don't tell your mother.
- I would never.
[Tires Screeching]
Where the heck is the darn expressway?
[Bell Chiming]
Oh, great.
- Hey, where do you think you're goin'?
- I need my fluids, Dad.
Oh, yeah.
The obligatory slushee stop.
- They have 'em in there, right?
- That or something worse for you.
- Do you have money?
- Yeah.
- Well, quick in and out, 'cause we gotta get home.
- All right.
Hey, honey, it's me.
I just wanted to let you know...
that our son is going to Canada
to play hockey.
He didn't want any kind of long, drawn-out
good-bye, so I dropped him off at the airport.
He says he'll call, but-
[Chuckles]
Of course, we may never
see our son again.
But as long as he's happy, right?
Okay.
- I love you, and we'll be home soon.
- [Man] Bullshit, man!
[Men Chattering, Shouting]
- [Shotgun Cocks]
- Get the fuck down,
or I'll blow your fuckin' head off!
Get the fuck down!
No! This is your man!
This is your man!
He's goin' for his gun, Billy!
[Man]
Come on, Bulldog!
[Tires Screeching]
[Grunts]
Get this mother! Get your guy!
Do this, or you're not one of us!
Do it!
Hey. You can do this.
- Kill that motherfucker, Joey.
- [Shouts]
That's my boy.
- Let's go! Let's go! Give me the gun!
- What about Joey?
- Come on! Let's go!
- [Tires Screeching]
Fuck!
[Groans]
Fuck you!
- Motherfucker-
- [Horn Honking]
Brendan! Brendan!
[Gasping, Gurgling]
Help! Help me!
Somebody help me!
[Brendan Gasping]
Help!
Where's Joe?
He's a man now.
He can take the subway.
[All Laughing]
Can we get some help?
Could somebody help us, please?
- Please! He's been- He's hurting!
- Doctor!
He was cut. Somebody cut him.
Get an airway open! Create an airway!
- He's my son. That's my son.
- Maggie, get him. Get him.
- Brendan, we're in the hospital now.
- Sir, you need to stay back here.
- We'll get Maggie to take care of you here.
- They'll get you fixed up now.
Sir, I'm sorry.
You need to stay right here.
- Why can't-
- The doctors need to do their job, sir.
- You need to stay back here.
- I can't go in there?
I'm sorry.
Okay. Well, he'll be okay, right?
That's my-That's my-That's my son.
His name's Brendan.
[Whimpers]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Five.
Number Five.
[Woman]
That's Joe Darley.
He's... a kid.
He's a runt, almost 23.
And he's an animal.
[No Audible Dialogue]
They're supposed to
have some kind of a, uh...
pretrial hearing tomorrow, and...
they want me to go and make a statement.
You wanna go with me?
You go.
Put that... animal in jail.
That's what the cops called him-
animal.
Are you gonna take that off?
The school said they wanted
to do a memorial.
At the next game, the team
wanted to do something.
That's nice of them.
[Crying]
He would have liked-
- [Sobbing]
- ## [Woman Singing Ballad]
- ## [Continues]
- [Door Creaks]
- [Crying]
- ## [Continues]
## [Ends]
[Man] Today's easy. I need you to
sit there, put the fear of God in this guy.
If the judge asks you, you tell him what
you told us and identify Darley in court.
Okay? The minute I get your statement,
and with you sitting right there...
the public defender's
gonna wet his pants and fold.
I'll make a deal in five minutes,
get this guy in jail today. Easy peasy.
Deal? Wait, wait.
Hang on. What do you mean?
What-What deal?
I want this guy to go away
for the rest of his life.
No. I can get you
three to five guaranteed.
That's a very decent result.
I'm talking guaranteed time.
Not maybe,
not the jury didn't feel up to it.
That's worth more than chasing some
make-believe 10 to life, and the guy walks free.
- You want that?
- He killed my son.
Mr. Hume,
I've got one eyewitness-you.
That's nice, but do you know
how many cases with one witness...
I don't even bother to try for a deal on?
The machete magically disappeared.
The only blood we could find on that weasel
was his own from when the car clipped him.
And you picked
the only gas station in America...
without a working surveillance camera.
We've just got your word. That's not bad,
if I can scare the guy into a deal.
You're using my son's death
like some kinda card trick.
Look- [Chuckles]
I get a banger off the street.
Ayear or so,
somebody does my job for me.
He doesn't get out of there alive-
fine with me.
He finds Jesus- fine with me.
But we get religion and go to trial-
as much as I'd love to-
and the defense starts working on...
when was your last eye exam and what
do you have against inner city youth?
And how unfair it is for them
to grow up so violent...
how they're forced into initiation killings
or face execution themselves.
Do you want a jury feeling sorry
for this fucker? Huh?
- You want him to walk?
- Wait. You said... initiation killing.
L-l- I thought this was a robbery.
It only looked like one.
It was an initiation. You kill someone
at random to get made in a gang.
It's the price of admission.
Are you saying that Brendan was killed...
so that some asshole
could feel more like a man?
So that he could be in some club?
[Sighs]
This is a "take it or leave it" thing,
I'm sorry to say.
[Prosecutor] Your Honor, I'd like
to enter the statement of a witness...
present at the time of the attack-
father of the victim.
We can enter that at trial,
can we not, Mr. Barring?
I believe, Your Honor,
if we enter it today...
defense will change their plea to guilty.
Save the People
the time and expense of a trial.
- [Judge] That's the statement?
- [Paper Rustles]
[Judge]
Mr. Hume.
You're giving evidence that
Mr. Darley here, before your eyes...
attacked your son
and caused his death?
You're saying you'll
testify to that in a trial?
No, Your Honor, I am not.
What?
It was... dark.
There were a lot of them.
I can't be sure anymore.
Mr. Barring, do you expect to obtain
evidence other than Mr. Hume's here?
No, Your Honor, I do not.
I'm dismissing this case. Mr. Darley,
you are released from custody.
You may return with a bailiff
to the holding cells...
to retrieve your personal effects.
[Siren Wailing In Distance]
[Engine Rumbling]
Joey!
[Hooting]
[All Chattering, Hooting]
You beat that shit!
- Whoo!
- Yeah! You did it!
[Laughing, Chattering Continue]
You scared that mother
pretty fuckin' bad.
I'm proud of you.
Who's a man now?
- [Engine Starts]
- Get in the car.
- [Engines Rumbling]
- [Chattering, Shouting]
[Engines Revving, Tires Screeching]
[Chattering]
[Laughing, Chattering]
- ## [Car Stereo: Hip-hop]
- Have a nice, fun time with this one here.
- All right, bro. Okay.
- All right?
I'm proud of you. All right?
## [Continues, Muffled]
[Shouting, Laughing]
[Lucas]
Dad?
Hey.
- What are you doin'?
- Nothing.
What are you doin'?
Don't play with that. Put it down.
So, uh-
It was like, uh, a gas station?
Where Bren got killed.
Yeah, it was-
it was a gas station.
Why do you wanna know?
Um, I just, uh-
You know,
I wondered where he died.
Yeah.
It was, uh, a Stop Spot in Rockside.
Oh.
Do you... think he was scared?
Yeah, Luke. I do.
I think he was scared.
- How did it go?
- They let him go.
- They did what? Why?
- I don't think it was him.
Well, but you said it was him.
You said they had him.
- Are they gonna keep looking?
- Yeah. That's a good one.
- [Sighs] Oh, Jesus!
- I'm sorry. What do you want me to do?
I'm sorry.
I left something at the office.
- L-I gotta go back.
- Now?
- Nick.
- I'll be home as soon as I can.
- [Car Engine Starts]
- [Door Slams]
Oh, God. What am I doin'?
[Bell Chiming, Engine Starts]
[Objects Clattering]
[Bell Chiming]
[Door Slams, Chiming Stops]
Piece of shit!
Fuck.
Jesus!
Fuck, man.
You fuckin' scared the shit-
Wait a minute.
You fu-fucking kiddin' me?
You?
[Shouts]
[Grunting]
Fuck! Fuck!
Aw, fuck!
[Grunting]
[Groans]
[Gasping]
Fu- Fu-
Oh, God.
[Gasping]
[Whimpering]
Oh! Fuck. Fuck.
[Water Splashes]
[Chattering On Video]
I've been meaning to do this for months.
It's very grown up of you to help.
- [Door Shuts]
- Yeah.
- Hi, guys.
- Hi.
- What happened?
- I slipped in the... driveway.
Honey? Oh, my God. Look at you.
- You're a mess.
- It's noth- It's okay. I cut my hand.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- It's okay.
- No, it's not okay.
- I'm gonna take a shower.
- I'm gonna get bandages. I'll bring them up.
- [Family On Video]... 13, 12, 11...
- [Mom On Video] Honey, hurry.
- 10, nine, eight-
- How you doin', kid? You okay?
- Five, four, three, two, one!
- I'm okay, I guess.
[Video Continues]
Happy New Year! Happy New Year!
Good. That's good.
I'm gonna take a shower.
[Lucas On Video]
How sweet.
[Nick] Brendan Hume,
you’ve just won M. V.P.
- [Lucas Exclaiming]
- What do you have to say for yourself?
[Brendan] Can I take this already?
Can I take the kiss?
Number one! Number one!
Brendan Hume, our golden boy.
[Exhales]
[Crying]
[Sobbing]
Honey.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
- It's okay.
I'm so sorry.
[Sobbing]
It's okay.
## [Man Singing Rock]
[Growling, Barking]
- [Man] Yo, Billy.
- ## [Continues]
## [Continues]
Watch the fucking pieces!
For Christ's sake, they're
worth something- unlike you.
Where you been, Nazi?
- What the fuck you call that?
- That's our night.
When I take pity on you
and your faggot half-wit friends-
give you a couple of corners to run-
you better deliver for me...
or I'll know you've been stealing
and I'll kill you.
You be the prince of Pian...
you fuckin' light-bag me,
I'll fuckin' kill you.
Lord knows I've been patient.
- [Coughs]
- [Chair Squeaks]
Yes.
You can get the fuck
out of my sight now.
## [Continues]
Fuckin' half-wit.
[Engine Rumbling]
What? What?
Somebody fuckin' tell me
what the fuck is goin' on.
You hear?
Joe, dude.
Somebody stuck him.
He's dead.
What?
You're lyin'.
Man, he's gone.
[Clatters]
Hey.
How you guys faring?
You, uh, gettin' through?
Yeah, we're okay.
You find compensations.
That's what we do, right?
We compensate for our losses,
move on.
If anything like that
ever happened to me, I'd just-
I don't know. I think I'd snap.
Well, you really don't know
what you'd do until it happens.
- Surprise yourself.
- [Woman] Excuse me, Nick.
Detective Wallis is here to see you.
Yeah. Come on in.
I, uh-
I'm sorry to break in on your day.
No, it's fine.
Uh, the guy we thought killed your son-
Somebody killed him.
Oh.
- Oh, what was that- some kind of a gang thing?
- We think so.
- Man, I guess there is justice, huh?
- Yeah, I suppose there is.
I thought you'd like to know.
If he was the guy, I mean.
Yes. Well, thanks-
thanks for letting me know.
Uh, all right,
I'll- I'll leave you to it then.
I guess I don't need
to say anything, Nick...
but the company would pay for counseling
if you guys want it.
We'll manage.
- Thanks, Owen.
- Okay.
[Man] He didn't deserve that.
No way he deserved that.
He was a true fuckin' soldier.
To Joe.
He was a good fuckin' boy.
- A good fuckin' boy!
- Yeah!
So that's what we're gonna do?
Why don't you show
a little fuckin' respect, at least?
See, that is why you guys are nothin'.
That is why you're a bunch
of fuckin' punks-
because you would rather drink up...
and toke yourselves fuckin' witless.
Witless and scared shitless!
[Sniffs]
No. My bad.
Let's- Here, cheers.
Get your fuckin' glasses up!
All of you!
## [Man Singing Rock]
Joe wasn't made for this shit.
That's all.
- He wasn't like us.
- No, wasn't like you, you mean.
He was not like you!
He was better than you!
We as good as brothers since we was kids,
and you fuckin' go this way!
What, I'm not as good as you now?
Joe was like blood to me, dog.
As good as fuckin' blood.
You too!
## [Continues]
- ## [Continues]
- Well-
I would like to catch
the motherfucker that did this.
- Oh, we will.
- Ain't no motherfuckin' doubt.
Do the right fuckin' thing by Joe, yeah?
- So who fuckin' did it?
- It wasn't the Cutty Macks, man.
I would know about it.
- Unless you were high.
- I'm not high.
Wasn't "B" Street, Billy.
Wasn't the Hall.
Wasn't any of those assholes.
Yo, my sister said she saw some fucker
in a suit down there just chillin'.
How many fuckers in a suit
you ever see at Stokely-fucking-Hall?
See, here's a comical thing.
When one of us gets killed,
we don't make the paper.
But the son of a senior V.P.
Of Starfish Capital-
whoo-wee!
Go talk to your sister.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Tapping]
Hey. Amy, what's up?
I'm going home.
You okay? You need anything?
No, I'm fine.
I'm just gonna finish this risk analysis.
Uh, actually, could you drop this off
with Owen, please, on your way out?
- Sure.
- Thank you. Good night.
[Siren Wailing]
[Register Beeping]
- [Woman Screams]
- [Man] What'd he do?
- Oh, my God!
- [Horn Honking]
- [People Screaming, Shouting]
- [Tires Screeching]
[Man]
Come on! Let's go!
[People Screaming, Shouting]
[Panting]
[Siren Wailing]
Get in there! Come on!
Come on! Get him, get him, get him!
[Panting]
Bust his ass!
- Through here! Go!
- Go, go, go, go, go!
[Grunts]
Get in there! Go! Go!
[Panting, Grunting]
- Go! Go! Go!
- Come on!
[Grunting, Gasping]
- [Whooping]
- [Grunts]
[Whooping, Shouting]
You're fuckin' dead!
Come on!
- [Pounding]
- Open the door! Open the door!
Hey, hey, hey. Which way is 1801?
[Shouting, Grunting]
- 1801 Main! Which way? Which way?
- Through the corridor right there.
- Go, go!
- [Woman Shouting]
Where the fuck did he go?
Heco, Dog, Spink!
Go! Cut 'Im off! Cut 'Im off!
Look! Look!
[Panting]
- [Car Alarm Wailing]
- Oh, shit!
[Panting]
[Grunting]
[Alarm Blaring, Horn Honking]
- [Second Alarm Wailing]
- [Blaring, Honking]
[Alarms Overlapping]
[Gasping, Panting]
[Grunts]
[Alarm Wailing]
- Did you talk to Sally?
- Yeah.
Search floor to floor!
Move your ass! Search the floor!
- [Woman Whimpering]
- Tommy! Door!
Jamie! Get your ugly ass up there!
Ain't gonna make
a fool out of me, motherfucker.
[Car Alarms Continue Blaring]
[Panting]
[Gasps, Panting]
[Door Slams]
[Gasping]
[Panting]
[Car Alarm Chirps]
[Grunting, Groaning]
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
[Shouts]