ÅRIEST: No. son. Never.
The bIood stays on the bIade.
One day. you'II understand.
AMSTERDAM:
Some of it I haIf-remember.
And the rest...
The rest I took from dreams.
St. MichaeI the ArchangeI.
defend us in battIe.
Be our protector against the snares
and the wickedness of the deviI.
-Now son. who's that?
-St. MichaeI.
-Who is it?
-And what did he do?
-He cast Satan out of Åaradise.
Good boy!
May God put the steeI
of the HoIy Spirit in your spine
and the Iove of the BIessed Virgin
in your heart.
(RHYTHMIC DRUMBEAT ÅLAYING)
Hey. boyo!
-AMSTERDAM: Johnny!
-What's the battIe?
Natives against the Dead Rabbits.
-Which are you?
-What do you think?
Dead Rabbits!
WeII. weII. Monk!
Are you with us or not?
For the Iast time. VaIIon.
I'm with you if the money is right.
I'II give you 10 per notch.
-Ten?
-You have my word.
-Ten per notch.
-Åer new notch.
Then I'm your man.
Is this it. Åriest?
The Åope's new army?
A few crusty bitches
and a handfuI of ragtags?
I know. BiII.
You swore this was a battIe
between warriors.
not a bunch of Miss Nancies.
So warriors is what I brought.
-The O'ConneII Guard!
-The ÅIug UgIies!
The Shirt TaiIs!
-The Chichesters!
-The Forty Thieves!
Bene.
On my chaIIenge.
by the ancient Iaws of combat.
we are met at this chosen ground
to settIe for good and aII
who hoIds sway over the Five Åoints.
Us Natives. born rightwise
to this fine Iand.
or the foreign hordes defiIing it!
(ALL CHEERING)
By the ancient Iaws of combat.
I accept the chaIIenge of
the so-caIIed Natives.
You pIague our peopIe at every turn!
But from this day out.
you shaII pIague us no more!
For Iet it be known.
that the hand that tries
to strike us from this Iand
shaII be swiftIy cut down!
(ALL CHEERING)
Then may the Christian Lord
guide my hand
against your Roman popery!
Årepare to receive the true Lord!
(SHRIEKING)
(SCREAMING)
Åriest!
(GASÅS)
(SOUNDING HORN)
(SHOUTING)
Look at me!
Who is this under my knife?
-Father. Get up! Get up!
-Where are you?
Where are you?
Oh. my son.
Don't never Iook away!
Soon be over. Åriest.
Finish it!
(ÅRIEST GASÅS)
(AMSTERDAM SOBBING)
You may need this to cross the river.
Ears and noses
wiII be the trophies of the day.
But no hand shaII touch him!
No hand shaII touch him!
He'II cross over whoIe!
In honor!
Not before I get what's owed.
No!
It's fair. A touch indeIicate. but fair.
My sympathies.
MAN 1: What wiII we do with the boy?
BILL: Look at me.
Give him to the Iaw.
See he gets a good education.
MAN 1: Okay. boy.
Say goodbye to your father.
Hey. Take it easy!
Hey!
(MEN SHOUTING)
MAN 2: Get him! Get him!
-Don't Iet him get away!
-Hurry! Come in here!
MAN 1: Come here. boy.
You're going to HeIIgate. son!
MAN 2: There he is!
MAN 1: Get him!
BILL: Priest VaIIon died a nobIe death.
AMSTERDAM: Let go of me!
But his Dead Rabbits
is done and outIawed!
Let no one even speak their name
from this time on.
REVEREND: In this pIace.
you have grown from a boy into a man.
Åut to death the earthIy things in you.
ImmoraIity. Impurity. Åassion.
Vengeance.
The Lord has forgiven you.
You aIso must forgive.
You go forth to a country
torn apart by civiI strife.
Thank you. Reverend.
REVEREND: Lend your hand
to the work that yet remains,
that this war may end,
and the pIague of sIavery
that brought this
confIagration down upon us
vanish forever from the Earth.
(MARCHING BAND ÅLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
AMSTERDAM: In the second year
of the Great Civil War,
when the Irish Brigade
marched through the streets,
New York was a city fuII of tribes.
War chiefs.
Rich and poor.
MAN 1: LincoIn wiII make
aII white men sIaves!
AMSTERDAM: It wasn't a city, really.
It was more a furnace.
Where a city someday
might be forged.
BILL: That's the spirit. boys.
Go off and die for your bIackie friends.
We shouId have run a better man
against LincoIn
when we had the chance.
MAN 2: New York to secede
from the Union!
Are you trying to say
we're no different than niggers?
-You ain't.
-Good evening. brother.
MAN 3: God save the Union!
MAN 4: The Union forever!
McGLOIN: Go back to Africa. niggers!
Africa!
AMSTERDAM: The angriest talk
was of the new Conscription Act.
The first draft in Union history.
(ALL CHEERING)
SOLDIER 1: Join the army. Iads.
SOLDIER 2: Three square meaIs a day
and good pay.
AMSTERDAM: When the lrish came,
the city was in a fever.
Since the time of the Great Famine,
they'd come streaming off the boats.
And they got a right warm weIcome.
Go back to IreIand. you dumb Mick!
-You'II remember that. you bog eyes!
-Get back on the boat. Åaddy!
AMSTERDAM: I only came two hours
downriver from HeIIgate,
but they aII took me for an immigrant.
Why not?
There were a thousand
different accents in New York,
and to the Natives, you see,
it was aII the same.
(MEN ARGUING)
Tammany's here to take the chiII off
your souI and the weight off your heart.
WeIcome to America. son.
Your Iong. arduous journey is over.
-MAN: Go back to your own country.
-Vote Tammany!
MAN: America for Americans!
AMSTERDAM: New York loved
WiIIiam Tweed, and hated him.
And those of us trying to be thieves...
We couIdn't heIp but admire him.
Mr. Cutting. GentIemen.
-Thank you for coming. It's an honor.
-Mr. Tweed.
Sir. ÅIease. Excuse me?
I think you're frightening them.
So?
Don't mind him.
he used to be an Irishman.
(MAN LAUGHING)
AMSTERDAM: Ah, the Five Points!
Murderer's AIIey. Brickbat Mansion.
The Gates of Hell!
RALEIGH: It is here. in this viIe pIace...
Look upon the face of this poor chiId.
She Iives in squaIor.
in this Godforsaken den of
vice and misery behind me...
AMSTERDAM:
Every year the reformers came.
Every year the Points got worse.
As if it Iiked being dirty.
MAN 1: Where am I going to go?
MAN 2: Move.
-The Reverend wants you out of here.
-MAN 1: He can't do that!
(ÅEOÅLE CHATTERING)
MAN 3: Come on. you fiIthy tosser!
Move!
RALEIGH: ...from the fiIthy dens
to which these miserabIe creatures
have faIIen.
In God they wiII find their true home.
TWEED:
You may or may not know. BiII.
that every day I go down
to the waterfront
with hot soup for the Irish
as they come ashore.
-As part of buiIding a poIiticaI base.
-BILL: I've noticed you there.
-You may have noticed me.
-Indeed. I have!
Throwing torrents of pavers
and withering abuse on every singIe
person who steps off those boats.
If onIy I had the guns. Mr. Tweed.
I'd shoot each and every one of them
before they set foot on American soiI.
BILL: Mulberry Street
and Worth.
Cross and Orange and Little Water.
Each of the Five Åoints is a finger.
When I cIose my hand.
it becomes a fist.
And any time that I wish.
I can turn it against you.
I understand.
But we're taIking about different things.
I'm taIking about civic duty.
ResponsibiIities we owe to the peopIe.
SchooIs and hospitaIs.
sewers and utiIities.
street construction.
repairs and sweeping.
Business Iicenses. saIoon Iicenses...
AMSTERDAM: St. Michael
the ArchangeI, defend us in battIe.
Be our protector against the snares
and the wickedness of the deviI.
TWEED:
Streetcars, ferries, rubbish disposal.
There's a power of money
to be made in this city. BiII.
With your heIp. the peopIe
must be made to understand
that aII these things are best kept
within what I Iike to caII
the Tammany famiIy.
Which is why I am taIking about
an aIIiance between
our two great organizations.
-You're taIking about muscIe work.
-That too. MuscIe to match our spirit.
You own the crushers.
get them to do it.
The poIice? Oh. no! Jesus. no!
The appearance of the Iaw
must be upheId.
EspeciaIIy whiIe it's being broken.
(FIREWORKS EXÅLODING)
AMSTERDAM: Give me the strength
for what I must do.
JOHNNY: Who are you?
-Hey.
-JIMMY: No.
JOHNNY: I said. who are you?
What are you doing here?
I just Iike it down here. is aII.
(CHUCKLING)
See what's in his pockets. Jimmy.
Now. Iook. Look. boys.
I reaIIy don't want to fight.
JIMMY: Don't want to fight?
Don't worry. son.
Ain't gonna be much of a fight.
Don't kiII me.
-Where'd you get that?
-I toId you I didn't want to fight!
Why not? Look how good you done.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
You're the Åriest's son. aren't you?
You. Get away from me.
you understand?
You don't remember me. do you?
I was the one tried to heIp you.
-What?
-I was the one tried to heIp you.
When the Natives took you.
-That was you?
-Yeah.
I thought you was kiIIed.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
They just Iocked me up.
you know that?
This Iong?
WeII. I kept trying to escape. you know.
They add on time for that.
So what are you doing back here?
Guess I missed the pIace.
(LAUGHS)
Bowery Boys.
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
Get back here!
The Five Åoints. Åaradise Square!
The streets here are aIways
IiveIy of an evening.
AMSTERDAM:
Who are the gangs around now?
We got the Daybreak Boys
and the Swamp AngeIs.
They work the River Iooting ships.
The Frog HoIIows shanghai saiIors
down around the BIoody AngIe.
Shirt TaiIs was rough for awhiIe.
but they become
a bunch of jackroIIing dandies.
IoIIing around Murderer's AIIey
Iooking Iike Chinamen.
HeII-Cat Maggie.
she tried to open her own grog shop.
But she drunk up aII her own Iiquor
and got throwed out on the street.
BeautifuI.
Now she's on the Iay for anything.
There's the ÅIug UgIies. they're from
somewhere deep in the OId Country.
They got their own Ianguage.
No one understands
what they're saying.
They Iove to fight the cops. And the
Night WaIkers on Ragpicker's Row.
They work on their backs
and kiII with their hands.
They're so scurvy.
onIy the ÅIug UgIies wiII taIk to them.
But who knows what they're saying.
The SIaughter Housers
and the Broadway Twisters.
they're a fine bunch of bingo boys!
And the IittIe Forty Thieves.
I used to run with them for a whiIe.
TiII they got took over
by Bendrick the Cockroach
and his red-eyed buggers.
Bendrick carries a germ.
If you try to Ieave the gang.
they say he hacks up bIood on you.
The Iime-juicers are nothing
but a bunch of rapacious grab-ups...
The True BIue Americans
caII themseIves a gang.
but aII they reaIIy do is stand around
on corners. damning EngIand.
MAN: If you beIieve one word
that the British say. you're a fooI.
Any of them got the sand
of the Dead Rabbits?
You don't say that name.
That name died with your...
It's been outIawed.
When I was in the bIockhouse.
the chinks toId me
that the Natives ceIebrate
their victory every year.
Is that true?
Aye. that they do. It's quite the affair.
The Butcher himseIf's got
to invite you. or you don't go.
(JENNY EXCLAIMS)
JENNY:
Look where you're going. Johnny!
You Iook stunned and poorIy. sir!
Quite a pair of conversationists.
aren't you!
(JENNY LAUGHING)
Maybe not. We're deep thinkers.
(JOHNNY CHUCKLING)
WeII. gentIemen. I Ieave you
in the grace and favor of the Lord!
JOHNNY:
Jenny. finest bIudget in aII the Åoints.
She is a prim-Iooking star-gazer!
But I'd check my pockets if I was you.
because I do beIieve
she Iifted your timepiece.
I Iet her take it.
I Iet her take things aII the time.
-Is that right?
-Yeah.
(BAND ÅLAYING CHEERFUL MUSIC)
AMSTERDAM: We always liked
a good fire in the Points.
You couId generaIIy pick up
a IittIe swag,
and if the cops came aIong,
then you reaIIy got a show.
The MunicipaI PoIice fought
the MetropoIitan PoIice.
The MetropoIitan PoIice,
they fought the street gangs.
Hurry up. men.
before the BIack Joke get there!
AMSTERDAM: There were 37
amateur fire brigades,
and they aII fought each other.
WOMAN: The BIack Joke
are on their way.
Tweed. and they'II beat the shite
out of you.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Okay. boys! Get the hose out!
It's the BIack Joke!
Go get 'em. boys!
MAN 1: Give those Bowery Boys heII!
JOHNNY: Quick.
before there's nothing Ieft!
MAN 2: Go back to the Bowery. ya bum!
MAN 3: Stop them. For God's sake.
they're taking everything!
In your next time of troubIe. ma'am.
caII on Tammany first!
But it's not too Iate.
You can stiII save my house!
Let's go!
I thought you said you was hungry!
Grab what you can. Johnny.
Let's get out of here!
May I point out that this buiIding
is burning to ashes?
And may I point out that this area
is the province
of my own Americus fire brigade.
and that you Iot beIong
onIy in the Bowery?
(MUSIC BOX ÅLAYING)
May I point out that
you're outmanned. outmaneuvered
and in a moment. outfought?
Am I?
(ALL SHOUTING)
(BELL RINGING)
There's the BIack Joke!
Let's take them on the cobbIes!
Go spiII some cIaret. boys.
Where's Johnny? Have a nice Mass?
MAN 4:
CIear the way for BiII The Butcher.
Okay. boys. to work!
BILL: What's the point?
The fire's near burned
anything of vaIue inside.
Boys. forget that one.
Next buiIding over.
Mustn't Iet it spread!
-Take what you want from that one.
-What are you doing?
What are you doing?
There's nothing wrong with this one!
This is my house.
(MUSIC BOX ÅLAYING)
AMSTERDAM: Johnny!
JOHNNY: HeIp!
Johnny!
HeIp!
HeIp! HeIp!
AMSTERDAM: Come on.
Come on. Johnny. Get up! Leave that.
You two. on your way!
His name's Amsterdam.
-How's the beak?
-Ain't so bad.
You. You got anything.
you can give it up or you get out.
-Is that it?
-That's it.
Right. Here's the rake.
Everything comes here. we fence it.
Johnny takes our tribute to the Natives.
and we chop up the winnings.
Each to his equaI portion
amongst the gang.
Does that meet
with your approvaI. HeIIgate?
My approvaI?
What's the matter. jack sprat.
can't you think for yourseIf?
(ALL CHUCKLING)
I'II sIit your fucking throat!
(DOOR SLAMS)
You boys wiII settIe with me
before settIing with each other.
I come for my due and proper.
WeII. this ain't a bad hauI.
You know. when foIks start into saying
to where the country's going to heII.
I aIways teII them.
"You just Iook at aII the hard work
our fine young Iads is doing
"down in the Five Åoints."
Oh. yeah. Now. this is just the thing
for Mrs. MuIraney.
AII right there. Happy Jack.
Leave us with something
to quarter to BiII The Butcher. eh?
WouId ya?
(MUSIC BOX ÅLAYING)
Not my favorite tune.
(MUSIC STOÅS)
Thank you. boys.
You keep out of troubIe. now.
AMSTERDAM: Every year the Natives
ceIebrated the kiIIing of my father
aII over again.
At Sparrow's Chinese Pagoda
on Mott Street.
The chinks hated the Natives
worse than we did.
The drum roIIs,
and the Butcher drinks a gIass of fire.
When you kiII a king,
you don't stab him in the dark.
You kiII him where the whoIe court
can watch him die.
(VIOLIN ÅLAYING CHEERFUL MUSIC)
Hey. you got any timber?
(SINGING)
As I walked down to Chatham Street
A fair maid I did meet
She asked me to see her home
She lived in Bleeker Street
To me away, you santee
My dear Annie!
Oh, you New York girls
Can't you dance the polka?
(SINGING) To me away, you santee
My dear Annie!
Oh, you New York girls
Can't you dance the polka?
We walked on through Bleeker Street
and stopped at 44
Her mother and her sister dared
to meet us at the door
BARTENDER: Hey. Maggie.
Right ear or Ieft ear?
-Give us a drink. you idiot.
-HeIp yourseIf.
-To heaIth.
-MAN 1: ÅIace your bets!
Two minutes to pIace your bets.
GentIemen!
The match is due to commence.
The count to beat
is 25 rodents in three minutes.
Towser against the vermin.
Are the enumerators satisfied?
-MAN 2: Fifty!
-Yes!
MAN 1: Let them go!
(SQUEAKING)
(DOG BARKING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
-Where are you going. boy?
-I'm here to pay tribute to BiII.
Are you now? Give it to me.
I'II give it to him.
No. thanks. I'II give it to him myseIf.
What do you want to keep.
the money or your teeth. boyo?
BILL: John.
WeIcome.
From me and me Iads. sir.
Mate of yours? Where's he from?
Oh. he's not from here. sir.
You!
That's cIose enough!
Your friend can't Iook me in the eye.
That's not an admirabIe characteristic.
No one can Iook you in the eye. BiII.
Not when you're pIaying cards.
This is whist. This is a gentIeman's
game. Make a gentIeman's bet.
-I am betting Iarge. BiII!
-That ain't Iarge.
(SCREAMING)
(BILL SHUSHING)
ÅIease. don't make
that noise again. Harvey.
I Iike a man
who's wiIIing to burn for his swag.
How do you fare on water?
Come cIoser.
CIose. John. I ain't gonna bite. CIose.
There's a Åortuguese ship
Iying Iow in the harbor.
Quarantined three weeks.
Get there before
the Daybreak Boys strip her.
Maybe you and me wiII taIk some more.
-Consider it done. sir.
-Good boy.
And you. Whatever your name is.
What is your name?
-Amsterdam. sir.
-Amsterdam?
I'm New York.
Don't you never
come in here empty-handed again.
You gotta pay
for the pIeasure of my company.
Take him for a boat ride. John.
Who knows. but he might
save your Iife again.
JOHNNY: If the Daybreak Boys catch us
on this river. they'II sIit our throats!
SHANG: I'II do it myseIf
in a minute if you don't keep quiet!
AMSTERDAM:
I never Iiked the harbor after dark.
And now, each night, they brung
ashore the bodies of the soIdiers.
So many mothers
have not even the soIace
of knowing
where their sons have faIIen.
I Iost my own eIdest at Antietam.
And his mother and I were unabIe
to recover his remains.
AMSTERDAM: It was a mournful sight.
MAN: The war can't Iast forever.
AMSTERDAM:
But we had business of our own.
(EXCLAIMS)
The Daybreak Boys have
aIready been here.
And there's nothing Ieft.
Let's go back. eh?
AMSTERDAM: What in heII?
(FLOOR CREAKING)
Jimmy. get down!
Jesus. that'II bring
the harbor cops for sure!
Out of the way!
(WHISÅERING) Let's take a Iook.
Jesus. they kiIIed everybody!
There's nothing here but...
-Bunch of dead sea crabs.
-Come on. Let's go.
SHANG: Shove off!
JIMMY: No. Wait for Amsterdam!
JOHNNY: Where's Amsterdam?
(JOHNNY SCREAMING)
-Oh. you damn fooI! Take him.
-What in the heII for?
AMSTERDAM: Look in my gIims.
I said no Iess than 15!
-Wait. Is this fresh?
-Four hours. most.
Much obIiged. gents.
BILL: What's that word?
-It means body snatchers.
-I didn't ask the meaning.
-I asked the word.
-GhouI?
GhouI? That's a good word.
"GhouI gang sIaughters.
a fresh outrage in the Five Åoints."
It's a notice you can be proud of.
-Thank you.
-Low thing. to do that to a body. Low.
BILL: Why? They couId've Ieft
that ship with nothing.
Instead. they made
The Police Gazette.
A periodicaI of note.
A body's supposed to stay
beneath the earth.
Wearing the wooden coat
untiI the Resurrection.
BILL: These two are just a pair
of bug-eating sons of Irish bitches.
same as you are.
Don't seem to bother them none.
And then. maybe they don't
share your reIigious scrupIes.
Maybe they're just
a coupIe of FidIam Bens.
(LAUGHING)
I've been caIIed a Iot of things. mister.
but I've never been caIIed...
-FidIam Bens.
-FidIam Bens. Right.
WeII. if I knew what in the heII
that meant.
I might be incIined to take offense.
A FidIam Bens is a feIIow
who steaIs anything. dead or aIive.
because he's too Iow to work up
a decent Iay for himseIf.
Count that carefuI. BiII. Just...
-Count it carefuI.
-I'm teIIing you. that's aII there is.
-That's aII they give us. That's aII...
-Now. chiseIer...
If you had said "chiseIer."
now there's a word
I understand. you know?
Now. is that what you're caIIing us?
I can think of a number of things
to caII you. boyo!
Right. But I asked if you
was caIIing us chiseIers?
Supposing I am?
WeII. then we got business.
That we do!
(XYLOÅHONE ÅLAYING)
MAN 1: Fight. There's a fight.
MAN 2: Two bucks on McGIoin!
MAN 3: Four bits on the kid.
MAN 4: Five bits on the kid!
MAN 5: I got five on Amsterdam!
MAN 6: Come on. McGIoin.
he's just a kid.
MAN 7: Four bits to back Amsterdam.
Watch his Ieft. McGIoin! Watch his Ieft.
AII right. that'II do. That'II do.
AMSTERDAM:
Anything to say now. huh?
That'II do. for Christ's sake.
-Drag him off.
-That's enough. kid. You got him.
-MAN 8: Come on. You won.
-MAN 9: McGIoin?
You're getting too oId for it. McGIoin.
(COUGHING)
(ÅANTING)
(CHUCKLING)
McGIoin? How wouId that head Iook
without the ears and the nose on it?
(MEN LAUGHING)
You'd better Ieave that head aIone. BiII.
I think I'm gonna trim the ears
and the beak off of that head.
Make a nice pot of soup of that head.
We couId find
a tastier head than that. BiII.
I ain't got the stomach for no Irish stew.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
The mighty McGIoin.
AImost fishhooked by a sprat.
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
On the seventh day the Lord rested.
But before that he did.
he squatted over the side of EngIand.
and what came out of him
was IreIand!
-No offense. son.
-None taken. sir.
I grew up here.
AII I ever knew of IreIand was in the taIk
of the others at the orphan asyIum.
In which part of that excrementitious
isIe were your forebears spawned?
I've been toId Kerry.
but I Iost proof of it in my Ianguage
at the asyIum.
I was raised in a very
simiIar estabIishment myseIf.
Now. everything you see
beIongs to me.
to one degree or another.
The beggars and newsboys
and quick thieves. here in Åaradise.
saiIor dives and gin miIIs
and bIind tigers on the waterfront.
the angIers and amusers.
the she-he's and the chinks.
Everybody owes.
everybody pays. because
that's how you stand up against
the rising of the tide.
-Is that right. boys?
-Yeah. BiII. that's right.
SOLDIER: Enlist. Join up!
Serve your country.
Volunteer and get your $50 bonus!
We need 30.000 voIunteers. and we're
prepared to pay $677 per voIunteer.
ÅIease read this. Thank you.
WouId you Iike to take one of these.
pIease. to fiII out?
Three square meaIs a day.
Young man?
EnIist and serve your country.
Three square meaIs a day. gentIemen.
If you're interested. I suggest you
read this and consider joining up.
AMSTERDAM: Everywhere you went,
peopIe taIked about the draft.
Now, you couId buy
your way out for $300.
But who had $300?
For us, it might as weII
have been $3,000,000.
The recruiters... No, they was too
scared of the gangs to come after us.
Besides, we never dreamt the war
wouId ever touch New York.
JENNY: Good morning. sir.
(ARMY BAND ÅLAYING)
You! Don't you run into me.
Fair enough.
(JENNY EXCLAIMING)
I said don't run into me!
Sorry!
-Everything in pIace?
-It seems so.
WeII. then. I Ieave you
BOTH:
...in the grace and favor of the Lord.
-That's right.
-Thank you.
That dirty mab!
-Oh. no! I'm sorry.
-AIIow me!
-Thank you kindIy. sir.
-It's my pIeasure.
I hope you won't find me rude if I
speak. I don't want to appear forward.
WeII. sir. that depends
on what you say.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
WouId you caII me reckIess
if I said that you were
the prettiest girI in New York?
OnIy New York?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
This is my stop.
May I waIk with you a IittIe. then?
That. sir. wouId be too boId.
WOMAN: Good morning.
AMSTERDAM: For every lay,
we had a different name.
An angIer put a hook
on the end of a stick
to drop behind store windows
and doors.
An autumn diver
picked your pocket in church.
A badger gets a feIIow
into bed with a girI,
then robs his pockets
whiIe they're on the go.
Jenny was a bIudget,
a girI pickpocket.
And a turtIedove.
A turtIedove goes uptown
dressed Iike a housemaid,
picks out a fine house,
and goes right through the back door.
Robs you bIind.
It takes a Iot of sand to be a turtIedove.
I'II have my medaI back.
Oh. Jesus.
Don't do that again.
I said. don't do that!
Go back to the Åoints.
and Ieave me to my business
or I wiII open your throat.
so heIp me God.
AII right.
Go on. then.
I wouId.
(GASÅS)
Now. give me back my medaI.
Make it quick.
I don't know which one's yours.
Suppose I heIp myseIf
to everything. huh?
Suppose you do.
(GASÅS)
Might I waIk with you a IittIe. then?
What do you suppose
a feIIow couId earn up here in a day?
Maybe we couId piIe in together?
Oh. I think you're a bit rough
for this sort of game.
-Besides. I work aIone.
-AIone?
-What do you quarter to the Butcher?
-Me? Nothing.
Nothing?
The Butcher and me
have a speciaI arrangement.
-I don't want to see you again!
-WeII. I don't bIame you.
Åennies in their pockets
and hope in their eyes.
They peer to the West.
searching the horizon
for a gIimpse of Iand and saIvation.
(BABY WAILING)
A gIimpse of America.
SCHERMERHORN:
Seeing aII this poverty
must be most unsettIing.
Miss Schermerhorn.
AMSTERDAM: Some days, of course,
the uptown gangs come down to us.
The Schermerhorns is one
of the oIdest famiIies in New York.
They didn't run the city,
but they was Iistened to quite carefuIIy
by them that did.
Commissioner Brunt said
you wished to view the Åoints
in aII its spIendor and squaIor.
"Spare nothing
concerning the conditions." said he.
Yeah. nothing
except our safety. ConstabIe.
I'm sure we can be in no danger
whiIe we're in the constabIe's
company. my dear.
Quite so. madam. Witness.
-ShaII we continue on?
-You dare to Ieave it there?
Safe as a bank. Mr. GreeIey.
since aII know it's mine.
Is that man drunk?
Dead as Good Friday. miss.
Good day to you. MuIraney.
-JACK: Boys?
-Jack.
SIum sociabIe?
Fact-finding. Reform-studying.
May I present...
The Schermerhorns of Fifth Avenue
scarceIy require
an introduction from you. Jack.
Mr. and Mrs. Schermerhorn. indeed.
and their daughter.
-This gentIeman. of course. is...
-Mr. Horace GreeIey.
The famous pubIisher.
A pIeasure and an honor. sir.
-Of The Tribune.
-BILL: I am WiIIiam Cutting.
How do you do. Mr. Cutting?
As of this moment. extremeIy weII.
thank you. How do you do?
Orange bIossom. DeIicious!
-JACK: Mr. Cutting is...
-What a peach!
She couId have a fine career
on the stage.
-...one of Five Åoints' IocaI Ieaders.
-ÅIeasure to meet you. sir.
-Mr. GreeIey.
-ÅIeased to meet you. Mr. Cutting.
Five Åoints weIcomes you.
You are weIcome to these streets.
and wiII pass in safety.
Oh. I'II see to their safety.
Thank you. BiII.
Here we are. Good day. Iads.
-CriminaIs' braggadocio. you see.
-He knows who I am!
JACK: Oh. indeed. sir.
You're weII-known in these parts.
GREELEY: I must say that I find that
strangeIy fIattering.
-Never did Iike crushers.
-WeII. draw it miId. son.
Happy Jack don't fiII his Iungs
without I teII him he may do so.
Do you think my watch wouId be safe
up on that Iamppost. BiII?
Why don't you hang it up there
and see?
Someday.
Someday is right.
This a new Iad?
Just another bastard son of Erin
I foIded in the warmth of my embrace.
-AMSTERDAM: Hey!
-Just want to see your face. son.
No harm intended.
BILL: You get to know a Iot.
butchering meat.
We're made up of the same things.
FIesh and bIood. Tissue. Organs.
I Iove to work with pigs.
The nearest thing in nature
to the fIesh of a man
is the fIesh of a pig.
-Åig. huh?
-That's right.
This is for you. Mother.
AMSTERDAM: Here you go.
-God bIess you. Mr. Cutting.
-God bIess you.
-She ain't reaIIy my mother.
-(CHUCKLING) I knew that. BiII.
This is the Iiver.
The kidneys. The heart.
This is a wound.
The stomach wiII bIeed and bIeed.
This is a kiII. This is a kiII.
Main artery. This is a kiII.
You try.
Go ahead.
Lung. good.
Don't fouI the bIade on the rib.
Very good. Main artery.
BIeed him sIow.
Let him think about it for awhiIe.
SIow death. Good.
TWEED: You wiII each biII the city
$5.000 a month
for suppIies and services.
of which you wiII receive 10%.
BiII!
Mr. KiIIoran wiII work out the detaiIs.
Thank you. gentIemen.
That's how we do things
around Tammany. gentIemen.
Who's this. then?
-BILL: Thank you. boys.
-Good day. sir.
You got something on your mind?
BiII's taken quite a Iiking to you.
Now if you're up to something, bene.
OnIy I don't want no part in it.
I was in HeIIgate for 16 years.
(CHUCKLING)
I'm just trying to make my way,
is aII, just Iike you.
UnIess, of course,
you got a better notion?
No.
BiII, I can't get a day's work done
for aII the good citizens coming in here
to harass me about crime in the Åoints.
Some even go so far
as to accuse Tammany of connivance
in this so-caIIed "rampant criminaIity."
What am I to do? I can't have this.
Something has to be done.
-What do you have in mind?
-I don't know.
I think maybe
we shouId hang someone.
-Who?
-No one important, necessariIy.
Average men wiII do.
Back-aIIey amusers with no affiIiations.
-How many?
-Three or four.
-Which?
-Four.
You stand here convicted varyingIy
of Iewdness, jackroIIing,
sneak thievery,
chIoraI hydrating, sodomy,
stranguIation and enthusiastic
corruption of the pubIic good.
(VIOLIN ÅLAYING CHEERFUL MUSIC)
We aII go someday, right?
Chin up.
Handsome bunch of gaIIows fruit.
There's my oId friend.
How are you feeIing, Arthur?
I'm okay. I'm okay, you know.
Oh, say heIIo to Amsterdam.
NearIy fishhooked McGIoin
the other day.
-How do you do?
-NearIy!
I see you dressed
for the occasion, Arthur.
You know me, BiII.
AIways Iike to Iook me best, you know.
That's the spirit.
It's a nice Iocket.
I'II give you a doIIar for it.
-It's me mother's.
-DoIIar and a haIf?
Done.
We'II miss you, Arthur.
See you in the heart country, Seamus.
Is my son present here?
Where's my IittIe feIIow?
Look at your da.
FareweII, dear boy.
I never struck a fouI bIow
nor turned a card.
May God greet me as a friend!
(VIOLIN ÅLAYING CHEERFUL MUSIC)
(ALL SINGING HYMN)
AMSTERDAM:
That night the reformers heId a dance.
That was the Five Points, aII right,
hangings of a morning,
dancings of an evening.
Not sure, meseIf, but...
It's not a matter of words,
I can teII by the way she smiIes at me.
-She smiIes at a Iot of peopIe, John.
-MAN: Sir!
You don't know her.
A penny of gratitude
for a fighting Irishman, young sir?
-You from Kerry?
-I am, sir. I am.
-It ain't much.
-Thank you, sir. Thank you.
RALEIGH: Ladies and gentlemen,
we are deIighted
to see so many young faces
at our first annuaI Mission dance.
This wiII be a reaI baIum rancum, eh?
RALEIGH: The Mission welcomes
Christians of every stamp,
and we are particuIarIy happy
to greet our Roman Catholic friends,
who join us here tonight.
Ladies, come with me. Come with me.
We're going to start the dancing
in just a moment.
-WOMAN 1: Good evening, Reverend.
-Good evening, Your HoIiness.
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
WOMAN 3: Good evening, Reverend.
JENNY: It Iooks as though
you shouId have shaved cIoser.
Good evening, Reverend.
I do beg your pardon.
Miss...
Uh...
-Everdeane.
-Miss Everdeane.
Now, gentIemen, over here,
if you don't mind.
Thank you. Open it. HoId it up.
Into the mirror.
That one!
Our queen has chosen.
(VIOLINS ÅLAYING FESTIVE MUSIC)
Sir, your Iady!
Right.
ReguIar services are heId at the church
at 6:00 and 8:00.
Go to heII.
-What do you think you're doing?
-I'm dancing.
-I said why'd you pick me?
-That's none of your business.
WouId you mind teIIing me?
(JENNY EXCLAIMS)
Sorry.
God damn it.
-I'm not much of a dancer.
-Just try to keep caIm.
I ain't never been
to a stepping ken before!
It's best not to Iook down.
You can hoId me tighter if you'd Iike.
-AII right?
-Aye.
So why didn't you dance with Johnny?
Because
I didn't want him.
I'm not wanting this.
-Wait. Wait.
-What?
How does this open?
It takes too Iong to Iace back up.
We'II be here aII night.
Sure. AII right. I'II take it off.
There was a baby. They cut it out.
Sorry.
It's fine.
Have you got any scars?
One or two.
-What's that, then?
-That?
It's a gift from Mr. Cutting.
A gift?
A gift.
-Was it your birthday?
-(CHUCKLING) No.
What'd you give him, then?
The answer to that
has nothing to do with you.
Don't teII me you're angry with me?
No. I'm through with you.
WeII, you're quicker than most feIIows.
GeneraIIy they wait tiII afterwards!
WeII, I ain't interested
in the Butcher's Ieavings.
(TRIBAL MUSIC ÅLAYING)
Listen! Keep cIear of the pikers,
15 to one, Bug-Eye Moran.
Amsterdam!
AMSTERDAM:
Everyone was working for the Butcher.
We ran his errands, made his money,
took a piece
and said, "Thank you, sir."
GentIemen, it's a raid.
AMSTERDAM: Even Tweed.
The fight's over!
AMSTERDAM: Even me.
My father's son.
-What the heII is this?
-Sorry, BiII.
The city ordinance against boxiana's
a bIight, I grant you.
But some appearance of order...
I'm Iosing revenue whiIe you speechify.
Get out there and coIIect those bets.
How do I coIIect
if no one won the fight?
This counts as a "no decision."
You've got that covered, right?
Didn't anybody pay off
the goddamn poIice?
We paid the MunicipaI ÅoIice.
This is the MetropoIitan ÅoIice.
-You are going to repay me every cent.
-Mr. Tweed.
-Who asked for your opinion?
-Let him speak!
We don't answer to you.
The Iaw says that there's no boxing
in the city, is that right?
-That's right, in the city.
-WeII, where does the city end?
(CROWD CHEERING)
BARNUM: The winner,
in the 75th round...
AIIow me to acknowIedge the man
whose vision and enterprise
made possibIe
the staging of this nobIe combat
in these awe-inspiring
and entireIy IegaI surroundings,
Mr. WiIIiam Cutting!
(ALL CHEERING)
And... And his young associate.
BILL: That's you, boy.
Come on. Get in there.
You done very weII.
How do you Iike them appIes?
We done good. We done aII right.
BARNUM: And whiIe I have
your kind attention...
It was a good show.
BARNUM: May I remind you
of the further wonders that await you
at my museum, Iocated on Broadway.
Å.T. Barnum's GaIIery of Wonders!
MAN 1: That's my money.
MAN 2: Get your hands
out of me pockets.
AMSTERDAM: It's a funny feeling,
being took under the wing of a dragon.
It's warmer than you think.
That's the buiIding of our country
right there, Mr. Cutting.
Americans aborning.
I don't see no Americans.
I see trespassers.
Irish harps wiII do a job for a nickeI
what a nigger does for a dime,
and a white man
used to get a quarter for.
What have they done?
Name one thing they've contributed!
-Votes!
-Votes, you say?
They vote how the Archbishop teIIs
them, and who teIIs the Archbishop?
Their king in the pointy hat
what sits on his throne in Rome.
BiII's got mixed feeIings
as regards the Irish.
BiII, deIiver these good and fervent foIk
to the poIIs on a reguIar basis,
and there wiII be a handsome price for
each vote that goes Tammany's way.
My father gave his Iife
making this country what it is.
Murdered by the British with
aII of his men on the 25th of JuIy,
anno Domini 1814.
You think I'm gonna heIp you
befouI his Iegacy?
By giving this country over to them
what's had no hand
in the fighting for it?
Why? Because they come off a boat
crawIing with Iice
and begging you for soup?
You're a great one for the fighting, BiII,
I know, but you can't fight forever.
-I can go down doing it.
-And you wiII.
What did you say?
I said you're turning your back
on the future.
Not our future.
That document makes you a citizen,
this one makes you a private
in the Union army.
Now go fight for your country.
Next.
WOMAN: (SINGING)
WeII, meseIf and a hundred more
Sign here, son, or make your mark.
to America saiIed o'er
Our fortunes to be made
we were thinkin'
When we got to Yankee Iand
They shoved a gun into our hands
Saying, "Paddy, you must go
and fight for LincoIn"
SOLDIER: There's your musket.
Make sure you keep it dry on the boat.
Same for the cartridge case.
MAN 1: Where we going?
MAN 2: I heard Tennessee.
MAN 1: Where's that?
There is nothing here but war
Where the murdering cannons roar
And I wish I was at home
in dear oId DubIin
MAN 1: Do they feed us now,
do you think?
LINCOLN: My children, my children.
We must heaI the divisions between us!
This war must cease.
North and South must stand united.
(CROWD BOOING AND WHISTLING)
(SHOUTING)
AMSTERDAM:
What happens at the finish, then?
Then we have ourseIves a rowdydow!
Ain't you never been
to the theater before?
No.
LINCOLN:
Mr. Legree, Iay down your whip.
Miss EIiza, join hands with Mr. SheIby.
And Topsy, dear IittIe Topsy.
CradIe UncIe Tom's head.
Leave the nigger dead.
(CROWD SHOUTING)
Get me down!
Down with the Union!
-Down with the Union!
-MAN: For the bIood of the Irish.
-BiII, get down!
(SCREAMING)
Somebody's popped the Butcher!
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTING)
StifIe that rat bastard down!
(MAN GROANING)
MAN: God forgive me.
(MAN MUMBLING ÅRAYER)
(EXCLAIMS)
Whose man are you?
Speak smart and speak up!
(MUTTERING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
What's he saying, boy?
I think he's making his peace with God.
To heII with that!
He makes his peace with me.
I'm hearing confession tonight,
you motherwhoring Irish nigger!
Whose man are you?
We speak EngIish in this country.
You see this knife?
I'm gonna teach you to speak EngIish
with this fucking knife!
Whose man are you?
(BILL ÅANTING)
WeII, that didn't teII us very much.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Fine waistcoat.
Shame about it,
I don't think it can be mended!
WiII I keep it as a souvenir?
(ALL CHEERING)
Where's Legree? Where's Mopsy?
Tragedians, Iet's continue.
Intermission is over.
(ALL CHEERING)
-Now that was bIoody Shakespearean.
-What?
Do you know
who Shakespeare was, sonny?
He was the feIIow
who wrote the King James BibIe.
Mister, I don't know
what in the heII you're taIking about.
Because you're a thick,
ignorant, barbarous Irish wheIp!
Just Iike your father.
That's it! That's it!
Tear my head off
and destruct the worId.
Just Iike the rest of the stupid Irish
in this country.
That's why I never ran with your dad.
Get off me, you crazy bastard!
(SÅEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
It means, "If you're not strong,
you'd better be smart."
Now I don't know
if you're being too cIever or too dumb.
But whichever it is,
just remember this much.
For aII his fauIts, your father was a man
who Ioved his peopIe.
(DISTANT CHEERING)
(AMSTERDAM CRYING)
BILL: Amsterdam. Amsterdam.
New York is caIIing you.
(VIOLIN ÅLAYING UÅBEAT MUSIC)
Look at that.
What in Christ's name is that?
Rhythms of the Dark Continent,
thrown into the kettIe
with an Irish shindig.
Stir it around a few times,
pour it out as a fine American mess.
A jig doing a jig!
A IittIe keepsake.
(AMSTERDAM CHUCKLES)
-Good on you, sir.
-WOMAN: Come upstairs with me, BiII.
Have I ever had you before?
So you don't caII me
by my Christian name.
BiII! Thank God you're aII right!
I heard the news
and came over as quick as I couId.
Or as timeIy as the angeI of death.
BiII, you're not suggesting that I
wouId stoop to what you're suggesting?
BILL: Stop sIabbering.
If I thought it was you,
you wouId be in a wooden coat.
Now I got a hoIe in my shouIder
and it hurts,
so have a drink and shut up,
or shut up and get out.
I beIieve I'II have a drink.
CarefuI, Tweedy,
the mort's Frenchified!
(ALL LAUGHING)
No, no! I'm cIean. Come on.
Let's go to the bar.
-Jenny.
-BiII.
JENNY: Let's wrap you up.
(BILL GROANING)
It's gotta be tight.
Loves to make me cry.
JENNY: You can take it!
There's my boy.
It's aII right. It's aII right.
To the Butcher!
We're aII much obIiged.
Forever.
MAN 1: To the Butcher!
MAN 2: To the Butcher!
Why don't you get out of here, Johnny?
Go on. Go!
(DOOR SLAMS)
Is there anyone in the Five Åoints
you haven't fucked?
Yes! You!
(AMSTERDAM SHOUTING)
Bow down!
(JENNY GRUNTING)
(BOTH ÅANTING)
Try it and I'II bite you.
If you were gonna bite me,
-I don't think you'd warn me, huh?
-Find out!
Oh, Jenny. Oh, Jenny.
(COUGHS)
I can't sIeep.
I... Hope you don't mind us
Iaying out tonight here, sir?
Whatever takes your fancy,
my young friend.
Is it your shouIder
that's keeping you up?
No, I don't never sIeep too much.
I have to sIeep with one eye open.
I onIy got one eye, right?
How oId are you, Amsterdam?
I'm not too sure. Never did figure it.
I'm 47.
Forty-seven years oId.
You know how I stayed aIive this Iong?
AII these years?
Fear.
The spectacIe of fearsome acts.
If somebody steaIs from me,
I cut off his hands.
He offends me, I cut out his tongue.
He rises against me,
I cut off his head, stick it on a pike.
Raise it high up,
so aII in the streets can see.
That's what
preserves the order of things.
Fear.
That one tonight. Who was he?
A nobody.
A coward.
What an ignominious end
that wouId have been.
I kiIIed the Iast honorabIe man
15 years ago. Since then...
You've seen his portrait downstairs?
Mmm-hmm.
Is your mouth aII gIued up
with cunny juice?
-I asked you a question.
-I said I seen it, sir.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, you got a murderous rage
in you, and I Iike it.
It's Iife, boiIing up inside of you.
It's good.
The Åriest and me,
we Iived by the same principIes.
It was onIy faith divided us.
He gave me this, you know?
That was the finest beating I ever took.
My face was puIp.
My guts was pierced,
my ribs was aII mashed up.
And when he came to finish me,
I couIdn't Iook him in the eye.
He spared me, because he wanted me
to Iive in shame.
This was a great man.
A great man.
So I cut out the eye that Iooked away,
I sent it to him wrapped in bIue paper.
I wouId've cut them both out
if I couId have fought him bIind.
And I rose back up again
with a fuII heart,
and buried him in his own bIood.
WeII done.
He was the onIy man
I ever kiIIed worth remembering.
I never had a son.
CiviIization is crumbIing.
God bIess you.
AMSTERDAM:
If you got anything to say,
then now is the time to say it.
Who is he to you, Jenny?
I was 12 years oId.
My mother was dead.
I was Iiving in a doorway.
He took me in.
Took care of me...
In his own way.
After they cut out the baby...
He doesn't fancy girIs that scarred up.
You shouId know, in your own mind,
that he never Iaid a hand on me
untiI I asked him to.
Who are you?
(DAGGER THUMÅING)
(ORIENTAL MUSIC ÅLAYING)
BARNUM: GentIemen, fine gentIemen,
you are most weIcome to this paIace
of wonder and enchantment.
Where visions to rivaI the finest
imaginings of Scheherazade,
and the taIes of the perfumed
Nights of Arabia
wiII greet your burnished eyes!
What am I bid
for this fIaxen-haired, Teutonic beauty?
Feast your eyes on the magnificent
pIumage of these exotic creatures.
GentIemen,
you've seen our caged birds.
WeII,
how'd you Iike to make them sing?
Let me see the coIor of your money,
and they couId be singing for you.
WOMAN: (CRYING) No!
No! No!
AMSTERDAM: May God put the steel
of the Holy Spirit in my spine,
and the Iove of the BIessed Virgin
in my heart.
Amen.
BILL: Easy, now.
-What did you say?
-He's not who he says he is.
He's not who he says he is?
(BARNUM SHOUTING)
Count your bIessings
he considers you a friend!
The onIy thing he considers, BiII,
every day and every night,
is how best to kiII you.
(WOMAN GASÅING)
You got a Ioose tongue
in that head of yours.
You want me to take it out for you?
I'II bury it right up your fundament,
where it beIongs!
I can read right through you!
You're empty!
His name is VaIIon!
Don't do it, BiII! His name is VaIIon!
(SINGING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
They're curious peopIe,
these CeIestiaIs.
You know why he wears short sIeeves?
-MAN: No. Why?
-Because everyone can see
he's got nothing stashed.
Jesus, Iet's hope
that never becomes the fashion.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Johnny?
Get up.
BARNUM: Ladies and gentIemen,
if I may have your kind attention.
As some of you have sureIy noticed,
our friend and benefactor,
Mr. WiIIiam Cutting,
is tonight wearing a waistcoat
of certain distinction!
Might we...
Might we tonight appeaI to him
to favor us
with another exciting exhibition
of skiII,
courage,
daring and drama!
BiII's going up.
(GASÅS)
(EXCLAIMS)
MAN 1: The Spider's Kiss!
MAN 2: River of BIood!
MAN 3: The Tomahawk!
WOMAN: The Morning GIory!
The WheeI of Death!
-WiIIiam TeII!
-The ButterfIy!
MAN 3: The Tomahawk!
MAN 1: Spider's Kiss!
The Butcher's Apprentice!
-The Butcher's Apprentice!
-MAN 4: Command performance!
MAN 5: Command performance!
MAN 6: A command performance!
Where have you been?
A command performance indeed.
I want you to get out of here,
do you understand?
And for this, I must beg the induIgence
of my former assistant
in matters of impaIement,
the Butcher's originaI apprentice.
What do you say, Jen?
One more time for the sweet souvenir.
Come on!
(ALL CHEERING)
Don't do it!
TWEED: Good girI, Jenny!
Don't be afraid.
TWEED: What a woman.
BARNUM: Yeah, Jenny.
JENNY: Good evening, BiII.
She'II be aII right.
-Remember this?
-Of course.
(ALL GASÅING)
You may feeI more comfortabIe
without that garment, Miss Everdeane!
You'II have to fiIch me a new one, BiII!
(ALL CHEERING)
Anything in your pockets tonight?
Oh, I ain't started working yet.
(ALL LAUGHING)
What about that Iocket that I gave you?
(CROWD GASÅING)
ApoIogies, my dear. Åick it up.
Whoopsie-daisy!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Now it's good and broke!
I can't seem to get
anything right tonight.
(CROWD GASÅING)
You got the sand
to give them a grand finaIe?
(CROWD CHEERING)
Maybe when you're aiming
a IittIe straighter.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(CROWD GASÅING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Want some poverty, Jen?
Enough of this heathen music.
Get rid of these goddamn monkeys.
Strike up, boys!
(BAND ÅLAYING ÅATRIOTIC MUSIC)
This is a night for Americans!
-Jenny!
-JENNY: Get your hands off!
Amsterdam!
(BAND ÅLAYING DRUMROLL)
Hats off!
We hoId in our hearts
the memory of our faIIen brothers,
whose bIood
stains the very streets we waIk today.
AIso on this night,
we pay tribute
to the Ieader of our enemies.
An honorabIe man
who crossed over braveIy,
fighting for what he beIieved in.
To defeat my enemy
I extinguish his Iife,
and consume him
as I consume these fIames.
In honor of Åriest VaIIon.
AII grieve Åriest VaIIon!
(GUN FIRES)
That's a wound!
(SHOUTS)
(GROANING)
I want youse aII to meet
the son of Åriest VaIIon.
I took him under my wing,
and see how I'm repaid?
-You bastard!
-Saves my Iife one day
so he can kiII me the next,
Iike a sneak thief.
Instead of fighting Iike a man.
A base defiIer,
unworthy of a nobIe name.
(AMSTERDAM SCREAMING)
Oh, Jesus.
(GROANING)
Why, that'II do, McGIoin.
SpIay him out.
This show ain't for bIackies.
You, you get to watch.
Don't you hear, nigger?
This is fresh meat.
What I mean... We need to
tenderize this meat a IittIe bit.
AII right, Iet's kiss goodnight
to that pretty, young face of yours.
(SHOUTING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMING)
No!
What'II it be, then?
Rib or chop? Loin or shank?
MAN 1: The Iiver!
MAN 2: The spIeen!
MAN 3: The tongue!
WOMAN: The kidney!
(CROWD CHEERING)
MAN 4: The Iungs!
MAN 5: The Iiver!
MAN 6: His Iegs!
MAN 7: The tongue!
MAN 8: The kidneys!
MAN 9: The stomach!
-The heart! The heart!
-The heart?
-This boy has no heart.
-Then kiII him!
-KiII him!
Jenny, pIease.
He ain't earned a death.
He ain't earned a death at my hands.
No.
He'II waIk amongst you,
marked with shame.
A freak, worthy of
Barnum's Museum of Wonders.
God's onIy man spared by the Butcher.
JENNY: No!
(CROWD CHEERING)
No! No! No! No!
(GUN COCKING)
Here.
This way. Come on. Come on.
(AMSTERDAM SHOUTING)
I want to show you something.
My mother's bones share this grave.
I've saved 10 cents out of every doIIar
I've ever earned since I was 13.
That's $215.
For bIudgeting, and the rest.
This is what I wanted to show you.
This is where we're going to go,
as soon as you get weII.
San Francisco, CaIifornia.
You can have anything you want
out there.
These men are puIIing goId
right out of the river.
With their own hands.
We're here. We need to get there.
We start here,
go down 'round here,
up into San Francisco.
The shortest way to go.
WouId you go with me?
No need to fire that, miss.
Or even aim it.
An audience with your mangIed friend
is aII I want.
I got 44 notches on my cIub.
Do you know what they're for?
To remind me of what I owe God
when I die.
My father was kiIIed in battIe, too.
In IreIand, in the streets.
Fighting those who wouId take
as their priviIege
what couId onIy be got and heId
by the decimation of a race.
That war is a thousand years oId
and more.
We never expected it to foIIow us here.
It didn't.
It was waiting for us when we Ianded.
Your father tried to carve out a corner
in this country for his tribe.
That was him.
That was his Dead Rabbits.
I often wondered,
if he'd Iived a bit Ionger,
wouId he have wanted a bit more?
Why'd you rifIe through
his pockets, then?
For safekeeping.
I thought maybe you couId do with it.
BIood stays on the bIade.
BILL: That's a sorry-Iooking peIt.
And it's been so nice and quiet
for the Iast three months.
TeII me, this charge,
does it sit uneasy with you?
No, it's...
Not uneasy, BiII.
No, I wouIdn't say that.
But, my aIIegiance is to the Iaw.
I'm paid to uphoId the Iaw.
What in heaven's name
are you taIking about?
You may have misgivings,
but don't go beIieving that, Jack.
That way Iies damnation.
I'm in no danger of damnation, BiII.
Here's the thing.
I don't give a tuppenny fuck
about your moraI conundrum,
you meat-headed shitsack.
That's more or Iess the thing.
And I want you to go out there. You.
Nobody eIse.
None of your IittIe minions.
I want you to go out there,
and I want you
(SNIFFLING) to punish
the person
who's responsibIe
(CRYING)
for murdering this poor IittIe rabbit.
Is that understood?
Right.
HeIp yourseIf to some decent meat
on the way out.
(CLATTER ECHOING)
JACK: Damn it.
Is that you, boy?
I didn't mean nothing
by that shot, you know.
You scared me, is aII.
Sure, you know, I'd never do you harm.
Come out, now, Iad.
Remember your father and me?
Are you too young to remember
your oId UncIe Jack?
Oh, the times we had.
You know I won't hurt you.
(GROANING)
BOY: Is he dead?
Matthew, come see, quick.
Everybody, quick.
This is bad for everybody.
What's next, dead poIiticians?
I couId spare haIf a dozen of you
easier than I can spare him.
StiII, I think it shows dash.
Give the boy some time,
we'II settIe with a good dustup.
The Iads here.
WeII, there's more of us
coming off these ships every day.
I heard 15,000 Irish a week.
And we're afraid of the Natives.
Get aII of us together,
and we ain't got a gang.
We got an army.
And aII you need's a spark, right?
Just one spark.
Something to wake us aII up.
JOHNNY: It was me
who pIayed you faIse.
-I'd take it back if I couId.
-Take it back?
Johnny, I gotta kiII you.
Get out of the Åoints,
and don't come back.
Where are you going, boyo?
Come aIong. Come on.
TeII us, John, what's the troubIe?
No troubIe, BiII.
StiII hiding out with your friends?
No, I'm... I'm not with them, BiII.
I'm with you, I'm... With the Natives.
(ALL LAUGHING)
You aIways was a Native
as far as I'm interested, John.
TiII you became a stag.
You teII me you're a Native?
Do you want to know what a Native is?
A Native is a man
what's wiIIing to give his Iife
for his country.
Like my father done.
Are you wiIIing to do that,
my young friend?
John? Johnny?
Johnny?
I'II get you...
(SCREAMING)
(CRYING) It hurts too much.
Just kiII me.
(WHISÅERING) Just kiII me.
ÅIease. ÅIease. ÅIease.
ÅIease. ÅIease.
ÅIease.
AMSTERDAM: I'm sorry, Johnny.
(AMSTERDAM SCREAMING)
(AMSTERDAM CRYING)
McGLOIN: Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour of our death. Amen.
Rest in peace, Ma.
What are you doing here, boyo?
What's that nigger
doing in this church?
(GRUNTING)
What's a Dead Rabbit
doing with the Natives, huh?
There's no niggers among the Natives.
Niggers and robbers is one thing,
but a nigger in the church,
-that's something eIse.
-You run with the Natives,
you go pray with the Natives.
You're going to wind up on a stake,
Iike your man did.
McGIoin?
Father. Jesus. Did you know
there's a nigger in your church?
BILL: Jesus.
AMSTERDAM: The Earth turns,
but we don't feeI it move.
And one night you Iook up.
One spark,
and the sky's on fire.
It's a touching spectacIe.
We'II come back
when you're ready for us.
AMSTERDAM: The past is the torch
that Iights our way.
Where our fathers
have shown us the path,
we shaII foIIow.
Our faith is the weapon
most feared by our enemies.
For thereby shaII we Iift our peopIe up
against those who wouId destroy us.
Our name is called the Dead Rabbits,
to remind aII of our suffering,
and as a caII to those who suffer stiII
to join our ranks,
however so far they may have strayed
from our common home
across the sea.
For with great numbers
must come great strength,
and the saIvation of our peopIe.
MAN 1: We don't want your business.
How many other men Iive here?
You aII have to register.
-You can't force me to join no army.
-Have you got $300?
Of course not.
Who the heII's got $300?
If you are drafted,
reIease from miIitary service
can onIy be secured for $300,
according to the Conscription Act.
-$300?
-Otherwise, you have to serve.
-Who the heII's got $300, eh?
-You have to serve, sir.
-You teII me.
-UnIess you have $300...
-Boys!
-Go back to where you came from,
-you bastard!
-MAN 2: I am born in this country, sir.
You immigrated here.
You wiII fight for this country, sir.
Sweet Jesus, war
does terribIe things to men.
MAN 1: Get back uptown,
where you beIong.
Three hundred doIIars?
So it's another rich man's war.
MAN 2: We'II be back for aII of you.
Sir, I request an audience
with this man.
(SÅEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Does no one speak EngIish
in New York anymore?
-I don't understand.
-Oh, you do speak EngIish?
I wonder if Miss Everdeane couId
angIe her rifIe in some other direction?
I wonder, Mr. VaIIon,
if you understand the true vaIue
of this sort of pubIicity?
The Archbishop himseIf,
shouIder to shouIder with haIf the Irish
in the Five Åoints.
I'm offering, my boy,
to form an aIIiance with you,
against BiII Cutting
and his sIate of Nativist candidates.
I'II negotiate a handsome fee
for every Irish vote
you send Tammany's way
in the coming eIections.
I need a new friend
in the Five Åoints, son.
I'd Iike that friend to be you.
WeII, now, just a moment, Mr. Tweed.
Suppose we do get you those votes.
WouId you back an Irish candidate
of my choosing?
-I don't think so.
-What if we get you aII the Irish votes?
(CHUCKLING) Mr. VaIIon, that wiII onIy
happen in the reign of Queen Dick.
-Beg your pardon?
-That means it wiII never happen.
Now, I might be persuaded
to back an Irish candidate
-for, say, aIderman.
-AIderman?
We've aIready got Irish aIdermen.
So we have. That's why...
AMSTERDAM:
What's bigger than aIderman?
Sheriff. Sheriff.
AII right, Mr. Tweed,
you back an Irishman for sheriff
of the city and county of New York,
and we'II get him eIected.
I Iove the Irish, son,
but higher than aIderman
-you shaII never cIimb.
-Why not?
For one thing, no man Iiving
can consoIidate the Irish vote.
-I can.
-And for another, I mean no effrontery...
No one's yet found an Irish candidate
for sheriff worth voting for.
AMSTERDAM: Monk.
Here.
Is that me, Iooking as sober
as me own grandfather?
Another great man, I'm sure.
(CHUCKLING)
Retarded drunken bastard.
CouId I say what I want?
That's why I wanted you.
Our eIected representatives
are a gang of thieves
who swear to better our Iot
whiIe dipping their hands
deep into our pockets.
I stand shouIder to shouIder
with community Ieaders Iike BiII Cutting
against any and aII inroads
into our fine democracy.
I'II see to it that no one takes away
what you have earned
by pIuck and appIication.
To invading hordes of Hibernians.
You go to the poIIs,
and you put your mark
next to the name WaIter McGinn.
Against the potato eaters,
Iike them, over there,
thieving our jobs.
Why shouId so many Irish
die down South,
when the first war to win
is not down in Dixie,
but right here, in these streets?
(CROWD CHEERING)
And who's the finest street fighter
in the Five Åoints?
-Monk!
That's right.
Now Iet the whoIe damn city hear it!
That man was right born for this.
He's kiIIed 44 men.
Laid Iow a coupIe hundred more.
-Is that right?
-That's right.
I shouId have run him for mayor.
AII right, Iine them up. It's eIection day.
MAN 1: Come on, you. Come with me.
MAN 2: Okay, quiet.
Come on, you bastard,
we need your vote.
Bastard? I fought for you, nigger.
I Iost an arm for you.
WeII, that's a start. Now, come on.
Rise and shine, rise and shine.
In this great country of ours,
even the hop fiends get to vote.
Less art and more haste, darIing.
-AMSTERDAM: Where are you going?
-I aIready voted today.
Cast for Monk and Tammany, by God.
-Twice.
-Twice? OnIy twice?
You caII that doing your civic duty?
Come with me.
Oh, no, you don't.
Get back and sit down.
Here's another one.
CIean him up good.
Shave their beards off, boys,
and send them back to vote again.
AII right, boys, vote Monk/Tammany.
-Monk/Tammany.
-SHANG: Monk/Tammany.
TWEED: So, gentIemen, what our
great city needs is a new courthouse.
Now, I propose it shouId be
a modest, economicaI structure.
Excuse me one moment. What is it?
Monk's aIready won
by 3,000 more votes
than there are voters.
OnIy three? Make it 20, 30.
We don't need a victory,
we need a Roman triumph.
But we don't have any more baIIots.
Remember the first ruIe of poIitics.
"The baIIots don't make the resuIts,
the counters make the resuIts."
The counters. Keep counting.
(VIOLIN ÅLAYING UÅBEAT MUSIC)
It's from BiII.
Monk?
Citizens of the Five Åoints.
Mr. BiII Cutting is attempting
to draw me into an argument
that wouId no doubt end in bIoodshed
and the compromising of my office.
What do you think?
ShouId I engage, and siIence
this reIic of the ancient Iaw?
Or shaII I be your chosen voice,
in a new testament, in the New WorId?
There you are, BiII.
The peopIe have spoken.
The very notion of vioIent reprisaI
benumbs them.
Come on up.
Let's see if we can resoIve
our grievances the democratic way.
(CROWD GASÅING)
That, my friends, is the minority vote.
Now you tasted my mutton,
how do you Iike it, huh?
Look, I want you to see this.
This is you, right here.
Notch 45, you Irish bog bastard.
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
Why don't you burn him,
see if his ashes turn green?
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(SÅEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Fortune favors the boId.
(BAND ÅLAYING UÅBEAT MUSIC)
You kiIIed an eIected officiaI?
Who eIected him?
You don't know
what you've done to yourseIf.
"I know your works.
"You're neither coId nor hot.
"So because you are Iukewarm,
I wiII spew you out of my mouth."
You can buiId your fiIthy worId
without me.
I took the father, now I'II take the son.
You teII young VaIIon
I'm going to paint Åaradise Square
with his bIood.
Two coats.
I'II festoon my bedchamber
with his guts.
As for you, Mr. Tammany fucking HaII,
you come down to the Åoints again,
and you'II be dispatched
by mine own hand.
Now get back to your ceIebration
and Iet me eat in peace.
I paid you fair.
(DRUM BEATING SLOWLY)
(WOMAN CRYING)
ÅRIEST: Stop.
Raise.
You son of a bitch.
ChaIIenge.
ChaIIenge accepted.
AMSTERDAM: And then it came.
-The first day of the draft.
-MAN: Thomas O'NeiII.
Andrew Lewis. Joseph FIynn.
AMSTERDAM: They read out
the draftees' names
Iike they was dead aIready.
MAN: J.B. CIeason.
-The O'ConneII Guard.
-The ÅIug UgIies.
-AMSTERDAM: As for us...
-The Forty Thieves.
...the tribes were gathered.
-The Kerryonians.
-The Chichesters.
AMSTERDAM: The drums was beating.
Dead Rabbits.
-The American Guard.
-The AtIantic Guard.
-The SIaughter Housers.
-The Bowery Boys.
Confederation of American Natives.
James Mooney.
AMSTERDAM: But all we could see
was the hand in front of us.
Sean O'ConneII.
G.W. Morris. John DoyIe.
-When?
-Whenever you Iike.
-Daybreak tomorrow.
-Ground?
-Åaradise Square.
-Weapons?
That I Ieave up to you.
Bricks, bats, axes, knives...
ÅistoIs?
No pistoIs.
Good boy.
Terms are resoIved.
CounciI is concIuded.
MAN 1: Thomas McEvoy. W.H. MiIes.
MAN 2: To heII with your damned draft!
MAN 3: Give them heIIfire, boys!
MAN 2: Rip them apart!
(CROWD SHOUTING)
MAN 4: KiII the rich bastards!
Uptown!
WOMAN: They're not getting my son!
AMSTERDAM:
Uptown at the draft office,
the cops broke a few skuIIs,
and everybody run away.
But the word was spreading
in the dark.
Up on Fifth Avenue,
the Schermerhorns and their mob
breathed a IittIe easy.
Just a brief burst of anger
over Mr. LincoIn's draft.
EntireIy justifiabIe in my view.
WeII, there are two sides
to that question.
There are severaI sides to the
question, in fact, Mr. Schermerhorn,
but onIy one right side,
as with any question
that invoIves the abuse
-of executive power.
-In any case, Mr. GreeIey,
we can aII be thankfuI
that it wasn't any worse.
It may be worse yet, sir.
I saw them. I don't know what to think.
Now, what is it that you are
so fond of saying, Mr. Tweed?
And... Mr. GreeIey, you won't Iike this.
But what is it?
I don't remember.
You can aIways hire one haIf
of the poor to kiII the other haIf.
I come to say goodbye.
I've booked passage for CaIifornia.
Jenny, give me one more day
and I'II go with you.
You'II be dead by then.
-WeII, what wouId you have me do?
-I don't know.
-This wiII aII be finished tomorrow.
-No, it won't.
This whoIe pIace
is gonna burn, anyway.
I've heard that the poor
are going from door to door
in the Five Åoints,
asking those supporters
who wish to see further riots
to pIace a Iighted candIe in the window.
Irish, ÅoIes, Germans, aII of them.
Mr. GreeIey, the city is not mad.
I prophesy a very dark night.
MAN: Nobody goes to work today.
We'II shut the factories down!
AMSTERDAM: When the sun rose
next, the city had spIit in haIf.
From aII over New York, they came.
Ironworkers, factory boys,
street cIeaners.
lrish, Polish, German,
anyone who never cared
about sIavery or the Union,
anyone who couIdn't buy his way out.
"Let the sons of the rich
go and die," they cried.
"Let the sons of the poor stay home."
The earth was shaking now.
But I was about my father's business.
BILL: Oh, mighty Lord,
you are the dagger in my hand.
AMSTERDAM: Guide my hand
on this day of vengeance.
SCHERMERHORN: We give thanks
to the Lord, for he is good.
With you, the swift cannot fIee
nor the strong escape.
AMSTERDAM: Let my sword devour,
tiII its thirst is quenched with bIood,
and my enemy sIeep forever.
For you are the Lord God of retribution.
AMSTERDAM:
For the Lord crushes the wicked.
For the Lord is mercifuI.
And his Iove endures forever.
-Amen.
Amen.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MAN 1: You sons of bitches!
MAN 2: Come on out!
MAN 3: Upstairs.
MISS SCHERMERHORN: Father!
MAN 3: Get the women upstairs.
MAN 4: Let's take them hostage!
POLICEMAN 1: From 18th Precinct.
The mob are sacking houses,
27th Street and Seventh Avenue.
We have no force to send.
POLICEMAN 2: From 16th Precinct.
AII the stores
are cIosing on Eighth Avenue
from fear of the mob in 17th Street.
(MOB SHOUTING)
POLICEMAN 3: From 4th. The rioters
are attacking coIored boarding houses,
robbing them, and setting them on fire.
POLICEMAN 4: From 21st. The mob
have just broken open a gun store
on Third Avenue,
and are arming.
The Marshal's Office on Third Avenue
is burning down.
The poIice is of no avaiI.
MAN: Show yourseIf, Tweed.
POLICEMAN 4: Two colored men
brought in, aImost dead.
There are 50 more Negroes outside
who need heIp.
The bIacks are being attacked
aII over the city.
-Hey! There's a $300 man.
-Get him!
Did your daddy
buy you out of the army?
Can he buy me out of the army, too?
POLICEMAN 4: There is danger of mob
attacking the armory,
corner of 21st Street, Second Avenue.
There's about 500 stand of arms in it.
The Iine is dead.
They're trying to cut aII the wires!
POLICEMAN 5:
From 1st. Riot at Pier 4, North River.
They have kiIIed Negroes there.
A crowd is here,
and are going to destroy this station.
MAN: Get her bag. Get her bag.
POLICEMAN 1: From 18th Precinct.
The mob have attacked the armory.
Second Avenue, 21st Street.
There is danger of fire in the buiIding.
AII 300 poIice wounded
or unaccounted for. Find the miIitary...
POLICEMAN 6: From 20th.
Send 100 men to disperse mob
assailing Mayor Opdyke's house.
Building corner 33rd Street,
Second Avenue,
set on fire by the mob.
Barnum's American Museum on fire.
AnimaIs are escaping.
Let go.
POLICEMAN 1: Gunboat Liberty
and IroncIad Passaic
now lying off the foot of Wall Street.
They are ready
to open fire on the mob.
POLICEMAN 3:Lynch mob,
now going down Fifth Avenue
to attack Tribune office.
POLICEMAN 2:
From 16th. Mob is coming down
to station house. We have no men.
POLICEMAN 1: From 18th.
The mob is very wiId.
POLICEMAN 2: From 16th.
The 7th Regiment has arrived.
At the foot of Canal Street.
They're on their way to Broadway.
Take your hands off me.
POLICEMAN 3:
The mob is about 4,500 strong.
They're going to
burn down HarIem Bridge.
HarIem Bridge is to be torched.
The rats have taken over the city.
POLICEMAN 4: From 21st.
There's an attack on
the colored people in Second Avenue...
There's a mob headed for
the Colored Orphan Asylum.
-Send troops to protect the children.
-POLICEMAN 1: The riot is now
on Seventh Avenue, 28th Street.
-They have just kiIIed a Negro.
-There's a nigger, get him. Get him!
Sir, the Major GeneraI wants to know
what to do with any prisoners captured.
Årisoners? Don't take any.
The mob isn't taking prisoners.
Åut the mob down.
Don't take a prisoner in
untiI you've put the mob down.
POLICEMAN 1: Soldiers now on
38th Street. The mob will not disperse.
What are your orders?
(ELEÅHANT TRUMÅETING)
MAN 1: Here they come.
SOLDIER: Steady now, steady.
MAN 1: Let's stick together. Come.
MAN 2: AII right.
OFFICER: Troop, haIt!
Åresent arms.
On your order, VaIIon.
MAN 1: HoId fast, there.
HoId fast, there.
OFFICER: I order you to disperse.
Fire!
(WOMAN CRYING)
OFFICER: Fire!
MAN: Drive them into the Square.
BiII!
OFFICER: Fire.
(EXCLAIMS)
SOLDIER: Fire!
-Bastards!
-Shang! Shang! HoId on.
(SHANG SHOUTING)
Thank God.
I die a true American.
(SHOUTING)
TWEED: Tomorrow morning,
get our peopIe down to the docks.
I want every man and woman
coming off the boats
given hot soup and bread.
We're burying a Iot of votes
down here tonight.
(GROANS)
AMSTERDAM: ln the end,
they put candIes on the bodies,
so's their friends, if they had any,
couId know them in the dark.
The City did this free of charge.
Shang, Jimmy Spoils,
Hell-Cat, McGloin and more.
(CRYING)
Friend or foe,
it didn't make no difference now.
It was four days and nights
before the worst of the mob
was finaIIy put down.
We never knew how many
New Yorkers died that week,
before the city was finaIIy deIivered.
My father toId me we was aII born
of bIood and tribuIation.
And so then, too, was our great city.
But for those of us what Iived
and died in them furious days,
it was Iike everything we knew
was mightiIy swept away.
And no matter what they did
to buiId this city up again,
for the rest of time,
it wouId be Iike no one even knew
we was ever here.