Movie & Captioning Synced By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You'll Like & Enjoy The Movie !!! "
Viv, I know there are only
three shopping days left, but they called...
and they want to see
your house i n an hour.
- && [ Rock ]
- Uh-huh.
- Mom! Make Buzz turn off the music.
- && [ Pop ]
- No problem.
- Mom!
- " Mom."
- Hang on, Viv.
- Let your sister rehearse.
- Like that'll help.
- And clean up the kitchen.
- But--
Now. Okay, Viv.
I'll seeyou in a bit.
I thought I told you
to clean up the kitchen.
- I did. Can I go to the movies
tonight with friends?
- No.
- No--
- No, no. I'm showing a house.
I need you to baby-sit Kevin.
- Why can't Megan do it?
- She has to go to rehearsal.
- You don't have to go to the movies.
- I do if I want a life.
You're baby-sitting Kevin.
Where is he, anyway? Kevin.
- What is it? What is it?
- [ Boy] A car!
- Whoa!
- [ Man ] Wait a second. That was--
Honey, that was mine.
[Buzz On TV]
Awesome. It's got an antenna and everything.
- [Dad] Merry Christmas, Mommy.
- [ Boy] Merry Christmas.
[ Mom On TV]
Merry Christmas.
- [ Dad] What did I get?
- [ Buzz ] What is this?
- [ Megan ] Thank you.
- [ Mom ] Everybody get in the shot.
- Everybody get together.
- [ Buzz ] Okay.
- [ Mom On TV ] Al I ri ght. Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas.
- Very funny, Buzz.
[ Mom Laughing On TV ]
- Last Christmas, huh?
- Yeah.
This Christmas isn't
gonna be any fun.
Of course
it will.
Honey, we're gonna do all
the same things we've always done.
Sing Christmas carols,
be with family and friends...
put cookies and milk
out for Santa.
- It's gonna be just the same.
- Except this year...
no Dad.
Right. That's the one thing
that's different.
Why can't you just
get back together?
[ Sighs ]
Honey, we're just gonna have to let that go.
- [ Chattering On TV]
- That's a no, right?
It means some things are
just out of our control.
I know you miss your dad.
And he loves me very much.
You both do, and it has
nothing to do with me.
- Did he tell you that?
- I'm nineyears old. I watch a lot ofTV.
Did he leave
because of me?
No. Of course not.
- I knew it. It was Buzz and Megan.
- [ Chuckles ]
Oh, it wasn't anyone...
or any one thing.
Then what was it?
That's not easy to explain.
But, uh, sometimes when...
people are married for a long time,
they get into kind of a rut.
- You know what a rut is?
- Yeah. Like, when people
aren't having any fun...
and they're really bored.
Kind oflike that.
Now, will you
come downstairs?
When you're ready.
[ Chattering On TV]
- Hey!
- [ Clapping ]
Wait a second.
- [Megan ] Kevin, come in here.
- [Buzz] Hurry,you've gotta see this!
[ Groans ]
Ow! Hey! Hey!
- You always fall for that.
- Let me up, zit-face!
- Lamebrain. When are you gonna learn?
- Get offyour brother.
- Andshouldn't you be rehearsing?
- [Kevin Grunting]
- How are you getting to the teen center?
- Ashley's mom's picking me up.
- [ Grunting Continues ]
- Can I please go to the movies?
No. I told you.
You're watching Kevin.
- Please let him go. I'll stay home alone.
- No.
- [ Scoffs ] I've done it before.
- Don't remind me.
You loused up
mywhole night.
And ifI'm gonna be miserable,
you're gonna be miserable.
- Mom!
- [DoorOpens ]
- [Man ] Hello. It's me.
- Dad!
- Hey, bigguy.
- [ Growls Playfully]
- I didn't know you were coming tonight.
- Oh, I thought I'd surprise you.
- Hey, Dad.
Hey, Buzz.
Oh, Kate. Gosh,
the place looks great.
Really nice decorations.
- Same as everyyear.
- [Kevin ]So, um...
Dad, why'd you
come tonight?
Actually, I want to talk to your mom
about something.
Privately.
- Do you think he wants to come home?
- Aw, Kev.
[ Huffs ]
- What?
- No " Hello, how are ya?"
Sorry. I have a business appointment, Peter.
What do you want?
Okay, gosh.
I wasn't gonna jump right into it, but--
Well, you know Natalie
and I are living together, and, uh...
well, when our divorce is final,
I'm gonna marry her.
Really?
You're getting married again.
Wow. That's, uh--
That--
[ Exhales ] Wow.
We've only been separated eight months.
Yeah, I-- It just happened real quickly,
and-- Listen, Kate...
I reallywant the kids to spend
a little time with me overthe holidays.
You want the kids for Christmas?
J ust a couple of days.
I want them to get to know Natalie better.
Oh, because she's gonna be
their, uh, stepmother.
Yeah.
Well, you're gonna
have to ask them.
I know.
- How am I supposed to see my friends?
- It's only a few days.
Well, duh, but that's just long enough
for me to fall out ofthe loop.
- Yeah, you can't expect us
to give up ourvacation.
- Well, Kevin?
There's a royal family
coming to visit.
Theyhave a son aroundyour age. You might
have a chance to play with a crown prince.
- A crown pri nce?
- Wouldn't that be cool?
- Yeah, way cool.
- And you guys wouldn't believe the room...
that Natalie has
set up foryou.
What do you say?
- I think I'm gonna pass.
- [ Exhales ]
It just wouldn't be right
leaving the family at Christmas.
- I'm sureyou understand.
- Yeah. Yeah, I do.
Well, it's-- it's
an open invitation, hmm?
And I won't be
back too late.
Sinceyou're staying home,
it wouldn't hurt to do some ofyour chores.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll make sure they get done.
Clean it, cheese-face.
Ow!
Oops.
My fault.
Hello, I'm home.
Hey.
- How'd it go?
- Awful.
I hate Buzz. I neverwant to be stuck
home alone with him as long as I live.
Oh, honey.
I know he picks on you.
Picks on me?
Humiliates me, tortures me.
I'm sick ofbeing everyone's
favoritejoke around here.
Yeah. Yeah,
it's hard to be the youngest.
Well, I hate Buzz.
I wish I didn't have a brother or a sister.
- You don't mean that.
- Yes, I do!
I wish I was
an only child!
Well, I'm sorry that
you're so unhappy.
Maybeyou should go toyour room
and think about whatyou have,
rather than whatyou don't have.
[ Scoffs ]
[ Sighs ]
Only children don't know
how good they have it.
Life would be perfect if
Buzz and Megan weren't around.
I mean, is it too much to ask for
a familywho actually likes me?
[ Sighs ]
I'd run away.
Ifl knew where to run to.
Hey, I do!
I have an open invitation.
[ CoinsJingling]
[Peter]
Can't get myseat belt unfastened.
[ Woman Laughs ]
[Peter]
Thanks, Alan.
Thanks.
Oh, what an incredible evening.
And not a bad night's work.
We raised over two million
for those children's charities.
Door, open.
And I am on the verge ofsigning
two ofthe biggest clients in Chicago.
That's because you're the best publicist
in the world.
- Doors, close.
- Have I remembered to thankyou
for telling everyone that?
Fire, light.
Not tonightyou haven't.
Perhaps I ought to
showmyappreciation.
- Music, on.
- && [ Classical Starts ]
- Curtains, close.
- [ Chuckles ]
Aw, nuts.Just when
things were getting good.
- Nice house, huh, pumpkin?
- Sure is, Marv.
You sure you don't wanna rob it?
No. No, I don't wanna rob it.
My robbery days are over. Darling, we're
moving up to the big money. All right?
The easymoney.
No middleman.
Pure profit. Strictly
a class operation, huh?
Three words, Vera.
Kid-- na-- pping.
I think that's only one word.
We're gonna wait for
the royals to arrive--
hup, dup, dodey-do--
and then we're gonna kidnap the prince.
[ High-pitched Voice ]
"Oh, don't kidnap me. I'm fancy."
You sure we can pull it off?
I mean, without
Harry making the plans?
Lookwhere Harry's plans
kept landing me, huh? In jail.
Well, not this time.
Because this time...
I'm the boss.
- [ Scoffs ]
- Who's the boss?
- You're the boss.
- I love being married. Eh?
- That's my girl.
- Hey!
Oh! Looks like
they got a visitor.
This where you want to go?
- Yeah, this is the place. Thankyou very much.
- [ CoinsJingling]
Keep the change.
It's all change.
[Snoring]
[Beep ]
[ Sighs ]
Who are you?
[ Gulps ]
[Man On Speaker]
Begyourpardon, ma'am.
Yes, Prescott?
Mr. McCallisterhas a visitor.
The young man claims to be his son.
Well, send him in.
- Kevin!
- Dad!
Hey! Oh! I thought
you said weren't coming.
Well, I started thinking, hey, it's not fair
if Mom gets all the kids for Christmas.
- [ Chuckling ]
- What's Christmas without kids, right?
Right. Hello, Kevin.
Hi, Natalie. I hope you don't mind me
just dropping in like this...
but my dad did invite me.
- Yes, I know.
- Is the invitation still open?
Ofcourse it is.
Molly, wouldyou come here, please?
I've been looking forward
to spending time with you.
Your dad talks about
you kids a lot.
Buzz is the troublemaker.
I'm the adorable one.
Oh. Ah, Molly.
This is Kevin McCallister, and he's going
to be staying with us for a few days.
Would you make up
the special guest room?
Ah, the special guest room.
Right away, ma'am.
- Oh, and Prescott, give Kevin a house key.
- Ifyou say so, ma' am.
What kind ofkey is this?
It's a key to the whole house.
This is a smart house, Kevin.
It does whateveryou tell it to.
Fire, out.
Curtains, open.
Wow! I think
I'm gonna like it here.
Go ahead. You try.
Door, open.
Wow! This stuff
is so cool.
Oh, mygosh!
This is such cool stuff!. Ah!
Oh! Look at this game!
This chair's
a remote control chair! Oh!
Oh,yeah!
This is so cool! Oh!
- Thinkyou'll be comfortable here?
- I'll say!
Thanks, Natalie.
This is gonna be the best Christmas ever!
Lights out, Kev.
Hey, Kevin?
Kevin.
How many times
can I lose this child?
- Kevin.
- [ Cell Phone Rings ]
- Hello.
- [ Peter] Kate, I...
wanted to let you know
Kevin just got here.
Oh, thank God...
he got there... safely.
- I was gonna call you, but uh--
- Are you okay?
Yeah. Yes, I'm fine.
Well, thanks for
letting him come.
- Well, thanks for calling.
- Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
[Molly's Voice ]
Goodmornin', Kevin.
Good morning.
- Who's there?
- Overhere, dear.
Hey. Hi.
Breakfast time.
Anything special you'd like?
Anything?
Anything.
- Wow!
- Sometimes I can't wait for Santa to come...
so I end up doing
some shopping bymyself.
- Would you like to open one?
- No, you're gonna spoil him.
Dad, it's her house. If she wants to spoil me,
she can spoil me.
All right. All right.
But just one.
And not...
the biggest one.
Does it really fly?
It really does,
but only outside.
- [Natalie ] We don't want to break anything.
- Wow! Thanks, Natalie!
Why do you have to leave?
It's so close to Christmas.
I know, but the royal family's coming
for one of Natalie's fund-raisers...
and it's myjob to make sure the event's
well-covered by press and photographers.
Hey, it's not gonna take that long, and I won't
have to work for the rest ofyourvacation.
And ifyou need anything, ask Prescott.
He'll take care ofyou.
It's a cool plane, huh?
I think she's trying
to buy my affection.
- [ Chuckles ] Kevin.
- What?
I'm not saying
it's a bad thing.
I'm glad you're here.
[Engine Starts ]
Mr. Prescott,
can I askyou a question?
- Yes.
- Can you make a milk shake?
Do you have chocolate?
What? Natalie said
anything I need.
- And you need a milk shake, do you?
- A chocolate one.
- Doyou thinkwe'll have a white Christmas?
- It seems highly unlikely...
given the recent
unseasonable temperatures.
What's this thing?
A mini elevator?
It's called a dumbwaiter.
- Why is it called a waiter?
- Because it carries food.
- Why is it called dumb?
- Because it doesn't speak...
or ask countless
idiotic questions.
[Machine Whirring]
- Can you read?
- [ Gasps ]
The door.
" No Entry."
- What, does that mean me?
- Especiallyyou.
This is the control center from which
I manage this entire household...
as well as
my personal quarters.
Miss Natalie may have
granted you run ofher home...
but this is my domain
and strictly off-limits.
Understood?
Any more questions?
Good.
&& [Humming]
Hey, Molly.
Whatcha doing?
Cleanin' the house.
- Gross.
- Oh, no, no. Not in this house.
Watch. Vacuum, on.
- Vacuum, off.
- Wow! The place even cleans itself!.
Want to see somethin'
really cool?
Open sesame.
Wow! This place is awesome.
[ Chuckles ]
Yes, it is.
- &&[Soul, Man Singing]
- [ Lip-synching ]
- [ Thud]
- [Prescott Groans ]
Music, off?
- Music, off.
- && [ Fades, Ends ]
I'm offto the store.
I'll be back in an hour or so.
And don't pick on
that dear child.
Door, open.
[ Marv]
She's out ofthe house.
All right.
The coast is clear.
- Let's go.
- Wait. Are you sure it's safe?
Pumpkin, would I take you
in there if it wasn't safe?
It's just ifthe prince don't arrive till tomorrow,
why are we going in there now?
To get the lay ofthe land.
What doya think, Vera...
we're just gonna go in there tomorrow
and start grabbing kids?
"Ooh, everybody
get in the van." No.
We gotta figure out the where,
the when, the how to get him out ofthere.
Doyou know the secret
to criminalsuccess?
Not getting caught.
Planning. Preparation.
Preparedness.
Be Prepared.
Be a prepared " preperator."
Eh? That's mymotto,
and that's whyI'm--
- A Boy Scout.
- No. The boss, eh?
- Who's the boss?
- You're the boss!
- Where's the boss?
- Right here.
- Hey. Boss, party of one.
- Right there.
All right.
Let's go, pookie.
No. It can't be!
It is! It's Marv!
Mr. Prescott?
Mr. Prescott, are you there?
Mr. Prescott! Help!
[ Gasps ]
Marv, the alarm is on.
Oh, no.
What are we gonna do?
Watch this, eh?
Oh.
- Alarm, off.
- [ Beeps ]
- Hmm.
- Door, open.
[Buzz]
- Ahh!
- That is one handy gadget.
Well, what's my motto?
You're the boss?
- Be Prepared. Yeah.
- Right.
I married a genius.
What doyou think that is?
Is that a turkeyball?
-Just put that down. Like a klepto here.
- All right.
- The prince should be staying
in one of these rooms.
- I think that's an elevator.
- Don't-- You give me such a headache.
- You give me a headache.
- You're giving me a headache.
- [Marv] Don't push me.
- Door, close.
- [ Whispering ] You're driving me crazy.
- You're driving me crazy.
- You're driving me--
- Oh, shut up.
Door, open.
- Door, close.
- I love this thing.
Marv--
The doorwas... shutting.
What's wrong with this thing?
Door, open.
[Marv Whispering]
I think there's somebodyhere.
Anybody in here?
- Well, not now. Shh!
- You shh!
[ Water Running]
Maybe the prince came early.
- [ Raspberry ]
- [Marv] What the--
[ Both Screaming ]
[ Groans ]
That's it. Come on.
Ow!
[ Groaning ]
[ Screaming ]
[WaterRushing]
- [ Gasping ]
- Up!
- [Marv] Come on, honey.
- Uh! Marv!
- [ Creaking ]
- [ Vera Gasping ]
[ Screaming ]
[Marv]
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Ay, ay, ay, ay, ay!
[ Vera Gasping ]
Mr. Prescott!
- You!
- Hello, Marv.
Well, long time, no see.
- Huh, kid?
- Is that the prince?
No, that's Kevin. Kevin, Vera.
Vera, Kevin.
If that ain't him, let's get outta here
before somebody sees us.
Yeah. I thinkwe got
the lay ofthe land.
I'll be back!
[ Yells ]
- Come on!
- Oh, all right!
[ Tires Squealing ]
- House, clean yourself up.
- [ Buzzes ]
Well, it was worth a try.
Okay, maybe
theywon't be too mad.
I mean, once I tell them what happened,
maybe they'll be okaywith it.
[ Screams ]
- Or maybe not.
- What-- What--
What-- What--
- [ Creaking ]
- What-- What--
Okay, I know
it looks bad, but--
- [ Screams ]
- Honey, what's the--
- [ Panting ]
- Kevin, what-- what-- what have you done?
Prescott! Prescott!
- It's not working. I tried.
- [Prescott] Yes, ma'am?
Get up here! Now!
- Well, it wasn't working.
- Kevin, what happened?
It wasn't me.
It was the burglars.
- The burglars?
- Yeah. And I recognized the one guy. Marv.
Did I evertellyou about him?
That's anotherstory.
But the point is theywere
gonna rip offyour house.
-So you chose instead to trash it?
-No. I was trying to protect it.
- By trashing it?
- What in the name of--
Hey, why didn't you come
when I was calling you?
Prescott...
wereyou aware of
anyburglars here today?
Burglars?
No, ma'am. All the alarms
were on as usual.
Maybe they turned 'em off.
They had one of these, you know.
I saw no intruders, and except for--
beg your pardon, ma'am--
the briefest ofbathroom breaks,
my eyes were on the monitors at all times.
How one child could do so much damage
in the time it took me to--
- Well, it's quite beyond me.
- It wasn't me!
Well, there was
no one else here.
- He's lying!
- Am not!
- Are too!
- With all due respect, sir...
I didsee MasterKevin
playing with the devices...
- as ifthe house were a big toy.
- [ Gasps ]
The only hooligan
here today was your son.
- [ Hyperventilating ]
- Give us a minute.
[Hyperventilating Continues ]
Kevin.
- Kevin, sit.
- Dad--
- What's going on?
- I told you. The burglars broke into the house.
Kevin, you know I can forgive
just about anything but lying.
Oh, right. So you wouldn't get mad
if I wrecked the place, which I didn't...
as long as
I admit that I did...
which I didn't?
Well, I thought
this over and, uh...
I understand that this is
a difficult adjustment foryou.
It's onlynatural thatyou'dbe acting out.
It's a need forattention.
- No, it isn't.
- Kevin!
[Natalie ]
Anyway--
Anyway,
what's a little damage?
It's not as if
I'm not insured.
Do you have something to say?
Thankyou.
- And?
- I'm sorry for the damage ofyour house.
[ Audio Rewinding ]
The security cameras must have
got the whole thing on tape.
What?
Prescott must have
turned offthe cameras.
[ Marv ]
It's unbelievable.
It is not to be believed!
I can't believe this!
It's the lousykidagain.
Everywhere I break into!
It's like he's stalking me
or something.
Come on, Marv.
He's just a little boy.
Yeah, well, I got
big scars from that little--
Never mind.
I'll tell you one thing...
this time he's
not gonna mess me up.
- Mm-hmm.
- This time it's all gonna go smooth as silk.
Because this time...
I got an inside man.
- [ Chuckling ]
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Tires Squeal ]
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- [ Horn Honking ]
- [ Marv ] Hey, come on!
Watch the road! Safety first.
- [ Screams ]
- What are you doing here?
- Tell me.
- I, uh-- I--
Nothing. I swear.
I thought all ofthis was cool.
I wanted to take a look at it.
You don't go to other people's homes
uninvited, and you don't touch their things.
Didn't I warn you what would happen
ifl ever caughtyou in here again?
Not specifically.
Trust me.
It won't be pleasant.
- [Knocking On Door]
- What doyou want?
I thought I heard
the boy. Ah!
And indeed I did.
I don't want him bothering you anymore,
so I'll just get him out ofyourway.
Come along, Kevin.
He'll be my responsibility
from now on.
Thankyou for
saving me, Molly.
Prescott is a good person
to stay away from.
You're telling me.
He's one ofthe bad guys--
the bad guys who
broke into the house.
Although technically they didn't break in,
because they had their own remote.
- And who do you think gave them that?
- Prescott?
- Mm-hmm.
- That sounds a bit far-fetched to me.
I know. And you probably think
I have an overactive imagination.
Most people do.
But you have to believe me.
Kevin, Prescott is a lonely man.
The only thing he has is this job.
Between you and me,
he hates working here.
- But to do what you're suggesting--
- Then it all makes perfect sense.
He hates his job, so he tries to pull off
a big heist so he can afford to quit.
- Ah, I don't know.
- Listen.
He told my dad I was lying
when I wasn't.
Andhe shut offthe security cameras.
So it can onlymean one thing.
- And that is?
- Marv and his new friend...
have an inside guy--
- Prescott.
- I thinkyou're right.
- I am?
- Yeah. You do have an overactive imagination.
But that's what I love
about children.
My own son was the same
as you atyour age-- a real handful.
You must have been
a great mom, Molly.
Well, you just try to keep
that imagination under control, okay?
&& [ Classical On Stereo ]
[Peter] You were veryunderstanding
about what happened today.
Well, Kevin's going through
a difficult time.
It's not easy
when your parents split up.
Believe me, I know.
But we'll get through it.
You're gonna be
a great stepmom.
&& [ Continues ]
[ Exhales ] I thinkwe just need to figure out
a way to make him feel more at home here.
Maybe do some ofthe Christmas things
he's used to doing, like trimming the tree.
- You do thatyourself?
- [ Chuckles ] Yes, I do that myself.
It's fun. That's exactlywhat we're gonna do.
We're gonna trim the tree.
It'll get us in the spirit
ofthings, unite us as a family.
- Okay.
- Okay?
No friends, no fun, no snow.
This is definitely gonna be
the worst Christmas ever.
Hey, Kev.
How you doing?
[ Sighs ]
What do you saywe forget
about today and start over, huh?
- You mean it?
- Yeah.
Natalie's really a great person.
You just gotta get to know her better.
I thinkwe should start having
a little more fun around here.
- I could live with that.
- Yeah?
Why don't we start
by trimming that tree?
- Now?
- Sure. Why not?
&& [Pop, Women Singing]
[Phone Rings ]
[Ringing Continues ]
Hello.
I can't hearyou.
Can you turn down the music?
- Music, off.
- && [Fades, Ends ]
What did you say?
Ofcourse we'll be there.
We wouldn't miss it.
- Let me call you back.
- [ Phone Beeps Off]
Evangelista's in town. Margaret's throwing
together a little impromptu supper...
but we shouldn't go,
should we?
Well, why don'tyou go ahead without me,
and Kevin and I will finish up over here?
Really? You wouldn't mind?
No. They'reyour friends anyway.
You're an angel.
I won't be home late.
Okay.
Where were we?
- You don't have to stay because of me.
- No, I want to stay. Really.
So, does Natalie go out
every night?
Pretty much. She leads a very exciting life--
more exciting than we're used to.
So you'd say
you're not in a rut?
No, I'm not in a rut. Why?
I thought maybe
that's whyyou left.
Kevin. Kevin, you know--
I didn't leave your mom
to be with Natalie, okay?
- That just kind ofhappened later.
- You wanna tell me about it?
[ Exhales ]
Adult relationships are just complicated.
Sometimes when two people get married
reallyyoung likeyour mom and I did...
you just end up
feeling kind of--
- You missed out on some things.
- Yeah.
Just 'causeyou grow up
on the outside...
doesn't mean you wanna
stop having fun.
I know all about
the inner child, Dad.
- Oh. You do, huh?
- That's why old guys drive sports cars.
You're probably right.
But the trouble with sports cars--
no room for anybody else.
Maybe one other person max.
But ifyou want to take a real road trip...
with luggage andall,
you don't even have room for a friend.
I mean, they're
cool and fast and all...
but who wants to be in a nice car
when you're all alone?
[ Kate Sighs ]
Well, that looks
just about perfect.
All that's left to do now
is put on the star.
Kevin always puts on the star.
That's right.
He does, doesn't he?
I always hold him up.
And then I give him a wedgie.
[ Chuckles ]
He makes a fuss. We all laugh.
Well, I guess we're just gonna
have to use the ladder this year.
Okay, Dad, you can
put me down now.
Wow. Looks pretty good.
I think it looks great.
I think it's
our best tree yet.
[ Peter On TV]
Hey!
[ Family Chattering ]
- Merry Christmas, Mommy.
- [Kevin ] Merry Christmas.
- [Kate On TV] Merry Christmas.
- [All Chattering]
Oh! Look at that!
- [ Kate ] Hey. Hey.
- [ Peter ] Hey.
[ Peter] I had this little
computer chip installed in Mom.
We're gonna get her
to make some breakfast.
- [ Yawns ] Morni ng.
- Morni n'.
Good morni ng, sleepyheads.
You're finally up.
What did you do
to our tree?
Oh, that's myfault. I have
a standing appointment with
the tree decorators everyyear.
In all the excitement,
I forgot to cancel.
Are you ever
gonna forgive me?
You undid our tree?
Well, it would have had
to come down eventually anyway.
Come on, Kev.
Look at all these presents, huh?
Oh, wait. Ooh, here's a big one.
I believe it has--
Yes, it has
your name on it.
Come on. Open it up.
It's from Natalie and me.
But shouldn't I open it
tomorrow on Christmas?
Ah, you got plenty to open tomorrow.
Come on. One won't hurt.
Go ahead.
- [ Gasps ]
- Super Spy bugging and listening device.
- Isn't that cool?
- Yeah. Thanks, Dad. Thanks, Natalie.
I'm glad you like it.
- Hey, Mom, where areyou going?
- I'm going to take Kevin some things.
- Mom, whereyou going?
- He doesn't have any clean clothes...
and I'm sure he doesn't have
anytoys to playwith.
To check out Dad's girlfriend.
Wanna go?
[Doorbell Rings ]
May I help you?
- Wow!
- I'm here for Kevin McCallister.
- Buzz.
- Are you here to take him home?
- No, I have something for him.
Right this way.
[Peter]
You should be able to hearthat.
- How do I sound?
- [ Kate On Headset ] Kids, stay close.
- Mom!
- Hey!
Hey!
Mmm! Ohh!
- [ Chuckles ]
- You guys remember Natalie, right?
- Buzz, Megan.
- Hi, Natalie.
Oh, and, uh,
Kate, this is Natalie.
- Natalie, Kate.
- Hello, Kate.
Hello.
So, areyou guys gonna stay?
- No, I just broughtyou some ofyour stuff.
- You guys gotta see this house.
- Is that okay, Natalie?
- Of course. Be my guest.
- Awesome tree!
- It used to look better.
- What is this thing on your head?
- A spy kit that Natalie got me
for an early Christmas present.
Really?
That was nice ofyou.
Well, I'm very fond
ofyour kids.
I've gotta showyou
this airplane she got me.
Would you like
a cup of coffee?
Oh, no, thankyou.
- I, uh, didn't know he would have
all this stuffto playwith.
- Yeah.
Oh, God. Hey.
Let me get that.
I wasn't even sure he could
even sleep without it.
Gosh. I cannot believe
he hasn't even asked for it.
Well, we could buy him
another stuffed animal.
- Oh, no, no.
- No.
This is, uh, his Teddy.
Teddy is his
transitional object.
Yeah.
Transitional object.
It's like something very, veryspecial
a child carries with him everywhere.
You're supposed to have a spare,
in case something happens to it.
- Ofcourse, we only had one, remember?
- Oh! How could I forget?
We were driving down the highway,
really in a hurry.
Kevin thinks, possibly Teddy
might want a little fresh air.
So he rolls down the window
and out flies Teddy!
He was ballistic.
He was crying. He was so upset.
It was-- Oh, my--
So Peter pulls over,
and I get out to retrieve the bear.
- I still can't believe you did that.
- [ Chuckles ]
Well, it was the slow lane,
and there wasn't much traffic.
Yeah, well, I don't know what
he would have done ifhe had lost it.
I think Kevin's going to have
so much fun playing with the prince...
that he's not even gonna
miss the stuffed animal.
It's going to be wonderful having a house
full ofchildren. I'm looking forward to it.
Children, watch
the garden sculpture!
Wel l, I... better get goi ng.
Before they break somethi ng.
Wel l, we're off to the airport
to pick up the royal family.
You all know
how important this is.
Now, the caterers
will be here momentarily.
And the guests will arrive
about an hour before...
- you and the royals
makeyourgrand entrance.
- [Molly] No need to worry.
Everything will be
taken care of.
- It's just that I want everything to go right.
- Come on. Let's not be late.
I don't want one single thing to go wrong.
Door, open.
And nothing will.
[People Chattering]
[Knocking On Door]
[Prescott]
Oh, good. You've finallyarrived.
- Mr. Prescott! Mr. Prescott! It's them!
- Hush, you.
- I 'll get him out ofyour way.
- Thankyou.
It's the burglars! It's the burglars!
Aah! Mr. Prescott!
[Kevin Yelling]
It's Marv!
I guess you already
knew that though.
Listen, you. I have just about had
enough ofyou and your melodrama!
This is a very important night, and if I have
to lockyou up to keepyou out of ourway...
- don't think I won't do it.
- Look!
Ow!
Ow! Ow!
Don't trifle with me,
you demon spawn!
Now that's a foolish place to hide.
[ Groans ]
One down, two to go.
[ Muffled ]
Let me out ofhere! Let me out ofhere!
It's freezing cold!
Let me out!
Kevin, haveyou seen Prescott?
- Not lately.
- Ah, typical.
Always poking around
when you don't want him...
- and when you need him--
nowhere to be found.
- [ Doorbell Rings ]
Ah! Guests already?
Whatever happened to fashionably late?
[Natalie ]
Well, I don't like to boast, but...
- yes, it will be the party ofthe season.
- [ Beep ]
Oh, I'm getting another call.
All right. See you there.
Hel lo? Carmel i na, how are you?
[ Mouthi ng Words ]
What? Oh, no!
They're snowed in.
Their flight's been canceled.
Wel l, so am I. Devastated.
Well, all right.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Merry Christmas.
[ Phone Beeps Off]
What are we gonna do now?
It's gonna be just an ordinary party.
Christmas Eve at your place
sounds anything but ordinary to me.
It's hardly the party
ofthe season.
Peter.
- What ifwe announce
our engagement tonight?
- Tonight?
I know we were gonna wait till
afteryour divorce was final...
but it's onlya few weeks away
andyourkids alreadyknow...
and it'll make tonight
so special.
Well, if it makes you happy.
Yes!
[ Chuckles ]
Where are those guys?
- Marv, I gotta tinkle.
- Vera, you can tinkle next week.
[ Marv On Headset ]
Always in a hurry.
Door, open.
All right.
Now, you remember the plan?
- Which plan? Harry's plan?
- What-- No! Not Harry's plan!
- The one involving rope and a bag!
- Why areyou yelling at me?
I'm notyell--
- Doyou remember the plan?
- Yeah.
- Now, when the prince comes up to bed--
- We bag him!
- That's right. We kidnap the kid napping.
- You're a genius, Marv.
That's right.
Door, open.
Now, the prince goes
in the bag.
- The bag goes out the window.
- Uh-huh.
We climb down the rope.
Door, close.
Right.
[ Marv On Headset ]
Everybody in the van.
And we're gone before
they know what hit 'em.
Beautiful plan, Marv.
Elegant in its simplicity.
All right. Let's tryit out.
Get in the bag.
Me? Why don't you
get in the bag?
Because I'm the boss.
Get in the bag, Vera.
- I don't wanna get in the bag.
- Vera, just get in the bag! Please!
You didn't tell me
I was gonna get in no bag.
I was saving it. It's gonna be fun.
Ooh, we're in the bag!
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Groaning ]
Nice. All right.
Window, open.
Ahh.
[ Grunts ]
[Vera ]
Uh, Marv. Ooh. Oh.
[ Grunts ]
Don't worry, honey. I got ya.
Marv! Let me down easy.
I always do, baby.
[ Straining ]
Shouldn't have had
that last piece of cake.
[ Yelps ]
[Rope Creaking]
- Perfect.
- Door, open.
[ Screams ]
- [ Groans ]
- Don't worry.
Everything's under control.
Uh, uh, Marv--
[ Screaming ]
- [ Thud]
- Easy...
but still way cool.
[ Marv Groaning]
Thanks for breaking
my fall, pumpkin.
[ Hoarse Voice ]
I always do, baby. Okay.
Get out and stay out!
- I know what you're trying to do.
- Oh, yeah, wise guy? What?
You're trying to
kidnap the prince.
Shut up,
ya little moron!
- I'm gonna kill him.
- Okay.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Raspberry]
Vera, honey.
Little help?
Oh, yeah, baby. That'd be great.
I sure could use it.
- [ Marv Groaning On Headset ]
- I got everyword.
[ Imitates Cheer]
&& [ Classical On Stereo ]
- Welcome back. Where's the royal family?
- Theywere snowed in.
- Ah!
- Where's Prescott?
- I can't find him anywhere.
- That's odd.
Well, Molly, make sure
everyone has champagne.
- We're going to make
a special announcement.
- Yes, ma'am.
- How areyou?
- Hi, how are you? Good to see you again.
Everyone, may I have
your attention?
Huh?
I am gonna kill that--
Uuh!
- [ Clattering]
- [Screaming]
This is always a special night,
and tonight may be even more special.
- [ Seething ]
- Get him!
- Peter and I are engaged!
- [ Crowd Exclaiming]
[ Screams, Shouts ]
- [ Teeth Chattering ]
- Prescott?
- [ Softly Moaning ]
- This could not be goin' worse.
Marv, you're on fire.
Oh, thanks, baby.
You're not so bad yourself.
No, sweetheart.
You're really on fire.
Well, I try to work out.
You know-- Aah!
Gaah!Aah!
- Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
- Kevin!
I'm not lying.
The bad guys are back.
We're not getting anywhere.
Kevin, I spoke to
all the caterers and to Molly.
Nobodysaw a thing butyou.
Now, how could that be?
I don't know.
But I heard they're gonna kidnap the prince.
- You heard them say that?
- Yeah, with mySuperSpybugging device.
- And Prescott's involved with the whole thing.
- This is absurd.
I'm going to call and make sure
the royal family's flight is okay for tomorrow.
Kevin, I know
what's going on here.
- You do?
- Yeah.
- You're out to destroy
my relationship with Natalie.
- What?
You knew how important tonight was to her,
and you went and pulled a crazy stunt like this.
- That's not the truth.
- I've given you a lot ofleeway...
because I know how tough
this divorce has been on you.
But tonightyou went
waytoo far.
I want you to go to your room
and think about what you've done.
And when you're ready to apologize to Natalie,
then we'll talk.
Door, close.
- Here you are, George! Merry Christmas!
- [Woman Crying]
[ Ringing ]
- Hello?
- Mom?
Kevin! Oh, Kevin.
I'm so glad you called.
Areyou okay?
Yeah, yeah. I'm just watching
It's a Wonderful Life.
- You are?
- You know how that gets to me.
- What channel is it on?
- Eight.
Ohh.
I guess I'm just a sucker
for happy endings.
So, how is your party?
Are you havin' a good time?
Yeah, it's all right. How aboutyou?
Havin' a good Christmas Eve?
Yeah. It's great.
[ Sniffles ]
- [ Sobs ] I loveyou, Kevin.
- Loveyou too, Mom.
[ Laughs ]
Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas.
- Okay. Bye.
[ Beeps Off]
[ Crying ]
[Knocking]
- Kevin, are you awake?
- Yeah.
Your father and I were a little rough
on you before. Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Because ifyou ever do anything like that again,
you'll be out ofthis house so fast...
your head will spin.
So your father's getting divorced. Boo-hoo.
Everyone's parents get divorced.
That's life. You'll get over it. But you're not
gonna come between your father and me.
He wants you in his life,
and I think that's admirable.
But ifyou want him in your life,
you better not cross me.
Understood? Good.
I'll have that window fixed first thing
in the morning. Sweet dreams.
[Man On TV] To mybig brother George,
the richest man in town.
[ Crowd Exclaiming]
I've just had
a nice little chat with Kevin.
I think we're beginning to understand
each other better. What are you watching?
It's a Wonderful Life.
They've been running it all night.
- Come on. Watch it with me.
- I 've seen it.
- So?
- So...
I don't understand people who
watch movies over and over again.
I saw it. I cried.
Once was enough.
You gotta be kidding.
Kate and I watch this everyyearwith the kids.
It's a familytradition.
- Well...
- [ Clicks Off]
now that you're going to have a new family,
maybe it's time for some new traditions.
They'll be back.
And if no one believes me...
I'll have to catch 'em myself.
[ Grunts ]
[ Marv's Voice ]
Shut up, you little moron.
[ Clicks Off]
[Keyboard Clacking]
Shut up, you moron.
- [Kevin ] Okay, stop.
- [ Beeps ]
[ Electronic Voice ]
Spin Faster.
[Keyboard Clacking]
[ Marv's Voice ]
Get in the bag. Shut up, ya bag!
- Christmas morning.
- Merry Christmas, Kevin.
- Merry Christmas, Dad!
- Hey, hey!
- Peter, are you ready to go?
- Go? Go where?
Kevin, Natalie and I gotta go
pick up the royal family right now.
Now? But aren't we
gonna open presents?
It's gonna have to wait
till we get back.
But it's Christmas.
And why doyou both have to go?
Look, you know how sometimes
you gotta do things you don't wanna do?
This is one ofthose times.
Hey, we'll be back before you know it, okay?
And I'm sure nothing will happen
while we're gone. Am I right?
- Right.
- Good.
Hang in there.
We won't be long.
- Door, open.
- [ Door Opens ]
[ Natalie ]
Merry Christmas, Kevin.
[ Door Shuts ]
Merry Christmas.
[ Cell Phone Rings ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Beeps On ]
Hello?
- No, we're awake.
- It wasn't me!
Shh! All right.
We're on ourway.
- [ Beeps Off]
- Oy. Sure makes me nervous.
Let's go, pookie.
I knewit. Here they come.
First step-- eliminate the inside man.
Oh, Mr. Prescott?
- Mr. Prescott, areyou in there?
- [Pounding]
- Yes.
- Mr. Prescott...
- can you help me with something?
- And what would that be?
- Another milk shake, perhaps?
- No. A bottle ofwine.
- Excuse me?
- Natalie said we need to get
some wine from the basement...
for the royal family.
Ifwe must.
So I guess you're right.
We're not gonna have
any snow this Christmas.
One can never go wrong
with low expectations.
You know, Mr. Prescott, it's been great
spending time with you these last few days.
Time flies when
you're having fun.
I know we got off to a bad start,
but things can be better-- much better.
- 'Cause you're down there, and I'm up here.
- Come get--
- [Pounding]
- Young man, open this door!
Let me out ofhere!
- Oh!
- Oh, boy! Am I glad to see you!
The kidnappers are coming.
But this time I'm one step ahead ofthem.
I locked thei r accom pl ice i n the basement.
I s this a perfect plan, or what?
It would be, dear,
except for one thing--
Prescott is not
their accomplice.
I am.
[ Gasps ]
You're-- You're the inside man?
- I'm afraid so.
- Hey, Mom.
We're here.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Mom? He's your son?
- I told you he was a handful.
- Aah! Hey! Get off of me!
- Oh, now, come on!
Isn't there a trapdoor
or something?
No. Not much demand for 'em
in a wine cellar.
Guess you're right.
Got any good ideas?
Not a one.
[ Sighs ]
- I do have a cell phone though.
- Perfect! May I?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
[ Beeping ]
[ Ringing, Beeps On ]
- Hello, Buzz?
- Kevin, is that you?
- Yeah. I'm calling from a cell phone.
- Oh, a cell phone.
Good foryou, puke-face. Is that another
present she gave you? What a showoff.
[ Beeps Off]
- I'll try again.
- [Keypad Beeping]
[ Ringing, Beeps On ]
Buzz, before you hang up, I need to
tell you something. I need to talk to Mom.
- Okay. You told me.
- [ Beeps Off]
- I'll try again later.
[ Sighs ]
Why in heaven's name did you
think I was the inside man?
Well, ifyou hadn't acted so strange,
I wouldn't have thoughtyou were... so strange.
And where wereyou the first time
these guys broke in?
Whydidn'tyou answerthe intercom?
Why didyou shut offthe cameras?
I didn't. But if those thugs
were using Molly's remote...
they could've turned off
the whole security system.
- But why'd you say I was lying?
- Well, because I thought you were.
And besides, I didn't want
Miss Natalie to know that I'd been...
well, napping on the job.
That woman. Ifshe could work me
24 hours a day, she would.
It's downright inhuman.
So, whenever she's not here, I, uh--
- You take advantage.
- I take a break.
A nice, well-deserved break.
With all the cameras and intercoms
turned off, I didn't notice anything.
- So I --
- You were covering your whoo-hoo!
[ Chuckles ]
Precisely.
- You want to try calling your mom again?
- Sure.
[ Ringing ]
- Hello?
- Mom?
- Kevin!
- [ Static ]
- Wait. Kevin, I can't hearyou.
- That's probably 'cause
I'm locked in a wine cellar.
No, I-- Honey, I can't hearyou.
There's too much static.
[ Yelling ]
I'm locked in Natalie's wine cellar!
- Areyou calling to say Merry Christmas?
- Mom, areyou there?
- Sweetheart?
- Areyou there, Mom?
- Kevin?
Mom? Mom?
[ Beeps Off]
Oh, great!
The battery's dead.
[ Sighs ]
Hmm.
[Ringing]
- [ Beeps On ]
- Kalban residence.
Hi, this is Kate McCallister, Kevin's mom.
May I speak to him, please?
- Kevin's not here right now.
- That's strange. He just called.
Really? Well, he's out with
his father and Miss Natalie.
Oh. Oh, he must have called from his Dad's
cell phone. That explains the line going dead.
Okay. Thankyou.
[ Clicks, Dial Tone ]
[Beeps Off]
Little rascal
called his mother.
- You want me to go show him who's boss?
- Sit down, Marv.
You're not the boss.
I'm the boss.
Okay.
[ Mouths Words ]
His cellphone is dead.
I don't think he'll be anymore trouble.
No.
Cookie.
- [ Cell Phone Rings ]
- Oh!
- [ Beeps On ]
- Hello?
Peter, it's me. I 'm calling Kevin back.
We got disconnected.
Kevin? Kevin's not with me.
He's back at Natalie's house.
Really? I was just told
he's with you.
Well-- Well, don't worry, Kate.
I'm sure everything's fine.
Okay.
- Wow, that's weird.
- [Phone Beeps Off]
- Someone told Kate that Kevin's with us.
- Hmm.
- Maybe I better go back and check on him.
- No.
That's exactlywhat he wants.
Peter, he's manipulating you.
Can't you see the pattern? Every time
we leave the house, he pulls something.
He's just trying to getyour
attention and sabotage me.
Hello!
Anybody out there? Hello!
There's gotta be something that
we can do to get outta here.
There is.
- Help me move these boxes.
- Okay.
But what's back there?
Definitely not
a "dumb" question.
- The dumbwaiter!
- Bingo.
- Let's hope it still works. -
I'm sorry I misjudged you, Mr. Prescott.
Likewise.
I'll never forget
Miss Natalie's reaction...
when she came home and saw
whatyou'd done to the house.
- [ Rapid Panting ]
- [ Wheezing, Laughing ]
I do love watching her hyperventilate!
[ Laughs ]
It's one ofthe few pleasures
ofthis job.
Ifyou hate this job,
why don'tyou quit?
Jobs aren't that easy
to come by.
Besides, I could end up
working for someone farworse.
You shouldn't stay someplaceyou hate
just 'causeyou're scared. Life's too short.
Hmm.
And voil.
Let's see ifyou fit.
Mm, up.
- Watch your head.
- As soon as I get up, I'm gonna letyou out.
- You just take care ofyourself, you hear?
- [Switch Clicks, Whirring]
[Marv]
I'm tellin'ya, I heardsomething.
All right.
Stay very alert here, Vera.
I tell you what. Why don't you go down,
check out the wine cellar?
- Okay.
- Yeah. There you go.
[Kevin ]
Down here!
You better stay-- Oww!
Vera! Ow! Aah! Vera!
- What? Ooh!
- Hit the button!
- Hang on, baby! Huuh!
- Oh! No, no! Hit the button!
- What? I can't hearyou.
- Hit the button!
- Oh!
- Oww!
No, no! Not that one!
The other button!
That's it! Oww!
Hey!
Man!
Over here!
- [ Groaning ]
- [Kevin Laughing]
- Hi, Mommy.
- [ Gasps ]
- Yes!
- [ Clicking Buttons ]
See ya. Door, open!
[ Grinding ]
Natalie, you go get the royals.
I'm gonna go back and check on Kevin.
- What, now?
- Yeah, somethin's up. I can sense it.
- Maybe you have to be a parent.
- That's not fair. You know
how much I care about kids.
How much do you care
about my kid?
Taxi!
Kevin? Are you all right?
[ Grunting ]
[ Horn Honking ]
Mom, do you thinkyou could slow down
a little bit? Kevin's probably fine.
You just keep an eye out
for cops, okay?
All right, Vera. Go check out the living room.
See ifhe's in there, all right?
God! I can't believe this.
I shoulda gone to college. Twoyears,
coulda been a dental technician. Twoyears!
Marv! He's in the bedroom!
- Mom?
- Get him!
Door, open.
Got ya.
Uuh! Gaah!
Aah!
Ooh!
Door, close.
- Hey, Molly!
- Get in there!
- Marv, honey. You in there?
- [ Beeps ]
- Shut up, Vera!
- Well, okay. I was just tryin' to--
- Shut up, you moron.
- Hey, I'm no moron, you jerk.
- Shut up, ya bag!
- Door, open!
- What's wrong with you?
I ain't no bag. And you know what?
You ain't no genius!
- Vera, honey--
- No! Don't "Vera, honey" me!
- Honey--
- You're not even as smart as this kid, who,
in case you hadn't noticed...
is totallykickin'ourbutts!
Well, from now on,
I am my own boss!
- Vera. Vera, honey--
- Don't " honey" me!
Pumpkin. Pumpkin.
Marv! Forget about her! Get the kid!
I'll be outta here in a few minutes.
[ Buzzing]
[ Thuds, Buzzing Stops ]
Oh!
[ Chuckling ]
Whoa!
[ Yelping ]
[ Both Groaning]
Hey! Hey!
Open sesame.
- Well, get a load of that.
- Holy majolie!
Come on, Vera!
All right! Come on out, kid!
Ah! All right.
- Open bar. Open bookshelf.
- [Buzzes ]
Open-- Open book-bar.
Open book-bar-shelf.
- Open-- Open book-bar-thing.
- Open sesame.
That's stupid.
Whoa!
- Who's stupid now, stupid?
- Hey, come on.Just get off me, all right?
[Marv]
I'm gonna take care ofeverything.
Bar, revolve sesame.
[Marv]
Watch this. It's all gonna be fine.
- Bar, stop.
- Oh! It's goin' faster!
Yeah, I know, Vera.
I know it's goin'faster.
- Speed faster sesame.
- Okay. The wife's not feelin'--
Faster sesame!
- [ Panicked Yelling ]
- Maximum speed sesame.
[Kevin Laughing]
Stop sesame.
[ Gasps ]
[ Screaming ]
Nice jump, Marv.
[ Groaning ]
Ohh!
[ Gasping ]
Oof!.
Merry Christmas to all,
and to all a good night.
- Good night. Aah!
- [Kevin Gasps ]
- Mr. Prescott!
- Atyour service.
- Boy, am I glad to see you.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Perhaps we should call the police.
- Good idea, Mr. Prescott.
Just " Prescott" to you.
" Prescott"!
- I thought you said you weren't worried.
- I don't know.
I just had a feeling.
- [ Marv, Vera Gasping ]
- [Peter] Kevin!
Dad!
- Mom!
- Mom?
- Who are they?
- Uh-oh!
- Let's get outta here!
- Around the back!
- We're on it. Let's go!
- Kevin!
Ooh-ooh!
Yes!
- Uuh!
- Yeah! Way to go, guys!
[Kate ]
Kevin!
- Kevin!
- Mom!
- Oh, honey! I'm so glad you're all right.
- Ohh!
- I am now!
- I'm so sorry I didn't believe you.
- Mmm!
- [Prescott Clears Throat]
The police
have been summoned.
I've got lots offun
planned foryour stay.
Can we go to Wrigley Field?
And the aquarium? Doyou have any kids?
No. But I promise we'll have
a very exciting time.
- [ Sirens Wailing ]
- Cool!
- Oh, come on. No, prison's not so bad.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah. On Thursdays you get Salisbury steak.
- Yeah, I know about prison.
- That's where I metyou.
- Calm down. Calm down.
- You calm down.
- Women, eh?
- Yeah.
- Hey, don't touch me.
- Peter! What's he done now?
- Well, he saved the day, that's what.
You should be thanking him.
Molly? What in the world
is going on?
It seems they were gonna kidnap the prince.
Best we can gather, she's the boss.
She's my maid.
I'm her boss!
Well, looks like you're
gonna have to find a new maid.
Anda newbutler,
I'm afraid.
- I resign.
- Resign?
But... why?
Because as a wise young man
once said, " Life's too short."
Peter, do something.
All right. Here goes.
Natalie,
I think I mistook...
infatuation andexcitement
forlove.
Look, this--
this is yourworld. It's not mine.
The whole time I was here,
all I did was miss my family.
I'm in love
with mywife and kids...
and I belong with them.
And I wanna come home. I mean, I
understand ifyou need time to think about it.
Mom?
- Oh!
- [ Crying ]
- I love you.
Young man, how are we ever
going to showyou our gratitude?
Would your family like to spend
Christmas with our family?
That sounds cool.
- Is that okay?
- [ Chuckles ] Yes.
You're going to be with them?
Today? On Christmas?
[ Crying]
[Panting]
Thankyou.
- Music, on.
- && [ Christmasy]
Snow, fall.
Ha ha! Hey!
I knew this was gonna be
the best Christmas ever!
[ All Exclaiming ]
THE END
Movie & Captioning Ripped By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You've Liked & Enjoyed The Movie !!! "