Man: IT'S A FUNNY THING.
NO MATTER HOW LOW YOU SINK,
THERE'S STILL
A RIGHT AND A WRONG,
AND YOU ALWAYS
END UP CHOOSING.
YOU GO ONE WAY SO YOU CAN TRY
TO LIVE WITH YOURSELF.
YOU CAN GO THE OTHER
AND STILL BE WALKING AROUND,
BUT YOU'RE DEAD
AND YOU DON'T KNOW IT.
[RECITINGOUR FATHER
IN SPANISH]
I WAS COMING THROUGH TEXAS
ON MY WAY TO MEXICO.
I NEEDED SOME TIME
TO HIDE OUT.
I HAD SPENT MOST OF MY LIFE
ON THE DODGE.
DRUNK OR SOBER,
I GOT NO COMPLAINTS,
EVEN IF I DID GET MY HANDS
DIRTY ON THE WAY.
JERICHO...
WAS A JERKWATER TOWN
MAYBE 50 MILES FROM THE BORDER.
DIRT STREETS,
RAMSHACKLE BUILDINGS.
ONE THING FOR SURE,
YOU COULDN'T FIND IT
ANYWHERE ON THE MAP.
FOR THE MOST PART,
I WAS A BIG-CITY GUY.
I LIKE PAVEMENT
UNDER MY FEET
AND BRIGHT LIGHTS
AFTER THE SUN GOES DOWN,
BUT I FIGURED
THIS LITTLE BURG
WAS JUST THE KIND OF PLACE
YOU GASSED UP THE CAR,
GOT SOMETHING TO EAT,
AND IF YOU GOT STUCK,
MAYBE SPENT A NIGHT.
THEN I GOT A LOOK AT HER,
AND THAT'S WHEN
ALL THE FUN STARTED.
IT'S NOT A GOOD IDEA
TO BE LOOKING
AT MR. DOYLE'S GIRL
THAT WAY.
I REMEMBER
A GUY ONCE TOLD ME
THIS IS A FREE COUNTRY.
JOCKO, THIS GUY
THINKS IT'S
A FREE COUNTRY.
NOW YOU'RE FREE TO GO.
[PUNCTURES TIRE]
SHERIFF'S OFFICE
IS RIGHT OVER THERE
IN CASE YOU WANT TO
COMPLAIN ABOUT ANYTHING.
YOUR LIGHT'S OUT.
I SEEN IT,
RIGHT OUTSIDE
THE WINDOW.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M GOING TO DO
ABOUT IT?
NOT A GODDAMN THING.
BUT I KNOW WHAT
YOUOUGHTTO DO.
YOU OUGHT TO
GET YOU A SPARE,
PUT IT ON YOUR CAR,
AND JUST DRIVE ON
OUT OF TOWN.
AIN'T THAT RIGHT,
BOB?
YOU GOT TO FORGIVE
OLD BOB.
HE AIN'T MUCH
FOR TALK. HA HA!
OH, HOLD IT.
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
IF YOU'RE
REALLY PLANNING
ON STICKING AROUND,
DON'T BE COMING
TO ME FOR HELP.
YOU'RE ON
YOUR OWN HERE.
WE ALREADY GOT
A FELLA IN THE WINDOW
OF THE UNDERTAKER.
DO YOURSELF A FAVOR:
FIRST THING,
GET A FIREARM.
FIRST CUSTOMER
I SEEN ALL WEEK.
WANT A WHISKEY
OR A BEER?
DON'T HAVE
MUCH ELSE
TO OFFER.
WHISKEY.
YOU UNDER PROHIBITION?
OH, WE DON'T PAY
MUCH ATTENTION
TO IT HERE.
YOU GOT A PHONE
IN THIS PLACE?
WHO YOU
WANT TO CALL?
MY MAMA.
[SNORTS]
HA HA HA HA!
SURE, WE GOT PHONES,
BUT THEY AIN'T
WORKIN',
SINCE YOU GOT TO HAVE
A SWITCHBOARD OPERATOR
TO RUN THEM.
YOU GOT
ELECTRICITY?
YEAH. GOT THAT.
RUNS ON
GAS GENERATORS.
HOPE THEY
STAY WORKING.
NOBODY LEFT
TO FIX THEM
IF THEY GO BUST.
TELL THE TRUTH,
MOST OF WHAT THEY CALL
DECENT FOLKS
HAVE BEEN RUN OFF.
REALLY AIN'T
MUCH LEFT HERE
BUT A GHOST TOWN.
SOME DAMN SHERIFF,
MAKING A PROFIT
JUST STAYING
IN THE MIDDLE,
GRAFTING OFF BOTH SIDES.
I THINK MR. DOYLE
BOUGHT HIM OFF FIRST,
OR MAYBE IT WAS
STROZZI.
WHO'S STROZZI?
OH...
THAT'S THE OTHER GANG HERE.
STROZZI AND
THE ITALIAN FELLAS.
BOTH GANGS
TOOK OVER THIS TOWN,
RUN OFF
ALL THE REGULAR FOLKS.
COME FROM THE SAME
BIG CITY,
BUT THEY DON'T
LIKE EACH OTHER MUCH.
BOOTLEGGERS.
YOU GOT STROZZI
AT THE SWEETWATER
AND DOYLE'S BUNCH
DOWN AT THE ALAMO.
THEY LEAVE ME BE
BECAUSE I STAY
TO MYSELF.
THEY THINK I'M CRAZY.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
I'M GOING
TO GO SEE THE FELLAS
THAT WRECKED MY CAR,
HAVE A LITTLE TALK
WITH THEM.
I HADN'T GOTTEN
A REAL WARM RECEPTION,
BUT I STARTED THINKING
MAYBE THIS WAS MY LUCKY DAY.
A CROOK FOR A SHERIFF
AND 2 BOOTLEGGER OUTFITS
THAT HATED EACH OTHER.
IF I PLAYED IT RIGHT,
I COULD MAKE SOME EASY MONEY
AND MOVE ON.
MA'AM.
I THOUGHT I MADE IT
REAL CLEAR
WHO YOU CAN AND CAN'T
BE LOOKING AT
AROUND HERE.
THAT'S MR. DOYLE'S
PROPERTY.
I CAME HERE
TO SEE YOU.
YEAH?
YEAH.
DID YOU GET
THAT CAR OF YOURS
FIXED YET?
I'M RUNNING A LITTLE
LOW OF CASH.
I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU COULD MAYBE
HELP PAY THE DAMAGES.
I GUESS MAYBE YOU'LL
HAVE TO KILL ME.
IT'LL HURT IF I DO.
YOU TELL MR. DOYLE
IF HE'D HAVE HIRED SMARTER GUYS,
NONE OF THIS
WOULD HAVE HAPPENED.
Man: IT'S ALL
ABOUT BOOZE.
GETS SMUGGLED
THROUGH HERE
FROM MEXICO.
WE'RE PART OF
A FAMILY OPERATION
IN CHICAGO.
SO WHAT WE GOT HERE
IS CLOSE TO A CIVIL WAR,
EXCEPT NOW
WE GOT A TRUCE.
IT WAS MY GUESS,
THIS TRUCE
AIN'T GONNA LAST,
ESPECIALLY
AFTER HICKEY GETS BACK.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HERE.
WHO'S HICKEY?
HICKEY IS DOYLE'S
RIGHT-HAND MAN.
HE'S A SWEETHEART,
THIS GUY.
LOOKS LIKE SOMEBODY
CARVED HIM UP
FOR SUNDAY DINNER.
[HOARSELY]
TALKS LIKE THIS.
FORGET IT.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
YOU GOT A NAME?
HUH?
SMITH.
WHAT, SMITH WHAT?
WHAT, YOU GOT
A FIRST NAME?
JOHN.
Man:
JOHN SMITH.
HA! JOHN SMITH.
THAT'S A GOOD ONE.
YOU ON THE RUN,
HUH?
WHERE ARE YOU FROM,
MR. SMITH?
BACK EAST.
JOHN SMITH
FROM BACK EAST.
ALL RIGHT.
I HEARD YOU WANTED
TO SEE ME.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT?
DID I INTERRUPT
SOMETHING IMPORTANT?
SHE WAS
DOING HER NAILS.
WELL, THIS IS LUCY.
YEAH, SHE A REAL
NICE GIRL.
SHE A REAL PRETTY GIRL.
SHE GOT A BIG MOUTH,
BUT SHE'S GOING
TO KEEP IT SHUT
AND ACT VERY FRIENDLY
NOW, RIGHT?
LUCY, WOULD YOU PLEASE
TAKE MR. SMITH
TO HIS ROOM?
Lucy: SO I GUESS
STROZZI HIRED HIMSELF
ANOTHER BUM.
GOT IT ALL
FIGURED OUT, DO YOU?
YEAH. I'M
A FORTUNE-TELLER.
DON'T WORRY.
WORKING FOR STROZZI
HAS ITS ADVANTAGES.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE
YOUR ROOM.
Smith: THE SKIRT WAS FROM
JUST OUTSIDE OF CICERO.
STROZZI TOLD ME
HE HAD HER SENT DOWN HERE
TO KEEP UP HIS MORALE,
BUT THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
I EVER HEARD IT CALLED THAT.
YOU TRY AND KEEP IT
DOWN UP HERE, OK?
MY ROOM'S
RIGHT UNDERNEATH.
I'LL TRY NOT TO MAKE
TOO MUCH NOISE
WHEN I'M JUMPING
UP AND DOWN ON THE BED.
Smith: SUNDAY DINNER
WAS A REAL EVENT.
STROZZI MIGHT HAVE BEEN
A SMALL-TIME HOOD,
BUT HE TRIED TO RUN THINGS
LIKE HE WAS SOMEBODY IMPORTANT
BACK IN CHICAGO.
HE HAD AN ARMY
OF 20 SHOOTERS.
AS FAR AS I COULD SEE,
MOST OF THEM WERE GOOFBALLS.
IT WAS ALL
RIGHT OUT OF SOME DIME NOVEL.
Strozzi:
HOW'S THE FOOD?
Smith: GOOD.
HUH? I BROUGHT
THESE MAMAS
IN FROM CHICAGO.
FOOD HERE
WAS TERRIBLE.
IT'S GOOD, HUH?
YEAH. I LIKE GARLIC.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT IS THIS? NOBODY WAITS?
Strozzi:
YOU'RE LATE.
I HAD IMPORTANT BUSINESS.
WHILE YOU WERE DOING
YOUR IMPORTANT
BUSINESS,
THINGS
ARE HAPPENING.
WE NOW HAVE
A NEW EMPLOYEE.
MR. SMITH, THIS IS
GIORGIO CORMONTE.
KILLED FINN.
THAT'S DOYLE'S BEST GUY
NEXT TO HICKEY.
NO?
I KNOW ALL ABOUT IT.
AND YOU HIRE HIM.
YEAH.
YEAH, WHAT DO YOU THINK
THAT LOOKS LIKE TO DOYLE
IN KEEPING A TRUCE?
YOU WANT TO TIP
DOYLE OFF?
PLUS, WHO THE HELL
IS HE?
DOYLE'S GUYS
ARE SCARED OF HIM.
HELL, HE WAS IN TOWN
20 MINUTES,
HE KILLED ONE OF THEM.
DOYLE AIN'T GONNA
DO A GODDAMN THING
WITH HICKEY OUT OF TOWN.
THE ONLY THING
THAT COCKROACH MIGHT TRY
IS TO HIRE THIS GUY
FOR HIMSELF.
YEAH, WELL,
I DON'T LIKE IT.
I DON'T LIKE CHANGES
AT THE LAST MINUTE,
AND I DON'T LIKE
NEW FACES--
YOU GOT A PROBLEM
WITH ME, GIORGIO,
YOU TAKE IT UP
WITH YOUR BOSS.
I JUST WORK HERE.
Smith: SO I DECIDED TO GIVE UP
MY FREE ROOM.
I HAD SEEN THE REAL THING,
AND THESE GUYS
WERE A LONG WAY FROM IT.
I WASN'T SURE IF HE WAS GETTING
A WOODEN BOX READY FOR ME
OR IF HE JUST WANTED
TO SAY THANKS FOR THE BUSINESS.
WELL, LOOK
WHO'S HERE.
LAST TIME I SAW YOU,
YOU WAS GONNA HAVE
A TALK WITH SOME FELLAS.
NEXT THING I HEAR,
ONE OF THEM'S DEAD.
CONVERSATION
SORT OF WENT DOWNHILL.
AIN'T THAT RIGHT, BOB?
HE DON'T TALK MUCH,
BUT HIS EARS WORK GOOD.
YOU GOT A ROOM
YOU CAN RENT ME?
I'M SURPRISED YOU AIN'T
STAYIN' WITH YOUR FRIENDS
AT THE SWEETWATER.
THERE'S A ROOM UPSTAIRS.
TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I CAN USE THE MONEY.
YOU GOT A NAME?
MINE'S JOE.
OK, JOE.
[COUNTING MONEY]
YOU LET ME KNOW
WHEN THIS RUNS OUT,
AND I'LL GIVE YOU
SOME MORE.
YES, SIR.
YOU GOT GIRLS
FOR HIRE
IN THIS TOWN?
HELL, YES.
YOU IN WEST TEXAS.
ROUND THE CORNER,
THIRD DOOR ON THE LEFT.
YOU CAN CERTAINLY
AFFORD THEM.
YOU REMIND ME OF THIS GUY
THAT USED TO COME SEE ME
WHEN I WORKED
IN NEW ORLEANS.
HE LOOKED A LOT
LIKE YOU.
YOU EVER BEEN
TO NEW ORLEANS?
HE WAS NICE.
HE WASN'T AS QUIET
AS YOU, THOUGH,
BUT YOU TWO ALMOST
LOOK LIKE BROTHERS.
EXCEPT HE HAD TATTOOS.
I THINK THAT HE
WAS IN THE NAVY,
BUT, UH...
NO.
AND HE USED TO COME
AND SEE ME
EVERY FRIDAY
OR SATURDAY NIGHT.
HIS NAME WAS CLARENCE.
I HAD A LOT OF FUN
IN NEW ORLEANS.
SORRY I EVER CAME
TO THIS LOUSY TOWN.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO DO HERE.
...SO I TOOK EVERY KIND
OF DANCE CLASS IMAGINABLE
BECAUSE I WANTED--
UHH--TO BE A DANCER,
AND SO I CAME HERE
BECAUSE IT'S OFF-SEASON--
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
Man: COME ON,
GET OUT OF HERE, GIRLS!
GO! GO!
I DIDN'T HAVE NOTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
WHAT?
I DIDN'T HAVE
NOTHING--
WHO SET ME UP?
WHO?!
THEY FORCED ME!
THEY SAID THEY'D KILL ME.
I DIDN'T HAVE
NO CHOICE.
GIVE ME A NAME.
GIVE ME A NAME,
GODDAMN IT!
IT WAS A GUY
THAT WORKED FOR DOYLE.
IT WAS DOYLE'S BUNCH.
PLEASE DON'T TELL THEM
I TOLD YOU.
SHUT UP!
PLEASE.
I'M SORRY.
Smith: HER NAME WAS WANDA.
CROSSING ME
WAS NOTHING PERSONAL.
SHE WAS JUST TRYING
TO MAKE A LIVING
IN A WORLD WHERE BIG FISH
EAT LITTLE FISH.
COME ON.
BY THE TIME THE LAW SHOWED UP,
I WAS LONG GONE,
BUT THE SHERIFF
DIDN'T LET ME DOWN.
HE INVESTIGATED
THE WHOLE THING,
THEN ARRESTED
THE HOOKER.
Lucy: I WENT DOWN
TO THE RED BIRD
AND ASKED THAT OLD GEEZER
WHO RUNS THE PLACE
WHERE I COULD FIND YOU.
WHERE ARE WE HEADED?
A JUKE JOINT
OUTSIDE OF TOWN.
STROZZI WANTS
EVERYBODY THERE.
HE'S GOING TO MAKE
ANOTHER SPEECH?
HE DON'T KEEP ME
TOO WELL INFORMED.
GIORGIO'S ALWAYS ACTING
LIKE HE'S IN CHARGE
BECAUSE HE'S THE SON
OF SOMEBODY IMPORTANT--
STROZZI'S BOSS IN CHICAGO.
STROZZI AND GIORGIO
ARE REALLY COUSINS.
STROZZI DON'T
ADMIT IT, THOUGH.
NOT A FAMILY MAN.
WHERE DOES THAT
LEAVE YOU AND HIM?
Smith: CELINA'S WAS
A FAST 20 MINUTES
OUT ACROSS THE DESERT.
2 STORIES OF WOOD
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
IT WAS THE KIND OF PLACE
THAT LOOKED LIKE THE SPECIAL
WAS CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
STROZZI TOLD ME
THAT GIORGIO
AND THE OTHER GUYS
GOT A REAL HOT HEAD
ABOUT THE KIND OF MONEY
YOU'RE GETTING.
GIORGIO DON'T
LIKE YOU TOO MUCH,
IN CASE YOU
HAVEN'T NOTICED.
WHY DOES A GUY
SEND HIS GIRLFRIEND
TO COME FIND ME?
STROZZI FIGURES
I WOULDN'T BE
DUMB ENOUGH
TO DO ANYTHING
OUT OF LINE,
SO HE SENT ME.
WELL, THAT MUST
MAKE YOU FEEL
REAL PROUD.
QUIT BEING
A SHITHEEL,
ALL RIGHT?
I GET ENOUGH OF THAT
FROM STROZZI,
THANK YOU.
YOU SURE YOU'RE
NOT DUMB ENOUGH
TO DO ANYTHING
OUT OF LINE?
I'M JUST CURIOUS.
YOUR BOYFRIEND
GOT A FIRST NAME?
YEAH.
BUT ONLY
IN THE BEDROOM.
Smith: AS USUAL,
SHE WAS TRYING TO ACT TOUGH,
BUT ANYBODY COULD SEE
IT WAS PAPER-THIN.
EVEN WITH A SECOND-RATER
LIKE STROZZI,
SHE WAS IN
WAY OVER HER HEAD.
WELL, FOR CHRIST'S SWEET SAKE.
IT TOOK YOU TWO LONG ENOUGH.
KISS MY ASS.
IT'S RAINING OUTSIDE,
GIORGIO.
HARD TO DRIVE
IN THE RAIN.
LIKE HE SAID,
WHAT TOOK YOU
SO LONG?
MAYBE YOU DON'T
HEAR TOO GOOD--
IT'S RAINING.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU'RE GETTING TO BE
MORE OF
A WISE-ASS POLACK
EVERY DAY,
AND IT AIN'T
SO CUTE NO MORE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
HAPPENS TO WISE-ASS
POLACK DAMES?
THEY GET THEIR
WISE ASSES KICKED!
WHEN I WAS IN
THIS WHOREHOUSE,
DOYLE SENT A COUPLE GUYS
TO VISIT ME.
I HAD TO KILL THEM BOTH.
YOU KILLED 2 MORE
OF DOYLE'S GUYS?
IS THAT BULLSHIT,
OR IS THAT TRUE?
LOOK, I DON'T GIVE
A DAMN ABOUT DOYLE.
IF HE LOST
2 MEN TONIGHT,
THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
THIS DOYLE,
HE'S TRYING
TO OUTBID ME
WITH
MY OWN SUPPLIERS,
MICK BASTARD.
YEAH, I TRY TO DO
BUSINESS WITH HIM,
IT'S BULLSHIT.
NOW, WE GOT
A SHIPMENT COMING IN
FROM MONTERREY
NEXT WEEK.
MR. DOYLE HAS GOT
ONE COMING IN
TOMORROW.
THIS IS WHERE YOU'RE
GOING TO START
TO EARN YOUR PAY.
Strozzi: THAT'S 5 TRUCKS.
MAYBE 200 CASES.
WE DELIVER
200 BUCKS A CASE.
THAT'S 200 GRAND
IN OUR BOOKS.
PLUS, YOU KNOW WHAT'S
REALLY THE FROSTING?
WE GET DOYLE'S TRUCKS.
YOU KNOW HOW HARD IT IS
TO BUY A TRUCK IN MEXICO?
Smith: WE CROSSED THE BORDER
A COUPLE HOURS BEFORE DAWN.
STROZZI HAD COME UP WITH A PLAN
THAT HE THOUGHT
WOULD MAKE HIM LOOK GOOD
TO THE BIG BOSS
BACK IN CHICAGO.
IT INVOLVED HIJACKING, MURDER,
CORRUPTION OF THE MILITARY,
AND STICKING ME
RIGHT OUT FRONT.
WHO IN THE HELL
ARE YOU SUPPOSED
TO BE?
THIS MIGHT BE A GOOD TIME
FOR YOU GUYS TO GIVE UP.
BUENO, AMIGOS.
ENSENEN
NUESTRAS ARMAS.
WHAT THE HELL'S
THIS?
I TOLD YOU
WE COULDN'T TRUST
THESE MEXICANS.
I'M GOING TO SEND SMITH
BACK WITH SANTO
TO KEEP AN EYE ON DOYLE.
YOU STAY WITH THE TRUCKS
TILL THEY GET
TO MATAMOROS.
MATALOS.
Smith: IT WAS A MASSACRE.
COULDN'T SAY
I WAS REAL SORRY,
BUT IT WAS A ROUGH WAY
TO CHECK OUT.
Sheriff: NOW,
I DON'T KNOW
HOW RELIABLE
SHE'S EVER
GOING TO HOLD UP
AS A WITNESS.
SHE'S SOME KIND
OF A VAGRANT.
MIGHT EVEN
BE HERE FOR
IMMORAL PURPOSES.
HOW MUCH
TO GET HER OUT?
OH, 100 WILL
SEND HER ON HER
WAY RIGHT AWAY.
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT HOW DOYLE'S MEN KNEW
I WAS AT THAT WHOREHOUSE.
I FIGURE YOUR DEPUTY HERE
HEARD ME LAST NIGHT
AT THE RED BIRD,
CAME OVER HERE
AND TOLD YOU ABOUT IT,
AND YOU SOLD
THE INFORMATION TO DOYLE.
HOW AM I DOING
SO FAR, SHERIFF?
WELL, YOU ARE ONE
SUSPICIOUS FELLA.
AIN'T HE, BOB?
MAYBE I WAS A LITTLE
ROUGH ON YOU LAST NIGHT.
MAYBE I SHORTCHANGED YOU.
IF I WAS YOU,
I'D GET OUT OF HERE.
DOYLE'S MEN
ARE GOING TO THINK
YOU TIPPED ME OFF.
YOU GOT A BUS
COMES THROUGH THIS TOWN?
Sheriff: YEAH.
AT NOON EVERY DAY.
MAKE SURE
SHE GETS ON IT.
I GOT SOME INFORMATION
YOU MAY WANT TO SELL
TO MR. DOYLE.
HE'S GOING TO FIND OUT
SOON ENOUGH,
BUT YOU MIGHT BE
THE ONE TO GIVE IT TO HIM.
A SHIPMENT OF BOOZE
HE HAD COMING UP
FROM MEXICO
GOT HIJACKED
BY SOME BANDITOS.
A TIP LIKE THAT
OUGHT TO BE WORTH
AT LEAST A GRAND.
YOU BETTER BE RIGHT,
BECAUSE IF DOYLE SHOULD
SEND HICKEY AFTER ME,
HE'S COMING
DIRECTLY FOR YOU.
YEAH. I KEEP
HEARING ABOUT HICKEY.
SOUNDS LIKE
A REAL SCARY GUY.
LET ME TELL YOU
JUST HOW SCARY.
IT GOES THAT WHEN
HE WAS 10 YEARS OLD,
GETS A BUTCHER KNIFE
AND CUTS HIS FATHER'S
THROAT FROM EAR TO EAR.
THEN THEY STICK HIM
IN AN ORPHANAGE.
15 YEARS OLD, HE BURNS
IT TO THE GROUND.
YOU JUST MAKE SURE
YOU MARK ME DOWN FOR
HALF OF THAT THOUSAND.
THINK MAYBE
YOU AND I SHOULD TALK.
I DON'T THINK THESE
PEOPLE APPRECIATE YOU.
YOU GOING TO BE
MY HERO?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
JUST A GUY WHO DID
THINGS FOR MONEY.
YEAH. I'M JUST A GUY
THAT DOES EVERYTHING
FOR MONEY.
ANYBODY SEE YOU
COME UP HERE?
NO.
APPRECIATE ME?
YOU DON'T KNOW THE HALF OF IT.
LET ME TELL YOU,
I DON'T HAVE TO TAKE IT
FROM THESE BASTARDS.
GOING BACK TO CHICAGO
ON THE FIRST THING OUT
OF HERE THAT MOVES.
[CHUCKLING]
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
YOU'RE NOT GOING
ANYWHERE.
YOU'RE JUST BLOWING OFF
A LITTLE STEAM.
OH, YEAH? YOU HEAR
THE WAY STROZZI
TALKED TO ME?
THAT GREASE BALL?
TO HELL WITH HIM.
YOU KNOW,
STROZZI'S OUT OF
TOWN FOR THE DAY.
SO IS GIORGIO.
SO?
DID STROZZI TELL YOU
HE'S PAYING ME
A LOT OF MONEY?
WELL, THERE MAY BE
A WAY FOR YOU
TO GET YOUR HANDS
ON SOME OF IT.
YOU GOING TO TELL ME
WHY YOU WOULD DO
SUCH A NICE THING?
BECAUSE I'M
A NICE GUY...
A SWEET GUY.
YEAH, RIGHT.
LIKE I SAID...
I DON'T THINK THEY
APPRECIATE YOU.
SEE, I THINK YOU'RE
A VERY SMART GIRL.
YOU HEAR THINGS...
INSIDE WORD.
I'M THE KIND OF GUY
THAT LIKES TO HAVE
ALL THE INFORMATION
HE CAN GET,
SO IF YOU GIVE ME
THE INSIDE WORD,
I'LL GIVE YOU
AN EXTRA HUNDRED
OR SO A WEEK,
JUST BETWEEN
ME AND YOU.
Smith: STROZZI AND GIORGIO WERE
GOING TO BE BACK THE NEXT DAY,
BUT I SMELLED THE REAL MONEY
WAS GOING TO COME FROM WORKING
DOYLE'S SIDE OF THE STREET.
THEY'D MAKE THE FIRST MOVE.
MR. DOYLE WANTS YOU
TO COME WORK FOR US FULL-TIME.
I'M NOT SURE
HE CAN AFFORD IT.
TRY ME.
$1,000.
A WEEK OR A DAY?
I'M SURPRISED YOU'RE
NOT MAD AT ME.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
HOLD IT AGAINST ME,
ME KILLING
3 OF YOUR GUYS.
IT'S THE ONLY CURE I KNOW
FOR BEING STUPID.
HEY, DUMMY. BRING US
YOUR BEST STUFF.
YES, SIR, MR. DOYLE.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
I KNOW YOU ALREADY
GOT A JOB WORKING
FOR STROZZI,
BUT I FIGURE YOU FOR
THE KIND OF GUY WHO GOES
TO THE HIGHEST BIDDER,
JUST LIKE THOSE MEXICANS
THAT WERE SUPPOSED
TO GUARD MY BOOZE.
[LAUGHING]
STROZZI WAS BEHIND THAT,
WASN'T HE?
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO KILL STROZZI AND THAT
LITTLE PUNK GIORGIO?
FROM WHAT I HEAR,
A GUY LIKE YOURSELF,
YOU ONLY CARE ABOUT
THE MONEY, RIGHT?
I MEAN IT
AS A COMPLIMENT.
THAT'S WHY
WE'RE ALL HERE.
WHERE'S HICKEY?
YOU HEARD
ABOUT HICKEY, HUH?
Smith:
I HEARD HE TALKS
KIND OF FUNNY.
YEAH, WELL, THAT'S
THE WAY YOU SOUND WHEN
SOMEBODY SLICES YOUR FACE,
JAMS AN ICE PICK
IN YOUR VOICE BOX.
HICKEY CAN GET
AWFUL MESSY, THOUGH.
THIS SHOULD BE
AN INSIDE JOB.
WE NEED SOMEBODY
NICE AND NEAT, LIKE YOU.
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
YOU'RE MAKING
A MISTAKE!
MAYBE YOU'RE JUST
NOT VERY SMART.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
HOLDING BACK FOR?
YOU THINK THE MEEK
ARE GOING TO INHERIT
THE EARTH?
IF THEY DO, YOU WON'T
BE THERE TO ENJOY IT.
Smith: I MIGHT HAVE BEEN
A GUN FOR HIRE,
BUT I WASN'T EXACTLY
AN ASSASSIN.
MAYBE DOYLE FIGURED
THERE WASN'T MUCH DIFFERENCE.
TELL HICKEY
I SAID HELLO.
IF I WAS GOING
TO GET INTO DOYLE'S WALLET,
I NEEDED SOMETHING BIG
TO SELL HIM.
Strozzi: HEY! OH!
YOU DON'T QUIT ME.
NOBODY QUITS ME.
WHAT IS IT? DOYLE?
WHAT DID HE DO?
HE OFFER YOU MORE MONEY?
KEEP THE $500
YOU OWE ME.
THE REST IS MINE
FOR THE WORK I DID
DOWN IN MEXICO.
YOU LET HIM
WALK AWAY?
HE DOESN'T GO.
NOBODY GOES.
YOU GET BACK
HERE, YOU YELLOW
SON OF A BITCH.
[INDISTINCT YELLING]
PUT THOSE DOWN!
PUT THEM...
SMITH!
Smith: SOMETHING YOU WANT
TO SAY TO ME, GIORGIO? HUH? HUH?
FUCKING KILL YOU,
BASTARD.
IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT
GIORGIO'S A HALF-WIT.
YOU REALLY WANT TO GET
KILLED FOR A HALF-WIT?
LET IT GO.
PUT IT DOWN.
HEY. TELL MR. DOYLE
I TURNED STROZZI DOWN.
[LAUGHING]
WHAT THE HELL
YOU GRINNING ABOUT?
Joe: GODDAMN,
THAT WAS GREAT.
I GUESS YOU DON'T
WORK FOR STROZZI
NO MORE.
[LAUGHING]
YOU EVER
WASH THESE, JOE?
Smith: WORKING FOR STROZZI
HAD ABOUT PLAYED ITSELF OUT.
UNTIL HICKEY SHOWED UP,
I WAS OUT OF MOVES.
I DECIDED TO DRY OUT
A LITTLE.
WENT 2 DAYS WITHOUT A DRINK.
FOR ME, THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
YOU KNOW, SITTING
OUT HERE IN THE OPEN
JUST MIGHT NOT BE
A REAL GOOD IDEA
FOR A FELLA THAT'S
GOT AS MANY ENEMIES
AS YOU GOT.
I THOUGHT EVERYBODY
LIKED ME.
I'M SUCH A NICE GUY.
THIS IS MR. DOYLE'S GIRL.
I'M BRINGING HER BACK
FROM CHURCH.
I GUESS GOING TO CHURCH
MAKES HER FEEL BETTER
ABOUT KEEPING COMPANY
WITH MR. DOYLE.
THAT RIGHT, HONEY?
YOU DON'T WANT TO MISS OUT
ON THE BIG MONEY.
THIS LITTLE WAR WITH STROZZI'S
GOING TO BE OVER SOON.
HICKEY'S BACK.
Man: WE
GOT PROBLEMS.
STROZZI
BROKE THE TRUCE,
HIT OUR TRUCKS
IN MEXICO,
KILLED ALL
OUR GUYS,
JACKED
THE WHOLE LOAD.
[KNOCKING]
HEY, HOW'S MY CAR?
Man: OH, I FIXED
THAT INNER TUBE,
AND I FIXED THAT HEADLIGHT.
SHE'S GOOD AS NEW,
EXCEPT FOR THAT
WINDSHIELD.
I ORDERED NEW GLASS,
BUT IT GONNA
TAKE A WHILE.
WILL THIS COVER IT?
$20? THAT'S
WAY TOO MUCH,
BUT I GOT
SOME INFORMATION
I'LL TRADE YOU
FOR THE CHANGE
ON IT.
A FELLA COME
AROUND HERE
ASKING ME
ABOUT YOUR CAR,
WANTED TO LOOK
AT THE REGISTRATION
AND CHECK YOUR NAME.
WHAT DID YOU
TELL HIM?
I DIDN'T
TELL HIM NOTHING.
HE JUST
WENT ON AHEAD
AND LOOKED ANYWAY,
BUT GUESS WHAT.
HE DIDN'T FIND
THAT REGISTRATION,
DID HE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN KEEP
THAT CHANGE.
THIS FELLA SAY
WHAT HIS NAME WAS?
HE DIDN'T SAY,
BUT I KNOW WHO IT WAS...
ONE OF THEM ITALIAN BOYS
BEEN HANGING AROUND TOWN
NAMED GIORG--GIORGIO.
THANKS.
?? BA BA BUM ??
[RING]
JESUS CHRIST!
SOMEBODY ANSWER
THE GODDAMN PHONE!
MAYBE CHICAGO FOUND A WAY
TO GET THROUGH.
YEAH?
WELL, LOOKS LIKE
I STRUCK PAY DIRT.
WHO'S THIS? GIORGIO?
YEAH. WHO'S THIS?
YOU REMEMBER ME--
THE HIGH-PAID NOBODY.
I GOT A MESSAGE
FOR STROZZI.
YEAH, WELL, WE DON'T
NEED ANY MESSAGES
FROM JERKS LIKE YOU,
ALL RIGHT?
DON'T BE STUPID.
JUST BECAUSE I DON'T
WORK FOR YOU DOESN'T MEAN
I CAN'T BE A FRIEND.
I DON'T WANT TO SEE
YOUR BOSS GET HURT.
YEAH. WELL,
YOU TELL HIM
THAT DOYLE KNOWS
THAT HE'S THE ONE
THAT HIJACKED
HIS SHIPMENT,
BUT MAYBE YOU GOT
A BIGGER PROBLEM.
THERE'S A RUMOR RAMIREZ
IS GOING TO GO BACK
ON DOYLE'S PAYROLL.
WHO KNOWS?
MAYBE IT'S ALL
JUST BULLSHIT.
YOU GETTING THIS,
GIORGIO?
YEAH, I'M GETTING IT.
ALL BULLSHIT.
YEAH. GOOD BOY.
YOU TELL YOUR COUSIN
TO WATCH HIS ASS.
THE ITALIANS WERE WINNING
IN NEW YORK AND CHICAGO,
BUT THEY WEREN'T DOING TOO GOOD
IN JERICHO.
A LITTLE PAST 9:00 THAT NIGHT,
I GOT A LOOK AT GIORGIO
LEAVING TOWN.
YOU COULD ALMOST SEE
THE PRICE TAG HANGING
AROUND HIS NECK.
Lucy: I JUST CAME BY
TO TELL YOU
THAT ME AND STROZZI
MADE IT UP THIS MORNING.
I GOT AN INVESTMENT THERE,
SO WE CAN FORGET ABOUT
THE OTHER DAY
LIKE IT NEVER HAPPENED,
RIGHT?
I MEAN, IT WAS JUST
ONE TIME FOR FUN, RIGHT?
BUSINESS IS BUSINESS.
I DON'T WANT TO GET
MYSELF IN THE MIDDLE
OF ANYTHING HERE.
STROZZI'S GOING
TO TAKE CARE OF ME.
I SAW THAT PUNK GIORGIO
SNEAK OUT OF TOWN.
WHERE IS HE HEADED?
HE WENT TO EL MORADO.
WHAT'S HE DOING
DOWN IN MEXICO?
WHAT HE ALWAYS DOES:
DRINKS, MESSES AROUND,
GOES TO WHOREHOUSES.
I'M SURPRISED
STROZZI DIDN'T GO.
HE MUST BE
GETTING PRETTY USED
TO WHORES BY NOW.
GODDAMN YOU!
WHAT?
I THINK
YOU'RE FORGETTING
ABOUT OUR DEAL.
NOW, WHY DID GIORGIO
GO TO MEXICO?
HE WENT TO FINISH
DOING SOME BUSINESS
WITH RAMIREZ...
PAY HIM OFF
AND THE COP THEY
GOT FOR SECURITY.
I GOT TO GO.
WE'RE QUITS NOW,
RIGHT?
WE'RE QUITS.
Smith: THAT MOUTHY
LITTLE COUSIN OF
STROZZI'S, GIORGIO,
IS ON HIS WAY DOWN
TO MEXICO RIGHT NOW
TO SEE A FRIEND
OF YOURS, A FELLA
NAMED RAMIREZ.
YOU KNOW A GUY NAMED
RAMIREZ, DO YOU?
GOING
TO PAY HIM BACK
FOR THE HIJACK.
HOW DO YOU LIKE
THE STORY SO FAR?
Doyle: GOOD.
KEEP TALKING.
HE'S GOING TO SEE
A COP DOWN THERE, TOO.
THIS COP'S
RESPONSIBILITY
WAS SECURITY ON THIS
SIDE OF THE BORDER,
SO I GUESS HE'S GOING
TO GET PAID, TOO.
THEY'RE PROBABLY
ALL PLANNING THEIR
NEXT SHIPMENT,
GOING TO
USE YOUR TRUCKS.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T WANT
TO BE PUSHY,
BUT THIS KIND
OF INFORMATION'S
A LITTLE TOO VALUABLE
TO BE GIVING AWAY.
GIORGIO'S VERY IMPORTANT
TO STROZZI.
IF SOMETHING WERE
TO HAPPEN TO HIM...
IT WOULD BE
VERY BAD FOR STROZZI,
DON'T YOU THINK?
[SETS DOWN GLASS]
TAKE AS MUCH AS YOU WANT.
[THROWS DOWN MONEY]
YOU WORK FOR ME NOW.
I'LL JUST TAKE
THAT $2,000
WE AGREED UPON.
YOU WORK WITH US,
YOU WORK WITH THE WINNERS.
ANYTHING ELSE IS STUPID.
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
HOLDING BACK FOR?
I DON'T PLAY THIS STYLE!
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
HOLDING BACK FOR?!
HIS NAME'S SMITH,
AT LEAST THAT'S
WHAT HE SAYS.
THIS IS HICKEY.
I TOLD YOU ABOUT HIM.
TOLD ME ALL ABOUT YOU.
I BEEN HEARING ABOUT YOU
ALL OVER TOWN, ACTUALLY.
I ESPECIALLY LIKED
THAT ORPHANAGE STORY.
THEY TELL YOU ABOUT
ALL THEM LITTLE KIDS
BURNING UP LIKE CANDLES?
MY FAVORITE PART.
YOU SHOT
SOME OF OUR GUYS.
I GUESS I DID,
THE ONES THAT
DESERVED IT.
WELL, YOU GOT FINN.
HE'S DOYLE'S BEST SHOOTER.
I THOUGHT YOU
WERE THE BEST.
NO. JUST
THE BEST LOOKING.
ENOUGH OF THIS BULLSHIT!
THIS GAME IS FINISHED.
COME ON. WE GOT TO TALK.
I GUESS YOU
BETTER GO TALK.
YEAH.
DON'T BELIEVE
EVERYTHING YOU HEAR.
Smith: EL MORADO WAS ABOUT
30 MILES ACROSS THE RIO GRANDE.
THE WHOLE TOWN WAS CELEBRATING
SOME SAINT'S DAY,
WHICH MEANT EVERYBODY WAS
EITHER DRUNK OR WORKING ON IT.
DOYLE TOOK MY BAIT AND
SENT A CAR DUE SOUTH
THE NEXT MORNING.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO BE REAL SMART
TO GUESS WHO THE PASSENGER WAS.
BUENOS DIAS, SENOR.
¿¿QUIERES TOMAR ALGO?
NO, THANKS.
Woman:¿¿PERO POR QUE NO?
LOOKS TO ME YOU'RE A COP.
YOU'RE WEARING
A GUN, RIGHT?
YES, SIR.
THAT'S GOOD.
MAYBE YOU'RE THE KIND
OF GUY...
TO SHOOT AN UNARMED MAN
IN THE BACK.
MAKE YOUR PLAY.
WE'RE TAKING YOU
OUT OF HERE, GIORGIO.
JUST DON'T SHOOT ME.
Hickey: COME ON.
OK. OK. OK.
[WOMAN PRAYING SOFTLY
IN SPANISH]
SHE LOOKS LIKE
HER MOTHER.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE'S ASLEEP.
I PARKED A COUPLE
OF MILES FROM HERE
AND WALKED IN.
WHY DO YOU
COME OUT HERE?
DOYLE LETS ME
BE ALONE HERE.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
THEY DON'T WATCH ME.
WHY DO YOU
STAY WITH HIM?
PEOPLE DON'T OWN
OTHER PEOPLE.
A YEAR AGO,
MY HUSBAND GAMBLED
WITH MR. DOYLE.
AFTER HE LOST ME,
HE WENT BACK
ACROSS THE BORDER.
HE WAS ASHAMED.
WHEN DOYLE TOOK ME
FROM MY DAUGHTER...
I WENT TO SLEEP.
ALL I HAD LEFT
WAS TO PRAY.
MI MIEDO
ES MI MALDICION.
MY FEAR IS MY CURSE.
WHAT'S YOURS?
I WAS BORN WITHOUT
A CONSCIENCE.
Sheriff: THERE'S A, UH,
FELLA HERE COME TO SEE YOU.
JOHN SMITH,
MEET CAPTAIN TOM PICKETT.
HE IS THE HEAD RANGER
HERE IN MY DISTRICT.
HE GENERALLY
JUST COMES DOWN WHEN, UH...
SHUT UP, GALT.
SIT DOWN, MR. SMITH.
Pickett: NOW, SHERIFF,
MR. SMITH AND I ARE
GOING TO HAVE A DRINK.
WE GOT A LOT
TO TALK ABOUT TONIGHT.
I'M HERE ABOUT
A MURDERED POLICEMAN.
HE GOT HIMSELF KILLED
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE RIVER
IN SOME CRUMMY,
LITTLE MEXICAN TOWN.
A FEW LOCALS KILLED, TOO,
AND A DOUBLE-DEALING
COMANDANTENAMED RAMIREZ.
BUT THE MAN
I'M CONCERNED ABOUT
WAS AN AMERICAN
ON THE BORDER PATROL.
HE HAD A FAMILY. WELL LIKED
BY HIS BROTHER OFFICERS.
I GUESS HE STRAYED A LITTLE BIT
IN SOME DEPARTMENTS,
BUT HE WAS AN OFFICER OF THE LAW
JUST THE SAME.
YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT HIS DEATH, SON?
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
THAT'S ODD.
DON'T HARDLY
SEEM POSSIBLE.
MR. GALT HERE
SAYS YOU'RE REAL
WELL-INFORMED
ON WHAT HAPPENS
AROUND HERE.
YOU SAYING I DID IT?
I ASKED IF YOU KNEW
ANYTHING ABOUT IT,
NOT IF YOU DID IT.
THE CRIME
HAS BEEN SOLVED, SON.
MEXICAN POLICE PICKED
UP 2 ARMED DRIFTERS FROM
THE STATE OF FLORIDA
JUST ACROSS THE BORDER,
HANDED THEM OVER TO US.
THEY AIN'T CONFESSED
YET, BUT THEY WILL.
I JUST CAN'T GET PAST
THE IDEA THAT MAYBE
ONE OF THESE 2
BOOTLEG GANGS HAD
SOMETHING TO DO WITH IT.
I LEARNED
A LONG TIME AGO
TO TRUST MY INSTINCTS.
NOW, LISTEN
REAL CAREFUL BECAUSE
HERE IS THE POINT, SON.
THINGS IN THIS TOWN
ARE OUT OF CONTROL.
2 GANGS IS JUST
ONE TOO MANY.
I'M NOT AN IDEALIST.
I KNOW A LOT OF THINGS
THAT PEOPLE DO
ARE AWFUL LOW,
BUT THAT'S BETWEEN
THEM AND GOD.
DO YOU BELIEVE IN GOD?
I BELIEVE IN GOD, SON,
BUT WHAT I'M CONCERNED
WITH IS KEEPING A LID
ON THINGS,
AND WHAT WE GOT HERE
IN JERICHO IS JUST
WAY OUT OF HAND,
AND SHERIFF GALT HERE,
HE CAN'T DO MUCH ABOUT
IT, RIGHT?
MATTER OF FACT,
IT MIGHT BE FAIR TO SAY
THAT HE'S PART OF
THE PROBLEM, RIGHT?
NOW, YOU BEEN GOING
BACK AND FORTH
PLAYING BOTH SIDES,
ACCORDING
TO MR. GALT HERE,
MAKING YOURSELF
A LOT OF MONEY
OUT OF ALL THIS.
WELL, IT'S OVER, SON.
I'M COMING BACK HERE
IN 10 DAYS.
I'M GOING TO BRING ABOUT
20 RANGERS WITH ME.
I WILL TOLERATE
ONE GANG BECAUSE THAT
IS THE NATURE OF THINGS.
A CERTAIN AMOUNT
OF CORRUPTION
IS INEVITABLE,
BUT IF I FIND
2 GANGS HERE
WHEN I GET BACK,
THEN IN A COUPLE OF
HOURS THERE WILL BE
NO GANGS HERE,
SO IT'S SIMPLE.
ONE GANG QUITS
AND GOES HOME.
YOU BOYS WORK IT OUT.
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
WHICH ONE.
JUST AS LONG
AS ONE SIDE LEAVES
OR MAYBE ONE SIDE LOSES.
THAT'S FINE,
TOO, SON.
KILL AS MANY
AS YOU WANT,
JUST DON'T KILL
NO INNOCENT PEOPLE
AROUND HERE.
I WOULDN'T
LIKE THAT.
IT'S BEEN REAL NICE
TALKING TO YOU, CAPTAIN.
LIKEWISE, SON.
ONLY ONE MORE THING.
WHEN I COME BACK,
IF I WAS YOU,
I'D BE GONE.
YOU TELL STROZZI
WE GOT HIS BOY
GIORGIO.
TELL HIM, HE WANTS
HIM BACK, TO BRING
US 100 THOU
OUT TO THE CROSSING
AT THE 5-MILE ROAD.
TELL HIM
TO MAKE IT 3:00
IN THE AFTERNOON.
THE TRUCKS.
OH, YEAH.
AND WE'LL GIVE YOUSE
2 DAYS TO GIVE US
OUR TRUCKS BACK.
Smith: ALL THE VULTURES
SHOWED UP FOR THE EXCHANGE.
IF I WAS HONEST, I GUESS
I'D HAVE TO INCLUDE
MYSELF IN THE ROLL CALL.
BUT IF THERE WAS 100 GRAND
BEING HANDED OVER FOR GIORGIO,
I WANTED TO TAKE
A REAL GOOD LOOK AT IT.
STICK AROUND.
YOU GET THE BRIEFCASE,
YOU LET GO OF THE ROPE.
Man: DON'T SHOOT!
THEY GOT GIORGIO!
WE'RE EVEN NOW!
YOU GOT ONE CHOICE!
GIVE UP
YOUR WHOLE OPERATION!
[WOMAN STRUGGLING]
WHAT'S WRONG?
[COCKS GUN]
SON OF A BITCH!
UNTIL I GET GIORGIO BACK,
SHE STAYS WITH ME!
AND I GUESS YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M GOING TO BE DOING
WITH HER, RIGHT, DOYLE?
BRING HIM ACROSS!
Strozzi: DON'T TRY
ANYTHING STUPID, DOYLE.
NICE AND EASY, HUH?
YOU DON'T WANT TO GET
THE GIRL KILLED, RIGHT?
GO! GET HER
BACK NOW!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
DID THEY TOUCH YOU?
DID THEY DO ANYTHING?
STROZZI!
I'M GOING TO SETTLE THINGS
WITH YOU, STROZZI!
I PROMISE,
YOU WOP BASTARD!
Doyle: I PROMISE!
I PROMISE!
Smith: I HAD A VISITOR
ABOUT 3:00 IN THE AFTERNOON
THE NEXT DAY.
SHE'D HAD ENOUGH
OF JERICHO
BUT WAS TOO BROKE
TO BUY A BUS TICKET OUT.
I SLIPPED HER 500 BUCKS.
USUALLY I WASN'T
SUCH A SUCKER,
BUT SOMEBODY HAD SMACKED HER
AROUND PRETTY GOOD.
HE'S BEEN
IN A REAL BAD MOOD...
EVER SINCE HIS COUSIN GOT
TRADED BACK FOR THAT GIRL.
BEEN FIGHTING WITH GIORGIO,
ACTING LIKE A REAL JERK...
YELLING AT ANYTHING
THAT GETS NEAR HIM.
I NEVER SEEN HIM
DRUNK BEFORE,
BUT HE WAS REALLY
IN THE BAG LAST NIGHT.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
I CALLED HIM A NAME.
SO HE SLAPPED ME,
SLUGGED ME
A COUPLE OF TIMES.
HE THREW MY CLOTHES
OUT ON THE STREET,
SO I FIGURED
I'D GET EVEN.
I TOLD HIM
ABOUT ME AND YOU.
WELL...I GUESS
THINGS COULD BE WORSE.
AHH...
YOU GET BACK TO
WHEREVER IT IS
YOU'RE GOING,
MAYBE YOU SHOULD TRY
AND FIND YOURSELF
A BETTER
CLASS OF GUY.
NO GUY IS GOING TO EVER
WANT TO MESS WITH ME AGAIN.
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
YOUR FACE
WILL HEAL UP.
YOUR LOOKS
ARE ALL RIGHT.
HOW IS THIS
GOING TO HEAL UP?
LIKE HE SAID,
I GOT A BIG MOUTH.
HE HAD 3 GUYS
HOLD ME DOWN...
TOLD GIORGIO
TO SLICE IT OFF.
THEY WERE REAL DRUNK.
BUT EVERYTHING
YOU EVER DID TO ME,
YOU DID
ON PURPOSE, RIGHT?
RIGHT?
DID YOU FINISH ALL
YOUR BUSINESS INSIDE
WITH THE LITTLE
PRINCESS?
[SIGHS]
JUST MAKE SURE
SHE GETS ON THAT BUS.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING,
AMIGO?
I THINK I JUST SPOTTED
THE CHINK IN YOUR ARMOR.
WHEN YOU GO DOWN...
IT'S GOING TO BE
OVER A SKIRT.
Smith: FOR MOST OF MY LIFE,
I MADE MY OWN RULES.
YOU DON'T DO ANY FAVORS.
YOU DON'T ASK FOR ANY.
WATCH THE PERCENTAGES.
[LOADING AMMO CLIP]
BUT YOU CAN KNOW THE RULES
AND STILL DO THE WRONG THING.
THE ONLY THING
I KNEW FOR SURE WAS THIS:
STROZZI, DOYLE,
AND EVERY SON OF A BITCH
THAT WORKED FOR THEM...
[COCKS PISTOLS]
THEY WERE ALL GOING TO BE
BETTER OFF DEAD.
THERE'S, UH, SOMEBODY
OUT HERE TO SEE YOU,
MR. DOYLE.
I THOUGHT IT OVER.
I'LL TAKE THE JOB.
YOU MUST SMELL
A WINNER.
I GET A THOUSAND
IN ADVANCE.
NOBODY'S
WORTH THAT MUCH.
Man: HE'S GOOD.
BETTER THAN THAT?
PUT THAT GODDAMNED
GUN AWAY!
PUT IT AWAY!
SAVE IT FOR STROZZI!
SUIT YOURSELF.
BUY HIM.
A THOUSAND.
A THOUSAND MORE
WHEN WE WIN.
IT'S SETTLED.
LET'S HAVE
A DRINK ON IT.
WHAT ABOUT
THE GIRL?
WHAT GIRL?
THE ONE YOU KEEP.
IF STROZZI GETS
AHOLD OF HER AGAIN,
HE'LL BLACKMAIL YOU
RIGHT OUT OF TOWN.
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT IT.
WE GOT HER
IN A SAFE PLACE
AND 8 GUYS
OUT THERE ON WATCH.
EIGHT'S NOT GOING
TO BE ENOUGH.
STROZZI'S GOT
SOME NEW TRIGGERMEN
COMING IN TOWN
TONIGHT.
WHERE DID YOU
HEAR ALL THIS?
MAYBE IT'S
JUST A RUMOR.
YOU WANT ME
TO CHECK IT OUT?
I WANT YOU
AND HICKEY
HERE WITH ME.
IF STROZZI'S GOT
NEW HELP COMING IN,
CHANCES ARE
HE'S GOING TO TRY
TO RUSH US HERE.
YOU GO OUT
TO THE COUNTRY,
CHECK ON HER.
SHE MEANS
A LOT TO ME.
McCOOL CAN TELL YOU
HOW TO GET THERE.
[BRAKES SQUEAK]
[ENGAGES PARKING BRAKE]
[KEYS JANGLE]
THE GIRL UPSTAIRS?
YOU DON'T
HAVE TO.
DON'T COME
ANY CLOSER!
IT'S OVER.
I'LL KILL HER!
PUT THE GUN
DOWN.
I SWEAR TO GOD,
I'LL KILL HER.
NO--
GET DRESSED.
WE GOT TO GET
OUT OF HERE.
GOING TO GET YOU
TO MEXICO.
COME ON. MOVE.
HERE.
TAKE THIS MONEY.
TAKE IT. I GOT IT
FROM DOYLE.
I WANT YOU
TO USE IT.
GET ACROSS THE BORDER
AND DON'T COME BACK.
COME ON. GET GOING.
[STARTS ENGINE]
GO.
[ENGAGES TRANSMISSION]
Smith: I ALWAYS LIKE SINNERS
A LOT BETTER THAN SAINTS.
SHE WAS REAL EASY
TO LOOK AT,
BUT I HOPED
I NEVER SAW HER AGAIN.
THEY'RE ALL DEAD INSIDE.
I FOUND THEM LAST NIGHT.
WHERE'S THE GIRL?!
I DON'T KNOW.
STROZZI MUST HAVE
TAKEN HER.
ALL OF THEM.
THIS IS
A SLAUGHTER.
YOU WERE RIGHT
ABOUT THOSE
EXTRA TRIGGERMEN.
MUST HAVE
TAKEN 15 OR 20
OF STROZZI'S GUYS
TO PULL THIS OFF.
THIS WHOLE THING
IS TURNING ON US.
WHEN YOU FOUND THEM
OUT HERE,
WHY DIDN'T YOU DRIVE
BACK TO TOWN AND TELL US
INSTEAD OF JUST
WAITING OUT HERE?
I FIGURED THE GIRL RAN OFF
WHEN THE FIGHTING STARTED.
I STUCK AROUND, HOPING
MAYBE SHE'D COME BACK.
SHE DIDN'T.
THIS ONE HASN'T
BEEN FIRED.
MUST HAVE GOT KILLED
BEFORE HE GOT A SHOT OFF.
Doyle: STROZZI'S
JEALOUS OF ME
GIVING HER A CHANCE.
SHE GREW UP IN SOME
FILTHY LITTLE VILLAGE.
TOLD ME HER MOTHER
WAS A YAQUI INDIAN.
DIDN'T KNOW MUCH
ABOUT HER FATHER...
EXCEPT HE WAS WHITE.
SHE MARRIED
SOME LOWLIFE WETBACK.
THE ONLY THING
HE EVER GAVE HER...
WAS A KID.
JESUS CHRIST, SHE
ONLY HAD ONE DRESS
TILL SHE MET ME.
THE WAY
SHE LOOKED...
THE WAY HER EYES
LOOKED...
I COULDN'T HELP
TAKING HER OUT
OF ALL THAT.
WE GOT TO HIT
STROZZI SOON.
GET HER BACK.
WE HAVE TO
GET THIS THING
OVER WITH.
I'M GOING TO HEAD
BACK INTO TOWN,
SEE WHAT
I CAN FIND OUT.
MAYBE STROZZI DOESN'T KNOW
I WORK FOR YOU GUYS YET.
WE HAVE TO GET
THIS THING OVER WITH.
Smith: HICKEY
WAS SUSPICIOUS,
DOYLE WAS NUTS,
AND McCOOL WAS STUPID,
EXCEPT MAYBE
I WAS THE DUMB ONE.
IF I HAD ANY BRAINS,
I WOULD HAVE KEPT ON DRIVING
STRAIGHT SOUTH INTO MEXICO.
KEEP IT GASSED UP
AND READY TO GO.
YES, SIR.
I'LL DO HER,
BUT PRETTY SOON,
YOU GONNA BE
ON YOUR OWN.
COME NEXT WEEK,
I'M GETTING
THE HELL OUT.
T'AIN'T NO
BUSINESS HERE.
THIS TOWN...
IS FINISHED.
Smith: AS USUAL,
IT WAS HOT AS HELL,
AND THE WIND PICKED UP
THE DUST SO MUCH,
YOU COULD TASTE IT.
THE WHISKEY HELPED,
BUT I DIDN'T WANT TO GET SLOPPY,
SO I SWITCHED TO BEER.
SOMEHOW I HAD THE FEELING
THE WALLS WERE MOVING IN ON ME.
IT'S FUNNY
HOW IT ALL WORKS OUT.
FOR ONE LITTLE SECOND,
YOU THINK YOU'RE GOING TO
GET AWAY FREE AND CLEAR.
BUT YOU END UP
PAYING THE PRICE.
NO EXCEPTIONS.
EVERYBODY PAYS
THE PRICE...
EVEN A BUM LIKE ME.
TAKE THE GUNS.
WHAT IS IT?
STROZZI DOESN'T HAVE
DOYLE'S HALF-BREED.
McCOOL WENT
ACROSS THE BORDER
LOOKING FOR HER.
DOWN IN EL MORADO,
HE RAN INTO A GUY WITH
AN INTERESTING STORY.
HE'D SEEN HER
HEADING OUT.
SHE'D SOLD OUR CAR
TO SOME GUY FOR
A COUPLE HUNDRED BUCKS
AND TOOK A BUS SOUTH.
SO...STROZZI
DIDN'T TAKE HER.
MAYBE...IF YOU BELIEVE
THE GUY'S STORY.
WHY WOULD
A GUY LIE?
WHICH LEAVES THE QUESTION
OF HOW SHE GOT AWAY.
BIG QUESTION.
NOT THAT
WE GIVE A DAMN.
Hickey: INDIAN GIRL,
YOU KNOW.
IT'S NOT LIKE SHE WAS
THE BLESSED VIRGIN, IS IT?
OUT THERE
IN THE COUNTRY...
ONLY A REAL FINE GUNNER
COULD HANDLE THAT MANY
ALL BY HIMSELF,
BUT YOU WORK FOR US.
WHY WOULD YOU DO THAT?
MAYBE YOU DON'T
WORK FOR US.
MAYBE YOU TAKE THE MONEY,
DO WHAT YOU WANT.
YOU'RE ONE OF THEM.
YOU'RE AN INDEPENDENT.
WHO ARE YOU RUNNING FROM?
JERICHO'S
A GOOD PLACE TO STOP
ON YOUR WAY TO MEXICO
RUNNING FROM THE FEDS.
FOR CHRIST'S SAKES,
EVERYBODY'S RUNNING
FROM SOMETHING.
NAH. SEE, WORKING
FOR PEOPLE LIKE ME
AND DOYLE WORK FOR
HAS AN ADVANTAGE.
THE PAYROLL COVERS
A LOT OF GROUND.
YOU'RE SCARED.
THE WATER'S
GETTING COLD.
[BODY BEING PUNCHED]
[SMITH GROANING]
WHERE IS SHE?
HE'S NOTHING...
WITHOUT A GUN.
Smith: AFTER A WHILE,
YOU STOP HEARING
YOUR BONES BREAK,
YOUR TEETH RATTLE.
YOU JUST CONCENTRATE
ON HOLDING TIGHT
TO THAT LITTLE PART
RIGHT AT THE CENTER.
THE REST DOESN'T MATTER.
THEY'RE GOING TO
TAKE THE REST ANYWAY.
[THUNDER]
MUST HAVE CRAWLED OFF.
BLOCK THE STREETS!
WALL HIM UP!
FIND HIM FOR ME!
SEARCH THIS WHOLE
HICK TOWN!
LOOK OVER THERE! OVER THERE!
THERE! THERE! OVER THERE!
TEAR UP EVERY GODDAMNED
INCH OF THIS PLACE!
FIND HIM!
McCool: YOU GUYS
COME WITH ME.
GET THOSE CARS!
WALL UP THESE STREETS!
FIND HIM!
NOW!
CLEAR!
OVER HERE!
LET'S GO!
COME ON!
FIND HIM! FIND HIM!
HE'S HERE!
HE'S GOT TO BE HERE!
SEARCH THIS PLACE!
UPSTAIRS! BEHIND THE BAR!
NOW! FIND HIM!
YOU. WHERE IS HE?
I KNOW HE'S HERE.
WHO?
SMITH! DON'T HOLD
OUT ON ME, YOU SHITHEEL!
I'LL STICK A KNIFE
IN YOUR THROAT!
Man: CHECK
THE CLOSETS!
Doyle: I'M TELLING YOU--
DON'T YOU MESS WITH ME!
THIS IS NOT A GAME!
DON'T PLAY AROUND!
YOU DON'T WANT TO
TALK TO ME?
YOU WON'T TALK
TO ANYBODY ANYMORE!
YOU THINK
I'M KIDDING?
WHERE IS HE?
LITTLE FELLA...
DOESN'T WANT TO
TALK TO US.
HE CAME HERE,
DIDN'T HE?
HOLD IT!
GODDAMN IT! HOLD IT!
Doyle: YOU HOLD IT,
JOHN LAW!
IT'S GONE
WAY PAST YOU!
THIS THING
WITH STROZZI'S OVER!
STROZZI! YOU
KNOW WHERE HE
IS RIGHT NOW?
HE'S HOLED UP
WITH THE REST
OF HIS GANG,
WAITING FOR
SOME NEW SHOOTERS
THAT ARE COMING
FROM BACK EAST
TO HELP HIM OUT.
WHERE'S SMITH?
HE'S AT SLIM'S
ROADHOUSE.
WE CHECKED ALL OVER.
HE AIN'T UPSTAIRS.
COME ON! LOAD IT UP!
WE'RE GOING
TO THE ROADHOUSE!
YOU BETTER BE RIGHT!
WHAT TOOK YOU
SO LONG?
I HAD TO MAKE IT
LOOK GOOD.
YOU KNOW,
MY HELPING YOU OUT
DON'T MAKE A HELL
OF A LOT OF SENSE,
BUT I'M BETTING
ON THE RANGER.
I KNOW THAT
THE BIG MONEY DAYS
ARE JUST ABOUT DONE,
BUT DON'T KID
YOURSELF, BOYS.
IT COULD STILL
COME DOWN REAL HARD.
MR. SMITH, I WILL
HELP HIDE YOU,
BUT I PREFER
YOU BE UNARMED
AND ON YOUR WAY
THE HELL OUT
OF THIS TOWN.
THAT MOVE YOU
MADE FOR DOYLE'S
LITTLE HONEY--
IN THIS LEAGUE...
THAT'LL GET YOU
BROKE AND DEAD,
BOTH
AT THE SAME TIME.
Smith: BY THE TIME WE GOT
TO SLIM'S ROADHOUSE,
STROZZI'S MEN WERE TRAPPED
INSIDE THE BURNING BUILDING.
THE ONES THAT MADE
A RUN FOR IT GOT SHOT.
THE ONES THAT STAYED INSIDE
GOT COOKED.
NONE OF THEM WERE GOING TO
MAKE IT HOME TO CHICAGO.
DON'T SHOOT!
DON'T SHOOT ME!
I KNOW WHERE THE MONEY IS!
HOW ABOUT IT, STROZZI?
WHAT'S IT GOING TO BE?
I GIVE UP.
YOU CAN HAVE IT.
YOU CAN HAVE EVERYTHING.
TAKE IT ALL!
NO!
KILL HIM.
LET'S GO.
AFTER THE FIRE
DIES DOWN, GO INSIDE.
PULL OUT SMITH'S BODY,
IF YOU CAN FIND IT.
HE'S GOT TO BE DEAD.
HE DIDN'T COME OUT.
EVERYBODY IN THERE
HAS GOT TO BE DEAD.
Smith: A LITTLE
AFTER DAWN,
JOE AND GALT GOT ME
TO THE ABANDONED CHURCH.
THE BILL FOR HELPING
THE INDIAN GIRL
INCLUDED KICKED-IN RIBS,
A BROKEN NOSE,
ONE EYE MASHED UP
PRETTY GOOD,
BUT ALL I NEEDED WAS A GUN
AND SOME TIME TO HEAL.
[DOOR OPENS]
HEY, JOE.
OH!
Man: GIVE HIM
ANOTHER DRINK!
NO!
[MEN LAUGHING]
WE KNOW HE AIN'T
DEAD YET.
WE COUNTED
THE BODIES
OUT THERE.
MAYBE YOU
SHOULD TAKE
YOUR SHOES OFF
AND LOOK
AT YOUR TOES.
HICKEY GETS BACK,
WE'LL BE CUTTING
THEM OFF ONE BY ONE.
Smith: I KNEW BY THE SOUND
OF THE CAR IT WASN'T JOE.
IT'S A FUNNY THING
ABOUT PEOPLE--
ONE TIME OUT OF A HUNDRED,
THEY TURN OUT BETTER
THAN YOU EXPECT.
[KNOCKING]
JUST YOUR OLD AMIGO.
JOE GOT CAUGHT
MAKING HIS DAILY RUN.
THE FOOD, THE BANDAGES--
THEY JUST GAVE HIM AWAY.
HICKEY?
NO. McCOOL
AND A COUPLE
OF OTHER GUYS.
HICKEY AND DOYLE
ARE IN MEXICO.
DOYLE'S STILL LOOKING
FOR THAT HALF-BREED
INDIAN GIRL.
I MEAN, IS THAT
A PERSISTENT LITTLE
BASTARD OR WHAT?
WHERE'D
THEY TAKE JOE?
THEY'RE ALL OVER
AT STROZZI'S HOTEL.
DOYLE MOVED THEM
ALL OVER THERE
AFTER WINNING THE WAR.
[GROANING]
YOU REALLY THINK THAT
YOU'RE GOING TO FIGHT
ANYBODY WITH THAT?
I CAN GET
A GUN WITH IT.
THAT'S THE ONLY HELP
YOU'RE GOING TO GET.
Smith: I ALWAYS HATED IT
WHEN I OWE SOMEBODY.
BUT SOMETIMES YOU JUST GOT TO
PLAY OUT A BAD HAND.
THERE WERE GOING TO BE
A LOT MORE WOODEN BOXES
IN SMILEY'S WINDOW,
BUT, WHAT THE HELL,
EVERYBODY ENDS UP DEAD.
IT'S JUST
A MATTER OF WHEN.
WELL, THANK YOU.
GOD...
DAMN!
GO BACK
TO THE RED BIRD.
GET MY VALISE.
BRING ANOTHER
BOTTLE OF WHISKEY.
YES, SIR.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
Galt:
WHAT'S THAT?
IT'S A MESSAGE
FOR HICKEY.
HIM AND DOYLE
GET BACK,
YOU TELL HIM I'M OUT
AT SLIM'S ROADHOUSE.
SLIM'S ROADHOUSE?
IT'S BURNED TO THE GROUND.
IT'S GONE,
THE WHOLE PLACE.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHEN'S THAT RANGER
DUE BACK?
DAY AFTER TOMORROW.
THAT WILL GIVE YOU
ENOUGH TIME TO
GET IT CLEANED UP.
CLEANED UP? I'M JUST
GOING TO HAUL THOSE
BODIES OUT OF THE HOTEL,
TAKE THEM OUT
IN THE DESERT,
AND LET THE COYOTES
CHEW ON THEM FOR A WHILE.
THEN I'M HEADED
FOR HOUSTON.
EVEN FRANK THE UNDERTAKER
IS LEAVING TOWN,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
WHAT KIND OF TOWN
ARE WE GOING TO HAVE
WITHOUT AN UNDERTAKER?
HOW ABOUT YOU, JOE?
YOU'RE STAYING PUT,
AIN'T YOU?
NO, SIR. RIGHT NOW,
I'M GOING WITH HIM.
LIKE HELL YOU ARE.
I JUST WANT TO SEE
THIS THING FINISHED.
I EARNED IT.
Smith: JOE AND I SAT UP
ALL NIGHT WAITING FOR
HICKEY AND DOYLE.
WHEN THIS THING
GOT STARTED,
ALL I WANTED TO DO
WAS MAKE SOME MONEY.
SOMEWHERE ALONG THE WAY,
IT ALL GOT PERSONAL.
YOU KNOW, FOR A GUY
WITH NO PRINCIPLES,
SOMETIMES YOU ACT
KIND OF PECULIAR.
DON'T GO GETTING
MUSHY ON ME, JOE.
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO SAY THANK YOU.
I HEAR PEOPLE
THANKING ME,
I GENERALLY
START RUNNING.
HOW'S YOUR WOUND
DOING?
HURTS LIKE HELL.
CLOSEST DOCTOR
TO HERE ANYMORE
IS JUST ACROSS
THE RIVER
IN MEXICO.
I CAN SHOW YOU
THE WAY.
GO ON BACK THERE
AND HIDE.
GO FIND A SPOT.
GO ON.
STAY HIDDEN.
YOU HAD ME
FOOLED.
I REALLY THOUGHT
YOU BURNED UP
WITH THE REST
OF THEM.
NAH. I KNEW BETTER.
IT WAS ALWAYS GOING TO COME DOWN
TO SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
I WANT YOU
THINKING ABOUT ME
WHEN YOU'RE DYING.
LOOKS TO ME LIKE
YOU'RE THE ONE
BLEEDING.
Doyle: NOW HOLD IT.
WE CAN GET YOU A DOCTOR,
GET YOU PATCHED UP.
YOU'RE GOING TO RUN THIS TOWN
WITH US. I NEED YOU.
GIVE ME A FAIR FIGHT,
HE WON'T NEED A DOCTOR.
Doyle: WAIT!
WE DON'T NEED THE GUNS!
YOU, ME, AND HICKEY--
WE WON THIS WAR.
WE'RE SURVIVORS.
WE WON! WE WON!
HA HA HA!
I HAVEN'T FOUND
THE GIRL YET.
YOU KNOW, THE GIRL.
YOU MUST KNOW
WHERE SHE IS.
YOU THINK
WE CAN STILL FIND HER?
WE CAN GO TO MEXICO.
SHE'S UP THERE
IN THE MOUNTAINS--
SOME LITTLE VILLAGE.
SHE HAD A KID...
A LITTLE GIRL.
I GOT TO GET HER BACK.
I'M TELLING YOU,
WE CAN BE PARTNERS.
THAT'S FOR WHAT HE DONE
TO MY TOWN!
YOU GOING TO HAVE
HIM KILL ME, TOO?
NO. DON'T WORRY.
I'M ALL DONE.
I'M JUST GOING TO WATCH.
I DON'T WANT TO
DIE IN TEXAS.
CHICAGO, MAYBE.
YOU CAN MEET ME
THERE IF YOU WANT
AND TRY
AND KILL ME OR...
MAYBE YOU'RE
THE KIND OF GUY
WHO'D SHOOT
AN UNARMED MAN
IN THE BACK.
I'VE DONE WORSE
THAN THAT.
Smith: I CAN'T SAY IT ALL WENT
EXACTLY THE WAY I PLANNED,
BUT I WAS RIGHT
ABOUT ONE THING...
THEY WERE ALL
BETTER OFF DEAD.
GODDAMN.
I WASN'T
REAL SURE
THIS OLD GUN
WOULD STILL
SHOOT.
IT LOOKS LIKE YOU
GOT YOURSELF A NEW CAR.
Smith: AND THAT WAS IT.
IT ENDED ABOUT THE SAME PLACE
WHERE IT STARTED...
OUT IN THE DESERT
ON THE ROAD TO MEXICO.
I WAS JUST AS BROKE
AS WHEN I ARRIVED,
BUT SOMETHING
WOULD TURN UP.
IT ALWAYS DOES.
[STARTS ENGINE]