XXXX:
When I was born...
the world was
a far simpler place.
It was all just...
cops and robbers.
[FC KAHUNA'S "HAYLING" PLAYING]
Fuckin' get down!
Get down now!
And you! Stay down!
Stay down!
XXXX:
But it wasn't for me.
Then came the Summer of Love.
Hashish and LSD arrived
on the scene.
[WOMAN GIGGLES]
There were villains locked away
for 12 years
for robbing a bank of 10 grand,
doing time with drippy hippies
who were doing 12 months
for smuggling 2 million quid's
worth of puff.
I mean, work it out, mate.
We're in
the wrong fucking game.
Drugs changed everything.
Always remember
that one day all this drug
monkey-business will be legal.
They won't leave it
to people like me.
Not when they finally
figure out
how much money
there is to be made.
Not millions. Fucking billions.
Recreational Drugs plc.
Giving people what they want.
Good times today,
stupor tomorrow.
♪ Just be glad
To be here ♪
♪ Don't think about
All those things ♪
But this is now.
So until prohibition ends,
make hay while the sun shines.
♪ Just be glad
To be here ♪
I'm not a gangster.
I'm a businessman
whose commodity
happens to be cocaine.
I mean, ten years ago,
a bit of charlie
was for pop stars
or a celebrity's birthday bash.
It was demonized
by Daily Mail readers
getting drunk
in naff wine bars.
Now they're my biggest clients.
This is Clarkie.
Double first at Cambridge
in Industrial Chemistry.
Well, he's gotta pay off
his student loan somehow.
Today, I only deal in kilos.
And depending on
which tariff you use,
that'll cost you
either 28 grand
or 15 years in prison...
which is more time
than a rapist.
C'est la vie.
It is vital that we work
to a few golden rules:
Always work in a small team.
Keep a very low profile.
Only deal with people
who come recommended.
I mean, it's like
selling anything:
washing machines,
handmade shoes, blowjobs.
As long as you don't
take the piss,
people will always
come back for more.
I mean, that's not to say
that we don't weave
that special kind of magic
that makes two kilos
into three,
but never be too greedy.
[SIREN WAILING]
♪ Think about all those
Things you fear ♪
Know and respect your enemy.
It is only very,
very stupid people
who think the law is stupid.
Fuckin' love you.
I know.
XXXX: And avoid like
the fucking plague
loud, attention-seeking
wannabe gangsters
in it for the glory,
to be a face, to be a name.
Hello, Slavo.
Yeah, this is Duke.
Everything's sweet.
When can we meet?
XXXX:
They don't mean to fuck up.
They just do.
You know, forgive me
for stating the obvious,
but stay away
from the end-user.
They are guaranteed to bring
you trouble.
As do guns.
I hate guns. And violence.
But...as some Roman general
once said,
"If you seek peace,
plan for war."
Morty and his assistant Terry,
they watch my back.
Morty learnt to be
cautious the hard way.
He did ten years inside.
He's my bridge
to the criminal world,
and he ensures
that the traffic is one-way.
DUKE: Look, there's Amsterdam,
and there's Oofdorfe. Dorfe.
GAZZA: Hey,
I've no fuckin' clue.
None of 'em
speak English.
Get in the car.
I'm sure
it's that way.
Here you are,
move up.
I bet you
it's that way.
SLASHER:
We've already been that way.
Yeah, but we're gonna go
that way again.
Give us
the map.
Say "please."
Gimme the map,
I'm not saying please.
Oh, don't start,
the pair of you.
For fuck's sake, it's like
being out with a pair of kids.
[ALL YELLING]
All day
you've been moaning.
It can't be that difficult.
Oh, it's not me.
GAZZA: How many fucking
greenhouses can there be?
Morty.
Hello.
Terence.
Thanks, mate.
Clarkie.
XXXX:
Very, very important:
Pay your supplier prompt.
In our case,
that's Mr. Jimmy Price.
He's the top of the pyramid.
Pay him.
In full, on time, without fail,
no short counts.
You get no second chances.
Jimmy calls the shots.
Where the fuck
is Gene?
I don't know, mate.
Ask me one on sport.
What time does
your watch tell?
Probably the same
as yours.
Well, he's never late.
Will you two
shut the fuck up?
[KNOCKING]
[WHISPERS]
Patience.
XXXX: Gene here is
Jimmy's right-hand man.
Been with him since way back.
All the drugs and cash
go through Gene.
Jimmy trusts him with his life.
Mm-hmm.
GENE:
Oh, by the way...
Jimmy would like to see you
tomorrow for a spot of lunch.
MORTY:
Wait a minute.
Is--? Is there
a problem?
[SCOFFS]
Why does everybody assume
there's a problem,
just because Jimmy
wants to have a word?
Maybe he's
grateful.
He fuckin'
should be.
See you at Stoke Park
at 1.
All right.
[♪]
WOMAN:
This is just so beautiful.
Right, we need to get in
and out of here sharpish.
Paul and the tide
ain't gonna wait.
XXXX: Everyone likes to walk
through a door marked "Private."
Therefore, have a good reason
to be affluent.
I own a share in a very
successful letting agency.
It gives me an honest income.
Looks good on
the self-assessment.
Whereas years ago,
scallywags were trying
desperately hard
to get money out of banks.
Now your problem is,
how to get your ill-gotten
gains into the bank.
Well, that's a job
for Mr. Singh.
He does my laundry.
And in a week's time, it will
be ready for collection
in the form of a nice, clean
check for a round million.
The business is
on the up and up.
But I've always said,
have a plan and stick to it.
Quit while you're ahead.
So barring any fuck-ups,
I'm leaving it all behind.
DUKE:
No. No, we got the parcel.
Yeah, better than
expected, actually.
But it's just that
things have gone
a little bit slightly
turbo this end.
Come on, boys.
Lively, lively.
PAUL:
If we miss this tide,
we're not going anywhere
till daylight.
Paul, you ain't being
paid to moan, mate.
You're being paid
to get my cargo home.
Come on, babe. You all right?
Yeah.
Careful here,
it's a bit wobbly.
XXXX:
Life is so fucking good,
I can taste it in my spit.
I'll treat tomorrow's lunch
like the Last Supper,
feign interest in the old boy's
nostalgic tales...
and then leave quietly forever.
[THE CULT'S
"SHE SELLS SANCTUARY" PLAYING]
♪ Oh, the heads that turn
♪ Make my back burn
♪ And those heads that turn
♪ Make my back
♪ Make my back burn
Thank you.
♪ The sparkle in your eyes
♪ Keeps me alive
♪ And the sparkle
In your eyes ♪
This is
pure class.
♪ Keeps me alive
♪ The world...
Please, follow me,
gentlemen.
♪ And the world turns around
Mr. Price is
in the Oval Room.
♪ The world
And the world, yeah ♪
♪ The world drags me down
Your guests,
Mr. Price.
Thanks, Angelo.
Welcome.
Sit down.
How you gettin' on with that
Paki accountant I put your way?
He still doing
the business?
Raj is doing a very
good job. He's--
Good, good.
Paying your bit of
straight-goer's tax, eh?
Well, we all have to do our
bit, don't we, Mr. Price?
Say hello from me
next time you see him.
You hungry?
The grub here will make
your bollocks tingle.
Let's eat.
Right.
All we gotta do now
is test
the ol' snap-crackle-and-pop
factor on these little babies.
Well, don't ask me.
I ain't fucking touchin' 'em.
You are a miserable
bastard, you really are.
Brian.
What?
Sit down, mate.
Got a little
treat for ya.
Help yourself.
[CRUNCHING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
A little privacy,
please, Angelo.
What do you want, son?
Excuse me?
In life.
What are
you after?
A shot at the title?
A seat by the band?
Well, I don't know,
Mr. Price.
That's a very
expansive question.
[LAUGHS]
Right, expansive.
Good answer.
You know,
years ago,
some people would've thought
you were a homosexual,
usin' a word
like "expansive."
You're not a
homosexual, are you?
No.
Not behind
with the rent?
No.
No, I didn't
think you were.
No harm in it,
I suppose.
Times change.
You know why people like you
can't leave this business?
Because you make too much
money for people like me.
Anyway, I'll get
to the point.
I need a favor.
I need someone who's a bit cute,
a bit of a smooth operator.
Not a two-a-penny loudmouth.
Too many grasses around.
Well...
it'd be a pleasure,
Mr. Price.
Jimmy.
You can call me Jimmy.
Now, this favor.
It's not for me,
if the truth be told.
It's for a good friend
of mine.
Like a blood brother.
We were at school together.
Now he's a right
wheeler-dealer.
Flinging up
skyscrapers.
His wife's
a proper blue blood.
I'll give you
a clue.
Eddie Temple.
Does that name
mean anything to you?
I know who you mean.
Now, Eddie's
got a daughter,
Charlie, bless her.
The light of his life.
He worships
the ground she walks on.
She's a proper
beauty, Charlie.
Or to give her
her correct moniker,
Charlie Spencer-Temple.
But she ain't behavin'
like a lady.
She's hooked
on the white powder
and loves a wrong one.
And this is where
you come in, right?
You're gonna find her.
Find her?
She's gone missin'.
Well...you should get
a private detective.
Oh, right!
What, some nosy
ex-policeman,
still on the payroll
at Scotland Yard?
Yeah, but--
She's done a runner
from a drug-rehabilitation unit
in the West Country.
Right, rehab.
She got loved up
in there
with some fuckin' lowlife
crackhead called Kinky.
Well, I reckon
they've licked it
back to London.
I-- I wouldn't even
know where to begin.
Every now and then, we're
asked to do somethin'
above and beyond
the call of duty.
It's called
sacrifice, son.
Ask Gene.
Ask Morty.
I'll do my best.
You do your best
and find her.
Keep Mr. McGuire
posted.
I've also got a little business
more in your usual line.
Gene will fill you in
on the details.
I hope everything was to your
satisfaction, Mr. Price?
Fuckin' excellent,
Angelo!
Thank you.
"Details, details.
"Things to do,
things to get done.
"Don't bother me with details.
Just tell me when they're done."
Who said that,
son?
W-Winston
Churchill?
Close.
No, I said it.
James Lionel Price.
Good boy.
I'll see you two at the yard
tomorrow. Say, 4:00?
I'll tell you about
that bit of business.
I've set up a meet for 5
with the Duke.
[MAN LAUGHING]
What's with him?
[LAUGHING]
He's just had one of these.
These are super E's, mate.
We're gonna make millions!
Hey, I don't care.
This is my boatyard,
man.
Now, I want
those pills
and that fuckin' idiot
out of here now.
I can't afford
to get nicked.
Paul, Paul. Calm down, mate.
What's a matter with ya?
I got Gene comin' down
with a buyer.
You'll be
in your whack.
Here, chill.
Have a pill.
[LAUGHS]
XXXX:
Gene...
why are we doing business
with the Duke?
Yeah, why are we
dealing with this joker?
He's a fucking maniac,
a relic, a throwback.
Belongs to
the Dark Ages, Gene.
Will you just
shut the fuck up?
We're dealing with
the Duke
because he has
one million Ecstasy pills
of very high levels
of MDMA, okay?
One million?
Gene, that is a lot of pills.
What's the tax on that?
Jimmy wants
50 percent netto.
[BUZZES
DOORBELL]
Love a bit of cloak-and-dagger,
this lot, don't they?
Oh, yeah.
Driving a bright-yellow
Range Rover.
Very subtle.
GENE:
Will you two calm down?
You'll feel better
once you've got your money.
Yeah, but how much
can you spend
in Parkhurst
or the Scrubs, Gene?
Come on.
Mm-hm.
Oh. Don't go
gettin' Duke at it.
Jimmy doesn't want him
fucked about, okay?
Who? Me?
Don't you fucking talk to me
like I'm some kind of mug!
SLASHER: Easy.
Don't you talk--
Duke...
don't take
this personally.
It's business.
Now, you wanna know how
much these pills are worth.
Yes! Fucking! Please!
Right. Now just because
you pay a fiver a pop
down the local cattle
market, don't...
Don't, for fuck's sake,
start thinking these pills
are worth millions.
They're not.
We've gotta find someone
to buy these pills.
And they've gotta split them up
into parcels of, say, 100,000.
They've gotta find these
people. It's hard work.
Oh! You'd give a fucking
aspirin a headache, pal!
Then you've got
currency fluctuations.
You've got police activity.
You got adverse publicity.
You tell me, who has got
the readies lying around
to pay
for a million Es?
This is
fucking bollocks!
Slasher, shut the fuck up!
Duke, we all want a
good deal out of this.
Mate, mate, mate,
mate, mate.
Mate, look.
That parcel of pills has got
to be worth 5 million easy.
Five pound each.
Yeah!
You are fucking joking!
It doesn't work like that!
Don't keep fuckin'
saying that to me!
I've got
some samples.
I'll stay in touch
through Gene, okay?
You wouldn't be
so fuckin' flash
if you didn't have him
behind you, would ya, eh?
Yeah.
Well, he fuckin' has,
ain't he?
Where the fuck did these
monkeys get a million Es?
Don't worry about that.
Can you place them?
Well, we know someone up
north who can buy them.
Morty, set up a meeting with
Trevor and Shanks in Liverpool.
What's really bothering me,
of course,
is what color
to get the Aston.
Uh...well, as you're
driving it yourself,
probably green
is a good idea.
Green?
Yeah.
Well, that's a trifle
dull, I thought.
What do you think,
girls?
Black.
Yeah, black.
Black. You can't
have black.
Black's the color
for a hearse or a taxi.
Don't be so
conservative.
I think black's
a splendid idea.
Oh, hello.
Look who it is.
Sit down.
Do join us.
Can we have a word?
[TIPTOES GROANS]
Our dreary broker
has arrived.
Hugo,
follow me.
Don't go anywhere.
We're coming back.
Drink some more champagne.
Especially you.
I like it when you're drunk.
[GIRLS LAUGHING]
Yeah, you're
the master of that.
What are you up to
at the moment?
Oh, we're doing the number on
these young American birds.
TIPTOES:
Who am I today?
You, my son, are in fact,
the Earl of Oxford.
Heh. The Earl
of Oxford.
Fuckin' hell.
So, what's this
bit of business?
It's something
a bit strange.
Can you find somebody
for me really quickly?
Well,
how quickly?
Twenty grand
quickly.
[WHISTLES]
Okay, you've got
our attention.
[CLEARS THROAT]
What you got
there?
CODY:
Mmm, very nice.
I suppose this is
the boyfriend?
It's a bit unusual for
you, this, isn't it?
What's going on?
Doesn't matter.
Can you do it?
Yeah.
Should be
a doddle.
All the same,
aren't they?
Fucking junkies
and crackheads.
Chuck 'em a few quid,
they'll cough.
CODY:
Is there anything else?
No.
All right, well, we must
get back to work, old boy.
[KYLIE MINOGUE/NEW ORDER MASHUP "CAN'T
GET BLUE MONDAY OUT OF MY HEAD" PLAYING]
Hey, look--
Oi.
All right, mate.
I'm the--
I'm the Duke's nephew.
Remember me?
Sidney.
Sidney. Yes. Hello, mate.
How are you?
I'm just off.
You have a nice night.
How--? How you doin'?
What you doin' here?
I hear you're doin' business
with my uncle, the Duke.
Oh, great, why don't you tell
the whole fuckin' room?
This is Tammy.
Who's your mate,
Sidney?
He's a good mate of
my uncle's, the Duke.
He was just going.
Yeah, well, stick around
and have a drink
before you do, yeah?
Yeah. All right.
Yeah. I got VIP down here.
Nice little booth.
Charisma,
he's fucking got it.
I mean, I know he's my
uncle and all that,
but you can't deny it,
know what I mean?
Oi, if you want anything,
all right,
just tell me, because I got 'em
right straightened out in here.
If you want any running
about here, I'm your man...
[THE SOURCE'S
"YOU GOT THE LOVE" PLAYING]
♪ Sometimes I feel like saying
"Lord, I just don't care" ♪
♪ But you've got the love
I need to see me through ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ Ooh-hoo, hoo-ooh
♪ Well
♪ Every once in a while, I say,
"Lord, I can't go on" ♪
SIDNEY:
Line?
What?
I said,
"Do you want a line?"
No, mate.
You knock yourself
out.
♪ You've got the love I need
To see me through ♪
SIDNEY:
Lovely, isn't she?
Isn't she
a darling?
Isn't she.
Siddy, baby, I could
do with a livener.
[MOUTHS]
Ring me.
Sidney.
It's been great.
I'll see you, man.
Thank you.
Thanks
for the champagne.
All right.
♪ Sometimes...
SHANKS: You let me know when
you're happy, Mr. Lucky.
TREVOR: Too warm down your way?
MORTY:
We're kept busy, Trevor.
Everyone wants
a slice as well.
Same wherever
you go.
Greedy people.
Yeah. It's all clear,
Shanks.
You...lot...
would know all about
that, wouldn't you?
What the fuck's that,
Shanks?
Well, not you lot,
but, uh...
that team
down your end.
Like you
don't know.
No offense,
Shanks,
but what the fuck
are you talkin' about?
You really do surprise
me, do you know that?
Do you know something
we don't?
Don't...
be givin' it...
the big fuckin'...
innocent, pal.
Because I am not
a fucking prick.
I never said
you were, Shanks.
TREVOR:
Cool it, Shanks.
They really
don't know.
Explain.
SHANKS:
I was over in Amsterdam.
Last weekend, right?
The whole place
is alight...
with a rumor
about how this hooligan
outfit from down your end,
run by this, uh,
this joker.
He's called
the Duke...
DUKE:
Gazza, go and find
them fuckin' pills.
All right. Come on.
Have a look
in here.
[♪]
SHANKS:
Now, they skanked this outfit,
like a proper, nutty
Serbian militia.
SLAVO:
No, Mr. Duke,
you're the first person ever
to be foolish enough
to steal from me.
Shut up.
But you're not the first
to hold a gun to my head.
Shut up, or
I'll be the last.
Fuck me.
SHANKS:
And they got lucky
because he'd just knocked up
a massive batch.
Fucking jackpot.
There's fucking millions
of the fuckers in here.
Ooh. Ooh-hoo-hoo.
Stay there. Yes?
You watch them.
That looks very heavy
for you...darling.
Fuck off.
Why don't you
put it down?
Why don't you shut up?
Look at you.
Little girl
playing games with guns.
I ain't no fuckin' little girl.
Why don't you shut up?!
[LAUGHS]
You-- You are shaking.
Fuck off! Why don't
you shut up?!
Look at your arm.
I said,
fuck off, yeah?
Put it down.
I ain't listenin'
to you!
Shut up!
Sit down!
Fuck off!
[SCREAMING]
[WAILING]
Baby, baby, baby, baby!
Baby. Come here.
Come here.
Baby, calm down,
calm down. Shh, shh, shh.
[LAUGHING]
This will not be the end
of this, Mr. Duke. Believe me.
Gazza...
go and load them pills.
SHANKS:
But he got unlucky
because this lot are wanted
for fucking war crimes!
Mass murder,
ethnic cleansin'.
They're
lunatics.
They're wanted by
the United fuckin' Nations.
Think about that.
MORTY:
Let's get this clear.
Duke has absolutely
sweet fuck-all to do
with us, understand?
Everyone in Amsterdam
believes that he has.
Bandied
your names about.
What?
Word on the straat
is they've unleashed
their top boy.
His name is...
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
Now, his party piece,
right...
is lopping people's
heads off...
then fetching 'em
back to his boss.
It's all about
honor and respect
with these head-bangi''
nationalist outfits.
SHANKS: That's right, they can't
have it gettin' about that anybody
has took liberties
with them.
CLARKIE: But we had absolutely nothing
to do with the acquiring of....
said merchandise.
SHANKS:
Okay, we accept that, okay?
But, uh...
with you lot up here...
puntin' this shipment,
you tell me,
how does it look?
Bad.
You do know,
don't you, that...
we're only talkin'
pennies an article?
Stolen goods.
You won't
want them, then.
Sit down, lad.
Let's not be
too hasty.
Me and him need to
have a little think.
Well, don't think
too long.
because someone's gonna make
a killing on these pills.
They already have.
That's the problem,
kidder.
[♪]
That prick Duke's made us look
a bunch of fuckin' amateurs.
I told you he was trouble,
didn't I?
But he ain't gonna
drag me down with him.
Try Gene again.
[PHONE BEEPING]
What a fucki''
show-up!
He's not answerin',
Mort.
Okay.
Try Jimmy at home.
You sure?
Will you fuckin'
ring him?
Where are we goin',
Morty?
Back to
that boatyard.
Somebody's about to get
a fuckin' slap.
Yes, Morty.
About fucking time.
[♪]
Paul?
[STEAM HISSING]
MORTY:
What a way to go.
An iron burning a hole in your
chest until your heart boils.
Paulie would've told him
anything, then, wouldn't he?
You see...
that's what happens
when you do business
with loons.
Clarkie.
Have a sniff about.
Make some phone calls,
but really quietly.
Find out where
the Duke's holed up.
We're gonna need
an insurance policy.
JIMMY:
What's the fuckin' idea
of phonin' me at home
and leaving messages,
you little prick!
Jimmy, it was an emergency.
Don't fucking call me Jimmy,
you little toerag!
And what's the idea
of telling Duke those pills
ain't worth shit?
Oh, you don't know
the problems you've caused.
And don't be leavin' it
to that pair of ponces,
Cody and Tiptoes,
to be findin'
that bitch Charlie.
I fucking told you
to do it!
You listenin'?
Find a buyer
for those pills.
The person charged
with moving those pills
met with
a very nasty end.
I don't give a fuck!
[♪]
[BEEP]
That was
quick.
Well, I gotta tell you,
the gaff is rotten in there.
Kinky's still here,
isn't he?
Look, didn't Tiptoes
tell you on the phone?
Tell me
what?
Have you
let him go?
No, I haven't.
He's in here.
Kinky.
I still want to
be paid.
CODY: So if I've assessed
the situation correctly,
which I think
I have,
you three gearheads will
be clucking very soon.
In fact, you look like
you're clucking already.
You'll be climbing the fuckin'
walls any minute, aren't you?
But I'm prepared
to do you a favor.
You see, we can do this
one of two ways.
We can do it
the nice way.
Which I think you'll prefer.
Because the other way is,
is that my friend here takes you
one by one
and puts your head through
the fuckin' window!
Right, so...
was Charlie here
with Kinky?
Yeah, she was here
for a couple of days.
Kinky turned up
with 5 grand.
Five grand.
Who's givin' Kinky 5 grand?
RENT:
We don't know.
Them two kept arguing.
She was saying,
"Do you think it's that easy
taking the five grand,
messing him about?"
But she was still
canin' the rocks,
and smokin' the gear.
CODY: Where is she now?
Brighton. She kept beggin'
Kinky to go with her.
The other night,
I hears this noise.
I'm like lookin' out there.
And it's dark.
But I sees
this geezer, like,
and he's creepin' around,
all in black.
It's like something out of
a fuckin' kung fu film.
Pay no attention to him.
He's a fuckin' nutter.
You, son,
shut the fuck up!
And you...
You fucking tell him now.
What geezer?
I don't know.
I goofed out myself.
And the next morning,
she's gone,
and fuckin' Kinky's dead.
What, you tryin' to tell me,
that somebody's topped Kinky?
RENT: Kinky fuckin' overdosed.
He always was a greedy fucker.
HOISTER: He didn't go over, man,
I saw it with my very own eyes.
You smoke too much
of that fucking crack!
Shut the fuck up!
I told you!
You twat!
Shut the fuck up!
Money, money!
Get the fuckin' money!
Morty!
Oi, this is
dodgy, mate.
That kid's talkin'
about murder.
He's talkin'
shit.
Now, just get to Brighton
and finish the job.
I gotta talk to Tiptoes.
It smells fishy.
I'll double your money.
All right. And I want
ten G for finding Kinky.
That wasn't
the fuckin' deal.
[BANGS WALL]
Yes or no?
Yes.
Hello.
Ambulance, please.
185 Kirby House,
King's Cross.
There's a dead boy.
The door's open.
My name...?
185 Kirby House.
[POP PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
I'm not happy.
This shit is out of control.
You sort it out,
or I'll sort you out.
Morty...Kinky OD'd,
that's all.
Charlie woke up,
found him cold,
freaked out,
fucked off down to Brighton.
Cody's gonna find her.
Look, I'm gonna freshen
these teas up. They're cold.
[DOOR OPENS]
Morty?
[LAUGHING]
Is that you?
Where you been hiding, then, eh?
[LAUGHS]
Fuckin' hell.
What you doing
down this neck of the woods, eh?
Hello, Freddie.
Yeah.
[DURAN DURAN'S "ORDINARY WORLD"
PLAYING OVER JUKEBOX]
♪ Pride's gone out the window ♪
♪ Cross the rooftops
Run away ♪
♪ Left me in the vacuum
Of my heart ♪
So...
Mr. Mortimer, eh?
[LAUGHING]
Here, Morty,
couldn't spare us
a few quid, could ya?
For old times' sake,
know what I mean?
You look
well flushed, bruv.
Fuck me,
he's loaded.
[LAUGHING]
Here, couldn't make it five,
could you...
mate?
Let's make it ten.
Yeah.
Ten's...
a nice...
round number.
What's the matter with ya?!
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh
♪ Uh, huh
What's happening? Been away?
Yeah. Ten fucking years!
You want off?
Or you need a red light?
♪ Suffering and greed
Morty. Enough.
He's had enough!
I'll tell you
when he's fucking had enough!
What is this?
What the fuck is this?
♪ Here beside the news
Of holy war and holy need ♪
But let's forget about all that.
Let's have a cup of tea,
Mr. Hurst.
♪ And I don't cry
For yesterday ♪
♪ There's an ordinary world ♪
♪ Somehow I have to find
♪ And as I try to make my way
♪ To the ordinary world
♪ I will learn to survive
What the fuck?
I'm sorry about that.
I won't be around for a while.
♪ Every one
♪ Is my world
♪ I will learn to survive
♪ Any one
XXXX: It's me.
Hey.
Yeah, come on up.
I'll leave the door open.
♪ Is my world
♪ I will learn to survive
♪ Any one
♪ Is my world...
Hey.
[SIGHS]
How's your day
been so far?
Very fucki''
funny.
[CHUCKLES]
Have you eaten?
I'll have a Chinky sent up.
No, I'm fine,
thank you.
Gene, who the fuck
is Freddie?
Freddie used to run
with me, Morty and Jimmy
in this real
kamikaze firm.
In those days,
we were headed up by this
guy called Crazy Larry.
XXXX: Yeah. Got shot, didn't he?
Bit of a lunatic.
GENE: That's an understatement.
They were a spun-out bunch.
Always doing
loads of drugs.
Hey!
ALL:
Not worried about keeping a low profile.
I love you.
Turn over anyone who couldn't
go screamin' to the law.
No fuckin' problem.
Boys will be boys.
Until one of them,
Kilburn Jerry...
[GUNSHOT]
...shoots himself
stone-fuckin' dead.
Now this is a bit of a dilemma,
because this desperate posse
can't call the law
or an ambulance.
Morty, out of some mad
fuckin' sense of loyalty,
actually volunteered
to dispose of the body.
No head. But things
went a bit wrong.
The guy Larry told to help him
was Freddie Hurst.
The total imbecile had fallen
asleep at some traffic lights
in a drunken,
drug-induced stupor.
Morty was still shut up
in the back of the van
with the headless body
of Kilburn Jerry.
In those days, bein' black was
even worse than bein' Irish.
They threw the book at Morty.
Freddie got three years
for aiding and abetting.
So Morty did ten years because
Freddie Hurst fell asleep?
But he kept his mouth shut.
Did his bird.
Earned a lot of respect
for that.
And all because some kid
was being ridden
against his will
by a bullyin'
psychotic lunatic.
Who?
But you!
You fuck!
Larry.
Crazy Larry was gay.
He was never gay.
Larry used to say...
Fucking females is for puffs.
So who shot Crazy Larry,
one of his boyfriends?
Probably.
Larry made enemies
very easy.
Took liberties
with too many straight lads.
Not for me.
Listen, son.
Let me explain
something to you.
Freddie's in intensive care
with a bit of
a brain hemorrhage.
You were there
at the scene.
That's called
joint venture.
Now, if Freddie dies,
you're either
in the dock with Morty,
or you're in the witness box
putting him away.
Think about that.
You know, I--
I will have one of those.
[MAN & WOMAN MOANING
ON TV]
WOMAN:
Oh, yeah.
All right,
fellas?
Where's Duke?
I don't know.
What do you mean,
you don't know?
I don't know.
I thought he was here.
Well, go
and fucking find him!
He's probably
havin' a night out
while us fuckin' mugs
babysit these.
Gene.
What the fuck am I gonna do
about these Serbs?
Come here. I have
something for you.
You're gonna need
one of these.
Fuck me, Gene.
I fucking hope not.
Are you trying to scare
the shit out of me?
I mean,
I fucking hate guns.
Although that one
is really pretty.
What is that,
Second World War?
Hey! Point it
upwards, huh?
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Here, let me see
if it's loaded.
Huh.
You look like you could
do that blindfolded.
I can.
And I do.
I find it very relaxing.
Good for meditation.
See, meditation...
is concentratin' the front of
the mind with a mundane task
so the rest of the mind
can find peace.
And you find peace
with guns.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
On occasion.
It has been known.
Listen.
I know
it's not your thing.
[♪]
But if you ever have to
kill somebody,
never, ever
tell a living soul.
[PHONE RINGING]
[GROANS]
Who is this?
[SERBIAN ACCENT]
My name is Dragan.
[♪]
How'd you get
this number?
Boatman Paul gave me
your number, in the end.
I believe
you have some property
that belongs to my employer.
And you're the person
I should talk to
about the return of this cargo,
stolen by your associate,
the Duke.
Uh...Dragan...
the Duke is nothing
to do with me.
Mr. Duke came to Amsterdam,
used your name,
said he worked for you.
Are you listening?
Dragan...
I've got an idea.
Why don't you come round
for breakfast?
I'll squeeze some orange juice
and grind some coffee,
and we can talk about this
like adults.
How does that sound?
Hmm?
Sounds very hospitable.
Do you know
where I live?
No.
Well, fuck off,
then.
GAZZA:
Duke's gone missing.
He's a fuckin' liability.
The pigs are everywhere.
This was meant to
be piss easy,
no fuckin' sweat.
Calm down, Gazza.
I'm sure Duke's
just fine.
Well, you've got 48 hours
to find a buyer
or I'm sending 'em back, Okay?
Now, listen.
Don't do anything
stupid, Gazza.
Nah, it ain't worth the grief.
We've gone
underground, mate.
Off the radar.
Nothing personal,
but I don't trust you
or any fucker.
Oh.
Listen...
I just had
a phone call from Gazza.
Bein' a crybaby.
Threatenin' to offload
those pills in 48 hours.
Between you
and that gobshite Duke,
he's promised Jimmy
a bumper payday.
So better get busy,
hadn't you?
Hey, look, I said
to Jimmy I'd try and--
He put yous together.
You and Duke.
That's his job. Huh?
If you two
can't make music...
he's gonna want
his whack out either way.
[♪]
That's business.
TERRY: Well, I hope you
put this Dragan straight.
Yeah. I told him
to fuck off.
What? Please tell me
you're fucking joking.
Well, I am beginning
to regret it now.
We've gotta find
the Duke.
Find these
fucking pills.
We can't rely
on these monkeys
to call Gene
whenever it suits them.
I've looked everywhere. There's no sign.
They've gone offside.
You're telling me you can't
find any of his firm?
Maybe this Dragan
geezer's
already found the Duke
and, you know...
[CLICKS TONGUE]
...done the business.
Well, there is someone
I can call.
You two, keep looking.
Uh, wait, wait.
You're gonna
leave it to us?
This Dragan geezer
is phoning me.
I am the target.
And if we don't find
the Duke, this...
everything, all over.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello.
XXXX: Hello, it's me...
Sidney's mate.
Oh, hiya.
What took you
so long to call?
I've--
I've been busy.
You sound sleepy.
You just woken up?
Yeah, not long ago.
So when am I gonna see ya?
Well, what are you doing now?
Nothing.
No, I was just
lyin' in bed,
wondering what to do.
You still in bed?
Yeah.
You lying there naked?
I've got a little T-shirt on.
But that's all.
Here, wait, listen to this.
[LAUGHS]
What's that?
I was just rubbin' the phone
against my fanny.
Did you like it?
My, oh, my,
it's fresh this morning.
Look at my nipples...standing up
like little soldiers.
What is a girl to do, eh?
Tammy...
Uh, why don't we
meet up now, and...
I'll book
a table for lunch.
St. Martin's Hotel.
Don't worry about a table.
We'll have room service.
Yeah, okay.
One hour.
[LAUGHS]
[THE ROLLING STONES'
"GIMME SHELTER" PLAYING]
♪ Oh, a storm is threat'ning ♪
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
♪ My very life today
♪ If I don't get some shelter ♪
Hang on.
♪ Oh, yeah
I'm gonna fade away ♪
♪ War, children
♪ It's just a shot away ♪
♪ Ooh, see the fire
Is sweepin' ♪
♪ Our very street today
[PHONE RINGS]
Oh, shit.
♪ Burns like
A red coal carpet ♪
Oh, leave it off,
Sidney.
He's drivin' me
fuckin' mad.
♪ War, children
We're not expecting
Sidney, are we?
No, he's too busy
kissing Duke's arse.
Not round here,
I hope.
No. Over by Greenwich
market.
So you can relax,
lover-boy.
It's just
the two of us.
Patience.
All good things come
to those who wait.
Uh-huh.
Stay put.
Come on.
[WHISPERING]
Hello, it's me.
It's me.
Look, shut up
and listen.
Sidney, Duke's nephew,
is working down
by Greenwich Market.
Go and
have a look.
[KNOCKING]
MAN:
Room service.
Yeah, well, look for
that yellow Range Rover.
Okay.
♪ It's just a shot away ♪
♪ Rape
♪ Murder
Your champagne, sir.
I didn't order--
[GROANS]
[♪]
[MUFFLED YELLING]
MAN:
One moment, Mr. Troop.
I want to hear
what this callous bastard
has to say for himself.
I'm Jimmy's old colleague...
Eddie Temple.
Fuck!
He told you
to locate my daughter,
hunt her down
like some lost mongrel.
He said you asked
for his help.
Mr. Troop...
could find
anyone on the planet
in 10 minutes flat.
If you laid a finger on my
little daughter, Charlotte,
you'd be over
the edge like...
[SNAPS]
...that.
You'd join that other
little shit, Kinky,
who thought he could take my
5 grand and fuck me over.
The audacity.
How fuckin'
dare you?
I've known Jimmy Price
for 45 years.
It pays me
to keep an eye on him.
Do you know
what a remora fish is?
Yes.
Oh, you do?
Well, Jimmy has been
swimming in my slipstream
all my fuckin' life.
I thought he might put some
volatile psychopath on the job.
But I've checked
you out, son.
You're a smart boy.
But you keep very,
very bad company.
You know, I host a charity
golf tournament every year.
It's quite an event
in the social calendar,
even though
I say so myself.
I like to invite Jimmy.
Some of my friends find him
absurdly hilarious.
Drinks are on me!
Drinks for everyone!
Champagne!
Fucking good gear
and all!
EDDIE: But I've come
unstuck in my attempts
to provide a spectacle...
for my chums.
Jimmy, as usual,
on the lookout for tidbits,
has made the acquaintance
of the development minister
of some tin-pot republic.
They're trawling the West
for investments.
They have vast deposits
of natural resources.
Quite an investment
for the right man.
They've sent in men
from Timbuktu,
explaining all the details:
profits, shares,
long-term investments,
short-term investments.
They've even made him
an honorary citizen.
Even made him
one of the tribe.
♪ Bom, bom, bom
Bom, bom ♪
What we didn't know,
until it all ended in tears,
was that the hard-line
communist insurgents
who control the country
outside the mining areas...
Bad news about
our little venture, Jim.
The communists have broken
through the government lines,
headin' for the capital
with little resistance.
What the fuck
are you on about?
EDDIE: I got word they were
planning a major push.
The final coup de grâce.
I told Jimmy...
It's all over,
Jim.
Fuck's sake!
Keep your voice down,
would ya?
Get my money out.
Quick. Now.
As if it was some little
kiddie's piggy bank.
[LAUGHS]
Now, I explained
that wasn't possible.
We thought we'd
bought a government.
Maybe someone made
a better offer.
Have a drink,
forget about it.
You win some,
you lose some.
How much are we talking
here, Mr. Temple?
It's only
a cheeky half-mil, Jim.
It's much more than that.
How much?
Thirteen.
Thirteen what?
Thriteen million pounds.
I'm fucked.
[GASPS]
What the fuck?
Have you gone fucking mad?
Thirteen million pounds!
[LAUGHS]
Cor--
How could you be
so fucking stupid?
You've been right grafted,
royally turned over,
like some fucking Yank
buying London Bridge.
Don't you talk to me
like that.
He accused me of instigating it.
It's no coincidence I met those
fuckers at your tournament.
Are you fucking demented?
Asked me to fly to Zurich
to negotiate with the minister
who was still parked up
in La Maison Grande,
still eating well.
Big fat fucker.
[CHUCKLES]
On little Jimmy's nest egg.
So Jimmy thought he could
keep Charlotte hostage
while you went to Zurich
to get his money back.
Little Jimmy was so stupid,
he thought he couldn't
lose either way.
I-I'm sorry, what?
Well, if you'd find Charlotte,
he's got his hostage.
If I find you
trying to find her,
I do his dirty work.
I'm still not with you.
Your lives are
inextricably linked.
You see, I've found out
something very interesting
about Jimmy...
something I've
long suspected.
But...
I'll let
Jimmy explain.
You follow me.
[♪]
EDDIE: You've no doubt
suffered Jimmy's
"CID was geezers you was
at school with" routine.
The other chap's
Albert Carter,
another twisted bastard
from the old neighborhood.
Member of the Regional
Crime Squad.
Now you sit back,
relax, enjoy.
JIMMY:
It ain't like doing business
with your lot
in the old days.
They've all gone squeaky on me.
ALBERT:
Tell me about it, Jim.
I have to box real clever
with those wired-up college boys
from Anti-Corruption.
Fucking dogs. Slags.
Ten grand?
Well, that's
the going rate, Jim.
Ten K. Hardly seems
worth the bother.
Well...
[PAPER RUSTLING]
...there's only so much
in those informer funds.
Now, what about Gene?
Does he suspect anything?
What?
About me workin' for
the old firm? Listen.
Gene...
is too loyal
for his own good.
He can do
a cryptic crossword...
I don't
fucking believe it.
You better believe it.
Because it's fuckin'
happenin'.
Where did you get this?
Mr. Troop made it for me.
It's one of
his little hobbies.
XXXX:
I don't fucking believe it.
Shhh.
Don't you want to hear what
Jimmy has to say about you?
I've got one
for you.
Plucked and ready
for the pot.
Just give us a name,
and he's gone.
In time.
I don't want a bunce.
I want him out of the way.
Flash young runt.
One of the new breed,
ain't he?
Reckons he can just
waltz off into retirement.
I want him away
for 12.
Well, if he's got a kilo
of class A onboard,
he's looking
at double figures.
I'll put it there myself.
Sounds personal, Jim.
Ah, he's got a few quid
tucked away.
He's gonna come
right in handy.
It was me
that set him up
with that slippery accountant
in the first place.
Fucking rag-head let slip,
didn't he?
[PAKISTANI ACCENT] "You will miss
him when he's gone, Mr. Price."
[JIMMY LAUGHS]
Is that you? The flash runt
who thinks he's retiring?
You'd no idea
what Jimmy was up to?
How do you think these
fuckers earn a living?
I would've thought a
smart young man like you
would know that
already.
Can I have that?
Mr. Troop.
[CD RATTLES]
Yup.
Thank you.
This looks like you, son.
Smart part of town.
Anyway, I'll keep
an eye open.
Must dash off. Get home.
Wash and brush up.
Opera tonight.
The Damnation of Faust.
Man sells his soul
to the devil.
All ends in tears. These
arrangements usually do.
One more thing,
young man.
Always remember,
the art of good business
is being
a good middleman.
Bye-bye.
[♪]
Fuck!
[BREATHING
HEAVILY]
[♪]
MAN: Are you dead?!
Why can't you--?
MAN 2:
Please...
cut away the shades,
then bend it gently
back to the museum.
This cutaway poster--
[GRUNTS]
...by bending it
gently back to--
[PHONE RINGING]
XXXX:
Yes.
I've got him.
Got who?
Sidney, remember?
Yellow Range Rover?
Seems they sent
our little friend out
to get somethin' to eat.
Good.
Tell Morty.
[♪]
So, what do we
do now?
Call Morty.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello.
DRAGAN:
Shut up and listen.
No more insults,
no more games.
If I do not get my cargo back,
you're a dead man.
Dragan.
Dragan...
I've been doing some checking.
I've found out who
you represent.
Good.
I think
I can point you
in the direction of
your boss's merchandise.
Come to my hotel room--
No, look, please,
I don't mean to be
discourteous,
but I think I'd rather meet you
in a public place.
You have nothing to fear.
I'm a reasonable man.
That's not
what I've heard.
I'll meet you at...
I'll meet you at Greenwich
Park Observatory.
Any taxi driver
will drop you off there.
I can read a map.
Tomorrow. Midday.
Tomorrow at 12.
I'll be there.
[LINE CLICKS]
That's rude,
Mr. Dragan.
[♪]
[WHISPERS]
Hey.
Condition's red
down there, pal.
They're didgy as fuck.
They haven't moved
from that lockup.
Have a look at the geezer
at the front, on the door.
I definitely know him
from somewhere.
This could get a bit messy,
you know.
What about the blokes in the red?
What're they doin'?
They're just
mechanics.
They got their own
ringing coup goin' on.
The lorries come in
at night one color,
and go out
in the morning another.
But they're nothin'
to do with the Duke's boys.
Fuck me, look who
it isn't.
Who's that?
It doesn't matter.
I've got work to do.
You stay here. If those pills
move, you call me, right?
Yeah, you got it.
You got it.
Day and night,
Terry.
What do you mean "night"?
Day and night.
I've been here all day.
Get Clarkie to do it.
Day and fuckin' night.
You got it?
[SIGHS]
EDDIE:
Hello, young man.
Thank you for coming
at such short notice.
I hope you didn't feel
too summoned.
How are ya?
I'm in the best
of health, Mr. Temple.
Thank you for asking.
How are you
keeping?
I'm very well,
thank you.
How was the performance
of Faust?
Complex.
No wonder it took him
60 years to write it.
How's the family?
What the fuck is this?
A vicar's tea party?
Well, Mr. Temple,
you have been known
to take your conversations
away with you.
Oh, being a clever
bastard, are we?
How do I know
you're not wired up?
Well, I'm not.
Then we'll have to trust
each other, won't we?
Sit down.
[♪]
EDDIE: I've been thinking,
after our chat the other day.
Your pills.
How much for the lot?
No, I've already
got a buyer.
Nearly took
my hand off.
Puttin' the money
together now.
I told you, lad.
I'm still thinkin'.
It's only been three days.
What's the fuckin' hurry?
What's he paying
for 'em?
I can't tell you that.
It's confidential.
Don't be an idiot.
Let me match his offer.
They've got
history.
Bad juju.
And anyway, this Serbian
maniac's in hot pursuit.
See, the thing is,
if I sold them to you,
I'd have to disappoint him.
And he is definitely
not the sort of person--
I did you a big fucking favor
lettin' you know about Jimmy.
I think you owe me.
Two and a half million,
in sterling and euros,
high-denomination
used notes.
So if I gave you three million,
that would keep everyone happy.
Let me state
my position.
You can sell these pills
to whoever you like.
That's your privilege.
That's your business.
But I'll tell you,
I'll be very, very unhappy...
if you don't sell them to me.
You understand?
Okay, Mr. Temple.
Three million. Done.
My buyer's not gonna
be happy, though.
Fuck him.
He'll get over it.
I'm gonna need
some help.
Someone who can eliminate
the problem.
Someone who's
a bit handy, yeah?
Whoa!
Slow down, kidder.
Mr. Lucky does a drop
of freelance work.
I don't need
to know.
It's none of
my business.
You tell him when, and he'll
come down on the train.
Thanks, Trev.
[PHONE RINGING]
Excuse me.
Mr. Temple.
You deliver them
to my bonded warehouse.
When do I get
my consignment?
Monday. No, wait.
Tuesday, probably.
Tuesday? I'm paying
over the odds, remember?
England!
Typical.
Even drug dealers
don't work weekends.
MORTY: That's good news.
That should cheer Gene up.
XXXX: Yeah. Everything's
under control. Mm-hmm.
Better be. Cody's been chasin'
his 10 grand. Better pay him.
Yeah. I'll call him
later.
Hey.
Hey, Geno,
what's up?
Got some
good news, Gene.
Oh, yeah?
What's that?
You murderin'
bastard!
Gene, open
the fuckin' door!
Stay out of this, Morty.
You're gonna tell me...
Gene!
You murderin' bastard!
Murder? Who's dead?
GENE: Jimmy.
Jimmy's dead?
He killed him.
Blew his fucking
head away.
Open this
fuckin' door!
Why? Why?
Open this
fuckin' door!
You're fucking dead!
What the fuck...?
Get off him.
No, listen!
Listen. Just listen.
What
the fuck--?
Listen to me,
Morty!
I got a call earlier
from a cozzer we've got bent.
They found Jimmy's body
last night!
In his own backyard.
It was this sly bastard.
This boy's
no killer, man.
Somebody's made
a fucking mistake.
All right, look. Here.
We'll see, we'll see.
Read it.
Read it out loud.
"To senior ranks only.
Murder Squad investigation.
Victim: James Lionel Price."
The ballistics report.
Read the fuckin' ballistics report.
"Preliminary
ballistics report.
"No arms recovered.
Disintegrated on impact.
One recovered
cartridge casing."
You forgot to take
the cartridge case.
Didn't you?
You got sloppy!
"Eject pattern consistent
with weapon used
"in unsolved homicide
of Lawrence Francis Gower,
also known as
Crazy Larry Flynn."
Wait a minute.
I got it.
Whoever killed Crazy Larry
must've killed Jimmy.
No, no, no.
The gun. The fucking
gun was the same!
The one he stole
from my flat.
You killed
Crazy Larry?
So?
This fucker
killed Jimmy.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Why did you do it?
He was an informer!
He was
a police informer!
Jimmy a grass?
Are you fuckin' mad?
You'll have to do
better than that.
I've got a recording
at home...
of Jimmy and a cozzer
called Albie Carter.
Gene...
let's listen to this shit.
If he's lyin'...we'll
both fuckin' kill him.
JIMMY [OVER SPEAKERS]:
Mr. Mortimer reckons
the Tylers
are bringing in shooters
from Jamaica via Manchester.
They got someone in Immigration
straightened out.
ALBERT: Oh, I don't think
anybody gives a fuck
about spades shooting spades.
JIMMY: Don't you care about
dead darkies, Albert?
[JIMMY LAUGHING]
ALBERT: And what about Gene?
Does he suspect anything?
JIMMY: What? About me
working for the old firm?
[BEEPING]
Convinced?
You don't fuck about,
do you?
Jimmy was
skint, huh?
That's why he set up the whole
Amsterdam business with Duke.
Mm-hm.
I really think
that we should
keep all of this
to ourselves, right?
Really?
Why did you
kill Larry?
Well...
funny enough, it was
Jimmy who persuaded me.
Jimmy never liked Larry
from the start.
Look at that wrong'un
wavin' his money around.
It ain't right.
[♪]
Hey, I love you,
man.
Because he saw
the future was drugs,
and it needed to be
run like a business.
Crazy Larry was
no fuckin' businessman.
After that business
with Kilburn Jerry...
That's it, son.
You do him.
Bollocks!
...he wanted
him gone.
I didn't have
any problem doin' him.
That's why
I did it.
But why did you
keep the gun?
Sounds silly now,
but...
it was
me favorite.
Hope you don't tell the other
guns you got favorites.
[ALL LAUGH]
So what's
the next move, boss?
Well, I'm
going to bed.
Don't know what
you two are doing.
We can talk about it
tomorrow.
[♪]
Bonjour. Ça va?
Sorry?
Mesdames, messieurs,
mes enfants.
Sorry, mate, what was that?
Would you pack
that in, pal?
I've got a fuckin' test
next week.
Okay.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I was just saying...
Je m'appelle
Jean-Paul.
Je suis Anglais.
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
So when does the
target get here, then?
The target?
Um, the target's gonna be
here at exactly midday.
Where?
Here. Right
fucking here.
You got a photo?
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
Who's worried?
I'm gonna have
some binoculars.
I'll give you a little
signal when he...
I could get the 10
past 1 home from here.
Let's have
a little recce.
After we do the business,
walk slowly back.
Remember,
it's a stroll in the park.
Don't run,
whatever you do.
The first
five minutes,
nobody's gonna have a clue
what's goin' on.
Hopefully,
it'll be mayhem.
So try to stay relaxed.
Don't do anything to
draw attention to yourself.
Or me.
Afterwards,
take me to
the Underground station.
I'll look after meself.
There.
Time?
Uh...
6 minutes to 12.
I hope this fellow's
not gonna be late.
Maybe he'll be early.
That'd be nice.
[♪]
Can you see that guy
on the left?
Big fella,
marchin' up the hill.
That's our man.
Are you sure?
For fuck's sake.
I'm gonna call him.
It's up to you.
You're the client.
As soon as he answers,
he's gone, okay?
Okey-dokey.
[LINE RINGING]
Stand by.
Now.
[FLESH SPLATTERS]
[LINE RINGS]
Hello.
May I help you?
[♪]
Don't move a muscle.
Do I have
your attention?
Yes.
You English...
You have no idea
of honor and respect.
I usually kill for less.
I want my cargo and the Duke.
I haven't got your pills.
Just give me a day.
Ooh, jeez!
Don't piss in my pocket
and tell me it's raining.
Now listen for the last time.
You'll bring me what is mine.
Look, I don't--
Jesus!
You have one more day.
See you tomorrow
at dusk by the statue.
And remember,
I will be watching you.
[LINE CLICKS]
What the fuck
were you thinkin' about?!
Gettin' Trevor's
man down here
to shoot this Serb
in a public park?!
MORTY:
Trevor's gonna go ballistic.
Now, what the fuck
do I tell him? Hmm?
What a fucking mess you've made!
You've gone fuckin' mad.
You think you're a gangster?
Fuck off!
You wanna play?
Well, you do it somewhere else.
Because if you do it
near me,
I'll put you in
a fucking wheelchair.
Stick to
your fuckin' sums.
Listen. Listen to me.
Dragan's already killed Paul.
He's done the Duke.
He just put a bullet
right between Lucky's eyes.
I was fuckin' there!
He's watching our every move.
I mean, who's next, me?
I wish.
Oh, fuck off!
Look, it could
be you or Morty.
Dragan said he wanted the pills and the Duke.
Where's the Duke?
What?
I should've told you
this earlier.
Duke and Slasher came by
the office the other day.
What?
Look, Paul the Boatman was
topped last night, right?
I mean, I've got to get
on my toes sharpish.
Oi! I want Jimmy
brought here right now, yeah?
Getting that smug
fuckin' yuppie bastard
to tell Duke
those pills were useless
after sendin' us over there
in the fuckin' first place!
Hey, hang on.
You've lost me now.
Yeah, well,
if you have us over,
I swear by fuckin' almighty
God, I'll call the fuckin' law.
Oi, Slasher, what are
you talkin' about?
SLASHER: I swear I'll
fuckin' call the law!
She didn't mean that.
I do!
She's upset.
Shut the fuck up!
I'll call the fuckin'--
Oh!
That's where playin'
at bein' a gangster gets you.
You're not in there
because I like you.
I'm beginnin'
to feel left out.
Why?
I seem to remember Freddie Hurst
is still in intensive care
after your jolly little
reunion the other day.
Fuckin' hell,
Duke.
For once,
you might be of some use.
[♪]
That was Gazza
on the phone.
It's on.
He'll pick you up
at 9:00 in the morning.
Gallows Corner.
You know it?
Yeah.
Hey...
With Jimmy gone,
these pills are gonna make
a nice, fat contribution
to my retirement fund,
so don't fuck things up
again, okay?
If you do...
you'll wish this Dragan
had shot you
between the eyes,
understand?
Best of luck.
Thanks.
[RINGS]
Hello.
Fuck off!
Sidney, I've told you,
stop answering my phone, okay?
Who was it?
Wrong number, Tam.
[INDECIPHERABLE LYRICS]
All right, mate?
Hello, Sidney.
How you doin',
then?
I'm all right, thank you,
Sidney. How are you?
I'm all right,
mate, yeah.
[HONKS]
XXXX:
Gazza, this place stinks.
We want to
get you out of here.
Fifty pence
a pill.
At least that way, we all
come out with something.
Yeah, I think they're
worth a lot more than that.
Oh, for chrissake, Gazza,
this is a reality check!
Now, Paul's dead.
Jimmy's dead.
Duke and Slasher,
fuck knows where they are.
This gear
is knock-off,
and the Serbs
you nicked it from,
well, they'd kill you
like you'd take a piss.
Gazza, the old bill
are outside!
[♪]
Gazza, no!
Go, go, go!
Let's take the front!
Come on,
let's have it!
Don't point that gun
at me. Put it down!
We're goin' in!
Goin' in!
Gazza, look at me.
Look at me.
Put the gun down.
You're gonna get us all shot.
Fuck it! Boat!
Go! Go! Go!
[YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
Stay there!
Fuck!
Come on! Come on! Go!
Gazza! Wait!
Fuckin' hurry up,
then!
Get in.
Get the fuck in!
Come on!
Take off!
[YELLS]
Ugh!
[♪]
Is this for me?
Yes.
Your cargo's gone,
I'm afraid.
It was seized by--
I know already.
How do you know?
I watched.
COP:
I don't believe this!
Cox's gonna go
fucking spare!
We are in shit!
You lot have fucked up again!
Aw, fuckin' hell.
All right,
leave it to me, lads.
I'll explain
to Inspector Cox
that his suspect has scarpered
because of your blunderin'.
Fuckin' knobheads.
Helmets off.
DISPATCH:
Delta Uniform Kilo Echo.
Does this settle
things, then?
[SIGHS]
DISPATCH:
Tango Foxtrot, over.
Delta Uniform...
GENE: How did that other
little errand go?
Success...
far as I could make out.
DISPATCH: Sierra Alpha, are you
receiving this directive, over.
Where is my fucking prisoner?
You old ladies couldn't
catch a cold if you tried!
Sir, I just wanna say--
Shut up, you soppy wanker!
Indigo...
Dingo Bongo.
[BOTH SNICKER]
So tell me,
is this area now secure?
Yes, sir.
Well, you can fuck off, then.
So where are
the pills, genius?
I think this is
them now.
What the fuck?
Couldn't leave this behind.
Greenies.
You are in the wrong game, mate.
You should work
with us.
Are we square?
Yeah, we're sweet.
Seems so.
So your pills are in the back.
Help yourself.
[♪]
XXXX:
Hello.
Okay.
Yes, it will do.
Bye-bye.
You're off
the hook, Morty.
Freddie Hurst
is out of his coma.
Good news.
Eh?
Yeah.
Good news, mate.
Listen, I've got one
for you.
Irishman caught his son
snorting charlie.
He said, "If I catch you
doin' that again,
I'll rub your fuckin'
nose in it."
[ALL LAUGHING]
TROOP: Do you have the pills?
In the cars.
Boss wants to see you
in his office.
Ah, come in.
Sit down.
Here you are.
Payment.
You look
shocked, son.
You taking
the fucking piss?
You and Jimmy...
have caused my little
angel Charlotte...
considerable anxiety.
She's off to Arizona
for a course of
intense treatment.
I'm keeping those
pills for myself,
by way of
compensation.
I think
I'm entitled.
Simple. End of.
The amount of trouble
you've caused the last few days.
Jimmy.
Poor little
I think it would be
in your interest
if this thing finishes here,
now, today. Understand?
Well, it doesn't matter
what I do.
This lot are gonna
come after you.
[CLICKS INTERCOM]
No, they're too long
in the tooth to go
[OVER SPEAKERS]
rampaging round the country,
looking for revenge.
Look at 'em.
Bunch of underendowed, aging
fuck pigs.
Are you enjoying this?
No. On the contrary.
Take it as a compliment.
You're a bright
young man.
This monkey business is in
your blood, under your skin.
You're not gettin' out,
you're just getting in.
You're only getting started.
I've every faith in you.
And one day
in the future,
it'll be you
sitting here in my place,
telling some Young Turk
the facts of life.
And they are, Mr. Temple?
[♪]
You're born,
you take shit.
Get out in the world,
you take more shit.
Climb a little higher...
take less shit.
Till one day, you're up
in the rarefied atmosphere,
and you've forgotten
what shit even looks like.
Welcome to the layer cake, son.
[CAR DOOR OPENS]
This thing ends here,
tonight. You understand?
Drug money's easy money,
not grief.
The odds, as you can see,
are against you.
Good night.
XXXX: If you're gonna
hang around in this game,
that's where
you've got to aim to be:
sitting in
your bonded warehouse
with
the ex-professional soldiers
doing the dirty work
while you deliver the highly
suspect educational lecture
to baffle your opponents
and cover your tracks.
The art of good business...
is being a good middleman.
Putting people together.
I'll always thank Eddie
for telling me that.
It's all about honor
and respect.
This is the end,
Mr. Duke, as I told you.
Pilule?
Polizia.
Hmm.
Ahh!
Do you know what?
[CHUCKLES]
I fuckin' enjoyed that,
brother.
Just like
the old days, Shanks.
Nice bit
of armed robbery.
XXXX:
Hello.
Yeah, all right.
Where do you want
the money sent, lah?
Soon as I do, Trev.
And again, look,
I am sorry about Lucky.
Don't worry about it, kidder.
Man was a prick, anyway.
Later.
Ready?
Yeah. Let's go.
XXXX:
Did I really think
Eddie was gonna give me
3 million for those pills?
Did I, fuck.
But suddenly
there was a void
where once there was
Jimmy Price.
And after a couple of days
of going around in my head,
Eddie's little "getting in
and getting out" speech
started to make sense.
Angelo. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Can we get some privacy?
Of course.
King is dead.
Long live
the king.
[CHUCKLES]
Well,
I'm honored.
But for me this is all over.
I'm getting out.
What was true then
is true now.
Have a plan. Stick to it.
So I'm sure you gentlemen
must have lots to discuss,
but I have no business
being here.
I've someone to meet.
Adios, amigos.
Paul the Boatman.
Kinky.
The Duke.
Slasher.
Kilburn Jerry.
Crazy Larry.
Mr. Lucky.
Troop.
Jimmy.
I don't want to
add my name to that list.
My name?
If you knew that,
you'd be as clever as me.
No!
[WHIMPERING]
I'm sorry.
[JOE COCKER'S "DON'T LET ME
BE MISUNDERSTOOD" PLAYING]
♪ Baby
♪ Do you understand me now?
♪ Sometimes you see
That I'm mad ♪
♪ Don't you know no one alive ♪
♪ Can always be an angel?
♪ Whatever thing goes wrong
You seem so bad ♪
♪ Oh, but I'm just a soul
Whose intentions are good ♪
♪ Oh, Lord
♪ Please don't let me
Be misunderstood ♪
♪ You know, sometimes
♪ I'm so carefree ♪
♪ With a joy that's hard
To hide ♪
♪ And sometimes, again
It seems ♪
♪ All I have is worry
♪ Then you're bound
To see my other side ♪
♪ Hey, but I'm just a soul
Whose intentions are good ♪
♪ Oh, Lord
♪ Please don't let me
Be misunderstood ♪
♪ If I seem edgy
♪ I want you to know
♪ I never mean
♪ To take it out on you
♪ Life has its problems
♪ And I've got my share ♪
♪ But that's one thing ♪
♪ I never mean to do
♪ No
♪ 'Cause I love you ♪
♪ 'Cause I love you, darling ♪
♪ And I love you
♪ Now, baby
♪ I'm just human ♪
♪ Got my faults like anyone
♪ But sometimes I find myself
♪ All alone regrettin' ♪
♪ All the foolish things
that I have done ♪
♪ Hey, but I'm just a soul
Whose intentions are good ♪
♪ Oh, Lord
♪ Please don't let me
Be misunderstood ♪
♪ No, don't let me
♪ Yeah
♪ Just please don't ♪
♪ Oh, yes, indeed, baby
♪ Yeah, yeah