(SIREN WAILING)
AGENT 1: Get those people out of the way!
AGENT 2: Go! Go! Go!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
REPORTER:
The President has been shot!
There were at least
three gunshots.
(GUNS FIRING)
There appear
to be at least...
AGENT 1: Get those people
out of the fucking way.
Let's go!
I'm all right.
To the van.
Let's go! Let's go!
Was anyone else hit?
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Call my wife.
Tell her I'm okay.
- He got through security.
Repeat, he got
through security.
Tell her I'm okay.
- We will, Mr. President.
God damn it!
- We'll call her.
NEWSCASTER:
MSNBC has confirmed
that a few minutes ago,
US war planes struck
military bases in Venezuela
in retaliation for the
assassination attempt
on President Lyman
three weeks ago.
Our Emily Boyd is on
the ground in Caracas.
Emily, what are
you hearing now?
EMILY: Jim, as you can
imagine, the situation
on the ground in Caracas
can be described
as a state of chaos.
Apparently, President Lyman
responded to a CIA report
said to have overwhelmingly
and conclusively asserted
Venezuela's involvement
in the assassination attempt.
President Lopez's
government...
CHILDREN: # Four bottles
of milk on the wall
# Four bottles of milk
# You take one down,
you pass it around
# Three bottles of milk
on the wall
on the wall #
Oh, my God, this song.
Is this what we got in
trouble for in Abu Ghraib?
(CHUCKLES)
I don't know why anybody
actually signed up
to be a room mother.
Yeah.
(SINGING CONTINUES)
Hey, Timmy!
What are you doing?
- Sorry, Mom.
Can you just,
like, sing along with
everybody else?
I don't have
a good voice.
Well, me, neither.
Come on, sing along.
Come on.
Mrs. Robinson?
- Yeah, what is it, dear?
Nicky Ludlow keeps
pulling on my hair,
and he won't stop.
Well, just switch seats.
But the bus is full.
You know what,
just stay right here.
Okay?
I'll deal with it.
You're a tattletale!
I am not!
- You just told on Nicky.
That's because
he won't stop.
You're a tattletale.
- Timmy, that's enough.
Stop it.
That's enough.
- But you're not
supposed to tattle.
Well, you're not supposed
to have to put up
with bullies, either.
Come on.
WOMAN: Capital Sun Times.
LARRY: It's gonna
be the Redskins.
You know what you call
53 people watching
the Super Bowl?
MAN: No, sir.
- The Washington Redskins.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
That's what
you call them.
MAN: Larry, you should be
supporting the home team.
I would support
the North Koreans
if they were playing
the Washington Redskins.
All right, Judy, give it
four hours as top story
on the Net, I guess.
JUDY: Thank you, B.B.
- That's it, boss.
I think.
Okay. Thanks, everybody.
Let's make it a good one.
LARRY: Let me ask you
a question.
How many Olympians
do we have in town?
MAN: Oh, quite a few.
Rache, stick around
a minute, would you?
LARRY: You know there's
that track star, right?
From Georgetown?
Yeah.
- Okay, get on him,
too, all right?
Get the door for me,
would you, Kelly?
KELLY: No problem.
Thanks.
Okay, Rache.
We're gonna fast track
the story. Your story.
Really? When?
The New York Times has
gotten hold of some
of the information,
so we're going to beat
them to the punch.
Yeah. Want to get it on
the doorsteps tomorrow.
I mean, it's a killer story.
No, I know.
It's Watergate.
It's Iran-Contra.
It mean, it's a "holy shit"
piece, Bonnie.
It's gonna take them down.
- Rachel.
Sorry. Gotta rein it in.
I'm kind of excited.
Okay, we gotta
remain objective.
Well, fine. We'll objectively
bring down the White House.
What else do you need to do
to finish the story?
I gotta call the White House.
Of course, go to
Van Doren herself.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Out of curiosity,
why haven't you
spoken to her yet?
Avril, I already told you,
if we went to her too early,
we give the CIA time
to shut the story down.
We go now, there's
nothing they can do.
Okay. Look, legally
the story is solid.
Everything is factually
in line. There's no libel.
Well, that's all
that's important,
right?
I wish you would let me know
who your source is on this.
A title,
a job description.
Okay, look, we have
two confirming sources.
Rachel told me
who they are, and I'm
comfortable with them.
We have Van Doren's letter
to the CIA director
that the Feds
gave to Rachel.
That's enough to go to press.
-
I'm just saying
that what you guys
are okay with,
the government may not be.
The laws are murky.
I'm sorry, what?
It's illegal for a
government official
to reveal the identity
of an undercover CIA agent.
Okay. Well, I'm not
a government official.
I don't understand
why you're bringing...
You know what?
We've already discussed this.
Bonnie's signed off on it.
As long as we all know
what we're dealing with.
All right, we know.
Okay, do you know how
to find her? Van Doren?
Yeah. I'll go to her
as soon as I
get out of here.
Our kids go to school
together, if you
can believe that.
No shit?
Yeah.
Okay, you feel comfortable
going to her for comment?
Absolutely.
GIRL 1: Yeah! That's it!
Come on! Pass it in!
GIRL 2: Stay open, Ali!
GIRL 3: Angela, pass it to me.
GIRL 2: I got it! I got it!
MAN: Come on now!
Push up! Push up!
WOMAN 1: Yes, Ali! Good job!
Good job!
WOMAN 2: Kick it, honey!
Kick it hard!
MAN: Good pass!
(PEOPLE CLAPPING)
WOMAN 3: Spread out, girls!
Spread out!
MAN: Get in there!
Come on!
Hey.
- Hello.
Oh, no. Defense!
Come on, defense!
Allison.
She's doing great out there.
- Yeah.
Every one of them
chases the ball.
Well, nobody likes defense.
Come on, Ali! Come on.
She is in Mr. Cody's class.
Right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, my son, too.
- Oh! I see.
Come on, Allison.
MAN: There you go,
there you go, honey!
Could we talk in private?
I'm with the Sun Times,
I need a few minutes.
It's kind of important.
Yeah. Sure.
I'm just concerned
she might have
seen me slip away.
I won't keep you long.
Okay. So, what's up?
Erica, I'm writing a story.
I work for the national desk.
Okay?
- Neat.
And it's gonna run tomorrow,
and it's gonna say,
among other things,
that you are
a CIA operative,
and that you went on
a mission, a fact-finding
mission to Venezuela.
What? This is...
Hear me out, okay?
You went there on
a fact-finding mission
to determine if
its government
was responsible
for the assassination
attempt on
President Lyman.
You determined it was not,
and you informed
your bosses of this.
This is the stupidest
B.S. I have ever heard.
Wait, wait. What?
Can you...
How do I know
that you're from
the Sun Times?
The White House ignored
your findings and launched
an attack anyway,
still claiming
retribution for the
assassination attempt.
I've been on the national
desk for five years.
I have a column
every Tuesday
on the editorial page.
My son goes to
school here, too.
Yeah, I know.
You said that.
You people.
You people! My God!
You fucking people!
You know, this isn't
about me. Once again,
it's about my husband.
My source is impeccable.
Your source is 110%
fucking peccable.
I'm a CIA operative?
I can't even use
the navigation system
in my Prius.
This is...
This is absurd!
Your paper... Your paper
has been trying to
fuck my husband
ever since he spoke out
against this administration.
We have your memo.
- What memo?
We have your findings.
- You know. My attorney
is Harry Timmers.
Do you know him?
- Sure.
He's gonna take a lead pipe
to you, and he's gonna
shove it up your ass.
Well, I certainly
don't want that.
What are you doing?
What are you doing? Our kids
go to school together, Robin.
Rachel Armstrong.
- Right. Whatever.
Are you denying
you're CIA?
You know what?
You stay away from us.
Okay? I mean it.
DAVID: Just say
that the White House doesn't
comment on security issues.
Is that what you're saying?
Come on, David.
Give me something
I can spell.
Off the record,
this is bullshit.
You're gonna set off
a shit storm for nothing,
for a lousy column
inch of space.
Rachel, it's your
son on line five.
- You're gonna have
egg on your face.
I gotta go, David.
I got my son
on the other line.
Hey, kiddo.
TIMMY: Hi, Mom.
Did you get my paper?
Yeah, I'm just getting it now.
Can I read it
and call you back?
Okay, but I gotta
go to bed soon.
Okay. Well, you can
wait up for me to call you.
But Dad said
I had to go to bed.
Well, we'll do it in
the morning. I promise.
Okay.
(WHISPERING) It's just, I have
a real big story, honey.
It's fine, Mom.
Okay, I love you. Bye-bye.
Sorry.
- Hey, what's that?
My son had to do a paper
on India. I was just
looking over his outline.
I bet you he could give me
10 inches on India's nuclear
buildup with Pakistan.
Oh, yeah.
- How'd you do with David?
"White House doesn't
comment on security
issues." Blah-blah.
Yeah, well, I know you'll
give it more eloquent
phrasing than "blah-blah."
Sure.
- Feels good, huh?
It's worth every
dime I don't make.
Look, I want you
to start on a major
profile of Van Doren,
from Yale to CIA, to the
marriage to the ambassador
20 years older than her.
He was her professor.
He was married.
A whole drama, I hear.
Now, that's
some good stuff.
Look, by the way,
you deserve
a good night's sleep.
If I were you, I'd turn the
ringers on my phone off.
(DOOR OPENS)
MERRILL: Hey, Erica.
Why are we meeting
here, Merrill?
- For the chili.
No. Why are we meeting
out in the open like this?
We're not out in
the open, Erica.
No one knows who you are.
Now tomorrow, when that
goddamn story comes out,
tomorrow you'll be
out in the open. Shit!
Your husband had to go
and write those articles,
didn't he?
Keep him out of this.
You're right, Erica.
It's not Oscar's fault.
Oscar hasn't been
trained in covert ops.
Oscar didn't take
an oath of secrecy.
No, it's your fault.
You shouldn't have
told him anything.
Okay, hey, guys.
Here's the SITREP.
The paper will be out
in two hours. They haven't
put it up on the Net.
They didn't want to
give the West Coast
papers a chance
to put it in their
morning editions.
And Justice is scrambling.
They're bringing in
a special prosecutor to
find out who exposed you.
I can't believe this.
I mean, our kids go
to school together,
you know, the reporter's
kid and mine.
Wait a second.
You know her?
Well, I kind of
recognized her today,
but we'd never spoken
before that moment.
Let me ask you straight out,
Erica. Was it you?
Was it me, what?
- Was it you who leaked
to the Sun Times?
I mean,
it's understandable.
The White House
ignored your report,
and you got pissed.
You goaded Oscar to write
those quote-unquote,
opinion pieces.
When that didn't get
traction, you went to
the press yourself.
I went to the press myself.
Someone you knew.
Someone you trusted.
Fuck you.
Fuck me? Touche.
The prosecutor,
Patton Dubois,
he'll be in tomorrow.
He'll get Armstrong
before the grand jury.
Law says Armstrong has
to give up her source.
Could it have been Oscar?
No. Could it have
been you, O'Hara?
How we all doing?
Still doing good?
Doing good.
- You sure?
Good.
- All right.
I'm gonna put you
on the box.
Oscar, too.
Fine. But I want everybody
in the agency who
knows my identity,
I want them with
polygraph wires
up their asses, too,
because there's
a traitor among us.
We'll find that person
if they're in the CIA.
Nonetheless, we should think
about relocating you
for your own good.
No. No. I will send Allison
away for a little while,
but none of this shit
was my fault. I'm not
gonna be punished.
This Lois Lane
and her newspaper,
I'm not gonna let her
turn me into
a scared little girl.
Uh-uh. I'm staying here.
Whatever.
In the meantime,
we'll assign a protective
detail to your home.
I feel so much safer.
Thank you.
I can't fucking
believe this.
ALLISON: Mommy.
Wanna stay home
from school today?
- Yeah.
This is very interesting.
It's awesome.
Thank you.
- You're welcome. Wow.
I didn't realize they made
so much coffee in India.
It also has the most
democrats in the world.
Well, not quite.
India is the biggest
democracy in the world.
Isn't that the same thing?
No, it's not the same thing.
Jesus Christ.
Don't give your carrots
to Brandon today. Okay?
Okay, Mom.
You did it.
This changes everything.
You're gonna win a Pulitzer.
(LAUGHS)
I don't know about that.
Timmy, come on.
Eat your breakfast.
- I don't like them.
Come on, don't give
Mommy a hard time.
Finish your eggs.
Eggs give you cancer.
Eggs don't give you cancer.
All right, you know what?
I'll finish your cancer,
okay. Okay?
Feels pretty good though.
That was a lot of work.
You didn't tell me
half the stuff
that's in here.
Well, you don't tell me
anything that goes into
your novels, so it's fair.
MAN ON RADIO: A spokesman
for the newspaper says
because her husband is
a vocal opponent
of the administration,
this makes Mrs. Van Doren's
employment with the CIA
absolutely newsworthy.
Mom?
- In Mexico City...
What's up, kiddo?
- Can we go to the zoo today?
To the zoo?
It's a school day.
Maybe we can go tonight?
Well, the animals
are sleeping at night.
You don't want to mess
with sleeping animals.
They might be a bit cranky.
Okay, come on, sweetie,
you're gonna be late.
You got your stuff?
- You want to finish it?
(CHUCKLES)
Great, thank you.
Hey. Come on,
you're forgetting.
Give me a kiss.
I love you.
Have a good day.
Hey, Connor.
(KNOCKING AT WINDOW)
I'm sorry, you scared
the hell out of me.
I'm Special Agent Coddington.
I'm with the FBI.
We need you to
come with us, please.
What for?
I don't know, ma'am.
They just asked me to
come here and pick you up.
Hey there, Miss Armstrong.
Come on in.
I'm Patton Dubois,
federal prosecutor.
Please come on in.
Thanks for coming by.
Did I have a choice?
Of course you did.
I don't have
anything to say,
so if you have a problem,
contact my editors.
Can I get you
a cup of coffee?
No, thank you.
Sure, sir, I'm
gonna take some.
Great scoop,
by the way.
If this doesn't
make your career,
God knows what will.
Holy moly.
That was something.
Well, I'm gonna be
announced in a few days,
just as soon as all the
paperwork goes through,
as the special counsel
to investigate this leak
about Erica Van Doren.
That was fast.
Yeah, I know,
it's kind of unusual,
but the boys over at Justice
seem to think this is
a pretty urgent matter,
a not-a-second-to-lose
kind of thing.
So they called me
in last night,
and I just checked into
the hotel this morning,
and here we are.
The Attorney General's office
has to disqualify itself.
Maybe somebody over there
was your source, eh?
I think I should call
my lawyer.
- That's not necessary.
I'm not gonna be asking
you any questions.
Not here, anyway.
This is neither the
time nor the place.
I just wanted to get kind
of an unofficial head start.
Can I talk to you
off the record?
Sure.
I mean,
a just-between-you-and-me
kind of thing.
Off the record is
off the record.
Okay, good.
I'll do all the yada-yada.
Now, you were within
your rights to print the
information that you obtained.
However, you're not
within your rights
to protect who it was
that gave Erica up to you,
who exposed her.
It's a 1982 law called
the Intelligence Identities
Protection Act.
Your source is in
a great deal of trouble.
I've no intention of
discussing my source...
- Hold on.
I'm doing the yada-yada,
remember?
Okay.
Okay, look,
you're gonna be asked
to appear before
a grand jury.
You're gonna be asked
to identify your source.
I'll be doing the asking.
Now, if, for some reason,
you don't reveal your source,
you'll be held in contempt,
and that means jail time,
and we're not talking
about some sort of
a Martha Stewart cell
with a butler, nonsense.
Look.
Rachel, go to your source.
Ask him to permit you
to reveal his name.
You may be surprised
at his willingness
to protect you.
People are inherently
decent, I have found.
(LAUGHS SARCASTICALLY)
Well, if that were true,
that would put you
out of a job, no?
Hmm.
Well, that's all I've got
to say. You'll be notified
of your court date.
I'm afraid I'm gonna
disappoint you, Mr. Dubois.
That's not possible.
MALE REPORTER:
You ready? Here she is.
FEMALE REPORTER:
Here she is.
Ready to roll?
CAMERAMAN: Rolling.
MALE REPORTER: Hey, Erica,
why do you think your
report was ignored?
FEMALE REPORTER:
Is Erica your real name?
How long have you
been with the agency?
All right, I know
you're trying to
do your jobs, okay.
I'd love to speak to you.
Now is not a good time.
I have an appointment here
to read to the kids.
FEMALE REPORTER:
Is Erica your real name?
MALE REPORTER:
Did you give your husband
top-secret information?
Does your family know
that you're here?
You know, I'm a mom.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
If this CIA report exists,
as the Sun Times
claims it does,
that would seem to indicate
the President launched
a full-fledged act
of war in Venezuela
without justification...
- Thanks.
Really nice work.
- ...and just based
on his own gut instinct.
It would also mean that either
the President lied to the
nation and the Congress...
Hey, Rache,
they're waiting for you
in Bonnie's office.
...what is arguably the worst
foreign policy decision
in this nation's history.
So far, the White House
is standing by its actions,
but they're not
denying the report.
Rachel.
- Yeah, I'm going.
Kick-ass story, by the way.
- Thank you.
...there's a reason to
question the findings.
"'Wait for me. Wait for me.
I'm a fast runner,'
said Ruthie.
"'And I'd sure like to
catch something great,'
"she added, with
a fishing pole in hand.
"So off they went.
Up a hill, down a path,
through a grove of trees,
"and just as Granny Annie
was about to tell Ruthie what
she was going to catch..."
AVRIL: If I'd been
a little bit more forceful
with you and Larry,
saying don't
rush this to press,
maybe we wouldn't
be in this situation.
I told you, the government's
gonna take this
very seriously. I told...
The next time the FBI
hauls you into
a fucking interrogation,
your first goddamn
phone call is to me!
- I got it. I'm sorry.
Before you even take off
your fucking seat belt,
you call me!
All right, Avril.
You okay?
Yeah, I was dropping
Timmy off at school,
and the FBI were there,
and they asked me
to go with them and...
Pretty unnerving, huh?
Being questioned like that.
It was really fast.
They want your source, right?
Yeah. I didn't give it
to them. I won't give it
to them. No way.
Okay, please.
First of all, this is
appalling behavior
on the part of the FBI.
Snatching you in front
of your kid.
Strong-arming you.
I want to know the name
of the agent that
interviewed you.
Well, it wasn't an FBI agent.
It was this guy Patton Dubois.
He's being appointed
special prosecutor.
What? You know him?
AVRIL: No.
No. But a special prosecutor,
that's no good.
See, his only requirement
is to find your source,
with nothing else
to divert him.
He's gonna have
unlimited time,
unlimited moolah,
and the chance
of unlimited publicity.
There's a lot more
investigative power
for a special prosecutor
than there is for a Fed.
Yeah, well, not enough power
to make me reveal my source.
I have a right to
protect my source.
What?
The federal government
doesn't have a shield law.
Not on issues
of national security.
49 states do have
some form of protection
for journalists,
but not the federal
government.
- The administration
will back off
when they see how far we
will go to protect Rachel.
The federal government
is fighting for
a principle, too.
You see, somebody
revealed top secret
information to you.
That is an act of treason.
That is how they see it.
They're gonna take this very,
very seriously.
Yeah, well, so am I,
gonna take it very seriously.
WOMAN: Officer,
what's the hold-up?
OFFICER 1: Sorry, ma'am.
Are you kidding?
My house is right there.
OFFICER 2: She's on the list.
All right, go ahead.
I want a half-hour
of reading every day.
You hear me?
ALLISON: Am I going
to get into trouble
for not going to school?
- No.
I'll miss my friends.
- I know you will,
but it's just gonna be
for a little while.
You're gonna have
a private tutor.
He's really great.
You'll love him.
I promise. Kisses.
Butterfly kiss,
Eskimo kiss.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
(KISSING)
I love you.
I told you this
would happen.
You just don't get it,
do you?
- This is your fault.
What do you want
to listen to, baby?
Who's your best friend?
Who?
ALLISON: You!
ALLISON: Bye!
Are we off the record?
Sure. I'll meet you
in the back.
You didn't come here
to kick my ass, did you?
'Cause it's not fair.
I'm not trained
in that whole,
"Knock somebody's nose
into their brain with the
palm of my hand," thing.
No, I use poison darts.
RACHEL: Funny.
I like your mums.
The yellow ones
are very cheerful.
Thank you.
Is your husband
still writing?
Yeah, all the time.
Every day.
I read his novel about
the Mossad. I read it while
I was on vacation. It was...
It was very entertaining.
Thank you. He's just
trying to get out
the second one.
So...
I'm sorry I lost
my cool with you.
Usually it takes a man
to bring out the
heinous bitch in me.
Oscar and I...
It's probably it,
you know,
the dagger and all.
He's gone. He left.
We had it out,
and he went to go
stay with Allison
'cause we had to
send her away, too.
Allison's a great kid.
She seems very grounded.
How do you know her?
You been digging
in her past, too?
No. No, I'm
a room mother.
Room mother? Man.
You should get
hazard pay for that.
I come in once every two
weeks to read to the kids.
It's a big production.
TIMMY: Mom?
- I love it.
I'm outside, Timmy!
What can I do for you?
I know you can't tell me
who your source is.
I respect that. Okay?
I know about
keeping secrets.
Just tell me yes or no.
All right? Is...
Is it someone
close to me?
Is it?
Is it someone I work with?
I can't tell you anything.
(SIGHS)
You know what?
When you go
before the grand jury,
you will have to speak.
You are an
unpatriotic little cunt...
Okay.
...who's gonna walk
right off the plank
into the bowels of hell.
Do you know that?
- I hear that every day.
If you want to go
on record, we'll give
you amazing placement.
Thank you.
What?
- Hi, Mrs. Van Doren.
Hello, handsome.
How are you?
How's Allison doing?
She hasn't been in school.
Is she sick?
No, no, no.
She is great. She's...
She's just spending
time with a relative.
Can you tell her
I said hi?
You bet. Yes, I will.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
RACHEL: Is it the door?
RAY: Yeah?
Rachel Armstrong?
- What do you need?
I'm here to serve you,
ma'am.
I just barely had time
to type that up
and get over here.
Is it okay? Does it
make sense to you?
- Yeah.
I thought the law was
supposed to move slowly?
Except for
when it doesn't.
Hey, this is all bullshit,
barging in on you in
the middle of the night,
dragging you into the
Mayflower, it's all just
meant to intimidate you.
It's working.
Well, don't let it
intimidate you. Okay?
- Okay.
You're gonna be fine.
Miss Armstrong.
Okay, I'll be down
in the lobby.
Okay.
- Don't worry.
Rachel Alice Armstrong.
15 Trinity Pass,
Washington, D.C.
Thanks. Okay,
Miss Armstrong.
You work as a reporter
for the Capital Sun Times,
is that correct?
Yes.
As the national
political correspondent,
is that right?
I am, yes. One of them.
- Okay, good.
Okay, great.
I'm batting a thousand.
You wrote an article
a few days ago, here,
in which you revealed
Erica Van Doren,
married to the former
US ambassador,
Oscar Van Doren,
that she was
a covert CIA operative.
I did, yes.
And you feel confident
with this story's veracity?
I do, 100%.
Who was your source?
Miss Armstrong...
- One second. I'm sorry.
"I respectfully refuse
to answer that question
"on the grounds that
it would violate my rights
"under the First Amendment
and federal common law."
You're aware that anybody
with official knowledge
of the identity
of a CIA operative
is forbidden by law
to release that information?
I am, yes.
So, who was your source?
I can't reveal my source...
Okay, look,
Miss Armstrong.
This is a very
serious matter.
I want you to
take your time.
We're gonna take a recess
and come back at, say, 1:30.
I want you to go home.
I want you to
talk to your family.
I want you to talk
to your editor. Okay?
And then I want you
to talk to your source.
Mull it over and see if you
all think this is worth
a contempt citation,
and then we're
gonna reconvene,
and then I'm going
to ask you again.
I wouldn't hold
your breath.
Well, I'm not the
one that'll need
to hold my breath.
Okay, everybody,
we're gonna break it up.
We'll come back at 1:30.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
FEMALE REPORTER: How long
have you been in the CIA?
MALE REPORTER:
Ms. Van Doren...
"'Can I come too?'
asked Charlie.
"'I promise to help you catch
whatever it is,' he said.
"'Come on,' said Ruthie Joe
and Granny Annie.
"So off they went
across the bridge..."
My watch says I'm early.
We just feel like this
is not the best time for
you to be with the kids.
It's just that,
you know, we're really
not equipped to deal
with a lot of craziness.
Okay.
I think it's idiotic,
is what it is. I understand,
the press can be a nightmare.
Maybe if you were to
stay away for a while,
then they would go away.
I hope we can work this out,
Jerry. I really look forward
to reading to the kids.
I mean, I'm pretty good
at it, too. I do all
the little voices.
You are. So...
When were you planning
on bringing Ali
back to school?
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
I see. Okay.
Are you saying that she
can't come back, Jerry?
How was your lunch?
- Terrific. Thank you.
Yeah, what'd you have?
- I actually didn't
have anything.
Really?
I wish I had
your will power.
Your source,
Miss Armstrong,
who is it?
Hey.
Well? How did it go?
Okay, I guess.
Excuse me. Rachel Armstrong?
Yes.
- I'm Deputy U.S.
Marshal Jones.
I have a summons for you
to appear in US District
Court in two hours.
No, no, no.
- What happened to two weeks?
Hey!
I'm Avril Aaronson,
counsel to the
Capital Sun Times.
- Oh, yeah,
I read your amicus
brief on the Celeste
matter last year.
I think you could take
credit for her release.
I really do.
I understand all the
theatrics up until now,
but this?
This is too fast.
This is outrageous,
and we're getting into
some pretty serious
Fifth Amendment issues here.
Look, Avril, there's a traitor
out there revealing the
names of CIA operatives.
Now, I think we should get
somebody like that out
tout de suite. Don't you?
We're bringing
in Albert Burnside.
Oh...
I'll have to go home
and get my autograph
book, then.
AVRIL: Don't worry about it.
It's not a problem.
It's already in
the Sun Times budget.
Hi, Avril.
Hey, there he is. Albert,
thanks for coming.
This is Rachel Armstrong.
Glad to meet you.
- Hi, me, too.
Hey, I'm Ray, Rachel's
husband. Why is this
happening so fast?
Avril said it'd be weeks
until I went before a judge.
Well, Mr. Dubois wants
to get this done before
the press catches up.
It's okay. The press can
just complicate things.
Let's concentrate on
keeping you out of jail.
Jail? What do you... When?
You're gonna ask
for a continuance?
Yeah. Sure. Sure.
Look, I've been through this.
Judge Hall is a good egg.
We exchange Christmas cards.
He's certainly not
gonna jail you today.
Jesus Christ.
RACHEL: Ray, relax.
I mean, if Albert's
this calm, then we
can be, too. Right?
We'll be out of here
in five minutes.
Then we'll get a cup of
joe and we'll strategize
how we can protect you
and the constitution
and democracy itself
for generations to come.
That's a Theory, right?
Yeah.
- It's classy.
Thanks. Nice suit.
It's not a suit. It's
a Zegna. Hand stitched,
15 mil mil 15.
What's that
you're wearing?
I don't know.
I'm putting you in
touch with my tailor.
You always know
when you're in a Zegna.
Court room three.
Your Honor, this morning,
Miss Armstrong appeared
before the grand jury.
I furnished you
with the transcripts.
And as you know, she was
asked to reveal the name of
the source who provided her,
quite possibly illegally,
with secret information
revealing the...
Excuse me,
Your Honor. If I may?
Yes.
All right?
It's perfectly okay with me.
Your Honor,
I just met my client.
I ask you to continue this
matter for, say, a week, so
we can get our bearings here.
Let me get my bearings first.
Why don't we proceed for now?
Well, here's how it is,
Your Honor.
Mr. Dubois will say
that my client was asked
to name her source
and that she won't
do so, and, thus,
you should compel her.
He'll say that the
information that my client
received is highly classified
and the GJ is entitled
to know the name of the
source and to find it out.
He'll also say that there's
no federal shield law
protecting her
and that there's no First
Amendment protection, either,
because this is a matter of,
quote-unquote,
national security.
JUDGE: Is that about right,
Mr. Dubois?
In fact, that's it
in a nutshell.
We contend that the
First Amendment does
protect Rachel Armstrong.
I'm well aware of cases
in this circuit in which
this contention is...
Well, I am aware
of those cases
in this circuit,
and they do not authorize
her to refuse to
respond to these questions.
Why don't the three of you
come up here right now?
Rachel, Rachel,
come on. Come on up.
ALBERT: Over here
to where the bench is.
JUDGE: Miss Armstrong,
I want you to understand
that if I should order you
to reveal your source,
that if you don't do so,
I'm gonna hold you
in contempt of court
and that you will
be jailed until you...
Hold on, Your Honor.
Can you rule, please,
on my request for
a continuance?
Right. I'm gonna
deny that motion.
I'm only asking for
a few days, Judge.
I understand.
There is a serious
national security...
There's no reason
not to grant a continuance.
Let me run my courtroom.
Now, Miss Armstrong,
I direct you to reveal the
identity of your source.
If you want a few
days to consider it,
I'll give it to you.
I can't do that.
Mr. Burnside, if you want
a few days to advise
her to obey my order.
I can't advise my client
to betray a confidence.
Okay, look, Your Honor,
given the direct threat
to our national security,
I ask that Miss Armstrong
now be held in
contempt of court
and that she be
jailed immediately.
JUDGE: Well, it seems to me
that I have before me somebody
who is defying my order
and who seems to
believe that she is
above the law itself.
I hold you in
contempt of court,
and I remand you to
the custody of the
United States Marshal.
Help.
ALBERT: Judge...
Wait. No, no. Your Honor.
Judge. Wait... No, wait.
Ma'am.
- Your Honor!
JUDGE: As soon as you're
prepared to speak,
you will be released.
Could I have a minute
with my client to confer?
You may consult with her
in the detention center.
Timmy needs to be
picked up from the
Hobermans' at 5:30.
This proceeding is closed.
Judge.
Judge. Your Honor!
A lot of people looking
to get famous here.
So now what?
What do we do now?
I'll call you tomorrow.
Don't worry about it.
What are you gonna do now?
- I'm gonna call you
in the morning.
All right? Okay?
Well, at least you'll
take him off your
Christmas card list. Right?
That's right.
It's a scare tactic.
- You think?
I'll deal with it.
I'll see you back
at the paper.
Okay, I'll head over there.
Mr. Burnside, this is
a real honor for me.
I studied you, growing up.
My dad was also a lawyer.
This is a big,
big mistake, Patton.
Well, there's nothing like
learning from our mistakes.
Yeah, well, sometimes
a mistake is like wearing
white after Labor Day,
and sometimes,
a mistake is invading
Russia in winter.
Hmm.
Okay, there are two things
I need to know.
First, the story itself.
- Rock solid.
Rock solid. Well,
are we talking talc or
are we talking granite?
Albert, please.
We wouldn't have
put it through
if it wasn't...
- Okay. Second,
how many people
know the...
How many people
at the paper know the
names of the sources?
We know the corroborating
source. Well,
Bonnie does, anyway,
and one of Rachel's sources
at the FBI gave us a copy
of Van Doren's report.
And why don't you have
the name of the
original source?
Well, for one thing,
Rachel agreed to
complete confidentiality,
and because her story
was confirmed, it wasn't
necessary to know.
Well, the good news is,
you can't be
compelled to testify
on something
you don't know.
Bosca wallet.
Prada sunglasses.
You can keep that.
- Thank you.
Tape recorder...
I'm gonna need to
get your jewelry.
The wedding ring.
I'd like to hold on
to those.
It's diamond, baby doll.
You don't want
that in there.
Miss Armstrong,
come up front, please.
Take a stand in front
of the machine, please.
Would you give me
your right palm, please?
Take it off.
Left, please.
It feels like his
only real target is
Rachel Armstrong
for publishing the article,
which is not a crime.
In fact...
PATTON: Okay, if we've got
Armstrong in jail, that's our
biggest ace in the hole.
Two. The Van Dorens
and everyone at the CIA
who worked with her
have agreed to submit
to polygraphs.
Jeez, could we turn
this guy off? I can't
listen to this anymore.
Better.
You know, that's the
only thing that Armstrong's
got going for her
is the media, getting them
to turn her into some
sort of a cause celeb.
We can't allow
that to affect us.
MAN: Well, under the
Branzburg case, they've got
no chance on appeal.
Even if they point out
that you didn't exhaust
any other possible sources
before going to her.
Yeah. No, the Miller case
made that perfectly clear.
GUARD: Sit still
for the camera.
PATTON: But our objective,
our goal, is not to...
Is not to keep her locked up.
I want to let her go.
That means we have
got our source
and we can prosecute him,
and, frankly,
that's all I care about.
MAN: Sit as still as you can,
looking straight ahead.
Answer with the word "yes"
or the word "no."
Is your name Erica Van Doren?
ERICA: Yes.
Were you born in
Ossining, New York?
- Yes.
(POLYGRAPH MACHINE SCRATCHING)
Have you ever lied
on any official document?
No.
Did you reveal to
Ms. Armstrong you were
an employee of the CIA?
You gotta know
a few rules.
First, ain't no smoking
anywhere in the building.
Cigarettes
are contraband.
No drugs, no fighting.
Fighting just buys
you time in deseg.
What's that?
- Desegregation.
In the movies,
they call it the hole.
I'm taking you to the
spillover room. We house the
more violent girls in cells.
What are you, a doorman?
Get out of here.
Come on. Let me out.
- Get out of here. Get out.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
And ain't no fucking.
No kind of sex at all.
No eating pussy,
no kissing, nothing.
If you're here for more than
eight months, you can apply
for a kite or a conjugal.
Here you go.
But the turnover here is
normally two weeks. You won't
even be here in eight months.
Hey!
What's your name?
- Olivia.
Olivia what?
- Olivia James.
Well, Olivia James,
this is Rachel...
Armstrong.
Rachel Armstrong,
your new bunkie.
Be nice.
And show her how
to make the bed.
There you go.
Lights out in an hour.
Lights up at 6:00 in
the morning. All right?
Okay. Excuse me.
Is there any way
of seeing a newspaper
in the morning?
No. But if you wanna watch
the news, you have to convince
all of them to do it.
(TV CHATTERING)
MAN ON TV: On his birthday,
who was driving...
WOMAN 1: He ain't no fool.
WOMAN 2: I don't care.
WOMAN 3: Ain't no tomming
in the yard, you know.
WOMAN 4: That's just sad.
Are you one of those
trained prevaricators,
Erica?
You know, they teach
you that at Langley?
Box beater.
Kicked ass, didn't I?
Who do you think
spoke to her?
To Armstrong?
God damn it. I don't know!
But when you figure it out,
just give me five minutes
with the prick, okay?
Well, it's been my
experience that
Miss Armstrong will tell us.
Right. She's never had
her Vassar ass in jail.
She'll break.
I don't know. I met her.
I looked her in the eye.
She's a water-walker.
I wish we had
the cookies, though.
Those were pretty good.
Hey. Hey.
- Hey.
Guess who's here?
Little man wanted to say hey,
make sure you're okay.
All right. Here he is.
Say hi.
RACHEL: Hey, baby. Hi.
- Hi.
Hey. Why don't you tell
Mommy what we brought her?
Mom.
- Yeah.
We brought you some cookies,
but they took them away.
No way.
Well, maybe they'll let me
have them later for dessert.
Dad made them.
- Dad made them? Yucky.
Hey,
I'm gonna be okay, sweetie.
Hey, how was
your spelling test?
It was okay, I guess.
I bet you aced it.
Practiced really hard,
didn't you? Didn't you?
Yeah.
- You sure did.
Hand the phone
to your dad, okay?
Hey.
- Hey.
Hey. How are you?
I'm fine.
- Yeah?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Don't bring him
anymore, Ray.
This is not a good
place for him.
- What are you talking about?
He's freaking out.
He wanted to see you.
What do you mean?
He wanted to make sure
you were okay.
Well, of course he wanted
to see me. But...
I mean, I'm really
serious about this, Ray.
- Okay.
I'm not gonna be
here forever.
It's a couple of days.
It's a few days.
- Okay. Okay.
So what is going on
in the news?
I haven't heard a thing.
- You haven't?
No, there's no
newspapers in here.
The TV is perpetually
tuned into Jerry Springer.
Well, your jailing,
your stance,
it's in every newspaper,
on every channel.
No, no, no. I mean with
the President. What have
they said about the article?
No, same thing.
Same as always.
"The White House
refuses to comment
on intelligence matters."
What else are they
going to say? Right?
I mean, the President,
he's not making any press
conferences, that's for sure.
Hey, listen,
I was thinking...
I mean, if this
gets crazy, crazier,
maybe you should
tell me who it is.
And that way, I can
maybe talk to the guy.
I don't know,
like on a human level,
you know?
Ray.
- What?
I've never asked you,
not once.
But this is...
This is getting crazy.
Okay, let's not
go there. At all.
You don't trust me?
- That's not the point.
(TIMER BUZZES)
Is it... What is...
- I guess that's it.
It's over.
Okay. I miss you.
I miss you, too.
Can you pass
the phone back to...
Hey, can you hear me?
- Yeah.
Okay. I need you to
make your bed in
the morning. All right?
I need at least one
responsible male in the house.
Okay? Don't tell Daddy
I said that, okay?
(GIGGLES)- I'll...
(INAUDIBLE)
RAY: She can't hear you,
buddy. Okay? She'll come
home soon. Come on.
COURT BAILIFF: All rise.
Hear ye, hear ye.
Armstrong. Let's go.
- All persons having business
with the United States
District Court in the District
of Columbia will draw near.
Give your attention
and you shall be heard.
Mr. Burnside, your client
is here now, so you may
proceed when you're ready.
Thank you, sir.
Your Honor, I would ask
that you would
release Ms. Armstrong
until such time as
the U.S. Court of Appeals
can rule
on the validity of
this contempt citation.
Now that would vitiate
the whole purpose
of her incarceration
in the first place.
She has the key
to her own cell.
A key that comes in the
form of a loss of integrity
is no key at all.
Integrity is subjective.
Miss Armstrong,
I'm sympathetic, but
you've gotta help me out.
Will you represent to
me that if you're home
that you'll pick up the
phone and call or contact
your source
and try to get permission
for you to release
the source's name
so we can put
an end to all of this?
I would be dishonest
if I said I could do that.
Well, then, you're really not
giving me any basis at all.
The motion is denied.
Sir, I would ask
that the court now
impose a fine of $10,000
a day against the Sun Times
until such time
as Miss Armstrong's
source be revealed.
Your Honor,
with all due respect to you,
this court and Miss Armstrong,
we don't know
who her source is.
I don't see how we could
be held accountable.
Sir, obviously, with
the representation
on display here,
obviously, the paper
not only supports,
but is encouraging
Miss Armstrong's position.
They're enabling her.
The Sun Times should
be obliged to obey
Your Honor,
and dismiss Miss Armstrong
if she does not.
That is out of line!
Your Honor, respectfully,
I ask you to deny this motion.
Don't even think of buckling.
Don't even think it.
You pay the fine,
and you let Rachel hold
strong, exactly the
way she's been doing.
You didn't need
to say that.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
ERICA: Such a beautiful day.
MAN: I like coming here.
- Yeah.
It reminds me why
we do what we do.
- I agree.
You know, my daddy
is buried right over there.
I feel it best that
we not meet at Langley
for the time being.
- Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. You know,
I'm just glad that you
asked to see me.
I've been wanting to
speak to you
since this all broke.
You know, I was hoping
I'd convince you
to give me a crack
at the CBD in the Balkans.
There's other business
to attend to first.
- Okay.
Erica, we've investigated
to the fullest degree
all of those people
who were aware
of your cover.
We've looked at
phone records,
emails, the works.
We're dead ending here.
- Really?
So far, the reporter is
in jail and not talking.
It's essential we find out
where this leak came from.
I know. I understand.
You know, and I couldn't
agree with you more.
You know, we don't know if
this person had it in for you
or had it in for the agency,
so can I just pick
your brain a little bit?
Yeah, of course. Please.
I completely understand.
Ask me whatever you want.
When did you first meet
Rachel Armstrong?
Knowingly?
When she came to me
at the soccer game,
when she confronted me.
And you're both volunteers
at Potomac Shores
Elementary School, right?
I am. Well, no, I'm not.
I was, but I'm not now,
but she was a room
mother there, she said.
You never met at school
functions before that?
No.
- Your volunteer work
never overlapped?
You guys never perhaps
talked mom to mom?
No. No.
Ever go to a school
event where alcohol
was being served?
What? What?
You know, when my wife
went to those functions,
those
let-your-hair-down
things,
my God, I can't tell you the
things she said that she now
wishes she could take back.
Sir, wait.
Are you still
investigating me?
Well...
- I just passed a polygraph.
Well, given your training,
I'm not sure how
valuable that is.
It is a clinical
investigation. You don't
need to take it personally.
I don't need to
take it personally?
"We think that you're
either incompetent,
a drunk, or a liar,
"but you don't need
to take it personally."
How dare you?
How fucking dare you?
Okay, you need to watch
your tone here, Erica.
Let me ask you
a question, sir.
What, in my absolutely
unblemished record,
can you point to and say,
"Yeah, yeah,
that's somebody
we can't trust"?
What?
Point is, I don't
even know you.
You've been a NOC
for so many years,
there are very few people
who actually know you.
Okay, well, you know what?
I know you. I know you, sir.
I know your type.
I see where this is going.
I smell it.
You know, if somebody
in the CIA messed up,
somebody messed up,
gave me up
and now you guys are walking
around investigating it
like the Keystone Kops.
You're just aching
for it to be me. I see it.
This way you can tell
the press, "You know what?
It's not a rogue agent.
"It is just some silly little
girl whose feelings got hurt
"that her investigative
conclusions were ignored
"by the President
of the United States."
Findings that
absolved Venezuela
from having anything at all
to do with the assassination
attempt on him.
Now you're being
dramatic, Erica.
- Fine, okay.
You know what?
You can speak to my
attorney from now on.
You can drop my
protective detail.
You can stop cutting me
checks. Okay? I quit.
You don't just quit, Erica.
Really? What is this,
The Sopranos? I can't leave
the family? I'm stuck?
Well, it's a process.
You're full of
privileged information.
You don't trust me?
Fine, okay.
I'm gonna give you
reason not to. Okay?
My husband's not the only one
in the family who can write.
Look, you sure you want
to get in a war with
the government, Erica?
Do you need the messiness?
You're in the middle
of a custody battle, right?
You sure you want to
drag Allison into
the middle of all this?
You are so lucky
you are a woman.
Why is that?
Because I don't hit girls.
You know, you weren't
the only agent investigating
the Venezuelans,
but you were the only
one that concluded
that they were not
involved in the attack
on the President.
Yours is not the only report
the President read.
I wish you the very best
of luck with your daughter
and the custody battle.
I hope you get
to see her again.
Thank you.
WOMAN 1: Yeah, watch this.
WOMAN 2: If there was enough
money in the world, I'd be
buying my way out of this.
WOMAN 3: Honey, if there was
enough money in the world,
I wouldn't be in here
in the first place.
WOMAN 2: You got that right.
What's that?
A Christmas present
from my son.
How old is he?
- Seven.
Shit, ain't nobody
in the whole world
seven years old no more.
I'm moving in.
That fat piece of shit
over there keeps
farting all night.
About to turn my carjacking
beef into a homicide
if I stay over there.
Well, welcome to
the neighborhood.
Congratulations, everyone.
We have three Pulitzer
finalists in our midst.
(ALL CHEERING)
BONNIE: For investigative
reporting.
Yo, Armstrong.
A message for you
from somebody
named Bunny.
I just took it for you.
We couldn't
find you upstairs.
So you won something, huh?
I ain't never
won nothing.
Thanks.
- Sure.
RACHEL: How was school today?
TIMMY: Okay, I guess.
- Yeah?
What was the best part?
- I don't know.
Hey, I won an award.
Though I almost did.
A big one, for being
a good reporter.
That's nice.
- And the first person
I wanted to tell
was you 'cause you're
my most special guy.
Uh-huh.
You want to put
your dad back on?
- Okay.
Okay.
RAY: Hey, he really
misses you.
Really?
- So, the Pulitzer?
Yeah. You told me,
remember?
(PHONE LINE BUZZES)
That's not that...
(SIGHS)
Everyone to your bunk!
Shake down!
Lock your hands
behind your head.
Come on, Armstrong,
let's get to your bunk.
Lock your hands behind
your head. Shake down!
GUARD 1: Let's go!
GUARD 2: Let's go, ladies!
I can find your head
by your bunks.
GUARD 2: Move!
GUARD 1: Let's go, ladies!
Let's go!
FEMALE GUARD:
Get to your racks now!
GUARD 1: What is you doing,
Miss Jones?
Get to your bunk, now!
You know this is not allowed
in here. It's contraband.
Sorry.
You been taking these
from the IK for weeks.
More contraband.
Hey, that's personal stuff.
- Mmm-hmm.
Can I have that back?
What the fuck is this?
You can't take that!
What did you say?
- She can't take that.
It's mine!
Get back to your bunk!
You hold that noise,
ma'am, or I will take
you to the hole!
You understand me?
Lock your hands
behind your head.
Deseg for you.
Fuck.
BONNIE: Well, it's amazing
news about the Pulitzer.
Congratulations.
Yeah. No, that's
great. I just...
I'm not surprised
Tom Williams got it. His story
got the mayor to resign.
The President is so popular,
nobody gave a damn
about what I wrote.
Well, we're
all proud of you.
No, I know. Thanks.
I'm sorry.
They took my journal,
my notes, for taking an
apple out of the chow house.
I can't write,
and it's driving me nuts.
They took my pen.
I can't even write
to Timmy anymore.
I was wondering if
you could possibly
write an editorial or
something, shame them a bit.
Yeah, of course.
Tomorrow, tomorrow's paper.
Thank you.
So, look,
Molly Meyers wants
to interview you.
What? Why?
I'm not anorexic.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm not in rehab. I'm not
dating Justin Timberlake.
Human interest, I guess.
Look, she's a journalist.
She has to be
on your side, right?
The top dogs are
really pushing for it.
It's like you said,
no one's writing about
your case anymore.
We're losing traction.
The government isn't feeling
the public pressure.
And the fines
and the legal fees
are growing.
I get it. Say hi to Avril...
- Don't think about that.
No. No, no.
We just need to get you
out in front again, and,
for what it's worth,
Molly Meyers will get
the eyeballs on you.
So?
Okay. But it's
gotta be live.
She's not gonna edit me
into a doddering idiot.
Absolutely.
- And I'm not fucking
crying, either.
All right.
ALBERT: What are you wearing?
What is this, the new Cartier?
It's a wonderful watch.
No, it's not a watch.
It's jewelry.
Here, look at here.
I'm suddenly nuts
about this de Grisogono.
I love the numerals.
All different sizes.
Isn't that nice?
- It's a beauty.
Ready, Molly.
All right, have fun.
Okay. They're telling me
it's gonna be substantive.
It's gonna be serious.
Really?
- Well, that's what
they're telling me.
This will be your moment,
not hers. You'll be great.
MAN: Here you go.
Rachel, hi.
I'm Molly Meyers.
- Right, we met once.
I interviewed with you
to be your research assistant.
Oh, no kidding.
WOMAN: We are not going
to have time for this.
If you have time for
the Identities Act.
Great. If not, so be it.
That's fine.
- One minute.
All right. Thank you so much
for doing this, Rachel.
And congratulations
on the Pulitzer.
It was just a finalist.
Well, bravo.
We're all with you.
Thank you,
that's very nice.
Of course, I can't
say it on the air.
Objectivity and all that.
WOMAN: All right, ready?
You know we're live?
- Todd is gonna toss it
to you in three, two...
MOLLY: Thank you, Todd.
Rachel Armstrong,
thank you for joining us.
Rachel, you have been
here for seven months.
How are you feeling?
Well, physically I feel fine.
I don't get the exercise
that I need, but I feel fine.
You know, I look at you
and I get this sort of,
"How do you do it?" sensation.
Vassar girl,
Columbia Journalism,
suburban soccer mom...
How Twilight Zone -ish
is this for you?
I must say, when I
wake up in the morning,
it does take me a few seconds
to realize where I am.
I mean, I haven't grown
accustomed to it.
You're married to the
novelist, Ray Armstrong.
How is the marriage
holding up?
Well, obviously,
it puts pressure...
- It must be very hard.
It is hard.
But we're strong.
You know,
he's very supportive of me,
and we're best friends.
That really helps.
And what about your son?
Timothy.
When was the last
time you saw him?
It's been a long time.
How long?
He came to see me when
I was first brought here,
but I have asked that he
not visit me in this place.
Well, that must be brutal.
Most mothers, though,
are going to have a
hard time understanding.
I guess I would have, too,
but most mothers
would have no idea
what they would do
unless they were
in my position.
The truth is, bringing Timmy
here would be selfish.
You know,
it would be for me.
And I do wonder a lot
if I can survive another
day not seeing him,
but I know Timmy,
and I saw the look in his eyes
when he was brought here,
and I know the damage
that it would do
to see his mother
in this place, caged up.
So, you know,
I can't do that to him.
Rachel, let's get
to the meat of it,
because I have to try.
On your story, on uncovering
the identity of the CIA
agent Erica Van Doren,
who was your source?
Well, Molly, let me ask you.
Why do you have to try?
Try to get a fellow journalist
to betray her integrity?
I know you know
better than that.
I know you do.
Before the cameras rolled,
you said you were,
quote-unquote, with me.
Look, I have empathy.
Like you, I would never
give up a source.
But you know what?
Sometimes sources
have motives.
Right, okay.
If the information
they're giving is
valuable and truthful,
like with Watergate or the
Pentagon Papers, then their
motives really don't matter.
Any real journalist would
be prepared to put up
with the discomfort of jail
to protect their principle.
I know you say you would
protect your source,
as if you're saying,
"There but for the
grace of God go I,"
and you're never gonna
have to worry about
the government
coming after you.
- Why?
Because the government
really doesn't care
how you found out where
Paris had dinner last night.
(CHEERING)
That's my bunkie
right there, y'all.
That's my bunkie!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Ray.
Hey. Hey, Albert. Hey.
Hi, I'm Albert Burnside.
Hi, I'm Gretchen Monroy.
- Hi.
So, did you see the
Molly Meyers thing?
- Yes. Yes.
Rachel was real terrific.
It was great.
- Yeah, she was unbelievable.
I'll catch up with you.
- Sure.
Nice to meet you.
Look, Albert.
- It's none of my business.
No, no, no.
No, you don't.
There are things about us
that you just don't...
When you say "us"?
- Rachel and me.
Look, Ray, if you can
sleep at night,
you can sleep at night.
She made a choice.
Choices have consequences.
Yeah, if you think your wife
felt like she had a choice
in this, then maybe you
two shouldn't be together.
Well, you can tell her or not.
That's entirely up to you.
Keep up the good work.
Excuse me, ma'am. Excuse me.
Didn't mean to startle you.
That's okay.
- I'm looking for
the Stein residence.
Stein residence?
You know, I don't know.
I don't think there is
a Stein on the block.
Harv and Sheila?
Harv and Sheila...
(GUN FIRES)
(PACKAGES CLATTERING)
MAN: Oh, God.
BONNIE: Rachel?
Who do you have
working the story?
Evans and Merkow.
The shooter belonged
to a right wing fringe group.
I guess he thought Erica
had it in for our
beloved President.
Name's Alan Murphy.
He's nuts and stupid.
Drove his own car to the
murder site, then crashed
it half a mile away.
Once she resigned from
the CIA, she lost her
protective detail.
God, this is so crazy.
Evans and Merkow will
want to get a statement
from you of some kind.
I know. I get it.
It's okay.
How's Allison doing?
- Who is Allison?
Erica's daughter.
Bonnie...
- It is not your fault.
Am I doing
the right thing?
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
What's the problem?
We still have 15 minutes.
Judge wants to see her.
I've got a van waiting.
PATTON: The President now
seems to feel compelled to
get involved personally.
He wants to get to the
bottom of this debacle.
What happened is terrible,
and my heart goes
out to her little girl,
but it hasn't changed
my position.
- Okay, that's not what I need.
I have here
copies of waivers
that have been signed
by all White House staff
and senior CIA.
It authorizes you,
gives you permission
to reveal their names
if they were your source.
It's a blanket waiver.
That should do it for you.
Have a look. See if
your source has signed.
These people were
obviously coerced.
These people here?
These people have signed
of their own volition.
Yeah, if you don't
sign these, then
we'll harass you,
we'll investigate you,
we'll make your
life hell on earth.
I'm not even going to
look at them, Judge.
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
Anybody want some tea?
- Yes, please.
No, thank you.
JUDGE: It's from Greece.
What are we going
to do with you?
This has gotten to the
point now where my wife
is pissed off at me
and is telling me that
I'm some sort of bully.
Well, you're not gonna get
much sympathy from me there.
Your Honor, can I borrow
your library for a second?
You think I should
look at the waivers.
A man can live a good life,
be honorable, give to charity,
but in the end, the number
of people who
come to his funeral
is generally dependent
on the weather.
What? I'm sorry.
I'm not following.
The weather has changed,
Rachel.
I'm sorry, but it has.
That's the truth.
In the old days,
this would have been
a lot easier to fight.
The public would
have called you a hero.
But I don't know,
somewhere along the line,
the press...
The press stopped
being the white knight,
and started being the dragon.
That's the way
people see it.
You want to know why
no paper in this country,
including your own,
has continued
covering your story?
Why don't you tell me?
Because your 48-hour news
cycle dried up months ago.
I mean, look at you, Rachel.
You look like shit.
Your kid is growing up
without you...
Don't bring
Timmy into this.
It's not fair. Okay.
I'm a good mother.
Fair? Fuck fair!
Look, you may not want to
bring your son into this,
but I do. You want
to know why?
- Why?
Because I'm defending
Rachel Armstrong,
not a principle.
A man leaves his family
to go to jail to
protect a principle,
and they name
a holiday after him.
A man leaves his children
to go fight in a war,
and they erect
a monument to him.
A woman does the same thing,
and she's the monster.
If we back down,
what are we saying,
Albert?
"Trust reporters as long as
they're not mothers,
because they'll crack."
The truth is, if I had
known that writing
this fucking story
would have separated me
from Timmy, then maybe
I wouldn't have done it.
But here we are.
The story's been published,
and the path has been chosen,
and there's no way back,
and in the end,
my son will be fine.
You know,
Ray is a great father,
and Timmy's gonna be okay,
but that will not be
the case with my source.
My source will be publicly
saddled with the death
of Erica Van Doren,
and that, I promise you,
will mean the destruction
of the person
we're talking about,
and that, Albert,
that is not fair.
AVRIL: Why?
I mean, your source knew
full well the ramifications
of speaking to you.
My source didn't know
what they were doing
when I got the information.
Was he drunk?
Was he talking in his sleep?
Hey, take a fucking walk.
We're trying to swim
a fucking waterfall
here, Albert.
We have a responsibility
to the shareholders
not to go bankrupt.
If you're so worried
about that, then I'll go
pro bono from here on in.
How about that?
- Sold.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Come in.
Okay. I just got
off the phone.
Stan Riggens has agreed
to speak to the grand jury.
I guess signing that
waiver spooked him.
Stan?
I owe that kid in
my office 10 bucks.
When is all this
supposed to happen?
As soon as possible.
It'll have to wait until
tomorrow morning.
Once he confirms
he was your source,
you're off the hook.
Pack your bags, Rachel.
You were chief of staff
to the Vice President.
I resigned
11 months ago.
And were you the source
of information provided
on the October 6th edition
of the Capital Sun Times
in which the identity
of the covert CIA
agent was revealed?
STAN: I was.
Can you tell us all
how that came about?
Well, I guess I was just
so angry at Erica Van Doren
and her husband,
my emotions got
the better of me.
I'm not interested
in your motivations.
I want to know how
you came to reveal
this information.
STAN: I was at a party.
RACHEL: ...you guys,
it's muddy right here.
I had been drinking.
Stan.
Hello there, young-ish lady.
How are you?
Can I get a beer, please?
Good. Great.
Just here with my son.
They're cute now,
but they grow up.
You know?
So I've been reading.
So I heard Glen invited you.
It's good to see you.
Yeah, and you thought,
"Well, how can I pass
up this opportunity?"
That is exactly
what I thought.
Can I ask you a question?
- Anything.
Ambassador Van Doren.
What about him?
- His wife.
Is she a spook, Stan?
(STAN CHUCKLING)
Come here.
Now, look, you did not
hear this from me.
- Of course not.
Not from me.
- Absolutely not.
But, everybody knows
she's at the CIA. Everybody.
But you can't use that.
Hey, I won't say it came
from you, but we're
not off the record.
(SIGHS)
Screw it.
Everybody knows anyway.
Common knowledge.
Do you know if she
happened to get out
to Venezuela at all?
Wait a minute.
She came to you
and asked you if
Ms. Van Doren was a spy?
She already knew.
That's right.
ALBERT: They're not satisfied
with Riggens.
He was just your
corroborative source.
So was the FBI guy
who gave you her report.
They still want the original
source, which puts us
back at square one.
RACHEL: Well, how much
longer can this go on?
It's seven months or so
before the grand jury
is required to disband,
and then Dubois can just
order up a new one.
I can't...
I'm gonna have to tell
the Warden I did this.
Look,
if you're gonna be here
another seven months,
then you should know,
in every way
how this will affect you.
(BED CREAKING)
Albert told me.
Well, do I get
any details?
Details? Yeah.
The details are
you're in here,
and whatever it is
keeping you in here
is more important to you
than what's on the outside.
Well, how long have
you been seeing her?
Just a few weeks.
Do you love her?
- I don't know.
You don't know?
It's only been a few weeks.
You don't know her.
What do you do
with Timmy?
- What?
When you're fucking her,
what do you do with Timmy?
He's with a sitter
when we go out.
Has he met her?
- No.
Do I know her?
- You don't know her.
I told you that.
She lives in Maryland...
- Okay. You know what,
I don't want to
hear any more.
- Look...
Ray, I know this is
impossible for all of us.
I get it. You're lonely.
I'm lonely.
Look, all you have
to do to keep me,
to keep my respect,
is just tell me
it means nothing.
That you love me,
and that...
I'd like to see Timmy now.
Something you should know
is I speak only the best
about you to him.
All right, don't
patronize me. Okay?
I need to see him,
and he needs to see me.
That's it.
- Okay. Okay.
I'll see what we can do.
They don't allow visitation
on weekends anymore,
and his school routine
is pretty locked in.
So, now, on top
of everything else,
you're gonna try
and keep my son
from me?
No. No, it's not like that.
- Isn't like what, Ray?
It's not like you're
cheating on your wife
while she is fucking
rotting in jail?
- Keep your voice down.
Rache.
- Is that what it's not like?
Fuck you!
- Hey! Hey!
Fuck off!
- Okay, okay, okay.
RACHEL: Go to hell!
It's okay.
Really, this is
how you want...
You know what?
Thanks for the fuck, Ray!
That really hit the spot!
Right, 'cause you're the
only one who got fucked
by all this. Right?
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
Hey.
What the fuck
is your problem?
You're in my bunk.
Get a new fucking bunk.
Hey. That's my stuff!
Stop it!
- Yeah. It's going down here!
Hey!
- Get your skanky ass
stuff out of my bunk!
Go get a new bunk!
- Get your ass out
of my fucking bunk.
This is not your bunk!
WOMAN: That ain't right.
You want the bunk?
Your bunk?
You want that bunk? Huh?
You want that bunk?
(WOMEN SHOUTING)
You want your fucking
bunk now, huh?
Yeah.
WOMAN: Come on,
leave her alone.
(ALARM BLARING)
Get down! Get down!
Get down!
Oh, God.
What happened?
I got the shit kicked
out of me, Albert.
That's what happened.
How? What?
Over what?
We both wanted the top bunk.
- What?
Well, you've always
known the important
things to fight for.
Are the doctors saying
you're gonna be all right?
Yeah. Whatever
that means.
You know, I'm the most
senior prisoner in this jail.
I've had 32 different bunk
mates since I've been here.
I gotta say,
that's a record.
Is that a new tie?
No, I've had it a while.
Domenico Vacca.
I took you for
a Kenneth Cole man.
Kenneth Cole?
Well, I'm glad you retained
your sense of humor.
You look like a woman
who could use
some good news.
It's great news.
They've agreed.
They're going to
take your case.
It's gonna be an
expedited hearing.
JUDGE: The next case this
morning is in re Armstrong.
We'll hear first
from Mr. Burnside.
Mr. Chief Justice,
and may it please the court.
In 1972 in
Branzburg v. Hayes,
this court ruled
against the right
of reporters
to withhold the names
of their sources
before a grand jury,
and it gave the power
to the government
to imprison those
reporters who did.
It was a five-four
decision. Close.
In his dissent in Branzburg,
Justice Stewart said,
"As the years pass,
"the power of government
becomes more
and more pervasive."
"Those in power," he said,
"whatever their politics,
"want only to perpetuate it
"and the people
are the victims."
Well, the years have passed,
and that power is pervasive.
Ms. Armstrong could have
buckled to the demands
of the government.
She could have
abandoned her promise
of confidentiality.
She could have simply
gone home to her family.
But to do so
would mean that no source
would ever speak to her again,
and no source would ever speak
to her newspaper again,
and then tomorrow when
we lock up journalists
from other newspapers,
we'll make those publications
irrelevant as well,
and thus we'll make
the First Amendment
irrelevant.
And then how will we know
if a president has
covered up crimes?
Or if an army officer
has condoned torture?
We, as a nation, will no
longer be able to hold
those in power accountable
to those whom
they have power over.
And what then is the
nature of government
when it has no fear
of accountability?
We should shudder
at the thought.
Imprisoning journalists?
That's for other countries.
That's for countries
who fear their citizens,
not countries that cherish
and protect them.
Some time ago,
I began to feel the
personal human pressure
on Rachel Armstrong,
and I told her that I was
there to represent her
and not a principle.
And it was not until
I met her that I realized
that with great people,
there's no difference
between principle
and the person.
Come on. I got
new digs for you.
ALBERT: You know, they
brought him out here...
JUDGE: It's nothing.
He's not
a real person here.
Soccer isn't
a real thing here.
- They don't respond
to it the same way.
Judge, good afternoon.
- It's just not.
Good afternoon,
thanks for coming over.
Mr. Burnside.
We're talking about
soccer not law.
Just want you to know.
Look, the reason I asked
the two of you to come
over here today
is that the Supremes
have decided your case.
The ruling will be
down on Monday,
but I've been told by
a confidential source
what it is,
and I wanted to
share it with you.
Five-four, opinion
against you, Albert.
Same as before.
National security,
First Amendment,
the court went with
national security.
And I want to say to you,
Patton, congratulations.
You did a great job.
The court once again
has made clear that in
a case where journalists
are not cooperative,
they may have
to be incarcerated.
Well, thank you, sir.
That having been said,
I've decided to let her go.
I'm sorry, sir. What?
I've gotta let her go.
I've been doing this
a lot of years now,
and I am sure that
this woman is not going
to reveal her source.
She's been locked up
for almost a year.
She has been beaten
within an inch of her life.
She is resolute.
- That's exactly right.
Exactly right.
I can only keep her in jail
if I think doing so will get
her to reveal her source.
She's not going to talk.
I really have no choice
but to let her go.
If I may. This is a...
This is a woman
who's been protecting
a criminal.
That makes her a criminal.
Oh, come on.
She's not a criminal,
and she won't be a criminal
unless she is duly charged
and duly convicted by a jury,
and that's not my call.
When are you gonna
sign the paperwork,
Your Honor?
I want to get her out
of there right away.
I'm gonna go to court
Monday morning.
I'm gonna announce
that I'm freeing her.
And, Patton,
you got a choice. You can
beat me to the punch.
Just dissolve the grand jury.
PATTON: As I'm sure your
attorney has informed you,
the grand jury has
been disbanded.
We're gonna have to
wait till midnight
to let you go.
ALBERT: Midnight?
What? You're keeping
the reporters away
from your losing cause?
Rachel,
I know almost all of it.
I am indicting two
government officials
for talking to you.
I wish I knew who it was
that first tipped you off,
but I'm not gonna
get greedy.
I'm losing custody
of my kid.
You want the
wedding ring?
Kind of a trophy.
You know, vilify me
if you want, Rachel,
but I had a job to do,
and I had every right
to do what I did.
I think you're confusing
your rights with your
power, Mr. Dubois.
It's okay.
We booked you a room
at the Mayflower,
but you know you're
welcome to stay with me
as long as you need.
Thank you. Thanks.
Sure.
I spoke to Ray.
He's gonna bring Timmy by
first thing in the morning.
Thought maybe
you would like to
take him to school?
Yeah.
That's okay?
- Yeah.
That'd be amazing.
God, I'm gonna scare
him to death, though.
And, well, you let me
know what you want to
do in terms of work.
You can if you want to.
No one's going to pressure
you about writing
about your experiences.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Oh, please.
Rachel, look in the glove,
hand me the insurance
and registration, would you?
I was only going 30.
Ma'am, would you please
step outside of the car?
What's going on?
- We just need you to step out.
Not you, ma'am.
Are you kidding me?
- Get out of the car, Rachel.
What's the problem, sir?
- I can't believe this.
What do you want?
- I'm gonna ask you to
turn around, please.
What is it?
What are you doing?
- Hey, hey! Go easy on her.
Rachel, I'm sorry
that it's come to this.
What is going on?
- Back in the car, ma'am.
Rachel, you're
being charged with...
BONNIE: What's going on here?
They're arresting me, Bonnie.
You're being charged
with criminal contempt
of court.
What does that mean?
Well, it means you have
obstructed justice,
and you're going on trial.
Come on. Let's go.
- Hasn't she been
through enough?
God damn it.
Oh, no. God.
BONNIE: Dubois! Dubois!
PATTON: Rachel, you're
looking at a possible
five-year sentence
for impeding
a federal investigation,
but I don't wanna
go to trial.
So, I want to give you
a chance to plead
this sentence down.
I want you to look
in my eyes and gauge
my sincerity.
Use your reporter's instincts.
Okay? You're good with those.
I'm gonna offer
you two years.
- No. No.
No, it's gonna be suspended
sentence, probation.
You have to respect
what she's been through.
Albert, two years is
not as good an offer
as it could be,
but it's not as bad,
either.
Because you're guilty,
Miss Armstrong.
You're guilty as charged,
and if you want to waltz
into a courtroom
in a martyr's cloak,
trust me, you're gonna
see something that
you have not seen yet.
Because this polite,
country lawyer demeanor
is gonna give way
to a wave of
self-righteous indignation
that you can't even
begin to imagine.
That jury is gonna hear
fire-breathing oratory
about a country
whose security has
been compromised,
a husband widowed,
and a little girl who's gotta
visit her mother's grave
because you wanted to
chase a Pulitzer Prize.
So, if you force me
to take you to trial,
I'm gonna make sure
that you don't make it home
for your son's high
school graduation.
ALBERT:
Come on, that's enough.
So, what's
it gonna be, Rachel?
If I agree to this,
there is one thing I need.
Oh, my God. You have
gotten so handsome.
You're a real little man.
I'll bet you got
all the girls chasing
after you, huh?
No.
No? Well, you will.
I don't care. Whatever.
Hey, I kind of like
your hair this way.
Look, I know
you're mad at me.
No, I'm not.
Well, I think you are,
and I haven't let you
see me in a long time.
I'd be mad at me, too.
- Well, I'm not. Okay?
Okay.
Look, kiddo,
it hasn't been easy
for me, either.
If I'd known it was
gonna go on this long,
I would have done
things differently.
I would have let you see
me every single day.
I am so sorry.
Dad says you could have
got out of here many times.
Well, your dad is wrong.
Look, kiddo...
- I'm not a kid anymore.
Okay, you know what?
You can pretend not to
love me all you want,
and I can pretend
to believe it,
but I love you,
and I think about you
every minute of every day.
Okay?
Dad says you're
going to prison.
I am.
- Isn't that where
you are now?
No. This is jail.
Jail is where you go
when they decide
your punishment,
and then you go to prison.
And what's
your punishment?
Two years.
That's a long time.
Yeah. But if I'm
well-behaved, then
I might get out earlier.
So...
Is it dangerous there?
You know what?
If you visit me,
come check on me,
I'll be okay.
Okay. I'm kind of busy,
but I'll try.
I think we should go now,
on account of traffic and all.
Hey, hey, how about
a kiss? Just one.
TIMMY: Bye.
TIMMY:
You're a tattletale!
ALLISON: I am not!
You just told on Nicky.
That's because
he won't stop.
You're a tattletale.
RACHEL: Timmy,
that's enough. Stop it.
That's enough.
- But you're not
supposed to tattle.
Well, you're not supposed
to have to put up
with bullies, either.
Come on. Come on.
Are you a writer
or something?
Yeah, I'm a reporter.
I work for the
Capital Sun Times.
We get that newspaper.
Oh, yeah? Well,
tell all your friends
to do the same.
The Internet is killing us.
- Mom, how long
till we get there?
About 18 hours, Timmy.
No, Mom, really.
I don't know.
My daddy is a writer.
He is? What does he write?
- He writes articles,
though my mom doesn't
really like what
he writes about.
What's he write about?
- He writes about
the President.
What's your last name?
Van Doren.
Why doesn't your mommy
like what he writes about?
I heard her yelling
at Daddy once.
'Cause he used her
secret stuff,
she found out.
What she found out?
- When she was in Venezula.
Why was your mom
in Venezuela?
Was she on vacation?
Uh-uh, she was working.
Working?
- Uh-huh.
For the government.
But don't tell anybody
it's me who told you. Okay?
You bet.
(NOTHING BUT THE TRUTH
PLAYING)
# Hey, baby,
do you see what I see?
did you hear the decree?
# Hey, baby,
can you look in his eyes?
# And does it still
make you feel high?
# And are you ready to go?
# Go out to,
to be at your man
# Do you see
the sound of the stars?
# Red road to Mars
# One thing we share
is the silence of God
# We got nothing to do
but wait out our trip
# To the end of the way
and you get used to it
# And all we are asking for
# Is nothing but the truth
# And are you feeling
a free will
# And is it
burning in you still
# While this whole,
whole world just dies
# And as we move
from the light
# Do you see
the sound of the stars?
# Red road to Mars
# One thing we share
is the silence of God
# We got nothing to do
but wait out our trip
# To the end of the world
and you get used to it
# And all we are asking for
# Is nothing but the truth #
Subtitles by LeapinLar