[classical music plays]
[deep, rumbling
percussive music]
[distant crowd cheering]
[music plays, crowd cheers]
[speaking foreign language]
[crowd cheering]
[indistinct chatter]
[crowd clamoring]
[bell dings]
[shouts]
[bird's wings flutter]
My brother's right.
You're a good fighter.
Don't spend it all in one place.
Time to meet the devil.
[vehicle approaching]
Are those women?
Yeah, 50 percent.
I'm looking for a girl.
A young girl.
I want to fuck
a 14-year-old.
Only what you see.
Let me ask you a question.
You got a daughter?
Bring her in.
I'll pay you 15,000 baht.
No, no, no. Sorry.
Hello.
Hey, not do like that.
Come on. Oh...
[glass shatters]
[women screaming]
[footsteps echoing]
[lights click off]
[door locking]
[rain pattering]
[man grunting]
[low rumbling]
[metal scrapes, rings]
- [metal slices]
- [screaming]
[gasping]
[moaning]
[man] It's about your brother.
Billy's dead.
[piano plays]
[lounge music plays]
[singing in foreign language]
I'm checking in.
One moment, please.
I'm afraid the room wouldn't
be ready until four o'clock.
It's a policy.
Get your manager.
He'll be here in a minute.
What's your problem?
Good morning, madam.
How may I help you?
Listen to me.
I have just traveled 10,000
miles to see the corpse
of my first-born son.
I haven't slept in 30 hours.
And this bitch says
I can't have my room.
[elevator dings]
Ask him why he
killed my brother.
[inaudible dialogue]
Did you miss me?
I missed you so much.
Did you get the guy
that did it?
How did you kill him?
I let him go.
Get the door.
Are you out
of your fucking mind?
Some cunt killed your brother
and you let him go?
It's a little more complicated
than that, Mother.
Meaning what, exactly?
Billy raped and killed
a 16-year-old girl.
I'm sure he had his reasons.
Now sit!
I know it's hard
for you emotionally.
You've lost your brother.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of the yellow
nigger who killed my son.
It's too much for you.
Now get up and kiss your mother.
[screams]
If you ever come back,
I'll kill you.
- Is it done?
- Yeah.
How's business?
Yeah, it's OK.
I could do with having
Billy back, though.
Isn't Julian taking care
of everything?
He hasn't told you, has he?
There was
someone else involved -
when Billy was killed.
- Who?
- Some cop.
Don't worry.
I'll find him.
And then we'll kill him.
Good.
[indistinct chatter, laughter]
[groaning]
[grunting]
[gagging]
[woman] She doesn't
know what to think.
[foreign language] He says
he didn't see it, Mum.
A foreigner called up Liang
and spoke English.
Then he went with him
and took the phone with him.
Hey, Julian.
The cops want to see you.
- What do they want?
- Probably money.
- You want me to ask how much?
- No, I'll go.
[man] You're Julian?
- Do you know Choi Yan Lee?
- Who?
Your brother killed
his daughter.
What's that have to do with me?
Choi Yan Lee was murdered.
- When?
- Yesterday.
[mid-tempo
electronic music plays]
You can't go around
killing cops anymore.
[woman] How much do you want?
It's not about the money.
What's in it for me?
I have five kilos of blow
arriving Friday. I need
someone to help me move it.
You got any questions,
you ask him.
And what about Julian?
Don't worry about Julian.
- Are you in or out?
- I'm in.
I'd like you
to meet my mother.
I want us to pretend
that we're a couple.
Can you do that?
Will you wear this?
So, tell me, Mai.
What line of work are you in?
- I'm an entertainer.
- An entertainer?
And how many cocks
can you entertain with that cute
little cum-Dumpster of yours?
What do you think
of his line of work?
I'm not talking
about the fag boxing club.
I'm talking about
where the money comes from.
You know what he does, right?
He deals drugs, Mai.
Heroin, cocaine. That's
where the money comes from.
That's how he can afford
to pay you to fuck him.
Oh, great. I'll get the crab.
He'll have the spicy chicken.
And May here will have a salad
with the dressing on the side.
It's Mai.
I'm sorry.
I apologize for my behavior.
It's just that
I'm a little upset.
I have lost my first son.
I'm sorry for that.
Thank you.
It's good to know someone cares.
'Cause I swear to God, sometimes
I think Julian hated Billy.
Maybe "hate" is the wrong word.
But you were always
jealous of him.
You know the way boys are, May.
Competitive.
And what with Billy
being the older brother
and having a bigger cock...
Julian's was never small,
but Billy's was...
Oh, it was enormous.
How can you compete with that?
Billy was everything
Julian wanted to be.
Is that not true?
'Cause let me tell you,
if the tables were turned,
your brother would
have found your killer
and brought me his head
on a fucking platter!
And you just sit there thinking
he got what he deserved!
Fuck you.
I don't want to talk
about it anymore.
Do you mind if I smoke?
[Julian] You can keep
that dress if you want to.
[Mai] I don't want it.
Why do you let her
treat you like that?
[gasps]
'Cause she's my mother.
Now if you don't want
that dress, take it off.
[screaming] Take it off!
[inaudible dialogue]
[engine revving]
[siren blaring in distance]
[police sirens approaching]
[sizzling]
[screaming]
[low rumbling]
[metal scrapes, rings]
[inaudible dialogue]
[blood spattering]
[Thai music plays]
[singing in foreign language]
Who the fuck are you?
Get out of my club.
Can somebody tell me
what the fuck this cunt
is trying to say?
Who put out the hit?
Go fuck yourself.
How about that?
[screaming]
[panting]
She said you murdered her son.
She wanted you dead.
[sobbing]
[man continues sobbing]
[man screaming]
[gasping] Fuck you.
[man moaning]
[moaning]
[screaming]
[screaming continues]
[inaudible]
[man singing faintly
in foreign language]
You know who he is?
Want to fight?
[electronic music plays]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[punches landing]
When I was pregnant with you...
...it was strange.
You were different.
They wanted me to terminate...
...but I wouldn't.
And you're right.
I don't understand you.
And I never will.
[whispers] What have you done?
I fucked up.
I tried to do right by Billy.
And now I'm going to pay.
He's coming after me next,
and I have no one left
to protect me.
I know after your father I said
I'd never ask you again,
but please, Julian,
just this once.
Take care of this for me.
Don't let them hurt me.
Then we can get out of here.
We can go home.
I can take care of you.
I can be your mother again.
Who's going to do the kid?
We're just here for him.
But that's not what she said.
What did she say?
She said to kill them all.
[elevator dings]
[woman] I came here to
collect my son's body.
Now that it's been released,
my business here
in Bangkok is done.
I'm ready to go home.
- [man] When are you leaving?
- I was leaving tonight.
And your other son?
Is he going with you?
What, Julian? Oh...
I haven't had any
real contact with Julian
since he left America.
But you were there last night.
Yeah.
He's not much of a fighter.
And it breaks my heart that
Billy got caught up in the scene
here because of him.
Billy was my first son.
We had a very
special relationship.
Julian was so jealous.
It was like he was
cracked or something.
He had paranoid delusions
about us.
And it pains me
to say this to you,
as it would pain any mother,
but he killed his own father
with his bare hands.
That's why he had
to get out of America.
He's a very dangerous boy.
[indistinct chatter]
[gunfire, bullets rattling]
[metal scrapes, rings]
[blood spattering]
[blade slicing,
blood spattering]
[wind blowing]
[electronic music plays]
[singing in foreign language]
[song ends]