ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]:
Brooklyn, borough of churches...
... and the site of this year's National Public
Safety Football League championship game.
This has been a tough-fought
battle all night.
BOBBY:
Hut. Hut, hut.
ANNOUNCER:
O'Reilly sacked on a play by Donaldson.
He didn't see it coming.
So that's gonna bring up fourth down.
New York will have to punt it away.
BOBBY:
Huddle up! Come on, let's go!
ANNOUNCER: N.Y.P.D. team had only
one loss in the past two years...
... but these are some tough cops
from Detroit Metro.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Let's go, Finest! Let's go, Finest!
ANNOUNCER: New York leads 14- 10,
with time running out for Detroit.
Silvano to punt it away for the Finest.
BOBBY:
Hut.
NYPD PLAYER 1:
Bobby!
NYPD PLAYER 2:
Yeah, good punt, Bobby!
Defense, get ready. Head up, head up.
- Come on!
- Get him! Get him!
[GRUNTS]
[WHISTLES BLOW]
ANNOUNCER: Terror from Detroit
almost took it to the house...
- ... with a return of 50 yards.
- Let's go.
- Jimmy! Jimmy!
ANNOUNCER: Stopped by Romero with a hit.
Watch number 31, the tailback.
He's hitting the flats.
I got it, I got it!
- Go, Jimmy!
- Go, Uncle Jimmy!
ANNOUNCER:
Ball spotted at the New York 35.
JIMMY: Huddle up.
NYPD PLAYER 3: Let's go.
Hey, Ace.
- Nice of you to show up, Ray.
- I'm sorry. I got hung up. Hey, Slim.
CAITLIN: Hey, Uncle Ray.
RAY: Hey, kids.
FRANCIS:
Hey, Uncle Ray.
Oh, my God, it looks like my brother.
I think. Is that my brother?
Gonna bust my balls or kiss me?
JIMMY:
Turn left!
CARPENTER:
Boss 2! 22! Set, hut!
JIMMY: Watch the flat! Watch the flat!
NYPD PLAYER 6: Catch him, Manny!
JIMMY:
Get the back! Go right, go right!
[GRUNTS]
ANNOUNCER: Egan.
- Make noise! Make noise!
- Well done, Jimmy!
- Whoo! Go, Daddy.
SHANNON:
Yeah! Go, Daddy!
ANNOUNCER: The captain has made
a huge contribution to tonight's game...
... with 15 tackles and two sacks.
CROWD [CHANTS]: Let's go, Finest!
FAN 1: Hurry up, hurry up! Hurry up!
Spike the ball! Spike the ball!
DETROIT PLAYER 1: Hustle! Hustle!
CARPENTER: Break! Break!
Set, set! Down, hut!
[WHISTLES BLOW]
ANNOUNCER: Carpenter spikes
the ball with only three seconds left.
NYPD PLAYER 4: Come on, let's go!
FAN 2: Jimmy!
ANNOUNCER: New York leads 14- 10.
Standing by now for Detroit.
- Come on, baby. All right.
- All right.
Remember, bro,
there's no time on that fucking clock.
Give me 43 Mike Fire, Cover 3. All right?
From the heart, Jimmy.
FAN 2:
Let's go, Jimmy!
Let's go! Let's go!
JIMMY:
Here we go, baby, here we go.
Where would you rather be
than right here, right now?
One snap. Weight of the fucking world.
All right?
43 Mike Fire, Cover 3. 43 Mike Fire,
Cover 3 like fucking champions.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Defense!
I love you fucking guys.
Give me a Finest on three.
- One, two, three!
ALL: Finest!
CROWD:
Defense! Defense! Defense!
NYPD DEFENSIVE COORDINATOR:
Defense! All right, one play!
- This is what we've been waiting for, baby.
- You got one play right here!
ANNOUNCER: Three seconds left
in the game. And this is it.
Come on, Jimmy!
DETROIT PLAYER 2:
Watch 39 in the flats!
JIMMY:
Tight-end splits! Slide right, slide right!
CARPENTER:
Red 22! Red 22!
- Defense!
CARPENTER:
Watch 9!
Get set, get set.
Down, set! Hut!
ANNOUNCER: Carpenter rolling left. Egan
breaks through the line, chasing him down.
Ball's in the air.
Whoo!
- Yes!
ANNOUNCER: Incomplete.
Incomplete. Great pressure from Egan...
... blitzing up the middle,
forcing Carpenter to rush his pass.
Yeah! All right, Jimmy!
Who's number one?
FRANCIS: We are, we are, we are.
FRANCIS JR: That's right, baby.
PLAYERS [CHANTING]:
N.Y.P.D! N.Y.P.D! N.Y.P.D!
Jimmy!
ANNOUNCER:
Now, the winner of the PBA 50-50 raffle...
... will be announced
at tonight's championship dinner.
- It's at DiStefano's...
MEGAN: Ray, you coming down or what?
[PHONE RINGING]
No, no, no. Go, I'll catch up.
MEGAN: Come on. You ready? Be careful.
Watch your step. Let's go see Daddy.
FRANCIS JR:
Inspector Tierney.
CROWD:
Finest! Finest!
What?
JIMMY:
Chase me. Come on. There you go.
What's the location?
I'm en route.
RAY: Franny.
- 10-13. They got four guys down.
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
Central. We're possibly going to Central.
FRANCIS JR: Yeah. Yeah,
it's Jimmy Egan's guys.
Yeah, of course he's on his way,
he's their fucking sergeant.
No, no, he's coming with Ray.
Yeah, yeah, my brother Ray. Yeah.
Look, that's all I know right now.
I'll call you when I have anything more.
I'm here. All right.
[SIRENS WAILING]
FRICKER: Inspector, it's up this way.
FRANCIS JR: What do we got, Lou?
- SNEU team took it hard.
- Who?
FRICKER: Ruiz and Gillick, DOA. Mercer and
Cavanaugh, getting worked on now.
FRANCIS JR: Motherfucker.
We know how this happened?
Still sorting it out.
FRANCIS JR: Is the XO working?
- No.
I want his ass notified and here,
forth-fucking-with.
FRICKER: Yes, sir.
- Duty captain 84?
FRICKER: Captain Banks.
- Where?
FRICKER: Inside.
- Keep the press back...
...and I mean fucking very.
- Make a lane for these buses.
FRICKER: Yes.
- Now!
- FRICKER: Yes, sir.
BANKS:
This is a royal cluster, sir.
- What do we know, Tom?
- We don't know shit, sir.
We know there was an anonymous call,
shots fired, that SNEU picked up...
...and went 84 immediately on.
Two minutes later, the neighbors call in,
another shot's fired.
They think the fucking building's
coming down around them.
Sectors respond, and they come to this
fucking bloodbath.
FRANCIS JR: How's he doing?
- Multiple gunshot wounds.
FRANCIS JR: He likely?
PARAMEDIC: Lost a lot of blood.
Inspector, we got this covered.
You ought to be with your men.
- These are my fucking men.
- Yes, sir.
MAN 1 [OVER RADIO]: Central, you got
Aviation in the air? Notify Aviation.
MAN 2:
Aviation, 1-Central-8...
OFFICER: Yeah. Let's get him on the bus.
MAN 2: Have them check the yards, Central.
FRANCIS JR: Hey, how's he doing?
OFFICER: Critical, we gotta get him out.
You hang tough, Billy.
You fucking hang on, brother.
I'm gonna see you at the hospital,
all right? You fucking hang tight, man.
OFFICER:
Watch the door.
OFFICER 1: Let's fucking move.
Get these cars out of here!
OFFICER 2:
Yo, we gotta make a lane for the bus.
OFFICER 1: Right here.
OFFICER 2: Move that one out of here.
OFFICER 1:
Open it up, come on. Let's go.
Right there. Let's go.
PARAMEDIC: Coming through.
JIMMY: Who is it?
Lonnie. Oh, my God.
EMT: You know this guy?
RAY: We know him. We know him.
RAY: I'll ride with you.
EMT: Talk to him. Keep his eyes open.
OFFICER 3:
Upstairs, second floor.
BANKS: We've got the block locked down,
the crime scene secured.
A level-three mobilization
worked out on anything...
What the fuck is Ruiz doing in here
lying with these scumbags?
BANKS: Go.
- Get him out of here!
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
Central, you got any...?
- I want you to oversee the hospital plan.
BANKS: Yes, sir.
I want someone with the families
every moment...
Jimmy! Listen to me! Jimmy.
[PANTS AND MUMBLES]
What the fuck?
Fuck, no!
Jimmy.
JIMMY:
What the fuck?
[CRYING]
FRANCIS JR: They entered a tenement
at 186th and Audubon.
FRANCIS SR: For the purpose of?
FRANCIS JR: Responding to shots fired.
Two were DOA at the scene,
Officer Cavanaugh pronounced en route.
My last guy Lonnie Mercer's
up in surgery now.
AVERY:
All right. Where are we on task force?
FRANCIS SR:
Being assembled. Smitty's on point.
AVERY:
All right. I want the best men available.
The severity of the situation
is such I want cops we can trust.
Don't beat yourself up here, Franny.
There's no blame in this.
There's not a goddamned thing
any one of us could've done.
My cops, my command, Pop.
We lose officers in the line, Francis.
It's not your fault.
Forty years wading through shit like this,
watching our guys die.
You keep the rage.
You cut the rest of it loose.
Any word?
Pop's here.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
Dr. King, please call the operating room.
TRISH: Excuse me.
ORDERLY: I'm sorry...
TRISH: Let me go! I wanna see
my fucking husband.
ORDERLY: I can't let you back here.
There's nothing I can do.
TRISH:
I wanna see my fucking husband!
FRANCIS JR: Trish.
- I wanna see my fucking husband!
I wanna see his face.
I'm sorry, Trish. I'm so sorry.
[SOBBING]
TRISH:
Oh, my God.
Hey, kiddo.
Hey, Pop.
Hell of a thing, huh?
Good you came.
You were there for Lonnie at least, huh?
Yeah.
I sat down with Bill Avery and Armstrong.
We're gearing up task force.
RAY: Yeah, well, everyone's gonna
want in on that.
You're gonna get all the oranges.
How about you throw your hat in the ring?
Make a phone call.
Me?
No. No, definitely not.
Don't you think it's time you got back...
...after two years on the tit
feeling sorry for yourself?
I don't feel sorry for myself.
I'm just not up for that.
How about Lonnie? You feel sorry for him?
His wife, his kids?
- You guys came up together.
- Oh, come on. Don't lay that on me, okay?
- If it was you, he'd be all over this.
- Yeah.
- Be the first one signing up.
- I know that.
Not a goddamn thing I can do
for Lonnie now, Pop.
I held his hand
in the back of that ambulance...
...and even that didn't do any good.
He died looking into the face
of a friend, Raymond.
Yeah.
You're too smart not to know
that you're wasting your talent...
...in goddamn Missing Persons.
- For you, it's a fucking dumping ground.
- Yeah, well, it doesn't bother me.
It bothers you.
Yeah, look.
Pop, it's been a shitty night, okay?
I just wanna get out
of these fucking clothes...
...and wash this whole day off.
I'll see you.
Don't turn your back on me, Raymond.
You're my kid, my blood, but you
might as well be a fucking Martian.
Okay.
I'm gonna say what I'm gonna say,
and then I'm out of here.
I'm walking out, and it's over.
I want you on the task force.
But fuck if I'm gonna go after
a favor and have you run from it.
Now, the men who were killed
were under your brother's command.
You could be a benefit here and show you're
worth all that early praise and promise.
Show everybody that gives a shit
that you haven't abandoned them.
Now, Raymond, do me a favor.
Forget the past.
Forget Mott Haven, all that shit.
Now is now. I know it's a hell of a thing
to break back in on...
...but you worked those streets. You know
the neighborhoods up and down. Yes?
Yeah, I worked those streets, Pop.
Okay, so you take the task-force spot...
...and you go at it
with all the gifts God gave you.
Cops died here, Raymond.
Four cops.
And no matter what we've forsaken
of ourselves, we can't forsake them.
Don't sit on your hands here, kiddo.
Don't sit on your hands here.
MILLER: I knew you couldn't stay away
from all this forever.
RAY:
Yeah, don't get used to it.
So, what do we got?
Crime Scene process these tracks?
MILLER:
Yeah, it's done.
RAY: They get anything off the canvass?
- Uh-uh. Still pending, bro.
RAY:
So they found our guy up there?
Yeah, Gillick.
Must've went up when it popped off.
Got hit halfway up,
fell back on the landing.
Wait, they're still calling this a 911, right?
Shots-fired call?
MILLER:
Yeah. Why?
Well... I mean...
I don't know, man.
How you figure this went down?
I mean, our guys go in, maybe they
take down the guy right inside the door.
Then the whole thing touches off and you
got a lot of firing, very close quarters.
So that shooter, I mean, wherever he is,
he could've split, but he didn't.
He dug in, shot it out.
I mean, maybe he
surprised them somehow.
Maybe.
RAY:
Somebody hit him.
He comes out,
catches Gillick coming up the stairs.
Then he comes down,
he's dumping blood all over the place.
And he splits for the street.
Then he does what?
He didn't hail a cab.
He have a car waiting?
MAN: Go.
- Could've jacked somebody.
Whoever he was, he was no amateur.
No, he's just a lucky
motherfucking perp, man.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Maybe.
What's up, Ray?
Is that you?
No.
Is that yours?
Where is that?
COP: I got it, I got it.
- No, no, don't touch that. Don't touch that.
You got a bag?
LIEUTENANT: All right. All right, listen up.
Here's what we got.
We ran the stamp name on the smack
recovered at the scene.
It's called WMD.
Six hits, six names.
Their sheets and mug shots are inside.
Not a big group, so we should be able to
iso these fuckers and close them out.
So I'm gonna say it again.
Share your information. Anything.
Hints, hunches,
any scrap or shred of information.
I don't care if it goes off the back
of a matchbook, a strung-out CI.
Put it inside the fives, get it in print
and get it to me.
- Where's our list?
DETECTIVE 1: I got it.
Anybody speak Spanish?
- Yeah, I'm all right. What's up?
- I need some help with an interview.
Hey, vouch that and do a dump on it.
- See how quick they can turn it around.
- All right.
- What's up?
- Got a kid inside...
...who might have seen something, but
I can't understand a word they're saying.
And papi's giving me a hard time.
- Yeah, all right. I'll give it a shot.
- All right.
[RAY & BODEGA OWNER
SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[BODEGA OWNER'S WIFE SPEAKING
IN SPANISH]
Yeah, all of it.
That's right. Take it easy.
You hit the calm button, all right?
If I gotta put an arm on you, you're
gonna spend Christmas in central booking.
He's just a little boy.
You don't understand.
No, I know, I know.
I just need him to point me
in the right direction. Please.
Come on, now. We really need
your help here. Just five minutes, okay?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. My man, calm down.
It's the fucking holidays.
It's Manny?
- You speak English okay, Manny?
- Uh-huh.
Okay. This is gonna be easy. Okay.
So...
Now, you remember last night?
There was some loud noises
across the street.
Guns?
Yeah, there were guns.
You know what guns sound like?
I hear them lots of times.
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
Okay, so when you heard the guns,
where were you?
Were you over by the door
in your daddy's shop?
Uh-huh.
Yeah? Could you see out onto the street?
Did you have a good view of the street?
Mm-hm.
Okay. Now, when the guns
stopped shooting...
...do you remember if a man ran out
from behind that building?
Uh-huh.
And did he get into a car?
- Uh-huh.
- He did.
Okay, now,
I want you to think for a second.
Did that man look like
he was hurt to you?
In the leg, he was bleeding.
- In the belly, he was...
- In his belly?
Uh-huh.
Okay. Manny, that's the guy
that I'm looking for. Okay?
So I'm gonna show you some pictures.
Just a couple pictures of people.
And if you see the guy that you saw,
the guy who got in that car, you tell me.
BODEGA OWNER'S WIFE:
Manny.
RAY:
Okay? All right.
How about this guy?
Is that him?
How about him?
No?
How about that one?
That's the man?
That's the man that you saw?
BODEGA BOY:
Mm-hm.
You sure?
Do you remember
what color that car was?
- Um. White.
- White.
- You sound pretty sure about that.
BODEGA BOY: Uh-huh.
It was a cab.
But not the yellow kind.
RAY:
Manny, you're good, man.
You don't remember if it had two doors
or four doors, do you?
BODEGA BOY:
Um... Four.
RAY:
You have a great memory.
Anything else?
You remember anything else?
BODEGA BOY:
He looked scared.
RAY:
Who? Who looked scared?
BODEGA BOY:
The man driving the car.
He looked really scared.
KENNY:
What do we got?
It's the fucking cabbie. Tezo must've
whacked him and had someone pick him up.
He's a fucking que pasó, Jimmy.
Fucking termite choking on splinters,
had a run of good fucking luck.
JIMMY:
No one's that fucking lucky, Kenny.
Tezo got tipped off our boys were
coming through that door to get him.
Christ.
You gotta give
the little fuck credit, though.
On the fly, under pressure?
It's a fucking tight piece of work here.
We gotta find this guy, Jimmy.
We gotta kill this prick.
These guys were... Jesus.
JIMMY: Hey, do me a big favor, all right?
All of you.
Say nothing about this I don't already
know. It's a waste of fucking words.
[SNORTS]
They're dead. Our money's missing. There's
only one of those things we can get back.
Yeah, we all loved those guys.
It was a shitty way to punch out,
so pray they died quick and leave it alone.
First things first, we got handed up.
By who, we're gonna find out
real quick. Get the can.
We gotta pull the pin on this fuck now.
- The rat squad gets an angle on this...
- They'll blow our shit sky-high.
EDDIE:
What about Casado?
What about him? Still wants Tezo
taken out. Nothing's changed.
EDDIE: How do we know Tezo
didn't jet out of town?
Because his fucking juice is here.
Goes somewhere else speaking next to no
English, he's fucking washing dishes.
Get it good, Kenny.
We leave nothing for them. We stay out
in front of the task force on this.
You got a gun, you got passport
to wherever this prick's holed up.
Toss every block in the five boroughs
till we find this piece of shit.
[WINCES AND SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
KHOMAR:
I'm sorry, Mr. Tezo.
I'm sorry.
TEZO:
Baby.
Bring me a potato.
KHOMAR:
I'm sorry.
Damn it. Fuck, I don't like that.
[THUGS SPEAKING SPANISH]
KHOMAR: Okay, okay. I'm sorry.
It hurts. I am sorry.
THUG 2:
Hello?
TEZO: Oh, you think?
- Shh. Shh. Shh.
TEZO:
I'm gonna fucking cut you, doc.
KHOMAR: Okay, we are done.
That should do it for us.
TEZO: We need money for this mamañé,
this bullshit dagabanza.
[LISETTE MOANING AND YELPS]
KHOMAR:
Oh, very good.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Tezo.
Hey, doc.
Hey, who's this?
Hey, Filk, it's Ray Tierney.
Yeah. Hey, can you
check something out for me?
That perp who was right inside the door,
the one who had his coat on?
Yeah, see if he got processed
that afternoon.
Yeah.
Hang on.
It's Lupa. L-U-P-A. Sam...
Son of a bitch.
I got water in my bedroom.
Don't ask.
Sammy Lupa. Yeah.
It's not on his sheet, but look at the...
Look at those photos. He's got...
He's got no laces in his shoes,
he's got no belt on.
I mean, what does that say to you?
Well, that's why I thought so.
All right, let me know.
Yeah. Merry Christmas. Bye.
Shit.
["RUDOLPH THE RED-NOSED REINDEER"
PLAYING AND PEOPLE LAUGHING]
Hey.
You weren't gonna knock or anything?
Yeah, I wasn't sure...
I thought you'd be out, anyway.
Figured you were out
doing your last-minute shopping...
...tearing around, you know.
I found that a while ago.
I've been meaning to give it to you.
Thanks.
You gonna go your mom's?
- No, they're coming here.
- Oh.
My sister's in town with the kids.
Good. Good.
I miss them. Give them my love, okay?
You? You going over to your parents'?
No.
We're gonna get everybody
over at Fran and Abby's this year.
Just better. You know?
How is she?
She's the same.
Franny, how's he holding up?
He's okay, I guess.
He doesn't talk that much about it.
But we had a bad couple days.
You heard?
Yeah, I heard.
I know how close you and Lonnie were,
and I'm really sorry, Ray.
Would it have killed you to call me?
- We can't keep doing this.
- Doing what?
It's Christmas morning.
You're leaving presents on my stoop. Why?
You're my wife for another month.
I can't leave you a Christmas present?
Are we down to that?
We have tried and we have tried, Ray.
We went over it and we went over it...
...and we keep coming up
against the same wall.
Come on. Come on.
No. No. That's not true.
- Tash, if you knew how much...
- I know.
I feel the same way, Ray.
But I'm doing what I have to do.
This is what I need to do for me.
Okay.
Have a merry Christmas, okay?
Yeah, you too. You too.
Okay. Okay, okay.
RUBEN:
Whole thing's fucked.
Tezo's gone with the wind...
...and we're out here doing this shit
on Christmas fucking morning.
Hey, fucko, you forget
four of our guys got killed?
Tezo was out of control. He was dishing
on the street, dealing his shit.
The cocksucker was a fucking liability.
Lived by it, now he's
gonna fucking die by it.
Think Casado's any better?
Casado knows.
Keep it inside, man,
behind closed doors.
Out of sight, out of mind.
And the fucking envelope's on time.
The way it was.
Just the way it was.
You gotta keep your head up.
We're not paying the piper on this.
There's no way.
We're not going to fucking jail. Okay?
Family seeing us behind glass, fuck that.
Fuck that.
Fuck it. Come on.
Let's go pay Pepe a visit.
Let me get a couple AA batteries, bro.
Angel Tezo. You know him, right?
No, I don't.
- Angel Tezo, you know the cocksucker?
- No.
- You don't know Angel Tezo?
- No, I don't.
- Aah!
EDDIE: Fucking liar.
Try to be a fucking gentleman.
Get on your knees.
Get on your fucking knees!
- Tezo, where is he?
OWNER: I don't know.
You think I don't know you're running
drugs here for him, you greasy fuck?
- Angel, you work for him? You feel that?
- Yes, I do.
- You do. Where is he?
- I don't know. I don't know.
EDDIE: You tell me where he is and you live.
- I don't know. I'm telling you, I don't know.
- I know you're hooked up.
- I don't know.
EDDIE: Where?
- I don't know!
I'm gonna put a bullet right in your head.
You're gonna die for that shit.
I'm gonna count to three,
then I'm gonna shoot you.
Where the fuck is he? Where is he? One.
OWNER:
I swear to God, I don't know!
- Where the fuck is he?
- I don't know!
EDDIE: One.
- Eddie!
- He knows where he is!
OWNER: I don't know!
- Eddie. Eddie, he doesn't know where he is.
- He fucking knows! Back off! Two. Three!
[GUN CLICKS]
- Eddie, what the fuck, bro?
EDDIE: Ha-ha-ha.
I'm fucking with you, man. See? See?
Get up. Get up. Get up.
Look at your fucking nose, bro.
What the fuck?
Tell you what.
I'm coming back tomorrow.
I want you to find out
where that motherfucker is.
Hey, we're still friends, right?
We're friends, right?
Let's get out of here.
Tomorrow, I'm gonna have bullets
in my gun, though. All right?
Clean up your nose, man.
Feliz Navidad, brother.
RUBEN:
Let's go.
I'm not playing!
FRANCIS SR: Think that's right to do that?
- Yep.
That is not right to do that, Bailey.
I'll have you...
- It is not right to do that.
- I could have you in cuffs.
That's silly. I know what's gonna
happen next, you'll jump me.
- How you doing?
- I'm good to go.
You all right?
- Last chance to slip out the back.
- Not a chance.
All right.
FRANCIS SR: What are you gonna do?
Yeah, that's a good...
MAUREEN: Bailey.
- Yeah?
You wanna come help Mo-Mo
bake some Christmas cookies?
BAILEY:
Uh-huh.
Oh, good. We got stars, we got snowmen,
we got Santa Clauses...
- If you forfeit the game, you lose.
- I didn't forfeit the game, I won.
And for you, mister, we got no more
of this. Come on, give me the drink.
- No, no.
- Give me the drink.
- You've had enough for a while.
- No.
- You've had enough.
- My dear.
I know.
[CHUCKLES]
What have you done?
FRANCIS JR:
You gotta open it up to find out.
Is?
Gaelic.
What does it say?
It says "Mo Cion Daonnan."
- What does that mean?
- It means "My love eternal."
MEGAN: They can go. They can eat them.
JIMMY: You got it, sweetheart?
- Merry Christmas! Hello?
FRANCIS: Hey, Grandma.
Oh, here they come, Mo-Mo.
- Look who's here.
BAILEY: Aunt Megan! Aunt Megan!
Sorry I'm late.
Uncle Jimmy's got presents.
There he is. There's Pop-Pop.
FRANCIS: Can we open presents now?
- Merry Christmas. Not yet.
JIMMY:
Merry Christmas, chief.
- Hey, Ma.
MAUREEN: Merry Christmas.
There's my girl. How are you, buddy?
- You get good stuff?
- Yeah.
SHANNON: I heard Santa Claus
comes out of the chimney.
FRANCIS:
Whoa, it's a ball!
- What is that?
CAITLIN: What about mine?
FRANCIS SR:
No opening, not yet. We don't open yet.
- Oh, look who's here.
- Ma, can we open the presents now?
ABBY: Yes.
FRANCIS: Yeah, presents!
Okay. You can open the presents.
- Hey there.
FRANCIS JR: Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas. You look so beautiful.
Doesn't she look beautiful?
FRANCIS JR:
All right, Christmas time. Presents.
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
You look beautiful.
ABBY:
Thank you so much.
FRANCIS: Come on, Dad.
- Thank you. Merry Christmas.
JIMMY:
All right, kids. Gifts. Gifts, gifts.
- Hi, handsome.
RAY: Hey.
ABBY:
How you doing?
- I'm okay, you know.
- Yeah? Did you see her?
Yeah, I went by this morning.
And?
It's the same.
- Holy smokes.
MATTHEW: One more.
Rescue gear.
FRANCIS JR: What's going on? Talk to me.
JIMMY: Nothing. We ain't got shit.
FRANCIS JR:
What do you know about Tezo?
He's a lowlife dealer.
He operates a couple blocks.
So you're telling me we're in the clear?
Franny, I was with Jack Gillick
last week at the range...
- He didn't say anything?
- Not a word.
Are you sure about that?
My guys were doing something,
I'd know about it.
- We gotta get this guy.
- Give me a couple days. Let me ask.
- And we'll find out. Trust me.
- All right. Yeah.
Come on, we're missing Christmas.
Come on.
FRANCIS JR:
All right, who wants ham?
SHANNON: I need a knife.
FRANCIS JR: Hot stuff.
FRANCIS: Where's?
ABBY: Megan, this is...
FRANCIS JR: All right.
MEGAN: There you are.
Franny.
- Last but not least.
MAUREEN: Oh, potatoes.
ABBY: They don't want the
Brussels sprouts. That's a little big.
MAUREEN:
So we got sweet potatoes.
FRANCIS SR:
Do these kids need any sweet potatoes?
- Only Monday of next week.
- Monday?
Well, yeah. It wasn't just today, right?
I bring back souvenirs...
ABBY:
Didn't that happen with Jimmy Jr?
We went to the Poconos.
That was the first time we ever took a trip.
I'd like to go on a great vacation.
What are you talking about?
[LAUGHS]
Wait three years and I'll take you
anywhere you want, sweetie pie.
[CHUCKLES AND IMITATES FART SOUNDS]
So how you finding being back?
Good. I mean, I wish it was a better
circumstance, but we've got a good team.
- Guys treating you all right?
RAY: I worked with these guys.
- You remember Chris Miller?
- Yeah, yeah.
- I was on some cases with him.
- He's a good guy.
RAY: Yeah.
- It's just like riding a bicycle.
You never forget to ride a bicycle.
It's just like him.
Look how happy you made the old man.
It's the best Christmas present.
- Caught a lucky break with that kid.
FRANCIS SR: There's nothing lucky about it.
You have the instinct for it.
You have the talent for it.
You can see everything
when they're kids.
I could see him when he was a kid.
JIMMY: Mm-hm.
He was the brains. He was the thinker.
He solved problems.
And that's what he does now as an adult,
he solves problems.
And he was always a leader.
He was a leader of men,
and people listened to Franny.
He has a personality.
He's gonna be a full inspector
before you know it, Abby.
And then there's my little baby girl there.
And she was always just
the way she is right now.
She had a heart
as big as the whole world.
As big as the whole world.
And that's why... That's what she is now.
That's why she's a nurse.
My kids.
That's my kids.
Most important thing in the world.
That's a pretty high bar we set,
me and Mo-Mo, huh?
Pretty high bar we set.
MAUREEN:
You're okay, old man.
You're not bad yourself.
[ALL SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
THUG 2:
Shit.
TEZO:
Lisette.
THUG 1:
Fuck, man! I fucking...
[GUNSHOTS]
[LISETTE SCREAMING]
COP:
10-13, 10-13...
DETECTIVE 1:
Okay, this is what we got.
Number one's got a bullet in the head.
You're looking at an exit wound.
Went out the window.
Number two put his arm up, bullet went
through the arm and into the head.
Number three back here, he's been here
a couple days. He's a little ripe.
Took one to the back of the head.
And we don't really know
where the fuck he fits in just yet.
[SIRENS WAILING]
We're thinking that's the way he took off,
through that fucking window.
You wanna see the witness?
- Yeah.
DETECTIVE 2: Look at me.
DETECTIVE 1: She's back here.
DETECTIVE 2: Hey, Lisette.
Now, fuck this
you-don't-understand-me bullshit.
DETECTIVE 1:
Steve.
Want you to meet Ray Tierney
from the task force.
- Hey, Ray.
- Hey. Ray.
How you doing?
So, what do you got?
Well, she's pretty scattered.
About half a gram of coke, some hypos,
two decks of heroin...
...you know, out of her purse.
- Why he didn't just waste her...
- Yeah.
What'd she say?
Nothing I can understand.
It's all ghetto shit.
- Can I have a few minutes?
- Yeah.
- Get a crack at it?
- Yeah, sure.
RAY:
Lisette.
[RAY SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[CRYING]
Is that your little girl?
You're gonna lose her.
We're gonna bust you for possession.
Child Services is gonna
take her away from you.
Is that what you want to happen?
Is that what you want?
Wait a minute, what is that?
What's this? What is this?
What happened there?
He do that to you?
Did Tezo do that to you?
Did he, Lisette?
Did he put that gun to your head?
What happened?
[LISETTE SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
- Has anybody looked at her?
DETECTIVE 1: There's a bus on its way.
Okay. Look, I wanna help you, okay?
But you gotta give me something.
I know you got something.
Give me something.
Who?
Sandy.
Sandy helped him escape. Who's Sandy?
What?
DETECTIVE 1: She talking about us?
- No. Shh. Shh.
Hey, look at me. Look at me.
[WHISPERS]
Sandy's policía?
Tezo's friend's a cop?
If you're lying to me...
...I'm gonna take your fucking kid
away from you.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] She's bugging out.
She doesn't know what she's saying.
I tell you what, do me a favor.
Hold on to her till she gets straight.
I'll meet you at the house.
- All right.
- Nobody talks to her.
- Okay?
- I'll handle it.
- Thanks.
PRIEST: Why does a man choose
to be a police officer?
What kind of man gets up in the morning,
showers, shaves, and goes to work...
...not knowing whether he'll be alive
at the end of the day?
What kind of man has the courage
to stand at the door of the temple...
...and say to those who seek to corrupt,
rob and harm our citizens:
"Not on my watch.
You will not harm one of mine"?
Lonnie Mercer was that kind of man.
As we commit his body to the earth...
...we ask God to take Lonnie's soul
into everlasting light.
May his soul rest in peace.
Amen.
POLICE SERGEANT:
Present arms.
Hey.
Franny.
FRANCIS JR: Hey, Ray.
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- I'm okay.
- Hey, you did good.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
Yeah.
Wanna get a cup of coffee?
I gotta go home and see Abby and the kids.
Wanna spend the day with them, you know?
Sure, yeah. Listen, I gotta talk to you
about some things.
Okay. What's up?
You and Jimmy coming up with anything
about why your guys were in that building?
No, Ray. They were just
being cops, you know?
Are you sure your guys didn't run
a plant-and-bust on Tezo that day?
It feels like they popped that guy
on nickel-and-dime shit...
...so they could use him on a door knock.
I know these SNEU guys.
They'll go around a warrant doing that.
I need to know
if you were giving them that.
Wait a minute. What are you saying?
Did I miss something here?
Did you already catch the scumbag
that killed four of my guys? Did you?
Listen to me. Listen.
We found a cell phone outside
of that apartment. It was Tezo's.
We dumped it. Somebody called him
right before our guys went in.
Now, I checked it against the trace
on that 911 call.
It's the same number, Fran.
And you know where the call came from?
It came from Coney Island.
How are shots fired in Washington Heights
heard in Brooklyn?
- I don't know. You tell me.
- Tell me that.
Half your guys were at that
football game, okay?
If you were gonna pull a sting,
that would be a good time.
Look, I'm not trying to put you on the spot.
I'm helping. I'm trying...
Do you wanna help me?
Do you wanna fucking help me?
You find that scumbag
that killed four of my guys.
Yeah. Hey, hey, that's what I'm doing.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
I talked to this broad Lisette.
She says that a friend of his called him
and tipped him that our guys were coming.
She says it was a cop, Franny.
She said, "La policía."
She said it was someone named Sandy.
You got any cops in your precinct
named Sandy?
No.
No nicknames, nothing?
- I said I don't know anyone named Sandy.
- Okay, okay, listen.
I have not shared this around, Franny.
It is not gonna take peerless detective work
for someone else to connect these dots.
I know you're trying to protect your guys...
...but you gotta get...
- Protect? Protect? They're gone, Raymond.
Freddie, Jack, Billy, Lonnie.
They're all dead.
What the fuck do I gotta
protect them from now, huh?
Fran. I'm trying to protect you.
You know, these questions are gonna come,
Fran. We gotta start dealing with it.
FRANCIS SR: Find fucking Tezo, Ray,
all right? Do me a favor.
FRANCIS SR:
Anybody in?
RAY:
Yeah.
- Hey.
Come on in.
What happened?
My carpet. What happened to the carpet?
You're supposed to fix the leaks before you
put the carpet down, Pop. You know that?
Oh...
Boats leak, Raymond.
It's the nature of things.
Close the door, will you?
There you go.
- Have a few nips this evening, Pop?
- Had a glass of Scotch, officer.
Just one, huh?
I used the same glass, yeah.
Let me put on a pot of coffee.
Oh, boy.
Got some memories in this tub.
Here. Drink that.
It's nice and warm.
Your brother called me.
Oh, yeah? Did he get something?
Ears to the ground,
but they're getting blanked.
He said you came at him a little bit.
Asking about his boys,
how they were operating.
I ran up against some shit
didn't feel right.
I went to see if Franny and Jimmy
could clear it up for me.
But it didn't file?
You didn't put it down in the fives?
No, I didn't put it in the fives yet.
But some of it, Pop, I gotta.
Raymond, you got
something case-pertinent...
...help us catch this cocksucker,
by all means, share.
But you start looking for loose ends...
...where your brother's boys
are concerned, where's that gonna fall?
You think I'm not thinking about that?
This isn't loose ends.
Pop, I got the shooter's girl saying...
Saying that he got tipped off.
And she says it was a cop
that made the call.
Are you telling me
we're gonna suppress that?
Not suppress, Raymond.
Sit on, for the moment,
anything that might go sideways on us.
Oh, come on. It's the same thing.
You know what position
that's gonna put me in?
Raymond, eight years
as a Major Case narc...
...and you never let something settle
before you put it in print?
Made sure it wasn't gonna come back,
bite you, jam you up?
I'm not looking to jam anybody up,
not intentionally.
Intentionally, unintentionally.
Doesn't matter.
Anything that makes cops look culpable
is no good, Raymond.
What do you want me to do with it?
- You want me to spell it out for you?
- Yeah.
Stay on point. Keep your focus
on finding the fuck who killed our guys.
And if you find anything else
that seems off...
...you come to me
and we deal with it. Okay?
If you say so.
I say so.
Okay.
[CHATTERING]
- Hey, Lou, you still here?
LIEUTENANT: Yes, boss.
FRANCIS JR: No one goes downstairs.
- You got it, boss.
Hey, Sandy.
Hey, boss.
What are you doing here this late?
Come here.
Hey, guys. Clear it out.
Zach, take it upstairs.
RUBEN:
What's up?
I'm gonna ask you this one time, Sandy.
Okay.
And if your first impulse is to lie,
you better fucking resist like hell.
Boss, what are you talking about?
Angel Tezo.
Yeah?
This girl they hauled in
up in the Bronx, Lisette Rivera...
...she was the last one with him.
She said a cop tipped Tezo off
to the Washington Heights raid.
She said this cop
went by the name Sandy.
- Really?
- Yeah, really.
Well, shit, I don't know no...
You set them up to die?
- Your own men!
- I didn't know.
- You let them walk into that?
- I didn't know! Jesus Christ, cap, please.
He was... I've known him since we
were kids. He was my ex-wife's cousin.
You fucking piece of shit!
I told him to get out, they were coming.
I didn't know he'd stay.
You didn't know he'd stay?
I swear, I didn't know
it would end up like that!
What did you think would happen, Sandy?
They were going in there to kill him.
Egan said for them to kill him.
What...? What?
Jimmy? Jimmy Egan said what?
He wanted Tezo dead.
He sent them in there to do him...
...take his money.
Are you fucking telling me Jimmy Egan
was going after drug money?
Kill Tezo, steal his shit,
get into business with Casado.
That was the deal.
You're telling me the fucking SNEU team
was going after drug dealers?
That Jimmy Egan was fucking putting hits
out on people for fucking money?
- That's what you were doing on the street?
- Yeah.
And you dealt with that
by setting up your own crew?
By sending them into a fucking ambush?
You don't call me?
You don't fucking come to me, Sandy?
- I'm your fucking CO!
- I didn't know they'd die.
And I thought you knew.
Everybody knew.
[MEN LAUGHING]
FRANCIS JR:
Hey, get out of here.
Get the fuck out of here!
You're done. Tonight.
Turn in your gun, shield, ID card.
And if I see you around here, Sandy,
I will shit-can your pension for good.
This is all I got.
Well, you don't got this anymore.
[CRYING]
[SOBBING]
Fuck!
MEGAN:
Aah! Whoo!
[MATTHEW SCREAMS]
MEGAN: Ready?
MATTHEW: Yeah.
JIMMY: Four.
SHANNON: Hut-hut.
JIMMY:
Hike.
[SHANNON GIGGLES]
There's nothing wrong with...
That means we're gonna have,
what, four kids?
Four kids? I can't afford that shit.
Four kids?
MATTHEW:
This one.
You think that's fun?
It's definitely time for hot chocolate
and marshmallows.
Do you have ice in your boot?
Okay. There we go, baby. Whoo!
- All right, honey, boots.
MEGAN: Okay.
- Ow, ow, ow.
- Oh, I'm sorry, pumpkin.
- I'm okay.
MEGAN: Okay.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
Oh, who's that?
Who is that? Let's go get the door.
What's up, guy?
MEGAN: Hi there.
- Good afternoon, Mrs. Egan.
Is Jimmy home?
Yeah. I'm sorry, who are you?
- I'm a old friend of his.
- You're an old friend of his?
Baby, I got it. Jimmy, come here.
Come here. Get inside.
- Get some hot chocolate. I got it.
- He's an old friend.
JIMMY: What the fuck you doing here,
Casado? Get around back. Now.
MEGAN:
Who's that, baby?
Nobody. He's out of here in five minutes.
- Where do you know him from?
- From work. He shouldn't be here.
So why is he here?
I'm gonna get rid of him.
Kiss for me? Rah!
- I love you, Daddy.
- I love you too.
You too, Mommy.
Do you have any juice?
Jimmy, Franny's called you
like a thousand times today.
- You gonna call him back or what?
- Yeah, Bobby's going on vacation.
Probably wants me to cover.
I'll talk to him tonight.
You know how many cops
I got as neighbors, moron?
I figured that.
What got into your head,
you come to my home?
Well, I call you on your jack
and it's disconnected.
You could have caught a tail. They could
have eyes and ears on us right now.
Better slow down how you talking to me.
I'll smack fire out you.
And I don't give a fuck
if you a cop or no cop.
- Understand me?
- Listen, you fucking cocksucker.
I don't care how much jack you think
you got, who's backing your play.
You come to my house, you try to
press me in front of my kids, my wife...
...it's a fucking mistake.
- Yeah, laugh, you fucking scumbag.
- You hard as fuck, Jimmy, wow.
But you slipping, J. You slipping.
- Why is this motherfucker still breathing?
- We on a buzzer beater with you?
- Is this a clock?
- Might as well be.
I give you money,
and this shit ain't handled?
You fucking with old boy,
you should be fucking with me, Jimmy.
- What's the problem? What's the problem?
- You glance at a TV lately?
- Yeah.
- What'd you see?
Your boys been getting blasted lately,
but I don't give a shit about that.
I just wanna know, are we straight?
Are we straight, Jimmy?
Did I make the arrangement?