Metal screams...
something hit me
square in the chest...
there's no up or down...
I don't weigh a thing...
I don't remember a thing.
Arr...this doesn't look good at all,
I must have done something again.
Wish I can remember what.
How did I get here, what have I done, and why...
I must have forgotten my medicine.
I got a condition. It's bad to forget your medicine
when you got a condition.
Caught myself a bullet,
the wound is fresh.
Maybe an hour old?
I can't remember how I got it.
For the life of me,
I can't remember.
The Projects...
ugly as ever.
What the hell am I doing here?
Put the pieces together.
Remember.
It's Saturday...
So I must have started the night at Kadie's Joint...
just another Saturday night...
Me and all the other losers
like me...
Sucking back the sauce, drooling like fools, over Nancy....
I wasn't in the mood,
even watching Nancy couldn't cheer me up.
I get that way sometimes.
Empty in the gut, hollow in that lonely place
and wishing I had an
excuse to break somebody's face.
It was just another Saturday night.
I was wondering what I was gonna do with myself,
when I smelled something awful.
Burning hair.
Burning meat.
Like this poor old guy
didn't have it bad enough already.
Damn frat' boys!
Damn rich spoiled brats!
Leave him be.
Crawl back into your bottle, Bernini boy!
Why did he call me "Bernie"?
At least I know they're bad guys.
Nothing wrong with
killing a bunch of them.
Hell, it's practically my civic duty.
Oh, these wormy little twits.
I hate these guys.
God just help my friends.
They made a run for it. I did  what
any good citizen would do.
Go to hell!
What the hell!
That's when I get my idea.
If they got back to the university out in Sacred Oaks
I'd never catch them.
I bang them around
like a hockey puck,
cut them off at every turn.
I left them no choice but to
head over the hill, to The Projects.
I can just turn my back
and leave them here.
My old neighbors will
take care of them but I couldn't.
What the hell, why should they have all the fun!
The Projects...
I was born here.
My old neighborhood.
Ted, he's a dead man!
Tell you what,
I'm gonna get you a  good shot.
And hes a dead man!
My old neighbors.
They let me know they're watching.
I remind them who I am.
I tell them what to do.
No, no please, please,
I got money.
I got a trust fund, I can pay.
You'll pay...
Before you shot me, you called me "Bernie",
why did you call me "Bernie"?
Bernini, its a brand name.
That coat you're wearing, it's a Bernini.
Thanks for clearing that up, kid.
Knife!
Bernini, huh?
That one fine coat it is...
somebody must have
spent a fortune on it.
I wonder who.
And while I'm at it, where
the heck did I get these gloves?
I can't remember
for the life of me.
[police siren blaring]
Poker...
savage power...
in gentleman's hands.
It's a good game!
Now, who wants to play?
Sin City is where you
go in with your eyes open
or you don't come out at all.
But the city is
like a woman or a casino.
Somebody's gonna win
and it's gonna be me.
It's the kind of place
your father doesn't want to talk about.
But where I come from...
father is a thing no one seems to be able to find.
I was feeling lucky
I had won money in joints all over town.
I finally made it to Kadie's
Where the real score is.
What happened to the show?
Have a trick, stranger?
- Heads or tails?
- Head.
That's a trick.
That won't get you anywhere.
Follow the shiny object.
Where'd you come from handsome?
Do me a favor, blow on this.
Does lady luck have a name?
Marcie.
Lucky man!
Every time ma'am, where's the real action ?
Baby, you don't want to know.
I do want to know.
Whatever you say, boss.
Back at the bar, it's your funeral.
He'll eat you alive back there.
I'm pretty tough to chew.
Kiss it this time.
- Hey Marcie, you want to go make some real money?
- Um...hmm, yeah.
I'll check.
Goodnight.
I'll play.
Who's the slicker?
I busted this one
for crabs at Josie's once.
Play on, it's okay.
Whatever you do kid,
don't win too much.
I never lose.
What's with bringing
a fair lady here?
That's my good-luck-charm.
Besides, i intend on making a pretty nice dime tonight.
Gotta have someone
to spend it on, right?
Silvio, let our young friend
here do the honors.
Cut.
Woo...
This boy's good.
Nancy, Nancy, Nancy, Nancy!
Nancy, Nancy!
And the dealer will take two.
One hundred.
I'll play.
I'm out.
- I fold.
- I'm done.
How dumb are you feeling now, boy?
Pretty dumb.
Nancy, Nancy, Nancy, Nancy...
Well senator, I'm ready for your worst.
Boy, you don't even want to
dream about my worst.
No, I don't imagine I do. That's why
I'm gonna let you just flatten
your ass right now and we can call it a night.
Sure, it is a fair game
played by honorable men.
I'm gonna raise you 300.
Easy, kid.
You got any idea
what you're up against?
Looks to me I'm up against a man.
You're up against a Roark.
Yeah I was born here, senator.
I know who you are.
We all die here sooner or later.
I'm gonna raise you another 500.
I like this kid.
I like him a lot!
I'm gonna call you.
You won't be needing
anything for cab fare, will you?
Now that's as fine a hand
as you'll ever have friend.
Just keep in mind
what hands are made out of.
Will do.
Hey!
Get your ass outta here, run like hell,
you might still have a chance.
No, I can't miss tomorrow night's game,
not any more than you can, officer.
Besides, I aready promised
Marcie a night on the town.
I can't protect you.
Then why are you a cop?
Where are we going, Johnny?
Everywhere.
One of these days
she'll pull the trigger
and then there's nothing I can do.
There's nothing I can do now.
All I can do is ask...
...listen, don't,
don't avenge me, Nancy.
It'll be the death of you.
I can't help.
I can't watch.
Death is just like life in Sin City.
There's nothing you can do
and love doesn't conquer anything at all.
Good luck, Nancy.
Live while your alive.
Just try, sweetheart.
We made Sin City history.
Hit every hot spot in town.
I blow through almost as much cash
as I make at the table
The trouble starts when
I try to use my credit cards.
I'm sure there must be some mistake.
We'll be happy to extend your
line of credit.
How can all of em go bad on the same night ?
It's not like you don't have cash.
That's not the point, come on.
We gotta get you home.
Something comes up behind us.
It smells all wrong.
This will slow us down.
You get to the side, Marcie.
I gotta break some bone.
What are you talking about, you silly.
You just stay right there.
Gentleman, listen. I think I know what this is about,
I want you to know you'll have
no resistance from me
But that black jack you got in your hand
could split somebody's skull open.
What the hell was that all about?
You stay out of sight now,
you'll be safe in Old Town.
Meet me at the 3 Sheets Hotel.
Room 166.
6...what?
Let's get this over with.
I enjoy too much wealth.
You made a fool of me, boy.
Right in front of the wrong people.
You took your chances like
we all did and you lost!
You have any idea how easy
I kill little snots like you.
Now, let's see about that winning hand.
Powerful men watched
what happened at that table.
I need them to know
the price of defiance.
Power is a...fragile thing.
It tolerates no threat.
Defiance must be met with
an example of the wages of defiance.
You'd be smart to kill me now.
I'll do far worse
than kill you, boy
What you havent counted/have encountered, boy,
is power.
Everytime the wind blows cold and wet the thing that was your hand, now clutches your leg in
arthritic agony.
Whenever it rains, you'll remember me
You'll remember me, all the time,
my son.
Oh yeah, I know who you are.
I knew you were one of mine
the minute I saw you. Family resemblance, my boy.
But I don't give a damn.
I only have one real son and
he's already rest in peace.
And he couldve been president.
Did you really think...
that I was going to claim you?
He beat me, Roark.
but when I get back,
it'll be a whole different game.
It's another hot night.
Dry and windless, the kind that
makes people do sweaty,
secret things,
things worth money to me.
This is the last time, Sally.
This has gotta be the last time.
You always say that.
I mean it this time!
She glides out of her coat
like it was Christmas wrapping.
playing it for all it's worth
and it's worth plenty.
- This is the end for us.
- The end for us?
It's my wife.
She's asking all kinds of questions.
She suspects something.
She'll sue and she'll
get everything. Everything!
Everything you worked so hard for.
I worked my butt off.
I built my business up
out of nothing.
Nothing.
Nobody appreciates you,
do they, Joey?
Not the way you deserve.
Nobody.
My employees would be out on the street if it wasn't for me.
Not my wife who I found on the street!
- The jewels and that mansion you bought her.
- Your wearing all those clothes that I got her!
With my money! My hard-earned money!
I think you're so strong.
You're damn right about that.
Do I get any credit? They just
take and take and take!
One of these days I'm gonna
fire the whole pack of women.
I'm gonna show them who's boss!
Show me, Joey.
Show me who's boss.
It's all over pretty quickly.
I get everything I need.
The sad thing is some
of the composition is pretty good.
You make me feel like a woman.
I know it sounds corny but it's true.
I love you, baby.
You know I love you
Even though you lie to me.
My wrist hurts, Joey
Can you can go get the key,
it's just in my purse.
You don't have any idea
how much I've sacrificed.
What are you doing, Joey?
It's tearing me up how much
I love you and what I gotta do
but I worked too hard
and Lori will get everything
and I can't let that happen.
I don't have any choice.
It's all her fault.
Joey please...
I won't tell anyone, I swear.
I know you don't wanna talk.
I know that!
but you're only human.
Lori is gonna find out about you
if she doesn't know already and
she's gonna offer you a lot of money, my money.
And she's gonna  give it to you
to bring me down!
- I'll go away!
- Who's gonna pay for the ticket?
That ticket and God knows what else!
Then the apartment, the clothes, the car. You're gonna suck me dry and you'll never, ever stop!
No, please no!
Kill him!
Nobody is killing anybody,
not while I'm around.
Then can I have a ride?
I grab the key and uncuff her.
She gives him a goodbye that will still hurt like hell when he comes to.
I leave the slob handcuffed to
the bed for housekeeping to find.
I take Ridando over the hill toward Old Town.
Thanks for my life, man.
Sally blends into the sea of flesh that is Old Town.
They all come back.
The damn Old Town memories, drunken mornings and sweaty sex and stupid bloody brawls
and that thing I did.
You can't just pick and choose.
You can't take the good
without the bad,
not once you let the monster out.
I can't let it out. Never again.
I drive 10 blocks out of my way and stop for gas I don't need,
avoiding the worst of this job.
My employer, the wife.
This one's got a lawyer
to pay the tab, so it's easier.
Please leave by the servant's exit.
The Mustang shudders, begging to cut loose and show what it can do.
It wants to take me all the way
I don't let it.
I think about all the ways I've screwed up and what I'd give for one clear chance to wipe the slate clean.
I'd give anything, just to cut loose,
just to feel the fire,
one more time.
Never lose control,
not for a second.
Never let the monster out.
Remember when you did.
Remember what you did.
Yeah?
Dwight, is that you?
Ava.
I'm sorry to call.
I know I've got no right
but I need to see you,
tonight.
Please Dwight, don't hang up, please.
She keeps talking.
Like an idiot, I keep listening.
Ava.
Damn.
I should tell her to go to hell.
Instead I show up 20 minutes early.
What the hell does she want with me now?
You can't drive 2 blocks in Sin City without coming across a saloon.
The bad kind.
Why here, Ava?
With you everything always
had to be first class.
And when I couldn't foot the bill,
you sure as hell found somebody who could.
I ordered up a ginger ale and stared at it for the better part of an hour.
She's late,
like she always was
and like always,
she is worth the wait..
Dwight.
How long has it been?
4 years?
Yeah, that sounds about right.
Have a seat.
So many times I wanted to call you.
I found myself thinking about you.
Constantly.
I got places to go, how about
you just tell me what you want.
Don't be cold.
I don't think I could stand that right now.
I must still mean something to you.
You came here, you must have cared.
Sure.
You called and I came running.
You still got that much of a hold on me, maybe you always will
but I got no reason at all
to be nice to you.
I guess I deserve that.
Let's not screw around.
I'm here.
I'm listening.
Just tell me what the hell it is you want?
There's only one thing I want from you, I want it so desperately that I could scream.
I want you to forgive me.
So you've got a conscience afterall.
Fine.
I forgive you, you got your wish.
Now go home,
sleep tight.
You're right about me.
I'm a selfish slut who threw away the only man she ever loved.
But I was wrong.
Good one.
I was born at night but
it wasn't last night.
I'm in hell, Dwight.
It's worse than you can imagine.
You made your bed, sleep in it!
- Forgive me, darling, I beg you.
- No!
- I love you.
No!
You do that again, I swear to hell I'll kill you.
If you can't forgive me,
then please remember me.
They say you never die as long as somebody remembers you.
What the devil are you talking about?
Mrs. Lord.
The weather is inclement,
the neighbourhood is bad
and your present company...is low.
You're due at home, Mrs. Lord.
- I'd say that's up to Mrs. Lord.
- This is none of your concern, sir.
Any physical contest between us
Would have one outcome.
Hey buddy, is that dickhead giving you a hard time?
You want me to break him down for you?
I got nothing going on tonight.
That would be an interesting contest.
It's not his fight.
Never mind Dwight, it's too late.
I'll go with him.
Too late for what, Ava?
For everything.
Just remember me, my love.
Remember me.
You have business tonight, Mrs. Lord,
unpleasant business.
I don't care anymore.
The night air hasn't got any colder,
it just feels that way.
Buddy, I don't mean to poke my nose
right where it don't belong but
that there, is a dame to kill for.
Ava...damn!
Night turns to day and then it's night again
and there's no where to hide.
She isn't worth a moment's thought
and I can't get her out of my head.
What am I doing smoking?
Where did I get these cigarettes?
It's Ava making you crazy.
All over again.
Never let the monster out.
Shake her off, whatever she's in for, she deserves it
but I have to know what's wrong.
It's a couple hours of drive out to Sacred Oaks.
It shouldn't take too much effort to get to the bottom of this.
Just a simple job of breaking and entering,
punishable by up to 5 years in the slammer even if I don't kill anybody.
I wind up seeing a lot more of Ava than I bargained for.
She seems perfectly goddamn fine.
Not roughed up,
just the rich man's wife she always intended to be.
I'm a damn fool.
Freeze! Pervert!.
Let me through, Manute.
I'm sorry, Dwight.
An atom bomb goes off between my legs.
A freight train barrows into my jaw.
I've taken a beating before but never like this.
Never like this.
The sounds go wet.
Maybe he keeps hitting me.
I don't know...
...I'm gone.
Gone to that place where there's no pain or thought.
I wake up in mid air.
The pavement rushes up to give me a big sloppy kiss.
I'll be damned.
Door to door service.
Then I spot my Mustang,
which makes no sense.
Why would they return my car?
Get out of here.
No.
Put your clothes back on and get out of here, now!
You had your chance. I would've stayed away but you came for me.
You still want me
and I'm yours, now!
Tonight!
Get out of my life once and for all
or I'll bash your teeth in.
If you can't love me,
hate me.
If you can't forgive me,
punish me.
Make me hurt, like I've hurt you.
I call her every foul name there is.
She makes my name sound like music,
like a chant to some dark god.
She's slippery with sweat.
Before long, my hatred is spent.
But she won't let go. She kisses me and coaxes me
and the fire grows again.
I say all the things I swore I'd never say again.
She owns me.
Body and soul.
Tell me everything.
Manute, the man who beat you.
He's a specialist in inflicting pain.
Hideous pain in all the places
you just gave him joy.
That's sick, it's crazy.
Damien, my husband, he talks and talks and watches.
It's worse each time.
It's getting closer to his final sick climax.
He says it'll be very ugly before  I die.
Ava, you're not gonna die.
You're coming with me.
It's hopeless.
He lets me run away,
Even laughs about it.
Doesn't care where I go,
what I do.
He knows Manute will
always find me.
Isn't that right, Manute?
Madam, Mr Lord would require
that you be disciplined.
No, wait, Dwight, don't fight him!
He'll kill you!
He's not human.
I punch a vault door, it doesn't fall down.
So I punch it again.
A wrecking ball hits me square in the chest.
Mrs. Lord, your clothes.
We have an appointment.
They can't take her away from me.
Not this time.
I know exactly what to do.
I know exactly where to go.
Now here's a girl with protection.
She maybe showing off everything she's got
but Nancy's the safest gal in the world.
Make a grab for Nancy and you're up against 300 pounds of iron
that goes by the name of...
...Marv.
Marv.
Dwight, mighty good to see you here.
What can I do you for?
I need your help.
It's bad and it's gonna be
up against a lot of guns.
Count me in.
I could use a change of pace.
We finished off the bottle
but it's liquid darkness that filled us both.
When I'm sure he's had enough to make him good and dangerous,
I tell him about Ava
and his eyes go killer red.
I know he's willing to die for me if that's what it takes.
So I'm using him, so what?
So he breaks the faces I want him to break instead of
somebody's elses.
So he helps me get Ava back in my arms again instead of sleeping it off in a slum house or gutter.
His life isn't worth a damn anyway.
If I don't get him killed, the world will,
one way or another.
I want you to leave that thing in the car.
Nobody's getting killed tonight.
Oh come on Dwight, you aint no fun at all.
We split up at the gate.
It doesn't take Marv long to get their attention.
You're the slug that freaked my friend out?
Shall we?
Oh, I gotta have my hand wrapped one of these days.
I'll find the truth about Ava
and what's happening to her now.
He'll tell me. I'll get it out of him.
Damien Lord.
Where is she?
What have you done with her?
Have you come to take her away from all this?
And what is all this in her present stories?
I haven't the slightest notion what nonsense my wife has told you
nor do I care.
It's all lie.
Stay away from the desk.
The woman is pathological.
You have been deceived.
What did it feel like?
What?
Murdering an innocent man.
I just want to know what it felt like.
It must've been beautiful.
What are you talking about, innocence?
I knew I could count on you.
Sex always made you stupid, ready to believe anything.
You've just made me a very rich woman.
Do me one last favor, lover.
Stay still long enough for me to blow your brains out.
I'm not much of a shot
- but I'll do my best.
- Ava...
I planned it and you fell for it.
This is the last time I'm ever gonna need anything from a man.
The last time I make my living on my back.
- Manute never hurt you...
- He wouldn't dare!
- You're insane.
- No, Dwight.
A crazy person would be anyone who believes me
and that would be you.
If I kissed you now, Dwight,
would you still believe it was... love?
No...
Ava...
Damn.
Hey, I handled that big slug just like I promised.
I didn't kill him, I didn't even cripple him.
6 months in traction, that's all, tops.
I took an eye out of him though.
Listen, before you say anything.
I know I was supposed to take the Mustang to make my getaway
but when I saw this beauty here sitting there, you know
the key in the ignition and everything, I couldn't pass a chance on it.
Pull over!
You know they only made a couple dozen of these beauties.
I saw a movie about it once.
Oh, here I'm, jabbering and you're leaking all over the place.
I'll get you to a guy I know.
He's good with bullets and uh,
he don't ask no questions.
Get me to Old Town.
Let me level with you, pal.
You ain't gonna make it to Old Town.
I'll make it.
I got too much I've got to do
to let myself die.
Old Town.
He left a lot of blood, Mrs. Lord.
He won't get far.
You said you knew him.
The killer's name is Dwight.
Dwight MCcarthy.
You know him in what sense?
Well, we dated once.
I'm sorry, lieutenant. You've been so very patient with me.
You and I barely met but already...
I feel I can trust you.
You can trust me.
We were together for a while a few years ago.
It went badly.
He went insane.
He started imagining things,
accusing me of things.
He followed me wherever I went.
Recently, he broke into this very property.
Did he beat you?
When he drank.
- He drank a lot.
- You stayed with this nutcase?
- You'll be surprised how much a woman can take.
- You were terrified.
It was Damien who took me away.
He was so...gentle and sure.
I suppose I'm a woman who needs...protection.
He made me feel safe
but then, Dwight, he found me somehow.
He started calling me late at night, making awful threats.
And now Damien is dead
and I'm alone.
Oh please, lieutenant.
Call me Mort.
Nothing like a widow in need of comfort.
I got a stiffy just watchin' her.
- Man, she's prime.
- Just drop it, Bob.
- You don't pass up a chance like that.
What's the point of being a Sin City cop if you don't get the perks?
We're married men, Bob.
I don't care what you are.
Just take a look at that babe!
That's enough, Bob.
This doesn't look good.
One squad car still chases us.
Must be a rookie driving.
His buddy should've told him the girls of Old Town have laws all their own
and they don't take kindly to cops.
Oh, you're a genius, girl.
Here we are, pal.
All of a sudden this doesn't look like the brightest idea you ever had.
You have 10 seconds to tell us what you're doing bringing cops to Old Town.
Here's the problem.
I don't fight girls.
Gail!
- It's me.
- Dwight.
What have they done to you?
The cork screw stamps me square in the chest
and twists.
Get Molly!
Get everybody.
It's about time.
- Hello?
- Mrs. Lord.
Lieutenant...Mort. You're so kind to call.
I hope I didn't wake you.
No, I wasn't sleeping. I haven't slept at all.
I'm jumping at every sound, just knowing he's still out there.
I guess I'm not a very strong person.
And me in this house all alone.
You shouldn't be so hard on yourself, Mrs Lord.
You're having a very understandable reaction.
Is there any thing at all I can do for you?
I know it's a bad thing to
think of you the way I do.
It's...inconvenient
but whoever loved, love not at first sight?
I thought about you since I saw you.
I'm thinking about you now.
Were you thinking about me?
Yes.
I hate myself for saying this but
I just don't know if I could
bear to be alone tonight.
My heart beats.
I take in the rich burnt smell of coffee.
Gail! She's reason enough to open my eyes.
Can you hear me, Dwight?
The cops want you bad, Dwight.
Really bad.
Don't worry.
We'll fix you up
and when we do,
when you're all better,
I'll deck you for leaving in the first place!
I told you, you'd be back.
I told you.
You belong here.
Jerk!
I thought there was another world out there.
I thought I could be a part of it.
There's only Sin City.
Molly said you're ready to leave.
No, I'm staying.
Wrong answer.
Miho.
Deadly little Miho.
If she recognizes me,
she doesn't let it show.
Oh, you picked the
wrong neighborhood for your hideout.
Alive or dead, you're leaving.
I'm staying.
I don't think he can feel it, Miho.
Give it a twist.
You won't give with anymore lip about staying here, Miho will have to...exhale.
And that heart Molly worked so hard
to fix will just pop like a grape.
He's staying.
And if you're going to kill him,
you better kill me too,
even though he doesn't feel the same way about me.
He's the only man I've ever loved.
They all seem to be waiting
for the other shoe to drop
Gail drops it.
It was dark in that alley, Miho.
When you were 15, you killed three of the thugs.
But the last two had the drop on you.
You were dead,
until someone appeared.
You never got a good look
at the man who saved you.
Take a look now.
I get more time
and more surgery.
Listen, there's only one person
that has anything to gain from snuffing Damien Lord
and you're too busy banging the broad to bring her in for questioning!
You don't know her.
You don't know anything about her
and I'll be damned if I'm gonna let you use that kind of language when you talk about her.
You're in love with her!
You stupid schmuck!
It's one thing to poke a babe on the side but you can't even think straight.
Shut the hell up!
I know what I'm doing.
I guess I should've told you everything.
You're damn right you should've.
He raped me.
He almost killed me.
That son of a bitch!
I thought I could reason with him but
he was worse than ever.
His hands at my throat,
strangling me while he did what he needed to do.
He will kill me, kill me, kill me...
I have only you.
I love you, Mort.
Keep me safe.
Keep me, keep me, keep me...
Ava Lord.
For once you missed my heart.
I'm healing quickly, Ava.
I'll be coming for you soon.
You know where he is and
you won't do a damn thing about it!
You don't know what you're asking.
We have to wait for Old Town to give him up, it's the only way.
You're a Sin City cop.
You've got a badge and a gun.
You've got power.
Use it!
If you ever want to
have this woman again,
be a man. If you're a man...
kill him!
Don't move.
McCarthy...
...you never tortured her.
You two cooked that up.
You were her lover.
You were a fool.
The goddess takes no lover.
The goddess makes slaves of men.
In an instant, she can see through the heart of you
and transform to your deepest desire.
To Damien Lord, she was the princess bride.
To you, a damsel in distress.
She devoured all of you.
You cannot defeat the goddess.
She cannot die.
You're as crazy as she is.
If you were as rotten as her, I'd blow your brains out right now but I'm trying to be careful about who I kill
and all you did was pound the crap out of me.
You already paid an eye for that.
I'm letting you go with a warning.
Stay in bed.
Don't go back to work
and don't get in my way.
No, Ava, you're no goddess.
You're a witch.
A predator.
Maybe I only got what I deserved
but what about the others?
Good men driven mad.
You really lost it.
Bad enough you leave your wife for that skank.
You watch what you call her,
you son of a bitch.
Your throwing away your career.
Now you commit suicide,
you stupid shit!
I know what I'm doing, I'm going to Old Town and I'm going to nail this guy once and for all.
If I have to go it alone, I will.
Do me a favor, turn the car around and you go back to the station.
You gotta come clean with the captain.
I'm a cop. I'm doing my job.
You've gotta ditch that dame!
That's enough!
You won't talk about Ava!
Somebody's gotta set you straight.
You've gotta forget about
that stupid whore!
Turn the car around
or I'm turning you in!
I warned you.
Everyday, I warned you
but you keep asking for it!
You're asking for it!
Well, here it is, pal!
Mort, No!
A witch,
a predator,
destroying lives.
Sometimes for power,
sometimes for profit,
sometimes...for sport.
But now you're locked away in your mansion.
A bird of prey in a guilded cage.
Are you ready to do something stupid?
I'm so happy you chose to attend my little party Wallenquist.
Your invitation surprised me, Mrs. Lord.
Your husband had no criminal associations.
Believe me, I tried.
May I speak truthfully, Mr. Wallenquist?
Please.
Old Town is a thorn in your sight.
Indeed it is.
All those profits
in the hands of whores.
Surely you've wanted to put them in their place.
Make some adjustment
to the balance of power.
Show them who rules Sin City.
You have limited influence on me, Mrs. Lord.
I haven't been doing so very badly.
But those two policemen, that was an embarassing blunder.
Yes, I'm out of my league.
I need a stronger, more experienced hand.
I need all enterprises joined...
in matrimony, with the experties and iron fist of a rich Wallenquist.
What you need is the corpse of Dwight Mccarthy
and a suicide note which he confesses to the murder of Damien Lord.
And you need to show those
Old Town bitches who's boss.
Indeed, I do.
There's a specialist in Texas.
I could have him on a train tomorrow.
I'll brief him myself.
He'll be on your doorstep at midnight.
And I'll be yours forever.
Pray for your soul, Ava.
This won't be his last to visit Sin City.
Good evening, Mr. Kelvar.
- I'll take your bag.
- Nobody touches my gear.
And I got somebody picking me up who's one hell of a lot cuter than you.
It was our understanding
that you would travel alone.
I'm full of surprises.
Shuffle that bootie
over to the shotgun side doll.
I'm driving.
- How about you?
- Mrs. Lord may not be pleased.
She's the one with the problem. I can always get back on the train.
Wait here.
Hurry back!
You know I get impatient. You know I get a little crazy when I get impatient.
Kruger, watch this woman.
Jacoby,
If this man moves, kill him.
Strictly  business.
My compliments to your surgeon,
Mr. McCarthy. Remarkable transformation...
But you still have the eyes,
the eyes of a dead man.
I hate being left alone.
When I'm alone, it makes me want to do all kinds of crazy things.
No woman should be left alone with a man like you.
Do you want me...
To do something we shouldn't?
My lips are sealed.
There's something I need in the trunk.
Bear witness.
Mrs. Lord, the specialist has arrived.
The bathing thing with her was never about bathing.
It was always theater, or maybe it was retail.
You can't make a sale without showing the goods.
It's McCarthy.
Do you mind if I say that you're twice the man I thought you were?
You're a warrior,
a killer.
You're everything I want of a man but I can never get the honesty out of you.
You could've been eveything that I needed.
You still could be, you're a new man!.
Remember what she did.
Remember what she is.
Wait for your opening.
Wait for Gail to do her bit.
When you're immune to me,
I'll let you know.
Step back Mistress, let me kill him.
Please...
...do.
Six shots, without a single head wound.
Then it all gets down
to speed and luck.
Her eyes are wet and full of love.
I never dream,
you're everything I've ever wanted,
everything I need...
...you and me, forever.
It's over.
Pain has set you free. You're not good anymore, Dwight. You're more like me.
Be like me.
Let the old Dwight go.
Let it go, this old face.
She pulls close and I've got to look.
And all I want is to be lost in the sight and sound and smell of her.
- I can't think straight.
- We can be free.
- We can be happy, together, forever.
- No...
Her kiss is a promise of paradise.
- Dwight...
- The gun barks and bucks in my hand.
Life leaves Ava, with a sigh.
Sirens climb the hill , we'll take the backroads,
the old bootlegged roads,
They'll never catch us
I'm going home.
A walk down the right back alley in Sin City and you can find anything.
I was told I could find a man here by the name of Mr.Kroenig.
That's doctor Kroenig.
to you.
Yes, sir.
License or no license, these hands still got what it takes once I'm prepped.
How much you got?
Forty bucks you got?
Forty bucks worth you get!
Steady as a rock...
...once I'm prepped.
Forty bucks got you that bullet.
but that hand of yours,
a lot of bones need help.
I'll give you an hour,
for your shoes.
Take them.
I did my best to think about winning, revenge.
The old man must have liked popsicles, he uses the sticks for splints. He licks them first.
Not so much of a goddamn thank.
Generosity dont count for shit in this day
and age!
Quite a job he did on me, Roark.
Even my shoes.
There's nothing more you can take,
except...
Marcie, the girl.
Oh my Christ.
Marcie.
Oh, Marcie, you weren't a part of this.
You were just there to
throw them off their game.
What have I dragged you into?
This has turned into one long, bad night.
The windows not locked.
Never a good sign.
Not in Sin City.
Look who decided to show up.
Give the man a hand.
Give the man another hand.
Run penniless, friendless and forgotten.
You really be better off dead, Johnny.
But I like you just the way you are.
I got cocky.
I got cocky and I got Marcie dead.
Damn it, Johnny.
Hate yourself when you get the time.
Think about tonight's game.
That's all that matters now.
And all you need is money, just one lousy buck would be enough to get you started.
Hello, ma'am.
I don't have the money to pay but could I ask you for a glass of water?
Yeah.
Time's are tough all over.
Thank you.
What's with the hand?
I beat the wrong guy at cards.
Tough break.
Thank you very much.
Just a second, you.
You don't stink of anything I don't like and you kinda remind me of an old boyfriend, okay?
This won't take you very far.
Sweetheart, it's going to
take me to the moon.
Sin City, you never know.
Don't spend it all in one place.
Hey, handsome, what are you gonna do with all that?
I'm going to kill Roark.
That Roark there, don't die easy.
I just might surprise you.
Looks like something happened to your game hand, son.
I fold.
What's wrong, hotshot?
Not good without that lady luck
you brought here last time?
I'll be fine.
- I'm done.
- I'm out.
I need three.
Dealer takes two.
- Check.
I bet a hundred.
Shit!
Fold.
Just not the same without your game hand, is it?
I'm ambidextrous.
Cut.
Check.
Five hundred.
I'm in.
I'll raise you...
...five hundred more.
- I fold.
- I'm done.
- Here is your five more, pretty boy.
- Shit!
I favored your mother, she was a whore, not a very good one.
She was an angel.
I'm all in.
Call.
Four aces.
See, I told you, I never lose.
I beat you,
twice, that means I'm better than you are
and everybody knows it
'cause I beat you again every time somebody tells that story
and they'll all say they won't tell it but they will.
That's the story that will be told again and again until you're dead and long after you're dead.
I beat you forever.
And they all know what happens when you do.
Say hello to your mama.
She always was a stupid bitch.
Power is as power does.
If i could give any young man advice, it would be this, wear a rubber.
Now take out that trash,
let's get back to the game!
JOHN HARTIGAN
I can't lose you, not again.
You'll never lose me, Nancy.
All this time, she..was right there.
Dancing in the club where you play poker.
You gotta have been looking for a chance to put this one through the ringer, senator.
Nancy Callahan.
My son, Ethan was killed because of her.
It's been 4 years now and still, she's planting flowers at Hartigan's grave.
She's showing gratitude from the looks of it to the cop.
Gratitude to the cop,
who ripped your son to pieces.
Hartigan turned my son into a freak.
Now, completely as a freak
but I hardly blame the young lady for...
...obsession.
It's nothing more than a little fluff sorrow.
It might not be that simple.
Somehow she got her hands on Hartigan's old pistol.
She hits the range every night just before work.
She's become quite a good shot.
And I can only imagine whose face she sees on that target.
I'm listening.
She's been acting kinda crazy sometimes, at work.
She's drinking, just for the past few weeks.
She never drank before.
It's all like, she's building up to something.
Maybe, building her...nerve.
That will be all, lieutenant.
This little bitch is turning me on.
This place stinks.
I never use to notice.
not when I danced.
Now I smell everything.
I see it all.
Every damn thing.
I know exactly where I am.
I know exactly what I am.
I don't use the stripper logic anymore,
that they're losers and I'm not.
It was when I couldn't shoot at him
that I realized I was dead,
that I wasn't a woman with a plan.
I was just a drunk...
I give them what they want
and I get the hell outta there.
You shot him in the gut.
...rotten town, it soots anybody it touches.
it is a rotten town
but it can't corrupt its soil.
It's soil to you, John Hartigan.
Put that bottle down, Nancy.
You've had enough.
They made you lie to me,
you're not even here right now.
- You said you'd never leave me.
- I never left you.
I never would.
Never.
You're not even here right now.
You're dead!
You blew your brains out.
You stuck a gun in your mouth
and you blew your brains out.
I had my reasons, there was no way out.
I hate you!
- You swore you'd always love me.
- And I always will.
No one has ever really guessed what hell is.
It's watching the people you love...
...in pain.
You're the only man I ever loved
and you left me alone.
You never thought I'd stand a chance with that goddamn son of Roark.
You didn't believe in me.
You didn't think a little piece of ass like me could take down the most powerful man in the state.
Maybe I'll prove both of you wrong.
Maybe I'll go crazy.
- Crazy is sounding pretty good right now.
- I love you, Nancy.
You little slut!
Your gonna scream before you die.
You're out of your mind...
I appreciate the obsession
but you've got nothing...
You could've killed me 50 times
if you had the nerve but you don't.
You're nothing...
You'll scream,
just like my boy wanted you to...
Darling, where have you been and
what have you done to your beautiful hair?
Don't worry, those bastards are
getting what they want.
They always get what they want.
This is great, isn't it?
What's up with you?
Something's wrong, I'm out of here.
Oh, what a place, it's getting nasty,
I'm taking a hike.
Your beautiful Nancy, Don't do this to yourself.
Pretty, pretty, pretty...
If a man did that to you,
I'd tear him to pieces.
Lieutenant Hartigan,
you just gave me a great idea.
No baby, Nancy...
Just give me a damn name.
Roark.
Roark has lots of thugs,
we need tools.
Looks like trouble.
Looks like Christmas.
We're ripping this place a new asshole.
Move or die!
I hope you don't mind me saying this, but...
you look hot.
There's no reason to leave anybody alive.
Nobody's innocent.
We can't leave anybody alive to talk.
Don't go soft on me, kid.
Don't leave anybody breathing.
I won't. I'll work the perimeter
and nail the guards.
Baby, you're a natural.
I'll work the inside.
How will I know when you're in?
You'll have a pretty good idea.
Damn thing misfired on me.
I nearly got them all but this
piece of shit over here, he came up on me.
This piece of crap...
I think I'm almost done.
Here.
Take a seat.
You're a peach.
I got this.
You clever, clever little whore.
I can't believe you made it this far.
Your Hartigan blew my son's pecker off.
So...where shall I shoot you next?
That tight little belly of yours?
I'm holding a gun on you, young lady.
The rules are, you pretend there's
a chance that I won't shoot you.
I told you, you would scream before you die.
I owe it to my son.
Frankly, between you and me,
I finally accepted that...Ethan is not...presidential material.
I had a hard time buying him
an election in an insane asylum.
but he was my son, honey.
He was my son.
And now, he's going to hear you scream.
Scream...
This is for John Hartigan, fucker!
This rotten town, it soils everybody...