[raindrops pattering]
[thunder rumbling]
Man:
Listen, I'm from the bronx,
so you need to keep it simple.
Why is the bank buying all
this missile-guidance stuff
From Calvini?
I don't get it.
[lighter clicks]
The window
Will stay closed.
You need to relax.
I'm more comfortable
tense.
You came to us,
remember?
You wanted a way out and now
I'm here offering you one.
I only met you
30 minutes ago,
And now you expect me
just to walk away
From everything
I know,
Put my life
in your hands.
You want a little more time
to think things through,
I get it.
But we're gonna need
another meet.
And I'm gonna need
to see some paper.
Yes. Now get out
of the car.
[engine starts]
[music]
Woman: Hey.
Ella?
You done?
Yeah, I just met with him.
And?
Oh, he's real.
He's real enough
to blow this thing wide open.
He told me the bank's buying
$200 million worth
Of missile-guidance systems.
What do they need those for?
I don't know.
You gonna see him
a second time?
Yeah, yeah. Listen,
we're gonna meet again.
He's agreed to bring me paper.
Right,
I'll call you later.
Thanks, Elle.
Ah.
[tires squealing]
[horns honk]
Man:
Hey.
[ringing]
Man 1:
Are you experiencing
any blurred or double vision?
Man 2:
No.
Nothing.
Just follow the light,
please.
It's been noted that
you were experiencing
Some ringing
in your ears.
Yes.
Well, I would like to keep you
here overnight for observation.
That won't
be necessary.
Where's my colleague?
[music]
Thomas schumer.
It was definitely
a heart attack?
"acute myocardial
infarction." yes.
Your penlight,
can I use it?
What are you doing?
Can you help me
turn him over?
I'm afraid I
can't allow you to--
Just help me.
We need to contact
the berlin police
And request
an immediate autopsy.
Why?
Because I don't think this man
died of natural causes.
Man:
Come on, Ella.
If schumer met with this insider
at a train station in berlin,
The odds are this guy's
a foreign national.
So it's federal.
But you're not listening to me.
Let them meet again.
He's gonna bring paper,
Tommy will close him.
Then we have
a situation--
You still have to coordinate
with Justice
If you want him in
witness protection.
I just tried both their cells
again. Straight to voicemail.
Oh, shit.
I'm gonna try Tommy's
wife at work.
If I have to bring DOJ
into this
They're gonna do what
they've always done
With this investigation.
They're gonna stall us
out with red tape,
This informant's gonna bolt,
And I'm telling you,
he could be the bombshell
We've spent the last
two years looking for.
Voicemail.
[phone rings]
What's going on? Why aren't
they calling us back?
What do you want me
to do?
I can't afford another
turf war with Justice.
It's Salinger.
Uh, finally.
Put him on speaker.
Jesus, lou.
What took you guys so long?
Hello? You there?
Salinger:
Yeah.
Eleanor:
So, what's up?
Tommy's dead.
What?
He's dead, Ella.
I need you to get over here
as soon as you can.
[music]
Salinger:
Unnaturally red blood,
lambent nasal membranes.
These are two key indicators
of hydrocyanic poisoning.
This lesion
on the back of the neck
Is how the poison
was introduced
Into the bloodstream,
percutaneously.
The lesion tested negative
for any poison,
And there are any number
of reasons
For this discoloration
of the blood,
The least likely of which
is a hydrocyanic--
I'm telling you,
he was murdered.
Well, I'm assuming
you suspect a combination
Of prussic acid
and DMSO,
But then the reaction time
would have been immediate.
Within one minute.
Which means the killer would
have had to deliver the toxin
After schumer
exited the car.
[music]
So did you see
anything unusual?
Anybody approaching
schumer?
No. I mean--
I don't know.
What is it that makes
you so certain
He was assassinated?
Agent Salinger and I
Have reason to believe
this might be connected
To an ongoing investigation
being conducted
By both my team at the manhattan
da's office and interpol.
What investigation?
I run a group at interpol
That focuses
on financial operations
Associated with
organized crime.
About two years ago,
We began receiving
correlated intelligence
Regarding the illicit
activities
Of a bank based out
of Luxembourg.
The international bank
of business and credit.
Under the direction of its
chairman, Jonas Skarssen,
We believe the ibbc
has quietly become
The bank of choice
for monies associated
With organized crime,
capital flight--
How is any of this
related to schumer,
And the New York
da's office?
The ibbc's
manhattan branch
Is the epicenter of its u.S.
Money-laundering operation.
Schumer and I were working
this case together.
Agent Salinger
and his department
Have been assisting us.
Why weren't we informed
of these details
Prior to this briefing?
[whispering indistinctly]
[sighs]
What was schumer doing
here in berlin?
I set him up on a blind date
with an ibbc executive
Who was aware
of our investigation
And looking
to make a deal.
And the identity
of this informant?
We don't know.
He took precautions
To keep his identity
anonymous.
But for the past 12 hours, I've
been trying hard to find him,
Because I believe that if this
man isn't already dead,
He soon will be.
Why?
Because,
just like schumer,
Anyone that's been in a position
to move against this bank
Has either ended up dead
or disappeared.
Agent Salinger,
Given your history
with this matter,
I should think
you would be more careful
Before making
such extreme accusations.
My history?
What are you talking about?
We've reviewed
your dossier.
Have you?
Well, that means you know
just about shit.
[clears throat]
I realize this is
a trying time for you both,
But until I'm provided
With something more compelling
than unsubstantiated theories,
Pursuing the ibbc
Is simply not going
to happen here in germany.
Concorde hotel,
please.
What was that
back there?
What history was
diemer talking about?
Don't worry about it.
Don't give me that shit.
What do they know that I don't?
They don't know anything.
They know enough to
get a rise out of you.
I'm not getting into it.
You're so curious,
read my file.
I should never have let
Tommy walk into this.
You didn't.
I approved the meet.
I was across
the fucking street, Ella.
I was right there.
I saw him go down.
I didn't see a thing.
We won't let them
bury this, lou.
[music]
[ringing]
[gasps]
[music]
This canvas
appeals to you?
I like the look
of agony.
Why?
Because I know it's true.
What am I doing here?
Umberto Calvini is
disengaging from the deal.
Your principle would
like to bring you in
To troubleshoot
the situation.
If Calvini refuses
to move forward,
I don't see my involvement
Will make any difference.
Your involvement
would allow them
To appeal to Calvini's
two sons,
Who are much more
open-minded.
You'll find all the details
in the file.
I'll contact you once
negotiations are underway.
[music]
Rene?
What are you doing here
so early?
Salinger.
I found the insider.
What?
I found the guy that schumer
met with in berlin.
André clément?
The ibbc's senior vice president
of acquisitions.
He was killed
in a road accident
Just outside Luxembourg
Approximately nine hours
after schumer's death.
And this is the gendarmerie's
preliminary accident report.
He arrived in berlin
at 8 a.M.
On luxair, flight 9871
from Luxembourg.
But what doesn't track
is in his statement,
The ibbc chairman,
Jonas Skarssen,
Claims that clément had
been with him in Luxembourg
Since 10 a.M.,
Which is obviously
impossible
If clément arrived
in berlin at 8 a.M.
Did the gendarmerie say anything
about this inconsistency?
Nothing.
I Haven't told them.
What?
I wanna go to Luxembourg
and question Skarssen myself.
No. Absolutely no.
Viktor, listen to me.
I go to Luxembourg, Skarssen
confirms that statement,
I catch him in that lie,
I can build--
For chrissake, lou, you're
not at the yard anymore.
Interpol is not in the
law-enforcement business.
We deal in intelligence
and facilitation.
Focus on that,
work that,
And pass your take onto
the appropriate authorities.
And then what?
You know, we've been
circulating our take
Since the very beginning.
No one ever does anything,
no one ever can.
Whatever case we have
gets lost
In the complexities
of international law.
Schumer,
Clément,
This entire fucking wall.
There's nothing that complex
about cold-blooded murder.
[music]
Hi. I've got an appointment
with Mr. Skarssen.
Your name, please?
Mr. Salinger?
Please follow me.
[speaking indistinctly]
Mr. Skarssen.
Agent Salinger?
Please follow me.
Mr. White.
Agent Salinger.
I apologize for the wait.
I'm Martin white,
the ibbc's legal counsel.
This is commissioner villon
of the gendarmerie.
I thought it would be useful
for him to join us,
Considering the nature
of your query.
Please, have a seat.
I think there's
some misunderstanding.
I'm here to speak
with Mr. Skarssen.
Yes, but as
Mr. Skarssen's attorney,
I insisted that
I speak with you first.
Mr. White, I had
a confirmed meeting
With Mr. Skarssen
at 11:00.
If I was gonna meet
with you first,
Why didn't anybody tell me?
I understand, and I'm sorry
for the confusion,
But, uh, I'm sure I can help
answer your questions.
Now, please,
have a seat.
As I'm sure you're aware
I have some questions
regarding andré clément.
Yes.
It's my understanding
that Mr. Clément was working
At Mr. Skarssen's residence
the night he was killed.
The night
of the accident, yes.
What time did he arrive
at Skarssen's home that day?
If I recall correctly,
around 6 p.M.
You were there?
Yes.
And you're certain
about this time?
Quite.
I'm confused.
What you're telling me
right now
Conflicts with
Skarssen's statement
In the gendarmerie's
accident report,
Which was that clément
had been working with him
At his home since
10 a.M. In the morning.
Well, I was present when
Mr. Skarssen gave his statement.
That is not what he said.
It is according to this report.
May I?
Oh. There is an error
in the preliminary draft.
The time is wrong.
The finalized report here
says clément arrived at 6 p.M.
Villon:
Clerical errors like this
can happen from time to time.
This is why the gendarmerie
discourages the release
Of any preliminary
documentation
Pertaining to open cases.
So is there anything else
We can do for you,
agent Salinger?
[music]
[phone rings]
Yeah.
Eleanor: It's me.
I just got the results
from the full tox analysis
I ran on schumer.
And?
It's inconclusive.
Inconclusive? What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
They found Trace elements
of cyanide in his blood,
But the levels
are not nearly high enough
To meet their criteria
for poisoning.
Are you there?
[music]
[yells]
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
[woman speaking in French]
[music]
[sighs]
[woman speaking in French]
Madame clément?
Oui.
Oh.
It's Eleanor whitman
From the New York
district attorney's office.
I already left a couple
messages just--
[beeping]
[music]
[redialing]
[woman speaking
in French on recording]
[beeps]
Mrs. Clément,
I'm sorry to keep calling you.
I can only imagine
what a difficult time
This must be for you.
But I'm not convinced
your husband's death
Was an accident.
Look, here's my cell number.
001-917-135-6565.
You can call any time--
Mrs. Clement:
Stop calling me.
I have nothing to say to you.
Just leave me alone.
Please. I just need to ask you
a few questions.
I have two children. They've
already lost their father.
I understand.
No, you don't.
Are you aware your husband met
with one of our investigators
The day he was killed?
[beeping]
Man:
You ever planning
to come to bed?
Oh.
I heard your voice.
I'm sorry.
When'd he come in here?
An hour ago.
T. Rex was
in the closet again.
Let me take him back.
[phone vibrates]
man: Come on, buddy.
[chimes]
[vibrates]
[sighs]
[phone vibrates]
[knocking on door]
[dog barking]
[viktor speaking
in foreign language]
Lou?
They knew about
the discrepancy in the report.
They had Skarssen's
statement changed.
How did they know,
viktor?
Come inside.
No.
[mouthing words indistinctly]
Are you insane?
It's freezing out.
Come outside.
Stop it!
Lou, wait.
Lou.
[dog barking]
Have you lost
your mind?
[music]
I think we take the dog
for a walk.
Get some fresh air.
Who did this?
Who do you think?
From my apartment.
Whitman's
got them too.
We need to inform the secretary
general immediately.
You gotta be kidding. Viktor,
we start setting off alarms,
The opportunity
Will be lost.
Opportunity?
The last thing schumer
told ella was that clément
Was giving him information
On an ibbc arms deal.
Salinger:
Umberto Calvini.
Chairman of Calvini defense,
One of the largest defense
contractors in europe.
And probably
Italy's next prime minister.
This guy standing next to him,
that's our insider.
André clément.
And?
Whitman found out that clément
was negotiating for the ibbc
To purchase a large number
of missile guidance
And control systems
from Calvini defense.
But at the very last minute,
the deal collapsed.
What happened?
We don't know.
Whitman's meeting me
in milan tomorrow.
We're gonna talk to Calvini
and find out.
[music]
[gunshot]
[speaking in Italian]
Grazie.
[woman speaking over microphone
in Italian]
Hey.
Eleanor whitman, this is
inspector Alberto cerutti.
Charmed.
Nice to meet you.
[speaking in Italian]
Please, there's not
much time.
Calvini leaves
for turin
Immediately after
this engagement.
I didn't realize we were meeting
at a political rally.
Best we could do
on such short notice.
Thirtieth floor.
I'll be waiting outside.
You need to
press the button.
You look awful.
Thanks.
When was the last time
you got any sleep?
Don't know.
When was the last time
you had a healthy meal?
Can't remember.
How about the last time
you got laid?
Why, are you offering?
You need to take better care
of yourself, lou.
I can't have you crash and burn
like you did two years ago.
[elevator dings]
[speaking in Italian]
Please follow me.
This meeting is strictly
off the record.
Mr. Calvini cannot in any way be
entangled in your investigation,
Nor can his participation
in this discussion
Find its way
to the press.
We understand.
Wait here for a moment.
So you read my file.
I made a few calls
to London.
You should've told me
everything that happened
With your ibbc case
at the yard.
You should've told me
it's why you left.
What did they tell you?
That you screwed up
'cause the witness
you brought in was a joke.
And when you were forced to
drop him, the case fell apart.
You flipped out,
Attacked the assistant
commissioner and broke his nose.
My case did not fall apart.
It was shut down,
And my witness was rock-solid.
He gave us everything we needed
to move against the bank
And then suddenly,
out of nowhere,
My ac forced me
to cut him loose.
Three days later, they all
died in a car crash.
"they"?
He had a wife and two kids.
Eleanor:
Mr. Calvini, we'd like to know
why the ibbc, a bank,
Would be purchasing
hundreds of millions
Of dollars worth
of missile guidance
And control systems
from your company.
The ibbc has purchased
billions of dollars worth
Of silkworm missiles from
the people's republic of china,
Which they have presold
to clients in the middle east,
Contingent upon
the missiles
Being equipped with
volcon guidance systems.
My company's one of
only two in the world
Which produce the volcon.
Who's the other?
Sunay. Ahmet sunay.
Of turkish aerotech?
But why is the bank committing
so much capital and resources
To the sale
of these missiles?
It's a test.
Small arms
are the only weapons used
In 99 percent
of the world's conflicts,
And no one has the capacity
to manufacture them
Faster and cheaper than china.
What Skarssen
is attempting to do
Is to make the ibbc
the exclusive broker
Of Chinese small arms
to the third world.
And the missile deal
is the gateway transaction.
Yeah, but billions
of dollars invested
Simply to be a broker?
There can't be that much
profit for them.
No. This is not about making
profit from weapon sales.
It's about control.
Control the flow of weapons,
control the conflict.
No.
No, no.
The ibbc is a bank.
Their objective isn't
to control the conflict,
It's to control the debt
that the conflict produces.
You see, the real value
of a conflict,
The true value,
Is in the debt
that it creates.
You control the debt,
You control everything.
You find this
upsetting, yes?
But this is the very Essence
of the banking industry.
To make us all,
whether we be
Nations or individuals,
Slaves to debt.
You sound like you're not
very fond of the ibbc.
What happened?
I was fond of andré clément.
I trusted him,
And he was
a good friend.
[speaking in Italian]
Then help us make sure
he didn't die in vain.
Find me
after the speech.
We can talk in the car
on my way to the airport.
[woman speaking over microphone
in Italian]
[crowd cheering]
Umberto Calvini.
[speaking in Italian]
[ticking]
[music]
[continues speaking
in Italian]
[crowd cheering]
[gunshot]
Connected to any--
[music]
[screams]
[chatter]
[speaking in Italian]
[music]
[crowd screaming]
[gunshots]
[speaking in Italian]
[officers shouting]
[gunshot]
[music]
[engine starts]
[tires squealing]
Oh, my God.
Are you all right?
I think so.
Take that left.
Maybe you can cut him off.
Go!
[music]
[tires squealing]
[horns honking]
Turn off the engine
And stick your hands
out of the window!
Turn off the engine
And stick your hands
out of the window! Now!
Man:
Our relationship with the
swiss has become impossible
Over the past year.
They are discounting
our dollar deposits
By 160 basis points
below par.
They have doubled the cost
of moving our money.
Well, general,
what do you expect?
You've been living in
the jungle long enough
To know that when
the lion kills,
It's the jackal
that profits.
Yes.
The ibbc is
specifically structured
To handle the particular needs
of your type of organization.
Of course we can give you
better rates and terms
Than any other competitors,
But we can offer you
much more:
Weapons,
Intelligence,
logistical support,
Everything that the
revolutionary freedom front
Would need
to revive itself.
But in exchange
for what?
You must understand,
the rff has no money.
Money is not
this institution's
Primary medium of exchange.
[music]
What are you
proposing exactly?
We believe that
With the right kind
of direction and support,
The rff could become
a very influential force
In your country.
Perhaps potent enough
To stage a successful coup
in the coming months.
And if this were possible,
What does your bank
hope to gain from it?
The gratitude and consideration
Of a very influential friend.
Excuse me.
[whispers]
Mr. White and Mr. Ehames
asked me to interrupt.
Would you excuse me, general?
I'll be right back.
What is it?
Approximately
30 minutes ago,
Umberto Calvini
was assassinated,
While giving a speech
at a political rally in milan.
We've been discussing it.
I think
we should wait
Until the authorities
resolve the matter,
And then approach the sons
to revive negotiations.
How long will this take?
I've been assured
the investigation
Will move swiftly, but, uh,
Unexpected fallout
of an event like this
Can always
complicate things.
Man:
We only have 60 days left
to deliver the worms.
There's no time
for complications.
That's a risk you take
with such an ambitious agenda.
White:
I don't foresee any problems.
Had it not been
for their father,
Mario and Enzo Calvini would've
made our deal long ago.
Now there's no reason
for them not to move forward.
An important man
and devoted father
Has just been killed.
I suggest that we send a letter
to Calvini's family,
Extending our heartfelt
prayers and condolences
For their
terrible loss.
Eleanor:
I don't know, but I'm okay.
The doctors
checked me out thoroughly.
Kiss Jake for me, Will you?
Cerutti:
So the shooter was identified
as a member of the red brigade.
Eleanor:
What about the guy in the car?
Cerutti:
The car was stolen.
They were unable to lift
prints, fibers or residue,
Or locate any witnesses who
saw him exiting the vehicle.
So?
The carabinieri are announcing
the red brigade
Was responsible
for the assassination
At the press conference
tonight.
Salinger:
We're not convinced
the red brigade's behind this.
Someone could simply be making
it appear as though they are.
This isn't my case,
And the man in charge of the
investigation is very powerful
And a real bastard.
All we wanna do
is just look around a little.
[music]
[speaking in Italian]
Antonio.
Alberto.
Just a moment.
[speaking in Italian]
They done the trajectory
analysis yet?
Cerutti said no.
[chatter]
If there was a second shooter,
He could've positioned
himself here.
The stopwatch they found
in the room,
It was set on
a one-minute countdown, yes?
Right. Calvini
was killed
A little over one minute
into his speech.
What if this was
all synchronized?
Okay.
Let's say I'm
the second shooter.
The guy below
doesn't know I'm here,
But I'm positioned
right above his room.
I'm armed with a sauer 200
rifle, just like he is.
I have a stopwatch set
on a one-minute countdown
Which I start when Calvini
begins his speech.
The sniper below has been
instructed to do the same,
Because that's when he's
gonna fire his first bullet.
If he misses,
I'm ready to follow through
with one of my own.
The sniper fires, misses.
Seconds later...
[gunshot]
I take Calvini out
with a headshot.
It's a good theory,
but there's one problem.
Why?
Two shots were fired
from the window,
Two slugs were recovered
from the stage,
And two casings were found
next to the gun.
Ballistics confirming
that the casings
Came from the gun
in the hotel room.
So if the kill shot came from
a second shooter on the roof,
That'd be a total
of three bullets fired.
How do you explain the absence
of the third bullet?
I can't.
[air sucking]
[beeping]
[air blowing]
Salinger:
I think I've seen
this print before.
Eleanor:
Where?
Hanging on the wall
of my office.
[beeping]
[buzzing]
So this was lifted
from the scene
Of the Stefan heuss hit
in brussels last year.
A former
imf executive director.
Has he ever seen a tread
pattern like this before?
[speaking in Italian]
He believes it came
from a custom shoe
Made for a leg brace.
The braces are typically
made out of steel,
Or alloy,
but the condition of the leg
Would determine the specific
type of device used.
[speaking in Italian]
He says that the prints
are a probable match.
Alberto, can you please
get these over to Alan kovacs
At fbi impressions
right away,
And make sure
he has my contact numbers.
Thanks.
Ella,
if the fbi confirms
That these prints
are a match
It means the bank's
used the same assassin twice.
Which means
if we can get him,
We can get the bank.
[footsteps approaching]
[speaking in Italian]
[speaking angrily in Italian]
[scoffs]
What was that?
[loud bang]
That was
capitano barillo,
The man in charge of
the Calvini investigation.
What did he want?
My ass on a platter,
And both of you on
the next flight out of milan.
Well, didn't you tell
him what we just found?
I tried.
Fuck him. He can't
force us to leave.
He has already spoken
to your superiors.
You have both
been ordered home.
Eleanor:
Arnie, you can't just sit there
And lecture me about
protocol and procedure.
You know
what's happening here.
Well, who gives a shit about
jurisdictional provenance?
We just had
a major breakthrough.
[chatter]
Ah, that's great, arnie.
You're a real stand-up guy.
This is
total bullshit.
[sighs]
I wish I could've
been more helpful.
Oh, no, you've been great,
Alberto.
I'm gonna do everything I can
to take the heat off you.
Ciao.
Thanks.
Salinger:
Thanks for everything. Sorry
for all the trouble we caused.
[cerutti speaks in Italian]
[buzzing]
What?
His leg brace would
be made of metal, right?
So?
If he left through an airport,
Security would've made him
show it to them.
[music]
That's definitely him.
He doesn't
look like much.
I think
that's the idea.
Eleanor:
He almost seems to know
where the cameras are.
Look how he always angles his
face out of our line of sight.
Even if you do find him,
that's not enough evidence
To convict the man
without a confession.
If we find him,
prosecution will be irrelevant.
He'll be a marked man.
He can either die for
the bank or flip for us.
[door opens]
I got him.
He is traveling under the name
sherwood. Timothy m.
He boarded flight
alitalia 422,
Departing milan
at 6 p.M. Yesterday,
And arriving in New York
at jfk at 10 p.M.
[music]
What time's the next
flight to New York?
[music]
[horns honking]
Detectives hubbard,
ward, ornelas,
This is agent lou Salinger.
Finally.
Let me take that.
So, what do we have?
Ornelas:
Well, we got lucky.
Some clip shots of him
moving through customs.
That's a good one.
[indistinct speaking
over speaker]
The sherwood id he used?
It's clean.
All of it attached
to a dead address.
Where'd he go
after he cleared customs?
Don't know. Cctv footage
lost him at the curb.
We canvassed all limousine and
taxicab companies in the city.
Airport parking,
rental agencies.
Didn't come up
with shit.
We think there's a Chance
he might live in the city.
Why is that?
Kovacs from fbi
impressions called.
"the footprint
was left by a shoe
"used for knee-ankle-foot
orthosis.
"the tread pattern
is exclusive to shoes
"produced at the isaacson
orthopedic institute
Here in the city."
The shoe could have
only come from there.
Do you have a contact
person to run down?
We got dr. Isaacson.
All right. You guys
go check it out.
I'm expected at the office.
Hubb?
Get ready for the smackdown.
He's gonna come at you hard.
[music]
[siren wailing, horn honking]
Man:
Who is it?
N.Y.P.D.
[lock opening]
Dr. Isaacson?
Yeah.
Detective ornelas,
n.Y.P.D.
This is my partner,
detective ward.
We'd like to ask
a couple questions.
Why?
W-what do you want?
Why are you here?
Calm down, doctor.
We just wanna ask you
A few questions
about a patient of yours.
Patient?
What patient?
Come on, guys, you know
what time it is?
Listen, I'm sorry.
I must go.
I really didn't do anything.
I'm sorry. Good night.
Doctor, if we could--
[sighs]
[door locking]
Douche bag's
pinned out of his mind.
He thinks we're here
to bust him.
Dr. Isaacson,
please.
We have reason to believe
your life is in danger,
Grave danger.
We think one of your patients
is trying to kill you.
[music playing]
[lock opening]
Kill me?
I'm agent Salinger,
I work with interpol.
We're assisting
in this manhunt.
W-why would a patient
wanna kill me?
I'm an orthopedist.
This man's a psychotic.
He's already butchered
seven doctors in europe.
We've got some serious evidence
to suggest you may be next.
Have you ever seen
this man?
No, no.
I-I-I don't think so.
Does the name timothy sherwood
mean anything to you, doctor?
No.
How do you know
he's a patient of mine?
We have his footprint.
Ornelas:
Yeah, the shoe was manufactured
By agm biomechanics, exclusively
for the isaacson institute,
Model k-a-f-o 1-2-1.
K-f-o 1-2-1?
We started prescribing
orthosis three years ago.
We've used it on hundreds
of our patients.
Well, then we're gonna need
to review all of your files.
Right now?
Salinger:
Doctor,
We need to find this man
before he finds you.
Arnie:
What are you trying
to do here, Ella?
I'm doing my job.
You have any idea
of the shitstorm
You've gotten me into?
We're just trying
to get to the truth.
I get it.
But what you need
to remember
Is that there's what people
wanna hear,
What people wanna believe,
There's everything else,
then there's the truth.
And since when
is that okay?
I can't even believe
you're saying this to me.
The truth means
responsibility, arnie.
Exactly, which is
why everyone dreads it.
[sighs]
Look...
The ibbc is using
One assassin
for all their hits,
And we've tracked him
here to New York.
This guy can bury them.
They want me to put
a gun to your head.
You don't find this guy,
and I mean quick,
They're gonna make me
pull the trigger.
[woman speaking in danish]
[speaking in danish]
[speaks in danish]
[ringing]
[beeps]
Gentlemen.
Man 1:
Sorry to disturb you at home.
I'm afraid this couldn't wait.
Yes?
Man 2:
Salinger was in milan.
Man 1:
Whitman too.
Man 3:
They have the scent.
It's only a matter
of time
Before they find
our consultant.
Any recommendations?
Man 2:
I strongly advise
against doing anything
That would heighten
your exposure right now.
White:
Wilhelm, we've leveraged
ourselves over the edge.
If we don't meet
the delivery date,
Our buyers
Will cancel the orders,
Our plans with
the Chinese will implode,
And this bank will be left
to foot a Bill it cannot pay.
Heightening our exposure
is the least of our problems.
Man 4:
I agree. We're about
to engage Calvini's sons.
We can't allow anyone
to put our agenda at risk.
We must sever all ties
with the consultant.
Man 2:
Consider the Mark,
gentlemen.
Doing this could be
A very messy affair.
Man 4:
Well, then make it one.
Man 2:
I don't know why you pay me
to advise on these matters.
It is clear that you
don't want my counsel,
Only my corroboration.
Man 3:
Really, wilhelm.
We've had just about
all we can take of you.
Man 2:
Yes. I've had about all
I can take of myself.
White:
How would you like
us to proceed?
[speaking in danish]
[cassian speaking in danish]
[music]
[coughs, sniffs]
Fucking disgusting,
you know that?
What are you,
my mother?
No, but I could be your old man
for all you know, asshole.
[exhales]
Hey, doc.
Gabriel hansen?
I don't know.
My associate handled this.
Well, the address
is a post-office box and...
He paid cash for all
of his medical bills.
There are no
diagnostic photos. Why?
I don't know.
Is there a number?
Yeah,
212-157-6421.
It's a dead line.
I'll put a call in to hubby,
have her run it down.
See if we can't get
a crack warrant
For the p.O. Box
in jersey.
What do all these gt's
Next to the appointment
entries mean?
We have a kickback account
with go taxi,
And they indicate when we use
their service for a patient.
[isaacson sniffs]
Eleanor [over phone]:
Hey. Hubb says
you caught a lead.
Salinger:
We've got an address.
We're en route.
What is it?
Well, it could be him.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, they gotta
bring him in now.
This is our last shot.
What do you mean,
"our last shot"?
Arnie and I had it out
last night,
And our clock's run out.
If we don't get this Guy
right now, it's over.
Well, it better be him, then.
[siren wailing
and horn honks]
[music]
I'm here.
Yeah.
I know that.
This is definitely
the right address?
Ornelas:
Checked the dispatcher's
log myself.
This is where they dropped
him off every time.
Well, he could be anywhere.
So, what do you think
he was doing here?
Beats the shit out of me.
Ward:
It's a big, empty lot.
Well, look,
I'm starving.
I'm gonna get something.
You want anything?
Yeah,
a coffee, black.
I'm going back down to
headquarters after this.
Okay, all right.
[siren wailing]
[speaking indistinctly]
Bye.
How long do you think
This has been like this?
I don't know,
But we need
to find out.
The doctor's records
say the last time
Somebody got dropped off
here was five weeks ago.
I mean, there's not even
a temporary office or anything.
How you doing?
[music]
[beeping]
Son of a bitch.
What's the matter
with you?
I just made our perp.
Eleven o'clock, blue overcoat.
You sure that's him?
A hundred percent.
Where did he come from?
Shit if I know.
I'm at the counter and boom, I
see him rolling past the window.
You wanna go for the collar?
No.
We tail him, find out where
he sleeps, then take him down.
A, b, c.
Keep the box tight.
[music]
[siren wailing]
[tires squealing]
[horns honking]
[chatter]
[dialing]
[ringing]
Mechanical voice [over phone]:
Five-oh-two-six. Designator?
Samuel koppler.
[beeps]
Message:
Your uncle
wishes to see you immediately.
Response?
The guggenheim,
fifth floor of the rotunda,
40 minutes.
[music]
Ornelas: Hi, how you doing?
Woman: Hello.
Ornelas:
N.Y.P.D. I need to speak
to your security chief.
Woman:
Okay, one moment.
Rick?
How you doing?
I'm detective ornelas.
I need to be able
to clear security, please.
Okay.
Thanks.
We're clear.
[chatter]
[music]
[male narrator
speaking in German]
Directly behind me.
There you go.
Thank you.
[elevator dings]
Who's the old scag
sitting next to him?
I don't know,
but I saw him
At the bank's headquarters
in Luxembourg.
You don't
look well today.
We all begin better
than we end.
What would you prefer
your ending to be like?
Oh, more purposeful,
And certainly more climactic.
A finale.
Circumstances can
always be arranged.
As much as the thought
appeals to me,
I'm afraid your consideration
is needed elsewhere.
What is this?
Salinger.
The method and manner
is entirely up to you.
Your principle
would simply like him
To vanish
without a Trace.
Any other provisions?
Yes.
No mistakes.
I'll follow.
Where's iggy going?
Following a new lead.
[music]
Shit.
We gotta go.
N.Y.P.D. Lock your hands
behind your head.
Do it now.
They'll never let you
bring me in.
Do it,
or I'll take you down.
Cuffs.
On the belt.
[gunshots with silencer]
Ah!
[gurgling]
Woman:
Oh, my God!
There's a Guy
right up there.
[gurgles]
[people yelling]
[woman screams]
[gunshot]
Ah!
[crowd screaming]
[music]
Where'd he--?
Up there! Up there!
[panting]
Get down!
[screams]
God! Oh, my God!
It's okay.
Ah, ah!
Down there.
[clicks]
Shit.
[woman sobs]
[shooting]
[gunshots]
Drop the gun.
[gun cocks]
If I drop the gun,
we'll both die.
I said, drop the gun!
They're here for me
but they'll kill you too.
Now help me
get this off.
I can't breathe.
[screams and glass shattering]
Stairs.
[groans]
[shooting]
Fuck.
You okay?
[shouting]
The ramp is
the only way out.
[exhales]
[gunshots]
[music]
[gun cocks]
[sobbing]
[squeaking]
[groans]
[gunshot]
[music]
[groaning]
[gunshots]
[groans and screams]
[woman screaming]
[gunshots]
[yells]
[groans]
Hey.
Don't you fucking dare.
[gunshots]
[groans]
[metal clanging]
[clang]
[woman screaming]
[shattering]
Mechanical voice:
I'm calling from the dark side.
Sorry. Sorry.
I'm calling from the--
sorry.
[music]
[groans quietly]
[sirens wailing]
Get back.
[tires squealing]
[panting]
I told you.
What? You told me what?
They'd never let you
bring me in.
[music]
F--
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
[sirens continue wailing]
Man [over loudspeaker]:
Move away from the building.
Can everybody please
move away from the building?
[indistinct speaking
over radio]
They know you're coming.
We gotta hurry.
Where'd they
find him?
Sitting on a bench
near the reservoir.
Has he said
anything yet?
Nothing.
He's pretty shaken up.
Who else
knows he's here?
Everyone.
Nothing I could do.
Heavies from the bureau
and Justice are on their way.
Man [on TV]:
--With an unidentified
third man.
How long do I have?
Five,
10 minutes, Max.
--Wanted for questioning
in an ongoing investigation.
Now, a guggenheim employee
tells me
That while they were
in the museum--
[door closes]
This isn't over.
[music]
Are you sure about this?
[sirens wailing]
Just read it.
[horn honks]
They recognize you?
Don't think so.
[horn honks]
[horns honking]
Man:
Back it up!
[tires squealing]
[music]
Woman [on TV]: Came crashing--
how you doing, al?
[door closes]
there was glass everywhere.
As compared to what?
And just on the ground.
Man [on TV]:
When you heard all of this
commotion, did you think--?
Anything you need, Ellie,
just let me know.
Thanks.
Woman [on TV]:
I just heard gunshots.
And people were hit
and screaming,
And people just started
running out the door,
And I didn't know
what was going on.
You okay?
Yeah.
You flip this guy.
You make sure my partner
wasn't killed for nothing.
Woman [on TV]:
I know that-- I think random
people were going down and--
I mean, there was
police running up
As other people
were going down.
[music]
You ready for this?
[door closes]
Good evening,
colonel wexler.
I'm agent
Louis Salinger.
I know who you are.
Of course you do.
I was at the guggenheim
this afternoon.
Salinger [over speaker]:
The assassin you met with...
I know you were his handler.
And I know that you arranged
for him to be killed
At the behest of the bank,
Because I was obviously
getting too close.
But if a hit team at the
guggenheim is what happens
Because I was
getting too close to him...
What do you think
the bank's gonna do
When it realizes
how close I am to you?
Death comes for us all,
agent Salinger.
Yeah, but based on everything
I've read about you,
You seem like the kind of man
Who aspired to die
for something more than this.
Well, this is the difference
between truth and fiction.
Fiction has to make sense.
I'm confused, colonel.
Why would a tried
and true communist,
A hardliner that spent
30 years in the stasi
Fighting against the evils
of capitalism...
Why would this man waste
His final days
working for an institution
That was the very embodiment
of everything he once despised?
Salinger:
You dedicated your life
to the communist ideal.
You sacrificed everything
for the good of the party.
For what?
You lost your wife
to betrayal.
Your daughter to suicide.
And when the wall fell,
Your whole life
fell apart with it.
You know nothing about me.
I was lost long
before the wall fell.
I was once destined to become
a man much like yourself.
True-hearted,
Determined,
Full of purpose.
But, uh,
Character is easier kept
than recovered.
We cannot control
the things life does to us.
They are done
before you know it,
And once they are done,
They make you do other things,
Until at last
everything comes between you
And the man you wanted to be.
No.
We all have choices in life.
You made yours.
Sometimes a man
can meet his destiny
On the road
he took to avoid it.
Skarssen and that bank need
to answer for what they've done.
They have to be
brought to Justice.
You can help me do that.
Justice
Is not possible.
Why not?
Because, agent Salinger,
Your idea of Justice
is an illusion.
[over speaker]
don't you understand
the very system
That you serve
and protect
Will never allow
anything to happen
To Skarssen
or the bank?
Wexler:
On the contrary.
The system guarantees
the ibbc's safety,
Because everyone is involved.
What do you mean,
"everyone"?
Hezbollah.
Cia.
The columbian drug cartels.
Russian organized crime.
[over speaker]
governments of iran, germany,
china, your government.
Every multinational
corporation, every one.
They all need
banks like the ibbc
So that they can operate
Within the black
and gray latitudes.
And this is why
your investigative efforts
Have either been ignored
or undermined,
And why you and I
will be quietly disposed of
Before any case
against the bank
Ever reaches a court of law.
[over speaker]
so, what are we all
supposed to do?
We just supposed
to give up,
And accept that this
is the way of the world?
I'm not gonna do that.
I still believe--
I know--
That there has to be a way
to bring down this bank,
And you are
gonna help me.
You understand...
If you really want
to stop the ibbc,
You won't be able
to do it
Within the boundaries
of your system of Justice.
You will have to go outside.
Once you do...
There will always be
collateral damage.
[over speaker]
yes.
Should you sacrifice your own
ideals for the greater good?
That's a difficult choice,
one I understand all too well,
But as you so
eloquently put it,
Sometimes a man
can meet his destiny
On the road
he took to avoid it.
What?
What are you doing?
I think it's time
for you to leave.
Leave? What are you
talking about?
You know what
I'm talking about.
No way, lou.
No fucking way. You've
already got him turned.
Now go back in there and get
him to come in on his own.
We can use everything.
We'll blow this
whole thing wide open.
I don't think so.
Why not?
Because I'm not gonna make
the same mistake twice.
I can protect him, lou.
No, you can't.
They'll get to him.
If they can't,
they'll get to you.
If they can't get to you,
they'll get to your family.
I can't just
walk away from this.
You're walking away
so I don't have to.
How can you trust him?
That relic in there
is looking for redemption.
I'm the only one
who can give it to him.
And who gives it to you
when this is all over?
You need to cut me loose.
Tell 'em I escaped
from your custody.
Te-- tell 'em
whatever you have to.
Just use my history.
They'll believe you.
I don't know.
Ella, listen to me.
Sometimes the hardest
thing in life
Is to know which bridge
to cross and which to burn.
I'm the one you burn.
[exhales]
[music]
[speaking in Italian]
We've been waiting here
for an hour.
I'm sorry, Martin,
but none of us
Have been able
to reach them.
Unfortunately,
Mario and Enzo Calvini
Are not known
for their punctuality.
They do realize
this is the closing?
[whispering indistinctly]
Man:
Mr. White,
I've been instructed
to escort you
And your associates
from the building.
Please gather your materials
and come with me.
Instructed by whom?
Man:
Please, Mr. White,
if you could just comply.
[engine starts]
[music]
Our father never
trusted these people.
Thank you for
telling us the truth.
Had you not
come forward,
We would have made
a terrible mistake today.
I'm just glad
I could be of service.
I don't know, Jonas.
I was told nothing.
I-I was simply thrown out.
Skarssen [over phone]:
They know.
Look, I-I can't discuss
this right now.
I'll call you
when I'm in the air.
Woman [on TV]:
Welcome to world news.
I'm tristana moore.
We're live today
In the democratic
republic of niberia.
As we go on air,
we're getting reports
That thousands
of troops loyal to
General Charles motomba's
revolutionary freedom front
Are moving towards
the capital of dénué.
According to
eyewitnesses,
Several explosions
have been heard
And there've been
heavy outbreaks of gunfire
In many parts of the city.
Man [on TV]:
The people of niberia
have suffered greatly.
It is time to begin
a new chapter
In our country's history.
We will not stop
until national liberation
And the restoration
of nationhood--
[beep]
News about Martin?
He didn't show up at his hotel
or at the airport.
The Italian police
have been unable
To locate his car
or driver.
I think Enzo
and Mario Calvini
Are sending us
a message.
How could they possibly
have found out?
This is precisely
what we pay you to know.
Man:
We're out of time and options.
We must make the deal
with sunay.
How can we trust
this man?
The Israeli government
is his biggest customer.
Why would he agree
To help us
provide missiles
To the iranians
and the syrians
That have a
first-strike capability
Against the Israelis?
I know sunay. I believe
he has every intention
Of selling you
the guidance systems,
Because he's already
provided the Israelis
With the countermeasures
to defeat them.
Would the turk really play
such a dangerous game?
We are.
The only way we can
make this work
Is to guarantee
that sunay keeps
This information
in complete confidence.
If our buyers find out
the missiles are worthless,
They'll pull
all their orders
And this bank will be
left insolvent.
Have him here
by tomorrow afternoon.
Tomorrow he's going to a
funeral service for his cousin.
He'll be unavailable
till Monday.
Unless, of course,
you'd be willing to attend.
Make the call.
Get me ahmet sunay.
[music]
It's tomorrow.
It's right there.
Do you want to be escorted?
We'll be fine,
thank you.
The sunay funeral,
please.
Man:
It will be over soon.
You may wait here.
Wexler:
Is there a bathroom
I could use?
Man:
Just over there.
I won't be a moment.
Right.
Wexler: The signal?
Salinger: Good.
Skarssen [on tape]:
The sunay funeral, please.
Where'd you put the spike?
Inside the lapel
of his jacket.
The lawyer?
White?
He's gone.
I told you,
There will always
be collateral damage
When you take matters
into your own hands.
Your plan is working.
It has left Skarssen
with only one option.
Record the conversation
and you'll gain your end.
[people speaking indistinctly
in turkish]
How can you be so sure
they'll talk about
Sunay's deal with Israel
and the countermeasures?
It is the key issue.
Once you let
the iranians and syrians
Hear that the missiles
are completely useless
Against the Israelis,
They will cancel
their orders
And the ibbc
Will collapse.
[chatter]
Wilhelm.
Ahmet.
It's been a long time.
Sunay [over earphone]:
Yes.
Wexler:
My sympathies for the loss
of your cousin.
Sunay:
Thank you.
Jonas Skarssen,
ahmet sunay.
If you'd simply come
to me in the beginning,
It would have
been better.
[chants in turkish
over loudspeaker]
Sunay:
Midday prayers
Will begin soon.
Should only take a short time
to settle on the broad strokes.
Skarssen:
The rest can be sorted out
at your leisure.
Sunay:
We have 10 minutes.
Wilhelm, would you mind
if I spoke to Mr. Sunay alone?
I believe I understand the
particulars of your situation.
Skarssen:
Perhaps we should discuss this
in a more private place.
Sunay:
Yes, of course.
Allow me to show you something
very special.
Something that very few
outsiders know exists.
It's my understanding
That the product you purchased
are the XW-41s.
After you.
Skarssen:
Yes. Forty-two hundred units.
[radio static]
What kind of guidance
are they currently equipped--?
[radio static]
Skarssen:
They all need to be upgraded
with volcon systems.
Sunay:
Launch platforms?
Skarssen:
Ground-based vehicles
and fixed-wing aircraft.
So you understand
I have a terminal deadline.
First of February,
yes.
Skarssen: Can you meet it?
Sunay: To be sure.
But you must arrange
For the end-user certificates,
transport...
Skarssen:
Yes. We'll arrange for it all.
Where would the work be done?
Sunay:
Cyprus. I've a facility there.
We would start
retrofitting the worms
Within a day
of their arrival.
So if you deliver them to me
within the next two weeks,
We'll meet your deadline.
[wings fluttering]
[bats squeaking]
I'm concerned
that we limit
Any and all knowledge
of your involvement.
Sunay:
If we structure my involvement
through a thick veil of shells
I don't foresee
any complications.
[speaking in turkish]
Sorry?
You. Come here now.
Sunay:
Usually we would involve our
import partners from Russia.
What?
I-I'm just a tourist.
Now,
you must leave.
Could you get
that light out of--?
Get your fucking--
[groans]
So shall we discuss numbers?
There is a more
salient deal point
That needs to be resolved
before we can do that.
Sunay:
And what point is that?
[groans]
Skarssen:
The point of Fidelity.
[radio static]
[all groaning]
I know you provided
the Israeli government
With the countermeasures
to this guidance system.
Last year alone
I did more than 300 million
in business with the Israelis.
[radio static]
I would never
put that at risk.
How can I trust you
not to divulge
This information
to anyone else?
It's mutual interest,
not trust,
That will be the bond
of our relationship.
[radio static]
Your compensation will be held
in an escrow account.
[radio static]
Skarssen:
--Released until
our clients pay in full.
And those are the terms.
[radio static]
Skarssen [distorted]:
The payout structure--
The transfers will be begun
by tomorrow morning.
Ehames will contact you
With the number
for the escrow account.
[music]
So ends the bloody business
of the day.
[clatters]
[sighs]
We're closed. I need you
and ehames here tomorrow
To work out all the details
with sunay's people.
Yes. We're on our way home.
Wilhelm?
[music]
Wake up.
[chatter]
Who are you?
[Skarssen panting]
I'm Louis Salinger.
You don't have
the authority to arrest me.
Who said anything
about arresting you?
What do you want?
I want some fucking Justice.
Wait, wait. Wait.
Executing me
won't change anything.
There will be a hundred other
bankers to take my place.
Everything will continue.
The only thing
you'll succeed in doing
Is to satisfy
your own blood lust.
[chanting in the distance]
And you know it.
[music]
[gunshot]
[body thudding, tiles shuffling]
[gun cocks]
[exhales]
With compliments of
...Enzo and Mario Calvini.
Thank you.
[ringing]
[heavy breathing]
[silence]
[music]