This film contains some strong
language, and some scenes of
violence.
'God said to Abraham,
"Kill me a son."
'Abe says,
"Man, you must be putting me on."
'God say, "No." Abe say, "What?"
'God say,
"You can do what you want, Abe,
"but the next time you see me comin',
you better run."
'Abe says, "Where do you want
this killing done?"
'And God says...
'"Out on Highway 61."'
This programme contains
some strong language and some
violent scenes.
SCREAMING
The Serbs have taken over
this Albanian village.
They're killing everyone in sight.
It's not a war. It's a slaughter.
The Serb commander
is in that mosque.
This is three villages in a week
he's destroyed.
We are to identify
and neutralise him. We will proceed
under cover of NATO airstrike,
commencing...
right...about...now! Move!
SCREAMING
CONVERSATION IN SERBIAN
EXPLOSIONS
I'm in the nest.
Copy that. Raven is in the nest.
Cover fire, on my mark.
Three, two...
one!
SHOUTING IN SERBIAN
SERBIAN
Sgt First-Class Aaron Hallam.
It is my privilege
to present to you the Silver Star,
one of our top awards for valour.
Your bravery, judgement and resolve
are an example to all soldiers.
Your courageous actions
are the bedrock upon which peace
and democracy are built.
Congratulations, Hallam.
WHIMPERS
STRAINED BREATHING
GIRL'S SCREAMS ECHOES
ECHOING SCREAMS
WOLF WHINES
Hey.
What happened to you?
WOLF SNARLS
You stepped on a snare, didn't you?
WOLF GROWLS
Easy. Take it easy.
Be still.
All right. Let me have that.
Nasty thing.
Next time you see one of these,
you go the other way.
OK...
There we go.
You're good, you're good.
OK.
Now get out of here.
CONVERSATION, LAUGHTER
Anyone here with the initials JW?
Yeah.
This yours?
Yeah, it is.
What the...?!
No more snares on wolves, guys.
I got him.
He was down there. What?
I saw him.
You need all that equipment
to kill a deer?
COCKS GUN
That's how we make sure
they're dead.
You guys don't look like
deer hunters.
When you kill with your own hands,
there is a reverence.
Is that right?
There is no reverence
in what you do.
Where's your weapon?
BLADE SINGS
Holy smoke.
You're not here for the deer,
are you? What's that?
You think you can hunt me
with those rifles?
Your rifles against my knife.
What are you, nuts?
What do you think?
Yeah, well, don't push it, asshole.
STRAINED BREATHING
Where the fuck are you?
Come on, man...
HE GROANS
SHOTS RING OUT
HE PANTS
BIRD SCREECHES
GUNSHOT RINGS OUT
HE GASPS
YELLS:  God...!
BLADE SINGS, SHRIEKING
GASPS AND GROANS
SCREAMS
SCREAM ECHOES
STOMPS FEET
You want antifreeze with that?
It's not that cold out.
Maybe not to you.
Thought you were on the wagon.
Wheels fell off.
You running a fever? It's the cold.
Not crazy about the thaw, neither.
Get a hot-water bottle.
Keep you company at night.
Forget it. I wanna go to California.
Do a little fishin'.
I hear the yellowtail jump into
the boat this time of year.
Zander, yellowtail aren't running
at this time of year. ..Hello, Ted.
LT. How d'you know it was me?
I saw your pigeon-toed tracks.
What're you doing this far north?
Van Zandt wanted me
to show you something. Personally.
Been a few years.
OKeechobee, 1996.
Your agents got scared of alligators.
One shat in his pants. Mike Hannay.
You disappeared after that.
Did a few more then quit.
Been at Portland three years now.
We reached out for you a few times.
LT, let me ask you something.
What the hell you doing out here?
Working for the Wildlife Fund.
Took a lot of trouble to get here.
You're a hard man to find.
No, I'm not. How hard am I to find
if you found me?
Van Zandt thinks it's important.
He thinks everything is.
This is different.
I don't do that kind of work anymore.
Why don't you have a look?
I don't want to go back there.
All we're asking you to do
is take a look, LT.
Tom, can we get
prints off that paper? Sure.
Do. And the door handles.
I'm worried about the SWAT agents.
I want these guys alive.
Reid, deploy some of your men
across the canyon.
Contain this area and establish
a perimeter. It's your call.
HE RETCHES
You gonna be all right? No. I hate
those things. I'm afraid of heights.
I'm Abby Durrell, the ASAC here. I'm
not sure how much Harry told you...
Tell me what he told you to tell me.
We'll take it from there.
HE RETCHES
They were found half a mile away.
They were killed with a hatchet
then gutted, it seems in ritualistic
fashion. Every organ was cut.
My deputy's talking to
the local Peyote chief.
There's no Peyote ritual
for gutting humans.
The bodies were quartered like you'd
quarter deer. Peyote are upset...
A Peyote wouldn't quarter
two deer hunters unless...
What? He's gonna eat them.
There were two men killed the same
way last week in Washington State.
They were Forest Rangers,
so we got jurisdiction.
Where are the bodies?
We sent 'em to the lab yesterday.
You need to see 'em? No.
You got too many men and horses here.
All these tracks. It's chaos.
You find a deer stand or coolers
for packing meat?
Not within a five-mile radius.
Still looking.
What do you know about the victims?
As far as we know,
two businessmen from Metford.
FLIES BUZZ
What else can we do for you?
Nothing. Ask everybody to fall back.
Bobby, get everyone out of there.
Guys, everybody, fall back.
Come on. Let's go!
Move back! Yeah, everyone!
BIRD CALL
HE SIGHS
This is him. Who?
The guy who did it. We don't know
how many killers there were.
Just one. How do you know?
Left his signature in that tree.
These were able-bodied men.
They had rifles with sophisticated
'scopes. One had a 9mm handgun.
You think one man with a hatchet...?
Not a hatchet. A knife.
With a serrated edge on one side.
And he threw it it at this tree,
then killed two men?
Yeah. Size ten shoes, no tread,
almost a slipper. Kind of like this.
He's out there.
You can't go alone.
That's how I work.
Take this. I don't need that.
Humour me. It's fully charged.
Make sure you leave it on. OK.
Need a gun? I don't like guns.
How much time do you need? If I'm
not back in two days, I'm dead.
WINGS FLUTTER
LT.
Remember me? No.
You taught me.
I taught a lot of people.
How come
you didn't answer my letters?
How come you're chopping up
all these people?
You see the scopes they used?
They weren't hunters, LT.
They were sweepers.
You have to come in, son.
HE GROANS
LT GRUNTS
HE GRUNTS
HE GROANS
CRUNCH, MOANS
Move up.
Down! He's down!
Stay back, don't touch him.
Find the weapon.
BEEPING
Haul it in!
Bring him in.
LT. Sir.
Helluva job.
He's one of yours, isn't he? Yeah.
That's what I thought.
He's our man? Yeah.
Any idea why?
No. That'd be your job.
Would you like some coffee?
No, thank you, ma'am.
You don't have to talk to us
if you don't want to. I understand.
How about telling us your name?
We could start with that.
He knows my name.
Want to tell me
what happened in the woods?
You known six billion chickens will
die in slaughterhouses this year?
Does that connect to Silver Falls?
What if we had a species above us in
the food chain? How would you feel
if that species lost respect for us
and started slaughtering us
wholesale?
I don't know.
But it's very interesting.
Do you understand it?
Oh, yeah. Good.
What else did you want to tell
Mr Bonham you don't want to tell me?
I'd like to talk about
Operation Eagle, Cobra.
Shuddup! You'll get yourself killed.
He's Aaron Hallam. You remember me?
They're recording this shit.
So put it on record.
It'll never say what you want it to.
Then what am I doing here, people?
Moret, help me out here.
Is this our guy or not?
I know there are variables, Moret,
there always are,
but we can't indict a variable.
Hey, boss.
Sir, we understand you have a man
named Aaron Hallam in your custody.
How much do you know about him?
Born in 1968, raised in West
Virginia. High school equivalency,
although he scored
off the charts in science.
Joined the army at 18.
That's the strange part.
What's that, sir? Well, it doesn't
really tell us any more about him.
The record's incomplete.
Not even a date of discharge.
Sgt Hallam is unofficially
missing in action. Sir.
Unofficially.
That's a cover. That means
he's still doing work for you.
We're here to take possession
of your prisoner, sir.
This is not a military base.
Your man very likely
killed and mutilated four hunters
on Federal land.
I think you should take a look
at this, sir.
Unless we've been invaded
by a foreign power
and are officially at war,
you don't have any authority here.
I know you want to go
but we need the results.
And your statement.
You ever use that thing?
You mean have I shot anyone?
Yeah.
Would you ask a guy
the same question? Yeah.
Well, as a matter of fact I have.
Do we have to go into it? No.
OK.
Not a great view of the city.
It's a wilderness.
What's your relationship to Hallam?
I trained him.
To do what?
Trained him to survive.
I trained him to kill.
I trained a lot of people like him,
best of the best, shit like that.
I pulled your file.
You were never in the military.
No.
You just worked for them? Yeah.
Like a contractor.
You don't like to talk about it,
do you?
No.
HE SIGHS
My father was an army colonel.
When my brother was killed
in Vietnam, he decided
not to lose another son to that war.
End of story.
Dad was a tracker
before he joined the army
and I learned what I do from him.
What about Hallam? He's unusual.
He can kill anybody, without regret.
Most of those he killed never knew
he was in the same room as 'em.
How's that make you feel? Can't say.
I never killed anybody myself. I...
HE SIGHS
I just taught people how.
In many ways,
Hallam is a fine warrior.
After a tour in Kosovo he was given
another sensitive assignment,
off the books.
He went too far.
Innocent people lost their lives.
Hallam's battle stress
has become so deep
it's part of his personality.
And it's impossible to reverse.
He's a killing machine.
There is no way he can be indicted,
or tried in open court,
or any court.
He cannot be processed,
interviewed, charged with a crime
or copped out as a psycho.
He cannot appear in any newspaper.
As far as the world is concerned,
sir,
Aaron Hallam doesn't exist.
He's one of them.
They'll handle it.
You know why you're here, Aaron.
You wandered off the range.
It was way too messy, man.
We're supposed to be precise.
They weren't his family.
They were soldiers, Dale. There was
no backup, no way I could get out.
I was set up. That's bullshit.
You fucked up. You caused injury
and death to unarmed civilians.
They had weapons.
Well, that's the problem.
You can't tell the sharks
from the guppies any more.
That's what they're using now?
They say it's painless.
Course, they never use it on...
Release him, Aaron! Release him now!
You flying to Vancouver? Yeah.
Then a connecting flight?
No. A drive. Eight hours.
Right. You don't like flying.
Must be worth it.
It's a special place.
Come up sometime. You'd like it.
You don't have to wear two guns.
The whole posture would change.
It's an open invitation.
HE MOANS
GASPS, SHRIEKS
HE WHIMPERS
Is it painless, Dale?
We need paramedics here!
Help!
See if you can help people.
No, I can't!
Does anyone know what's going on...?
Ma'am, just sit down.
Paramedic! Paramedic!
I'm OK, I'm OK!
My buddies are in there.
Get 'em out, get 'em out!
I'm OK, I'm OK...
OK?
Horrible, yeah...
Get 'em out!
Hello?! Oh, shit...
Hello? You're breaking up!
Don't leave the house yet...
PA ANNOUNCEMENTS
"Do not leave your bags unattended.
Unattended bags will be destroyed."
You go over there,
I'll go down there. All right!
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
Ready or not, here I come.
Hey.
MOUTHS SILENTLY
SHE CHUCKLES
LAUGHTER
'Now a breaking story
from reporter Jeff Gionola,
'who is live outside the tunnel
to Forest Park. Jeff?'
'Ken, we have just arrived
on the scene of a terrible accident
'just outside Forest Park. A truck
or van transporting people. We...'
SHOUTED INSTRUCTIONS
I will teach you...how to kill.
Quickly. Accurately. Efficiently.
It will become a reflex action.
You will learn to enter a combat zone
and evaporate into shadow.
You will learn how to survive.
Or you will not.
Ready!
Arm. Heart! Leg, leg!
Reverse your grip. Bring your knife
from the inside of his arm,
sever the tissue.
Pull his finger off the trigger,
come over his left shoulder,
grab the strap, choke.
Cut into his heart
and bring him down. Go.
Arm, throat, heart, leg, leg,
arm, lung. Good. Good.
'Enter the thigh here,
slicing the femoral artery,'
into this thigh and that artery.
This arm is in your way.
It cannot hurt you. The only thing
it can do is block the lung puncture.
Push it in front of his face
and go into his lung.
Now. Arm, neck, heart,
leg, leg, lung!
One, two, three, four, five, six.
One. Two. Three.
Power assist, four. Five. Six.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
Make this a good power assist.
You're looking for his backbone.
There we go.
Go.
There we go. Once again.
'LT.
'I don't think
I can do this any more.
'The nightmares are getting worse.
'I think I'm losing it, LT.
'I need to talk to you.
'I don't know if you've been
getting my letters, LT.
'I need to hear from you
or talk to you.
'You've been like a father to me.
'Please write.'
Once you are able to kill mentally,
the physical part will be easy.
The difficult part...
..is learning how to turn it off.
All we know for sure is
that we have three fatalities.
We don't know if there were other
passengers. Access is very limited.
We have no new information
from the police or the FBI.
However, the van seems to be
a military vehicle,
possibly for carrying prisoners.
We'll try to confirm that.
Information is sketchy.
Rescue crews are still here,
with FBI agents and technicians.
We're getting no comment
from the FBI agents...
What happened? He's loose.
Hello, Irene. Ohhh, Aaron.
You scared me.
It's good to see ya.
I'm not listening to you.
Everything you said was a lie.
I've never lied to you. Where've
you been the last six months?
Working for the government.
That's a lie.
A damn lie. Get out of here. I don't
want to see you again. Aaron?
Aaron, you're back!
Hey, Loretta. Hup...!
It's so good to see you. I miss you
so much. Where have you been?
Loretta, go do your homework.
Can I visit with Aaron some more?
Later.
Will you stay for dinner, Aaron?
Go do your homework.
You can't just step back into
our lives, Aaron. I understand.
I don't even know
what you do for a living.
Did you look in my locker?
How could I do that?
You have four locks on the thing.
What track is that?
A squirrel.
That's right. Where's the next one?
Erm...
Bring it down. Where's the next?
I can't tell.
Hold it flat.
See? Every nine inches.
That's the gallop pattern.
Every nine inches.
Oh, yeah. I see.
What's this one?
That's a raccoon.
How come you never see him?
Well, they hide.
To survive.
Men don't respect animals any more.
They run 'em down or kill 'em
any chance they get.
I think that's sad.
RUSTLING, SHE GASPS
That's only Kitty. Here, Kitty.
No, don't bother him now. Why?
He's hunting, too.
(Does he know we're here?)
Oh, he knows.
How?
He can sense it.
She's so happy to see you.
Sit down.
What's this?
You've gotta leave.
You gotta get out of Portland.
What do you mean?
You're in danger, Irene. Why?
You and Loretta. They'll come
and burn this house down.
What are you talking about, Aaron?
RADIO: "We've got a visual.
"Copy that. Stand by for intercept."
Right, sweetie. Wait for me
at school. I'll pick you up, OK?
Right. Is everything OK, Mommy?
Everything's fine.
OK. I love you.
See you later, alligator.
"She's approaching. Intercept at
six o'clock. Roger. We got her."
Irene Kravitz? Agent Durrell.
That your little girl?
Loretta, is it?
That's right.
We'd like to talk to you.
About what? Just routine, but
it'd be easier to talk inside.
If you make us come back
with a warrant, it won't be routine.
Going somewhere, Mrs Kravitz?
Nah, I'm just cleaning stuff up.
Trying to get organised.
We're looking for a man
named Aaron Hallam.
Have you seen him?
Not for a few months.
But you know him? Is this about
his government work?
When was the last time you saw him?
I don't know. A few months ago he...
sort of took off.
That's the way he is.
Is he here, Irene?
What's this about?
What's Aaron done?
Have a seat, Irene.
Nobody said he's done anything.
FBI wouldn't call if he hadn't.
When did you and Aaron meet?
Eight months ago. He stayed here
a while then just took off.
He tell you where he was going?
Ms Kravitz, is he still here?
I said I ain't seen him in months.
How many times do I have to say it?
Excuse me, where are you going?
Irene.
You aren't doing him any good.
Nor your daughter. What do you know
about my daughter?!
VOICES CONTINUE
You want someone here, I know. But
think of her safety. Ask yourself,
is he a guy you want around
your daughter? What has he done?
We just want to talk to him.
Did he kill somebody?
Come in.
SIGHS: You care about
these people here, Aaron?
You're gonna get 'em hurt.
You here to sweep me, LT?
I don't do that.
How do I know that?
They are coming for you.
They've been coming for me
for a long time, LT.
You have to answer
for what you've done.
I have to live with what I've done.
You can say whatever you want.
I don't trust you, LT.
If you cross this line...
..you'd better be ready to kill me.
GUN COCKS
Don't move.
Hands on your head.
Get on the floor.
I said get on the floor! Now!
Get down!
GUNSHOTS
SIRENS WAIL
TYRES SCREECH
RADIOS AND SHOUTING
Move!
Block the sidewalk...!
SHOUTS AND SCREAMS
SIGHS: That's a silver star.
That is a sketch
that I made for a knife.
It's addressed to you.
"LT, those guys you...
trained to come and kill me,
"they're not soldiers,
they're...robots."
SIREN WAILS
Positive ID at the Riverfront
Construction site. Heading there.
'Over."' Ten-nine that location.
Agent in charge, Van Zandt,
Agent Moret. The site foreman.
He pulled up by that tunnel.
How many men down there?
Maybe three dozen.
Get an exact count. And plans.
This is an overview.
Four major sections there.
Probably in the red section, tunnels
8 to 12. How far does this extend?
About 12 blocks, into downtown.
Cover the red section, Ted.
Show me the rest.
He went in here. There's three more
entrances. Block 'em off.
KLAXON, SHOUTING VOICES
RUMBLING
I got it...
MUFFLED RADIOS
FBI! Step away from the column
with your hands up!
Let me see your hands!
720, this is number one. I need
backup, now. Red section, tunnel 8.
Did you hear me? I said step away
from the column now!
Step away from the fucking column!
HE GROANS
THUD
DISTANT SHOUTS
GROANS ECHO
Shit...
Oh, Jesus Christ. Bobby!
Leave it in! Don't touch him!
Open his mouth.
Keep pressure on. On the wound.
Command post, this is number two.
Agent down. Sector red.
CHOKING
Get me them EMTs now. ASAP.
Bobby. Bobby, listen to me.
Bobby, listen to me!
TRUCK HORN BLARES
SIRENS WAIL
SIRENS BLARE
Ain't nobody...
RADIO: 'Charlie one. Subject on foot,
eastbound, on the 11 bridge.'
Close off both ends.
Two SWAT teams on their way.
SIRENS WAIL
Get everybody off the bridge!
SIRENS AND RADIOS
No cars!
Leave that car!
Excuse me.
WOMAN SHRIEKS
Hey!
Get down!
Keep this between us!
Don't get in the way.
Get everybody down on the floor.
Get down! Down!
He's on the tower!
Targeting opportunity!
Fire!
GUNSHOTS RING OUT
Cease-fire! Cease-fire!
Hold your fire!
GUNSHOT
I need two, three officers on each
bridge. Sweep the western seawall.
Shut all bike paths. SWAT, recon
teams on both sides of the river.
Sniper units to cover each team.
Forget it. Currents'll take him
and he's like a fish.
This is our show, Bonham.
How many people can you lose?
He will kill as many as he can.
So decide an acceptable body count.
Enough!
You want more dead? You'll get 'em
if you declare war on my boy.
I made him what he is. I can stop
him. We've lost two of our people.
Best I ever served with.
Hallam belongs to us.
DOGS BARK
POLICE RADIOS
WATER ROARS
WATER HISSES
BIRD CALL
CREAKING
ARROW WHISTLES
HE GROANS
If he's alive he won't come in.
Right.
Hallam! Get on the ground!
WATER POUNDS
'God said to Abraham,
'"Kill me a son."'
# There's a man goin' 'round
takin' names
# And he decides who to free
and who to blame
# Everybody won't be treated
all the same
# There'll be a golden ladder
reaching down
# When the man comes around
# The hairs on your arm
will stand up
# At the terror in each sip
and in each sup
# For you partake
of that last offered cup
# Or disappear
into the potter's ground
# When the man comes around
# Hear the trumpets, hear the pipers
# One hundred million angels singin'
# Multitudes are marching
to the big kettle drum... #