IT STARTED A HALF HOUR AGO.
SHE RAN IN SCREAMING,
GOING NUTS.
- MA'AM, OPEN THIS DOOR!
- SHE WOKE THE WHOLE
DAMNED PLACE UP.
- Man: SHUT THE FUCK UP, BITCH!
- GET BACK!  GET THOSE
PEOPLE BACK-- NOW!
-
- MA'AM, OPEN THIS DOOR NOW!
Woman:
HE'S TRYING
TO KILL ME!
Man: BITCH!
HE'S GONNA KILL ME!
MA'AM, ARE YOU ALONE
IN THIS ROOM?
I DIDN'T DO NOTHIN'!
I DIDN'T-- I DIDN'T!
PLEASE DON'T HURT ME!
I CAN'T GET THESE OFF.
GET THESE FUCKING THINGS
OFF MY HANDS!
PLEASE, GET THEM--
GET THEM OFF OF ME!
GET-- GET THEM OFF.
- CALM DOWN, HOLD ON.
- GET THEM OFF!
PLEASE GET THEM OFF!
IT'S OKAY.  IT'S OKAY.
IT'S OKAY.
SHHH.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE'S NOT COMING.
Woman:
SHE'S HAD INTERCOURSE.
SOME OLDER BUMPS AND BRUISES.
THE ONLY FRESH MARKINGS
ARE FROM THE CUFFS.
MA'AM, PLEASE
STAY IN THERE.
- CAN'T I JUST GO?
- WE'RE GONNA NEED YOU
TO COME DOWN TO THE STATION
AND GO OVER A FEW THINGS.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT ELSE
I CAN TELL YOU.
- I KNOW.
- I TOLD YOU EVERYTHING.
- MISS, WE'RE GONNA NEED
TO KEEP YOUR ITEMS.
SIGN THIS.
YOU CAN PUT THESE ON.
Man:
HER DETAILS CHECK OUT.
ADDRESS, CAR REGO--
ALL MATCH THE SUSPECT.
NOW SHE SAID SHE GOT AWAY
- WHEN HE WAS
PUTTING HER IN HIS PLANE.
- YEAH WELL, HE DENIES IT.
SAYS HIS FAMILY IS
OUT OF TOWN AND HE WAS
AT TWO FRIENDS' ALL NIGHT.
BOTH CONFIRM IT.
EVEN SOME PIZZA GUY
SAYS HE SAW HIM THERE.
Man #2:
...AND THEN HE
CHAINED YOU TO A POST
AND THEN HE RAPED YOU?
I TOLD YOU ALREADY,
THAT WAS BEFORE.
- ON A BEARSKIN.
- YOU TOLD THE OTHER OFFICER
IT WAS A BED.
NO, IT WAS A BEARSKIN
ON THE FLOOR.
WHAT THE FUCK
IS HE TRYING TO DO?
HOW MANY TIMES
DID YOU SAY HE HAD
INTERCOURSE WITH YOU?
ONCE.  HE...
JUST ONCE.
WAS IT VAGINALLY OR--
OR ANALLY?
I MEAN, BEFORE YOU SAID
IT WAS BOTH.
LOOK, HE DID IT NORMAL--
ON TOP.
AND THEN HE--
HE WRAPPED THE CHAIN
AROUND MY NECK.
HE WAS GONNA KILL ME.
- YEAH, BUT WHAT ABOUT THE BED?
- THERE WAS NO BED!
WHEN HE CHAINED ME
HE PUT A BLANKET
DOWN ON THE GROUND.
YOU'RE A PROSTITUTE,
AREN'T YOU?
- IS 23 YOUR REAL AGE?
-  YES.
WHY WOULD HE WANT
TO PUT YOU ON A PLANE?
HE SAID HE WANTED
TO TAKE ME TO HIS CABIN.
HMMM.
AM I BEING BOOKED?
Listen, I've spoken
to this Bob Hansen.
HE HAS TWO FRIENDS THAT SAY
HE WAS WITH THEM ALL NIGHT,
AND NOW I'M TRYING
TO WORK OUT IF YOU WERE EVEN
WITH THIS GUY LAST NIGHT.
YEAH?
- WAIT, WHAT JUST HAPPENED?
-
- OH SHHH.
- OKAY.
I...
DID YOU ALREADY
PACK THE CEREAL?
YEAH, THE KITCHEN'S
MOSTLY PACKED.
- HEY, DAD!
- OH, YOU GONNA CATCH
SOME GRIZZLY BEARS TODAY?
WHERE YOU GOIN'?
- ONLY TWO MORE WEEKS.
- WHY DON'T YOU COME ON
BACK TO BED?
I GET THE NEXT DECADE, OKAY?
- DID YOU SIGN THAT CHECK?
- I'M LATE AS IT IS.
HON, THEY'RE NOT GONNA COME
AND MOVE ALL THIS STUFF
- IF YOU DON'T PAY THEM.
-
FOUND HER LAST NIGHT
WAY UP THE KNIK.
SERGEANT HAWKS IS TAKING
THE BOAT DOWNRIVER
FROM THE BRIDGE.
THANKS.
SARGE, SHE'S RIGHT
OVER HERE.
I DON'T KNOW.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
Man:
HEY, JACK.
- THIS ONE
OF YOUR MISSING PERSONS?
- EH, IT COULD BE.
SHE'S FEMALE.
LATE TEENS,
MAYBE EARLY 20s.
MY GIRL HAS A JACKET
JUST LIKE THAT.
BEAR DUG HER UP.
BEEN IN HERE--
I DON'T KNOW--
SIX MONTHS,
MAYBE A YEAR.
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
SHE WAS HIKING.
- A PURSE?
- THEY'RE STILL SEARCHING.
IT'S GONNA BE A HARD ONE.
ONE OF THE BOYS FOUND
THIS THOUGH,
IN THE GRAVE.
EXECUTION STYLE.
YOU EVER WISH YOU'D STAYED
IN WHITE COLLAR, LYLE?
YOU SOUND
JUST LIKE MY WIFE.
- YOU GONNA TAKE OVER?
- Jack: YEAH.
SHE'S NOT MISSING
ANYMORE.
...SO I ASKED HIM STRAIGHT.
I SAID "DID YOU DO THIS?"
HE SAID "YOU CAN'T RAPE
A PROSTITUTE, CAN YOU?"
HOW THE FUCK'S THAT?
HEY, YOU CAN LET HER GO.
- SHE'S TELLING THE TRUTH.
- SHE'S A PROSTITUTE THAT
REFUSED A POLYGRAPH.
- IT'S A DEAD END.
- WHAT DO YOU EXPECT HER TO DO?
- WE SHOULD BE GOING BACK THERE
AND GETTING A WARRANT!
- HEY, LISTEN,
WHO KNOWS WHAT THE FUCK WENT ON.
HANSEN'S AN UPSTANDING CITIZEN.
THE MAN HAS A WIFE,
CHILDREN AND NO RECORD
ON THE COMPUTERS.
THE LIEUTENANT AND I
SPOKE WITH THE D.A.
AND THERE'S NOT ENOUGH
TO SAY SHE WAS EVEN
IN THE GUY'S PLACE,
SO THERE WON'T BE A WARRANT.
I'M TAKING IT FROM HERE.
THE VICTIM WAS
SHERRY MORROW, 23,
A.K.A. SHERRY GRAVES
OR SHERRY GEORGIA.
SHE WAS REPORTED MISSING
LAST NOVEMBER
AFTER SAYING SHE WAS
GOING TO MEET A MAN
- FOR A $300 PHOTO SESSION.
-
ANY CONNECTION
TO THE JANE DOE
FOUND LAST YEAR
- CALLED EKLUTNA ANNIE?
- NO, SHEILA.
ANOTHER OFFICER DESCRIBED
SHERRY AND SUE LUNA
AS CARBON COPIES?
THEY WERE BOTH DANCERS
AT THE WILD CHERRY
AND GOOD TIMES CLUBS
AND BOTH SAID THEY
WERE LEAVING TO MEET
A PHOTOGRAPHER.
LOOK, WE AND A.P.D. ARE
LOOKING AT ALL THREE CASES,
BUT LET ME BE CLEAR:
THERE IS NOTHING NOW
THAT INDICATES ANYTHING
OTHER THAN A COINCIDENCE.
- Woman: ANY EVIDENCE?
- Sheila: WHAT ABOUT
THE OTHER GIRLS?
AS OF NOW THEY'RE ONLY
CONSIDERED MISSING PERSONS.
- DETAILS ARE IN YOUR HANDOUT.
- Sheila: WHEN ARE YOU
GONNA ADMIT
THERE'S SOMEBODY TAKING
THESE GIRLS?
WELL, WE'RE INVESTIGATING
ANY LINKS,
BUT WE DON'T BELIEVE THAT
THERE'S A MASS MURDERER
OUT THERE.
THAT'S ALL WE HAVE.
THANK YOU.
Jack:
SOMEBODY WENT TO A LOT
OF TROUBLE GETTING HER THERE.
THERE'S NO ROAD ACCESS.
PROBABLY USED A BOAT.
- WHAT, DUMPED?
- COULD HAVE DONE THAT CLOSER.
SUSPECT WANTED HER
OUT THERE ALIVE WHERE
THEY WOULDN'T BE DISTURBED.
HE SHOT HER FOUR TIMES--
TWO IN THE LEGS,
TWO IN THE CHEST,
LIKE SHE WAS RUNNING.
THEN HE REDRESSED HER,
WRAPPED A BANDAGE
AROUND HER HEAD.
- SHELL CASE IS A .223.
- SO WHAT ARE WE LOOKING AT?
PICKED HER UP FROM A BAR,
OVER AN HOUR DRIVE TO A BOAT.
ALL THE TIME THEY'RE
NEITHER SEEN OR MISSED.
HE'S NOCTURNAL,
METHODICAL.
PROBABLY WORKS NIGHTS.
HIS JOB GIVES HIM TIME.
LIKE--
LIKE A SHIFT WORKER.
CHRIST, THAT'S HALF
THE PEOPLE HERE.
BUT WHY LEAVE A SHELL?
IT DOESN'T FIT.
I DON'T THINK
HE'S CARELESS,
MORE OVERCONFIDENT.
HE DIDN'T COUNT ON
THE BODY BEING FOUND.
LIKE THE OTHERS.
WHAT OTHERS?
LIEUTENANT, THIS WAS
TOO WELL-PLANNED.
IT'S NOT A FIRST TIME.
IT'S NOT A ONE-OFF.
HE'S DONE IT BEFORE,
HE'LL DO IT AGAIN.
Dispatcher:
Lieutenant, I have a call--
- I'M NOT HERE.
GIVE ME 10 MINUTES.
- JUST GOT THIS FROM A.P.D.
ONE OF THE MISSING GIRLS'
SISTERS CALLED, WANTS
TO TALK TO SOMEONE.
THIS ALSO
FOR WHOEVER'S HEADING UP
THE MISSING DANCER'S CASE.
SAID IT'S URGENT.
NO, I'M THE WRONG GUY
TO GET IN THE MIDDLE OF THIS.
- THIS IS MY LAST TWO WEEKS.
- WELL, BAD LUCK.
YOUR PRECIOUS OIL MONEY
AND 800 MILES OF PIPE
AIN'T GOING ANYWHERE.
PULL WHATEVER TEAM
YOU NEED.
{ door slams,
engine starts }
HOW MANY OPEN CASES
HAS HE GOT?
WITH HUNTERS, HIKERS,
BOATERS AND IDIOTS
JUST WANDERING OFF,
ABOUT 600 FROM
THE LAST TWO YEARS.
600.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GET STARTED.
GRAB A BOX.
- JODI, I'M GOING
TO THAT PHOTO SESSION.
- FUCK!  CAN YOU WAIT?
- CAB'S ALREADY HERE.
CAN I BORROW THIS?
- ONLY IF YOU DROP OFF MY MAIL.
- DEB, HAVE YOU
SEEN MY NECKLACE?
- UH... NO, I HAVEN'T.
- WHAT TIME WILL YOU BE BACK?
-  NOT TILL LATER.  I'LL MEET YU
AT THE BAR.
HI, I'M DEBBIE.
SORRY I'M LATE.
I BROUGHT MY DOG
IF THAT'S OKAY.
-
- ¶¶ ...deep inside
¶¶ Give my love to you--
-  OH HEY, BOBBY.
- HEY, AL, GOOD MORNING.
HEY, JOHN SAYS
THE COYOTES ARE RUNNING.
I WAS THINKIN' ABOUT
TAKING THE BOYS,
- FLYING UP, GETTING A FEW?
- MAYBE NEXT WEEK.
I SURE WOULD LIKE TO.
WE'RE STILL ON FOR DINNER
WITH JOAN, YEAH, TUESDAY?
IF THAT'S WHAT
THE GIRLS ARRANGED.
- YOU KNOW, WHATEVER THEY SAY.
- YEAH.
- OH HEY, BOB.
- HI.
MORNING.
GOOD MORNIN', BOB.
- HI.
- Woman: HEY.
- OH NO!
- I KNOW.
I CAN NEVER SEEM TO GET
THE HANG OF THIS, BOB.
MORE PRESSURE.
LIKE THAT.
OH NICE.
- DID THAT CLAUSEN ORDER
COME IN?
- IT DID.
THEY CALLED
AND CHANGED IT TO TODAY,
BUT I CAN HANDLE IT.
OKAY.
DO THAT, PLEASE.
YEAH.
HEY, I GOT THAT.
- I'LL SORT
THAT OUT FOR YOU, BOB.
- OKAY, THANK YOU.
- YOU WANNA TAKE
ONE OF THESE HOME?
- I SURE DO.
OKAY.
ARE WE STILL HAVING
HALLOWEEN HERE?
- YOU BETCHA WE ARE.
- MY KIDS ARE ALL EXCITED.
- ARE THEY?  THAT'S GOOD.
- YEP.
- ALL RIGHT, KEEP AT IT NOW.
- ALL RIGHT.  SEE YA.
I'M GOING OVER
SUSPECTS FROM COURT
AND RAPE-CENTER CASES.
I'LL CHECK THE REST
IN THE MORNING.
ARE YOU STAYIN'?
YOU HAVE ANYTHING
ON A ROBERT C. HANSEN?
GRABBED SOME GIRL
BACK IN '71.
DROVE HER AT GUNPOINT,
HANDS BOUND AND NAKED, TO
KENAI LAKE AND THEN RAPED HER.
HE GOT FIVE YEARS,
HE WAS OUT IN THREE MONTHS.
IT SEEMS
HE JUST HAD A RUN-IN
WITH A PROSTITUTE.
SHE TOLD ANCHORAGE POLICE
THE EXACT SAME STORY.
- WHY ISN'T
THIS GUY ON OUR LIST?
-  THAT WAS 12 YEARS AGO.
- IF WE OPEN IT UP THAT MUCH--
- GET EVERYTHING YOU CAN
FROM ARCHIVE.
- AND CHECK ALL MISSING PERSONS
FROM THE SAME PERIOD.
-
- DO YOU KNOW
ANYONE DOWNTOWN-- VICE?
- YEAH, ONE GUY.  WHY?
- I NEED A MEET.  TONIGHT.
- GOT IT.
EIGHT GIRLS
IN THE LAST TWO YEARS--
ALL LATE TEENS, EARLY 20s,
5'2" TO 5'7", 120-125 LBS,
ALL MADE BIG MONEY DATES
WITH A STRANGER
AND THEN DISAPPEARED.
CINDY PAULSON, 23,
5'2", 120 LBS
WAS OFFERED $200 FOR A BLOWJOB
AND THEN RAPED AT GUNPOINT.
GUY SAID HE LIKED
TO TAKE PICTURES,
WAS GONNA TAKE HER
TO HIS CABIN IN THE WILD,
BUT SHE GOT AWAY.
THERE'S NOT ONE LEAD
ON ANY OF THESE GIRLS,
EXCEPT HER.
WHEREVER SHE IS,
WE NEED TO FIND HER.
- HE'S ON.
YOU WANT ME TO COME?
- Jack: NO.
GO BACK THROUGH ALL THE OLDER
FILES AND SEE IF THERE ARE
ANY OTHER GIRLS THAT MATCH.
- Man: LET ME GUESS.
- GENTILE?
HALCOMBE.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
THE NIGHT'S STILL YOUNG.
DON'T THANK ME YET.
HERE, PUT THIS ON.
TAKE THIS SHIT OFF.
THERE, NOW YOU LOOK LIKE
AN EIGHTH-GRADE TEACHER
OUT LOOKING FOR A PERV.
I GOTTA WARN YOU.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA MAKE
MANY FRIENDS
FOR REOPENING UP
THIS CASE,
NOT DOWN HERE.
WORD TRAVELS FAST.
WHOEVER GAVE YOU
THAT FILE JUST FUCKED
HIS NEXT PROMOTION...
AND YOUR CAREER.
THEY CALL IT THE TRACK,
LIKE FOR HORSES.
THE HO-STRO--
WHERE THE HO'S STROLL.
EVERYONE KNOWS EVERYONE.
ALL THE PIMPS
KNOW ALL THE OTHER PIMPS,
WHO OWNS WHICH GIRLS,
WHICH GIRLS
ARE THE WILD ONES.
BLACK GIRLS ARE BOOSTERS,
WHITES ARE FLAT-BACKS.
GOOD MONEY-EARNING
BITCH CAN DO BOTH--
THEIR WORDS NOT MINE.
IT'S MOVE AND HUSTLE.
GIVE THE LEAST, GET THE MOST.
YOU KNOW, IT'S ALL
ABOUT THE PAPER.
LET'S DANCE.
I CHECKED AROUND.
BEFORE HERE,
CINDY WAS ARRESTED
UNDER P&L IN PORTLAND.
HAS PRIORS FOR PROSTITUTION
IN CALI, WASHINGTON,
OREGON AND DENVER.
SHE'S BEEN ON THE STREET
SINCE SHE WAS 11 YEARS OLD.
QUITE A TRACK STAR.
PIMP'S A CLAYTON JACKSON.
S.F.P.D. HAD HIM
FOR TRYING TO REARRANGE
HIS LAST GIRL'S FACE
WITH A TIRE IRON,
BUT HE GOT OFF.
REAL NICE PIECE
OF FUCKIN' WORK.
SOME OF THESE BARS ARE
PART OF A MOB CIRCUIT
RUN OUT OF SEATTLE.
THEY MOVE
THE GIRLS AROUND,
L.A., PORTLAND,
UP HERE,
HAWAII, FLORIDA.
SOMETIMES WITH NO NOTICE,
THEY'RE JUST GONE.
IT KEEPS THE TALENT FRESH.
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS GIRL?
HAVE YOU SEEN HER?
- HAVE YOU SEEN THIS GIRL?
- NAH, JUST STARTED.
HER NAME'S CINDY.
IF SHE'S STREET,
WE KEEP 'EM OUTTA HERE.
MIGHT'VE COME IN.
I DUNNO.
TRY THE SLEEPING LADY.
MAYBE SHE'S THERE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
HAVE YOU SEEN HER?
HER NAME'S PAULA.
SHE WAS A WALK-IN.
NOT ON THE CIRCUIT
OR NOTHIN'.
SAID HER NAME WAS ANGEL.
THEY ALL DO.
FIRST NIGHT
SHE WENT ALL THE WAY.
KEPT HER HEELS ON,
GOING FOR THE BIG MONEY.
THAT TAKES GUTS.
NOT MANY GIRLS DO THAT.
HEY LOOK, I KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
THEY'RE NOT WHORES REALLY.
JUST GIRLS.
- JANET.
- I GOTTA GO.
- BOSS SAYS BACK INSIDE.
- SHE'S DOIN' HIM A FAVOR.
FUCK OFF.
NOT ANY MORE.
OKAY, BIG BOY.
MOVE ON.
IF SHE'S HERE,
WE'LL FIND HER.
I'LL LOOK AROUND
A COUPLE MORE HOURS.
MRS. MOREHEAD?
SERGEANT HALCOMBE.
I WAS TOLD YOU
HAD SOME INFORMATION
ABOUT YOUR SISTER.
I DO.
LYLE ASKED ME FOR THESE
A LONG TIME AGO.
- THEY'RE SUSSIE'S
DENTAL RECORDS.
- OKAY.
SHE ONLY CAME UP
FOR TWO WEEKS, YOU KNOW?
THAT WAS 15 MONTHS AGO.
SHE LEFT
HER DAUGHTER LIZZIE
WITH OUR FOLKS.
SHE'S FOUR.
EVERY TIME THE PHONE RINGS
I THINK IT MIGHT BE HER.
OH...
WE WON THOSE
WHEN WE WERE KIDS.
IT'S A PAIR.
AND SUSSIE NEVER
TOOK HERS OFF.
MRS. MOREHEAD,
I KNOW HOW YOU FEEL.
I KNOW.
WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING
WE CAN TO FIND HER.
SERGEANT,
I KNOW IT'S SELFISH,
BUT I WANT YOU
TO REMEMBER HER
OVER THE OTHERS.
I JUST WANT TO FIND HER
AND LAY HER DOWN
SOMEWHERE NICE.
- I UNDERSTAND.
- YOU KEEP THAT.
{ answering machine
rewinds, beeps }
Woman:
Hi, Bob, the kids
just wanted to say good night.
Call us back
if it's not too late.
We're having a great time.
It's-- it's really
beautiful here
and Mom and Dad are
really enjoying the kids.
We'll be back in two days.
God bless.
Man on TV:
The crocodile returns,
covered in fresh red earth.
At first, her peculiar
behaviour is a puzzle.
Then her secret
is revealed.
There is no escape.
LYLE BACK?
ANYTHING FROM THE FBI?
YEAH, HE'S BEEN SEARCHING
COURT RECORDS AND NOTHING
FROM THEM YET.
SOMEBODY'S
LOOKING OUT FOR YOU.
SHE'S PRETTY SCARED.
WON'T SAY WHERE SHE'S
LIVING OR WORKING.
- WILL SHE TALK?
- I DON'T KNOW.
THAT'S UP TO YOU.
REMEMBER SHE'S A KID,
BUT DON'T GET FOOLED.
I'M SERGEANT HALCOMBE.
- HOW OLD'S YOUR DAUGHTER?
- SHE'S SIX.
IS THAT YOUR SISTER?
SHE'S DEAD, ISN'T SHE?
- SHALL I CALL YOU CINDY?
-
UH-HUH.
AND HOW OLD ARE YOU?
UM, I'M SEV.
I'M 18 NOW.
I WAS 17 AT THE TIME.
YOU'RE NOT 23?
WHY DON'T YOU JUST START
AT THE BEGINNING?
WHAT YOU TOLD
THE POLICE DOWNTOWN.
OKAY.  UM...
I WAS ON THE CORNER
OF 5th AND DENALI
AND HE RODE BY
AROUND 11:00,
AND HE OFFERED ME
$200 FOR A--
YOU KNOW, A BLOWJOB
AND I SAID FINE, NO PROBLEM.
UM...
HE BROUGHT ME
TO HIS PLACE.
HE SAID
HIS FAMILY WAS AWAY.
UM, AND HE--
HE TOOK ME DOWN...
TO-- HE CALLED IT HIS DEN.
IT WAS--
IT WAS MORE
OF A DUNGEON AND...
THANKS.
UM...
Man:
¶¶ My love
¶¶ How do I begin
¶¶ To tell you
what's been in ¶¶
¶¶ A heart that's
filled with love ¶¶
¶¶ From end to end
Woman:
¶¶ My love
- ¶¶ A world
you have to share... ¶¶
-
AH, DAMN IT.
NO NO NO,
DON'T STEP THERE.
SORRY.
- WHAT THE HELL'S THAT?
- I'M SORRY.
DISGUSTING!
- CLEAN IT UP.
-
I CAN'T REACH IT.
I CAN'T REACH.
YOU THINK YOU'RE READY?
YOU READY FOR SOME MORE FUN?
OH GOD,
PLEASE JUST LET ME GO.
YOU'RE THE--
YOU'RE THE BEST ONE
I EVER HAD.
PLEASE JUST LET ME GO.
I HAVE A LITTLE GIRL.
I WANNA SEE MY MOM.
I WANNA--
I WANNA GO DO IT
ON THAT BEARSKIN.
-
BOBBY?
HEY, BOB, YOU HERE?
- BOBBY?
- HEY!  NOW NOW NOW.
IF-IF HE HEARS YOU-YOU,
YOU GOTTA BELIEVE THERE
WILL BE A PROBLEM, RIGHT?
-
- THERE'S GONNA BE A PROBLEM
AND YOU'RE GONNA DIE.
- BOBBY?
- SHHH.
SHHH.
-
- DIDN'T HEAR YOU COME IN.
HOLY SHIT, MAN!
YOU JUST ABOUT SCARED
THE HELL OUT OF ME.
OH JESUS.
HEY, I BROUGHT YOU A PLATE.
I WAS JUST HAVING DINNER
AT THE TELEVISION.
I SEE.
WELL, YOU KNOW, JENNY,
- SHE SAYS WITH FRAN
BEING AWAY AND ALL...
- YEAH.
...THAT MAYBE WE SHOULD
BRING SOMETHING OVER.
OH THANKS.
I'M JUST HAVING
A QUIET NIGHT IN.
HEY, LOOK, YOU SURE
YOU WON'T COME JOIN US?
YEAH YEAH.  YOU AND JENNY
ARE TOO GOOD TO ME.
SHE'S A GOOD WOMAN.
BE CAREFUL WITH HER.
YEAH.  DON'T GO WORKING
TOO HARD NOW, OKAY?
YEAH.  THANK YOU.
WHEN HE--
WHEN HE RAPED ME,
I SAW IN HIS EYES...
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYONE'S EYES
GO BLACK LIKE THAT BEFORE.
I MEAN ANIMAL HEADS
EVERYWHERE.
I SAW THAT
AND I KNEW THIS GUY
LIKED TO KILL THINGS.
THAT'S WHEN I KNEW IT WOULDN'T
DO ME NO GOOD TO BEG.
LIKE MAYBE HE WAS
HALFWAY DECENT.
I JUST HAD TO NOT
BE SO SCARED.
TAKE ANY CHANCE
I COULD GET.
- HOW DID YOU GET AWAY?
- IN THE CAR.
I WAS--
I WAS LOOKING
OUT THE WINDOW
AND HE WAS FIXING THE SEAT
IN THE BACK OF THE PLANE.
THAT'S HOW I RAN.
AND HE DIDN'T WORE NO RUBBER
AND I WAS ON MY PERIOD
AT THE TIME,
AND I HAD A TAMPON
IN MY WOMB.
I KEPT IT IN ME
BECAUSE I THOUGHT
THAT IF THERE WAS ANY CHANCE
THAT I WAS GETTING OUT OF THERE,
I NEEDED EVIDENCE.
AND THAT WAS
THE FUCKING EVIDENCE--
HIS SEMEN.
AND I THOUGHT IF THERE WAS
ANY WAY THAT I WOULD--
WOULD ESCAPE,
THAT HE WASN'T GETTING
AWAY WITH IT.
BUT HE DID.
DO YOU THINK
HE'S DONE THIS BEFORE?
HE SAID THERE WERE
SEVEN GIRLS BEFORE ME...
AND THAT I WAS LUCKY BECAUSE
THEY USUALLY STAY FOR A WEEK.
IS THAT--
IS THAT ENOUGH?
I-I GOTTA GO.
-
HEY, BITCH, SLOW DOWN.
NEED SOME HELP, GIRL?
HEY HEY, WHERE YOU
RUNNING TO, GIRL?
- COME BACK HERE, GIRL.
COME BACK HERE.
- HEY, HANDSOME, FUCK OFF!
WHAT?  MY MONEY'S NO GOOD?
FUCK YOU, BITCH!
ARE YOU FUCKING CRAZY, HONEY?
YOU AIN'T GOT NO MAN?
LOOK.
HONEY, I DON'T KNOW YOUR STORY
AND I AIN'T GONNA ASK YOU,
BUT YOU GOTTA GET
THE FUCK OFF THE STREET.
MAYBE DANCE.
- YOU CAN DANCE, HUH?
- YEAH.
LISTEN, HONEY, I DON'T
WANT NOTHING FROM YOU,
BUT I'VE SEEN GIRLS
LIKE YOU BEFORE.
I'VE FUCKIN' BEEN
LIKE YOU, OKAY?  ONLY I WAS
TOO STUPID TO TAKE SOME HELP.
YOU'RE GONNA
TAKE SOME HELP.
LET'S GO.
IT'S COURVOISIER--
FRENCH COGNAC.
IT SOFTENS THE EDGES.
MY GRANDMA WAS
FROM FRANCE, I THINK.
- I'M LIKE PART IRISH-FRENCH.
- REALLY?
I'M BROOKLYN-TRAILER.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE ARE TWO CASES
DOWN THE KENAI IN '71.
HANSEN HAD A BOAT OVER
THE FOURTH OF JULY WEEKEND
IN SEWARD IN '73 AND '75.
I CROSS CHECK IT
EACH TIME A GIRL
DISAPPEARS.
HE GETS FIVE YEARS
FOR THEFT IN '76.
SUPREME COURT OVERTURNED IT,
HE GOT OUT IN 15 MONTHS.
OKAY.
KENAI, SEWARD,
'75 KIDNAPPING
IN PALMER HERE.
BEAR LADY
FOUND HERE IN 1980.
ANOTHER NEAR EKLUTNA.
SHERRY MORROW FOUND
ON THE KNIK HERE.
SINCE THEN 11 GIRLS
MATCHING THE PROFILE
HAVE GONE MISSING
FROM DOWNTOWN.
NOW, I'VE ONLY GONE THROUGH
HALF THE FILES, BUT THAT'S--
THAT'S 150-,
200-MILE RADIUS,
SO IF HE IS OUR GUY,
HE'S COVERING A FAIR
PART OF THE STATE.
WAIT, JUST SLOW DOWN HERE.
THESE ARE ALL OLD CASES.
YOU GOT ONE BODY AND IF YOU
WANNA START CONNECTING 'EM,
YOU NEED MORE
THAN A GUESS.
- AND WHO THE HELL
IS THIS BEAR LADY?
-  JOANNA--
JOANNA MESSINA.
SHE WAS A YOUNG,
UNEMPLOYED NURSE-- SHOT.
FOUND FROZEN AND BEING EATEN
BY A 500-LB BLACK BEAR.
- THE BOYS HAD TO SHOOT IT.
- AND THEY GOT THE GUY ON THAT.
NO.  PASSED A POLYGRAPH,
NO CONVICTION.
SHE MATCHES THE PROFILE,
SHE STAYS ON THE LIST.
WELL, I GOT A CALL
FROM THE BRASS AT A.P.D.
AND THEY ARE PISSED OFF.
THEY WANNA KNOW WHY
THE HELL WE'RE LOOKING AT CASES
THAT THEY ALREADY CLOSED.
IS SHE EVEN GONNA TESTIFY?
- I DON'T KNOW YET.
- WELL, CHRIST, JACK,
YOU BETTER FUCKING MAKE SURE.
AND STAY AWAY
FROM THE A.P.D.
IF THIS THING FALLS APART,
WE'LL ALL BE LOOKING AT JOBS
IN OIL COMPANIES.
SHIT.
THEY JUST FOUND ANOTHER BODY--
A MILE FROM THE LAST ONE.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
NO FINGERPRINTS LEFT.
FACIAL DILAPIDATION.
STILL SOME
LARVAE INFESTATION.
CONSIDERABLE
TRAUMA FROM ANIMALS.
YOU CAN SEE THE TEARS.
THE FLESH WAS TOUGH.
SAY SHE'S 20s, EARLY 30s.
JAW INTACT
SO MIGHT GET AN I.D.
IF YOU CAN GET ME DENTAL.
AND HOW DID SHE DIE?
FATAL GUNSHOT WOUND
TO THE STERNUM.
BULLET ENTERED FRONT AND PASSED
CLEAN THROUGH HER HEART,
EXITED RIGHT SHOULDER BLADE.
ALSO OTHER SHOTS TO LEG
AND TORSO-- ALL FROM BEHIND.
LACERATIONS TO SKULL,
DEEP STABS TO THE RIBS.
SHE PUT UP QUITE A FIGHT.
SHIRT AND BRA BOTH
CUT OPEN IN THE FRONT.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
EVER TRY TO SAW A BONE
WITH A FLAT BLADE?
I'D SAY SOMEONE TRIED
TO REMOVE HER HEAD.
HOW LONG WAS SHE OUT THERE?
MAYBE FOUR MONTHS,
AS FEW AS TWO.
SHE SPENT
THE SUMMER OUT THERE.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN ANYBODY
DO ANYTHING LIKE THIS BEFORE?
NO.
NEITHER HAVE I.
Girl:
WE WAITED UP.
MOMMY'S ASLEEP.
SHE SAID YOU DIDN'T CALL.
OH!
YEAH, I SHOULD'VE CALLED.
LET'S GO BACK TO BED.
DON'T EVER
GROW UP, HONEY, OKAY?
OKAY, SO LISTEN.
YOU DON'T CHEAT US,
AND WE WON'T CHEAT YOU.
OKAY?
WE'RE GONNA SPLIT
EVERYTHING 50-50.
THE FUCK, MAN?
I DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN DO THIS.
I MEAN TURNING A TRICK
ON THE STREET IS ONE THING,
BUT GETTING UP THERE
AND LETTING IT ALL HANG LOOSE
- IN FRONT OF
A FUCKING ROOM, I--
- YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
- YOU JUST NEED SOME HELP.
-
NOW LISTEN,
I REMEMBER THE FIRST TIME
I GOT UP ON STAGE, OKAY?
I WAS SO NERVOUS, I PEED
ALL OVER THIS COWBOY
IN THE FRONT ROW.
COME ON.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU NEVER MET
CRYSTAL BEFORE?
SHE'S GONNA BE
YOUR BEST FRIEND.
GO AHEAD.
-
READY?
YOU GET IT
NICE AND HOT.
- YOU GOT IT?
-
COME ON,
YOU GOTTA TRY AGAIN.
ONE MORE TIME.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S GOOD.
-
- YEAH.
- YEAH, YOU'RE BETTER.
YOU'RE GOOD NOW.
-
- TAKE THIS OFF.
- LOOK AT YOU.
- OH MY GOD!
YOU'RE FUCKING GORGEOUS.
LOOK AT YOU.  LOOK AT YOU!
OH FUCK.
- YOU NEED GOOD SHOES, OKAY?
- OH MY GOD, THESE SHOES.
- THOSE ARE GOOD SHOES.
- OH, I GOT SHOES.
- YOU GOOD?
- I'M GOOD.
YEAH?
YOU REMIND ME
OF MY MOM.
FUCK YOU!
REMIND YOU OF YOUR MOTHER!
- YOU DO.
- YOU'RE SO BEAUTIFUL.
YOU JUST GO OUT THERE,
YOU LISTEN TO THE MUSIC, OKAY?
THAT'S IT.
JUST LISTEN TO THE MUSIC.
- LISTEN TO THE MUSIC.
- YEAH, YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
YOU'RE GONNA DO
JUST FINE.
¶¶ I heard my mama cry
¶¶ She said,
"Boy, don't tell no lies" ¶¶
¶¶ She can't see
the evil in his eyes ¶¶
¶¶ Wild deed
ain't no big surprise ¶¶
¶¶ Well, I said to you
back in the day ¶¶
¶¶ When I had
hell to raise... ¶¶
-
-  ¶¶ Now it's high time
¶¶ Going in for the kill
¶¶ Now it's high time
¶¶ Going in for the kill...
FUCK!
- HEY, COME HERE.
- FUCK OFF!
- HEY, BITCH, COME HERE.
- THE FUCK YOU DOING HERE?
I CAME HERE TO GET YOU.
- MY FUCKING NECKLACE.
- LISTEN, MOTHERFUCKER.
THIS IS FOR MY BITCH
OUT THERE ON THE TRACK
GETTING REAL MONEY.
YOU IN HERE BULLSHITTING
IN THIS MOTHERFUCKING DUMP?
AIN'T NO MONEY IN HERE.
- LET ME SEE WHAT YOU GOT.
- IT'S MY SHIT!
WHY DO YOU
THINK I CAME BACK?
WHY YOU THINK I'M HERE?
I'M HERE FOR YOU.
WHY DO WE GOTTA
GO THROUGH THIS
EVERY TIME?
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
STRONGER THAN THIS.
I MEAN, YOU GOT YOUR THING
GOING ON AROUND HERE
AND I GOT MY THING.
CHECK IT OUT.
TAKE IT.
YOU NEED ME.
SOONER OR LATER
YOU GONNA SEE.
- YOU NEED ME.
-
TIME TO GO.
YOU DO EXACTLY AS I SAY,
- YOU WON'T GET HURT.
GET IN THE PLANE.
-
-  LOOK AT ME.
GET GOING.
- NO!
SHHH.
DON'T SAY ANYTHING!
GET IN THAT FUCKING PLANE.
DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR THIS SHIT.
HELLO?
YEAH YEAH, HEY, JERRY.
YES YES, I'M STILL
JOINING YOU, OF COURSE.
YOU'LL GET THEM TODAY.
BYE.
- HEY.
- YOU HEAR FROM CINDY?
GENTILE SAID
IT'S TOO EARLY.
YOU KNOW I NEVER
ASKED FOR THIS CASE.
WELL, I'M GLAD YOU'RE ON IT.
SO ARE THE GUYS TOO.
- WHAT'D YOU FIND?
- HANSEN'S ALIBI IS
STILL HOLDING OUT.
THERE'S NO CABIN IN HIS NAME.
APPARENTLY ALL HIS TROPHIES
AND FURS WERE STOLEN
A FEW YEARS BACK.
HE USED THE INSURANCE PAY-OUT
TO BUY A NEW PLANE.
SO I RAN THE CROSS-CHECK
AGAINST OUR SUBJECTS,
SEE WHO HAS A PILOT'S LICENSE.
THEY DENIED IT
FOR PSYCHIATRIC REASONS,
BUT THAT DIDN'T STOP HIM.
- HE'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO OWNS A PLANE.
- PSYCHIATRIC REASONS?
- WHEN'S SURVEILLANCE START?
- WITHOUT EVIDENCE IT'S STILL
NOT APPROVED,
- SO WE'RE ON OUR OWN.
SOME OF THE GUYS MIGHT HELP.
- GOOD.
I CALLED TO GET
CINDY'S EVIDENCE
FROM THE ANCHORAGE POLICE.
-
- THEY SAID THEY COULDN'T
FIND HER RAPE EXAM RESULTS.
AFTER THEY LET HER GO,
THEY NEVER BOTHERED TO GET IT
FROM THE HOSPITAL.
- IT'S STILL THERE.
- THIS FUCKER KIDNAPS,
RAPES AND TORTURES
A 17 YEAR-OLD GIRL,
NOT TO MENTION
HOW MANY OTHERS,
AND I'LL BET THESE GUYS
AND THE D.A. ALL BUT
BOUGHT HIM LUNCH
FOR THE INCONVENIENCE
OF ASKING HIM QUESTIONS
ABOUT IT.
MAKE IT OFFICIAL.
WE'RE REOPENING THE CASE.
METRO CAN THINK WHATEVER
THE FUCK THEY WANT.
THIS GUY DID IT AND THEY
LET HIM GET AWAY WITH IT.
-
OH GOD, PLEASE NO.
PLEASE NO NO.
- COME HERE.
- NO NO, PLEASE, NO.
- COME ON.
- NO NO NO!
- COME ON!
- NO NO.
- COME ON, GET UP!
-
COME ON.
ALMOST THERE.
PLEASE DON'T.
I WON'T TELL ANYBODY.
I PROMISE.
PLEASE.
OH GOD.
OH PLEASE.
YOU'RE A REALLY GOOD GIRL.
YOU'VE DONE EVERYTHING
I ASKED YOU TO DO.
-
- SHHH.
- WHY ARE YOU SCREAMING?
-
PLEASE PLEASE,
LET ME GO.
-
- PLEASE, LET ME GO!
HELP!  HELP!
HEEE-ELP!
NOBODY CAN HEAR YOU
OUT HERE.
PLEASE LET ME GO,
PLEASE.
I WON'T TELL ANYBODY.
I WON'T SAY
ANYTHING, PLEASE.
YOU'RE GONNA KILL ME,
AREN'T YOU?
HELP.
HELP!
PLEASE.
LET ME GO.
PLEASE, LET ME GO!
ARE YOU GONNA EAT THAT?
IT'S THEIR SPECIAL.
THE OTHER NIGHT YOU SAID
YOU SAW A HOLE IN THE POST.
WHY'D YOU SAY
A BULLET HOLE?
CINDY?
UM, BECAUSE
I SEEN ONE BEFORE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHEN?
SHIT, I DUNNO.
ONE CHRISTMAS WHEN I WAS
LIKE SIX YEARS OLD MY--
MY POP SHOT HIS GUN INSIDE
AND LEFT A HOLE RIGHT THERE
IN THE WALL.
IT LOOKED JUST THE SAME.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
A GLACIER?
OR, LIKE, YOU LOVE
ANIMALS OR ANYTHING?
Woman:
WATCH OUT!
I ALWAYS DREAMED
THAT ONE DAY
I WOULD EITHER BE A FIREMAN
OR WORK WITH ANIMALS.
IT'D BE SO COOL.
WHERE'S YOUR FAMILY?
WHY YOU WANT TO KNOW
THAT SHIT, HUH?
'CAUSE YOU'RE JUST LIKE
ALL THE OTHER SQUARES.
I GOT GUYS ASKING ME
ALL THE TIME WHAT HAPPENED,
WHERE MY FOLKS THINK I'M AT.
YOU WANNA FUCK ME?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
NO, CINDY, I DON'T.
YOU THINK-- YOU THINK
KNOWING MAKES US FRIENDS?
MAKES ME HELP YOU?
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR SISTER?
YEAH, SEE?  FUCK THAT.
I AIN'T A FRIEND.
I AIN'T NOTHING.
I JUST THOUGHT IF
YOU MIGHT WANNA GO HOME,
- MAYBE I COULD FIND A WAY--
- FUCK, MAN.
ARE YOU FUCKING FOR REAL?
WHAT THE FUCK DO YOU THINK
I'M GONNA DO THERE, HUH?
SAY "HERE'S MY NIGGER"?
"OH, YOU DIDN'T KNOW
I BEEN A HO SINCE LIKE
THE SIXTH GRADE?
SOME DUMB PIMP'S BITCH?"
THEY DIDN'T RAISE ME
FOR THAT SHIT.
YOU CAN'T ALWAYS
BE ON THE RUN.
YOU DON'T THINK
I WANNA BE HERE.
I CAN GO HOME
ANY TIME I WANT.
- MAYBE I DON'T WANT TO.
- DON'T YOU CARE?
YOUR PARENTS MIGHT
BE WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
YEAH.
YEAH, THEY'RE WORRIED.
LIKE THEY SHOULD HAVE
DONE THAT WHEN--
THOSE MOTHERFUCKERS.
I HAD SHIT HAPPEN TO ME
THAT AIN'T SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN
TO NO LITTLE KIDS,
AND THEY JUST LET IT.
THEY FUCKING LET IT.
THEY WANTED TO HIDE ME.
IT'S-- IT'S--
IT'S NOT RIGHT TO BE ASHAMED
OF YOUR BABY, IS IT?
TO LET BAD THINGS
HAPPEN TO IT?
I DIDN'T ASK
FOR ANY OF THAT SHIT.
AND YOU WANT ME
TO GO BACK TO IT?
I'M FUCKING OUTTA HERE.
I DON'T NEED YOUR SHIT NO MORE.
I'LL SEE YOU AROUND.
IT TOOK THEM TWO HOURS
TO CUT HER OUT OF THE CAR.
THE GUY WAS A DRUNK DRIVER.
IT WAS MY 21st BIRTHDAY.
SHE HAD KNITTED ME THIS...
AWFUL ORANGE SCARF
AND TOLD ME HOW PROUD SHE WAS
OF ME AND THEN RAN OUT.
I WANNA THINK
SANDY DIDN'T SEE IT
WHEN HE SMASHED INTO HER.
BUT ANYWAY, I WENT WITH HER
TO THE HOSPITAL.
I DON'T KNOW IF SHE
KNEW I WAS THERE--
JUST HOLDING
HER HAND.
I KEPT TELLING HER
SHE'D BE ALL RIGHT.
RIGHT UP UNTIL SHE DIED.
SHE WAS YOUR AGE.
CINDY?
¶¶ You turn the screw
¶¶ Make me do
all the things I want to ¶¶
¶¶ Why even try
¶¶ You know
I don't know... ¶¶
HEY THERE, HONEY.
YOU WANNA GIMME
SOME MONEY?
¶¶ You, you always
get your way ¶¶
¶¶ It's true,
all I want is to... ¶¶
Bouncer:
GET OVER THERE!
I GOT IT,
I GOT IT, I GOT IT.
- I GOT HER.  GET UP.
-
SIT DOWN.  WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
GET YOUR FUCKING SHIT TOGETHER!
WHAT THE FUCK?
STOP IT.
STOP!
HEY, LOOK.
WHAT THE FUCK
IS WRONG WITH YOU?
STOP IT!
HI, YOU-YOU-- YOU HAVE
A-A-- A GIRL CINDY?
UH...
JU-- UH, SHE-- GOOD--
GOOD GIRL, YEAH.
BRUNETTE.
JUST, UH...
I DON'T KNOW.
CIN-- CINDY.  JUST--
GOD DAMN IT, BOB!
Halcombe:
WE'RE WASTING TIME.
HE WON'T STOP.
- AND WE KNOW WHO HE IS.
- YEAH, BUT YOU CAN'T PROVE IT.
HE'LL BE KEEPING
MEMENTOES, TROPHIES.
METRO SAW ACE BANDAGES
IN HIS CAR,
A PISTOL-- THE SAME CALIBER
AS THE SHELLS AT THE GRAVES.
SHELLS DON'T KILL PEOPLE.
BULLETS AND PEOPLE DO.
YOU KNOW THAT.
NONE OF THIS HOLDS.
I NEED MORE, OR YOU'RE RIGHT,
I AM WASTING MY TIME.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH LONGER
SHE'LL BE SAFE OUT THERE.
BRING HER IN.
ARREST HER IF YOU HAVE TO.
PUT HER IN A SAFE HOUSE.
SHE WON'T HELP IF I DO THAT.
SHE'LL RUN AND I CAN'T MAKE HER.
WHAT ABOUT THE INSURANCE FRAUD?
IS THAT ENOUGH TO GET HIM
OFF THE STREET?
IF YOU BRING HIM IN,
HE'LL PROBABLY CALL HIS LAWYER
AND REFUSE TO COOPERATE.
YOU NEED MORE.
LOOK, I'M NOT GOING TO TELL YOU
HOW TO DO YOUR JOB, OKAY?
BUT I NEED SOMETHING
A LOT MORE SOLID
- BEFORE I'LL SUPPORT
A WARRANT.  THAT'S ALL.
-
YEAH?
SEND IT THROUGH.
SERGEANT?  IT'S FOR YOU.
OVER THERE.
HELLO.
NO!
DON'T LET HER LEAVE.
I DON'T CARE.
TELL THE AIRLINE TO DELAY
THE FLIGHT IF YOU HAVE TO,
- JUST DON'T LET HER LEAVE!
-
CINDY.
THOSE SEVEN GIRLS
HE TOLD YOU ABOUT--
I KNOW YOU THINK
ABOUT THEM.
YOU GOT AWAY
FOR A REASON.
THESE OTHERS...
WEREN'T SO LUCKY.
WITHOUT YOU, ALL I HAVE
IS CIRCUMSTANTIAL.
THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
I SEEN HER BEFORE...
IN PORTLAND.
SHE ALWAYS SMILED.
CINDY, I CAN'T MAKE
YOU STAY.
YOU CAN STILL
GET ON A PLANE,
BUT THE ONLY WAY
I'M GONNA STOP THIS
IS WITH YOU,
IF YOU'LL HELP ME.
NOW I KNOW YOU STOPPED
WHAT WAS HAPPENING TO YOU
WHEN YOU WERE GROWING UP
BY RUNNING.
THIS TIME YOU STOP IT
FOR THEM.
BUT YOU GOTTA STAY.
DID YOU CATCH THAT GUY?
THE ONE WHO KILLED
YOUR SISTER?
WELL, I WASN'T
AN OFFICER THEN.
THE JUDGE GAVE HIM SIX YEARS
FOR MURDERING A BEAUTIFUL GIRL.
HE WAS OUT IN TWO.
I KNOW WHERE HE LIVES,
I KNOW WHAT HE DOES.
NOT A DAY GOES BY,
I DON'T THINK ABOUT HER...
OR HIM.
YEAH, BUT HE GOT AWAY.
LOOK, CINDY, HANSEN WON'T.
YOU GOTTA TRUST ME.
I PROMISE, OKAY?
I PROMISE, NOTHING'S GOING
TO HAPPEN TO YOU.
Boy:
FOR WHAT WE ARE
ABOUT TO RECEIVE,
MAY THE LORD MAKE US
TRULY GRATEFUL.  AMEN.
AMEN.
PA WANTED TO KNOW
WHEN WE COULD TAKE
THE KIDS BACK DOWN AGAIN.
THEY WERE THINKING
MAYBE THANKSGIVING?
THANKSGIVING WE HAVE
THE STAFF DINNER,
REMEMBER?
I JUST THOUGHT, UM...
YOU KNOW,
- DEBBIE WAS GONNA
BRING HER BABY DOWN AGAIN--
-
- I'M SORRY.
HELLO?  YOU BET.
- I'VE GOTTA GO OUT.
GO TO WORK.
- OKAY.
THANKSGIVING HERE!
Halcombe's wife:
AND YOU DIDN'T ASK ME
IF IT WOULD BE ALL RIGHT?
Halcombe:
I DIDN'T THINK
IT COULD BE WRONG.
- SHE'LL BE
LEAVING IN THE MORNING.
- SHE'S NOT YOUR PROBLEM!
WHAT ABOUT YOUR OWN DAUGHTER?
BECAUSE THIS IS OUR HOME
-  AND SHE SHOULDN'T BE HERE.
- I HAD NO CHOICE.
WHERE ELSE
IS SHE SUPPOSED TO GO?
IT'S ONLY ONE NIGHT.
JACK, YOU ALWAYS
HAVE A CHOICE, OKAY?
SHE'S NOT YOUR PROBLEM.
- SHE'S NOT YOUR RESPONSIBILITY.
- I DON'T THINK THAT'S FAIR,
ALLIE.
AND I'M TAKING THAT OTHER JOB
TO GET US AWAY FROM ALL THIS.
OH RIGHT!
WHAT'S GOING ON WITH THAT?
JERRY CALLED.
HE TOLD ME YOU STILL
HAVEN'T SIGNED THOSE PAPERS.
I QUIT MY JOB!
OKAY?
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF THIS MESS,
LEAVING OUR HOME.
THIS IS NOT A HALFWAY HOUSE.
COME ON, ALLIE,
THAT'S NOT RIGHT.
IF SHE WAS OUR KID,
YOU'D BE RAISING FIRES
ALL OVER TOWN.
NO NO, SHE'S NOT.
SHE'S NOT OUR KID!
WELL, SHE'S SOMEONE'S.
AND NO ONE CARES
AND THIS GUY KNOWS IT.
- AND IF THAT DOESN'T CHANGE,
WHAT HOPE HAVE THEY GOT?
- I CARE, JACK.
- I CARE ABOUT OUR FAMILY.
- PLEASE, JUST QUIET.
AND DON'T YOU DARE MAKE ME
WRONG BECAUSE OF IT!
- ALLIE, I'M NOT
MAKING YOU WRONG.
- I'M SORRY-- NO NO.
YOU HAVE TO GET HER OUT!
-
- SHIT!
- CINDY!
-
CINDY!
HEY, IS CLATE HERE?
I'M-- I'M FELISHA.
HE TOLD ME TO COME BY.
YEAH.
SO YOU DECIDED
TO COME BACK
TO YOUR MAN, HUH?
- CLATE, I-- I JUST--
- I AIN'T GOT TIME
FOR THIS SHIT.
GET YOUR ASS BACK TO WORK.
LET'S GO.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO
BE ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE STREET.
THE BOUNCER UP THERE
SAID SHE CAME THIS WAY.
HAVE YOU SEEN HER?
SHE'S 5'2", NOT VERY TALL.
SHE WAS GUESTING OVER
AT KITTY'S FOR CHELLE.
- ALL RIGHT.  THANK YOU.
- THANK YOU.
HEY.
HOW YOU DOING?
MAYBE I'M NOT
MAKING MYSELF CLEAR.
I SAID DO YOU
KNOW THIS GIRL?
- SHOULD I?
- DON'T FUCK WITH ME.
YOU GAVE HER A JOB.
YOU TELL ME WHERE SHE IS!
YOU BACK UP!
BACK UP NOW!
WELL, FUCK YOU.
I DON'T WORK HERE.
A LOT OF GIRLS,
THEY COME THROUGH HERE.
THEY'RE CALLED CINDY
OR TAMMY OR SOME SHIT.
- FUCKING HOS WITHOUT A CLUE.
- OH REALLY?
WELL, THIS ONE DOES HAVE
A CLUE AND COME TOMORROW
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
KNOW WHAT TO CALL 'EM,
'CAUSE I'M GETTING THIS
WHOLE SHITHOLE SHUT DOWN!
ALL RIGHT?
SO START PACKING!
LOU!
YOU MOTHERFUCKER!
YOU KNOW, YOU OUGHTA
TRANSFER DOWN HERE.
WHERE WOULD SHE GO?
ANYWHERE
IF SHE NEEDED MONEY.
HAVE YOU SEEN
THIS GIRL?
- DO YOU KNOW HER?
- HUH-UH.
¶¶ So welcome
to the long trails ¶¶
¶¶ Then among the costs
¶¶ The broken and the lost
¶¶ There was
a brand-new... ¶¶
FUCK.
HAVE YOU SEEN HER?
WHO THE FUCK ARE YOU?
YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED
BACK HERE!
CINDY!  CINDY!
- WHAT IS SHE ON?
WHAT'D YOU GIVE TO HER?
- SHE'S NOT MY TYPE.
I'LL GIVE YOU TWO
SOME PRIVACY.
- IT'S OKAY.  IT'S OKAY.
-
YOU'RE SAFE NOW.
IT'S OKAY.
IS SHE YOUR MOM?
YEAH.
SHE WAS 15 WHEN
SHE HAD ME SO THEY--
THEY TOLD ME
SHE WAS MY SISTER.
IT'S LESLIE'S HOUSE.
HER UNCLE
DID STUFF TO ME
FOR... YEARS.
REALLY BAD STUFF.
WHY DIDN'T...?
DID YOU KNOW
YOUR FATHER?
I USED TO PRETEND
THAT HE WAS IN THE NAVY.
THAT'S WHY
HE COULDN'T COME SEE ME.
IT'S SO LAME.
- YOU KNOW, I DIDN'T MEAN
TO CAUSE YOU NO TROUBLE.
- THAT'S OKAY.
TRY AND GET SOME REST.
YOU KNOW,
ALL MY LIFE SINCE--
SINCE I WAS
REAL YOUNG I JUST--
I REALLY WANTED A CHANCE
TO BELIEVE SOMEONE.
YOU KNOW, LIKE WHEN
THEY SAY THAT
EVERYTHING IS GONNA BE OKAY,
THAT THEY WERE ACTUALLY
TELLING THE TRUTH.
THAT'S OKAY TO ASK,
ISN'T IT?
YEAH.
IT SURE IS.
¶¶ Evil's darkness
stalks my side ¶¶
¶¶ I can't find it
any other way... ¶¶
SO, MAN, LONG TIME
NO FUCKING SEE.
YEAH.
YOU MUST REALLY WANT
THAT PIECE OF PUSSY BAD,
YOU COME FIND ME.
WHO IS SHE?
I'LL FIND HER.
COST YA 10.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN IT'S DONE.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
OOOH!
WHAT THE FUCK, MAN?
IT'S COLD OUT HERE, MAN.
LET'S GET IN WITH
THE BITCHES.
WHAT THE FUCK, MAN?
- WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO
WITH YOU, BOY?  HUH?
- COME ON, MAN.
WE HAD A DEAL.
YOU OWE SOME FRIENDS
OF MINE A LOT OF MONEY.
- I'M GONNA GET IT
FOR 'EM, I SWEAR!
- THAT'S NOT WHAT I HEAR.
-  I HEAR YOU SPEAK SHIT
ABOUT THEM.
- NO!
YOU WANNA MAKE THIS GO AWAY?
WHERE'S THAT
SWEET LITTLE BITCH
I SAW YOU WITH?
YOU FUCKING FIND HER
AND BRING HER TO ME
AND WE'RE EVEN, OKAY?
I'LL GET HER FOR 'EM.
I'LL DO WHATEVER YOU NEED!
YOU GOT TWO DAYS
TO HAND HER TO ME.
THAT'S IT.
NOW GET THE FUCK
OUTTA HERE.
WAKE ME
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS.
BUTTON UP THE COAT.
HEY!
HEY, JACK, HEADS UP.
Bob:
HEY, PAL, COME WITH ME.
YEAH, THERE'S NO WAY IN HELL
HE'S GOING UP IN THIS.
TELL THE CONTROL TOWER
TO STALL HIM IF HE TRIES
TO TAKE OFF.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT FUCKING
SON OF A BITCH IS CRAZY.
TOWER SAYS HE'S HEADED
NORTHEAST PAST KNIK,
- BUT HELL,
HE COULD BE GOING ANYWHERE.
- HE'S GONNA DUMP IT ALL.
FUCK!
- BANG BANG, RIGHT, DAD?
- YEAH, THAT'S WHAT WE DO.
HEY, NOW LISTEN,
YOU KEEP AN EYE
ON THE PLANE.
YOU DON'T WANT PEOPLE
COMING OUT HERE AND STEALING
ALL OUR GEAR, DO YOU?
Halcombe over radio:
Any news?
YEAH, HE LANDED AN HOUR AGO.
WENT STRAIGHT HOME.
You might want
to get back here.
Yeah, it just came through.
You know, that profile thing?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
BELIEVE THIS.
- Clives: WELL,
AFTERNOON, GENTLEMEN.
- Halcombe: AFTERNOON.
YOU KNOW FRANK ROTHSCHILD.
I ASKED HIM TO JOIN US.
- I HOPE YOU'VE
GOT SOMETHING NEW.
- LEGAL AFFIDAVIT
AND SEARCH WARRANT REQUEST
THAT COVERS HANSEN'S HISTORY,
LISTS ITEMS WE EXPECT
TO FIND IN HIS HOME, HIS WORK,
HIS VEHICLES,
INCLUDING HIS PLANE.
FROM THE FBI'S NEW
PROFILING TEAM.
THEY SAY WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A WHITE MALE, EARLY 40s,
AVERAGE HEIGHT,
RESPECTED MEMBER
OF THE COMMUNITY,
WIFE PROBABLY
VERY RELIGIOUS
AND NOT TOTALLY AWARE
OF WHAT HE'S UP TO,
HISTORY OF THEFT,
SEXUAL ASSAULT,
PROBABLY STUTTERS.
ALSO EXPERT OUTDOORSMAN
AND AVID HUNTER.
THAT'S HANSEN.
THIS IS ALL
SECONDHAND INFORMATION.
I NEED PHYSICAL EVIDENCE.
THESE GUYS AREN'T
EVEN PROVEN YET.
HELL, THE FBI CAN'T WORK
OUT IF THEY'RE FOR REAL.
I HAVE TESTIMONY
FROM ANOTHER VICTIM
WHO ESCAPED IN '79,
AND A WITNESS WHO HAS SEEN
HANSEN'S STOLEN TROPHY HEADS
BACK IN HIS DEN.
WE HAVE CINDY PAULSON
AND EVERYTHING I HAD
LAST TIME STILL CHECKS OUT.
- WHO WROTE THIS?
- PAT DOOGAN, ASSISTANT
DISTRICT ATTORNEY FAIRBANKS.
HE FLEW DOWN YESTERDAY,
WORKED THROUGH THE NIGHT.
- YOU BEHIND THIS, BOB?
- AND THE COLONEL.
SO YOU STILL WANT TO SEARCH
FOR INSURANCE FRAUD,
USE THAT WARRANT
TO GET HIM ON MURDER?
THAT WASHES OUT,
GETS THROWN OUT
OF COURT, THEN WHAT?
EVERY WAY WE TURN
IT ALL LEADS BACK TO HANSEN.
NOW I'M NOT GONNA TELL YOU
HOW TO DO YOUR JOB,
BUT IF YOU DON'T START
DOING SOMETHING,
YOU'LL BE THE ONE HELD
RESPONSIBLE FOR THESE,
AND ANY OTHER GIRLS
WHO ARE KILLED.
NOW IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I SHOULD PROBABLY CHECK
ON MISS PAULSON.
SERGEANT.
WE'LL LOOK THESE OVER,
GET BACK TO YOU IN A FEW DAYS.
YOU KNOW...
HE STALKS THEM LIKE
HIS NEXT TROPHY ANIMAL,
HE RAPES THEM
AND HE KILLS THEM.
HE IS PROBABLY
DOING IT RIGHT NOW.
WE DON'T HAVE A FEW DAYS!
I WANT A WARRANT.
NOW!
IF HE'S WRONG,
IF THIS GUY GETS OFF...
WE'LL NEVER
GET HIM IN AGAIN.
THEN UNLIKE IN THE PAST,
WE ALL BETTER MAKE SURE
THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN.
Man:
HEY, BOB?  YOU HAVE A MINUTE?
I WAS HOPING YOU COULD
HELP US DOWN AT THE STATION.
IN 1971, THERE WAS
AN INCIDENT
INVOLVING A MISS ALLEN
OVER IN SPENARD.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT HAPPENED THERE, BOB?
WELL, UM,
THAT, UM-- I DON'T
KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
I GUESS YOU COULD JUST...
CALL THAT AN URGE.
AND IS THAT TO DO
WITH WHAT DR. McMANNUS
SAID AT YOUR SENTENCING?
- I CAN'T REMEMBER--
- SCHIZOPHRENIC OR MANIC-
DEPRESSIVE PROBLEMS.
A MENTAL STATE YOU WOULD
SOMETIMES GO INTO
AND THINGS WOULD JUST...
HAPPEN,
BUT THEN
YOU WOULDN'T REMEMBER.
WAS HE OFF-BASE ON THAT?
IS THAT BOTHERING YOU, BOB?
HEY, LISTEN, WHATEVER
THE PROBLEM IS HERE,
I WANT TO HELP
YOU GENTLEMEN CLEAR IT UP.
YOU KNOW,
BUT BY THE SAME TOKEN,
UH, MY LAWYER ALWAYS TOLD ME
NEVER TO-- YOU KNOW.
BUT I CAN
HELP YOU CLEAR IT UP.
WHAT'S YOUR QUESTION?
- THERE WAS A SECOND INCIDENT...
- MM-HMM.
...IN DECEMBER OF '71.
- YOU WERE ARRESTED
FOR THAT ALSO?
- YEAH YEAH.
-  HER NAME WAS BOWDEN.
- THAT SITUATION,
THERE IS YOUR BASIC,
YOU KNOW,
MONEY FOR SEX...
PROP-PROPOSITION.
I SAID,
"LOOK HEY, YOU KNOW, THIS--
WE AGREED ON A PRICE,
AND GOD DAMN IT,
THAT'S THE WAY
IT'S GONNA BE."
AND SHE JUST KEPT
ARGUING WITH ME--
MORE AND MORE MONEY,
MORE AND MORE MONEY.
AND THEN, YOU KNOW,
I JUST DROPPED HER OFF
IN ANCHORAGE.
SHE SAYS YOU BOUND HER
WITH A SNARE TRAP AND PUT
A GUN TO HER HEAD.
- NO.
- AND YOU STARTED GOING
DOWN TOWARDS THE KENAI
- TO THE SUNSET LODGE
AND RENTED A CABIN.
- THAT PART'S TRUE.
AND SHE SAYS YOU RAPED HER.
AND YOU WROTE HER MOTHER AND
FATHER'S NAME AND ADDRESS
AND HER SON'S NAME DOWN
AND SAID IF SHE TOLD ANYONE,
YOU'D HARM 'EM.
WELL, I DO REMEMBER
HER NAME BEING WRITTEN DOWN
ON A PIECE OF PAPER
THAT SHE GAVE ME
TO CONTACT HER,
BUT I DON'T REMEMBER--
-
- Trooper: SERGEANT.
Lyle:
IT'LL TAKE LONGER
THAN WE THOUGHT.
EVERY WALL
IS A HIDDEN CLOSET
CRAMMED WITH STUFF.
OKAY.  AS SOON
AS YOU GET ANYTHING.
- OKAY, I'M ON IT.
- PLEASE.
SHE WORKED
AT THE EMBERS BAR, 1979.
OH OH, YEAH YEAH, OKAY.
YEAH, I REMEMBER HER.
THAT WAS, UH,
PRIMARILY THE SAME THING.
HAVEN'T YOU LEARNED BY NOW,
BOB, THAT THESE GIRLS
AREN'T JUST GONNA
PLAY IT COOL WITH YOU?
I MEAN,
YOU KNOW THAT THEY KNOW
THAT THEY HAVE
A COMMODITY THAT YOU WANT--
AND WITH A NICE WIFE
AT HOME.
- IS THERE A PROBLEM THERE?
- NO.
AT HOME THERE'S
NO PROBLEM AT ALL.
I-- I MENTIONED TO YOU-YOU
BOTH THAT, UH...
BOTH OF THESE TIMES, UH...
I WANTED ORAL SEX.
BUT THAT'S NOT SOMETHING
THAT I WOULD WANT-- WANT
MY WIFE TO PERFORM, OKAY?
YOU KNOW,
NOT SOMEBODY THAT
I LOVE AND RESPECT AND--
AND CHERISH AND--
WE'VE GOT
ALL THE BANK STATEMENTS,
OTHER DOCUMENTS,
NOTHING THAT HAS ANYTHING
TO DO WITH ANY GIRLS.
- I'm heading to the plane.
- Okay, good.
ALL RIGHT.
THE PROSTITUTES ARE UPSET,
YOU'RE UPSET.
- YEAH.
- THINGS CAN HAPPEN
IN THAT SPECIFIC ARRANGEMENT.
BUT LET'S GO BACK
TO MISS ALLEN FOR A MOMENT--
THE YOUNG LADY
OVER IN SPENARD.
SHE WORKED
FOR A REAL-ESTATE COMPANY.
YEAH. WELL, THE FIRST TIME
I'D SEEN HER SHE WAS DOWNTOWN,
AND I HAD AN ATTRACTION
TO HER RIGHT AWAY.
SO, YOU KNOW,
I FOLLOWED HER HOME
AND, UM, SHE JUST SEEMED
LIKE A REALLY NEAT PERSON.
WHAT HAPPENED THE SECOND TIME
YOU WENT OVER?
- YOU HAD A GUN.
- YEAH WELL...
I HADN'T INTENDED TO RAPE HER
OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
YEAH NO.
IT'S THE SAME.
THERE'S STOLEN STUFF
EVERYWHERE.
- YEAH, WE GOT GUYS
OUT AT THE CAMPER TOO.
-  I need more
OR HE'S GONNA WALK.
I SAID TO MYSELF,
"YOU KNOW-- YOU KNOW, BOB,
YOU GOTTA HAVE SOME
PRIORITIES IN YOUR LIFE."
WHEN I'VE DONE THIS NOW,
I'VE DONE IT TO MY FAMILY TOO.
AND I PUT MY WIFE THROUGH
AN AWFUL LOT OF GRIEF
AND I DON'T WANT
TO DO THAT ANYMORE, OKAY?
YOU TOOK SOME
OF THESE GIRLS OUT OR YOU
PICKED 'EM UP FOR SEX?
- I'M NOT DENYING THAT.
- YEAH, BUT I'M TALKING
ABOUT CASE AFTER CASE
OVER A PERIOD OF 12 YEARS.
AND ALL THESE GIRLS' CASES ARE
SAYING THE EXACT SAME THING:
"I WAS BOUND.
I WAS THREATENED."
A GUN OR KNIFE
WAS INVOLVED.
AND YOU'RE TELLING ME
THAT EVERYBODY'S MAKING UP
THE SAME STORY?
I'M SHOWING YOU
A PATTERN, BOB,
AND YOU'RE LYING TO ME.
WELL, IT JUST SEEMS LIKE
YOU'VE GONE TO THIS
UNTOLD AMOUNT OF TROUBLE.
YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE BRINGING UP
THINGS FROM MY PAST,
I WOULD BE AS HARD PRESSED
TO REMEMBER
BACK WHEN I WAS BORN
IN IOWA.
A .223 SHELL CASING
WAS FOUND AT HER GRAVESITE.
SHE WAS SHOT AND KILLED.
YOU'RE TELLING ME
I SHOT THIS PERSON?
BULLSHIT!
I DID NOT SHOOT ANYBODY
AND I WOULD NOT
HURT ANYBODY.
- AND THAT'S THE TRUTH.
- HANSEN'S WIFE DOESN'T
KNOW ANYTHING.
IT'S LIKE THEY LIVE
IN TWO SEPARATE WORLDS.
WE FOUND HIS STOLEN MOUNTS
RIGHT ON THE DAMNED WALL.
THE .223,
THE ARROWHEAD NECKLACE?
ANYTHING THAT LINKS HIM
DIRECTLY TO ONE
OF THE GIRLS?
- HOW'S IT GOING WITH HIM?
- HE STILL DOESN'T WANT
A LAWYER,
BUT HE'S GIVING US
EVERYTHING WE ALREADY KNOW.
THE REST IS BABBLE.
LOOK, I NEED THE .223
OR SOMETHING!
WHO IS THAT?
THAT'S SHERRY MORROW.
SHE WAS FOUND ON THE KNIK
WITH AN ACE BANDAGE
WRAPPED AROUND HER FACE
AND HER ARMS.
OR WHAT WAS LEFT OF THEM.
THERE WAS ALSO
A .223 SHELL CASING
FOUND AT HER GRAVESITE.
IDENTICAL EXTRACTOR MARKINGS
TO THE SHELL
- WE FOUND AT PAULA'S GRAVE.
- YOU THINK THAT CAME
OUT OF MY GUN?
- BULLSHIT IT DID!
- WHY ARE YOU TELLING US
THAT EVERYBODY'S WRONG?
- BECAUSE IN THIS CASE THEY ARE.
- YOU SAID THE PSYCHIATRISTS
WERE WRONG,
BUT ADMITTED YOU LIED TO THEM
AND TOLD US YOU DON'T REALLY
HAVE A PROBLEM.
YOU'RE NOT HEARING VOICES,
YOU'RE NOT SEEING THINGS.
AND IF THAT'S TRUE...
THEN THERE'S
A FAR WORSE PROBLEM,
AND IT CANNOT CONTINUE.
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
IT CAN'T BECAUSE IT
NEVER STARTED.
I DIDN'T SHOOT ANYBODY.
YEAH, WE'VE GOT
17 WEAPONS SO FAR.
AL'S RUNNING NUMBERS NOW,
BUT NONE OF 'EM ARE A .223.
WELL YEAH, IT'S ALL
AS CINDY SAID,
BUT THERE'S NO PRINTS,
FIBERS, ANYTHING.
YEAH WELL, WE'RE RUNNING
OUT OF PLACES TO LOOK.
PROBABLE INSURANCE FRAUD.
NO, NOTHING ON ANY GIRLS.
MOST OF US DON'T
HAVE MUCH RESPECT
FOR A PROSTITUTE.
THEY'RE BENEATH US,
AREN'T THEY?
- I THINK SO.
- WHY ARE THEY BENEATH US, BOB?
WELL, IT'S OBVIOUS.
DIDN'T YOU FIND,
GROWING UP, THAT GIRLS HAD
A CERTAIN POWER OVER YOU?
THEY KNOW WHAT BOYS
WANT AND THEY CAN DICTATE
WHEN THEY CAN HAVE IT.
ISN'T IT NICE
WHEN WE GET OLDER
AND WE CAN TURN THE TABLES,
DOMINATE, TAKE THE LEAD?
ISN'T IT?
DETERMINE WHEN YOU TOUCH
THEM OR WHATEVER?
- WHEN YOU PAY FOR IT.
- RIGHT.
AND THEY WON'T REJECT YOU.
YOU'RE PAYING FOR IT,
THEY'LL DO WHAT YOU TELL THEM.
THEN YOU PULL OUT THE GUN
AND YOU'RE REALLY
IN CONTROL.
THEN THEY'RE DEAD.
NOW YOU SAY YOU
DIDN'T RAPE THEM, YOU SAY
YOU DIDN'T SHOOT THEM,
BUT TURN IT AROUND, BOB.
IF YOU'D READ THOSE REPORTS--
TURN IT AROUND,
PRETEND YOU'RE US--
WOULD YOU THINK
THOSE GIRLS LIED?
- I BELIEVE THEM.
- WELL, DO YOU WANT
TO CONVICT ME ON THAT?!
I WANNA FIND OUT
WHO I'M TALKING TO.
I WANT TO SEE
IF YOU HAVE THE GUTS
TO BE HONEST WITH ME!
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK THAT THIS IS
SERIOUS AS HELL,
AND I THINK THAT I'D LIKE
TO TALK TO MY ATTORNEY.
IF YOU WANNA TALK ABOUT
ALL THIS BACK-PASSING STUFF--
AND ABOUT THAT?
I DIDN'T DO THAT!
YOU THINK YOU GOT AWAY
WITH WHAT YOU DID TO CINDY.
I KNOW WHAT YOU DO
TO THOSE GIRLS.
- AND I'M GONNA PROVE IT.
- THAT'S GONNA BE HARD,
SERGEANT.
- I HEARD YOU WERE LEAVING.
- I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE YET.
ROBERT HANSEN,
I'M ARRESTING YOU
FOR THE KIDNAP AND RAPE
OF CINDY PAULSON.
READ HIM THE REST
AND GET HIM OVER
TO THE COURTHOUSE.
ROBERT CHRISTIAN HANSEN...
FUCKING SON OF A BITCH!
IS THERE ANYTHING FROM HER?
- THE TRUCK, THE PLANE?
- MAYBE HE DID DUMP IT ALL
ALREADY.
CAN YOU GUYS GIVE ME
A MINUTE?
-
Halcombe:
GENTLEMEN, I KNOW
YOU'VE BEEN AT THIS ALL DAY,
BUT WE STILL HAVEN'T
FOUND WHAT WE NEED.
AND IF WE DON'T
BEFORE WE LEAVE,
WE'LL NEVER GET
ANOTHER CHANCE.
SO WE'RE GONNA START AGAIN.
FROM TOP TO BOTTOM,
EVERY DAMN INCH.
IF IT MEANS WE STAY ALL NIGHT,
DIG UP THE ENTIRE PROPERTY,
WELL, THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE GONNA DO!
CALL IT TROOPER'S INTUITION.
I KNOW IT'S HERE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU HEARD HIM.
LET'S GET TO IT.
HI.
- YOU OKAY?
-
WE ARRESTED HIM.
THE JUDGE SAID NO TO BAIL.
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
SAID YOU WANNA PUT ME
IN SOME SAFE HOUSE.
- I DON'T WANT TO.
- YOU HAVE TO, CINDY.
IT'S FOR THE BEST.
WELL, AM I GONNA
HAVE TO TESTIFY?
'CAUSE I DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN FACE HIM AGAIN.
HIS LAWYER
IS GOING TO WANT
TO INTERVIEW YOU.
AND THEY'RE GONNA TRY
TO MAKE YOU LOOK BAD,
LIKE--
I JUST WANT YOU
TO BE READY, OKAY?
I NEED TO GET MY STUFF.
I'VE GOTTA GO.
- I SAID I NEED
TO GET MY STUFF!
- YEAH.
I'LL COME BY TOMORROW
AND WE CAN GO GET IT.
ANYTHING YOU WANT, OKAY?
Lieutenant:
HEY, JACK, OVER HERE!
WE FOUND A TRAP DOOR.
YOU MAY WANNA SEE THIS.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
HE DIDN'T DUMP IT ALL.
THAT'S A MINI-14
AND A THOMPSON CONTENDER.
BOTH .223s.
WE FOUND THE GUNS!
IS CINDY OKAY?
I GOT HER A NEW TOOTHBRUSH
AND SOME SOAP
AND SOME THINGS.
WE FOUND THE GUN.
HE DIDN'T CONFESS.
JUST BECAUSE THE SYSTEM
ISN'T PERFECT,
IT DOESN'T MEAN YOU QUIT
TRYING TO MAKE IT BETTER.
I THOUGHT A CHANGE
IS WHAT WE NEEDED.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I LOVE THIS OLD PLACE.
I'M JUST GONNA
GO GET MY JOB BACK.
YOU'VE GOTTA DO
WHAT'S RIGHT FOR YOU.
AND HELPING THIS GIRL...
THIS IS WHO YOU ARE.
YOU CAN'T LET THIS GUY
GET AWAY WITH IT.
I DON'T INTEND TO.
Man:
YOU'LL DO SOMETHING
MINOR ON THE FRAUD.
BUT WHAT ABOUT THIS GIRL,
THIS CINDY?
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
THAT WAS A MISTAKE?
'CAUSE IF SHE TESTIFIES,
IT COULD BE TROUBLE.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
WELL, I'M SAYING
A KIDNAP AND RAPE CHARGE,
THAT COULD BE 99 YEARS
RIGHT THERE.
AND THESE TYPES OF TRIALS
CAN BE A MESS...
FOR YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
I'LL BE BACK
IN THE MORNING, BOB.
YOU'RE CINDY, RIGHT?
'CAUSE SOME GUY CAME IN,
DESCRIBED YOU AND ASKED
IF CINDY WAS IN TOWN.
SAID HE WAS
A FRIEND OF BOB'S?
I TOLD HIM
YOU'D BE BACK SOON.
WHO'S BEEN IN TO SEE HIM?
Man:
Just his lawyer and wife.
His brother picked up
a letter to his kids.
- There was nothing in it.
- HANSEN DOESN'T HAVE
A BROTHER.
HAS ANYBODY
CHECKED ON CINDY?
THERE'S AN OFFICER
OVER THERE.  WHY?
I NEED TO SPEAK
TO SERGEANT HALCOMBE.
OH, COME ON, PICK UP!
FUCK NO.  PLEASE, COME ON!
- WELL, WHERE-- WHERE IS HE?
-
- JUST CONNECT HIM, PLEASE?
- Clate: FUCK, BITCH, COME ON!
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
FOR YA ALL NIGHT!
GET IN THE FUCKING CAR!
LOOK, I ONLY TOLD THE COPS
MY NAME WAS CINDY.
THEN I USED FELISHA, OKAY?
IT'S HIM.  I KNOW IT.
LOOK, MAN, WE'RE GETTING
OUT OF THIS MOTHERFUCKING
STATE TONIGHT!
NEVER COMING BACK.
-
- Clate: HELLO.
- Thug: You got her?
- YEAH.
IT'S NOW.
REMEMBER,
YOU DO WHAT
I TOLD YOU, WE'RE EVEN.
Cindy:
WHY ARE YOU
TURNING HERE?
WHERE THE FUCK
ARE YOU TAKING ME?
CLATE, I ASKED
YOU A QUESTION.
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
CINDY?
WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
YOU JUST LET HER LEAVE?
GET OUT.
C'MON, GET OUT.
GET OUTTA THE
MOTHERFUCKING CAR!
- Cindy: WHAT'S GOING ON?
- CALM YOUR ASS DOWN.
CLATE, WHAT THE FUCK
IS GOING ON?
JUST RELAX.
THIS WILL BE OVER SOON.
GET THE FUCK
OUTTA HERE.
- WE'RE EVEN.
-
- NO.  NO!
- WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING, HUH?
-
- CLATE, WHY ARE YOU
DOING THIS TO ME?
-
PUT THE FUCKING GUN DOWN!
PUT IT DOWN!
YOU'RE A FUCKING DEAD MAN,
YOU DO THIS.
- WHAT THE FUCK YOU DOING?
-  GO GET THE CASH OUT A THE CA.
AHH, I'M FUCKING--
I'M FUCKING BETTER THAN THIS.
- LOOK, BITCH,
I AIN'T GOT TIME FOR THIS.
- I'M BETTER THAN YOU!
COME ON, NOT NOW!
WHERE THE FUCK
YOU GOING?
THERE GOES YOUR
FUCKING BITCH RIGHT THERE.
YOU STUPID FUCKER.
- WHERE'S THE FUCKING MONEY?!
-
- I CAN'T FIND HER.
- Dispatcher: Sergeant,
I have a call
from a Cindy Paulson for you.
PUT HER THROUGH!
LOOK, HE'S GONNA TAKE ME.
HELP ME, PLEASE!
- GO SOMEWHERE YOU KNOW.
-  Clate's place, okay?
-  Gentlemen's Heaven.
- I KNOW WHERE THAT IS.
JUST GO THERE.
I'LL FIND YOU.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
LOOK, HE'S COMING, OKAY?
I WANT OUT!
JUST GET A ROOM
AND LOCK THE DOOR.
HIDE UNTIL I GET THERE.
I'LL BE THERE.
WHERE THE FUCK IS SHE?
SHIT.
NO!
-
CINDY?
- CINDY?
- OH HEY!
JACK!
REAR FIRE ESCAPE!
SHUT THE FUCK UP.
DROP THE GUN!
DROP IT!
STATE TROOPERS!
DROP THE GUN NOW!
NOW!
IT'S YOUR
LUCKY DAY, BITCH.
I JUST GOT WORD
FROM CLIVES' OFFICE.
IT DOESN'T LOOK
LIKE THEY'RE GONNA GO
WITH THE MURDER CHARGES.
I HAVE THE GUN!
I HAVE THE SHELLS!
THEY'RE JUST GONNA ARGUE
THAT SOMEBODY ELSE
COULD'VE PULLED THE TRIGGER,
YOU KNOW THAT.
I MEAN, OUR WARRANT'S
BEING QUESTIONED.
WITHOUT A MATCH ON
THE JEWELRY HE'S WORRIED
THAT IT'S A GAMBLE
THAT HE'S GONNA LOSE
AND HANSEN'LL WALK.
SORRY, JACK.
I DON'T THINK
WE'RE GONNA GET
A MURDER INDICTMENT
UNLESS HE CONFESSES.
LOOK, YOU'RE SMARTER
THAN HE IS, RIGHT?
NOW REMEMBER, WHEN YOU GET
A GUY LIKE THIS DROWNING,
YOU POUR ON MORE WATER.
YOU KNOW, I SPENT
LAST NIGHT, UH,
LOOKING OVER EVERYTHING
WE SEIZED AGAIN.
WE FOUND THIS
BEHIND HIS BED,
AND THE WIFE SAID
HE WAS ALWAYS READING
IT AT NIGHT.
- WHAT ARE THESE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT IS IT?
ED?  ED!
WHERE WERE EKLUTNA ANNIE
AND JOANNA MESSINA'S
BODIES FOUND AGAIN?
EKLUTNA WAS RIGHT HERE
WHERE YOU HAVE THIS MARK.
SEWARD'S DOWN HERE
AND THE HIGHWAY RUNS--
SO JOANNA WAS
RIGHT AROUND HERE.
THIS MARK.
JESUS.  THAT'S MORE
THAN 20 OF 'EM.
OH MY GOD!
WHAT HAS HE DONE?
WAS THERE ANYTHING
LIKE THIS FOUND?
EXACTLY LIKE THIS?
THIS IS THE ONE
THAT SUE LUNA'S SISTER
GAVE TO ME.
SHE SAID THAT SUE WAS
WEARING AN IDENTICAL ONE
THE DAY SHE DISAPPEARED.
NO, THERE'S NOTHING
LIKE THAT.
- YES.
- AND I PAID THE PRICE
FOR THAT.  OKAY?
- RIGHT?
- Lawyer: YES.  ABSOLUTELY.
BUT JUST BECAUSE I DID
SOME THINGS IN MY PAST,
DON'T SAY
THAT I'VE DONE THIS HERE,
BECAUSE I DID NOT!
- I DID NOT--
I DID NOT KILL ANYONE!
-  OKAY OKAY, BOB, JUST--
- BOB, JUST CALM DOWN.
-
SORRY I'M LATE.
BOB,
WE FOUND THIS AT YOUR HOUSE.
CAN YOU TELL ME WHAT IT IS?
I HAVEN'T SEEN THIS!
WHAT-- WHAT IS THIS?
IT'S A FLIGHT CHART.
I'M SURE YOU'VE SEEN
HUNDREDS OF THEM.
RIGHT.  AND WHAT'RE
ALL THESE LITTLE MARKINGS
ON IT?  THESE "X"s?
THOSE ARE PLACES
WHERE I HUNT.
BUT, BOB, WHY IS
THIS ONE AND THIS ONE
- AND THESE TWO?
- Lawyer: ALL RIGHT,
JUST HOLD IT NOW.
YOU'RE SAYING-- NO WAY.
THOSE ARE JUST PLACES
WHERE I HUNTED.
OH, I BELIEVE
THEY WERE, BOB.
- PLACES WHERE YOU'VE HUNTED.
- YEP.
AND THEN ONE NIGHT WHILE YOU
WERE STUDYING THIS CHART,
YOU ADDED ON WHERE YOU
HUNTED A GIRL,
AND THEN ANOTHER AND ANOTHER,
UNTIL IT'S JUST SOMETHING
YOU CAN'T LEAVE ALONE.
YOU PUT THESE GIRLS
OUT THERE, DIDN'T YOU, BOB?
- YOU HAD THEIR BLOOD ALL OVER
YOUR HANDS AND YOUR CLOTHES?
- SERGEANT.
WE FOUND THE GUNS.
JUST A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE THE LAB CONFIRMS IT.
- WELL, NOW JUST
GODDAMNED MINUTE--
- SERGEANT!
THAT'S-- THAT'S HIM.
PRETTY BAD WEATHER
FOR A FLIGHT THE OTHER DAY.
QUITE A PILOT.
WE ALMOST LOST YOU
A FEW TIMES.
BUT WE FOUND IT.
THE TRACKS WERE STILL FRESH.
WHAT IS THAT?
WELL, BOB KNOWS.
DON'T YOU, BOB?
SHE HAD A CHILD!
ALMOST THE SAME AGE
AS YOUR SON, BOB.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHY ARE YOU SO QUIET?
DON'T YOU REMEMBER
KILLING SUE LUNA?
DID YOU TAKE IT OFF HER
BEFORE OR AFTER
YOU RAPED HER?
- THIS MEETING'S OVER.
I NEED TO TALK TO MY CLIENT.
- NO, I'M TRYING TO HELP HIM.
YOU SEE, WE'RE GONNA BE TAKING
A CLOSE LOOK AT WHERE ALL
THESE LITTLE MARKS ARE.
NOW THIS MAP HAS 24 ON IT,
LEADING US TO CONCLUDE THAT
THERE MIGHT BE 24 GIRLS
OUT THERE,
AND IF WE FIND A BODY,
WE'RE GONNA CHARGE HIM
WITH MURDER!
BOB, I CAN'T STOP IT--
YOU, YOUR FAMILY, THE MEDIA.
THE GROUND'S FROZEN NOW,
BUT COME EVERY SUMMER
WHEN THE SNOW
AND THE ICE MELT,
I'LL KEEP GOING
UNTIL I'VE CHECKED
EVERY LAST MARK.
I'M GOING TO ASK
THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY
TO PETITION THE GOVERNOR
WITH ALL THE BODIES WE'LL FIND,
HE'LL GET IT, SO IF YOU DON'T
WANT TO TELL US THE TRUTH NOW,
- WE CAN'T HELP YOU THEN!
- YOU THINK CAN THREATEN ME?
- YOU THINK YOU CAN THREATEN ME?
- Lawyer: BOB, BOB, BOB!
YOU THINK YOU KNOW WHO I AM?
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO I AM!
YOU LITTLE CUNT!
YOU THINK YOU CAN THREATEN ME
WITH THIS LITTLE WHORE?
- BOB, TAKE IT EASY!
- I SHOULD HAVE KILLED YOU
WHEN I HAD THE CHANCE!
-
Lawyer: BOB.
OH, BOB.
¶¶ I'LL TAKE TIME,
OH MY LOVE ¶¶
¶¶ I LIVE WITH THE SILENCE
¶¶ THAT WE'VE GOT
¶¶ AND I COULD BE
THE ONE PLACE ¶¶
¶¶ THAT YOU RUN WHEN
MY MEMORY FINDS YOU ¶¶
¶¶ OH, WASTE NOT
ALL YOU NEED ¶¶
¶¶ AND I COULD
CARRY BURDENS ¶¶
¶¶ THAT YOU KEEP
¶¶ AND I WILL BE
THE SILENCE ¶¶
¶¶ THAT YOU NEED WHEN
MY MEMORY FINDS YOU ¶¶
¶¶ 'CAUSE I AM THE DAWN
¶¶ BEFORE YOUR LIGHT
¶¶ YOU ARE THE FIRE
¶¶ IN MY EYES
¶¶ YOU ARE TRUTH
BENEATH THESE LIES ¶¶
¶¶ WHEN MY MEMORY FINDS YOU
¶¶ OH, WASTE NOT
ALL YOU KEEP ¶¶
¶¶ I'LL KEEP
ALL THE MEMORIES ¶¶
¶¶ THAT YOU NEED
¶¶ AND SOMEWHERE
THERE'S A SILENCE ¶¶
¶¶ THAT YOU SEEK
WHEN MY MEMORY FINDS YOU ¶¶
¶¶ 'CAUSE I AM THE DAWN
¶¶ BEFORE YOUR LIGHT
¶¶ YOU ARE THE FIRE
¶¶ IN MY EYES
¶¶ YOU ARE TRUTH
BENEATH THESE LIES ¶¶
¶¶ WHEN MY MEMORY FINDS YOU
¶¶ 'CAUSE I AM THE DAWN
¶¶ BEFORE YOUR LIGHT
¶¶ YOU ARE THE TRUTH
¶¶ BENEATH THESE LIES
¶¶ YOU ARE THE FIRE
IN MY EYES ¶¶
¶¶ WHEN MY MEMORY FINDS YOU
¶¶ I'LL TAKE TIME
¶¶ MY LOVE
¶¶ I LIVE
WITH THE SILENCE ¶¶
¶¶ THAT WE'VE GOT
¶¶ I COULD BE
THE ONE PLACE ¶¶
¶¶ YOU'D RUN WHEN
MY MEMORY FINDS YOU. ¶¶