???? [ Techno Beat ]
???? [ Continues ]
[ Man Narrating ]
THIS IS THE STORY
OF A MAN NAMED HUBERT,
HUBERT FIORENTINI.
FORTY-SEVEN YEARS OLD,
TWO HUNDRED TWO POUNDS,
SIX FOOT FOUR.
A MAN OF QUIET STRENGTH
WHO WOULDN'T HURT A FLY.
THE THING IS,
THIS WOMAN IS NO FLY.
THAT WAS OUT OF LINE.
- GET TO THE STATION BEFORE
PUNCHING THEIR LIGHTS OUT.
- WHAT? COME AGAIN?
YOU AND I HAVE TO TALK.
LET'S GO SOMEWHERE QUIET.
[ Blowing Nose ]
I HAVE TO GO SEE JAWS.
LEAN ON THIS GUY
UNTIL HE BREAKS.
MORNING, HUBERT.
HEY, HUBERT.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
YEAH?
-MR. FIORENTINI,
I FINALLY GOT YOU ON THE PHONE.
-HELLO, MR. VAN EYCK.
I KNOW YOUR POLICE WORK
KEEPS YOU BUSY ALL DAY.
THAT EXPLAINS WHY YOU HAVEN'T
RESPONDED TO ALL THE TELEPHONE
MESSAGES, I SUPPOSE?
ACTUALLY, MR. VAN EYCK,
COME TO THE POINT BECAUSE
I'M WORKING ON A CASE.
YOUR ACCOUNT IS OVERDRAWN
FOR THE THIRD TIME THIS MONTH.
YOU HAVE UNTIL
THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS TODAY,
OR YOUR OVERDRAFT IS REVOKED.
- IS THAT TO THE POINT?
- I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
- NO!
- YOU WANTED TO
SPEAK TO ME, SIR?
HUBERT, YOU HAVE SOME PROBLEMS.
WHAT IS IT WITH YOU?
NO, NO PROBLEMS.
JUST THE USUAL.
IT'S PRETTY CALM RIGHT NOW.
YOU BEAT THE CRAP
OUT OF EVERYBODY YOU SEE,
IT'S A PROBLEM.
IF YOU MEAN THAT YOUNG
FEMALE I'M QUESTIONING,
SHE'S ACTUALLY A MAN.
WHAT DO YOU TAKE ME FOR?
NOT THE TRANSVESTITE,
THE OTHERS.
THE OTHERS? WHAT OTHERS?
HUBERT, HUBERT.
TRY TO PICTURE IT IN YOUR MIND.
- AH.
SOMEONE INTERFERED IN MY DUTIES.
I ALMOST FORGOT ABOUT IT.
HUBERT, THAT'S NOT ALL.
I ALMOST FORGOT.
A FIGHT BROKE OUT
AS I WAS LEAVING.
GOOD. NOT THAT,
BUT I FEEL WE'RE GETTING CLOSE.
- [ No Audible Dialogue ]
- SOME GUY BY THE STAIRS
SAID SOMETHING TO US.
THERE WAS TOO MUCH NOISE.
I COULDN'T MAKE OUT
WHAT HE SAID.
- KNOW WHAT HE SAID?
- MY DAD'S THE CHIEF OF POLICE!
- AH. IT SLIPPED MY MIND.
- AH.
HE REMEMBERED.
THE OLD MAN'S OUT OF TOWN.
- APOLOGIZE TO THE KID
BEFORE HE GETS HERE.
- WHAT WOULD I SAY?
WHATEVER YOU WANT. YOU THOUGHT
HE WAS A FELON YOU'VE BEEN
HUNTING. JUST FLATTER HIM.
- I HAVE TO INTERVIEW
THE TRANSVESTITE AND--
- HUBERT.
- OKAY, WHERE DO I FIND HIM?
- WHERE YOU THINK
YOU'LL FIND HIM?
[ Knocking ]
HELLO THERE, IT'S ME.
YOU REMEMBER ME, RIGHT?
- [ Groaning ]
- I RAN INTO YOU LAST NIGHT.
- NO, DON'T WORRY, I'M NOT HERE
TO BUST YOU OR ANYTHING.
I'M NOT HERE TO--
NO, IN FACT I--
[ Groaning ]
I CAME TO APOLOGIZE.
[ Groaning Continues ]
IT WAS SO DARK,
SO MUCH SMOKE. I DIDN'T KNOW
THE POLICE CHIEF WAS--
[ Muffled ]
WATER, WATER.
ANYWAY, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE A BURGLAR.
I MEAN, THIS HARDENED CRIMINAL
WEARS THE SAME BLACK SUIT,
RIGHT?
SO, WELL, I'M REALLY SORRY.
YEAH. I'LL BE GOING NOW. BYE.
[ Cell Phone Rings ]
HELLO!
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE
IN A GOOD MOOD.
CAN'T YOU TALK?
LOOK, SOFIA,
RIGHT NOW I'M REALLY
BUSY WITH A CASE.
SURE, NATURALLY.
BUT YOU'RE ALWAYS
BUSY WITH WORK.
NOT ON SUNDAYS.
THAT'S TRUE, BUT THEN
YOU PLAY GOLF.
- A MAN'S GOT TO RELAX SOMETIME.
- AND THAT'S PRECISELY
WHAT I HAD IN MIND.
AFTER GOLF,
I'LL PICK YOU UP, AND
YOU'LL TAKE ME OUT TO EAT.
LOOK, SOFIA, LATELY
MY STOMACH'S BEEN UPSET.
I'VE LOST MY APPETITE.
[ Hangs Up ]
"NO APPETITE"?
WELL, THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
I'VE HEARD THAT ONE.
WE TRIED EVERYTHING, HUBERT.
COULDN'T GET A THING.
THE DIRTIER WE GET,
THE MORE HE LIKES IT.
- MIND IF I TRY?
- SURE, GO AHEAD. BE OUR GUEST.
IF YOU GOT TIME TO KILL.
[ Gags ]
[ Tooth Rattles ]
CIGARETTE.
YOU REALLY HAVE A WAY
WITH WOMEN, LIEUTENANT.
COMES NATURALLY,
I MEAN, A MAN AND A WOMAN
ARE MEANT TO GET ALONG, RIGHT?
ANYWAY, WHERE ARE
YOUR GIRLFRIENDS? TELL ME.
WOW.
AN IMPRESSIVE LOOKING PEN.
IT WAS A GIFT.
I USE IT ONLY
ON SPECIAL OCCASIONS.
NOW GO AHEAD.
- WHO'D YOU GET IT FROM,
A WOMAN?
- THE ONLY ONE FOR ME.
SHE JUST DISAPPEARED AND...
THIS IS ALL SHE LEFT BEHIND.
OKAY, OLIVIER, GIVE ME
THE NAME OF THE BANK.
LET'S FINISH THIS.
BANQUE de l'Etoile.
EVERYBODY'S IN ON IT.
IT WAS THE LAST JOB.
OUR GRAND FINALE.
[ Grunts ]
WHEN IS IT?
- IT'S TODAY.
- WHAT TIME?
IT SHOULD'VE STARTED 30
MINUTES AGO. YOU'LL BE LATE.
PUT IT OUT ON THE WIRE!
EVERYTHING UNDER CONTROL?
THEY'RE ALL INSIDE?
YOU SURE YOU CHECKED THE PLACE?
[ Tires Squealing ]
WATCH OUT!
OH, FUCK, NOT HIM.
WE'RE COOL.
WE'RE IN GOOD SHAPE HERE.
NOBODY'S COME OUT.
GOT ALL THE EXITS COVERED
AND A PHONE HOOK-UP.
SHOULD I TELL THEM SOMETHING?
SAY THEY GOT A VISITOR.
SOMEONE'S COMING TO VISIT US?
BUT I'M NOT EXPECTING ANYONE!
SO WHAT WE HAVE HERE, GIRLS?
NEED MONEY? WHY NOT USE
THE A.T.M. LIKE EVERYONE ELSE?
OKAY, EVERYONE'S LEAVING.
I HAVE TO CLEAN UP HERE.
GO AHEAD.
I GIVE THE ORDERS!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
DON'T MOVE. ONE STEP
AND I'LL MAKE A HOLE
IN THIS MAN'S HEAD!
SORRY, BUT I'M
THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN
PUT A HOLE IN SOMEONE'S HEAD.
LOOK AT THIS.
THIS IS ALL THAT'S LEFT
OF YOUR GIRLFRIEND.
NOW KISS YOUR PRETTY FACES
GOOD-BYE OR FORGET ALL THIS
AND SURRENDER.
IRENE, MY HEAD IS SPINNING.
HE'LL DO SOMETHING BAD TO US.
RELAX.
ALL THIS PRETTY DYNAMITE,
AND I HAVE A GUN IN MY HAND.
- HE WOULDN'T DARE TRY IT.
HE'S BULLSHITTING.
- OH, YOU HAVE A GUN.
FROM HERE IT LOOKED LIKE
ONE OF THOSE MACHINES
THEY USE FOR PIERCING.
THAT'S GOOD. SO VERY FUNNY.
WHAT KIND OF EQUIPMENT YOU GOT?
- [ Exhales ]
LOOK AT THAT.
- THAT'S BIG ENOUGH FOR A HORSE.
- GONNA HURT REALLY BAD.
- GIVE IT UP, GUY.
THE BACKFIRE MIGHT JUST
BURN YOUR NAILS RIGHT OFF.
IF YOUR COMEDY ACT'S DONE,
PUT YOUR B.B. GUN ON THE TILE,
AND PUSH IT GENTLY MY WAY.
OKAY, BUT I WARNED YOU.
[ Laughing ]
HEY, HOW DO I LOOK?
OKAY, GIRLS. GAME'S OVER.
I'M GOING TO COUNT TO TEN.
DON'T WORRY, I'LL BE
NICE AND SLOW ABOUT IT.
- WE'LL KEEP IT AT YOUR LEVEL.
- COME ON. WHAT YOU GONNA DO?
I GOT YOUR PIECE RIGHT HERE.
ONE, TWO--
- STOP FUCKING AROUND.
I'LL BLOW US ALL SKY HIGH!
- THREE--
- [ Clicks ]
- AND TEN!
[ Wailing ]
NOW WHY DID I EXPECT
TO BE LEFT ALONE TODAY?
HUBERT, HUBERT.
IT'S SUNDAY, SIR.
SURE, BUT EVERY DAY IS MONDAY
WHEN YOU'RE ON THE JOB.
I JUST SAW THE POLICE CHIEF.
WHEN I TELL YOU TO APOLOGIZE,
WHY IS IT YOU RUB SALT
IN THE WOUND?
ALL I DID WAS POUR
A GLASS OF WATER.
LOOK, HUBERT, HE REQUIRES
AN OPERATION WHENEVER
YOU TWO CROSS PATHS.
NO WONDER HIS OLD MAN
QUESTIONS YOUR METHODS.
I JUST APOLOGIZED
AND BROUGHT FLOWERS.
RIGHT, AND NOW HE'S GOT TWO
MONTHS IN SUSPENDED POSITION.
AND THE POLICE CHIEF
SUGGESTED YOU--
YOU GET THAT TOO.
TWO MONTHS' SUSPENSION.
I SEE.
HUBERT,
NO ONE CONTESTS YOUR RESULTS,
BUT YOUR METHODS, HUBERT.
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH MY METHODS?
- THEY'RE COMPLETELY ILLEGAL.
WE'RE NOT IN THE FAR WEST.
THERE ARE LAWS AND
A CODE APPLYING TO THE POLICE.
AS A POLICE OFFICER,
YOU'RE REQUIRED TO RESPECT
THOSE TWO CODES.
RESPECTING THOSE CODES
LOST ME EIGHT GUYS
TWO YEARS AGO.
I GO VISIT OFTEN.
THEY APPRECIATE FLOWERS.
THEY'RE NO LONGER AMONG US.
TAKE A GOOD LOOK AT THE FACTS.
YOU'RE OUT OF STEP WITH REALITY.
NO FRIENDS, NO WIFE,
NO KIDS, NO ROOTS.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO GET A LIFE,
HUBERT. GO START A FAMILY.
IT'LL MAKE YOU WANT
TO LIVE AGAIN, YOU'LL SEE.
COME ON. MAKE AN EFFORT.
HUBERT.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM WITH WOMEN?
- NO, OF COURSE NOT, BUT--
- SO HAVE YOU BEEN
GOING WITH ANYBODY?
I LOVED SOMEONE
BUT THAT WAS LONG AGO--
EVERYONE'S HEARD THE STORY.
YOU MET A WOMAN
ON A JOB IN JAPAN.
ONE DAY SHE JUST UP AND LEFT.
EVERYONE'S HEARD THE STORY.
BUT FIFTEEN YEARS HAVE GONE BY.
- NINETEEN YEARS.
- OH, NINETEEN. FORGIVE ME.
MOVE ON TO SOMETHING NEW.
YOU CAN'T SPEND YOUR WHOLE
LIFE CRYING ABOUT HER.
DO ME A FAVOR,
USE THESE TWO MONTHS TO RELAX.
- GO SHOPPING, HUBERT.
- I DON'T LIKE SHOPPING.
OF COURSE YOU DO!
GO GET YOURSELF SOME NEW...
CLOTHING. HOW ABOUT THAT?
A HANDSOME GUY LIKE YOU
IN A NEW SHIRT BY ARMANI.
BELIEVE ME,
IT WON'T BE HARD
TO MEET SOMEONE.
- YOU'RE SUSPENDING ME?
- NO. I'M SAVING YOU, HUBERT.
GO BE A MAN A WHILE.
AND PROVE YOU'RE NOT
JUST A COP. ALL RIGHT?
- DON'T YOU WANT TO COME IN?
- YEAH, YEAH.
EXCUSE ME FOR STARING,
BUT THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
I'VE SEEN YOU WEARING BUTTONS.
- ALL MY T-SHIRTS WERE DIRTY.
- OH, I FEEL MUCH BETTER.
WHAT'S WRONG?
NOTHING. I WAS GOING
TO TAKE YOUR COAT.
OH, I'M SORRY.
WHAT'S THAT LOVELY SMELL?
PORC AU CARAMEL!
NO, I THINK IT'S YOU.
YOU'RE WEARING COLOGNE?
IN THE BOTTOM OF A DRAWER
I FOUND AN OLD BOTTLE.
THE BOTTLE THAT
I GAVE YOU TWO YEARS AGO?
THAT BOTTLE? REALLY?
REALLY. YOU GOT IT.
APPETITE'S IMPROVED TODAY.
CAN'T LIVE ON BREAD ALONE.
I'M OUT OF CHAMPAGNE,
BUT I HAVE SOME GOODSHOCHU.
THAT ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
- IS WORK GOING ALL RIGHT?
- [ Coughing ]
- DID I SAY THE WRONG THING?
- I DON'T WORK ANY MORE, HUBERT.
I STOPPED WHEN MY HUSBAND
PASSED AWAY. SEVEN YEARS AGO.
HOW ABOUT A SPRING ROLL?
A SPRING ROLL
WOULD BE JUST GREAT.
THANKS.
THAT WAS JUST PERFECT,
HUBERT. PERFECT.
THANKS. IT'S, UH,
A SIMPLE DINNER, NO BIG DEAL.
- WHICH YOU PROMISED ME
TWO YEARS AGO.
- THAT LONG?
- TIME SURE FLIES, HUH?
- YEAH.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
JAPANESE CUISINE, YOUR EX?
- RIGHT.
- I THOUGHT YOU ONLY SPENT
EIGHT MONTHS WITH HER.
WELL, BELIEVE ME,
YOU CAN LEARN AN AWFUL LOT
IN EIGHT MONTHS.
GUESS YOU'RE RIGHT.
- CALL ME A TAXI?
- RIGHT NOW?
WHY DO YOU LOOK SO SURPRISED?
I MEAN, WELL, IT'S UH--
I MEAN--
WE KNOW EACH OTHER
A BIT BETTER NOW, SO I--
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
WANT TO STAY HERE TONIGHT.
IN FACT THE NIGHT AIR
MIGHT CLEAR MY HEAD.
I'LL WALK AND END
THE PERFECT EVENING
IN THE PERFECT WAY.
SOFIA, I'M SORRY.
I DON'T GET IT.
YOU'RE REALLY CUTE, HUBERT,
WHEN YOU'RE TRYING SO HARD.
BUT YOU DON'T TRUST WOMEN.
HOW AM I TO TRUST WOMEN?
AS SOON AS I TURN AROUND,
THEY LEAVE OR BREAK MY HEART.
I DON'T WANT TO DO EITHER.
YOU MUST UNDERSTAND,
ALL I WANT IS TO SPEND
SOME TIME TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHAT THEY MEAN BY "LOVE".
NOT CRYING OVER SOMEONE
WHO'S BEEN GONE OVER 20 YEARS.
NINETEEN YEARS.
NINETEEN YEARS, IF YOU PREFER.
BUT THAT JAPANESE WOMAN
WOULD STILL BE HERE TODAY
IF SHE REALLY LOVED YOU.
AND YOU'D HAVE HAD
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN TOGETHER.
BUT SHE'S GONE, HUBERT.
ALL THAT SHE LEFT WAS MEMORIES
AND A FEW RECIPES.
THE SECOND YOUR HEART
IS FREE, CALL ME.
I'M NOT VERY GOOD
AT JAPANESE CUISINE,
BUT I KNOW HOW TO PLEASE A MAN.
OUR KIDS WOULD BE BEAUTIFUL.
YOU'RE REALLY
LOOKING BURNED OUT.
YOU SHOULD TAKE A VACATION.
I THINK IT'S TIME
WE SEPARATED. HOW ABOUT YOU?
[ Phone Ringing ]
- YEAH.
- MR. FIORENTINI, RIGHT?
LIEUTENANT,
PARIS POLICE DEPARTMENT?
- YEAH? WHAT'S IT ABOUT?
- DO YOU KNOW A WOMAN
NAMED MIKO KOBAYASHI?
YEAH, I KNOW HER, YES.
- YOU KNOW WHERE SHE IS?
- YES, AT THE MORGUE.
MRS. KOBAYASHI PASSED AWAY
YESTERDAY, IN TOKYO.
I'M SORRY TO ANNOUNCE
SUCH SAD NEWS.
I AM MR. HISHIBASHI.
I'M HER LAWYER.
AND TOMORROW MORNING
I WILL BE EXECUTING
HER LAST WILL AND TESTAMENT.
AS YOU ARE THE SOLE LEGATEE,
I WOULD LIKE YOU TO BE PRESENT.
SHE PUT ME IN HER TESTAMENT?
YES.
FROM BEGINNING TO THE END.
BUT AS YOU LEFT JAPAN,
FINDING YOU WASN'T EASY.
TOMORROW AT THREE, OKAY?
TOMORROW?
I'M-- I'M IN PARIS, I--
THERE'S A FLIGHT
DEPARTING PARIS AT 6:00.
AND ANOTHER AT 8:30.
OH.
I MADE
A RESERVATION ON BOTH.
THERE'S A TICKET
PREPAID FOR YOU,
GOOD FOR EITHER FLIGHT.
I CAN'T JUST GO.
I'LL HAVE TO TALK
WITH MY EMPLOYER.
- I PUT A CALL IN TO YOUR C.O.
MR. JAWS, RIGHT?
- RIGHT.
HE SAID YOU COULD GO.
EVEN TOLD ME YOU COULD HAVE
AS MUCH TIME AS YOU WANT.
- I'LL THINK IT OVER, ALL RIGHT?
- THINK IT OVER, BUT HURRY,
MR. FIORENTINI.
WHAT DOES IT MATTER NOW?
I'M IN NO RUSH.
WELL, YOU SEE, ACCORDING
TO THE WISHES, THE DECEASED
WILL BE CREMATED TOMORROW.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
WANT TO SEE HER ONE LAST TIME.
BE THERE.
[ Jet Engines Whining ]
DID YOU COME HERE
FOR VACATION OR BUSINESS?
NEITHER ONE, SIR.
EXCUSE ME. WHERE DID
YOU BOARD YOUR PLANE?
AT AN AIRPORT.
YOU'RE VERY FUNNY,
BUT YOU HAVE TO USE HUMOR
WHEN IT'S APPROPRIATE.
SORRY.
NOW, ANSWER THE QUESTION.
IF YOU LIFT YOUR EYES
TOWARD THE ARRIVAL BOARD,
YOU'LL SEE ONE FLIGHT
JUST GOT IN, FROM PARIS.
BUT IF YOU'D PREFER TO BE
LOOKING DOWN,
THEN THE TICKET ON MY BAG
HAS THE INITIALS "C.D.G.,"
THE ABBREVIATION
FOR CHARLES DE GAULLE AIRPORT.
YOU SEE I NOT ONLY
HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR
BUT I'M ALSO FAIRLY OBSERVANT.
ONE MOMENT.
I TOO AM OBSERVANT.
YOU ASKED FOR IT.
OPEN YOUR BAG!
JUST MAKE IT QUICK. I'M LATE.
YOU'RE LATE?
I'M SORRY FOR YOU.
WHERE IS HE?
THERE. IN ROOM 138.
HOPE HE'S STILL IN ONE PIECE.
OUR MEN AREN'T SAVAGES,
MAURICE.
IT'S JUST THE LAST TIME
I SAW HIM WAS YEARS AGO.
ALL BLOODY, I WON'T
BE ABLE TO PICK HIM OUT.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
HANG ON. ONE SECOND.
I'M REALLY A NERVOUS WRECK.
LIKE I CAUGHT THE BOUQUET.
SO HOW DO I LOOK?
DO I LOOK PRESENTABLE?
[ Man Shouting In Japanese ]
- MOMO?
- HOW WONDERFUL!
HUBERT, YOU RECOGNIZED ME!
OH, HUBERT! HUBERT!
HUBERT. OH, HUBERT. OH, HUBERT.
LET ME LOOK AT YOU.
YOU LOOK BEAUTIFUL, MAN!
JUST ARRIVED AND ALREADY
IN DEEP SHIT.
TRY TO BE
A LITTLE MORE DISCREET
UNTIL WE GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S OKAY, HE'S ONE OF OURS.
WHEN I WAS A ROOKIE,
I WORKED WITH THIS GUY.
HE WAS ALREADY A LIEUTENANT.
WE WERE SPECIAL COMMANDOS
IN THE EIGHTIES, IN JAPAN
TO WATCH THE RUSSKIES.
MAN, I CAN'T TELL YOU
THE TROUBLE WE MADE.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT. YOU CAN'T.
NOW TRY TO SPEND FIVE MINUTES
WITH YOUR MOUTH SHUT.
I APOLOGIZE FOR THIS INCIDENT,
BUT YOUR EMPLOYEE INSULTED ME
AND I TAUGHT HIM A LESSON.
I WAS A BIT OUT OF LINE.
SO PLEASE ACCEPT MY APOLOGIES.
YOU DO HAVE A REPUTATION,
MR. FIORENTINI.
DO YOU HAVE A CASE IN TOKYO?
IS THAT WHY YOU'RE HERE?
IT'S A VACATION.
DON'T WORRY,
I WON'T BE LONG.
DON'T WORRY.
WITH MY FRIEND,
NOTHING TAKES TOO LONG.
GOOD-BYE AND GOOD LUCK.
"GOOD-BYE AND GOOD LUCK."
[ Laughing ]
"GOOD-BYE AND GOOD LUCK"
FIFTEEN YEARS.
- YOU'RE STILL
DRIVING THE SAME CAR.
- I LOVE THIS BABY.
YOU WOULDN'T
BELIEVE THE MILEAGE I GET.
SO WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
NOTHING, REALLY.
I'M ALL DONE WITH THE COMMANDOS.
I'M JUST YOUR AVERAGE
NEIGHBORHOOD COP ON THE BEAT.
I FINISH MY SHIFT
AND GO HOME.
QUIT FUCKING ME AROUND.
TELL ME YOU TOOK UP KNITTING
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT.
NOT KNITTING, BUT I PLAY GOLF
AND I'M ACTUALLY NOT BAD.
GOD, HOW PITIFUL.
IT'S A GOOD THING YOU CAME BACK.
WHAT DO WE BLOW UP? GOT A BOAT
WE COULD SINK? ARE WE GONNA
SABOTAGE A POWER PLANT?
REMEMBER WHEN WE GOT
THE WRONG TARGET AND
TWO TONS OF AMMO BLEW?
OH, THAT WAS GREAT!
[ Laughing ]
I'M HERE
ON A PERSONAL MATTER, MOMO.
OH.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN
WITH THAT JAPANESE LADY?
WHAT WAS HER NAME AGAIN?
- MIKO.
- MIKO. OH, RIGHT.
SHE HAD YOU
ON A FREAKIN' LEASH.
[ Howls ]
SHE JUST PASSED AWAY, MOMO.
I'M HERE FOR HER CREMATION.
I HAD NO IDEA,
I'M REALLY SORRY.
OKAY. HOW DID YOU KNOW
I WAS ARRIVING?
WELL, I STILL WORK
WITH INTELLIGENCE.
- COULD I DROP YOU OFF?
- HERE'S THE ADDRESS.
SHINJUKU. AH, THE RED-LIGHT
DISTRICT. YOU GOT
THE PRETTIEST HOOKERS IN TOWN.
OF COURSE, YOU'RE NOT
IN THE MOOD FOR THAT.
???? [ Mid-Tempo Hip-Hop ]
?? I JUST CAME TO SEE ????
OVER THERE!
HISHIBASHI-SAN?
HAI, DOZO.
DOZO.
OH, MR. FIORENTINI,
I ASSUME?
A GOOD ASSUMPTION.
OH, BUT IT WASN'T DIFFICULT.
YOU'RE THE SPITTING IMAGE...
OF THE PORTRAIT
MRS. KOBAYASHI DID OF YOU.
BUT 20 YEARS OLDER OF COURSE.
NINETEEN YEARS.
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S TRUE.
YOU'RE RIGHT TO BE PRECISE HERE.
LET'S BEGIN RIGHT NOW.
HAVE A SEAT, PLEASE.
- THANK YOU.
- MRS. KOBAYASHI NAMES YOU...
AS HER SOLE LEGATEE.
SHE LEFT YOU
ALL HER POSSESSIONS,
WHICH FOR PRACTICAL REASONS...
HAVE BEEN PLACED
INSIDE THIS BOX.
IF YOU WOULD BE SO KIND
AS TO SIGN THIS RECEIPT
AND THE ACCEPTANCE OF THE WILL.
[ Sighs ]
YOU WERE QUITE POETIC BACK THEN.
BUT I PREFER THE PICTURE
OF YOUR UNIFORM PERSONALLY.
[ Woman's Voice ]
WHERE IT ALL BEGAN,
WHERE IT ALL SHALL END.
DID SHE EXPRESS ANY LAST WISHES
SHE WANTED ME TO CARRY OUT?
ONE. ONLY ONE.
THAT YOU BE THE GUARDIAN
OF HER DAUGHTER UNTIL
SHE COMES OF AGE.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
THAT'S RIGHT.
HER DAUGHTER.
- HOW OLD IS SHE?
- NINETEEN YEARS OLD
AND ABOUT ELEVEN MONTHS.
WELL, ARE YOU SAYING
HER MOTHER-- THAT HER MOTHER--
ARE YOU SAYING THAT I--
THAT HER MOTHER--
WELL, I MEAN--
BUT, WHAT? I MEAN-- WHAT-WHAT?
- YOU MEAN WHAT'S HER NAME?
- RIGHT.
HER NAME IS YUMI.
SHE MAKES QUITE AN IMPRESSION.
YOU'LL SEE.
HANG ON THERE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- I WAS GOING TO BRING HER IN.
- YOU MEAN THE DAUGHTER'S HERE?
RIGHT BEHIND THE DOOR.
SHE GOT OUT OF PRISON
THIS MORNING.
- GOT OUT OF PRISON?
- THE OFFENSE WAS MINOR.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
SHE HAD A SORT OF BREAKDOWN
WHEN SHE HEARD HER MOTHER DIED.
DRANK TOO MUCH. AND THEN
SHE PUNCHED SOME POLICEMEN.
- SOME POLICEMEN?
- YES, BUT I'LL LET HER
TELL YOU ABOUT IT.
WAIT A SECOND. WAIT.
WAIT. YOU BRING ME HERE
AND TELL ME...
I HAVE A NINETEEN-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER I NEVER MET
WHO JUST GOT OUT OF PRISON.
I ADAPT WELL TO NEW SITUATIONS,
BUT I'M GOING TO NEED TO THINK
ABOUT THIS FOR A SECOND, OKAY?
HOW CAN YOU BE SURE
THAT I'M THE FATHER?
BECAUSE IT SAYS SO RIGHT HERE
ON THE BIRTH CERTIFICATE.
YOUR NAME IS WRITTEN
IN THE BOX NEXT TO "FATHER."
MRS. KOBAYASHI CONFIRMS IT.
ACCORDING TO HER TESTAMENT,
YOU ARE ONLY MAN IN HER LIFE.
- WHY'D SHE LEAVE ME, THEN?
- THAT, SHE SAID NOTHING ABOUT.
DID YOU SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT THIS TO YUMI?
NO. I ASSUMED YOU
WANT THE PLEASURE
OF TELLING HER YOURSELF.
OH, SURE, JUST IMAGINE.
SURE, I'VE BEEN AWAY
NINETEEN YEARS!
- HELLO, I'M YOUR DAD!
- WELL, I IMAGINE
SHE WILL BE VERY HAPPY.
AFTER LOSING HER MOTHER,
SHE GETS HER FATHER BACK.
BUT HOW CAN WE BE SO SURE?
HER MOTHER MIGHT'VE MET SOMEONE
JUST AFTER ME.
HUH? A COUPLE OF MONTHS.
WHO COULD REMEMBER?
I SUPPOSE YOU COULD
HAVE A D.N.A. TEST DONE.
SURELY YOU WOULD SETTLE IT.
BUT FROM WHAT I'VE SEEN OF YOU,
I'M FAIRLY CERTAIN
YOU ARE HER FATHER.
AND SHE'S RIGHT
BEHIND THE DOOR?
YES.
LET'S KEEP THIS
TO OURSELVES.
NO MENTION OF FATHERS.
ALL RIGHT.
BECAUSE YOU COULD
TRAUMATIZE HER.
IT'S REALLY DANGEROUS.
ACTUALLY, THEY'RE
FRAGILE AT THAT AGE.
I AGREE.
EVEN IF THEY PRETEND
THEY'RE NOT.
VERY TRUE.
SO ARE YOU GOING TO OPEN IT?
[ Speaking Japanese ]
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
- SHE ASKED ME WHO YOU ARE.
- JUST TELL HER--
JUST TELL HER I'M A GOOD
FRIEND OF HER MOTHER'S.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
- SO WHAT'S THE NAME
OF THIS GOOFBALL?
- SAY MY NAME'S HUBERT.
MR. FIORENTINI, SHE JUST
SPOKE TO YOU IN FRENCH.
OH, RIGHT.
HELLO, MY NAME IS HUBERT.
[ Scoffs ]
IF YOU'RE NOT POLITE,
YOU GO BACK TO THE POLICE.
YOU NOT SCARE ME.
WHO CARES ABOUT POLICE?
THEY ALL SUCK!
- COULD I PLEASE HAVE
SOMETHING TO DRINK?
- SAKE?
YEAH, GREAT.
[ Scoffs ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
THANKS. I FEEL BETTER.
IF YOU'RE A FRIEND
OF MY MOTHER'S, WHY SHE
DIDN'T EVER TELL ME ABOUT YOU?
YOU MUST KNOW YOUR MOTHER
HAD MANY FRIENDS FROM FRANCE.
AND THOSE ARE FRIENDS
SHE MEETS THROUGH WORK.
SO DID WE.
AT THE FRENCH CONSULATE.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
-MR. FIORENTINI IS HERE...
BECAUSE YOUR MOTHER
DESIGNATED HIM AS SOLE LEGATEE.
HE WILL THUS TAKE CARE
OF YOU UNTIL YOU'RE OF AGE,
WHICH IS IN--
TWO DAYS! THAT'S GREAT!
I DON'T HAVE TO BE
WITH HIM LONG!
YUMI, BE CAREFUL HOW YOU SPEAK
TO YOUR-- YOUR GUARDIAN.
THIS IS YOUR MOTHER'S
LAST REQUEST. I'M SURE
IF SHE CHOOSE MR. FIORENTINI,
IF SHE TRUST HIM WITH SO MUCH,
SHE MUST HAVE THOUGHT
VERY HIGHLY OF HIM.
EVEN IF SHE
NEVER TOLD YOU ABOUT HIM.
NOW, IF YOUR MOTHER FELT
HE WAS SO WORTHY OF HER TRUST,
HE MUST BE WORTHY
OF YOUR TRUST.
WELL, FOR ABOUT TWO--TWO DAYS.
COME ON.
LET'S GO SEE HER.
WE CAN WALK THERE.
IT'S A FEW BLOCKS.
WE COULD PROBABLY GET A TAXI.
I'M VERY FRAGILE RIGHT NOW.
YOU HAVE TO BE
EXTREMELY INDULGENT.
OH, OKAY. I WILL BE.
BOY. THE OLD MAN
HAD ME FOOLED.
COULD I
ASK YOU A QUESTION?
IT'S NOT UPSETTING.
NO! FOR TWO DAYS,
I'M THE ONLY ONE
WHO ASKS QUESTIONS.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
OH, OKAY.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
HEY, YOU STILL GOT IT, MAN.
TWENTY MINUTES ALONE AND
YOU GOT YOURSELF A PRINCESS.
IDIOT! THAT'S MIKO'S DAUGHTER.
AND MY DAUGHTER, APPARENTLY.
GREAT BODY ANYWAY.
WHAT?
NO, JUST I NEVER IMAGINED YOU
HAD CHILDREN WITH GREAT BODIES.
WELL, IT'S NEWS TO ME TOO.
NOW FOLLOW AT A DISTANCE
AND SHUT YOUR TRAP.
BOY, IS THIS
ABOUT TO GET MESSY.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
PSST.
COME ON.
HELLO, MIKO.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
YOUR MOTHER MANAGED
ALWAYS TO SMILE LIKE THAT,
NO MATTER WHAT.
AND YOUR MOTHER
LEFT YOU HER SMILE.
HAS IT BEEN VERY LONG
SINCE YOU'VE BEEN
WITH MY MOTHER?
NINETEEN YEARS.
WELL, THEN,
I'LL LEAVE YOU ALONE.
IT'S BEEN SO LONG.
THE TWO OF YOU MUST HAVE
A LOTS OF STUFF TO SAY.
WHY DID YOU KEEP IT
A SECRET? WHY?
YOU WANTED ME TO TAKE
CARE OF HER AND I WILL.
BECAUSE SHE'S ALL
THAT REMAINS OF YOU.
WAIT, WAIT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- NOTHING, JUST A HABIT
OF MY PROFESSION.
- ARE YOU A DOCTOR?
- RIGHT, THAT'S RIGHT, A DOCTOR.
- DO YOU KNOW HOW
YOUR MOTHER DIED?
- YES. CANCER.
YOU HAVE THE FILE
FROM THE HOSPITAL,
A DEATH CERTIFICATE?
YES. THEY'RE AT MY HOUSE.
ARE YOU A SPECIALIST?
UH, SURGERY.
PLASTIC SURGERY.
AH, THAT'S GREAT!
WOULD YOU EXAMINE MY NOSE?
I WANT TO HAVE IT RE-DONE.
LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S TOO BIG!
IT'S NOT ATTRACTIVE
FOR A GIRL MY AGE TO
HAVE A NOSE LIKE THIS.
- YOUR NOSE IS VERY PRETTY.
- IT'S HORRIBLE!
- I MUST GET IT
FROM MY BASTARD FATHER.
- HE'S A BASTARD?
- HAVE YOU, UH--
HAVE YOU YOU EVER MET?
- NO.
IF HE SHOWED UP ONE DAY,
I WOULD SLIT HIS THROAT!
WHAT'S HE EVER DONE
TO MERIT SUCH HATE?
HE SEDUCED MY MOTHER AND
OBLIGED HER TO HAVE SEX.
NO! NO.
YES.
YES. BUT TOMORROW
I COME OF AGE,
AND I'M GOING TO GET...
ALL THE YAKUZA
IN THIS COUNTRY AFTER HIM,
WHATEVER I DO!
I THINK I BETTER
SIT DOWN FOR A SECOND.
- YOU WANT SOME MORE SAKE?
- NO, I'M FINE. JUST THE CHAIR.
YUMI, THIS IS
A FRIEND OF MINE, MOMO.
HE'S BEEN LIVING
IN TOKYO FOR YEARS.
WOW, WHAT A RESEMBLANCE--
MOMO.
- UH, TO YOUR MOTHER.
- YOU KNEW MY MOTHER?
NEVER MET HER, NO.
LET'S GET GOING.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
YOU TELL HER
YOU'RE A COP YET?
NO, SHE HATES COPS.
IF I TELL HER, SHE'S GONE.
I'M NOT LETTING HER GET AWAY
LIKE HER MOTHER DID.
SHE'S NOT A KID.
TELL HER
AND SHE'LL ACCEPT IT
'CAUSE YOU'RE HER BLOOD.
YOU'RE HER BLOOD.
BUT SHE DOESN'T EVEN
KNOW I'M HER DAD.
IF SHE KNEW, SHE WOULD'VE
STABBED ME ALREADY.
I GUESS.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
HEY, DOES SHE KNOW
THAT MIKO'S HER MOTHER?
SOMETIMES YOU'RE REALLY
VERY DUMB, YOU KNOW THAT?
- WELL, OBVIOUSLY
SHE KNOWS HER MOTHER.
- OKAY.
THIS STORY GETS MORE COMPLICATED
BY THE MINUTE. I'M A LITTLE
MIXED UP, THAT'S ALL.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
KONNICHIWA.
THIS IS MY AUNT ATSUKO,
OLDER SISTER OF MY MOTHER.
MY GOD.
KONNICHIWA.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
SHE SAID SHE'S SEEN
YOUR UGLY FACE SOMEWHERE,
BUT SHE CAN'T REMEMBER WHERE.
OH, GOOD.
UM, WELL, THAT'S TOO BAD.
THE HOSPITAL RECORD.
OH, YEAH.
I'VE GOT IT OVER THERE.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
MOMO, GO WAIT IN THE CAR.
ARE YOU SURE?
COULD I TAKE A PISS?
NO.
I DON'T THINK
I CAN HOLD IT IN.
WELL, ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
- THIS IS A NICE ROOM.
- I WAS THINKING ABOUT
CHANGING THE WALLPAPER.
- WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- SURE. HOW ABOUT SOMETHING
WITH ANIMALS? FAWNS, BEARS--
SURE, AND PICTURES
OF WINNIE THE POOH.
NO, NO, NO.
HERE'S WHAT I PICTURED.
A NUCLEAR CLOUD
THAT'S EXPLODING IN THE AIR,
WITH A LOTS OF SPACED-OUT
CHARACTERS ALL AROUND,
DANCING TO TECHNO.
THAT WOULD PROBABLY BE
ALL RIGHT. WHAT'S YOUR
MOTHER'S BEDROOM LIKE?
MOM CAME HERE ONLY ON WEEKENDS.
SHE HAD AN APARTMENT IN TOWN.
- ALL RIGHT
IF I PLAY SOME MUSIC?
- ALL RIGHT, GO AHEAD.
???? [ Techno ]
???? [ Stops ]
[ Chuckles ]
WELL, MAYBE LATER,
OR SOME OTHER DAY.
THE HOSPITAL RECORD.
YEAH.
AH!
OKAY, HERE IT IS.
THANKS.
- WHAT DID SHE DO FOR A LIVING?
- SEARCH ME.
MOM ALWAYS WAS
SORT OF MYSTERIOUS.
THAT'S THE UNDERSTATEMENT
OF THE YEAR.
- WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING
FOR IN THERE?
- NOTHING! JUST ROUTINE.
YOU'RE GONNA BE SPENDING
TWO WHOLE DAYS WITH ME, AND
IF YOU WANT THEM TO BE PLEASANT,
YOU'VE GOT ABOUT TWO SECONDS TO
REALIZE I'M A GROWN-UP PERSON,
NOT A BLEEDING IDIOT!
YOU TOOK SAMPLES OF CRYSTALS
THAT WAS UNDER HER NOSE,
AND THE DIRT UNDER HER NAILS.
LOOK, THERE IS SOMETHING
STRANGE HERE, BUT INCONCLUSIVE.
NOW AS A... MEDICAL DOCTOR,
YOU'VE GOT TO BE ABLE
TO SUPPLY EVIDENCE.
YOU MEAN, LIKE THE POLICE?
YEAH, LIKE THE POLICE.
[ Sighs ]
I'M HAVING TESTS DONE.
WHEN I KNOW SOMETHING FOR SURE,
YOU HAVE MY WORD
YOU'LL BE THE FIRST TO KNOW.
DEAL?
YEAH, MAN.
- YOU'RE PRETTY CLEVER, HUH?
- JUST A LITTLE.
- WOULD YOU LIKE TO HELP ME
TO TRACK DOWN MY FATHER?
- I'D BE GLAD TO.
ARE YOU SURE YOU WANT
TO MEET HIM? SO SOON
AFTER LOSING YOUR MOTHER.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
HE MUST BE FAR AWAY FROM HERE.
TELL ME. WHO SAID THAT
HE FORCED HER TO HAVE SEX?
MY MOTHER.
SHE'S GOT A LOT OF NERVE.
THA-THAT'S A SERIOUS CHARGE.
YOU BELIEVE YOUR MOTHER WAS
THE KIND OF WOMAN WHO GETS
FORCED INTO THAT KIND OF THING?
BUT WHY WOULD SHE
LIE TO ME THEN?
PERHAPS TO PROTECT YOU,
OR TO PROTECT YOUR FATHER.
WHAT REASON WOULD SHE HAVE
TO PROTECT A SCOUNDREL?
MAYBE HE'S NOT
AS BAD AS ALL THAT.
YEAH,
IT'S PRETTY UGLY WALLPAPER.
WE'LL GET IT CHANGED.
RIGHT NOW!
[ Speaking Japanese ]
[ Giggling ]
HI.
TAXI!
GIVE ME YOUR PHONE NUMBER
AND HAVE THIS ANALYZED.
WHAT IS IT?
IF I KNEW, I WOULDN'T
NEED IT ANALYZED.
OKAY, YOU'LL
HAVE IT TOMORROW.
YOU'VE GOT AN HOUR.
DAMN, SURE IS GOOD
TO HAVE HIM BACK.
I WANT TO PUT SOME MONEY
IN YOUR ACCOUNT
FOR YOU AND YOUR AUNT.
YOU'RE RICH?
NO, I HAVE
AN UNDERSTANDING BANKER.
I'LL WIRE YOU MONEY EVERY WEEK.
YOU'LL USE IT AS YOU SEE FIT.
THAT'S FUNNY.
THAT'S WHAT
MY MOTHER USED TO DO.
THAT'S A COINCIDENCE.
YES, EVERY FRIDAY,
SHE'D WIRE ME $200.
BUT IN TWO DAYS,
I'D SPEND IT.
WELL, JUDGING BY THE WILL,
THERE CAN'T BE VERY MUCH
IN YOUR ACCOUNT.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
WOULD YOU EXPLAIN
I WANT A BALANCE,
AND THEN I'LL MAKE YOU
A WIRE TRANSFER.
YEAH.
NO PROBLEM, SIR.
I HEARD YOU.
OH. WELL, GREAT.
AH.
WHAT'S THAT?
ELECTRONIC SIGNATURE.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
HERE YOU ARE.
THANKS.
- AND UH--
AND HOW MUCH TO THE YEN?
- OH, THAT'S A DOLLAR AMOUNT.
OH.
THERE MUST BE SOME MISTAKE.
WOULD YOU CHECK IT?
OH, YES OF COURSE.
I UNDERSTAND YOUR SURPRISE.
THIS IS ONLY THE PRINCIPAL.
THE INTEREST
IS ON A SEPARATE ACCOUNT.
SHOULD I GET IT FOR YOU?
I SUPPOSE, YEAH.
- THOSE ARE DOLLARS TOO?
- THOSE ARE DOLLARS.
SHOULD I CALCULATE THE TOTAL?
OH, NO, THANKS. SPARE ME.
I GET THE PICTURE.
APPROXIMATELY.
[ Yumi Speaking Japanese ]
BYE-BYE.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
WELL? THERE ENOUGH?
LET'S SEE.
YEAH, YEAH.
YOU--YOU--
YOU'RE DOING OKAY.
AND THE WIRE TRANSFER, SIR?
IN WHAT AMOUNT?
- HUH?
- WHAT AMOUNT?
- TWO THOUSAND.
- DOLLARS?
FRANCS.
RIGHT.
FRANCS?
OH, THANK YOU, HUBERT!
I'LL ALWAYS REMEMBER
WHAT YOU DID FOR ME.
NO, IT'S NOTH--
REALLY, IT'S NOTHING.
IT'S GREAT!
- YOU'RE TREATING ME LIKE
I'M YOUR OWN DAUGHTER!
- NO, I'M SURE YOUR FATHER,
IF HE WAS IN MY SHOES,
WOULD'VE DONE THE SAME THING.
RIGHT. BUT HE DISAPPEARED.
AND I'M REALLY A VERY HAPPY GIRL
TO HAVE YOU AROUND.
SIGNATURE?
HUH?
AND NOW WE GO SHOPPING!
WELL, BE REASONABLE.
I NEVER SPEND ONE PENNY
MORE THAN WHAT I'VE GOT.
GOOD, JUST KEEP THAT UP.
???? [ Humming ]
TWO HUNDRED MILLION DOLLARS.
- IT'S PRETTY, HUH?
- VERY PRETTY.
[ Laughing ]
COULD I BORROW
YOUR PHONE ONE SECOND?
MOMO, GOT THE RESULTS YET?
NOT ON THE FINGERNAIL SAMPLE.
BUT I JUST GOT THE RESULT
ON THE CRYSTALS.
FERRO-MERCURIC POTASSIUM,
A.K.A.--
CYANIDE.
IS THERE A TREATMENT FOR
LIVER CANCER USING CYANIDE?
I'LL BET THERE ISN'T.
BUT HEY, YOU'RE THE DOCTOR.
AS A COP, WHAT'S YOUR OPINION?
AROUND THE NOSE, CYANIDE.
THE HOSPITAL RECORD IS FICTION.
MARKS ON THE VICTIM'S HAND.
HER STRUGGLE WAS PROLONGED.
YOU CONCLUDE WHAT?
THAT THE VICTIM WAS MURDERED.
AND THE MAN WHO MURDERED HER
WASN'T EXPECTING MR. FIORENTINI.
- PUT IT ON THE WIRE.
CODE SEVEN ONE.
- YES!
- MEET ME IN ONE HOUR AT
THE IMPERIAL. RESERVE A SUITE.
- HOW ABOUT EQUIPMENT?
BRING ALL THE EQUIPMENT
YOU FIND.
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S LIKE MY BIRTHDAY.
UH, WHAT'S HAPPENED?
NOTHING. BUT YOU GOT
PERFUME FOR A WEEK NOW.
HOW ABOUT TRYING SWEATERS?
AAAH!
LEAD THE WAY!
[ Speaking Japanese ]
I'M WARNING YOU.
THIS GONNA TAKE
THE WHOLE DAY.
YAHOO!
HUH?
[ Laughs ]
THANKS.
[ Yells ]
[ Man Yells ]
FIORENTINI. MY FRIEND
CALLED TO RESERVE FOR ME.
HERE IT IS, SIR.
WELCOME TO THE IMPERIAL.
- THANKS.
- I'M SORRY
FOR BEING INDELICATE,
BUT IS THE YOUNG WOMAN
OF LEGAL AGE?
I'M HER FATHER.
HE'S MY DAD.
[ Laughs ]
PLEASE ACCEPT
MY SINCERE APOLOGIES.
PUT ALL THAT
IN THE OTHER ROOM.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
[ Laughing ]
THANK YOU.
NICE GOING,
SAYING YOU'RE
MY FATHER.
I DIDN'T HAVE A CHOICE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE HE'D BUY IT.
BECAUSE...
I DON'T LOOK ONE BIT
LIKE YOU, HUH?
EXCEPT FOR THE NOSE,
MAYBE A LITTLE.
- YOU WANT ORANGE JUICE?
- NO, THANK YOU.
- HOW 'BOUT SAKE?
-[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
[ Knocking On Door ]
MMM--
MAYBE LATER. WANNA TRY ON
THE NEW STUFF YOU GOT?
OH, GREAT. SHOULD I PUT ON
A FASHION SHOW FOR YOU?
YEAH, A FASHION SHOW. FINE.
GUESS WHO WENT SHOPPING.
I GOT ALL YOUR FAVORITE
STUFF. I MADE A HAUL.
YOU'RE GONNA FLIP.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE THIS.
HEAT-SEEKING, GROUND-TO-AIR
ROCKET LAUNCHER. WEIGHS ONLY
A POUND. FIGURED I'D BUY TWO.
COMPRESSED AIR MINI-MISSILES,
A RANGE OF TWO CITY BLOCKS.
YOU CAN KNOCK OUT AN ARMY
AND REALLY KICK SOME ASS.
[ Doors Open ]
???? [ Hip-Hop ]
SHE'S YOUR DAUGHTER?
THAT'S DEFINITE?
WHAT'S IT TO YOU?
WHEN I SAID SHE LOOKED
LIKE YOU, I GUESS
I MIGHT HAVE BEEN WRONG.
I-I MEAN, EXCEPT THE NOSE.
WHERE WERE WE?
ANTI-PERSONNEL BAZOOKA
MADE IN KOREA.
IT CAN STOP A TANK.
YOU GOT SOMETHING
I CAN USE IN TOWN?
A BIT MORE DISCREET?
A LITTLE MORE DISCREET.
SOMETHING NICE AND LIGHT.
FOR THE CITY.
THIS IS A CLASSIC .357 MAGNUM.
THE LATEST UZI. FIFTY ROUNDS
TO THE SECOND IT FIRES.
AND FROM RUSSIA WITH LOVE,
YOU CAN USE MUSTARD GAS
WITH THAT.
???? [ Hip-Hop ]
?? QUICK TO PULL THE TRIGGER
QUICK TO PULL YOUR CARD ??
?? WHORE
MAKE FOR THE BOULEVARD ??
?? IS THE BEAT TO THE R-A-T
WITH THE BUMP ??
?? SENDIN' GOOD VIBRATIONS
FROM THE TRUNK
TO THE FRONT OF YOUR RIDE ??
?? WHERE I LIVE
THAT'S WHAT THEY DRIVE ??
MOMO--
THIS ONE'S ARGENTINE.
COMES WITH ANTI-RIOT BULLETS.
I BROUGHT SOME GRENADES
TO GO WITH IT.
- I'M GOING TO TAKE THIS ONE.
- [ Sighs ]
I KNEW YOU'D PICK THAT.
YOU WANNA COUPLE
OF GRENADES JUST IN CASE?
NO, MAYBE LATER.
WOULD SCARE THE GIRL.
I WANT TO TRY
TO KEEP THIS DISCREET.
CAN YOU GIVE ME THE JUICE?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW MUCH.
THE WOMAN I LOVE DISAPPEARS
AND THEN ABOUT 19 YEARS LATER,
SHE GETS MURDERED,
LEAVING HER DAUGHTER WITH ME
AS WELL AS $200 MILLION.
$200 MILLION?
THAT'S THE BALANCE
OF THE GIRL'S BANK ACCOUNT.
BUT DON'T WORRY,
AT THE RATE SHE SPENDS IT,
I DON'T THINK IT WILL
LAST TOO LONG.
OH, COME ON, MAN.
200 MILLION IS A LOT.
A BUNCH OF MORONS
WITH GLASSES TAILED US
WHEN WE LEFT THE BANK,
SO THE MONEY HAS CREATED
A CERTAIN CURIOSITY.
I SUPPOSE, YEAH.
$200 MILLION.
"WHERE IT ALL BEGAN,
WHERE IT ALL WILL END."
IT'S NO ACCIDENT
I'M IN MIKO'S WILL.
SHE KNEW I WOULD BE NEEDED,
I JUST KNOW IT.
[ Sighs ]
SHE COULDN'T JUST SAY IT
FOR SOME REASON, SO SHE
LEFT ME CERTAIN KEYS.
YEAH, KEYS.
AND $200 MILLION.
JUST FORGET THE $200 MILLION.
SOMEBODY SAY IT WAS FOR YOU?
YOU GOT SOME WAY
TO HAVE ACCESS
TO INFORMATION ON MIKO?
THAT SHOULDN'T BE THAT
COMPLICATED. I KNOW A GUY
IN JAPANESE INTELLIGENCE.
IF SOMETHING IN HER PAST
COULD EXPLAIN WHAT'S
GOING ON, I GOTTA HAVE IT.
- I'M READY.
- READY FOR WHAT?
I'M GOING OUT TONIGHT.
BUT YOU CAN'T GO WEARING THAT.
IT'S, UH--
IT'S REALLY CHILLY OUT.
PUT ON AN OVERCOAT
OR A JACKET.
A LONG RAINCOAT.
I'M NOT PLAYING BRIDGE,
ALL RIGHT? I'M GOING DANCING!
- ANYWAY, I'M ALWAYS TOO HOT.
I TAKE AFTER MY MOTHER.
- YEAH, I REMEMBER HER MOTHER.
YOU GO OUT BY YOURSELF
AT NIGHT? THAT COULD
BE DANGEROUS. RIGHT?
- OH, YEAH, THERE'S FREAKS
ALL OVER LOOKING FOR GIRLS.
- WHAT?
NOT ALWAYS,
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
WHEN YOU GOTTA GO,
YOU GOTTA GO. SO WHY
NOT HAVE A LITTLE FUN?
COME ALONG AND CHAPERONE,
THEN NOTHING GONNA
HAPPEN TO ME.
THAT WAY, YOU COULD
PRETEND THAT YOU'RE
BIG DADDY.
I CAN SEE
YOU JUST LOVE THAT.
BRING THE GRENADES.
???? [ Hip-Hop ]
[ People Chattering ]
HEY, GUYS!
COME ON!
DO DISCOS ALWAYS HAVE
VIDEO GAMES ALL OVER?
COME ON.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
UNCLE HUBERT AND UNCLE MORRIS.
MAURICE.
HEY!
THAT'S FUNNY.
HAI,IRENE.
-IRENE.
- [ Speaking Japanese ]
HAI,AADESHI.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
HAI,CHOLO.
HAI,RIYUCHI.
OKAY, COME ON EVERYBODY.
- [ Speaking Japanese ]
- [ All Speaking Japanese ]
ARE YOU READY?
???? [ Dance ]
???? [ Singing In Japanese ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
NO, THANKS, BUT I THINK
I'M A LITTLE OLD FOR THAT.
AND BESIDES, MY KNEE HURTS.
HEY, WOULD YOU
DO THIS FOR ME, PLEASE?
???? [ Continues ]
CROSS YOUR LEGS TOO.
-???? [ Ends ]
- [ Video Game ]
KEEP PRACTICING. YOU CAN--
YOU MADE ME PROUD OF YOU.
THAT WAS A GREAT TRY.
- HEY, MOMO, IT'S YOUR TURN.
- OH, NO. I GOT PROBLEMS WITH
MY KNEES, MY WHOLE BODY.
MOMO!
MOMO! MOMO!
MOMO! MOMO! MOMO!
OKAY, OKAY, SURE.
BUT ONLY ONCE.
[ All Chanting ]
MOMO! MOMO! MOMO! YEA!
???? [ Dance ]
- HEY!
[ Speaking Japanese ]
- WHAT DID HE SAY?
IF YOU'D LIKE TO PLAY ANOTHER
ROUND, HE KNOWS A GAME THAT
WON'T BE HARD ON THE KNEES.
- AND WHERE IS IT?
- OVER THERE.
LET'S GO.
HEY, WHAT IS IT?
I WAS WINNING.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I EXPLAIN LATER.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
YOU FIRST. YOU CAN
SHOW ME HOW TO PLAY.
OK, MAN, YOU'RE UP.
OH. OKAY.
[ All Speaking Japanese ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
I THINK THE REMATCH
WILL HAVE TO WAIT.
OKAY WITH YOU?
- ANY OTHER WAY OUT?
- OVER THERE.
[ Chuckles ]
I'M SURE GLAD HE'S BACK.
[ Vomits, Coughing ]
I'M SORRY. I DIDN'T MEAN
TO RUIN YOUR EVENING.
- WHO ARE YOU?
- UH, UH, I'M NOT A DOCTOR.
YEAH, THAT'S PRETTY CLEAR.
YOU MADE THAT OBVIOUS
JUST NOW.
TELL ME WHO YOU ARE,
TO KILL PEOPLE LIKE THAT.
TELL ME WHY
YOU KILLED THEM.
TELL ME WHO THOSE MEN WERE
AND WHY THEY HAD GUNS.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
- DID YOU CATCH ANY OF THAT?
- NO, IT DOESN'T MATTER.
IT'S GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
[ Sniffling ]
IF YOU'LL LET ME,
I'LL EXPLAIN.
HERE, DRY YOUR TEARS.
[ Coughing ]
AH, THAT REMINDS ME
OF A GUY I KNOW.
GO GET THE STUFF ON MIKO
INSTEAD OF ACTING SILLY.
AND THE LAB REPORT...
ON THE DIRT
UNDER HER FINGERNAILS.
I'LL MEET YOU AT THE HOTEL
IN AN HOUR.
I SPEND MY LIFE IN MY CAR.
MOMO--
OKAY.
[ Sighs ]
YOUR MOTHER ASKED ME
TO COME HERE.
SHE TRUSTED NO ONE.
BUT EVEN AFTER ALL THESE YEARS,
I THINK SHE TRUSTED ME.
YOUR MOTHER WANTED ME HERE
SO I'D KNOW SOMETHING, A SECRET.
BUT SHE WAS KILLED BEFORE
SHE HAD A CHANCE TO EXPLAIN.
NOW SOME MEN IN DARK SUNGLASSES
HAVE BEEN FOLLOWING US ALL OVER.
FOR SOME REASON, THEY WANT YOU.
ME? WHY? I MEAN,
WHAT HAVE I DONE?
WHY WOULD SOMEBODY HARM ME?
THAT'S WHAT
I'VE BEEN WONDERING.
REMEMBER YOU SAID
YOUR MOTHER KEPT
AN APARTMENT IN TOWN?
SHE BROUGHT ME THERE
ONE FRIDAY, TWO YEARS AGO.
SHE FORGOT SOMETHING
THAT WAS IMPORTANT, SHE SAID.
SO I CAME ALONG.
BUT I STAYED
OUTSIDE THE DOOR.
SHE WENT IN,
WOULDN'T LET ME INSIDE.
I ARGUED. I SAID I JUST
WANTED TO GO IN FOR A WHILE
TO SEE WHERE SHE LIVED.
SHE SLAPPED ME ACROSS THE CHEEK.
IT WAS ONLY ONCE.
THE ONLY TIME SHE HIT ME.
DO YOU STILL
KNOW THE ADDRESS?
WAS YOUR MOTHER
ALWAYS SO ZEN?
SHE WAS PRETTY ORGANIZED.
BUT I MEAN, COME ON!
THEN SOMEONE'S
BEEN HERE ALREADY.
BUT REMOVING FURNITURE?
IT'S TOO MUCH TROUBLE.
THEY WERE AFTER SOMETHING.
BUT THEY DIDN'T
KNOW YOUR MOTHER.
YOUR MOTHER
WOULDN'T HIDE SOMETHING
IN ANOTHER MOVEABLE OBJECT.
[ Hollow Knock ]
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- YOU'LL SEE IN A MINUTE.
OKAY, BUT I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
EXPLAIN WHY MY MOTHER
HIDE THIS IN THE WALL.
'CAUSE THAT'S
PRECISELY WHAT I'D DO.
TELL ME. WHAT IS THIS?
NUMBERS AND NAMES.
NOW I'M STARTING
TO HAVE A COUPLE OF IDEAS.
YEAH, WELL, I'M CONFUSED.
YOU MURDER PEOPLE
AND MAKE HOLES IN THE WALLS,
I JUST LOST MY MOTHER
AND I DON'T KNOW ANY MORE.
YUMI, LOOK, I'M ASKING
FOR YOUR TRUST.
THIS WHOLE NIGHTMARE
WILL SOON END.
ALL RIGHT?
OKAY, LET'S GO.
OH, WELL, AT LEAST
THE FURNITURE
DIDN'T DISAPPEAR.
WHAT ARE THEY AFTER?
NOTHING, IN MY OPINION.
LOOKS TO ME LIKE
SOME KIND OF INTIMIDATION.
THEY SHOULD BE GETTING
IN TOUCH WITH US SOON.
THEN WHAT DO WE DO?
SHOULD WE RUN?
NO. WE SIT DOWN AND WAIT.
AH, WELL, THEY DIDN'T
MAKE ANY "PHOOS."
- ANY WHAT?
- ANY "PHOOS."
- ANY HOLES.
- ANY "HOOS."
NO, IT'S "L, L, L."
- "AHAHL?"
- "LE, LE, LE."
"ACHH."
WATCH ME. "L."
- "ELCH?"
- "LLLLLLLLLE."
"ELLLL."
GOOD. AND NOW,
"O" AS IN "GO."
"OOOOOO."
"OOOO."
- "OOO."
- GREAT. HOLE.
HOLE.
GREAT. TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
-[ Phone Ringing ]
- HOL--
HELLO?
WELCOME TO JAPAN.
THANKS.
MY NAME IS
KAZUHIRO KATANAWA.
BUT I GUESS THAT
MEANS NOTHING TO YOU.
NOTHING AT ALL.
I'D LIKE VERY MUCH
TO MEET YOU, MR. FIORENTINI.
IF YOU CAN SPARE
A FEW MINUTES.
WITH PLEASURE.
HOLE.
I WAS TOLD THAT
YOU LIKE TO PLAY GOLF.
I FIND IT
VERY PLEASANT, YEAH.
SO DO I.
LET'S PLAY A ROUND TOGETHER.
MY MEN ARE DOWNSTAIRS.
THEY WILL DRIVE YOU.
THAT'S FINE.
HOLES.
THAT'S BETTER.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
I'M INVITED
TO PLAY GOLF.
YOU'RE GOING GOLFING
AT A MOMENT LIKE THIS?
IT HELPS YOU TO GET
PERSPECTIVE ON THINGS.
AND BESIDES, IN GOLF, YOU GOT--
HOLES.
AH.
- "HOOS."
- FORGET ABOUT IT.
- COULD YOU HAVE
THE ROOM MADE UP?
- RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
HUBERT!
LOOK, HUBERT! HUBERT.
CLEAN OUT YOUR EARS.
- I GOT EVERYTHING.
- MOMO, WE GOT FRIENDS
WAITING FOR US AT THE DOOR.
TEN FOUR. I GOT THE STUFF
ON MIKO. AND HER NAILS.
I HAVE ALL THE RESULTS.
TAKE THIS AND DON'T LOOSE IT.
FOLLOW US AT A DISTANCE.
ANY TROUBLE, YOU GOT US COVERED.
[ Starter Firing ]
COME ON,
YOU MOTHERFUCKER. START.
HUBERT--
I, UH--
SHOOT.
[ Starter Firing ]
???? [ Guitar ]
?? STARS SHINE ??
?? NEVER GONNA FIND ME ??
?? WHERE YOU GONNA FIND ME ??
OH, NO. COME ON.
YOU LOOK LIKE AN AMATEUR.
USE THE PROPER STANCE.
?? NEVER GONNA FIND ME ????
ADDRESS THE BALL.
YOU LOOK LIKE A DUCK
WHO'S ABOUT TO MATE.
AT LEAST KEEP
YOUR EYE ON THE BALL.
LOOK AT THAT.
GOLFING ON PLAYSTATION
IS MORE FOR YOU.
YOU WON'T LOOSE
A LOT OF BALLS, ANYWAY.
YOU PLAY VERY WELL,
SO I'VE HEARD.
WELL, I DON'T USUALLY MISS.
- THEY TELL ME YOU ARE SO GOOD
IT'S DANGEROUS.
- LET'S NOT GO CRAZY.
COULD I PREVAIL ON YOU
TO GIVE ME A DEMONSTRATION?
WHY HAVE YOU RETURNED?
WHY COME BACK TO JAPAN
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS?
- MEMORIES AREN'T BAD ENOUGH?
- AFTER A FEW YEARS,
YOU REMEMBER ONLY THE GOOD.
ISN'T WHAT BROUGHT YOU
TO JAPAN, IN REALITY,
A VERY HUGE SUM?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
ABOUT THE $200 MILLION
YOU DISCOVERED THIS AFTERNOON
IN YOUR DAUGHTER'S ACCOUNT.
MY FATHER?
BASTARD! I HATE YOU!
YOU LIAR!
YUMI, CALM DOWN.
YOU DIRTY LIAR!
I HATE YOU!
CALM DOWN, YUMI.
I TRIED TO TELL YOU,
BUT YOU HATE SO MUCH
YOU WOULDN'T LISTEN.
TO YOU? THE JERK WHO
ABANDONED MY MOTHER AND ME?
NO, YOUR MOTHER ABANDONED ME.
SHE JUST DISAPPEARED
ONE DAY WITHOUT A WORD.
AND NO ONE TOLD ME
YOU EXISTED UNTIL
THE READING OF THE WILL.
IF I KNEW I HAD SUCH
A GREAT DAUGHTER,
I'D HAVE COME RIGHT BACK.
AND NOTHING COULD
HAVE TAKEN YOUR MOTHER
AND YOU AWAY FROM ME.
I NEED YOU TO BELIEVE THAT.
MY FATHER--
MY BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTER.
SO TOUCHING.
SORRY TO DELAY THIS
WARM REUNION BETWEEN
BELOVED DAUGHTER AND HER FATHER.
I ASK YOU TO GIVE BACK
OUR MONEY NOW--
BUT EVEN YUMI CAN'T
WITHDRAW IT FROM THE BANK.
IT'S FROZEN UNTIL
SHE REACHES... MAJORITY.
WHICH SHE WILL REACH
IN AROUND NINE HOURS.
WE CAN ALL GO
TO THE BANK AT 10:00.
THE BIRTHDAY OF A DAUGHTER
IS A FINE THING.
CONGRATULATIONS.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
FATHER! FATHER!
WAIT.
THIS IS A PRETTY DIFFICULT SHOT.
BUT WHEN YOU GET IT RIGHT,
YOU CAN KNOCK 'EM DEAD.
[ Shouts ]
NOBODY MOVE!
FRENCH ARMY INTELLIGENCE!
[ Coughing ]
SHIT--
HUBERT,
Y-YOU ALL RIGHT?
IT'S TOO BAD.
YOU ONLY GOT HERE
A FEW SECONDS TOO LATE.
OH, MAN--
THE GRENADE.
WHAT? WHAT GRENADE?
I TOOK THE PIN OUT.
HELL OF A GRENADE.
NO, I LEFT
THE CASE IN THE TRUCK.
I GUESS THEY WENT OFF.
- SO WHAT DID YOU FIND?
-MIKO LEFT THE CONSULATE 19
YEARS AGO ON MATERNITY LEAVE.
SHE NEVER WENT BACK TO WORK.
AND HER WHOLE FILE DISAPPEARED.
BUT THE DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE
AT THE SAME TIME
OPENS A NEW FILE.
ONLY IT'S TOP SECRET.
I COULDN'T GET
MY HANDS ON IT.
HOWEVER,
I GOT PICTURES.
THESE ARE FROM MIKO'S FILE?
THEY LOOK LIKE WEDDING PICTURES.
LOOK CLOSELY. THE GROOM.
HE'S THE SON OF A YAKUZA HEAVY
HITTER. BIGGEST IN THE NORTH.
KATANAWA, ALSO KNOWN AS
"THE ZEBRA." HE'S GOT A--
- YEAH, RIGHT,
HE'S GOT A SCAR.
- Y-YOU KNOW THE GUY?
ONCE PLAYED GOLF
WITH HIM. GO ON.
IN THE BACK, SECOND ROW.
- MIKO?
- MIKO. SO WHAT'S MIKO
DOING WITH THOSE FIENDS?
MIKO WAS SO HONEST.
I DON'T GET IT.
HANG ON. I'M NOT FINISHED.
MIKO IS IN WITH THE MAFIA.
THE SAME MIKO,
ONLY TWO WEEKS LATER,
GETS THE MINISTER'S AWARD...
FOR DISTINGUISHED SERVICE
IN A CLOSED-DOOR CEREMONY.
- WORKING UNDERCOVER.
- FOR THE GOVERNMENT.
THAT EXPLAINS WHY
SHE NEVER WENT BACK TO WORK.
INFILTRATE...
THE YAKUZAS IN ORDER
TO DESTROY THEM.
BUT IT WAS IMPORTANT
TO LEAVE HER PAST BEHIND
AND ME WITH IT.
A SACRIFICE SHE MADE...
FOR HER COUNTRY.
YOU WOULD HAVE DONE IT
IN HER SHOES.
I PROBABLY WOULD.
THE REST IS SIMPLE.
SHE DOES SOME GOOD WORK.
PUTS A FEW PEOPLE AWAY
BEFORE GETTING DISCOVERED.
HER GOAL IS TO MAKE SURE
THE ZEBRA WILL CRUMBLE.
SO SHE PUTS HIS MONEY SOMEPLACE
WHERE I CAN UNDERSTAND
AND FINISH THE JOB.
- IF I WERE YOU,
I'D BE CAREFUL WITH THAT.
- SURE, BUT--
I STILL FEEL THERE IS
SOMETHING MISSING.
WHAT'S THAT?
I DON'T KNOW, BUT--
WHY'D SHE WAIT SO LONG
TO TELL ME I WAS A FATHER?
MAYBE SHE DIDN'T
WANT YOU TO BE AWARE
OF THAT STUFF AND...
THEN WHEN THEY MADE HER,
IT PUT YOUR DAUGHTER IN DANGER.
- SHE KNEW YOU WOULD PROVIDE
FOR THE PROTECTION OF YUMI.
- HER PROTECTION?
YEAH, BECAUSE YOU KNOW YUMI.
SHE KNEW VERY WELL THAT...
IF I WASN'T THERE, SHE'D SPEND
THE 200 MILLION OVERNIGHT.
- TELL ME, WHAT'S THE NAME
OF THIS STUFF?
- WASABI.
REAL GOOD.
REALLY. DELICIOUS.
[ Chokes ]
[ Hiccups ]
[ Gags, Drinks ]
DID THE DIRT UNDER HER NAILS
GIVE YOU SOME LOCATION?
[ Squeaks ]
[ Gurgles ]
[ Gibberish ]
- KYOTO.
- KYOTO!
OF COURSE!
THAT'S WHERE IT BEGAN, WHERE
I DECLARED MY LOVE TO MIKO.
AND NOW I KNOW WHY
THAT'S WHERE IT ENDS.
WE HAVE TO GO.
[ Man On P.A.
Speaking Japanese ]
[ Woman On P.A. ]
KYOTO. KYOTO.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
HURRY, WE HAVE TO BE
BACK IN TOKYO BEFORE 10:00.
[ Woman's Voice ]
DEAREST HUBERT,
I SACRIFICED MY LIFE
FOR MY COUNTRY
AND NOW I REGRET IT.
I WISH I HAD SPENT
ALL THE YEARS AT YOUR SIDE
EVEN THOUGH, IN A WAY, I DID.
BECAUSE YOU WERE ALWAYS SORT OF
WITH ME. YOU REMAINED IN MY
HEART, AND YOU ALWAYS WILL.
TAKE GOOD CARE OF OUR DAUGHTER.
SHE'S WONDERFUL, BUT SHE SPENDS
TOO MUCH MONEY.
HERE'S THE PIN NUMBER,
SO YOU CAN KEEP AN EYE
ON HER ACCOUNTS.
THERE SHOULD NOW BE ENOUGH
MONEY FOR YOU AND OUR DAUGHTER
TO LIVE COMFORTABLY.
IT ISN'T MUCH COMPENSATION
OF COURSE,
BUT I HOPE OUR DAUGHTER
WILL MAKE ALL THOSE
BAD MEMORIES GO AWAY.
LOOKING BACK THOUGH,
AREN'T ALL MEMORIES GOOD?
YOURS FOREVER,
MIKO.
ANY OF THE OLD GUYS
STILL UP HERE?
ALMOST ALL OF THEM,
THE ONES WHO ARE LIVING.
LET'S GET EVERYBODY WE CAN.
[ Yumi Yells ]
[ Slap ]
AH!
[ Speaking Japanese ]
CAPTAIN YASUMOTO, PLEASE.
OH, HELLO.
DEPOSIT OR WITHDRAWAL?
A WITHDRAWAL.
CASH OR
BANK-TO-BANK TRANSFER?
BANK-TO-BANK.
FINE. HERE WE GO.
REAL SIMPLE. ON THE LEFT
YOU PUT THE NUMBER
OF THE ACCOUNT YOU'RE FILLING.
AND ON THE RIGHT,
THE ONE YOU'RE EMPTYING.
- I SUPPOSE YOU CAN
HANDLE THAT, RIGHT?
- RIGHT.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
"LAUSANNE." "LAUSANNE--"
IS THAT IN SWITZERLAND?
- SWITZERLAND, YES.
- THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
- WE HAVE NO TIME.
HURRY UP, PLEASE.
- OF COURSE, SIR. RIGHT AWAY.
[ Typing ]
[ Typing Continues ]
ALL DONE!
NOW HOW MUCH
ARE WE TRANSFERRING?
- ALL.
- CLOSING BOTH ACCOUNTS?
RIGHT. CLOSE BOTH ACCOUNTS.
- YEAH, YOU COULD BUY A LOT
OF POONTANG WITH THAT.
- BUY WHAT?
NO, I FIGURE IT'S, UH--
$200 MILLION IS ENOUGH
TO BUY SOME GOOD TIMES.
I-IT'S A FAIR AMOUNT.
HERE. UH--
YOU ARE OF AGE?
YES. SHE TURNED 20 THIS MORNING.
VERY GOOD, MY FRIENDS.
HOW 'BOUT SIGNING THEN?
[ Under Breath ]
SIGN IT.
[ Chuckles ]
SIGN IT!
THAT'S ALL! FINISHED.
MANY HAPPY RETURNS, YUMI.
GIVE ME A RECEIPT.
STOP FOOLING AROUND.
AH, NO, NO.
THE RECEIPTS, UH--
THE RECEIPTS ARE RIGHT HERE.
T-THE RECEIPTS
ARE THAT GUY.
UH-UH. IF I WERE YOU,
I'D THINK TWICE ABOUT THAT.
[ Yelling Japanese ]
IF YOU HOPE TO LEAVE THIS BANK
UNHARMED, YOUR FRIEND
BETTER LOWER THAT WEAPON.
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO WILL HAVE TROUBLE
LEAVING HERE UNHARMED.
YOU WIN,
MR. FIORENTINI. GOOD PLAY.
TO BE A WINNER,
YOU HAVE TO LOSE SOME HANDS.
WHAT'S YOUR PRICE?
I'LL PAY IT.
YOU CAN'T AFFORD
TO PAY MY PRICE.
ALL THE MONEY'S
NOW IN MY ACCOUNT.
I'M SORRY TO RUIN YOUR PLANS.
SO LONG, $200 MILLION, HUH?
YUMI, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
COME HERE.
[ Man On P.A. Indistinct ]
[ Chattering ]
I SHOWED YOU WHAT
I CAN DO IN GOLF.
WITH THIS MOTHER,
I AM EVERY BIT AS GOOD A SHOT.
HAVE YOUR MEN
SURRENDER THEIR WEAPONS.
[ Speaking Japanese ]
[ Man On Loudspeaker
Speaking Japanese ]
[ Speaking Japanese ]
IT'S OKAY. IT'S OVER.
[ Breathes In, Out ]
OKAY, COME ON.
- HEY, WAIT FOR ME.
- [ Speaking Japanese ]
- THIS MUST BE A DREAM.
- DOES KATANAWA
MEAN ANYTHING TO YOU?
- YES, OF COURSE.
- YOU'LL FIND HIM INSIDE
LYING DOWN.
HE AND A FEW OF HIS MEN
WERE TRYING A HOLDUP
SO I... DISSUADED THEM.
WHEN'S YOUR VACATION OVER,
MR. FIORENTINI? SO WE CAN
HAVE OUR COUNTRY BACK.
[ Chattering In Japanese ]
GO AHEAD.
IT'S ALL, UH--
WELL, YOU'LL SEE.
YES?
EXCUSE ME.
MR. FIORENTINI'S
OUT OF THE RED.
IT'S ABOUT TIME TOO.
- [ Coughing ]
200 MILLION EUROS?
- [ Whimpering ]
[ Woman on P.A. Indistinct ]
THANKS FOR THE POLICE ESCORT.
BUT I DON'T NEED
ALL THIS PROTECTION.
WELL, IT'S NOT
FOR YOUR PROTECTION.
IT'S FOR EVERYONE AROUND YOU.
THANKS FOR COMING.
IT'S DONE ME A LOT OF GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
- NOW IT'S YOUR TURN TO VISIT.
- FOR THIS MUCH FUN,
I'LL BE THERE. HERE.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- IT'S WASABI.
YOU SEEMED TO ENJOY IT.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT LIKE IT
WITH PANCAKES OR EGGS.
THAT'S NICE, MOMO. THANKS.
- I'M LEAVING HER IN YOUR HANDS.
- SURE. I KNOW. DON'T WORRY.
I JUST GOT A FATHER SO I WASN'T
PREPARED FOR GIVING HIM
A TEARFUL GOOD-BYE.
TWO DAYS AGO YOU WANTED
TO MURDER ME. NOW YOU
WEEP BECAUSE I'M GOING?
A TYPICAL TEENAGER.
I CRY VERY OFTEN.
AND I CHANGE MY MIND A LOT.
HERE, I HAVE
SOMETHING FOR YOU.
I DIDN'T HAVE TIME
TO GO SHOPPING, BUT--
IT WAS YOUR MOTHER'S.
I KEPT IT FOR 20 YEARS
BUT NOW I WANT YOU TO TAKE IT.
ONE MONTH. DON'T WORRY,
IT'S ONE MONTH. YOU JUST
FINISH THIS SCHOOL YEAR.
I'LL GET THE PAPER
WITH THE EXPLOSION
FOR YOUR ROOM AND THAT'S IT.
YES, BUT IT'S GONNA BE
THE LONGEST MONTH OF MY LIFE.
WELL, FOR ME,
IT'LL BE JUST AS LONG.
[ Blows ]
- NO PROBLEM, SIR.
GO AHEAD. HAVE A GOOD TRIP.
- THANK YOU.
[ Exhales ]
NEWSPAPERS, SIR?
OR SOME CHAMPAGNE?
NO, THANKS.
BUT IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I DON'T WANNA BE DISTURBED.
NO PROBLEM, SIR.
YOUR ATTENTION, EVERYONE!
WHERE IS THE PERSON
WHO REGISTERED THIS?
OH, NO.
???? [ Pop ]
[ Man ]
THIS RECORDING IS A COLLECTION
OF UNINTENDED INDISCRETIONS...
BEFORE MICROPHONE AND CAMERA.
???? [ Women Singing In Japanese
]
???? [ Techno ]
[ Woman ]
??YOU'VE GOT QUESTIONS
ABOUT WHEN AND WHY, MY BABY ??
?? YOU NEED SO MUCH TASTE
TO GET YOU BY, WHATEVER ??
?? NO TIME TO SPARE
HANGIN' TIGHT, BABY, TONIGHT ?
?
?? OH, OH, YEAH ??
?? NO ONE CAN GIVE YOU
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN LOOKIN' FOR
NOBODY ??
?? WE MUST BE PATIENT
FOR A KNOCK ON THE DOOR
OH, BABY ??
?? BREAK OUT YOUR SOUL
OPEN MY HEART ??
?? THAT'S HOW IT STARTS
WE'RE TWO HEARTS ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? LET'S PICK UP THE PIECES
WITH THE POWERS THAT BE ??
?? IT COMES FROM HEAVEN ABOVE ??
?? A LITTLE OLD THING
WE JUST CALL LOVE ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? 'CAUSE I NEED YOU THERE
TO RESCUE ME ??
?? WHENEVER I'VE LOST FAITH
REMIND ME WE STILL GOT LOVE ??
?? YOU DIDN'T ASK TO BE
INVITED, BABY ??
?? AND I SEE YOU DON'T WANNA GO
WELL, TELL ME ??
?? I KNOW THAT FEELING
'CAUSE I'VE BEEN THERE ??
?? JUST LIKE YOU ??
?? OH, OH, YEAH ??
?? THOUGHTS MAY BE CRASHING
AND BRIGHT LIGHTS FLASHING
TELL ME ??
?? THANK GOD THERE'S PEOPLE
LIKE YOU AND ME, MY DARLING ??
?? LET'S CHECK OUT
THE MODERN YOU ??
?? I WANT YOU TO ??
??  OH, OH, YEAH ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? LET'S PICK UP THE PIECES
WITH THE POWERS THAT BE ??
?? IT COMES FROM HEAVEN ABOVE ??
?? A LITTLE OLD THING
WE JUST CALL LOVE ??
?? NO TURNING BACK ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? 'CAUSE I NEED YOU THERE
TO RESCUE ME ??
?? WHENEVER I'VE LOST FAITH
REMIND ME ??
?? WE STILL GOT LOVE ??
?? LET'S KEEP IT ON TRACK ??
?? DON'T HAVE TO WAIT
TILL TOMORROW ??
?? DON'T HAVE TO
SUCK UP THE SORROW ??
?? IF WE HAVE TO
BEG, STEAL OR BORROW ??
?? AND NO TURNING BACK ??
?? LET'S GIVE IN AND TRY ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? LET'S PICK UP THE PIECES
WITH THE POWERS THAT BE ??
?? IT COMES FROM HEAVEN ABOVE
THAT LITTLE OLD THING
WE JUST CALL LOVE ??
?? NO TURNING BACK ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? LET'S PICK UP THE PIECES
WITH THE POWERS THAT BE ??
?? IT COMES FROM HEAVEN ABOVE
THAT LITTLE OLD THING
WE JUST CALL LOVE ??
?? NO TURNING BACK ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? LET'S PICK UP THE PIECES
WITH THE POWERS THAT BE ??
?? IT COMES FROM HEAVEN ABOVE
THAT LITTLE OLD THING
WE JUST CALL LOVE ??
?? NO TURNING BACK ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? 'CAUSE I NEED YOU THERE
TO RESCUE ME ??
?? WHENEVER I'VE LOST FAITH
REMIND ME ??
?? WE STILL GOT LOVE ??
?? LET'S KEEP IT ON TRACK ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? LET'S PICK UP THE PIECES
WITH THE POWERS THAT BE ??
?? IT COMES FROM HEAVEN ABOVE
THAT LITTLE OLD THING
WE JUST CALL LOVE ??
?? NO TURNING BACK ??
?? FOLLOW ME
FOLLOW ME ??
?? 'CAUSE I NEED YOU THERE
TO RESCUE ME ????