[♪]
[BLONDIE'S "HEART OF GLASS"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ Once I had a love
And it was a gas ♪
♪ Soon turned out
Had a heart of glass ♪
♪ Seemed like the real thing
Only to find ♪
♪ Mucho mistrust
Love's gone behind ♪
♪ Once I had a love
And it was divine ♪
♪ Soon found out
I was losing my mind ♪
♪ It seemed like the real thing
But I was so blind ♪
♪ Mucho mistrust
Love's gone behind ♪
♪ In between
♪ What I find is pleasing
And I'm feeling fine... ♪
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[MOANING]
MAN:
Bobby!
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Bobby, are you in there
with Amada?
Bobby!
Oh, Jumbo.
I'll be out in a second, Jumbo!
You gotta come out here.
There's chicks dancing naked
right in the bar, in the lobby.
Unbelievable.
We gotta go.
What?
Oh, fuck, I forgot.
Bob!
Fucking animal.
I gotta ask Mr. Buzhayev
if we can take the night off.
I love you.
I'm gonna run across the street.
Meet me at the car, okay?
Okay. Go.
Amada...
I'm the luckiest man
on the planet.
If I died right now,
I'd be happy.
[ALL CHEERING]
MAN: Hey, Mr. Green,
thanks for hooking me up, man.
How are you?
MAN 2: Hey, Bobby.
Hey.
You got the best club
in Brooklyn, man.
Just wait till I take over
Manhattan, baby.
Do me a favor. Give 'em
a couple of drinks, all right?
[MEN CONVERSING IN RUSSIAN]
♪ Once I had a love
And it was a gas ♪
♪ Soon turned out
To be a pain in the ass... ♪
Hey, baby, give me my purse.
I'm meeting the family tonight.
Uh-oh.
[CHUCKLES]
Hey, I don't want Coco paying
for his shit tonight.
Not after that little mix-up
we had last weekend, ladies.
All Right.
Bye.
Bye, Amada.
Good luck, girl.
MAN:
Take it off! Take it off!
[CHUCKLES]
Hey!
Hey, get the fuck down
from there!
Hey, you!
Get the fuck down!
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
Calm down.
Let's give 'em space.
Good looking out, Jumbo.
No problem, Bob.
MAN:
Oh, what the fuck!
Don't strain yourself.
JUMBO: You got it.
Looks like everything's
under control.
I'm gonna go take
my break now.
I didn't do nothin'.
Come on, look at you.
You're bleeding
all over the place.
Go home.
Freddie, take him home.
Go easy on 'em, Jumbo.
Hey, Cortez, I'm going across
the street to see the boss.
Bring my car around.
You got it.
I'll be right back.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
[GASPS]
Hi, Kalina.
Look at you.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
Want to go with me to the club?
Do a little dance?
[LAUGHING]
BOBBY:
Hi, everybody.
Hey, Bobby.
BOBBY:
Hey, Mr. Buzhayev, how are you?
Look, she got the watch.
Oh, yeah, it's great.
I told you.
He's the best.
Yeah.
I know deals.
Digital.
Yeah, it's great.
Hey, listen, I gotta go
do something tonight,
but Freddie will watch
the place
and he'll make the night drop
for you later.
Good. So how is my club doing?
Everything's fine.
Good.
For me? Just this one.
Amada tells me
I put on 5 pounds
every time I come over here.
I'm telling you,
you guys are fattening me up.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
Good?
Mmm.
Excellent.
Always. Real good.
Listen, Bobby...
Mm?
Next week you come by, we talk.
We talk about plans for you.
We like what you do
at the club very much.
Yeah?
Yeah.
All right.
Good.
KALINA: Something more?
More? I just said
I can't eat it.
I can't even eat this.
I can't have another bite.
What are you doing to me?
Oh, no, no, Amada's waiting.
I have to go.
You're too good to me.
Why do I deserve this?
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
No, I gotta go.
Where?
Where you run off to?
[LOUIS PRIMA'S "SHOULD I"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
It's my bike. Don't!
Stop it!
BOY: It's mine too.
No, you can't do that.
You can't push me away.
It's mine. Okay?
I can't see--
♪ Would I?
♪ Could I?
♪ Should I?
Keep doing better, okay?
Thank you, thank you.
Take care.
SPIRO: Your right.
Your right.
Keep it up. Keep the guard--
Careful.
Sorry, babe. Keep--
BURT:
Joseph.
All right, hey, hey, hey.
Quit fooling around
over there.
Did he bag it?
No, he never did.
His gun jammed,
so he started crying.
That's terrible. A nine-point?
Joseph, come on.
Pop's calling. Look...
What?
we'll go to Metropole next week,
cut loose a little.
You got it.
BURT: Come over here.
SPIRO [LAUGHING]:
Gotcha.
JOSEPH:
What's up?
BURT: Get your picture taken.
It's your big night.
JOSEPH:
We took them already.
The more the better.
Get your face out there.
Stevie, come here, buddy.
The P.C. will see this
in the magazine, all right?
All right.
Use it, it's good.
Good.
Thanks, chief.
Go over there to Mommy,
all right?
It's almost 11.
Where's your brother?
If he comes at all,
he'll come late, Pop.
You know him.
Yeah.
AMADA:
Baby.
There's cops all around.
They're all fucking drunk.
Give me some.
I'm nervous.
Don't be nervous.
They're harmless.
Jumbo came through.
It's good, right?
[MOANS]
Yeah, it's good. Okay.
You coming?
Do we have to?
I don't know if I can
fucking deal with them tonight.
Come on, honey.
It's your family.
You gotta support 'em.
Hey, remember
what I told you, right?
Nobody at the club knows about
my family. Not even Jumbo.
I know. Baby, I'm not gonna
say anything. Come on.
Last thing I need is anybody
thinking I'm a fucking cop.
[LAUGHS]
Never happen, baby.
I could be a cop.
What do you have to do?
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Freeze. All right, spread 'em.
Spread 'em.
[IMITATING GUNFIRE]
Ah! Get him!
Get him, get him!
BOBBY: Arrest her.
Where you going?
AMADA:
Just kidding, officers.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Oh, shit, look at this.
Bobby. Bobby Grusinsky.
[LAUGHING]
Is that you?
It's me, Russ De Keifer
from across Union Turnpike.
How you doing?
All right.
Hey, you still bartending
at the Russian joint?
No, I'm managing it now.
I got to go down.
Listen to you.
Did he just call you
"Grusinsky"?
Talk to you later, man.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Oh, my God.
[LOUIS PRIMA'S "I AIN'T GOT
NOBODY" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
That's them.
In the corner there.
Hey, Pop.
Mm?
They don't look that bad,
though, for cops.
[BOTH LAUGH]
All right, let's go.
He's got company.
Give me a break.
Here comes trouble.
Look at you.
You came.
Congratulations,
you're moving up.
Mr. Big Shot honors us
with his presence.
At your service.
You look great.
Hey, everybody, this is
my girlfriend, Amada.
That's my father...
AMADA: Nice to meet you.
Chief Burt Grusinsky.
My brother, Joe.
Hi.
That's Michael and Jack.
BOBBY:
You guys look good.
You put up with this guy?
Hey, I'm a Leo.
I can put up with anything.
[AMADA LAUGHS]
If you got a minute,
we'd like to talk to you.
Yeah, let's get a drink first.
No, no, no, right now.
It's only gonna take a minute.
BURT: Upstairs in the church.
"Right now."
Come on.
JOSEPH: Don't worry. We'll
bring him back in one piece.
BOBBY: That's a great crowd
you got down there, Joe.
You know all the right people.
MICHAEL: That's a nice
suit you got, Bobby.
Was that funny?
I didn't know you had a sense
of humor, Michael. I like it.
How much that earring
set you back?
What?
You heard what I said.
Bobby, I asked Pop
to bring you up here.
Bobby, please.
I'm serious.
Why? What's the matter?
Well, I'll be heading up
this new narcotics team
starting this week.
Russian unit
out of PSA-One in Brighton.
What--? Heh.
You brought me up here
to tell me that?
Do any of you fucking guys
talk?
You ever say anything
back there?
I'm old-fashioned.
I listen first.
Oh, God.
Excuse me.
JOSEPH: We're looking at
this guy, Vadim Nezhinski.
Served time
in the Soviet Union
for black-market activity,
come over around 1979.
He's dealing H,
cocaine, angel dust.
This guy's bringing in
major weight
and we need to track it.
He's operating out of that spot
you manage, the El Caribe.
Oh, I don't know nothing
about that. I'm not--
No, we know. We checked
the rest of the management too,
his uncle, the owner.
The old man?
Well, he is his uncle.
What, you been
fuckin' watching me too?
Everybody else came up clean.
It's just Nezhinski
we're looking at.
You want me to inform?
No.
Are you kidding me?
Just observe, that's all.
It's a closed community.
You're our only way in
right now.
Great. Look, you guys are
the fucking cops.
Why are you coming to me? Why--
Why is this my problem?
The whole city's falling apart.
Don't you have any sense
of responsibility at all?
Let me think.
No. No, not really. I don't.
I got enough
fucking problems, Joe.
JOSEPH: The streets are
in fucking chaos, Bobby.
Our guys are dropping
like flies.
Joseph, come on. I--
Joseph, you go downstairs.
Let me talk to him, all right?
JOSEPH:
Yeah, thanks for coming.
It's always a pleasure.
Thank you.
You better be careful out there
the next couple weeks.
What's that supposed to mean?
Oh, you know.
Joseph.
Fine, Pop. You fucking deal
with him.
Take care, Bobby.
Yeah.
Move over. Move over.
Been a long time
since we've seen you.
Your brother says you don't
answer the phone anymore.
Ah, I've been busy, Pop.
That's all.
Yeah?
What's going on
with you?
You can't talk?
I don't know.
You what?
Things are all right.
You're all right?
Yeah.
Yeah?
You know, I could've, uh,
gotten you a good job with us.
A safe job.
If you would have asked.
If you'd been around.
I got a job.
A good job.
That's the whole point
of this conversation we had.
That's why your brother
was here, because of this club.
And your brother says that
you've been using
your mother's name these days.
Yeah, just for the business.
You know, it's-- It's easy.
"Bobby Green"?
Well, people can pronounce it,
you know?
Puerto Rican
you brought.
She been hooking you up?
[CHUCKLES]
What do you mean?
Come on,
I can smell it on you.
You keep laughing.
Your mother, rest in peace,
I think she was too easy on you.
All right.
I got to go, Pop.
Bobby,
let me tell you
something.
Sooner or later,
either you're gonna be with us
or you're gonna be
with the drug dealers.
This is like a war out there.
Now,
do you understand that?
Do you?
[CHUCKLES]
I'll see you.
Careful.
[TITO PUENTE'S "MAMBO DIABLO"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
It's getting late. How are
the kids doing? They tired yet?
They're always tired.
They worry about you
when you're out at night.
Baby, sit up straight.
Baby, do me a favor.
Don't start, all right?
[FEEDBACK RINGING]
Excuse me, everybody.
Can I have your attention,
please?
Hi, my name is Deputy
Commissioner Spiro Giavannis
and we're here
this holiday season
to honor one
of our new leaders...
Let's get out of here
and go party with Jumbo.
Why?
Baby, your family don't like me,
I don't care.
I'm here for you, okay?
Fuck them. Let's go.
It's boring.
Fuck them, they're stiffs. Yeah.
Heh. Really?
And I'm sure the chief
would like to say a few words.
So I'd like to bring him
up here now. Chief?
[ALL CHEERING]
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
You know,
I used to tell my kids,
"Work first, play later."
And my son Joseph
really took that to heart.
Been a real fighter
over the years.
He overcome the dyslexia
and eventually wound up
graduating John Jay
as salutatorian,
and hey...
I-I'm very proud here tonight.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CLEARS THROAT]
I want to thank
you all for coming.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Uh, before I say
anything else,
one of our brothers was killed
in the line of duty last night.
[OVER SPEAKERS] Detective
Edward Conlon was gunned down
serving a warrant
on Northern Boulevard.
Hey. Come here.
The clock is about
to strike 11.
I thought
we might be able
to give a moment
of silence to remember.
[CHURCH BELL TOLLING
IN DISTANCE]
[THE CLASH'S "MAGNIFICENT SEVEN"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
AMADA:
Come on, get over here.
Which one?
Come on, I'm meeting
with Buzhayev tonight.
Which one? This one?
That one. Hey, baby.
I got good news.
Yeah?
So I, um-- I talked
to my mom yesterday.
And she's feeling better.
So I can move in
whenever I want.
Really?
Don't joke with me.
I'm not.
I like it. I like it.
It's official. You get your side
of the bed, I get mine.
Seriously,
it's great news.
Hey, I got you something.
What?
You've been working
so hard lately.
[BOTH LAUGH]
What is it?
Open it up.
Now?
Open it, open it.
It's nice.
I like it.
Thank you.
I love you so much.
I love you too, babe.
We'll have a lot of kids...
big house.
Yeah?
Can we get big kids
and a lot of houses?
Mm-hm.
JUMBO: Hey, Bobby!
Get your ass out here.
Pobably Jumbo.
Come on, let's go hang out
with them for a minute.
Everybody, the life
of the party is here.
MAN: Hey, Falsetti, you
get what we wanted?
Absolutely. I got a little of
what everybody asked for here.
I got uppers, I got downers.
Hash, mescaline, some blow.
The troops require sustenance.
Oh, ho-ho!
♪ So get back to work
And sweat some more ♪
♪ The sun will sink
And we'll get out the door ♪
♪ It's no good for man
To work in cages ♪
♪ Hit the town
He drinks his wages ♪
♪ You're frettin'
You're sweatin' ♪
♪ But did you notice
You ain't gettin'? ♪
♪ You're frettin'
You're sweatin' ♪
♪ But did you know
It's not getting anywhere? ♪
♪ Don't you ever stop
Long enough to start? ♪
♪ To take your car
Outta that gear ♪
♪ Don't you ever stop
Long enough to start? ♪
♪ Get your car
Outta that gear ♪
♪ Karl Marx
And Friedrich Engels ♪
♪ Came to the checkout
At the 7-11 ♪
♪ Marx was skint
But he had sense ♪
♪ Engels lent him
The necessary pence... ♪
ALL:
Go! Go! Go!
You gotta get dressed.
Come on, get dressed.
You can't be late
for your boss, baby.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
[GROUP CHATTERING
IN RUSSIAN]
GIRL:
Bobby!
Hello, how are you?
I thought you could ride.
Not riding so good.
You don't ride bareback,
do you?
How are you?
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
Bobby.
You wouldn't believe
it's 40 degrees out,
line's halfway around the block.
It's unbelievable.
[SPEAKING
IN RUSSIAN]
I'll grab something in a second,
thank you.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
Take kids
in the other room.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
ELI:
Don't worry, kids.
You will see Grandpa on Tuesday
to ride the horses.
[IN RUSSIAN]
Not on the furs!
[IN ENGLISH]
Bobby.
Pop.
Have a seat.
Why? What'd I miss?
Listen, we're thinking
about expanding.
Maybe we'll open another spot
next year across from Brighton.
I like it.
Yeah, good.
And we think you'll run it and
we'll do it exactly like here.
Could be good.
Good?
Good, yeah. Listen...
I've been thinking.
If you want to open
another spot, I mean,
why not try Manhattan?
ELI:
Manhattan's very expensive.
BOBBY: It depends
on where you go.
I mean, you get in there now,
get something for cheap.
I'm talking a big space,
a big warehouse.
You get
different levels going.
We could do something different
on each floor, you know?
Like one floor
could be rock 'n' roll.
Then you do another floor,
you got disco.
Something like that.
[LAUGHING]
[IN RUSSIAN]
Marat, he's got so many ideas.
And don't let your hair-brained
nephew Vadim screw it up.
ELI:
It's a lot of money, Papa.
Your fur business can
support that right now?
[IN ENGLISH]
My son-in-law,
he worries people
take advantage of me.
BOBBY:
I understand that.
But I think we can do
something special, different.
Worst-case scenario,
it's a great investment.
I mean, I think
it's worth looking into.
All right.
So bring some details.
We'll figure out the numbers.
Yeah?
Okay?
Good.
I love you.
[DAVID BOWIE'S "LET'S DANCE"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
JUMBO:
Hey, who is this?
You are in the presence
of the future king of New York.
The future king?
What the fuck you talking about?
Listen, nothing's definite
so don't say anything.
I was just with Mr. Buzhayev.
He's talking about opening
another spot in Manhattan.
He wants me to run it.
I want you, my brother,
to be a host.
[LAUGHING]
Of course!
I'm a people person.
That's my specialty.
I know.
My fucking man.
I'm the "hoster"
with the "moster."
That's beautiful news, Bob.
Beautiful.
Now you'll finally be getting me
all the women I deserve.
What's Amada doing
at Vadim's table?
JUMBO: She's doing what
she's supposed to be doing.
She's charming
the customers.
What do you hear
about him, Jumbo?
I don't know what I hear.
I hear stories.
You hear stories.
Like what?
Stories.
Like last year...
one of his guys
was gonna rat him out.
Cops found his head in
the middle of Brighton Avenue.
Fucking dick was in his mouth.
Sure it wasn't your dick?
Are you sure
it wasn't your mouth?
[LAUGHS]
JUMBO: But I tell you,
Bob, he wouldn't be
running around here
like a king
if his uncle didn't own
the place.
That much I know.
AMADA:
I gotta get back to work.
Yeah, nice talking to you.
Bye.
BOBBY:
I'm gonna talk to Amada.
All right, I'll see you later.
I'll be downstairs.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
I was just telling her how you
stuffed a pill up her nose.
Yeah, that's going
on the wall of shame.
[LAUGHING]
See you later.
Hey, babe, listen,
I don't think you should
be around Vadim so much
right now, okay?
Why? You jealous?
No, I'm not jealous. It's
nothing for you to worry about.
Okay.
I want to tell you about
my meeting with Buzhayev.
[BANGING]
MAN: This is the police!
This is a raid!
Let's go.
[CROWD CLAMORING]
MAN 2: Police!
Fuck.
JOSEPH: Let's find this
motherfucker right now. Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
JOSEPH: Everybody get your
hands on your fucking heads.
Let go of me, man.
Get the fuck down!
[CROWD SCREAMING]
MAN: Empty your pockets!
Oh, jackpot.
Get on the bar.
Hands on the bar.
Who authorized this? Wait.
Tell me who authorized it.
I have the right--
What's the matter?
Don't fucking touch me.
You on something? Come here.
JOSEPH: That's right. Hands on
your fucking head and don't move!
MAN: Hey, easy, easy.
Toss them all, Pudge!
Where is he?
Get on--
Get on the fucking ground!
Give him the charcoal.
Open your fucking mouth!
Who the fuck authorized this?
JOSEPH:
I'm looking for Vadim Nezhinski.
MAN:
He must be on something.
Get the fucking charcoal. What,
you doing a little dust? Huh?
Bring him
the fuck down here now!
Get this piece of shit up.
JOSEPH: Where is he?
MAN 2:
Up here! We got him.
How about some charcoal
to absorb the toxins? Huh?
JOSEPH: Clear some space
here for me, ladies, please.
Turn him, he's gonna puke.
Where's Nezhinski?
MAN: Get this piece of shit up.
Here we go.
JOSEPH:
Give me some space here, please.
MAN:
Get the fuck out of here.
Who else?
MAN 2: Don't you move.
Here we go.
What are you looking at?
Turn your head the other way.
[IN RUSSIAN]
Turn around.
[IN ENGLISH]
What is this?
MAN:
Stay down, stay down.
A tough guy, huh?
What, you want me
to double your money?
Huh?
MAN:
Stay down.
There it is. It's doubled.
How's that?
What are you looking at?
Turn around.
JOSEPH: What else you got
in here, huh, joker?
What about the girls?
Come here.
You got anything in here?
You got a cross
and a Jewish star on you.
What's the matter? You confused?
Not me.
What do you got?
This one's holding.
Couple dimes of cocaine,
some PCP.
Good. You and you,
you're under arrest.
Possession and sale
of narcotics.
[IN RUSSIAN] Talk to them and
we go after your mother.
[IN ENGLISH] What the fuck
did you just say to him?
Nothing.
Your boy's gonna
open up on you.
And when he does,
I'm coming back.
All right. Let's go.
MAN:
Come on!
MAN 2:
Good night, everybody.
Pleasure doing business
with you. Wrap it up.
Let's go.
MAN 3:
Mr. Buzhayev.
Yes?
I'm Captain Jack Shapiro.
Nice to meet you.
This has nothing
to do with you,
but do you have a nephew
named Vadim Nezhinski?
Yes.
SHAPIRO:
Does he have an office here?
MAN: Clean him up
the best we can.
I don't want to get it
all over the car.
You got him dirty,
you clean him up.
Does he have an office here?
No.
Okay.
We'll be in touch.
Thank you.
MAN: Oh, shit!
MAN 2: Oh, my God!
MAN 3: How'd the fuck
did he get out here?
MAN: Get out!
What do you got?
Bringing him in for possession
and resisting arrest.
He's also got $207 on him.
Two-o-seven?
Take him in the back.
Come on. Let's go.
MAN 2:
Who frisked this asshole?
Don't forget the pedigree.
All right.
MAN: We've got to
stop the bleeding.
DESK COP:
What do you got?
He's bleeding
all over the place.
Come on. Don't touch him!
Jesus Christ, what the fuck?
MAN: The Russian guy
cut himself open.
MAN 2:
Where'd he get the blade?
MAN 3:
He had it on him, man.
JOSEPH: Hey, hey. What the
fuck is going on in here?
MAN:
He cut his throat.
MAN 2: He pulled some cutting, man.
Put pressure on him.
Put pressure.
Why are you standing there?
Get us a fucking bus.
All right, all right,
all right.
Shit.
MAN:
Good morning, chief.
You ready to go home?
Or do you have a home?
Your brother wanted me
to let you out.
If it was up to me,
I'd let you stay here
another couple of days
or a week.
Maybe a month.
Do you want me to thank him?
Disgusting.
[LAUGHS]
You're uncontrollable.
You know?
Give him a bath.
I ought to rap you one.
Hey, sign out
with the desk sergeant
before you leave, please.
MICHAEL: The fucking guy
cut his own throat.
Nezhinski must have put
the fear of God in that guy.
Look, that guy knew how they're
bringing the product in. Okay?
Absolutely.
That's the key.
We find the right guy,
we're gonna get him--
We waited till it was
your day off. We had to go.
I'm sorry. That's it.
You had to hit that spot.
Of all the places, you've got
to come to my place?
That's where Nezhinski's
been seen. Okay?
What, are we suppose
to announce it in advance
and compromise the whole thing?
I told you
I'm very sorry. Okay?
Sorry's not good enough.
You don't come in there,
act like you own the place.
Got your fucking guys
putting shit down my throat!
You want me to come in here,
fuck everything up,
push everything around?
Hey, Bobby.
You wouldn't be in shit
if you didn't fuck around.
I wouldn't be in this shit if
you weren't trying to be top cop
and impress everybody!
You know
fucking Nezhinski's guy?
His fucking throat cut open.
Congratulations, Captain Joe.
Good job!
You're above it? Fuck around
with your Puerto Rican?
Grow up and act like a man--
Why don't you try thinking
about my Puerto Rican
while trying to fuck
your fat wife!
How's that?
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Knock it off! Bobby!
BOBBY:
Get off!
Come on!
Get off me!
Don't touch me!
You come at me like that?
I'm done with you.
I don't want to see
your fucking face anymore.
Get out of here!
I'm going home.
It's a fucking holiday.
MAN [OVER RADIO]: Winter, spring,
summer, fall, call 966-7210
for reservations
at Pocono Gardens
and Beautiful Mount Airy Lodge.
Shit.
[♪]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[DOGS BARKING]
BURT:
Jab. Combination.
Come on, dig.
Dig. Come on.
Let's go. Dig.
Dig. Dig. Combination.
Combination.
Jab. Jab. Jab.
Dig. Dig. Dig.
With authority.
Dig. Dig.
Finish it up.
With authority.
That's it. That's it.
Whoo!
Good. Take a rest.
Take a rest.
Hoo.
Chief.
Yeah.
Which kid is it?
It's Joseph.
He's in Jamaica Hospital.
It, uh, don't
look good right now.
MAN: Want us to contact
your other son, chief?
No, I'll do that. Thanks.
You okay, chief?
You guys go on.
I'll be right out.
Thank you.
Chief.
Yo, chief. You all right?
I'm all right.
MAN:
C-note.
[THE SPECIALS' "MESSAGE TO YOU
RUDY" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
MAN 2: Come on, man.
Let's go.
[LAUGHS]
All right, tell you what, José.
I'll see you...
[SNIFFS]
...and I'll bump you two C's.
Oh.
[PHONE RINGING FAINTLY]
Call.
Hello.
BOBBY: Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to introduce you
to José's new friends,
Siegfried and Roy.
Two queens.
[ALL YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
AMADA: Hey, Bobby.
How you like that, huh?
AMADA: Bobby!
What? Hang up on 'em.
What you got?
Come on, you fold
with that?
See, that's what--
It's the police.
All right, all right,
deal again. Deal again.
I'm feeling hot!
José, I thought you knew
how to play poker!
I told him to keep going.
He was gonna pack it in.
Go fuck yourself and just deal
the fucking cards.
Hello.
MICHAEL [OVER PHONE]: Bobby?
Yeah.
Bobby, it's Michael Solo.
I've got some bad news.
[GRUNTS]
It's your brother.
Your brother's been shot,
about an hour ago,
outside his house.
W-what? Who?
Can you hear me?
Your brother's been shot.
He's at Jamaica Hospital.
They're working on him now.
What are you talking about?
I was just with him.
Listen, your father's coming.
I got to go.
But he's at Jamaica. I just
thought you should know.
[LINE CLICKS]
[QUIETLY]
What happened?
My brother was shot.
Oh, my God.
They're operating on him--
They're operating
on him right now. I've got to--
Bobby.
Um...
where are my keys?
They should be on your desk.
I'm gonna go get my coat.
I'm gonna go with you.
No. No.
Stay here-- Stay here tonight.
I'll call you later.
Bobby, I want to go with you.
No. I'll call later.
Bobkes?
Where you going?
MAN:
Deal the cards, man.
[♪]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Pop, Joe going to be all right?
Is he all right?
You got into a fight with him,
I heard.
No.
Well, you got
what you wanted...
and you stayed out of it.
Why would you say that?
The union sent
a shrink over for you.
BURT:
I don't need that crap.
Your Honor.
Chief.
Chief, I'm sorry.
BOBBY:
What happened, Michael? Tell me.
What the fuck is going on?
I'm glad you're here. I want
to tell you how sorry I am.
We'll get 'em, Your Honor. I'll
come back in and run it myself.
The bullet went
into his cheek
and came out his jaw.
It missed his brain,
thank God.
Jesus.
He's very lucky, considering.
Do you know who did it?
No.
Definitely a professional.
They bombed his car.
It's a calling card.
We think it's the Russians.
You know, it's a real shame
we didn't get
to Nezhinski before this.
Are you fucking blaming me?
No.
But I'm not the only one
around here with an opinion.
MICHAEL: Best-case scenario,
doctor says your brother's
gonna have to be here
for at least a couple months.
Anyway, let's just, uh--
Let's just hope
he pulls through.
I'm going to see him.
Easy.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Nobody's allowed in
except immediate family.
I'm his fucking brother!
Take it easy!
Officers, hold on!
Let him in. It's all right.
His nametag says "Green."
It's his brother.
Okay, boss.
[♪]
I'm sorry, Joe.
[SOBBING]
JUMBO: This guy, okay--
He got two queens
and he bumps the guy $200?
And then he wins and where
the fuck do you run off to,
like a Jew, huh?
The place went fucking bananas.
I got to go in there
and straighten things out.
I had to bust some heads
like Bruce Lee.
I'm in there busting
fucking heads. They start--
All right, Jumbo?
Jumbo, do me a favor.
Would you grab the check?
Let's get out of here.
I'm tired.
All right, fine.
I'll go pay the check.
But, Bob, just don't forget
that nobody could ever do
for you what I did.
Busting heads.
Hey, don't say nothing to Jumbo
about what happened, all right?
Of course.
I just thought
he could cheer you up a little,
that's all.
BOBBY:
Thanks.
Look who's here.
AMADA:
Hi, Vadim.
Hey.
We were just about to leave.
How you doing?
I'm all right.
Made it through the bust okay?
I'm here.
Good. Good.
Glad to hear it.
Your uncle's got
some trouble now, though.
You fucked up
the club.
He does what he's got to do,
I do what I got to do.
He don't own me.
He's got grandkids to worry
about, chasing them around.
Hey, baby...
go keep Jumbo company
for a sec, all right?
Nice girl you got there.
PAVEL [IN RUSSIAN]: One is prettier
than the other. He knows everybody.
[IN ENGLISH]
He's pretty popular.
I mean, you must know a whole
network of people out there.
Clubs, everything, huh?
Listen, um...
I got some shit coming in.
And some of us think maybe you
could help us get it out there.
My product needs
a reputation.
A little dangerous right now,
don't you think?
We got a lot
of muscle behind this.
Muscle?
Yeah, that's right.
You know a cop got hit today?
Do you think
that was a coincidence?
[♪]
Well, they're not gonna
s-sit still for that, you know?
PAVEL: Police are a
fucking joke, dude.
Mickey Mouse ain't
gonna do nothing.
Cop got lucky. He zigged
when he should have zagged.
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
You sit with them.
Bobby.
The cops,
they ain't no problem.
So don't worry about it.
We'll get 'em all.
You cut the head off,
the body will fall.
Am I right?
We do it until they get
the message.
We just heard
that cop's father
is going to be
in charge now.
We'll get him too.
We got all their names
on a list.
The chief of police
will be next.
If you change your mind,
call Pavel.
I got a great product.
Why don't you come down
and check it out for yourself?
All right.
MICHAEL:
Well, you're wrong, chief.
We got to make a move.
We got to make a move now.
BURT:
No! We don't go nuts.
MICHAEL:
You heard what Bobby just said.
Nezhinski's got a contract
out on us, Burt.
BURT: I know that.
What do you want to do?
You want to take over
my department?
You want to run it, Michael?
What do you want to do?
I want an answer.
Answer for what?
I have no answers now.
We're looking for him,
all right?
Use your head.
If we go arrest 'em,
they'd be back
on the street in a day.
We got to try and catch 'em
with their hands full,
find out where they got
the real weight,
then we make the move.
We don't have time.
Doesn't matter.
It's the right play.
I say we go hit 'em all.
What?
Wipe 'em out.
No survivors.
Don't be
a first-class schmuck.
SHAPIRO: We don't have
time to infiltrate.
Listen to what--
That is exactly my point.
Then we make the time.
MICHAEL: At whose expense?
Hold on!
I want you all to understand
something, all right?
We don't ever play
in the dirt here.
Not ever, no matter what.
When you piss in your pants,
you can only stay warm
for so long.
Bobby.
Is there anything else you know
or anything you can tell us?
BOBBY:
Nezhinski come in
and he was saying
how they're trying
to create a brand name,
that they want
to corner the market.
SHAPIRO:
Why did he tell you this?
I don't know.
He thought I could help him
build a reputation.
Nice friends you got there.
Know what, Pop?
He's not my friend.
All right? He came at me.
All right.
I'm not interested in that.
I don't deal.
SHAPIRO:
But didn't you lead him on?
No, I didn't fucking
lead him on.
The guy's crazy.
I mean, he--
He told me I could come look
at his operation.
I didn't even ask.
MICHAEL: He talked
about his operation?
Maybe that's it.
M-maybe that's key.
BURT:
What's your point?
We put a Kel on him.
Then send one of our uncles in.
Wait. Wait a minute.
Who's going to be the tail?
No, forget about it.
No way.
No, no, no.
Forget it. Forget it!
Well, you go to his spot, right?
And you let him talk.
You let him hang himself.
And then we-- We trail you,
you know, to the location.
A week later,
we pop him.
And your name's cleared. No--
A-and nobody knows it's you.
BURT: Mike, it's too dangerous for him.
He's my son.
He's connected to all of us.
No one knows
I'm connected to you.
What?
I don't talk about you.
What about your girlfriend?
She knows about you, right?
Huh?
Yeah.
All right, leave me alone
a minute. Okay?
I've got to fill
out these line-of-duty reports
for your brother,
for Joseph.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[DOOR CLOSES]
I didn't know this
was gonna happen, Pop.
Yeah, well,
what can you do, right?
I don't want you to get hurt.
Don't worry about me.
Just worry about yourself.
If I hear anything about
your brother, I'll call you.
Goodbye.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[♪]
AMADA:
Hey, baby.
Hey, babe.
How's your father?
Is he holding up okay?
Yeah.
Good.
I heard on the television
your brother's doing better.
Me and my mom,
we said a prayer for him.
Thanks, baby.
Did they find out who did it?
Baby?
It was Vadim.
Vadim shot Joseph.
Oh, my God.
They tried to tell me,
but I didn't listen.
Oh, my God.
Bobby, what are we gonna do?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER
OVER RADIO]
BOBBY:
Michael.
Hey.
You been up to see Joe?
Yeah. He's doing much better.
They reset his jaw
this morning.
He was awake
when I left him.
Your old man's up there
with him now.
How you doing?
You can't protect my father.
We'll do the best we can.
Those guys aren't afraid
of the police.
If anything
should happen to him--
Listen, that thing
you were talking about,
if I wanted to help you,
what would I have to do?
I'll call you.
[LIGHTER FLICKS]
MICHAEL:
There's a wire in here.
We hear everything
that goes down.
We'd also have a tail on you,
so we'd be with you
at all times.
Small.
Light as a feather.
You're fucking kidding me.
That's it?
That's it.
That's the risk.
You just gotta find
that stash house.
This can't get out.
It won't.
Well, what if
something goes wrong?
Give me a word.
First word comes to your mind.
F-feather.
Okay.
Anytime we hear
the word "feather,"
we come in early.
Otherwise, stay there,
do what you gotta do
and get the fuck out.
This will all be kept
confidential.
Yeah,
it better.
You get burnt, we have
to put you into protection.
That's better
than ending up dead.
Fuck.
Listen...
nobody will ever know
you're involved.
Not your father,
not your girlfriend, nobody.
And maybe someday your brother
will thank you for all this.
So, Bobby...
...you call Vadim's people
and set it up.
You won't see us, but we'll be
following your every move.
Don't be a hero.
Don't make conversation.
You sense they're onto you,
just remember
the word is "feather."
Your life is in that lighter.
Good luck.
[BLONDIE'S "RAPTURE"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Bobkes. Jesus.
Where you been?
I left you a message.
Yeah, I got your message,
thanks.
You all right?
Yeah.
What's the matter?
You sick?
Yeah, I've been out of it.
I gotta--
Come on,
Amada's here.
Can I get two Jack Daniels here,
please.
No, no, no. I gotta
take care of something.
See you later, all right?
I'll call you tomorrow.
All right. Call me tomorrow.
♪ Wall to wall
People hypnotized ♪
♪ And they're
Stepping lightly ♪
♪ Hang each night
In rapture... ♪
Please.
See my friends out there?
Vadim is really glad
that you made up your mind.
He's very happy.
You ready?
Yeah.
You'll meet me at the boardwalk
in one hour.
For your protection,
and for ours,
you'll be searched
and blindfolded as we arrive.
You'll be able
to sample the product.
See if you like it.
I'm sure you will.
You will discuss the rest
of the details with Vadim.
Don't raise your voice,
he doesn't like it.
And for me...
I'm taking you to the place
where I never
took anybody before,
especially no Americans.
And I don't trust you
the way Vadim does.
So don't.
All right?
And if you want to see
your girlfriend ever again,
you will come alone.
Boardwalk. One hour.
[CAR APPROACHING]
[♪]
You don't mind that I--
I sit behind, do you?
Do what you have to.
Let me see your hands.
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
[PAVEL SPEAKING
IN RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[MAN SPEAKING
IN RUSSIAN]
[BOBBY BREATHING]
[BRAKES WHINE]
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
PAVEL [IN RUSSIAN]:
Take this. Put it on.
[IN ENGLISH]
What do you think?
BOBBY:
It's good.
What do you say you got there?
How many keys?
What, like three
to four months?
It's not gonna dry up
on us, is it?
VADIM: We got a whole lot
of stuff coming in...
in a way nobody
could ever trace.
All the shit I got in here,
at least 86 percent pure.
Sasha.
VADIM: The whole city's gonna
be sucking our glass soon.
We'll push the guineas out.
The Domos will work for us.
BOBBY:
It's good.
So where's this coming from?
You're breathing heavy.
Yeah,
'cause I just took a hit.
You know, I seen fighters
breathe like that.
It means they get nervous.
Are you nervous?
No.
[SCOFFS]
I just told you,
it's 'cause I took some shit.
What do I have
to be nervous about?
They already searched me.
Vadim, I'm not here
to fuck you.
What are you doing?
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
How come you got both
matches and a lighter?
Oh, I'm feeling light
as a feather from that shit.
Hm?
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
What'd you say?
I'm feeling light
as a feather...
from that stuff.
He's wired.
No, ho-- Wait.
[IN RUSSIAN] You were right.
Kill the motherfucker.
[IN ENGLISH]
Wait. Wait! Wait!
[GRUNTS]
[GUNSHOT]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
[BOTH GROANING]
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Go! Get over there!
Take the roof.
Bobby!
[GRUNTS]
[GUNSHOTS]
MAN:
Get the weapon!
MAN 2:
Go, go, go!
[GRUNTS]
[HIGH-PITCH WHINING]
[GUNSHOT]
MAN:
Police! Don't move!
I'm with you!
[GUNSHOTS]
MAN:
Don't move!
[GASPS]
[SIRENS WAILING]
MAN:
Police! Don't move!
Put your hands up!
Back up to my voice!
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
MAN: Who is he?
Is he one of us?
MAN 2:
He's still breathing.
Get him a stretcher, quick!
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]: Copy that, Rescue 238.
Patient is a Caucasian male.
Mid-30s, with a leg fracture,
broken ribs, abrasions
and a possible neck injury.
[♪]
Where's Bobby?
Where's my son?
He's in the bus, chief.
They said he's gonna be okay.
You guys go on an operation
like this without telling me?
You think
I was born yesterday?
He came to me.
Yeah, but he could've
been killed!
Are you out of your mind?
I-- I'm sorry.
Yeah, well, my son's gotta go
into protection now.
Thank you very much.
It was his idea, Burt.
Where is he?
I wanna see him.
Is he all right?
[IN RUSSIAN]
He's a dead man.
[SIREN WAILING]
[IN ENGLISH]
You hear me, son?
Crazy kid.
Stupid kid.
Pop...
my girlfriend.
Call my girlfriend.
Don't worry.
I'll call her, all right?
I'll let your brother know too.
We gotta get you--
Get you well again.
Things are gonna be different
for you now, Bobby.
We're gonna have
to protect you now.
ANNOUNCER [ON RADIO]: 1010 WINS.
Give us 22 minutes, we'll give you the world.
MAN:
This is Stan Brooks in Queens.
Police captain
Joseph Grusinsky
is leaving Jamaica Hospital
this afternoon.
His doctors cleared him
for release,
following a four-month stay.
The 11-year veteran
was shot in the face
by a masked gunman
outside his home
the night
before Thanksgiving.
[THE JARMELS' "A LITTLE BIT
OF SOAP" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Hey, big guys,
let's see what you got.
Hey! Oh!
Get out. Get lost.
WOMAN:
Everybody, I see the car.
Here they are.
[CROWD CHEERING]
MICHAEL:
Welcome home, Joe.
WOMAN:
Welcome home. We love you.
MAN:
Hey, kiddo. You look great.
Welcome home.
Hey, Bob.
I saw your guards out there.
Daddy!
I didn't think
they'd let you come.
No, I wanted to.
Hey, what's up, Steve?
What's up, buddy?
Hey, how's your leg?
You all right?
Yeah.
I'm glad you're home.
Hey, we'll talk later,
all right?
SANDRA: Everyone, let's move inside.
There's plenty to eat.
BURT:
Honey. Young lady, hello.
KID:
Stop it!
MAN:
Joe, you look just great.
Does it hurt at all?
Yeah, a little,
when I look at you.
Thank you.
Oh, finally. Finally he gets you back.
Do you think maybe
I could go see my mom?
No, honey, they made
an exception for this.
I'm sorry,
I don't think you can.
JOSEPH: Hey, Pop.
Yeah.
Wanna go outside and talk
a little business on the porch?
I mean, I think it's time you
brought me back up to speed.
Whatever you say.
Let's go.
Bobby, come on,
I want you to hear this.
It's for the trial.
All right.
No, baby, I wanna go.
No, stay here.
I'll be 10 minutes, tops.
Let me just go back.
No. Just wait here.
We'll go back
to the motel together.
MICHAEL: Hey, Sandra, these
brownies are really good.
Careful.
MICHAEL: Nezhinski's cache was
even bigger than we thought.
Forty kilos of yayo.
Angel dust too.
We gotta try and see if we
could make a deal with him.
Find out how
they're bringing it in.
He might not be
too reliable, Pop.
BURT: Hey, listen,
you marry an ape,
you don't complain
about the stench of bananas.
JOSEPH:
Where is he now?
SHAPIRO: He's at Rikers,
tucked in nice and comfy.
We take him
to the ADA's next week.
Good, I wanna
go with you on that.
I wanna see
his fucking face.
We gotta lean on him hard.
Gotta get him to open up.
We got nowhere else to look.
Well, what about his uncle?
Buzhayev?
No, he's clean.
We tapped his phone, tailed him.
We got nothing.
Went to his fur store
on Monday.
Tuesday he took his grandkids
horseback riding.
There's nothing there.
SHAPIRO: I'll tell you,
the streets are dead.
The junkies are out there
waiting for something big,
no question.
Well, we got their number one.
Gotta put the full-court press
on him, get him to fold.
It won't work.
What?
He won't trust you.
I mean, these guys think of you
like you're a joke.
They call you Mickey Mouse.
He's not gonna turn for you.
Listen to the expert here.
Bobby, you don't gotta get
involved in this.
I asked him to come in.
He's gotta know
all this to testify.
This is official
police business, Pop.
You gonna make him an honorary
member of the department now?
BURT:
What's the matter with you?
No, Pop, he's right.
Didn't you hear what I said?
I asked him to come in here.
I brought him in.
Your brother's got
a price on his head
and you talk to him
like that?
Let's go.
You have to wait
for another car.
Miss Juarez just left.
She went to her mother's.
Bobby.
What?
What was said in there,
he didn't mean it.
You know, ever since
this thing happened,
he flies off
the handle sometimes.
But, you know--
Doctor says it may be part
of a stress disorder.
Needs a little more time
to adjust.
I understand that, Pop,
all right?
I got my own shit to deal with,
I got my girlfriend
that's pissed off.
I just want this
to be over with.
Listen to me.
A lot of people been talking
about how good you did.
Now, I think,
considering the alternatives...
maybe you ought to think
about going on the job.
You got special knowledge.
The department likes that.
I'm gonna go, Pop.
Why do you have to go?
Where you going?
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Think fast.
Hey.
Hello.
When is she gonna marry me?
That is my mother.
That's gross.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[MAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Is it all clear? Good.
MAN:
Yes, it's clear.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
I'm sorry, but s-she can't
be here right now, okay?
Baby, I was
just finishing eating.
Just get your stuff,
let's go home.
I'll be outside.
I wanna talk to you.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
She can't do this, Jumbo.
There are people out there
trying to kill me.
You understand?
It's dangerous.
I-- I know.
She called me. I got no idea
where you guys are.
'Cause no one
can know.
You all right?
I miss you.
Jeez, Bob.
I'm stressed out.
Don't know what the fuck
I'm doing.
Me too.
Hey, Bob, everyone's asking
about you at El Caribe.
Freddie and all the girls...
and Mr. Buzhayev.
I mean,
you were like a son to him.
We were surprised
to hear about your family.
Your father's
like J. Edgar Hoover.
I'm sorry
I never said nothing.
Don't worry, Bob.
It's all right.
So I gotta get her out of here,
and we'll call you.
Let's go.
Okay.
MAN: We gotta move.
Let's go.
AMADA:
She misses me, Bobby.
You got to see your family.
I know, baby, but that's--
That's different.
How?
Mike and Vitt,
they have a route planned.
You can't just go
and jeopardize all this.
Nobody can even know
what motel we're staying at.
You gotta
understand that.
Listen, baby,
Vadim's trial's in two months.
Two months.
I'm sorry.
It just feels like sometimes
the walls are closing in on me.
BOBBY:
It's gonna be okay.
[♪]
JOSEPH:
I'll go in the lead car.
You stay with him
till we get to the ADA.
SHAPIRO: Yeah. We got two cars.
One behind, one in front.
If we make a deal with him,
then my brother don't
have to testify.
At least that's something.
I'm here for an inmate pickup.
Vadim Nezhinski.
Is he ready?
MAN:
Uh, yeah.
They took him
20 minutes ago.
What are you talking about?
He complained
of chest pains.
They had to take him down
to Elmhurst Hospital.
Elmhurst Hospital?
Yeah, we had to do it.
It's the law.
Give me the phone.
Are you deaf?
Give me the fucking phone!
Hey, hey,
what's wrong with you?
BOBBY [WHISPERS]:
Thanks for being here.
I know
it's been really hard.
[MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
BOBBY:
Yeah?
Bobby, your brother just called.
We have an emergency.
Nezhinski's out.
So get your stuff together,
we're moving you.
What?
He escaped.
They took him to the hospital
with chest pains. He--
He had cooperation
from the outside.
Our guys got ambushed.
Start packing up, sweetheart.
Let's go.
Somebody might know
this location.
We better get you moved.
I'll meet you outside,
all right? Let's go.
[♪]
The backup should be here
any minute.
Probably got held up
in the rain.
You all right?
Pop, I'm fucked.
No, you're not.
You'll be okay.
You're never gonna get
Nezhinski.
Me and Amada can't
take this anymore.
Bobby.
I don't know
what to do.
I'm gonna protect you,
all right?
I'll make you
a promise right now.
I'm gonna protect you.
Don't worry.
It's gonna be okay, son.
We'll see it through.
Chief?
Yeah.
We have three vehicles
on the way.
Okay.
We'll move 'em
to Corona.
I'll lead the line.
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
Let's go, son.
AMADA:
Bobby.
BURT: You guys stay
close behind my car.
[THUNDER CRACKS]
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
BURT [OVER RADIO]: There's flooding
up ahead. Watch my brake lights.
It's really coming down.
Hey, Vitt, where's the car
that's supposed
to be following us?
He should be
right behind us, Bobby.
Shit, I left the watch
you gave me at the hotel.
Is that it on the right?
[AMADA SCREAMS]
Vitt!
AMADA:
Oh, my god!
BOBBY:
Amada, get down! Get down!
Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
BOBBY:
That motherfucker!
AMADA:
Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
What the fuck?!
How'd they find us?
Amada, stay down!
BURT: Get off,
they're shooting here!
Get off the road!
Fuck.
[AMADA CRYING]
Fuck!
Get off! Now!
I'll take care of them!
Aah!
[PANTING]
BOBBY:
Shit.
[HORNS HONKING]
Aah!
[AMADA SOBBING]
Get off the road, Bobby!
Get off the road!
Get off!
Aah!
[AMADA YELPS]
You hit? Amada, are you hit?
You hit?
No! No!
You hit?!
[AMADA SCREAMS]
BOBBY:
Jesus.
[AMADA YELPING]
[AMADA WAILING]
Shit.
BOBBY:
Pop, pull over!
Pull over! Pull over!
[HORN HONKING]
[♪]
MAN: You're in a suite
at the Sheraton
near Kennedy Airport.
Your brother is here
for you.
I wanted to let you sleep
a little bit.
Where's Pop?
I had to go
and identify the body.
[CRYING]
I saw him die.
It's all right.
It's gonna be okay,
all right?
I don't wanna be alone.
JOSEPH: I know.
JOSEPH:
I'm here.
Now, don't worry, all right?
I'm gonna be ready to come back
and head things up,
and we're gonna get him.
Just wait
till after the funeral.
They're
gonna get Nezhinski.
BOBBY: How did they
know where we were?
How'd
they find us?
[♪]
Your father was a great man.
Thank you.
He gave me his combat ribbon
after we got back from Korea.
I was gonna put it
in with him,
but I think he would have wanted
you to have it now.
Thanks.
It's now in your hands,
but we're gonna help you
get Nezhinski.
MICHAEL:
And we got a lead, Joe.
Word got back
from one of our uncles
that a big Russian shipment's
coming in sometime next week.
We'll find it.
Your father will not
have died in vain.
[AIRPLANE ROARING]
You're not sleeping again?
Did you take the pills
the doctor gave you?
No.
What is this?
Is this a police exam?
Bobby, is this
a police exam?
Yes.
Were you gonna talk to me
about it?
Yeah.
When?
I don't know.
Bobby, do you know
how this makes me feel?
You just went off,
you made this decision.
You didn't even talk
to me about it.
After this nightmare
we've been through?
I don't know if I could
live through that again.
You're gonna join
the police, Bobby?
Baby, you could be killed.
Look at your brother.
Your father,
he died for nothing.
No! No!
Don't talk about them!
AMADA: Look at your brother!
You don't talk about them!
AMADA: Wanna get shot like him?
BOBBY:
Do not talk about them!
You don't understand!
Oh!
You can't do this!
I won't let you!
No, you can't!
I have to do this!
No, you don't!
I have to do it! I have to!
No, you're gonna
get yourself killed!
I fucking hate you!
[AMADA CRYING]
SPIRO: The commissioner's aware
you have special knowledge
for this case, Bobby.
He made it top priority.
COMMISSIONER:
Come.
We're all very sorry
about your father, Robert.
Thank you.
Pursuant to your request,
we've decided to grant you
a special dispensation
and appoint you as a conditional
member of this department,
effective immediately.
I appreciate that.
Good.
You will be required
to go to the academy
once this case is completed.
You know that?
Yes, I do.
All right, then.
Would you raise
your right hand, please?
"I, Robert Green,
hereby pledge and declare
that I will support and defend
the Constitution--"
I, Robert Green,
hereby pledge and declare
that I will support and defend
the Constitution--
COMMISSIONER: "--both of the
United States government
and the state of New York,
to the best of my ability."
BOBBY: --both of the
United States government
and the state of New York,
to the best of my ability.
COMMISSIONER: "I will
faithfully discharge my duties
in the rank
of probationary officer--"
BOBBY: I will faithfully
discharge my duties
in the rank
of probationary officer--
COMMISSIONER: "--in the New
York City Police Department."
--in the New York City
Police Department.
"So help me God."
So help me God.
Congratulations, Robert,
and welcome.
Thank you.
SPIRO: Congratulations.
BOBBY: Thank you.
SHAPIRO: They're all expecting
you down at the precinct.
Work all your contacts.
We gotta find out
where that deal is going down.
BOBBY: Jumbo, I'm not gonna
party, but I need to talk to you.
All right, so, look,
I'll come down later, all right?
And I'll see you then.
All right.
No, don't tell Freddie.
Jumbo, listen to me.
Just meet me at El Caribe
at 11:30, all right?
All right.
Hey.
You get your ID card
this morning?
Yeah, but they wouldn't
give me a piece.
I should have one.
I'll get you one.
Pop always said
you were a good shot.
What's the matter, Joe?
Nothing.
It's-- It's kind of weird
seeing you here.
Yeah, I know.
Bobby.
I never meant to get you
involved in all this.
I'm sorry.
You don't gotta apologize to me.
I never listened
to you or Pop.
You wanna hear
something funny?
I was kind of jealous
of you for that.
[CHUCKLES]
I was. I don't think I had
a lot of faith in myself.
You know, I just did
what Pop wanted me to do.
I mean, you--
I mean..
You know,
you were free.
Anyway, look,
I didn't mean to get
into all this. It just--
You know, maybe it's just 'cause
I ain't been sleeping lately.
I'm kind of having
some nightmares
about what happened to me.
Well...
[♪]
...all that matters is
that we finish this.
And we catch Nezhinski
when that deal goes down.
MAN: Bobby, an Amada Juarez
is calling for you on Line 3.
Uh, tell her
I'll call her back later.
MAN:
All right.
You gonna be okay?
I gotta go downstairs and get
fitted for a vest, all right?
Yeah.
BOBBY:
Amada?
Hey.
Miss Juarez left
about an hour ago.
She said
to give you this.
Hey, get me some food,
would you?
Yeah, sure.
And we're checking you out
at noon tomorrow.
Get your stuff together.
I'll bring the menus.
[SOBS]
[COATI MUNDI PLAYING
"QUE PASA - ME NO POP I"]
♪ I give you
Everything you need ♪
♪ Money, home
Insurance policies ♪
♪ And I don't even
Have for you ♪
♪ The money that guarantee
♪ You're with me
In my head ♪
♪ And when you say
I'm no good in bed ♪
♪ You ain't got no heart... ♪
Lou.
My brother. The grand return.
I can't believe you called.
Look at you. You look great.
You look different.
Who is this?
That's my bodyguard.
Look at this place.
Did you put more tables
up here?
No. I don't know. Come here.
Come on,
have a drink for a second.
Hazel, why don't you
get us some drinks, huh?
Don't you think
you've had enough?
What, you wanna be
a pain in my ass?
You my mother?
Come on, get us some drinks.
Ah, fuck you in the ass.
I'm ready.
Listen, I wanna talk to you
about something.
Sure.
You know of anything going down
the next few days?
Something major?
No.
I mean, they never tell me
their heavy stuff anyway.
Yeah, but you hear
about things.
Aren't people talking,
anything?
If I hear anything,
I'll let you know.
What about Freddie?
Is Freddie around?
Freddie's downstairs.
Come on, Jumbo, pay attention.
Where's Amada?
Bob.
She left.
She left?
What do you mean,
she left?
Jumbo, leave it alone.
Don't worry.
Amada, she probably
just needs some space.
She'll be back.
Come on, between you and me,
that place they had you in was
driving her crazy, I know that.
The Cue Motor Inn?
We used to call it
the "Screw Motor Inn,"
with all the hookers.
[CHUCKLES]
How'd you know
where we were staying?
Huh?
How did you know
where we were staying?
It was in the papers.
You know, those reporters,
they got their noses everywhere.
Always looking through
everybody's garbage.
Anyway, homeslice,
what do you think
of the floorshow?
You wanna go downstairs
for a bit?
Go outside? It's loud in here.
What?
Talk, catch up?
[CHUCKLING]
Wha--?
You wanna go outside?
We have-- We got drinks coming.
Forget the drinks.
I haven't seen you in forever.
Let's go.
It's cold out.
Get your coat.
Come on.
Give us a few minutes, okay?
It'll be all right.
Okay, but make it quick.
CHORUS:
♪ Me no pop I
♪ You no pop O
♪ Me no pop I...
It wasn't
in the papers, Lou.
Where's Nezhinski?
I don't know.
Don't play games with me.
I said, don't play games
with me.
[SOBBING]
Amada told you where
we were staying, didn't she?
She trusted you like a brother.
Bob. Come on.
I swear, I don't--
I-- I don't know nothing.
Aah! Get off me!
[GRUNTS]
My father's dead 'cause of you.
You know
I'm with the police now?
And I can do anything to you.
Bob, I told 'em where you were,
but it ain't what you think.
Amada said you moved
every couple days.
I thought you'd be gone by then.
It's the truth. I sw--
I swear to God.
I tried to give them
the wrong information.
I tried.
Come on. Tell me who.
Who?! Who? Who?
[WHIMPERING]
Marat.
Marat Buzhayev.
I'm sorry, Bob. I-I--
I know he was like
a father to you,
but he owns me.
BOBBY:
Don't say that!
[JUMBO YELLING]
BOBBY: Don't say that!
Don't say that!
JUMBO [SOBBING]:
My eyes.
You fuck!
You fuck.
Fuck! Fuck!
You fuck!
[SOBBING]
Get up. Get up!
Get up!
MAN: This Jumbo
Falsetti guy confirmed
that a major shipment
is coming tomorrow
for Buzhayev.
He says, uh, Buzhayev uses
his grandkids as couriers.
They go everywhere for him.
That's why we're never able
to catch him.
We should've been, uh,
putting a tail
on a couple
of 10-year-olds.
It's unbelievable.
Did Jumbo know
the location?
No.
No, we tried,
believe me.
We interrogated him all night,
he was crying
like a 4-year-old.
But he, uh-- He did say
he thought Nezhinski
would be there, though.
Tomorrow's Tuesday, right?
Buzhayev takes his grandkids
to Floyd Bennett Field
every Tuesday.
Takes 'em horseback riding.
SHAPIRO: Joe, we should
put our money on that.
No, that's--
That's not really much to go on.
You got a better idea?
Anyone?
We can sit on our fucking asses
or we can crush these--
JOSEPH: Bobby.
It's a process,
you know?
Look,
that's what we got.
I-- I guess that's what
we should go with.
You heard him. Let's go.
SANDRA:
Coats are on the porch.
Contact ESU. Make sure we don't
come up short, all right?
MAN:
We got it covered.
MICHAEL:
Sorry about the mess, Sandra.
Joe, you know, they're laughing
at us out there on the street.
Now, when we get there,
what we do will be up to you.
But I hope you drop
the hammer on 'em.
After your father
and everything else?
I mean, these people
are like fucking lice.
Just think about
what I'm saying to you.
Joe.
Joe, you okay?
I hear you, GQ.
Take that, all right?
It's one of Pop's.
I don't need any more guns
in my life, that's for sure.
But you should have one
to be safe.
It's better to be judged by 12
than carried by six.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
MICHAEL [OVER RADIO]:
Joe,  we're all ready. What's the move?
JOSEPH: Wait till they
complete the sale.
Then we move.
ESU will grab the kids.
They're so fucking close,
the two of 'em.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
[RUSSIAN CONTINUES
OVER RADIO]
[IN RUSSIAN] This is what
we've wanted for so long.
My nephew has stayed
just to see this through.
When this is done,
we'll control almost
the whole market.
Each load is completely
untraceable.
It's my own method.
Impressive.
You put the drugs
right on the coat.
VADIM: We are importing 200
imitation sables per week.
Try it.
Very good.
Give them the money.
JOSEPH [IN ENGLISH]:
All right, deal's about to close.
Let's go.
This is the police!
[OVER BULLHORN]
Drop your weapons. Come out!
Police! Put your weapons down!
MAN: They're firing.
Everybody get down!
[IN RUSSIAN]
Eli! The kids!
MAN [IN ENGLISH]:
Get down! Joseph! Get down!
Joe! Joe, are you hit?
MAN:
What happened?
MAN 2:
He's okay. He's okay.
He's all right.
He ain't hit.
BOBBY:
Should we move?
MAN 2:
I don't know what's wrong.
Bobby. Bobby,
take his shotgun.
Okay.
I'll stay here with him.
MAN 3:
Come on! Go, go, go!
[MEN YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: We got runners
around the back!
MAN:
It's okay.
Come with me.
MAN 2:
Keep going! Go! Go!
Watch your back!
Go! Go!
Kelly, we're gonna move
to the left! Let's go.
MAN 3:
Okay.
Halt! Police!
[GRUNTS]
[DOGS BARKING]
MAN: Freeze.
Hold it right there.
[BOTH YELL]
All right.
Fuck.
We'll kill each other
in here.
Nezhinski's in here
with us.
Let's smoke him out.
Radio our guys.
Tell 'em to clear out.
Absolutely.
MAN [OVER RADIO]: We got the old man.
We got Buzhayev.
All right, guys.
Clear out.
Go on.
Into the clearing.
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
MICHAEL:
Bobby!
Bobby, what are you doing?
Don't go in there!
We have Vadim surrounded.
Be patient, he'll come out!
Bobby!
[BRANCH SNAPS]
[COUGHING]
[GUN COCKS]
Bobby...
fuck you.
[♪]
[THUNDER CRASHES]
Bobby,
I didn't know
it would be your family.
Get on your knees.
We're done here.
BOBBY:
Hey, Joe.
Can't believe
how nervous I am.
Hey, Bobby.
Big day.
Look at you.
All dressed up, huh?
Looking like a chief.
I don't know about that.
Maybe a lieutenant.
You look good.
Captain?
Hey, Joe, I got through
to McClennan at Personnel.
And he's still holding
that slot for you
if you're ready to switch
to administration.
Yeah, can we talk about it
another time?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
Hey, good luck.
All right.
Now, what's this?
Look, I meant to tell you.
I gotta start doing
the right thing.
I gotta start spending
more time at home.
I got three kids now.
What am I supposed to do?
Look, I was gonna talk
to you about it.
Do what you need to do.
They're gonna get started.
We should probably go in.
Come on.
MAN:
Ladies and gentlemen,
we shall begin
today's ceremony
with the traditional invocation,
moving then
to the valedictorian address
to be given by
Robert Grusinsky,
son of the late
Deputy Chief
Albert Grusinsky,
brother of
Captain Joseph Grusinsky.
You know,
as I look at that
fine young man
seated behind me,
I can't help but think
of all the young members
of our department.
I get filled
with such pride.
Men like him are the future
of the force.
Let us remind ourselves
we are in God's presence.
Let us pray.
[♪]
O God, we come together
at this most joyous occasion,
the New York City Police
graduation ceremony.
We ask you to guide, bless
and protect those
who are graduating.
Please bless their families
and friends who gather
and share their joy.
I love you very much.
Strengthen us, our Lord,
now and forever.
I love you too.
Amen.
CROWD:
[♪]