So here's what you missed
on Glee:
McKinley's doing West Side
Story, and everyone's excited,
especially Coach Beiste
and Emma and Artie,
because they're the directors.
Blaine got the lead,
and so did Rachel, which made
Mercedes quit the glee club
and join Shelby's Troubletones
with Santana and Brittany.
Mike Chang's playing Riff,
even though his dad told him
he can't be a dancer.
Riff is perfect for you.
I think he wants him to go to
doctor college or something.
And that's what you missed
on Glee.
(school bell ringing)
ARTIE: You see this face?
This is what enlightenment looks like.
It doesn't matter if
he's in prison like Gandhi,
or trapped inside a woman's
body like Chaz Bono,
or stuck in a wheelchair
like me,
when a man finds his calling,
all is right in his world.
I still ve performing,
but thanks to Mr. Shue
and the school musical,
I've finally discovered
my true passion...
bossing everyone around.
I mean directing.
The key to being a director
is having opinions
about everything.
No.
Even stuff you have no id.
I think it's great.
Go.
Definitely.
Really?
That's it.
No.
(groans)
ARTIE:
I'm both sad and happy
that the musical
is just days away.
("Tonight" begins)
Tonight, tonight
It all began tonight
I saw you
and the world went away
Tonight, tonight,
there's only you tonight
What you are, what you do,
what you say
Today,
all day I had the feeling
A miracle would happen
I know now I was right
For here you are
And what was just a world
is a star
Tonight...
Are you going to cry
every time we sing?
I'm such a girl.
My only note is more teeth.
Can I be honest?
This song is about
sexual awakening,
as is the entire musical.
You two lack passion.
Have either of you two
actually...?
Wow, okay. I have to go.
Because I have...
Those footballs aren't going
to inflate themselves.
I'm out of here.
Let's go.
Look, I remember my
first time with Brittany.
The excitement, the way it
made me feel like a man...
even though she called me
the wrong name like four times,
during and after.
What was it like for you guys?
Um...
I'm, I'm waiting
for the right time.
Yeah. Yeah, me-me, too.
I'm so glad that
you're my Tony.
Look...
as your friend I support
your strange aversion to fun.
But as your director,
I'm concerned.
I'm, I'm sorry,
what do you mean?
Well, how do you expect
to convey
the human perience
to an audience
when you haven't even opened
yourself up to one of humanity's
most basic and primal ones?
By Mikhel for Subtitulos.es
==SPREAD THE WORD==
Glee S03E05
"The First Time"
(bell ringing)
Um... one over there.
Um...
So, you, um...
you still haven't told me
who you're ving for yet.
Well, I haven't decided.
Kurt's my brother.
It's kind of hard to vote
against your brother.
Well, I mean, you can't do
this with your brother.
Not unless you
live in Kentucky.
(giggles)
What's gotten into you?
Nothing. It's just the
confidence of success.
I mean, I sold out
the April Rhodes Auditorium
for three shows, Jacob Ben
Israel's poll have me in tied
for first place in
the presidential race,
and I have
the hottest guy in school.
I hope that my radiance
isn't too much for you.
It won't be after Friday night.
What's Friday night?
That is the day
that the recruiter
from Ohio State is coming.
They're looking for
a new quarterback.
Really?
That's amazing!
Yeah, I know.
You... you're not pissed?
No. No, of course not.
It's not like NYADA
has a football team.
It's really happening.
You know, our dreams are coming
true, and we're growing up.
I know.
And... hey,
I was thinking.
Um, Burt and my mom are
out canvassing all week
and I have the house to myself.
Maybe you could come over.
To your house?
I'll be there at 6:00.
Oh, boy.
(Roxy Music plays loudly)
God. Roxy Music makes me
want to build
a time machine just so
I can go back to the '70s
and give Brian Ferry
a high five.
Do you think I'm boring?
Are you crazy?
You're the single
most interesting kid
in all of Ohio.
I mean, like...
sexually.
I mean, we are playing
it very safe by
not granting our hands visas
to travel south of the equator.
Oh, I-I thought
that's what we wanted.
It is.
I'm just wondering,
have you ever had
the urge just to
rip off each other's clothes
and get dirty?
Uh, yeah. But that's why
they invented masturbation.
It's so hot in this room. Could
we, could we open up a window?
Hey, I'm serious. We're young.
We're in high school.
Yeah, we have urges, but
whatever we do, I want to make
sure that you're comfortable.
So I can be comfortable.
And besides,
tearing off all of your clothes
is sort of a tall order.
Because of the layers?
Because of the layers.
Man, I love to weld.
Clearly.
Coach, I'm concerned.
Why did you run out of
rehearsal the other day
when we started
talking about S-E-X?
Artie, this conversation
is totally inappropriate.
Wait.
Have you never...?
Why? Have you just never
found the right...
person?
Guy. I like guys.
And no, I haven't found him.
All right, I'll play.
There's this
one gentleman.
He's the bee's knees.
His name's Cooter Mankins.
He's a recruiter
for Ohio State.
He's beautiful. He makes me
feel like a girl...
but he's not interested.
You're a hell of a coach, Coach.
So much talent.
I'm famished.
Want to go get some lunch?
Nah.
But you can have
the rest of my chili.
There's nothing left but
gristle and a few beans,
but it eats pretty good.
So, anyway, that's my type.
Not that it matters.
(bell tolling)
(Billy Joel's "Uptown Girl"
begins)
Oh-oh-oh-oh...
Uptown girl
She's been living in her
white bread world
White bread world
As long as anyone
with hot blood can
Hot blood can
And now she's looking
for a downtown man
Downtown man
That's what I am
And when she knows
What she wants from her time
And when she wakes up
And makes up her mind
She'll see I'm not so tough
Just because I'm in love
With an uptown girl
You knoI can't afford
to buy her pearls
But maybe someday
when my ship comes in
She'll understand
what kind of guy I've been
And then I'll win
And when she's walking
She's looking so fine
And when she's talking
She'll say that she's mine
She'll say I'm not so tough
Just because I'm in love
With an uptown girl
She's been living in her
white bread world
As long as anyone
with hot blood can
And now she's looking
for a downtown man
That's what I am
Oh-oh-oh-oh...
Uptown girl
She's my uptown girl
Don't you know I'm in love
With an uptown girl
Uptown girl
My uptown girl
Don't you know I'm in love
With an uptown
Girl.
(laughs)
You guys killed it, as always!
We'd sound so much better
with you back in the mix.
Is this your triumphant
return to Dalton? Please?
Actually, I'm here
to invite you guys
to my opening night
at McKinley.
West Side Story.
I reserved a whole block of
tickets just for the Warblers.
It would mean the world to
me if you guys could come.
We'll be there. Once a Warbler,
always a Warbler, right?
(hooting, cheering)
Blaine Anderson.
Sebastian Smythe.
Hi. Are you a freshman?
Do I look like a freshman?
Uh...
(bell tolling)
So you're a legend at Dalton.
Well, I...
Don't be modest.
I was like, "I don't know
who this Blaine guy is,
"but apparently he's sex on a
stick and sings like a dream.
So... sucks that
I missed him."
All right.
Since I'm working to recreate
your meteoric ascent,
I-I need to ask.
Why did you leave Dalton?
Were you bored with all
the preppies around here?
Or is it that you broke
too many hearts to stay?
("A Boy Like That" begins)
A boy like that,
who'd kill your brother
Forget that boy
and find another
One of your own kind
Stick to your own kind
(laughs)
Uh, it wasn't like that.
Let's just say that
I miss Dalton every day,
but McKinley is
where my heart is, now.
A boy like that wants
one thing only
And when he's done,
he'll leave you lonely
He'll murder your love;
he murdered mine
Just wait and see
Just wait, Maria
Oh, no, Anita, no, Anita, no
It isn't true, not for me
It's true for you,
not for me
I hear your words,
and in my head
I know they're smart
But my heart, Anita
But my heart knows
they're wrong
You should know better
You were in love,
or so you said
You should know better.
I have to go
to lacrosse practice,
but could we meet again?
I could really use some more
insights from you, Blaine.
You know, Warbler to Warbler.
Sure.
(bell ringing)
Hey, dude, I got
a question for you.
I thought they were my sneakers.
BOTH:
What?
No, no, look, I figured since
you have some more experience
than I do, you could
recommend a brand of condom.
Are you cheating
on Rachel, dude?
Because if you are,
that is not cool.
And that's coming from me.
No. I want to use them
with Rachel.
Oh. I'm happy for you, dude,
and her.
I always thought it would be me,
but secretly hoped
it'd be you.
As for the condoms,
no idea... never used them.
It's worked out
for me about 99% of the time.
(blows whistle)
Gather round!
You all know Cooter Mankins.
Best eye for talent
in the country if you ask me.
Which is why I spend so much
time with you, Coach.
Hey, are those new
tube socks?
I got a whole new six-pack
if you need to borrow a pair.
(clears throat)
All right,
this Friday night I will be in
the stands watching you play.
And I'm not looking for boys
to play for the Buckeyes.
I'm looking for men.
(bell ringing)
If you see any of Rachel's
campaign posters
feel free to tear
them down.
Do you think we're
too sheltered as artists?
I'm serious.
West Side Story's all about
living outside
of your safe little world.
Don't you want to wake up
every day and be adventurous?
Experience everything
in life you can?
Of course, it's why
I made a bucket list.
Okay, you ready for this?
Okay.
All right, here you go.
Number 87: become CEO of Logo.
Of course.
Number 63: lay a rose at the
birthplace of Noel Coward.
Okay, number five.
All right, this one's
really embarrassing.
I wrote this before
I met you.
Have relations on a dewy meadow
of lilac
with Taylor Lautner
before he gets fat.
Oh, yeah, I know, it's stupid.
No, it's not. It's hot.
Well, anyway,
we're-we're young,
so we've got all the time in
the world to be adventurous.
Don't you think now is the
time to be adventurous
while we're still young?
(bell ringing)
Excuse me, Mr. Cooter,
I'm Artie Abrams.
Could I see you in my office?
It's important.
You don't mean the handicapped
stall, do you?
Uh, no. But that is hilarious.
Holy hell!
What is this, a movie
theatre or something?
You like Coach Beiste, right?
Yeah, yeah, of course I do.
She's the best
football coach in the state.
Yeah, but do you like her,
like her?
You know, I've asked her out
about a million times.
She's not interested.
Last week I told her
I had a gift
certificate to Applebee's.
She told me fancy restaurants
make her nervous.
You have to ask her out again.
No way, Andy.
She's gonna blow me off.
Trust me.
You need to ask her out again,
but make it really obvious.
I have the perfect idea
for a date.
I can't believe you asked
for a shot of Courvoisier
in your coffee.
I forget how lame
this town is.
When I lived in Paris,
I drank it like it was
mother's milk.
When...?
Oh, okay, wow.
What?
You're just so, you know,
you're out there.
And your whole bashful
schoolboy thing?
Super hot.
Look, Sebastian,
I have a boyfriend.
Doesn't bother me
if it doesn't bother you.
No, I mean, I really care
about him.
He doesn't need to know.
I'd just never want to mess
my thing up with him in any way.
He's really great.
Who's really great?
You!
We were just talking
about you.
Sebastian, this is Kurt,
my boyfriend, who I was just...
Got it.
Wow. Wow.
Pleasure.
And how do we know
Sebastian?
We met at Dalton.
Was dying to meet Blaine.
Those Warblers just won't
shut up about him.
Didn't think he could
live up to the hype,
but as it turns out...
Yes, he's even more impressive
in the flesh.
Hey, what are you guys doing
tomorrow night?
Well, we're rehearsing
for the school musical.
And then, at bedtime,
we do a rigorous skin-sloughing
regimen over the phone together.
And as sexy as that sounds,
what do you say
we shake things up?
I get you guys
a couple of fake IDs
and we head over
to Scandals in West Lima.
Scandals?
That's the gay bar.
The last time
I was there,
I met the man of my dreams on
the dance floor.
That's so sweet.
And are you two
still together?
Sadly, no.
We broke up about
20 minutes after we met.
Come on, guys.
Live a little.
We would love to,
Sebastian.
Thank you for the offer.
That's very nice of you,
but that just isn't
our kind of thing.
Let's do it.
What? Yeah.
We have a whole bunch of firsts
to start crossing
off our list.
We're in.
Great.
(Rachel sighs)
That was amazing.
I've never had
meat substitute before
that tastes that
much like real meat.
Of course.
Because you're a vegan,
which I remember because we know
each other so well.
More sparking cider?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Should we make a toast?
Yeah.
All right.
To four full months
of no fighting
or threats of us breaking up.
Nothing but love, love, love.
BOTH:
Cheers.
Oh, should I go
make dessert?
I've got pound cake.
It's Sara Lee.
Oh, actually I thought maybe we
could just go snuggle
by the fire first.
Okay.
I brought protection.
Me, too.
Every modern girl
comes prepared.
Wait, wait.
Before we do this,
I need to know, why now?
The last time we talked
about this, you said
you wanted to wait
until you won a Tony.
Or any other major award.
Emmy, Golden Globe.
People's Choice would have
gotten you to third base.
But I don't know what changed.
I mean, even the thought
of going to New York a virgin
felt silly to me.
But when and who's gonna feel
more right than you and now?
And I love you.
I just want to make sure this is
special enough for you.
I've been saving up
for a hotel for us.
Someplace nice like a Marriot
or something.
If we wait a couple of weeks,
I could probably...
No, I can't wait
a couple weeks.
I have to get this done before
opening night.
Get this done?
I can't play airl
who has a sexual awakening
if I'm not woken up myself.
So you're doing this
so you can act better?
No! No! I'm doing this
because I love you
and so that I can act better.
But that's
my business, okay?
It has nothing to do
with you, so...
Where are you going?
No, no, I'm-I'm ready.
Please come back.
I-I just need a minute.
I'm gonna make dessert.
When were you
gonna tell me?
- Tell you what?
- That you're doing the school musical.
I overheard your mother
talking about it on the phone.
You lied to me, and you made
a liar out of your mother.
You will quit immediately.
No!
I love being a dancer.
When I was in high school
I wanted to be a tennis player,
but then I had to wake up
and realize that
I wasn't good enough.
Grow up, Michael!
You need to learn the difference
between grown-up dreams
and kid dreams.
I'm not going to be a doctor.
I will be a professional dancer.
I'll pay my own way
through college.
I don't want your money.
As long as you continue
to waste your life
with this silly fantasy,
you will no longer be my son.
Then I guess I don't have
a dad anymore.
(bell ringing)
Need somebody to spot you?
No, I'm good.
I lift big and solo.
You'd be surprised how much
I could bench.
If I got the chance.
Gotcha.
I'll be through
here in a sec,
and then
they're all yours.
Did you need me for something?
Yeah. Yeah, I do. I, uh...
I got these.
Are you going to a graveyard?
No, no, I got them for you.
I'm not sick.
Dang it, Shannon, can you just,
can you drop the weights,
please,
and talk to me for a second?
Man, you ever just have
something
you really wanted to get out,
and you just
couldn't seem to do it?
I had a chigger in
my thigh once.
It was the size of a Tic Tac.
I want to take you out
on a date.
A real honest-to-God sit-down
date where you dress up
like a lady and I dress up
like a gentleman.
Yes or no?
Why are you doing this, Cooter?
Somebody put you up to this?
Geez.
Why don't you get
that I'm attracted to you?
Because you're the kind of man
that could have any pretty girl
he pointed at,
and I don't look the way
pretty girls look.
Well, good...
'cause I don't date girls.
I just date women.
Beautiful women.
Like you.
So, take the flowers.
Go on.
(sighs)
So, Friday...
after the game.
(door opens)
(sniffles)
This emergency meeting is now in
session.
Now I realize that we are a
house divided,
but I need the advice
of my girls.
The last time I called a meeting
like thiwas during
our Madonna lesson, and all of
you were wildly unhelpful.
But it's been two years now,
and we've all grown up,
so I'm optimistic.
Finn and I were...
almost intimate.
Almost? What happened?
He ran out.
I just... I wanted my
performance of Maria
to be as realistic as possible
and when he found out that
that's why I was doing it,
he got really, really hurt.
Of course he was hurt.
Yeah, that's really bad, Rachel.
I know. I know. I feel terribl
And now I realize that I was
just doing it for
all the wrong reasons.
Do you want my advice?
Just wait.
Just wait?
Look what happened to me.
You could've used protection.
I'm not just talking about
getting pregnant, I'm-I'm
talking about losing something
that you can never get back.
It changes you.
It makes everything more complicated.
I also think that
you should wait.
Speaking from experience,
Finn is terrible in bed.
Santana, that is not cool.
Oh, what?
If Rachel wants my sloppy seconds,
she should at least know the truth.
Look, it was like being
smothered by a sweaty,
out-of-breath sack of potatoes
that someone soaked
in body spray.
I lost my virginity at
cheerleading camp.
He just climbed into my tent.
Alien invasion.
Okay, well, then I guess
it's settled.
Obviously, things are heating up
between Finn and I.
But I think we should wait.
Losing my virginity was a great
experience for me...
because I was with
someone I love.
I have a love
And it's all that I have
Right or wrong, what else
Can I do?
TINA:
It happened this summer.
Mike and I had talked
about it for awhile,
because we knew that
the first time was gonna be
something we'd want
to remember forever.
I love him
I'm his
And everything he is
I am, too...
And when that
moment came...
we just knew.
It was right.
It wasn't rushed.
It was amazing.
RACHEL AND SANTANA:
When love comes so strong
There is no right or wrong
Your love is...
He's my first love.
And I'll always look back at
that moment as
absolutely perfect...
no regrets.
Your life...
KURT:
Chazz Donaldsworth?
This doesn't even
look like me.
Don't worry.
Mine says I'm 38.
They'll work.
Okay.
(ABC's "Poison Arrow" plays)
Aloha!
Enjoy.
It's Drag Queen Wednesday.
Great.
It's not very scandalous...
Au contraire.
Look at all the, uh,
glamorous drag queens.
Look, there's uh, Cher and
Tina Turner and, uh, uh...
is that Lucy or Reba?
That is Ginger from
Gilligan's Island.
KURT:
Of course.
Then I say "I love you"
and foul the situation...
I really don't
like that guy.
He's harmless.
A beer for Blaine,
and for Kurt, a Shirley Temple
with extra cherries.
I heard you're the
designated driver.
Like, all the time.
Cheers, boys.
To the glamorous life.
I thought you loved me,
but it seems you don't care
I care enough to know I can
never love you
Who broke my heart?
You did, you did...
You better watch
your boyfriend.
Could I get another
beer, please?
(Thelma Houston's "Don't Leave
Me This Way" plays)
So, how's life
at your new school?
Fine.
Look, I just want to have a
normal senior year and play
football without my teammates
hearing rumors about me.
Just so that you know, I would
have never told anyone.
It's not who I am.
So, you come here
all the time?
People like me here.
I feel accepted.
I'm what they call a bear cub.
Because you look like Yogi?
I don't know, because
I'm burly or something.
So... so is this the point
where you judge me?
No, as long as you're not
beating people up, I am all for
being whoever you have to
be at your own speed.
Oh, baby,
don't leave me this way
Right now, I'm just trying
to get through high school.
I can't exist
I'll surely miss
Here's to baby steps.
Your tender kiss
Baby steps.
Don't leave me this way
Baby, my heart is full of love
and desire for you
Now come on down and do what
you gotta do
You started this fire down in
my soul
Now can't you see it's burning
out of control?
BLAINE: This was the
best night of my life.
Okay. All right.
It's the best night of my life.
I want to live here.
And I just want to make art
and you know, just help people.
(laughs) You could certainly help
people make fires with your breath.
Hey, come on,
I only h one beer.
Sure, you did.
Hey.
What?
Kiss me. Kiss me.
Oh, no, no, no, no...
Come on...
Come on, you're riding
in the back. Come on.
Lay down.
All right, all right.
You're less likely to
throw up that way.
Get in there.
Whoa, wait! Okay...
(stammering)
All right, Blaine, all right.
Cold hand, cold hand!
Come on, come on.
Hey, Kurt, let's just do it.
I... I want you.
No, no...
I want you so...
No, Blaine, no, just... Stop it...
Hey, listen, I-I know you wanted
to do it in a field of lilacs
with Sting playing in the background and
all that, but who cares where we are?
It's all about us, right?
Right, it's about us.
Which is why I don't want
to do it on a night
that you spent half of
dancing with another guy
and that you're sober enough
to remember it the next day!
Why are you yelling at me? Because I have never
felt less like being intimate with someone
and either you can't tell
or you just don't care.
(sighs)
Where are you going?
I'm sorry if I'm trying to
be spontaneous and fun.
I think I'm just
gonna walk home.
Blaine!
(sighs):
God!
(audience murmuring)
Just so you know, your
Maria has disappointed you.
I'm still a virgin.
And your Tony has
disappointed you.
- Me, too.
- Look, the audience is smart.
The only sensible solution is to
just cancel the show.
I'd rather send everybody home than
give a false, inauthentic performance.
Five minutes!
Rachel, darken your eyebrows.
Blaine, tone down the blush.
My eyebrows are fine.
Artie? Artie, are you okay?
You look upset.
Everything is wrong.
The scenery, the costumes,
the staging.
You know, I thought if I just
pretended like I knew
what I was doing I could lie my
way through it,
but in five minutes that curtain
is going to go up
and everybody is going to know
that I'm a fraud.
Artie, you were brilliant.
Really, this show is absolutely amazing,
and that is all thanks to you.
It's awful.
I let everybody down.
Hey, Artie, some of the cast needs
to talk to you before we go on.
See? It's mutiny.
Dude, we have a problem.
We haven't officially thanked you for
everything that you've done for us.
All of us were so nervous, and we
didn't know what we were doing
and you were like the lighthouse
that lead us to the way.
But I didn't know what I was
doing, either.
When you're in a chair,
it hard to...
ever feel
like you've grown up.
Everyone's always doing stuff
for you,
they get freaked out about
saying the wrong thing,
so... they coddle you.
Sometimes it's hard to ever
picture a life
of being totally
self-sufficient.
But directing you ys,
the way you trusted me,
the way you looked at me
and listened to me,
it was the first time in my life
that I ever...
felt like a grown man.
That's the greatest gift
you can give a guy, so...
So, thank you guys...
for the flowers and for
everything.
All right, show circle.
(relieved laughter)
May I, chief?
Let's kick some ass!
(collective cheer)
When I think about how we came
to America!
Like children! Believing!
Trusting!
Ah, trusting with our hearts
open...
With our arms open...
(Irish accent): You
came with your mouth open.
We gotta work on this
kid's diction.
Without a doubt, the best
musical McKinley's ever done.
We'll see. It's a risky artistic
choice weaving the Jets
into "America,"
but Artie insisted.
(Latin music plays)
I just hope that people go with
it, you know?
Puerto Rico
My heart's devotion
Let it sink back
in the ocean
(laughing)
Always the hurricanes
blowing
Always
the population growing
And the money owing
And the sunlight streaming
And the natives steaming
I like the island Manhattan
I know you do!
Smoke on your pipe
And put that in
I like to be in America
Okay by me in America
Everything free in America
(all shout)
Lots of new housing
with more space
Lots of doors slamming
in our face
I'll get
a terrace apartmt
Better get rid
of your accent
Life can be bright
in America
BOYS:
If you can fight in America
GIRLS:
Life is so bright in America
If you're all-white
in America
La-la, la-la-la, America
La-la, la-la-la,
America
La-la, la-la-la, America
America!
Here you are free
and you have pride
Long as you stay
on your own side
Free to be anything
you choose
Free to wait tables
and shine shoes
I like to be in America
Okay by me in America
Everything free in America
For a small fee in America
I like to be in America
Okay by me in America
Everything free in America
For a small fee in America
La-la, la-la-la, America
La-la,
la-la-la, America
La-la, la-la-la, America
La-la,
la-la-la, America!
(cheering, shouting)
How are we, as virgins,
supposed to follow that?
Tony and Maria
were soul mates, okay?
Against all odds,
they found each other.
I know what that's like.
And you do, too.
So we just have
to play that, okay?
We, as actors,
have to tap into that.
Okay?
(quiet whooshing)
Shouldn't you be celebrating?
I'm going over this move.
I messed it up tonight.
I know I can do it better.
Beauty of the stage...
we get to do it all over again
tomorrow night.
Personally, I thought both of
you guys were perfect.
Thank you.
Your Officer Krupke killed.
Brought the house down.
Well, I can't help
but pull focus, sorry.
Don't apologize.
It was great.
All your friends
were here tonight.
The Warblers...
Sebastian...
They were all loving it.
Come here.
Give me your hand.
Hold it to your heart.
Just like the song?
Like the song.
Kurt...
Sebastian doesn't mean
anything to me.
And you were right...
our first time
shouldn't be like that.
I was drunk and... I'm sorry.
Well, sure beats the
last time you were drunk
and made out with Rachel.
(sighs)
(both laughing)
But I'm sorry, too.
I wanted to be your
gay bar superstar but...
try as I might, I'm still
just a silly romantic.
It's not silly.
You take my breath away.
Not just now;
tonight on that stage.
I was so proud
to be with you.
I hope so.
I want you to be.
Um... Artie's having
an after party at Breadstix.
Would you... accompany me?
No.
I want to go to your house.
Okay.
(dogs barking in distance)
(knocking)
Hi.
I got your flowers.
They were beautiful.
You were really good.
Can I come in?
Yeah.
Where is everybody?
Kurt's out with Blaine,
and Burt and Carole left
for Toledo right after the show.
They got some kind of
meet-and-greet in the morning,
so... spending the night.
Why didn't you stay for
the after party?
I mean, I know that you're still
mad at me abouthe other night.
He didn't like me.
What? Who?
The recruiter.
He watched the game and then
I waited like an idiot
for 20 minutes
while he talked to Shane.
I didn't even shower
or change out of my uniform,
because I was afraid
I'd miss him.
So you guys
are going after Shane?
Kid's a monster.
Look, kid,
just 'cause your football career
ends in high school,
it doesn't mean
your life does.
Wait... I don't,
I don't understand
what any of this means.
It means I suck!
It means I'm gonna
be stuck here forever.
Cooter's not
gonna recruit me!
He said I...
I'd reached my ceiling.
There are other colleges.
Like there are other schools
for you besides NYADA?
I'm not good enough!
I'm not a good enough
quarterback
to get a scholarship!
I'm not a good enough singer
to get into NYADA!
It's all over for me!
Stop it!
Finn, look at me.
Your dreams are
not dead, okay?
You've just
grown out of them.
You have to find
new ones now.
I don't know how.
Then we'll figure
it out together.
You're special.
You know how I know that?
Because I'm going
to give you something
that no one else is
ever gonna get.
You... You don't need
to do this, okay?
The play's over.
There's no point.
No, the point is, is that
I was wrong and stupid
and immature, and probably
not for the last time,
lost in my ambition and...
And now?
Now I'm just a girl,
here with a boy
that she loves,
and wanting to
remember this moment
for the rest of her life.
With this ring, I thee wed.
("One Hand, One Heart"
from West Side Story playing)
Make of our hands
One hand
Make of our hearts
One heart
Make of our vows
One last vow
Only death
Will part
Us now...
RACHEL:
Make of our lives
One life
Day after day
BOTH (in harmony):
Now it begins
Now we start
One hand
One
Heart
Even death won't
Death won't
Part
Us now.
By Mikhel for Subtitulos.es
==SPREAD THE WORD==