Previously on Smash...
What's this Marilyn thing
I keep hearing about?
- Ivy Lynn, Karen Cartwright.
- Classic.
You put in ten years
in the chorus
and Karen-something shows up.
Michael Swift is available
if you're interested
in making him
an offer for DiMaggio.
I had an affair
with Michael Swift.
- It's not going to be cheap.
- What's Jerry's involvement?
Jerry has no involvement.
[Big band jazz music]
That was incredible.
Do you think he gave me the part
because I slept with him?
He is a terrible human being!
[Piano music]
- Hey.
- Hi.
Wow.
[Indistinct conversation]
First day.
I love first days.
Me too.
I am so glad
that you're doing this.
- [Chuckles] Me too.
- Exciting, isn't it?
Hi, Linda.
Where am I?
You and Tom are here,
Derek's there.
Oh, good, you put him
at a different table.
Yeah, I've worked
with him before.
Can you put Tom's assistant
at a different table too?
She's the one who almost
took it out from under our Ivy?
Where's the Marilyn in that?
Could she be more midwest?
Actually no, she was
the golden sprout champion
at the Iowa state fair.
- You made that up.
- I didn't.
- She put it on her resume.
- She's coming, she's coming.
Hi, Dennis.
Karen.
- Yeah, I remember.
- Hi.
Hi.
So do I put
my stuff down here?
You can put it
anywhere you want.
[Clears throat]
The maestro arrives.
- Hi, Derek.
- Yeah, hi.
Hey.
Oh, Michael, hi.
Hi.
Yeah, hi.
[Chuckles]
- Great to be here.
- Well, we're thrilled.
As you know.
It's gonna be fine.
You don't have
to be nervous, okay?
I'm not.
I mean, we're
both adults right?
I was talking
about the workshop.
- Michael, hi.
- Hey, Tom.
You sound great on the demo
of Mr. and Mrs. Smith.
Oh, yeah, it's great.
He's gonna be so great.
- So great.
- [Chuckles]
Thanks.
I think I'm gonna warm up.
Excuse me.
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
- You just seem a little...
- Drop it.
- You know.
- I just mean...
- Drop it.
- Where's Eileen?
- I have no idea.
- Well, where's the money?
- It's not there.
Well, where'd it go?
We are trying
to figure that out.
You are my lawyer.
It's gotta be somewhere.
Jerry is swanning around town
spending as much money
as he ever did!
Well, his family
owns half of Manhattan.
Oh, I know about his family
and their stupid money.
Don't talk
to me about that.
All I need is $200,000,
that's it... $200,000.
Well, you have
access to $8,000.
The rest of it is frozen.
Your husband is...
Very clever.
Oh, I know
he's very clever.
I know he's clever.
[Piano music]
[Indistinct conversation]
- [Claps hands]
- Okay, everyone, here we go.
Welcome to Marilyn.
[Cheers and applause]
- Yeah!
- Bravo!
Okay, settle down, please.
Settle down!
Thank you.
Okay, obviously we're
not gonna have a table read
because the book
is still somewhat in flux.
This'll be primarily
for the ensemble.
We'll put the rest in when
the book is in better shape.
We'll be staging
some of the numbers.
Others will be
at music stands.
We'll have some
costume elements,
a few props
but basically...
It's up to you
to sell it.
Now remember...
This is a workshop.
The road to Broadway
is exceedingly long.
So...
Let's get to it.
- Tom.
- How about a little mambo?
[Laughter]
- Why not?
- Grab a chair, grab a stand.
Both: [Giggling]
Blondie.
[Gasps]
Trying to go to Broadway
without me, huh?
- Oh, my God.
- [Laughs]
Good to see you!
When did you get back?
- Last week.
- Everything okay, children?
- You hired Sam.
- I did.
We did Chicago together.
Six years ago?
- Ten.
- No, come on.
Ten years ago, baby.
We were both in the chorus.
- And you are Marilyn Monroe.
- Mm.
Yeah, actually
nobody is anybody
until we start rehearsing,
okay?
Got it, got it.
Welcome.
[Playing 20th Century Fox mambo]
All: ♪ For fame ♪
♪ play the game ♪
♪ change your name ♪
♪ to the 20th Century Fox ♪
almost.
[Chuckling]
Thanks, everybody.
That's a ten.
You have
a really fantastic voice.
- Did you hear her?
- Yeah, she sounds great.
I knew the song from before,
it was my callback piece.
Oh, your callback for what?
- For Marilyn.
- Well, I'm singing it now.
Mm.
[Giggles]
How come nobody told me
she was going to be here?
- Derek didn't tell you?
- No.
I'm so sorry
you missed it.
- Ivy is sublime.
- How's the rest of the cast?
Michael Swift
is gonna be amazing.
I know I had
my reservations
but I could not
have been more wrong.
The ensemble's terrific.
Even Tom had nothing
to complain about.
[Giggles]
Good.
- Here's to Marilyn.
- She was an interesting woman.
Oh, she certainly was.
God, what a life.
Marilyn had money problems.
Yeah, well the studios
never did pay her
what she was worth.
Of course they didn't.
Both: [Chuckling]
God.
Drinking at the office.
I love this.
Julia, you told me once
that you were
an art history major.
Yeah.
If that were a real Degas,
what would you pay for it?
That?
- Mm-hm.
- [Sighs]
- It is a real Degas.
- Yeah.
[Playing I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl]
♪ Here's a lesson
they should teach in school ♪
♪ when a girl gets curvy
and the boys all drool ♪
♪ if math and science
just ain't you style ♪
♪ just give that teacher
a wink and a smile ♪
♪ for a passing grade
you won't have to wait ♪
♪ and you can thank him
later when you graduate ♪
♪ 'cause I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl ♪
both: ♪ awooo! ♪
♪ no, I never met a man
who wasn't on the prowl ♪
all: ♪ shimmy, shimmy,
aah, gimme, gimme ♪
♪ if a nice diploma
you wanna get ♪
Take it down, Karen!
♪ well then make that teacher
the student's pet ♪
all: ♪ yeah, I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl ♪
I'm sorry,
can we just stop?
I'm sorry.
[Laughs] I'm so sorry.
I'm just having
a little trouble hearing myself.
The chorus is very...
Enthusiastic.
Ensemble.
Well, not everyone
seems to understand that
that means "as one."
[Laughs]
Okay, can
we take our ten now?
Actually, it's lunch.
Oh, sorry.
[Indistinct conversation]
- Hey.
Everything okay?
Absolutely.
Good.
Do you know the actor Lyle West?
That kid
from all the TV shows?
Yeah.
I gave him his first job
when he was eight years old.
I made him a star.
Aw, you're so sentimental.
[Giggles]
Yeah, well I'm sentimental
enough to throw him
a birthday party
on Saturday night.
Do you want to come?
Uh, well, sure.
I... I'd love to.
Good.
Ivy's doing the nasty
with the dark lord, huh?
That's what I said.
[Cell phone buzzes]
Who's the dark lord?
Sauron himself.
Darth Derek.
Oh, look, I better run.
I've got a lunch meeting.
Oh, I'm having lunch
with Tom.
Well, ask him
how the new song is coming.
She's sleeping with him?
I don't think they're
getting all that much sleep.
[Laughter]
- Just saying'.
- Stop talking about my friend.
Oh, calm down.
Why is he sending
messages through you?
If he wants to know
about the new number
he can just ask me.
I'm sure he will.
I know he's not
your favorite person.
What are you
talking about?
I love him.
What a stellar human being.
- A role model for us all.
- [Giggles]
He better treat you right,
that's all I have to say.
I'm a big girl, Tom.
I can take care of myself.
Listen, I have a question.
And I hope
this is okay.
You're my star,
anything's okay.
How come nobody told me
that Karen Cartwright
was gonna be
in the ensemble?
Oh, um...
Actually it was Julia's idea.
She wanted
to give her something.
She did work really hard
on those auditions
and she is impressive.
She completely is.
It just would have helped
to have a heads up.
Absolutely.
My fault.
So could you listen
to the wolf number
when we get back to it
after lunch?
She's just...
She's right next to me
and she's just
a little bit loud.
Oh, so did you hear
that Lyle West is in town?
[Gasps]
Lyle's in town.
God, I haven't
seen him in... forever.
Throwing
a big birthday party
for him this weekend.
He discovered him, you know.
- He did not say that.
- He did.
He told Ivy
he "discovered" Lyle.
[Laughs] What,
did he plant a flag in the kid?
Oh, I think it's so silly
when people take credit
for other people's careers.
Heh.
That was my show he directed.
And the fact is Derek
didn't discover that kid.
I discovered that kid.
He didn't even want to cast him.
I was the one who said
"we have to cast that kid."
How's the new number coming?
You'll get it
when you get it.
What's she upset
about this time?
Nope, no one's upset.
So I hear Lyle west
is in town.
You having a birthday party
for him?
Both true things.
Do you think maybe
you could invite Tom?
Tom!
Lyle West is in town.
I'm having a party
on Saturday night.
You like to come?
I think I have plans.
Well, I'm sure
he'd love to see you.
As would I.
You're welcome
of course too, darling.
And when am I gonna get
to see my new scenes?
I'm on my way home
right now to write them.
Good.
Derek's having
a big party, huh?
I need some bubble wrap.
- Bubble wrap?
- You've heard of it.
Bubble wrap.
[Playing I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl]
♪ ♪
all: ♪ Yeah I never
met a wolf who didn't ♪
- ♪ love to howl ♪
- ♪ awoo! ♪
all: ♪ No, I never met a man
who wasn't on the prowl ♪
all: ♪ shimmy, shimmy,
aw, gimme, gimme ♪
♪ even if that wolf's
just a grey old goat ♪
♪ he still would make
a nice fur coat ♪
Okay, hold on, hold on.
Okay, new idea.
Karen, step back next to Bobby.
What's wrong?
[Dancers murmuring]
Let's take it
from the dance break.
Again!
Five, six, seven and...
♪
- Sorry.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
You okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm just...
[Laughs]
[Sighs]
[Indistinct conversation]
Hey, when you do this
in the theater,
are the numbers still there?
Yes, Iowa, the numbers
are still there in the theater.
Okay, I've just
never done this...
We know.
Bobby, Karen?
- Ugh.
- Come on.
I don't...
What does he mean?
It means we're out
of the number.
Remind me not to stand
next to you anymore.
- What?
- Again!
Five, six, seven, and...
♪
So first she has me
put in the back row.
Then I'm out
of the number altogether.
Dev here.
Yeah, it went great.
A corrections officer got
arrested for a DWI in the Bronx.
The police desk
never even called.
Great, thanks.
[Cell phone beeps]
Sorry... Ivy has
that kind of power?
She's the star,
plus she's sleeping
with the director.
That apparently comes
with all sorts of perks.
She's sleeping
with the director, wow.
You buried the lead.
It's just depressing
that she's allowed
to do
whatever she wants to me.
Maybe you should
just keep your head down.
I'm an actress.
I'm not supposed
to keep my head down,
I'm supposed
to play to the balcony.
[Cell phone rings]
Sorry.
Dev here.
No, no, no, no, Andrew.
I've been on call now
for six days.
- I need a night's sleep.
- I'm going to the gym.
- Hang on.
- I'm okay, I'm okay.
Just... just breathe.
I can't.
Ivy might hear me.
Love you.
No, not you, Andrew.
[Dog barking]
I thought it was nice
that he invited you.
He invited me
because you told him to.
Tom.
You love that kid.
I've heard you say
so many times
how proud
you are of Lyle.
How impressive he was
as a little boy.
How long has it been
since you've seen him?
- Six years.
- Oh, go to the party!
Tom!
- I can't.
- Oh? Why?
- I have a date.
- You have a date?
Yes, I have a date.
Saturday night I have a date.
- You do not.
- I do.
With whom?
Someone my mother knows.
He's taking me
to a steak house.
Your mother...
Set you up?
On a date?
No, that sounds like fun.
That sounds like
a really good idea.
You should do that.
You should do that
instead of going
to a really cool party
honoring the kid
you discovered.
Who you've always liked,
who is now a big TV star.
No, seriously.
A steak house?
That sounds like
much more fun.
[Snores]
Oh!
Tom?
According to your records,
it was purchased from a dealer
in Paris in 1985,
Francois Melinot.
That's right.
I just spoke
to monsieur Melinot.
The provenance seems
to be accurately recorded.
And the sketch
is charming.
Any number of my clients
would love this.
Degas did many sketches
of the little dancers,
but this one
has extraordinary grace notes.
- How much?
- Heh.
Auctions are
notoriously unreliable,
but an authentic Degas sketch
of this quality, 350.
400.
What if I just wanted
to sell it?
Um...
Before we talk details,
I'm a little concerned
about the bill of sale.
Oh, it was a gift
from my husband.
A wedding gift
in fact.
But the bill of sale
is in his name, you see.
Unless you have
a letter of transfer?
He didn't want it.
He doesn't even like it.
Nevertheless, he owns it.
Perhaps you could
have him call me
and I could explain
the legalities.
[Playing
History is made at night]
♪
all: ♪ 'cause history
is made at night ♪
♪ so close the books,
turn off the light ♪
♪ and listen ♪
♪ let my heart
be the teacher ♪
Okay, hold on.
Hold on.
Just give us a second.
Your boys are hogging
all the melody.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Heh.
You know, um,
I should really get going.
I still have
a lot of work to do.
Stay.
I like an audience.
Yeah, well an audience
likes a coherent book.
- Ah.
- So...
You sound great.
Okay.
Let's take it again.
[Playing
History is made at night]
All: ♪ 'cause history
is made at night ♪
♪ so close the books,
turn off the light ♪
♪ and listen ♪
♪ let my heart
be the teacher ♪
♪ no one here
to disapprove ♪
♪ as we review the lessons ♪
♪ you've been missing ♪
Okay, guys.
[Laughs]
Give a girl a chance.
Yeah, she's right.
There's too much sound
in the mix, Tom.
It's eight voices.
They sound fantastic.
It's just... at least
while I'm learning it.
Sure, sure. Karen, why don't
you sit this one out?
- I can tone it down.
- It's just for now.
We just need to hear
the number without you.
Excuse me.
Let's take it again.
♪
all: ♪ 'cause history
is made at night ♪
♪ so close the books,
turn off the light ♪
♪ and listen ♪
♪ no one here
to disapprove ♪
♪ as we review the lessons ♪
How's it going in there?
How do you think
it's going?
It's horrible.
It's...
And you guys
are just horrible too.
- Whoa.
- Don't say "whoa," it's true.
She's trying to get me fired
and you guys are, like,
"she's a hick,
she's from Iowa."
I am just as good
as any of you guys.
- Shh! They can hear.
- It's true.
I am the same as you.
You were all beginners too.
And I'm good.
I could've done that.
I could've slept with him.
I could've, he...
And I didn't.
And I wouldn't.
And that doesn't make me
stupid or lame
or untalented.
And she shouldn't
be trying to get me fired.
And you should be trying
to help me.
[Pop song playing
inside store]
What are we doing?
Jessica had
a mother Theresa,
come-to-Jesus moment.
- We're helping.
- $250?
Flesh tone tights
with fishnet stockings on top
to get some texture.
You wear that
under some loose pants,
some high-top sneakers,
and a sweater
- cut off at the neckline.
- Okay.
You come into rehearsal
with your hair down,
go into the bathroom,
take off your sweats
and your sweater,
put your hair up in a pony tail
and come back in.
So it's like high school,
you try and look
like everyone else.
All: Exactly.
- Where do you take class?
- What kind of class?
- Dance class.
- [Laughs]
We'll get you into ours,
it's good.
But maybe tonight
we should do an intervention.
Could we?
Divorce is not
the most fun thing
that's ever happened
to me in my life.
I'm trying
to sell this sketch.
Yes.
Jerry's name
is on the bill of sale.
It's a problem.
- Yes.
- I hate Jerry.
I used to love him.
That sketch looks to me
like our happiness
and I... I don't know
why it still looks that way.
Let's get
you outta here.
Lyle west is in town,
do you know him?
We did Oliver together
when he was 11 years old.
Well, Derek is throwing
him a birthday party.
Uh, I don't think
I'm up to it.
Just come
for a little while.
Let me just call
and make sure that Jerry's
not gonna be there.
Lyle was such
a sweet little boy.
[As Oliver]
"Please, sir, I want some more."
[Laughs]
Yeah, well that sweet boy
is now a mega-zillionaire.
Oh, yeah,
don't you know?
His last show
was sold into syndication
for $80 million.
80 million?
It was just in the trades,
just last week.
Derek... oh, good.
I'm glad I caught you.
80 million, mm.
Hey, I'm just... I'm saying
you didn't have
to pull a diva on her.
I didn't even
pull half a diva.
And trust me,
they never would have cut her
just to make me
feel better.
Ivy, baby, it's not
like I know this chick.
I'm not all worried
about her feelings,
- it's just... oh, no, look at this.
- What?
My Mets, they have,
like, no pitching this season.
- None.
- Well, I'm not apologizing.
Woman, for the last time
I'm not asking you
to apologize,
I'm... oh, my God.
Sam, the Mets
are gonna be fine.
Not "oh, my God,
the poor Mets."
Oh, my God,
you look amazing.
- I do?
- You do.
- Really?
- Really.
It's a Zac Posen.
[Giggles]
I think it's only
been worn once.
And the zipper
still works and everything.
Me
[zipper zips]
Hey, love,
you're home late.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Hi, Bobby.
Dev, nice to meet you.
What the...?
Oh, mm!
Okay.
Karen?
Oh, sorry about this.
Everyone, this
is my boyfriend Dev.
Well done, Iowa.
Uh, you're
all here because...
We're doing
an intervention.
Oh, things haven't improved,
I gather.
I'm not gonna lie,
it's a disaster.
This is cute.
[Playing Haven't met you yet]
♪ I'm not surprised,
not everything lasts ♪
♪ I've broken my heart
so many times ♪
♪ I've stopped
keeping track ♪
♪ I talk myself in,
I talk myself out ♪
♪ I get all worked up
and then I let myself down ♪
♪ I tried so very hard
not to lose it ♪
♪ I came up
with a million excuses ♪
♪ I thought I thought
of every possibility ♪
♪ but somehow I know
that it'll all turn out ♪
♪ and you'll make me work
so we can work to work it out ♪
♪ and I promise you, kid,
that I'll give so much more ♪
♪ than I get ♪
♪ I just haven't
met you yet ♪
♪ they say all's fair ♪
♪ in love and war ♪
♪ but I won't need
to fight it ♪
♪ we'll get it right ♪
♪ and we'll be united ♪
♪ oh, you know
that it'll all tn n out ♪
♪ and you'll make me work
so we can work to work it out ♪
♪ hey, and I promise you, kid,
that I'll give so much more ♪
♪ than I get ♪
♪ I just haven't
met you yet ♪
[cheers and applause]
Thank you.
[Sighs]
- You look stunning.
- Your place is beautiful.
Thanks.
Lyle, this is Ivy.
She's playing my Marilyn.
I can immediately see
why they cast you as Marilyn.
That dress is amazing.
Lyle.
This is very precocious
behavior for a 15-year-old.
[Chuckles]
I'm 12, you jerk.
And precocious would
be showing her the bedrooms.
Would you like
to see the bedrooms?
Oh, you're adorable.
- She thinks I'm kidding.
- Mm-hm.
I so wish
you didn't think that.
You played beautifully.
I finished
my mba at wharton,
even though I knew
that ultimately the law
was going to be
more compelling to me.
Why?
How did you know?
"Applied principles
of macro-dynamics
in developing economies."
I was as bored
as you look right now.
[Laughs] No.
Don't be polite,
it's not necessary.
I'm boring myself, frankly.
I'm a little nervous.
You don't look nervous.
Seriously, I had no intention
of going out on a date
that my mother
set up for me
but then I checked you out
online and I thought... wow.
[Clinks wine glass]
Yay, mom.
Hm.
Hi, we're friends
of Derek's.
I know who you are,
Mrs. Rand.
I have something here, I'd
like to put it somewhere safe.
Sure, right this way.
I'll see you inside.
You know, Mrs. Rand,
I'm an actress and a dancer.
Not now, sweetheart.
Ellis?
Julia, hi!
Uh, this
is my friend Cynthia.
Cyn.
People call me "Cyn."
Oh.
Julia is Tom's
writing partner.
Oh, of course.
I know who you are.
Well, he talks about
you guys all the time.
He's, like, obsessed.
Not obsessed.
Interested.
I'm surprised
to see you here, Ellis.
Is Tom here?
I haven't seen him.
Excuse me.
Lyle?
- Eileen.
- Hi.
[Kisses]
Are you hiding here
all alone on the stairs?
I am.
It's so great that Derek
did this for me but sometimes
parties like this,
I feel like I have to be "on."
Well, you're
a big star now.
You'd think you'd
get used to it.
You'd be wrong.
I was really hoping
to just see my friends.
Well, I think you'll find
you have a lot of those
now that your show's
gone into syndication.
You got that right.
[Laughs]
I was reading the trades
and I thought,
"mm, my goodness,
what is Lyle gonna do
with all that cash?"
Well, I'm
all over the map.
My business manager
has me in Sri Lanka's
Colombo stock exchange,
the classic car market.
Mm.
Drinks!
Now what exactly
is the problem?
I think she's
a wonderful dancer.
Her dancing isn't the problem,
it's actually fierce.
It's not, like,
all trained and perfect.
- But it's watchable.
- Watchable?
I'm watching her
and I usually
like to watch myself
in the mirror.
That's true.
- Ivy's the problem.
- Ivy's fine.
The problem is you,
miss artichoke heart.
Golden sprout champion,
and it was a great day for me
so don't
make fun of it.
Yeah, but you didn't sign up
to be champion this time.
That's Ivy's job.
You signed up
to be her backup singer.
- I'm trying.
- Oh, my God.
You are so not trying.
Ladies...
Should we show her
how it's done?
Move this table.
Please, help me.
- I'm getting a show?
- You're getting a lesson.
Oh.
- This way?
- Yup.
We told you that
we're in the same dance class.
Now watch and learn.
What are we doing?
- Rumour has it.
- Ooh, perfect.
Lucky you.
Both: [Giggling]
Don't lose focus,
eyes out.
[Playing Rumour has it]
Nobody's bigger than anybody.
Nobody's out of line.
Everybody's in it.
♪ Ooh-ooh
ooh-ooh ♪
Five, six, seven, eight.
♪ She, she ain't real ♪
♪ she ain't gonna be able
to love you like I will ♪
- [laughs]
- Stop.
Okay.
♪ She is a stranger ♪
♪ you and I have history
or don't you remember? ♪
♪ sure, she's
got it all ♪
♪ but, baby, is that
really what you want ♪
[Laughs]
I'm surprised no one's
mentioned art to you.
It's the one investment
that never loses its value.
Art and gold bullion.
You know why?
- The Chinese.
- The Chinese like Degas?
No, the Chinese
like a good investment.
Currencies are failing,
the stock market is a mess.
Art and gold bullion.
Those are your choices.
How much do you need?
- 200,000.
- 200,000... that's all?
Well, for those of us
who aren't in syndication,
that's rather a lot.
I tell you what.
I'll give you 175
for the drawing.
Keep it as collateral
and you give me points.
Why would
I give you the sketch
if I'm giving you points?
If Marilyn flops
I still come out even.
And if it's a success,
then you get your sketch back.
Which you wouldn't
if you just sold it to me.
Little Lyle,
all grown up.
- One point.
- Three.
1 1/2,
and I get the money this week.
How do I know
if the show's any good?
I mean, it's
all in the execution.
That's a fair question.
- Scotch?
- Mm-hm.
- Find Tom.
- Oh! There you are.
Yeah, and
do me a favor.
Get our DiMaggio
on the phone too.
You want me
to call Michael?
Why?
He... he's probably
at home with his family.
I don't want to...
- Hold this.
- Oh.
Damn.
[Sighs]
And one, two, three, four.
And five, six, seven, eight.
And one, two... okay.
Too much.
Let me do it next to you.
Five, six, seven, eight.
- And one, two...
- No, no, stop pulling focus.
From the arms... seven, eight.
One, two...
You guys are worse
than the New York press.
One, two, three, four.
And one, two, three, four.
- Hi.
This better be good.
I don't actually
know what it is.
- Hi
- hi.
- Oh, John.
- What's going on?
- I... I don't know.
- God, look at you.
You need me?
A-ha!
The reinforcements
have arrived.
I knew they would.
It's showtime.
Today... is my birthday.
I'm so glad
you're all here with me.
Thank you.
Derek Wills and Tom Levitt
cast me my first musical
off-Broadway when
I was just eight years old.
So they were best friends as
well as being the best friends
an eight-year-old wannabe
musical theater star
could hope for.
And so I asked them, as a gift,
to play me a song
from their new musical Marilyn,
and they said yes!
[Cheers and applause]
[Clears throat]
Well, we've, uh,
just started learning
the big USO number where Marilyn
sings to the troops.
That sound like something
you might wanna hear?
All: Yeah!
[Cheers and applause]
It's in G,
very easy changes.
Just... read my mind.
Uh, ladies and gentlemen.
Marilyn herself.
Ivy Lynn.
[Applause]
[Playing I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl]
♪ When you are born
with sex appeal ♪
♪ in the forest
called Hollywood ♪
♪ you'll find more wolves
at your back door ♪
♪ than that
little red riding hood ♪
♪ now she and
her little old grandma ♪
♪ could have learned
from the men I've dated ♪
♪ that a wolf ♪
♪ can be quite ♪
♪ a devotee ♪
both: ♪ once
he's domesticated ♪
♪
♪ there's a lesson
they should teach in school ♪
♪ when a girl gets curvy
and the boys all drool ♪
♪ if math and science
just ain't your style ♪
♪ just give that teacher a wink ♪
♪ for a passing grade
you won't have to wait
♪ and you can thank him later
when you graduate ♪
♪ 'cause I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl ♪
all: ♪ awoo!! ♪
♪ no, I never met a man ♪
♪ who wasn't on the prowl ♪
♪shimmy, shimmy,
aw, gimme, gimme♪
♪if a nice diploma
you want to get
♪ well then make that teacher
the student's pet ♪
♪yeah, I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl ♪
all: ♪ whoo! ♪
♪ you never know
where a wolf might crouch ♪
♪ but his natural habitat's
the casting couch ♪
♪ so take lots of pictures
of the wildlife ♪
♪ to tell the wolf
you could share with his wife ♪
♪ the hunter gets
captured by the game ♪
♪ then Leo the lion
will be roaring your name! ♪
♪ yeah, I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl ♪
all: ♪ awooo! ♪
♪ no, I never met a man
who wasn't on the prowl ♪
all: ♪ shimmy, shimmy,
aw, gimme, gimme ♪
♪ if your face and figure
are whistle-bait ♪
♪ honey, you'll have the keys
to the studio gate! ♪
♪ yeah, I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl ♪
oh! Oh! Aah!
All: ♪ the three little piggies
sure had it wrong ♪
♪ when the wolf came a-knockin'
in that old song ♪
♪ if he's huffin'
and puffin' and saying' ♪
all: ♪ "Marilyn, I gotcha" ♪
♪ I said, "come on in,"
and I put on Sinatra ♪
all: ♪ oh, Frankie! ♪
♪ a wealthy wolf
likes to buy his toys ♪
♪ but he really
is just one of the boys ♪
♪ if you've got something
for which he's craving ♪
♪ it sure is good
that he's been saving ♪
♪ be a fan,
give his cheek a peck ♪
♪ but get his autograph
on a cashier's check! ♪
all: ♪ yeah, I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl ♪
♪ awooo! ♪
♪ no, I never met a man
who wasn't on the prowl ♪
♪ shimmy, shimmy,
aw, gimme, gimme ♪
♪ this wolf looks like
he's ready to dine ♪
♪ tell me where can I sign
on the dotted line? ♪
all: ♪ yeah, I never met a wolf
who didn't love to howl! ♪
♪ oh, yeah! ♪
You are thrilling.
- Ah.
- Honestly.
Thank you.
Are you still interested
in showing me those bedrooms?
Wonderful.
[Chuckles]
- [Giggling]
- And this is the third bedroom.
This is even nicer...
Eileen, hi.
I-I'm so sorry.
There's no need
to apologize.
I was just looking
at past happiness.
But you're
my happiness now.
You were wonderful.
Thank you.
I'll be by your office
on Monday, Eileen.
[Cries]
That was so much fun.
I gotta go.
She rocked it, didn't she?
Awesome.
Good night.
[Piano music playing]
♪
Wow.
- Wow?
- That was...
Impressive.
As impressive
as the TV star?
Is there
a TV star here?
I'm too dazzled
by the piano player to notice.
Yay, mom.
Hm.
[Rock music playing]
Yeah, yeah, no...
Apart from the, uh, explosion
at the Sewage Center
in Queens,
it was an utterly,
wonderfully uneventful weekend.
Is he always
on the phone?
He was in charge of
the press office all weekend.
Wow, he's important
and good-looking.
- Stop.
- I've gotta go.
- I'll take care of these.
- Ooh, I like him.
- Sweet.
- Thank you.
Hi.
- Gosh, I hate shots.
- Cheers.
Bottoms up.
Come on, Iowa, let's show 'em
what the chorus looks like.
- You ready?
- Okay.
- You ready for this?
- We can do this.
- I can do this.
- Come on.
[Indistinct conversation]
Hang on.
Where are you going?
Don't bother.
I saw you, Derek.
- Saw me what?
- That woman.
I saw you.
Everybody saw you.
Saw me what, flirting?
- Your hand was on her ass.
- Ivy.
Everyone at this party
is a potential investor, okay?
So, yeah, I am gonna flirt,
and I'm gonna put my hand
on the asses
of pretty women
if it makes them
feel that our show
is the one they want
to throw millions of dollars at.
It's meaningless.
How come you didn't
tell me you cast Karen?
She didn't get the part.
You did.
They loved you tonight.
This is who you are now.
Get used to it.
This show means
everything to me.
- I just want to feel safe.
- Then go back to the chorus.
There's nothing safe
about being a star.
You know, the bedrooms here
really are incredible.
Perhaps you should show them
to me then.
[Playing Rumour has it]
Five, six, seven, eight.
♪ She, she ain't real ♪
♪ she ain't gonna be able
to love you like I will ♪
♪ she is a stranger ♪
♪ you and I have history
or don't you remember? ♪
♪ sure, she's
got it all ♪
♪ but, baby, is that really
what you want? ♪
♪ bless your soul, you've got
your head in the clouds ♪
♪ she made a fool
out of you ♪
♪ and, boy,
she's bringing you down ♪
♪ she made
your heart melt ♪
♪ but she's cold
to the core ♪
♪ now rumour has it she
ain't got your love anymore ♪
♪ rumour has it, ooh ♪
♪ rumour has it, ooh,
rumour has it, ooh ♪
♪ rumour has it, ooh ♪
♪ rumour has it, ooh,
rumour has it, ooh ♪
♪
[music slows down]
♪ all of these words ♪
♪ whispered in my ear ♪
♪ tell a story that ♪
♪ I cannot bear to hear ♪
♪ just 'cause I said it ♪
♪ don't mean
that I meant it ♪
♪ people say crazy things ♪
♪ just 'cause I said it ♪
♪ don't mean
that I meant it ♪
♪ just 'cause you heard it ♪
[music speeds up]
♪ hey! ♪
♪ rumour has it ♪
all: ♪ rumour has it,
rumour has it ♪
♪ whoa-whoa-yeah-yeah! ♪
♪ whoa-whoa-whoa,
yeah-yeah! ♪
whoa!
- All: ♪ rumour has it ♪
- ♪ yeah-yeah ♪
♪ whoa-whoa-hey! ♪
♪ come on now! ♪
♪ rumour has it ♪
♪ he's the one
I'm leaving you for ♪
[cheers and applause]
Whoa!
♪ ♪
- That was great!
- [Laughs] Whoo!
Resync, corrected by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com