♪♪ [ Rock 'N' Roll ]
♪ Bye, bye, Birdie ♪
♪ I'm gonna miss you so ♪
♪ Why'd ya have to go ♪
[ Girls ]
♪ Bye, bye ♪
♪ No more sunshine ♪
♪ Sunshine ♪
♪ It's followed you away ♪
♪ You away ♪
♪ I'll cry, Birdie ♪
♪ Birdie ♪
♪ Till you're home to stay ♪
♪ I'll miss the way you smile
As though it's just for me ♪
♪ And each and every night
I'll write you faithfully ♪
♪ Bye, bye, Birdie ♪
♪ It's awful hard to bear ♪
♪ Guess I'll always care ♪
♪ Guess I'll always care ♪♪
[ Girls Screaming ]
Look! Look!
[ Chattering In Chinese ]
I'm gonna enter you in Washington.
Hey! Hey!
Ho! Hey!
Look! Look! Hey!
Oooh, hey!
[ Women screaming ]
[ Girls ]
♪ We love you, Conrad ♪
♪ Oh, yes, we do ♪
♪ And we'll be true ♪
♪ When you're not near us ♪
♪ We're blue ♪
♪ Oh, Conrad
We love you ♪
♪ We love you, Conrad ♪
This is John Daly reporting
with the CBS mobile unit...
in front of
the nation's capital...
bringing you special
on-the-spot coverage
of our current teenage crisis...
over the drafting
of Conrad Birdie.
Sociologists agree
that Birdie is a phenomenon.
And for those few music lovers
who have never attended
one of his concerts,
here are some news photos
tracing his meteoric rise.
And that- that is
our army's newest weapon.
Private Birdie reports
for his induction in ten days.
His income drops from
two million dollars a year...
to $78 a month.
It could only happen
in America.
Why?
Why did they
have to draft him?
Just when I finally write
a song he's gonna do.
The title song
of his next picture.
"Mumbo Jumbo Gooey Gumbo."
Now there's no picture.
There's nothing.
Albert, I have
your financial statement
if you really want to hear it.
Total assets: $312.08.
[ Coughing ]
Liabilities:
$4,030.00
[ Choking ]
You-
Confidentially,
you're a fiscal fiasco.
Good-bye, Albert.
It's a sad ending
to a long association.
Yeah. Oh, don't you wanna
say good-bye to Pidge?
Almaelou's busted, Pidge.
Better get yourself
another meal ticket.
In six years,
I never sold one lousy song.
Maybe they weren't lousy enough.
I don't care so much
about myself,
but I'm my mother's sole support.
I've wasted every cent
my father left Mama-
It's not your fault.
Your mother wants you
to be a songwriter.
You can make a good living
as a biochemist.
That's a wonderful profession.
But Mama, she wants-
Just because she was once
in vaudeville doesn't mean that
you belong in show business.
Confidentially, I respect my mother,
but I do what I want.
Well, Mama's sensitive.
When I upset her, she faints.
Why, with your ideas, you can
make a fortune in chemistry.
Chemistry. Chemistry.
Chemistry!
You sound like Rosie.
Where is she? Where's Rosie?
She phoned. she heard about
Birdie being drafted. Said she
was gonna see Ed Sullivan.
Sure, to get another job.
Oh, fine secretary.
Why, we have been
practically engaged!
Just waiting for an okay from Mama.
Now when I hit bottom,
Rosie deserts me.
Quits before my body's even warm.
Ed Sullivan!
Would you send in
Rosie De Leon, please.
I-Is it yes, Mr. Sullivan?
It's just got to be yes.
Rosie, it is yes.
Oh, hallelujah!
Oh, I love you!
Oh, that's marvelous!
Oh, I love you too!
I'm so glad!
Miss De Leon. I'd like you to
meet our producer Bob Precht.
- Oh, hi, how are you?
- Well, it's my pleasure.
You know, Rosie, if you
can overcome your shyness, tell me,
what's our using Birdie
on the show got to do with you?
Let's face it, I'm a scheming woman.
I have a promotion idea that'll knock you out.
If you buy it,
I want a little favor.
All right, let's try it on for size.
How'd you like a terrific
buildup before the show...
that'll have every TV set
tuned in to you next Sunday?
We will have. After all, we've got
the Moscow Ballet and Birdie.
- This is bigger.
- Bigger.
Before Conrad Birdie goes into
the army, he bestows a farewell
kiss on all the swooning girls...
who worship him on your TV show.
After all, it's only
an hour show and Birdie
only gets four minutes.
He kisses them all symbolically.
- What'd you say?
- Symbolically.
- Actually, he'll only kiss one girl.
- He kisses only one girl?
Can't you see it? Birdie,
their idol, their leader,
kissing one fabulously
lucky teenage tessie?
- Yeah! Yeah!
- It'll melt every bobby pin in America.
It's gigantic! The newspapers'll eat it up.
Think of the advance publicity.
Rosie, get Birdie's fan club file
right away, and get us a girl from Ohio.
Gotcha.
Bob, we'll do it from the stage
of the outdoor theater,
- Columbus, Ohio,right after the Ballet.
- I'll get the girl.
The network will handle
all the physical details.
And after the kiss,
Birdie sings a big song.
And that's where
Rosie gets her payoff.
I don't get it.
The song is "One Last Kiss."
- Never heard of it.
- Hasn't been written yet.
And who is going
to write this classic?
Who else, but my future husband,
Mr. Albert F. Peterson?
Who else?
Oh, Birdie's been wanting to give
Albert a break for six years.
I know he'll use the song
if you say so.
Okay, in a spot like this,
any song will do,
even though it's written
by your ever-loving Albert.
Thank you, Mr. Sullivan.
You know with a plug like this, that
song'll sell a million records.
Man, what royalties!
Well, we can sure use the money.
Any day now, Albert and I will
have another mouth to feed.
[ Sullivan ] Rosie.
- You're not even married yet.
- His mother.
- Oh?
- Bye.
Carmine, get me the publishing
department right away!
This batch'll do. Get 'em ready
for mailing right away.
- Hi, Marge.
- Hi.
- I need one of your fans from Ohio.
- You can have 'em all.
- Try file number six.
- Okay.
Uh, six- Here we go.
I'm about to make some
ga-ga little goof a queen.
Ohhh.
Hey, cute.
Long distance. I want, uh...
Miss Kim McAfee, Sweet Apple
135, Sweet Apple, Ohio.
Oh, Marge, it's amazing
what a woman has to do
to get a man to marry her.
- You mean you doped Albert's mother?
- No.
But if this doesn't work,
that's my next move.
What, operator? The line's busy.
Well, um, uh, never mind.
I'll try later.
Thank you.
Oh, Marge, right now, there's
a kid named Kim McAfee...
in Sweet Apple, Ohio,
gabbing on the telephone,
but little does she realize
I'm about to make her immortal.
[ Girl ] Hello?
- Hello, Urse? This is Kim.
And if I don't tell somebody,
I'm just gonna burst.
So, Ursula, you are
the very first to know.
I just got pinned
by Hugo Peabody.
Oh, no!
Kim McAfee, you didn't!
You really got pinned?
You mean you and Hugo have
a permanent understanding?
Uh-huh. Oh, it's Hugo
and I... forever.
Crazy, crazy!
Tell me, Kim.
How do you absolutely feel...
in your deepest, secret soul?
It's like-
It's like I've been reborn.
It's like all my life
until this very moment,
I was nothing.
- It's like-
- Kim, I must use the phone.
I've got to call Grandma.
In a second, Mom.
Hey, listen, Ursula,
I'm gonna have to get off.
- Where was I?
- You were nothing.
Oh, yeah.
And now I'm alive.
Fulfilled.
Now I know what it means
to be a woman.
It should only happen to me.
Kim, where did he pin you?
On the back seat.
Oh, bless that lovely
yellow school bus.
Kim, hurry, please.
Yeah, hang up, Kim,
so I can spread the word.
Okay, bye, Urse.
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ursula ]
♪ Hi, Nancy ♪
♪ Hi, Ursula ♪
♪ What's the story morning glory ♪
♪ What's the tale nightingale ♪
♪ Did you hear about Hugo and Kim ♪
♪ Hi, Margie ♪
♪ Hi, Alice
What's the story morning glory ♪
♪ What's the word, hummingbird
Have you heard about Hugo and Kim ♪
[ All Girls ]
♪ Did they really get pinned
Did she kiss him and cry ♪
♪ Did he pin the pin on
Or was he too shy ♪
♪ Well, I heard they got pinned ♪
[ Boys ] ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I was hopin' they would ♪
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ Now they're livin' at last ♪
♪ He's gone ♪
♪ Goin' steady for good ♪
♪ Hello, Mr. Henkel
This is Harvey Johnson ♪
[ Voice Cracking ]
♪ Can I talk to Penelope Ann ♪
♪ Is it true about Kim ♪
♪ Penelope ♪
♪ I just knew it somehow ♪
♪ About the prom ♪
♪ I must call her right up ♪
♪ Saturday ♪
♪ I can't talk to you now ♪
♪ Goin' steady ♪
[ Boys ]
♪ You know it, man ♪
♪ Goin' steady ♪
♪ It's crazy, man ♪
♪ You know it ♪
♪ It won't last ♪
♪ Not at all ♪
♪ He's too thin ♪
♪ She's too tall ♪
♪ Hello, Mrs. Miller
This is Harvey Johnson ♪
[ Voice Cracking ]
♪ Can I speak to Debra Sue ♪
♪ Hiya, Hugo
Hiya, stupid ♪
♪ What'd ya wanna go get pinned for ♪
♪ You don't know how to live ♪
♪ You meathead ♪
♪ You'd get pinned if you could ♪
♪ Lost your marbles ♪
♪ Kim and I are in love ♪
- ♪ Are you nutty ♪
- ♪ Goin' steady for- ♪
♪ Hello, Mrs. Garfein ♪
♪ Is Charity homefrom school yet ♪
♪ Did they really get pinned ♪
♪ Goin' steady ♪
♪ He's gone ♪
♪ I was hopin' they would ♪
♪ Goin' steady ♪
♪ He's gone ♪
♪ They're livin' at last ♪
♪ Goin' steady for good ♪
♪ She nailed him ♪
♪ If ya gotta go
That's the way to go ♪
♪ When they got you hooked
Then you're really cooked ♪
♪ Ooo-ooo ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do
Whatcha gonna do ♪
♪ Ooo-ooo ♪
♪ Well, I heard they got pinned ♪
♪ Oh, man ♪
♪ I was thinkin' they would ♪
♪ Now they're livin' at last
Goin' steady for good ♪
♪ Oh, man ♪
♪ Goin' steady, goin' steady
goin' steady for good ♪
♪ Ooo, ooo, ooo ♪
♪ He's in love with Kim
Kim's in love with him ♪
♪ Well, well, do tell ♪
♪ Goin' steady, Goin' steady for good ♪
♪ That's the way it should be ♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪ They'll be happy, I know ♪
♪ Goin' steady for me ♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪ That's the way it should go ♪
♪ Goin' steady ♪
♪ Steady for good ♪
♪ Steady for ♪
♪ Goin' steady ♪
♪ Oooooh... yeah! ♪♪
[ Cooing ]
Poor Pidge.
He'll starve.
Here, Pidge.
Here, Pidgie.
Here, boy.
[ Humming, Gasps ]
- Albert!
- Here, Pidgie.
Albert, no, no!
Don't jump! Don't jump!
Albert, it's all right.
Everything's all right.
Come on back.
Don't worry about-
Come on.
Ooh, Albert.
Oh. Oh.
Oh, thank heavens
I got here in time.
You almost pushed me out.
It's all right. I just came
from Ed Sullivan's office.
Sullivan!
- Yes.
- Go to work for Ed Sullivan.
Leap from the sinking ship
while the house is on fire.
Oh no-
But hear this, Miss De Leon.
I was loyal.
All the years I've employed you,
I never looked for a job behind your back.
- I went to Sullivan's office-
- Don't explain. You owe me nothing.
- Even though you were molded by me.
- Molded?
Yeah, like, that Eliza Doolittle
got moldy from Pygmalion.
- I was molded?
- Where were you when I found you anyway?
Hostess at La Casa Enchilada
Taco and Tamale Shop.
Well- Well, sorry
I interrupted you!
A man of my ilk
does not commit suicide.
I've had just about enough
of your kind of ilks too.
Suicide is for cowards.
I don't desert the woman I love.
Oh, Albert, I'm-
I'm... sorry.
[ Sighs ]
I should have known.
- Mama would never get over it.
- Mama?
Mam-
[ Stammers, Sighs ]
- What's the matter?
- I'm the prize dope of all time.
Thinkin' I could pry you away from
your Mama's ever-lovin' tentacles.
Rosie, I will thank you to leave
my mother out of this. Maybe
she does influence me, slightly.
- Slightly? Ha!
- She is old and frail.
- Which I will be, too, at this rate.
- Oh, I don't blame you, Albert.
I was living in fantasy,
telling myself you were serious.
Oh, Rosie, I was.
I am... in here.
Oh, I've thought about
marrying you every day,
a lot of nights too.
I've spent six years on Project Albert.
Well, now,
I haven't got the right.
I can't offer you security.
A wonderful girl like you,
you deserve more from a husband
than just personality and good looks.
But I'll always love you, Rosie.
You'd better always
love me, you nut,
because you're stuck with me.
Now, you've always worried
about repaying your mother, right?
Well, from now on,
she'll be set for life.
She can sit around on her big,
fat trust fund and you and I
will have our own little house-
No! I don't care what Sullivan pays you,
no woman is supporting Albert Peterson.
Oh, you're not listening, darling.
I am not a gigolo.
Will you get to that piano
and start composing?
- Mary, I want Kim McAfee, Sweet
Apple 135, Sweet Apple, Ohio.
- I'm through composing.
I was always through,
but now I know it.
Yeah, that's right.
You're a biochemist, but this
is one song you can sell.
- Huh?
- Okay, call me back.
- As I was saying, huh?
- Gee, you're slow today.
Now, you are going to write
a song called "One Last Kiss."
Is this Albert's floor
or is it the one below?
"One Last Kiss."
Now.
♪ Oh, one last kiss ♪
♪ There never was such bliss ♪
♪ I love your dentifrice ♪♪
- Uh, oh, a little too clinical.
- Yeah, you're right.
[ Shoes Squeaking ]
Albert!
Mama? she's never been to the
office since she discovered canasta.
Well, now's a perfect time for you
to tell her about dissolving Almaelou-
Yeah.
- And about us.
- Yeah.
Albert!
Sonny! Ohh!
- Mama!
- Baby!
What a nice surprise.
And you're just in time
for some wonderful news.
- Oh!
- What's the matter?
- It's nothing, son. I just fainted in the subway.
- Mama!
But I didn't fall down.
It was too crowded.
- I keep tellin' ya, take a taxi.
- Taxis?
Taxis are for my successful son.
A dirty, crowded subway
is good enough for a mother.
Mothers are nothin' nowadays.
Who's that?
Mama, you know Rose De Leon.
And guess what?
This is that pretty Rose De Leon?
Oh, I don't believe it.
Rose, what happened to you?
Ya had a fatal sickness or somethin'?
It's nice to see you again.
[ Typing ]
Always on the job.
She's a credit to the firm.
Look at her, son.
I wonder some older man
hasn't snatched her away.
- Personable matron.
- Mama, speaking of marriage-
Wonderful institution.
Your poor father and I,
that was a marriage.
May he rest in peace.
Don't worry, Lou.
Our only child is taking care of me.
He'd never do anything to break my heart.
What about marriage?
Well, if it was good enough
for you and Papa, it's-
In time.
You're just a baby.
[ Phone Ringing ]
Hello?
Yes, operator, I'll hold on.
I'm thinking of dissolving Almaelou.
Wait, Lou. I'm comin'.
I'll be right up there.
We can play canasta again.
- Mama. Mama, forget it. I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
Good-bye, sonny.
Take care of yourself.
Think of me on Mother's Day.
- Good-bye, Rosie.
- Good-bye, Mae.
Call me Mrs. Peterson.
Wear your rubbers.
That's right, operator.
Miss Kim McAfee.
[ Shoes Squeaking ]
I'll tell her, Rosie,
tonight.
It's entirely up to you, Albert.
The line is still busy?
Yes, Hugo. Mm-hmm.
Well, of course I'll always
wear it, on everything.
Oh, except my gym blouse.
Miss Turgnisht won't allow it.
Tonight? Well, I have no plans.
I think I can get out till about ten.
Oh, you have to be in by nine.
Well, c'est la vie.
Until tonight then,
mon amour.
Bye.
♪ When you're
a skinny child of 15 ♪
♪ Wired with braces
from ear to ear ♪
♪ You doubt that you
will ever be appealing ♪
♪ Then hallelujah.
You are 16 and the braces disappear ♪
♪ And your skin
is smooth and clear ♪
♪ And you have
that happy grown-up ♪
♪ Female feeling ♪
♪ How lovely to be a woman ♪
♪ The wait was well worthwhile ♪
♪ How lovely to wear mascara ♪
♪ And smile a woman's smile ♪
♪ How lovely to have a figure ♪
♪ That's round instead of flat ♪
♪ Whenever you hear boys whistle ♪
♪ You're what they're whistling at ♪
♪ It's wonderful to feel ♪
♪ The way a woman feels ♪
♪ It gives you such a glow ♪
♪ Just to know you're wearing
lipstick and heels ♪
♪ How lovely to be a woman ♪
♪ And have one job to do ♪
♪ To pick out a boy and train him ♪
♪ And then when you are through ♪
♪ You've made him the man
you want him ♪
♪ To be ♪
♪ How lovely to be a woman ♪
♪ Like me ♪
♪ How wonderful to know ♪
♪ The things a woman knows ♪
♪ How marvelous to wait for a date ♪
♪ In simply beautiful clothes ♪
♪ How lovely to be a woman ♪
♪ And change from boys to men ♪
♪ To go to
a fancy nightclub ♪
♪ And stay out after ten ♪
♪ How lovely to be so grown-up ♪
♪ And free ♪
[ Zipper Zips ]
♪ Life's lovely
when you're a woman ♪
♪ Like me ♪♪
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Woman ]
Hello? Oh. Oh,
hold on, operator.
- Kim, it's for you. she says it's long distance.
- Thank you, Doris.
Who could be calling-
Did you say "Doris"?
It's the modern way, dear.
It makes mother and daughter
more like friends.
Harry, I think you took
the news about Hugo and I
awfully well. Hello?
- She called you "Harry."
- Yeah.
Yes, this is Miss Kim McAfee.
Yesterday I was a mother.
Today I'm a friend.
- Yes, I'll hold on.
- Could call me "Mom"? That's modern.
[ Groans ]
Times are changing.
You go along or else
you're out of it.
Harry, do you have a cigarette?
I've run out.
So have I.
How 'bout my pipe?
[ Coughs ]
- Hello?
- Kim McAfee, I have a great surprise.
- Harry. Kids.
You have been selected from all
the teenagers in the United States...
to be kissed by Conrad Birdie
on The Ed Sullivan Show
this Sunday night.
We'll be in touch.
Good-bye.
[ Receiver Clicks ]
Conrad Birdie?
[ Slams Receiver ]
To kiss me?
Ohhh. Doris!
Mother?
Mommy! Mommy!
- Baby, what happened?
- Conrad Birdie's coming here to kiss me!
- Oh, isn't that nice. Sit down.
- But you don't understand.
Conrad Birdie's coming
to Sweet Apple to kiss me!
Oh, Mommy!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Well, I never thought I'd say it,
but God bless Conrad Birdie.
[ Screaming Hysterically ]
Oh, Conrad Birdie! Oh!
Conrad Birdie's coming here to kiss me!
[ Plane Roaring Overhead ]
Now, listen.
The absolute instant he appears,
now, I'll introduce Kim, to him.
And then we'll all recite
our Pledge Of Everlasting Loyalty.
The plane!
The plane's almost landed!
[ screaming ]
♪♪ [ Blowing Pitch Pipe ]
♪ We love you, Conrad
Oh, yes, we do ♪
and we'll be true ♪
♪ When you're not near us
We're blue ♪
♪ Oh, Conrad we love you ♪
♪ We hate you, Conrad
Oh, yes, we do ♪
♪ We don't hate anyone
as much as you ♪
♪ You're singing
makes us say "p-u" ♪
♪ Oh, Conrad we hate you ♪
♪ We love you, Conrad
Oh, yes, we do ♪
♪ We don't hate anyone
as much as you ♪
♪ When you're not near us
We're blue ♪
- ♪ Oh, Conrad ♪
♪ We love you ♪♪
♪ We hate you ♪♪
Hugo wants to talk to Kim.
Uh, that- that's if
it's okay with Kim.
- Certainly, Hugo.
- Uh, well, Kim-
Yes?
[ Crowd ]
Aw!
Hugo, what do you want?
Gee, Kim, the fellas
are making me do this,
but just the same,
they're right.
Kim, you can't go
through with this.
Hugo, please be mature.
Well, gee, doesn't gettin' pinned
mean anything these days?
Ohh. It means everything.
It's sacred.
Well, then how can you
let another man kiss you?
A-And in public?
- I assure you, I won't even feel it.
- Huh?
- I'm just a symbol.
- A symbol?
Ah, don't you see?
This is bigger than us.
Why, all this publicity
for Sweet Apple.
Thousands of people will move here.
We'll have a population explosion.
And just think what this'll do for
your father's undertaking business.
Hey! Hey, yeah,
you're right.
But you really don't go
for that Birdie creep.
Do ya?
What do my eyes tell you?
[ Sighs ]
No, you don't.
I can see you're all mine.
Forever.
Starting right after
the Ed Sullivan Show on Sunday night.
Right after
The Ed Sullivan Show
on Sunday night.
- Hey, we'll be late!
- [ Girls Gasp ]
One, two, three-
♪ We love you, Conrad
Oh, yes, we do ♪
and we'll be true ♪
- ♪ When you're not ne- ♪♪
- ♪ When you're not near us
we're blue ♪
[ Clears Throat ]
♪ Oh, Conrad
We love you ♪♪
Well, uh, I told her off, guys.
She knows where I stand.
But she's leaving.
Yeah, but that's only to make
the population explode.
Anyone for the reception,
kids?
Gee, Mr. Paisley,
we think you're okay, even
if you are the English teacher.
Well, it should be
a fascinating experience.
Yeah, but are you with them?
With "them"?
Yeah, that Birdie creep.
He's poisoned our women.
It's bad enough
the Mayor's a fink,
but you, Mr. Paisley.
Well, you see, fellas,
as a teacher and a brand-new
American citizen...
with an unquenchable
thirst for knowledge,
I feel I should witness
this unique, sociological
phenomenon, hmm?
Yeah, guys, suppose I-
suppose I did let Kim kiss him.
I only wanna see-
[ Stammering ]
a, uh, um, unique-
a so- uh, soci-
phenomenon.
[ Girls Screaming ]
Hugo the fink!
So long, fink!
Fink!
[ Boys Shouting ]
Fink! What a fink!
[ Girls Continue Screaming ]
♪♪ [ Marching Band ]
Here are the gentlemen from the press.
I'll handle them. You go find the Mayor.
We want him!
[ Muffled ] Kim. Kim.
[ Whistles ]
Here's your speech.
Learn it, and hurry.
We want him!
[ Photographer ]
Look this way, please.
[ Reporter ] What's your name?
- Conrad Birdie.
- No, no, your name.
- Oh.
Um, um... McAfee.
Kim.
Kim McAfee.
She doesn't even know her name.
♪♪ [ Marching Drums ]
[ Girls ]
We want him!
We want him. Eeew!
I beg your pardon. May I add
a welcome from Sweet Apple.
I'm Claude Paisley.
Kim McAfee's my student in English.
- Oh, how do you do? I'm Rose De Leon.
- Nice to know you.
- Uh, and you're, uh-
- Hugo.
- Oh, I'm sorry. I couldn't hear you.
- Hugo Fink.
Oh, hello, Mr. Fink.
How are you?
Please don't think me forward,
but if you should have any
spare time during your visit,
I-I'd appreciate discussing
Mr. Birdie with you.
Well, uh...
I'm afraid I'll be very busy.
Uh, but thank you.
[ Shoes Squeaking ]
Ow! Watch it, rube,
don't bend the fur.
He's coming!
- Look, everybody, he's coming!
Here he comes!
- [ Motorcycles Roaring ]
♪♪ [ Marching Band ]
♪ We love you, Conrad
Oh, yes, we do ♪
and we'll be true ♪
♪ When you're not near us
we're blue ♪
♪ Oh, Conrad
We love you ♪
♪ We love you, Conrad
Oh, yes, we do ♪
and we'll be true ♪
♪ When you're not near us
We're blue ♪
♪ Oh, Conrad
We love you ♪♪
[ Girls Cheering ]
[ Girls Screaming,
Gasping, Sighing ]
[ Girls Sighing ]
Before you hear from the girl
upon whom you have chosen...
to bestow your final kiss upon,
we will now recite
the Conrad Birdie pledge.
[ Screaming ]
I, being of sound mind and body,
do hereby promise...
to be loyal, courteous,
steadfast and true...
to Conrad Birdie and
the United States of America,
both indivisible,
with liberty and justice for all.
[ Cheering, screaming ]
As the fortunate girl
whom you have selected...
to represent all my fellow girls,
I welcome you.
[ screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
- Now, Mayor, now.
- Oh.
[ Clears Throat ]
And now I present
this key to our city,
to our honored guest,
uh, Conrad Birdie.
[ Hysterical scream ]
He said it!
He said the name!
[ Screaming ]
What happened?
All I said was "Conrad Birdie."
[ Screaming ]
Now, now, girls, you're gonna
have to stop that, or I-
or I can't finish my speech.
Who cares about your speech?
We wanna hear Conrad!
[ Girls Sighing ]
He's not so much.
♪♪
♪ You gotta be sincere ♪
- Ohhh.
- Edna! What's wrong?
♪ Ya gotta be sincere ♪
Birdie! What are you doing?
♪ Ya gotta feel it here ♪
♪ 'Cause if you feel it here ♪
♪ Well, then you're gonna be ♪
♪ Honestly ♪
♪ Sincere ♪
[ Gasping ]
♪ If what you feel is true ♪
♪ You really feel it
You make them feel it too ♪
♪ Write this down now
You gotta be sincere ♪
♪ Honestly sincere ♪
♪ Man, you gotta be ♪
[ Moans ]
♪ Sincere ♪
♪ If you're really sincere
If you're really sincere ♪
♪ If you feel it in here
Then it's gotta be right ♪
- [ Screaming ]
- ♪ Oh, baby
Oh, honey ♪
♪ Hug me ♪
♪ Ah, suffer ♪
[ Screaming ]
♪ In everything I do ♪
♪ Why, my sincerity
shows through ♪
♪ Yeah, I look you in the eye ♪
♪ I don't even have to try
It's automatic ♪
♪ I'm sincere ♪
♪ When I sing about a tree ♪
♪ Listen, why I really feel that tree ♪
♪ Yeah, when I sing about a girl
I really feel that girl ♪
♪ I mean I really feel ♪
♪ Sincere ♪
[ Sighs ]
♪ Why, if you're
really sincere ♪
♪ If you're really sincere
If you feel it in here ♪
♪ Then it's gotta be right
Oh, baby ♪
[ Screaming ]
♪ Oh, honey ♪
♪ Hug me
Ah, suffer ♪
Yeah, here we go now!
♪ Why, you gotta be sincere ♪
♪ Oh, you gotta feel it here
Oh, my baby ♪
♪ Oh, my baby
Oh, yeah ♪
Aw, yeah ♪
♪ Go, girl, go ♪
Angela! Angela!
What are you doing?
♪ Mm-hmm ♪
[ Sighs ]
♪ Are ya gonna be sincere ♪
- ♪ Are ya gonna be sincere ♪
Yeah!
- ♪ Are ya gonna be sincere
Are ya gonna be sincere ♪
Yeah!
- ♪ Are ya gonna be sincere
Are you gonna be sincere ♪
Yeah!
♪ Oh, my baby
Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Are ya gonna be sincere
Are you gonna be sincere ♪
♪ Oh, my baby
Oh, yeah ♪
[ Screaming ]
♪ Oh, my baby ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah
Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah ♪♪
[ Girls ]
♪ We love you, Conrad ♪
♪ Oh, yes, we do ♪
♪ And we'll be true ♪
♪ When you're not near us ♪
♪ We're blue ♪
♪ Oh, Conrad ♪
[ Whistling ]
♪ We love you ♪
Randolph, your father's warned you.
If you make another bomb,
you'll get spanked.
- It was an accident, Mom.
- Oh! Now, get this stuff out of here.
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
♪ We love you, Conrad ♪
[ Horn Honking ]
Doris. Doris!
♪ And we'll be true ♪
♪ When you're not near us ♪♪
- Doris, what's going on here?
Harry, where have you been
since supper?
In plenty of trouble,
but I'm not now. No siree.
You kids, go home before I sic
the constable on you!
Go on! Get that carnival
off my front lawn!
I'll show 'em who's boss here!
Harry McAfee's not gonna be pushed
around by any roll and rocker.
That's for sure.
- Harry, they'll hear you.
- Ah, let 'em hear me.
- Put those chemicals away and go to bed!
- Yes, Papa.
We're in trouble.
He can't stand Conrad living here.
Especially around
his pretty young daughter.
[ Whispering ]
She's still under the magic spell.
[ Sighing ]
Dear little Conrad certainly
has a devastating impact.
He might make a terrific soldier.
Turn him loose and the enemy'll
twitch itself to death.
I don't care.
I've changed my mind.
My daughter is not gonna be
publicly kissed by that- that wiggler.
The deal is off.
But, dear, you know
these adolescents. Kim'll lose face.
And if I don't get rid
of that Birdie, that's not all she'll-
Now, hear this.
I have decided...
that bunch of grafters
is getting outta here!
That is the unshakable decree that I
have made as head of this household!
So you upstairs and tell 'em.
Me? How can I tell Mr. Peterson
and that nice Miss De Leon-
Nice? Ha-ha!
I know that show business crowd.
Probably livin' in sin.
Harry Lionel McAfee!
I never told you. One summer
I worked with the circus.
Oh, those midgets, wild.
Not another word.
She's been engaged to Peterson
for six years. Don't tell me-
- We were engaged for five years.
- He's not as stupid as I was.
Are you stupid, Pop?
Find out for yourself!
That's the trouble with kids today: lazy!
Will you go up?
Get up to bed!
Oh, Harry, they'll be gone
day after tomorrow.
I'm a peace-loving man.
A good father and husband.
And the result,
the home that I hewed out
of this wilderness...
with my bare hands
is no longer mine.
Tonight, I had to wait
until 6:00 for my supper.
And that Peterson grafter,
running up my phone bill
with long distance calls!
- He offered to reimburse you.
- I don't take Diner's Club cards!
And then that snake in a
gold suit insists on parking in-
in my beautiful living room!
Yech!
- You know where I've just been?
- Where?
To a meeting with the big boys.
Kelsey, Judge Blanch,
Joe Kipp, my biggest customers.
They don't approve of this
kind of notorious goings-on.
Darling, they put pressure on you?
If I don't cancel this whole Birdie deal,
- they'll starve me right out of business.
- Oh, my heavens!
It's, it's, it's them or, or us.
[ Pops, Whistles ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Whining ]
- What happened?
- Are you all right?
- What's wrong?
- Just some of Randolph's chemicals.
A mixture of Iron Sulfide,
plus two parts H2SO4.
Smart boy you have there.
It isn't every lad
who can make a stench bomb.
- Which brings me to Mr. Birdie.
- Mr. Peterson is really a biochemist.
- I couldn't care less.
- Yes, I am. I have one formula...
which is miraculous in its ability to increase
the work output of domestic animals.
About this Birdie-
It speeds up the reflexes
so that an ox could outrun a racehorse.
By adding in his formula,
a hen will lay three eggs a day.
Three eggs a day? If that's so,
you can make a million-
I've been nursing this compound for a year.
Still needs more tests, but it works.
- Uh, aren't you in farming?
- He's McAfee Fertilizer.
- Oh, yes.
- Been in it for 20 years.
- Really?
- But I may be out if-
If you and Albert got together,
you could revolutionize farm production.
Would you like a demonstration?
Do you have a hen?
- Uh, how about trying it on that?
- A tortoise. I don't know.
Sure. It won't bite.
Here, let me.
Of course, there isn't
much demand for turtle eggs,
but, uh...
if it really works on farm animals
maybe you and me could do some business.
[ Gulps ]
I'll sure need something
if I let Kim go through
with this Birdie stuff.
Some of Harry's customers
are against it.
- So I've decided it's absolutely out of the question.
- Oh, your neighbors are going...
to be thrilled when they see
the two of you on The Ed Sullivan Show.
- The Ed-
- The Ed Sullivan Show.
- We, uh- we were saving that as a surprise.
- Yes, a surprise.
- Me,me on Ed Sullivan?
- Oh, I'd die. What would I wear?
Oh, we'll find something.
Gee, Ed sullivan.
He's my favorite human.
That's why I decided to let
Kim go on in the first place.
Me on The Ed Sullivan Show?
♪ Ed Sullivan ♪
Me, Harry McAfee,
appearing with-
♪ Ed Sullivan ♪
♪ Ed
Ed Sullivan ♪
♪ Ed ♪
♪ Ed Sullivan ♪
♪ Ahhh ♪
♪ Ed
Ed ♪
♪ Sull
Sull ♪
♪ Ed Sullivan ♪
♪ We're gonna be on Ed Sullivan ♪
♪ How could any family be ♪
♪ Half as fortunate as we ♪
♪ We'll be coast-to-coast ♪
♪ With our favorite host ♪
♪ Ed Sullivan ♪
♪ We're gonna be on Ed Sullivan ♪
♪ Ooo-oooh ♪
I've got a wonderful wife. Two swell kids.
♪ Ooo-ooh ♪
A good business.
And now this.
[ Laughing ]
♪ Someday we'll recall ♪
♪ The greatest day of all ♪
Ed, I love you.
♪ Ed sullivan ♪♪
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing ]
Hello?
Oh, yes.
Harry, it's the Mayor.
He sounds mad.
I'll handle this.
Yes? Yes, Mayor.
Yes, the boys talked to me.
Yep, I've decided.
Birdie stays right here.
And Kim's on TV.
And what's more,
I'm gonna be on the show too.
With Eddie Sullivan.
Now, listen, Harry.
You saw what that crazy galoot
did at the reception.
It was a disgrace!
Uh, look, Mayor,
you're gonna be on TV too.
They want you to make a speech.
They want me...
on Ed Sullivan?
A short speech.
Why, sure.
I could become a statewide face.
It's a deal, Mayor.
Sure, I'll plug you up for governor.
Bye, Sam.
What a hambo.
Well, it's, uh- it's been
a long day, so I think we'll-
[ Clicking ]
[ Screams ]
I'm thinkin'
of callin' 'em "speed-Up."
You like it, Mr. McAfee?
"Feed Up With Speed-Up."
I love it, partner.
- How will Randolph ever catch his tortoise?
- Just give him one of these.
Hi, Mr. McAfee. Gee,
I just wanted to thank you.
My dad said you're not letting Kim
go on TV and kiss that- That!
It can't be true!
Oh, Mr. McAfee,
you wouldn't destroy Kim,
your own flesh and blood.
Oh, sure he would.
A father has a right.
Right?
Hugo, my daughter's old enough
to make her own decisions.
So, I've decided to let her do it.
Well, in that case, your daughter's the
former future Mrs. Hugo Peabody.
- Oh, Hugo, stop acting like a child.
- Kim!
- Where is he? Can I see him?
- Conrad's asleep, poor dear.
You may peek through
his keyhole, while I-
while I discuss this tempest
in a tea bag with Hugo.
[ Sighs ]
You're lucky people.
What'd we ever do
to deserve such a daughter?
We got married.
Marriage.
But, Kim-
Yeah, but, Kim-
I don't have time for debate.
Ursula's waiting.
I've gotta learn my speech
for tomorrow's rehearsal.
Wait a minute, Kim.
Don't go yet, please.
Gee, you don't know what I've been
through with all the guys buggin' me.
- Well, about you and that Birdie creep.
- Oh, that.
- Yeah, that!
- Well, that's silly.
Aw, he means nothing to me.
♪ One boy ♪
♪ One special boy ♪
♪ One boy to go with ♪
♪ To talk with and walk with ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ That's the way it should be ♪
Yeah. Yeah!
That's the way it should be.
♪ One boy ♪
♪ One certain boy ♪
♪ One boy to laugh with ♪
♪ To joke with
Have Coke with ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ Not two or three ♪
♪ One day ♪
♪ You'll find out ♪
♪ This is what life is all about ♪
♪ You need someone who ♪
♪ Is living ♪
♪ Just for you ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ One steady boy ♪
♪ One boy to be with ♪
♪ Forever and ever ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ That's the way it should be ♪
Now, is that the kiss of a woman
interested in any other man?
I don't know.
How do I tell?
- Aw, but he made you faint!
- Oh, he did not!
I-I was just exhausted
cramming for my English exam.
Hugo. Hugo, you- you've got
to try to understand me...
as a woman.
Now, I might like Conrad as a friend.
But when it comes to the real thing-
oh, the grand passion-
well, that's
something special, Hugo.
That's you.
♪ One day ♪
♪ You'll find out ♪
♪ This is what life is all about ♪
♪ You need someone who ♪
♪ Is living ♪
♪ Just for you ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ One steady boy ♪
♪ One boy to be with ♪
♪ Forever and ever ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ That's the way it should be ♪
♪ That's the way ♪
♪ It should be ♪
Homework! Hey,
I got homework to do!
Come on.
♪ When will he find out ♪
♪ This is what life is all about ♪
♪ Will he ever see ♪
♪ I need him ♪
♪ And he needs me ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ One special boy ♪
♪ To be with always ♪
♪ One boy to be with ♪
♪ Forever and ever ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ I love him ♪
♪ One boy ♪
♪ I love him so ♪
♪ That's the way it should be ♪
♪ That's the way ♪
♪ It should be ♪♪
[ Rotary Dialing ]
Hello, Sweet Apple Drive-In.
I'm looking for my mother, Mrs. Peterson.
Are you sure there's no one
left in your drive-in?
Okay, thank you.
Don't worry, partner.
Your mother'll get along fine.
Sweet Apple's full of friendly folk.
Oh, if anything happens to her,
I'll never forgive myself.
[ Conrad ] What kind of a dump is this?
- Dump?
Conrad. Let's humor him, partner.
If he walks off The Sullivan Show, we're sunk.
Gotcha.
I can't find no church key
in my room.
Church key?
We've had a church here,
but it's open.
A can opener, man. Sheesh.
You're from nowhere-like.
[ Mock Chuckle ]
[ Can Popping ]
[ Both Chuckling ]
Well, that's my favorite brand.
Well, it's, uh...
bedtime, huh, Conrad?
Okay, for tonight.
But tomorrow's saturday.
And that's my real tense night.
[ Roaring ]
Thanks, Mr. McAfee.
The next time I have a daughter,
I hope it's a boy.
I am a lucky man,
though, Albert.
Meetin' up with
a biochemical wizard.
Peterson and McAfee
are goin' right to the moon.
I've got to.
Not just for my mother, for Rosie.
Well, I guess I'll get
a little air and turn in.
Take all the air
you want, chum.
[ Chuckling ]
Hi, Rosie.
Rosie, you don't have
to worry about Mama.
She'll show up.
- I'm certain she will.
- Well, then you oughta be happy.
Kim's on the show. Conrad does my song.
I promise I'll tell Mama about us.
[ Sighs ]
Come on.
♪♪
♪ Why look so awfully tragic ♪
♪ Put on a happy face ♪
♪ Smiling can work like magic ♪
♪ Take off the gloomy mask of tragedy ♪
♪ It's not your style ♪
♪ You'll look so good that
you'll be glad you decided ♪
♪ To smile ♪
♪ Pick out a pleasant outlook ♪
♪ Stick out that noble chin ♪
♪ Wipe off the full-of-doubt look ♪
♪ Slap on a happy grin ♪
♪ And spread sunshine
all over the place ♪
♪ Just put on a happy face ♪
Flowers?
[ Crying ]
♪ Put on a happy face ♪
[ Sinisterly ]
♪ It's such a strain ♪
♪ I always try to chuckle hourly ♪
♪ It clears the brain ♪
♪ I knew a girl so gloomy
She'd never laugh or sing ♪
♪ She wouldn't listen to me ♪
♪ Now she's a mean old thing ♪
♪ So spread sunshine
all over the place ♪
♪ Put on a happy ♪
[ Together ]
♪ So put on a happy face ♪♪
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Rustling ]
[ Laughs ]
Well, like I said,
you're a genius, Dr. Peterson.
Ah, honey, you sure
have put up with a lot,
but this time we're gonna make it.
- Let's live in a small town like this.
- Anything you say, dear.
Okay.
The last time we were alone together,
last summer at Palisades Park,
we went through the Tunnel of Love.
Your mother sat between us.
Oh, honey,
I told you, from now on,
things are gonna be different.
[ Mrs. Peterson ] Yoo-hoo! Albert!
- It's Mama.
Mama?
Mama!
[ Sighs ]
Boy meets girl.
Boy loses girl.
Boy gets mother.
Eeew-ooo!
- Mama, where have you been?
- Neglected! That's where I've been.
Well, I tried to find you.
Have you had any dinner?
A mother doesn't need food.
Besides, I'd rather be with my famous son.
- Albert, what is it?
- Oh, it's your mother. Oh, good evening.
- How are you, ma'am?
- How can I be?
Ripped from my native land,
alone in this jungle.
Gosh, Albert,
I wish we had room
to put up your mother.
Thanks.
A motel mattress full of lumps
is good enough for me.
Comfort is for my loving son.
Oh!
[ Sighing ]
I just came to tuck you into bed.
Mama's got a condition.
She won't tell me what it is.
Why worry a growing boy?
Okay, if you insist.
I got maybe one-tenth
a normal heart.
A mother doesn't need a heart.
As soon as Albert and I get
our new deal a-rollin',
you'll have the finest doctors
in the country.
Deal?
What deal, Albert?
Well, Mama, I'm quitting the music
business and going back to chemistry.
That Rosie!
She's finally turned you against me.
Ah, please, Mama, she didn't!
Albert, go, desert me!
But when I was expecting him
in the maternity ward,
three days I waited.
Did I desert him? No.
I stayed right there so he wouldn't
be alone when he was born!
Mama, please don't excite yourself.
Mama, you know I love you.
- It's just Rosie and I have plans.
- Okay.
Lou.
I'll be right up.
Start dealing.
[ Shoes Squeaking ]
Just bury me on your front lawn
so Rosie can walk all over me!
Mama! Mama, please!
It's not gas.
It's electric.
[ Kim ] Doris!
- Doris! Doris!
- [ Gasps ]
Doris, how do you like it?
Isn't it exciting?
No, no, no! I told you
not to dye your hair!
Oh, but I wanted to.
Isn't it a gas?
You dare defy your mother?
- Well, it's my hair.
- Not till you're 21.
What's the matter, Papa?
Young lady, you stay in your
room till it changes back!
- Do ya hear?
- I won't! I won't!
- I demand respect around here.
- It's my hair.
- Respect, do ya hear? Respect!
- I respect you, Papa.
I don't want your respect.
Who wants respect
from a ten-year-old kid?
♪ Kids
I don't know what's wrong
with these kids today ♪
♪ Kids
Who can understand
anything they say ♪
♪ Kids
They are disobedient
disrespectful oafs ♪
♪ Noisy, crazy, sloppy, lazy loafers
While we're on the subject ♪
♪ Kids
You can talk and talk
till your face is blue ♪
♪ Kids
But they still do
just what they want to do ♪
♪ Why can't they be like we were ♪
♪ Perfect in every way ♪
♪ What's the matter with kids today ♪
♪ Kids
I've tried to raise you
the best I could ♪
♪ Kids
All the things I've done
were for your own good ♪
♪ Kids
Can't you once appreciate
how I've sacrificed ♪
♪ Working, slaving
scrimping, saving pennies
And living with your father ♪
♪ Kids
No one knows the burdens
I've had to bear ♪
♪ And in my condition ♪
♪ Kids
I'm a poor sick woman
and does he care, ha ♪
♪ Go on, go on and kill me
That's what it's coming to ♪
♪ When a mother has kids like you ♪
♪ Kids ♪
♪ All the chicken soup
that I made for you ♪
Mama, take it easy.
♪ Kids ♪
♪ Now you throw me out
like a worn-out shoe ♪
Not in front of everybody, Mom.
♪ After all, I haven't been
such an awful son ♪
♪ I never sassed you back
or leave a ring around the bathtub ♪
♪ And don't I always phone you ♪
♪ Kids ♪
♪ You can give your life
to them night and day ♪
♪ Kids
Then they go get married
ând movie away ♪
♪ And move away ♪
[ All] Who's gettin' married?
♪ Why do we have these children ♪
♪ Better to have a pet ♪
You know where you stand with the pet.
- [ Growling ]
- [ Yells ]
♪ I've never asked for nothin' ♪
♪ Nothin' is what you'll get ♪
[ Together ]
♪ What's the matter with kids to- ♪
- I tried, Lou, but I failed.
- Oh, you didn't, Mama.
[ Mrs. Peterson ]
Don't try to pay me back, sonny.
I forgive ya.
so what if you're an ingrate,
so long as you're happy.
I don't wanna be happy.
Don't feel guilty. Just make
believe I'm an old, used car.
Junk me, leave me in the gutter.
I'll never leave you. Never.
You heard him.
You're a witness.
I promise, Mama. I never
broke a promise to my mama.
Good boy.
♪ Why can't they be like Albert ♪
-♪ Perfect in every way ♪
-♪ What's the matter with kids ♪
♪ Yeah, what's the matter with kids ♪
♪ Nothing's the matter
with kids today ♪♪
[ Whining, Barks ]
Mr. Paisley,
this is Rose De Leon.
You asked me to call if I had any free time.
Well, I'm free. Very free.
- Rosie!
- Ten minutes?
Oh, I'll be waiting for you.
Don't worry, sonny. You can
always get another secretary.
Rosie!
[ Girls Chattering, Screaming ]
Can you see him?
No. Babette,
can you see him?
I can't see him. All I can see
is the basketball hoop.
Hey, Gret, can you see him?
Conrad Birdie in our gym.
♪♪
♪ Uh, uh, oh ♪
♪ Gimme one last kiss ♪
♪ One last kiss ♪
♪ One more time
Baby, one more time ♪
♪ It really is sublime
Ah, baby, so sublime ♪
♪ You know I need your love ♪
♪ Uh, uh, oh
Gimme one last kiss ♪
♪ One last kiss ♪
♪ Ba-a-a-a-a-by ♪
♪ Gi-ive me one last kiss ♪
♪ Oh, one last kiss ♪
♪ Give me one last kiss ♪
♪ It never felt like this
Nah, baby, not like this ♪
♪ Ya know I need your love ♪
♪ Uh, uh, oh- ♪♪
- Okay, cut.
We'll rehearse the song later, Conrad.
Al, what's the exact length?
Oh, uh, one, uh- 1:20.
Check. That gives us
two minutes and forty seconds
for Sullivan's intro to Kim.
Kim's good luck speech
to Conrad. Then Conrad socks
over a plug for army enlistment.
Bangs into the song.
And we top it all off
with a big kisseroo. Kim?
Yes, sir.
Uh, uh, beg, beg pardon,
but when do I make my speech?
Speech? What speech?
I promised Mr. McAfee
he could say a few words.
After all, he's Kim's father.
- Yes, he is.
- Kind of a hello from a proud parent.
All right. But ya can't have
much time. In fact, all you can
have is 20 seconds on the nose.
Gotcha. I'll just say a
few words, get some big laughs.
And introduce the Mayor.
The Mayor?
Aw, come on, Al, what is this?
I- We had a problem.
I had to give the Mayor
a spot to humor McAfee.
All right. All right.
But we'll have to take ten
seconds away from McAfee.
I imagine songwriting must be
quite a lucrative profession.
Oh, yes, it is.
Well, how many records
of this song will they sell?
Oh, about one or two million.
You know, Claude,
I had a perfectly wonderful time last night.
- You really are a wonderful dancer.
- Oh, I don't know.
- When one's heart sings, one's feet take wings.
- Oh, how lyrical.
- Is that shelley or Keats?
- That, my dear, is Paisley.
- Really? That's wonderful.
- Uh-huh.
[ Both Laughing ]
Shall we go?
Surely.
[ Laughing ]
[ Stage Manager ]
Okay, everybody, take your places.
Now, come on, Kim,
move right over there.
Just read it like you normally would.
[ Shoes Squeaking ]
And we, your admirers,
are proud that our military
leaders have called upon you-
- Conrad, honey.
- Please, Mrs. Peterson, we're rehearsing.
All right now, Kim.
[ Shoes Squeaking ]
Could you move over one, please?
Kim, you're talking too fast.
Now once more, dear, but slower.
[ Kim ] To express to you-
- Mrs. Peterson, what does your husband do?
I don't know.
He's dead.
And-
[ Clears Throat ]
And I want to say
on behalf of all the girls...
who are your devoted admirers-
- Oh, I forgot what's next.
- Come on, man, let's go.
- Hiya, Hugo.
- Hi, Kim.
They don't want
this jazz. They want Conrad.
There's the camera.
I bail in. I sing up a storm.
I give this chick the message.
[ Gasps ]
[ Sighs ]
This is my best side.
- She's fainted!
- Applause. Applause. I'll dig you later, Dad.
- [ Hugo ] I've had enough!
I'll put my foot down!
I'm putting my foot down!
She's not going on that show!
Oh, yes, she is. You're
not wrecking my career.
Oh, what happened?
Tell him you're through
because you do not wish...
to humiliate your steady
in this sordid fashion.
Hugo Peabody,
you take that back!
I will not, but I will
take my pin back!
[ Groans ]
Oh, with pleasure!
Conrad, I know you're tense,
but we haven't finished
the number. It's not ready.
Conrad's a trooper, like I was.
Us troopers get tense.
Yeah man, like she said like.
Why don't you and I go for
a nice ride in the country?
Uh-uh. Man, I hope
I never get that tense.
I never should
have said that to Rosie.
[ Kim ] Who does he think he is?
- Al, I got a wire from Sullivan.
"Russian Ballet switching
to different dance, requiring
additional four minutes.
"Therefore, the entire Birdie spot
must be cut to less than 30 seconds.
Cut!?
Tell Peterson and Rosie
I'm sorry, song is out, but no choice."
Oh, no! No, no!
They can't do this!
They can't cut the song!
They've already done it, kid.
In thirty seconds, all Birdie
can do is take a bow.
I'm awfully sorry.
The Russians!
First they take Czechoslovakia,
now they take my four minutes!
Oh, Mama.
Oh, baby. Oh.
Well, that's-
that's show business.
[ Car Engine Revving ]
[ People Chattering ]
♪♪
♪ There are chicks
just right for some kissin' ♪
♪ And I mean to kiss me a few ♪
♪ Man, those chicks don't know
what they're missin' ♪
♪ I got a lot of livin' to do ♪
♪ Sizzlin' steaks
all ready for tastin' ♪
♪ And there's Cadillacs
all shiny and new ♪
♪ Gotta move 'cause time is a-wastin' ♪
♪ I got a lot of livin' to do ♪
♪ There's music to play
Places to go ♪
♪ People to see ♪
♪ Everything for you and me ♪
♪ Life's a ball if only you know it ♪
♪ And it's all just waitin' for you ♪
♪ You're alive so come on and show it ♪
♪ Yeah, we've got a lot
of livin' to do ♪
♪ There are men ♪
♪ With childhood behind them ♪
♪ Handsome men ♪
♪ From Yale or Purdue ♪
♪ Older men ♪
♪ And I'm gonna find 'em ♪
♪ I got a lot of livin' to do ♪
♪ I-I-I'm a-gonna have fun
Gonna be wild ♪
♪ Have my own way ♪
♪ I may break ♪
♪ A heart a day ♪
♪ Drink champagne ♪
♪ As if it were water ♪
♪ Pink champagne ♪
♪ And after a few ♪
♪ Daddy dear ♪
♪ You won't know your daughter ♪
♪ she's got a lot of livin' to do ♪
♪♪ [ Drumming ]
♪ Think I'll be a ring-a-ding drummer ♪
♪ Make each week a thousand or two ♪
♪ Gorgeous girls
will beg for my number ♪
♪ Hey, I've got a lot of livin' to do ♪
♪ Yes, I'm gonna break out
Gonna take off ♪
♪ Gonna be free ♪
♪ This town is awfully square
for a cat like me ♪
♪ Or I'll be a superjet pilot ♪
♪ Fly me high way out in the blue ♪
♪ Then they'll see
I'm no shrinking violet ♪
♪ Hey, I've got a lot of livin' to do ♪
[ Snapping Fingers ]
♪♪ [ Rumba ]
♪♪ [ Trilling ]
[ Snapping Fingers ]
♪ I got a lot of livin' to do ♪
- ♪ There's music to play ♪
- ♪ Places to go ♪
♪ People to see ♪
♪ Ah, everything for you and me ♪
♪ Life's a ball if only you know it ♪
♪ Yeah, and it's all
just waitin' for you ♪
♪ Oh, you're alive
so come on and show it ♪
♪ Yeah, we got a lot of livin'
Such a lot of livin' ♪
♪ Tonight's the night we're gonna fly ♪
♪ Let's kick this hick town into high ♪
♪ I want a taste of everything ♪
♪ Let's live it up and really swing ♪
♪ Got a lot of livin' ♪
♪ Livin', livin', livin' ♪
♪ Livin' to do ♪♪
Live!
[ Car Engine Revving ]
Hugo.
[ Car Pulling Away ]
♪♪ [ Ballet ]
But you needn't bite my head off.
I only asked a civil question.
Ten times you've asked me.
I don't know why they changed
to this slow dance for TV.
All I know is if Albert can't get 'em
to cut it shorter, tomorrow night
I won't be on Ed Sullivan.
And neither will Kim, and you
know how much it means to her.
How about m-
Well, anyway, Albert's
still in with the manager,
so that's a good sign.
If Eisenhower couldn't handle the Russians,
how's Albert gonna talk to 'em?
Uh- Ahem.
[ Speaking Russian ]
[ Russian ]
Jack Kennedy.
Oh, uh, long live Joseph Stalin.
- Stalin?
I mean, uh, Stalin- Stalin lived too long.
Long live Khrushchev.
[ Russian ]
[ Chuckles ]
Ah!
[ Russian ]
[ Clears Throat ]
Um...
[ Russian ]
[ Chuckles ]
Save your life? Me?
My friend, if you are sick,
see a doctor.
"If you're sick, see a doctor."
You-You speak English?
It saves time.
What can I do for you-
Uh, Mr., eh, Peterson?
Sir, I have- I have come
to appeal to you.
That ballet, the one you're doing
on TV tomorrow night.
Da. [ Russian ]
Mr. Ed Sullivan.
Yeah, that's the one.
Could, could you just
cut that four minutes?
Well, it's beautiful.
I love it.
But my life depends on it.
Desecrate this classic?
I need the time for
Conrad Birdie to sing my song.
Who sent you here?
Senator Goldwater?
Will you cut three minutes?
Two minutes?
A minute and a half?
To cut even ten seconds
would be artistic sabotage.
This ballet has historic significance.
It was performed the same day
as the funeral of the Czar.
Lenin himself made the arrangement.
- Lenin arranged music?
- No, funerals.
[ Russian ]
[ Kim ] Hello, Rose.
- Oh, hi, Kim. You still up?
Oh, I'm so miserable, Rose.
I've lost Hugo,
and now I'm not even
going to be on TV.
- Why not?
- Oh, the Ballet's taking four extra minutes,
so Birdie's song and the kiss are out.
Well, serves Albert right.
Oh, now come on, relax.
Faithless men like Albert
and Hugo, they're all alike.
From puberty to stupidity,
from Benedict Arnold to Mussolini.
Men... we laugh at them.
Right?
It's easy for you to pick up the
pieces of your shattered dream.
You've found a compensation.
Oh, that Claude Paisley's just too much.
[ Sighs ]
He's too much all right.
But I won't mention of what.
All that charm, so genteel,
so educated,
so underhanded!
You mean Mr. Paisley's
like all the rest? I thought
he was the marrying type.
Oh, he is. He is.
He wanted to elope tonight.
And you know what?
He'd like to live in New York.
Uh, not to teach.
To be a songwriter.
A songwriter?
He's all the things
I wanna get away from.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I never dreamed
that Mr. Paisley,
of all men-
Oh, well, men.
They're only out
to use us, Kim.
I know.
Hugo's used me since
we were freshmen.
All those years I wasted on Albert.
Rosie, the dependable one.
Rosie, the patient one.
Rosie, the good girl.
I know it sounds old-fashioned,
but... I'm not ashamed to admit it.
- I'm still a good girl.
- Rose?
- Hmm?
- So am I.
No kidding?
Well, you won't be sorry.
[ Kisses ]
- Are you going out so late?
- Mm-hmm.
My farewell to Sweet Apple.
A night to remember.
I'm going to Maude's Cafe.
Maude's!
That's a wild place.
You're not gonna do anything rash?
Whatever you hear about me, Kim,
just tell them...
that she loved not wisely,
but too well.
Ole!
♪♪ [ Big Band ]
This is the place, Albert.
Hottest spot in the county.
- How do you know?
- Oh, I heard, only heard.
- Albert, don't go in that place.
- I must. It's the only way.
- But drinking won't solve anything.
- He's frustrated.
Good-bye.
I'd go in there with you
if I weren't a happy family man...
and not allowed to enjoy myself.
[ Hugo ]
Oh, please, mister.
I just-
I'm telling you for the last time!
No drinks!
Now get lost!
Well, just a pint of bourbon?
Gin? Scotch?
- No!
- How 'bout a malted with a little vodka?
Come back when you're 21.
Oh, well, well, I'm way over 21 .
I only look young from too much drinking.
[ Moans ]
Oh, look at me. Look at
this shell of a human being.
The monster you've created.
Oh, I'm sorry about-
Hugo, don't worry, you'll get Kim back.
No, thanks.
The bloom is off the rose.
Rose. Little Rose.
A precious flower
that I trampled on.
[ Whimpers ]
There we go.
A toast.
To Mae, she's okay.
[ Laughing ]
I'm a songwriter too, huh?
Would you call the McAfee house
again and see my Al- Sonny!
Mama, what are you doing
in a place like this?
I'm playing canasta. I got lonesome.
Did you cut the Russians?
- Why are you consorting with that man?
- Glad to meet you.
Looks ain't everything.
Besides, Mr. Maude is
100% gentleman, and a widower.
Three times.
Sit down, Albert.
Any son of Mae Peterson
is a friend of mine.
Come, come.
[ Albert ] Mama,
get your things. We're taking
the bus to New York tonight.
[ Mrs. Peterson ] Your song? It's all off?
- It's dead, Mama, like I am.
- You ain't goin', Mae. Say you aint!
- You unhand her. Come on, Mama.
Okay, buster, set 'em up.
Double scotch and gin on the side.
And, uh... a bourbon chaser.
Make that a triple chaser.
And bring on the dancing boys!
Well, come on, make with the drinks, Meyer.
We gotta put out this fire.
Uh-
♪ Everything is Rosie
Cha-cha-cha ♪
- ♪ 'Cause my name is Rosie ♪
- Ah, the poor thing.
♪ Si, si, si ♪♪
She can't get over me.
- She's singing the song I wrote for her.
- You wrote her a song?
Only eight bars, Mama.
Somehow, I never could finish it.
Hey, what's with the red caps?
You got a train inside?
[ Laughing Hysterically ]
Eeew!
Hey, where ya goin'?
I'm gonna go and see what the
boys in the backroom'll have.
Albert!
Where are you going?
To save her from herself.
To save her for me.
She might get in trouble.
[ Man ]
Report on the charity bazaar
which we ran...
for the benefit of the old folks' home;
to wit, net cash receipts:
$840.06.
[ Albert ] Rosie!
Valuable goods contributed:
two milk cows, live;
Rosie!
80 lugs of fresh fruit;
45 young kumquat trees;
one ton of fertilizer-
Yoo-hoo!
Whoo-hoo?
And now, before the recording
secretary reads the minutes
from last week's meeting,
I wish to bring up a subject
that I know is on...
everybody's mind... tonight.
Whoo-ooo.
♪♪ [ Egyptian ]
As I was saying, gentlemen-
[ Gasps ]
[ Shriner Gasps ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Yells ]
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
[ Shriners Laughing ]
Hey!
Whoo-whoo-whoo!
[ Shriners Shout ]
[ Shouts ]
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Whoo-yeah.
Ah.
[ Shouts ]
Hey! Hey!
[ Shriners Howling,
Chuckling ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Gasps ]
No.
[ Rosie Gasping ]
[ Shriners Cheering ]
Oh. Oh! Oh!
[ Screams ]
[ Shriners ]
Hey!
[ Whimpering ]
[ Screams ]
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
[ Coughing ]
[ Clanging ]
[ Screams ]
No! No, listen,
fellas. stop!
[ Stammering ]
Haah!
Rosie!
[ Screams ]
Albert!
Whoa-oh!
[ Shriners ]
Whoo-oo.
- Albert! Whoa!
- Ole!
[ Shriners Cheering,
Shouting ]
Rosie?
Rosie, baby?
Good morning, darling.
It's way past noon.
Sleep okay, honey?
Mm-hmm.
I tried not to.
I wanted to keep reliving
that wonderful moment...
when my shining knight...
rushed into the sultan's cave...
and carried me off.
Well, that's just the beginning.
Pack. We're taking the bus
to Niagara Falls.
Oh, yes, dear.
- Rosie?
- Hmm?
You- You never saw me
in pajamas before.
Are you disappointed?
Mm-mm.
Are you?
[ Laughs ]
Uh-
Let's take a plane to Niagara Falls.
A jet!
Oh, Albert,
we came here to get your
mother set financially.
Our marriage wouldn't have
a chance if we started off feeling
guilty about deserting her.
That's right.
It may be a long time
before I make any money.
Not if Birdie sang your song tonight.
No chance. I pleaded.
They won't shorten the ballet,
not even ten seconds.
It's the slowest dance I ever saw.
They move like turtles.
Albert. Albert!
What?
Randolph!
Boys, those are really showstoppers!
Frank, Dean and Sammy.
Come out here and take a bow.
[ Applause ]
Frank, Dean and sammy McWilliams.
Thank you, boys.
Right now, here on our stage,
the magnificent orchestra...
of American composer-conductor,
Ray Block.
Now really, let's hear it.
- Well, that oughta do it. Any questions?
- No sir, not at all.
- Okay, I'm going backstage.
- Right.
Don't know why I let
that Albert drag us here.
Rosie said she might have
a big surprise for us.
Maybe they'll show us
sitting here on TV.
I bet that's it.
- Where did you get that money?
- I sold Mr. Peterson my chemical set.
- Two minutes, Maestro.
[ Maestro ] Borov will be there.
I've never been late
for performance in whole career.
- You say you from magazine?
- Uh, yes, American Ballet Magazine.
And we want a picture of
the world's greatest conductor,
Maestro Borov.
You flatter me.
So, shoot me quick.
Oh, drinking this milk.
- Milk?
- Yes.
[ Laughs ]
We drink vodka, little flower.
Oh, no, well, no. No, thank you.
Uh, please, Maestro, this milk.
You see, our President
has asked us to drink more milk
and it would be a goodwill gesture.
- President?
- Yes!
Uh, won't you please, Maestro,
to improve our relations?
You're pretty enough
to be un-American.
- Ahh.
- Ha-ha!
All right, here we go.
Drink up. That's it.
[ Shutter Clicks ]
Now, keep drinking until I frame
you- frame you perfectly.
All right, once more.
Bottoms up. That's it.
[ Mumbling ]
Very good.
Ah, you got it!
Uh, I mean, gotcha.
See you after, could be?
- Oh, I'll catch up with you.
- And for you, I do not go too fast.
We shall see.
[ Chuckles ]
Good-bye.
Thank you.
[ Speaking Russian ]
Mission accomplished.
- He drank it?
- Yeah.
My formula works on chickens
and Randolph's turtle,
but I don't know about humans.
If it doesn't, we're no worse off;
but if it does, this'll be
the shortest ballet in history.
Now, ready, America and Canada,
because here we go out to Columbus, Ohio,
where the Moscow Ballet
dances the "Rose Adagio" from
Tchaikovshy's Sleeping Beauty,
conducted by Maestro Borzoi Borov.
Take it away, CBS,
Columbus, Ohio.
We're on.
Up on one.
[ Audience Applauding ]
Lights.
♪♪
[ Applause ]
♪♪ [ Harp ]
Camera two, can you move to
your right a couple of feet?
[ Chattering In Russian ]
Magnificent!
[ Sighs ]
[ Whispers ]
It's not gonna work.
♪♪ [ Tempo Increases Rapidly ]
Well, this is crazy.
That's not the way it was rehearsed.
- [ Scattered Laughter ]
- What is it? What's the matter?
[ Chattering In Russian ]
What happened?
[ Chuckling ]
[ Audience Laughing ]
Borov! Borov!
Hello.
[Speaking Russian ]
Ed Sullivan.
[ Russian ]
[ Crowd Chuckling ]
[ Laughing ]
Bob! Bob!
We'll have to kill some time.
Put the Birdie song back in.
Got ya, Ed. Take over.
Be prepared for the Birdie spot.
Albert, "One Last Kiss"
is back in. Find Conrad.
Rosie, get Kim.
Put the Birdie spot on stage.
And let's go, go, go!
[ Laughing Continues ]
McAfee, hurry up. Come on.
Let's go. The song is back in.
- What? Come on!
- Let's go!
[ Crowd Laughs ]
Are you crazy, Borov?
♪♪ [ Music Ends ]
[ Yelling In Russian ]
[ Crowd Laughing, Applauding ]
Aye, yi, yi, yi, yi, yi!
I've never seen such speed in dancers.
Thank you, Moscow Ballet...
for that brilliant and
unexpected bit of burlesque.
And now, another great treat:
Conrad Birdie. Yee-hoo!
[ Girls Screaming ]
[ Hysterical screaming ]
- [ Mouthing Words ]
- What-
[ Sighs ]
On behalf of all the members
of the Sweet Apple chapter...
of the Conrad Birdie Fan Club,
[ Girls Screaming ]
we wish to express to you
our great pride...
- in your brave deed.
- Hiya, Ed.
- Oh, no.
- [ Mouthing Words ]
Oh, hi. How are ya?
I wish to convey our deep pride
in your brave deed, namely-
As a citizen, I'm proud to have
Conrad defend my... family...
and the McAfee Fertilizer Company.
Conrad, sing.
♪ Oh, one last kiss ♪
[ Girls screaming ]
♪ Gimme one last kiss ♪
♪ It never felt like this
Nah, baby, not like this ♪
♪ Ya know I need your love
Uh, uh, oh ♪
♪ Gimme one last kiss ♪
♪ One last kiss ♪
♪ One more time
Baby, one more time ♪
♪ It really is sublime
Ah, honey, so sublime ♪
♪ Ya know I need your love
Uh, uh, oh ♪
♪ Gimme one last kiss ♪
♪ One last kiss ♪
[ Girls Sighing ]
♪ Ba-a-a-a-by ♪
♪ Gi-ive me one last kiss ♪
♪ Give me one las- ♪♪
[ People Gasping ]
[ Crowd Chattering ]
[ Mrs. Peterson ]
Yoo-hoo! Albert!
[ Shoes Squeaking ]
Albert!
Albert, I saw it all on TV.
"One Last Kiss" was a disaster.
Who wants to buy a record
of a guy with a glass jaw?
Now, will you take Mama's advice
and get out of show business?
I am. My song may be dead,
but my chemical formula works on people.
Shh. The Russians
may have this place bugged.
It was Albert's formula that made
the orchestra leader go that fast.
My genius! Oh! You gotta
work on my cleaning woman.
She gets a dollar an hour.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah. Mama-
Mama, Rosie and I
are going to Niagara Falls.
Well...
it's about time.
Oh, Mae,
you have to come with us!
No. I'm one mother who
doesn't mix in. Maude!
Don't fall in the pit, Maude.
- Albert.
- Yes?
I would like to do things proper,
so I would like the honor
of becoming your stepfather.
Is it all right, Albert?
Mama, with my blessing!
Oh, I'm so glad,
because we just got married.
- [ Laughs ] What a surprise.
- Oh, how exciting.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Oh, congratulations.
Thank you very much.
Let's go, Maudie.
We're leaving for Akron.
Hubby has to open a new bar and he
wants me to throw out the first beer can.
Yeah, good-bye, son.
Niagara Falls is wet,
so take along your rubbers!
Bye!
How about that Maude
and Mrs. Peterson?
- Oh, ready here, Albert.
- Be right with you.
No hurry, partner.
I promise you one thing, snookums.
No matter how many millions
I make selling Speed-Up,
I'll still be the same humble,
lovable guy.
And if any of those hicks try to
push me around, I'll break 'em.
♪♪ [ Piano Run ]
♪ Everything is Rosie ♪
♪ Since I found my Rosie ♪
- Same old words.
♪ With a girl like Rosie ♪
[ Together ]
♪ How could I be blue ♪
Same eight bars.
Now what?
♪ Hand in hand we'll mosey ♪
♪ Me and little Rosie ♪
♪ We will be so cozy ♪
♪ By a fire built for two ♪
Oh, Albert,
you're too much.
♪ Oh, I once heard a poem
that goes ♪
♪ "A rose is a rose
is a rose" ♪
♪ But I don't agree
Take it from me ♪
♪ There's one Rose sweeter
than any that grows ♪
♪ And that's my Rosie ♪
♪ I'm so glad she chose me ♪
♪ Life is one sweet ♪
♪ Beautiful song to me ♪
♪ Everything is Hugo ♪
♪ I will go where you go ♪
♪ With a boy like Hugo ♪
♪ How could I be blue ♪
♪ We will be so cozy ♪
♪ Just like Al and Rosie ♪
[ Together ]
♪ But we're gonna mosey ♪
♪ In a hot rod built for two ♪
- ♪ And that's my Rosie ♪
- ♪ Gee, how delighted we'll be ♪
♪ I'm so glad she chose me ♪
♪ When you are cozy with me ♪
[ Together ]
♪ Life is one sweet beautiful song ♪
♪ When love is right
then what could be wrong ♪
♪ Life is one sweet ♪
♪ Beautiful song to me ♪♪
♪♪
♪ Bye, bye, Birdie ♪
♪ The army's got you now ♪
♪ I'll try, Birdie ♪
♪ To forget somehow ♪
[ Sighs ]
♪ No more sighing ♪
♪ Each time you move those lips ♪
♪ No more dying ♪
♪ When you twitch those hips ♪
♪ Your swivel and your sway
Your super-duper class ♪
♪ There's nothing left to say
but, Conrad, you're a gas ♪
♪ Bye, bye, Birdie ♪
♪ Ta-ta, ol' sweetie pie ♪
♪ Time for me to fly ♪
♪ Time to say good-bye ♪♪
Bye now.