(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
MAN: Walk!
WOMAN: Walk, please. Don't run. Don't run.
- Hey, behave yourself!
-Quiet! Quiet!
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
Hey, slow down!
WOMAN: Come on, you know the rules.
On the right. I can see you.
(INAUDIBLE)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(PLAYING SOFT MUSIC ON PIANO)
(SINGING)
Some folks dream of the wonders they'll do
Before their time on this planet is through
Some just don't have anything planned
They hide their hopes
and their heads in the sand
Now I don't say who is wrong, who is right
But if by chance you are here for the night
Then all I need is an hour or two
To tell the tale of a dreamer like you
We all dream a lot
Some are lucky, some are not
But if you think it, want it, dream it
Then it's real
You are what you feel
But all that I say
Can be told another way
In the story of a boy
Whose dream came true
And it could be you
(SINGING) I closed my eyes
Drew back the curtain
To see for certain
What I thought I knew
Far, far away
Someone was weeping
But the world was sleeping
Any dream will do
I wore my coat
With golden lining
Bright colours shining
Wonderful and new
And in the east
The dawn was breaking
And the world was waking
Any dream will do
A crash of drums, a flash of light
My golden coat flew out of sight
The colours faded into darkness
I was left alone
May I return
To the beginning
The light is dimming
And the dream is, too
The world and I
We are still waiting
Still hesitating
Any dream will do
Any dream, any dream, any dream
(INTENSE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Way, way back many centuries ago
Not long after the Bible began
Jacob lived in the land of Canaan
A fine example of a family man
Jacob, Jacob and sons
Depended on farming to earn their keep
Spent all of their days
in the fields with sheep
Jacob was the founder of a whole new nation
Thanks to the number of children he had
He was also known as Israel,
but most of the time
His sons and his wives used to call him Dad
Jacob, Jacob and sons
Men of the soil and the sheaf and crook
A remarkable family in anyone's book
Reuben was the eldest
of the children of Israel
With Simeon and Levi the next in line
Naphtali and Issachar with Asher and Dan
Zebulun and Gad took the total to nine
Jacob, Jacob and sons
Benjamin and Judah, which leaves only one
Joseph, Jacob's favourite son
Jacob, Jacob and sons
Dad!
Jacob
Hi, Dad.
Jacob and sons
Jacob,Jacob,Jacob
Jacob and
Sons
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Joseph's mother
She was quite my favourite wife
I never really loved another all my life
And Joseph was my joy because
He reminded me of her
Through young Joseph
Jacob lived his youth again
Loved him, praised him
Gave him all he could, but then
It made the rest feel second best
And even if they were
Being told we're also-rans
Does not make us Joseph fans
But where they have really missed the boat is
We're great guys, but no one seems to notice
Joseph's charm and winning smiles
Failed to slay them in the aisles
And their father couldn't see the danger
He could not imagine any danger
He just saw in Joseph
all his dreams come true
Jacob wanted to show the world
he loved his son
To make it clear
that Joseph was the special one
So Jacob bought his son a coat
A multicoloured coat to wear
Joseph's coat was elegant
The cut was fine
The tasteful style
was the ultimate in good design
And this is why it caught the eye
A king would stop and stare
And when Joseph tried it on
He knew his sheepskin days were gone
Such a dazzling coat
It's great!
Of many colours
How he loved his coat of many colours
In a class above the rest
It even went well with his vest
Such a stunning coat of many colours
How he loved his coat of many colours
It was red and yellow and green
and brown and blue
Joseph's brothers weren't too pleased
with what they saw
We had never liked him all that much before
And now this coat has got our goat
We feel life is unfair
And when Joseph graced the scene
His brothers turned a shade of green
His astounding clothing took the biscuit
Quite the smoothest person in the district
I look handsome, I look smart
I am a walking work of art
Such a dazzling coat of many colours
How I love my coat of many colours
NARRATOR:
It was red and yellow and green and brown
And scarlet and black and ochre and peach
And ruby and olive and violet and fawn
JOSEPH". I look handsome, I look smart
I am a walking work of art
Such a dazzling coat of many colours
How I love my coat of many colours
It was red and yellow and green and brown
And scarlet and black and ochre and peach
And ruby and olive and violet and fawn
And lilac and gold and chocolate and mauve
And cream and crimson and silver and rose
And azure and lemon and russet and grey
And purple and white and pink and orange
and blue!
(CHEERING LOUDLY)
(SINGING)
Joseph's coat annoyed his brothers
But what makes us mad
Are the things that Joseph tells us
of the dreams he's often had
I dreamed that in the fields one day
the corn gave me a sign
Your eleven sheaves of corn
all turned and bowed to mine
My sheaf was quite a sight to see
A golden sheaf and tall
Yours were green and second-rate
and really rather small
ALL: Small!
This is not the kind of thing
we brothers like to hear
It seems to us that Joseph
and his dreams should disappear
I dreamed I saw eleven stars
The sun, the moon and sky
Bowing down before my star
It made me wonder why
Could it be that I was born
for higher things than you?
A post in someone's government?
A ministry or two?
(JAZZY MUSIC PLAYING)
The dreams of our dear brother
are the decade's biggest yawn
His talk of stars and golden sheaves
is just a load of corn
Not only is he tactless,
but he's also rather dim
For there's eleven of us
and there's only one of him
- The dreams of course will not come true
-(WHISTLING)
That is, we think they won't come true
That is, we hope they won't come true
What if he's right all along?
The dreams are more than crystal clear
The writing on the wall
Means that Joseph someday soon
will rise above us all
The accuracy of the dreams
We brothers do not know
But one thing we are sure about
The dreamer
The dreamer, the dreamer
The dreamer, dreamer, dreamer, dreamer
The dreamer has to go
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Next day, far from home,
the brothers planned the repulsive crime
Let us grab him now
Do him in while we've got the time
Hi, guys! Hey!
- Hey!
-Kill him!
NARRATOR: This they did
and made the most of it
Tore his coat and flung him in a pit
Let us leave him here all alone
and he's bound to die
When some lshmaelites,
a hairy crew, came riding by
In a flash, the brothers changed their plan
We need cash, let's sell him if we can
Poor, poor Joseph, whatcha gonna do?
Things look bad for you
Hey, whatcha gonna do?
Poor, poor Joseph, whatcha gonna do?
Things look bad for you
Hey, whatcha gonna do?
(SCREAMS)
Could you use a slave,
you hairy bunch of lshmaelites?
Young, strong, well-behaved
Going cheap, and he reads and writes
In a trice, the dirty deal was done
Silver coins for Jacob's favourite son
Then the lshmaelites
galloped off with a slave in tow
Off to Egypt
where Joseph was not keen to go
It wouldn't be a picnic, he could tell
And I don't speak Egyptian very well
Joseph's brothers tore
his precious multicoloured coat
Having ripped it up,
they next attacked a passing goat
Soon the wretched creature was no more
They dipped his coat in blood
and guts and gore
Oh, now, brothers, how low can you stoop?
You make a sordid group
Hey, how low can you stoop?
Poor, poor Joseph, sold to be a slave
Situation's grave
Hey, sold to be a slave
(WOLF HOWLING)
(IMITATING HARMONICA)
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
Father, we've something to tell you
A story of our time
A tragic but inspiring tale
Of manhood in its prime
You know you had a dozen sons
Well, now that's not quite true
But feel no sorrow, do not grieve
He would not want you to
You see, there's one more angel in heaven
(VOCALISING)
There's one more star in the sky
Joseph, we'll never forget you
It's tough!
But we're gonna get by
There's one less place at our table
There's one more tear in my eye
But, Joseph, the things that you stood for
Like love and peace, never die
When I think of his last great battle
A lump comes to my throat
It takes a man who knows no fear
To wrestle with a goat
His blood-stained coat is tribute
To his final sacrifice
His body may be past its peak
But his soul's in paradise
(VOCALISING)
So long, little Joe
Adios, buckaroo
Ten-four, good buddy
There's one less place at our table
There's one more tear in my eye
But, Joseph, the things that you stood for
Like truth and light, never die
Carve his name with pride and courage
Let no tear be shed
- If he had not laid down his life
-Goldarnit, goldarnit
We all would now be dead
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL WHOOPING)
(SINGING) There's one more angel in heaven
There's one more star in the sky
Joseph, the things that you stood for
Like truth and light, never die
(ALL WHOOPING)
There's one more angel in heaven
There's one more star in the sky
Joseph, the things that you stood for
Like truth and light, never die
There's one more angel in heaven
There's one more star in the sky
Joseph, the things that you stood for
Like truth and light, never...
(MUSIC STOPS)
There's one more angel in heaven
(CRYING)
There's one more star in the sky
Father, the things that he stood for
(WEEPING LOUDLY)
Like democracy, never...
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(ALL WHOOPING)
Die!
(SINGING)
Joseph was taken to Egypt in chains
and sold
Where he was bought
by a captain named Potiphar
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(ZANY INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(SINGING) Potiphar had very few cares
He was one of Egypt's millionaires
Having made a fortune buying shares in...
Pyramids.
Potiphar had made a huge pile
Owned a large percentage of the Nile
Meant that I could really live in style
And he did
Oh, I did.
Joseph was an unimportant slave
Who found he liked his master
Consequently worked much harder
Even with devotion
Potiphar could see that
Joseph was a cut above the average
Made him leader of his household
Maximum promotion
Potiphar was cool and so fine
But my wife would never toe the line
It's all there in Chapter 39 of Genesis
She was beautiful but
Evil
Saw a lot of men against his will
He would have to tell her
that she still was his
You're mine!
Joseph's looks and handsome figure
Had attracted her attention
Every morning she would beckon...
Come and lie with me, love.
Joseph wanted to resist her
Till one day she proved too eager
Joseph cried in vain...
Please, stop! I don't believe in free love!
Pity.
Please.
(EXCLAIMS)
No,no,no.
(WOMAN GASPS)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
Potiphar was counting shekels
In his den below the bedroom
When he heard a mighty rumpus
clattering above him
Suddenly, he knew his riches
couldn't buy him what he wanted
Gold would never make him happy
if she didn't love him
Letting out a mighty roar
(POTIPHAR SCREAMING)
Potiphar burst through the door
Joseph, I'll see you rot in jail
The things you have done
are beyond the pale
Poor, poor Joseph, locked up in a cell
Things ain't going well
Hey, locked up in a cell
Poor, poor Joseph, locked up in a cell
Things ain't going well
Hey, locked up in a cell
Locked up
In a cell
(SOMBRE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Close every door to me
Hide all the world from me
Bar all the windows
And shut out the light
Do what you want with me
Hate me and laugh at me
Darken my daytime
And torture my night
If my life were important
I would ask, "Will I live or die?"
But I know the answers
Lie far from this world
Close every door to me
Keep those I love from me
Children of Israel
Are never alone
For I know I shall find
My own peace of mind
For I have been promised
A land of my own
Close every door to me
Hide all the world from me
Bar all the windows
And shut out the light
(ALL VOCALISING)
Just give me a number
Instead of my name
Forget all about me
And let me decay
I do not matter
I'm only one person
Destroy me completely
Then throw me away
If my life were important
I would ask, "Will I live or die?"
But I know the answers
Lie far from this world
ALL: Close every door to me
Keep those I love from me
Children of Israel
Are never alone
For we know we shall find
Our own peace of mind
For we have been promised
A land of our own
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Joseph's luck was really out
His spirit and his fortune low
Alone he sat, alone he thought
Of happy times he used to know
Hey, dreamer, don't be so upset
Hey, Joseph, you're not beaten yet
Go, go, go, Joseph, you know what they say
Hang on now, Joseph
You'll make it someday
Don't give up, Joseph
Fight till you drop
We've read the book
And you come out on top
The prison walls were wet and black
His chains were heavy, weighed him down
A candle was his only light
The hungry rats the only sound
Hey, dreamer, don't be so upset
Hey, Joseph, you're not beaten yet
Go, go, go, Joseph, you know what they say
Hang on now, Joseph
You'll make it someday
Don't give up, Joseph
Wait and you'll see
We've been outside
NARRATOR: And you're on the marquee
Now into Joseph's prison cell
Were flung two very frightened men
We don't think that we will ever
see the light of day again
Hey, Joseph, help us if you can
We've had dreams that we don't understand
Both men were servants of Pharaoh the King
Both in the doghouse for doing their thing
One was a baker, a cook in his prime
One was a butler, the Jeeves of his time
Tell me of your dreams, my friends
And I will tell you what they show
Though I cannot guarantee to get it right
I'll have a go
First the butler, trembling, took the floor
Nervously he spoke of what he saw
There I was standing in front of a vine
I picked some grapes
and I crushed them to wine
I gave them to Pharaoh,
who drank from my cup
I tried to interpret, but I had to give up
You will soon be free, my friend
So do not worry any more
The King will let you out of here
You'll buttle as you did before
Next the baker rose to tell his dream
Hoping it would have a similar theme
There I was standing with baskets of bread
High in the sky I saw birds overhead
Who flew to my basket and ate every slice
Give me the message, like his would be nice
Sad to say your dream is
not the kind of dream I'd like to get
Pharaoh has it in for you
Your execution date is set
Don't rely on all I said I saw
It's just that I have not been wrong before
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Go, go, Joe
Go, go, go, Joseph, you know what they say
Hang on now, Joseph
You'll make it someday
Sha la la, Joseph, you're still in your prime
You and your dreamcoat ahead of your time
Go, go, go, Joseph, you know what they say
Hang on now, Joseph
You'll make it someday
Sha Ia Ia, Joseph, you're still in your prime
You and your dreamcoat ahead of your time
Go, go, go, Joe!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, Joseph
You know what they say
Hang on now, Joseph
You'll make it someday
Sha Ia Ia, Joseph, you're still in your prime
You and your dreamcoat ahead of your time
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, Joseph
You know what they say
Hang on now, Joseph
You'll make it someday
Sha Ia Ia, Joseph, you're still in your prime
You and your dreamcoat ahead of your time
Ahead of your time
Ahead of my time
- Ahead of your time
-Ahead of my time
Ahead of your time
Ahead of your
Time
(CHEERING LOUDLY)
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Pharaoh, he was a powerful man
With the ancient world
in the palm of his hand
To all intents and purposes he
Was Egypt with a capital "E"
Whatever he did
He was showered with praise
If he cracked a joke
Then you chortled for days
No one had rights or a vote but the King
In fact, you might say
he was fairly right-wing
When Pharaoh's around
Then you get down on the ground
If you ever find yourself near Ramses
Get down on your knees
A pharaoh story
A pharaoh story, a pharaoh story
Down at the other end of the scale
Joseph is still doing time in jail
For even though he is in with the guards
A lifetime in prison seems quite on the cards
But if my analysis of the position is right
At the end of the tunnel
- There's a glimmer of light
-Glimmer of light
For all of a sudden indescribable things
Have shattered the sleep
of both peasants and kings
Strange as it seems
There's been a run of crazy dreams
And a man who can interpret could go far
Could become a star
Could be famous
Could be a big success
Strange as it seems
There's been a run of crazy dreams
And a man who can interpret could go far
Could become a star
Could be famous
Could be a big success
- A star
-Could be famous, could be a big success
Strange as it seems
There's been a run of crazy dreams
And a man who can interpret
Could go far
Could become a star
Could be a
Star
(CHEERING)
(INTENSE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Guess what?
In his bed, Pharaoh had an uneasy night
He had had a dream
that pinned him to his sheets with fright
No one knew the meaning of the dream
What to do, whatever could it mean?
Then his butler said
I know of a bloke in jail
Who is hot on dreams
Could explain old Pharaoh's tale
- Pharaoh said
-Fetch this Joseph man
I need him to help me if he can
Poor, poor Pharaoh, whatcha gonna do?
Dreams are haunting you
Hey, whatcha gonna do?
Chained and bound, afraid, alone
Joseph stood before the throne
My service to Pharaoh has begun
Tell me your problems, mighty one
(BLUESY ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Pharaoh is in the building!
Well, I was wandering along
the banks of the river
When seven fat cows came out of the Nile
Oh, yeah
And right behind these fine healthy animals
Seven other cows that were skinny and vile
(VOCALISING)
And then the thin cows ate the fat cows
Which I thought would do 'em good
Oh, yeah
But it didn't make 'em fatter
Like I thought a monster supper should
Oh, no
Because the thin cows were as thin
as they had ever, ever, ever been
This dream has got me baffled
Hey, Joseph, what does it mean?
Now you know that kings ain't stupid
But I don't have a clue
Don't you be cruel, Joseph
Help me, now, I'm begging you
I was standing doing nothing
in a field out of town
When I saw seven beautiful ears of corn
Oh, yeah
They were ripe, they were golden
But you've guessed it, right behind them
There were seven other ears
that were tattered and torn
Then the bad corn ate the good corn
Man, they came up from behind
Yes, they did
But, Joseph, here's the punch line
It's really gonna blow your mind
Flip your lid
Because the bad corn was as bad
as it had ever, ever, ever, ever been
Well, this dream has got me all shook up
Treat me nice
Tell me what it means
I understand the bit about the corn,
but I'm not quite sure about the cows.
I was wondering if you could just give it
to me one more time, Mr Pharaoh man.
Please?
Let me show you
how we rock and roll in Egypt.
I was standing doing nothing
in a field out of town
When I saw seven beautiful ears of corn
Oh, yeah
They were ripe, they were golden,
but you've guessed it, right behind them
There were seven other ears
that were tattered and torn
And then the bad corn ate the good corn
And they came up from behind
Yes, they did
But, Joseph, here's the punch line
It's really gonna blow your mind
This is gonna flip your lid!
Because the bad corn was as bad
as it had ever, ever, ever, ever been
Well, this dream has got me all shook up
Treat me nice
Tell me what it means
HEY
(SCREAMING)
Hey, hey, hey, Joseph
Won't you tell poor old Pharaoh
What does this crazy
Crazy, crazy, crazy dream mean?
Oh, yeah
Seven years of bumper crops
are on their way
(ALL EXCLAIM)
Years of plenty,
endless wheat and tons of hay
Your farms will boom, there won't be room
To store the surplus food you grow
After that the future doesn't look so bright
Egypt's luck will change
completely overnight
And famine's hand will stalk the land
With food an all-time low
Noble King, there is no doubt
What your dreams are all about
All these things you saw in your pyjamas
Are a long-range forecast for your farmers
And I'm sure it's crossed your mind
What it is you have to find
Find a man to lead you through the famine
With a flair for economic planning
But who this man could be I just don't know
Who this man could be I just don't know
Joe!
ALL: Oh!
Pharaoh said
Well, stone the crows
This Joseph is a clever kid
Who'd have thought that 14 cows
could mean the things he said they did?
Joseph, you must help me further
I have found a job for you
You shall lead us through this crisis
You shall be my number two
Pharaoh told his guards to
fetch a chisel from the local store
Whereupon he ordered them
to cut the chains that Joseph wore
Joseph got a royal pardon
And a host of splendid things
A chariot of gold, a cloak,
a medal and some signet rings
- Joseph
-Joseph
- Pharaoh's number two
-Pharaoh's number two
- Joseph
-Joseph
- Egypt looks to you
-Egypt looks to you
Joseph, Pharaoh's number two
- Joseph
-Joseph
- Egypt looks to you
-Egypt looks to you
Joseph
Seven summers on the trot
were perfect, just as Joseph said
Joseph saw that food was gathered
Ready for the years ahead
Seven years of famine followed
Egypt did not mind a bit
The first recorded rationing
in history was a hit
Joseph, how can we ever say
All that we want to about you?
We're so glad that you came our way
Okay.
We should have perished without you
Hey! Joseph, we are the perfect team
Old buddies now, that's you and me
I was wise to have chosen you
You'll be wise to agree
Joseph, how can we ever say
All that we want to about you?
We're so glad that you came our way
We should have perished without you
Hey! We were in a jam
that would have baffled Abraham
But now we're a partnership
It's just a piece of cake
Greatest man since Noah
Only goes to show-ah
Anyone from anywhere can make it
if they get a lucky break
This could be a happy ending
Perfect place to stop the show
Joseph after all has gone
about as far as he can go
But I'm sure that Jacob
and his other sons have crossed your mind
How had famine hit the family
Joseph left behind?
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING IN FRENCH ACCENT)
Do you remember the good years in Canaan?
The summers were endlessly gold
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
The fields were a patchwork of clover
How lovely.
The winters were never too cold
We strolled down the boulevard together
A promenade simply divine
Now the fields are dead and bare
No joie de vivre anywhere
Et maintenant, we drink a bitter wine
Those Canaan days we used to know
Where have they gone, where did they go?
Et bien, raise your berets
to those Canaan days
Do you remember those wonderful parties?
Ooh la la!
The splendour of Canaan's cuisine
Our extravagant, elegant soirees
(ALL LAUGHING)
The gayest the Bible has seen
It's funny, but since we lost Joseph
We've gone to the other extreme
No one comes to dinner now
We'd only eat them anyhow
I even find I'm missing Joseph's dreams
Those Canaan days we used to know
Where have they gone?
Where did they go?
Et bien, raise your berets
to those Canaan days
(MUSIC STOPS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHEERING)
Those Canaan days we used to know,
where have they gone?
Where did they go?
Et bien, raise your berets
to those Canaan days.
- It's funny but
-Since we lost
Joseph
- We've gone to the other
-Extreme
Perhaps we all misjudged the lad
- Perhaps he wasn't
-Quite that bad
- And how we miss his
-Entertaining
Dreams
Those Canaan days we used to know
Where have they gone?
Where did
Did they 90?
Et bien, raise your berets
To those Canaan
Days
Et bien, raise your berets
To those Canaan
Days
(SINGING)
So, back in Canaan the future looked rough
Jacob's family were finding it tough
For the famine has caught us unprepared
We are thin, we are ill, we are getting scared
It's enough to make anyone weep
We are down to our very last sheep
We will starve if we hang around here
But in Egypt there's food going spare
They've got corn, they've got meat
They've got fruit and drinks
And if we have the time
We could see the Sphinx
- So they finally decided to go
-Here we go!
Off to Egypt to see Brother Joe
So they all lay before Joseph's feet
Mighty Prince, give us something to eat
Joseph found it a strain not to laugh because
Not a brother among them knew who he was
I shall now take them all for a ride
After all, they have tried fratricide
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
I dreamed that in the fields one day
the corn gave me a sign
Your eleven sheaves of corn
all turned and bowed to mine
I dreamed I saw eleven stars
The sun, the moon and sky
Bowing down before my star
And now I realise why
(JAZZY MUSIC PLAYING)
How do I know where you come from?
You could be spies
Telling me that you are hungry
That could be lies
How do I know who you are?
Why do you think I should help you?
Would you help me?
Yes!
Why on Earth should I believe you?
I've no guarantee
Grovel, grovel, cringe, bow, stoop, fall
Worship, worship, beg, kneel, sponge, crawl
Grovel, grovel, grovel, grove!
We are just eleven brothers
Good men and true
Though we know we count for nothing
when up next to you
Honesty's our middle name
Life is slowly ebbing from us
Hope's almost gone
It's getting very hard to see us
from sideways on
NARRATOR: Grovel, grovel, grovel, grove!
Grovel, grovel, grovel, grove!
I rather like the way you're talking
Astute and sincere
Suddenly your tragic story gets me right here
This is what we hoped he'd say
All this tugging at my heartstrings
seems quite justified
I shall give you what you came for
and lots more besides
Grovel, grovel, grove!
Grovel, grovel, grovel, grove!
Thank you, thank you
Cringe, bow, stoop, fall
Worship, worship
Beg, kneel, sponge, crawl
Joseph handed them sackloads of food
And they grovelled with base gratitude
Then, unseen,
Joseph nipped out around the back
And planted a cup in young Benjamin's sack
When the brothers were ready to go
Joseph turned to them all
with a terrible stare and said...
No!
No! No, no, no!
- Stop!
-You robbers, your little number's up
One of you has stolen
my precious golden cup
Joseph started searching
through his brothers' sacks
Everyone was nervous, no one could relax
Who's the thief? Who's the thief?
-ls it Reuben?
-No!
- Is it Simeon?
- Is it Naphtali?
-No!
- Is it Dan?
- Is it Asher?
-No!
- Is it Issachar?
- Is it Levi?
-No!
Who's the man?
- Is it Zebulun?
-No!
- Is it Gad?
- Is it Judah?
-No!
Is it him?
Could it be, could it be?
Could it possibly be Benjamin?
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Benjamin, you nasty youth
Your crime has shocked me to the core
Never in my whole career
Have I encountered this before
Guards, seize him!
Lock him in a cell
Throw the keys into the Nile as well
Each of the brothers fell to his knees
Show him some mercy
O mighty one, please
He would not do this
He must have been framed
Jail us and beat us
We should be blamed
(WOMEN HUMMING)
(REGGAE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Oh, no, not he
How you can accuse him is a mystery
Save him, take me
Benjamin is straighter than the tall palm tree
I hear the steel drums sing their song
They're singing,
"Man, you know, you got it wrong"
I hear the voice of the yellow bird
Singing in the tree, "This is quite absurd"
- Oh, yes
-Oh, yes
- It's true
Benjamin is straighter than the big bamboo
- No ifs
-No ifs
- No buts
-No buts
Benjamin is honest as coconuts
Sure as the tide wash the golden sand
Benjamin is an innocent man
Sure as bananas need the sun
We are the criminal guilty ones
- Oh, no
-Oh, no
- Not he
-Not he
How you can accuse him is a mystery
- Save him
-Save him
- Take me
-Take me
Benjamin is straighter than the tall palm tree
(ALL VOCALISING)
Oh, no, not he
How you can accuse him is a mystery
Save him, take me
Benjamin is straighter than the tall palm tree
Sure as the tide wash the golden sand
Benjamin is an innocent man
Sure as bananas need the sun
We are the criminal guilty ones
- Oh, no
-Oh, no
- Not he
-Not he
How you can accuse him is a mystery
- Save him
-Save him
- Take me
-Take me
Benjamin is straighter than the tall palm tree
(VOCALISING)
Oh, no, not he
Not he
Save him, take me
Benjamin is straighter than the tall palm tree
WOMEN: Each of the brothers fell to his knees
Show him some mercy
O mighty one, please
He would not do this
He must have been framed
Jail us and beat us
We should be blamed
And Joseph knew by this
His brothers now were honest men
The time had come at last
To reunite them all again
Can't you recognise my face?
ls it hard to see?
That Joseph who you thought was dead
Your brother, is me
Joseph,Joseph
Is it really true?
Is it really you?
Joseph
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) So Jacob came to Egypt
No longer feeling old
And Joseph came to meet him
In his chariot of gold
Of gold
(MUSIC STOPS)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) I closed my eyes
Drew back the curtain
To see for certain
What I thought I knew
Far, far away
Someone was weeping
But the world was sleeping
Any dream will do
- I wore my coat
- CHILDREN: I wore my coat
With golden lining
Bright colours shining
Wonderful and new
- And in the east
- CHILDREN: And in the east
The dawn was breaking
And the world was waking
Any dream will do
A crash of drums
A flash of light
My golden coat flew out of sight
The colours faded into darkness
I was left alone
May I return
To the beginning
The light is dimming
- And the dream is, too
- CHILDREN: And the dream is, too
- The world and I
-CHILDREN: The world and I
We are still waiting
Still hesitating
Any dream will do
May I return
To the beginning
The light is dimming
And the dream is, too
The world and I
We are still waiting
Still hesitating
Any dream will do
Give me my coloured coat
My amazing coloured coat
My amazing
Coloured
Coat
(CHEERING LOUDLY)
(INTENSE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)