(MAN SCATTING)
(WHAT IS LOVE PLAYING)
WOMAN: (SINGING) What is love
if it's not with you?
I know when you're alone
you feel it, too
In your arms
is where I long to be
'Cause being with you
gives me sanity
MAN: Welcome to Rio!
WOMAN: Oh-oh
Listen to me, darling
Whoa!
I wake up every morning
Thinking 'bout the way you feel
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
I wonder if you know it
And what good is the party
If you're not around?
But listen to me now
ALL: What good is love?
If it's not your love
NICO: Is it a crazy love?
WOMAN: What good is love?
Am I your baby, love?
WOMAN: If it's not your love
Is it a crazy love?
This is a crazy party
I'm so glad I'm here
with everybody
Baby, move your body
Shake it to the ground
Break it, break it,
break it down, Blu
Me? (STAMMERING)
(WEAKLY) What's a song
if you can't hear it, too?
(SQUAWKS)
Can't imagine
dancing without you
Ooh!
A shooting star
ain't really nothing to see
If you're not right here
standing next to me
Oh. (LAUGHS)
ALL: Listen to me, darling
(SCATTING) Whoo!
I wake up every morning
Thinking 'bout the way you feel
(LAUGHS)
Hey! Hey! But...
I wonder if you know it
(STUTTERING)
What good is the party
if you're not around?
Listen to me now
What good is love?
Is it a crazy love?
If it's not your love
Whoa! Whoa, whoa...
For a bird from Minnesota,
you've got some moves.
Oh, that wasn't a move.
That was an accident.
But I accept the compliment.
It's great Rafael
could watch the kids.
Yeah, it looks like you're
stuck with me all night.
You're my one and only, Blu.
That's a good thing,
since I'm the only other one.
Hey, you lovebirds!
Happy New Year!
Rafi? Where are the...
The kids are with Luiz.
No worries!
Uh, worries. Right here.
(LUIZ VOCALIZING)
Luiz? Where
are the kids?
What? I don't have any kids.
BOTH: Our kids!
Oh, right.
I left them with Tiny.
BOTH: Tiny?
What? She's
an excellent babysitter.
I'm a terrible babysitter!
This is going to be awesome!
All right, I've done
all the calculations
and each explosion will be
perfectly synced to the beat.
Unless I didn't carry the one.
CARLA: Here's my vision.
Red, blue, green, yellow,
yellow! Purple. (CHUCKLES)
Here's my vision.
Hey!
Boom! Crash! Bang! Kapow!
Uh, I don't think your parents
would like this very much.
Here we go.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa.
Oh, where are you
going, little bird?
Hey, what is this?
Oh, Dad.
Guys, you know the rules.
No pyrotechnics
without adult supervision.
We asked Tiny.
That's even worse.
Sorry, Tiny.
You don't have to
pay me, Señor Blu.
(WHIMPERS)
Kids, next time, ask me.
But you always say no.
No, I don't.
Dad, you're in denial.
BLU: Okay.
Honey, do I always say no?
Yes. I mean, uh, no.
CARLA: Great.
Now Mom's saying it, too.
Ow! Ow! Ooh, ooh. Ow.
Listen, we are the last
blue Spix's macaws
left on the planet.
We have to stay safe.
Birds of blue feathers...
ALL: Have to stick together.
(SNIFFING)
I smell chicken.
(GASPS) No, no, no!
No, no, no! Ooh, ah!
Oh! (YELPS)
BLU: No, no, no!
No, no...
By my calculations, that's
like his 27th "no" today.
(BLOWING)
(GASPING)
(SIGHS)
(BLOWING)
Help!
Ah!
(GROANING)
CROWD: Five, four,
three, two, one!
Everybody, fly!
CROWD: Happy New Year!
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, man. How come Dad
gets to have all the fun?
Look! It worked!
Well...
Wow!
...this year's off
to a great start.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
TULIO: Amazon expedition,
day seven.
Two thousand miles from Rio,
we've reached the center
of the rainforest.
We are surrounded
by plants and animals
struggling for survival...
(LINDA GRUNTING)
...as we glide effortlessly
down the river.
Effortless for you.
(GASPS) How pretty.
(GASPS) Oh, spit it out,
spit it out! Oh!
We are near the nesting grounds
of the Amazonian wood quail.
Odontophorus gujanensis.
(GRUNTING)
Six months ago,
we rescued this little bird
from smugglers.
It was sick, malnourished...
(TWITTERING)
...with a broken leg. But
now, my trusty assistant...
(CHUCKLES) I mean loving wife
and colleague will release her
back to her natural habitat.
(WHIMPERING)
It's okay.
You can go now.
Just like this.
Let me talk to her.
(IMITATING BIRD CALLS)
Go on.
(SQUAWKING)
FREAKS!
Do you think
she's gonna be all right?
Hmm.
Give it some time.
(TWITTERING)
Mmm, welcome home.
LINDA: Wait a minute.
What is she saying, Tulio?
(SIGHS) It's just hard
for her to say goodbye.
No. I think it's... I think
she's trying to warn us.
(CHUCKLES) No, no, no, Linda.
It might be some
sort of mating dance.
(CHIRPING)
Tulio! Look!
Paddle! Now!
Whoa! Okay, okay, okay!
Paddle.
Watch out!
(SCREAMING)
Paddle, paddle!
Backward, backward!
To the right!
No, no, no, left!
Forward, forward! No, no!
Make up your mind, Tulio!
(STRAINING)
Cheese and sprinkles!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
TULIO: Paddle!
Whoa!
(PANTING)
(GASPS) Oh, no!
What?
Paddle, paddle, paddle,
paddle, paddle! Faster!
(SCREAMING) Tulio!
Whoa!
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING AND COUGHING)
Linda! Linda!
LINDA: Tulio!
(COUGHING) Ugh!
Yuck. Ah! Ugh.
Oh, thank heavens you're okay.
(BIRD CLUCKING)
(GASPS)
Tulio, is that a...
(SQUAWKING)
BOTH: Whoa!
(TULIO GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Oh! Linda!
This is incredible!
(GASPS)
(BOTH CHEERING)
(LAUGHS) Whoo-hoo!
(SPEAKING PORTUGUESE)
Good morning, Jewel!
(SQUAWKS)
(SIGHS) Hey! Everyone,
look what I found.
Blu?
Kids?
Where did everybody...?
BLU: Okay, who's ready
for some breakfast?
Ugh. Unbelievable.
Hmm.
BIA: Did you know that
these whole wheat pancakes
have twice the vitamins and
minerals of regular pancakes?
And with the blueberries,
it's four times as tasty.
Hey, where are the blueberries?
Oh, Dad!
Looking for this?
Bring it.
(GRUNTS)
It's down to the final minutes.
He's got magic in his feet.
He shoots!
BLU: He scores! Goal!
BOTH: Goal!
Oh, yeah,
I got it. I'm good.
Heads up, Dad!
Uh-oh. Ha. Ha!
Oh. No. Ah. Ah!
(GRUNTS)
Awesome. (SIGHS)
(CHUCKLING)
Hi, Mom. (CHUCKLES)
Busted.
Time to go.
Oh! Hey, honey.
Hey. You hungry?
Blu, we talked about this.
Did we? I don't... Yeah, so,
um, what do you got there?
Breakfast.
That's... That's funny.
But seriously, what is that?
It's a Brazil nut.
I never thought I'd find one
this close to the city.
I want to show the kids
how to open one.
TIAGO: You mean like this?
Dad already showed us.
(CHUCKLES)
CARLA: Wait. Wait, go back.
Mom! Dad! You're on TV!
Doctor Tulio Monteiro,
the "Bird Man of Brazil,"
announced an important
discovery today.
We believe we have encountered
a wild blue Spix's macaw
deep in the Amazon jungle.
The blue Spix's macaw
was thought to be
practically extinct,
with the last remaining family
living under protection
at the Blu Bird Sanctuary
in Rio de Janeiro.
We're famous!
If these birds can be found,
their home will be saved.
There may be
a whole flock out there.
And if there is, we will
find them and protect them.
Hi, Blu!
Ah! Hi, Linda!
We're not the only ones.
There are more of us out there.
Yeah, that's great.
(GASPS)
I'm sure they're...
All this time, I thought...
I... I thought
we were alone.
Hey, it hasn't been all bad.
Oh. Of course not but...
Just imagine if there was
a whole flock of us.
(CHUCKLING)
How amazing would that be?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
We gotta do something.
We do?
Yeah, we have to
fly to the Amazon
and help Linda
and Tulio find them!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, we can't
just pack up and go.
Why not?
It's about time this family
got a little air
under our wings.
Look at us, iPods, TV...
Hey.
Mom!
Pancakes?
We're not people, we're birds.
(ALL GROAN)
We have to get out into
the wild and be birds, Blu.
Let the kids
connect to their roots.
Show them what I had.
They need this.
We need this.
Come on, Blu, what do you say?
Uh, I don't know.
Uh, maybe.
He didn't say no.
Which means
he practically said yes.
Hey, wait a Sec...
It's going to be so much fun!
Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
We're going to the Amazon!
Wait. What's the Amazon?
NEWSREADER: The Amazon is one of Earth's
most endangered ecosystems,
due to illegal logging
and farming.
Let's hope Dr. Monteiro
and his team
can find these rare birds
so their home can be saved.
There may be
a whole flock out there.
And if there is, we will
find them and protect them.
BIG BOSS: Ugh!
Tree-huggers.
Get my boat ready.
I need to deal with
this personally.
(ALL VOCALIZING)
RAFAEL: Next!
That would be me.
Okay, everybody can go home now.
You're looking at the next
King of Carnival!
(ALL SCREAM)
Hey, big bird!
Break a leg!
(SCREAMING)
(CRASHING) Ooh.
Walk it off, buddy!
(SINGING OFF-KEY)
You can't see it coming
You won't find it anywhere else
(SHRILL SCREAMING)
Oh! Brava.
(LAUGHS) Brava! Brava!
That was amazing!
Eva, darling, you hit
every note. Huh, guys?
Yeah, yeah, along with a bunch
of notes I never heard of.
Rafi!
(STAMMERING) Don't worry.
I'll talk to them.
We'll find
the perfect spot for you.
(SCOFFS) Antarctica, maybe.
You better. Tchau-tchau.
Bye, boys.
See you back at home,
my tasty mango!
(SIGHS) None of these
acts are inspiring.
I'm just not inspired.
Carnival is
right around the corner
and our reputations
are on the line.
Copy that. We need something
that can make us wiggle.
Something that'll
make us jiggle.
We need something that pops.
Pop, pop, pop, pop, pop!
You know what "pop" is
backwards? Pop!
Next.
(SCREAMING)
BOTH: Blu?
LUIZ: Sorry, Bro!
It's okay, Luiz.
Good to see you, too. Ugh.
Listen, Blu, we are
looking for a singer,
a dancer, the whole package.
Yeah, and you're more
of a mumbler-shuffler.
You catch my drift?
Oh. No, no, no, no, no,
I'm not here to audition.
Uh, I've got news.
I am going to the Amazon.
Yay.
The Amazon?
Wow, that's wild.
Yeah, yeah, Jewel thinks
it'll be good for us.
Uh, how wild?
Real wild.
They got mosquitoes that suck
your blood like Slurpees.
(SLURPS)
Snakes that can
swallow you whole.
Flesh-eating
piranhas that...
Huh?
...eat flesh.
Oh, great, that sounds
really nice. I'm not going.
Guys, guys, guys.
Blu, you have nothing
to worry about.
All those stories
are highly exaggerated.
You think so?
Of course!
If this is important
to Jewel, just do it.
Happy wife, happy life.
Remember that.
Okay, yeah, you're right.
You know,
a little family vacation
might actually be fun.
Plus, it's not like
it's forever.
That's the spirit.
Yeah. Okay.
Thanks, guys.
See you in a couple of weeks!
RAFAEL: Safe travels, Blu!
Bring me back a souvenir!
Dawg, he ain't coming back.
He is de-e-e-e-ead.
Amazon!
Let's go! Come on, Dad!
Come on!
Okay. Bug spray, check.
(CHUCKLING)
Water purifier, check.
Band-Aids.
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
Oh, cool!
The all-in-one
adventurer's knife!
I'll be in charge of this.
No. Ah, ah, ah...
That's not for you.
Hey, Dad, look at this.
Did you know
the Amazon has snakes
that can swallow you whole?
Actually, Bia, all those stories
are highly exaggerated.
No, really. Look.
(BLU YELPS)
Huh?
Oh, that's sick!
All right, are we ready to go?
A fanny pack?
Yeah.
Linda gave it to me.
I need it for the GPS.
Oh, where's the GPS?
Hey!
Carla, we're leaving.
CARLA: I'm not going.
It's going to be lame.
(SIGHS) Okay, here it is.
The voice recognition
makes it totally foolproof.
Here, watch this.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Find Linda and Tulio.
AUTOMATED FEMALE VOICE: Searching for
”Dinner in Tokyo. ”
Oh, okay. Well, actually,
that does sound
like a nice suggestion.
You trust this woman?
(ROBOTIC VOICE) Yes, I do.
RAFAEL: (CHUCKLING)
Hey, wait up, family!
I'm coming, too!
Don't worry, buddy.
We got your back.
Eva let you come?
Sure. I promised her a spot
in the Carnival show.
NICO: You did what?
You guys are late.
Clock late.
But musician early.
Wait, you guys are coming?
We wouldn't miss it
for the world.
We're going to scout
the wildest,
coolest talent in the jungle!
It's our inspiration for
this year's Carnival show,
"Amazon Untamed."
Cool!
I mean, pfft, yeah. Okay.
I guess I'll go.
Amazon jungle or bust, baby!
Who is ready for
a tropical adventure?
(ALL CHEERING) I know I am!
All right!
Let's go, birds!
Wait, we didn't do a head count.
Hey, guys, wait up!
(SCREAMS)
GPS: Recalculating.
(BARKING)
Hey, birds! Come back!
They left without me. Again!
That's messed up. (WHINES)
(BELL TOLLING)
Oh.
ALL: Mmm.
(SPITS)
(HORN BLARING)
(EXCLAIMING)
GPS: Heavy traffic ahead.
Great. Thanks a lot,
GPS lady.
Whee. (LAUGHS)
(EXCLAIMS AND LAUGHS)
(COUGHS) Ah.
(BELCHES AND CHUCKLES)
Oh! (GRUNTS)
Faster, faster, faster!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Slower! Slower! Slower!
Help! (SCREAMS)
(GASPS) Wow!
(CHUCKLES)
Hey. Huh?
(GASPING)
Get away. Ah!
(YAWNS)
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
BLU: Here we are, kids.
The gateway to the Amazon.
NIGEL: "To be"
"or not to be,"
"that is the question."
"Whether 'tis nobler
in the mind"
"to suffer the slings and
arrows of outrageous fortune"
"or to take arms
against a sea of troubles"
"and, by opposing, end them."
Oh, that's beautiful, Nigel.
What does it mean?
Death, Gabi. It's about death.
Oh, Nigel, I love it when you
get all dark and brooding.
(CHUCKLES)
(MAN KNOCKING) Hey, bird.
It's show time!
My audience awaits.
From the streets of Rio
to the Amazon jungle,
the Bird of Mystery!
Miracle cures!
Poison frogs!
Gather round!
Fire ants!
Don't be shy!
Learn your destiny!
(GASPS)
(WHISTLING)
(PANTING) Ooh.
Hey! Get away from those!
Huh?
Back to work.
Mommy, Mommy, I want one!
I want a fortune!
Welcome, madame.
This amazing cockatoo
will reveal your future.
All right, bird.
Pick a fortune.
Come on, bird.
(GROANS)
You're doing great, Nigel.
(SIGHS)
MAN: Pick it already.
BLU: Come on, gang.
Almost there.
No more flying today.
We've got a boat to catch.
(SQUAWKS)
According to
my little friend here,
this boat will get us
there by morning.
ALL: Yeah!
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
He'll live,
but he'll never fly again.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
(WHIMPERING)
(DISTORTED) Come on, bird.
(DISTORTED) I want my fortune!
(DISTORTED)
You're doing great, Nigel.
What's taking so long?
(LAUGHING)
MAN: What's
the matter with you?
That blue bird caused my misery.
(SOBBING) Ah!
Wha...
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Nice birdie?
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Why are you hitting yourself?
Wow. Nigel is muy macho.
(YELLING)
Thank you.
Oh!
I'm free! (LAUGHING)
Poison frog!
(CROWD SCREAMS)
(STRAINING)
(LAUGHING)
The croaking cockatoo
doth bellow for revenge.
That's Shakespeare, by the way.
Without your performance,
it's nothing.
Fair point.
Hi-yah!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Oh, this air!
It's so fresh and full.
Goodbye, stinky city air!
Yeah, bye.
Hey. Thank you
for doing this.
I really appreciate it.
I would do anything for you.
You know that, right?
Of course I do.
Mmm.
(GROANS)
We aren't here to snack.
We are here to avenge.
Oh.
Once these pesky passengers
fall asleep,
we'll show our blue friends
some love.
Some poisonous love.
Ooh.
That's my specialty.
We attack
at the midnight hour...
because it's more evil.
Stay alert.
(SNORING)
Midnight! Time to attack.
(SOFTLY) Nigel! Nigel?
(SNORING)
(GASPS) Oh.
Look at us. Misfits.
A toxic frog and a flightless freak.
(CHUCKLES)
So different and yet the same.
My darling, while you sleep
All is well
We are friends and that's swell
But the truth is that
I have a secret to tell
I love you
(CHUCKLING)
(GROANING)
People say it's wrong
It's absurd
That a frog
and a bird are in love
But I know in my heart
This was so meant to be
(SNORING)
If only we could hug
and could kiss
It'd be heavenly bliss
But your lungs would explode
And you'd look just like this
And you'd gag
With your face turning blue
Eww
But darling, I'll protect you
I will, don't worry, just chill
'Cause there isn't a bird
That I wouldn't kill
For you
Can't you see?
Oh, we were destined to be
For we have love
NIGEL: Love
Poisonous love
Love
And oh, yes
I know that you can't hold me
(WHISPERS) Feel me close now.
Your loving wings enfold me
Fate told me
Love
Poisonous love
Standing here
You're so near
And yet
So far
Like a star
Here we are
Where?
What to do?
To do
Oh, pooh.
You're my Romeo
I'm Juliet
We're so perfect and yet
If we touch not by much
Still on all you can bet
It's goodbye
And I'll cry
As you die
From our poisonous love
(MOANS)
(BUZZING)
Hmm?
(GASPING)
Oh.
What a nightmare. (GASPS)
Charlie! You were
supposed to wake me!
It's time.
(SNORING)
(CHUCKLING) I love
being on Team Nigel!
Ow!
(GASPS)
(HUMMING LULLABY)
Shh!
Shh.
(ALL SNORING)
(SNIFFING)
(SQUEALS)
(SLURPS)
(GASPS)
(HUMMING)
(SIGHS)
(SNORING)
(CHARLIE SLURPING)
(GROWLS)
(SLURPING)
(WHIMPERS)
I can't think of anything
more romantic
than poisoning passengers
on a moonlight cruise.
(BLU SNORING)
Stop.
Oh!
That one is mine.
Twinkle, twinkle, little Blu.
How I wondered, where were you?
Up above the world so high,
are you ready
to die?
You need a breath mint.
Even in sleep, you mock me.
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
(HORN BLARING)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Whoa!
GABI: Wait for me!
Don't leave me!
(SCREAMS)
Tiago! Stop
fooling around.
I didn't do anything.
Tiago Gunderson,
listen to your mother.
Aw, man!
BIA: We're almost
there, right?
Yeah!
Hey, guys. Guys. Wait up.
Come on, Blu.
Remember, birds of a...
Never mind.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Ah, they're getting away!
Wake up, you insect-eating
idiot. Follow them.
(BLOWING)
Better.
Now go ten times faster.
(SCREAMING)
River hogs!
(BOAT ENGINE PUTTERING)
MAN 1: Let's get a chain on
and move that lumber!
MAN 2: Okay, chief!
MAN 1: I want 20 more trees
out before sundown!
MAN 3: I need
more bricks over here.
Ha-ha!
Hmm?
Hmm...
(GIBBERING)
You! (GROWLING)
BIG BOSS: I always suspected
you were dumber than a monkey.
And now I know.
(CHUCKLES) Boss! What
are you doing in the jungle?
Perhaps the better
question is...
(GASPS) What are they doing?
Nature freaks.
BIG BOSS: Two million
square miles of jungle
and they're playing
in my backyard?
Mmm. I don't think so.
As you know, my friends,
this logging operation
is a little, um...
illegal.
If those two nuts find those
birds, we're out of business.
And that's why
you must put an end
to their little
bird-watching expedition.
Find them and get rid of them.
The rest of you...
(BOTH GASP)
...go out some trees.
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GASP)
BIG BOSS: Who cares
about a bunch of birds?
LINDA: The macaws
should be nesting
near the Brazil nut trees.
So I think that we should
continue with go...
(IMITATING BIRD CALLS) Tulio!
Are you listening to me?
GPS: You have reached
your destination.
You see? It, uh, works
like a charm. Here we are.
CARLA: Uh, where?
Oh, these things
have a margin of error.
I told you not to
trust that woman.
(GASPS) That's
a Heliconious larva.
It's about to enter
the pupa stage.
(LAUGHS) You said "poop!"
Hey!
BLU: Hey, kids. Stay close.
It's "pupa", bird-brain.
(SIGHS) I'll get them.
Okay, uh, you guys stay put.
Um, I'll look around.
No worries. We'll be here.
(CHUCKLES)
We're not going anywhere.
My feathers is popping up
on the back of my neck.
I don't like this.
Mmm-mmm. Let's back it up.
Beep. Beep. Beep. Beep.
JEWEL: Bia? Tiago?
(SQUAWKING) Huh?
Come on, lady. (SIGHS)
Don't let me down.
Calculating route to Funky Town.
Oh, great.
Okay, guys! I...
Guys?
Ha-ha! That's a good one,
guys. Very funny.
Good, good. Very witty.
Jewel, where are you?
Kids? Jewel?
Ah!
(SCREAMS)
It's a macaw!
TULIO: Linda!
(GASPS)
Let me go! Ow! Ooh!
(BOTH PANTING)
Let me go, you heathens!
Blu?
Whoa!
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH PANTING)
I swear that sounded like Blu.
(PANTING)
That's impossible, Linda.
He's back home in Rio,
safe and sound.
BLU: I am an American citizen,
you savage!
I demand to see my ambassador!
I know my rights!
(SCREAMS)
Back. Back, you barbarian!
Yeah, that's right.
It's a spoon and a fork.
Be afraid! Be very afraid. Ah!
Whoa! Whoa, buddy.
Put the spork down.
NICO: Let me go! Let me go!
PEDRO: Bring it!
Come on!
You lucky I ain't big.
Hey! Hey!
(SCREAMS) Oh.
Oh.
(CAWING)
(ALL GASP)
Whoa...
I can't believe
we found them! (LAUGHS)
Well, technically...
Whoa!
...they found us.
Okay, we're going to
need some nametags.
Whoa! Ah, hello. Uh, okay.
No, no, those are breath mints.
Ah, not that you need one.
But they're good.
You eat them.
Oh! Whoa, no, no, no!
Not the whole box.
(CHOKING)
Get that out of your mouth!
What is this doing here?
What's going on?
We found them flying
too close to the humans.
What? And who are you?
BLU: Uh...
"Uh" is not
an appropriate answer.
(STAMMERING)
I asked you a question.
Where did you come from?
Hey! Back off!
Hey, excuse me, young lady.
(GASPS)
(VOICE BREAKING)
I can't believe it.
How... How... How is this...
When the loggers came,
there was fire and
so much smoke. And, and...
I had you under my wing
and then you were...
Gone.
I've looked everywhere for you.
I'm here. (SOBBING)
Daddy!
(SIGHS)
"Daddy"?
I missed you. (SNIFFLES)
It's okay. It's okay, now.
Daddy has you.
(CHUCKLES AND SNIFFLES)
Look at you.
It's my little girl,
all grown up.
You're so beautiful.
Just like your mother.
I'm so sorry I lost you.
I can't imagine you alone,
all this time.
Oh, no, it's okay, Dad.
I wasn't alone.
(CHUCKLES) Blu found me.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Sure is nice to meet you, sir.
Tuck that wing away, Stu.
Ah.
Now, come here.
Right, sure. Okay.
Closer.
Oh! Really?
Ah. Um...
You brought my Jewel
back to me. I thank you.
I'm going to hug you now.
Oh! Um, okay.
Oh!
Ow.
Now, come here, you.
Okay. There we are.
My pleasure.
(SOBBING)
Nico. You crying?
It's a heavy moment, and I'm
very vulnerable right now.
Come here.
Let me get you a hug.
(SOBBING)
(CHUCKLES)
Mom, are you okay?
(SNIFFLES) "Mom"?
I'm a grandpa?
I'm a grandpa.
Ow. Ow. Ow.
Look at me, I'm a grandpa!
(LAUGHING)
Daddy, this is Carla,
Bia and Tiago.
Nice to meet you, sir.
There is no "sir" around
here, young lady.
You will call me Pop-Pop!
CARLA: Pop-Pop.
Ooh, I like that.
It's got a nice ring to it.
I am a Pop-Pop!
(ALL CHUCKLING)
Yeah, I'm the Pop-Pop-Pop.
Kids, go easy
on old Pop-Pop.
Hey!
You can call me "sir."
My daughter has returned!
(ALL CHEERING)
EDUARDO: For years,
we have been on the run
as the humans push us
deeper into the jungle.
But as you can see,
we have found sanctuary.
A place we can
finally put down roots.
Everyone! Come on!
Everyone, out of your nests!
(GASPS) Oh.
My daughter is home!
Come on, birds.
My Jewel is back!
(GASPS)
(WARBLING)
Jewel?
Make way. Make way. Jewel!
Aunt Mimi? Aunt Mimi!
Whoo!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh! I missed you so much!
(LAUGHS)
My little wildflower
has returned!
I knew you were coming back.
I saw it in the droppings.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(GASPS) And look
at the little ones!
Huh?
Aren't you the fluffiest,
most delicious little macaws?
Oh! You're big
for your age.
Uh, Mimi. This is Sue.
Oh, actually, I'm Blu.
Aren't we all? (LAUGHS)
Oh! No, really,
that's my name.
That's why they call us
blue macaws.
(MIMI LAUGHS) (WHISPERS)
Just go with it.
(BIRD CALLING)
(VOCALIZING)
So, that's what a blue macaw
is supposed to look like?
(VOCALIZING)
(SINGING) Look at her shining
Her feathers, they glow
Now the jungle is smiling
(GASPS)
'Cause our baby's home
Can you feel what I feel?
The day has come at last
Our precious Jewel has returned
I'll be the first to sing
Welcome back
(CHUCKLES) Roberto. I...
Oh, welcome back
I said welcome, welcome, welcome
Back
Wow, you look great!
So do you! (CHUCKLES)
(BLU CLEARS THROAT)
Hi, hey.
Hi, there.
I am Jewel's, uh,
significant other.
Ah! So, you're the lucky bird
who swept Ju-Ju off her feet.
"Ju-Ju"?
ROBERTO: Yeah.
When we were kids, we always had
the cutest nicknames
for each other.
We did. I called him
Beto. (GIGGLES)
That's adorable.
I love doing the nicknames.
You never mentioned,
uh, any Roberto.
There's nothing to mention.
EDUARDO: Hey!
There's my wingman!
We can rest easy
with Roberto on the lookout.
Eduardo taught me everything I know.
He's the bird.
(CHUCKLING)
No. You're the bird.
No, you're the bird.
You're the bird!
We get it.
You're both the bird.
Now, can we stop yakking and
start partying? (CHUCKLES)
(GASP) Oh, wow!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I remember this song.
How could you forget?
It's in our blood, baby.
It's who we are.
You don't mind if I borrow
her for a minute, do you?
Oh, well, actually...
Come on, Ju-Ju!
Let's go! Whoo-hoo!
(SINGING) Let's come together
Singing love and harmonia
We are so different
But the same inside our hearts
Blue-tiful colors
As far as the eye can see
Open your wings
Fly when you hear the call
Yeah!
Let's celebrate
Whoo!
Calling all beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings
Dance and sing
songs about freedom
Like la-la-la, ooh-ooh
One for the jungle familia
Come on, Blu!
Ah!
Like ba-ba-ba, boom-boom
Calling all beautiful creatures
Hey, uh, hey, Jewel?
Jewel! (EXCLAIMING)
Come this way, celebrate
Laugh and dance all the way
Yo, this is untapped territory.
I'm loving this sound.
La-la-la-la, ooh-ooh
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa.
(ALL CHANTING TO MUSIC)
Ah! Whoa.
Oh! Ha.
(ALL CHANTING TO MUSIC)
Ha! Whoa.
Pop-Pop! I am a Pop-Pop!
I am... (SCATTING)
I am your Pop-Pop!
Yeah, I am the Pop-Pop-Pop
Hey, the Pop-Pop!
(ALL CHEERING)
Let's celebrate
Calling all beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings
Dance and sing
songs about freedom
(CHEERING) Like la-la-la, ooh-ooh
(ALL CHUCKLING)
One for the jungle familia
Like ba-ba-ba, boom-boom
Calling all beautiful creatures
(ALL CHEERING)
Whoo-hoo!
You're the only one who knows
what it feels like
to be all alone,
misunderstood. (GASPS)
You're the evil to
my lethal. (CHUCKLES)
I can see why
they call you Gabi.
Where are you, you filthy fowl?
(SQUAWKING)
Halt!
(YELPS)
(GRUNTING)
Oh!
Hmm. I've been going
about this all wrong.
I need to search
from higher ground.
(GROANS)
Oh!
Ah! You stayed airborne
for almost
a full second that time.
Bravo! Bravissimo!
Ow.
What are you looking at?
Get me up there.
(STRAINING)
Higher.
Higher! Even higher.
Little bit higher.
Lower. Lower, now.
Yes. Perfect.
NIGEL: Ugh.
It's an infestation.
(LAUGHS EVILLY)
Keep celebrating.
I'll be pooping
on your party promptly.
(CACKLING)
ALL: Hi, Nico! Hi, Pedro!
(LAUGHS)
We came to the right place.
This is popping.
It's popping in the Amazon.
We could bring these
macaws back to Rio
and have the best
Carnival show ever.
I am inspired!
Sorry to break it
to you, city boys,
but you'll have to find
some other talent.
Nobody leaves the tribe.
Oh, and, uh...
No human things in
the jungle. Understood?
What? What's his problem?
Uh!
I feel naked.
(GASPS)
We could have been legends.
I mean, we already are
super-mega-dope but...
You know what I'm saying?
We had it all.
The undiscovered talent,
the big idea, the inspiration.
But if we can't bring
these guys to Rio...
We got nothing.
RAFAEL: Nothing?
Hold your mangoes.
We still have Eva.
What?
Wow! You still got
the moves, Ju-Ju.
(LAUGHING) Phew.
Oh, I'm so exhausted.
Yeah.
We should get some rest.
Find a local inn or B&B nearby.
ROBERTO: What is this crazy talk?
No, you guys are
staying in my nest.
I'm on patrol tonight.
Mi casa es su casa.
That's really nice, Beto.
Thank you, but we're fine.
Besides, our whole family
couldn't possibly
fit in your bachelor pad.
(ECHOING) Whoa.
Real estate must be
pretty cheap around here.
Wow. This is incredible.
Ah, this old nest?
It's just something
I put together last-minute.
With my own two wings,
of course.
And my strength.
And my brawn.
Hmm.
Dad, it's huge!
It has six bedrooms!
I get the big one!
No! I'm the oldest.
Only by 3 minutes,
2.5 seconds.
(SIGHS) I'd hoped
to one day be blessed
with a flock of little
Robertos to call my own.
I bet you did.
TIAGO: No way!
A bird bath! (LAUGHING)
BLU: Tiago, caref... Ah!
(BUBBLING)
Jacuzzi.
(ROBERTO CHUCKLING)
(INHALES DEEPLY) Blu,
let me tell you something.
If anything,
and I mean anything,
ever happens to you,
I will take care of your family.
Uh...
All right, buddy.
Sleep well.
Goodnight, Ju-Ju!
Goodnight!
(GASPING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(WHIMPERING)
Mmm?
Ah, okay. All clear.
JEWEL: Moon beams
and starlight
Magical twilight
The warmest rain
Hear it whispering your names
Rainbows at midnight
Sparkling night skies
Don't go away
Stay another day
Can you sing it again, please?
(CHUCKLES) Time for bed now.
Mmm.
(SNORING)
(CHUCKLES) What an amazing day.
All this time, I...
I never let myself hope
that they were alive but...
(CHUCKLING) But they are.
We found our family,
Blu. (INHALES)
(SIGHS) This changes everything.
Yeah.
Wait. Wait, what?
What's changing?
Jewel?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MUTTERING)
(SNORTING)
(GASPS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MUTTERING)
(RATTLING)
(LINDA BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
Shoo, shoo, shoo. Go on.
(GIBBERING)
(CLATTERING)
(GROWLING)
(SNORING)
(MOANING)
Honey, stop. That tickles.
(ALL GIGGLING)
(BLU SCREAMING)
(ALL LAUGHING) That was fun!
(EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHING) Tiago!
Come on, Tiago. Let's go.
(SIGHS)
(WHIRRING)
Morning.
Or should I say "afternoon"?
Morning, sir.
Our days here in the jungle,
they start early.
JEWEL: Morning, Daddy.
That's my girl. See?
Already up and at 'em.
Morning, sweetie.
Why did you let me sleep in?
What are you talking about?
You sleep in every day.
Yeah, but...
BIA: Hey, Dad.
Aunt Mimi says clay
is good for your digestion.
Try some.
No, sweetie.
I just brushed my...
It's good, right? I'm going
to go get some more.
Smart girl.
(GAGGING)
So, I thought I'd
take Louie here
for a little tour of the area,
show him around.
Oh, that's a great idea.
What?
You go have fun with Daddy
and I'll explore around
here with the kids.
Oh. Oh. Yeah, okay. Sure.
(SOFTLY) You'll love it.
Yeah, great.
Um, I just gotta...
Okay, ready.
Okay.
Lou, come closer.
Uh, not so close.
Oh, okay.
Listen, uh...
I can barely look at it.
You gotta lose
that human pocket, okay?
Oh, this is a fanny pack.
"Fanny pack." Adorable.
It's human.
And now that
you're joining the tribe,
you won't be needing it anymore.
I'll meet you by the clay banks.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
"Joining the tribe"?
He doesn't actually think
we're moving
to the jungle, does he?
No, no. He's just
excited we're all here.
Let's not ruin the moment, okay?
Besides, it won't kill you
to leave behind the fanny pack.
All right, you win.
I will leave
the fanny pack behind.
Happy wife, happy life... Oh.
Bye, honey! Have fun.
Uh, yeah. Sure. Bye.
(SNORING)
You guys. Wakey-wakey!
Wake up!
Eva! You got it!
What happened to
"Amazon Untamed"?
Here's the plan.
Auditions today
and we preview
the show tomorrow.
"We"? What you talking about, "we"?
You speak French?
Come on, chop-chop.
Let's get started!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Whoa! Kid's been working.
(SINGING) Tell me when to go
Tell me when to go
Tell me when to go!
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
'Cause shawty got low,
low, low, low, low
(GROANING)
(EXCLAIMING) Uh...
Any time you're ready.
(SLOTH SNORING)
(SINGING) Every time
I come a fella gotta get it
Then I gotta go
And then I gotta get it
Then they gotta blow
And then I gotta show
that any little thing
A fella think that he be doing
'Cause it doesn't matter,
I'm done
(SNORING)
(VOCALIZING) Oh!
(SCATTING)
(SCREAMING)
(VOCALIZING)
NICO: Next!
We are the amazing
Capoeira turtles.
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(BUZZING FAST CLASSICAL TUNE)
Bravo! Encore! Encore!
Encore!
Ooh, sorry, guys.
Did I miss anything?
Ah! Mosquito.
Oh!
(SNORING)
BOTH: Whoa!
(ALL YELPING)
(GASPING)
Hi, my name is
Claira the capybara
and I will be singing
my favorite song.
ALL: Aw.
(SINGING) Memory
All alone in the moonlight
(ALL SCREAM)
CLAIRA: (ECHOING)
Touch me
It's so easy to leave me
If they keep eating each
other, we got no show.
This ain't an all-you-can-eat
competition!
Oh, hey. You are fast.
You are really, really fast.
I think I pulled a wing
or something.
You are really fast
for an old bird.
For such a wise, wise bird,
is what I meant to say.
Wise bird,
which sometimes comes with age
but also can happen
when you're young,
like you, in your case.
You can be wise and young,
which is kind of
a rare combination
but thrilling when it happens.
Be quiet.
Ah. Thank you, sir.
It's time to shake
that city off of you.
You need to learn
the basics of jungle survival.
I thought
we were going sightseeing.
(CHUCKLING)
It's training day.
BLU: Oh, oh, oh.
Come on!
The mud is your friend.
This is your camouflage!
Feel it. Taste it!
If you don't feel crusty,
you're not doing it right!
You don't wanna
be seen by humans!
Come on! Are you
a macaw or a turkey?
(BURPS)
Ah! Whoa!
(CHUCKLES)
Faster. Faster.
Oh! Ah!
Come on! You don't
want to be eaten!
(GASPING)
EDUARDO: You're alone
in the jungle.
You get caught in a trap.
What do you do?
Um...
If I had my fanny pack...
No! You use your beak.
My beak.
It's your most important tool.
Okay, okay.
No, I use my beak. Mmm.
Almost. Oof!
Time's up!
You're jaguar meat.
Roberto got it on the first try.
Ah. Of course he did.
Up, up! And hover!
Now, backwards!
What, backwards?
No, only hummingbirds
can fly backwards.
Backwards.
Over! Under! Over!
(GRUNTING)
Under! Over!
Good job.
Oh. Oh, thanks.
Not you.
Uh, hi. (SPITS) Ah!
Brazil nut trees.
These trees are the key
to our way of life.
The trees feed us.
They sustain us. They...
(BLU SNORING)
Wake up!
Ah! I'm up. I'm up.
Oh. Nutty Brazil...
Brazil nut trees, something.
Yeah, got it. (CLEARS THROAT)
This is important.
We have to protect these trees.
Our future depends on it.
Hey, yo, Eddie.
Who is your sidekick?
You got a nurse now?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hi, I'm, um...
Aren't you boys getting
a little bit too close
to our side?
We have a deal, Felipe.
(CHUCKLING) Hey, relax.
You know we got nothing
but mad love for you.
Come on, boys, let's fly.
Paint the sky.
Before they start to cry.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Well, they seem nice.
They have their side of
the grove and we have ours.
Food is scarce these days.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
IN DISTANCE)
Shh!
Never seen them this close
to the village before.
What?
Don't let them see you!
Oh, right, right.
Sorry. Uh...
Maybe we should go find Linda.
What's a Linda?
Oh, Linda is the person
that raised me.
What? You're a pet?
No, no, I mean, no, no,
it wasn't anything like that.
I was a companion.
You liked it? Ugh!
That explains everything.
Linda is family.
Family?
Humans aren't family.
No, you don't understand.
They're coming here to help.
Listen to me. We do not bring
humans into the tribe.
That is the only reason
we're still alive.
You cannot be confused
about this. Understood?
Yeah. Got it.
Sightseeing is over.
(STRAINING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
LINDA: Do you see the nest?
Hmm.
Whoa!
(GASPS) Tulio, are you okay?
I'm fine! I'm okay! I'm...
TULIO: Not okay.
(CHAINSAW BUZZING)
(GASPS) Tulio, they're
cutting down the forest!
Wait a minute! Linda...
Linda, where are you going?
To talk to them.
You talk to birds,
I talk to humans.
No! Wait, don't! Ow! Ooh.
Hey! Hey, mister!
Hello!
You take it easy
with that chainsaw.
There are rare birds
living around here.
You can't cut down these trees!
Ooh, sweetheart!
There you are.
Mmm, I was looking for you.
Hi, there. Beautiful
out here, isn't it?
MAN: You two lost?
Lost? No!
(CHUCKLING NERVOUSLY) Lost?
No. We're here
on our honeymoon.
We're actually just heading
back to join the tour.
It's, uh, karaoke night.
(CHUCKLES)
Come along, honey.
Moon River isn't going
to sing itself.
(WHISPERING) Linda, logs aren't
the only things these guys out.
(GASPS)
Run, Linda.
I'll hold them off.
Go, go, go! Run!
Okay, okay, okay!
(GRUNTS)
(SCOFF)
Ooh. (CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
LINDA: Excuse me, excuse me!
(PANTING)
Come on, I'll race you.
Whoo-hoo! This is great!
Whoo! All right, Tiago!
Oh, yeah!
Tiago!
(GRUNTING) Hey!
Mmm!
Whoa.
Oh, that is so good.
Hey, you're back. Oh.
How did it go?
Um...
Oh, we had a great time.
It was, uh, educational.
Dad! Uncle Beto showed me
some cool flying tricks.
"Uncle"? Ah.
Look, I can fly backwards.
Yeah, you're
a natural, T-Bird.
(BOTH CAWING)
(JEWEL CHUCKLING)
It's never too soon to learn
the ways of the jungle, Tiago.
(INHALES DEEPLY) Although
some may never learn.
I'm going to go, uh, clean up.
Roberto, we saw humans
near the grove.
I need you to stay alert.
Uh, ah. "Ways of the jungle."
I'd like to learn a way
out of this jungle.
Ooh! There he is.
Now is our chance.
Oh, I'm so excited!
(LAUGHING)
Prepare the tongue-a-pult.
Charlie, make me fly again.
(GRUNTS)
Oh, go get 'em, tiger!
(LAUGHING)
Ow!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Bow before
the conquering cockatoo.
What is your problem, dude?
Ooh.
Bird, that was sick!
Now, that's the energy
you bring into an audition.
Audition?
Yeah, that's actually
why I'm here.
I've got a great little...
(SCREAMS) Go on.
We're looking for a new star.
Star?
You look familiar.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
Uh, no, I don't think so.
Um, no. I'm, uh, um...
Bob. Yes. Bob the bird.
(GIGGLES)
Okay, Bob, whatever.
Show us what you got.
Um...
Well...
Well, at first I was afraid,
I was petrified.
I kept thinking
that I could never live,
I could barely fly.
And I spent, oh, so many nights
thinking how he did me wrong
and I grew strong...
(SINGING) And I learned
how to get along
Go on, now, go
(SQUAWKING) Walk out the door
Just turn around now (SCREAMS)
It is I who have the floor
Weren't you the one who
tried to hurt me with goodbye?
Did you think I'd crumble?
Oh, no!
Did you think I'd
lay down and die?
Oh, no, not Nige
I will survive
As long as
I know how to hate
I know I'll stay alive
(GABI VOCALIZING)
I've got all my life to live
And I've got all my love to give
And I will survive
You will survive
I will survive
We will survive
(RAPPING) I'm a survivor
I've got the eye of a tiger
Been training again
And eating my fiber
You been staying alive
Well, I've been staying aliver
Watch where you sit when
I spit my saliva, like boom!
You've never seen a Cockatoo
Rocking and shocking
and dropping
And popping and looking, too?
Watch what I can do
Without no Auto-Tune
Say what?
(ULULATING)
Oh, no, he didn't.
If you try to keep me down
(GABI VOCALIZING)
I'll just come back stronger
You try to cut me short
I'll just come back longer
If you beat me at ping pong
I'll just play ping ponger
Give me my throne,
I am ready to thrive
One thing I know Ah!
I will survive
(ALL CHEERING)
Yes, thank you.
I've been Bob the bird.
(PANTS)
He is so hot.
Boom. That's it.
You in.
You're no Eva,
but you're awesome.
We'll see you at the
performance tomorrow night.
Everyone from
the village is coming.
It's going to be off the charts.
Everyone?
It's the perfect plan.
Ow!
Be happy we're only
plucking you, porcupine.
Ow!
Go away.
Instead of chasing that bird
all over the jungle,
we let him come to us,
at the Carnival show.
I'll mesmerize them
from the stage,
while in the audience,
you, my little Gabi...
(PURRING)
...you'll be my petite
weapon of mass destruction.
It will be a performance
to die for.
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
(GABI LAUGHING EVILLY)
It only works when I do it.
Okay. Love ya.
(GRUNTING)
Ah!
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(BUZZING) So minty.
Ah!
Yes!
(BUZZING CONTINUES)
Ugh.
Ooh! Ah.
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh. Hey, sweetie,
there you are.
What's taking you so long?
Enough with that GPS, really.
The whole tribe's gathering
to watch the sunset. Come on.
Oh, no, no. Hang on.
No, I just found
Linda and Tulio's
coordinates. Hmm.
They are just on
the other side of the grove.
Look, they're really close.
Oh.
Yeah.
Now, I know your dad
doesn't totally trust humans
but I'm sure if he met them,
he would change his mind.
They can help keep
this place safe.
Yeah, Blu...
My dad knows what he's doing.
And can't you just
forget Linda and Tulio
for one minute
and enjoy a sunset?
But I thought that was our plan.
GPS: Route
guidance complete.
(SIGHS) I...
You know, maybe some places
shouldn't be found.
Maybe they should
just be left alone.
(BUZZING)
Wha... Ah. Ow. (GASPS)
She ate a bug. A bug!
Blu, Blu, Blu! Calm down.
Calm down? We had a plan.
Help Linda and Tulio find
the flock and get home.
But when I mentioned it to her,
she completely shut me down.
Oh! Oh, oh, oh...
And her father?
Mmm, total nut job.
He's got this weird
thing about humans.
thing about humans!
He loves them. He's a pet!
A bet?
He called me a pet.
I can't believe he used
the P word to my face.
It's like he thinks
I'm the enemy or something.
He's not one of us, Roberto.
Keep an eye on him.
Oh, and that Roberto?
He is always watching.
He is always
hovering around Jewel.
He is always singing something.
I can't compete with that.
You gotta bird up, bird!
You gotta emancipate yourself
from domestication.
Try to see this place
through her eyes.
Taste the flavors she's tasting.
Ooh, so I should eat a bug?
Ew, that's just nasty,
thinking about it.
Glitter. Where
is my glitter?
Oh, I'm sorry. Sorry.
I don't want apologies.
I want glitter.
Ugh. Glitter is
absolutely essential...
Oh, Nigel!
...for a magical performance.
Do you know nothing?
Guys!
Rehearsals, big day tomorrow.
Ring a bell? Come on.
You're coming, right, Dad?
Oh, yeah, yeah, of course.
That girl put the "business"
in "show business."
Blu, remember...
I know, I know.
Happy wife, happy life.
Whoo-hoo!
What a glorious morning!
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, I forgot I could have
mornings like this. Mmm.
(BLU VOCALIZING)
Yeah.
Your favorite.
Oh.
You remembered.
Isn't that nice?
(LAUGHING)
It's so crazy good.
Thank you so much, Blu.
(VOCALIZING)
(GASPS) That's it!
Oh.
I'll be the one to surprise her.
Breakfast in bed coming up.
(HUFFING)
(GASPING)
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Brazil nuts,
where are you?
Ah. I know you're
around here somewhere.
Ah. Ow!
What?
Hey! Whoa, hey.
(CHITTERING)
No! Hey, hey,
come back here. Wait!
No! (PANTING)
That's not a toy.
GPS: Erratic driving.
Pull over.
(STAMMERING)
(CHITTERING)
(GROANING)
(WHIRRING)
No, no. Don't do it.
(CHITTERING)
Oh! Oh, oh, oh.
Whoa! Huh?
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH CHITTERING)
(WHISTLING)
Hmm! Mmm.
Got you! Hmm. Thank you.
BLU: Huh. Finally!
Brazil nuts.
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
This is my most important tool.
(GRUNTING)
(STRUGGLING)
Huh?
Well, well, well.
What do we have here?
(CHUCKLES) I guess
old Eddie's rules
don't apply to everyone.
(ALL LAUGHING)
You're on our side.
Oh. Oh, really? Okay, my bad.
Uh, I didn't know that. Sorry.
Ah!
Oh. Oops, sorry! Sorry.
You come over here,
take our food
and now you insult me?
Oh. Oh, no, no, no.
This is all just
a big misunderstanding.
You know, I wish
I could accept your apology.
You seem like a nice bird.
But this means war!
(ALL LAUGHING)
What? Does it have to?
Can it mean something else?
Today, in the Pit of Doom.
(SNICKERING)
Sorry, the "Pit of Doom"?
Really? Oh, really?
High noon.
Oh, I'll make some room.
Sweep you up like a broom.
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
You did what?
It was an accident.
An accident?
Hey, whoa, what's going on?
Thanks to Drew here,
we could lose our entire
side of the grove.
I was just trying
to get a nut. One nut!
You don't even like nuts!
What's gotten into you, Blu?
I was getting it for you.
Aw, you were?
Roberto, I want
your best birds on this.
We are not giving up
without a fight.
Got it.
You. Stay out of it.
You've done enough.
Wait!
Blu, he's right.
Maybe you should just let
Dad and Roberto handle it.
You don't think I can do this?
No, I just don't know
if it's your exact area
of expertise.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Pit of Doom, now!
Yeah, let's get 'em!
Yeah!
Ooh!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Radio!
Huh?
BIG BOSS: Oh,
I hope you don't mind.
I made myself at home.
Lollipop?
(CHITTERING)
(SNARLING)
(GASPS)
LINDA: Hey!
It's a shame, really,
you came all this way
to protect the jungle.
Let's see if it will
return the favor.
Tree-huggers. (CHUCKLES)
(MONKEY LAUGHING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CROWD TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Roberto.
Felipe.
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL BOOING)
No mercy!
I have to stop this.
What? Blu!
Stop! Stop!
Eduardo, this is crazy.
We are
an intelligent species with
advanced
problem-solving capabilities.
You brought this on us.
Now, watch.
(CAWING)
(SCATTING)
Ooh-ah!
ALL: Ooh-ah!
Heads.
Tails.
(GRUNTS)
I hate this job.
(WHISTLING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
Ha!
Oh, it's a game.
Oh, it's a game!
It's not a game!
It's war.
TAPIR: Ay-yi-yi!
It's a beautiful day
in the Pit of Doom!
It's winner take all!
It's the best of seven.
The winner will take control of
the entire Brazil nut grove!
Oh, it's just like soccer.
I can do this.
All right,
any special strategies?
What are we running,
a 4-4-2 or a 5-4-1?
What are we doing here, coach?
What position do I play?
Actually, I do have
a perfect spot for you.
Water. Water here.
Get your water.
Ah, okay, thanks.
TAPIR: Roberto is unstoppable!
He's incredible!
He's everywhere!
ALL: Go, Roberto!
(SCOFFS) I could have done that.
TAPIR: Roberto springs free!
There he goes, there he goes,
there he goes! He shoots!
(GRUNTING)
(ALL CHEERING)
BOTH: Goal!
ALL: Goal!
TAPIR: Goal! Goal!
Goal!
(GRUNTING)
TAPIR: Oh, my! Ay-yi-yi!
Felipe has the ball.
The Red Macaws
are making a comeback.
Felipe pass to Tito.
Tito with Mario.
Mario with Cesar.
Cesar to Antonio.
Now!
Felipe scores!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(LAUGHS) Yeah!
In your face!
TAPIR: Felipe, Roberto.
Roberto, Felipe.
Roberto, Felipe. Roberto,
Felipe. Felipe, Roberto!
(ALL CHEERING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
TAPIR: Goooooal!
(GRUNTS)
Ooh! Ay-yi-yi.
That's got to hurt.
Go, go!
(GRUNTING)
TAPIR: Felipe-lipe-lipe!
(GROANS) Hey!
Foul!
Aw. Come on, ref!
(GROANING)
Okay, you're in.
Really?
Not you. You.
(CHUCKLES) Watch and
learn, water boy.
(SCREAMS)
All right, just get in there.
Yes!
Okay. Here we go, coach.
ALL: Yeah, Dad!
A new player
is coming off the bench.
Is he a secret weapon?
(IMITATING GUNSHOTS)
Oh. I think
it's the water boy.
Hey, I'm open!
I'm open, toss it to me!
Hey, pass to me, I'm open.
I'm wide open!
Pass the ball to me... Oh!
ALL: Ooh!
(GRUNTS)
Thanks for the pass, Blu!
Mind if I borrow this?
TAPIR: Roberto moves in.
He shakes one, then another!
Roberto! Gooooo...
ALL: Oh, yeah! Uh-uh!
Oh, yeah! Uh-uh!
(CROWD CHEERING)
ALL: Yay!
Hey!
...oooooooal!
We are tied in the Pit of Doom.
Whoever scores next...
TAPIR: Wins it all!
Oh, I got it, I got it!
Come on, Blu.
(GROWLS) Ah!
Ow! Ow!
Wow! The water boy is
suddenly playing like a pro!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS) Ooh, ooh, aah.
Pass the ball to Roberto!
Ooh! Yeah. Oh! Oh!
Pass the ball! Pass the ball!
Blu, wait!
Nah, this bird's got it covered.
(GRUNTING)
Yeah. Ah...
Goooooal... Oh, oh.
(ALL SIGHING)
(WHISTLING)
Oh!
(CHEERING)
It looks like the secret
weapon just backfired!
Let's go to Eduardo
for his reaction.
(SCREAMING)
I'm gonna kill you, fanny pack!
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING) Check
it out, old Eddie.
Looks like you guys
are going to have
to start a nut-free diet.
(LAUGHING)
We're going to be talking
about that for a long time.
I shouldn't have expected
more from a human's pet.
Hey.
Um...
What happened back there?
I was trying to be
one of the tribe.
But I guess I'm never
going to be "the bird"
like your dad wants me to be.
What?
I think it's time to go home.
We should talk about this.
Talk about what?
Blu, look around.
The kids are thriving. They
love being in the wild.
Maybe this place is home.
Home? How could this
be home?
I have done everything I can
to fit in and help out
but no matter what I do,
it's wrong.
That's not home, Jewel.
Maybe for you, but not for me.
You know what? You need to
figure out what you want.
And maybe stop thinking
about just yourself
and start thinking about us.
(GROANING)
MAN 1: Keep it coming.
Keep it coming. Whoa.
MAN 2: Right here.
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Okay,
you heard the boss.
Move out! Let's go!
(SPEAKING PORTUGUESE)
Beautiful. (CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTING)
Linda! Tulio!
Goodbye, Linda.
Goodbye, fanny pack.
GPS: Turn around
when possible.
Sorry, GPS lady.
It's not you. It's me.
Goodbye, pancakes.
Goodbye, coffee.
Ugh. Goodbye, coffee.
(GASPS)
Linda?
Linda!
Whoa!
Ha! Eduardo was right!
Traitor!
Wait, you don't understand.
What don't I understand?
Siding with humans?
What do you even
know about humans?
Oh, I know everything.
They lure you in, they trap you.
They destroy your mind!
Polly want a cracker?
No! Enough crackers!
I hate crackers!
(RUMBLING)
(BOTH GASP)
Come on, Roberto!
It's them. It's them!
It's them!
Roberto, get out of...
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
Not again! Not again!
No more crackers!
Snap out of it!
Ah!
Look!
We've got one chance
to stop this, okay?
I have to find my friends.
You fly back and warn
the others. You got it?
Yeah. I got it.
Okay. Go!
Okay!
(GROANS)
Ah! Humans, humans!
Your left! Your right!
My left?
Left or right?
(BOTH STRAINING)
Your right leg, my left leg.
Okay.
LINDA: Good! Good! Good!
(GROANING)
Now, go up.
Go up.
(BOTH STRAINING)
Reach! Almost there!
(BOTH SIGH)
Linda, I'm so sorry.
As bad as this is,
there is no place I would
rather be in the whole world
than with you.
Even if it is tied to a tree.
(GASPS)
(CAWING)
Oh, Linda!
(IMITATING BIRDCALLS)
Blu! Blu!
Linda?
LINDA: Down here!
(GASPS) What? Blu!
What are you doing here?
This is dangerous!
That's incredible!
It's a 2,000-mile flight!
Let's follow him!
It's amazing!
Ow! Ow...
I told you I heard him.
(GROANING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Ooh, ah, ooh, ooh, ah!
(WHIMPERING)
(EXHALING)
Hey! Get back... Whoa!
I'll take those.
Ah. Whoa!
(GASPING)
Ah! Game over! It's over!
Humans!
The lights! The lights!
(SCREAMING) It's over!
He's been blabbering like
this since we found him.
The loggers are coming!
And Blu is with them!
Traitor!
No! No,
Blu is trying to help us.
What? By himself?
Let's evacuate! We're leaving.
Let's go. Everyone move out.
Go, go, go!
Dad?
No, not this time.
I'm not going with you.
You have to go with me!
I will not put my family
in danger again.
Blu is my family and
I'm not leaving him behind.
BLU: You don't have to.
Are you okay?
Look, Eduardo, I might not be
the birdliest bird in the flock
but for once, that's
actually a good thing.
You know the jungle,
I know humans.
And I know that together,
we can stop them.
We can't let them take our home.
Sure, it's hot and loud and
filled with creepy bugs,
but it's ours.
Let's fight for it.
Who's with me?
I'm with you!
(SCREAMS)
(THUDS)
Anybody else?
(BOTH PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Last one.
(SPEAKING PORTUGUESE)
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
Eek.
Oh, yeah.
Respect the rainforest!
(GASPS)
Oh!
I knew it!
I knew it! I knew...
Oh!
(EXCLAIMS IN FEAR)
(PANTING)
Hey. Where do you think
you're going?
It's just a bunch of pigeons.
Get back to work!
Lead the way, Blu.
Huh?
That's my name!
Yes! You called me Blu.
Yes, I am Blu!
(CLEARS THROAT)
What? Oh. Oh, right.
Birds of blue feathers...
ALL: Have to stick together!
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Huh?
(SHUDDERING)
Everybody ready? And under!
(SCREAMING)
Over!
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Backwards!
(SINGING) I will survive
I will survive
(SCREAMING)
Ow! Oh!
Got him!
Wow, precise.
(GRUNTS) I ain't
afraid of no birds.
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(GAGGING)
Attack!
It's on in the Amazon!
All right, hit it!
Oh!
Ooh!
Whoo! High-five!
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
Why? Why?
Geta grip!
(CAWING)
(GASPS)
Incoming!
Halt!
(SQUEALS)
There he is.
Charlie, prepare
the nose-zooka.
(GRUNTING) Tiago!
Now we're talking.
(GRUNTS)
NIGEL: Ready... Aim... Fire!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Foiled again.
(GRUNTS)
TIAGO: Yay!
Good job, Tiago.
We're a great team, Dad!
Hey, old Eddie.
Felipe.
You think I'd miss
this party? Game on!
(MEN SCREAMING)
Hey! Come back!
(GROANING)
You're useless, all of you!
Look out!
Ow!
Pick on someone your own size.
(GROWLING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(LINDA GRUNTS)
(GASPS) No! No!
I got you, I got you.
It's okay, it's okay,
you're safe now.
Ah!
(GROANS)
Whoo-hoo!
That's a Linda.
LINDA: Whoo!
Oh, yeah! Whoo!
(SCREAMING)
(MEN SCREAMING INDISTINCTLY)
(LAUGHS) Yeah!
Whoo!
(ALL CHEERING)
We still got it, Blu!
Boh, boh, pow!
(EXPLOSION)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SIGHS AND GASPS)
I have to do everything myself.
(SQUAWKS) Ah!
Hey! Get away from that!
Oh, no!
No one steals my scene.
(GROANS)
Lollipop?
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What?
(LAUGHING)
What are you doing?
Let go! Save yourself!
(GRUNTING)
Come on, let go!
Never!
Are you crazy?
You'll bring both of us
down! Let go!
Ooh! Ooh! Ah! Fly!
Déjà Vu, Blu.
Nigel!
Blu!
(MOANING)
(BOTH YELL)
You!
Uh-oh.
You will pay a painful price
for your pestilence!
Hey, stop that!
Hey, get off of me!
A flurry of furious feathers
in your face!
Hey, you don't have to do this!
No, I just want to.
Ow. Ow. Ow.
Hey, stop! Stop!
Oh, my goodness. Charlie!
This is it. This is it!
Steady. Steady.
Slap fight!
(LAUGHING)
Shoot! Shoot!
BLU: Ow. Ow.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh! Nigel!
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
Is this the end?
I was too young,
too beautiful to live.
Bob?
Hold up! That ain't Bob!
I told you I knew him
from somewhere.
My final curtain call.
And it's standing room only.
Goodbye.
(CHOKING)
No!
No! What have I done?
If I cannot, liveth with thee,
then I shall not liveth at all.
(CHOKES AND SQUEAKS)
(VOCALIZING)
That frog is not poisonous.
What? Oh!
(GASPING) We're not dead?
It's a very common mistake.
But she's a harmless
pseudo-dendrobate.
You can tell by the pink spots.
But my parents always
told me I was poisonous
and shouldn't touch anyone.
(SCOFFS) You just had
really mean parents.
Oh, wow. (CHUCKLES)
So, now... (GASPS)
We can be together!
Oh.
(CHUCKLING)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
Oh, Nigel!
My Nigel-Wigel-Wigglepuss!
No! No.
Somebody, help me!
GABI: I'm going to
never let you go.
I'm sorry, I'll be nicer. No!
Never gonna let you go!
No, Charlie!
(SQUEAKING)
NIGEL: Charlie!
(SCREAMING) This is unnatural!
(GIBBERING)
(LAUGHING)
Okay, hi, guys! Hi!
(CHUCKLING) There's nothing
in my hair, right? Okay.
Directly from the heart
of the Amazon rainforest,
we have some breaking news.
Thanks to Dr. Monteiro
and his team,
the entire area
will be designated
as a National Wildlife Refuge.
And together, we'll make sure
this place stays safe.
Right, Blu?
(SQUAWKING)
But that's not
the only good news.
We found this Cockatoo
deep in the Amazon
and he seems to have bonded
with a tree frog.
We are bringing them back to Rio
for continuing observation.
(GASPS) Oh, Nigel! Wow!
A honeymoon in Rio!
Oh.
Yay! (LAUGHS)
Put your paws, talons
and tails together
for the most amazing talent
ever gathered in one jungle.
It's "Amazon Untamed"!
PEDRO: Hey, come on!
Hey, get up!
Yeah! Hey!
(SINGING) What's up? Don't bite
it What's up? Don't bite it
(BIRDS VOCALIZING)
Where my birds at?
We're together no matter
Where we might go
(VOCALIZING)
Flap your wings!
If we're not all together
We can't go far
Amazon!
Uh-huh.
It's the emerald we treasure
Coming from the jungle to you
Bam!
Beating like its heart beats
(LAUGHING)
Playing rhythms we've grown to
It's the emerald we treasure
Coming from
the place where we live
The place where we live
The home of
freedom and happiness
Happiness
Time flies forever
The jungle's like a breeze
It's a wonder
Now get out your tutu
In case someone
wants you to dance
(SNORING)
Hello, Amazon!
Hey, Luiz!
Hey birds, I made it!
Welcome to the jungle, dawg!
(SCATTING)
All my turtles!
Hardcore turtles!
(SCATTING)
(LAUGHING)
Whoa, whoa
Sing it, baby!
(SINGING OFF-KEY)
Rafi!
(CHUCKLING) Phew.
Are you sure you can make
the Amazon our home?
With the heat
and the creepy bugs...
What? Are you kidding?
I am Mr. Jungle.
Totally wild and very birdly.
(GASPING)
(CHUCKLING)
Maybe we can do summers in Rio.
You're my one and only, Jewel.
Aw.
Forever together
Wherever we may go
We can go far
BOTH: Ah!
That's the end?
(RIO RIO PLAYING)
(IT'S A JUNGLE OUT HERE PLAYING)
(WHAT IS LOVE PLAYING)