[ lightning cracks ]
[ thunder rumbles ]
[ intro to "SCIENCE FICTION/DOUBLE FEATURE" plays ]
♪ MICHAEL RENNIE WAS ILL
THE DAY THE EARTH STOOD STILL ♪
♪ BUT HE TOLD US WHERE WE STAND ♪
♪ AND FLASH GORDON WAS THERE
IN SILVER UNDERWEAR ♪
♪ CLAUDE RAINS
WAS THE INVISIBLE MAN ♪
♪ THEN SOMETHING WENT WRONG ♪
♪ FOR FAY WRAY AND KING KONG ♪
♪ THEY GOT CAUGHT IN A CELLULOID JAM ♪
♪ THEN AT A DEADLY PACE IT CAME FROM ♪
♪ OUTER SPACE ♪
♪ AND THIS IS HOW THE MESSAGE RAN ♪
♪ SCIENCE FICTION ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ DOUBLE FEATURE ♪
♪ WOW, WOW, WOW ♪
♪ DR. "X" ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ WILL BUILD A CREATURE ♪
♪ WOW, WOW, WOW ♪
♪ SEE ANDROIDS FIGHTING ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ BRAD AND JANET ♪
♪ WOW, WOW, WOW ♪
♪ ANNE FRANCIS STARS IN ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ "FORBIDDEN PLANET" ♪
♪ WHOA-OH-OH, OH-OH ♪
♪ AT THE LATE-NIGHT DOUBLE-FEATURE ♪
♪ PICTURE SHOW ♪
♪ OOH ♪
[ cheers and applause  ]
♪ I KNEW LEO G. CARROLL
WAS OVER A BARREL ♪
♪ WHEN TARANTULA TOOK TO THE HILLS ♪
♪ AND I REALLY GOT HOT
WHEN I SAW JANETTE SCOTT ♪
♪ FIGHT A TRIFFID
THAT SPITS POISON AND KILLS ♪
♪ DANA ANDREWS SAID PRUNES
GAVE HIM THE RUNES ♪
♪ AND PASSING THEM USED
LOTS OF SKILLS ♪
♪ "AND WHEN WORLDS COLLIDE,"
SAID GEORGE PAL TO HIS BRIDE ♪
♪ "I'M GONNA
GIVE YOU SOME TERRIBLE THRILLS" ♪
♪ LIKE A ♪
♪ SCIENCE FICTION ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ DOUBLE FEATURE ♪
♪ WOW, WOW, WOW ♪
♪ DR. "X" ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ WILL BUILD A CREATURE ♪
♪ WOW, WOW, WOW ♪
♪ SEE ANDROIDS FIGHTING ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ BRAD AND JANET ♪
♪ WOW, WOW, WOW ♪
♪ ANNE FRANCIS STARS IN ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ "FORBIDDEN PLANET" ♪
♪ WHOA-OH-OH, OH-OH ♪
♪ AT THE LATE-NIGHT DOUBLE-FEATURE ♪
♪ PICTURE SHOW ♪
♪ I WANNA GO ♪
♪ WHOA-OH ♪
♪ TO THE LATE-NIGHT DOUBLE-FEATURE ♪
♪ PICTURE SHOW ♪
♪ BY R.K.O. ♪
♪ WHOA-OH, OH-OH ♪
♪ TO THE LATE-NIGHT DOUBLE-FEATURE ♪
♪ PICTURE SHOW ♪
♪ IN THE BACK ROW ♪
♪ WHOA, OH ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
♪ TO THE LATE-NIGHT ♪
♪ DOUBLE-FEATURE ♪
♪ PICTURE SHOW ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
[ sighs ]
Oh, Brad,
wasn't it wonderful?
Didn't Betty look
radiantly beautiful?
I can't believe it.
just an hour ago, she was
plain Betty Munroe,
and now she's
Mrs. Ralph Hapschatt.
[ sighs ]
Ohh. Yes, Janet,
Ralph's a lucky guy.
Yes.
And everyone knows
Betty is a wonderful
little cook.
Yes.
And Ralph himself will be
in line for promotion
in a year or two.
Yes.
Hey, Janet?
Yes, Brad?
I-I-I got something to say.
Yes?
I really loved
the skillful way...
Yes?
...you beat the other girls
to the bride's bouquet.
Oh, Brad.
♪ THE RIVER WAS DEEP,
BUT I SWAM IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ THE FUTURE IS OURS,
SO LET'S PLAN IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ SO PLEASE,
DON'T TELL ME TO CAN IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ I'VE ONE THING TO SAY,
AND THAT'S, "DAMN IT, JANET ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU" ♪
♪ THE ROAD WAS LONG,
BUT I RAN IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ THERE'S A FIRE IN MY HEART,
AND YOU FAN IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ IF THERE'S ONE FOOL FOR YOU,
THEN I AM IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ I'VE ONE THING TO SAY,
AND THAT'S, "DAMN IT, JANET ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU" ♪
♪ HERE'S THE RING TO PROVE ♪
♪ THAT I'M NO JOKER ♪
♪ BUM-BUM-BUM-BUM ♪
♪ THERE'S THREE WAYS
THAT LOVE ♪
♪ CAN GROW ♪
[ GIGGLES ]
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ THAT'S GOOD, BAD,
OR MEDIOCRE ♪
♪ J-A-N-E-T,
I LOVE YOU SO ♪
OH! IT'S NICER
THAN BETTY MUNROE HAD!
♪ OH, BRAD ♪
♪ NOW WE'RE ENGAGED,
AND I'M SO GLAD ♪
♪ OH, BRAD ♪
♪ THAT YOU MET MOM
AND YOU KNOW DAD ♪
♪ OH, BRAD ♪
♪ I'VE ONE THING TO SAY,
AND THAT'S, "BRAD, I'M MAD ♪
♪ FOR YOU, TOO" ♪
♪ OH, BRAD ♪
♪ OH, DAMN IT ♪
♪ I'M MAD ♪
♪ OH, JANET! ♪
♪ FOR YOU ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU, TOO ♪
[ both ]: ♪ THERE'S ONE THING
LEFT TO DO-O-O ♪
♪ AND THAT'S GO SEE
THE MAN WHO BEGAN IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ WHEN WE MET
IN HIS SCIENCE EXAM, IT ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ MADE ME GIVE YOU THE EYE
AND THEN PANIC ♪
♪ JANET ♪
♪ I'VE ONE THING TO SAY,
AND THAT'S, "DAMN IT, JANET ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU" ♪
♪ DAMN IT, JANET ♪
♪ OH, BRAD, I'M MAD ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU ♪
[ church bells ringing ]
[ cheers and applause ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ sighs ]
[ laughter ]
You smell.
I would like, if I may...
Audience: YOU MAY!
...to take you...
TAKE ME!
[ laughter ]
Perhaps later.
...on a strange journey...
HOW STRANGE?
[ chuckles ]
Oh, you'd be surprised.
[ laughter ]
It seemed a fairly
ordinary night...
ORDINARY?
Mm.
When Brad Majors...
ARSEHOLE!
[ laughter ]
You've met.
and his fiancé --
or do you prefer fiancée? --
Janet Weiss...
SLUT!
Two ordinary, healthy kids...
HEALTHY?
Mm, -ish.
left Denton that late
"Nomever" evening...
...left Denton that late
[ mumbles ] evening...
[ laughter ]
to visit a Dr. Everett Scott.
SIEG HEIL!
ex-science tutor,
and now friend to both of them.
It's true that there were dark
storm clouds...
DESCRIBE YOUR BALLS!
[ laughter ]
Heavy, black,
and pendulous.
[ cheers and applause ]
Curses upon you.
...towards which
they were driving.
It's true also that the spare
tire they were carrying
was badly in need of some air.
BLOW JOB!
Yes, please.
[ laughter ]
but they, being normal kids
and on a night out, well...
IT WAS A NIGHT IN!
they were not going to let
a storm spoil the events
of their evening.
CERTAINLY NOT!
No.
On a night out...
IT WAS A NIGHT IN!
On a night out --
and we --
Oh, have it your own way.
[ laughter ]
...they were to remember...
FOR HOW LONG?!
For a very, very long time.
[ thunder crashes ]
[ cheers and applause ]
Hmm.
What's the matter,
Brad, darling?
Uh...I think we took the wrong
fork a few miles back there.
We better go on ahead
up the road
and see if we can find
our way back.
[ pop, air hissing ]
Oh, darn, Janet!
what was that bang?
Audience: GANG BANG!
[ laughter ]
We seem to have a blowout in
the front left-hand tire.
Ohh.
[ thunder crashes ]
You better stay here and keep
warm while I go for help.
But where will you go?
we're in the middle of nowhere.
DIDN'T YOU PASS A CASTLE
BACK DOWN THE ROAD A FEW MILES?
[ laughter ]
Hmm.
Didn't we pass a castle back
down the road a few miles?
[ cheers and applause ]
Maybe they have a telephone
I might use.
I'm coming with you.
THAT'LL BE A FIRST!
There's no point in both
of us getting wet.
I'm coming with you.
Besides, darling,
the owner of the phone
may be a beautiful woman.
HE IS!
And you may never come back.
[ laughs ]
[ maniacal laughter ]
[ thunder crashes, rumbles ]
[ intro TO "OVER AT THE FRANKENSTEIN PLACE" plays ]
♪ IN THE VELVET DARKNESS ♪
♪ OF THE BLACKEST NIGHT ♪
♪ BURNING BRIGHT ♪
♪ THERE'S A GUIDING STAR ♪
♪ NO MATTER WHAT ♪
♪ OR ♪
♪ WHO YOU A-A-A-RE ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT ♪
♪ OVER AT
THE FRANKENSTEIN PLACE ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT ♪
♪ BURNING IN THE FIREPLACE ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT, LIGHT ♪
♪ IN THE DARKNESS ♪
♪ OF EVERYBODY'S LIFE ♪
♪ I CAN SEE THE FLAG FLY ♪
♪ I CAN SEE THE RAIN ♪
♪ JUST THE SAME ♪
♪ WELL, THERE HAS GOT TO BE ♪
♪ SOMETHING BETTER HERE FOR ♪
♪ YOU AND ME ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT ♪
♪ OVER AT
THE FRANKENSTEIN PLACE ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT ♪
♪ BURNING IN THE FIREPLACE ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT, LIGHT ♪
♪ IN THE DARKNESS ♪
♪ OF EVERYBODY'S LIFE ♪
♪ THE DARKNESS MUST GO ♪
♪ DOWN THE RIVER
OF NIGHT'S DREAMING ♪
♪ FLOW MORPHIUS SLOW ♪
♪ LET THE SUN AND LIGHT
COME STREAMING ♪
♪ INTO MY LIFE ♪
♪ INTO MY LI-I-I-I-I-I-FE ♪
♪ LIFE! ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT ♪
♪ OVER AT
THE FRANKENSTEIN PLACE ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT ♪
♪ BURNING IN THE FIREPLACE ♪
♪ THERE'S A LIGHT, LIGHT ♪
♪ IN THE DARKNESS ♪
♪ OF EVERYBODY'S LIFE ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
[ thunder crashes ]
Oh!
It's all right, Janet.
Oh, Brad, let's go back.
I'm cold, and I'm frightened.
Well, just a moment, Janet.
They may have a telephone.
[ doorbell rings ]
Audience: ARSEHOLE CALLING!
[ door creaks ]
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE
LIONEL RICHIE SONG?!
HELLO.
[ laughter and applause ]
Oh, uh, hi there.
We're in a bit of a spot.
I wonder, could you help us?
Our car has broken down
about two miles back.
Do you have a telephone
we might use?
You're wet.
SHE'S ALWAYS WET!
[ laughter ]
YES.
It's been raining.
Yes.
[ thunder crashes ]
I think perhaps you'd better
both [bleep] --
[ laughter ]
Come inside.
Uh...thank you.
You're too kind.
"You're too kind."
[ laughs maniacally ]
[ cheers and applause ]
[ clears throat ]
And so...
[ laughter ]
after braving
the inclement weather
in some not too little time,
it seemed that fortune
had smiled on Brad and Janet,
and that they had found
the assistance
that their plight required.
ARE YOU SURE?
I'm not quite,
but we'll find out.
[ laughter ]
There was certainly something
about this castle
to which a flat tire and a wet
night had brought them,
and it made them
both feel...
HORNY!
That's not what it says here.
[ laughter ]
...apprehensive and uneasy.
But if they were to reach
their destination that night,
they would have to ignore such
feelings and take advantage...
OF EACHOTHER!
...of whatever help was offered.
[ cheers and applause ]
[ door slams ]
Wait here.
HE SAID WAIT THERE!
[ laughter ]
[ applause ]
Oh... oh, Brad, what sort
of a place is this?
It's probably some sort of a
hunting lodge for rich weirdoes.
IT'S A CASTLE!
I'll keep a look out
for the undertaker.
I'm scared.
Oh, for god's sake, keep a grip
on yourself, Janet.
I'm here.
there's nothing to worry about.
[ high-pitched laughter ]
It's all right, Janet.
Excuse me. Hi.
Uh, look, if we could just use
your phone,
we'll move right along.
I'm sure you got
lots of things to do
and a great evening planned.
Oh, yes.
You've arrived on a rather
special night.
HURRY UP, THEN!
The master is having one of
his affairs.
Lucky old him..
Yeah. He's lucky.
I'm lucky.
You're lucky.
We're all lucky!
All except Eddie.
Shh!
Eddie?
The delivery boy.
His delivery
wasn't good enough.
The master only wanted to help
the boy better his position.
Oh, that's very commendable.
Yes. it seems like only
yesterday since he went.
Where?
To pieces!
[ intro to "THE TIME WARP" plays ]
♪ IT'S ASTOUNDING ♪
♪ TIME IS FLEETING ♪
♪ MADNESS TAKES ITS TOLL ♪
♪ BUT LISTEN CLOSELY ♪
♪ NOT FOR VERY MUCH LONGER ♪
♪ I'VE GOT TO KEEP CONTROL ♪
♪ I REMEMBER ♪
♪ DOING THE TIME WARP ♪
♪ DRINKING THOSE MOMENTS WHEN ♪
♪ THE BLACKNESS WOULD HIT ME ♪
♪ AND THE VOID WOULD BE CALLING ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
It's just a jump to the left...
♪ AND THEN A STEP TO THE RI-I-I-I-GHT ♪
with your hands on your hips...
♪ YOU BRING YOUR KNEES IN TIGHT ♪
♪ BUT IT'S THE PELVIC THRUST ♪
♪ THAT REALLY DRIVES YOU INSA-A-A-A-A-NE ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ IT'S SO DREAMY ♪
♪ OH, FANTASY, FREE ME! ♪
♪ SO YOU CAN'T SEE ME ♪
♪ NO, NOT AT ALL ♪
♪ IN ANOTHER DIMENSION ♪
♪ WITH VOYEURISTIC INTENTION ♪
♪ WELL SECLUDED ♪
♪ I SEE ALL ♪
♪ WITH A BIT OF A MIND FLIP ♪
♪ YOU'RE INTO THE TIME SLIP ♪
♪ AND NOTHING ♪
♪ CAN EVER BE THE SAME ♪
♪ YOU'RE SPACED OUT ON SENSATION ♪
♪ LIKE YOU'RE UNDER SEDATION ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ WELL, I WAS TAPPING DOWN THE STREET ♪
♪ JUST A-HAVING A THINK ♪
♪ WHEN A SNAKE OF A GUY
GAVE ME AN EVIL WINK ♪
♪ IT SHOOK-A ME UP,
IT TOOK ME BY SURPRISE ♪
♪ HE HAD A PICKUP TRUCK
AND THE DEVIL'S EYES ♪
♪ HE STARED AT ME,
AND I FELT A CHANGE ♪
♪ TIME MEANT NOTHING,
NEVER WOULD AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
Whoo!
[ tapping ]
[ cheering ]
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
It's just a jump to the left...
♪ AND THEN A STEP
TO THE RI-I-I-I-GHT ♪
with your hands on your hips...
♪ YOU BRING YOUR KNEES IN TIGHT ♪
♪ BUT IT'S THE PELVIC THRUST ♪
♪ THAT REALLY DRIVES YOU INSA-A-A-A-A-NE ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
Whoo!
[ cheers and applause ]
Wow! Whoo!
Say something, Brad!
Oh! Do you guys know
how to Madison?
♪ ♪
Oh, Brad, let's get out of here.
It seems so unhealthy!
I'm cold, and I'm wet,
and I'm just plain scared!
I'm here, Janet.
there's nothing to worry about.
Brad, I want to go!
[ intro to "SWEET TRANSVESTITE" plays ]
♪ HOW D'YOU DO? I ♪
♪ SEE YOU'VE MET MY ♪
♪ FAITHFUL HANDYMAN ♪
♪ HE'S A LITTLE BROUGHT DOWN BECAUSE ♪
♪ WHEN YOU KNOCKED ♪
♪ HE THOUGHT YOU WERE THE CANDY MAN ♪
Didn't you, Freaky?
♪ DON'T GET STRUNG OUT ♪
♪ BY THE WAY I LOOK ♪
♪ DON'T JUDGE A BOOK BY ITS COVER ♪
♪ I'M NOT MUCH OF A MAN ♪
♪ BY THE LIGHT OF DAY ♪
♪ BUT BY NIGHT,
I'M ONE HELL OF A LOVER ♪
♪ I'M JUST A SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ FROM TRANSSEXUAL ♪
♪ TRANSYLVANIA ♪
♪ UH-HUH ♪
♪ SO, LET ME SHOW YOU AROUND, MAYBE ♪
♪ PLAY YOU A SOUND ♪
♪ YOU LOOK LIKE
YOU'RE BOTH PRETTY GROOVY ♪
♪ OR IF YOU WANT SOMETHING VISUAL ♪
♪ THAT'S NOT TOO ABYSMAL ♪
♪ WE COULD TAKE IN
AN OLD STEVE REEVES MOVIE ♪
I'm glad we caught you
at home.
Uh, could we use your phone?
[ clears throat ]
We're both in a bit of a hurry.
Right.
We'll just
say where we are,
then get back to the car.
We don't want to be
any worry.
♪ SO, YOU GOT CAUGHT
WITH A FLAT, WELL ♪
♪ HOW 'BOUT THAT? ♪
♪ WELL, BABIES, DON'T YOU PANIC ♪
♪ BY THE LIGHT OF THE NIGHT ♪
♪ IT'LL ALL SEEM ALL RIGHT ♪
♪ I'LL GET YOU A SATANIC MECHANIC ♪
♪ I'M JUST A SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ FROM TRANSSEXUAL ♪
♪ TRANSYLVANIA ♪
♪ UH-HUH ♪
♪ WHY DON'T YOU STAY FOR THE NIGHT? ♪
♪ NIGHT ♪
♪ OR MAYBE A BITE ♪
♪ BITE ♪
♪ I COULD SHOW YOU
MY FAVORITE OBSESSION ♪
♪ I'VE BEEN MAKING A MAN ♪
♪ WITH DARK HAIR AND A TAN ♪
♪ AND HE'S GOOD OR RELIEVING MY ♪
♪ TCH, TCH, TCH, TCH,
TCH, TCH, TCH ♪
♪ TENSION! ♪
♪ I'M JUST A SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ FROM TRANSSEXUAL ♪
♪ TRANSYLVANIA, HA HA ♪
♪ HIT IT, HIT IT! ♪
♪ I'M JUST A SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ SWEET, SWEET ♪
♪ FROM TRANSSEXUAL ♪
♪ TRANSYLVANIA ♪
♪ UH-HUH ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
[ scattered cheers and catcalls ]
So...come up to the lab...
and see what's on the slab.
I see you shiver with antici...
[ all ]: SAY IT! SAY IT!
SAY IT! SAY IT!
pation.
♪ BUT MAYBE THE RAIN ♪
♪ IS REALLY TO BLAME ♪
♪ SO I'LL REMOVE THE CAUSE ♪
[ chuckles ]
♪ BUT NOT THE SYMPTOM ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
[ doors slam ]
It's all right, Janet.
It's all right.
Everything's gonna be all right.
we'll just play along for now
and pull out the aces when
the time is right.
This is no time
for card tricks, Brad.
Are you sure
we'll be all right?
I'm sure, Janet.
Hi, there.
I'm Brad Majors.
ARSEHOLE!
And, uh, this is my fiancée
Janet Weiss.
SLUT!
You are?
You're very lucky to be invited
up to Frank's laboratory.
A lot of people would give their
right arm for the privilege.
People like you, maybe.
I've seen it.
Is he --
is Frank your husband?
[ cackles ]
The master is not yet married.
Nor do I think ever will be.
We are simply his servants.
[ all cackling ]
[ sighs ]
[ gasps ]
Janet!
Brad!
Brad...
[ liquid bubbling ]
[ electricity crackling ]
Unlock a mind, un-mind a lock.
It's the same as the beginning
of the end -- do you follow?
No.
Well, it's an anagram, Janet.
I wonder, may I offer you
something refreshing?
[ both ]: No.
No, you're right.
I won't.
How delightful to have
fresh faces around!
Uh, Magenta, Columbia,
go and assist Riff Raff
while I entertain, uh...
Brad Majors.
[ chuckles ]
And, uh, this is my fiancée,
Janet Vice.
Weiss.
Enchanté.
WHAT'S THAT MEAN?
How nice.
[ laughter ]
And what charming underclothes
you both have.
But, here, put these on.
It'll make you feel less...
NAKED!
...Vulnerable.
We don't often
receive visitors here,
let alone offer them hospitality.
Hospitality?
Mm.
All we wanted was to
use your phone.
A reasonable request which you
have chosen to ignore!
Don't be ungrateful, Brad.
Ungrateful?!
How forceful you are, Brad!
LIKE MARGARET THATCHER!
What a perfect example
of manhood.
So dominant.
You must be very proud, Janet.
Well...yes, I am.
Mm.
[ both giggle ]
[ laughter ]
Tell me, Brad,
do you have any tattoos?
[ gasps ]
Certainly not.
Mnh!
Oh, well.
How about you?
Oh...
Stop, stop.
[ both laugh ]
Everything is in readiness, Master.
We merely wait for you
to give the word.
Tonight, Brad and Janet,
you are to witness a
new breakthrough
in biochemical research,
and paradise is to be mine.
Well, how wonderful for you.
[ laughter ]
It's strange the way it happened.
Uh, one of those
quirks of fate, really.
One of those moments when
everything looks black.
The chips are down,
your back's against the wall,
You panic.
[ gasps hysterically ]
You're trapped!
there's no way out!
And even if there were,
it would probably be a one-way
ticket to the bottom of the bay.
And then, suddenly, you get a break.
All of the pieces
seem to fit into place.
What a sucker you'd been.
What a fool!
The answer was there
all the time.
It took a small accident
to make it happen.
Accident?
An accident!
It's how I discovered the secret.
That elusive ingredient,
that spark that is the
breath of life.
Yes, I have that knowledge.
I hold the key
to life itself!
[ laughs maniacally ]
[ guests applaud ]
Mm-mrrm!
[ applause stops ]
So, you see, Brad and Janet,
you really are quite fortunate,
for tonight is the night
my beautiful creature is
destined to be born.
Throw open the switches on
the sonic oscillator!
[ dramatic music plays ]
And step up
the reactor power input!
Oh!
Three more points!
[ machine pulsing 3 times ]
[ laughing insanely ]
Ohhh!
♪ THE SWORD OF DAMOCLES IS
HANGIN' OVER MY HEAD ♪
[ Frank laughs ]
♪ AND I'VE GOT A FEELING ♪
♪ SOMEONE'S GONNA
BE CUTTIN' THE THREAD ♪
OH! OH, HO!
♪ OH, WOE IS ME ♪
♪ MY LIFE IS A MISERY ♪
♪ AND CAN'T YOU SEE ♪
♪ THAT I'M AT THE
START OF A PRETTY BIG DOWNER? ♪
♪ I WOKE UP THIS MORNING ♪
♪ WITH A START AS I FELL OUT OF BED ♪
♪ THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ AND LEFT FROM MY DREAMIN' ♪
♪ WAS A FEELING OF UNNAMEABLE DREAD ♪
♪ THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ MY HIGH IS LOW ♪
♪ I'M DRESSED UP
WITH NO PLACE TO GO ♪
♪ AND ALL I KNOW ♪
♪ IS I'M AT THE
START OF A PRETTY BIG DOWNER ♪
♪ SHA-LA-LA-LA, THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ WHOA, WHOA, WHOA ♪
♪ OH, NO, NO ♪
♪ SHA-LA-LA-LA, THAT AIN'T NO CRIME,
THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
Rocky Horror,
you need peace of mind.
I want to tell you
that you're doing just fine.
You're the product of
another time,
so feeling low, well,
that's no crime.
♪ THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ THE SWORD OF DAMOCLES IS
HANGIN' OVER MY HEAD ♪
♪ THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ AND I'VE GOT A FEELING ♪
♪ SOMEONE'S GONNA BE CUTTIN'
THE THREAD ♪
♪ THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ OH, WOE IS ME ♪
♪ MY LIFE IS A MISERY ♪
♪ AND CAN'T YOU SEE ♪
♪ THAT I'M AT THE
START OF A PRETTY BIG DOWNER? ♪
♪ SHA-LA-LA-LA, THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ WHOA, WHOA, WHOA ♪
♪ NO, NO, NO ♪
♪ SHA-LA-LA-LA, THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ THAT AIN'T NO CRIME ♪
♪ SHA-LA-LA! ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
( audience applauding )
( Frank laughing)
Well, now, that's no way
to behave on your first day out.
Well, nobody's perfect.
Audience: YOU ARE!
But I do think you made a pretty
good job of the bodywork.
[ cheers and applause ]
OOH!
[ giggles ]
You are the result of
many hours of toil.
AND WANKING!
[ laughter ]
[ chuckles ]
And now,
my beautiful creature,
you're ready for the ultimate test.
Uh-oh.
heh, heh.
But first, meet the family.
UH, OOH!
Magenta, Rocky.
Hello, Rocky.
[ as Magenta ]
Hello, Magenta.
Oh!
[ giggles ]
Uh, Riff Raff, Rocky.
Hello, Rocky.
[ as Riff Raff ]
HELLO, RIFF RAFF.
Aww!
[ giggles ]
Columbia, Rocky.
Hello, Rocky!
[ as Columbia ]
Hello, Columbia!
A-ha ha!
Well, what do you think?
He is a credit to my -- [gasps]
your genius.
A-a triumph of the will.
He's okay!
[ audience oohs ]
"Okay"?
[ chuckles ]
"Okay."
I think we can do better than that.
Well -- [chuckles]-- uh,
Brad and Janet,
What do you think?
I-- I don't like men with
too many muscles.
JUST ONE BIG ONE!
[ laughter ]
I didn't make him for you, dear.
He carries the Charles Atlas
seal of approval.
[ barking ]
♪
♪ A WEAKLING ♪
BRAD!
[ laughter ]
♪ WEIGHING 98 POUNDS ♪
♪ WILL GET SAND IN HIS FACE ♪
♪ WHEN KICKED TO THE GROUND ♪
♪ SO SOON, IN THE GYM ♪
♪ WITH A DETERMINED CHIN ♪
♪ THE SWEAT FROM HIS PORES ♪
♪ AS HE WORKS FOR HIS CAU-U-U-SE ♪
♪ WILL MAKE HIM GLISTEN ♪
♪ AND GLEAM ♪
♪ AND WITH MASSAGE ♪
♪ AND JUST A LITTLE BIT OF ♪
♪ STE-E-E-E-E-AM ♪
[ CHUCKLES ]
♪ HE'LL BE FIT ♪
♪ AND QUITE LEAN ♪
♪ HE'LL BE A STRONG MAN ♪
♪ OH, HONEY ♪
♪ BUT THE WRONG MAN ♪
♪ HE'LL EAT NUTRITIOUS ♪
♪ HIGH PROTEIN, AND SWALLOW RAW EGGS ♪
♪ TRY TO BUILD UP HIS SHOULDERS ♪
♪ HIS CHEST, ARMS, AND LEGS ♪
♪ SUCH AN EFFORT!
IF HE ONLY KNEW OF MY PLAN ♪
♪ WHEN IN JUST SEVEN DAYS ♪
♪ I CAN MAKE YOU ♪
♪ A MA-A-A-A-A-N ♪
♪ HE'LL DO PRESS-UPS
AND CHIN-UPS ♪
♪ THE SNATCH, CLEAN AND JERK ♪
♪ THAT DYNAMIC TENSION ♪
♪ MUST BE [gags] ♪
♪ MUST BE HARD WORK ♪
♪ SUCH STRENUOUS LIVING,
I JUST DON'T UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ WHEN, IN JUST SEVEN DAYS,
OH, SUGAR ♪
♪ I CAN MAKE YOU ♪
♪ A MA-A-A-A-A-N ♪
Eddie!
-Eddie?
[ screaming ]
♪ WHATEVER HAPPENED TO SATURDAY NIGHT? ♪
♪ WHEN YOU DRESSED UP SHARP
AND YOU FELT ALL RIGHT ♪
♪ IT DON'T SEEM THE SAME SINCE COSMIC LIGHT ♪
♪ CAME INTO MY LIFE,
I THOUGHT I WAS DIVINE ♪
♪ I USED TO GO FOR A RIDE WITH
A CHICK WHO'D GO ♪
♪ AND LISTEN TO THE MUSIC ON THE RADIO ♪
♪ A SAXOPHONE WAS BLOWING
ON A ROCK 'N' ROLL SHOW ♪
♪ CLIMB IN THE BACK ♪
♪ YOU REALLY HAD A GOOD TI-I-I-ME ♪
♪ HOT PATOOTIE, BLESS MY SOUL ♪
♪ I REALLY LOVE THAT ROCK 'N' ROLL ♪
♪ MY HEAD USED TO SWIM FROM
THE PERFUME I SMELT ♪
♪ MY HANDS KIND OF FUMBLED WITH
HER WHITE PLASTIC BELT ♪
♪ I'D TASTE HER BABY PINK LIPSTICK ♪
AND THAT'S WHEN I'D MELT ♪
♪ SHE'D WHISPER IN MY EAR
TONIGHT SHE REALLY WAS MINE ♪
♪ GET BACK IN FRONT
AND PUT SOME HAIR OIL ON ♪
♪ BUDDY HOLLY WAS SINGING
HIS VERY LAST SONG ♪
♪ WITH YOUR ARM AROUND YOUR GIRL
YOU TRY TO SING ALONG ♪
♪ IT FELT PRETTY GOOD, YOU
REALLY HAD A GOOD TI-I-I-ME ♪
♪ HOT PATOOTIE, BLESS MY SOUL ♪
♪ I REALLY LOVE THAT ROCK 'N' ROLL ♪
[ chainsaw starts ]
Whoo!
♪ HOT PATOOTIE, BLESS MY SOUL ♪
♪ I REALLY LOVE THAT ROCK 'N' ROLL ♪
♪ I REALLY LOVE THAT ROCK ‘N’ ROLL ♪
[ cheers and applause  ]
[ Columbia sobbing ]
[ all gasp ]
Shush!
HE'S DEAD, THEN?
[ LAUGHTER ]
One from the vault.
[ laughs ]
Ha, ha-ha, ha, ha.
[ laughter ]
Unh.
Ohh!
Ugh.
[ grunts ]
[ muttering ]
[ grunts frustratedly ]
Ugh!
How could you keep him around?
He's so ugly.
[ all gasp ]
We had a mental relationship.
Oh. he had a certain...
naive charm.
But no muscle.
Oh!
♪ BUT A DELTOID AND A BICEP ♪
♪ OH, OH, OH ♪
♪ A HOT GROIN AND TRICEP ♪
♪ MAKES ME
WHOO-HOO-HOO-HOO-HOO ♪
♪ SHAKE ♪
♪ MAKES ME WANNA TAKE
CHARLES ATLAS ♪
♪ BY THE...HA-A-ND ♪
♪ IN JUST SEVEN DAYS ♪
♪ I CAN MAKE YOU A MA-A-A-A-A-N ♪
♪ I DON'T WANT NO DISSENSION ♪
♪ SENSION, SENSION ♪
♪ JUST DYNAMIC TENSION ♪
♪ TENSION, TENSION ♪
♪ I'M A MUSCLE FA-A-AN ♪
♪ IN JUST SEVEN DAYS ♪
♪ I CAN MAKE YOU A MA-A-A-A-A-N ♪
♪ DIG IT IF YOU CA-A-A-N ♪
♪ IN JUST SEVEN DAYS ♪
♪ I CAN MAKE YOU A MA-A-A-A-A-N ♪
[ Wagner's "WEDDING MARCH" plays... ]
[ cheers and applause ]
[ overture plays... ]
Oh! oh, Brad!
Oh, yes! Yes, my darling!
Oh, what if --
It's all right, Janet.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Oh, I hope so, my darling.
I'm scared.
You?!
I'm afraid so, Janet.
But wasn't it nice?
Oh!
Oh, you beast!
You monster!
What have you done with Brad?
Nothing.
Why, do you think I should?
Oh! You tricked me.
I wouldn't have.
I've never.
Never.
I know.
But it wasn't all bad, was it?
Mm.
Not really even half bad.
In fact, I think perhaps you
found it quite pleasurable.
Mm.
Oh, so soft, so sensual...
Oh! No!
Stop...
[ laughter ]
I mean...help.
I...oh, Brad!
Oh...oh...
Brad!
Shhh! Brad is probably
asleep by now.
Do you want him to see
you like this?
Like this?
Like how?
It's your fault.
You're to blame.
I was saving myself.
Well, i'm sure
you're not spent yet.
And it was an enjoyable
experience, was it not?
Ooh, you did like it,
didn't you?
There's no crime
in giving yourself over
to pleasure, is there?
We could try for an action replay.
Ohh, Janet, you've wasted --
[ gasps ]
so much time already.
Brad needn't know.
I won't tell him.
Are you sure
you won't tell him?
[ laughter ]
[ both moaning ]
Oh, yes! Oh!
[ cheers and applause ]
[ cheers and applause continue ]
There are those who say that
life is an illusion...
Audience: LIFE IS AN ILLUSION!
and that reality as we know it
is merely a figment of
our imaginations.
If this is so, then
Brad and Janet are quite safe.
There are those, however, with
a far more physical philosophy.
Those who would stop at nothing
to satisfy their base desires.
it could be that Brad and Janet
are amongst those
who hold the devil's reins.
[ cheers and applause ]
[ moaning ]
Oh, Brad.
Oh, yes!
Yes, my darling!
[ moans ]
It's all right, Janet.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Oh, I hope so, my darling.
[ gasps ]
You!
I'm afraid so, Brad.
[ laughter ]
But wasn't it nice?
Why, you!
What have you done with Janet?
[ laughter ]
[ cheers and applause ]
Nothing.
Why, do you think
I should?
You tricked me!
I-I wouldn't have.
I've -- I've never -- never!
I know.
But it wasn't all bad, was it?
Mm.
Not really even half bad.
In fact, I think perhaps you
found it quite pleasurable.
Mm.
So soft, so sensual.
[ gasping ] Ohhhh!
Nooo, stop!
Oh, Janet! Janet!
Shhh-sha!
Janet is...
[ laughter ]
Janet i--
Janet is --
[coughing]
[ laughter ]
[ cheers and applause ]
Janet is probably asleep by now.
Do you want her to see you
like this?
[ gasps ]
Like this?!
Like how?
it's your fault!
You're to blame!
I thought it was the real thing.
Oh, come on, Brad.
Admit it.
It was enjoyable, wasn't it?
[ hisseS ]
You liked it, didn't you?
There's no crime in --
[ chuckles ]
[ laughter ]
There's --
[ laughs ]
[ audience oohs ]
There...  there's no crime...
Whoa.
[ laughter ]
in giving yourself
over to pleasure, is there?
We could try for an action replay.
[ gasps ]
Oh, Brad.
You've wasted so much time already.
Janet needn't know.
I won't tell her.
Are you sure
you won't tell her?
[ grunts ]
[ high-pitched scream ]
[ Riff Raff ]:
Master, the laboratory is empty.
Rocky has vanished.
The new playmate is loose
and somewhere in the building.
[ both moaning ]
♪ COMING! ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
Oh!
What's happening here?
Where's Brad?
Where's anybody?
WHOOO!
If only we hadn't made
this journey.
BUT YOU DID!
If only the car hadn't broken down.
BUT IT DID!
If only we were amongst friends.
BUT YOU'RE NOT!
Or sane persons.
WHOO!
[ cheers and applause ]
"IF" and "ONLY,"
two small words...
[ man shouts indistinctly ]
[ laughter and applause ]
Very good.
Throw him out.
[ laughter ]
Words that kept repeating themselves
again and again in Janet's thoughts.
But it was too late
to go back now.
It was as if she were riding
a giant...
COCK!
[ laughter ]
I have "tidal wave," but cock is better.
[ cheers and applause ]
It would be folly to fight against it.
Her only chance would be to ride
it out, adapt, and perhaps...
SWALLOW!
...Survive.
[ laughter ]
Thank you.
[ cheers and applause ]
Oh, It's you!
Look, I'm trying to hide from
my creator and his minion.
They scare me.
I feel all is not well here.
I've been thinking a lot
about...
Sex!
Eddie.
I have a feeling of foreboding.
It's all like some terrible dream.
A WET DREAM!
[ laughter ]
Is it true you don't like men
with too many muscles?
Well, uh,
I'm engaged to Brad.
Just the same as Betty Munroe
was to Ralph Hapschatt.
But Frank's kisses overwhelmed
me with an ecstasy
I'd never dreamed of before.
Hot, burning kisses.
I could see Brad's face
before me,
and my mind screamed no,
but my lips were hungry.
[ laughter ]
Too hungry.
I wanted to be loved,
and loved completely.
My body throbbed excitedly.
Oh, Brad.
Brad, my darling, how could
I have done this to you?
This room is a womb to me.
A WOMB WITH A VIEW!
[ laughter ]
Yes. there, you see?
It's instinctive.
You returned here for one thing
and one thing only.
SEX!
Security.
Oh, where's Brad?
What have they done with him?
[ blips ]
Janet's feelings ran wild...
[ cheers and applause ]
as she frantically manipulated
the selector switch on
the TV monitor.
The screens threw up images
of empty rooms and corridors.
Finally, she stopped --
at Frank's bedroom.
Oh!
You can't rely on anyone.
Oh, Brad!
How could you?!
Tell us about it, Janet.
♪ I WAS FEELING DONE IN ♪
♪ COULDN'T WIN ♪
♪ I'D ONLY EVER KISSED BEFORE ♪
YOU MEAN SHE'S A --
UH-HUH.
♪ I THOUGHT
THERE'S NO USE GETTING ♪
♪ INTO HEAVY PETTING ♪
♪ IT ONLY LEADS TO TROUBLE ♪
♪ AND SEAT WETTING ♪
♪ NOW ALL I WANT TO KNOW ♪
♪ IS HOW TO GO ♪
♪ I'VE TASTED BLOOD
AND I WANT MORE ♪
♪ MORE, MORE, MORE ♪
♪ I'LL PUT UP NO RESISTANCE ♪
♪ I WANT TO STAY THE DISTANCE ♪
♪ I'VE GOT AN ITCH TO SCRATCH ♪
♪ I NEED ASSISTANCE ♪
♪ TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH ME ♪
♪ I WANT TO BE DIRTY ♪
♪ THRILL ME, CHILL ME, FULFILL ME ♪
♪ CREATURE OF THE NIGHT ♪
♪ THEN IF ANYTHING GROWS ♪
♪ WHEN YOU POSE ♪
♪ I'LL OIL YOU UP
AND RUB YOU DOWN ♪
♪ DOWN, DOWN, DOWN ♪
♪ AND THAT'S
JUST ONE SMALL FRACTION ♪
♪ OF THE MAIN ATTRACTION ♪
♪ YOU NEED A FRIENDLY HAND ♪
♪ AND I NEED ACTION ♪
♪ TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH ME ♪
♪ I WANT TO BE DIRTY ♪
♪ THRILL ME, CHILL ME, FULFILL ME ♪
♪ CREATURE OF THE NIGHT ♪
♪ TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH ME ♪
♪ I WANT TO BE DIRTY ♪
♪ THRILL ME, CHILL ME, FULFILL ME ♪
♪ CREATURE OF THE NIGHT ♪
♪ TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH-A, TOUCH ME ♪
♪ I WANT TO BE DIRTY ♪
♪ THRILL ME, CHILL ME, FULFILL ME ♪
♪ CREATURE OF THE NIGHT ♪
♪   CREATURE  OF  THE  NIGHT   ♪
♪   CREATURE  OF  THE  NIGHT!   ♪
[ both cackle ]
[ cheers and applause ]
[ whip cracks ]
Aah!
[ gasping ]
OOH!
[ whip cracks ]  Mercy!
How did it happen?
[ whip cracks ]
Ooh!
I understood you were
to be watching!
I was only away for a moment.
[ grunts, whip cracks ]
Well, see if you can find him
on the monitor!
Very well.
[ gasps ]
I've located him...
Mm?
in the female's quarters.
Master!
Oh, Rocky. Rocky!
Rocky!
[ laughter ]
Oh, Janet.
[ gasps ]
Janet!
[ gasping ]
How could she?!
That's it...
It's over!
Over?
What was over?
[ cheers and applause ]
My career, yes.
Actually, um,
y-you're kind of right.
It was pretty much
dead in the water.
until I discovered...
MINECRAFT!
Thank you.
[ cheers and applause ]
It's got a lovely rise, actually.
It's got a lovely rise.
And a great...
SOGGY BOTTOM!
Show us -- yes, my bottom
is extremely soggy, sir.
I'm so sorry.
[ cheers and applause ]
[ cheering ]
PIECE OF CAKE!
[ muffled ]
Not the --
[laughs]
That was such a bad mistake.
[ laughter ]
Not the night,
that was certain --
Sorry about the front row.
You're getting a lot of
red velvet.
Just spat.   I'm sorry.
Brad and Janet's engagement?
Their love for one another?
Who -- sorry.
[ laughter ]
Oh, it's a very rich icing
that's going down the throat, there.
Very rich icing.
Let's -- let's get back.
Let's get back.
Their love for one another?
Who could say?
Too perky!
For questions such as these...
[ laughter ]
are not to be answered by
the academic;
they must be left
for the heart to solve.
And Brad, you may be sure,
had plenty of heart.
[ cheers and applause ]
♪ ONCE IN A WHILE ♪
♪ SHE DON'T WANT TO CALL YOU ♪
♪ SPEAKING ON THE TELEPHONE ♪
♪ AND ONCE IN YOUR LIFE ♪
♪ SHE WON'T WANT TO KNOW YOU ♪
♪ YOU LOOK AROUND ♪
♪ THE ONE YOU'VE FOUND ♪
♪ SHE IS GONE ♪
♪ AND THAT'S ALL THE TIME ♪
♪ THAT IT TAKES ♪
♪ FOR A HEART
TO TURN TO STONE ♪
♪ THE SWEETER THE WINE ♪
♪ THE HARDER TO MAKE THE BREAK ♪
♪ YOU HEAR SOMETHING ♪
♪ ABOUT SOMEONE
YOU THOUGHT YOU'D KNOWN ♪
♪ SO, BABY DON'T CRY ♪
♪ LIKE THERE'S NO TOMORROW ♪
♪ AFTER THE NIGHT
THERE'S A BRAND-NEW DAY ♪
♪ AND THERE'LL BE NO PAIN ♪
♪ AND NO MORE SORROW ♪
♪ SO WASH YOUR FACE ♪
♪ AND PHONE MY PLACE ♪
♪ IT'LL BE OKAY ♪
♪ AND THAT'S ALL THE TIME ♪
♪ THAT IT TAKES ♪
♪ FOR A HEART TO BEAT AGAIN ♪
♪ SO GIVE ME A SIGN ♪
♪ THAT A LOVER MAKES ♪
♪ YOU LOOK AROUND ♪
♪ THE ONE YOU'VE FOUND ♪
♪ IS BACK AGAIN ♪
♪  IS  BACK  AGAIN  ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
How maudlin.
How pathetic.
Your baggage has dared to
defile my beautiful creature.
Oh, Rocky, how could you?
Master!
We have a visitor!
Ooh!
[ blips ]
[ gasps ]
Great Scott, Scottie!
Dr. Everett Scott!
SIEG HEIL!
You know this Earthling?
Gah!
[ whip cracks ]
I mean, "person."
Why, yes, I do.
He's an old friend of mine.
I see.
So, this wasn't simply a chance
meeting after all.
You came here with a purpose.
That's not true.
My car broke down.
I told you.
I know what you told me, Brad.
But this Dr. Everett Scott,
His name is not unknown to me.
Well, he was a science teacher
at Denton High.
And now he works for your
government, doesn't he, Brad?
He's attached to the bureau of
the investigation
of that which you call
U.F.O.s!
That's right, isn't it, Brad?
Well, he might be.
I don't know.
OOH...
[ BLIPS ]
The intruder's
entered the building, Master.
[ EASTERN STRING MUSIC plays ]
Ah, he's in the zen room.
[ laughter ]
Seal off all exits and all doors
except for those that lead here.
Riff Raff, bring Rocky and Janet.
I think we should make this
a social occasion.
The three unexpected guests
shall entertain us with
a floor show,
which I shall direct.
[ whip cracks ]
[ JAZZ MUSIC plays ]
Dr. Scott!
Brad!
What are you doing here?
Don't play games, Dr. Scott.
It was part of your plan,
was it not?
That Brad Majors and his female
should check the layout for you?
Heh!    Unfortunately for you all,
there is to be a change of plan.
I'm sure you're adaptable,
Dr. Scott.
I know Brad is.
I can assure you that
Brad's presence
comes as a
complete surprise to me.
As does this setup you have here.
I didn't expect it to
be quite so...
Sophisticated, Dr. Scott...
or should i say
Dr. von Scott?
[ German accent ]
They never proved nothing!
What exactly are you implying?
That's all right, Brad.
Ah, what exotic container
you have there?
What do you think it is, Doc?
[bleep].
At this precise moment,
it's hard to tell.
But it seems to be made of a
metal that is not of this earth.
I would say it came from
another...
IKEA!
...planet!
[ all gasp ]
Brad!
Janet!
Rocky!
Dr. Scott?
Brad!
Janet!
Rocky!
Dr. Scott?
Brad!
Janet!
Rocky!
Dr. Scott?
Piss off!
[ laughter and applause ]
Listen, you -- I made you, and I
can break you just as easily.
I'll pull your plug out.
I suppose you intend to do
with us as you did with Eddie?
Eddie?!
Shh!
Eddie! I've seen him.
He looked terrible.
Uh, what do you know of Eddie,
Dr. Scott?
I happen to know a great deal
about a lot of things.
You see, Eddie happened to be
my nephew!
[ all gasp ]
Dr. Scott!
Yes, Brad.
My sister's son.
I knew he was in with
a bad crowd,
but it was
worse than I imagined!
MUTANTS!
Aliens!
[ all gasp ]
Aliens?!
Tell 'em, Doc.
♪ FROM THE DAY HE WAS BORN ♪
♪ HE WAS TROUBLE ♪
♪ OOH, AHH ♪
♪ HE WAS THE THORN ♪
♪ IN HIS MOTHER'S SIDE ♪
♪ OOH, AHH ♪
♪ SHE TRIED IN VAIN... ♪
♪ OOH, OOH, OOH ♪
♪ BUT HE NEVER CAUSED HER
NOTHING BUT PAIN ♪
♪ HE LEFT HOME THE DAY SHE DIED ♪
Eins, zwei, drei!
♪ FROM THE DAY SHE WAS GONE ♪
♪ ALL HE WANTED ♪
♪ WAS ROCK-'N'-ROLL, PORN ♪
♪ AND A MOTORBIKE ♪
[ all ]: VROOM! VROOM!
♪ SHOOTING UP JUNK ♪
♪ HE WAS A LOWDOWN,
CHEAP LITTLE PUNK ♪
♪ TAKING EVERYONE FOR A RIDE ♪
♪ WHEN EDDIE SAID HE DIDN'T
LIKE HIS TEDDY ♪
♪ YOU KNEW HE WAS
A NO-GOOD KID ♪
♪ BUT WHEN HE THREATENED YOUR
LIFE WITH A SWITCHBLADE KNIFE ♪
♪ WHAT A GUY ♪
♪ MAKES YOU CRY ♪
♪ AND I DID ♪
♪ EVERYBODY SHOVED HIM ♪
♪ I VERY NEARLY LOVED HIM ♪
♪ I SAID,
"HEY, LISTEN TO ME ♪
♪ STAY SANE INSIDE INSANITY" ♪
♪ BUT HE LOCKED THE DOOR
AND THREW AWAY THE KEY ♪
♪ BUT HE MUST HAVE BEEN DRAWN ♪
♪ INTO SOMETHING ♪
♪ MAKING HIM WARN ME
IN A NOTE WHICH READS... ♪
[ all ]: ♪ WHAT'S IT SAY?! WHAT'S IT SAY?! ♪
♪ "I'M OUT OF MY HEAD, ♪
♪ "HURRY, OR I MAY BE DEAD ♪
♪ THEY MUSTN'T CARRY OUT
THEIR EVIL DEEDS!" ♪
♪ WHEN EDDIE SAID HE DIDN'T
LIKE HIS TEDDY ♪
♪ YOU KNEW HE WAS
A NO-GOOD KID ♪
♪ BUT WHEN HE THREATENED YOUR
LIFE WITH A SWITCHBLADE KNIFE ♪
♪ WHAT A GUY ♪
♪ MAKES YOU CRY ♪
♪ AND I DID ♪
♪ WHEN EDDIE SAID HE DIDN'T
LIKE HIS TEDDY ♪
♪ YOU KNEW HE WAS A NO-GOOD KID ♪
♪ BUT WHEN HE THREATENED YOUR
LIFE WITH A SWITCHBLADE KNIFE ♪
♪ WHAT A GUY ♪
♪ MAKES YOU CRY ♪
♪ AND I DID ♪
♪ WHOA, WHOA, WHOA ♪
♪ WHAT A GUY ♪
♪ MAKES YOU CRY ♪
♪ AND I DID ♪
♪ HEY, HEY, HEY ♪
♪ WHAT A GUY ♪
♪ MAKES YOU CRY ♪
♪ AND I DID ♪
♪ YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ WHAT A GU-U-UY ♪
♪ MAKES YOU CRY-Y-Y ♪
[ glass shatters ]
[ laughter ]
♪ AND I DID ♪
♪ AND HE DID, YES, HE DID ♪
♪ EDDIE ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
Say a prayer for Eddie.
I just defrosted him.
[ giggles ]
His destiny is in the bag.
[ gasps ]
Waah!
Aah!
Piss off!
[ cheers and applause ]
I'll put him down the
waste disposal.
Clever girl.
Why, you --
[ warbles ]
There.
That should restrain you all.
My feet!
I can't move my feet!
My wheels! My God,
I can't move my wheels!
It's as if we were glued
to the spot.
You are!
so quake with fear
you tiny fools, okay?
It's star time!
Riff Raff, set the sonic
transducer on program eight.
Secure all levels at zero.
You won't find Earth people
quite the easy mark you imagine!
This sonic ‘transjuicer’, it is,
I suppose, some type of
audio-vibratory physio-molecular
transport device.
You better believe it, Baby.
What? You mean he's gonna send
us to another planet?
Planet, shmanet, Janet.
♪ I'LL TELL YOU ONCE,
I WON'T TELL YOU TWICE ♪
♪ YOU'D BETTER WISE UP,
JANET WEISS ♪
♪ YOUR APPLE PIE
DON'T TASTE TOO NICE ♪
♪ YOU'D BETTER WISE UP,
JANET WEISS ♪
UNH!
♪ I'VE LAID THE SEED ♪
♪ IT SHOULD BE ALL YOU NEED ♪
♪ YOU'RE AS SENSUAL
AS A PENCIL ♪
♪ WOUND UP LIKE
AN "E" ON FIRST STRING ♪
♪ WHEN WE MADE IT,
DID YOU HEAR A BELL RING? ♪
♪ YOU GOT A BLOCK?
TAKE MY ADVICE ♪
♪ YOU'D BETTER WISE UP,
JANET WEISS ♪
♪ THE TRANSDUCER
WILL SEDUCE YA ♪
♪ IT'S SOMETHING
YOU'LL GET USED TO ♪
♪ A MENTAL MIND-[BLEEP]
CAN BE NICE ♪
♪ YOU'D BETTER WISE UP,
JANET WEISS ♪
♪ YOU'D BETTER WISE UP ♪
♪ BUILD YOUR THIGHS UP ♪
ST-O-O-OP!
♪ DON'T GET
HOT AND FLUSTERED ♪
♪ USE A BIT OF MUSTARD ♪
[ all ]: ♪ YOU'RE A HOT DOG ♪
♪ BUT YOU BETTER NOT
TRY TO HURT HER ♪
♪ FRANK FURTER ♪
♪ YOU'RE A HOT DOG ♪
♪ BUT YOU'D BETTER NOT
TRY TO HURT HER ♪
♪ FRANK FURTER ♪
♪ YOU'RE A HOT DOG ♪
♪ BUT YOU'D BETTER NOT
TRY TO HURT HER ♪
♪ FRANK FURTER ♪
♪ YOU'RE A HOT DOG ♪
♪ BUT YOU'D BETTER NOT
TRY TO HURT HER ♪
♪ FRANK FURTER ♪
[Solo]
♪ YOU'RE A HOT DOG ♪
♪ BUT YOU BETTER -- ♪
Magenta.
♪ NOT TRY TO HURT HER ♪
♪ FRANK FURTER ♪
♪ YOU'RE A HOT DOG ♪
Magenta!
[ cheers and applause ]
[ chuckles softly ]
Relax.
Columbia, the artistes are in
a molecular state
somewhere between entrance and exit.
When they have
pulled themselves together,
see to it that they are prepared
for the floor show.
My God!
I can't take any more of this.
First you ditch me for Eddie,
and then you throw him off
like an old overcoat for Rocky!
You chew people up, and then you
spit them out again.
I loved you!
Do you hear?
I loved you.
and what did I get?
[ scoffs ]
[ laughter ]
I'll tell you.
A big fat nothing!
You're like a sponge --
you take, take, take,
and drain others of their affections.
Well, I've had it!
Ah!
I'm out of here.
[ laughs ]
and I mean --
[ hisses ]
Whoa!
Do that again.
[ hisses ]
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Oh, I dig that!
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho!
It's wicked!
Oooh!
[ squealing ]
Rowr!
Oh, it's a gas!
It's a gas, it's a gas, it's a
gas, it's a gas, it's a gas!
Mmmm!
OH!
[ laughs ]
I'm groovy.
Oh, I am hip, man!
Pow!
Pa-pow! Pa-pow! Pa-pow!
[ cheers and applause ]
Ohhh.
It's like a trip.
Ohhh, freak out!
Baby!
Pbht!
Dig ya later!
[ cheers and applause ]
It's not easy
having a good time.
Even smiling
makes my face ache.
And my children --
my children turn on me.
Rocky is behaving just as
Eddie did.
Ugh.
Maybe I made a mistake,
splitting the one brain between
the two of them.
[ Transylvanian accent ]
When will we return to Transylvania?
I grow weary of this world.
[ Transylvanian accent ]
Magenta...
I am indeed...
...grateful...
to both you
and your brother, Riff Raff.
You have both served me well.
Loyalty such as yours...
must be rewarded.
And you will discover that,
when the mood takes me,
I can be quite generous.
I ask for nothing!
[ laughs ]
[ mockingly ] Master.
And you shall receive it...
in abundance!
[ growls ]
Mmmmmm!
Ohhhh!
[ Riff Raff  laughing ]
[ cheers and applause ]
And so,
by some extraordinary
coincidence,
fate, it seems, had decided that
Brad and Janet
should keep their appointment
with their friend, Dr. Everett Scott.
SIEG HEIL!
Gesundheit.
But it was to be in a situation
which none of them
could possibly have foreseen.
And just a few hours after
announcing their engagement,
Brad and Janet
had both tasted...
FRANK'S COCK!
I'm sure it would rattle
in your mouth, dear.
...forbidden fruit.
This in itself was proof that
their host was a man of little morals
and some persuasion.
What further indignities were
they to be subjected to?
[ man shouts indistinctly ]
[ laughs derisively ]
[ laughter and applause ]
And what of
the sonic transducer?
And the floor show
that had been spoken of?
What indeed?
From what had gone before,
it was clear that this was
to be...
A PICNIC?
I forgot my thermals.
...no picnic.
[ cheers and applause ]
[ playing opening of  "ROSE TINT MY WORLD"  ]
♪ IT WAS GREAT WHEN IT ALL BEGAN ♪
♪ I WAS A REGULAR FRANKIE FAN ♪
♪ BUT IT WAS OVER
WHEN HE HAD THE PLAN ♪
♪ TO START WORKING ON
A MUSCLE MAN ♪
♪ NOW THE ONLY THING
THAT GIVES ME HOPE ♪
♪ IS MY LOVE OF A CERTAIN DOPE ♪
♪ ROSE TINT MY WORLD ♪
♪ KEEP ME SAFE
FROM MY TROUBLE AND PAIN ♪
♪ I AM JUST SEVEN HOURS OLD ♪
♪ TRULY BEAUTIFUL TO BEHOLD ♪
♪ AND SOMEBODY SHOULD BE TOLD ♪
♪ MY LIBIDO
HASN'T BEEN CONTROLLED ♪
♪ NOW THE ONLY THING
I'VE COME TO TRUST ♪
♪ IS AN ORGASMIC RUSH OF LUST ♪
♪ ROSE TINT MY WORLD ♪
♪ KEEP ME SAFE FROM MY TROUBLE AND PAIN ♪
♪ IT'S BEYOND ME ♪
♪ HELP  ME, MOMMY ♪
♪ I'LL BE GOOD -- YOU'LL SEE ♪
♪ TAKE THIS DREAM AWAY ♪
♪ WHAT'S THIS? ♪
♪ LET'S SEE ♪
♪ I FEEL SEXY ♪
♪ WHAT'S COME OVER ME? ♪
♪ HERE IT COMES AGAIN ♪
♪ OH, I FEEL RELEASED ♪
♪ BAD TIMES DECEASED ♪
♪ MY CONFIDENCE HAS INCREASED ♪
♪ REALITY IS HERE ♪
♪ THE GAME HAS BEEN DISBANDED ♪
♪ MY MIND HAS BEEN EXPANDED ♪
♪ IT'S A GAS THAT FRANKIE'S LANDED! ♪
♪ HIS LUST IS SO SINCERE ♪
[ fanfare plays  ]
♪ AHH ♪
♪ AHH, AH-AH AHH,
AH-AH AHH ♪
♪ OHHHH ♪
♪ AHHH ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
♪ WHATEVER HAPPENED ♪
♪ TO FAY WRAY? ♪
♪ THAT DELICATE ♪
♪ SATIN-DRAPED FRAME? ♪
♪ AS IT CLUNG TO HER THIGH ♪
♪ HOW I STARTED TO CRY ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I WANTED TO BE DRESSED ♪
♪ JUST THE SAME ♪
♪ GIVE YOURSELF OVER ♪
♪ TO ABSOLUTE PLEASURE ♪
♪ SWIM THE WARM WATERS ♪
♪ OF SINS OF THE FLESH ♪
♪ EROTIC NIGHTMARES ♪
♪ BEYOND ANY MEASURE ♪
♪ AND SENSUAL DAYDREAMS ♪
♪ TO TREASURE FOREVER ♪
♪ CAN'T YOU JUST SEE IT? ♪
♪ WHOA-HO-HO! ♪
♪ DON'T DREAM IT ♪
♪ BE IT ♪
[ chorus and Frankie together]:
♪ DON'T DREAM IT ♪
♪ BE IT ♪
[ Frank laughs ]
♪ DON'T DREAM IT ♪
♪ BE IT... ♪
We've got to get
out of this trap,
before this decadence
saps our wills!
I've got to be strong,
and try to hang on,
or my mind may well snap!
and my life will be lived...
♪ FOR THE THRILLS! ♪
♪ DON'T DREAM IT ♪
♪ BE IT ♪
♪ IT'S BEYOND ME ♪
♪ HELP ME, MOMMY ♪
♪ GOD BLESS LILI SAINT CYR ♪
♪ MY, MY, MY,
M-M-MY, MY, MY ♪
♪ MY, MY, MY, MY...MY! ♪
♪ I'M A WILD
AND AN UNTAMED THING ♪
♪ I'M A BEE
WITH A DEADLY STING ♪
♪ YOU GET A HIT,
AND YOUR MIND GOES PING ♪
♪ YOUR HEART'LL THUMP,
AND YOUR BLOOD WILL SING ♪
♪ SO LET THE PARTY
AND THE SOUNDS ROCK ON ♪
♪ WE'RE GONNA SHAKE IT TILL
THE LIFE HAS GONE, GONE, GONE ♪
♪ ROSE TINT MY WORLD, KEEP ME
SAFE FROM MY TROUBLE AND PAIN ♪
♪ WE'RE A WILD
AND AN UNTAMED THING ♪
♪ WE'RE A BEE
WITH A DEADLY STING ♪
♪ YOU GET A HIT,
AND YOUR MIND GOES PING ♪
♪ YOUR HEART'LL THUMP,
AND YOUR BLOOD WILL SING ♪
♪ SO LET THE PARTY
AND THE SOUNDS ROCK ON ♪
♪ WE'RE GONNA SHAKE IT
TILL THE LIFE HAS GONE ♪
♪ ROSE TINT MY WORLD, KEEP ME
SAFE FROM MY TROUBLE AND PAIN ♪
♪ WE'RE A WILD
AND AN UNTAMED THING ♪
♪ WE'RE A BEE
WITH A DEADLY STING ♪
♪ YOU GET A HIT,
AND YOUR MIND GOES PING ♪
♪ YOUR HEART'LL THUMP,
AND YOUR BLOOD WILL SING ♪
♪ SO LET THE PARTY
AND THE SOUNDS ROCK ON ♪
♪ WE'RE GONNA SHAKE IT TILL
THE LIFE HAS GONE ♪
♪ ROSE TINT MY WORLD, KEEP ME
SAFE FROM MY TROUBLE AND PAIN ♪
♪ FRANK-N-FURTER, IT'S ALL OVER ♪
♪ YOUR MISSION IS A FAILURE ♪
♪ YOUR LIFESTYLE'S TOO EXTREME ♪
♪ I'M YOUR NEW COMMANDER ♪
♪ YOU NOW ARE MY PRISONER ♪
♪ WE RETURN TO TRANSYLVANIA ♪
♪ PREPARE THE TRANSIT BEAM ♪
Wait!
[ breathing heavily ]
I can explain.
[ tenuous piano notes ]
[ saxophone plays ]
♪ ON THE DAY I WENT AWAY ♪
♪ GOODBYE ♪
♪ WAS ALL I HAD TO SAY ♪
♪ NOW I ♪
♪ I WANT TO COME AGAIN AND STAY ♪
♪ OH, MY, MY ♪
♪ SMILE AND THAT WILL MEAN
I MA-A-AY ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE SEEN BLUE SKIES ♪
♪ THROUGH THE TEARS ♪
♪ IN MY EYES ♪
♪ AND I REALIZE ♪
♪ I'M GOING HOME ♪
[ chorus ]: ♪ I'M GOING HOME ♪
♪ EVERYWHERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN THE SAME ♪
♪ FEELING ♪
♪ LIKE I'M OUTSIDE IN THE RAIN ♪
♪ WHEELING ♪
♪ FREE TO TRY AND FIND THE GAME ♪
♪ DEALING ♪
♪ CARDS FOR SORROW,
CARDS FOR PAIN ♪
♪ OH ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE SEEN BLUE SKIES ♪
♪ THROUGH THE TEARS ♪
♪ IN MY EYES ♪
♪ AND I REALIZE ♪
♪ I'M GOING HOME ♪
♪ I'M GOING ♪
♪ HOME ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
[ cheers and applause continue ]
How sentimental.
and also presumptuous of you.
You see, when I said "we"
were to return,
I referred only to Magenta
and myself.
I'm sorry, however, if you
found my words misleading,
you see,
you are to remain here...
in spirit, anyway.
[ all gasp ]
Good God, that's a laser!
Yes, Dr. Scott.
A laser capable of emitting
a beam of pure antimatter.
[ Brad ]: Wha-- you mean you're
going to kill him?
You saw what became of Eddie.
Society must be protected.
Exactly, Dr. Scott.
Now, Frank-N-Furter,
your time has come.
Say goodbye to all this...
and hello to oblivion!
[ woman in audience shouting ]
Do your worst.
Do your worst, inferior one!
No! No!
Aah!
No!
[ crying ] No...
No...
[ crying ]
Yes.
[ laughs ]
Get away from me!
Aah ha ha ha ha!
[ laughs ]
Help me!
Somebody!
[ laser fires ]
[ all vocalizing ]
[ screams ]
[ laser fires ]
[ vocalizing continues ]
I thought you liked them.
They liked you.
They didn't like me.
They never liked me!
You saw the way things were,
the way they were going.
You did right.
You should leave now, Dr. Scott,
while it's still possible.
We're about to beam
the entire house
back to the planet of Transsexual
in the galaxy of Transylvania.
Go now.
Our noble mission
is almost complete,
my most beautiful sister.
And soon we shall return
to the moon-drenched shores
of our beloved planet.
Ahh, sweet Transsexual,
land of night.
To sing and dance once more
to your dark refrain.
Activate the transit crystal.
[ warbling, electricity crackling ]
Five, four, three, two, one.
♪ AHH, AHH, AHH, AHH ♪
♪ AHH, AHH ♪
[ vocalizing continues ]
[ piano solo plays ]
♪ I'VE DONE A LOT ♪
♪ GOD KNOWS I'VE TRIED ♪
♪ TO FIND THE TRUTH ♪
♪ I'VE EVEN LIED ♪
♪ BUT ALL I KNOW ♪
♪ IS DOWN INSIDE I'M ♪
♪ BLEEDING ♪
♪ AND SUPERHEROES ♪
♪ COME TO FEAST ♪
♪ TO TASTE THE FLESH
NOT YET DECEASED ♪
♪ AND ALL I KNOW ♪
♪ IS STILL THE BEAST IS ♪
♪ FEEDING ♪
[ guitar solo ]
[ chorus vocalizing ]
[ cheers and applause ]
♪ AND CRAWLING ON ♪
♪ THE PLANET'S FACE ♪
♪ SOME INSECTS CALLED
THE HUMAN RACE ♪
♪ LOST IN TIME, AND LOST IN SPACE ♪
♪ AND MEANING ♪
[ chorus ]: ♪ MEANING ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
♪ SCIENCE FICTION ♪
♪ DOUBLE FEATURE ♪
♪ FRANK HAS BUILT AND ♪
♪ LOST HIS CREATURE ♪
♪ DARKNESS HAS CONQUERED ♪
♪ BRAD AND JANET ♪
♪ THE SERVANTS GONE TO ♪
♪ A DISTANT PLANET ♪
♪ WHOA-OH-OH, OH-OH ♪
♪ AT THE LATE NIGHT ♪
♪ DOUBLE FEATURE ♪
♪ PICTURE SHOW ♪
♪ I WANNA GO ♪
♪ WHOA-OH ♪
♪ TO THE LATE NIGHT ♪
♪ DOUBLE FEATURE ♪
♪ PICTURE SHOW ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
[ cheers and applause continue ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
Richard O'Brien!
[ cheers and applause ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
DAVID BEDELLA!
[ cheers and applause ]
Shall we?
Okay, everybody,
let's do THE TIME WARP again!
Hit it!
[ INTRO TO "THE TIME WARP" PLAYS ]
♪ IT'S ASTOUNDING ♪
♪ TIME IS FLEETING ♪
♪ MADNESS TAKES ITS TOLL ♪
♪ BUT LISTEN CLOSELY ♪
♪ NOT FOR VERY MUCH LONGER ♪
♪ I'VE GOT TO
KEEP CONTROL ♪
Go, Go!
♪ I REMEMBER ♪
♪ DOING THE TIME WARP ♪
♪ DRINKING THOSE MOMENTS WHEN ♪
♪ THE BLACKNESS WOULD HIT ME ♪
♪ AND THE VOID WOULD BE CALLING ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
It's just a jump to the left...
♪ AND THEN A STEP TO THE RI-I-I-I-GHT ♪
with your hands on your hips...
♪ YOU BRING YOUR KNEES IN TIGHT ♪
♪ BUT IT'S THE PELVIC THRUST ♪
♪ THAT REALLY DRIVES YOU
INSA-A-A-A-A-NE ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
It's just a jump to the left...
♪ AND THEN A STEP
TO THE RI-I-I-I-GHT ♪
with your hands on your hips...
♪ YOU BRING YOUR KNEES IN TIGHT ♪
♪ BUT IT'S THE PELVIC THRUST ♪
♪ THAT REALLY DRIVES YOU
INSA-A-A-A-A-NE ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
[ intro to "SWEET TRANSVESTITE" plays ]
♪ HOW D'YOU DO?   I... ♪
♪ SEE YOU'VE MET MY ♪
♪ FAITHFUL HANDYMAN ♪
♪ HE'S A LITTLE
BROUGHT DOWN BECAUSE ♪
♪ WHEN YOU KNOCKED ♪
♪ HE THOUGHT YOU WERE THE
CANDY MAN ♪
Didn't you, Freaky?
♪ DON'T GET STRUNG OUT ♪
♪ BY THE WAY I LOOK ♪
♪ DON'T JUDGE A BOOK BY ITS COVER ♪
♪ I'M NOT MUCH OF A MAN ♪
♪ BY THE LIGHT OF DAY ♪
♪ BUT BY NIGHT,
I'M ONE HELL OF A LOVER ♪
♪ I'M JUST A SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ SWEET TRANSVESTITE ♪
♪ FROM TRANSSEXUAL ♪
♪ TRANSYLVANIA ♪
♪ UH-HUH ♪
[ cheers and applause ]
Ladies and gentlemen, our guest
narrators for the evening:
[ cheers and applause ]
Anthony Head.
Emma Bunton.
[ cheers and applause ]
Ade Edmondson.
And the lovely Mel Giedroyc.
[ cheers and applause ]
[ laughs ]
Richard, shall we?
Oh, yes. Why not?
One more time?
We're here, anyway.
One more time.
Yes, go on then.
[ laughs ]
Hit it!
[ drum beats ]
It's just a jump to the left...
♪ AND THEN A STEP
TO THE RI-I-I-I-GHT ♪
with your hands on your hips...
♪ YOU BRING YOUR KNEES IN TIGHT ♪
♪ BUT IT'S THE PELVIC THRUST ♪
♪ THAT REALLY DRIVES YOU
INSA-A-A-A-A-NE ♪
♪ LET'S DO THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
♪ LET'S DO
THE TIME WARP AGAIN ♪
Whooo!
[ cheers and applause ]
[ chuckles ]
Thank you very much.
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
Thank you for joining us
all over Europe
and all over Great Britain.
Shall we?
Good night, you all!
[ "TIME WARP" plays ]
[ cheers and applause ]
[ "TIME WARP" continues ]
[ band finishes, cheers and applause ]