MAN: A great pally once said,
"Christmas is a day that holds
all time together."
I never really
believed it before now.
People take from Christmas
their memories of
happy times and sad,
past, present and future.
A moment on this one,
special day
could forever change
how you see everything.
BOY: Dear, Santa...
♪ I have a secret Christmas wish
♪ I know you know it well
♪ It's something that
I want so much
♪ I cannot even tell
♪ If I believe
with all my heart
♪ I know it can come true
♪ But if that never happens
♪ Still I'll always
believe in you ♪
MAN: Sweet, eh?
We'll get to that kid later.
For me, my memories of Christmas
will never be quite the same again.
All I wanted to be
was something else.
Something better
than I thought! was.
This is my story.
And it's all true.
- My name is Bernard.
(SNORING)
And I'm an elf.
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROANS, MUTTERING)
(SIGHS)
Oh, no!
Mint chocolate cookies,
I slept in!
Not today, not today!
Oh, where the blinking...?
Ah, there you are.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(GASPS) No pants!
Wait! Wait up!
(TRAIN WHISTLING)
Wait up!
Hold the train!
Oh! (GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Huh?
(EXCLAIMS)
(ALL GASP)
Ah! Thanks!
Merry Christmas!
Excuse me, sorry!
Excuse me, coming through!
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Oh, sorry!
Morning, Blitz!
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Still no sign of the
North Pole, Mr. Baddington.
(GROWLING) Where are you, fat man?
(ALL GASP)
What are you staring at?
Do something useful
and get my mother on the com.
(DOOR SLAMS)
There will be no need for that.
Mother, what a
delightful surprise.
You look even more
radiant than ever.
Luminous and brilliant,
like a... a...
newly-bloomed rose,
shimmering with dew
in the morning...
That's enough bottom-snogging
from you, boy.
This is hardly a pleasure trip.
Need I remind you that you have
a shipping empire to run?
Since you have taken the
Quickest Airborne Delivery,
the only thing you have
managed to deliver is failure.
Of course. It's still marvelous
to finally have you here.
Put a sock in it!
Christmas Eve is the busiest
day of the year for us,
and here you are, chasing
a mystical, flying elf!
I'm here for the presentation.
- Name.
- Bernard D. Elf.
- You're late!
- I know, I'm sorry.
My alarm clock was broken
and I forgot my pants.
(GASPS)
Yeah, I'm wearing them now.
- Down the hall, back...
- Thanks!
You're out of time.
And voila!
With my electrified
chipmunk decoy,
unwanted Christmas tree guests
will be a thing of the past.
One little nuzzle
of the nose, and he'll...
Good morning, everyone!
(YELPING)
Uh... Oops.
Uh, sorry I'm a bit late.
I'm sorry, Bernard, but
you've missed your time slot.
- Missed your time slot.
- Please?
I've been working all year on
this invention. It's my best yet!
Better than the mind eraser
invention from last year?
Santa sightings, unavoidable, right?
Maybe.
But what if we could erase them forever?
(GASPING)
Let's imagine that this
toy doll is a little girl
who's just seen Santa.
Now, one quick zap...
(ALL YELLING)
Who are you and why are you wearing
that ridiculous elf costume?
- Hey, I'm wearing one, too.
- Me, too.
- We're all wearing them.
- Where are we?
WOMAN: Some kind of
Christmas nightmare.
WOMAN 2: What is Christmas?
- It took us months to recover.
- Months to recover.
Poor Nutmeg still can't
remember his own name sometimes.
Isn't that right, Nutmeg?
- See?
BERNARD: - Please!
I've worked on this
all year long.
MAN: - No.
WOMAN: - Say no. Say no.
MAN 2: - Don't do it.
- You've got one minute.
Thank you.
(ALL GROANING)
(CLEARS THROAT) Ask yourselves,
what is the one thing Santa
can't fit into his bag?
The answer, of course, is...
...memories!
Christmas memories, to be exact.
Every year, millions are created,
but where do they go?
The get lost in our brains.
And my machine locks on to
our happiest Christmas memory
and projects it
right in front of us.
Exactly what purpose
does this serve?
Raising people's Christmas
spirits, of course.
(CHUCKLES, CLEARS THROAT)
I need a volunteer.
(ALL SCREAMING) Ooh!
I'm not going. Let go!
(GRUNTS)
Minty, thanks for volunteering.
(WHIMPERS)
Oooh.
(BUZZING) (GASPS)
Great Grand-elf's
chocolate-chunk cookies!
(GIGGLES) They were my favorite.
- Oh!
- Oh, this is great.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Don't be a cinnamon twist!
(DEVICE HUMMING)
My first Christmas kiss.
Give me that!
(CACKLING) Yes!
Yee-haw!
Ooh, this isn't so hard.
(SPLUTTERING)
Sir, please, careful.
No, no, no, don't do that.
Let me. No, no, no!
No, not now!
Oh, man!
(ALL MURMURING)
Ah! Back on.
Just a small, uh, power surge.
Can you believe those Christmas lights?
(NERVOUS CHUCKLE)
One goes out, they all go out.
- That will be all, Bernard.
- All, Bernard!
But it worked.
It worked, you saw...
And merry Christmas to you.
Yes, sir.
Merry Christmas to you.
And I'd better not see you back here
with another one of your
hare-brained inventions.
(GRUNTING)
Santech is only for
the greatest elf minds, not...
(INHALES)
...reindeer poop-scoopers.
GUARD: Poor fellow.
Poor fellow? He caused a
blackout on Christmas Eve.
Piece of junk.
(ZAPPING)
Ow!
(GRUNTS)
(DEVICE LANDS)
(MAN GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS, SNIFFS)
Hi, Dasher, hi, Dancer,
Prancer, Vixen...
Hi, Comet, hi, Cupid. Hi...
Donner, where's Blixen?
(GIBBERISH) Ooh!
(STRAINING) You're on
my gingerbread basket!
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(SIGHS)
That thing still won't
translate to English, eh?
Oh, jingle bells,
I can't do anything right.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
If you're asking how
the presentation went,
prepare to be underwhelmed.
As usual, I'm a miserable failure.
My Christmas memory machine
knocked the power out in the room.
So embarrassing.
But I guess I'll just have
to face the Christmas music.
I'll never be one of
Santa's trusty inventors.
(GRUNTING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(CLEARING THROAT)
Ah! Mr. Claus, I'm so sorry,
sir. I'll get that right off.
Ho, ho, ho!
That's nothing!
You fly around the world behind
eight well-fed reindeer,
as long as I have and...
(GUFFAWS)
...and you get used to getting
hit with a few warm brownies.
Say, what's this nifty contraption?
It's a reindeer vocalizer.
(BROADCASTING GIBBERISH)
You made this?
How clever.
It would be if I could
get it to speak English.
Merry Christmas, Blitzen.
Are you ready to fly tonight?
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
See?
(SANTA RESPONDING IN GIBBERISH)
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
Works for me, I speak
all languages. Ho, ho, ho!
Put down the brush
and come with me.
There's something
I want to show you.
Do you know there are tens of millions
of children who celebrate Christmas?
Every year.
When I started,
there were only a few thousand.
Ever heard how I do it?
Well, just rumors, sir.
I haven't been snooping,
if that's what you mean,
I swear, I don't go near the sleigh.
Except to admire it, of course.
And I found a cup holder,
which is a nice feature,
but I don't look at
anything else, so...
(CHUCKLES) I know.
You're a good egg.
Go on. How do you
think I do it? Hmm?
Well, uh... Some of the guys
think you teleport.
That theory isn't
scientifically sound.
Now, time travel, on the other hand...
Oh, you're one clever little elf!
(CHUCKLES)
You know your stuff. (LAUGHS)
Santech's very first invention:
the Time Globe.
Absolutely tip-top secret.
It's what started it all.
Heh. Wouldn't be able
to keep up with my deliveries
- if it weren't for this.
- It's real!
Amazing! Can I see?
Ho, ho, no.
No touching, now.
This can also be very dangerous,
lots of rules to follow.
A very delicate thing,
the fabric of time.
Once something is done,
it cannot be undone, only added to.
Or if you were to interact with yourself:
incredibly dangerous.
Speaking one word to yourself
would unravel our very...
Well, we can go into that
some other time I suppose.
Santa, why are you
telling me all of this?
Because, uh... Well, because you
remind me of the elf that invented this.
(CHUCKLING)
He was a lot like you.
Though a bit older, if I remember.
All the other elves
gave him a lot of guff
because he thought differently
about everything, but...
(CHUCKLES) But of course,
that's what made him so very special.
You think I could
be like him one day?
Mmm, I don't know.
It all depends on you.
Enough show and tell for now.
You've got to finish getting
my reindeer ready for tonight.
Of course, Santa, I'm right on it.
- Good. Don't give up.
- I won't.
Shoveling the
reindeer poop, I mean.
The team has to be ready
by nightfall to be on schedule.
Oh, yeah, that's what I meant.
Merry Christmas.
You hear that, Blitzen?
I remind Santa
of a great inventor.
And if he sees something
great in me, then...
Well... maybe I can be great one day.
♪ Sure, now I'm an ordinary elf
♪ Doing ordinary things
♪ That other ordinary elves
refuse to do
♪ Like scooping up the reindeer...
♪ You know what I do
♪ But I, one day I'll
fly up on his sleigh
♪ Going up, up and away
♪ And all the other
elves will say
♪ "Hey look"
(SINGS GIBBERISH)
♪ "There he goes again
♪ What a wonderful guy
- ♪ How did he get to be
- ♪ Ooh
♪ The elf he is today?"
♪ That's when the future me
- ♪ Will turn to them and say
ALL: - ♪ Ooh
♪ Even a flea has prospects
♪ Even a skunk has flair
♪ Even a reindeer
with a sleigh in tow
♪ Can beat a crow in the air
♪ So even that crow
has prospects
♪ Shouldn't an elf like me
♪ Never give up till you're up
♪ Where you want to be
(ALL HUMMING)
♪ So if you keep on trying
♪ Someone soon will see
♪ You're not really
a mouse, you're a lion
♪ Roar!
♪ You can rely on me
♪ Even a snake has prospects
♪ Even a swan can bite
♪ Even a tiny spider
spins a web
♪ That will hold
you good and tight
♪ So if everyone else
has prospects
♪ Wouldn't you all agree?
♪ Whether you're
two legs or four legs
♪ Eight legs or more legs
♪ Never give up till you're up
(EXCLAIMING)
♪ Never give up
when you're down
♪ Never give up till your up
♪ Where you want to be ♪
(PEOPLE YELLING)
(HELICOPTERS THUNDERING)
(ANGRY SHOUTING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GASPS)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(CACKLING)
Oh, it wouldn't be Christmas
without complete chaos
and utter panic.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Do you smell that?
Cookies?
Hot cocoa?
Hmm, well you can
smell those things, too.
But the more palpable odor
is that of vindication.
After years of searching,
the secrets of Santa's
sleigh will be mine.
Look! A Pancake Palace!
- I should...
- We should...
...definitely check that out.
Probably a lot of secrets in there.
There'll be plenty of time
for pancakes later.
First, find the sleigh.
It is, after all, what we're here for.
I want to know how a man that big
gets around the world in one night.
Find that sleigh!
Let's start in the Pancake Palace.
Good call.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(SNEEZES)
(GASPS)
(GROWLING)
- Why, you little...
MAN: - Yeah, where's the sleigh?
SANTA: You two are not
being very good this year.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Kris Kringle. (CACKLES)
Can I call you Kris?
Let's have a chat in that
quaint workshop of yours.
We've so much to discuss.
(GRUNTING)
Help! Blitz, we're under attack!
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
They're after the Time Globe.
We've gotta hide it!
(CRASHING AGAINST DOOR)
(GASPING)
They're here!
(GRUNTING)
(REINDEER CHATTERING)
Fine time to have a chat.
You want to help, maybe?
(CRASH) They're coming!
Oh, I just wish I had time to think.
I just wish I... had... time.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
Not now, I'm thinking.
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTS)
More time? The Time Globe!
I can go back and warn Santa.
Blitz, you're a genius!
(SMACKS)
Were you eating pancakes?
- Move it in!
MAN 2: - They're here!
MAN: Go, go, go!
Where the elf is it?
MAN: Spread out.
You check that side.
MAN 2: - We're clear.
MAN: - Got anything?
MAN 3: - Where is it?
- Yes!
- There!
- Get it!
(GIVES COMMAND)
(GRUNTING)
A twist here and a pop there.
Where do they keep the directions?
(GROANING) Come on, come on!
(EXCLAIMING)
Why won't you work?
He's activated the sleigh!
I have?
How did I do that?
- Get him!
- Move it out!
(ALL YELLING)
(DEVICE THRUMMING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
(REINDEER SNORING)
(FOOT SQUISHES)
(GASPS)
(SNIFFS)
Oh, come on, I just cleaned up in here.
(BLITZEN SNORING LOUDLY)
(GROANING)
(WHISPERING) Hey. Hey, Blitz. Wake up.
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
Listen to me.
I know this sounds crazy,
but I'm pretty sure
I've traveled back in time.
(SIGHS)
Would you wake up?
This is serious!
This big, scary man
drops out of the sky,
the North Pole is invaded,
they start rounding up elves,
all of these lights shine down
and everything and...
There was this girl
who saved me, and...
You don't believe me,
do you? (SIGHS)
(GRUNTING) Come on!
Wait. Wait, I can...
I can prove it.
I can show you that
I traveled back in time.
Come with me.
(GRUMBLING)
(COMPLAINING IN GIBBERISH)
(SNORING LOUDLY)
(GASPS) I told you.
You're looking at the world's
first time-traveling elf.
With the world's most obnoxious snore.
Now, listen. It won't be long
before those guys get here.
We have to warn Santa and
the others. Are you with me?
Good boy! Here.
(SNIFFS)
Excuse you. You don't eat it,
you just smell it.
Now, get a good sniff.
(SNIFFING)
Smells just like Santa, doesn't it?
Got it?
(PANTING)
Good. Now, go find him.
(SNIFFING)
What is it, Blitz?
(EXCLAIMING IN GIBBERISH)
The Pancake Palace.
We're looking for Santa,
not breakfast.
(GIBBERISH)
Santa does love pancakes.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Welcome to the Pancake Palace.
Try our streusel, butterscotch chip
and caramel-filled buttermilk flapjacks,
topped with powdered sugar,
whipped cream
and crushed candy canes.
Or try the Santa special,
steaming hot cocoa
pancakes topped with...
No, we can't eat pancakes
at a time like this.
We need to find Santa.
This isn't working.
I'm too short to see everywhere.
I need a higher vantage point.
Ah.
Hold it steady, Blitz.
Uh, everyone, can I
have your attention?
(CHATTERING CEASES) Good, hi.
I have urgent news.
We don't have much time.
There are people coming,
outsiders, from, um...
...the outside. I don't
know who they are, exactly,
but they want to capture Santa
and steal his sleigh.
Well, not the sleigh, itself,
but there are secrets held...
Gumdrop, this is Sugar Plum.
We've got a crazy on our hands.
You got eyes on Big Red?
- I'm on him.
- How does it look out there?
Not a creature is stirring.
Not even a mouse.
Welcome to the Pancake Palace...
WOMAN: - Hi, Santa
- Santa!
WOMAN: It's Santa!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
BERNARD: Listen to me!
Santa! Blitz, it's...
Oh, you are unbelievable!
Santa! (GRUNTING)
Santa!
They're coming to get you,
Santa, you're in danger!
Santa!
(GRUNTING)
Lump of coal in the stocking.
Threat neutralized.
Nice tackle, partner.
(GRUNTING)
You! You're the one who...
Take this marshmallow head
back to base for questioning.
(GRUNTING, MUFFLED)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
You're making a big mistake!
I need to warn Santa.
Someone's coming and they're
after the Time Globe!
Let me go! Santa!
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
MAN: Santa, sir.
Your beard stylist had to cancel.
He has the chimney flu.
Would you like me to reschedule?
Blitz, over here!
Listen, you have to find the other me.
I should be on my way to Santech
for the presentation right now.
You have to convince me to warn
everybody about the invasion.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
I don't know what that means.
But do whatever it takes.
Do you understand? Stop me and get me
to listen to you no matter what!
This is more important
than the presentation.
Santa is in real danger!
BERNARD 1: Excuse me. Coming through!
BERNARD 2: - There I am!
- Oh, sorry!
Go, go!
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
Where am I?
The Christmas Defense Department.
The Christmas De-who
and the what now?
You know how Santa knows
when you are sleeping?
And knows when you're awake?
That's us!
I'm Agent Snowy and you, little elf,
have a lot of explaining to do.
Well, I know what this looks like.
But there is a perfectly
logical explanation.
- I'm listening.
- First off, I'm from the future.
Just to put that out there.
I believe him.
(GASPS)
I'm being the good cop.
Agent Shortbread!
Do you have his naughty
or nice record up yet?
Just one second.
(COMPUTERS HUMMING)
Let's see...
Bernard D. Elf. Hmm.
Height: three feet.
Favorite candy: gumdrops.
Occupation...
poop-shoveler.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Director of Droppings.
- Excuse me?
- I prefer "Director of Droppings."
"Disposal Administrator."
I am a professional, after all.
This one's a real piece of work.
- Claims to be from the future.
- Uh, everyone, can I...
(SHORTBREAD) Something
about a Time Globe.
If there were such a thing
as a time travel globe,
which we cannot confirm
or deny the existence of,
how would you know of its existence?
If it were to exist.
Hmm?!
That is the most confusing
question I've ever heard.
Answer it!
(SIGHS)
- Santa showed me.
- Would Santa confirm
that he showed you the Time Globe?
He hasn't shown me it yet.
He showed it to me
after I caused the blackout
in the Santech building.
(LAUGHING) Oh, this just
keeps getting better!
And when, exactly,
does that happen?
Hmm?
(ALARM BLARING)
- What's going on?
- Any minute now.
We've got a problem.
We've got no power anywhere.
The cloaking device is down.
Were exposed!
I need more power!
Sir, I think the equipment
is malfunctioning.
- I'm... I'm getting a blop.
- You mean a blip?
No, sir, it's a blop. It's far
too large to be a blip.
Put it onscreen for Mommy.
Mommy, there it is!
The North Pole!
Let me see.
What are you talking about?
I don't see any North Pole.
What? Impossible.
(SARCASTIC LAUGH)
Oh, look. Nothing!
No workshop. No sleigh.
No secrets.
More failure?
(SHEEPISH LAUGH)
(BOTH GASP)
If you do not have Santa's
sleigh by midnight tonight,
you are cut off!
(GASPS)
You'll be living on a deserted island
when I'm through with you.
Is that clear?
I will find it, Mommy.
And all of the secrets it holds.
Then QAD will truly be the quickest
package delivery service...
...in the world.
Find that blip.
That... That thing
that we saw on the radar.
Take me there now!
Whoa!
(POWER GRID HUMMING)
It's working.
Power is restored to the hologram.
- Were we seen?
- It's too early to tell.
Looks like you were right, Bernard.
Bernard?
He's getting away!
Hold it right there!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Don't let him get away!
(GUMDROP) Get back here!
Which way did he go?
(MAN SNIFFING) Cookie breath!
He went that way!
(ELEVATOR BUTTONS DINGING)
- What the...?
- Hah! Found you!
Get him!
(GRUNTING)
Get over here, you little...
(ALL STRAINING)
(GRUNTING)
COMPUTER VOICE: Welcome to the Mail-evator.
(CHRISTMAS CAROL PLAYING)
(BUZZING)
COMPUTER: Elevator out of service.
COMPUTER: Elevator operational.
(YELLS)
(RUMBLING)
(HOLLERING)
(MUSIC FALTERS, STOPS)
(GROANING)
And I'd better not see you back here
with another one of your
hare-brained inventions.
(GRUNTING)
Santech is only for the
greatest elf minds, not...
(INHALES)
...reindeer poop-scoopers.
GUARD: Poor fellow.
Poor fellow? He caused a
blackout on Christmas Eve.
It was me.
Piece of junk!
(ZAPPING)
Ow!
(GRUNTS)
(DEVICE LANDS)
(MAN GRUNTS)
They found the North Pole
because of me.
(SIGHS)
♪ What kind of an elf
♪ Runs away to sulk
♪ When he's not the best?
♪ Who bumbles along
♪ Wearing last night's
dinner on his vest?
♪ Insists that he's smart
♪ When all other elves
declare he's dim?
♪ A kind of an elf like him
♪ Head in the clouds, Bernard
♪ Heart on the floor
♪ Best to go back
to the place you belong
♪ Back where you were before
♪ Time to regroup, Bernard
♪ Time to repair
♪ Time to go back to the poop
♪ And the shoveling scoop
♪ And that whiff in the air
♪ That's where the future me
♪ Will turn to them and say
- ♪ Even a flea
- ♪ What kind of an elf
♪ Doesn't realize when
the world's gone wrong
♪ Who flounders around
like a dying fish
- ♪ To a silly song
- ♪ And even that crow
♪ You're best to rely on an elf
- ♪ Like me
- ♪ Never give up
- ♪ Which is who that elf
♪ Aspires to be
♪ What kind of an elf
♪ Doesn't shy away
from a mucky task?
♪ What kind of an elf
♪ Answers "Yes!"
no matter what you ask
♪ What kind of an elf
♪ Has the wherewithal
to put this right
♪ An elf who'll
fight and never flee
♪ A kind of an elf like me ♪
Mr. Baddington?
There's nothing here.
Oh, it's here, all right.
We're directly above the coordinates.
We would see it, don't you think?
Oh, of course.
Silly-billy me.
Clearly, there is nothing there.
I mean, any rational person
would see that there
is nothing beneath us
but a bunch of mountains and snow.
And not a clever facade
masking Santa's workshop.
Surely not.
Only a madman would think
we'll surely crash and explode
into fiery bits and pieces
if we flew straight down...
(YELLING)
Aha!
Merry Christmas to me!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(ANGRY SHOUTING)
(GASPS)
Excuse me!
Excuse me, coming through!
(GASPS)
(NEVILLE CACKLING)
Oh, it wouldn't be Christmas
without complete chaos and utter panic.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Do you smell that?
MAN: Cookies?
Hot cocoa?
Hmm, well you can
smell those things, too.
But the more palpable odor
is that of vindication.
- Sorry!
- Hey!
NEVILLE: There'll be plenty
of time for pancakes later.
First, find the sleigh!
MAN: Come on! Give it up!
(GASPS)
Where's the sleigh, round boy?
Yeah! Where's the sleigh?
SANTA: You two are not
being very good this year.
(GROANING)
(CACKLING)
(NEVILLE CONTINUING, INDISTINCT)
(NEVILLE, THROUGH DOOR)
We've so much to discuss.
We have something
in common, you and I.
We're both in the delivery business.
But unlike some lazy-pants
jelly-bellied holiday showboats,
we operate 365 days a year.
It's hard to believe,
but once upon a time,
Christmas was my favorite holiday.
Singing carols,
eating fresh cookies...
Oh, the memories.
You know, that for years,
I looked up to you?
I wanted to be
just... like... you.
You were such a good boy.
What happened to you?
Hah! All-knowing, are we?
Clearly not.
What happened?
I grew up.
I saw through your phony generosity,
giving your worthless toys away,
keeping naive children
drunk with sugary sweets,
while you keep all of the
good stuff to yourself!
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Oh, no?
How do you make it all around
the world in one night?
Huh? Or fit all of those presents
into one bag? Huh? Huh?
How do you fly?
How do you live forever?
Huh? Huh? Huh?
- Stop that!
- Sorry, sir.
Every year, I wrote to you,
asking for the answers,
And all you ever gave me were toys.
This Christmas, I will
have my Christmas wish!
I will give the secrets
of your sleigh to my mother,
and Quickest Airborne Delivery
will be, at last,
the fastest delivery service on Earth!
(RADIO SQUAWKING)
Neville! Pick up, you
moon-faced feather-brain!
Excuse me, I have a business, uh...
A foreign dignitary client
important person.
- That needs my...
- Neville!
Pick up the radio,
you dunder-headed dolt!
Oh, hello, Mommy.
Good news.
I found Santa's workshop.
Have you, now?
(BERNARD WHISPERING) Santa!
Santa, it's me, Bernard.
Bernard! (CHUCKLES)
Clever disguise.
Do you think you can
get us out of here?
He's after the Time Globe.
I have a better idea.
I think I know a way to stop him,
but I'm gonna have to go back in time.
Again.
Bernard! Be careful!
I told you.
You can't undo the past.
- Only add to it.
- I have to try.
If I can stop myself from making
it to the presentation, I can...
Who are you talking to?
Ow!
I see with that thing!
- How do you like it?
- Ow!
I... Little...
(ALL SHOUTING) Come here, you!
Gotcha!
(SIGHS)
Great. Dead end.
(DOLL SQUEAKS)
(GUN BEEPS)
(SAGS)
Come out, little elf.
There's nowhere to run.
And you wouldn't get very far
on those stubby little legs of yours.
Ah. Don't mind if I do.
(ENGINE ROARS)
What's that sound?
(HORN TOOTS)
I'm going back, Santa!
If I can destroy the memory device,
I can stop the presentation!
Good luck, Bernard!
(GRUNTS) Don't move, Beardy.
(EXCLAIMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GIGGLING)
Get that elf!
(BOTH YELL)
(GASPS)
(YELLING)
Snow long!
(CHUCKLING)
(YELLING)
They're coming!
(YELLING) Come here!
- Move it in!
- Here, here!
- Go, go, go!
- Yes!
Come on, Bernard,
just a few more seconds!
(ISSUING COMMAND)
(GRUNTING)
Deck the halls, I made it!
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
What did you do that for?
MAN: He's activated the sleigh!
OTHER BERNARD: I have?
How did I do that?
(YELPS)
- Get it!
- Follow me!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(YELLING)
Oh, my whole life and I had to
repeat this day three times.
(WHISPERING) Watch out for the...
(SQUISH)
Oh, come on, I just
cleaned up in here.
Well, duh,
you went back in time.
(SNORING LOUDLY)
Nah, too loud.
(ALARM CLANGING)
OTHER BERNARD: What are you doing here?
I expressly ordered
nine ladies dancing.
(RESUMES SNORING)
(GASPS) I told you.
You're looking at the world's
first time-traveling elf.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Excuse you!
You don't eat it, you just...
(EXCLAIMING)
(THUMP)
(SLEEPY MUTTERING)
Oh no!
Mint chocolate cookies,
I slept in!
Not today, not today!
Oh, where the blinking...?
Ah, there you are.
(GASPS)
Oh, now I'll never stop
the presentation!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(GASPS) No pants!
No pants!
(YELPS)
(GASPS)
- Huh?
(PANTING)
I've got a presentation to stop.
If I could just get there first!
Ooh, this is gonna sting!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
Wait! Wait up!
Wait up!
Hold the train!
Ooh!
Oh, sorry!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
That way!
Ooh!
Morning, Blitz!
(BERNARD GROANS) Ow!
(INQUISITIVE GIBBERISH)
How long have I been out?
Oh, great! It happened again!
Ow! What'd you do that for, anyway?
Jumping on me like that.
Have you lost your mind?
(GIBBERISH)
(LAUGHS) Me?
It was my fault?
You are ridiculous.
BERNARD 2: Listen,
you have to find the other me.
Stop me and get me to listen
to you, no matter what!
It was my fault.
You just got the wrong "me."
(SIGHS)
What's the point of
having a time machine
if you can't go back and
prevent things from happening?
(POWER GRID HUMMING)
Hah! There are the lights!
Brilliant! Disaster
is right on schedule!
(SIGHS)
(INQUISITIVE GIBBERISH)
Oh, just leave me alone, would you?
You should stay away.
As far away from me as possible,
if you know what's good for you.
Just go back to the stables
before I mess everything
up for you, too.
Can't you see what
a muck-up I am?
Go... Go on, Blitz.
Go on, will you?
Go!
MAN: Santech is only for
the greatest elf minds, not...
(INHALES)
...reindeer poop-scoopers.
Could this day get any worse?
(ZAPPING)
BERNARD 1: Ow!
(BERNARD 1 GRUNTS)
SNOWY: Wake up, Bernard!
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Thought you could get away, did you?
Well, Bernard, if you
are indeed innocent,
how do you explain this?
Huh? We found this outside Santech.
We believe that you intentionally
caused the blackout
that disabled the cloaking hologram!
(SIGHS) I'm not the one you
should be worried about.
Neville Baddington. He's the one
you should be worried about.
- Who's that?
- Neville Baddington.
Height: six foot one.
Weight: blah, blah, blah.
Oh, here we go!
Heir to the Quickest
Airborne Delivery empire.
(FANFARE PLAYS)
WOMAN ON SCREEN: Globe-trotting millionaire
and all-around eccentric heir
to the Quickest Airborne
delivery service,
Neville Baddington claims
"I can find Santa Claus."
(SIGHS)
WOMAN: You heard it right, folks.
This particular purveyor of parcels
looks to unlock the secrets
of Santa's speedy sleigh.
NEVILLE ON SCREEN: I've been
documenting him for years.
I have photographic proof
here, here and here.
- Hmm?
- That's him.
He wants to learn how Santa
travels round the world
in one night
(BUZZING)
- (GASPS)
Sir! I think we've got a blip!
A blip?
Uh, I think it looks
more like a blop.
NEVILLE: Oh, of course!
Silly-billy me.
Clearly, there is nothing there.
I mean, any rational person
would see that there
is nothing beneath us
but a bunch of mountains and snow.
And not a clever facade
masking Santa's workshop.
Surely not.
Only a madman would think
we will surely crash and explode
into fiery bits and pieces
if we flew straight down...
(YELLING)
(KLAXON SOUNDING)
Sir, someone has
breached the hologram!
Put it onscreen.
It's an invasion.
Everybody panic!
Don't we have a plan for this?
For an invasion of the North Pole?
Who plans for that?
- Run!
- Hide!
(ALL YELLING)
Out of my way! Out of my way!
Bernard! You must know some way
we can stop Neville Baddington.
You can't.
I've tried everything!
Three times!
What's gotten into you?
Earlier, you were so
desperate to save Santa.
And now you just don't care?
I've failed.
There's nothing I can do.
He's going to invade.
(GASPS)
I'm sorry.
It's like Santa said,
once something is done,
it can't be undone.
(SIGHS)
I'm no hero.
I'm just a poop-scooper.
♪ Say you've got another shot
♪ At saving Christmas Eve in you
♪ These other elves
They don't know where to turn
♪ Take a good long look at me
♪ 'Cause somehow
I believe in you
♪ That kind of elf belief
you have to earn
♪ So stop and think
♪ 'Cause you know what's in store
♪ An elf with that much vision
♪ Is an elf we're fighting for
♪ But before I do
the big hard sell for you
♪ I need to know
what kind of elf are you
♪ Sink or swim
Do or die
♪ Make this stand
Or stand by
♪ When everyone around you
wants to run and hide
♪ It's time to decide
♪ What kind of elf
you want to be
♪ You've got brains
I know you have
♪ You've brains enough
for two in there
♪ So come up with a
plan to save the day
♪ Think back over everything
♪ There has to be
a clue in there
♪ You find it and we're
with you all the way
♪ So stop and think of
the children big and small
♪ 'Cause a Christmas
without Santa
♪ Doesn't sound much fun at all
♪ Sink or swim
Do or die
♪ Worth a shot
Worth a try
♪ When everyone around you
wants to run and hide
♪ It's time to decide
What kind of elf...
♪ Look, if you say
that you trust me
♪ Then, OK
I'll trust you too
- ♪ As long as children
- ♪ Believe in Santa
- ♪ Believe
♪ Then I won't give up on you
WOMAN ON SCREEN: Is it true
your mother is the real CEO of QAD?
Excellent question.
Let me think.
Get over here, you pesky,
little good-for-nothing!
WOMAN: Well, someone seems to
have lost their Christmas spirit.
Holy eggnog, that's it!
He has Christmas spirit.
But it's lost in his brain!
- Oh.
- I know how to stop Neville.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING) Quiet down!
Calm down, everyone.
I've got it!
This memory machine caused it,
and it can end it.
But I need help fixing it.
Who's with me?
(GASPING)
(EXCLAIMING)
- ♪ So stop
- Stop!
♪ I can put this right
I swear to you
♪ I'll have the big man
flying high tonight
♪ Sink or swim
Do or die
♪ Rally round or say goodbye
♪ Each one of you's a hero
if you only knew
♪ So who's on my crew?
♪ I need you and
you and you and you
♪ Sink or swim
Do or die
♪ Whata team
You and you and you and I
♪ When everyone around you
wants to run and hide
♪ It's time to decide
♪ What kind of elf
you want to be
♪ Are you an oaf like that?
♪ Or an elf like me? ♪
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
BERNARD: Quickly! We have to get
to the sleigh before Neville does.
The coast is clear.
Move!
Secure the front door.
Go, go, go!
Hurry everyone!
Blend in!
MAN: Nothing here.
(GASPS) Here he comes.
MAN: You two,
stop right where you are!
Nobody move!
(EXCLAIMS)
Pucker up, lass.
(CHUCKLES)
(GIGGLES) Shh!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
MAN: Run this way, you two!
Now, now, now!
(CACKLING)
Oh, it wouldn't be Christmas
without complete chaos
and utter panic.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Do you smell that?
I don't think this is going to work.
There's too many of them.
And, frankly, too many of me.
You're right. The only way around this
is to jump from the roof.
Really?
The only way?
No way. No roof!
(GRUNTING)
No! I'm a delicate snowflake.
- Hey!
- Sorry!
NEVILLE: I want to know
how a man that big
gets around the world
in one night!
Find that sleigh!
MAN: Let's start in the Pancake Palace.
MAN 2: Good call.
(SNEEZES)
(GASPS)
- Why, you little...
MAN: - Yeah! Where's the sleigh?
SANTA: You two are not
being very good this year.
(GROANS)
Santa! (GRUNTING)
(BERNARD STAMMERING)
That really is high.
Step aside, please.
Hmm...
(WHIRRING, BEEPING)
There we go.
How much do you weigh?
Fifty... Uh, forty-two...
one... ish.
That should hold.
Probably.
OK, let's do this!
(YELLING)
(♪ ASHLEY TISDALE: "SOME KIND OF MIRACLE")
Ha-ha! Whoo-hoo!
No, not now!
(YELLING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Oh, poo!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GASPS)
(YELLING)
Hold on, I've got you!
- Good luck!
- Thanks!
(ALL GROANING)
Are you sure
he's just a poo-shoveler?
(EXCLAIMING)
How do I stop this thing?
(YELLING)
Ooh!
(DOOR RATTLES)
(GRUNTING GROANING)
I guess that was the only way.
MAN: Follow me!
(GASPS)
Right here!
(CAR APPROACHING)
(YELPS)
A fine time to have a chat.
You want to help, maybe?
(TIRES SCREECH)
(DOOR THUMPS)
BERNARD 1: They're coming!
Oh, I just wish I had time to think.
I just wish I had time.
(BLIXEN SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
Not now, I'm thinking.
(GRUNTS) More time.
The Time Globe.
I could go back and warn Santa.
Blitz, you're a genius!
(GROANS)
BERNARD 1: Were you eating pancakes?
(GRUNTING)
- Move it in!
- They're here!
Go, go, go!
BERNARD 1: Oh, where the elf is it?
Spread out.
You check that side.
We're clear!
Yes!
- There!
- Get him!
(ISSUES COMMAND)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
What did you do that for?
MAN: He's activated the sleigh!
- Get it!
- Follow me!
Don't move!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(ALL GROANING)
What is this?
I turn my back for two seconds
and you're having a little nap.
Hey! Stop that elf!
You!
Yes, you, you tick-infested nitwit.
Pull the sleigh outside.
I want everybody to see my triumph!
(ALL GASPING)
NEVILLE: Witness, all of you!
Santa's sleigh and all its secrets,
beneath my icy boots.
Neville Baddington.
CEO and majority stockholder
in the world's soon-to-be-biggest...
Nay, only package delivery
mega corporation!
You can almost hear the "whoosh"
of packages whizzing around the world
at the speed of Santa, 365 days a year!
Hah!
And mother, if her tear ducts do,
in fact, exist,
tears of pride will stream down
her sweet, prunish cheeks,
as she embraces me with
her jagged, bony frame.
"Good job, Neville," she'll whisper.
As of this moment,
Christmas is outsourced!
"Dear Neville,
what I want for Christmas
is to be able to go back in time
and tell you the secrets
of the North Pole.
Love, Santa."
"Dear, Santa,
Too late!"
BERNARD: Actually, it's not too late.
Who said that?
BERNARD: Me, sir.
And you are...?
I'm... I'm the, um...
...chief inventor for Santech.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Put him down.
(GRUNTS, GROANS)
Chief inventor, are we?
Then you are familiar with
the secrets of this sleigh?
Yes, sir.
If I promised to show you...
Huh?
...would you release Santa?
I would be inclined.
Uh, may I?
(GRUNTING)
A little help, please?
I'm vertically challenged.
Oh!
The question on everybody's mind,
on your mind, your whole life,
was "How does he do it?"
How does one man
make it around the entire
world in one night?
Especially for someone like you,
who delivers packages all year round.
The answer?
Time travel!
(ALL GASPING) Time travel?
Time travel?
This is more fascinating
than I thought.
Mother will be pleased.
But... there are rules.
Do I look like someone who
concerns himself with rules?
Then let's skip those and get
to the good stuff, shall we?
I'm gonna need a volunteer.
- Me! Me!
- You're fired.
Aww.
Me! Me!
- You?
- Oh, yes please.
OK, Neville, I'm just gonna need
you to place your hand here.
Then... hope for
a Christmas miracle.
Oooh...
Feels time-travel-y.
Hold on.
That's my old home.
That's me.
As a young boy.
YOUNG NEVILLE: Dear, Santa.
♪ I have a secret Christmas wish
♪ I know you know it well
♪ It's something
that! want so much
♪ I cannot even tell
♪ If I believe with all my heart
♪ I know it can come true
♪ But if that never happens
♪ Still I'll always believe
♪ In you
♪ Someone was listening
♪ Someone was there
♪ While you were whispering
♪ Your dreams to the air
♪ Someone was watching you
♪ And someone can say
♪ Your hopes and your dreams
aren't forgotten
♪ They might just
all come true today
- ♪ Someone is listening
- ♪ I have a secret
- ♪ Someone is there
- ♪ Christmas wish...
- ♪ While you are whispering
- ♪ Something that! want so much
- ♪ To the air
- ♪ I cannot even tell
♪ Someone is watching you
♪ And someone can say
♪ Your hopes and your dreams
aren't forgotten
♪ They might just all come true today
♪ Because you believe
♪ I'm happy to say
♪ Your hopes and your dreams
aren't forgotten
♪ And when one day that happens
♪ They might just all
come true today ♪
Mother.
MOTHER: Neville?
Your time is up.
Mother, what are you doing here?
You're not the only one that
can follow a bleeping blop.
Of course. Merry Christmas.
Don't you "Merry Christmas" me.
If this were a merry Christmas,
I would be poolside, getting a rubdown
from a muscular, Latin cabana boy.
Not freezing to death while my idiot son
wastes my time and fortune
looking for.. for...
Oh, my!
Is this...?
Indeed it is, Mommy.
Santa's sleigh, right here beneath...
Beneath your icy boots, yes, yes.
I've heard you rehearse that drivel
in the bathroom a million times.
Though, I must congratulate you.
For once, you've delivered.
So, you're... proud of me?
I'm not disappointed,
if that's what you mean.
After all, you're finally
following in my footsteps
and putting profits over people.
(CACKLES)
All of our aircraft will be
redesigned to these specifications.
Rudders and all.
St. Nick and his band of munchkins
will be obsolete when our fleet
of sleighs takes to the sky.
(CACKLES) Next Christmas, we'll be
cashing in on every Christmas wish.
And this place, it will make
a wonderful theme park.
Or perhaps a meat locker.
Instead of "Ho, ho, ho,"
they'll all be crying,
"Boo, hoo, hoo!"
(CACKLING)
Load up that sleigh and
whatever else you can find
and bring it back to the base.
The sooner we're out of this
candy cane nightmare, the better.
NEVILLE: No.
What?
I... I said...
I won't do it!
Santa's sleigh will remain here,
where it belongs.
MOTHER: What?
Why, you ungrateful,
you insolent little...
How dare you disobey me?
You're through, do you hear me?
The mind eraser?
- Good boy!
MOTHER: - I'll see to it you don't
get a whiff of your inheritance
Not a penny!
You'll be delivering
crates of rubber ducks
to Siberia by the time
I'm through with you!
I'll have that sleigh stripped of
its secrets and sold for scrap.
Mother, I'm sorry.
What I meant to say was,
we don't need the sleigh.
We've got its secret right here.
Give it to me!
It's amazing!
It's extraordinary!
What does it do?
Turn it on and see for yourself.
(GASPING)
(SHRIEKS)
Where... Where am I?
Uh... Your retirement party, Mommy!
Congratulations on
so many glorious years
of dedicated service.
Oh, yes, my retirement party.
How silly of me.
Will someone please take
Mommy back to the base?
Who are you adorable little children?
I seem to have lost my cabana boy.
Santa, I'm so sorry
for everything I've done.
And you, little elf,
thank you for giving me
back my Christmas spirit.
Merry Christmas, Neville.
Merry Christmas.
Release everyone!
We're going home for Christmas!
(ALL CHEERING)
- Merry Christmas!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(GRUNTING)
So you're a Director of Droppings,
an inventor, a time traveler,
and an action hero?
What can't you do?
(GASPS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
WOMAN: Good luck, Santa!
BOY: Take care, Santa!
Everything is set for takeoff, Santa.
Not everything.
Now we have everything.
- We'd better get going.
- We?
If you're gonna be one
of my Santech inventors,
you need to see this baby
in action, don't you think?
Me? A Santech inventor?
You mean...?
I don't know how to thank you.
No need. You're going to
do great things, Bernard.
This was just the first of them. Ho, ho!
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas to you, Bernard.
Oh, can I geta hug, too?
We are go for takeoff!
(WHISTLES)
Ho, ho, ho!
Hang on! This thing
has a time machine on it
but no seat belt?
(LAUGHING)
Merry Christmas to all,
and to all, a good night!
BERNARD: The present becomes the past,
every second of every day.
(SNORING)
But if we hold Christmas
in our hearts,
we have the power to
turn back time itself.
(♪ ASHLEY TISDALE: "SOME KIND OF MIRACLE")