The leader's Danny O'Neil.
Do you know him?
Oh, sure he's the best trumpet
player this college has ever had.
Let's get closer.
I thought you'd like the music.
Great, wasn't it, Ellen?
Hi, Stu.
Where've you been?
Oh, I've been around.
Funny I was just saying the other day
I ought to see more of old Stu.
Well, er, we'd better go
and sit down or something Ellen.
See you later.
Your playing
was wonderful.
Thanks.
You don't think she
meant you, do you?
You don't think
she meant you, do you?
Wait a minute.
You don't think she'd fall for that
station house music of yours?
It's not so much
my music, it's my personality.
I'll show you.
Hello Stu.
Oh, Mr. O'Neill,
won't you join us?
Oh, thank you.
See you later son.
Well Stu.
Do you want something?
Me? Oh, no, no.
I've been wanting
to meet you for some time Mr. O'Neil.
That's wonderful!
You mean you like the band?
Oh I didn't mean I wanted
to meet the band exactly,
although I thought
they did back you up rather well.
Thanks. Is there any special
number you'd like to hear?
I would like to hear the
Call-Me-Up-and-Call-me-down blues.
The what?
The Call-Me-Up-
and-Call-Me-Down blues.
I know what you mean.
I'm afraid I haven't got the number.
Oh, I'm sure you'll be
able to get hold of it.
Why don't you go back
to the bandstand and look for it?
No hurry Stu.
It's such a long time since we got
together. I want to make the most of it.
It's heartwarming
that's what it is.
Nothing like old college friends,
I always say.
All for one
and all for one. Ha, Ha.
Yes sir, I think I'd better
be getting back. So long Stu.
So long.
Alright let's play
number nine.
Why can't you
go on a picnic?
Mr. Dunn is inside,
Mr. Taylor.
Mr. Dunn?
He wouldn't be any fun on a picnic.
This is a collection agency.
Not an escort bureau.
Now will you please
get of my desk?
Is this fellow annoying you
Miss Miller?
Hello.
- Hello.
I was just seeing Miss Miller here
about the encyclopedias.
I figure
I can take care of the details.
As Miss Miller was kind enough
to serve me with the summons,
I'll explain the details.
What is there to explain?
Seven years ago,
you bought a set of encyclopedias
for which you've never paid.
But I didn't buy them.
Please,
you're wasting my time.
See,
you're wasting Miss Miller's time.
As I was saying seven years ago,
I must have broken a mirror
because that walked in
and became my roommate.
I was only a simple
freshman at the time.
What are you now?
A simple sophomore?
Oh, Miss Miller
you're being a bit unkind.
After all, we've worked hard
to stay in college this long.
It's not easy for a couple of bright guys
like us to go on flunking year after year.
What in the world
are you talking about?
Well, it's like this.
As long as we can stay in college,
the band makes us a comfortable living.
That's right five,
six thousand dollars a year.
That's more than
you can make on Wall Street.
Besides, it's a nice life.
Cultural, relaxing, gay.
Getting back
to the subject.
This roommate whom I trusted ordered
a set of encyclopedias in my name.
That's gratitude.
It was a birthday present.
You were crazy about them.
I was crazy about them
till I got the bill.
(Mr. Dunn)
Miss Miller.
What's this?
Mr. O'Neill,
Mr. Taylor, Mr. Dunn.
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes! Step right in.
Now look Mr. Dunn.
Here's the situation:
we're temporarily embarrassed.
You see we're working
our way through college.
You've been working your way
through college for the last seven years.
Well, takes time.
Specially when you're struggling.
Boys you don't pull any wool over me.
You ain't broke, you ain't struggling.
You mean you
doubt our word?
You said it. I've got your number.
You're businessmen.
Now pay up or go to jail.
That's final!
Final, Eh?
Final.
Final!
Well, maybe we ought to ask
for an extension, hit it.
(Overlapping dialogue)
Ok. Dunnsy boy we do make money.
We haven't got any
right now just give us one month.
Just one month's extension.
- OK Dunnsy.
I won't listen.
(Overlapping dialogue continues)
I'll be around in a -
What do you think we are?
- Fly-by-nights?
My word is
good enough, isn't it?
Everybody in town can-
Have that money here tomorrow
or I'll see you in court.
No!
No.
That's a sordid little fella, isn't he?
Sordid little place.
Must be a sordid
life for such a lovely girl.
Oh, there's nothing
so sordid about it.
Except the people
we deal with.
It's a pity we can't
take Miss Miller out of this.
Yes.
How'd you like some fresh air?
Sorry, I have work to do.
She's very businesslike,
isn't she?
Yes.
I like that in a secretary.
In fact, I'd like to have
a secretary like that.
You know, there's an
awful lot of work running a band.
Come to think of it,
we do need a secretary.
But I don't need a job.
So she doesn't
need a job.
Whatever it is I won't do it.
Now, I want to tell you.
Ssh!
Now look Mr. Dunn
I want to do the right thing.
We don't care anything about
the encyclopedia company.
No, we care
about you.
Oh yeah - er, well maybe
I said a few hasty words, boys.
Let bygones
be bygones, eh?
Two dollars?
But the bill's a hundred and ten.
That's for you
to fix things up.
What are you
talking about?
Are you asking me
to take a bribe?
A two dollar bribe?
Oh, come on, Dunn. We're all
men of the world, you know.
We'll keep it under our hats.
Don't worry about it.
Sure, you can depend on us.
She'll tell you.
She? Who?
Miss Miller.
Miss Miller!
Come in here please.
Did you intimate to these men
that I could be bribed?
She didn't say your could be bribed,
she said you could be fixed.
Well Mr. Dunn,
I didn't say any such thing.
(Overlapping dialogue)
Oh get her.
Oh yes you did,
she didn't want us to tell you.
Don't believe him
Mr. Dunn,
I heard her myself.
Didn't you hear her?
Wait a minute!
I'll have you deadbeats
put in jail,
and as for you Miss Miller
you're fired!
Oh!
Thanks a lot
old man.
Thanks old boy.
Miss Miller,
wait a minute!
Haven't you rover boys
caused enough trouble already?
It was really
a kindly gesture.
A very kindly gesture.
Now I haven't even a reference.
But I don't demand
a reference.
We know you
for what you are.
Yes.
You mean you
really want me to work for you?
Sure,
Wouldn't you like it?
What's your salary?
Eighteen a week.
He'll double it.
Yeah - er - Yeah!
Well.
Hit it.
(overlapping dialogue) Let me tell you,
here's the chance of a lifetime:
we’re going all the way to the
- You can't go wrong if...
Alright I'll take it.
Good.
When do I start?
Right now.
Well now that I'm
working for you,
I'll tell you something.
Dunn can be bought
but his price isn't two dollars,
It's ten!
Here you want
to take care of the details
Hey!
Well, here we are.
You can have half of that desk, a quarter
of that rack and just - go to work.
There's only one detail
that you've omitted.
What are my duties?
Oh, you type a little.
- Telephone a little.
Keep the leader happy.
Keep your eye
on the brass section.
I thought you said
this was a job.
Lining up good
engagements is no cinch.
What's so difficult about it?
Operator get me
The Riverdale Country Club.
Oh no, we've already tried.
Who's in charge there?
Mr. Bent, isn't it?
Bent real sourpuss.
Hello Mr. Bent?
This is Mr. O'Neill 's
Secretary
No Danny O'Neill,
the orchestra leader.
I read in the paper that
you're planning a Halloween dance...
Hob Harvey's
Cornell Clippers oh,
but we entertain too
Do we entertain?
No but we can
dream up something.
Oh but our entertainment's terrific.
That's our strongpoint.
Mr. Benn until you've seen
the Perennials you haven't lived.
It isn't
that I don't admire Emil Colman,
but isn't his music...
shall we say rowdy?
Now, Mr. O'Neill 's salon ensemble
play everything gently but with a lilt.
And all his boys
are from such nice families.
Very well, we'll expect
them at seven-thirty.
Thank you.
Believe me, bud, my outfit are killers.
Just what you need for one-nighters.
Can they pack 'em in like Dorsey?
- Solid Jack!
Murder!
Furthermore, I could come
down the day before the dance
and help you with
the decorations.
That is, of course,
if you want me to.
(Shouts of approval)
Wait a minute men,
we took a poll on the campus
and almost everybody
voted for Artie Shaw's band.
Artie Shaw?
Who's Artie Shaw?
(Shouts of approval)
(Both agents together)
You were terrific, Chief.
Yeah, yeah -
glass of water please.
What about that prom,
is it set?
Not exactly, chief.
They hired that college band.
- Danny O'Neill's Perennials.
O'Neill again, Huh?
This is the fourth time
we've run into them on college dates.
Either they've got a
great band or a fine manager.
I gotta go up
and hear them sometime.
Oh, I wouldn't worry
about them.
They'll be graduating
in another week.
Hmm!
Not The Perennials.
OK, boys. No graduation this year.
I flunked three courses.
(Cries of congratulations)
Alright, boys,
break it up break it up.
Oh, Danny you're wonderful.
Well Danny old boy,
we made it again, Huh?
Er...
What's the matter?
Well Hank,
I don't quite know how to tell you.
What do you mean
I passed?
Oh, I couldn't graduate -
not with my marks.
What are you kiddin' me?
Oh, listen there must
be some mistake.
I'm not gonna
take this lyin' down.
I'm gonna see
the Dean about it.
They can't do this to me.
Oh, Danny.
Poor old Hank
he got careless.
You didn't have anything
to do with this, did you?
Why Ellen!
Of course - a little peace and quiet
won't hurt either of us.
But poor Hank.
You still have me.
I guess we'll have to carry on as good
old Hank would have wanted us to.
It seems to me.
It seems to you?
I said it seems to me.
You said it seems to you.
It seems to me
I smell a mouse.
Somewhere about the house.
(Tempo)
It seems to me.
It seems to you.
I said it seems to me.
You said it seems to you.
That such embarrassing situation
calls for concentration.
Do you dig me Jack?
(Unison)
We dig you Jack.
Can you think of a plan?
We solid can.
To get me out
of this mess?
Er- yes, yes, yes.
(Unison) We'll start the music
and play it back.
Solid, Jack.
(Unison)
Solid Jack.
Can ya sing and dance?
- I'll take a chance.
Are your boots on right?
- I got 'em laced up tight.
Is Miss Miller a killer?
- From Spanish villa.
Is her dancin' mellow?
- Why mello as a cello.
(Unison)
Then it seems to me ob-vious-ly.
Why not go right
into your terpischore?
What will it be?
Don't look at me.
Now, let me see
what will it be?
I never could do
the Conga
Could never get
thru' the Conga.
But if you say
'do the Conga'
I ain't hep to that step.
but I'll dig it.
I never could
see Mazurkas
There poison to me
Mazurkas
But if it's to be
I ain’t hep to that step
but I'll dig it
(Unison) When they invented
the Charleston
He was a total flop.
Right! But say -
if you want to Charleston
I'll never stop
or dance till I drop.
I never could
dig the polka.
The corniest jig,
the polka.
But if you say
dig the polka.
I ain't hep to
that step but I'll dig it.
Hi Hank.
Hello there.
Did you get anywhere
with the Dean?
No, it seems that the article I wrote
on the decline of the harpsichord
and her sister instruments
is what really put me across.
Is that so?
Yeah, funny I don't even
remember writing that article.
Yet the Dean said it was so good, he
couldn't possibly think of flunking me.
Tough luck.
Yeah.
Cheer up boy it's probably
all for the best.
What have you
got there?
Encyclopedia.
Think of it Hank.
You'll go into your father's textile
business, a cog in a great industry.
Stamping you personality
on miles and miles of tweed
making the wheels turn.
Punching the clock -
listening to the song of the looms -
what volume is that?
It's... Ham to Ilk.
Why?
Oh, nothing.
Music wasn't for you, Hank.
You could never have got anywhere
with that beat-up trumpet of yours.
Your medium is textiles.
Your father was a textile man -
so was his father before him.
Why, you've got wool
in your blood Hank.
What's the bookmark for?
Oh, it's an article there -
rather interested the Dean.
You know, funny thing
about that article.
It's almost identical
with my thesis.
Interesting coincidence.
Yes, that's what
the Dean thought.
I had quite a time persuading him
that the marginal notes weren't mine.
As a matter of fact, I tried to convince
him that the handwriting wasn't yours.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What did he say?
He said you were fired.
You dog!
Now, take it easy,
Danny.
You low,
conniving dog!
You too will have
to face the world.
Fall right into your
father's concrete.
You'll be a cog
within a cog.
You can't get away
from it, Danny my boy.
You've got concrete
in your bones.
(Ellen) Danny, hey! Hurry!
Wonderful news!
A telegram!
"Will be in town Saturday. Would like
to look over your outfit." Artie Shaw.
Well, what do you know?
Hey, well there it is.
Shaw wants to look me over.
Look you over?
Look us over.
Alright, us. Hmm, seems to be
in a kind of a rush about it.
I wonder how soon
he wants me to start.
Hey, it didn't take him long
to find out I'd be available, did it?
You'll be available indefinitely,
I'm afraid.
Yeah. Now then, first thing tomorrow,
I must find Ellen a new job.
Don't bother.
As soon as I get set, I'll send for you.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
Alright. Let's get organized.
Call the boys and tell them
to be there early. Summer uniforms.
And you - you go home
and run your scales. Come on!
Look, fella. Don't bury it.
I'll be out in a few minutes.
Artie Shaw!
Artie Shaw, he's here!
Good, thanks.
Hey, what about
the buck you promised me?
Alright, alright beat it.
OK, gang. Sweet Sue.
Hank!
Shaw, he's coming in now!
Swell. Thanks, pal.
Come on, give out.
I'll bring you
some change.
Now, a nice and easy background
on this one, boys.
Hey, Danny.
Why don't you lay out on this one?
Save your lip till Shaw comes.
I'll take the lead.
Are you kiddin'?
I'm OK, I've been
in the woodshed.
You've been in the cornfield.
Alright, boys. One-two.
(Band plays "Sweet Sue")
Say, that's quite a little
shindig you're pitchin' in there.
Gee, thanks,
Mr. Shaw.
Band on straight
salary or percentage?
Oh, percentage.
Oh smart, uh!
Thanks again, Mr. Shaw.
Where's Mr. Miller?
Mr. Miller?
Yeah,
the manager of the band.
Oh, that Mr. Miller...
There she is.
This is Mr. Shaw, Mr. Miller -
I mean, er...
We've been expecting you,
Mr. Shaw.
Swell. If you're not too busy, I'd like
to talk to you for a few minutes.
Fine.
Won't you stay
and hear the band, Mr. Shaw?
I'd like to but I'm on my way
down to Trenton to play a date.
Anyway, it was nice
talking to you.
Thanks and goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Thanks.
No trouble.
Where is he?
He's gone.
Gone?
Where's Shaw? What did he say?
- He's gone. You ruined it.
What are you talkin' about?
I was terrific. When do I start?
Oh, take ten, son.
What was his proposition?
Well, his proposition
rather surprised me.
Oh!
Quibbled about salary?
Wait a minute,
I don't work on Sundays.
Look, Ellen,
what gives? When do I start?
You don't.
What?
Well, then what did he want?
Me.
Ellen!
- Oh, Danny!
I brought you this!
Oh, I guess I'm a little late.
Oh, Danny. How darling of you.
Hank's inside getting a ticket.
Is he?
Gosh, Ellen,
I hate to see you go.
Oh, I hate to go,
Danny.
I - I kinda
hoped that...
What Danny?
Oh, nothing. I guess
it was just silly, that's all.
No, it wasn't.
What was it?
Excuse me.
You're sprouting.
Here's some popcorn. Sonny, hold this
for the lady. Here's your ticket, Ellen.
Come on, I'll tell the conductor
when to let you off.
Now, be a good girl
and don't talk to any strange men.
I won't.
I'll see you in New York?
(Over-lapping) - I hope so.
- Yes.
Well, I don't know.
Portland's a long way from New York
and concrete
kinda holds a man down.
Well,
you'll be there, Hank?
No. I've gotta pay a lot of attention
to those mills in Fall River.
Well, I won't be seeing
either of you?
No.
Well, I'm afraid not.
(Conductor)
All aboard!
Well, goodbye, you idiots.
- Goodbye. Look after her orchids.
Goodbye!
Bye!
When do you start for Portland?
- Tonight.
When do you leave for Fall River?
- Oh, about an hour.
I'll see you off.
No, don't bother.
You've got to pack.
Yeah. Well, this is it.
Right. So long, Danny.
So long, kid. It's been a lot of fun.
- You bet it has. Take care of yourself.
I'll drop you a line.
- Do that.
A college band?
Whoever heard of a good college band?
Oh, we were under the impression
that this was an important affair.
Oh, it is.
Oh well in that case,
I know you'll want Mr. Shaw.
That's fine. Thank you.
A couple of relatives.
Well, what's cookin', Ellen?
We close the Atlantic City job
on our own terms.
That's swell.
And the intercollegiate prom.
Not a bad two day's work. Looks like
my hunch about you was pretty good.
I'm glad. Mr. Shaw, I...
I wonder if I could ask you a favor.
Of course.
It's - it's about
a couple of trumpet players.
Oh, well, you see I always pick
my own men, Ellen and I don't...
Of course, but all I want you to do
is hear these boys.
They're marvelous.
- Where are they? Around town?
Practically. One's in Portland
and the other's in Fall River.
But they could be here in a jiffy.
Isn't that a lot
of travelin' just for an audition?
But they wouldn't mind. And once you
hear them, you'll know what I mean.
If you think they're that good,
I'll listen to them.
Thank you.
- Not at all.
Call the Western Union boy to pick up
two telegrams. Thank you.
What floor is Artie Shaw on?
- (In unison) Seventeenth.
Going up.
Hold it, buddy.
What floor is Artie Shaw on?
- (Unison) Seventeenth.
Aren't you going
to Fall River the hard way?
I suppose this elevator
stops at Portland.
No, sir.
Last stop is the 22nd floor.
So you were going
to give a lot of time to the mills.
Listen, I've got as much right
here as you have.
Why don't you face facts, Hank?
Ellen's not even established yet.
She can't possibly
get us both in the band.
I'm going to get
a try-out with Artie Shaw
if I have to tear down
this building floor by floor.
17th floor next.
Here's a present
for you, Sam.
Have one on me, Sam.
Oh, excuse me.
Where's Artie Shaw's office, please?
- Right that way.
Oh, thanks.
(Overlapping dialogue)
Mr... Mr. Taylor to see Miss Miller.
Miss Miller's very busy
right now.
(Overlapping) She'll see me,
we went to college together.
Hey, is that 34 or 54
Highcroft Road?
34. Hey, wait a minute.
What have you got there?
Why, this is for me!
Yeah.
Hank, Shaw's
sending for me.
Me too. You know, I knew he'd
get around to that sooner or later.
Any answers?
We'll take care of the answers, bud.
Here.
Thanks.
It's alright.
What do you make of this?
- Look at that, Fall River.
Say! Excuse me...
Something phony about this.
Yeah.
He walked out on us
at the Prom, didn't he?
Yeah.
You don't suppose it was deliberate?
- Why would he?
You mean he'd want us to cool
for a while so we'd work for peanuts.
Listen, we're not that hard
to get.
No. But then he got Ellen
down here as a decoy,
thinking we'd work for nothing
on account of her.
That's it.
How do ya like it?
I don't like it.
He can't treat a friend of ours like that.
No, sir!
I'll fix him. Just for that, I'm gonna
ask for 25 dollars a week more.
Fifty!
Young lady, you can tell Shaw
that we'll see him.
Mr. Shaw is very busy.
Never mind, we'll tell him.
Thanks. Come on, Hank.
Hey, wait a minute.
Hi, Shaw.
Now, just a minute, fellas.
You'll have to wait outside.
I'm the new trumpet player
you just sent for.
And me too.
We've just got your wire.
What the?
Oh, yeah-well, you certainly
took your time getting here.
Well, we had a couple
of other offers to consider.
Alright, boys,
I tell you what you do.
Drop down to the hotel tonight and
play a couple of tunes for the band.
That'll be swell.
- Love to.
See you then,
I'm sorry, I'm pretty busy now.
Well, that's alright.
Which is Miss Miler's office?
Right across the hall.
Oh, thanks. Think I'll have
a little talk with her.
OK, Artie -
ha, ha, ha.
Ellen!
Danny! I can't believe
my eyes.
It's so good
to see you.
Kinda surprised you,
huh?
And Hank,
wherever did you come from?
Artie Shaw's office.
We were just talking
a little business.
But Portland?
Portland's loss
is your gain.
And Fall River?
Fall River will have
to suffer too.
Did Artie say anything
about giving you a try-out?
Oh, sure.
Oh, darlings,
that's wonderful!
Yes, but we haven't
promised him anything yet.
Straight ahead.
Hey, there!
Good evening, Cap.
I'm the new trumpet
player with Artie Shaw.
I ain't never seen
you before.
It's alright, you're going
to see plenty of me from now on.
Oh, by the way. If my brother
happens to drop around here tonight,
tell him that Shaw's not giving
any more auditions, see.
If he makes a fuss,
just throw him out.
You know how these little
family jealousies are. Thanks.
What's your name?
Danny O...
O' Taylor.
Danny, I'm so glad
you got here early.
I was lonesome. I haven't seen you
since late this afternoon.
Not a bad house.
How long are we booked here for?
You're only booked
for one number.
This audition?
Mere formality.
Where's Hank?
Hank?
How do I know?
Am I my brother's keeper?
I thought he was coming
with you.
He probably got
cold feet.
Couldn't face the humiliation
of being turned down.
Poor boy, I wish I could
do something to help him.
Oh, yes.
Ah, now, Ellen.
I'm very fond of Hank.
After all, he did bring
us together.
If it hadn't been
for those encyclopedias
I might never have met you.
I'll always be grateful
to him for that.
Won't you?
Danny, this is no time.
- Yes, it is. This is just the time.
Yesterday, what was I?
A carefree schoolboy.
Today what?
A man with his career assured,
a man with plans
for the future.
Danny, don't you think
you ought to be warming up?
I've been warmed up
a long time.
Ellen...
Shall I take
the vocal?
(Starts singing) Would you like to be
the love of my life
for always.
And always watch over me.
To square my blunders
and share my dreams.
One day with caviar.
Next day a chocolate bar.
Would you like
to take the merry-go-round,
I'll lead you
I need you - just wait
till you see.
I hope in your horoscope
There is room
for a dope who adores you.
That would make the only
dream of my life...
come true.
For the love
of my life...
is you.
Ellen.
So, I'm your brother,
huh?
I was afraid you
wouldn't make it.
You shouldn't worry about me,
brother Danny.
Ellen, I think
you'd better leave.
No, no, stick around.
What happened, Hank?
Brother Danny here
framed me with the doorman.
All I wanted was to be
alone with you for once.
See that?
He admits the whole thing.
Oh, now wait a minute.
- That doorman hit me in the lip.
He did?
- Yeah.
Oh, that's too bad.
- How'd you like to even it up, huh?
Oh no, boys, please.
You have to go on in a minute.
You're putting me
in an awful position.
Now, come on, let's forget it. I'll tell
Artie you're here. Good luck, darlings.
Yeah, darlings.
You haven't forgotten
the two trumpet players?
No, I'll be right with you.
(Applause)
Quick, let's go.
I'll put your boys on, but first give me
a hand with that character over there.
He's been here ten nights in a row.
He's an awful ear bend.
Well, well.
Mr. Chisholm,
this is Miss Miller.
How do you do,
Miss Miller?
Well, sir, did that last number
jump for you?
Oh, very peppy.
Very peppy indeed.
By the way,
what chord did we finish on?
Er, B flat.
Shaw, I missed it again.
Won't you two join me?
I'm sorry, I've got to get back
and play the next number.
But Miss Miller
can tell you all about the band.
Is Miss Miller hep as you boys say?
- Hep as they come.
Fascinating, swing jargon.
I'm becoming hep to it myself.
Well, see you later, Mr. Chisholm.
- So long, gate.
That's short for alligator.
Please be seated.
Are you a musician,
Mr. Chisholm?
Oh, I should have been
but I was forced to give it up.
I said music and father said
bottle caps. Father won.
Oh, what a pity. I take it
that the banjo is your instrument.
Oh, no, the mandolin.
The flat-back mandolin.
Alright, you're on.
What do you want to play?
How about
"I'm Yours"?
That's a tough
arrangement to play at sight.
I'll play anything
that's on the paper.
OK. How about you?
Pick one.
Alright, I'll leave the book with you.
Look 'em over.
Artie! On the question of who plays first,
may I suggest alphabetical order -
in the interest of fairness?
Sure, OK. Alright,
we're on in about three minutes.
What's the matter? Aren't you
going to look over your parts?
I couldn't hit a bad note
if I tried. Not tonight.
Why is tonight
an exception?
Oh, I don't know.
It makes all the difference when you
know someone's depending on you.
What?
Oh, nothing, nothing
nothing at all
Who's depending
on you?
Nobody. Forget it, Hank,
forget it.
Say, you were alone here
with Ellen when I came in.
For almost the first time
since I've known her.
Yeah? Well, what happened?
What did you say to her?
Look, Hank.
Ellen and I...
I don't suppose it's
any concern of yours,
but when I get set with Shaw,
Ellen and I...
You proposed to her.
What did she say?
She just looked at me and gave her
tender unspoken yes.
How do you know
it wasn't an unspoken no?
A fella can tell.
One of those rare occasions when
silence was more eloquent than words.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Alright. That's the way it is. I wish
you all the happiness in the world.
Have me over
for dinner sometime.
Thanks, Hank.
- Alright.
I'm glad you're not gonna
let this come between us.
OK. Here we go.
Here we are, Danny. You know
what I wish you, Danny boy.
Yeah.
(Out of tune)
Fascinating music.
I can't understand it.
(High-pitched note)
Well, that was just dandy.
I'll be sure and call you.
In the meanwhile, if anything
else comes up, take it!
You sure you know
what you're doing?
Say the word.
OK, fellas.
Here we go - one, two.
See what I mean?
I've even got music in my feet.
(Noise of fighting)
Excuse me.
(Arguing)
Well, have you finished, the both
of you? You've ruined everything.
After all you've pretended
to think of me.
After I've tried so hard.
After Artie went...
Please, I never want to see
either of you again.
Danny O'Neill?
Who have you played with?
Er - O'Neill's Perennials.
Never heard of them.
Have you heard of
Artie Shaw?
Oh, were you associated
with him?
Associated with him?
I made a deeper impression on him
than any trumpet player he ever heard.
One moment please.
Artie, there was one thing about
last night. Maybe I shouldn't bring it up.
Now, wait a minute.
If it's about those...
No, no, no. It's about Mr. Chisholm.
No, I mean it.
(Phone buzzes)
Yeah? Who? Him? Are you kiddin'?
Well, throw him out.
Anything serious?
Naw!
Out!
- Alright.
Hello. Tell Tommy that
Hank Taylor's here, will you?
Get off the desk.
Uh? Alright.
Of course, Mr. Chisholm
talks a lot but he's sweet.
He says he has the soul of an artist
but that his money's stifling it.
Now, you've always wanted
to give a concert.
I know I can get him
to back you.
How do I know he's different from those
crunchy, crinkle breakfast food guys?
They've all got some angle.
Alright, I'll guarantee to get him
without one string attached.
No musts about what I should play?
- None.
No bottle cap ads?
- Honor bright.
OK. Sounds swell if you can do it.
- Good. I'll get to work on it right away.
(Phone buzzes)
Yeah? What? Him?
Throw him out.
Alright. Now wait a minute, I've got
offers from Miller, Duchin, Goodman.
I got plenty of jobs.
Don't say I didn't give you a chance.
I think I'll put a small wager
on Magic Melody.
Lester, you're wonderful.
Always willing to back
something musical.
Artists need a man
like you.
You think so?
(Trumpet playing "Hunting song"
in a jazzy fashion)
Old English hunting song,
I believe.
My dear, are you choking?
(Russian-sounding music)
This place was one of my finds.
They're all real musicians.
Too bad they're not
better known.
Ellen, you remember what you said -
I might be able to help?
Why can't I give
these musicians to the world?
Oh, but your first duty
is to the American artists.
Oh, yes. So it is.
Look at him. Centuries of Slavic
balance have gone into that dance.
Vos goot!
Vos goot? Vos perfect!
(Sings "Love Of My Life"
in pseudo-Russian gobbledygook)
He's miles away. Perhaps dreaming
of a little girl on the Steppes of Russia.
You can tell by his face
he's loved and suffered.
Oh, please take me home,
I can't stand any more of this.
I can't tell you how much I appreciate
you letting me back this concert.
Not at all, not at all.
And how grateful I am
to you, Ellen.
To think, after all these years,
I'm back in my true medium.
By the way, how much
did you say I should arrange for?
Er, roughly fifteen thousand.
Oh, wouldn't you say
that twenty would be safer?
After all, J. Lester Chisholm
must stand for nothing but the best.
There she goes, there she goes -
always thinking of me.
I can't tell you what a jewel
you have in this little girl.
I'm finding out every day.
And what an inspiration.
Mother thinks that every girl
who's attracted to me
is after the
Chisholm money.
(Door buzzer)
Come in. Oh, Lester.
Stay where you are.
Don't move.
You don't know what a picture
you make in the candlelight.
Lester, you've brought
your mandolin.
For you.
Oh, you shouldn't have.
Why not? Tonight's
our night to celebrate, isn't it?
I thought we might have
a quiet evening of music.
Just you and I.
I always say there's nothing
like duets to make a home a home.
Can I use your house phone, please?
- Certainly.
Who do you wish to speak to?
- Miss Miller.
Who's calling?
- Mr. er... Dunn.
Oh, Mr. Dunn.
Hello.
Hello, Ellen. It's me, Danny.
I've been trying
to get in touch with you.
I'm downstairs.
And I thought maybe I could...
No, I can't see you tonight.
No, I'm not being vindictive.
I just can't see you.
Of course, Hank isn't here.
Look, Danny,
I'll have to talk to you tomorrow.
No, he isn't.
Ellen, wait a minute.
Goodnight, Mr. Dunn.
Er, goodnight.
Mr. Dunn...
That was just an old college friend
I was talking to.
We won't be disturbed again,
Lester.
Shall we continue while
we're in the groove?
(Chisholm singing)
(Singing badly) Beautiful Dreamer,
queen of my song.
List while I woo thee
with soft melody.
What was that?
B-flat.
No, I heard a noise.
Is there someone in there?
Hardly. That's my bedroom.
Now, don't be nervous.
I'm not a bit nervous.
See, just as I told you,
it's your imagination.
(Door shuts)
(Like a dog) Grrr...
Yes boy, yes boy.
(Sniffing, then howling)
Sport, shut up.
Ouch!
Hank!
What do you hear
from the gang in college?
What do you think
you're doing under this bed?
Looking for a collar button.
I've got as much right
under here as you have.
Say, if you're in here,
I wonder who's out there?
That's right.
I thought it was you.
Better investigate.
No, wait a minute. We don't want
to upset Ellen - today of all days.
That's right.
Not today.
So that's why you came up.
I thought so.
What are you
talkin' about?
Well, you just happened to call on the
day Shaw announced his concert.
Well, I read something
about the concert in the paper.
But I'm much too
busy to help Artie out.
I'm working like a horse.
You're working?
Sure.
Not with Dorsey.
No. He wouldn't change his style
to suit me.
I've got a little engagement
just out of town.
I never had such
a big audience.
Fourth trumpet, huh?
No sir, boy.
Strictly solo stuff.
Why? Is the concert
the reason for your visit?
Who, me?
- Yeah.
I'm much too busy for that.
- Doin' what?
After I quit Whiteman.
- You quit Whiteman?
Sure, too big a
band for me.
If I'd stayed with him,
I'd have lost my individuality.
Same thing happened
to Bix.
So you're unemployed,
huh?
No, not at all. I've just hooked up
with a terrific European outfit.
I never dreamed such
things could be done to music.
I wonder what's going on
out there?
Sounds as if she's giving
somebody an audition.
I never heard of Shaw with
a mandolin section.
What about a breather?
- That's a wonderful idea!
Sometimes it's a little tiring.
- Yes.
Let's have a toast
to the concert.
(Chisholm off screen) Ellen, you've
made me feel like a boy again.
(Ellen off screen) Really?
(Chisholm) You've made me believe
that money really isn't a handicap.
(Cork popping)
(Ellen) That's what I want you
to believe, Lester.
(Chisholm) To think,
after all these years,
I've something to look forward to.
Well, to our big night.
- To our big night.
She's being
taken advantage of.
She seems to be liking it.
I've seen that fella before.
Where was it?
At the Russian restaurant -
The Little Bear.
The Little Wolf. I saw him
with her at the racetrack.
We've got to get her out of this.
- What are we waitin' for?
Would you have another glass?
- I don't think I should.
Well, you know best.
That's what I admire
about you, Ellen.
You're so different
from the other girls in this town.
Oh. I can hardly
believe that, Lester.
You wouldn't.
You're so innocent.
You wouldn't believe
the carryings-on.
Oh, I've been told things.
(Sound of bucket
being kicked over)
What's that?
Somebody out there.
You're just imagining
things again.
No, look.
(Whistle sound)
What in the world?
(Danny off-screen) He's not home,
is he, Ellen?
Who is it?
Danny!
Oh, er, it's just a neighbor.
He always wants to borrow the lawn-
mower or something. Excuse me.
Danny, Danny, is it you?
Is that guy here again?
Pardon me, Mr...
Chisholm.
Oh, Chisholm, yes.
Ellen told me about you.
Yeah, I guess she's
getting rid of him.
Well, she'd better.
You know, I told her flatly -
I said it's either him or me.
You know, I used to
trust that guy.
I went to college with him. I shared
my room, my tie, my troubles.
But I won't share Ellen.
You don't blame me,
do you?
I didn't know.
I think I'd better be going.
No, I didn't mean you.
Stick around.
Make yourself at home.
Do you need anything?
No.
Glad to have met you.
Oh, mercy!
Danny,
how dare you come up here?
I'm glad I came up.
Well, I'm not.
Get off this roof this instant.
You need me, Ellen.
What?
Oh, I'm not blaming you
for one moment, but.
What are you
talking about?
He's not the kind of person
to be around you.
You don't know
what you're getting into.
Of course, it's not your fault.
Hank and I both realize that.
Hank? Is he here
too?
Yes, he's inside
taking care of the details.
Good heavens!
Oh, dear.
Lester! Lester, wait a minute -
Lester.
Why didn't you tell me
you were married?
But I'm not married.
Then who's that man?
Oh, that was just Hank.
Ellen, I can't believe it.
You of all people.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
Well, you mustn't
be so upset.
I'll send him away.
Now, don't make
it worse, Ellen.
I can't stand it.
I'm leaving for Cincinnatti
in the morning.
Cinncinnatti?
Well, what about the concert?
Well, you can tell Mr. Shaw how much
I appreciate the chance he gave me.
Under the circumstances
I can't accept it.
Oh, but Lester you can't throw away
your whole musical career.
My musical career is over.
Here, I'll never touch it again.
Oh, he said "I didn't know."
Poor Mr. Chisholm.
- Poor Mr. Chisholm
Poor Mr. Chisholm
played on the mandolin
But he couldn't win
Cos he tried to swing
And he broke a string
every time.
Oh, he says -
"I'd better be going."
Poor Mr. Chisholm.
Just couldn't dig the jive.
When he did arrive
at the proper note - he...
Now look Ellen.
Now, this is all
for the best
What we did may have
been a little drastic.
Yes, it may seem
a little brutal at first.
But you'll thank us
for it later.
So I'll thank you for it.
I suppose that Artie'll
thank you for it too.
Artie?
What do you mean, Artie?
What's Artie got to do
with Mr. Chisholm?
Nothing.
Nothing in the world.
He was only the backer
of the concert.
Concert?
Oh!
Alright, let's go again.
Shh!
Ellen, you've got
to listen to me.
There's only one thing
I've got to do.
Tell Artie the concert is off. Then
leave town by the first train I can get.
Ellen, you can't. I'm awfully
sorry about all this trouble.
I wouldn't hurt you for the world.
You know how I feel about you.
Remember the other night,
when I took the vocal?
I wasn't kidding.
There's one part I remember -
the merry-go-round I'll lead you.
You weren't kidding.
- That's over, the merry-go-round is out.
No, Danny. It's too late.
- No, it isn't.
Go back in and act
as if nothing's happened -
I'll have Chisholm
back here in an hour.
What can you do?
Don't worry. Just don't say anything
to Shaw until I get back.
What can I say?
You can do it. Give me an hour.
Alright, Danny.
One hour.
That's right.
Hurry up,
he's checking out.
What 20,000?
Oh, that 20,000.
Send it back
to Cinncinnatta.
I'm going back
there myself.
On second thought,
Joe, you just leave it where it is.
You bounder.
Leave this room immediately.
Mr. Chisholm, I brought
you your mandolin.
I won't listen.
Leave this room.
Take it easy. You're going to listen
whether you want to or not.
We've come
to clear Ellen's name.
I won't hear her name
mentioned in my presence.
Oh, now don't
say that, Mr. Chisholm.
Who are you?
I'm a man who
wants to see justice done.
Alright, talk.
- No, I can't.
Come clean.
- Alright.
Mr. Chisholm,
I have a confession to make.
I've never done this before
in my life. I lied to you.
Go on.
- Alright.
Ellen is innocent.
Innocent?
I saw with my own eyes.
He framed her deliberately.
Impulsively.
I am not Ellen's husband.
I know that.
Who are you?
Me?
He's her -
her brother, Hank.
Brother?
Aren't you ashamed?
Yes.
Why did you endeavor
to create this false impression?
I - I - I was trying
to protect her.
Hit it.
(Rapid dialogue)
We didn't know who you were.
And how much
you meant to her.
You're just about
the most important man in her life.
Oh, I didn't realize.
Oh, what have I done?
You've acted shabbily.
You have misjudged
a wonderful girl.
Jumped to brutal
conclusions.
Oh, dear. Do you think
she'll ever forgive me?
Well, there's a chance -
if you go about it in the right way.
Yes, if you crawl back
to her on your hands and knees.
And beg her
to forgive and forget.
Oh, I will. Do you think this will interfere
with letting me back the concert?
Well, I don't think so.
No. Ellen isn't small.
But you'd better hurry.
Oh, I will. I'll get my hat
and gloves.
Er, you make yourselves
at home.
Poor Mr. Chisholm.
Well, we've finally
done right by our Ellen.
It's about time.
Yeah. Makes you
feel good, doesn't it?
You know, self-sacrifice,
doing unto others.
That's the life.
Yeah, but a little self-sacrifice
goes a long way.
We ought to think of our
own careers for a change.
After all, we are the intimate friends
of Shaw's backer.
No, we mustn't use Chisholm.
We owe it to Ellen not to
take any more chances.
Oh, no. Ellen won't respect
a couple of failures.
It's true if it wasn't for us
the concert would be off.
Certainly.
He owes us a break.
Here I go. Boys, if there's ever
anything I can do.
Nonsense, Mr. Chisholm.
We're glad to do a good turn.
If there's anything
we can do for you.
Oh, you've already
done enough.
Oh, I mean helping you
select numbers for the concert
and that sort of thing.
You see, I don't select
the numbers for the concert.
Why, I hardly dare
venture an opinion.
But you should.
After all,
I'm only the backer.
Only the backer?
Why, Mr. Chisholm,
you're the impresario.
The most important man
in the entire organization.
You've got to be
the guiding hand.
Choose the music.
Pick the men.
It's your duty.
Think of the other backers.
You're letting them down.
You're letting Shaw down.
This is terrible. Why didn't anyone
ever tell me this before?
Why, I would have been
delighted to do it.
It's not too late.
- Not if you work fast.
I don't know which way to start.
What would you suggest?
First of all,
line up a number.
That's a good idea,
but off-hand I can't think.
Oh, sure you remember the...
rolling-back-to-mammy-
on-the-big-river blues.
Rolling back to mammy
on the big river blues.
That's it, he's got it.
- He's got it.
Now, don't be too hasty.
Perhaps I can think
of something better.
What about
a folk song?
A folk song.
I've got just the
number for you.
Listen to this.
Oh, you're gonna
like this Chis.
This is back to the good earth,
full of sweep - play that, Danny.
I like that.
What's it called?
"Hoe-down the bayou."
Do you hear that?
That's New Orleans.
I visited there.
Three weeks.
I don't recognize it.
You don't?
Well, that's the spirit
of New Orleans.
I can almost smell
the Delta.
I can smell the Delta.
Can't you smell
the Delta?
I have a slight cold.
Well, nothing that
your mandolin won't cure.
Now you pick this up,
Chis. Pick it up, boy.
Yeah, yeah, come on, son.
The train won't wait.
That's it.
Now, we're sailin' up that river
on the Memphis, Chattanooga.
Hold on, Chis.
Hear them steamboat whistles blowin.'
Tote that barge, pull that bale.
There's a cabin in the cotton,
Solid South, solid North, solid Jack.
Solid Jack.
Right, wagon wheels-a-creakin'
Westward.
Now, we're rollin' past that junction
on to Kansas, Cincinnatti.
Cincinnatti, my home town.
His hometown, your hometown,
everybody's hometown. Cincinatti!
Boys, words fail me.
I must see Shaw at once.
That's the spirit, Chisholm.
Don't let America down.
You sure it's my duty
as a backer?
You can do anything.
Anything?
Certainly.
Alright. I'll not only see that this
epic-making number of yours
is given the finest presentation
in the world, but I'll go further.
I'll play in it myself -
on my mandolin.
What?
A rhythm in letter B.
I'll set the tempo at C.
Trombones make a definite entrance.
Saxes come in good and strong,
and strings pick it up
from there.
Ellen, can you ever forgive me?
- Oh Lester.
I know I don't deserve it. I've let you
down in more ways than one.
But I'm going to make up
for it right now.
Shaw, can I see you
a minute.
Hi!
Take ten, fellas.
Hello Mr. Chisholm
glad you dropped in.
I didn't just drop in Mr. Shaw.
Sit down please. And you Ellen.
I realized I've shirked my duties
but I've got something to make up for it.
A folk song for the concert,
it'll kill you.
Folk song?
It's got everything.
The sweep of the prairies,
creaking of wagons,
the Mississippi.
Sounds peachy.
It goes like this.
Da da da da da.
Hoe down the bayou.
Can't you smell the delta?
(Whistles)
Chattanooga, Louisiana,
solid North, solid South.
Hoe down boy, hoo!
That's the steamboat whistle.
That's my home town, your home
town, everybody's home town.
Cincinatta!
Are you kidding?
It'll sweep the country.
I insist that you play it
at the concert.
(Overlapping)
If that's the way you feel about...
Prairies, wagons, steamboat whistles.
- That's its sweep.
Listen Artie I've heard part of it.
It's not a bad song.
How can I tell from that?
Get me someone who can play it.
I'll get you the composer himself.
He's right outside, right away.
I fixed it.
Good boy Chis.
You've done
a great job.
Go in there and give 'em
all you've got.
Maybe we'd better explain
about our secret.
I could back you up
on the mandolin.
No, no, no. Save it.
You don't want to give
away the big surprise.
No practice comes first.
Besides you're no
song plugger.
Would Heifetz go around
selling songs to band leaders?
That's fine I'll stand by
and explain it as you play it.
Er...
We'd better stay out here, too many
people might make Shaw nervous.
Well I might be needed.
Come on down the lobby,
I'll buy you a cigar.
I don't like cigars.
Don't you worry about it
I'll smoke it myself.
Artie he'll be here
in a minute.
I know but I'm holding up
a whole rehearsal Ellen.
Hello Mr. Shaw.
Oh, it's you again,
huh?
I guess so.
You aren't going
to let something that's over
stand in the way
of a good song?
OK. Let's hear it, this better be good.
- Yes sir.
Poor Mr. Chisholm played
on the mandolin.
But he couldn't win.
'Cos he tried to swing
and he broke a string, every time.
Poor Mr. Chisholm
just couldn't dig the jive.
When he did arrive
at the proper note,
he arrived by boat,
every time.
He tried to jazz up
his mandolin.
But never could
quite control it.
He always brought
Bach and Handel in.
When he took a lick,
he always broke a pick.
Poor Mr. Chisholm
you're quite a gay old blade
with your serenade.
But you're corny Jack,
better truck on back
to the buke.
Get a uke.
You disgraced your kin
on the mandolin, every time.
Did you like the tune Artie?
- Kinda cute.
Make an arrangement of it
and maybe we can find a spot for it.
But remember
no trouble this time.
Don't worry Mr. Shaw.
And thanks a lot.
Mr. Chisholm playing a mandolin,
that'll really be something.
Alright Ben,
call the boys.
I'm within the hour.
Chilsholm is back.
I'm making an arrangement.
You see Ellen I've settled down.
The merry-go-round's out.
Out nothing, you just happen
to get the brass ring.
This is your big chance, Danny.
- I hope.
Did he understand it?
- Did he go for it?
Hook, line and Cincinatti.
- Nice going boy!
Wonderful!
Calls for a celebration.
Attaboy Danny.
Fellow artists, I give you the concert.
- We accept it.
Lester we're proud
of you.
Oh Ellen,
I'm only the backer.
That's a very important
role Lester.
It's not as though
I was a real contributor,
as though I was one
of the performers.
Well, now look...
We just about killed this bottle.
What kind of a host are you?
How about a refill?
Oh excuse me,
of course, of course.
Oh, you won't tell her
while I'm gone?
Not a chance.
- Don't worry about it.
Lester, wait a minute,
tell me what?
It's just a little surprise. Let's tell her.
I'm gonna play in the concert.
Lester you're not.
Well I am,
I knew you'd be delighted.
What am I standing here for?
Wine is what we need, wine.
So the merry-go-round
is still on?
We couldn't help it,
all we did was flatter him a bit.
If we disillusioned him,
he'd call the whole thing off.
What do you suppose Shaw will do?
- Shaw will never find out.
Hank's going to keep
Chisholm away from him.
Me? Oh no!
But I'll be busy
with my arrangement.
Alright I'll make a bargain
with you.
You get me a job with Shaw
with a nice fat trumpet part
and I'll look after
Chisholm.
Oh sure.
I'll do my best.
You'll do better
than that or else.
(Applause)
That'll get 'em Artie.
- Oh, it was wonderful.
Glad you like it.
Here's my
arrangement.
Oh fine. You make all the
changes we talked about.
Yeah, but I don't know
how good it'll sound after that.
Artie, there's one little favor
I want to ask you.
You're gonna use some extra
trumpets. I know a fella that...
Not that partner of yours,
that guy can't get through number
without falling off the stand.
Nothin' doin', period.
We'll run over this in the morning.
Danny, what are we going to do
about poor Hank?
It's going to be tough
but we'll keep on trying.
Ninety-six, two, three, seven...
Two, three... ninety-eight...
Two, three, ninety-nine... Two, three
and one hundred and stop.
One hundred times
without a slip.
No, no. You were pretty fuzzy
on thirty-seven.
You were a quarter
beat off on seventy-six.
Now you take one more
hundred and we'll turn in.
No, now it's just two days
before the concert.
I'd better go down
and tell Artie our secret.
No not yet.
It's too late tonight anyhow.
It isn't, the band's
staying late to rehearse.
You haven't
practiced enough.
I've practiced for ten days,
twelve hours a day,
six hours a night.
I'll go stale.
Are you ready?
One... Two...
Tonight at 8:30,
Artie Shaw will present an interesting
newcomer to the musical world.
Interesting newcomer
that must mean me.
What?
Yes sure, sure, sure.
Henry, are you worried
about the rehearsal?
Me no.
Is it worrying you?
Not at all. There are few troubles
that a good nights sleep won't cure.
Look you watch
your own health,
I've got insomnia.
Insomnia, that's too bad
you should er...
(Knock on door)
Come in.
Good afternoon
Mr. Chisholm.
Hello,
well what about a drink?
Good idea.
I'll be right back.
I just want to spruce up a bit.
Hello. Give me
the Majestic Theatre, will you?
It's better so...
What? What's that?
What about her?
Yeah. Wait a minute, excuse me Chis,
this is a personal matter.
Say Danny you wouldn't lie to me
at a time like this, would you?
It's all set, you're in!
You gotta' get down here right away.
Well this makes up for
a lot of things Danny.
What Chisholm?
Wait a minute don't you worry
about Chisholm.
I just got a plan
to keep him here.
You bet, so long.
Good news?
- It depends on your point of view.
One man's drink is
another man's poison.
Yeah... Well Henry everything
happens for the best.
You know it's always
darkest just before dawn.
S'right.
The lad worthwhile is the lad
who can smile
when the rest of the word's
gone wrong.
Right, right as rain.
We'll have it over here.
Henry if ever anything
comes between us,
always remember I had your
best interest at heart.
That cuts both ways
partner.
Well happy days.
- Happy dreams.
Bottoms up.
There must be
some answer.
Well never mind.
I can't raise Hank anywhere.
He'll never believe
I didn't have anything to do with this.
Last week I'd been sure
you had, but this week no.
You know you're improving
so amazingly Danny
I think I'll make you
my manager.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen
we have a little blues number,
which recently came to my attention
bearing the somewhat ambiguous title,
"Hoedown the Bayou".
Since then it has grown up and been
transformed into something special.
Before playing it, I'd like to introduce
the man who wrote it: Danny O'Neil.
Go on.
How do you feel?
Alright.
OK. It's all yours.
Danny you were
wonderful.
Nice work Danny!
I'm gonna' have to hire you after all.
Thanks Artie.
Only because I don't want
to lose a good secretary.
(Crowd)
Artie Shaw, Artie Shaw!
Nobody.
Ninety-nine... One hundred...
Take it again.
I hope in your horoscope
there is room for a dope,
who adores you.
Vas goot!
Vas perfect!