♪♪ [Orchestra]
Where's that
marine lieutenant?
Lieutenant Cable!
Yes?
The captain wants to know
if you’d like to sit up
in the cockpit with him.
Sure. Thanks.
Ah, pull up a chair,
marine.
I'm Buzz Adams.
Glad to know you.
Joe Cable.
Nice to meet you, Joe.
What are those islands
over there?
[Buzz]
Japanese.
All of'em?
Just a minute.
[Explosions]
Yeah, they're unfriendly.
Well, take it up!
What's the idea?
It's all right.
I just wanted to show
the lieutenant.
Thanks. I'll take
your word for it.
You gotta do something
to break the monotony,
Lieutenant.
If this war ever
really gets started—
It'll get started.
Sure, sure,
it'll get started.
Yeah.
You, uh, ever hear of
a French civilian
down where we're going...
named Emile De Becque?
Yeah.
What do you know about him?
Nobody knows much about him.
He's rich, got a big
plantation on a hill,
hunts, fishes.
What's he doing out here?
Story goes that he had
to beat it out of France
some 15, 16 years ago.
Nobody seems
to know much why.
How 'bout taking me
on your mission
with you, Lieutenant?
Who says I'm on
any mission?
My mistake?
Your mistake.
Sorry.
Now, here we are.
You see over there?
That's the fleet hospital
where they keep the nurses.
That's where
the Seabees play.
[Male Chorus]
♪ Bloody Mary is the girl I love. ♪
[Laughing]
♪ Now ain't that too damn bad! ♪
♪ Her skin is tender as a baseball glove. ♪
♪ Her skin is tender
as a baseball glove. ♪
♪ Her skin is tender as a baseball glove. ♪
♪ Now ain't that too damn bad! ♪
♪ Bloody Mary's chewing betel nuts, ♪
♪ She is always chewing betel nuts, ♪
♪ And she don't use Pepsodent! ♪♪
[Men Clapping, Whooping]
[Men Hooting, Clapping]
♪ Now ain't that ♪
Hey, Stewpot, Professor!
♪ Too damn bad! ♪♪
[Men Cheering]
Here you are, Mary.
Put 'em down, Professor.
These beautiful
grass skirts...
were made by myself,
the Professor and Stewpot
and three other Seabees...
in half the time
it takes your native workers
to make 'em.
See? No stretch.
Look 'em over, sweaty pie,
and give me a price.
- All hand-tied.
- Now, what do you say, sweat-so.
What am I offered?
Gee, pretty nice work.
Did you hear that?
You can probably sell these
to the chumps...
for five or six dollars apiece.
Now, let's make a quick deal.
I'll let you have the whole
batch for say, um, 80 bucks.
Give you 10 dollar.
What?
[Men Chuckling]
Aah! Now, see here,
dragon lady. You—
Hey, what's that
you got there?
A boar's tooth bracelet.
Where'd you get that?
Over there on Bali Ha'i?
You like?
Hey, come here.
Come here.
You don't run into
these things every day.
They're scarce
as hen's teeth.
They're bigger too.
That darn Bali Ha'i.
Why does it have to be
off-limits?
You can get everything
over there—
shrunken heads, bracelets.
Only officers
can sign out boats.
I'll get a boat,
all right.
I'll latch on
to some officer who's
got some imagination,
who would like to see that
boar's tooth ceremonial
as much as I would.
It's a pip
of a ceremonial.
Dancin', drinkin',
everything.
Why, you big phony.
We all know why you
wanna go to Bali Ha'i.
Yeah? Why?
Because
the French planters...
put their young women
over there when they heard
the G.I.'s were coming.
That's why.
Just as if they
didn't trust us.
The trouble with you is,
ain't boar's teeth.
It's women.
It is boar's teeth...
and women.
♪ We got sunlight on the sand,
We got moonlight on the sea, ♪
♪ We got mangoes and bananas
We can pick right off a tree, ♪
♪ We got volley ball and ping pong
And a lot of dandy games. ♪
♪ What ain't we got? ♪
♪ We ain't got dames. ♪
♪ We get packages from home, ♪
♪ We get movies,
We get shows, ♪
-♪ We get speeches from our skipper ♪
-♪ And advice from Tokyo Rose, ♪
♪ We get letters doused wid poifume,
We get dizzy from de smell! ♪
♪ What don't we get? ♪
♪ You know damn well! ♪
♪ We got nothin'
to put on a clean
white suit for, ♪
♪ What we need is what there
ain't no substitute for. ♪
♪ There is nothin' like a dame, ♪
♪ Nothin' in the world, ♪
♪ There is nothin' you can name ♪
♪ That is anythin' like a dame. ♪
♪ We feel restless,
We feel blue, ♪
♪ We feel lonely and, in brief♪
♪ We feel ev'ry kind of feeling ♪
♪ but the feeling of relief. ♪
♪ We feel hungry
as the wolf felt when
he met Red Riding Hood. ♪
♪ What don't we feel? ♪
♪ We don't feel good! ♪
♪ Lots of things in life are beautiful,
But brother, ♪
♪ There is one particular thing
that is nothing whatsoever
in any way, shape or form ♪
♪ like any other. ♪
♪ There is nothin' like a dame, ♪
♪ Nothin' in the world, ♪
♪ There is nothin' you can name ♪
♪ That is anythin' like a dame. ♪
♪ Nothin' else is built the same! ♪
♪ Nothin' in the world ♪
♪ Has a soft and wavy frame ♪
♪ like the silhouette of a dame. ♪
[Deep Voice]
♪ There is absolutely nothin' ♪
♪ like the frame ♪
♪ of a dame. ♪
[Women]
Hup, two, three, four.
Pick 'em up. Set 'em down.
Hello.
Luther.
[Mockingly]
Yes, Miss Forbush.
Have you done
what you promised?
Yes, Miss Forbush.
I did it all last night.
Uh, uh, you don't
have to open it now.
Oh!
Why, you do
beautiful work, Luther!
Gosh, I guess I'm just
about the luckiest nurse on
this island to have found you.
You're a treasure.
Hup, two, three, four.
♪♪ [All Whistling]
She's a nice little girl.
But some of them nurses,
the officers can have 'em.
They got 'em.
Well, they can have 'em.
♪ So suppose a dame ain't bright,
Or completely free from flaws ♪
♪ Or as faithful as a bird dog
or as kind as Santa Claus? ♪
♪ It's a waste of time
to worry over things
that they have not. ♪
♪ Be thankful for ♪
♪ the things they've got! ♪
Hup, two, three, four.
[Men]
♪ There is nothin' you can name ♪
♪ That is anythin' like a dame ♪
♪ There are no books like a dame ♪
♪ And nothin' looks like a dame. ♪
♪ There are no drinks like a dame, ♪
♪ And nothin' thinks like a dame, ♪
♪ Nothin' acts like a dame. ♪
♪ Or attracts like a dame. ♪
♪ There ain't a thing
that's wrong with
any man here ♪
♪ That can't be cured
by puttin' him near ♪
♪ A girly, womanly, female, ♪
♪ feminine dame! ♪
♪ There is nothin' you can name ♪
♪ that is anythin' ♪♪
Hello.
You make trouble for me?
Huh?
Are you crummy major?
No, I'm even crummier
than that.
I'm a lieutenant.
"Lootellan."
Lootellan.
Hiya, Lootellan.
New on the rock?
Just flew in
on that P.B.Y.
- Where from?
- Little island south of Marie Louise.
Hey, Lootellan.
You sexy man.
[Men Laughing]
Thanks. Uh, you're
looking pretty, uh,
fit yourself.
[All Laughing]
Sexy!
Who's she?
Ah, nobody.
She's Tonkinese.
You got sweetheart?
Take home Chicago
to sexy sweetheart.
Oh, no, she's a Philadelphia girl.
I doubt that she'd quite appreciate.
What's that
"Philadelia" girl?
What's that mean?
No sexy?
[All Laughing]
You like,
I give you free.
Free? You never give me
anything free.
You no sexy
like Lootellan.
[All Laughing]
Take.
No, thanks.
Where'd you get that anyway?
Bali Ha'i.
[Female Chorus]
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪♪
There's your officer.
[Whispering]
Leave it to me.
Intriguin' little island,
ain't it, Lieutenant?
Officers can get launches
and go over there.
Bali Ha'i.
What's that mean?
Bali Ha'i mean
"I am your special island."
Mean "Here I am."
Bali Ha'i your special
island, Lootellan.
I know.
You listen.
You hear island
call to you.
Listen.
You no hear something?
You hear voice?
♪ Mos' people live ♪
♪ on a lonely island ♪
♪ Lost in de middle ♪
♪ of a foggy sea ♪
♪ Mos' people long ♪
♪ for a nudder island ♪
♪ One where dey know ♪
♪ dey would like to be ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i may call you ♪
♪ Any night,
any day ♪
♪ In your heart
You'll hear it call you ♪
♪ "Come away, come away." ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i will whisper ♪
♪ On de wind of de sea; ♪
♪ "Here am I,
Your special island!" ♪
♪ "Come to me, come to me!" ♪
♪ Your own special hopes, ♪
♪ Your own special dreams ♪
♪ Bloom on de hillside ♪
♪ And shine
in de streams. ♪
♪ If you try, ♪
♪ You'll find me ♪
♪ Where de sky
meets de sea, ♪
♪ "Here am I,
Your special island!" ♪
♪ "Come to me.
Come to me!" ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪
♪ Someday you'll see me, ♪
♪ Floatin' in de sunshine, ♪
♪ My head stickin' out ♪
♪ F'um a low flyin' cloud. ♪
♪ You'll hear me
call you, ♪
♪ Singin' through
the sunshine, ♪
♪ Sweet and clear ♪
♪ as can be, ♪
♪ "Come to me, ♪
♪ Here am I, ♪
♪ Come to me!" ♪
♪ If you try
you'll find me ♪
♪ Where de sky
meets de sea ♪
♪ Hear am I,
Your special island ♪
♪ Come to me ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪♪
Of course, Lieutenant,
uh, right now,
uh, that island
is off-limits.
Of course,
you being an officer,
you could get a launch.
I'd even be willin'...
to requisition
a boat for you.
[Chuckles]
But another thing
goes on over there.
The, uh, ceremonial
of the boar's tooth.
After they kill the boar,
they... pass around
some of that, uh,
coconut liquor.
And women, uh, dance
with just skirts on.
And everybody gets
to know everybody
pretty well.
And I thought you bein'
up in the shootin' war...
for such a long time
without getting any recreation,
uh, thought you might
be interested.
[Whooping]
Iron belly.
[Men Whooping]
[Whooping Continues]
Here she is, sir.
You are causing
an economic revolution
on this island.
These French planters
can't find a native
to pick a coconut...
or milk a cow...
because you're paying them
10 times as much...
to make these ridiculous
grass skirts.
French planters
stingy stinker!
Like you,
crummy Captain!
I want you to pick up
every scrap of this
paraphernalia now.
And for the last time,
carry it way down there...
beyond that pier...
off navy property.
All right, you men!
Take this stuff down there
past that pier!
Snap to it!
Who is he?
Don't know, sir.
All right, all right.
Come on. Let's go.
Get it down there.
Let's go. Let's go.
Come on. Come on.
Way down there.
Off navy property.
You go too.
All right, Lootellan.
Thank you.
Lieutenant?
Who are you anyway?
Lieutenant Joseph Cable, sir.
I just flew in
on that P.B.Y.
A joyride?
No, sir. Orders.
A marine under orders
to me?
Yes, sir.
This is Commander Harbison,
my executive officer.
Commander.
Lieutenant Cable.
Well, what's it
all about?
Well, sir,
my colonel feels...
that all these islands
are in danger...
because none of us
has been getting any
firsthand intelligence.
We don't know
what the Japanese
are really up to.
He couldn't be more right.
He feels that what
we need is a coast watch.
A coast watch?
Yes, sir.
One of our men
with a radio...
hiding out on one
of the enemy-held islands...
where he could watch
for enemy ships...
when they come down
through the bottleneck
down this way.
What do you think,
Bill?
Well, sir, our pilots
could do a lot of damage...
to enemy convoys with
information like that.
How would you get a man
on one of those islands?
Have to sneak him ashore
somehow, sir.
How long do you think
he could hold out there
sending messages...
before the Japanese
spotted him?
It could be done, sir.
Yeah, but who's
going to do it?
Well, sir,
I've been elected.
You got yourself
quite an assignment, son.
I think I'd be okay...
if I could take a man
with me who really
knew the country.
Headquarters has found out
that there's a French
civilian here...
used to have a plantation
on Marie Louise Island.
Did a lot of hunting
and fishing there.
Marie Louise.
That's a good spot.
Right on the bottleneck.
What's this
Frenchman's name?
Emile De Becque.
Ah! He lives
right up there.
[Cable]
Yes, sir. Do you know him?
Well, I've met him.
But I don't know
very much about him... yet.
Is all this yours?
Yes.
[Miss Forbush]
Is it true that all the planters
on these islands—
Are they really running away
from something?
Uh, who is not running away
There are fugitives
everywhere.
New York, in Paris,
even in Small Rock.
Yeah, where you come from.
Oh! Little Rock.
Oh, Little. Oh.
[Chuckles]
Yes.
Small Rock.
Excuse me. Little Rock.
You know
any fugitives there?
I'll show you a picture
of a Little Rock fugitive.
I got this clipping
from my mother... today.
Hey.
[Chuckles]
"Ensign Nellie Forbush,
Arkansas's own
Florence Nightingale."
That was written
by Mrs. Leeming,
the social editor.
Hmm.
She went to school
with my mother.
Pretty girl, huh?
That picture was taken
before I knew what...
rain and heat and mud
can do to your disposition.
[Sighs]
But it isn't
raining today.
Gosh, it's beautiful here.
Just look
at that yellow sun.
And way off in the distance,
those lovely little
white clouds.
Those lovely little
white clouds could
easily be gunfire.
Oh, how awful.
On such a day.
Boys getting killed,
people getting—
But you know, Emile, I don't
think it's the end of the world
like everyone else thinks.
Do you?
Perhaps the end
of some worlds.
Not this one.
It can't be.
I— I can't work myself up
to getting that low.
You think I'm crazy too?
They all do over
at the fleet hospital.
You know what they call me?
Knucklehead Nellie.
I suppose I am.
But I can't help it.
♪ When the sky is
a bright canary yellow ♪
♪ I forget ev'ry cloud
I've ever seen ♪
♪ So they call me
a cockeyed optimist, ♪
♪ Immature
and incurably green! ♪
♪ I have heard people
rant and rave and bellow ♪
♪ That we're done
and we might as well be dead ♪
♪ But I'm only
a cockeyed optimist ♪
♪ And I can't get it
into my head, ♪
♪ I hear the human race
is falling on its face ♪
♪ And hasn't very far to go, ♪
♪ But ev'ry whippoorwill
Is selling me a bill ♪
♪ And telling me
it just ain't so. ♪
♪ I could say life is just
a bowl of jello, ♪
♪ And appear more intelligent
and smart ♪
♪ But I'm stuck (like a dope!)
With a thing called hope, ♪
♪ And I can't get it
out of my heart ♪
♪ Not ♪
♪ this ♪
♪ heart. ♪♪
Do you wanna know
anything else about me?
Yes.
Would you like
to see the view?
Mmm.
You say you are
a fugitive.
When you joined the navy,
what were you running
away from?
Gosh, I don't know.
It was more like
running to something.
I wanted to see
what the world was like—
outside of Little Rock, I mean.
And I wanted to meet
different kinds of people...
and find out if I liked 'em better.
And do you?
Well, I-I don't
really know yet.
I guess they're...
different.
Would you like some cognac?
I'd love some.
[Nellie's Voice]
♪ Wonder how I'd feel ♪
♪ Living on a hillside, ♪
♪ Looking on an ocean, ♪
♪ Beautiful and still. ♪
[Emile's Voice]
♪ This is what I need, ♪
♪ This is what
I've longed for, ♪
♪ Someone young and smiling ♪
♪ Climbing up my hill! ♪
[Nellie's Voice]
♪ We are not alike. ♪
♪ Probably I'd bore him. ♪
♪ He's a cultured Frenchman, ♪
♪ I'm a little hick. ♪
[Emile's Voice]
♪ Younger men than I, ♪
♪ Officers and doctors, ♪
♪ Probably pursue her, ♪
♪ She could have her pick. ♪
[Nellie's Voice]
♪ Wonder why I feel ♪
♪Jittery and jumpy! ♪
♪ I am like a school-girl, ♪
♪ Waiting for a dance. ♪
[Emile's Voice]
♪ Can I ask her now? ♪
♪ I am like a school boy! ♪
♪ What will be her answer? ♪
♪ Do I have ♪
♪ a chance? ♪♪
In peacetime,
the boat from America
comes once a month.
The ladies—
the wives
of the planters—
often go to Australia
during the hot months.
It can get
very hot here.
Oh, it can get hot
in Arkansas too.
It can?
Uh-huh.
I have many books here.
Marcel Proust?
Anatole France?
Did you study French
in school?
Oh, yes.
Then you can read French.
No.
I can conjugate
a few verbs.
I'll bet you read a lot.
Out here, one becomes hungry
to learn everything.
Not to miss anything.
Not to let anything good
pass by.
[Sets Glass Down]
Yes?
One waits so long
for what is good,
and when at last it comes,
one cannot risk to lose.
So one must speak
and act quickly,
even if it seems
almost foolish
to be so quick.
I know it's only two weeks.
A dinner given at your
Officers Club, wasn't it?
Yes, it was, Emile.
And that is the way
things happen sometimes.
Isn't it, Nellie?
Yes, it is, Emile.
♪ Some enchanted evening ♪
♪ You may see a stranger, ♪
♪ You may see
a stranger ♪
♪ Across a crowded room ♪
♪ And somehow you know, ♪
♪ You know even then ♪
♪ That somewhere
you'll see her ♪
♪ again and again. ♪
♪ Some enchanted evening ♪
♪ Someone may be laughing, ♪
♪ You may hear her laughing, ♪
♪ Across a crowded room ♪
♪ And night after night, ♪
♪ As strange as it seems ♪
♪ The sound of her laughter ♪
♪ will sing in your dreams. ♪
♪ Who can explain it? ♪
♪ Who can tell you why? ♪
♪ Fools give you reasons, ♪
♪ Wise men never try. ♪
♪ Some enchanted evening ♪
♪ When you find
your true love, ♪
♪ When you feel her
call you ♪
♪ Across a crowded room, ♪
♪ Then fly to her side ♪
♪ And make her your own, ♪
♪ Or all through
your life ♪
♪ you may dream ♪
♪ all ♪
♪ alone. ♪
♪ Once you have
found her, ♪
♪ Never let her go. ♪
♪ Once you have
found her, ♪
♪ Never ♪
♪ let ♪
♪ her ♪
♪ go! ♪♪
I am older than you.
If we have children,
when I die,
they will be growing up.
You could afford
to take them back
to America,
if you like.
Think about it.
Monsieur De Becque.
[Speaking French]
[French Continues]
Oh! Oh, my jeep.
Thanks, Henry.
Tell 'em I'll be right there.
Good-bye, Emile.
I had such a lovely time. I—
Before you leave, Nellie,
I want to tell you
something.
A while ago
you asked me a question:
Why did I leave France?
Emile, that was nothing—
But I want to tell you.
I had to leave France.
I killed a man.
Why did you kill him?
He was a wicked man—
the town bully.
Everyone in our village
was glad to see him die.
And it was not
to my discredit.
Do you believe me,
Nellie?
You— You just told me
that you killed a man...
and that it's all right.
I hardly know you.
And yet I know
it's all right.
Thank you, Nellie.
And you like my place?
Yes.
You— You will think?
I will think.
Shh.
♪ La, da-da, da-da, da ♪
[Children]
♪ La, la-la, la-la, la ♪
Oh.
[Chuckles,
Speaks French]
[All Speaking French]
♪ Dites-moi ♪
♪ pour quoi ♪
♪ La vie est belle ♪
[All]
♪ Dites-moi ♪
♪ pour quoi ♪
♪ La vie est gaie? ♪
♪ Dites-moi ♪
♪ pour quoi ♪
♪ Chere mad'moiseille ♪
♪ Est ce que ♪
♪ Par ce que ♪
♪ vous m'aimez ♪♪
I'm Lieutenant Cable.
[Brackett]
Oh, come in, Cable.
Come over here.
Look at this.
We've got some dope
on your Frenchman.
Had a plantation
on Marie Louise Island.
Moved down here
to this island
16 years ago.
Married to a Polynesian
woman for about five years.
Two children by her.
She died.
Here's one thing
we've got to clear up.
Seems he left France
in a hurry.
Killed a guy.
What do you think of that?
Might be a handy man
to have around.
[Intercom Buzzes]
Cable.
Good. Send her in.
Here she is.
Oh, come in, Miss Forbush.
Captain Brackett,
please excuse the way I look.
I was just—
Oh, you look fine.
May I present
Commander Harbison?
I have the pleasure
of meeting Miss Forbush
twice a week.
We serve together
on the G.I.
entertainment committee.
Oh.
How's the Thanksgiving
entertainment coming along?
Very well. Thank you, sir.
We practice whenever
we get a chance.
May I also present
Lieutenant Joseph Cable?
Miss Forbush.
Sit down, Miss Forbush.
Miss Forbush, you've been
seeing a French planter,
Emile De Becque.
Yes, sir.
Good. What do you know
about him?
Well, uh, uh,
what do I know about him?
That's right.
Well, I, uh—
We met at
the Officers Club dance.
He was there.
And I met him.
Yes. Now, what kind
of a man is he?
Well, uh,
he's very nice.
He's kind.
He's attractive.
I just don't know
what you wanna know, sir.
Miss Forbush,
Captain Brackett
wants to know,
did you discuss
politics?
No, sir.
Would you have discussed
politics, Commander?
What we're specifically
interested in is—
well, when these fellas come
out from France, it's generally
because they've had trouble.
Has he ever told you
anything about that?
Well, uh, what do you know
about his family, for instance?
Oh, uh, he has no family.
No wife. Nobody.
- He doesn't have any children?
- No, sir.
And you say
he's never told you
why he left France?
Yes, sir.
He left France
because he killed a man.
Did he tell you why?
No, but he will
if I ask him.
Well, Miss Forbush,
that's exactly what
we'd like to have you do.
Find out as much
about him as you can—
his background, his opinions
and why he killed
this man in France.
In other words,
you want me to spy on him?
Well, I'm afraid it is
something like that.
Why? Do you suspect
him of anything?
No. It's just
that we don't know
very much about him.
And he's— Will you
help us, Miss Forbush?
I'll try.
Thank you. You may
go now if you wish.
Thank you.
I don't know very much
about him, really.
Do I?
He's kept a few secrets
from her, hasn't he?
Well, you don't spring a couple
of Polynesian kids on a woman
right off the bat.
I'm afraid
we aren't gonna get
much out of her.
She's obviously
in love with him.
That's hard to believe, sir.
They tell me he's
a middle-aged man.
Cable,
it is a common mistake
for boys of your age...
and athletic ability...
to underestimate men
who have reached
their maturity.
Sir, I didn't mean—
Young women frequently find
a grown man attractive,
strange as it
may seem to you.
I, myself, am over 50.
I am a bachelor.
And, Cable,
I do not by any means...
consider myself... through.
[Chuckles]
What's the matter, Bill?
Nothing, evidently.
[Laughing]
Okay, Cable,
see you at chow.
Yes, sir.
Anything
for Ensign Forbush?
Oh, uh, your mail,
Miss Forbush.
Oh, thanks, Luther.
And, uh, your hot water's
still waiting for ya.
Oh, thank you, Luther.
You're sweet.
Don't change your expression,
Lieutenant. Just act like
we're talkin' casual.
I got the boat.
What boat?
We're shoving off
for Bali Ha'i
in 45 minutes.
What are you talking about?
The project you and I got
to go to Bali Ha'i.
Oh, yeah.
Well, you can forget it.
Lieutenant, what
are you doing to me?
I signed this boat out
in your name.
Well, then you're just
the man to cancel it.
Forget the whole thing.
Okay, mate?
Lieutenant, you and me
are going on a boat trip...
whether you like it
or not.
Letter from home?
Oh, yes.
Do you get letters
from your mother telling you
that everything you do is wrong?
No. My mother thinks
everything I do is right.
Of course, I don't tell her
everything I do.
My mother is so prejudiced.
Against Frenchmen?
Against anyone living
outside of Little Rock.
She makes a big thing
out of two people having
different backgrounds.
You mean ages?
Oh, no.
Mother says older men
are better for girls
than younger men.
This has been
a discouraging day for me.
Suppose you had a sister
and she was in love...
with a man like—
De Becque?
Yeah.
I'd tell her to lay off.
You don't have to worry
about me anymore
because it's all off.
[Woman]
With him?
Uh-huh.
- Smart girl, Nellie.
- I'm gonna break it off clean
before it's too late.
Do you think you can?
Before I go any further,
I just better not get started.
Don't you think
so too, Gracey?
Yes, I do.
You do, huh?
Yes.
Well, I guess I do too.
Well, you don't have to
look so dramatic about it.
Things like this
happen every day.
♪ I'm gonna wash that man
right outa my hair, ♪
♪ And send him on his way. ♪
Get the picture?
♪ I'm gonna wave that man
right outa my arms, ♪
[All]
♪ I'm gonna wave that man
right outa my arms, ♪
♪ And send him on his way. ♪
♪ If the man
don't understand you, ♪
♪ If you fly
on sep'rate beams, ♪
♪ Waste no time!
Make a change, ♪
♪ Ride that man
right off your range, ♪
♪ Rub him outa
the roll call ♪
♪ And drum him outa
your dreams! ♪
[All]
♪ Oh ho! ♪
[Blows Raspberry]
♪ I went an' washed that man
right outa my hair, ♪
♪ And sent him on his way! ♪♪
[Trills]
Hyah!
Oh, hello.
Hello.
Uh, that song—
is it a new
American song?
Well, uh, uh,
it's an American-type song.
We were just kind of, uh,
putting in our own words,
you know.
Uh, uh,
where is everybody?
I left a note for you
at the hospital.
It was to ask you to my home
for dinner next Friday.
Oh, uh—
Well, Emile, I don't think
I'll be able to come.
I have these rehearsals—
I have already invited
some of my friends.
The planters' colony.
Oh. Oh, a big party.
Well— Well,
then if I can't come,
you won't miss me.
But it is for you.
It is for my friends
to meet you...
and, more important,
for you to meet them.
To give you an idea
of what your life
would be like here.
I want you to know
more about me—
how I live and think.
More about you.
Yes. You know
very little about me.
That's right.
Uh, would you sit down?
Do you think about
politics much?
And if so, what do you
think about politics?
I've—
Do you mean that—
Do you mean
my political philosophy?
I think that's what I mean.
Oh.
[Chuckles]
Uh, well,
to begin with, I—
I believe in
the free life and
freedom for everyone.
Like in the Declaration
of Independence?
C'est ça.
All men are created
equal, isn't it?
Emile, you really
believe that?
But of course, Nellie.
Well, thank goodness.
Oh.
It's why I am here,
why I killed a man.
Oh, yes, I, uh—
[Clears Throat]
I meant to ask you
about that too.
Now, uh, I don't want you
to think I'm prying
into your private life...
asking a lot of personal
questions, but, uh,
I always think
it's interesting...
why a person... kills...
another person.
But of course, Nellie.
That has worried you.
When I was a boy,
I carried my hat
in my hand.
So, when this man
came to our town,
though my father
said he was good,
I thought he was bad.
I was young.
He attracted all the mean
and cruel people to him.
Soon he was running
our town.
He could do anything,
take anything.
I didn't like that.
I was young.
I stood up
in the public square.
I made a speech.
I called upon everyone
to stand with me
against this man.
- What did they do?
- They walked away.
- Why?
- Because they saw him
standing behind me.
I turned.
And he said to me,
"I'm going to kill you now."
We fought.
I was never so strong.
I knocked him
to the ground.
And when he fell,
his head struck a stone and—
I ran to the waterfront
and joined a cargo boat.
I didn't even know
where it was going.
I stepped off that boat
into another world...
where I am now,
and where I want to stay.
Nellie, will you
marry me?
There are so few days
in our life, Nellie.
The time I have
with you now...
is precious to me.
Have you been thinking?
I've been thinking.
♪ Born on the opposite
sides of a sea, ♪
♪ We are as different
as people can be. ♪
♪ It's true ♪
♪ And yet you want
to marry me. ♪
♪ I do. ♪
♪ I've known you a few
short weeks ♪
♪ And yet somehow you've made
my heart forget ♪
♪ All other men
I have ever met ♪
♪ but you, ♪
♪ but you. ♪
♪ Who can explain it? ♪
♪ Who can tell you why? ♪
♪ Fools give you reasons, ♪
♪ Wise men never try. ♪♪
Will you come
next Friday?
Uh-huh.
[Women Laughing]
[Woman]
Well, she sure washed him
out of her hair.
- [Woman #2]
She sure did.
- [Women Laughing]
♪ I expect ev'ry one
of my crowd. ♪
♪ To make fun of my proud
protestations of faith
and romance ♪
♪ And they'll say
I'm naïve as a babe
to believe ♪
♪ Any fable I hear
form a person in pants ♪
♪ Fearlessly
I'll face them ♪
♪ and argue
their doubts away ♪
♪ Loudly I'll sing
about flowers and spring ♪
♪ Flatly I'll stand on
my little flat feet and say ♪
♪ Love is a grand ♪
♪ and a beautiful thing. ♪
♪ I'm not ashamed
to reveal ♪
♪ The world famous feeling ♪
♪ I feel ♪
♪ I'm as corny
as Kansas in August, ♪
♪ I'm as normal
as blueberry pie, ♪
♪ No more a smart little girl
with no heart ♪
♪ I have found me
a wonderful guy! ♪
♪ I am in
a conventional dither ♪
♪ With a conventional star
in my eye, ♪
♪ And you will note
There's a lump in my throat ♪
♪ When I speak
of that wonderful guy! ♪
♪ I'm as trite and as gay
As a daisy in May, ♪
♪ A cliché coming true! ♪
♪ I'm bromidic and bright ♪
♪ As a moon happy night
pouring light on the dew! ♪
♪ I'm as corny
as Kansas in August, ♪
♪ High as a flag
on the fourth of July! ♪
♪ If you’ll excuse
an expression I use, ♪
♪ I'm in love, I'm in love,
I'm in love, I'm in love, ♪
♪ I'm in love
with a wonderful guy! ♪
♪ I'm as corny
as Kansas in August, ♪
♪ High as a flag
on the fourth of July! ♪
♪ If you’ll excuse
an expression I use, ♪
♪ I'm in love, I'm in love,
I'm in love, I'm in love,
I'm in love, ♪
[All]
♪ I'm in love, I'm in love,
I'm in love, ♪
I'm in love, I'm in love, ♪
♪ I'm in love
with a wonderful guy! ♪♪
Now, before you give us
an answer,
I wanna impress you
with three things.
First— you are a civilian
and you don't have to go.
Second— this is
a very dangerous mission...
and there's no guarantee
that you will survive...
or that it will do
any good.
Third— that it might
do a great good.
It might be the means
of turning the tide
of the war in this area.
Yeah, I understand
all these things.
Are you ready to give us
your answer?
Yes, I am.
My answer must be no.
When a man faces death,
he must weigh values
very carefully.
He must weigh
the sweetness of his life...
against the thing
he's asked to die for.
The probability of death
is very great...
for both of us.
I know that island well,
Lieutenant Cable.
And, uh, I'm not certain
that I believe...
that what you're asking me
to do is— is that—
[Brackett]
We're asking you to help us
lick the Japanese.
It's as simple as that.
We're against the Japanese.
I know what
you are against.
What are you for?
When I was 22,
I thought the world
hated bullies
as much as I did.
I was foolish,
and I killed one.
I was forced to flee
to an island.
Since then, I have asked
no help from anyone...
or any country.
I have seen
these bullies multiply...
and grow strong.
And the world sat by
and watched.
Oh, the hell
with this, De Becque!
Let's be honest!
Aren't you just a guy in love
with a girl and you're putting
her above everything else?
Yes.
I do care about
my life with her...
more than anything else
in the world.
It is the only thing
that is important to me.
This I believe in.
This I'm sure of.
This I have.
I cannot risk
to lose it.
Good day, gentlemen.
He's an honest man,
but he's wrong.
Of course we can't
guarantee him
a better world if we win.
The point is we can be sure
it'll be worse if we lose,
can't we?
Well, can't we?
I don't know.
What should I do now,
Captain Brackett?
Go back to
my outfit tonight?
- Why don't you take a couple
of days off and unwind?
- Unwind?
Sure. Take a boat.
Go fishing.
Boat.
[Chorus]
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪
♪ may call you ♪
♪ Any night,
any day ♪
[Man]
There's a ceremony today,
Billis. The whole town's out.
♪ "Come away, come away." ♪
[Ringing]
♪ Bali Ha'i will whisper♪
♪ On de wind
of de sea; ♪
♪ "Here am I,
Your special island!" ♪
♪ "Come to me,
come to me!" ♪
♪ Your own special hopes, ♪
♪ Your own special dreams ♪
♪ Bloom on de hillside ♪
♪ And shine
in de streams. ♪
♪ If you try, ♪
♪ You'll find me ♪
♪ Where de sky
meets de sea, ♪
[Giggling]
♪ "Here am I, ♪
[Billis Chuckles]
♪ "Your special island!" ♪
♪ "Come to me.
Come to me!" ♪
Here you are. [Chuckles]
[Chuckles]
That's it.
Dance it up, kids.
[Chorus]
♪ "Come to me. ♪
♪ Come to me!" ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪♪
[Bloody Mary]
Welcome Bali Ha'i.
- What are you doing here?
- Here I live.
[Chuckles]
You like?
Bali Ha'i call you, eh?
You no escape Bali Ha'i
when she call you.
Are you guys with the boar's
tooth ceremonial? You know—
[Growls]
Yes. You go with them,
big dealer.
Lootellan,
you come with me.
Will you get your carcass
out of here!
He's going with me.
Which way is it?
All right. Come on.
[Natives Chattering]
[Billis]
That ain't all halibut
in that net, Lieutenant.
The place
is loaded, ain't it?
Well, ain't it?
No comment.
♪♪ [Drums Continue Beating]
[Sticks Rattling
Rhythmically]
[Chanting In Native Language]
♪♪ [Singing In Native Language]
That's the chief.
He's the one that
takes out the tooth.
[Snorting]
Look at those tusks.
Yeah, they've gone through
the pig's face twice and
once through his jawbone.
That's why they're
so hard to get out.
[Groans]
♪♪ [Singing Continues]
Hey, look!
He's dancing on those
hot coals! Come on!
Now for the cuttin'.
I'm not gonna
wait around for that.
[Birds Twittering]
What's this all about?
You wait.
There's nobody
around here.
You wait, Lootellan.
What's going on, Mary?
What—
[Rustling]
You like?
Who is she?
Liat.
[Bloody Mary]
Is French name.
But she no French girl.
She Tonkinese,
like me.
We are very
pretty people, no?
Liat nice daughter, no?
Make nice wife.
Yes?
You speak English?
Only few word.
She talk French.
Français.
Je parle français...
un peu.
Moi aussi. Un peu.
[Laughing]
Afraid of me?
Oh.
Avez-vous peur?
Non.
Oui.
You’re just a kid.
How did an innocent kid
like you get mixed up
with Bloody Mary?
C'est vieux femme—
votre amie?
Ma mère.
Your mother!
Bloody Mary really
is your mother.
That's why she's been
looking me over
like that.
[Bell Clanging]
It's the boat,
all right.
Ah, let 'em wait.
♪ I touch your hand ♪
♪ and my arms
grow strong ♪
♪ Like a pair of birds ♪
♪ that burst with song ♪
♪ My eyes look down ♪
♪ at your lovely face ♪
♪ And I hold the world ♪
♪ In my embrace. ♪
♪ Younger than springtime
are you ♪
♪ Softer than starlight
♪ Warmer than winds
of June ♪
♪ are the gentle lips ♪
♪ you gave me. ♪
♪ Gayer than laughter
are you ♪
♪ Sweeter than music
♪ Angel and lover, ♪
♪ Heaven and earth ♪
♪ are you to me. ♪
♪ And when your youth ♪
♪ and joy ♪
♪ invade my arms ♪
♪ And fill my heart ♪
♪ As now they do... ♪
♪ Then... ♪
♪ Younger than springtime
am I ♪
♪ Gayer than laughter
♪ Angel and lover, ♪
♪ Heaven and earth ♪
♪ am I ♪
♪ with you. ♪
[Bell Clanging]
♪ Younger than springtime
am I ♪
♪ Gayer than laughter
♪ Angel and lover, ♪
♪ Heaven and earth ♪
♪ am I ♪
♪ with ♪
♪you. ♪♪
[Chorus]
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪
♪♪ [Singing Continues]
♪♪ [Continues Faintly]
Ring the bell again!
[Bell Clanging]
[Bloody Mary]
You no worry, Billis.
He be here soon.
Look!
[Chorus]
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪
♪ Bali Ha'i ♪♪
Is gonna be
my son-in-law.
[Laughing]
[People Speaking French]
[Speaking Broken French]
[Emile Laughing]
Au revoir.
Nellie.
Huh?
Nellie, please,
stay for just a moment.
You know I can't stay.
Why not? No one
will think anything.
And-And I gotta get
this jeep back.
I stole it.
You must never return
anything you steal.
Then they'll know you stole it.
But I really just borrowed it.
Or rather someone
stole it for me.
A wonderful man named Billis.
I have to sneak around
behind the hospital as it is.
In that case,
I forbid you to go.
If you have to sneak back
without anyone seeing you,
you might as well
sneak back later.
You're absolutely right.
[Man]
Au revoir, Emile.
Au revoir.
[Emile Speaking French]
Oh! I never had such
a wonderful time
in my whole life.
They're nice people, no?
Oh, they're lovely people.
That cute old man
that spoke French with me and
made believe he understood me.
And that exciting
native couple
who danced for us.
Oh.
Oh, it's so different
from Little Rock!
[Laughing]
What on earth
are you laughing at?
Am I drunk?
Oh, no.
Oh, yes, I am.
But it isn't the champagne.
It's because—
♪ I'm in love
with a wonderful guy ♪
♪ I am in
a conventional dither ♪
♪ With a conventional star
in my eye ♪
♪ And you will note
There's a lump in my throat ♪
[Chuckles]
♪ When I speak
to that wonderful guy. ♪
♪ I'm as trite and as gay
As a daisy in May, ♪
♪ A cliché coming true! ♪
♪ I'm bromidic and bright ♪
♪ As a moon happy night
pouring light on the dew ♪
♪ I'm in love I'm in love
I'm in love I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love
with a wonderful guy! ♪
♪ I'm in love, I'm in love,
And the girl that I love, ♪
♪ She thinks
I'm a wonderful guy. ♪♪
[Sighs]
Oh! Imagine
leaving all of this
wonderful champagne.
[Chuckles]
Mmm!
Here, Emile.
You have some too.
It's such a waste.
Here. Here is
another bottle.
[Nellie's Voice]
♪ This is how it feels ♪
♪ living on a hillside ♪
Here we are, just like
two old married people are.
Our guests have gone home
and we're alone.
[Emile's Voice]
♪ This is what I need ♪
♪ This is what
I've longed for♪
♪ Someone young and smiling ♪
♪ Here upon my hill ♪♪
Emile.
Hmm?
My mother says
we have nothing in common,
but she's wrong.
We have something
very important in common—
very much in common.
Yes. We are both in love.
Yes, but more
than that.
I've had enough.
We're the same kind
of people,
fundamentally-
you and me.
We appreciate things.
We get enthusiastic
about things.
It's really quite exciting
when two people
are like that.
We're not blasé.
Mmm.
You know
what I mean?
Yes.
You know
what I mean?
Yes.
We are both knuckleheads.
Cockeyed optimists.
♪ I hear the human race
is falling on it's face ♪
♪ And hasn't very far
to go ♪
♪ But ev'ry whippoorwill
Is selling me a bill ♪
♪ And telling me
it just ain't so. ♪
♪ I could say life is
just a bowl of jello ♪
♪ And appear more intelligent
and smart ♪
♪ But I'm stuck (like a dope!)
With a thing called hope, ♪
♪ And I can't get it out
of my heart ♪
♪ Not ♪
♪ this ♪
♪ heart ♪♪
Nellie. Nellie,
I have a surprise for you.
Oh!
No, stay there.
Oh! Why, you're the cutest
things I ever saw
in my whole life.
What are your names?
You probably can't understand
a word I'm saying.
But oh, my goodness,
you're cute.
Nellie, I want you to meet
Ngana and Jerome.
Ngana and Jerome, Nellie.
Nellie?
[Chuckles]
[Speaking French]
Bonsoir, Nellie.
Aren't they adorable!
Those big black eyes
staring at you out
of those sweet little faces.
[Chuckles]
Are they Henry's?
They're mine.
Oh, of course they are.
They look exactly like you.
Where do you hide
their mother?
She's dead, Nellie.
She's—
Emile, they are yours?
Yes, Nellie.
I'm their father.
And— And their mother
was a—
Polynesian.
She was beautiful, Nellie,
and charming too.
And you loved her.
I want you to know
I have no apologies.
I came here as a young man.
I lived as I could.
Of course.
But I have not been selfish.
No woman ever hated me
or tried to hurt me.
No— No woman could...
ever want— want
to hurt you, Emile.
What time is it?
I promised to get
that jeep back.
Oh! Oh, this is awful.
Oh— Oh, why just look
at the time!
Please, Nellie.
Wait.
I'll drive you home.
Oh, you'll do
no such thing.
But—
Anyway, I couldn't leave
the jeep here. I've gotta
get it back by—
Don't go now, Nellie.
Don't go yet, please.
Oh, well, I have to go.
Yes, this— this is
just terrible.
I— I won't be able to face
the girls at the hospital
as it is. I—
You can't imagine the way
they look at you
when you come in late.
Yes, Nellie—
I'll call you. I'll
come by tomorrow. Yes.
Nellie—
Oh, no.
[Panting]
Oh, dear.
There are those
awful rehearsals
for Thanksgiving day.
I'm teaching them a dance
and they wanna rehearse
night and day.
But after that—
Thank you for tonight, Emile.
I had a wonderful time.
It was the nicest party
and you were a perfect host.
Good-bye.
Nellie, I-I—
Please, Emile.
Please stay here.
Please don't come
to the jeep. Please!
Nellie.
I love you.
Do you hear me?
And I love you too.
Honestly, I do.
Please let me go.
Oh, please let me go!
[Sobbing]
♪ Once you have
found her ♪
♪ Never let her go. ♪
♪ Once you have
found her, ♪
♪ Never let ♪
♪ her ♪
♪ go! ♪♪
♪♪ [Orchestra]
[Bell Clanging]
[Squeals]
[All]
Whoa!
Come on. Allons.
Whoo!
[Laughter]
Happy, Lootellan?
[Laughing]
Jacques Barrere want
to marry Liat.
He ask again
last night.
You mean, that old
French planter
you told me about,
the one
you despise?
You can't let her marry
a man like that!
- Is white man, too,
and very rich.
- I don't care!
You can't let her
marry him.
Okay. Then you marry her.
Lootellan,
you have good life here.
I am rich.
Since war,
I make 2,000 dollar.
War go on,
I make maybe more.
Give all the money
to you and Liat.
You no have to work.
I work for you.
All day long,
you and Liat play together.
Make love, talk happy.
No think about
"Philadelia."
It's no good!
♪ Happy Talk,
keep talkin' Happy Talk ♪
♪ Talk about t'ings
you'd like to do. ♪
♪ You got to have a dream ♪
♪ If you don't
have a dream ♪
♪ How you gonna have
a dream come true? ♪
♪ Talk about a moon ♪
♪ Floatin' in de sky ♪
♪ Lookin' like
a lilly on a lake ♪
♪ Talk about a bird ♪
♪ Learnin' how to fly ♪
♪ Makin' all de music
he can make. ♪
♪ Happy Talk,
keep talkin' Happy Talk ♪
♪ Talk about t'ings
you'd like to do. ♪
♪ You got to
have a dream ♪
♪ If you don't
♪ How you gonna have
a dream come true? ♪
♪ Talk about a star ♪
♪ Lookin' like a toy ♪
♪ Peekin' through
the branches of a tree. ♪
♪ Talk about a girl ♪
♪ Talk about a boy ♪
♪ Countin' all de ripples
on de sea. ♪
♪ Happy Talk,
keep talkin' Happy Talk ♪
♪ Talk about t'ings
you'd like to do. ♪
♪ You got to have a dream ♪
♪ If you don't
have a dream ♪
♪ How you gonna have
a dream come true? ♪
♪ Talk about a boy ♪
♪ Sayin' to the girl ♪
♪ "Golly baby, ♪
♪ I'm a lucky cuss!" ♪
♪ Talk about a girl ♪
♪ Sayin' to de boy ♪
♪ "You an' me is lucky ♪
♪ to be us" ♪
♪ Happy Talk,
keep talkin' Happy Talk ♪
♪ Talk about t'ings
you'd like to do. ♪
♪ You got to have a dream ♪
♪ If you don't
have a dream ♪
♪ How you gonna have
a dream come true? ♪
♪ If you don't
talk happy ♪
♪ An' you never
have a dream ♪
♪ Den you'll never have ♪
♪ a dream ♪
♪ come true. ♪♪
Is good idea?
You like?
[Laughing]
Wait a minute.
Liat, I want you
to have this.
It was my grandfather's.
My dad carried it
through the last war.
First minute I see you,
I know you right man
for Liat...
and she right girl
for you.
You have special
good babies.
Mary, I can't
marry Liat.
Was your last chance!
Now she marries
Jacques Barrere!
Come, Liat.
[Sobs]
Give me watch!
[Shattering]
[Whimpering]
Stingy stinker!
♪ Younger than springtime ♪
♪ were you ♪
♪ Angel and lover, ♪
♪ Heaven and earth ♪
♪were you ♪♪
♪♪ [Piano]
[Nellie]
Step together, step together.
Point, point.
Bounce, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Hitch, kick!
Scissors!
Hi, Bill.
Hello, sir.
How's it going?
Just fine, sir.
What do you think of it?
Oh, looks pretty good.
I guess we'll get
opened all right.
[Cries]
I'm sorry. I can't go on.
♪♪ [Piano Stops]
Ah, sure you can,
Miss Forbush.
You're the whole show.
I'm sorry, Luther.
I don't know what's
the matter with me.
What's the matter?
Well, sir, would you
take care of her, please?
I-I'm so sorry.
Please excuse me.
It's nothing, honest.
It's really—
It's nothing.
I know—
All right, all right.
Let's go. Come on.
Back to the deck.
Get them weights.
Let's dance!
Come on. Okay.
Hitch, kick and scissors!
♪♪ [Piano]
A transfer?
Yes, please.
To any other island
but this one.
Miss Forbush,
I don't want to pry
into your affairs, but...
whatever is bothering you
is some personal thing,
of course.
But I wonder
if you realize just
how unimportant it is.
Unimportant?
Yes.
And how important you are
at this particular time.
I mean,
the Thanksgiving Follies.
Why, you're the star,
the choreographer,
the whole spirit
of the thing.
I don't think
a little show like this
is very important.
And that’s just
where you're wrong.
Miss Forbush,
up to now, in this war,
our side has been having
a merciless beating
in two hemispheres,
and nobody's going
to be going home until
that situation is reversed.
It may take a long time
before we can get any
big operation under way,
before the boys here
get off this island.
They're lonesome,
homesick boys.
And no matter
how tough they talk,
don't you think...
they're not looking forward
to this "little show,"
as you call it.
This isn't a little show,
Miss Forbush.
This is a big show.
♪♪ [Band]
[Cheering]
♪♪ [Piano: Glissando]
♪ My doll is as dainty
as a sparrow ♪
♪ Her figure is something
to applaud. ♪
♪ Where she's narrow
she's narrow as an arrow ♪
♪ And she's broad, ♪
♪ where a broad ♪
♪ should be broad. ♪
- [Man]
Get it?
- Sit down!
Quiet down there!
Let her sing!
♪ A hundred and one
pounds of fun ♪
♪ That's my little
honey bun! ♪
♪ Get a load
of honey bun tonight. ♪
♪ I'm speakin' of
my Sweetie Pie, ♪
♪ Only sixty inches high ♪
♪ Ev'ry inch is packed
with dynamite! ♪
[Laughing]
♪ Her hair is blonde
and curly, ♪
♪ Her curls
are hurly burly, ♪
♪ Her lips are pips!
I call her hips:
"Twirly" and "Whirly" ♪
[Cheering]
♪ She's my baby,
I'm her pap! ♪
♪ I'm her booby,
She's my trap! ♪
♪ I am caught
and don't wanta run, ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm havin'
so much fun
with Honey Bun! ♪
♪ A hundred and one
pounds of fun ♪
♪ That's my little
honey bun! ♪
♪ Get a load
of honey bun tonight. ♪
♪ I'm speakin'
of my Sweetie Pie ♪
Billis, get off that stage!
♪ Only sixty inches high ♪
Knock it off. All right.
♪ Ev'ry inch is packed
with dynamite! ♪
♪ Her hair is blonde
and curly. ♪
♪ Her curls
are hurly burly. ♪
♪ Her lips are pips! ♪
♪ I call her hips:
"Twirly" and "Whirly" ♪
Hey, Billis! Who does your hair?
[Growls]
[Jeering]
[Booing]
♪♪ [Vocalizing]
[Cheering]
♪ I am caught
and don't wanta run, ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm havin'
so much fun with honey bun ♪
♪ (Believe me, sonny) ♪
♪ She's a cookie
who can cook you
till you're done ♪
♪ (Ain't bein' funny) ♪
♪ Sonny, put your money ♪
♪ On my ♪
♪ honey bun! ♪♪
[Cheering Continues]
Miss Forbush.
Oh, Luther.
Oh, thank you.
[Men]
Whoa!
[Whistling]
♪♪ [Band]
♪ A hundred and one
pounds of fun ♪
♪ That's my little
honey bun! ♪
♪ Get a load
of honey bun tonight. ♪
♪ I'm speakin'
of my Sweetie Pie ♪
♪ Only sixty inches high ♪
♪ Ev'ry inch is packed
with dynamite! ♪
All right, all right!
Leave it alone!
♪ Her hair is blonde
and curly, ♪
♪ Her curls
are hurly burly ♪
♪ Her lips are pips! ♪
Ah, come on, wise guy!
Cut it out!
♪ I call her hips:
"Twirly" and "Whirly" ♪
♪♪ [Drum]
[Man]
Come on. Go home!
[Man #2]
Hey, Billis! You got
a hole in your boat!
[Laughter]
[Cheering]
♪ Fly, navy
down the field ♪
♪ Anchors aweigh ♪
♪ From the halls
of Montezuma ♪
♪ To the shores of Tripoli ♪
♪♪ [Drum]
♪ She's my baby,
I'm her pap ♪
♪ I'm her booby
She's my trap ♪
♪ I am caught
and I don't wanta run ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm havin'
so much fun with honey bun. ♪
Ow!
♪ And that's the finish. ♪
Who did that?
♪ And it's time to go
for now the show is done ♪
All right, who did that?
♪ We hope you like us, ♪
Who did it?
♪ And we hope that when you
leave your seat and run ♪
♪ Down to the Mess Hall. ♪
♪ You'll enjoy your dinner
each and ev'ry one. ♪
♪ Save me
some turkey! ♪
♪ And put some
chestnut dressing ♪
♪ on our honey bun ♪♪
Cigarettes, anybody?
♪ bun. ♪♪
[Chattering]
Luther? Luther?
Oh, Luther,
you really are
a honey bun.
These beautiful flowers.
I needed someone
to think of me tonight.
I appreciate it,
Luther.
You don't know
how much.
Miss Forbush, I would
like to have you know...
that— that I
consider you...
the most wonderful woman
in the entire world,
even including the fact
that you're an officer.
And— And I just can't
go on being such a heel...
as to let you think
I thought of giving you
those flowers.
Oh, but you did
give them to me, and—
No.
Here's the note
that came with them.
[Emile's Voice]
I lie in the loneliness
of evening,
looking out
on a silver-flaked sea,
and ask the moon,
"Oh, how soon—
how soon will my love
come home to me?"
[Nellie's Voice]
Will my love...
come home to me?
What's the matter,
Nellie the Nurse?
Joe Cable!
Having
diplomatic difficulties
with France?
Joe, who let you out
of the hospital?
Me! I'm okay. Come on.
Nellie?
Are you ready?
Oh, Bill—
Bill, would you wait
just a minute, please?
Sure.
You're trying to get over
to Bali Ha'i.
That little girl
you told me about.
I've got to.
All the time
I've been in the hospital
with that darn malaria,
I haven't been able
to see anything
but her face.
I love her, and—
What kind of a guy
am I anyway?
I love her,
and yet I said I couldn't
marry her, and—
I don't understand myself.
If I love her,
why don't I marry her...
and stay here and—
You’re just far away
from home, Joe.
We're both far away
from home.
But it doesn't
make sense!
Oh, yes, it does.
I guess it does anyway.
I guess
people like us—
well, we just have to
go back to where we belong.
What about that girl of yours
back in... Philadelphia?
♪ My girl back home ♪
♪ I'd almost forgot! ♪
♪ A blue-eyed kid, ♪
♪ I liked her a lot. ♪
♪ We got engaged, ♪
♪ Both fam'lies were glad; ♪
♪ And I was told
by my uncle and dad ♪
♪ That if I were clever
and able ♪
♪ They'd make me a part
of a partnership, ♪
♪ Cable, Cable, ♪
♪ and Cable! ♪
♪ How far away ♪
♪ Philadelphia, P.A. ♪
♪ Princeton, N.J ♪
♪ How far are they ♪
♪ From coconut palms
and banyan trees ♪
♪ and coral sands ♪
♪ and Tonkinese! ♪
♪ How far away ♪
♪ Little Rock, ARK ♪
♪ Princeton, NJ ♪
♪ How far are they ♪
♪ From coconut palms
and banyan trees ♪
♪ and coral sands and ♪♪
Nellie,
I must see you.
Emile, I—
Will you excuse us,
Lieutenant Cable?
No, Joe! Stay.
Stay, please.
I've been meaning
to call you, Emile.
You have asked
for a transfer. Why?
What does it mean,
Nellie?
I— I'll— I'll explain it
to you tomorrow, Emile.
No. Now.
What does it mean, Nellie?
It means that I
can't marry you.
Do you understand?
I— I can't marry you.
- Because of my children.
- Oh, not because
of your children.
They're sweet.
It is their Polynesian
mother then—
their mother and I.
Yes.
I can't help it.
I-It isn't as if I could
give you a good reason.
I—
There is no reason.
This is emotional.
This is something
that's born in me.
It is not.
I do not believe
this is born in you.
Well, then why— why do I
feel the way I do?
All I— All I know is,
I— I can't help it.
Joe? Joe, explain
how we feel.
Joe!
Nellie—
Bill! Bill!
Bill?
Can we go now?
Please?
What makes her
talk like that?
Why do you have
this feeling—
you and she?
I do not believe
it is born in you!
I do not believe it!
It's not born in you!
It happens
after you're born.
♪ You've got to be taught ♪
♪ to hate and fear, ♪
♪ from year to year, ♪
♪ It's got to be drummed ♪
♪ in your dear little ear ♪
♪ You've got to
be carefully taught. ♪
be taught ♪
♪ to be afraid ♪
♪ of people whose eyes ♪
♪ are oddly made, ♪
♪ And people whose skin ♪
♪ is a diff'rent shade ♪
♪ You've got to
be carefully taught. ♪
be taught ♪
♪ before it's too late ♪
♪ Before you are six ♪
♪ or seven or eight, ♪
♪ To hate
all the people ♪
♪ your relatives hate ♪
♪ You've got to
be carefully taught! ♪
♪ You've got to be
carefully taught! ♪♪
You've got
the right idea,
De Becque.
Live on an island.
Yes, sir.
If I get out
of this thing alive,
I'm not going back there.
I'm staying here.
All I care about
is right here.
Yes. So, when all you
care about is here,
yeah, this is
a good place to be.
When all you
care about is...
taken away from you,
there is no place.
I came so close to it.
So close.
♪ One dream
in my heart ♪
♪ One love
to be living for ♪
♪ This nearly was mine. ♪
♪ One girl ♪
♪ for my dream ♪
♪ One partner
in paradise ♪
♪ This promise
of paradise ♪
♪ This nearly was mine. ♪
♪ Close to my heart she came ♪
♪ Only to fly away ♪
♪ Only to fly ♪
♪ as day flies ♪
♪ from moonlight ♪
♪ Now, now I'm alone ♪
♪ Still dreaming of paradise, ♪
♪ Still saying ♪
♪ that paradise ♪
♪ Once nearly ♪
♪ was mine. ♪♪
You know,
back home,
whenever I got in a jam,
I used to go hunting.
That's what I think
I'll do now.
Good hunting up there
around Marie Louise.
Carriers.
Cargo boats.
Troop ships.
Big game.
De Becque.
Would you
reconsider...
going up there with me
to Marie Louise Island?
I mean, now that
you haven't got
so much to lose?
We could do a good job,
I think.
You and I.
How could a P.B.Y land
anywhere near that island...
without being seen
by the enemy?
It will not land
near the island,
but far out at sea.
I know the fishing grounds
my friends use,
and I know
two fishermen there—
Inato and Basil.
They will help us.
The equipment's
all aboard, sir. We loaded it
while it was still dark.
You'd better wait
a while yet
before you take off.
Above all, this must look
like a casual, routine flight.
Well, there's still
plenty of time
to change your mind.
Hey, Buzz!
Captain?
Yeah?
Are you we gonna need
the parachutes or not?
No, it looks calm enough
for us to set down.
No parachutes!
[Emile]
All right.
[Cable]
Looks like a summer day
in Maine.
That's a state
in America.
Yeah.
Lobsters.
Hey, you guys
better start getting
into that gear!
Hey, we're approaching
Marie Louise.
[Explosions Continue]
- [Loud Explosion]
- What's going on here?
What? Roger.
Hey, we got it
in the tail section.
I'll go take a look.
[Explosions Continue]
Well, say something!
Who's driving
this airplane anyhow?
I hope you realize
there's a hole
in this plane!
Oh, hello,
Lieutenant, everybody.
It's Luther.
What are you doing
on this plane? How'd you
get on here anyway?
Well, I— I thought
maybe you might need
an extra man.
Seemed like
an interesting project,
and I—
What's the matter, Lieutenant?
You feeling sick or something?
If you don't like the idea,
we'll just forget it.
I'll go back
to the baggage compartment.
Just pretend you never saw me.
- I'll kill him.
- Now, Lieutenant.
If I thought you were gonna
take this attitude, I wouldn't
have volunteered my services.
How do you like
this character?
I'm gonna have you
court-martialed for this,
Billis!
You better take it easy!
I'm gonna ride you
out of the navy!
Do you realize that
this is a secret mission
of the utmost importance?
I realize this is a secret
mission, and I'm gonna keep
the mission. I'm gonna—
[Explosion]
[Screaming]
Pull the handle!
Which one?
Hey, Captain!
Man overboard!
Boy, that Cable
plays it rough.
His parachute's opening.
Secret mission, huh?
Well, it's no secret now.
Hello. This is
Beer Bus to Brewery,
Beer Bus to Brewery.
Yeah, look. Say, look,
I got a man parachuting down
into the Empress Augusta Bay.
That's right.
You guys are gonna have to
help me 'cause I can't.
Right.
Roger and out.
So, it's gonna be
one of those days, huh?
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey! Wait!
Don't leave me!
Look, drop a boat
back there, will you?
[Screams]
[Machine Gun Fire Continues]
Can't you get him out of there?
He'll be shot to pieces!
I can't. I gotta get
you guys in first.
After that, I'll come back
and pick up the pieces,
if there are any.
Okay. Let's go.
Looks like he's an American,
and they're shootin' at him.
Well, let's make 'em
shoot at us.
Hey! That's it, boys! Go!
Hey! That's it! Hey!
He must be down
about there.
Well, get him out of there.
Use anything you need.
We'll send in a destroyer,
if necessary.
Aye, aye, sir.
The admiral says
go all out.
Do you see
any fishing boats?
Ah!
Yeah, there we are.
That's the fishing grounds.
- Can you go lower here?
- Roger.
Hey!
That's Inato's boat!
Basil! Inato!
Inato!
All right.
Can we set down here?
De Becque,
I can set down
anywhere.
I'll take it.
This is a black day
for the navy!
A black, black day!
How much did you say
this cost, Bill?
It's estimated
at $600,000, sir.
Did you hear that?
That's what your
little stunt today
cost the taxpayers!
Six hundred—
$600,000?
What are you
grinning about?
I was just thinking
about my uncle.
Remember my uncle
I was telling you about?
He used to tell my old man
I'd never be worth a dime.
Excuse me, sir.
Billis, you've been
striking for the brig
ever since you hit this island,
and today
you finally made it...
because Captain Brackett and I
are gonna throw the book at you!
Sir, may I barge in?
My copilot and I, sir-
we've been sort of kicking
this thing around,
and, well, we feel that Lu—
well, Billis here—
down in that rubber boat
with all the airplanes
buzzing around him...
caused sort of
a diversionary action.
It made it a lot easier for us
to land Cable and the Frenchman
without being seen.
In fact, it turned out
to be an awful lucky break
for us, sir.
What do you want me to do,
give this guy
a gold medal?
[Sighs]
I don't want
no gold medal, Captain,
but, uh, I could use
a little more, um, freedom,
a little room
to swing around in,
if you know what I mean,
if you get the picture.
Get out of here.
Get the hell
out of here!
[Emile On Radio]
Come in, Kennel.
Captain! Captain!
Kennel, come in.
This is
the Frenchman.
Do you hear me?
This is Kennel.
Go ahead, Frenchman.
This is our first chance
to send news to you.
We have made contact
with former friends
of mine.
We have set up quarters
in a very nice hole in a rock.
No room,
but a lovely view.
We can see right down
into the bottleneck.
First the weather.
Rain clouds
over Bougainville,
the Treasuries,
Choiseul,
New Georgia.
We expect rain
in this region
from 9:00 to 2:00.
[Cable]
0900 to 1400.
Oh, my friend Joe
corrects me.
0900 to 1400.
You must not expect from us
any regular communication.
There are hundreds
of Japanese
in this region.
It will be necessary
to constantly change
our quarters.
And now, our
military expert Joe.
[Cable]
All you navy, marine
and army pilots,
write this down.
Surface craft—
19 troop barges...
headed down
the bottleneck,
speed about 11 knots.
Ought to pass Banika...
at about 2000 tonight,
escorted by
heavy warships.
As for aircraft,
22 bombers, Betties—
A bottle of beer says
I get the first strike!
went by at 0600,
[Cheering]
headed south southwest.
About time!
[Cable] There ought to be some
way to knock off a few of those.
- Hey, wait for us!
- That's all for now.
Good luck.
Two weeks?
Well, how can those guys
stick it out for two weeks?
Yeah. Everybody thought
they'd be dead pigeons
in a couple of days.
I tell you,
those two guys are doing us
a lot of good.
That Frenchman
reported 40 bombers
north of Munda.
We took off,
and 40 bombers right
on the nose— boom, boom.
How do those guys
keep alive up there?
The enemy's all around.
How do they do it?
That Frenchman knows
these jungles around here
like the palm of his hand.
He's a hunter, see?
All I know is, they changed
the whole setup here.
I think
we got the Japanese
on the run.
That's what
the Frenchman said.
Well, is it my lead?
Yeah.
Let me see.
Come on, come on.
I got money on this.
[Emile]
Listen carefully, please.
Ceiling today unlimited.
Thirty-three fighters,
Zeros,
have moved in
from Bougainville.
Their course
is approximately
0-2-3 degrees true.
[Engines Droning]
I'm certain
heavy bombers
will follow.
I think something big
is afoot.
That's all
I have time for now.
Joe and I must change
our position immediately.
Planes are
directly overhead.
Two only, but they're
looking for us, I think.
They know about
where we are.
I will try to
get back to you later.
Good luck.
They got us
pretty well pinpointed.
Stay here.
In a few minutes,
it will be dark enough
to run for it.
You know, I think
we're right.
It looks like
they're going all out.
Even these planes.
They've stopped
looking for us.
They're going away.
Let's make
a run for it.
All right. Let's go.
[Machine Gun Fire]
A-And we have
a lot of fighter pilots
over in the ward,
and— and they keep talking
about a Frenchman.
The Frenchman said this, and
the Frenchman said that, and—
I was just wondering
if the Frenchman they're
talking about could be...
my Frenchman.
Yes, Miss Forbush,
it is.
I couldn't tell you
before, but—
Then he is
behind enemy lines.
With Lieutenant Cable.
Hello. This is Emile De Becque.
Please listen to me carefully.
I haven't much time.
My message today
must be brief and sad.
Lieutenant Cable—
my friend Joe—
died a few minutes ago.
I will never know
a finer man.
I wish he could have
told you the news.
The Japanese
are pulling out.
There is
great confusion here.
My guess is that the enemy
will try to evacuate troops
from Cape Esperance tonight.
This is the opportunity
we've been waiting for.
Make the most of it,
my friends.
You may not hear from me again.
They are coming back.
[Engines Droning]
They're right above me.
[Machine Gun Fire]
- Good-bye!
- Is that all? Is that all?
Can't you get him back?
Kennel to Frenchman.
Come in, Frenchman.
I'm sorry, sir.
He's cut off.
How far away.
Philadelphia, P.A.
Poor Joe Cable.
Captain Brackett, do you think
there's a chance I'll ever see
Emile De Becque again?
There's a chance.
Of course there's a chance.
I didn't even know
he was going.
Of course not.
How could he tell you?
Don't blame Emile De Becque.
He's okay.
He's a wonderful guy.
Uh-huh.
He has got a chance,
hasn't he, Bill?
Of course.
There's always a chance.
Emile?
Emile, come back
so I can tell you something.
I know what counts now.
Just you.
All those other things?
The woman you had before?
Her color?
What— What piffle. I—
What a pinhead I was!
Come back so I can tell you.
Oh, don't die before
I can tell you.
All that matters
is us being together.
That's all.
If you think of what
you said to me that day,
you can stay alive, Emile.
I know you can.
Think of what you said.
♪ When you find
your true love ♪
♪ When you feel her
call you ♪
♪ Across ♪
♪ Then fly to her side ♪
♪ And make her your own ♪
♪ Or all through
your life ♪♪
Live, Emile.
Live, Emile!
Live. Live!
Live.
[Bloody Mary]
Miss Nurse.
Please.
Please, Miss Nurse.
Where is
Lootellan Cable?
Who are you?
I am mother of Liat.
Who?
Liat.
She will marry no one
but Lootellan Cable.
Oh. Oh, my darling.
[Man On Speaker]
All right, hear this.
All those outfits
that are waiting for loading,
please keep in position.
We'll be loading
immediately.
Hey, Billis.
Let's head back, huh?
Our outfit's about
a mile back down the beach.
Suppose they call our names.
Yeah, they may be ready
for us to board the ship.
They won't be ready for hours.
This is the navy!
Huh. Look at that beach,
swarming with eager beavers.
10,000 guys.
All right, you men.
Stay down there with your own
unit where you belong!
You Seabees, you belong
down the beach this way.
Excuse me, sir.
Can you tell me where I can
find Captain Brackett, sir?
Down the beach this way.
Thank you, sir.
That's all.
I beg your pardon, sir.
Can I speak to you
a moment, sir?
Who is it?
Billis, sir.
Luther Billis.
Yes, Billis.
What is it?
We're moving out now.
I know, sir.
Stewpot, the Professor
and me was wondering...
if anything is being done
about rescuing the Frenchman
off that island.
We hereby volunteer
for such a project.
A triple diversionary activity
like I done to get him on there.
You could, uh—
You could drop us
in three rubber boats...
on three different sides
of the island.
Confuse them
out of their minds!
Get the picture?
That's very fine, Billis,
but you're too late.
Operation Alligator
is under way.
Landings were made on a bunch of
Japanese-held islands during the
night and early this morning.
Mary Louise Island
was the first one they hit.
How about
that Frenchman?
Did they get him?
- Is he alive?
- We don't know.
Lieutenant Buzz Adams
flew up there to find out.
But it would be just too bad
if a part of this huge operation
couldn't have saved...
one of the two guys
who made it all possible.
The big ones
are battleships.
And the little ones
are, uh, destroyers.
They're moving out,
you see, because—
well, there's been
a big change.
They won't be around
here much anymore.
Just off and on,
a few of us.
Did you understand
anything I said?
[Sighs]
Vous ne comprenez pas?
Oui, oui.
Nous comprenons.
Oui.
Now, while I'm down
at the hospital,
you've got to promise me
to mangez everything—
everything that's put
before you on the table.
Sur la table.
Sur "le" table?
Oh. Sur la table.
Merci.
Jerome! Come back here
and sit down.
Asseyez-vous!
Now, you have to learn to
mind me when I talk to you
and be nice to me too...
because I love you
very much.
Je t'aime.
[Chuckles]
Je vous aime.
Now, mangez.
Chantez, Nellie.
Mmm. I will not
sing that song.
You just want to laugh
at my French accent.
All right.
But you gotta help me.
♪ Dites-moi ♪
♪ pour quoi ♪
♪ La vie est belle ♪
♪ Dites-moi ♪
♪ pour quoi ♪
Pour quoi what?
♪ La vie est gaie? ♪
[Both]
Papa!
♪ Dites-moi ♪
♪ pour quoi ♪
♪ Chere mad'moi selle ♪
♪ Est ce que ♪
♪ Par ce que ♪
♪ vous m'aimez? ♪♪
Mangez. Mangez.
♪♪ [Orchestra]
♪♪ [Continues]