[SINGING]
Here's to the beautiful ladies
Here's to those wonderful girls
This is the mixture to start the picture
So bring on the beautiful girls
NARRATOR: When Fred Astaire sang
this song in the film Ziegfeld Follies...
...the year was 1946...
...and MGM was at the height of its success
in creating incredible fantasies...
...and setting them to music.
Here, Lucille Ball tames a pack
of exotic cat-women.
It was imaginative, outlandish imagery,
and audiences loved it.
It was a time before television and VCRs,
when on the average...
...90 million Americans
went to the movies each week...
...and the MGM musical
was king of the box office.
The most popular entertainment
in the world.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
This is the mixture to start the picture
So bring on the beautiful girls
NARRATOR:
Once upon a time, there was a factory...
...that created wonderful musical dreams.
It happened when a special group
of talented artists came together...
...to create some of the world's
most enchanting movies.
Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
was not the only studio...
...that made musical motion pictures.
But it did make more than anyone else...
...and somehow did it better.
To tell us more
about those remarkable days...
...here's one of MGM's best:
Mr. Gene Kelly.
The 44 acres behind me...
...was where it all began.
When I first arrived here...
...MGM's dream factory
was in full swing.
And every week
the studio released a new film...
...and musicals
were always a big part of the lineup.
But the success of the MGM musical
did not happen overnight.
It all started
when the movies learned to talk.
[ALL SINGING]
KELLY: At first, the studios were unsure
of what to do with this new invention.
Then they hit on the idea
of filming popular vaudeville acts.
ALL [SINGING]: My pet told me cutely
That I'm set absolutely
- So I pet with nobody else but my, my pet
- Whose pet?
- I repeat that he's my pet
Ain't he sweet?
And I pet with nobody else
But my pet
KELLY:
In The Hollywood Revue of 1929...
...one of the first all-talking, all-singing,
all-dancing movies...
...the studio gave its huge roster
of stars...
...a chance to get their feet wet...
...in the newfangled talkies.
The finale introduced a brand-new song
that did a lot for me much later.
But at the time it was so new...
...that some of the performers
had trouble remembering the lyrics.
ALL [SINGING]: Let the stormy clouds
Chase everyone from the place
Come on with the rain
I've a smile on my face
I walk down the lane
With a happy refrain
Just singin'
Just singin' in the rain
Singin' in the rain
KELLY: Suddenly, the musical became
an overnight sensation...
...delighting audiences
with bigger casts...
...lavish sets and costumes...
...and even a new gimmick
called Technicolor.
MGM began its most ambitious film
of this kind...
...in late 1930...
...and filmed
all the big production numbers...
...before the public lost interest
in these plotless musicals...
...and the project was abandoned.
One of the numbers
featured The Dodge Twins...
...performing... What else?
- "The Lock Step"...
...from the unfinished March of Time.
[SINGING] Shake your stripes
Beat your pipe
Start crooning the jailhouse wail
Lock your cell
Step light, hello, warden
Join in and lock step
It'll get you fizzin'
Like bottles of pop
Get hep to the new jazz prison
Lock step
Clean as a whistle
Fresh as a daisy
Brand-new
Clean through
On my way
Just wearin' that smile of mine
Clean as a whistle
Fresh as a daisy
Spick-and-span
Spend my day
Just wearin' a great big smile
KELLY: To capture an audience,
producers knew they could always turn...
...to the old reliable sex.
Imagine that.
This number,
set in the shower room of a girls' school...
...shocked audiences in 1933.
ALL [SINGING]:
All wearin' a great big smile
Can't you see we're all excited?
They might be relaxing
But, gee, I'd rather
Exercise myself into
Say, the water stopped.
- Water.
KELLY: Such scenes fuelled
the growing public outcry.
Faced with threats of boycotts
and censorship...
...MGM conformed
to the stern Production Code.
- That the vulgar, the cheap
and the tawdry is out.
There is no room on this screen
at any time...
...for pictures which offend
against common decency.
And these, the industry will not allow.
EDDY [SINGING]:
Ah, sweet mystery of life
At last I found thee
Ah
KELLY: Among MGM's efforts
for the new morality...
...was a series
of wildly successful operettas...
...with Jeanette MacDonald
and Nelson Eddy.
BOTH [SINGING]: My heart has heard
The answer to its calling
For it is love that rules
Forevermore
KELLY: In 1934, the studio lifted the public
out of the Depression...
...and into a make-believe
Hollywood party.
[SINGING] Hollywood party
Get up, get up, get in it
Hollywood party
Nobody sleeps tonight
Going a mile a minute
Hollywood party
Nobody sleeps tonight
Let the laughter spring out
Music ring out
Satan sing out, "Yeah, man"
At that crashing, furniture-smashing
Hollywood party
Nobody sleeps tonight
And now, here's to beauty,
laughter, romance, music.
On with the biggest party
ever given in Hollywood.
[SINGING]
Feelin' high
What's the use
Feelin' low?
On that wagon
On the town
Gonna be up
Never down
There's a reason
If you'd like to know why
I'm in love
I'm feelin' high
KELLY: Even the biggest production numbers
needed stars.
So Eleanor Powell
became MGM's first big dancing star.
In Broadway Melody of 1938
and almost all of her films...
...Eleanor becomes a huge sensation
by the last reel.
ALL [SINGING]:
Follow in my footsteps
Follow them
Your Broadway
And my Broadway
Got that rhythm
Inside me
Everybody dance
You are my lucky star
Hear the rhythm of the music
And the music of the rhythm
Got a pair of new shoes
Gotta dance
Tap your feet
Light, long and sweet
And dance
Dance
Now Broadway dance
A Broadway dance and go singing
The whole town is waking up
Your Broadway
And mine
KELLY:
It took a lot of hard work...
...to make musical production numbers
for the big screen.
And here's a good example.
Eleanor Powell's tap dance
of "Fascinating Rhythm"...
...from Lady Be Good.
On the right, we see what went on
behind the scenes.
Stagehands using little tractors
called mules...
...quickly take the set apart...
...allowing the camera to move forward
to follow her dancing.
CHORUS [SINGING]: Fascinatin' rhythm
You've got me on the go
Fascinatin' rhythm
I'm all aquiver
What a mess you're making
The neighbors will know
I'm always shaking like a flivver
Each morning I'm wakin' up
Very happy
Just to find that no work has been done
Once it didn't matter
But now you do wrong
When you start to patter
I'm so unhappy
Won't you take a day off?
A couple of weeks?
Somewhere far away off
And make it snappy
Oh, how I long to be the man
That I used to be
Oh, fascinatin' rhythm
Won't you stop picking on me?
- Good morning
- It's a lovely morning
- What a wonderful day
We've danced the whole night through
Good morning, good morning to you
How do you do?
KELLY: When MGM teamed
Mickey Rooney and Judy Garland...
...in Babes in Arms...
...it launched the most successful
musical team at the studio.
BOTH [SINGING]:
Good morning, good morning to you
KELLY: With World War II raging in Europe,
the Mickey-Judy musicals...
...provided an uplifting diversion
for audiences of the day.
ALL [SINGING]: Qherever freedom's banners
Are unfurled sing a song from our hearts
To the hearts of the world
We send our greetings to friendly nations
We may be Yanks
But we're your relations
Drop your sabers
We're all gonna be good neighbors
Here in God's
God's
Country
KELLY: As Andy Hardy,
Mickey Rooney was always falling in love.
Esther Williams played his love interest
in her first film.
A fashion model
and champion swimmer...
...Esther was working in an aquacade...
...when she caught the attention
of an MGM talent scout.
In the 22 films she made at Metro...
...she was seldom out of the water.
WILLIAMS:
This is MGM's famous saucer tank.
I did many of
my underwater scenes here.
It's a huge, all-steel swimming pool...
...with porthole windows
just below the water line...
...so that you can see
anything that's going on inside.
This tank was originally built as a place
for Tarzan, Johnny Weissmuller...
...to fight his rubber crocodiles.
But I really had it
pretty much to myself...
...once my swimming musicals
became popular.
DURANTE [SINGING]: Every time they start off
Wit' a water ballet
There's the customary swimmin' pool
To swim in
But we don't wanna do it
In the customary way
So we start off
Just with bathin' suits and women
WILLIAMS: It had been five years
since my Andy Hardy movie.
By this time,
I had starred in several films.
And MGM was committed
to finding new ways...
...to get me out of my clothes
and into the pool...
...as in This Time for Keeps
with the great Jimmy Durante.
DURANTE [SINGING]:
Take ten percent off for your agent
Take ten percent off for the press
Then take another ten
For your publicity men
What's another ten more or less?
Then take off a few incidentals
It's the little things that really count
Anyone with half a brain
Can show a capital gain
If you take off the proper
Listen to your Papa
Take off the proper amount
WILLIAMS:
I was called America's mermaid...
...because it appeared
that I could stay underwater indefinitely.
In Jupiter's Darling...
...I swam into
a sunken Roman amphitheater...
...where my presence had the magical effect
of bringing statues to life.
In Dangerous When Wet...
...I swam into a cartoon sequence
where I met Tom and Jerry.
You know, they were more animated
than some of my leading men.
In Texas Carnival, I became
Howard Keel's underwater dream...
...right there in his own living room.
For 12 years,
I was the center of an amazing series...
...of vivid sights and water pageantry.
And I loved every minute of it.
ALLYSON [SINGING]: I'd be like Cleopatterer
If I could have my way
Each man she met she went and kissed
And she'd dozens on her waiting list
I wish that I had lived there
Beside the pyramid
For a girl today don't get the scope
That Cleopatterer did
WILLIAMS:
If one performer could exemplify...
...the lighthearted spirit
of the MGM musical...
...then June Allyson would surely be it.
Here, from Till the Clouds Roll By...
...she romanticizes the virtues
of that ancient Egyptian princess...
...Cleopatterer.
ALLYSON [SINGING]: Gaping in a line
And watch her agitate her spine
It simply use to knock them flat
When she went like this
And then like that
At dancing Cleopatterer
Was always on the spot
She gave these poor Egyptian ginks
Something else to watch
Besides the sphinx
Marc Antony admitted
That what first made him skid
Was the wibbly, wobbly, wiggly dance
That Cleopatterer did
This was the original main gate at MGM.
In the early days,
when a star came to work...
...they'd drive in here...
...and then the studio car
would whisk them off...
...to their destination on the lot.
It was all so glamorous.
MGM liked to boast...
...that it had more stars
than there are in the heavens.
I just felt lucky to be counted among them
when I was still just a kid.
[SINGING] I never wanna hear
Johann Sebastian Bach
ALLYSON:
That's me on the right.
Still wet behind the ears
from the Broadway show...
...Best Foot Forward...
...which the studio bought
and took me along as part of the package.
It's not hard to tell...
...that Nancy Walker,
Gloria DeHaven and I...
...desperately wanted
to make good at Metro.
ALL [SINGING]: Yes, the barrelhouse
The boogie-woogie and the blues
Oh, the barrelhouse
Makes you want to carol
Every boogie beat will raise your heat
When they start to play the blues
You'll never choose to lose the blues
Oh, the blues will really get you
And the barrelhouse
Is bound to upset you
And the boogie-woogie beat
Will drive you straight to distraction
Hey, let's go professors
Get a solid reaction
From a barrelhouse
The boog-boog-boog-boog boogie
And the blues
I love the boogie
'Cause it tickles my spine
'Cause it's fresh and it's fine
Just like a cigarette with modern design
That's why I love the boogie-woogie
Yes, yes
It seems to knock the wind
Right out of my chest
It's so darn good
It makes a fool of the rest
Just goes to show you
That the boogie's the best
That's why I love the boogie-woogie
Yes, yes
It's right as rain
As low as thunder
High as a cloud
And sweet as a cake
It's got a kick like mountain liquor
And it's as slick and hard
To take as Veronica Lake
It picks you up
And then it knocks you right down
It makes you laugh and play
And act like a clown
No other music has the right
To the crown
'Cause there's nothing
That will raise your heat
- Like the boogie-woogie beat
- Don't mean the barrelhouse
- Don't mean the blues
I love the boogie-woogie beat
- She loves the boogie-woogie beat
- Great
ALLYSON: Each year,
hundreds of performers like me...
...were brought to MGM,
hoping to get a break in the movies.
There were acting teachers,
instructions in posture and grooming...
...and everybody had to learn
to sing and dance.
It was an extensive crash course...
...designed to find those
with that special something...
...known as star quality.
And if you had it,
you got to take the next big step:
The screen test.
For instance, Kathryn Grayson
had to wait two years at MGM...
...before she was given
her first screen test...
...represented here in Anchors Aweigh.
But the wait paid off because she became
one of MGM's leading sopranos...
...in the 1940s and '50s.
GRAYSON [SINGING]:
To the thrill of the night
Shakin' the blues away
Unhappy news away
If you were blue, it's easy to
Shake off your cares and troubles
ALLYSON: Ann Miller was only 14 when
she got her first movie contract at RKO...
...and was a seasoned pro
when she came to MGM...
...for Easter Parade.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
Shakin' the blues away
Unhappy news away
If you are blue
It's easy to
Shake off your
Shake off your cares
And shake off your troubles
Provin' that there's a way
To chase your cares away
If you would lose
Your weary blues
Shake them away
Away
ALLYSON: Joan McCracken
was a wonderfully talented artist...
...from the Broadway stage...
...brought to enrich
MGM's galaxy of dancing stars.
Here, Joan and Ray McDonald
bring their infectious enthusiasm...
...to pass that peace pipe
from Good News.
ALL [SINGING]: Solid potato salad
Is the groovy movie salad, Jack
Solid potato salad bowl
Da-do da-do da-do-day
Bring it back
ALLYSON: Sometimes the studio
tried out a novelty act...
...that just didn't catch on,
no matter how hard they worked.
Meet The Ross Sisters
from Broadway Rhythm.
Whoo! Whoo!
[SINGING]
We're going on the town
ALLYSON: MGM musicals had a special
enthusiasm all their own.
In the 1949 hit On the Town...
...Frank Sinatra, Jules Munshin
and Gene Kelly...
...teamed with Betty Garrett,
Ann Miller and Vera-Ellen...
...as three sailors and their dates...
...go out on a night in New York City.
ALL [SINGING]: And hit the heights tonight
Get high as kites tonight
East side, west side, rouse the city
One day, one night, that's the pity
But we won't look ahead
Won't let the light of dawn get us down
We're really living, Jack
We're going on the town
We're kicking back the traces
We're gonna do the places
We've never done before
We're going on the loose
We're throwing all our dough in
And we'll keep right on going
As if no one before had any fun before
Hot spots, swank spots
Roofs and cellars
Three smart girls
And three slick fellers
We're going to paint it red
We'll fill 'em up
And then drink 'em down
Let's have a ball tonight
We're going on the town
What a dame, what a dame
She belongs in the hall of fame
ALLYSON: I have always admired
the strength and stamina of dancers.
And one of the greatest
is Cyd Charisse...
...whom Fred Astaire
called "beautiful dynamite."
And I completely agree.
ALL [SINGING]:
I'm flat
Baby, you knock me out
You're the whistle in the kisser
Super sweet
You're the top
People stop when you're on the street
You're a wow with the power
I admit defeat
One, two, three, four
Five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, boing
I'm beat
Star light, star bright
I see stars when you move in
One, two, left, right
You win
You got me hangin' on the ropes
Baby, you knock me out
You're the broad
I'd applaud in a Broadway show
You're the chick with the kick
Like a rodeo
Mighty punch, you got the punch
That lays me low
One, two, three, four,
Five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, boing
KO
Bam, slam
Hear me shout
Baby
You knock me out
This was MGM's scenic backdrop building
where talented artists...
...created their movie magic,
and this is just one section...
...of a huge painting
re-creating the Scottish countryside...
...for the film Brigadoon.
Altogether, it was originally
600 feet long...
...and 60 feet high
and wrapped around the entire interior...
...of MGM's Stage 15.
Gene Kelly and I spent many hours...
...rehearsing and filming our dance numbers
in front of these heathered hills.
I've always had such respect for Gene.
Dancer, singer, actor, choreographer...
...and director.
He did it all...
...and always brought
exciting new dimensions...
...to the musical motion picture.
BOTH [SINGING]: First, you put your
Two knees close up tight
Then you sway 'em to the left
Then you sway 'em to the right
Step around the floor kinda nice and light
Then you twist around and twist around
With all of your might
Stretch your lovin' arms
Straight out in space
Then you do the Eagle Rock
With the style and grace
Swing your foot way 'round
And bring it back
Now that's what I call Ballin' the Jack
CHARISSE: Gene's first big break came
on Broadway, starring in Pal Joey.
MGM soon grabbed him...
...and started him off
as Judy Garland's leading man...
...in For Me and My Gal.
BOTH [SINGING]:
Ballin' the Jack
CHARISSE:
Gene had a style all his own...
...charming and athletic,
with boundless energy.
In Summer Stock,
he created a classic number...
...using only a squeaky floor
and a newspaper as dance partners.
CHARISSE:
As a choreographer...
...Gene staged this exciting
and bittersweet ballet...
...to Richard Rodgers'
"Slaughter on Tenth Avenue"...
...from Words and Music.
His partner: The wonderful Vera-Ellen.
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
[WHISTLE TOOTING]
CHARISSE: Gene's inventiveness
seemed inexhaustible.
In An American in Paris...
...he even danced into
a Toulouse-Lautrec painting...
...to find Leslie Caron...
...and the incomparable music
of George Gershwin.
The film won six Oscars
plus a special award to Gene...
...for his brilliant achievements
in the art of choreography on film.
BOTH [SINGING]: Fit as a fiddle and ready
For love I can jump over the moon up above
Fit as a fiddle and ready for love
CHARISSE:
Gene teamed with Donald O'Connor...
...to perform this marvelously
comic vaudeville routine...
...for Singin' in the Rain.
BOTH [SINGING]: Soon all the church bells
Will be ringing and I'll march with Ma and Pa
How the church bells will be ringing
With a hey naughty-knotty
And a hotcha-cha
Hi, diddle-diddle, my baby's OK
Ask me a riddle, I'm waiting to say
Fit as a fiddle and ready for love
CHARISSE: It was my pleasure
to dance with Gene in several films...
...but I think this one is my favorite.
"The Heather on the Hill"
from Brigadoon.
[SINGING]
You are my lucky star
CHARISSE: Gene inspired
a whole new generation of stars.
One of the brightest
was a young California girl...
...named Debbie Reynolds.
Here's Debbie in a rare outtake
from Singin' in the Rain.
REYNOLDS [SINGING]:
Rod La Rocque and Valentino
You are
My lucky star
I was only 16
and still Mary Frances Reynolds...
...when I entered
the Miss Burbank contest.
I did it as a lark
to get a blouse and a scarf...
...that they were giving away
to all the contestants.
Well, as fate would have it...
...an MGM talent scout
was in the audience...
...and in a year, I was under contract
to the biggest studio in Hollywood.
It was at MGM that I learned the workings
of the studio's glamour mill...
...comprised of dozens
of talented artists and technicians...
...who made MGM's leading ladies
appear on the screen...
...as images of unsurpassed beauty.
REYNOLDS: Gorgeous gowns created by
the world-famous designer Adrian...
...were part of the treatment.
As well as Makeup
and Hair Departments...
...that could accomplish
any style imaginable.
A star like Joan Crawford
would sometimes...
...have her look redesigned
numerous times...
...until it matched the exact mood
of the role she was to play.
The studio prided itself
on presenting some of the most...
...glamorous women
seen anywhere in the world.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
You stepped out of a dream
You are too wonderful
To be what you seem
Could there be eyes like yours?
Could there be lips like yours?
Could there be smiles like yours?
Honest and truly?
You stepped out of a cloud
REYNOLDS: In 1941, the glamour age
had reached its zenith...
...with Tony Martin and an all-star cast
in Ziegfeld Girl.
MARTIN [SINGING]:
And have you all to myself
Alone and apart
Out of a dream
Safe in my heart
Of you
REYNOLDS: I even got the glamour treatment
in a dream sequence...
...to the song "A Lady Loves"
in the film I Love Melvin.
[SINGING] A lady loves expensive clothes
And pretty jewels and furs
And French chapeaus
She loves her lingerie in black
It suits her zodiac
Loves a penthouse
Where she'll be content to stay
Finds little gifts on her breakfast tray
But now and then pack and sail away
For a simple Riviera holiday
REYNOLDS: Donald O'Connor plays
my boyfriend in the film.
He envisions a different role in life
for my character.
His version of me
as a stay-at-home farm girl...
...was dropped from the final film.
Now, at last, you can see
our differing points of view.
A lady loves the simple things
She loves her dreams tied up
With apron strings
There are no yachts
In all her plans
Just little pots and pans
In the doorway
She'll wait for his warm caress
And he'll be handsome
Well, more or less
But he will notice that brand-new dress
Saying, "You look nice
Oh, never mind the price"
A lady loves beaucoup I'amour
But first of all she loves to be secure
And she adores the subtle phrase
That it's the man who pays
Yet there is one vital thought
She will place above
All of the things I make mention of
But most of all a lady loves to love
And what is more a lady loves to live
And what is more a lady lives to love
Thanks for the present
Of the silver-blue mink
Thanks for the plane
And the ice-skating rink
Thanks for the yacht
And for the solid-gold sink
Thanks a lot, but no thanks
REYNOLDS: Dolores Gray uses glamour
as a weapon...
...in this spoof of the power
of the devastating female...
...over the hapless male...
...from It's Always Fair Weather.
GRAY [SINGING]:
However classy
By which this lassie can be had
Thanks for the banks
And for the Santa Fe line
Thanks for the darling uranium mine
But I'm a gal
With only one valentine
Thanks a lot, but no thanks
For I am just a faithful lassie
Waitin' for her faithful lad
And there's no gift
However classy
By which this lassie can be had
Thanks for losin' your mind
And thanks for Fort Knox
Sealed and signed
But I've got a guy who's Clifton Webb
And Marlon Brando combined
Thanks a lot, but no
No thanks
I don't know why they scold me
For doing what I'm trying not to do
REYNOLDS: In Torch Song, Joan Crawford
made her final musical film...
...as a fading legend...
...performing in tropical makeup
for the song "Two-Faced Woman."
The recording wasn't a new one at MGM.
Sung by voice double India Adams...
...it had originally
been used with Cyd Charisse...
...for The Band Wagon,
but was cut from the final film.
It's been suggested that they may have
dropped the wrong version.
CRAWFORD [SINGING]:
Makeup
CHARISSE [SINGING]:
I don't belong
CRAWFORD [SINGING]:
I can't help being a two-faced woman
A little bit of boldness
A little bit of sweetness
A little bit of coldness
A little bit of heatness
Don't fall in love
With a two-faced woman
Givin' you a warnin'
I'll leave you in the mornin'
Got another lover under cover
I'm like a weathervane
That goes with the breeze
My disposition
Makes me do as I please
That's why they call her
A two-faced woman
A little bit of day
And a little bit of night
A little bit of sad
And a little bit of bright
A little bit of boldness
A little bit of sweetness
A little bit of coldness
A little bit of heatness
Good and bad
Sweet and sad
Black and white
Wrong and right
They call me two-faced woman
REYNOLDS:
In the early 1940s...
...Hollywood began a fascination
with things tropical...
...and south of the border,
and MGM was no exception.
Exotic rhythms and costumes...
...transported audiences
away from cold climates...
...and the troubled times of a world war.
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
REYNOLDS: Many Latin artists were recruited
to add an authentic sound to these films.
One of the most popular
was Xavier Cugat and his orchestra.
[SCREAMS]
REYNOLDS: Ricardo Montalban
became a sensation at Metro...
...as the Latin lover,
driving female audiences wild.
Here with Ann Miller and Cyd Charisse
from The Kissing Bandit...
...there doesn't seem to be
enough Ricardo to go around.
REYNOLDS: From Nancy Goes to Rio
comes the Brazilian bombshell herself:
The incomparable Carmen Miranda.
[SCATTING]
He's got the kind of appeal
That turns your head like a wheel
[SINGING] And what a wonderful feeling
That feeling you feel
Your heart will beat like a bongo
Just like was beating in mine
The heat of the sun may be 101
But you make it 109
And there is more to it yet
I'm gonna bet you a bet
That you can pack up and go
But you'll never forget
[SINGING IN PORTUGUESE]
REYNOLDS:
Carmen, of course, had her imitators...
...but none quite like Mickey Rooney...
...in Babes on Broadway.
[SINGING IN PORTUGUESE]
Hey, Ma
It seems we've stood and talked
Like this before
REYNOLDS: One ofthe performers at MGM
whom I admired the most...
...was the legendary Lena Horne.
[SINGING]
But I can't remember where
Or when
Some things that happen
For the first time
[SINGING]
Seem to be happening again
It was a long time ago
I stood in this very spot...
...and recorded that lovely song.
When I first walked onto
this recording stage in 1942...
...it looked pretty much as it does today.
Although the technology
was prehistoric...
...compared to what we use today.
I recorded all of the music
for my movies here...
...and it is still considered
Hollywood's greatest recording stage.
I have many memories here...
...good and bad.
I never felt like I really belonged
in Hollywood.
At that time, they didn't quite know
what to do with me, a black performer.
So I usually just came on,
sang a song and made a quick exit.
[SINGING]
It was just one of those things
Just one of those crazy things
HORNE: This was true of my first film
in the studio, Panama Hattie.
Yeah, I got to sing a great Cole Porter tune
in a featured appearance...
...but what I really wanted was to be given
an acting role in the movies.
Just one of those fabulous flights
A trip to the moon on gossamer wings
Just one of those things
If we thought a bit of the end of it
Before we started painting the town
We'd have been aware
That our love affair
Was too hot not to cool down
So goodbye, dear, and Amen
Here's hoping we meet now and then
It was great fun
But it was just
One of those things
Said that gal, Du Barry
"Ain't it the truth?"
HORNE:
In 1943, I got to play a part.
Georgia Brown in Cabin in the Sky.
And this good song, "Ain't It the Truth,"
was cut from the movie...
...because studio bosses
thought it too risqu...
...to show a black girl in a bubble bath.
[SINGING]
Love is a ripplin' brook
Man is a fish to cook
You got to bait your hook
Rise and shine
And cast your line
You got to get your possum
Ain't it the truth?
While you still in blossom
Cleopatra and Delilah
Had it way over Ruth
Them gals did mighty swell
They sure did ring that bell
Ain't it the gospel truth?
It's the truth
The truth
It's the solid
Mellow truth
HORNE:
In 1946, I played the role of Julie...
...in an excerpt from Show Boat
in Till the Clouds Roll By.
I was being considered for the part
for the 1951 version of Show Boat...
...but the Production Code Office
had banned interracial romance...
...on the screen.
So the studio gave the part
to my good friend Ava Gardner.
And she was wonderful in it.
The studio had Ava rehearse
singing the role...
...to the recordings that I had made
hoping to get the part...
...which annoyed us both.
Anyway, she did a great job
on her own...
...but just before releasing the film,
the studio dubbed her...
...with Annette Warren's voice.
GARDNER [SINGING]:
Fish got to swim, birds got to fly
I got to love one man till I die
Can't help lovin' that man of mine
HORNE: This is what audiences
would have heard...
...if they had allowed Ava's voice
to be used.
GARDNER [SINGING]:
Tell me he's lazy, tell me he's slow
Tell me I'm crazy
Maybe I know
Can't help
Lovin' that man of mine
HORNE: Though Ava was
one of my few good friends...
...I was deeply disappointed
that I didn't get the part.
[SINGING]:
That's a rainy day
But when he comes back
That day is fine
The sun will shine
He can come home
As late as can be
Home without him
Ain't no home to me
Can't help
Lovin' that man
Of mine
HORNE: I was not the only one
to lose a role here.
In Annie Get Your Gun,
Betty Hutton was a big hit...
...as Annie Oakley.
But Betty wasn't
the studio's first choice.
Judy Garland had begun filming the role
and completed two numbers...
...when she suffered a breakdown
and had to be replaced.
Retrieved at last
from the MGM film vaults...
...is Judy's version of
"I'm an Indian Too."
[INDIANS YELPING]
Am I an Indian yet?
Hoh!
[INDIANS CHEERING]
[INDIANS CHANTING]
[SINGING] Like the Chippewa
Iroquois, Omaha
Like those Indians
I'm an Indian too
A Sioux
Some Indian summer's day
Without a care
I may run away
With Big Chief Sun-of-a-Bear
And I'll have totem poles
Tomahawk
Small papoose
Which will go to prove
I'm an Indian too
A Sioux
Oh, I'm an Indian, I'm an Indian
I'm an honest Injun Indian
I'm an Indian, too
Ow
Folks are dumb where I come from
They ain't had any learning
HORNE: This is the only other number
Judy shot forAnnie Get Your Gun.
As you can see, whatever conflicts
Judy struggled with as a person...
...she always came through
as an entertainer.
GARLAND [SINGING]:
Still we've gone from A to Z
Doin' what comes naturally
You don't have to know
How to read or write
When you're out with a feller
In the pale moonlight
You don't have to look
In a book to find
What he thinks of the moon
And what is on his mind
That comes naturally
My uncle out in Texas
Can't even write his name
He signs his checks with "x's"
But they cash them just the same
Grandpa Dick was always sick
But never saw a doctor
He just died at 93
Doin' what comes naturally
The sleepless nights
The daily fights
The quick toboggan
When you reach the heights
I miss the kisses
And I miss the bites
I wish I were in love again
HORNE:
Words and Music was the last time...
...that Judy and Mickey Rooney
worked together at MGM...
...ending the most popular
song and dance team...
...the studio would ever have.
GARLAND [SINGING]:
No more pain
No more strain
Now I'm sane
But I would rather be gaga
The pulled-out fur of cat and cur
The fine mismating of a him and her
We've learned our lesson
And we wish we were in love
Again
[APPLAUSE]
Judy Garland and I
grew up together at MGM...
...and completed high school
between long days of shooting.
Here on the lot
we made 10 pictures together...
...and even when
we worked separately...
...we turned to each other
for friendship and encouragement.
We were the very best of friends,
more like brother and sister.
I still miss her very much.
Judy was 11 years old
when I first heard her sing...
...and I told her right off
what I felt then...
...and what I feel today.
I said to her,
"Darling, you're the best in the world."
ROONEY: By the time 15-year-old Judy
appeared in Everybody Sing...
...she had already been on-stage
for more than a decade...
...billed as the little girl
with the great, big voice.
[SCATTING]
[SINGING]
Teach me how to sing
Music with a modern rhythm
Let me swing
Mr. Mendelssohn swing
Music is a thing
That's no good without that rhythm
Sweet and hot
Fast and slow
So get yourself
A little dash of holy ho
And swing it
Mr. Mendelssohn swing it high
Hey, swing it low
[ALL SCATTING]
And swing it
Mr. Mendelssohn swing
I'm past the stage
Of doll and carriage
I'm not the age
To think of marriage
I'm too old for toys
And I'm too young for boys
I'm just an in-between
ROONEY:
In Love Finds Andy Hardy...
...Judy laments the fact
that she's not a little girl any longer...
...and not quite a grownup either.
GARLAND [SINGING]:
Grownups ignore me
And in every sense
I'm just on a fence
I'm just an in-between
ROONEY: For a few years,
Judy was an in-between.
Even though the critics
had compared her talent...
...to that of a teenage Sarah Bernhardt...
...the studio had to search
for just the right part...
...to showcase her grownup gifts.
They found it in her first starring role:
Dorothy Gale in The Wizard of Oz.
When Judy stepped into
the Technicolor land of Oz...
...it mirrored her arrival as a major star.
Toto, I have a feeling
we're not in Kansas anymore.
We must be over the rainbow.
MUNCHKINS [SINGING]: Follow the yellow
Brick road follow the yellow brick road
Follow, follow, follow, follow
Follow the yellow brick road
Follow the yellow brick
You're off to see the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
You'll find he is a Whiz of a Wiz
If ever a Wiz there was
If ever, oh ever, a Wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
Because, because, because
Because, because
Because of the wonderful things he does
ROONEY:
The Wizard of Oz was to become...
...the most widely seen
motion picture of all time...
...and Judy's wonderful performance
in the picture...
...earned her a special Academy Award...
...which I was lucky enough
to present to her.
And, Judy, I hope you win
many more of them, honey.
Thank you.
And how about doing us all
a little favor now...
...and singing "Over the Rainbow"?
Will you do that?
[APPLAUSE]
[SINGING]
Somewhere over the rainbow
Blue birds fly
Birds fly over the rainbow
Why, then
Oh, why can't I?
I like New York in June, how about you?
I like a Gershwin tune, how about you?
I love a fireside when a storm is due
I like potato chips
Moonlight and motor trips
How about you?
ROONEY: My favorite memories
of working with Judy...
...are when it was just the two of us
performing a simple...
...song and dance routine together...
...like this one from Babes on Broadway.
[SINGING]
I love to dream of fame, maybe I'll shine
I'd love to see your name
Right beside mine
I can see we're in harmony
Looks like we both agree
On what to do
And I like it, how about you?
Down on an island, the southern seas
There lived a lassie named Minnie Breeze
And all the natives agree
That she's the hottest thing in Trinidad
ROONEY: Judy became one of the country's
top 10 box-office stars.
The little girl was growing up.
So the studio gave her
the full glamour treatment...
...in this Busby Berkeley extravaganza
from Ziegfeld Girl.
GARLAND [SINGING]:
They call her Minnie from Trinidad
They all love Minnie from Trinidad
And all the natives would be so sad
If Minnie ever left Trinidad
And all the natives would be so glad
If Minnie
Came back to Trinidad
For Minnie
Minnie
Came back to Trinidad
Who, stole my heart away
Who, makes me dream all day
Dreams I know can never come true
Seems as though I'll ever be blue
Who, means my happiness
Who, would I answer yes to
Well, you ought to guess who
No one but you
ROONEY: By 1946, Judy was one
of the studio's most valuable assets...
...and made a special guest appearance
as Marilyn Miller...
...in the Jerome Kern biography,
Till the Clouds Roll By.
[SINGING]
March on, little doagies
March on, down the trail
ROONEY: One of Judy's biggest hits
was The Harvey Girls.
The film was so big, in fact...
...that there wasn't time
for this extraordinary production number...
...in the final film.
Here are Judy, Ray Bolger, Cyd Charisse,
and a cast of hundreds...
...in a never-before-seen
"March of the Doagies."
GARLAND [SINGING]:
We don't know where we're goin'
But we're on our way
March on, little doagies
March on, down the trail
Till we're past the last fence rail
Out there lies the prairie
Out there breaks the day
Oh, we don't know where we're goin'
But we're on our way
- Me for a campfire out on the trail
- Me for an old cayuse
- Me for the sound of the coyote's wail
- And I'm all set to vamoose
- You for a pipe, when the evenin' is still
- You for your own backyard
- I'll be the first fella over the hill
- Me for a campfire out on the trail
An old cayuse and a coyote's wail
With nothin' to do
And nobody asking me why
Give me a cowhand song
And I'll be gettin' along
March on along
March on
The doagies on the trail
Are marchin' on
Until the last grand swale
Out there lies the prairie
Out there breaks the day
Oh, we don't know where we're goin'
But we're on our way
ROONEY: In Summer Stock,
Judy was seen for the first time...
...wearing what was to become
her trademark for years to come.
The top half of a tuxedo.
Two years before, however,
she had worn the same outfit...
...in a scene removed from
the released version of Easter Parade.
Irving Berlin had based a song
on just a few notes...
...and called it "Mr. Monotony."
This is Judy at the top of her career.
GARLAND [SINGING]:
Playing on his slide trombone
In a certain monotone
He was known as Mr. Monotony
Any pleasant interlude
That would mean a change of mood
Didn't go with Mr. Monotony
Sometimes he would change the key
But the same dull melody
Would emerge from Mr. Monotony
Folks for miles would run away
Only one preferred to stay
She would come around and say
"Have you got any monotony today?"
"Haven't got any monotony
Today
Can't play
Haven't got any monotony
Today"
[APPLAUSE]
It only happens when I dance with you
ROONEY: Another legend at Metro
was my good friend Fred Astaire...
...who always romanced
a glamorous partner in his motion pictures.
In Easter Parade,
it was the one and only Ann Miller.
ASTAIRE [SINGING]:
Seem quite so near
Why does it happen, dear
Only with you?
Two cheeks together can be so divine
But only when those cheeks
Are yours and mine
I've danced with dozens of others
The whole night through
But the thrill that comes with Spring
When anything could happen
That only happens with you
It was at a rehearsal hall like this...
...that I spent my first days at MGM...
...preparing for the production numbers
in Easter Parade.
Oh, and I was just scared stiff
because I was going to dance...
...with the master.
But Fred Astaire was as charming
off the screen as he was on...
...and he put me at ease right away.
Especially after I agreed to dance with him
in ballet slippers...
...so I wouldn't be taller than he was.
Fred was a perfectionist.
After exhausting hours of rehearsal...
...when we all thought we had it just right,
he would say:
"Come on, Annie,
let's do it one more time."
What I wouldn't give
to do it just one more time again.
Fred and his sister Adele
were already stars...
...in the New York and London theater
before he came to MGM in 1933.
Do you feel like going through
that number with Mr. Astaire?
- All right.
- Freddie.
Show Miss Marlowe the routine
on that opening number.
- Good evening.
- Miss Marlowe.
ASTAIRE: Do you know the routine?
- I've seen it often enough. I'll try.
That's fine. Harry, give us the pickup
on that gang number, will you, please?
MILLER: It was a little more
than a guest appearance for Fred...
...for he was soon to be under
contract to RKO Pictures...
...where they were about to team him
with Ginger Rogers...
...causing a string of hit musicals
to follow.
Fred didn't return to MGM
until seven years later...
...at which time he starred
with Eleanor Powell...
...in Broadway Melody of 1940.
MILLER: In 1945, Fred and a new partner,
Lucille Bremer...
...stepped out to "Coffee Time"
in Yolanda and the Thief.
Its director, Vincente Minnelli.
[APPLAUSE]
[SINGING]
That's for me
I'm drum crazy, yes
I'm plumb crazy for drums
MILLER: Fred could make music
out of almost anything.
And he often found new challenges
that stretched his talents.
In Easter Parade, he uses drums
to make a melody.
ASTAIRE [SINGING]:
First, soft violins
Then, sweet saxophones
Then, blue clarinets croon
When it's my turn I turn into a loon
When the drum takes the melody
When the drum carries the tune
MILLER: Hard-boiled private eyes
were all the rage in the '50s.
Perfect for the musical spoof,
"The Girl Hunt" ballet...
...from The Band Wagon.
In it, Fred plays a tough detective
tracking down a killer.
The femme fatale, Cyd Charisse.
ASTAIRE:
She came at me in sections.
More curves than a scenic railway.
She was bad. She was dangerous.
I wouldn't trust her
any farther than I could throw her.
She was selling hard,
but I wasn't buying.
MILLER: A team that had no equal
was Fred Astaire and Ginger Rogers.
In The Barkleys of Broadway,
they dance the "Swing Trot"...
...under the main titles of the picture,
but with the titles removed...
...another musical gem is revealed...
...from the most beloved
dance team of all time.
CHORUS [SINGING]: And you're the greatest
Dancer in the land
It's bill and coo-y, tea for two-y
Just watch your partner's
Eyes grow dewy
Entrenous-y you're slightly screwy
But irresistible
On and on
Oh, what a natural they've hit upon
It gets you going till you're really gone
And you will never rue the day
The day you realize
The Swing Trot is here to stay
[APPLAUSE]
MILLER: For The Belle of New York,
the studio decided to reshoot this scene...
...because Fred's costume
didn't suit his famous dapper style.
So by putting the original
and the reshot versions together...
...it gives us a rare opportunity
to see just how perfectly rehearsed...
...Fred really was.
ASTAIRE [SINGING]:
I wanna be a dancin' man while I can
Gonna leave my footsteps
On the sands of time
If I never leave a dime
A dancin' man
With footsteps
On the sands
Of rhythm
And rhyme
[APPLAUSE]
Anything you can do, I can do better
I can do anything better than you
MILLER: Another one ofmy favorite
leading men was Howard Keel.
Best known for his rich baritone voice,
he had a very competitive romance...
...with Betty Hutton
in Annie Get Your Gun.
- No, you're not
- Yes, I am
- Yes, I am, yes, I am
I can shoot a partridge
With a single cartridge
I can get a sparrow
With a bow and arrow
I can live on bread and cheese
- And only on that?
- Yes
- So can a rat
- Any note you can reach, I can go higher
- I can sing anything higher than you
- No, you can't
- Yes, I can
Yes, I can
Anything you can wear, I can wear better
In what you wear I'd look better than you
- In my coat?
- In your vest
- In my shoes?
- In your hat
- No, you can't
- Yes, I can, yes, I can
Anything you can say, I can say faster
I can say anything faster than you
- No, you can't
- Yes, I can
- I can jump a hurdle
- I can wear a girdle
- I can knit a sweater
- I can fill it better
I can do most anything
- Can you bake a pie?
- No
Neither can I
Any note you can sing
I can sing sweeter
I can sing anything sweeter than you
No, you can't
Yes, I can
- Yes, I can
- No, you can't
- No, you can't, can't, can't
Yes, I can, can, can
- No, you can't
- Yes, I can
This is the vault where thousands
upon thousands of MGM films are stored.
Their worth in dollars, film history,
entertainment...
...is immeasurable.
There are a few of these, of course,
in which I appeared.
This one, Rose Marie...
...was the first wide-screen,
CinemaScope musical.
Now, in the 1950s,
Hollywood went into a panic...
...that rivaled the advent
of talking pictures.
A monster had taken over
the movie-going public: Television.
So the movies
went into new technologies...
...such as CinemaScope,
stereophonic sound...
...to try to recapture their audience.
[SINGING] Today to get the public
To attend a picture show
It's not enough to advertise
A famous star they know
If you want to get the crowds
To come around
You gotta have glorious Technicolor
Breathtaking Cinemascope and
Stereophonic sound
KEEL: In Silk Stockings,
Janis Paige and Fred Astaire...
...spoof the necessary elements
to make a modern motion picture.
PAIGE [SINGING]:
This lover boy's technique
If you want to hear
Applauding hands resound
You gotta have glorious Technicolor
Breathtaking Cinemascope and
Stereophonic sound
The customers don't like to see
The groom embrace the bride
Unless her lips are scarlet
And her mouth is five feet wide
In glorious Technicolor
Breathtaking Cinemascope
Or Cinerama, VistaVision or
Superscope or Todd-AO and
Stereophonic sound
And Stereophonic sound
There was a time when dancing
Was so intimate and sleek
A fella hugged his partner
As they'd cuddle cheek to cheek
Now he doesn't even know
If she's around
Because they're in glorious Technicolor
Breathtaking Cinemascope and
Stereophonic sound
It's not enough today
To see a dancer at his ease
He's got to throw his back out
And come sliding on his knees
He's gotta have glorious Russian ballet
Or modern ballet or English ballet or
Chinese ballet or Hindu ballet or
Bali ballet or any ballet
And Stereophonic sound
And Stereophonic adds an extra tonic
Stereophonic sound
- Shakin' the blues away
- Away
- Unhappy news away
If you were blue, it's easy to
Shake off your cares and troubles
KEEL: In 1955, the studio
cleverly combined the new technologies...
...with the old-fashioned backstage musical
and starred Doris Day...
...in the Oscar-winning hit
Love Me or Leave Me.
DAY [SINGING]:
Do like the voodoos do
Listen to a voodoo melody
They shake their bodies so
To and fro
With every shake
A lucky break
- Provin' that there's a way
- A way
- To chase your cares away
- Away
If you would lose your weary blues
Shake 'em away
- Shakin' the blues away
- Away, away
- Unhappy news away
If you were blue, it's easy to
Shake off your cares and troubles
Tellin' the blues to go
They may refuse to go
But as a rule they'll go
If you'll shake 'em away
Do like the voodoos do
Listen to a voodoo melody
They shake their bodies so
To and fro
With every shake
A lucky break
- Provin' that there's a way
- A way
- To chase your cares away
- Away
If you would lose your weary blues
Shake 'em away
Shake those blues away
Gotta chase those cares away
Just to prove that there's a way
A way to shake, shake your blues
Away
[APPLAUSE]
The warden threw a party
In the county jail
The prison band was there
And they began to wail
The band was jumpin'
And the joint began to swing
You should've heard
Those knocked-out jailbirds sing
Let's rock
KEEL:
Times were changing, and so was music.
MGM began appealing
to a new generation of filmgoers...
...with Elvis Presley
and the "Jailhouse Rock."
ELVIS [SINGING]:
Was dancin' to the Jailhouse Rock
Spider Murphy played
The tenor saxophone
Little Joe was blowin'
On the slide trombone
The drummer boy from Illinois
Went crash, boom, bang
The whole rhythm section
Was the Purple Gang
Let's rock, everybody, let's rock
Everybody in the whole cell block
Was dancin' to the Jailhouse Rock
Number forty-seven said to number three:
"You're the cutest jailbird
I ever did see
I sure would be delighted
With your company
Come on and do the Jailhouse Rock
With me"
Let's rock
Go, go, go
Everybody, let's rock
Lay it on me, daddy-o
Everybody in the whole cell block
Was dancin' to the Jailhouse Rock
Dancin' to the Jailhouse Rock
Rock, rock, rock
Gigi, am I a fool without a mind...
...or have I merely been
too blind to realize?
Oh, Gigi.
KEEL:
In 1958...
...the golden age of the MGM musical
came to a grand finale...
...with Lerner and Loewe's Gigi.
The film became
the studio's top box-office musical...
...and won nine Academy Awards,
including one for this lovely song.
The film stars Louis Jourdan
and the lovely Leslie Caron.
JOURDAN [SINGING]:
Oh, no
Overnight there's been
A breathless change
In you
Oh, Gigi
While you were trembling on the brink
Was I out yonder somewhere
Blinking at a star?
Oh, Gigi
Have I been standing up too close?
Or back too far?
When did your sparkle turn to fire?
And your warmth become desire?
Oh, what miracle
Has made you the way
You are?
What a time it was.
Life was simpler then.
And so was the movie business.
MGM's dream factory
created a rich, romantic...
...compelling world of illusion.
And although we may not
see anything like it again...
...we're blessed with memories...
...and miles and miles of film.
In the words of Irving Berlin:
"The song is ended...
...but the melody lingers on."
PEOPLE [SINGING]:
A show that is really a show
Sends you out with a kind of a glow
And you say as you go on your way
That's Entertainment
A song that is winging along
Or a dance with the touch of romance
Is the art that appeals to the heart
That's Entertainment
The world is a stage
The stage is a world
Of entertainment
[ENGLISH SDH]