[WINNIE THE POOH]
[NARRATOR] This could be the
room of any small boy.
But it just happens to belong
to a boy named Christopher Robin.
Like any small child, Christopher
Robin had toy animals to play with.
Together they shared many
exciting and unusual adventures.
- Oh. Uh... Huh?
- [MUSIC STOPS]
- Uh, where was I?
- [MUSIC RESUMES]
Oh, yes.
They shared many
exciting and unusual...
- [MUSIC STOPS]
- Huh?
What is going on here?
Hello? Is anyone there?
Yaa-hoo!
Hi, Mr. Narrator.
[CHUCKLES] Hello, Roo.
Are you gonna tell a story
about Winnie the Pooh?
And Piglet?
Well, not exactly.
Although I can assure you,
they'll be joining us very soon.
Then it must be about
my best bouncing buddy, Tigger.
Ah, Tigger's right in the
thick of things, as always.
But this story isn't
really about them.
Oh, then who's it about?
Actually,
the story begins with you.
Me?
No way!
Yes, way!
[KANGA] Roo, dear, your breakfast
is getting cold.
That's my mama. I gotta go.
- Oh! See you later!
- [NARRATOR CHUCKLES]
See you in a few pages.
Our story begins on
a fine spring day
in the Hundred Acre Wood.
And on that quiet
and peaceful morning,
the only sounds to be heard
were the chirping of the birds,
the buzzing of the bees, and...
Today's the day!
It's finally here.
Easter!
[CHUCKLES] Perhaps I'll just let
Roo take it from here.
I'm going to Rabbit's
for the Easter egg hunt, Mama.
It certainly is a
beautiful day for it.
Me and Tigger are gonna find every
egg in the Hundred Acre Wood.
I'm sure you will, dear, but
first come and eat your breakfast.
If I find any pink eggs,
I'm giving them to Piglet.
The pink ones are his favorite.
How sweet of you!
You're gonna make him very happy.
I sure hope so. And I'm
gonna bring you a blue one,
'cause those are the prettiest.
[LAUGHS]
Well, you better eat up then.
You can't hunt eggs
on an empty stomach.
That's what
Winnie the Pooh says, too.
And he's exactly right.
So, you can go just
as soon as you're finished.
[ROO] All done!
[CHUCKLES]
Hoo-hoo!
Happy Easter, Tigger!
You bounced me good, Roo boy.
Whatcha got in the bag?
Just a little something
to help you find Eastery eggs.
First a compass, so you'll
know where you are.
A backpack for Eastery eggs.
Rope for whatnots,
and in case you don't need a knot.
Some of this, some of that. Can't
forget this, little extra of that. Ah!
Different holiday.
Of course, you gotta have one of these.
In short, everything you need but Roo.
- Roo? Roo? Roo?
- [CHUCKLES]
Here I am, Tigger.
Oh, there you are!
You're getting kinda big, kiddo.
Now let's get going.
Goodbye, dears. Have fun.
[CHUCKLES] Oh! She called us "dears."
Goodbye, Mrs. Kanga, ma'am.
Um, ah. Oh!
And hello, too. I guess.
[NARRATOR LAUGHS] Now, I promised that
Winnie the Pooh would be in this story.
And here he is now.
[HUMMING]
- Oh, hello, Piglet.
- Oh, hello, Pooh.
I'm glad I ran into you.
Because now we can go
to Rabbit's house together.
I can't wait to see
what he's doing for Easter.
Yes, Piglet,
especially if there's honey.
My tummy and I have been
so looking forward to this day.
[sniffs] Ah.
Even you must be happy
on a day like this, Eeyore.
Positively tickled pink.
Oh, just like Piglet.
[LAUGHING] I do love Easter.
All the flowers are blooming.
And the bees are busy
buzzing for honey.
- Yep. Makes me feel downright...
- Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Peaceful.
- Oh, hello, Tigger.
- Don't you mean, "Happy Easter"?
And if that is what you mean,
you know what that means.
Hoo-hoo! We get to
go hunt Eastery eggs.
With my special pink
Easter basket.
And my lovely Easter honey pot.
Wouldn't be Easter without
my super stripety Eastery egg.
Or my fluffy bunny ears.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Stop your talking
and start your walking.
We're hunting eggs today
[ALL] We're hunting eggs today
And I can hardly wait
For what we'll find there
We're hunting eggs today
[ALL] We're hunting eggs today
The Easter bunny's left
a lot behind there
Red ones, blue ones
Yellow, pink and green
Purple polka-dotted ones
Even tangerine
A bouncy strippety-stripedy one
I bet you've never seen
We're hunting eggs today
[ALL] We're hunting eggs today
And that's our favorite way
[ALL] And that's our favorite way
To spend a flippity-floppity
Hippity hoppity
Happy...
Spring Cleaning Day!
Oh, it's Spring Cleaning Day,
everyone.
That wasn't quite
what I had in mind.
But, Rabbit, don't you
remember what today is?
Yeah, we're supposed
to be celebrating...
Spring Cleaning Day,
that's what I said.
- [HONKS]
- [STAMMERS] But, Rabbit,
aren't you forgetting something?
Your detailed list of chores and
duties. I've got it right here.
But, Rabbit, today's the day that
I always get my very special...
Mop and bucket,
that's right, Pooh.
Now, step lively, everyone.
Can't afford to dilly-dally.
You've got a lot of work to do.
Ah, you fooled us good, Rabbit.
- Now, we can go celebrate...
- Enough chit-chat, Roo. [LAUGHS]
This is no time for fun and games.
- No, no.
- But it's such a pretty day outside.
Yes, and it will be
just as pretty inside.
As long as you all do exactly
as I say.
Oh, pay attention now, everyone.
The theme for this year is,
"Spic and Span for Spring."
Kinda catchy,
if I do say so myself.
Now, if you'd all direct your attention
to this scale model I've created.
Oh, please excuse
the rudimentary workmanship.
I just threw it together
at the last minute.
When I give the signal,
you will disperse to your
assigned cleaning stations.
Tigger, Piglet, Pooh.
You'll dust, sweep, mop and scrub.
And don't spare the soap.
You can never be too clean,
you know.
On the floor, go with the grain.
Always...
You don't suppose
this could be a honey pot?
Do you?
No, Pooh, I don't suppose.
Empty. Not even a smackerel.
And Eeyore, your job is to sweep
all the soot out of the chimney.
Thanks for noticing me.
[ECHOING]
I beg your pardon, Rabbit.
Yes. What is it, Pooh?
Well, this honey pot appears
to be rather, um,
empty.
That's because it's not
a honey pot, Pooh.
- It's a bucket.
- Oh, bother.
Because if it were a honey pot,
I should fill it with honey.
No, no, no honey!
Honey's no good
for anything but making messes!
And eating, Rabbit.
Doh!
Mm... On second thought, Pooh,
I'm going to promote
you to supervisor.
Hey! Congratulations,
Mr. Super-de-dupervisor!
Oh, how exciting, Pooh!
Yes, it is exciting!
[CHUCKLES]
What is a supervisor, Rabbit?
A supervisor is someone
who sits right here
and doesn't cause trouble.
Ah, Rabbit, it's no trouble at all.
[CHUCKLES]
[GROANS]
- Can I ask a question?
- Oh, yes, Roo. I almost forgot.
I've given you the
simplest task of all.
You're to clean the closet.
All you have to do is
organize, sanitize
and alphabetize every box
and leave them
all neatly closed, dusted
and placed at right
angles on the shelf.
[GROANS]
Very well. You have your orders.
Now, I expect this place to
be spotless when I get back!
Where will you be, Rabbit?
Tidying up in the garden.
Outside?
Can I help?
No, Roo. No, no. Better
leave it to me and me alone.
Now, to work, everyone!
Rabbit, wait! What about...
Easter.
[NARRATOR] As you can see, Rabbit
didn't pay attention
to what anyone else wanted.
Only to what he wanted.
That's why he was happiest
of all, out here in his garden,
where nobody could question his
orders and everything would be just so.
Good morning, Franklin.
Oh, and you're looking well,
Frederick.
[SIGHS, SMACKS]
There you go, Belinda.
- Snug as a bug in a rug.
- [CROW SQUAWKS]
Hmm? What?
Oh, no! Oh, no, no!
Oh, no, get out! Shoo!
All of you! Shoo! Shoo!
- [SQUAWKING]
- [LAUGHS]
Much better.
[HUMMING]
Hm? Uh-hmm.
Mm-hmm.
[NARRATOR] Rabbit weeded and swept
and raked all the way from page 122,
to a rather immaculate page 127.
Meanwhile, back inside...
Ohhh!
Cleanin' up the cobwebs
Is what Tiggers do the bestest
Bouncin' high into the sky
To get up where the mess is
Now I don't wanna boast
But what I really must confess is
That cleanin' up the cobwebs
Is what Tiggers do the bestest!
All together now!
Or not.
Why so glum, chums?
Didn't think I looked so glum.
I miss my Easter honey pot.
And I especially miss the
honey that comes with it.
And I miss my pink Easter basket.
Oh, come on, fellas.
Let's get to saniterisin'
and niftyifyin'.
We don't want to let
ol' Rabbit down now, do we?
I guess not.
What're we waiting for?
Let's hop to it!
Yeah. Let's hop to it.
Just like the Easter bunny!
[CHUCKLES]
Just like the Easter...
Hey, Roo boy, you made a funny.
A, uh, Bunny funny!
Did someone mention honey?
Come on, Tigger.
We gotta spring into action!
Attaboy, Roo boy!
We'll have this place
spiffy in a jiffy!
And, uh...
Uh, okay, maybe two jiffies.
[POOH] Ah-choo!
Gesundheit, Pooh!
[GRUNTS] This cleanin' stuff
sure is dirty business!
Say, how you comin'
in there, Roo boy?
Almost done!
Just one
more
box.
[NARRATOR] Tigger and the gang were
cleaning up quite a storm.
However, as they swept
the dust out of the corners,
they swept it right into
Winnie the Pooh.
[SNEEZES] Oh, bother.
Sniffley-sniff
Whistley-wheeze
Here it comes
A great big sneeze
I feel it in
My ears and knees
Here it comes
A great big sneeze!
Oh!
[HIGH-PITCHED SNEEZE] Ah.
I close my eyes and
wiggle my nose
And I itch and
scrunch my face
I shiver and shake
down to my toes
And wave my arms
all over the place!
Oh, goodness!
Sniffley-sniff
Whistley-wheeze
Here it comes
A great big sneeze
I feel it in
My ears and knees
Here it comes
A great...
Big...
[SHUDDERS]
[STAMMERS] Oh, dear!
[GASPS] Better hang on to somethin'!
I think he's gonna blow!
Ah-choo!
[narrator] Winnie the Pooh
sneezed the biggest sneeze
that had ever been sneezed
in the Hundred Acre Wood!
Ah!
Piglet?
Stuff and fluff.
Excuse me, Mr. Dust Bunny?
Did you perchance see
my friend Piglet?
Ooh. It's me, Pooh.
- Oh. [LAUGHS] So it is.
- Where's Tigger?
[GROANS, COUGHS]
- Found him.
- Hi!
Eeyore, where are you?
Oh, there he is!
- Are you all right, Eeyore?
- Been better.
Been worse, too.
Hey, where's Roo?
Yoo-hoo, Roo!
[ROO] In here, Tigger!
Oh, what is all this stuff?
[TIGGER GASPING]
Wait a cotton-pickin' second.
That's Rabbit's Easter Bunny hat!
And look! I found
your Easter honey pot, Pooh!
And I believe this is your
favorite Easter basket, Piglet!
And my fluffy bunny ears.
Here's your stripedy
Easter egg, Tigger!
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Roo boy, you found
our old Easter decorations!
Yeah,
they were hidden way up there.
I did the biggest bounce ever
to reach 'em!
Maybe Rabbit couldn't find them,
and that's why he forgot about Easter.
Well, now that we have everything,
why don't we surprise him?
We could paint Easter eggs!
And fill honey pots!
Sounds awfully festive.
And then can we have an
Easter egg hunt? Can we, huh?
You're way ahead of me,
Roo boy!
No, I'm not, Tigger!
I'm right here beside you!
So you are! So you are!
Now, you do remember what to do with
all this Eastery stuff, don't you?
I kinda sorta do.
Oh, right. That's on account
of because you only did it once,
when you were an even littler
little fella. Come here, you!
Allow us to remember you
all there is to know
about havin' fun at Easter!
Hold on to your socks
And open up the box
The streamers and the
sparkles and confetti
All the stuff we need
for gettin' ready
For the biggest thing
We've seen this spring!
This place could use some bounce
In extra large amounts
We'll decorate it super
great and then
We'll be set for
Easter once again!
Then we'll have a bright
and sunny Honey of an Easter
With painted eggs and
jellybeans, too!
Of all the fun and neat stuff
The candy and the sweet stuff
My favorite Easter
wish'll come true
When I share this
Easter day with you!
Tell me more, Tigger!
Tell me more.
Well, Roo boy, I almost forgot
the most importantest part.
'Cause what I like
most about Easter
Is the way we show
our pals that we care
For the fun never ends
When you give to your friends
And you share the wonder of a
[ALL] Bright and sunny honey
of an Easter
With painted eggs and
jellybeans, too!
- Of all the fun and neat stuff
- The candy and the sweet stuff?
My favorite Easter
wish'll come true!
[ALL] When we share
this Easter day with you
Lots of fun and neat stuff
The candy and the sweet stuff...
[HUMMING]
Hunt for eggs and chase balloons
And shout "hip-hip-hooray!"
[HUMMING]
With you
Yeah!
[GIGGLES]
[GASPS]
Ah? Huh?
Happy Easter, Rabbit!
[WHIMPERS]
[PIGLET LAUGHING]
Easter? Easter?
Sure, you remember Easter,
don't you?
You know, with jellybeans
and Easter baskets
and a great big Easter egg hunt?
Well, Roo, [GULPS]
I'm afraid you've been
terribly misinformed.
Why, this is Spring Cleaning Day.
And you've all ruined it.
I don't believe it.
I told you exactly what to do.
And you didn't do any of it!
But, Rabbit...
Not another word.
I want you all out of here at once.
Out!
- Out!
- But...
All of you, out!
[LAUGHS]
I'll take that!
[SIGHS] That went well.
Maybe we should've sung it
in a different key.
I don't think so, Tigger.
I don't think Rabbit
wants us to sing anything.
Now that you mention it,
I'm startin' to get the feelin' Rabbit
doesn't wanna celebrate Easter...
[GULPS] At all!
Huh?
[SIGHS]
Ah, Easter.
Humph!
Guess there's nothing left
to do but go home then.
[sighs] Come on, Roo boy.
Roo?
Oh, Roo, there you are.
You wanna go bouncing?
Ah, no, thanks.
I don't feel like it.
Look on the bright side,
at least you don't have to do
anymore springity cleanin'.
What are we gonna do about Rabbit?
He did get pretty hot and bothery.
Tigger?
Why is Rabbit so unhappy?
I kinda got the compression it had
something to do with this Eastery stuff.
Does this mean we're not gonna
do Eastery stuff anymore?
What? Not do Eastery stuff?
[CHUCKLES]
Why, of course we're
gonna do Eastery stuff!
All we gotta do is
stuff that is, per se...
Eastery in nature,
which would necessitate
the doage of...
[SOBBING] We're never ever gonna
get to do Eastery stuff again!
But why not?
Why not? "Why not?"
you ask.
Actually,
that's a good question.
And I know just who
to ask it to, too!
- Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
- You're gonna go talk to Rabbit?
Why, Roo boy, I'm gonna hit him with
all the powerses of my persuasion.
If that doesn't work, I'll just
rely on my irresistibibble charm!
Do you really think
you can change his mind?
Do I?>
Everything changes
in springitytime.
Cocoonses become flutterbies.
Seeds become flowers.
And little Roos
become bigger Roos.
- [LAUGHS]
- Anyone can change. Even Rabbit.
If we had Easter again,
we could make everyone happy!
Attaboy, Roo boy!
I'll get everybody together
while you go talk to Rabbit!
And I'm not comin' back
until I come back...
Or Rabbit gives us Easter back!
Whichever comes first!
Okay! See you later!
If I don't see you sooner!
Hiya, Mama.
Roo? You're home already?
Uh-huh, Rabbit canceled Easter.
Huh?
I'm so sorry, dear.
I know how much you were looking
forward to your Easter egg hunt.
It's not just me.
Everyone's sad.
I see. You seem to be taking
it rather well, though.
That's 'cause me and Tigger
are gonna fix everything.
And then you'll have
your Easter egg hunt?
I don't mind if we never
hunt for eggs, Mama.
I just want to give
everybody a happy Easter.
- Is that okay?
- I think that's wonderful.
We'll practice doing Easter
stuff till Tigger comes back.
That ought to cheer everybody up.
[NARRATOR] So Roo ventured off
to gather his friends
and bring them home
to practice for Easter.
Meanwhile, Tigger had gone
back to have a word with Rabbit.
The only problem was, he couldn't
make up his mind which word to have.
Okay, let's see...
Uh, Rabbit, I...
You...
Well, when...
Oh!
I just gotta get
this right for Roo boy.
Okay, self,
pull yourself together.
You just gotta be cool,
calm, and collectivated.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Rabbit, old friend,
I have a matter of grave
importance to discuss with you.
Oh, that's it!
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Apparently, bein' cool,
calm and collectivated
is yet another thing
that Tiggers do the...
[GRUNTING]
Rabbit!
[SCREAMS]
- What is it?
- Rabbit!
Go away.
Ah, what do you want from me?
[GROANING]
- Ah, no!
- Rabbit!
Who are you?
- Ah!
No!
It's me. Tigger!
[WHIMPERING]
Ah, gee, Long Ears.
You look like you just saw a ghost.
- Maybe you better sit down.
- No, I think I better...
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute!
Tigger!
What on Earth are you doing here?
- Eh...
- Well?
Rabbit, I... I mean, you...
- When...
- What?
Roo's really upset about
what happened today!
Oh, I see. Roo's upset?
What about me?
Look at all this mess you've caused
on Spring Cleaning Day, no less.
I'm not talking about
Springity Cleanin' Day.
I'm talkin' about...
Don't say it, Tigger.
Do not say that word in my house.
- [SPITS] What word?
- I refuse to say it.
If you won't tell me what
word I'm not supposed to say,
then how am I gonna
know not to say it?
Let's see, is it...
- Carrots?
- No!
- Rutabagas?
- Thingama-whatchama-higgity-jigs?
- That's not even a word!
Onomatopoeia? And that is a word.
Why would you ever say that?
Why wouldn't you say it?
Onomatopoeia, onomatopoeia
All I wanna be is an onomatopoeia
Easter! The word is Easter!
That was gonna be my next guess.
Tigger,
would you please just leave?
Come on, Rabbit.
Aren't we never ever gonna have
another Eastery egg hunt again?
No, not never, ever.
Never again!
[GASPS]
But you used to love Easter!
Says who?
[NARRATOR CLEARS THROAT]
I beg your pardon, Rabbit.
You did used to love Easter.
Yeah! Says him.
[GROANS]
I don't believe you.
I don't believe either of you.
Then perhaps you should
see for yourself.
Don't you remember what
happened back in Chapter 3?
Hey, that's right!
- What are you talking about?
- Come on, I'll show you.
And so, Tigger took Rabbit
back in time, into the past.
Past Chapters 23 and 21.
Whew. It used to be
around here somewheres.
Just a bit farther back, Tigger.
Oh! Mucho obligado,
Mr. Narrator, sir.
[CHUCKLES]
You're quite welcome.
Ahh! No!
[GROANS, GASPS]
[WHEEZING]
And so they arrived at Chapter 3,
in which Rabbit organizes a
very organized Easter celebration.
Oh, my! Look at that!
[HUMMING]
Hey, look! I made a rainbow!
No, you didn't.
A rainbow goes like this.
Red, orange, yellow,
green, blue, indigo, violet.
See?
All the colors are
in their proper order.
Well, maybe this is a
different kind of rainbow.
There's only one
kind of rainbow, Tigger.
The right kind.
[GASPS] Pooh!
The jellybeans are for decorating,
not for eating!
Bother.
[CLEARS THROAT] Oh!
I have an idea.
Since this is Roo's first Easter
in the Hundred Acre Wood,
why don't all of you
go get our special guest,
while I stay here and make
everything perfect? Hmm?
Yes sir,
General Long Ears, sir!
Come on, fellas.
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Hmm, hmm.
Oh, it's flawless. Precise.
Why, it's an absolutely
perfect Easter.
And why shouldn't it be?
I was the Easter bunny.
Of course you were, Long Ears.
Hoo-hoo-hoo.
It'd be kinda ridickerous to have
an Easter Tigger, wouldn't it?
Yes, it would,
as a matter of fact.
You see,
when I was the Easter bunny,
Easter was a sheer delight.
I created the plans and
organized the schedule,
and everyone did exactly
what I told them to do.
I loved being the Easter bunny.
Oh. Sounds like
you do miss Easter.
- What?
- It's okay. We all miss it.
Especially little Roo.
Come on. Let's give 'em back
their Easter celebration!
What do you say?
Come on, Ra-Ra.
Ra-Ra? Ra-Ra?
My name is Rabbit!
And I most certainly
do not miss Easter.
Oh, but look. Look.
You used to love being
the Eastery bunny.
You were the head bunny in charge!
Yes, and that's why I liked it.
But I certainly
don't like it anymore.
But on account of why?
I had Roo's first Easter
planned to perfection,
until you had to get involved.
I remember it like it
was only last year.
It was only last year.
It's all coming back to me now.
Happy Easter,
Mrs. Kanga, ma'am.
Well, happy Easter, everyone.
Hiya. Tigger!
Morning, little bouncin' buddy.
- What are you doing?
- I'm helpin' Mama unpack!
[SIGHS]
We're down to the last boxes.
Why don't we take the little
nipper over to Rabbit's
for a great big Eastery egg hunt?
Can I, Mama? Can I?
Ah, Oh!
[GASPS]
- [GASPS]
- Oh, dear!
Well done, Kanga.
I think I could spare
him for a few hours.
Okey-dokey, Roo boy!
Are you ready for your
very first Eastery egg hunt?
You bet!
Um, Tigger,
what's an Eastery egg hunt?
Why, an Eastery egg
hunt is practically
the mostest fun a little
nipper can have is all!
Or even a big nipper, too!
- Are Easter eggs hard to catch?
- No. Hoo-hoo-hoo.
You just gotta have
the right technique.
First, you sneak up on 'em,
like a great big sneakity-snake,
and then you bounce!
- Hiya, Long Ears!
- Tigger.
Hi, Mr. Rabbit.
Hoo-hoo. Taught him
everything he knows.
That explains a lot.
Happy Easter, Easter bunny.
Won't be so happy if I don't
get these supplies in order.
We're already ten minutes
behind schedule! [GASPS]
No, no, no!
What do you think you're doing?
Making Easter eggs.
But you're going
completely out of order.
Hey, this looks like fun.
It isn't fun. It's Easter!
Aw, go easy on him.
It's his very firstest
Easter celebration, you know.
Yes, yes, of course I know.
That's why I want
everything to be perfect.
Oh, come on, Rabbit.
He's really got his little
heart set on this.
Let him hunt just
one Eastery egg.
But they aren't even decorated yet.
You're right. We'll hunt them
first and decorate them later.
Good idea, Tigger!
Then we wouldn't have to worry about
grass stains on our colored eggs.
Have you all gone mad?
You can't possibly do
these things out of order.
I don't mind if
it's not decorated.
No! No! No!
Perhaps I should explain to our new
guest how we do things around here.
For our yearly Easter fun
We use the checklist, number one
We get the eggs, then we lay them out
Like so, number two
We color them and dye them
Then we take them out and dry them
And we line them up precisely
In a row
Next we stack them and we pack them
Make a list so we can track them
Tie the ribbons,
stuff the baskets
When it's done
Then we count them out precisely
And we decorate them nicely
And when all of that is finished
We'll have fun
'Cause that's the way
It must be done, see
From step one, see,
that's how we win
We have to be aware to
Start to prepare to
Commence to get ready to begin!
Oh, dear.
Now, shall we get to work?
Me, first.
I have all the jobs
assigned here on my clipboard.
- I'll take this one.
- I'll do the basket.
Wait a minute.
- I'll paint this red!
- No, blue!
- I'll take this egg!
- No, that's for Pooh.
- I'll use this brush.
- That's not for you.
- I'll tie the bow.
- No, that's for Roo.
What do you want me to do?
You take the scissors
and the glue
How 'bout we paint this something
new, like maybe stripes!
- Me, too!
- No, no, no, no!
Stop having fun!
We have to systemize, prioritize
Coordinate and organize
Or else we'll never
ever get this done!
We need order, concentration
This situation needs
focus, control
We're painting and drying
And packing and tying
Get together or we'll
never reach the goal!
- I'll paint this red
- We need order
- Or maybe blue
- Concentration
- I'll stuff the baskets!
- I'll dry these two
- I'll tie the ribbon
- Painting, drying
- I'll write the card
- Packing, tying
- We can do it, nothing to it
- Look at us
We're almost through it
- I got the baskets.
- Stripes.
You're not doing it right!
Hold on.
Stop!
There! Do you see
what you were doing?
Well, ain't it oblivious?
Everybody was havin' fun!
Humph. Is that so?
Oh, I see your point.
- Everybody was havin' fun but you.
- [GASPS]
But there was plenty
of fun to go around.
What did you have to stop us for?
[STAMMERS]
Well, I didn't have a choice.
It was complete and utter chaos.
A disaster in the making.
Yes, yes, that's it.
You were completely
out of control.
That's why I had
to put my foot down.
I think you all need a remedial
lesson on the rules of Easter!
There certainly are
an awful lot of rules, Rabbit.
I'm sorry. But I'm the Easter bunny,
so I make the rules!
And rule number one is,
the Easter egg hunt does not begin
until the Easter bunny says so!
That, of course, would be, uh...
Me.
Where did they get off to now?
- Found another!
- Good boy!
Oh, how pretty.
[ROO] Hey, look! Here's some more.
[EEYORE] Prettiest egg I ever saw.
[TIGGER] Boy, you're a good Eastery
egg finder. Watch this, guys!
[HUMMING]
Nice catch there, Roo boy.
Just lucky, I guess!
Luck had nothing to do with it.
Just look at all them eggsies.
[LAUGHS]
Roo boy, you are a natural.
I did it just like you taught me.
First, you sneak up on 'em,
and then you bounce!
Just like I taught him.
[SOBS]
[ROO] Look, look! Another one!
[EEYORE] I think I found another one.
[PIGLET] Come on, Roo!
[ROO] Over there.
[TIGGER] Here, I found one, too.
[ROO] Here's some more.
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Here's some more!
So many eggs!
Mm, yes, and so much honey!
[CHUCKLES]
Kinda tickles.
Roo boy, I think you're just about
the bestest Eastery egg hunter, ever!
And you gave me
the greatest Easter, Tigger!
So, I guess that makes you
the best Easter bunny ever.
- But what about me?
- [ROO] Hooray for Tigger!
I'm the Easter bunny!
You're bunny number one.
[EEYORE] Hooray.
How could they have Easter
without me?
[TIGGER]
Well, anybody could have done it.
[ROO] Three cheers for Tigger.
[GRUNTING]
Every spring,
I look forward to
one thing most of all.
Being the Easter bunny.
You took that away from me.
Well, we... We never
meant to hurt you, Rabbit.
We were just trying to
give Roo a happy Easter.
I mean, didn't you want to
give him a happy Easter, too?
Go away, Tigger.
I want to be alone.
Well, I guess I better
tell Roo the bad news.
We're never going to have
another Eastery egg hunt...
[GULPS]
Again.
- [NARRATOR] Rabbit.
- What?
Why are you following me?
What do you want?
Would you like to see more?
No, I've seen enough.
I want to go home.
Very well, Rabbit. Go on then.
While Rabbit makes his way home,
perhaps we should also return
to the present day.
It seems that while
we were away,
Roo and the gang
have been hard at work!
- [KANGA] Roo, dear.
- Hi, Mama.
I thought you might like a break.
What exactly are you doing?
- We're getting ready for Easter!
- [GRUNTING]
Is that a rock?
Well, we were all out of eggs.
So we're hunting for
Easter rocks instead!
My goodness,
you've certainly been busy!
We're practicing,
so when Tigger gets back,
we'll be ready to go
on our Easter egg hunt.
Guess you could call
it spring training.
Look, Mama!
We even made new decorations.
The old decorations kinda
got broken by Rabbit.
Oh. So, when does
the official celebration begin?
As soon as Tigger gets back
from Rabbit's.
[GASPS] There he is! Tigger!
Oof!
Did you talk to him? Did ya?
Yeah, we kinda sorta talked.
So, we're gonna have Easter now.
Right, Tigger?
Tigger?
Well, it's probably best
to get right to the point
in the most briefest and
directificated manner possible, so...
Um, the answer is no.
Does that mean
Rabbit's still not happy?
But, Why?
Well, you see, when we did
the Eastery egg hunt without him,
we took away Rabbit's most
special Eastery thing of all.
So now, I'll never see
my Easter honey pot?
Or my very special Easter basket?
Or my fluffy bunny ears?
Or my strippety-stripedy
Eastery egg, either.
[SOBS]
I'm really sorry, Roo boy.
There's gotta be
something we can do.
Right?
Why, of course there is!
We just have to think of it first.
Think, think...
Think... Think...
- Think, think...
- Um...
- Think. Think. Think.
- Think! Think! Think! Think, think.
- Think! Think! Think! Think!
- Think. Think.
[NARRATOR CHUCKLES]
Ah, there you are, Rabbit.
Welcome back to the present.
We've been waiting for you.
Oh.
Home, at last.
[STAMMERS]
This isn't my house.
What on earth?
Those look like Easter decorations.
Where am I?
This is Roo's house.
Oh. So it is.
I must have stopped
on the wrong page.
You stopped here on purpose!
Why did you do that?
Why don't you see for yourself?
'Cause what I like
most about Easter
Is the way we show
our pals we care
For the fun never ends
When you give to your friends
And you share
Feel like a cookie before bedtime?
No thanks, Mama.
Well, okay. Maybe just one.
Hmm? Is that a picture of Rabbit?
- Mm-hmm.
- It's wonderful, Roo.
He looks really happy.
That's 'cause I
drew him like that.
I'm sorry you didn't get to
have your Easter egg hunt today.
I'm more sorry for Rabbit.
He must be really, really sad.
When Rabbit stopped
being the Easter bunny,
he lost his favorite thing of all.
I wish I could make Rabbit happy
for real.
I'd say Rabbit's very lucky
to have you as a friend.
[SMACKS]
Night, Mama.
Good night, dear.
When I share
This Easter day
With you
Humph!
That's it. Not my fault.
I'm supposed to be
the Easter bunny.
If they'd just listen.
If they'd follow orders.
Do what I say. But no.
[GROANING]
Humph!
[NARRATOR] Oh, dear. This is going to be
more difficult than I thought.
Well, sometimes a
narrator has to do
what a narrator has to do.
- [SPOOKY VOICE] Rabbit...
- [GRUMBLES]
[MUTTERS]
Rabbit...
Easter bun-bun...
Rabbit!
Huh? What?
What! Who's there?
[SPOOKY VOICE] It is I,
the narrator.
What do you want?
And why are you talking like that?
[CHUCKLES, CLEARS THROAT] There's
something I'd like you to see.
Humph! This better be good.
[COUGHS]
Where am I?
Where are you taking me?
These are the pages that
have not yet been written.
- [GASPS]
- Welcome to your future, Rabbit.
Oh, my! It's lovely.
Yes,
it's Spring Cleaning Day.
You finally got your wish.
It's all been done
exactly the way you want.
It's perfect!
[CHUCKLES]
I thought you might be pleased.
Well, where is everyone?
Late as usual, I suppose.
Late? Oh, goodness, no.
They're gone, Rabbit.
Everyone moved away.
[STAMMERS] Moved away?
Without telling me?
This is ridiculous.
I'll go get them right now.
Why would they
do a thing like that?
No one leaves the Hundred Acre Wood
without telling me. It's preposterous.
Pooh?
Oh, Pooh Bear?
Where are you, Pooh?
Oh, wait! Wait, I know.
He must be at Piglet's.
Piglet? Pooh Bear?
Piglet, where are you?
[LAUGHS]
I thought for sure they'd be here.
Oh, dear!
Eeyore?
[BOUNCING]
Tigger!
Tigger, it's me. Rabbit!
[BOUNCING]
Where is everyone?
[GASPS]
Oh.
Roo.
Roo? Roo?
Roo?
I don't understand.
Roo, who was so
looking forward to...
Spring Cleaning Day, was it?
No.
Easter.
What have I done?
Where are all my friends?
Friends, you say?
You certainly didn't
treat them like friends.
Don't you remember...
I'm sorry. But I'm the Easter bunny,
so I make the rules!
It isn't fun. It's Easter!
I told you exactly what to do.
And you didn't do any of it!
You see, Rabbit?
You never thought about
what your friends wanted.
All you ever did was
think of yourself.
No, I didn't.
Did I?
It looks as if you got
what you wanted.
Now you can always
have things your way.
No, that's not what I want.
Narrator, you said that the pages
of the future haven't been written yet.
So, does that mean
these words can be changed?
Please, tell me I still
have time to change!
[SOBBING]
No! No, it's not too late.
It can't be.
I'll be a good friend.
Yes, that's it. I can change.
I'll get their special
Easter things.
I'll give them Easter.
I will!
It's not too late.
[GASPS]
No!
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[GASPS]
Huh?
What?
It's morning.
I don't understand.
Was it all just a bad dream?
[GASPS] The box!
Oh, please! Let it be a dream.
They're here.
They're still here!
[LAUGHS]
Look at that. Oh!
That means there's still time.
I can change. I can change.
Oh!
[LAUGHS]
I want to jump like a jack rabbit.
Oh, I'm as giddy as
a school bunny.
[LAUGHING]
Wait a second.
I'm having a brainstorm.
It's brilliant, inspired...
Absotively,
posolutely electrifying!
Oh, I'm starting to
sound like Tigger.
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Lucky me!
They won't believe it's true
I know exactly what to do!
We're gonna sing, we're gonna laugh
We're gonna dance
I'm going to bring us all together
For the grandest Easter ever!
Though I can't believe
I got another chance!
'Cause, this is how it
Will be done now!
I'm having fun now
I'm out of control
I love it!
Hip-hooray, it's Easter Day
And it's gonna be
the grandest of them
[LAUGHS]
The biggest, grandest
Easter of them all!
[SIGHING]
That's it!
I know what we gotta do!
- Bye, Mama!
- Roo?
Where are you going?
I know how to make
Rabbit happy again!
[POOH] Yummy, yummy, honey.
Just a smackerel more...
Pooh! Wake up!
What about breakfast?
No time!
We've got a job to do!
- Wake up, Piglet!
- Ah! Who's there?
Hello, Piglet!
[ROO] Rise and shine, Eeyore!
I'm shinin'.
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Come on, Tigger!
We gotta spring into action!
[ALL] Whoa!
So, where're we springin' to?
We're making Rabbit happy.
[ALL] Whoa!
[TIGGER]
Who turned out my lights?
[ROO] Knock, knock, Mama.
[TIGGER] Are we there yet?
- [SCREAMS]
- [CRASHES]
[GRUNTS]
- [EEYORE GROANING]
- [KANGA] Oh, dear.
Mmm, breakfast!
This is no time to dilly-dally.
Let's get to work.
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
There. All done.
[LAUGHS] It's really quite nice.
Don't you think?
I just hope Rabbit thinks so, too.
Why don't you ask him yourself?
- [TIGGER] Gasp!
- [ALL GASPING]
- [ALL SHUDDERING]
- [GASPS]
What is the meaning of this?
Hi, Rabbit.
We just wanted to say,
[GULPS]
We're sorry we ruined your Eas...
Don't say the E word,
little buddy!
What did you say?
Um, Springity Cleanin' Day.
We're sorry we ruined...
"Eas". Ha-ha. I distinctly
heard him say "Eas."
Now, what could he possibly
have meant by that?
Were you about to say...
Easter?
- [ALL GASPING]
- Oh, dear!
Well, I have something
to say about that.
You can't have Easter!
[CHUCKLES]
Well...
What I mean is...
[CLEARS THROAT]
You can't have
Easter without all this!
Why, it wouldn't be Easter
without your stripedy egg, Tigger.
Or your honey pot, Pooh.
And I believe this is your
lovely basket, Piglet.
And Eeyore, here are
your fluffy bunny ears.
And I even made you a tail to match!
[LAUGHS]
Gettin' attached to it already.
And Roo! Didn't think
I'd forgotten you, did you?
I believe I owe you
an Easter egg hunt!
No way.
Yes, way.
I know it's a little late,
but Happy Easter, Roo.
Wow!
Happy Easter, everyone.
What the dickens, and I do
mean "Dickens," is going on here?
What's going on here?
Easter! That's what!
Now Tigger, [CLEARS THROAT]
I thought perhaps you might
like to lead the Easter egg hunt!
- But, Rabbit...
- No buts! I'm the Easter bunny,
and I make the rules!
Rule number one is...
There aren't any
rules about Easter!
Now go, go have fun!
Go! Go! Go!
[ROO] Everyone, wait!
You can't have Easter!
What I mean is...
You can't have Easter
without this.
Is that my Easter bunny hat?
For our one and only Easter bunny!
- Hip, hip, hooray!
- [CHEERING]
Hooray for Ra-Ra!
I came here this morning to
give you a very special Easter.
But,
you've given me
the grandest Easter ever!
Now, what do you say
we go hunt some Easter eggs?
- Think you can teach me?
- Yeah! Come on!
First you sneak up on 'em,
and then you bounce!
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Pooh Bear!
What happened to Rabbit?
Well, I would like to explain.
But I can't.
You see, Rabbit isn't who he was
on the holiday that wasn't,
and he is who he wasn't
on the holiday that was.
So there you have it,
if you see what I mean.
Which we don't.
Oh, well, what I mean is,
he's the Easter bunny!
'Cause what I like
most about Easter
Is the way we show
our pals that we care
For the fun never ends
When you give to your friends
[ALL]
And you share the wonder of
A bright and sunny honey
of an Easter!
With painted eggs and
jellybeans too!
Of all the fun and neat stuff
The candy and the sweet stuff
My favorite Easter
wish'll come true
When we share this Easter day
With you!
Oh! [SNIFFLES]
I just love a hoppy ending.
[NARRATOR] And so,
they all hopped off together
on this grandest Easter ever
in the Hundred Acre Wood.
B-B-F-N! Bye-bye for now!