We need blood, damn it.
Lots of it and then some.
I had to get rid of every
drop we had in stock.
You heard right, Captain.
Couple of boys we treated
turned up later with hepatitis.
And you don't catch that
sitting in a draft.
If you can't do anything,
put me on to someone who can...
someone with
a little authority, Captain!
Who's this?
Sergeant Frankle?
Peachy. Sergeant, I've told
everyone else. I'll tell you.
The 4077 th is out of blood.
We're squeezing turnips here.
All my personnel have donated
at least twice.
Dracula couldn't find a quick snack
around these parts.
You're either gonna have to get us
some blood or call off the war.
- We're doling it out by the corpuscle now.
- Hold on, Pierce.
- I'll wait, Sgt.
- I just gave that Turkish
captain another ten units...
bringing his grand total up to 30.
- That's a complete oil change in 24 hours.
- I'm trying to order some.
- Tie up your horses.
- I am. We might need 'em as donors.
Yes, Sergeant. What?
Which flunky
am I talking to now?
Oh, excuse me, Colonel, but I've
been getting the royal runaround.
I appreciate you boys are low down
there, but this is an emergency.
I'm not asking.
I'm begging.
And I'm threatening! If there aren't
100 units delivered by tonight...
the boys and I are gonna come down there
and alter the pants on all your dress uniforms.
You gotta reason with these guys.
Hello?
- Good job, Pierce. He hung up.
- Did he leave his inseam?
[Man On P.A.] Attention, all personnel.
Incoming wounded.
- Triage team report to the evac bus.
- That's not what I ordered.
I.V. For him. He's in shock.
Get him right into pre-op.
- Just once I'd like to see a few empty seats.
- Or an empty bus.
- Take it easy, fella!
Come on. Take it easy.
- Let me help you there, Doc.
- I could use a wrestler, but you'll do fine.
- Nessen, take it easy.
It's me, Moody. Doc here
is gonna help you, okay?
- Where'd you come down from?
- Munsan. About 20 miles north.
- It was a town until last night.
- I'd hate to be the guy
who makes the maps here.
You know it.
Haven't you been a guest
in this hotel before?
Six months ago.
Yeah, I remember. You offered
to stuff me in my duffel bag.
[Chuckles] Jerris Moody.
How you been, Captain Pierce?
Okay. Litter!
Start a whole blood I.V.
- This one can wait.
- Great.
- Give me a hand with this one.
- I thought you'd be proudly
serving in the stockade by now.
First impressions can fool you.
Mine was you hated
everybody and everything.
Yeah, I guess I did, but lately
I haven't had time to do anything...
except keep myself
and my buddies alive.
- You're a different guy, huh?
- Yeah, I'm a regular Florence Nightingale.
For Pete's sake, why are you just standing
around? Can't we get moving here?
Sure, Nurse. Would you help us
move this guy into pre-op?
- Nurse! You're talking to a major.
- Oh, sorry.
- Would you help us move this
guy into pre-op, Major?
- Litter!
[Pierce] This kid's back is covered
with shrapnel. I feel like a prospector.
- Pierce, do you always
have to talk while you work?
- You're right, Frank.
Nurse, from now on I'll blink my left eye
for a clamp, my right eye for a sponge...
and when I wiggle my ears, that means
meet me under a jeep in half an hour.
Yuck, yuck, yuckety, yuck.
- Quiet, Frank. We're working.
- Quiet, all of you!
I've got a bullet near the heart.
I don't need all this hubbub.
Shh!
[B.J.]
Get him to post-op.
600,000 units of Procaine
penicillin every six hours.
That's the easy part.
Now I gotta tell him I removed his leg.
Start it off with,
"Son, you're alive."
[B.J.]
Well, break's over.
[Potter]
Orderly!
Give me some more light there.
Tilt it up.
[Sighs] Clamp.
That's enough! That's enough!
Gloves.
Nurse, there are pits
in my orange juice!
- Can we get a surgeon
to remove those pits?
- I'll do it. Nurse, strainer!
I've had it with you crumbs.
Eighteen hours of slaving over these wrecks.
I got better things to do with my time.
- Shut up, Burns! Clamp.
- What's the matter, Pierce?
Cracking up, huh?
Sponge. I mean, clamp!
Frank, as soon as I patch up this kid's arm,
I'm gonna break one of yours.
- I got dibs on the other one.
- I'll pound all your bones into mulch.
I'll pound your mulch
into brains.
All right, we've let off enough steam.
Let's holster our mouths.
Nurse, pull down my mask.
- Frank?
- Hmm?
Thank you.
Colonel, only ten units
of whole blood left.
[Sighs]
Thank God we're almost done.
You want me to call
Seoul again?
No, I'll take another shot at
that idiot colonel. It'll be the
capper of a perfect day. Hypo.
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to our show.
We have a two-bullet minimum
and no flashbulbs, please.
- Colonel, any word from Seoul yet?
- Yeah. The word is "wait."
You'd think those monkeys
could spare a little blood.
Speaking of monkeys not giving blood,
you haven't donated a drop, Frank.
Strategy. One of us should
always have a full tank.
- Why didn't I think of that?
- 'Cause you're not an idiot.
It was the weirdest thing.
I was sitting in this foxhole.
It seemed like nothing was happening,
so I was reading...
one of those Communist leaflets, the ones
that say we're all fighting for Wall Street.
Personally, I refuse to read them.
And suddenly, I look...
and here's this Chinese
G.I. standing over me.
How could you let him
sneak up on you like that?
He was my age, no older.
We just stared at each other.
I guess he was surprised as I was.
Probably the first time
he'd seen an American close up.
- And then he shot you.
- No.
He got this scared look.
For a second, I thought
he was gonna run away.
- And then what happened?
- We both fired.
I got hit in the shoulder,
and it knocked me flat on my back.
What happened to him?
- The medic said I got him.
- Good for you.
I guess so.
Anything else
I can get for you?
I'd like to drop a line to Mom,
tell her I'm okay.
Of course.
- Dear Mother...
- No.
- It's Mom. She hates
when you call her Mother.
- [Chuckles]
Dear Mom.
- Hey, have you got a mirror?
- Settle for a compact?
- A what?
- Just don't ask,
"Who's the fairest of them all?"
Oh, damn!
Why they have to do that?
- I've had a moustache all my life!
- You were born with a moustache?
Well, since I was 12.
They had to shave it
to stitch up your face.
They should have
left it alone, man.
What's the big deal? So you don't
look like Gilbert Roland for a while.
Oh, you don't understand, man. No
moustache, I might as well be wearing a dress.
- Watch it, bub.
- All the real men in
Puerto Rico have a moustache.
I think you look okay.
You got nice bushy eyebrows.
Oh, leave me alone, man.
And take your mirror with you.
I got nothing to look at.
Nice chatting with you.
We'll be able to ship you back to Tokyo.
You'll be more comfortable there.
Thanks. That'll be terrific.
- You're gonna be all right.
- I thought I had it made.
Stay in the rear,
clear out land mines.
"It's great, Herb.
No one shoots at ya.
"Just take your time.
"Snip the wires.
You got no problems."
No problems.
- What happened?
- [Sighs]
We lay our mines out
in a pattern...
so we know how
to pick 'em up.
But we booby-trap a few, so the enemy
won't sneak in and snip the wires.
I forgot about that.
Next thing I know...
I'm lying across the road.
My leg's kind of numb.
I say to myself, "Herb...
you got a problem."
Colonel Potter! Colonel!
Why the ruckus, Major?
- Sir, this man's unconscious.
- I can see that.
- Well, he shouldn't be.
He's... He's my patient.
- That's a good enough reason.
- He's not wounded. I can't
find anything wrong with him.
- What are his signs?
- He's shocky, rapid pulse, low
pressure, diminished breathing.
- Strange.
- It's not my fault. I did my job.
- Nurse!
You're right.
The nurse is probably to blame.
- I'm not blaming anybody.
- I'm as conscientious as they come.
Put a cork on it, Burns. Able, has this
patient been unconscious since arrival?
Yes, Doctor.
- Beats the wampum out of me.
- I think he's sick.
I never could sleep
on my stomach.
Me neither. I could sleep
on anyone else's but mine.
- How bad is it?
- Well, I wouldn't go
horseback riding for a while.
- This is very embarrassing.
- Why?
'Cause when I go home, people are
gonna be asking me where I got shot.
What am I gonna tell 'em?
Just say, uh,
"I got shot in Korea."
What if they ask me
where I got hit?
Look them right in the eye and say
without blinking, "I got hit in the butt."
And if they keep bugging you,
drop your pants and show them your scar.
Don't make me laugh.
Whitney, we're talking about your body.
It's been invaded by a bullet.
- There's nothing amusing about that.
- Don't I know it.
On the other hand, you should be proud.
You have a very special wound.
It's symbolic of this entire war.
This whole thing has been
one gigantic pain in the butt.
And when they hand you your Purple Heart,
you can tell them exactly where to pin it.
Thanks, Doc.
You're welcome.
Why am I always handed
the trouble patients?
- Kellye. I wanna see his latest X rays.
- Yes, Colonel.
- We have an emergency.
- Ask someone else!
He's handling my patient first.
The Turkish captain needs a transfusion.
His blood refuses to clot.
- Let me see him.
- That's all right. You can go.
- Thank you.
- We don't have the blood to do the job.
Tell me something I don't know.
He needs a refill, quick.
- Even if we get donors, it'll be too late.
- Get him to pre-op.
- We'll remove his spleen.
That may start some clotting.
- Right away.
- Hawkeye, get on the horn
to that colonel in Seoul.
- What'll I tell him?
Tell him I need 100 pints of blood,
and I'm gonna come down there
and take it all from him.
Come on. What happened?
Confide in your trainer.
I went into Rosie's Bar
last night.
There were some rear echelon guys in there
who wanted to know if I could tap dance.
Ah. Dale Carnegie graduates.
Yeah. Well, I showed 'em
a few steps, all right.
I did a buck-and-wing
on their chests.
I've always loved "the dance."
Boy, those guys really surprised me with their
garbage. I went off like a firecracker.
I can understand that.
Boy. When I was up in the front,
my boys needed me.
They always used to scream for
old Moody to come and get 'em.
I had the guts to go up there
and drag 'em back to the aid station.
And you come back here,
and a couple of jerks call you names.
When I was a kid, I was fighting all
the time when somebody put me down...
'cause I believed 'em.
Those guys surprised me last night.
But they're not gonna
get me next time...
'cause I got something that
guys like that will never have...
self-respect.
There's not one valid reason I can think of
why that soldier should be unconscious.
I gave him
the once-over twice.
- If you couldn't find it...
- If I couldn't find it,
it means my brains are clogged.
They discovered that boy in a sleeping bag,
dead to the world or almost anyway.
Doesn't make any sense at all.
- Unless he had company in there.
- Colonel, please.
I don't mean human company.
Four-oh silk.
I mean, maybe a snake. Those little poison
ropes are all over these hills.
- A good dose of venom
would turn anybody's lights dim.
- For heaven's sake.
- Kellye.
- Yes, Colonel?
Did any of those boys come off
the meat wagon in their bare feet?
- A couple of them did, sir.
- Tell Pierce to check
that patient for snake bite.
Especially the feet and ankles. If he finds
a bite, give him some antivenin, pronto.
- Brilliant, Colonel.
- If I'm so damn brilliant...
how is it I just put
a stitch in my glove?
So what if I recover? They'll send me
right out there to do it again.
[Frank] Those are the breaks, fella.
Lucky for me, I'm going home soon.
Back to Indiana,
the good life. [Chuckles]
- Lord knows I deserve it.
- Major, I don't wanna hear about home.
I've been out here
almost since the beginning.
- I haven't seen my wife in all that time.
- That's tough.
She's changed too. I'm only getting cookies
a couple of times a month.
That's why I'm positive
she's been fooling around.
Sort of a floozy, huh?
Watch it, pal.
You're talking about the woman I love.
I hired a private dick to follow her.
Trailed her everywhere...
P.T.A. Meetings,
church functions.
And he came up with nothing.
[Chuckles]
Then I added it all up.
He was one of
her caballeros too.
So I hired another cop to follow him.
And the second guy wanted expenses.
They get paid
by the day, you know.
Major, I'm very tired.
Ha! I'd have had enough money for ten
detectives if my disease had come through.
- What's that, Major?
- I didn't tell you about my disease, did I?
No, you didn't.
But never mind. It's okay.
A kid came through here with
an unidentified rash. I spotted it first.
I called it "Burn's Blight."
Catchiest name since diarrhea.
I was all set to make the lecture circuit
and pick up my big fat research grant.
- And, uh...
- Well, what happened?
He got well,
the ungrateful simp.
That's enough about me.
Now what about you, hmm?
Uh, you don't wanna
hear about it, Major.
Of course I do. We have orders
to be compassionate.
I don't wanna fight anymore.
I've seen enough death,
and I wanna go home.
Why don't you save that
for the chaplain, chicken?
There's no law that says I have to sit
here and listen to you bleeding hearts.
It's very common, son.
You ran across a snake with a foot fetish.
It's a good thing he wasn't a neck man, or
you might have died from a terminal hickey.
What do you say after work
we choose up sides for a football game?
- Nurses' shower's the end zone?
- Good. I'm playing end.
Uh-uh. Last time you went out for a pass, I
didn't see you again till the fourth quarter.
Sergeant Raymond McGill, it's my duty to
inform you that you're doing beautifully.
- Spare me the good news, Doc.
- What's the matter with you?
They're gonna send me stateside
'cause of this stupid wound.
That's the way it usually works.
I can't go home.
I have a family to support.
- You got a Korean family?
- No, no, in the States.
Once more, with clarity.
Doc, I'm making a fortune
over here in Korea.
- You got the Band-Aid concession?
- I got some enterprises going.
Like selling booze, you know.
A fifth costs me a buck
and a quarter in Tokyo.
Some friends fly it to me here,
and I let it go for 12 bucks a crack.
- Fifty up at the line.
- Right neighborly of ya.
That's nothing. I also have the only
Polaroid camera in this whole sector.
All the guys want shots, so I put 'em
on film for two bucks a piece.
Heaven help the economy
when you go.
Maybe I don't have to go, Doc.
Put a few good marks on that chart,
you'll be swimming in whiskey.
- I didn't bring my trunks.
- I'll let you borrow the camera.
You can take so many pictures of yourself,
your wife will think you're back home.
- Sorry, McGill.
- Come on, Doc. Please!
How am I gonna make
any money in Jersey City?
They say America
is the land of opportunity.
Sending me home, huh?
I heard you doctors had no hearts.
- Very chic, Klinger.
- I just threw it on.
Hey, Robelo.
Stay away from me, man.
I look at you, and I get nightmares.
- I solved your problem.
- What are you talking about?
An unofficial, government-issued,
one each moustache.
That ain't funny.
Try it on.
I used my own hair.
Hundred percent Lebanese.
It'll probably keep growing.
- How does it look?
- It's you.
Hey! Hey, that's not bad.
Vaya, man. It's even thicker
than my real one.
Gracias, huh?
Anytime. Give me a couple of weeks
and I can make you one with handlebars.
Hey, you're okay, man.
I know,
but don't spread it around.
- Nurse?
- Hmm?
You have any idea
how beautiful you are?
[Chuckles] Have you any idea
how many times I've heard that line?
- No, I'm not kidding.
On a scale of one to ten...
- I know.
- I'm a nine.
- Would you like to try for ten?
- Over your dead body?
- I'm in better shape than I look.
- Aren't we all?
- Listen.
- What time do you get off?
- What did you have in mind?
Well, I thought maybe when you get through
with your shift, we can do something.
- Like go dancing?
- No, that's how I hurt my foot.
I thought maybe we can talk about
all the great times we had together...
We haven't had any.
Well, we can talk about them tomorrow night.
What are you doin' for dinner?
I'm meeting one of my nurses.
The guy in the next cot's in a coma.
Maybe we can double-date.
- That sounds exciting.
- Listen. You live alone?
I happen to have
a fiance in Tokyo.
So what? I happen to have
a wife in Philadelphia.
Donald is a lieutenant colonel.
Sharon's a C.P.A.
Don't you think we owe them
a little consideration?
You're right.
We're overdoing it.
I happen to take my engagement
very seriously.
Well, you should. What do you think
engagements are for?
It's a test period.
You're supposed to make comparisons.
- I've done enough comparing.
- You have?
Tell me about 'em.
The only conversation
I'm having with you is medical.
Okay, fine. Pull the screen around my
bed and give me a complete physical.
- You guys are all alike.
- No, no, no. I'm really in love with you.
I wanna spend the rest of my life with you...
starting tonight. What do you say?
I say good-bye.
[Sighs]
Nurse, do you happen to have
any idea how beautiful you are?
Do you have any idea how many
times I've heard that line?
Testing, testing.
Sorry. Attention, everyone.
This is Colonel Potter.
I know it hasn't been 48 hours,
but I'm gonna ask you for more blood.
We're as dry as a hump-less camel
in the sunshine.
Anyone giving a pint will be
excused from attending...
my hygiene lectures
for the next month.
Please report to the Mess Tent.
And don't knock anybody down
running to volunteer.
Toodle-oo.
That'll last us for about 12 hours.
- [B.J.] Coming through.
Eager volunteer here.
- It's my blood! It has rights!
- We're doing it a favor.
We're taking it away from you.
- It'll only hurt a lot.
- Next.
- No!
- When you sit in Santa's lap,
don't spit in his beard.
- I won't go!
- They give balloons.
- Aha. Major Burns at the front of the line.
- Good for you.
- Of course!
- These two bozos tried to butt in ahead of me.
- He's our leader.
- An inspiration to us all.
- Darn right.
- [Hawkeye] What's this?
- [B.J.] I think it's a truck.
I'm Sergeant Attias
of the Turkish brigade.
- We understand the 4077 th MASH
needs blood.
- In big red letters.
My men and I want to contribute
for saving the life of our captain.
Your table is ready.
Our special tonight is tomato juice.
[Shouts In Turkish]
Thank you very much.
It's our pleasure. It's a small thing to do
for such brave people.
- You're not touching me,
you vampire! Leave me alone!
- This won't hurt at all.
- What's wrong with him?
- He's one of our brave people.
Right now he wants
his mommy.
- Right this way.
- Uh, yes.
- Uh, after you.
- Oh, no, no, no. After you.
- No, by your pleasure.
- No, no, no, you have the blood.
- Thank you very much.
- [Both] Thank you very much.
How you feeling tonight, son?
A lot better than I was.
You're very lucky. All you got was
a concussion from that grenade.
Could have cracked your coconut.
Where's your home, son?
If I remember right,
I'm from Chicago.
Boy, do I know that town. I was a bachelor
stationed at Camp Grant for two years.
- Used to hit Chicago like a tornado.
- I'm from the Near North Side.
Then you'll get a kick out of this.
The Dewdrop Inn.
It's a tavern at the southeast corner
of Broadway and Lawrence.
- There's a bank there.
- A bank? When did they put that up?
Around 1900, sir.
Well, I used to drink a lot
in those days.
Used to hop off the "I" at Diversey and
catch the White Sox at Comiskey Park.
Colonel, I think that's
the Cubs at Wrigley Field.
Baseball's a wonderful game
no matter who's playing.
Hmm, sure is.
My favorite tavern was The Shamrock
at the corner of State and Dearborn.
- Sir?
- Yeah?
- State and Dearborn never meet.
- They don't?
No, sir. They run parallel
to each other.
- Listen. Ever been to Detroit?
- No, Colonel.
Good. We'll talk about Detroit
tomorrow. Meanwhile, rest.
Remember,
you've had a concussion.