This is President Jeffrey Michener
addressing all Americans
from the Navy ship
the USS Nathan James,
which is now entering the
heart of this great nation,
the Mississippi river.
We are survivors of this
great plague, just as you are.
We have struggled, just as you have,
and we still have great hope
in the future, just as you do.
Court! Court, look!
I know that you've
stayed alive this long
- by isolating yourselves...
- What you got, baby?
And your families,
that many of you have
been living in fear,
- [radio tuning]
- Fear of the virus, fear of each other...
Sonia, come listen to this!
Fear of the unknown.
There have been people out there
who have taken advantage of that.
Despicable rumors
and misleading videos
have been broadcast
from this network,
lies designed to manipulate you,
to make you believe that this ship
and the people on it are your enemy.
Nothing could be further from the truth.
The men and women on this ship
are some of the bravest, noblest
that I have ever met, and it is an outrage
that their commitment to
bring all of us the cure
has been undermined by those
who thrive on your fear.
I can tell you now that we do
have the cure for the red flu.
Attached to this message is video footage
where you can see for yourself
our doctor attending and curing
patients sick with the virus.
It is our mission now to spread this cure
to as many of you as we can.
At noon tomorrow, the 18th,
we expect to land at
the docks in Vicksburg,
where we will remain in port for six hours.
On the 20th, we'll arrive in Tennessee.
We have made contact
with a few brave citizens
at the college of Memphis.
Our team will meet people
there at 9:00 A.M., again,
for a period of six hours.
We'll end our journey at
10:00 A.M. the following day,
the 21st, at the port of St. Louis.
It's time to turn the
tide and the bloodshed,
put the past behind us,
and heal this great nation,
all of us together.
Thank you.
[Camera beeps]
Run that every 15 minutes
for the next three days.
Got it.
♪
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Val: On each phone is an app.
Just press the eagle, and
it'll take you right in.
You hit the icon, first thing you'll see
is a photo of immune
leader Kevin MacDowell...
number three under the Ramseys,
one of their founding members,
came to America months ago,
started the movement here.
He's still at large, last seen in Florida.
Are we expecting him to be in Vicksburg?
Unlikely. He maintains the ability
to communicate over the deadman network,
so he can still cause trouble. Dr. Scott?
With the wide radio call,
[sighs] We've hopefully given
a large enough number of people enough time
to make it to the port.
As we pull in to shore, you'll
all be given booster shots
to compliment the vaccinations
already running through your bodies.
Within an hour, these
boosters will make you vessels
for the contagious cure.
For how long?
You'll be contagious
for five to eight days,
during which time, it is imperative
that you pass it on to as
many people as possible,
who will then have five to eight days
to do the same, and so on.
We need a minimum of
10,000 people at each stop
to sufficiently spread the cure
across these sections of the country.
What about dropping the cure from the sky?
Didn't you find a way
to make the aerosol work?
I did.
Unfortunately, I only
have a limited supply,
perhaps not even enough
for the crowd the size
that I am hoping for.
So... The contagious cure
really is our best hope.
Okay, so, we make port,
and then we go around
breathing on anyone we can find?
The cure is in the sweat on your bodies
and the moisture in your breath.
In order to maximize the chance
of successful transmission...
would you be so kind?
You shake the target's hand,
you bring them in gently.
Within six inches, you breathe normally,
but forcefully for about five seconds
as you're holding their hand
and maintaining eye contact.
I'm sorry for the onions.
[Light laughter]
You try to make it
as natural and as friendly as possible.
Thank you so much.
Equally effective would be taking a drink
and share it with them.
If they drink any small
amount and your saliva mixes,
then you are good to go.
I guess kissing would work,
too. You didn't mention that.
Oh, for sure. Kissing could be a way to go
if you're up for it and
can get written consent.
Now, one important thing to mention...
you can only get the booster shot once,
so if the chain of immunization is broken
and we don't successfully
spread the contagious cure...
We don't get another chance.
Cruz: We're going up river
with no Tomahawks, no SM-2s,
no shells for the 5-inch,
and barely enough AMMO for our sentries.
Jeter: Thanks to val's network,
the president's spoken
to most of the immune
leaders around the country.
They've agreed to stand
down in exchange for pardons.
And we're trusting their word?
We have to repair the
ship, and we have to refuel.
Now, the airfield in St. Louis
give us the best shot at that.
And heading upriver
means we spread the cure,
win hearts and minds, which is our mission.
I get that, Master Chief.
But we're putting out a
call on an open channel,
letting the whole country
know where to find us.
If people come looking for a fight,
we'll be outmanned and outgunned.
So, I heard you've been
pardoning everybody.
That's real presidential of you.
Your offer expires in 20
minutes. Surrender now.
Oh, my dear Jeffrey,
how quickly you've changed your colors.
Let's make it 10 minutes.
I believe I have the coordinates, sir.
He's still in northern Florida.
We know exactly where you are, Kevin.
A Tomahawk missile can
be sitting in your lap
in 90 seconds, if that's what you want.
So, which is it then... mercy or threats?
You better get your story straight.
You can't win this, MacDowell. It's over.
And you haven't hung
up, so what do you want?
You were my protégé.
[Sighs] Do you remember how I found you,
all curled up in a ball,
moaning about your wife, your children?
Such a sad sack you were.
And where is it that you're going?
We're a global organization.
You know how big our reach is.
I'll get out of your hair
for now, but rest assured,
you and me, we've got unfinished business.
You sure you don't have one missile left?
Can you track their phones?
- [Keys clacking]
- Please don't insult me.
Alisha: The transmission came over VHF.
They asked for you specifically.
Do you know where they are?
I didn't have a chance to ask.
Who are they?
They're my wife's parents.
Remember... it's an open line.
This is Russell Jeter
hailing Sonia and Henry Morris
on channel 1-6. Over.
Sonia: Russell? It's Sonia and Henry.
Henry: How are you, son?
Hanging in there, sir.
Question is, how are you? Where are you?
We're down in Laurel.
Found an abandoned old cabin
with a well and a generator.
It's just a couple hundred
miles from Vicksburg.
We heard the message over the broadcast
that your ship has the cure. Is it true?
It is true. It is absolutely true.
Sonia: We have a truck,
and there's a gas station
a couple of miles from here
that might have some fuel.
Should we try to get to you?
Henry: We think we can
make it if we leave now.
Where you are... it's safe there?
Haven't seen another soul for months.
We've been rationing our food,
making runs when we need to.
And there's decent hunting.
Can you hang in a few more weeks?
I can come and find you then.
Sonia: Why, Russell?
Is there something wrong with Vicksburg?
I will try and reach you
back on this frequency
once I know what the situation is there.
Until then, I need you to stand by
and wait to hear from me, okay?
Henry: Well, if you think it's
safer for us to stay put...
That is what I think... For now.
Make sure they stay turned on.
Why can't we just toss them?
Because the Navy's gonna
be tracking them, Dimwit.
Our cargo loaded up?
Yeah, everybody's packed in tight.
We're ready to roll.
You get the uniforms? It's just nine.
It's all we could get from the surplus.
Nine it is, then.
You go with Darren and his
team and get rid of the phones.
Man ♪1: Okay, got it.
The rest of you men with me. Let's go!
We've got a schedule to keep.
Man ♪2: All right, boys, let's move it.
Man ♪3: Let's go. We're rolling.
The Mississippi.
Snipers every six feet.
Bet you Mark Twain didn't go
up the river with sentries.
Not even close.
Commodore still keeping a guard on you.
He is nothing if not a man of his word.
You can say that again.
I wanted to let you know that once we land,
I'm going my own way...
To Jackson.
For your daughter.
Thing is, is you said
the booster lasts only five, six days.
I was thinking I could bum
a couple of the old-fashioned
shots of the vaccine,
in case I don't find them by then.
I think that could be arranged.
Chandler: Is this MacDowell?
Val: He's over the Atlantic.
Looks like he's headed for Ireland.
Scotland, maybe?
What's your range on those phones?
I'll probably lose him
somewhere over Newfoundland,
but I'm trying to link
into a Swedish satellite,
see if I can create a handoff.
There's no authority there even to warn.
Europe's next on the docket.
- How soon till Vicksburg?
- 48 minutes.
Seen it yet?
Should be coming up just
now, sir, to the east.
Slattery: Where is everybody?
What the hell happened?
It's not enough.
It's not nearly enough.
127 people, no one else for miles.
Well, we're still
broadcasting on all channels.
Hopefully we'll get a few more stragglers.
Can we stretch it any longer?
Not if we still want to stop in Memphis
and make it to St. Louis.
Garnett says we barely have enough fuel
to idle here for the six hours.
Maybe we send the land teams
inland, spread the cure,
get us some answers why people stayed away.
They can catch us upriver,
depending how it goes.
Let's make sure we put our tightest detail
on the president.
He's gonna want to shake hands himself,
encourage people to fan
out and spread the cure.
It's a P.R. game as much as anything now.
Aye, sir.
If things are going
south, I can stick around.
Find your girl, Tex.
Meet me in St. Louie, Louie.
♪
The president shook my hand
himself, gave me the cure.
Anybody wants or needs it,
I'm in Greenville,
Mississippi, at the old church.
They're spreading it.
You heard the other ones.
Vicksburg was a bust.
Michener threw a party,
and nobody showed up.
They got word of mouth now.
What's that gonna mean for Memphis?
Well, the more the better,
as far as I'm concerned.
We'll handle all takers.
[Pounding]
Man: [Muffled] Hey, we're
hungry! We need water!
Suppose we should feed them.
We got to keep them alive a
little while longer, right?
[People coughing]
We need water!
Alisha: This is USS Nathan
James on channel 1-6
calling Sonia and Henry Morris.
If you are out there, please respond.
Listen to this. Man: I'm not lying.
It was someone from that Navy ship.
They said Vicksburg wasn't safe,
told his own family not to come.
Woman: That's what we heard, too...
- Patch me through.
- Yes, sir.
But I just got some chatter from people.
Supposedly, they had the cure,
and the president even came out.
This is Master Chief Russell Jeter
of USS Nathan James.
I was the one who told my
family not to come to Vicksburg.
I was wrong. It was safe there.
There was no fighting.
If you can hear this,
please spread the word.
We have the cure.
We will be in Memphis tomorrow, 9:00 A.M.
Meet us there.
Become part of the healing of this country.
[Birds chirping]
Stop right there, easy rider.
[Engine shuts off]
Turn around and go back
where you came from.
I'm not gonna tell you twice.
I'm looking for my daughter... Kathleen.
Her mother... Claire Nolan.
You know where they are?
So, you're Ken.
Yeah.
My friends call me Tex.
I'm Court.
Claire and Kat were staying here with me.
"Were."
Where are they?
Kat heard about that ship with the cure.
I talked her out of it
for a day and a night,
but she said she had
to find out for herself.
It's too late to catch
that stop in Vicksburg,
so she took off, heading towards Memphis.
And Claire?
Looters came in the night
about three months ago.
I thought a raccoon had got in the kitchen.
[Inhales sharply] Claire...
Was the first down the steps.
It was quick, but she managed to warn us.
I had my hands full with the guys in front.
Kat ran to my room,
hauled this old shotgun out of my closet,
held it at her waist like I taught her,
and fired point-blank through the door,
got the rest of those fellas
as they were coming in.
That girl of yours...
[Chuckles] She's got a hell of a heart.
Still... Hail Mary call to that ship.
I told her not to go.
I mean, how do you know
if it's real or not?
It's for real.
We got to start spreading it.
Michener: Val and your comms
team estimated that there may be
as many as 10,000 people
in and around St. Louis,
that there's some kind of
power and infrastructure
still in place.
I don't want to get my hopes up,
but look at all these arteries
feeding into the city...
rivers, highways, rail roads.
D.C. was the center of the
country back in the 1790s.
It was a good place for
the capital then, but now...
now the Midwest is the center.
The gateway to the west. Hm.
As much as I'd fancy
living in the White House,
this is a more expedient plan.
- [Knock on door]
- Come in.
I'm sorry to disturb you both,
but there's something I
feel I need to tell you.
Not long after the
president's radio message,
comms picked up a call for me
from my mother and father-in-law.
When they asked if they should
come meet us in Vicksburg,
I told them no.
Now I can't get ahold of them.
And it's clear there's been a...
there's been a negative domino effect
from anyone who might have overheard me.
It was an open line?
I got back on that channel
myself and tried to undo it.
But I thought you should know.
It looks like I may have
contributed to the low turnout,
and if so... I deeply regret it.
I appreciate you letting
us know, Master Chief.
[Inhales sharply]
He lost the rest of his family years ago.
Those people are all he has left.
Everyone's suffered losses.
This could jeopardize Memphis
and undermine everything
we've been trying to do.
For people to get a message
like that from our ship?
It's gonna take a while
for people to trust again,
whether or not they heard
what the master chief said.
He knew it was an open
line, and he made a choice.
You're right.
I'm sorry, sir.
Won't happen again.
[Engine shuts off]
[Birds chirping]
♪
Roberto: Stay away from me.
Stay back.
Stay away from me.
[Coughs] I'm sick.
Who did this? They still around?
Tell me what happened.
Immunes.
They saw that I had the virus.
The grabbed me back in Tallahassee,
brought me here.
All the way from Florida, huh?
Mm.
How many?
They got a truck full of
sick people, maybe 8, 10 guys.
[Clears throat]
They stopped here for gas,
forced me to walk around... [Groans]
Try to expose the virus to everybody.
They fought back.
The immunes took care of
them the old-fashioned way.
I got caught in the cross fire.
Where were they taking you?
Memphis.
Copy that. Vulture Team's
30 miles outside of Memphis.
Tex is gonna try to
hook up with them there.
They ditched all their phones.
I-I can't track them at all.
That's smart...
Flying them over the Atlantic.
You want me to send out a message
telling people to stay away from Memphis?
We do that, we lose all
our credibility... For good.
I get that, but we don't want
another New Orleans on our hands.
They're not looking for
a shoot-'em-up this time.
They're trucking in the
sick to infect the crowd,
create a panic so that no one
ever answers our call again.
- How far out are we?
- Four hours.
How many miles, as the crow flies?
37.
- Send the helo?
- With the aerosol.
This is enough for how many?
It should blanket an area
of half a square mile,
depending on the winds and
how concentrated an area
the people are packed into.
Given our limited supply,
we'll have one chance.
How many people are we expecting this time?
Just give me everything you've got.
This is the last of it.
[Indistinct conversations
and birds chirping]
There's got to be thousands
shown up by now, boss.
Jeffrey thinks they had a
shabby crowd at Vicksburg.
After this, the only Americans who show up
to greet that ship will
be looking to sink it.
You let the good people of Memphis see
that the U.S. Navy didn't
bring a cure after all.
And then you chase them out,
and you let them run as fast as they can,
spreading the virus and the bad news.
[Indistinct conversations]
Kathleen Nolan!
Kathleen!
- Hey, can I use that?
- Yep.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Kathleen!
Kathleen?
Kathleen G. Nolan!
It's your old man! Kathleen!
Kathleen, are you out
there? Kathleen Nolan?
Dad!
[Exhales deeply]
- Kathleen.
- Daddy.
[Laughs] Baby.
[Crying] Dad, mom...
I know.
I can't believe you're alive.
I missed you so much.
[Voice breaking] Can you forgive me?
Can you forgive me for not being there?
Yeah?
Those are not our guys.
Wait a second.
Aw, hell.
You keep your head down.
All teams, this is Tex. I found MacDowell.
Here's here at the college.
Shaved his beard, 6'5",
and the bastard is dressed like Navy.
I repeat... eyes on MacDowell,
northeast corner of the campus.
He has other fellas with him.
I'm guessing that they're immunes,
and they're all in digi blues.
That guy was right.
They're here to infect
people with the virus.
This is Cobra Team, headed
northeast to intercept.
I got eyes on more immunes,
also sporting Navy blue.
Stay tuned.
Man: Navy's here.
That's right. At your service.
We're here to get you all sick,
courtesy of your United States Navy.
- He's got the virus!
- Get back!
Run, everybody! It's a trap!
- It's a trap!
- [Laughs]
- [People screaming]
- Run! It's a trap!
Get down. Keep your head down.
Come with me. Come with me.
Chandler: How far out is that helo?
Five minutes away.
Boss! Boss!
I can't get the guys at
the gate on the radio.
I'm telling you... the
Navy got here early, boss.
Oh...
Nathan James, we have the package.
- I'm gonna open the gate.
- No! Wait!
If these people have been exposed,
we can't let them leave.
We have to keep them contained
until the helo arrives.
- Danny, we can't just...
- We're not coming back.
If these people leave here infected,
we can't cure them with the aerosol.
[Indistinct shouting]
- Stay back!
- Back up!
Nathan James, we have
a panicked crowd of civilians,
sick and healthy, who
are trying to get away.
They think the Navy tricked them.
I don't know how long
we can hold them back.
No, no, not again.
Copy, Vulture Team. Saberhawk
one is three Mikes out.
Man: Saberhawk one en
route with the payload.
Everybody, just stay where you are!
- No! Don't leave!
- Please, the cure is coming.
- Stay where you are!
- The cure is coming!
- Don't leave. The cure is coming.
- Tex: Stay where you are!
The cure is coming. Please stay.
- Stay where you are!
- Don't leave. Don't leave.
- The cure is coming.
- The cure is coming!
- It's gonna come.
- Please.
- The cure is coming!
- The cure is coming.
- The cure is coming. Trust us.
- Look!
- Yes! That's the cure!
- [Helicopter blades whirring]
- All you have to do is breathe it in.
That's our helicopter
right there. Just stay calm.
That's the cure. We're
gonna put our weapons away.
It's okay. We're gonna take it, too.
Look. We put down our guns.
Take it in.
Just relax. Just relax.
It's okay.
- Yeah?
- Breathe it in.
Yeah.
Masks off! Breathe it in!
All you have to do is breathe it in!
Yeah, that's right. Breathe it in.
Now we're all immune, asshole.
Well, if it isn't Mr.
president, gone all Navy blue.
You're not still blubbering
over your poor children, are you?
I'm gonna spell it out for you, Kevin.
The more people we save, the
more your men will realize
immunes aren't so special anymore.
Your movement will dissolve
as quickly as it rose,
and your followers will
fade into the background.
Point is, we can make you a
martyr, but who would care?
Work with us.
Get your men to stand down,
and you may live to see your
freedom again... One day.
I'm not sure I can sell that.
I have confidence in you, Kevin.
Lord knows you can be very persuasive.
You still offering me one of your pardons?
Gator: O.O.D., navigation holds
us on track in the channel.
Recommend maintaining course and speed.
How's our depth?
60 feet, sir.
Closest shoal water 250
yards off the starboard bow.
2% fuel remaining, sir.
We're coasting in.
Sir, recommend slowing to bare steerage.
O.O.D., bring her in.
Aye, sir.
St. Louis or bust.
[Michener sighs]
However this plays out, thank you both
for everything you've done to get us here.
[Cheers and applause]
[Laughs]
Yes!
You were right, Mr. President.
This is the place.
♪
Doc! Hey, doc!
You must be Kathleen.
That'd be me.
I can't tell you what a
pleasure it is to meet you.
[Chuckles]
My God, you're pretty.
She takes after her mother.
[Laughs]
Alisha: Master Chief...
they've been looking for you.
[Voice breaking] We got to Memphis late,
so we just [Sniffles]
decided to just keep driving.
I thought something happened to you.
[Voice breaking] All those years...
And we never reached out to you.
I understand. You couldn't.
We could, we just didn't.
And we left you all alone.
[Cries]
Well... [Sighs]
[Voice breaking] You found me now.
I, Jeffrey Allen Michener,
do solemnly swear...
"... that I will faithfully execute
the office of president
of the United States... "
that I will faithfully execute
the office of president
of the United States...
"... and will, to the best of my ability,
preserve, protect, and defend... "
and will, to the best of my ability,
preserve, protect, and defend...
"... the constitution
of the United States... "
the constitution of the United States.
- "... so help me God."
- So help me God.
[Laughter, indistinct conversations]
[Glasses clinking]
Here you are, ma'am.
[Soft piano music playing]
Quite the ball, Mr. President.
I thought it might be a bit unseemly,
given the circumstances.
Eisenhower had them.
So, did Lincoln during the civil war.
People need to celebrate,
even in the worst of times.
Seeing as the James is
in dry dock for months, well,
I'm gonna need you here...
As chief of naval operations.
That's a pretty big jump, sir.
Don't forget... I was number 12.
Fly your family out. They'll settle here.
There'll be plenty to do.
I'm already hearing from the northeast
about more lawlessness,
factions of warlords
fighting over big cities,
battles over natural
resources in the southwest.
South America... they're
even in worse shape than us.
We have a nation to build
and a world to repair.
And there's no one I trust more.
Sounds like an order.
It is.
Tonight we rest and enjoy our success.
Tomorrow, the fight for America
and the rest of the world begins.
All right, it was Christmas Eve.
We're doing this anti-piracy mission
off the coast of Somalia.
We come across this poor
Hungarian freighter...
engine problems, 50-person
crew, nowhere to go.
Frankie and I were... were running point.
Meanwhile, back on our ship,
our mail arrives from home...
presents from our families.
Frankie turns to me, and he says,
"what about the Hungarians?
Don't they get a Christmas?"
And I'm like, "Frankie, like,
this is a hostile situation."
But he's not hearing it, not for a second.
30 minutes later,
our helo is hovering
over that Hungarian ship.
Frankie is fast-roping down,
dressed as Santa Claus...
[Laughter]
Handing out presents to that entire crew.
- Man ♪1: Oh, wow.
- [Chuckles]
That is awesome.
That was Frankie Benz.
To Frankie Benz.
- Man ♪2: Frankie.
- Man ♪1: Frankie Benz.
- Frankie Benz.
- Benz.
Benzo.
- Benzo!
- Benzo.
Benzo.
O'Connor: To Chung.
To Lynn.
To Maya.
Smith.
To Berchem.
To Barker.
To Cossetti.
To Cody.
To Bivas.
Hear, hear.
All: Hear, hear.
Beat me to it.
I was gonna leave this under your door.
Flying out first thing in the morning.
I wanted to make sure you got
the epidemiological
models for the president.
Where you going?
First Lincoln, Nebraska...
a fresh outbreak's been reported there,
most likely immune dead-enders...
then Toledo, Sioux Falls, then on west.
So, the president ordered this?
He did.
He also included me in his pardon.
- Hence, no more guards.
- Mm-hmm.
We're not on the ship,
so it's not really up to you anymore.
No. It isn't.
Well, I have to say, I'm
slightly disappointed.
I was... Kind of looking forward
to seeing you squirm on the witness stand.
[Chuckles]
I would have stood by my decision.
I would have counted on that.
But I would have given you a
sterling character reference.
Of course, you wouldn't have needed mine.
You would have gotten 204 of those.
Great dress, by the way.
[Laughs]
The judge's daughter loaned it to me.
She insisted that I couldn't
really go to an inaugural ball
dressed in jeans.
Mm.
You could have pulled it off.
♪
I'll see you when I see you.
Be safe.
When you get back...
Find me.
Sing us a little chantey, Tex.
Little bit drunk. [Laughs]
Tex: I need a little help with this one.
♪ We'll be all right between
the devil and the deep ♪
All: ♪ we'll be all right
between the devil and the deep ♪
♪ We'll be all right between
the devil and the deep ♪
♪ And we'll all hang on behind ♪
♪ So, we'll roll the
old chariot along ♪
♪ We'll roll the old chariot along ♪
♪ And we'll all hang on behind ♪
♪ We'll be all right 'cause we
sail the Nathan James ♪
[Cheers and applause]
All: ♪ we'll be all right 'cause
we sail the Nathan James ♪
- [Singing continues]
- Is now a good time?
I've been trying to find
the right moment to do this.
I got this ring from your mom in Norfolk
and her blessing, and I-I
just think it's probably...
♪ we'll roll the old chariot along ♪
♪ We'll roll the old chariot along ♪
♪ And we'll all hang on behind! ♪
[Cheers and applause]
Man: Hi.
Are you the lady who made the cure?
Yes.
Can I get it?
Well, weren't you in the park earlier?
No. I missed the party.
Well, with so many people exposed,
it's likely you caught it
just walking into the hotel.
Still, I'd like to get it from you...
For history and all.
How close do you have to be?
Uh... That's close enough.
Yeah.
I think so.
Sic semper tyrannis.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -