Castillo: Citizens...
It is with great pride
that I address you today
from Los Angeles.
These are trying times,
but our hard work
is paying off.
In only two weeks
since the restructuring
of our government,
the Michener shortages
in our region are over.
Law and order has been
restored,
riots quelled.
Population centers
are experiencing
surpluses in food and energy
for the first time in months.
Let's all work together
to bring back this st...
[ Radio shuts off ]
Where are we?
Tex: Castillo country...
Vegas, baby.
From here, it's a five-hour
shot to San Diego.
Might take us
a little bit longer,
given that we're... you know.
Wanted criminals,
dodging checkpoints
and stealing gas
out of abandoned cars?
We're down to our last can.
We can stock up in Vegas.
It was a refugee center.
We are all working
for the greater good here.
So I urge you... obey our men
and women in uniform.
Turn that off.
They are our peace keepers.
I can't listen to that.
Every road block we dodged
had military personnel
still in uniform.
I don't know why they're going
along with this.
Castillo and the rest,
they sold the people
a line of crap
that breaking up the country
was the only way to save it.
The rank and file soldiers
and sailors
probably don't know the truth,
and they're just doing
what they do
because they were trained to,
to serve the people.
All the more reason
to make it to San Diego,
meet up with the James.
They've got a resistance
ready to go.
Assuming they're on schedule.
We haven't had a status update
since Dennis skipped town.
He'll be there... guaranteed.
Message from Naval Base
San Diego...
"Nathan James,
rendezvous with tugs,
vicinity of Coronado Bridge,
Moor port side, Pier 3, berth 1.
"Rep..."
[ Sighs ]
"Report to General Bradley"
with California United Forces
and turn over your prisoner.
"Thomas W. Chandler."
They have a General
running a Navy base?
And what does the California
United Forces even mean?
It means in the last two weeks
it took us to cross the Pacific,
they dismantled
the entire military.
That doesn't seem possible.
Sasha: It's actually textbook,
Captain.
When you want to take down
a government from the inside,
there's a pretty standard
formula.
First, you put the leadership
in a position where
they have to make immensely
unpopular decisions.
Like Ration cards, bank closures.
And you start a few riots,
force the President
to put them down
and broadcast the violence.
Finally,
you manufacture a crisis.
Like an assassination
or a hostage situation.
Or both.
In the meantime,
you're presenting
an alternative leadership
through the media.
- Regional leaders.
- My God.
Six hours
to Buoy San Diego, sir.
Castillo owns that base.
We're gonna be on his radar
in under four hours.
In a few minutes,
we'll start scanning
for microwave emissions
along the coast,
find the biggest one,
the most people talking.
10 to 1 that'll be their local
center of gravity.
- Sir?
- Von Clausewitz...
Center of gravity is a source
of strength...
Could be comms, transpo,
munitions.
We don't just disrupt it,
we destroy it,
make Castillo show his face,
grab him and use him
to smoke out the others.
Still, we're invading
a country with a single ship.
That's never happened
in the history of the world
and for good reason...
it's impossible.
Nothing's impossible,
not if you have the will,
the courage, and a good plan.
Von Clausewitz?
Thomas W. Chandler.
Bullshit!
You expect me
to go along with all of this?
Randall! Hear him out.
[ Scoffs ]
Beatty's Northwest Region
has gone ungoverned
for nearly a month.
With each passing day,
the resources are drying up.
Someone needs to take control.
I have the infrastructure
and the access.
Unless you want to cross
the Rocky Mountains
and pitch in, I'm the guy.
So geography gives you
all of Beatty's assets?
And the advantage
over the rest of the us.
Do you have any idea
what I'm dealing with up there?
You know what happens
if I don't clamp down?
Chaos spreads... You want some?
How 'bout you? How 'bout you?
I'm putting my security people,
boots on the ground
in the Pacific northwest,
and I'm not waiting
for your damn permission.
Oh, so it's a fait accompli,
then.
You know he's already started
mining the whole region
for resources.
Take it all, Manuel.
Go ahead, see how far you get
when I stop my oil shipments
to the west coast.
What? Roberta... I hope you
like walking everywhere...
Enough! Because I...
Here is what's
going to happen...
For the benefit
of all the partners,
Mr. Castillo will mine the
resources out of the northwest.
Ms. Price is going to provide
the oil that allows him
to do so.
In return, Mr. Castillo
will share the spoils
evenly among the partners.
Look, you had me here
to settle disputes like this.
Objections?
No.
Good.
- It's this pod here.
- Still triangulating this area.
[ Indistinct chatter ]
- All right.
- There.
Man: I understand. Weren't they
stationed in east gate?
Shaw:
What's the word from San Diego?
Witt: Nathan James
has been picked up on radar
on its way to the Naval base
as scheduled.
- Good.
- That's a relief.
And everything is in order
to "receive" him?
Colonel Witt here has something
of a fireworks show in mind.
This is gonna work?
You're sure?
It's one few things
Jeffrey Michener did right
was centralizing control
of the weapons systems.
Hmm... Such a tiny,
little thing.
Looks can be deceiving.
Let's hope so.
Underestimating the CNO
is what got us in trouble
in the first place.
Isn't that right, Ms. Shaw?
Arm it, Colonel.
[ Device beeps ]
Just need thumbprints
from two of you.
Unh-unh. Let me in on this.
[ Glass thuds ]
I want to be the one
that finally kills
that son of a bitch
Tom Chandler.
[ Rapid beeping ]
[ Beep ]
Good.
[ Device beeps ]
Done.
In a matter of hours,
the Nathan James
will be at the bottom
of the ocean.
There she blows... Sin City.
Why is there no power?
Something's not right.
We'll figure it out.
In the meantime,
let's stock up on supplies.
[ Engine shuts off ]
You good?
[ Gun cocks ]
All right, nobody move!
Take it easy, friend.
No one needs to get hurt.
Oh, that's up to you now,
isn't it?
Then give me
all the food you got.
We're out.
That's why we stopped.
- Ah, come on.
- Seriously?
You wouldn't be lying to me,
now, would you?
No, sir.
I say we search them.
[ Guns cocking ]
What?
I thought I warned you to stay
the hell away from here.
- Go!
- Let's get out of here.
- Come on.
- Go!
Much obliged.
You're not from around here.
No, sir.
But you look familiar.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
Sir, we mean you no harm.
Well, come on then.
Best get off the road.
Thank you.
New shipments of food
stopped coming,
told us they were being
redirected.
Few days later,
a bunch of soldiers showed up
with container trucks,
loaded everything up,
and I mean everything.
It's just me now.
Kara: What about the city?
There's supposed to be
30,000 people there.
Most all of them
followed the food.
You're not a Peacekeeper,
you're working 16 hours
in some factory or another,
keeping lights on,
water running.
16 hours for a day's rations.
They're creating
food shortages.
And people complained
about Michener's ration cards.
How long has it been
since you've had something
to eat, old timer?
Name's Bob.
Bob.
It's been about three days.
I can't go far on account of
this bum leg.
Got no vehicle...
It's only a matter of time now.
You want a lift?
I've been here all my life.
I already beat the odds
10 times over.
If I'm gonna die, I'm...
It's gonna be here.
This is home.
It's all we got.
[ Sighs ]
I know it doesn't seem like it
looking around,
but hope is coming very soon.
So hang in there
a little longer, Bob, okay?
I think I do recognize you...
People on TV saying
nasty things about you.
Hope you don't believe
everything you hear.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Inhales deeply ]
Quiet out there.
Too quiet.
They made it.
Tex: Right on time, as usual.
Heading into the mouth
of the harbor,
Chandler's got to realize.
Castillo will arrest him
on site.
Can we signal them?
No. But he must have a plan.
CIC reports no contacts
on surface or subsurface.
Very well.
Let's bring her in.
Man: Starboard beam 0-6-0.
[ Alarm beeping ]
Vampire! Vampire! Vampire!
Bearing 115.
Two missiles incoming!
[ Alarms blaring ]
No!
[ Voice breaking ] No!
No! No!
No, no!
Oh, no!
No!
[ Sobbing loudly ]
- No!
- My God.
[ Sobbing continues ]
Those missiles
came out of no where.
They were circling.
Damn things can loiter
at high altitude for hours.
James didn't even see them coming.
Unh-unh.
Kara: They should have.
We're all that's left now.
So, what do we do?
I want to go home, get Frankie,
and just keep moving.
But first, I want to kill
everyone who's responsible
for what just happened.
Hell, yeah.
- You want revenge?
- You don't?
You bet I do...
blood for blood.
We do this smart...
asymmetrical hits.
Get down.
You see that?
Big eyes mounted on the flatbed.
An observation team...
Probably out here to confirm
the sinking of the James.
They're off to report back.
So we follow them.
Let's roll.
[ Doors close, engine starts ]
[ Indistinct radio chatter ]
Cameron: Any sign
of the Chinese destroyer?
Henan's gone, sir.
They bought it.
You were right, sir.
They wanted you dead so bad,
they tried to kill us all.
As long as we stay more than
40 miles off the coast,
we'll stay dead.
In the meantime,
Captain Slattery and I
will lead a land team,
identify Castillo's CoG.
- T.A.O.
- Sir?
Show us the results
of your microwave scanning.
Yes, sir.
These are the areas
with the most activity.
That one's not far
from the Navy base.
Could be a command center.
Lot of chatter...
Anyway we can listen in
on those comms?
I'm on it, sir.
So, you finally killed
the man who couldn't be killed.
I'm not gonna lie, Allison,
I was starting to lose faith.
We all were.
Here's to redemption.
St. Louis... We were prepared
to give it to Oliver
if you played ball.
He didn't. And now you
think you've earned it.
Oh, I know I've earned it.
Technically, St. Louis
is Wilson's territory.
Take it up with him.
He'll only go for it
if you back me up.
He's afraid of you.
And with good reason.
I delivered kingdoms for you,
and I expect more.
Castillo is a snake.
Make sure my shipment arrives
from California in good shape,
and I'll talk to Wilson
about St. Louis.
¶¶
[ Brakes screech ]
- What is this place?
- Store owner Bob said
they loaded his food
into shipping containers.
Maybe that's what it is...
a warehouse,
a distribution center.
By the looks of all of those
"Peacekeepers,"
I'd say you're right.
Castillo's hoarding his stash
and doling it out to his people
as calories for their
hard-earned labor.
- Why don't we steal it back?
- That would be the plan.
Army, Navy, Marines,
there's even
some Coast Guard down there.
Versus the four of us.
We're not even
the dirty half-dozen,
but we got heart
and we got smarts, okay?
Kara, you and I are gonna scout
the place, see what we can find.
And you two,
you watch the front...
shift changes, patrol patterns,
anything like that.
Remember what I taught you.
Okay.
[ Gun cocks ]
Be safe.
Hey, hey, hey.
[ Muffled scream ]
It's me. Hey. Hey.
Hey.
It's me.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Commodore,
I don't mean to be rude,
but I thought you were dead.
Tex, why am I not
surprised to see you here?
Whenever there's trouble
and long odds, my friend.
Hey, where's Frankie?
He's fine. He's with my mom.
Look at you.
[ Both breathing heavily ]
So, this Chinese ship you,
what, put it on cruise control?
Something like that, sir.
Master Chief's being modest.
This was his plan.
Glad to see you're on side,
Mr. President.
And good to see you're alive.
Hey.
Hey, it's good to see you.
Looks like we all had
the same idea.
Yes, ma'am.
So, this is Castillo's
center of gravity.
Yep. It's food.
We were hoping to find
a resistance force.
You're looking at 'em.
Well, let's get to work.
Burk, Kara, Tex...
I want you to set a perimeter,
motion sensors,
bells on a string,
whatever we got.
Green, Master Chief...
Establish a comms hub
up on that rooftop.
Nathan James is in Emcon,
but she'll be listening in.
Wolf, find me a nice, empty
building we can drop loudly.
That'll draw
the bulk of their forces away
when we make our move.
Mike, Sasha... You're on recon.
All right, let's move.
Yes, sir.
Just like old times.
We've cracked the military code
the California Forces are using.
I need you all to sift
through the message logs
for any critical intel.
How will I know what's important
and what isn't?
You'll know it
when you hear it.
Just make sure you get it
cleaned up, recorded,
and print it out.
Yes, ma'am.
[ Indistinct chatter ]
[ Radio chatter ]
[ Fence rattling ]
Jeter: [ On radio ]
Comms hub is up, Captain.
Slattery: Four-star.
General, cargo's intact,
ready for transpo.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Is there a problem, son?
Sir, some of the men
were talking.
They saw the Nathan James
blow up.
I just...
I can't believe it, sir.
Try not to lose
any sleep over it.
Tom Chandler was a traitor.
It's a new day, son.
Some can make the adjustment,
some can't.
Take my advice...
make the adjustment.
Yes, sir.
Kathleen: There's a round
in the chamber...
[ Gun cocks ]
so just pull the hammer back,
and it's ready to fire.
Oliver: I can tell
you've had practice.
Got to keep both arms firm
to guard against recoil.
You left town pretty quick.
After the doc, yeah.
Yeah.
I have a feeling
you blame me for Rachel.
I blame the both of us.
[ Sighs ]
I forgave you.
This, uh, Sasha gal...
She can handle herself?
With the best of 'em.
Good.
Hey, think I found
that General Bradley
we were supposed to report to.
He's the one that we need
to lure Castillo out.
Fellas, we might have read
this situation wrong.
Food's not being stored,
it's being shipped.
I found train tracks running
directly into a warehouse,
and they've been used
in the last 24 hours.
All right, next time
a train loads up here,
get out in front of it...
hit them hard
in the middle of nowhere,
not surrounded by 100 soldiers.
We don't have to destroy
the food... we can steal it.
Enough food to feed an army.
And then we steal the army.
[ Train bell dinging ]
Vulture team,
Elvis has arrived.
I hear you. We are in position.
Wolf? Wolf: We're on schedule.
Setting charges at the far end
of a turn...
They wont' even
see it coming, sir.
Overwatch, how's the view?
Best seat in the house.
Fire only in the event
that we are fired upon
as we approach.
Check that.
Mother, get a bearing
on my transmission.
We may need medevac
for casualties
once we take out the train.
Vulture out.
I hate that silence.
James will be there
if we need her.
Are we ready to go?
Loading is underway.
A call for you, sir.
This is Bradley.
Yes, Mr. Castillo.
Mother, our Charlie team leader
is broadcasting.
Prepare to intercept and decode.
Are you getting that signal?
Uh, yes, ma'am.
It's staticky as hell,
but I'll get what I can.
I'm recording.
I'll put it through the filter
as soon as they're done.
You done yet, mate?
Yeah.
[ Engine starts ]
[ Train bell dinging ]
Elvis is leaving the building.
[ Engine shuts off ]
Bradley: [ Distorted ]
Don't worry. The... won't be...
if say anything different.
"Don't worry,
the cargo won't be..."
Hundred, hunkered?
What's that word?
Hunters? Hundrey?
[ Train horn blowing ]
[ Radio clicks ]
She's singing our song, guys.
[ Blowing continues ]
[ Distorted ] Don't worry.
The... won't be hungry.
Turn the treble
all the way down,
and cut the low frequency.
Don't worry.
The cargo won't be hungry.
And don't believe them if they
say anything different.
Don't worry.
The cargo won't be hungry.
And don't believe them if they
say anything different.
I even brought some cookies
for the kids.
"Cargo won't be hungry."
Oh, my God.
CIC, comms...
We need to break EMCON.
Alisha: Captain, the resource
on that train is not food.
It's people.
They're transporting
carloads of people.
Shit.
How long till the train
hits those charges?!
Wolf: We've got five minutes
if we're lucky!
Let's go! Let's go!
[ Engine starts ] Go, go, go!
Man, I missed you guys!
[ Train horn blows ]
I'll get you as close as I can!
Closer!
[ Tires squeal ]
Oh! [ Grunts ]
Wolf: Hang on, Mike!
Come on! I got you.
[ Grunts ]
- Let's go!
- Come on, move!
Come on! Move it!
Oh, hey! Get down!
[ Bullet whistles ]
[ Casing clinks ]
[ Train horn blows ]
You! What the...?
Hit the brakes!
[ Horn blows ]
[ Grunting ]
Get the lever!
Come on.
[ Brakes screeching ]
Fight's over. Mind letting
off on my friend there?
Another 10 seconds,
I'd have had him.
[ Groans ]
[ Both breathing heavily ]
I need to see hands...
everybody's hands.
Open it.
Open it yourself.
[ Lock clacking ]
[ Indistinct chatter ]
What happened?
You can come out.
What'd he say?
Why? Out where?
It's safe now.
You're free.
W-What do you mean?
You're not slaves.
You don't have to go
where these people tell you to.
You don't have to work
where they tell you to.
- You mean we won't get fed?
- Yeah, we got to eat.
There's food at the other end
of this line.
- They said they'd feed us.
- We were promised food.
And my kids haven't eaten
since day before yesterday.
I haven't eaten since Sunday.
Please,
just let us go on our way.
Just close the door!
Let us go, please.
Just close the door.
Welcome to the new America,
Captain.
"New America" my ass.
I know these times
are desperate, believe me,
but there's another way.
None of you
are going to starve.
We can get things back
to the way there were
if you just come with us.
There's enough food
on this very train
to keep us all fed
for at least a few days.
And after that?
After that?
General, or whatever
the hell you're called,
tell the men and women under
your command to stand down.
If you think
you can get them back,
why don't you go ahead and try?
What the hell
were you thinking?
You took an oath!
To what?
To what?!
To the service! The country!
Captain, the thing I swore
an oath to, it's gone!
It was torn up two weeks ago.
I might as well swear an oath
to the tooth fairy.
[ Sniffs ]
You go hungry for a week,
and then you can stand
in judgment.
You could have fought back.
My commanding officer
tried that.
They cut his throat
in his office.
I play ball, and I live,
and my kids live.
It's that simple.
Oliver: Come on.
Help each other.
What happened?
I'm trying
to get confirmation now.
Manuel, we worked this out.
If this is some kind of ploy...
I had my general on that train
to deliver it personally.
I assure you, there is no ploy.
I've got half a dozen
power plants that can't work
because there's no one there
to operate them.
I need bodies.
Roberta... I am not kidding.
This place goes dark,
so do you.
I'll put your territory
back into the stone age
with the flip of a switch.
Don't do that.
Mr. Castillo, find that train,
get it moving,
or you will lose
Beatty's territory.
Get a secure line.
Call the base in San Diego.
I need divers in the water
to confirm
that the ship that we sank
was the Nathan James.
Slattery:
Nathan James, be advised...
We have dozens
of malnourished citizens
who need medical attention
and a full complement
of unaffiliated military...
Have dock prep helo bay 1
for triage.
All right, ma'am.
[ Satellite phone ringing ]
Easy, now.
Captain, we're monitoring
a microwave signal
that's being received
by a device at your location.
Who's calling?
Signal emanates from an area
of high microwave origination
north of Los Angles.
[ Ringing continues ]
It's your boss.
Tell Castillo
you want to see him.
You thought you had no choice.
Well, you have a choice now.
Let's take him down together.
[ Keypad beeps ]
Mr. Castillo.
Yes.
Sir, there's been an...
an incident with the train.
No, sir,
the cargo is intact, but...
Yeah, I just think you better
come down to the depot.
Yes, sir. I'll meet you there.
You're gonna
have to kill him, you know.
We don't work that way.
We'll give him his chance
to surrender.
No, no, no. Listen to me.
You have to kill this guy.
If you don't,
he's gonna kill every one of us.
Man: We'll have them fall in
at battalion support!
Man ?2: It's the third sentry
rolling in!
[ Engine shuts off ]
[ Indistinct chatter ]
Well, what happened?
Where's my train, General?
Today is not the day
to screw with me.
Shoot him!
He doesn't work
for you anymore.
I changed my mind.
Shoot him instead.
[ Gunshots ]
I suggest you put down
your weapons.
Lieutenant Burk,
please arrest Mr. Castillo
and prepare him for transport
to back to the James.
With pleasure, sir.
I made you a goddamn general!
Have you forgotten
who feeds you, your families?!
This man will take
the food from their mouth
to give it to the... [ Grunts ]
Sorry.
This too tight? Good.
So, I take it
I answer to you now, CNO?
No.
You answer to him,
just like I do.
Commander in Chief!
Man: Attention!
We'll need to give them
the oath.
They're rejoining the service
of the United States.
Yes, sir, Mr. President.
¶¶
[ Grunts ]
[ Scoffs ]
Tom Chandler.
Saved America from the virus,
and they loved you for it.
Then they got hungry.
They miss things like heat,
clean water, and Wi-Fi.
They don't have any time
for heroes now.
So do your victory dance,
and when the filthy masses
turn against you,
give me a call.
I'll show you
how to keep them in line.
But I will never cooperate.
Here's the deal, Manuel...
From here on out,
you no longer get to decide
what you will and will not do.
See, you had the chance
to kill me, again,
and you blew it...
again.
So you will cooperate.
And why is that?
Your army turned on you
without hardly a shot fired.
Once your partners find out
you lost control
of your region and Beatty's...
They will cut you out
like the cancer you are.
And let's not underestimate
the "filthy masses."
Once they hear
what you're really about,
you'll need more than an army
to keep them in line.
But we can always drop
you back off at the depot,
see for ourselves.
Witt: He must have commandeered
a Chinese destroyer back in Asia
and then navigated it
through the channel remotely.
We need to warn Castillo,
ma'am.
It's too late. By now,
Chandler already has him.
He may be Navy,
but he's a badass.
Shut up, will you?
[ Sighing ] I need to think.
[ Exhales sharply ]