(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(CHORUS SINGING)
(BIG BEN TOLLING)
(CLOCK TOLLING)
Thank you, Bridges.
- Everything ready, Bridges?
- Yes, sir.
I thought we should never get here in time.
I'm sure that cabbie was tipsy, Robert.
So am I. He called me his old cockalorum.
- Oh, what did you say?
- Gave him another shilling.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
ROBERT: You didn't mind our leaving
the others and coming on home'?
Why, darling, I loved you for thinking of it.
I hoped you would.
- Oh, Ellen, what lovely flowers.
- They're from Bridges and me, ma'am,
with our very best wishes, I'm sure.
- Oh, Ellen.
- Thank you both, so much.
Not at all, sir. It's a...
It's a pleasure, indeed.
(COUGHS)
How sweet of them to think of
giving us flowers on New Year's Eve.
Rather touching.
So touching that I almost want to cry.
Well, if you must.
This evening was planned sentimentally.
Sentimentally, but not tragically.
(LAUGHS) Splendid!
(WOMAN HUMMING)
You'll have to hurry up, cook,
if you want to see them celebrations.
Now...
Now, which would you wear, Mr. Bridges...
This nice porkpie hat or the lovely
picture hat the missus give me'?
Well, why not wear them
both and go as Lady Godiva?
You're vulgar.
Oh, look what you're doing,
squeezing that thing in people's eyes
and blinding them.
You'll be blinding someone
if you went as Lady Godiva.
Oh? Indeed?
Watch your step, cookie,
when you're celebratin'.
You know what you're like
after you've had a couple of snifters.
Don't be disgustin', Mr. Bridges.
(DOOR SLAMS)
New Year's Eve's gone to her head
and no mistake.
She's been queer all day.
Says she feels like as if
it's the end of everything.
Oh, so do I, for that matter.
Oh, don't start that all over again.
Oh, Alf, we've been so happy
here in service.
Can't bear to think what it's going
to be like when you've gone to the war.
Well, don't.
You were never cut out for a soldier.
Never mind what I was cut out for.
I am a soldier now, see?
What's gonna happen to me and baby
if anything happens to you?
Now, look here, old girl.
You married me for better or for worse.
Not for this kind of worse, I didn't.
You gallivanting in Africa,
and me stopping at home.
Oh, you got a lot to take on about,
I don't think.
Look at the missus and her brother
out there in that there Mafeking,
besieged by them there Boers
right from the beginning.
Not enough to eat, only horses and rats.
Yes, and now her husband's going
and two growing boys to look after.
- Have some sense.
- Sense? What's the sense in the war?
Nobody wanted to have a war.
We have to have wars now and then
just to prove we're top dog.
(BABBLING)
Now, stop arguing and help me
get out this punch
or the bells will be ringing
and they won't have anything to drink.
You look so beautiful tonight.
- Do I, Robert?
- Only your dress, I suppose. Very deceiving.
Yes, Robert.
- And the star in your hair.
- And the star in my hair.
And the fact that I love you
so very, very much.
After ten whole years
and two enormous children,
how can you?
Perhaps you're hideous
and ill-dispositioned
and tedious really, and I never knew.
- Perhaps.
- Well, it's too late now.
I'm set in the habit of loving you.
I shall never know the truth.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh, how wonderful our marriage has been.
“Has”?
Give the future a chance.
We don't know if there
is to be a future, now.
(LAUGHS) That's a cheerful thought
for the new century.
About as cheerful
as the thought of being without you.
Oh, Robert, my dear, I shall miss you so.
What does it matter about the war,
about the Boers?
It can't matter, really.
Aren't you forgetting about
your brother Jim in Mafeking,
- hemmed in by the Boers?
- No, I'm not forgetting Jim.
- But it does seem so desperately hard.
- What does?
- Nothing. I was merely behaving badly.
- You?
You couldn't behave badly.
- I suppose this war will end someday.
- Why, of course.
- In a few months!
- Perhaps it'll be over before you get there.
Perhaps.
I believe you'd hate that.
I wonder if Jim's still alive.
Of course he's alive. They're all alive.
Mafeking's bound to be relieved soon.
- Just on time, sir. Nearly midnight.
- Put it down there, Bridges.
- Stay and drink with us, won't you?
- Thank you very much, ma'am.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- That's right.
- JOEY: Mum!
- Oh, the children.
Sounded like Master Joe.
(HOOFBEATS)
How very impolite of the 20th century
to wake up the children.
Mum.
Oh, Joey, you awful child.
How dare you make such a noise.
Oh, darling,
you haven't got a pain, have you?
- I want to see New Year.
- Little boys mustn't.
What would you say if I spanked you
soundly and sent you to bed?
I would say,
old woman that lived in the shoe.
And what would you say
if I spanked you again
for calling your mother an old woman?
I would say nothing.
Mum, can we see
New Year tomorrow instead?
Shh. You'll wake up Edward.
By George, we ought
to have the children down.
A new century is a new century.
Ellen, go and get 'em
some milk to drink good luck.
- Darling...
- Shh. They're asleep.
Thank heaven they're too young to fight.
Peace and happiness for you, my darlings.
Please, God.
Peace and happiness always.
Darling, let's take them downstairs.
No, it's bad to break their sleep.
Once in a century won't matter, surely.
Just for once.
- Oh, well.
- Oh, Mum, how lovely!
Quiet, you naughty little scamp. (LAUGHS)
- Come along, Edward.
- What, Mum, what?
- JOEY: We're going down to see New Year!
- New Year?
Come on. Put this on, dear.
- Do we sing, Daddy?
- Do we not?
Should old acquaintance be forgot
And never brought to mind
La da da-da
Da de da-da
(SINGING)
- This is yours, Joey.
- Thank you.
- Here you are, dear.
- Thank you, darling.
Nineteen hundred! Happy new century!
ALL: Nineteen hundred!
Nineteen hundred!
(VOICES CLAMORING)
(CELEBRATORY SHOUTING)
(BAND PLAYING)
ls Mrs. Marryot in?
- To you, ma'am, yes.
- Come on.
But, Mum, we wanted to go down
and see Daddy off on the ship.
I know, darling, but you simply can't.
- Joey's cold's much too bad.
- (SNIFFLES)
You wouldn't leave Joey all alone,
would you?
Mrs. Harris and Miss Edith, ma'am.
- Oh, Margaret, how nice of you.
- Jane darling.
Edith, run along.
Robert's gone to report at the barracks.
He's got leave to travel down to the boat
with me.
Oh.
Oh, then, perhaps you'd like me to stay
and amuse the children till you get back.
- Oh, my dear, do.
- Mmm.
Oh, hello, Margaret.
You're on parade early.
- I just ran in to say good-bye.
- Oh, how kind.
Uh...
What the dickens?
Stand easy.
Now, youngsters, I want you to look
after your mother
very carefully while I'm away.
- Yes, Dad.
- And be very good
and learn your lessons and all that.
Dad, is Bobs a very big soldier?
Lord Roberts, if you please.
He's head of all the soldiers.
- Who's head of all the Boers?
- President Kruger.
And you and Bobs
are going to fight Kruger?
(LAUGHS) That's right.
Are you going to cut Kruger
all in pieces with your sword?
- You blood-thirsty little devil!
- Oh, promise you will, Daddy.
All right. Little tiny pieces.
(LAUGHS) There, I told you he would!
(SOBBING)
Oh, El, it won't seem like no time at all
till Mr. Bridges comes home again.
- If he ever does come home again.
- Mother.
Now what have I said?
Well, we'll all have a good laugh
when he does get back.
(LAUGHING AND SOBBING)
That's what they said about
my poor Uncle Harry's brother Bill
in the war against the Zulus.
But they never had that laugh
'cause he was cut in half
with a assegai the day he landed.
- Mother, don't!
- (SOBBING)
(HUMMING)
Attention!
Oh, here, here, here, here.
Now, let's have a bit of life in it.
Here, half a mo, cookie.
Someone's gonna eat that pastry
- you're cryin' into.
- Oh, Alf, don't be such a fool.
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
Oh, my Lord.
Here, Fanny.
You can give your old dad a smile.
Come and have a look at your old dad.
Look at his buttons.
All shined up nice and bright, ain't they?
(WEEPING)
Oh, now, come on, old girl, now.
Cryin' won't do no good.
Fanny, your old dad's goin' to the war.
He's gonna be
a soldier of the Queen, my lass
Who's been, my lass, to sea
(CHEERING)
How many days will they be at sea,
Colonel?
Sixteen. It's 6,000 miles to South Africa.
You see, they land here at Cape Town,
then proceed by rail to Kimberley.
Then, by forced march, to Mafeking.
Let's hope they get there in time.
Mafeking's in a very bad way.
It's doubtful they can hold out much longer.
(BAND PLAYING)
Isn't it a wonderful sight?
I'm wondering how many of them
will come back alive.
It's come at last, hasn't it, this moment?
- You'll be brave, won't you?
- Take care of yourself.
I shall probably be seasick.
Then lie down flat
on every possible occasion.
- I'll try to remember.
- Bridges will look after you.
Perhaps he'll be lying down flat, too.
- (BAND CONTINUES PLAYING)
- (CHEERING)
This is horrid, isn't it?
I must go, too.
No, not just for a minute.
I really must go.
I'm going to kiss you,
then I want you to turn away
and go on talking so you won't see.
Mm-hmm.
I'm glad I didn't bring Edward and Joey.
They're too young, really,
and they'd get overexcited.
Besides, Joey has a cold.
Take care of yourself, my darling.
I felt you go when I said
that bit about Joey.
Oh, Robert! Robert!
(BAND PLAYING)
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
(SHIP HORN CONTINUES)
(SHIP HORN BLARING)
Well, so far, they seem to be all right.
Thank God.
(SCREAMS)
Bang! Bang! Bang!
Dirty old Kruger! Dirty old Kruger!
Shut up, you silly kid, firing without orders!
- But I'm relieving Mafeking.
- You can't relieve it like that.
All right, then, I'm defending Mafeking.
- Shut up. You're wasting ammunition.
- Bang! Bang! Bang!
Don't do it again!
You kids have no idea how to fight a battle.
- Sorry, Bob.
- Get your men and guns over there.
- You're the Boers.
- But I don't want to be the Boers.
- Somebody's got to be the Boers.
- And that's all a girl's good for.
- I don't want to be the Boers.
- But I tell you.
I won't be the Boers! I won't be the Boers!
I won't be the Boers!
Oh, you cheat!
- Come on. Stop, stop!
- (ALL SHOUTING)
- What's the matter?
- Edith doesn't like being the Boers.
Well, and who would?
- Bang! Bang! Bang!
- Oh, now...
Oh, Joey, you're a naughty,
wicked little boy.
- Go straight upstairs this minute.
- Now, come here, Edith.
(CRYING)
- Come here and don't be so silly.
- Oh, go away, all of you.
Edward, take Joey upstairs.
Can't you play any other game
but soldiers,
fighting each other, killing each other?
(STREET ORGAN PLAYING)
Now, run along up to the nursery,
all of you.
And behave yourselves.
(ORGAN CONTINUES)
There's no escape
from that tune anywhere.
- Well, shall I throw him something?
- Yes, you could throw it at him.
Oh, Jane dear.
Hi! Hi! Will you go away?
Further down the street.
Jane dear, do sit down.
You've been standing about
all the afternoon.
- I don't believe I shall ever see them again.
- Nonsense.
Mafeking's bound to be relieved
in the next few days.
- All the papers say so.
- Everyone's been saying that for months.
My brother's still out there,
dying by inches,
starvation, disease and horror.
And Robert...
I can't bear to think of it
and I can't stop thinking.
Oh, no news yet, Ellen.
Have a nice cup of tea, ma'am.
Don't fret about the master, ma'am.
He's all right.
You see, he's got my Alfred with him.
And we'd be bound to hear
if anything happened.
Poor Ellen. It must be just as bad for you.
Well, no news is good news,
and what must be, must be.
That's what I say. You'd never
believe how that cheers you up.
(SOBBING)
Now, come, darling. Drink this tea.
Extra! All about the war!
Extra! Special, all about the war!
- Hi! Hi!
- Latest from the front! Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you, lady.
Extra! All about the war!
- Extra! All about the war!
- What is it, Ellen?
What is it?
- Nothing, ma'am.
- Paper! All about the war!
Extra! Paper!
(STREET ORGAN IN DISTANCE)
"No news is good news
and what must be, must be."
Now, look here, Jane dear.
I'm going now,
and I'm coming back at a quarter to 7:00.
Quarter to 7:00. Why?
We're going out to dine at a restaurant
and we're going to a theater.
Restaurant? Theater? By ourselves?
Oh, Margaret.
Well, why not?
Now, there's no sense
in sitting at home fretting.
And it doesn't do any good.
We'll get Ronnie James to take us.
And if he can't, then we'll go by ourselves.
I don't care what people say.
It's sweet of you, Margaret,
but I simply can't.
Now, Jane dear...
I'm going home to have a bath
and to put on my new Redfern model,
- and I shall be back at a quarter to 7:00.
- But, Margaret, I...
Now, don't argue.
Do just what you're told.
Robert and Jim would hate to think of you
sitting at home weeping and wailing.
They're being gallant enough.
We must be gallant, too.
We'll dine at the Café Royal.
- Margaret, honestly, I...
- Now!
We'll dine at the Café Royal.
- (STREET ORGAN CONTINUES)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
(STREET ORGAN CONTINUES)
Play louder! Play louder!
Soldiers of the Queen, wounded and dying,
suffering for their Queen.
(ANGUISHED CRY)
Play louder!
(SOBBING) Play louder!
(U P-TEMPO ORCHESTRAL INTRO)
(SINGING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(SINGING ENDS)
- Heeey! Hey!
- (GIGGLING)
- Tell me something, Ada.
- What?
- You're not a dairymaid, are you?
- (AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Mr. Inquisitive!
Well, what are you?
- Me?
- Uh-huh.
Oh, I'm lady's maid
to the Princess Mirabelle.
The princess? Then he wins his bet after all.
Who? What bet?
Lieutenant Edgar.
All the officers on the ship wagered him
that he would not win the hand
of Princess Mirabelle.
He said he would marry her
if she was as ugly as sin.
- Oh!
- He needs the money!
- Tom! What are you doing here?
- Yes, sir.
- Just coming, sir.
- Stop!
What gives? What gives?
What happened here?
My friends, you heard my call
And so I thank you all
But while you chatter here
My heart has been betrayed
Not so, not so
What foolish words you said to me
'Tis naught but your pride that's hurt
I'm very much afraid
Have you seen this? Have you seen this?
It's been all around
Who is this man who dares offend
The Princess Mirabelle?
Lied to me and cheated me
My daughter, let it be
Your poor heart's breaking
Whatever future
You are mistaking
All my life I have been dreaming
Now my dream must die
Within my heart I hid the song away there
But now I find the melody will stay there
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mafeking has been relieved!
(SHOUTING AND CHEERING)
(AUDIENCE SINGING)
(CHEERS)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- (BAND PLAYING)
Come and hold this fork a minute, Annie,
or they'll have to call
a fire brigade to put my face out.
I once knew a woman whose front hair
caught fire when she was making toast.
And before you could count ten,
the whole room was ablaze.
They'd never have been able
to recognize her remains
- if it hadn't been for her cameo brooch.
- Fancy that now.
And how's our ladyship today?
Who's a lovely girl?
Don't burn that toast, Annie.
Kitchy, kitchy, kitchy, kitchy, kitchy.
Your dad's comin' home today, love,
safe and sound.
Safe and sound.
I only hope he is safe and sound, I'm sure.
You're a nice, cheerful body, I must say.
I've had experience.
When I was a girl, a friend of mine's
husband come home unexpected-like
from the Crimea with no legs at all.
(GIGGLING)
Stop it, Annie!
Now look what you've done.
Put another piece, quick!
They'll be here in a minute.
I do hope Ellen didn't cry at the station.
It does make her nose so red.
Alfred will be that pleased to see her
that he won't care whether it's red or blue.
(GIGGLING)
Come on, Annie. Hurry up.
- Where is Africa?
- What do you mean, where's Africa?
Where is Africa?
- Don't be silly.
- Well, where is it?
I never heard such an ignorant girl
in all my life.
Haven't you ever seen it on the map?
I seen it on the map.
But where is it, really?
You ought to be ashamed
of yourself asking such daft questions.
Well, do you know where it is,
Mrs. Snapper?
Oh, get away, Annie.
You're getting on my nerves.
Well, I would like to know where it is.
Whoa!
- I was dying and laughing at the time.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
That's right, Ellen, you pay.
I want to see that baby of mine.
Cheers, old blowhard. Takes my kit in.
- ELLEN: How much?
- DRIVER: Half a crown.
ELLEN: Ooh-eh!
Where's my love-a-duck? Hello, cook.
Hello, Ma.
- Where's my girl?
- There she is.
Hello, Fanny.
Ooh, ain't you grown?
You ain't half been feedin' her up, Ma.
Look at her smile. She knows her old dad.
(CHUCKLES)
Here. Put it down there.
- Good luck, old man.
- Same to you, mate.
Ooh, I thought it would never
come to an end, that I did.
And all the people yelling and screaming.
(CACKLES)
Here, Alfred. Take your great head out of
that pram or you'll frighten her.
Oh, she's knows me, that's what.
She knows her old dad.
Look at her, rosette and all.
Smart as me eye.
Hello. Who's this?
We haven't had the pleasure.
- COOK: That's Annie.
- Hello, Annie.
Oh, welcome home, Mr. Bridges.
(GIGGLES)
- Well, Ma, how's everything?
- Well, I mustn't grumble.
I should just think not.
I've got a surprise for you.
- What is it?
- Ellen knows. I told her in the cab.
- Tell her, Ellen.
- No, you. Go on.
Well, Ma...
You know I said in my letters
about a lad named Herbert Smart?
Yes. Ellen read your letters out loud.
- Not all of them, I hope.
- Get on with you.
You never let yourself go further than
a PS and a couple of crosses.
- (ANNIE GUFFAWS)
- (LAUGHING)
Well, listen, Ma. This chap's got a pub.
- Pub?
- A pub. A beer house.
Oh, now, don't pretend you don't
know what a pub is, you rascal.
Well, anyhow,
he's got a pub in London here.
But he's stayin' in Africa,
so I bought it from him cheap.
Now, you can come and live with us, Ma.
What do you say?
Is it a respectable pub?
Oh, well, of course, it all depends
how you behave, Ma.
You know what you're like
after you've had a couple of snifters.
(CACKLES)
- Well, what do you think?
- What about them upstairs?
Oh, that's all right.
I took the master into me confidence.
He helped me with the money.
Oh, I can hardly believe it,
not having to live alone anymore.
(SOBBING)
Here, cheer up.
Have a cup of tea.
Let's all have a cup of tea! Come on.
Well, cookie, old girl, here,
how would you like to be a barmaid?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Where is Africa, Mr. Bridges?
Well, I don't rightly know where it is,
but it's bloody hot when you get there.
(ALL LAUGHING)
- BOYS: We're so glad you're home, Daddy!
- Ohh.
I'll be glad too when you stop
pounding the breath out of me.
- Children, not quite so rough.
- Did you see many Boers?
Mmm? Oh, yes, lots of them.
- Did you kill any?
- No, we won't go into that.
- Did you kill any lions?
- Forty-four lions, a zebra, two ostriches
and, uh... Oh, yes, a cockyolly bird.
What is a cockyolly bird?
I'll come up and tell you
tonight in the nursery.
Now, then, off with you both.
I want to talk to your mother.
- Can I wear your hat, Daddy?
- You may.
Off with you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
- (WOMEN LAUGHING)
- (MAN SHOUTING)
Quiet, Annie.
- (MAN SHOUTING) Paper! Paper!
- What's he yelling about?
(MAN SHOUTING)
Paper! Extra special from the palace!
- The Queen! Paper!
- Well, what's the matter? What's up?
It ain't nothing to concern us.
Oh, Ellen, how can you,
when it concerns the whole country?
- (SHOUTS CONTINUE)
- What concerns the whole country?
Alfred's coming home
is all that concerns me.
Well, what are you all looking
so miserable about?
COOK: The Queen.
The Queen?
The Queen. It says she's sinking.
- There, I told you so.
- Let's have a look.
She's very old, ain't she?
Oh, be quiet, Annie.
What's that got to do with it?
Well, I never seen her.
I have.
Driving along Birdcage Walk once...
Years ago.
God.
England won't half seem
funny without the Queen.
Mum, will Father be riding in the beginning
part of the procession or at the end'?
At the beginning, darling.
He'll be with the troops
that go in front of the gun carriage
with the Queen's coffin.
All these crowds of people.
They've been waiting for hours,
so patient and quiet.
There's hardly a sound.
I feel listless and sad...
As though her death were a personal loss.
Mum! Mum! There's a policeman
on a lovely white horse!
Oh, darling, don't jump about
and get excited.
- Edward, keep Joey quiet.
- Yes, Mum.
- Mum, could I ever be a policeman?
- Perhaps, if you're very good.
- Are all policemen good?
- Oh, as good as gold.
Why did Queen Victoria die, Mum?
Because she was a very old lady
and very tired.
Could I have another piece of cake?
Only a tiny piece, then.
There.
And a piece for Edith.
- And Edward.
- Yes.
- There now, run along.
- All right.
- Here, Edith. Here's your piece.
- Thank you.
- Which hand?
- That one.
- That's not my piece.
- Yes, it is.
- It is not!
- (GRUNTING)
- Edward's quite good, but Joey...
- (CHUCKLES)
- Well, Edward, are you all behaving?
- Yes, Mum.
- Listen, they're coming!
- The procession's in sight,
- and the servants are here.
- Oh, come in, all of you.
- You'd better go out on that balcony.
- Yes, ma'am.
(ANNIE GIGGLING)
(DIRGE PLAYING)
(CARRIAGES RATTLING)
- Look! Look! There's Father!
- Joey, stand still. Be quiet.
(PEOPLE CHEERING PROCESSION)
(HOOFBEATS)
That was Lord Roberts.
He held up his hand to stop them
from cheering.
Is that Bobs, Mum? Is that Bobs?
Now, children, stand absolutely still,
to attention as your father showed you.
Five kings riding behind her.
Mum, she must have been a very little lady.
(FANFARE)
(WALTZ PLAYING)
Adjutant General of the forces.
Lord and Lady Cumberland.
Captain Sir Albert Montague
and Lady Montague.
His Eminence,
the Cardinal Humbolt de la Torre.
Maharajah of Rantoula.
Earl and Countess of Norfolk.
- WOMAN 1: I met Lady Marryot there.
- WOMAN 2: Who did you say?
Marryot... Jane Marryot.
Oh, her husband's just been knighted,
you know.
Oh, those Marryots. I know them well.
- He thoroughly deserved his knighthood.
- Yes.
His war record was splendid.
You don't get a VC for nothing, you know.
Mrs. Harris and Captain Ronald James.
- Good evening.
- HOSTESS: How do you do.
- How do you do.
- Sir Robert and Lady Marryot.
- Nice to see you.
- How do you do.
- And you, Sir Robert.
- So glad you could be here.
- Thank you very much.
MAJORDOMO:
Mr. and Mrs. Geoffrey Pellier.
How do you do.
Well, Sir Robert.
Well, my lady.
- Isn't this fun?
- I think I want to run away and hide.
However, it may get me a little
respect from your children.
Oh, darling, they're wild with delight.
I'm so proud of you, Robert.
It's all you, darling. Always has been.
Is my hair all right?
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
I remember we was just near Pretoria
with the old regulars...
Fusiliers and that lot.
They all seemed sort of helpless-like.
So I went up to the commanding officer,
and I said, "Look here..."
Mr. Bridges, is Harry good for a drink?
- Has he had it?
- Yes.
He's good for it.
- What say, Harry?
- Hello, Alf.
So I went to the commanding officer.
I said, "Look here," I says.
"These lads ain't got no initiative," I says.
"Righto, Bridges," he says.
"You go down and tell them from me..."
- ELLEN: Alfred!
- Coming.
"Go down, Bridges," he says, "And tell
the commanding officer from me..."
Alfred, will you kindly
come in here a minute?
(CASH REGISTER DINGS)
I'll tell you what he said when I come back.
Well, what is it?
Oh, come in here.
Alfred, how can you go on like this
day after day?
- What's the matter?
- I thought you was gonna pay
the rent to the brewers this afternoon.
- Well, what about it?
- What about it?
You ain't never been
on time with the rent yet.
Do you want to have us
turned out of the place?
Well, I've got to look after me bar,
I suppose.
You ain't gotta go
and drink up all the profits.
Oh, Alfred, ain't you got no pride left?
You were so respectable
when we was in service.
Well, you don't have to
snap a man's head off
just 'cause he wants to be his own boss.
Fine boss you are.
Dressed up like a public house loafer.
Now look here, Ellen. Don't you make me
have to speak to you severe.
I'm the boss here, see?
And my clothes are my affair.
Matter of fact, I was going along
to the brewers now, see'?
But don't you tell me what I gotta do.
- Has he gone?
- Yes, he's gone.
Hello, Fanny, me girl.
Been doing your lessons?
Yeah. Come on. Give your old dad a kiss.
Oh.
Too proud to kiss your old dad, eh?
Come on, now. You'll do as you're told.
Go on. Get inside.
Don't stay out here playing on the streets.
Freedom ain't for everybody.
There's some that it's better for them
to have a firm hand over them.
Oh, Mother. My, you are late.
Here, put your books down.
And go upstairs and put on
your white dress. Go on, hurry!
- Hello, Alf.
- Hello.
- Hello there. Hello, mate.
- Hello, Alf. How 'bout one?
- No, nothing to drink.
Just going to the brewery. Business, see?
Oh, one won't hurt ya.
All right.
- Only one, mind you.
- That's all we're going to have, just one.
(APPLAUSE)
Why, Ellen, she dances beautifully.
Come here, dear.
I knew you when you were
a little tiny baby.
The child's a born dancer, if you ask me.
Highly talented.
Highly.
On the go, you know,
from morning till night.
Have you any children, Annie?
Well, I haven't exactly,
if you know what I mean.
George don't believe in families.
Not in the retail business.
Now, what I mean, you've got
enough to do to look after the shop.
JANE: Oh, I see.
ELLEN: You see, my cousin George
is a greengrocer, milady.
(CLEARS THROAT)
JANE: I see.
Can I press you to another cup,
my ladyship?
Oh, no, thank you, really. We've...
- it's getting very late.
- Yes, Mother.
And how was Cambridge
when you left it, Master Edward?
Oh, awfully nice, I suppose.
I'm at Oxford, you know.
Oh, Oxford. I've never been to Oxford.
But my husband has. Haven't you, George?
Yes. Nice place, Oxford.
Very antique, if you know what I mean.
Sir Robert will be so sorry to hear
of Bridges's illness, Ellen.
Ill? Alf ill? What's the matter with him?
Before you and Annie come, George...
I was explaining to her ladyship
about poor Alfred's bad leg.
- Bad leg?
- Yes, very bad.
He's been in horrible agony since Sunday.
(LAUGHS)
You would laugh at someone being hurt.
- Where is he?
- Upstairs in bed.
- I'll pop up and have a look at him.
- No, he mustn't be disturbed.
And how did he come to have the accident?
Eh... Cycling, Annie.
He was cycling and he fell off.
I didn't know he had a cycle.
He hasn't anymore.
Well, please tell him how sorry we are.
Come, Edward.
We really must be going now.
Here you are, dear.
It was ever so kind of you, milady,
to come all this way to see us
and to give Fanny that lovely doll
and everything.
Say good-bye to her ladyship, Fanny.
- Good-bye, milady.
- Good-bye, dear. Good-bye.
Good-bye, Annie.
I'm so glad you settled down so happily.
Pleased to have made
your acquaintance, I'm sure.
Good-bye, Ellen.
Please remember us to Bridges.
- We miss you both still.
- We miss you, too, milady.
Well, time changes many things,
but it can't change old friends, can it?
No, milady. Oh, no, milady.
Good-bye, Ellen, and good luck.
Good-bye, Master Edward,
and thank you for coming. Good-bye.
Alfred!
Oh, so this is why you wanted me
out of the way, eh?
Alfred Bridges, behave yourself.
Pleased to see you again, milady, I'm sure.
Welcome to our hovel.
Oh, proud and haughty, are we?
- Alfred, stop it! Stop it!
- Ellen. Dear Ellen.
I'm so very, very sorry.
I quite understand, quite.
I'll come and see you again soon.
You drunken great brute!
You shut your mouth.
You mind your business, and I'll mind mine.
Look here, old man. You better come up
- and have a lay down.
- Leave me alone!
Lot of snobs, that's what.
- Lot of blasted snobs!
- Now! Now!
Oh, I'm not good enough
to be at home when the quality comes.
Oh, no! I'll show you who's good enough!
I shall never be able
to hold my head up again.
Never! Never!
Oh, who give Fanny that doll?
Her noble ladyship, I suppose.
Well, we don't want none of her blasted
charity around here. Get out!
- (SCREAMS)
- Come here!
No, let go! Let go!
Come on up here. You're going upstairs.
That's what you're going to do.
You're coming right up here.
Blasted snobs!
(SOBBING)
She was right. She was right.
Time changes many things.
(SOBBING)
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (INAUDIBLE YELLING)
(INAUDIBLE ARGUING)
(CHATTERING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Running out of the house like that,
swearing before Fanny and hurting my leg.
He needs a lesson, a good lesson.
- That's right, a good lesson.
- All right. That's all right.
Look here, Ellen. Alf will tell you
how sorry he is when he gets back.
Hey, Mrs. Bridges,
I think you'd better come.
Alf's met with an accident.
He hurt bad?
Yes.
Stand back, all of you.
Alf. Alf! Alf!
(SCREAMS, SOBBING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MAN SINGING)
You've got to settle down
You save up all the money you can
Till someone comes around
Then away you go
To a spot you know
Where the cockerel shells are found
Oh, I do like to be beside the seaside
I do like to be beside the sea
I do like to stroll along
the prom, prom, prom
Where the brass bands play
tiddly-om-pom-pom
So let me be beside the seaside
And I'll be beside myself with glee
There are lots of girls besides
I would like to be beside
Beside the seaside
Beside the sea
I do like to be beside the seaside
I do like to be beside the sea
I do like to stroll along
the prom, prom, prom
Where the brass bands play
tiddly-om-pom-pom
So let me be beside the seaside
And I'll be beside myself with glee
There are lots of girls besides
I would like to be beside
Beside the seaside
Beside the sea
Ladies and gentlemen...
And kiddies...
I am happy to be able to announce to you
the winner of this week's
song-and-dance competition.
It is... ls... ls...
None other than little Miss Fanny Bridges.
Come on up here.
It gives me great pleasure to present
you with this magnificent prize,
a souvenir of Uncle George
and His Merry, Merry Men.
(SCREAMS, SOBBING)
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
to conclude our program,
Uncle Dick will sing
Take Me Back To Yorkshire.
(PIANO PLAYING)
Give us a loose leg.
Take me back to Yorkshire
Any girl's face will do
Drop me down in any old town
Ease back with a ship in Halifax
Take me back to Yorkshire
I'll be glad as a good little lad
And I'll never leave Yorkshire again
(CHILD CONTINUES SCREAMING)
JANE: Edward.
- We're going down on the beach.
- Oh, Lord.
We have to, dear.
Your father's going to join us there.
Yes, I know, darling. He has strong nerves.
But he doesn't need
a whole deputation of us to meet him.
Edith and I are going to
the concert on the east pier.
Concert? How loathsome.
Nobody's asking you, my little man.
You just take your spade and your
bucket and have a nice little paddle.
- EDITH: Oh, Edward.
- Come along, Edith.
You don't mind, Mummy?
Of course not, darling.
Do just what you like.
Are those two children
getting romantic by any chance?
- Romantic? They're absolutely pathetic.
- Oh, Joey, behave.
Oh, but, Mum, can't you see they've gone
completely dippy about each other?
Why, it seems only yesterday they were
quarreling over their toys in the nursery.
I wonder if Joey's right.
- Would you mind?
- Jane, dear, of course not.
- Would you?
- My son and your daughter?
Darling, you know I'd be delighted.
Well, if we're ever gonna meet Father...
- Oh, yes, we mustn't keep him waiting.
- Come along.
Why, Ellen, what a surprise.
Oh, milady, fancy you being here.
- How do you do, Ellen'?
- How do you do, ma'am?
- Hello, Ellen.
- Oh, Master Joe.
Oh, you have grown.
I got your letter, milady,
when my Alfred died.
It was kind of you to write, I'm sure.
We were so sorry.
- I hope your business affairs are...
- Oh, quite all right, milady.
I kept on the place.
I left my manager in charge.
We're just only here to give Fanny
a holiday.
(CHUCKLES)
She goes to dancing academy now.
She won this prize today for dancing.
- Oh, it's lovely.
- Not half good enough, if you ask me.
- Dances like Pavaliver, that child.
- Dances like who?
Pavaliver, the Russian dancer.
Don't be so ignorant.
Oh, she wants to go on the stage,
I suppose.
- Oh, Jane darling, there you are.
- Oh, hello, dear.
Oh, Sir Robert.
- Why, Ellen, how are you?
- Quite well. Thank you, sir.
- Grand.
- This is my cousin, Mr. Grainger.
- How do you do?
- And his wife.
How are ya? I never met you before,
- but I met your missus, all right.
- Oh, yes.
I don't think she told me.
Why, it was the day poor old Alf popped off.
(GIGGLING)
I do believe you'd rather be
at that revolting concert
on that peculiarly hideous pier
listening to Mendelssohn's Spring Song
or a great beefy contralto
singing Sweet And Low.
I adore contraltos.
I love Sweet And Low. And I simply
worship Mendelssohn's Spring Song.
What are your other vices?
Oh, sitting on boats
with cynical young men
and looking far out to sea.
Oh, but, Edith,
I am not a cynic, only a realist.
Look, big steamer.
EDWARD: Bearing her precious
human freight
to the farthest flung
outposts of the Empire.
Don't laugh.
I'd love to be on board. Wouldn't you?
Together?
- Perhaps.
- We'll be seasick.
- Hideously.
- Oh, everyone is.
- What?
- Seasick hideously.
Horrors.
All the same, I'd risk it.
Would you? Together?
On the loveliest ship in the world.
And the most wonderful
honeymoon in the world.
Oh, Edward, darling...
Edith, I'm so terribly in love with you.
(AIRPLANE APPROACHES)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Look! Blériot flying the Channel.
He's done it!
(WALTZ PLAYING)
- it's getting colder, isn't it'?
- Well, that's to be expected in mid-ocean.
We're nearing the banks of Newfoundland.
- Would you like to go in?
- No. It's all right.
(WALTZ CONTINUES)
- EDITH: Too big, the Atlantic. Isn't it?
- EDWARD: Far too big.
- EDITH: Ooh, and too deep.
- EDWARD: Oh, much, much too deep.
EDITH: I don't care a bit. Do you?
(CHUCKLES) Not a scrap.
Wouldn't it be awful
if a magician came to us and said,
"Unless you count, accurately,
every single fish in the Atlantic,
- "you will die tonight."
- We should die tonight?
How much would you mind...
Dying, I mean?
Oh, I don't know. A good deal, I expect.
I don't believe I should mind so very much.
You see, we could never in our whole lives
be any happier than we are now.
Could we?
Sweetheart.
- Are all honeymoons like this?
- Exactly.
Oh, Edward.
It's rather disheartening, isn't it?
I do so want this to be unique.
It is, for us.
Did you ever think when we were children,
- going to the pantomime and the zoo...
- That we should end up by getting married?
- Mm-hmmm.
- Of course I didn't.
You were a horrible child.
Well, so were you. And so was Joey. Vile.
Yet we all liked each other, really.
Dear Joey.
He's passing gallantly through
the chorus girl phase now, isn't he?
Mm. Gallantly but not quickly.
- Well, darling, you took your time over it.
- Now, Edith.
Didn't you?
Light of my life, shut up.
You'd be awfully cross if I'd had affairs.
- If you'd what?
- Had affairs.
Love affairs before you.
- You didn't.
- Hundreds.
(CHUCKLES) You liar.
I rather wish I had sometimes.
Perhaps then I should have learned
some tricks to hold you with
when you begin to get tired of me.
I shall never do that, tricks or no tricks.
Oh, yes, you will one day.
People always do.
This complete loveliness will fade,
and we shall forget what it was like.
- Edith, don't.
- Oh, it's bound to.
Just a few years and the gilt wears off
the gingerbread.
Darling, answer me one thing truthfully.
Have you ever seen gingerbread
with gilt on it?
- Oh, fool!
- Then the whole argument is disposed of.
Anyway, look at Father and Mother.
They're perfectly happy
and always have been.
Oh, yes, but they had
a better chance in the beginning.
Things weren't changing so swiftly,
and life wasn't so restless.
How long do you give us?
I don't know. Oh, and, Edward, I don't care.
This is our moment,
complete and heavenly.
I'm not afraid of anything.
This is our own, forever.
(TRAIN CLACKING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(SIGHS) Oh, dear.
It'll be 10:00 before we get to London.
If we're held up by many more
troop trains, it'll be tomorrow morning.
- Oh, Joey.
- Or next week.
May I see your paper, Robert?
Hmm? Oh, of course, my dear.
Thank you.
(CLAMORING)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Darling, what's the matter? Can I help you?
- No, it's all right.
- Shall I get a taxi, Father?
- Yes, go ahead, Joey.
- All right.
Oh, here they are.
MAN: Hello, Charlie.
- JOEY: Mum, where shall I put these bags?
- Oh, put them anywhere.
All right.
Oh, really, why does one ever go abroad?
It's misery when you're away,
and you come back to this sort of thing.
I'm absolutely dead beat.
(GROANS)
No servants, no food in the house,
no nothing.
Oh! I thought that awful journey
was never going to end.
Oh!
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, it was awful, wasn't it?
Oh!
Come on, Margaret.
Help me with these abominable things.
Mm-hmm.
What fools we were to start back
without making sure of the servants.
Well, anyway, it's much better
to be here in London.
If anything is going to happen...
It's going to happen, all right.
This is a lark, isn't it?
I put the bags up...
- Hello. Spring cleaning?
- Where's your father?
Oh, groping about in the cellar,
like an angry old beetle.
- He wants a drink.
- Hear! Hear! So do I.
Well, I'd better go and see if I can
find some biscuits or something.
- Cigarette?
- Oh, thank you, Joe.
- Pretty thrilling, isn't it?
- Just a bit too thrilling, my dear.
Oh, rot, Aunt Margaret.
It's absolutely marvelous.
Passing all those supply trains and guns.
Being pushed aside
to make way for the troops.
The crowds waiting
for something to happen.
Oh, it was wonderful.
Jane's howling for you
in the kitchen, Margaret.
(GROANS) Oh, all right.
Well, I can't find anything but Hock.
We'll have to drink to Germany's
downfall in their own damn wine.
(CHUCKLES)
- I rather like Germans. Don't you, Father?
- Enormously.
Give me a hand, Joey.
If there is a war,
how long do you think it'll last?
Oh, three months at the outside.
- We shall win.
(CORK POPS)
Perhaps it'll last six months.
Economically impossible.
Have you any idea what a war costs?
- Hell of a lot, I suppose.
- Hell of a lot.
The Germans can afford it
even less than we can.
- Then there's Russia.
- Good ol' Russia.
And France, Italy and America.
Japan, China, Nicaragua, Guatemala.
Oh, why, we've got 'em licked
before we start.
- Don't be silly, Joey.
- Sorry.
What's the time?
Nearly 12:00. Is that right?
Well, it oughta be.
Hasn't varied a minute in the past 10 years.
(BELL TOLLING)
(BELL CONTINUES TOLLING)
It's all happening now.
Short of a miracle, it's all happened.
Are you glad you left the army, or not?
Absolutely delighted.
- Will you go back again?
- I expect so.
- How will you feel about that?
- Absolutely delighted.
I suppose I ought to do
something about it, too.
- You want to?
- Terribly.
Why?
I don't know.
I wish...
I wish Edward hadn't been drowned.
We could have started off together.
Don't be too impulsive
and patriotic and dashing, Joey.
Think of your mother.
Think of me, too. You're all we've got left.
Found some potted meat and biscuits
and Worcester sauce and...
(MAN YELLING) War declared official!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
We are at war! War declared official!
War declared official! We are at war!
My dears, we're at war with Germany.
No.
Listen. Listen.
It's very hot, isn't it?
Don't look sad, Mum. It won't last long.
Father says it can't possibly.
And it's terribly exciting.
I feel rather tired.
Here, Mum, dear, have a nice sozzle.
We all oughta get drunk, really,
and go roaring about the streets.
Edward missed this anyhow.
At least he died when he was happy...
Before the world broke over his head.
Jane darling, we've had wars before
without the world breaking.
My world isn't very big.
(YELLING CONTINUES)
Drink to the war then.
I'm not going to. I can't!
Rule Britannia!
Send us victorious, happy and glorious.
Drink, Joey. You're only a baby still,
but you're old enough for war.
Drink as the Germans are doing tonight.
To victory and defeat
and stupid tragic sorrow.
But don't ask me to do it, please!
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
On Sunday, I walked out with a soldier
On Monday, I'm taken by a Tar
On Tuesday, I'm out
with a baby Boy Scout
On Wednesday, a Hussar
On Thursday, a gang oot wi' a Scottie
On Friday, the Captain of the crew
But on Saturday I'm willing
if you'll only take the shilling
To make a man of any one of you
Oh, we don't want to lose you
But we think you ought to go
For your King and your country
Both need you so
Those awful recruiting songs again.
You can't get away from them
anywhere in London.
Oh, they give me rather a thrill.
The girls give me a thrill.
I'll bet that little dark one
sung her share of fellas into the war.
(SINGING CONTINUES)
By George, I'm excited.
Finally leave off to France Saturday.
Marvelous.
Marvelously marvelous.
Oh, good Lord, Ainger, do you mean
to say you don't want to get back'?
Seriously, don't you feel pretty marvelous?
I feel pretty thirsty.
Well, that's easily remedied. Uh, waiter.
- Uh, some more wine, please.
- Ah.
Oh, it's a bit of luck,
the war coming when it did.
I was properly fed up at Oxford.
Oxford?
I was just starting in an accountant's office.
Well, you'll probably finish up
under the poppies in Flanders.
Drink up and have another.
(SINGING IN COUNTERPOINT)
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
My hat, that girl can dance.
- Who is she'?
- A kid by the name of Fanny Bridges.
- Fanny Bridges?
- Yes. Know her?
- Excuse me, old chaps.
- It's all right.
Come on. Drink up.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOG)
- (MUSIC ENDS)
- (APPLAUSE)
(HUMMING)
You are my daydream
You're my boy blue
I'm just a daydream
Nothing to you
For you I'm pinning
the whole night through
You are my...
Wonderful you
(HUMMING)
Oh!
I... Now, don't be afraid.
I say, you're marvelous.
What are you doing here?
What are you doing?
- I was waiting for you.
- Waiting?
You don't mean to say you've been here
all this time while I...
Oh, no, no. I mean, as a matter of fact...
I say, you are marvelous.
- Who are you?
- One of your oldest friends.
Oh, what a lie.
I've never seen you before in my life.
- Oh, but you have.
- Oh, but I haven't.
Oh, really you have.
We lived under the same roof for years.
Oh, I'm sure this is a very good joke,
but I'm awfully busy and...
- My name's Joey.
- Oh, how interesting.
And I have a dog called Towser.
Now, do you mind going?
'Cause I have to finish dressing.
But you don't remember anyone
called Joey when you were a little girl?
Little girl?
You're not Joey Marryot?
Fanny! Isn't it marvelous?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(EXPLOSIONS IN DISTANCE)
(WHIRRING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
MAN: Take cover! Take cover! Take cover!
(SIRENS WAILING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
- MAN 1: Take cover! Take cover!
- MAN 2: Under cover, please.
Under cover, please.
(BOMBS WHISTLING)
- Did you hear that?
- Yes.
Air raid. Take cover in the basement.
Well, that's all very well,
but where is the basement?
Oh, never mind the basement.
Let's go up on the roof.
- JOEY: Oh, that's that. I can't see a thing.
- (EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
(CLATTERING)
JOEY: Oh, curse the dark.
I'm smashing the room to bits.
JOEY: What on earth have I got hold of?
Feels like a tray of squashed bananas.
- FANNY: Thanks. That's my makeup box.
- (JOEY LAUGHS)
FANNY: Here, we're missing all the fun.
Catch hold of my hand.
- JOEY: That's better.
- FANNY: This way. Now, don't fall over.
JOEY: Oh, dear. I can't see a thing.
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
Oh. There it is.
Oh, Joey, isn't it thrilling?
Marvelous.
It's a long way to Tipperary
It's a long way to go
To the sweetest girl I know
(OVERLAPPING SONGS)
- (WHISTLING)
- (SINGING CONTINUES)
(OVERLAPPING SONGS)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOG)
Yes, it's pretty hard at times...
All the muck and filth.
And it's a bit weird when you find
yourself the only surviving officer
who went out with the battalion.
'Course it may be sort of
the law of averages,
to make up to Mother for Edward
going down on the Titanic.
Or perhaps I'm just lucky.
Anyway, what's the good of talking?
Gotta go back tonight.
Just one last twinkle.
Oh, my darling, don't give me any more.
I shall be tight.
You don't want me to fall down
during my first number, do you?
(CHUCKLES)
Fun, having dinner here, wasn't it?
Lovely fun, darling.
- (KNOCKING)
- WOMAN: Curtain's up, please.
Oh, heavens. I'm on in five minutes.
Will you really write to me tonight?
Of course I will.
I promised.
Well, you'll be smothered with people
after the show, and you won't have time.
I'll write you in the first interval
and send Maggie out to post it.
(CHUCKLES)
Dear old Maggie.
Darling.
In about one minute,
we've got to say good-bye.
Flowers, miss.
Oh, give them to Maggie
and tell her to put them in water.
Yes, miss.
Don't go yet, Joey.
Stay till my first act. Wait.
Can't. I promised to go home.
Mother's waiting for me.
- Do stay, darling.
- I can't. Really, I can't.
I'm sorry.
Of course you can't.
So I'll give it to you now.
What?
Just a little something I had made for you.
With my love.
Oh, how marvelous.
Oh, it's nothing.
Just a reminder of all the fun we've had.
You're a darling.
Oh, but you've missed the whole point.
It opens. Look.
I'll keep it... Forever and ever...
And ever.
Oh, darling, I almost wish
I didn't love you quite so terribly.
It makes going back
just a bit too thick somehow.
I shall miss you...
- Dreadfully.
- (KNOCKING)
WOMAN: Miss Bridges, please.
Heavens, that's my call.
It has been fun, hasn't it?
Heavenly.
And you don't regret it? Any of it?
Not a moment.
Oh, how wonderful you are.
Do you really love me?
Deep down inside, I mean.
Of course, I do.
Enough to marry me?
Yes, but I wouldn't.
- Oh, why not?
- Too difficult.
Besides, we shouldn't be happy married.
- And your mother wouldn't like it.
- She'd be all right.
Let's not talk about it now.
Let's wait until you come back.
- Oh, no.
- No. No, not now, dear.
- I see.
- (APPLAUSE)
- (KNOCKING)
- WOMAN: Miss Bridges, please!
Listen, Joey. I love you, and you love me.
And I've got to go now. I'm late.
And you've got to go, too.
But I'm not going to say good-bye.
We've had fun, grand fun.
And I don't want you to forget me.
That's why I gave you the locket.
Keep it close to you, Joey.
- (KNOCKING)
- Darling Joey.
MAN: Miss Bridges,
you're keeping the stage.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(APPLAUSE)
(CHATTERING)
Not much time for good-byes.
- I'm glad, really. Aren't you?
- Awfully.
- I never know what to say.
- I'm almost hardened.
This has happened so often.
Dearest Mum, you are wonderful.
You never make a fuss.
Don't be too sweet to me, Joey.
I don't want to behave badly.
You? You couldn't behave badly.
Oh, how funny.
Robert said that to me years and years ago.
'Twas the Boer War then.
This is all so different.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Good-bye, dear.
Good-bye, darling.
Take care of yourself.
Try to see your father on the way.
- Yes, if I can. Good-bye.
- Good-bye.
(STEAM HISSING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(CLAMORING)
- Cigarette?
- Thanks.
- First time out?
- Yes, marvelous, isn't it?
- Marvelously marvelous.
- Aren't you glad to be going back?
Terribly.
I thought it was all going to finish
before I was old enough to go out.
So did I, once.
- Sorry, I gotta see the RTO.
- RTO? What's that?
Railway Transport Officer.
Don't you know anything?
- Excuse me, sir.
- Yes. What is it?
Returning from leave. First Greenjackets.
Staff Sergeant, see about
this officer's train, will you?
Yes, sir.
May I speak to you a moment?
I'm fearfully busy.
Won't the staff sergeant do?
I'm afraid not, Father.
What the...
How'd you know I was here?
- Found out at the base.
- Oh, you young devil. How's Mother?
- Splendid.
- Just about killing herself, I suppose,
with war work and all that.
She's pretty wonderful.
You look pretty tired, too, sir.
Well, we're moving troops very rapidly.
Enemy's on the run.
- What did you do with your leave?
- Oh, I don't know. Lots of things.
- I saw Aunt Margaret.
- Yes. Couldn't dodge it, I suppose?
- How is she?
- She's all right.
- When do you go on leave, sir?
- Probably never again.
Good Lord, why?
Because they're talking about
an armistice.
- No.
- Fact.
We may all be home in a few weeks.
Train for First Greenjackets,
number one platform, five minutes, sir.
Five minutes? I gotta collect my kit.
- Good-bye, Dad.
- Good-bye.
Good of you to look me up, Joey.
Good-bye.
(TRAIN WHISTLE)
General Staff Home Command speaking.
"An armistice has been signed and
hostilities will cease today
"at 11:00 ack-emma.
"At 11:00 precisely, the Hyde Park battery
will fire a salute of 21 guns.
"And the officer in charge of mortars
will let off a salvo of maroons.
"Written orders will follow.
"Officers will now proceed
to synchronize watches."
Are you ready?
Her ladyship will not keep you
a moment, madam.
Much obliged, I'm sure.
Why, Ellen.
My maid said, "Mrs. Bridges."
it never occurred to me that it was you.
Yes, I just thought I'd call.
It's rather important, as a matter of fact.
Do sit down.
I'm delighted to see you again.
Thank you.
- How's Fanny?
- Oh, very well.
She's in Over the Moon now, you know.
It's about her I've come to see you, really.
Oh. Well?
Well, it's rather difficult.
Oh, what's the matter?
About her and Master...
(CLEARS THROAT) Her and Joe.
- Joe'?
- Yes, Joe.
They've been having a...
(CLEARS THROAT) Well, to put it frankly,
if you know what I mean...
They've been having an affair.
His last two leaves
he's spent a lot of time with her.
I wouldn't have come
to see you about it at all, only...
Well, I think Fanny's very upset about it.
Now that the war is over and he'll
be coming home, I thought that...
- What did you think?
- I thought they ought to get married.
Does she want to marry him?
No, not exactly. That is...
Oh, well, I haven't talked about it to her.
She doesn't know I know.
- How do you know?
- Found a letter from him.
- And you read it?
- Yes. I've got it here.
- I brought it with me.
- I don't wish to see it, thank you.
Oh, but I only brought it
because I thought you might...
Tell me, is Fanny in any sort of trouble?
Oh, no, nothing like that.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
I think we'd better wait until Joe
comes home. Then they can decide.
Well. I'm sure I didn't wish to upset you.
I'm not in the least upset.
But it's been on my mind.
It's been worrying me to death.
I think you should have spoken to
your daughter before you came to see me.
I never interfere with my son's affairs.
I'm sure I'm ever so sorry.
Please, don't let's discuss it any further.
Good-bye, Ellen.
Oh, I suppose you imagine
that my daughter isn't good enough
to marry your son.
Well, if that's the case, I can
assure you you're very much mistaken.
Fanny's received everywhere.
She knows all the best people.
How nice for her. I wish I did.
Things aren't what they used to be,
you know.
- No, it's all changin'.
- Yes, I see it is.
But Fanny's at the top of her tree now.
She's having the most wonderful offers.
- Oh, Ellen!
- What is it?
I'm so very, very sorry.
I don't know what you mean.
Oh, yes, you do. Inside, you must.
Something seems to have
gone out of all of us, and I...
I'm not sure that I like what's left.
Good-bye, Ellen.
I don't know why you should talk like that.
Some of us have got on in their world,
and some of us haven't.
I said, "Good-bye, Ellen."
(MAROONS FIRING)
Yes, what is it?
It's all over, milady.
The maroons are going off.
Excuse me.
- (PEOPLE CLAMORING)
- (MAROONS CONTINUE FIRING)
There's no answer.
What is it? What's happened?
You needn't worry about Fanny and Joe.
He won't be able to come back.
He's... Dead.
Oh, your ladyship.
Oh, milady.
(CHEERING)
(BAND PLAYING)
(MOUTHING WORDS)
Why are we here in Geneva?
To bear witness to the truth
that if the world war
is to be crowned by peace,
the world must disarm.
All efforts to appoint this paramount...
You talk of disarmament, but where is it?
What defense does it offer?
But this poison gas gives us security.
What's all this talk
about balancing the budget?
The whole world's broke.
We're all broke.
The whole thing is a heartless mockery.
After centuries of investigation,
it comes to this.
God is a superstition too crude
to impose upon a child.
We abandon the primitive yearning of
a savage for an object of worship
- and focus instead...
- We are all free to join the scramble
for power and riches,
and to sell our beliefs to buy success.
But each of us must one day
face an awful question
that is echoing down through the ages.
What shall it profit a man
if he shall gain the whole world?
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (NO AUDIBLE DIALOG)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOG)
(APPLAUSE)
Introducing Miss Fanny Bridges
and her new song hit.
(APPLAUSE)
(BAND BEGINS)
Why is it that civilized humanity
Can make this world so wrong?
In this hurly-burly of insanity
Our dreams cannot last long
We've reached a deadline
A press headline
Every sorrow
Blues value is news value
Tomorrow
Blues
Twentieth-century blues
Are getting me down
Blues, escape those dreary
Twentieth-century blues
Why if there's a God in the sky
Why doesn't he grin?
High above this dreary
Twentieth-century din
In the strange illusion, chaos and confusion
People seem to lose their way
What is there to strive for
Love or keep alive for?
Say, hey, hey
Call it a day
Blues
Nothing to win or to lose
It's getting me down
Blues, escape those dreary
Twentieth-century blues
(APPLAUSE)
(UPBEAT MUSIC)
There.
But, Jane dear, I like jazz.
I don't see the sense in sitting,
waiting for the grave.
Oh, I'm not waiting for anything.
I have a perfectly good time.
I go to the opera.
I go to theaters. I go to the zoo.
So far, I must say, I found the zoo
infinitely the most entertaining.
Really, Jane dear, you're quite hopeless.
Well, I refuse to be jostled about it.
All this jazz and whizzing about.
No wonder you're always
in the clutches of a new doctor.
Now, dear, I don't think
it's quite fair to say that.
He's the most wonderful man I've ever met.
And he has the most marvelous touch.
He's completely cured me.
Cured you of what, darling?
Oh, of my ailment.
(CHUCKLES) Well,
I'm perfectly comfortable where I am...
Without taking cures for ailments
I haven't got.
Yes, but how do you know
you haven't got any ailments?
Because I'm sane and active
and as strong as a horse. So is Robert.
- It's nearly time, milady.
- Oh, put it on the coffee table.
Good heavens! I must fly.
I wouldn't interfere with
your little ritual for the world.
Oh, my dear, you wouldn't interfere.
- You're an old friend.
- Oh, that's very sweet of you, Jane dear.
All the same, I must go.
Why, I'm late as it is.
- Oh, going already, Margaret?
- Yes, Robert.
Why, I promised to be at the embassy
at half past 11:00.
And now don't forget that
you're both dining with me on Tuesday.
Oh, my dear, how can we,
if you're going to Paris on Monday?
Oh, but I shall be flying
back in the afternoon.
Flying? (CHUCKLES)
She would.
(CHUCKLES) Now,
Robert, don't bother to come down.
- Nonsense. Of course I will.
- No, no, no, I insist.
- Now, I can easily let myself out.
- Very well.
And a happy New Year to you.
- Bless you both.
- Good night, dear.
The same to you.
Twice over.
Well, Robert, here we go again.
One more year behind us.
One more year before us.
- Do you mind?
- No.
Everything passes, even time.
That means you do.
And you don't?
I still believe in the future.
Ah, that's your strength, my dear.
I believe in the future, too,
but not quite in the same way.
It's been quite an adventure,
our life together.
A great adventure, Robert.
Anxious sometimes and sad.
Sometimes unbelievably happy.
But thank God, never dull or sordid.
And most of it
has come to us in this house...
- In this very room.
- Yes.
Sometimes I've almost hated it.
- You wouldn't move?
- Oh, my dear, of course not.
Well, we might have
some new curtains, of course.
- We have, dear.
- Hmm?
Have we?
Oh, so we have. I never noticed.
- They've only been up a week.
- Oh! (CHUCKLES)
Dear Robert.
In one minute,
(CORK POPS)
it will be 1933.
Well, Robert, what toast have you
in mind for tonight?
- Something gay and original, I hope.
- No, just the future.
Our old friend, the future...
The future of England.
But first of all, my dear...
I drink to you.
And I drink to you, Robert.
Loyal and loving, always.
Now, let's couple the future of England
with the past of England...
The glories, the victories,
the triumphs that are over.
And the sorrows that are over, too.
Let us drink to our sons
who made part of the pattern.
And to our hearts that died with them.
Let us drink to the spirit
of gallantry and courage
that made a strange heaven
out of unbelievable hell.
And let us drink to the hope
that one day this country of ours,
which we love so much,
will find dignity
and greatness and peace again.
But this poison gas gives us security.
The world must disarm.
The whole world's broke. We're all broke.
God is a superstition...
if he shall gain the whole world,
and lose his own soul.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOG)
In the strange illusion, chaos and confusion
People seem to lose their way
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOG)
Dignity...
Greatness and peace.
(PEOPLE SINGING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYS)