DISTANT BIRDSONG
Is that him?
Yes.
Oliver!
CHORAL MUSIC PLAYS
God be with you, Oliver.
And you too, John.
This is Henry Ireton, a good friend.
Good day to you, sir. Mr Ireton.
I've just been taking
a last look at my land.
We had heard you were leaving.
We came from London directly.
You could have saved
yourself the effort, Mr Ireton.
If we could discuss it, I'm sure...
There is nothing to discuss, John.
Well, come back to my house.
You've got a long journey back.
You must forgive the
manner of our table, Mr Pym.
Our best crockery is
packed for the voyage.
Bridget, fetch the bread.
Yes, Mother.
We had hoped to persuade your
husband to change his mind
about going to America, ma'am.
I should have thought you would know
Oliver better than that, Mr Pym.
It was not an easy decision, John.
This is my country, my land.
God has been good to me here.
Then, sir, why are you leaving?
I have a family, Mr Ireton.
I owe it to my sons to
make a better life for them.
England is no longer a
country for a young man.
I recall you often spoke out strongly
in Parliament for the rights
and privileges of the common people.
Oh, that was a long
time ago, Mr Ireton.
I had a vision then.
A great nation.
Prosperous, God-fearing,
good laws, strong,
respected throughout the world.
That was the England I dreamed of.
Well, sir, you are a squire now,
a man of property.
Perhaps you no longer
care for the common people.
Perhaps I've been misinformed, sir.
I thought, as a Puritan, you would
see it as your God-given duty to do
the Lord's work in this land,
regardless of sacrifice.
Mr Ireton,
I was fighting for the liberty
of the common people when
you were in knee-britches.
Then why are you leaving?
I am leaving because this country
crawls with greed and corruption.
It is governed by adventurers and
profiteers who think more of their
pockets than their principles.
I am leaving, sir, because we
have a king who taxes the rich
beyond its means
and steals the land from the poor
to maintain his lavish court
and his Catholic wife.
And when Parliament objected
against these injustices,
he closed his Parliament down.
And our man dare not speak his
mind for fear of imprisonment.
Oh, yes.
All my life I believed it was God's
work to fight against such tyranny.
But God has turned his
back upon this nation,
and we are leaving it.
And what if Parliament should
be recalled, Mr Cromwell?
And why should a king do that?
He needs money, Oliver.
What? To build another palace?
No.
To fight a war.
A war, John?
A war against whom?
The Scots have assembled
an army on our border.
They may invade us at any moment.
The King needs money
to raise an army.
Ah.
By the King's own decree, Parliament
has not sat these past 12 years.
And now the King needs money.
Once Parliament is assembled, it
will lie within our power to change
the whole structure of
government in this country.
John, how many times did we sit
in Parliament in the old days,
and how many resolutions did
we pass, and how many times
did this king overrule us?
Oh, the King can have his war with
Scotland. We will be in America.
There will be a war, Mr Cromwell,
but it will not be with Scotland.
Henry.
With whom, Mr Ireton?
Henry, we have argued this matter
many times. I am convinced of it.
A war against whom, Mr Ireton?
Against the King, sir.
The King?
You mean a civil war?
In England?
You know not the ways of
this nation, Mr Ireton.
Such things do not happen here.
And, in my opinion,
it is long overdue.
I will not have
such talk in my house.
It is common enough
talk these days, I fear.
Then it is treasonable talk!
And I will not have it in my house!
I mark the time when you
were much against the King,
and not afeared to say so.
In truth, there is much in
this king that doth offend me.
Yet withal, I would not take up arms
against him, and I would oppose
any move to do so.
In such a cause, our swords
would be in God's hands.
That's an odd thing, Mr Ireton.
Every man who wages war
believes God is on his side.
I warrant God should often wonder
who is on his. Good evening, sir.
If I gave you offence,
I beg your pardon.
You're a young man, Mr Ireton.
It is fitting a young man
should want to change the world.
Not the world, sir. Only England.
With a civil war.
Good evening, Mrs Cromwell.
Good evening, Mr Ireton.
I'll get your cloak, Mr Ireton.
I hope you'll forgive him.
Goodbye, John.
God be with you, Oliver.
Come on, get these fences up.
Put your backs into it.
CATTLE LOWING
SHOUTING
You've no right to do this.
Leave them animals be.
This is the common land.
Any man who raises a hand against
the King's men will be arrested.
You have no right to do this.
This land is ours.
Now it belongs to the
Earl of Manchester.
By whose authority?
By the authority of the King.
Then I say the King is a thief!
You're under arrest.
Take him away! Bastards!
Release that man!
Who the devil are you?
This man works for me.
Whatever he has done, I will
take full responsibility.
He has spoken treason against
the King. Will you take
responsibility for that?
The rights to pasture
belong to the common people.
By what authority, Lord
Manchester, do you take that away?
By the authority of His Majesty's
commissioners granting me
and my friends
full rights to this land
for the purpose of improvement.
Such a contract cannot be legal.
It is in violation of
the law of this land.
As a magistrate, you should know
the King is the law of this land.
On the contrary, my Lord Manchester,
it is the King's duty to maintain
the law. This is common land.
It belongs to the people. This is
my land and you are trespassing.
It's only out of respect for
your rank I don't have you
arrested for obstructing the law.
Captain Lundsford! My lord?
See that no unauthorized
person enters this area.
Yes, my lord. Remove these people!
BELL RINGS
Good morrow to you, squire.
Good morrow, Mrs Cromwell.
Squire, have you news of my husband?
It's in God's hands, Mrs Carter.
And in the King's. Aye.
Let us pray.
Almighty God,
look down upon this, thy house,
and we, thy humble servants.
Grant us the spirit of thy grace
through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.
Who has done this?
Answer me.
An edict, squire, from the archbishop
himself and by order of the King.
By order of the King?
Is the Church of England
not a Protestant church?
Would the King turn the house of God
into a Roman temple?
Mr Cromwell, I beseech you.
Does the King think that
God can be bought with gold,
trinkets and gilded rubbish?
I know only that I
have been instructed.
Has this king
forgotten the Reformation?
Mr Cromwell...
Away with this popish idolatry!
Did the Lord not say unto Moses,
"Thou shalt not make unto thyself
any graven image,
"Nor bow down to them."?
Has this king forgotten the
Spanish Inquisition?
Is the Roman Catholic Church
to have a seat in Westminster?
SHE SCREAMS
Oh, my God.
My God. Oh, my God!
God damn this king.
CHURCH MUSIC PLAYS
King's guard, attention!
Here we are, my lord.
That'll do, damn it.
I'm not a damned cripple.
Me sticks, where are me sticks?
Come over here, boy.
Here they are, my lord.
Give me the damned things.
And who the devil are you?
Edward Hyde. Ah.
Let's in to His Majesty.
Where is he?
He's at prayers, my lord. Aye.
He might do well to pray, and all.
We're gonna need some help.
First the Irish and now the Scots.
You daresn't turn your
back on either of them.
Let us give thanks to almighty God,
that he has seen fit to bless this
table with the fruits of his bounty.
In the name of our Lord,
Jesus Christ. Amen.
Amen.
I did remark, madam,
with some distress,
that His Highness, Prince Charles,
was absent from prayers this morning.
He was with me, my lord.
He did pray with you? In your chapel?
Yes, my lord. I am most displeased.
It is not fitting that a future
king of England should make his
devotions in a Catholic chapel.
Your private beliefs are respected.
But this is a Protestant country,
and as head of both church and state,
it is my God-given duty
to see that it so remains.
His Highness found the
whole business so boring,
my lord, that he fell asleep.
Didn't you, Charles? Yes, madam.
I believe you will find your
church as solid as ever, my lord.
Nevertheless, you will kindly
see that it does not happen again.
Yes, my lord.
Your Majesty? The Earl of
Strafford awaits your pleasure.
My good Lord Strafford,
welcome back to England.
Thank you, my lord.
Your Majesty.
Your Royal Highness.
Most noble sovereign.
A chair for his lordship.
Thank you, my lord.
I'm sorry to see you in pain.
It is the agues
from the bogs of Ireland, my lord.
Godforsaken place.
Saving your presence,
my lord bishop.
We would not have summoned you, Lord
Strafford, had the situation here
not been of the greatest urgency.
You've doubtless heard
that the Scottish rebels
are marching on Newcastle.
Aye, my lord. You will whip
these barbarians to their senses.
But what of Ireland, my lord?
We'll deal with Ireland in good time.
You'll march an army on Scotland.
Army.
What army?
Most of your army lies rotting
beneath the bogs of Ireland.
And what's left of it is
hard-pressed to keep law and order.
Then we will raise a second army.
I fear Your Majesty may find
that easier said than done.
What? I guarantee I could raise
3,000 men under arms inside a month!
But could you guarantee
their loyalty, my lord?
Is there an Englishman
living who wouldn't draw a
sword against his king's enemies?
There be many Englishmen, my Lord
Stafford, who would more readily
draw swords against the King.
My God, who is this
jackanapes that mouths such
treason in your presence, my lord?
You've been away a long time,
Strafford. Much here has changed.
Aye, I can see it has.
I fear Sir Edward
but speaks the truth.
To put an effective army in the
field against the Scots will
cost almost a million pounds.
The Crown does not
have a million pounds.
Are we just going to sit here, then,
and do nothing?
Then I will summon Parliament and
instruct them to provide money.
Parliament?!
The King of England
go cap in hand to the
common people, like a...?
A beggar! Aye! A beggar.
I have no choice.
I say take the money.
You, my lord, are absolved
before God and before man
from any such action.
For in extreme necessity,
the King is acquitted
from all rule of government
and can do all
that his power permits.
Power? Where is the
power of a king without an army?
I'll warrant you,
I'll raise an army.
We'll reduce this kingdom
to submission in one summer!
Do you mean, sir, that I should
declare war on my own people?
Aye!
Before they declare war on you.
Well, sons,
there it is.
Parliament House.
Upon that place rests all the
hopes of this nation for a
settlement of its ills in peace.
Do you think it could
come to war, Father?
Well, Oliver, when men run out of
words, they reach for their swords.
Let's hope we can keep them talking.
The King demands money
to raise an army.
SHOUTING
This House demands
redress for grievances.
Grievances which the past 12 years
have laid heavy upon the nation.
I say that...
SHOUTING
Might I be heard? I say
therefore this House is resolved.
Welcome back to Parliament.
No money for the King!
SHOUTING
Order! Order!
Neither will we take up arms against
our Scottish brethren, unless...
unless...
this Parliament is allowed
to function as the true voice
of the people of England.
And not as a gathering
of lackeys to the King.
SHOUTING
Sir Edward Hyde, Your Majesty.
Well, Sir Edward?
Your Majesty, I believe the House
will grant a loan to the Crown.
But only on certain conditions.
Conditions?
What do you mean, conditions?
What are these
conditions, Sir Edward?
In essence, sire,
that the Crown relinquishes
all authority over Parliament.
And who put forward
this proposal?
John Pym, Henry Ireton,
John Hampden.
The Puritans.
They were well supported, my lord.
And they call themselves Englishmen?
My God, it's enough to make
a man deny his birthright.
Yet, withal, they
still be Englishmen.
They make a mockery of the Crown!
They abuse the privilege of free
speech with sedition and treason.
You're too loud, Lord Strafford.
It is most unpleasant to the ear.
So it has come to this, my lord,
that you now bargain for your crown.
What would you have me do?
Arrest every man who opposes me?
Hang them? Would you rather make
a gift of the Crown of England
to the rabble in the street?
It lies beyond my power to arrest
a citizen without proper charges.
Charges are immaterial.
Such an act would subvert
the fundamental laws
of this land, madam.
Such an act might save the
Crown of England, my lord.
I've governed this country justly
and fairly these 12 years without
reference to any Parliament.
You may be assured, I do not intend
now to be schooled in my high office
by illiterate farm hands,
cobblers and...
..basket weavers.
My Lord Strafford, you will
rid us of these troublemakers.
Pym, Ireton, all of them.
I'll arrest every one of
them, my lord. As you will.
I shall need a warrant.
That is imperative.
And what will the
charges be, my lord?
You're an experienced officer
of the Crown, Strafford,
you do not need to
be instructed by me.
SHOUTING
Mr Speaker.
May I have permission
to address the House?
By all means, sir.
Gentlemen. A matter has come
to my notice, which is
of deep concern to me,
and will, I am sure, be to
every single member of this House.
The Earl of Strafford has, this day,
put his hand to a warrant
for the arrest and impeachment
of myself and four other
honourable members of this House
upon a charge of high treason.
SHOUTING
Though Strafford's hand
be upon this warrant,
I see in this business, not the hand
of Strafford, but that of the King.
My lords!
I beseech you, do not
condemn this king too hastily.
For I am persuaded he has been
ill-advised upon this course.
Is not a king to be judged by those
from whom he seeketh counsel?
No, he is not!
It is not the function of this House
to sit in judgement upon this king.
The fault lies with those
very people from whom the
king has sought counsel.
Is the...?
I therefore move...
that this House demands
the arrest and impeachment
of the Earl of Strafford
upon a charge of high treason
against the people of this nation.
SHOUTING
Order!
Silence! Order!
The motion has been proposed.
Let it be put now to the question.
Is the motion agreed? NO!
In favour of the motion?
AYE! AYE! AYE!
The ayes have it.
CHEERING
I think my Lord Strafford's
condition...
will soon be far happier than mine.
SHE PRAYS IN FRENCH
Do you see, madam?
Do you see now what
you've made me do?
SHE CONTINUES PRAYING
Gentlemen, His Majesty.
Pray, be seated.
Your coming is nothing if not timely.
My Lord Strafford's head
has but barely fallen.
Gentlemen, it is for you to speak.
Your Majesty, you see here the
leaders of all parties of the House.
And though we be divided on many
issues, we are of one accord -
in that we place above all else,
our allegiance and loyalty
to our most gracious sovereign.
For which reason we are deeply
anxious for a settlement of
the differences between us.
I share your sentiment, Sir Edward.
The issue be this, my lord.
Parliament is persuaded that
without the right to govern this
nation by the will of the people
and with God's guidance,
we be not a Parliament at all.
And that unless some constitutional
reformation be brought about,
we would as well go back
to our homes and our farms
as pursue this mockery
of a government one more day.
In short, Mr Pym, you're asking me
to relinquish my sovereign power
over Parliament.
It does amount to that,
Your Majesty.
I do swear that I hold
this England and its laws
dearer to my heart than any here.
But, gentlemen, if you would reduce
me to a figurehead, a puppet king,
manipulated by Parliament,
how then would I serve my country?
What manner of king would I be?
I am persuaded, Your Majesty, that
England must move forward to a more
enlightened form of government
based upon a true representation
of a free people.
Such an institution
is known as democracy, sir.
Democracy, Mr...?
Cromwell, sir.
Democracy, Mr Cromwell,
was a Greek drollery
based on the foolish notion that
there are extraordinary possibilities
in very ordinary people.
It is ordinary people, my lord, who
would most readily lay down their
lives in defence of your realm.
It is simply that being ordinary,
they would prefer to be asked
and not told.
You know, as I do, even as we sit
here, the Scots rebels
are invading this land
and not an English sword
is raised against them.
I beg you, therefore, let us
bury our differences in defence
of both our church and kingdom.
The Scots invade our land,
and all is urgency and alarm.
Yet the past 12 months, our Irish
colonists have been slaughtered,
our churches desecrated,
our clergy persecuted.
The Crown has been
oddly reluctant to defend our church
and our kingdom over there, sir.
By my guard, I would as soon
take up arms against Rome
than against the Scots.
Would you have me declare war on the
entire Catholic world, Mr Cromwell?
It is your duty to
defend our Church, sir.
We are speaking now of a matter
of international policy.
Is Your Majesty sure that it's not
a matter of domestic expediency?
Cromwell! I would remind you, sir,
that you are addressing your king.
Mr Cromwell,
you are impertinent.
Such issues are beyond
good manners, sir.
Catholicism is more than a religion,
it's a political power.
Therefore, I'm led to believe there
will be no peace in Ireland until
the Catholic Church is crushed.
Your Majesty.
These gentlemen are
from the Parliament.
Your Majesty, Parliament has
drawn up this document in which
are set out our main grievances.
It's our belief
that the demands made here
are only those that are just and
lawful and in the best interests
of both crown and kingdom.
I shall examine these proposals
most carefully, Mr Pym.
Gentlemen.
It's not too late, my lord.
You have the power still.
And with God's help,
the strength to use that power.
Oh, my dearest Charles.
I married you as a king
and as a man.
I beseech you, do not
disappoint me in either aspect.
This House has time and again
expressed its wholehearted loyalty
to the Crown.
SHOUTING
Let Parliament
await in vain for a gesture...
The King is coming to arrest you,
John Hampden, Henry Ireton,
Sir Arthur Haselrig and Oliver
Cromwell for high treason.
I suggest you leave.
..That if the issues that
divide the King from his country
be not soon resolved,
then these issues
may soon divide the nation.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
The King is coming with
a warrant for our arrest. What?
We must leave at once.
Oliver, your name is on it.
Come!
My lords! My lords!
Gentlemen! The King comes.
He comes with 100 men at arms.
The doors! The doors! Bolt the doors!
SHOUTING
Stand aside, gentlemen,
if you please.
Halt! Open in the name of the King!
SHOUTING
Mr Speaker.
Gentlemen, you must pardon this
infringement of your privilege,
but I will not detain you long.
Mr Speaker, I must make
bold with your chair.
I have here a warrant for the arrest
of five members of this House -
John Pym, Henry Ireton,
John Hampden, Oliver Cromwell
and Sir Arthur Haselrig -
upon a charge of treason.
I see that the birds have flown.
Mr Speaker,
where are these gentlemen?
May it please Your Majesty,
I've neither eyes to see
nor tongue to speak
except as this House gives me leave.
Well, sir, I have eyes.
I see that one of them is here.
Captain.
Take him!
Any action against any member of
this House is a breach of privilege.
I move this House
declares as public enemies
any who lay hands upon its members.
SHOUTING
And I further move...
I further move that any such action
against this House be considered
a crime against the people...
and treason against this nation.
SHOUTING
So be it.
Mr Speaker, you'll inform the members
of this House that their presence is
no longer required by the nation.
This Parliament is,
by my authority, terminated.
Dissolved.
Your Majesty!
Are you aware that by your action in
this House you may have pushed this
nation to the brink of civil war?
Now do we see
in what contempt this king
holds this House and this nation?
It be either your king
or your Parliament.
Honourable members,
the decision is yours.
But I beseech you, in the name
of God, think well on it.
Fairfax.
Gentlemen, I move that this House
demand the control of the militia,
and that this country be put
in an immediate posture of defence.
Mr Speaker...
My lords,
honourable members,
this nation is now in
a state of civil war.
And let us pray that God
in his mercy will give us strength
in this terrible
and most unhappy hour.
CHEERING
Morning, William. Give you
good day, squire. Why the coffin?
If it be God's will that I die,
I'd have a decent Christian burial.
Let's hope it doesn't come to that,
William. I need you at the farm.
Hello, Father. Father. Morning.
Where's your sword, Richard?
I have no sword, father.
You must get one and wear it.
It's a mark of your rank, captain.
Yes. God bless thee!
Hallelujah! Hallelujah, brethren!
It is the Lord's work
we do this day!
The Lord's work!
This is no place for you, Hugh,
though you be welcome.
I've consulted God on this matter,
Mr Cromwell.
I asked him,
"Lord, whose side are you on?"
And he answered me, saying,
"On the side of truth and justice."
So here I am.
COMPANY, FORWARD!
CHEERING
# ..Ye gates of brass
# Ye bars of iron yield
# And let the King of glory
# Pass the crosses in the field
# That banner brighter
# Than the star
that leaves a trail of light... #
REGAL MUSIC PLAYS
CHEERING
Greetings, Uncle.
'Tis a fair day for a fight.
Where be the enemy?
My lords, I present my nephew,
His Highness, Prince Rupert,
Count Palatine of the Rhine.
My lords, I give you greetings.
Your Highness.
And good Cousin Charles,
most noble Prince of Wales.
How fare you, young sir?
I am well, thank you, cousin.
So, let us to action.
For I do swear by this sword
within a week we'll have severed
every Roundhead from its shoulders!
Well, said, Your Highness.
Let the standard be raised.
FANFARE PLAYS
Get those guns moving!
MARCHING DRUMS PLAYS
# Thou shalt proclaim his life
# Though granted... #
Halt!
Where the devil are we?
Edgehill, my lord, over there.
Morning, Robert. Morning, Edward.
Damn me, they've got
a lot of fellows over there.
Where's Cromwell?
Approaching now, my lord.
Morning, Cromwell. Morning, my lord.
Your men fit, colonel?
My men are ready, my lord.
You seem damned eager to get into
this business, Cromwell?
We all enter this reluctantly,
but the die is cast.
Is that not so, Lord Essex?
You are right.
Well, to your position. Let no
man move except upon my signal.
And may God look kindly
upon us this day. Amen to that.
Missed my breakfast.
Damned tricky things, stomachs.
God be with you, men.
God bless you. Thank you, sir.
God be with you.
Take care of yourself, William.
The Lord'll take care of me.
Have faith, John. I have, squire.
Come on, lads, have your muskets
at the ready. Come on, now.
Father.
May God take care of you, Richard.
And be with you, Oliver.
And with you too, Father.
O Lord, defend our cause
against the face of the enemy.
Save us from the violence
of the enemy.
O Lord of hope, fight for us
that we may glorify thee.
O Lord, God of mercy,
put thy strength in
our hands this day.
Give not the battle to the
strong, but to the righteous.
And be thou, O merciful God,
our saviour and mighty deliverer...
Defend me from them
that rise up against me.
In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.
AMEN!
Amen. Amen.
Father, look. It's Lord Essex.
Come, cousin.
Let's take a good look
at these Roundheads.
Your Majesty?
God's teeth, have we not
parleyed enough these past months?
Well, Essex, are you prepared?
We are. Shall we begin at ten?
Make it nine, my lord.
I'm positively starving.
Then in God's name, let's to it.
It's agreed then - 9 o'clock.
And by my faith, which I have not,
I swear that within the hour,
this field will be strewn
with English dead.
If this be so, they will have
been killed BY Englishmen,
for we have not seen fit to import
foreign mercenaries into OUR ranks.
I will mark you well for that
insult, sir. Be on your guard!
Colours to the rear!
The Lord is our strength.
Praise the Lord!
What in the name of God
are we waiting for?
Ireton!
I thought we came here to do battle.
We're waiting for the appointed time.
The appointed time?
Colonel Hampden, commence firing!
Fire!
What the devil is that fool doing?
Artillery, commence firing!
Fire!
O Lord, thou knowest how busy
I must be this day.
If I forget thee,
do not thou forget me.
Fire!
You'd better send Fairfax in.
Bugler, sound the charge.
BUGLER PLAYS THE CHARGE
Troop at the gallop. Advance!
SHOUTING
SCREAMING
HORSES WHINNYING
Signal Astley to advance.
Bugler, sound the advance.
BUGLER SOUNDS THE ADVANCE
The sport begins.
Tallyho!
Troops rear left.
At a gallop, charge!
SHOUTING
Give fire!
Advance!
Fire!
Advance pike!
Charge pike!
Agh!
Fire! Second rank forward!
At the run...!
SHOUTING AND CHEERING
HE SHOUTS
It's getting too damned
close for my liking.
Sound general retreat.
BUGLE SOUNDS
My lord! Why in the name of
Christ did you sound the retreat?
You've countermanded
my orders once today.
You'll do as you're told, sir!
Hold your ground, in the name of God!
Hold your ground!
Well, Uncle, did you ever see a
quarry so swiftly put to flight?
The King will for ever keep this
field and this day's service
in grateful remembrance.
CHEERING
HORSES WHINNY
Come nightfall, we
shall bury our dead.
And then, by God,
we shall bury this army.
With such pitiful men in
our ranks, it were better
this war were never fought.
Not a drop of English blood
soil this land.
It's a bad officer who
blames his men, Cromwell.
I blame them not, my lord,
for they are simple men.
But what match are farmers'
boys against gentlemen's sons?
The battle is not yet lost, Cromwell.
This battle were lost
before it ever began, my lord.
And in like manner,
so will this war.
In the morning,
I'm returning to Cambridge.
lf you desert the field,
I'll have you arrested.
This war will not be won with
untrained ploughmen, apprentices,
old, decaying serving men!
We need men
with fire in their bowels who
fear the Lord, but not the enemy!
As God is my witness, I am resolved
that this battle will be won.
Therefore, it is my intention
to return to Cambridge
and raise an army of handpicked men,
the like of which
this nation has never seen!
With or without your permission,
my Lord Manchester.
# Rejoice in the Lord
# Rejoice in the Lord.
# He girdeth me with strength
# And teacheth my hands to fight
Bristol will not be
permitted to fall.
It is our only seaport in the
west, and if General Goring is
incapable of holding it,
I will dispatch someone who can.
I've a mind to see Bristol, my lord.
'Tis a fair city, I hear.
Then I shall place Bristol
in your command, nephew.
Now, my lord general...
Your Majesty.
Yes, what is it? News of
Cromwell's army, Your Majesty.
Come forward. At last, Old Ironsides
ventures forth. Well, speak, man.
They're about six miles away,
Your Majesty. Just south of Naseby.
By my reckoning, there'd be about
1,000 horse and 2,000 afoot.
And what news of Manchester's army?
I saw no other army, Your Majesty.
Was not Cromwell to join with
Manchester's forces at Naseby?
That was our
intelligence, Your Majesty.
Then Manchester be still in Lincoln.
So Cromwell comes with his army of
3,000 to our 7,000!
By your leave, Uncle. Your Highness!
General Astley, sound the alert!
I want every man in
full battle order at once. Sir!
By God, we have him!
Manchester!
Where in the name of Christ is he?
Know you not we are at war?!
In God's name I do swear we fight
this war single-handed. Oliver!
What treachery is this?
We came to meet Manchester and
instead we find the King's army!
Well, I shall take on the King.
And after that if needs must,
I'll take on Manchester as well!
Before you stands the enemy,
his three to every one of us.
And where, in God's name,
is Manchester?
My Lord Manchester will rue the
day he has not joined us here.
And now to your positions.
These tactics we have practised
often enough these past six months.
Now let us put them to the test.
For upon this field of Naseby, we'll
turn the tide of this unhappy war.
God be with you all.
Is this wise, Oliver?
We're heavily outnumbered.
Was not Gideon
outnumbered by the Amalekites?
It is not numbers that count,
but speed and surprise.
Let no man move, except upon
the word of his commander!
Though we be outnumbered, we shall
win this battle, I promise you!
So now put your faith in God
and keep your powder dry.
CHEERING
Halt!
Attack order.
Double line abreast. Forward.
Forward!
The man must be mad.
Prepare to attack.
Prepare to attack!
Our swords are in God's hand.
And our faith is in the Lord.
Charge!
Fire!
Forward!
CHEERING
Cromwell!
Regroup! Regroup!
After them!
SHOUTING AND CHEERING
Fire!
Advance!
BUGLE SOUNDS
To the rear!
Forward!
Come on, lads!
At the gallop!
CHEERING
Your Majesty,
may I suggest that we withdraw? No.
Who goes there?
Captain Cromwell, 3rd Cavalry.
Richard.
Thanks be to God. Where is Oliver?
The outrageous incompetence
and inefficiency of the High Command
have tried my patience and that of
my hard-pressed army long enough.
By my faith, I swear it would be
better that those gallant generals
Essex and Manchester took up
swords with the King.
For then might we be assured
of victory. Hear, hear!
For by their reluctance to pursue
this war with the intensity
it demands,
they have proved themselves
treacherous both to our cause
and to this nation.
Hear, hear!
If we beat the King 99 times,
he will still be our King
and we his subjects.
If he beats us but once,
we shall all be hanged. Hear, hear.
If that is so, then why
in the bowels of Christ
did we take up arms against him
in the first place?
Gentlemen...
..honest men have served
us faithfully.
And many have died,
that this House may sit in freedom
and this nation live in liberty.
In the name of God,
I beseech you,
do not desert them now. Aye.
Unless Parliament
supports this war to the full,
I am bound to say, in all
conscience, that I will lay down
my sword
and let this House
make its peace with the King -
be that peace ever so base.
SHOUTING
Then, it is for
this House to decide.
I move that this House demands the
immediate resignation of the
High Command,
upon the grounds that they be no
longer competent to command
the armed forces of this Parliament.
SHOUTING
Order. Order. The motion has been
proposed.
Let it now be put to the question.
Those against Colonel Cromwell's
motion. No!
Those in favour of the motion.
AYE!!
The ayes have it.
The motion be carried.
CHEERING
I move...
I move that Colonel Cromwell be
appointed Commander in
Chief of the army.
CHEERING
Bristol. We must dispatch
aid to Bristol with
all possible speed,
for as long as Rupert
holds Bristol, this war be not lost.
General Digby, if you can detach
your forces in this area and
approach Bristol from the east...
To do that, my lord, would be to
expose this city to immediate attack.
Then we move the Marquis
of Huntly's army south...
The Marquis, my lord, surrendered
to Cromwell's forces yesterday.
Cromwell. I hear nothing but
Cromwell, Cromwell.
My lord, it is but a game
we play here, a game with
wooden armies and paper flags!
'Tis but a block of wood
you hold in your hand.
My lords, all I
ask for is a little time.
Time, my lord, costs us heavily.
If we can hold on here in Oxford for
six weeks, the Scots have
promised an army of 20,000 men.
Her Majesty is in communication
with my cousin, the King of France.
And I have good reason to hope
for support from Ireland.
An army from Ireland, Your Majesty?
Faith, I would as soon join forces
with Cromwell himself,
as take up arms with the Catholics!
I am the King
and defender of my people,
and I maintain the right to seek
relief from no matter what quarter.
As King, my lord, it is your
God-given duty to defend
the faith of this nation.
I do what I think to be right, sir.
Catholics as allies!
It is unthinkable!
My God, if it has come to this, let
us rather sue for an honourable peace
than fight a dishonourable war.
I will not countenance defeat.
Rather than abandon my kingdom
to Parliament, I would come to
terms with the devil himself.
Since you came to the
throne, Your Majesty,
your armies have persistently
persecuted our Church in Ireland.
And yet, now that your need is great,
you turn to us for help.
The King's actions in Ireland, Your
Excellency, will seem as nothing
should these Puritans come to power.
It is not only the Crown of England
that is in peril, Excellency -
all institutions of established
order throughout the
countries of Europe are threatened.
An Irish army of 20,000 men,
even 15,000, would forestall such a
threat, and bring this wretched
war to a speedy end.
I am instructed to say that His
Holiness would permit an Irish force
to take up arms in this country.
But there are certain conditions.
First, the Catholic Church in
Ireland must be completely restored,
and permitted to practise freely
without interference or oppression.
Secondly, all Protestant
churches in Ireland must be closed,
and all Protestant bishops
and ministers removed from office.
Oh, there are one or two other minor
conditions of little consequence.
What you demand, Excellency,
would be a betrayal of my coronation
oath as head of the English Church.
You have a duty,
Charles, to the Crown.
For without that, you
will be head of nothing!
May I tell His Holiness that
you will agree to these conditions?
You have something
to say, Sir Edward?
Your Majesty,
His Highness Prince Rupert attends
in the council chamber.
Rupert? Here in Oxford?
Yes, my lord.
I fear Bristol has fallen.
If Your Excellency will excuse me.
Your Majesty.
My lords, His Majesty.
Do you not rise, sir,
when your King approaches?
Rise, sir! Or to your knees
in shame.
You did give me your most solemn
promise that you would hold
Bristol for four months.
Yet you have not held
it for four weeks!
You promise mountains,
yet you perform molehills.
You make a knave of your King!
My lord...
We were besieged on all sides.
Our men are foot weary from battle,
ailing with plague and sickness.
Yet you contrived
to escape with your life.
I have brought you an army, my lord.
An army 2,000-strong, ready and
willing to fight on for their King!
In exchange for all the corn and
stores you held in Bristol
and 200 cannon.
That was the price of
your freedom, sir.
I did what I considered to be right!
You deserted your command, sir.
I made a military decision!
A decision that
may have cost us this war.
Your action in this matter is of
such affliction to me, sir,
that it is the greatest
trial that has yet befallen me.
My conclusion is...to desire you to
seek subsistence elsewhere,
not in my kingdom.
Most gracious lord,
I do not crave forgiveness, for by
all I hold most dear, I do solemnly
swear that I acted in good faith!
The matter is at an end.
I will hear no more.
My lord!
My lord, I beseech you.
In God's name, allow that
I may die with honour.
Condemn me not to live.
Captain Lunsford.
Do not put upon these shoulders
the terrible shame of exile
and dishonour.
I beg you,
take my life, most noble lord.
Good uncle...
..for pity's sake!
His Highness is to be kept
under close guard until such time
as he is deported.
Very well, Your Majesty.
Father, Mother says I'm to
go with her tonight to France.
Is that your wish, Father?
Yes.
My duty is to stay here with
you and fight beside you.
Your place now is at your
mother's side, Charles.
You will help her raise money,
perhaps an army.
Should I meet my death,
and you are safely in France,
then England will still have,
in you, a lawful king.
You will go with your mother.
I love this land.
And when this great
responsibility becomes yours...
..then I pray that with God's help,
you will reign more happily
than I have done.
Now go, with God's speed
and your Father's blessing.
Oh, Charles.
I love you.
Your Majesty,
it is my most solemn duty
to place you under arrest.
By whose command, sir?
By the command of Parliament, sir.
I know of no authority in England
above that of the King.
It is upon that issue that
this war was fought.
Whither am I to be taken?
To London, sir.
You must grant me
a little time to...
We leave for London at once.
And my children, what of them?
We will take care of your children.
His Majesty will have
all the time he requires.
As for your children, sir,
you may take them with you.
I thank you, sir.
# Him serve with fear
His praise foretell
# Come ye before him and rejoice
# The Lord ye know
Is God indeed
# Without our aid
He did us make
# We are his flock... #
General, John Pym is dead.
# He doth us feed
# And for his sheep
He doth us take... #
When did it happen? This morning.
What is it?
John Pym is dead.
Parliament is discussing
peace terms with the King.
Does the army have no say in this?
The army has been ordered to disband.
In God's name, did we fight this
war that the politicians should
take over behind our backs?
lf Parliament has decided the army
will disband, then the army
will disband.
I say we take the army and march on
Parliament. The sword will not
rule this land.
We fought a war to institute
a parliamentary system
and overthrow the very tyranny
which you now propose.
And who is talking to the King?
Parliament? I doubt it.
I warrant I know who is
doing all the talking.
I have these past three days
been in consultation with
His Majesty the King.
And I am pleased to inform the House
that the King is now prepared
to discuss peace terms,
provided that the army stand down.
SHOUTING
I have given this House's assurance
that his wishes will
be complied with.
Further, in recognition of the very
great debt this House owes its
Commander, General Cromwell,
it is proposed to award him a
pension of £3,000 a year
together with certain estates
in the county of Cambridge.
APPLAUSE
It is further proposed that
the sum of £2,000...
Such low treachery is not worthy
even of you, my Lord Manchester.
Am I to believe my ears?
Did this nation win a bloody civil
war in order that the King should
dictate the terms of peace?
I have discussed the matter at
great length with His Majesty.
YOU have discussed it?
It is a matter for this
House to discuss. Hear, hear!
The King will not come to terms,
sir, until the army stand down.
Hear, hear.
And the army will not stand down
until the King comes to terms.
So if the King will not
talk to this House,
then let the King talk to the army.
Out of the question.
The King would never agree.
Parliament is behind us, sir, and on
this occasion, we have the majority.
CHEERING
Sir Thomas Fairfax.
He's bringing in the army!
SHOUTING
Order! Order!
Order! Silence! Order!
SHOUTING
Silence! Order!
I believe, my Lord Manchester,
that now I have the majority.
This is dictatorship.
It will mean a new civil war. Aye!
Order!
Honourable members.
I swear before my God
that you give me no alternative.
When those liberties for which this
army and this nation have fought so
hard are most solemnly guaranteed,
then this army will stand down.
And upon that, you have my most
sacred promise.
Ah-ha-ha! And who have we here?
It is I, my lord.
You are supposed to run, Sir
Edward, not let me catch you.
I'm afraid I'm getting a little
too old for such games, my lord.
Cromwell is here to see you.
Oh.
You must play on your
own now, children.
Your father has other games to play.
Prince Henry, you will be good
enough to give me back my hat.
Sir.
Gentlemen, His Majesty.
We came to present
our terms, my lord.
If Your Majesty will be so kind
as to study these proposals.
Has Parliament approved this treaty?
Parliament no longer truly
represents the people of
this nation, Sir Edward.
And you, Mr Cromwell, do you truly
represent the people of this nation?
I represent the army, sir,
and the army is the heart and
conscience of the people.
So, having failed to come to terms
with Parliament, you would now
negotiate with the King?
I am not bound to
negotiate with anyone.
With 50,000 men under my command
I could impose a government
on this nation overnight.
One is given to wondering,
Mr Cromwell, why you do not do that.
I am deeply convinced, my lord,
it be the duty of Parliament
to frame a constitutional
government, and not the army.
Then I do not see that you have
any need of me at all.
On the contrary, sir.
An England without a King
is unthinkable.
But withal,
a King that can command respect,
a monarch
who governs, not from fear,
but by the affection
of a free people.
Such a King could
reunite this great nation of ours
and make the name of England
the noblest in all Christendom.
Should you adorn that inheritance,
my lord, all Englishmen would
be proud to call you King.
Mr Cromwell, I do confess
that I did greatly misjudge you,
for I did mark you
as an ambitious man.
To these ends, my lord,
I am ambitious.
Then you have my respect, sir.
Thank you, my lord.
We shall return in the morning, sir.
I shall require a little longer to
study this document. Perhaps a week.
As Your Majesty pleases.
I sincerely hope that our
future relations may be
equally amiable, sir.
That is my hope also, my lord.
A cunning fellow.
I believe him to be a
sincere man, my lord. Indeed.
lf these proposals be acceptable,
there never was a crown so nearly
lost, so easily recovered.
Whatever these
proposals may be, Sir Edward
they are not acceptable to the King.
Cromwell has betrayed us! Aye!
We have given our blood and our lives
in this war to put down this king!
lf Cromwell comes to terms with him
now, what price our freedom then?
Get back, will you?
I have served General Cromwell
faithfully all my life
and I reckoned him to be
a man who feared God
and did honour his word!
But in this business he has shown
himself to be a man of no honour!
We fought this war
to remove this King,
not to put him back on the throne!
I say, let us march on London,
let us take Parliament,
and then let the King
try to negotiate with us!
SHOUTING
Make way for Cromwell.
Traitors! Mutineers!
I don't have to tell you,
any of you, you could
all be hanged for this.
We are not serfs, General,
nor mercenaries.
We have fought for the Lord in our
cause, and now we have a right
to speak.
You have no rights
to preach revolt and mutiny.
As for you, John Carter,
I did expect a greater
degree of loyalty from you.
I am still loyal to
what I fought for, sir.
Can the same be said of you?
I have not betrayed my God, country,
Parliament or my conscience.
And where was your
conscience this day,
when you parleyed with the King?
I tell you, all of you,
I do most honestly believe that we
have taught this King a lesson.
And he will prove most honourable.
Upon that I would stake my life.
Traitor! Traitor!
This is a military camp,
sir, not a debating chamber.
Under military law, any man
inciting to mutiny can be hanged.
Colonel Harrison? Yes, General.
These three men will draw lots.
One of them will be hanged. Captain
Lancing, get a length of rope.
Yes, sir. You, man.
Yes, sir. Pick up some straws.
General, there is a Sir
Edward Hyde to see you.
Sir Edward, has the King considered
our terms?
The King, sir, has not
even read your terms.
Nor, will I venture, has he
any intention of so doing.
He has this day drawn up a secret
treaty with Manchester and Essex
to raise a Scottish army against
the Parliamentary forces.
He has already consented to
a Catholic army from Ireland.
While you negotiate a
settlement with him,
he is planning a second civil war.
I do confess that I have these many
years given my allegiance
to a man...
..not worthy of the
title, King of England.
HORSE WHINNIES
Colonel Harrison!
I will have this King's head,
aye, and the crown upon it.
This obstinate King,
this man of blood,
whose heart God has hardened,
can no longer be trusted,
for in prodigious treason, he has
revealed himself to be a traitor.
A man of no honour.
A man unfitted to bear the title,
king of England.
Hear, hear.
I demand, therefore, in the name
of the army and in the name
of the people of this nation
that Charles I, king of England be
brought hence to stand trial
for his life on a charge of treason.
Oh yay, oh yay, oh yay.
All manner of persons having
anything to do with this court come
forward and give your attendance.
Every man to keep silence
upon pain of imprisonment.
God save the King.
Let the prisoner be brought in.
The clerk of arraigns
will read the charges.
Charles Stuart, King of England,
you stand before this court
charged with high treason,
in that being admitted
King of England,
and therein trusted with power to
govern according to the laws
of the land,
you did out of wickedness and design
erect and uphold in yourself an
unlimited and tyrannical power -
to rule at your will
and to overthrow the rights
and liberties of the people.
And that you did
traitorously and maliciously
levy a cruel war
against Parliament and the people.
And are therefore guilty of all the
treasons, rapings, burnings, spoils,
desolations, damages and mischiefs to
the nation committed in the said war.
Thus, on behalf of
the people of England,
this court impeaches you as a tyrant,
traitor, murderer and public enemy
to the Commonwealth of England.
God save the King!
Silence!
Sir, you have heard
the charges against you.
The court expects an answer.
First, I would know by what
authority, I mean lawful authority,
I am brought here and carried from
place to place, and I know not what.
And by what authority you
presume to sit in judgement on me.
Remember, I am your lawful King.
Think well upon it.
I have a trust committed to me
by God, by old and lawful descent.
Therefore, let me know by what
authority I am brought here,
and I shall answer.
It is not for the prisoner
to question the court.
I am no ordinary prisoner, sir.
An answer, sir.
The court demands an answer.
Then I refuse an answer.
Sir, you are before
a court of justice.
Well, sir, I see that
I am before a power.
The court will keep silent.
Mr Solicitor General,
are your witnesses prepared?
They are, my lord.
Then let them be brought forth.
Call Sir Edward Hyde.
And you saw the King and his wife
alone in their chambers with this
Catholic Archbishop Rinuccini?
I did.
And what did you assume was the
purpose of this meeting?
You are obliged to
answer, Sir Edward.
To raise an Irish army, my lord.
To fight
against the Parliamentary forces?
And at this time,
was the King in communication
with any other foreign power?
Yes. Yes, with the King of France
and with the Dutch.
For the same purpose?
Yes.
To raise a foreign army
to invade this country...
..and to perpetuate the war
against the people of this kingdom.
Sir Edward?
Yes.
SHOUTING
To the blocks with him!
Sir, throughout the three days
of this hearing,
this court has patiently awaited
your pleasure,
to hear what you have to say in
answer to the charges against you.
Yet you have declined to speak.
I am most willing, sir,
to answer before Parliament.
But not before this assembly, whose
authority I refuse to acknowledge.
Sir, what answers you may offer
the Commons can be given here,
for this court does sit in the
name of the House of Commons.
Sir, if, as you have said, you do
love the liberty of the subject,
you will grant me, your King,
a hearing before Parliament, which
is the Lords and Commons assembled.
Sir, I submit you seek only
to delay the course of justice.
By your favour, sir,
I seek only those rights which,
as your King, I would grant
to any one of my subjects.
SHOUTING
Silence!
Sir, this court requires to know if
you have anything to say before
judgment is passed upon you.
I have nothing to say to you.
Then this court
will retire to judgment.
What ails thee? Art thou mad?
Have we come thus far that
you would betray us now?
There is nothing in the constitution
of this land that entitles us
to bring a King to trial.
Is not the King
answerable to his subjects?
The trial is clearly illegal...
Is not the King
answerable to his subjects?
The King, sir, is
answerable only to God.
Then by God, when he dies, he
shall have much to answer for.
We have gone too far in this matter.
This commission has no lawful
authority... Our authority lies with
the Parliament, sir.
Parliament is the law in this land.
If the charges against this King be
not proven, what terrible retribution
may he not bring down upon our heads?
Aye! Aye!
In the name of God! What are we all?
Men?
Cowering and quivering
like downtrodden serfs.
The King is not England,
and England is not the King!
It is not the survival of the King
that is at issue here.
It is the survival of England.
And this King, by his dishonesties,
by his treasons,
and by his secret treaties
with foreign powers,
has shown himself to be ill-fitted
to govern this great nation!
As God is my witness, Oliver,
I desire not the King's death,
but the settlement
of this nation in peace.
Do you think I don't desire that?
Go back to my farm and my family?
Very well.
Go again to this King.
Offer him once more our terms.
Though God knows, he should be
well-acquainted with them by now.
Tell him he may sit upon his throne,
but that this country will
be governed by Parliament,
and Parliament will be
elected by the people.
Now, Sir Thomas, if you can achieve
this, where we have failed,
this trial will end.
Here is a warrant demanding the
death of the King upon the charge of
high treason against this nation.
It will require all your signatures.
Sir Thomas...
I have come thus far with you,
Oliver, in our great cause,
but I will not sign this warrant.
Sign it. Oliver, I cannot.
Is he guilty or not guilty?
He is the King! Is he guilty?
Yes. Sign it.
Charles Stuart, King of England...
..you have been found
guilty of high treason against
the good people of this nation,
represented in Parliament,
by whose authority this court
does sit in judgment upon you.
And upon this charge,
it is the sentence of this court
that you be taken hence to an...
..appointed place...
..and put to death by the
severing of the head from the body.
And that is the sentence
of the whole court.
SOME SHOUTING
Remove the prisoner. Silence!
Will you hear me a word, sir?
No. You're not to
be heard after sentence.
By your favour, sir.
I know as much law as any man here.
I have the right to be heard.
No, sir. Guard,
Remove your prisoner!
SHOUTING
I demand to be heard!
I am your lawful King!
To the block for the traitor!
General.
Sir Thomas.
I have been this past
night to the commissioners.
They have instructed
me to lay before you
this warrant for £40,000
in return for the King's life.
How little you know me, that you
think you can buy my principles.
You insult me with that cheap bribe.
Will you not think on it?
I have thought on it.
And well.
By my God, I have thought on it.
"Then the soldiers of the governor
took Jesus into the common hall.
"And they stripped him and
put on him a scarlet robe.
"And when they had platted a crown
of thorns, they put it
upon his head.
"And they bowed before him
and mocked him, saying,
'Hail, King of the Jews!'
"And they spit..." Your Majesty.
Is it time? No, Your Majesty.
Her Royal Highness,
the Princess Elizabeth,
and his Royal Highness, Prince Henry.
Elizabeth, sweetheart.
Do not grieve for me. Henry...
Now, both of you...
Mark what I say.
They will cut off thy father's head.
Sshh. There now. Henry, pay
careful attention to what I say.
You must not let them make you king.
Not while your brother Charles is
still alive.
I would be torn to pieces first.
That's my son.
Today, your brother will be king.
Elizabeth, now.
It's a glorious death to which I go.
Tell your mother...
..that my love for her
was the same to the last.
And remember me in
your prayers.
The King's escort, Your Majesty.
Thank you.
God bless you both.
What kind of morning is it, Colonel?
Indeed it is
somewhat chilly, Your Majesty.
Then I was wise to
put on a second shirt.
For if I trembled with the cold, my
enemies would say it was from fear.
I would not expose myself
to such a reproach.
Please keep them.
Oh, Your Majesty!
I do not fear death, Sir Thomas.
It is not at all terrible to me.
I thank my God I
have prepared for it.
Are we to ride
to Westminster, or walk?
My orders are that we
walk, Your Majesty.
Admirable.
The morning air will do me good.
BELL CHIMES
The King's coming.
He's coming now! The King's coming!
Hey, you. Stop him!
Gentlemen, the King comes.
Traitor! Execute him!
Execute him!
..and a true, urgent sword in our
hands. God bless, Your Majesty.
God bless you!
Escort, halt!
Well, gentlemen, are you afraid to
kill your King with an open face?
I will not delay you long,
but will say only this to you -
as God is my witness,
I have forgiven those that
have brought me here.
And pray that my death
be not laid to their charge.
For I do endeavour even to the last
to maintain the peace
of MY kingdom.
I go now, from a corruptible
to an incorruptible crown.
To everlasting peace.
Will that suffice?
Permit me, sir, that I may pray a
while before the blow is struck.
Then when I put out my hands so -
that will be the sign.
Lord, let us now thy servant depart
in peace according to thy word.
For mine eyes have seen thy
salvation which thou has prepared
before the face of all people.
Glory be to the Father,
Son, and Holy Ghost.
As it was in the beginning,
is now and ever shall be.
Behold! The head of a traitor!
We did not assassinate.
Nor was this thing done in a
corner - it was done in the face of
God, and of all men.
The office of King is now abolished.
Long live Parliament.
Long live the Republic.
ALL: Aye, long live the Republic.
Richard, I want to
go back to Cambridge.
Will you come with me, son?
lf you wish, Father.
It will be peace
and quiet there now.
God knows,
my soul craves a little peace.
You must not think on it, Oliver.
'Tis over now.
The war, everything.
'Tis over and done.
Oliver, you're home now.
There's nothing more to think on.
Save that we two may grow
old together in peace.
Peace.
Father - Henry Ireton is at the
house with some men from Parliament.
I'll be along shortly.
Tom.
Arthur.
Henry.
Well, you all seem solemn enough.
It is a solemn business
that brings us here, Oliver.
Well...speak of it.
The country needs a head of state,
Oliver. It must be governed.
Is it not governed by Parliament?
There must be a figurehead.
It is our tradition.
The country needs a King, Oliver.
God knows, you've said so
many times yourself.
The country
will be ruled by Parliament.
Now, in the name of Christ,
how often must I say that?
And who will control Parliament?
The people, the people, the people!
It's not practical. It won't work.
It will work
and it must work.
We are here, on behalf of Parliament,
to offer you the Crown.
To offer...
Me, King of England?
King Oliver I of England!
Elizabeth, tell me,
do you see before you a king?
This tired, sickening man,
this country oaf,
crude in speech and manner?
This rough fellow -
does he display the
bearing of a king?
You are the one man who
can govern this country.
In the name of God!
Did we cut the head off this
king only to steal his crown?
This hollow golden ring,
this worthless trinket?
Give it to a whore,
for the price of her bed!
And if you would find a head to fit
it, let it adorn some court jester
or some strolling player that
he may play your king, but not I!
Power must be absolute,
or it be no power at all.
It was not for
power that we did this thing.
Have you not understood that yet?
Now, Ireton,
mark me, and mark me well.
That you be hard set upon
courses has not escaped me.
And if you should seek to
use me towards such ends,
though I love you like a brother,
I swear, I will destroy you.
Every freeborn Englishman -
be he the lowest of the lowest -
is entitled to a voice in the
governing of this country.
There is no vote for the poor,
for the underprivileged - no vote
for all those who took up arms to put
down the very autocracy that this
Parliament now imposes upon us.
You did not vote this
Parliament into office!
This gaggle of
buffoons, these villains!
Much has been said in this House
about the so called inequity of
certain members being financially
involved in national projects.
Members have ascribed to
this state of affairs
dark and sinister motives.
I say if we in Parliament cannot
gain from ruling the country,
there's really very little point
in our being here at all.
No member of this House should be
permitted to profit from his office.
Hear, hear! lf this
House knew its duty to the nation,
it would terminate its sitting,
and let a new Parliament be elected.
Order!
Gentlemen, I move that this House
be given power to remain in office
a further three years
without re-election.
In my opinion, a committee
of inquiry should be set up
to investigate the financial
involvements of certain members...
Order!
Mr Speaker - may I have your
permission to address this assembly?
By all means, sir.
My lords,
honourable members -
I have always desired,
above my life, a free Parliament,
sitting by the authority
of the good people of this nation.
A Parliament open and visible,
to be seen by all men.
It is six years since I handed over
to you this great responsibility,
in the hope that you would make good
and wholesome laws which the people
of this nation expected of you.
I must
confess to some
abatement of my hopes -
for what has happened in my absence.
Instead of uniting
the good people of this nation,
with righteousness and peace,
which would have been a glorious and
Christian thing to have done,
what do I find?
Anarchy, corruption,
division
and dissatisfaction.
I say that the enemies of
this nation have flourished
under your protection.
You were from the beginning
a provisional government, not truly
representative of the people.
For have the people elected you?
Has this House gone once to the
people it purports to represent?
No, it has not!
And after six years of
misgovernment, what do we find?
Sir Thomas Fairfax moves a bill to
give this House a further lease of
its worthless
and dishonourable life!
Gentlemen,
an immovable Parliament is more
obnoxious than an immovable king!
Drunkards, tricksters, villains,
whoremasters, godless, self-seeking,
ambitious tricksters.
You are no more capable
of conducting the affairs
of this nation
than you are of running a brothel!
You are...! You are scum, sir.
And not truly elected scum at that.
This is no Parliament.
I shall put an end to your sitting.
I hereby declare this Parliament
dissolved!
Colonel Harrison! Yes, sir.
Troops forward!
Rubbish.
Remove them!
Come on, get them out.
This is dictatorship, sir!
Dictatorship! Dictator!
Dictatorship!
This is illegal! Come, sir.
I refuse to quit this chair.
By your leave, sir.
Away with this bauble!
I seem to recall
that we cut off a king's
head...for such as this.
You are a traitor, sir.
It is the likes of you who
have turned my hand to this.
I have sought the Lord's guidance
night and day in this matter.
It is not idly done, but this
nation will be justly governed.
I will give this nation back
its self-respect.
We will walk in this world
with our heads held high.
I will liberate man's souls
from the darkness of ignorance.
I will build schools
and universities for all.
This will become
the golden age of learning.
I will bring the law within
the reach of every common man.
There'll be work and bread for all.
This nation will prosper because it
is a godly nation,
and because we walk
hand in hand with the Lord!
I swear by the name of the living
God that I will see this nation
properly governed,
if I have to do it myself.
Dear God, give me the strength to
do it...alone.
Oliver Cromwell ruled the nation
as Lord Protector for five years.
In that short time, he raised
England to be a great power, feared
and respected throughout the world.
Under his hand were laid
the foundations of a
truly democratic nation.
In 1658, he died.
Three years later, Charles,
Prince of Wales, was crowned King,
and a monarch sat once more
upon the throne of England.
But an England never
to be the same again.
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd