Kill them.
If you kill it,
it is I who will.
With a machete.
They will suffer greatly.
Do what he tells you.
You are now a rebel
Grand Tiger.
We have 10 children ...
20 Kalashnikovs.
Hurry.
Sit.
Take. It's like your father,
Your mother.
Should not hold the gun
like this ...
Must hold like this.
Got it?
Never lose, never
your weapon.
We are rebels.
Respect your arms ...
as your new daddy
and mom.
Look at me.
Why are you looking down?
Gives the biscuits!
It's been two days
I have not eaten anything.
Person needs to know
I've given you.
I'll tell you
a story ...
which tells how
military life is hard.
Look.
My scar.
This is a bullet wound.
It was said to smoke at night
but I still smoked.
The bullet hit me.
Lifted the rifle. Tire.
Save yourself!
- We ...
- A witch ...
- Who will win ...
- The Government!
It is said that ...
you can see ...
wizards government
in the forest.
I have a gift.
My wizard ...
was engraved with magic.
Wake up!
It not hit the witch
Grand Tiger!
I return.
I will fight.
We need to celebrate!
Ask better than that!
This is a book about
the history of the Grand Tiger.
While he was
incantations ...
sunlight,
he fell on 30 elephants.
But thanks â magic,
he was able to defeat the elephants.
You know why
it's called Grand Tiger?
Because his magic
is so powerful ...
he can eat
men!
What are you doing?
Sit down.
What is it?
This is the Eye of the night.
He sees what happens
in the night.
And it?
The protection of the ancestors.
Wings?
It is the bird of night.
He takes the Eye
in the sky.
I have something ...
You'll always
have on you ...
Give me your hand.
Put it in your pocket.
- What are you doing?
- I take the sap magic.
The son of the Chief wanted to marry ...
Then he invited the girls.
They are disguised ...
"You're pretty, miss."
It not return
at Grand Tiger!
- I'm not leaving!
- You're coming with us!
No, but I dream ...
You know what grigri?
It is you who will die
if you shoot, not me.
After all I've done
for you ...
I have protected the forest,
on the river ...
- We go to Grand Papa Tiger!
- No!
You've lost your mind.
They made you mad.
Come on, get out!
We're going.
- Leave me alone!
- Come on, I say!
Listen to me.
Come on, we're going.
It is backward or forward?
Not a pig
rowing better than you!
You say anything ...
We have already capsized
if it was not for me.
Give me a white cock!
Are you kidding me?
Are you in love?
You want to marry?
Mom Angela!
What makes you laugh
like this?
It seeks a white cock
to marry.
You are completly cracked!
Where can I find
a white cock?
Does not exist ...
It exists because I looking for one!
My father wanted to marry
the most beautiful girl in the country.
He has requested,
he has never found
when he married my mother
for 10 cows!
Well okay, where
chickens here?
There is a loose-down barn.
- But there's no white cock ...
- Forget it.
Bastards! You will
slaughtered die!
I do not want.
We need a white cock
to be together ...
The white cocks
do not exist.
Your father lied.
All those whom I asked â
told me.
The white cocks exist
in your village.
And you refuse my hugs
for a white cock that does not exist.
So I'm going.
My leg!
Stop your antics!
Money! For the hospital.
You hit my brother.
You will pay! Help!
Tell me ...
You know where I can find
a white cock?
They are difficult
â find ...
I know!
Give me a grigri
to protect myself against the war.
- That's all you want?
- Yes.
- Maestro is the all?
A white cock is três expensive
this is rare.
It'll cost money.
I say you're a magician?
I have three wives.
I see one on Monday,
one on Tuesday,
the other on Wednesday ...
â difficult to manage.
So you give me
some money ...
and you give me also
something for strength.
No troubleshooting,
I have what you need.
I can deal with it
15 women?
Get control
situation.
Here is the white cock.
This is to get married,
then show your courage.
Come.
Uncle!
You have finished making war?
My wife Komona.
You do not need it anymore.
Is pressed and the oil is extracted.
It picks up
the Witch King Tiger.
It's not her witch
This is my wife.
She's not going anywhere.
We start with the witch!
She does not.
Hold it!
Leave him alone!
Kill him.
You are my wife.
Be happy.
Take it!
Why are you looking at me?
I do not concern you.
You look at me.
You waiting for me?
You want to make love?
You are all the same.
Help me!
Guns are banned here.
Give me your gun.
No.
Okay, little one?
Help us, Komona.
Why not you help us?
Come.
Lead us.
This is a hearse.
I wait for a corpse ...
Go!
You go to the cemetery later.
- Faster!
- It does not ...
Where can you file?
They'll put you in jail
if you go â hospital.
My uncle, the butcher.
- You know where it is?
- Yes ...
Where is the house of the butcher?
At the end, â right.
Grows.
Why did you put?
You could stifle
child, you know.
The child is alive.
Rest.
You're like my daughter.
I'll teach you
â raise goats.
Where is my gun?
Give me my weapon
or I'll kill you.
My weapon is my child,
This is my father.
This is my mother ...
I'll kill you,
give me my gun.
You have a nightmare.
You want to force me
â confess.
You eat people at night.
I do not eat one!
You eat people at night!
How witchcraft
Is she into you?
She's not into me!
What do you want?
Witchcraft in me.
How witchcraft
Is it coming?
By Grand Tiger's gun.
What?
What do you want?
I want you to débarrassiez
witchcraft.
I need a gift
to pray.
You must pray much
â God and ask for forgiveness ...
so that the spirit of Komona
returned to you.
I'll kill you!
You killed my family, my husband!
Give me my gun!
What are you doing?
Wait!
Go, go, Dad.
Go, go, mom.
Where are you going?
My uncle, the butcher.
Monte.
I have no money.
Nobody has any money.
Leaves, I got it.
Sub-ttirage: CNST, Montreal