[MAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY
OVER RADIO]
MAN 1 [OVER RADIO]:
Clear deck.
[MAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY
OVER RADIO]
MAN 2:
Patrick Michael Williamson
interview, take one.
Commander Williamson,
there's a small
MAN 2:
Patrick Michael Williamson
interview, take one.
but growing concern
in Congress
MAN 2:
Patrick Michael Williamson
interview, take one.
that we might be getting in over
our heads in Southeast Asia.
MAN 2:
Patrick Michael Williamson
interview, take one.
How does this strike you?
MAN 2:
Patrick Michael Williamson
interview, take one.
Well, I think
we ought to be here.
South Vietnamese want
to establish a country
Well, I think
we ought to be here.
with values similar
to our own.
Well, I think
we ought to be here.
I think we ought to help.
Well, I think
we ought to be here.
And what values are those?
Freedom, the right to think
for yourself,
to follow your own faith.
Freedom, the right to think
for yourself,
You know,
individual freedom.
Freedom, the right to think
for yourself,
Is that why
you're here?
I think I've told you
why I'm here.
But if you want
the official reason,
I think I've told you
why I'm here.
you'll have to ask
the civilian authorities.
I think I've told you
why I'm here.
They lawfully
ordered me here.
I think I've told you
why I'm here.
On that level,
I'm serving my country.
I think I've told you
why I'm here.
I'm here to serve
my government.
I think I've told you
why I'm here.
[¶¶¶]
[GROANING]
They held down the eject?
I hit the tree
on the way down.
[GROANING]
You'll be all right.
MASON: Ahh.
[GROANING]
Medivac will be here.
Okay, thank God.
[GROANING]
There it is.
Christ.
Get us outta here, Pat.
I gotta get out
in the open.
Christ.
Get us outta here, Pat.
I gotta make
official contact.
Christ.
Get us outta here, Pat.
[RADIO BEEPING]
[BEEPING STOPS]
[PANTING]
[GROANING]
Hey, he's got a broken leg.
[SHOUTS IN VIETNAMESE]
Get him off me.
[GUNSHOT]
Mason! Mason!
Mason!
[¶¶¶]
The legacy
of colonialism.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
The legacy
of colonialism.
Replacement parts
from France
are very difficult to obtain,
to say nothing of the expense.
Replacement parts
from France
That you stand when I enter
is good, is proper.
Shows correctness
of attitude.
That you stand when I enter
is good, is proper.
Welcome to Hanoi
and Hoa Lo prison.
I am Major Ngo Doc.
And you are?
Welcome to Hanoi
and Hoa Lo prison.
2210771, Lieutenant
Commander Williamson,
Welcome to Hanoi
and Hoa Lo prison.
Patrick Michael,
16th October 1930.
Welcome to Hanoi
and Hoa Lo prison.
And where was your
aircraft destroyed?
Welcome to Hanoi
and Hoa Lo prison.
2210771, Lieutenant Commander
Williamson, Patrick Michael--
Welcome to Hanoi
and Hoa Lo prison.
Heh. Yes, yes, all well
and good, commander.
Welcome to Hanoi
and Hoa Lo prison.
You are, no doubt,
trying to hide
behind the Geneva convention,
n'est-ce pas?
You are, no doubt,
trying to hide
Well, commander,
when the United States declare
war upon my country,
Well, commander,
then we will fulfill our
international commitments.
Well, commander,
But for the moment,
there is no declaration of war.
Well, commander,
And since you cannot be
a prisoner of war,
Well, commander,
you are a criminal.
I suggest you should ask
for a pardon.
President Ho Chi Minh
is a great man.
He will personally protect
you while you are here
President Ho Chi Minh
is a great man.
in Hoa Lo prison.
President Ho Chi Minh
is a great man.
2210771, Lieutenant
Commander Williamson,
Patrick Michael,
16th October 1930.
2210771, Lieutenant
Commander Williamson,
Our war with the French
lasted for a decade.
You might be here
for several years.
Think carefully,
commander.
Now, where was your aircraft
shot down?
2210771,
Lieutenant Commander Patrick
Michael Williamson,
16th October 1930.
2210771,
Lieutenant Commander Patrick
Recently pictured
in LIFE magazine.
2210771,
Lieutenant Commander Patrick
Married to Sheila Powers,
June 15, 1954.
2210771,
Lieutenant Commander Patrick
Two sons,
age 7 and 9.
2210771,
Lieutenant Commander Patrick
Home is Philadelphia.
2210771,
Lieutenant Commander Patrick
No point continuing,
eh, commander?
So...
Let us try again.
Are you married?
I know what
you're trying to do.
Are you married?
If I start telling
you this,
Are you married?
I'll be on board
your program.
Are you married?
Are you married,
commander?
Are you married?
No.
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
It might be two
or three years
before I give you another
chance to cooperate.
It might be two
or three years
To show correctness
of attitude.
[SPEAKS IN VIETNAMESE]
[SHOUTS IN VIETNAMESE]
[¶¶¶]
You bow!
Okay.
You can handle this.
Won't be more
than a couple of months.
We can handle this.
[¶¶¶]
[SQUEAKING]
No eat?
You bad.
Down.
I said down.
No eat?
You bad.
[GROANING]
Damn.
[VIETNAMESE MUSIC
PLAYING FAINTLY ON RADIO]
[GUARD SPEAKS IN VIETNAMESE]
[WOMAN ON RADIO
SPEAKING IN VIETNAMESE]
[METAL CLATTERS]
[VIETNAMESE MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
[¶¶¶]
Hey, driver! Navy?
[SPEAKS IN VIETNAMESE]
[HUMMING]
[¶¶¶]
Oh, God, if there's another
Yank here, we can make it.
We can make it,
we can make it, God.
Oh, God, if there's another
Yank here, we can make it.
We can make it.
[SPEAKING IN VIETNAMESE]
Well, commander.
How have you been
these past few months?
Well, commander.
Surviving.
Heh, yes, indeed,
you have.
Well, commander.
And I think you should deserve
some reward for that.
Well, commander.
Some of your compatriots
may be joining us.
Well, commander.
Perhaps we should allow
you some contact.
Well, commander.
Move you around
from time to time.
Well, commander.
In spite of my threat
to leave you in isolation
Well, commander.
for three years,
I offer some change
after merely one.
Well, commander.
You can therefore see,
I am a very lenient man.
Lenient, hell.
I just outlasted you.
All clear.
Hi.
Welcome to the bridal suite
of the Hanoi Hilton.
All clear.
Williamson.
Lieutenant Commander
of the Hancock.
Williamson.
Yeah, well--
The Hancock?
Williamson.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
The only one
in the cellblock.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Hi, I'm Paul Kennedy.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Lieutenant JG off
the Enterprise.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Earl Hubman,
captain, Air Force.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Bill Oldham,
Marine major.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
I'd get up,
but the leg's gone.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Busted in two places.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Believe it or not,
I've been here the longest,
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
over six months,
over in the Annex.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Besides you.
Four for me.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
And the cripple here
is the new boy.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Three weeks.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
A year's a long time.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
Who also have you seen?
No one.
How long have you been--
A year. I think.
I saw a message
on the bath house walls.
It was signed a Navy driver.
That message
and that's all.
It was signed a Navy driver.
So it's been...
It's been a very long time.
It was signed a Navy driver.
I began to think that
I wouldn't see anyone, and so...
It was signed a Navy driver.
Seeing you guys is...
What's your name again?
Paul Kennedy, sir.
Paul Kennedy.
Seeing you guys is...
How are you?
And you're...?
Captain Hubman.
Seeing you guys is...
And you're...?
Bill.
Seeing you guys is...
Bill, how are you,
Bill?
Seeing you guys is...
Welcome, sir.
Welcome.
Seeing you guys is...
WILLIAMSON:
How long you in, Bill?
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
Twenty-one years,
semper fi.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
Where you from?
Philly.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
And you?
St. Louis.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
Oakland.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
Tell me about
what's going on at home.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
What have I been missing?
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
I'll tell you,
Williamson.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
For openers, they've got
this 16-year-old daughter.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
Brings home this kid,
a boyfriend.
Twenty-one years
in the corps.
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
so my wife asked him,
in a decent,
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
courteous way,
she says,
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
"Don't you find your hair
a little feminine?"
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
That little son of a bitch
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
looks at her straight
in the eye and says,
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
"Compared to you, maybe."
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
So I killed him.
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
[CHUCKLES]
Now, this kid has got hair
almost across his ears,
Heh, don't believe him.
Something wrong, commander?
WILLIAMSON:
Maybe.
Something wrong, commander?
I mean, I don't know
who you guys really are.
Something wrong, commander?
Why you're allowed company.
It's okay sir, relax.
Something wrong, commander?
There's no conspiracy here,
look.
Something wrong, commander?
Our war is over.
Once we're in here,
we're as good as discharged.
Something wrong, commander?
And as far as being together,
look, Oldham's hurt.
Something wrong, commander?
It's hot in here.
Give me a hand, will you?
Something wrong, commander?
I'm here
as an afterthought.
Something wrong, commander?
Until three weeks ago
I was in a jungle camp.
Something wrong, commander?
I'm not supposed to be
a fighting man anymore.
Something wrong, commander?
I did my war in Korea,
I'm a recall.
Something wrong, commander?
Right about now
I should be taking a 503
Something wrong, commander?
from Grand Central
to Scarsdale.
Something wrong, commander?
Nice place you got here.
Did a real A-1,
spit and polish job.
I'm going to need
an 8:00 wake-up call.
You bow.
I'm going to need
an 8:00 wake-up call.
You bow!
I'm going to need
an 8:00 wake-up call.
Never bow to you,
you lousy son--
I'm going to need
an 8:00 wake-up call.
[GROANS]
I'm going to need
an 8:00 wake-up call.
Never!
God damn it!
Get your skinny little
ass back here!
Never!
God damn it!
Voice to deep to be a V.
Must be a choir.
Never!
God damn it!
Choir! Hey, driver!
Never!
God damn it!
No do! No do!
You quiet!
Hey, don't put him back
in solitary.
No do! No do!
You quiet!
[¶¶¶]
No do! No do!
You quiet!
Fuck you!
Well, whoever just told me
to go screw myself
Fuck you!
had sure better outrank me.
Uh, who said that?
CATHCART: I'm Cathcart.
Fuck you!
Cameron Cathcart.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
Where are you?
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
Uh, sir.
Where are you, sir?
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
Keep talking.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
MILES:
I'm Miles,
captain, Air Force.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
Captain, huh?
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
You just keep talking.
MILES: Yes, sir.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
A little discipline around
here would be good, sir.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
I know I could use
some structure.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
Uh, I'm alone.
That's enough.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
Captain.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
I found it.
Air Force, colonel,
full colonel.
It's a hole.
Back of that pipe.
About 9 o'clock.
Get up on your bunk.
It's a hole.
Back of that pipe.
I'm sorry, sir.
I can't, I'm in stocks.
Oh.
I'm sorry, sir.
I can't, I'm in stocks.
I got contact with a man
on the other side.
He says he just got himself
60 days in irons
for trying to contact you.
He says he just got himself
60 days in irons
Tell him congratulations on
joining the ankle biters' club.
He says he just got himself
60 days in irons
And sir,
could you do me a favor?
He says he just got himself
60 days in irons
Uh, ask him how he works
the bucket in the stocks.
He says he just got himself
60 days in irons
I'll find out.
He says he just got himself
60 days in irons
In the meantime,
hear this.
And pass it on.
In the meantime,
hear this.
The code of conduct
In the meantime,
hear this.
will apply to all American
serviceman in here.
In the meantime,
hear this.
Nobody handed you a discharge
when you got captured.
In the meantime,
hear this.
We will keep the faith in God
and country and in one another.
In the meantime,
hear this.
We will honor military ranks
In the meantime,
hear this.
and obey the senior ranking
officer at all times.
In the meantime,
hear this.
For the time being,
until I hear different,
In the meantime,
hear this.
I am that SRO.
In the meantime,
hear this.
My orders are simple.
In the meantime,
hear this.
Firstly, save everything.
In the meantime,
hear this.
Collect every piece
of scrap you can find.
In the meantime,
hear this.
It'll all come in handy.
In the meantime,
hear this.
Secondly, stay in contact
at all times.
In the meantime,
hear this.
You must contact every arrival.
In the meantime,
hear this.
You must memorize every name.
In the meantime,
hear this.
And we will manipulate
the enemy,
In the meantime,
hear this.
but we will not
antagonize him needlessly.
In the meantime,
hear this.
You catch more flies with
honey than with vinegar.
In the meantime,
hear this.
No matter what they do to us,
we are Americans.
In the meantime,
hear this.
If we help
and support one another,
In the meantime,
hear this.
we will prevail.
No thanks,
I'm growing a beard.
Beat it!
Well, maybe just a trim.
No. You no good.
You tough guy.
You go away.
Well, maybe just a trim.
No. You no good.
MILES:
Hey, Einstein.
What are you doing?
Gassing up the gook H-bomb?
MILES:
Hey, Einstein.
Great disguise.
MILES:
Hey, Einstein.
No, really,
you had me fooled.
MILES:
Hey, Einstein.
I like it.
MILES:
Hey, Einstein.
[¶¶¶]
You got here just in time,
sir.
We needed an SRO.
You got here just in time,
sir.
Carry on, commander.
[SPEAKS IN VIETNAMESE]
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
Kennedy, cell eight,
a-okay, sir.
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
Williamson, cell six,
first-class shape, sir.
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
Me and Oldham in cell seven
are okay, sir.
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
We're fantastic over here.
Never better.
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
Ashby in cell five.
Coming along fine, sir.
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
Ashby?
How's the arm, son?
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
Can you use it?
KENNEDY: All clear.
Report out.
[GROANS]
It's getting there, sir.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
two things to remember.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Firstly,
you must resist any attempt
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
to make you act contrite.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Repeat,
do not act contrite.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Secondly, Williamson?
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
You keep working on that
transom with that nail
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
you found, you hear?
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
All right, carry on, gentlemen.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Okay, Ashby?
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
This time
I want a straight answer.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Understand?
Yes, sir.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
All right.
Now explain.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
If Rod Steiger
was on the czarist side,
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
why would he want
to help Omar Sharif?
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Because he really wants
Julie Christie.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
WILLIAMSON:
She was in love with
Tom Courtenay, right?
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Uh, no, sir.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Courtenay was on the train,
was all.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
I think it was meant
to be Trotsky.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Forget that.
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Colonel Cathcart,
what did you mean
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
that Johnson's ordered
a bombing pause?
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
Did the V respond?
Will they talk?
CATHCART:
Before we get down to business,
In Korea
they talked for three years
before the POWs came home.
Three years.
In Korea
they talked for three years
Hubman, you're a delight.
In Korea
they talked for three years
Living with a happy, upbeat guy
like you is a real delight.
In Korea
they talked for three years
You know something,
if this was World War II,
In Korea
they talked for three years
I'd escape.
In Korea
they talked for three years
I get away from you
and the gooks.
In Korea
they talked for three years
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
CATHCART:
Ashby, we don't have to tell
you that this is not Korea.
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
We're not gonna be here
forever.
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
Bombing pause or not, our
people, they know we're here.
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
They'll never let us down.
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
I know, sir. It's, uh, just
a little lonely, is all, sir.
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
I'm not used to being
alone like this.
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
Big family,
college fraternity,
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
the Air Force, I--
ASHBY:
Colonel, could it really
be that long?
I hate being alone.
You can always pray, son.
Then you're never alone.
Find yourself a mirror.
Just a mirror.
MILES:
¶ Oh, his name
Is Colonel Cathcart ¶
Just a mirror.
¶ He's the leader
of the group ¶
Just a mirror.
¶ So gather around,
All you Yanks ¶
Just a mirror.
¶ He'll give you
All the poop ¶
Just a mirror.
¶ He took no shit he gave them
But the guard on was pissed ¶
Just a mirror.
¶ They clamped him
In a stinking hole ¶
Just a mirror.
¶ They thought
He'd not be missed ¶
Just a mirror.
[SHOUTS IN VIETNAMESE]
Hey, hey! What are you doing,
taking your sister to lunch?
Just a mirror.
Trying to sing here. Jesus.
Everybody's a critic
around here.
Just a mirror.
"Colonel Cameron Cathcart.
United States Air Force."
Just a mirror.
Huh,
twice decorated Korean ace.
Just a mirror.
"Twenty kills."
Twenty kills.
You like flying, eh?
You like the war?
Twenty kills.
Perhaps I should read
a little bit more.
I've seen it.
There's no relevance here.
Perhaps I should read
a little bit more.
But this is a highly
respected publication.
Innocent enough, I suppose.
But this is a highly
respected publication.
But here in Hoa Lo prison,
it is your indictment.
But this is a highly
respected publication.
I have no need
to keep you alive.
But this is a highly
respected publication.
You have not been confirmed
as a prisoner.
But this is a highly
respected publication.
Heh, only last Sunday,
But this is a highly
respected publication.
The New York Times
listed you as an MIA.
But this is a highly
respected publication.
The other men know I'm here.
But this is a highly
respected publication.
Who knows what they
will remember in 10 or 15 years?
We had Frenchman here
for longer than that.
Who knows what they
will remember in 10 or 15 years?
So, American Colonel,
I am fully aware that
you are attempting to maintain
American ranks
and military discipline here.
I am fully aware that
you are attempting to maintain
You will stop immediately.
I am fully aware that
you are attempting to maintain
Cathcart,
things might get much worse.
The ranks do exist.
Cathcart,
things might get much worse.
Heh.
We are American servicemen.
Cathcart,
things might get much worse.
I am an American colonel.
Cathcart,
things might get much worse.
[GRUNTS]
Cathcart,
things might get much worse.
[SIGHS]
"There are those
in my government
"who dislike educated men..."
Oh, such as myself,
"There are those
in my government
who were schooled
by the Jesuits.
"There are those
in my government
They consider me, uh,
ideologically unsound,
"There are those
in my government
too prone to compassion
for people like you.
"There are those
in my government
They must see
that I have helped you
to cooperate, to put your
white man's arrogance aside.
They must see
that I have helped you
Stop the silly Army games.
I will consider it
an act of contrition.
The ranks do exist.
We are American servicemen.
I am an American colonel.
The ranks do exist.
We are American servicemen.
No, Cathcart.
American criminals.
The ranks do exist.
We are American servicemen.
Yes, criminals.
The ranks do exist.
We are American servicemen.
You wish
to maintain discipline here?
You wish to challenge me?
You wish
to maintain discipline here?
Good. Acceptable.
I will pick, at random,
one of your men,
and I will exert on him
the same physical pain
I will pick, at random,
one of your men,
you and your country inflict
on my people with your war.
I will pick, at random,
one of your men,
Yes, Cathcart.
You will only have yourself
to blame
for his pain
and his anguish.
You will only have yourself
to blame
I want you
to think about that.
[¶¶¶]
I want you
to think about that.
[GRUNTS]
[SIGHS]
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
Jeez, what I wouldn't give
for that suit though, heh.
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
Welcome to the pigsty.
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
Pigsty population doubles.
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
Young kid,
Air Force flight suit,
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
lieutenant bars.
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
Welcome, Lieutenant X.
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
Good luck.
You're gonna need it.
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
You might as well be dead
as here.
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
[MICE SQUEAKING]
What the hell
kind of haircut was that?
[SCREAMS]
Get away! Jesus! Aah!
Get out!
Oh, thank God, thank God.
Get away! Jesus! Aah!
And you too, heh. Hey, you too.
Okay, okay, guys.
Get away! Jesus! Aah!
All right.
Oh, Jesus Christ, oh.
Get away! Jesus! Aah!
No noise!
[GREGORY SCREAMING]
Get away! Jesus! Aah!
No! Stop!
GUARD:
No noise!
Get away! Jesus! Aah!
[GREGORY SCREAMING]
GREGORY:
Jesus! Bastard!
Gregory,
lieutenant, USAF, sir.
Who right now wishes
he'd gone to law school.
God bless you, son.
God bless you.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
I am told
you still insist
that you have some, uh,
special status here.
I am told
you still insist
[GREGORY SCREAMS
IN DISTANCE]
I am told
you still insist
So speak.
Speak for him.
[GREGORY SCREAMS]
GREGORY:
No!
Speak for him.
Will you not speak
to save him?
Speak for him.
It is time for you
to experience another part
of our prison system,
It is time for you
but not until you, yourself,
have visited Room 18,
It is time for you
and then
you will disappear.
It is time for you
Maybe three
or four years.
It is time for you
[DOC SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
MILES:
Soldier on, colonel!
[DOC SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Soldier on!
You too, flyer. You too!
[DOC SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Williamson's the new SRO.
Me? Oh, shit.
CATHCART: Good luck.
Williamson's the new SRO.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[KEYS JINGLE]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Hey, it's gonna be all right.
Hey, it's gonna be fine.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
It's gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine, all right?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Stay awake on me.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
[WHEEZES]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
You stay awake,
you stay alive.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
There's no way I'm gonna let you
die, all right? You got that?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
There's no way I'm gonna
let you die. Stay awake!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
[THUDDING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
All right.
SRO Williamson wants to know
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
what you did that
antagonized them the most.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Nothing, ahem.
Negative. Nothing.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Come on,
you stay awake on me.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
He wants to know
what you said.
After Room 18? Heh.
He wants to know
what you said.
Whatever they wanted.
He wants to know
what you said.
Why...
What's your name, soldier?
What's your name, flyer?
Gregory, first lieutenant.
Air Force.
What's your name, soldier?
What's your name, flyer?
[GROANING]
What's your name, soldier?
What's your name, flyer?
I know, I know.
Now listen to me.
What's your name, soldier?
What's your name, flyer?
Listen to me.
Now this is an SRO order.
What's your name, soldier?
What's your name, flyer?
And you can never
let them think
that you can be beaten
into anything.
And you can never
let them think
You lie to them,
mislead them, anything,
And you can never
let them think
but you never let them
break you, you got that?
And you can never
let them think
None of you guys broke?
And you can never
let them think
Why don't you get some sleep?
No, I've gotta know.
You didn't break? None of the
rest of those guys broke?
Why don't you get some sleep?
No, I've gotta know.
No.
No?
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
[SOBBING]
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so very sorry.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
I couldn't... I didn't.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
I'm a short-termer.
I'm not like you guys.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
But I love, heh, home.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
I want to go home.
I know. I know.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
Please! You've got--
Shh!
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
[MUFFLED SHOUTING]
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
Shut up!
Just be shut up, Gregory.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
[GUARDS SPEAKING IN VIETNAMESE]
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
Hey!
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
Can't you see this man?
He's hurt.
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
[SCREAMING]
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
You'll be all right, man.
You'll be okay.
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
You're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be okay, Gregory!
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
You're gonna be okay!
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
[KEYS JINGLE]
He's hurt. He's hurt bad,
he's hurt bad. He's hurt.
[COUGHING]
They must've been looking
for a fight.
[COUGHING]
It stinks, he stinks.
They've just never
been brutal like that.
[COUGHING]
Who cares about that?
The man broke.
[COUGHING]
He told the V
what they wanted.
[COUGHING]
GUARD:
Fischer? Fischer?
You. Go.
GUARD:
Fischer? Fischer?
[¶¶¶]
GUARD:
Fischer? Fischer?
[GROANS]
I'm... I'm Cathcart.
Cathcart, Colonel Cathcart,
Air Force.
I'm... I'm Cathcart.
What happened?
CATHCART: They broke me.
I'm... I'm Cathcart.
[CATHCART SOBBING]
CATHCART:
The others, the boys,
I'm... I'm Cathcart.
they won't be able
to help it either.
I'm... I'm Cathcart.
Tell them.
Take care of them, huh?
I'm... I'm Cathcart.
Fischer.
Your turn will come.
I'm... I'm Cathcart.
[KEYS JINGLE]
[GONG BANGING]
KENNEDY:
All clear.
WILLIAMSON:
Hey, new boy, cell three.
Work the transom.
I loosened that one myself.
WILLIAMSON:
Hey, new boy, cell three.
Work the transom.
Work the motor chips
in the corner, it'll slip out.
WILLIAMSON:
Hey, new boy, cell three.
Work the transom.
Ugh.
KENNEDY:
Hi. Welcome to the Hanoi Hilton.
Pretty nice, huh?
The food here's pretty lousy
KENNEDY:
Hi. Welcome to the Hanoi Hilton.
Pretty nice, huh?
but it's all room service,
so it's, uh...
KENNEDY:
Hi. Welcome to the Hanoi Hilton.
Pretty nice, huh?
I suggest
the continental cuisine.
KENNEDY:
Hi. Welcome to the Hanoi Hilton.
Pretty nice, huh?
This visual intercom
is courtesy of the SRO.
KENNEDY:
Hi. Welcome to the Hanoi Hilton.
Pretty nice, huh?
The rest of us chippers.
It's our version of escape.
KENNEDY:
Hi. Welcome to the Hanoi Hilton.
Pretty nice, huh?
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
but Oliviera, here,
who just joined us,
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
has said I got boosted a rank
the day the V got me.
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
Yeah, it's true, man.
Really?
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
WILLIAMSON:
That means
I'm senior ranking officer,
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
unless you outrank me.
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
What about Colonel Cathcart?
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
You saw him?
You saw the colonel?
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
Where?
I'm Williamson,
I was a lieutenant commander,
Are there no guards here?
It's siesta.
Three whacks, the gong,
pause, then one.
Are there no guards here?
They live by the gong here,
it tells you what to do
Are there no guards here?
and when to do it.
These two empty?
The one on my left
has a youngster who talked
These two empty?
and he's been in solitary
ever since.
These two empty?
Now how about you?
Who are you?
These two empty?
All right.
Name's Fischer,
major, 82nd Airborne.
These two empty?
Now attached to the Pentagon.
How did you get here?
These two empty?
I was here
for one helicopter trip.
It malfunctioned.
I was here
for one helicopter trip.
We crash landed
north of the DMZ.
I was here
for one helicopter trip.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
I was here
for one helicopter trip.
Shh! Tell us
about Cathcart.
As far as Cathcart's concerned,
let me say that I saw him.
Shh! Tell us
about Cathcart.
What was left of him.
What do you mean?
What's left?
What was left of him.
How was he,
how were his arms?
What was left of him.
Swollen. Very swollen.
Blue with rope burns.
What was left of him.
Gregory!
ALL:
What was left of him.
Look, major, I've been
in here almost 2 years.
The punishment
has been brutal
Look, major, I've been
in here almost 2 years.
but it's never been
life-threatening.
Look, major, I've been
in here almost 2 years.
Until Gregory?
He must've brought it
on himself.
Until Gregory?
He must have.
He's just a kid.
Until Gregory?
It doesn't--
Doesn't what?
Until Gregory?
Make sense.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
The peace loving people
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
of Vietnam wish to forgive
all American criminals.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
The people of Vietnam want you
to know the truth.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
Have you been wondered
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
why there are so little number
of new American criminals?
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
Did you think
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
it is because your cohorts
are winning the war? Heh.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
How you are wrong.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
Your own president
has ordered slow down,
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
no more do your bombers
strike at us.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
You are being deserted by your
own confederates in crime.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
Things will get worse,
fellows.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
Because as we suffer your war,
so will you.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
They won't
slow down the bombing!
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
This is the voice of the
Democratic Republic of Vietnam.
Christ.
We'll be here forever.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
Yes we will. We stick together.
We follow orders. We'll make it.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
Who cares
what happens in here?
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
Why should I take
orders from somebody
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
because he used to have
ranking?
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
He still does outrank you.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
[GONG BANGING]
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
GREGORY [OVER PA]:
I'm Lieutenant Donald
Allen Gregory, U.S. Air Force.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
I wish to admit my crimes
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
against the peace-loving
peoples of Vietnam.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
I have, many times,
flown my aircraft
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
at the Vietnamese people,
even enjoying the death...
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
[CRYING]
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
GREGORY:
I have used cluster bombs.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
I have used napalm.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
I am ashamed of myself
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
and of America
and of Americans.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
[TAPPING MORSE CODE ON WALL]
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
I plead forgiveness.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
I beg President Ho
to forgive my crimes.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
SRO order.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
If taken,
resist as long as poss.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
[TAPPING CONTINUES]
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
Then do the best you can.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
CATHCART [OVER PA]:
I am Cameron Cathcart.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
We are all together.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
God bless us all.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
I was a colonel
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
in the criminal
Armed Forces...
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
Yeah, I hope he does.
I hope he does.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
You can bet
Lyndon Johnson won't.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
Shut your
son of a bitch mouth.
We'll never get out of here.
Never!
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
I personally ordered
the execution...
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
Lord.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
...hundreds of innocent
Vietnamese women...
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
This is a psalm, I think.
I don't know which one.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
I shall lift up mine eyes
unto the hills
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
from whence
cometh my strength.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
My strength
cometh from the Lord
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
who made the heavens
and the earth.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
I thank Senator Fulbright for
demanding the bombing pause.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
I don't know the rest.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
I pray
for the victory of Vietnam.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
I am glad to again,
to be a civilian.
CATHCART:
As a senior officer
Kiss my rosy red
American ass!
Goddamn it!
...of the compassionate
Vietnamese captors.
Goddamn it!
And now, good night,
with the reminder that
despite your crimes,
Goddamn it!
Ho Chi Minh,
the president, loves you.
Goddamn it!
[SIGHS]
Now, there's one guy
that doesn't outrank me anymore.
Goddamn it!
Ah, I am also
very tired, Williamson.
Goddamn it!
It is late.
I can't do it.
Goddamn it!
I ask so very little.
I'll only lie. What good
is a biography full of lies?
Goddamn it!
Williamson,
you are an intelligent man.
Goddamn it!
You're a family man,
like myself.
Goddamn it!
Why will you not do
what I ask?
[¶¶¶]
Why will you not do
what I ask?
WILLIAMSON [ON RECORDING ON PA]:
My name is
Patrick Michael Williamson.
WILLIAMSON [ON RECORDING ON PA]:
My name is
I'm from Philadelphia.
WILLIAMSON [ON RECORDING ON PA]:
My name is
I was a professional athlete,
a university professor
WILLIAMSON [ON RECORDING ON PA]:
My name is
and part-time
bank president.
WILLIAMSON [ON RECORDING ON PA]:
My name is
[GUARDS SPEAKING IN VIETNAMESE]
WILLIAMSON [ON RECORDING ON PA]:
My name is
My brother was a professional
football player...
[DOOR LOCKS]
My brother was a professional
football player...
...who was killed in a game.
My brother was a professional
football player...
[SIGHS]
My brother was a professional
football player...
My sister was a concubine
for a United States senator.
My brother was a professional
football player...
[SOBS]
My brother was a professional
football player...
I understand...
Is that me?
My brother was a professional
football player...
Ah, no, it's me.
My brother was a professional
football player...
[¶¶¶]
My brother was a professional
football player...
The V blanket,
can't even
hang yourself with them.
The V blanket,
Hurts. Worse is
when they untie them.
I know how to help.
You know, I thought
we'd never lose a battle.
I know how to help.
Any battle.
And I'm so ashamed.
[CRYING]
But that means that
we've gotta stick together,
you and me,
and everyone who broke,
But that means that
we've gotta stick together,
we've gotta hang in.
We've gotta survive.
But that means that
we've gotta stick together,
Because we've got to
see home.
But that means that
we've gotta stick together,
We've got to see home. Damn.
But that means that
we've gotta stick together,
Tsk. Ahh.
But that means that
we've gotta stick together,
[BOTH CRYING]
Hubman.
The Vietnamese people is
in whose hands lie your fate,
have no wish
to keep you here.
The Vietnamese people is
in whose hands lie your fate,
Glad to hear that.
Delighted to hear that.
The Vietnamese people is
in whose hands lie your fate,
However, our intelligence
is not without limits.
The Vietnamese people is
in whose hands lie your fate,
There must be an entente.
The Vietnamese people is
in whose hands lie your fate,
You mean, uh,
like a bargain?
The Vietnamese people is
in whose hands lie your fate,
Precisely.
The Vietnamese people is
in whose hands lie your fate,
I'm sorry but,
uh, I can't do that.
Now, I have no wish
to antagonize you.
I'm sorry but,
uh, I can't do that.
But I can't.
I'm sorry but,
uh, I can't do that.
Hubman, you have no idea
I'm sorry but,
uh, I can't do that.
what we want
to ask of you yet.
I'm sorry but,
uh, I can't do that.
Now, Major Ngiap is a pilot.
I'm sorry but,
uh, I can't do that.
He understands
your language. Come.
I'm sorry but,
uh, I can't do that.
Sit, Hubman.
Now, we know you were
in an A-6 aircraft.
And we know
this aircraft has two men.
Pilot in front
and there is a backseat man.
And we know
this aircraft has two men.
And we have deduced that the
backseat man controls the radar.
And we know
this aircraft has two men.
Now, Hubman,
all we need to know is,
And we know
this aircraft has two men.
how does the radar
pick targets?
And we know
this aircraft has two men.
You know, I can't answer,
I'm sorry.
DOC:
You must never
gesture like that!
You know, I can't answer,
I'm sorry.
It is impolite to show
the palms of your hands!
You know, I can't answer,
I'm sorry.
Now, remember that!
You know, I can't answer,
I'm sorry.
Such arrogance does not speak
well of your sorrow.
You know, I can't answer,
I'm sorry.
Now, about the radar?
Oh, the, uh, A-6 radar
well, uh, you know, that's, uh,
exactly the same as the B-17.
Oh, the, uh, A-6 radar
You know, uh, the old bomber
from World War II,
Oh, the, uh, A-6 radar
the flying fortress,
they call it?
Oh, the, uh, A-6 radar
It's exactly the same.
Does he know that system?
Oh, the, uh, A-6 radar
[BOTH SPEAKING IN VIETNAMESE]
Major Ngiap,
uh, he say your statement
confirms the assessment
of our intelligence.
Major Ngiap,
uh, he say your statement
Heh, a smart bunch of guys.
[SPEAKING IN VIETNAMESE]
Hubman, this is
a small beginning.
You are closer to your home
now than ever before.
[GUARD SHOUTING IN VIETNAMESE]
[TRUCK APPROACHING]
[GUARDS CHATTERING]
How you been, Bob?
Hanging tough.
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
You're the first American
I've touched in 19 months.
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
It's so lonely,
I've gotta get out of here.
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
I gotta. I don't care
if it's in a fucking box.
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
Bullshit.
You've got to survive.
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
We didn't spend two years
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
getting every captive name
to you for nothing.
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
You're the recording secretary
of this operation.
I've been praying
for a bonus like this.
My old man, you know,
he was always preaching
that hang tough sermon.
My old man, you know,
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
Whole regiment.
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
He said when the Germans
had the British pinned down
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
on the beaches of Dunkirk,
it was a madhouse.
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
So when
the Grenadier Guards arrived,
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
they lined up in parade order,
band and everything.
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
[MARCHING MUSIC
PLAYING INTERNALLY]
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
German planes were
strafing the beach.
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
The truth of color.
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
Diving planes killing men.
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
[EXPLOSION INTERNALLY]
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
Men dying at attention.
His heroes
were the Grenadier Guards.
The only order they heard
was close ranks.
[¶¶¶]
The only order they heard
was close ranks.
Close ranks.
The only order they heard
was close ranks.
They swallowed their fear
and like the whole British army
lived to fight another day.
He's a tough son of a bitch,
my old man.
We're always with you, Bob.
Every man here.
He's a tough son of a bitch,
my old man.
We say your name.
God bless you.
GBU.
We say your name.
[GUARDS CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
They greet everyone
like this?
No. Where you from?
New Jersey.
They greet everyone
like this?
Oh, yeah, the gooks don't see
many people from New Jersey.
They greet everyone
like this?
Baptist?
Yeah.
They greet everyone
like this?
Yeah.
A Baptist from New Jersey,
They greet everyone
like this?
that's, uh, quite an oddity
around here.
They greet everyone
like this?
Got any advice?
They greet everyone
like this?
You hang tough
as long as you can.
They greet everyone
like this?
Every time they don't beat you,
they lose.
They greet everyone
like this?
Every time they don't break us,
we win.
They greet everyone
like this?
When they torture you,
They greet everyone
like this?
try to concentrate on the places
that don't hurt.
They greet everyone
like this?
Torture?
They greet everyone
like this?
[GROWLS]
This better look good
on my record.
[GROWLS]
This better look good
on my record.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hi, you pilots.
It's late summer.
This better look good
on my record.
And in Iowa, the corn
is as high as elephant's eye.
This better look good
on my record.
In Vermont,
the trees are red and gold.
This better look good
on my record.
And you all may be here
for another 10 years.
This better look good
on my record.
But Lyndon Johnson promises
to pull out American troops
This better look good
on my record.
if President Ho will surrender
the south to fascists.
This better look good
on my record.
Hey, criminals,
you don't want to die here.
This better look good
on my record.
Our relationship
is now entering a new phase.
This better look good
on my record.
You will be given
the opportunity to atone,
This better look good
on my record.
to make restitution,
This better look good
on my record.
to show the world the
righteousness of our cause.
This better look good
on my record.
Yes, yes. If you refuse,
it will be on your head.
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
They're guys
that would bomb you
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
back to the Stone Age
if they got the chance.
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
DOC:
The real war
is not in the Delta.
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
It is in the United Nations.
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
The Champs Elysees,
at the Berkeley, California,
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
on the Washington Mall,
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
the cities of America,
KENNEDY:
You push us too far
and they'll bomb you.
and what we will not win
on the battlefield,
your journalists will win for
us on your very own doorstep.
and what we will not win
on the battlefield,
And you will help
by cooperating with them
and other friendly Americans
And you will help
by cooperating with them
and you will do this
on film.
And you will help
by cooperating with them
Wendell Burke, program 21.
And you will help
by cooperating with them
Vietnam resists,
American bomber pilot, take one.
And you will help
by cooperating with them
And who have we here?
What is this?
BURKE:
It's a television interview
for syndication.
And who have we here?
Will they see this at home?
Possibly. Why?
And who have we here?
Is it that important to you?
It's important, yeah.
BURKE: Why?
And who have we here?
It's very important.
We gotta get the names home.
And who have we here?
People at home
remember us, right?
And who have we here?
Yeah, but not with any pride.
KENNEDY:
You've gotta tell them,
you see.
And who have we here?
There's lots of us here they
don't know about, you see?
And who have we here?
They're hiding us. There's
more here than you know about.
According to the Vietnamese,
They're hiding us. There's
more here than you know about.
it's, heh,
certainly true to say
They're hiding us. There's
more here than you know about.
that the number of American
prisoners increases daily.
They're hiding us. There's
more here than you know about.
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
has convened a war tribunal?
A war crimes tribunal?
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
You and your cohorts
will be the defendants.
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
No. You've gotta tell them,
you see.
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
You gotta tell the people
at home, you see?
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
They can kill an MIA but they
can't kill a confirmed POW--
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
BURKE: Such is the guilt--
Tell them!
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
Just one American,
just one very lonely man,
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
being educated by the humane
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
and lenient treatment
of his captors.
Are you aware that,
uh, Lord Bertrand Russell
Cut.
It'll edit but don't
bring me anymore like this.
Cut.
What's wrong with you,
Major Doc?
Cut.
Have you no control
over these men?
Cut.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
that you're only
here killing people
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
because gooks are yellow.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
Well, us gooks are people too.
Humane and lenient people
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
and the world
is going to see to that.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
We have a surprise for you,
black pirates.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
What are they gonna do?
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
Hey, I can't take much more
of this. Let's go home.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
She's right.
Let them kill each other.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
As long as I'm free,
fuck them!
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
Listen to me!
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
The minute
you play their game,
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
they have control
and you're nothing.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
You're not one of us,
you're not one of them.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
And all you have is us.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
One goes, we all go.
No early release.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
Get out of here!
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
I wanna be alone!
Let me out of here.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
[BANGING ON DOOR]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
I want out right now!
Right now! Right now!
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
[GROANING]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, pilots,
don't you get sleepy.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
There is big happening tonight
for each and every criminal.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
We will keep you up all night.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
This happen often?
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, guess what, boys.
Senator Fulbright told press
Sir? You okay?
Yeah, heh,
just thinking.
Sir? You okay?
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
Well, heh,
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
quite a bit older,
point of fact.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
And you know
I've got three daughters.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
And the middle one,
Lily, she's, uh, 18 now.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
And she's really beautiful.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
Oh, yeah?
She's a bit wild, I suppose,
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
she's fond of loud music
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
but she's not exactly
out of range for you
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
by the time
you get out of here.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
Look her up, will you?
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
Well, I'm sure you'll be the one
that introduces us, sir.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
No. I doubt it.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
You've only been here a few
weeks but listen to Hannah.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
Something's up,
I don't know what...
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
[GUARDS CHATTERING OUTSIDE]
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
Kennedy, I don't think I can
take much more of this.
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
[DOOR OPENING]
Lieutenant,
I'm older than you are.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Criminals,
this is a proclamation
of the People's Tribunal.
Criminals,
this is a proclamation
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"throughout North Vietnam,
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"we, the government of the
People's Republic of Vietnam
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"have been your protectors
and we have ensured your safety
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"but you have refused
to cooperate with visitors
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"and journalists and you
have shown no contrition.
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"So tonight,
we shall show the world
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"how our people truly feel.
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"Even now, the other blackest
of criminals
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"are being assembled
here in the center of Hanoi.
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"Tonight, criminals,
you will be reunited
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"so that you might confront
your innocent victims.
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
"And all of this will occur
before representatives
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
of the other friendly
peace-loving nations."
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
[ALL CHATTERING]
"Here in Hoa Lo Prison
and in our other facilities
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
[ALL SHOUTING
IN VIETNAMESE]
Keep your heads up!
We're Americans!
[CROWD CHANTING IN VIETNAMESE]
Keep your heads up!
We're Americans!
Watch it!
Ugh! God damn it!
Break away!
Come on. Lean on me.
Get up, buddy.
[ALL CLAMORING]
Thanks for helping
me out back there.
I thought it was
you helping me.
Thanks for helping
me out back there.
[CHUCKLES]
Thanks for helping
me out back there.
We're gonna let
the gooks have it.
Thanks for helping
me out back there.
ALL:
Yeah!
Thanks for helping
me out back there.
[ALL SHOUTING]
Thanks for helping
me out back there.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
DOC:
I fear our only common
language is English,
perhaps a small saving grace
of colonialism.
DOC:
I fear our only common
language is English,
To the peace-loving people
of the world
DOC:
I fear our only common
language is English,
and to their eternal
struggle for freedom.
DOC:
I fear our only common
language is English,
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
In fact, I would say
this realignment
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
will change the progress
of the war for you.
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
Perhaps. But we have been
known for our patience.
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
There were the Japanese,
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
the French,
now the Americans.
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
We are
not without experience.
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
Of course not.
I cannot tell you how
thrilled I am to be here.
Heh-heh.
Of course not.
[CHRISTMAS MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Heh-heh.
Of course not.
SRO on deck.
Heh-heh.
Of course not.
As you were,
gentlemen.
Dong chi. Comrades.
Finally we have news
in which we all can rejoice.
Dong chi. Comrades.
Yes.
Rumors that release would be
preceded by a change in diet
Dong chi. Comrades.
are indeed true.
[ALL CHATTERING AND CHUCKLING]
Dong chi. Comrades.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
World opinion guarantees
our victory
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
and the press predicts it.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
Yes, comrades.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
Since the valuable footage
of the parade,
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
you are of no longer use to us.
At least, not as a group.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
Then we must meet,
you and I.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
To discuss the method
of our release.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
There can be
no special cases.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
We are all one here.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
So if one goes,
we all must go.
Are you saying the war
is over, major?
DOC:
It behooves you to cooperate.
Particularly if you wish
for letters from home.
Major Fischer will offer a
homily with a scriptural basis.
When I was young...
[CHUCKLES]
...at religious school,
I remember a great deal was
made of Abraham and Isaac.
...at religious school,
How God ordered Abraham
to sacrifice Isaac,
...at religious school,
his only son,
his beloved child.
...at religious school,
Abraham stood
with a knife in his hand
and wrestled within himself
to decide whether to believe,
Abraham stood
with a knife in his hand
to trust God.
Abraham stood
with a knife in his hand
Or to deny him.
And I suppose that most
of us identified with Abraham.
Or to deny him.
Wondering how we would use
free choice if that was us.
Or to deny him.
Well, since I've been in here,
I've had time
to think about Isaac.
Well, since I've been in here,
Helpless.
Tied up on an altar
and audience to what
might become his own death.
Tied up on an altar
And he couldn't trust in God.
He had to trust in Abraham
and hope that God
Tied up on an altar
would act through him.
Well,
in the end, it all worked out
for Isaac and Abraham.
Just as it will for us.
in the end, it all worked out
for Isaac and Abraham.
ALL:
Amen.
in the end, it all worked out
for Isaac and Abraham.
Captain Turner?
Well, all my life...
I've tried to seek light
in the midst of darkness.
And I've learned that
the greater the darkness,
the greater the possibility
for light.
And I've learned that
the greater the darkness,
I know that all people
are not kind and just.
And I've learned that
the greater the darkness,
But I am reminded by you all,
every day,
that the voice of God speaks
through the conscious
and decent people.
that the voice of God speaks
through the conscious
CATHCART:
Closing prayer from
Commander Williamson.
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
from the words
of a 14-year-old boy
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
who wrote them
on a wall in Auschwitz.
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
"How can I believe in God
when I see what is around me?
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
"I believe in God in the same
way I believe in the sun.
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
"Even when it doesn't shine
and in love,
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
even when I don't feel it."
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
Dear Lord, we offer
you praise and thanks.
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
We are grateful
to be together,
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
we are thankful that
we are sound of mind,
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
we ask you to bestow blessings
upon our loved ones,
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
upon our countrymen,
upon America,
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
upon our families...
Dear Lord,
we can all grow strength
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
with your home.
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
As you can see,
the envelopes are empty.
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
When you cooperate, the letters
will be given to you.
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
That is the subject
of my sermon.
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
It concerns early release.
We have no more patience.
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
Those of you who are willing
to cooperate,
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
there will be freedom
and a trip home.
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
[¶¶¶]
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
Disassociate yourself from
the blackest of criminals.
There is one more formality
before you may make contact
Merry Christmas, sir.
G.B. you all.
PRISONERS:
Merry Christmas, sir.
G.B. you all.
Merry Christmas.
God go with you, Bob.
Merry Christmas, Pat.
Merry Christmas.
God don't know you're alive,
Williamson.
Merry Christmas.
He don't fucking
care about you.
Merry Christmas.
[MAN CLEARS THROAT]
Who wants a make
on the Cuban?
No go. Too dark.
Steady, man. We're gonna
get out of here,
No go. Too dark.
without kissing the V's ass.
Hang tough, just like you
showed me, remember? Hang tough.
No go. Too dark.
I think
I used up all my tough.
No go. Too dark.
[GROANS]
[CHUCKLES]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
I told you, he's nobody,
he's nothing.
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
He's Cat playing games,
trying to break us.
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
Someone to act tough
so Cat can go back
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
and try pumping sunshine
up our asses.
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
Pump what up where?
Where'd you get that, Miles?
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
No, he got it from me.
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
I got it from a guy who played
hockey with in college.
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
Ugh, I knew it. I knew it, man.
I knew you was part barbarian.
Cuban. Who the hell
is the Cuban?
Hockey? Barbaric?
Never. Hockey
is pure heart and grace.
Hockey? Barbaric?
A great hockey player
has courage and strength
Hockey? Barbaric?
and endurance,
just like a boxer.
Hockey? Barbaric?
That he moves
at 50 miles an hour,
Hockey? Barbaric?
like a ballet dancer.
Ballet dancer?
Hockey? Barbaric?
TURNER:
Sounds very honky
to me, Williamson.
Hockey? Barbaric?
That's because you've
never seen a game, Turner.
Hockey? Barbaric?
I'll take you to one.
And we'll go to New York,
Hockey? Barbaric?
see the Rangers.
I used to see the Rangers
play all the time.
Hockey? Barbaric?
Before my old man died.
He'd take me whenever
Boston came to town.
Hockey? Barbaric?
We'd grab something to eat near
his office at 57th, you know?
[CROWD CHEERING INTERNALLY]
We'd grab something to eat near
his office at 57th, you know?
And grab a cab.
We'd grab something to eat near
his office at 57th, you know?
Heh, he'd always make us wait
for a checkered cab.
We'd grab something to eat near
his office at 57th, you know?
Never liked the little ones.
We'd grab something to eat near
his office at 57th, you know?
I have a friend who has
great seats for the Rangers.
So we'll go, okay?
I have a friend who has
great seats for the Rangers.
Heh, sounds great.
I'll check my diary.
I have a friend who has
great seats for the Rangers.
So who do you think
the Cuban is?
I have a friend who has
great seats for the Rangers.
Desi Arnaz?
[DOOR OPENS]
I have a friend who has
great seats for the Rangers.
All right, gentlemen,
must be my attorney.
It's Murphy,
oh, my God, it's Murphy.
We were friend,
we were together on the Hancock.
You're here too?
No, I'm a veteran, man.
Oliviera. Lieutenant, Navy.
You're here too?
How the hell did you get here?
Swim?
You're here too?
Ahem, uh, no, sir.
I went up on deck
to watch them shell Haiphong.
You're here too?
I fell off the ship.
I got picked up by V fishermen.
You're here too?
[LAUGH THEN COUGHS]
Look, this joint's no fun.
You gotta get yourself a story,
you stick with it. You got it?
Look, this joint's no fun.
Don't let them fool you.
Stick with a story.
Look, this joint's no fun.
We're saying no
to early release.
Look, this joint's no fun.
They'd only do it
for propaganda.
Look, this joint's no fun.
A lot of pressure lately,
trying to break up the group.
Look, this joint's no fun.
We figure that's because our
guys are whipping their butts.
Look, this joint's no fun.
Even the food's getting
better. Fresh fruit.
Look, this joint's no fun.
[CHUCKLES]
Might as well give it to you,
as let it rot on the docks.
Look, this joint's no fun.
We've pasted Haiphong.
No shipment in or out.
Look, this joint's no fun.
We gotta set this.
[GROANING]
Look, this joint's no fun.
But things are
getting better, Murph?
Look, this joint's no fun.
I hope so because the folks back
home have just about had it.
Look, this joint's no fun.
Don't look for any help
before the election.
Look, this joint's no fun.
Election, that's 11 months.
There's no problem, Ashby,
Look, this joint's no fun.
Murph brought us
our absentee ballots, right?
Look, this joint's no fun.
[CHUCKLES]
Tropical heat.
Too humid.
[HUMMING]
You know something?
Frank Sinatra
himself uses this.
You know something?
Great artist.
Wonderful artist.
You know something?
Hey, Latino,
I wouldn't lie to you.
Back home, they say
you guys are criminals.
Hey, Latino,
But you got an excuse.
You're downtrodden.
Hey, Latino,
You, you're
a Spanish-speaking nigger.
Hey, Latino,
You know what I'm saying?
So you take a nice,
early release.
Your black ass's gonna
to be back on the streets
So you take a nice,
early release.
of Harlem in a week.
So you take a nice,
early release.
Go screw yourself.
Heh, go screw myself?
So you take a nice,
early release.
Hey, man, I know your
neighborhood. I lived up there.
So you take a nice,
early release.
110th street.
Yeah. Yeah.
So you take a nice,
early release.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
So you take a nice,
early release.
Heh, so there ain't nothing you
can tell me about honkies.
So you take a nice,
early release.
So why is a blood like you
sticking with white scum?
What difference does
it make to you, man?
So why is a blood like you
sticking with white scum?
This ain't no Cuban war.
So why is a blood like you
sticking with white scum?
Hey, this here is my
internationalist duty.
So why is a blood like you
sticking with white scum?
You understand?
So why is a blood like you
sticking with white scum?
Wherever we can kick Yankee
ass, you'll find my people.
So why is a blood like you
sticking with white scum?
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
We're all at war
with you, baby,
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
and my internationalist duty
gives me the right
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
to go anywhere
to hassle your ass.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Then go try Chicago.
[GROANING AND BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
You stupid Puerto Rican
son of a bitch.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
I'm offering you freedom, man.
I'm already free, man.
And scum ain't always white.
Baby.
One way or the other,
I'm already free, man.
you're gonna do
as I tell you.
I'm already free, man.
Just think of me
as another white man.
I'm already free, man.
You look like you got
lots of experience
I'm already free, man.
looking up white man's ass.
I'm telling you,
you should have listened
I'm already free, man.
to the chink
and stop all this one go,
I'm already free, man.
we all go, bullshit.
You are gonna do like
I tell you, huh?
I'm already free, man.
You're gonna go home
like I tell you.
I'm already free, man.
You're gonna
separate yourself
I'm already free, man.
from those white men,
like I tell you.
I'm already free, man.
And you're gonna stop
pretending a spic
I'm already free, man.
is an American,
like I tell you.
I'm already free, man.
You're gonna show the whole
world that's a lie.
I'm already free, man.
[CHUCKLING]
Adios, Latino.
Adios.
[GUNSHOT]
Aah!
Adios, Latino.
I heard it.
Just like the jungle camps.
Adios, Latino.
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
Oh. So, uh,
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
what can I do to help?
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
Name's Rasmussen,
sir, from Iowa.
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
Am I happy to be here?
Yes, sir.
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
I joined the Navy
five months ago, sir.
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
I just fell off my ship.
I fell off my ship.
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
They told me I was stupid
but I can't be
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
because I'm here.
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
[CRYING]
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
No more seasick
for me, boy. No, sir.
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
By the way, sir,
where is here?
Hi. Sure would
like to meet you.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Oh.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
MEN [CHANTING ON PA]:
Hey, hey, L.B.J., how many kids
did you kill today?
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Hey, hey, L.B.J., how many
kids did you kill today?
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Hey, hey, L.B.J., how many kids
did you kill today?
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
You know, heh, I'd like--
I'd love to strangle
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
of those bastards in his own
long hair, you know?
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Hell no, you don't know!
Long-haired hippie bastards!
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
[GASPS]
You're doing exactly
what the gooks want, Gregory.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
It doesn't matter
what they yell,
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
no one is making
them demonstrate.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
You don't understand.
If I wasn't stuck in here,
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
I probably be
one of them.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
[GUARDS CHATTERING]
Hey, tough guy.
They tell me you're SRO.
So I say to myself,
I say, what is SRO?
Hey, tough guy.
And then man, like a beauty,
it hits me,
Hey, tough guy.
it means, sings right out.
[LAUGHING]
Hey, tough guy.
That's it.
Hey, you gotta learn, I'm
your senior ranking officer.
Hey, tough guy.
Am I hurting you?
No, but it's the thought
that counts, isn't it?
Hey, tough guy.
It most certainly is,
you smartass motherfucker.
Hey, tough guy.
I'm gonna break you.
It'll make those other
assholes wise up. Yeah.
Hey, tough guy.
You have a good day.
[GONG BANGING]
Soles. This truck behind me.
Come here.
Comes once every two weeks.
Soles. This truck behind me.
Come here.
We're getting out
of here, buddy.
Soles. This truck behind me.
Come here.
Hey, Soles.
[SHOUTS IN VIETNAMESE]
How you're doing?
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
Uh, my commanding officer
Clark Kent told me to help
How you're doing?
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
as much as possible, sir.
How you're doing?
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
And so did his girlfriend,
Lois Lane.
How you're doing?
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
How you're doing?
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
No laughing!
Yeah. No laughing.
You were mean to me.
No laughing!
Yeah. No laughing.
I was the best one
on my ship, I was.
No laughing!
Yeah. No laughing.
And we had a good ship.
The USS Lollipop.
No laughing!
Yeah. No laughing.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
No laughing!
Yeah. No laughing.
[GONG BANGING]
No laughing!
Yeah. No laughing.
Williams has been
in irons for four days.
It's going to
the bricks tonight.
Williams has been
in irons for four days.
Want to take an early release?
What else? Who's next?
Williams has been
in irons for four days.
I don't know but the Cuban's
looking for somebody.
Williams has been
in irons for four days.
[GONG BANGING]
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Now, in back, oh, no,
Ms. Bogart was the teacher,
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
and in the first row
there was Robert Adams
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
and there was,
um, Mary Flora.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
And next to her was,
uh, Frank Young.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
If we can just get someone,
Miles, to cause a commotion,
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
we can cover the missing
hole for three shifts of gongs
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
until you leave
for the latrine.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Then we're safe
till bed check.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
It's four hours.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Have you considered what--
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Have you considered what might
happen once you go out?
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERS]:
She got busted
in demonstration,
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
busted in head by fascist cop.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Oh, Mr. Fish, I would
think of early release...
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Hey, man, that's all
a line of bullshit.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
She just talks a good line
of bullshit.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
It's Hanoi Hannah,
don't listen to her.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Lily is okay.
You understand me?
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Lily is okay.
It's all right.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
She told me, she can take care
of herself, sir.
In the third row
is Billy Zucker.
Gregory wants your okay
for escape.
What do you say, SRO?
Temporary SRO.
That decision will be made
when Williamson is better.
What do you say, SRO?
Temporary SRO.
Send this out, we're gonna
beat these sons of bitches.
What do you say, SRO?
Temporary SRO.
Gregory and Soles will go over
wall if all else fails.
First, we try
to get Rasmussen early release.
Gregory and Soles will go over
wall if all else fails.
Must get complete
roster to him.
Memorize every name,
must get complete roster to him.
This guy's as crazy as Miles,
he's gonna get us all killed.
Memorize every name,
must get complete roster to him.
One go, all go.
He's talking about escape.
Cuban will go ape.
Hey, heh, that rhymes,
you hear that?
He's talking about escape.
Cuban will go ape.
Semper Fi. Semper Fi.
He's talking about escape.
Cuban will go ape.
Semper Fi.
And in the third
row there, there was...
Was Sally Snyder.
Sally Snyder sat...
You. You.
Was Sally Snyder.
Ah? Ah?
You wanna rap
with them, Miles?
Ah? Ah?
Fuck you, faggot.
Fuck me, faggot?
Ah? Ah?
Hey, a tough guy.
You want him, tough guy?
Ah? Ah?
He ain't no good to me.
Now the world's seen me and you,
we've gotta keep him alive.
Ah? Ah?
But just barely. Just barely.
Oh, very touching.
Ah? Ah?
Touching. You're a whole
different story. On your knees.
Ah? Ah?
On your knees.
You can't kill Murphy.
He's confirmed POW.
Ah? Ah?
You're not going to be able
to keep Williamson alive.
Ah? Ah?
I don't give a fuck
what you do to me.
Ah? Ah?
Oh you don't, huh?
Huh?
Ah? Ah?
You're doing me a favor.
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
Dying is too good,
too easy for you.
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
[GROANS]
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
Look after your buddy
here.
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
[GROANING]
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
You'll get him back
on his feet,
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
I can count on you.
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
Then it's back to pigsty,
where you belong, tough guy.
You're right, Miles.
You're right.
[GRUNTING]
We showed him, huh?
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, air pilots.
Do you know some of you guys
have been here long enough
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, air pilots.
to become citizens?
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, air pilots.
We're winning the war.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, air pilots.
Don't you miss a McDonald's
fries and a Coca-Cola?
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, air pilots.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
What do I do with the name?
Keep it with you.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Anytime an MIA is confirmed POW,
it's harder for V to kill them.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Sir, this is getting mighty
tough. It's been 14 months.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Hey, stop your bitching,
Let me hear that song again.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Yes, sir, captain.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
¶ Major Cat, he had a farm
And heartbreak was its name ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
¶ And on this farm
He had some pigs ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
¶ They all have
Different names ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
¶ Cathcart here
Williamson there ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
¶ Soles, Ashby, Fischer
Oldham was it, to my friends ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
¶ Turner still remains ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Sir, there's 249 names,
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
I'm starting to go nuts
with this song.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Yeah? 250. Ueyama, Terry.
Lieutenant. U.S.A.F.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Ueyama? Ueyama, pajama.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Um...
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
¶ Ueyama had some pajamas ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
E-I, E-I, oh ¶
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
[¶¶¶]
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Hey, Hubman,
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
I feel great.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Just great.
Got reports of a new guy
at Dogpatch, sir.
Yeah. Great.
[ALL CHATTERING]
[GUARD SPEAKING
IN VIETNAMESE]
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
Hi.
What on earth are you
guys doing here?
We're here to try
and end the war.
What on earth are you
guys doing here?
[SIGHS]
What on earth are you
guys doing here?
ASHBY:
What can I do to help?
We want you to try
and set the record straight.
ASHBY:
What can I do to help?
How?
Apologize.
ASHBY:
What can I do to help?
To whom?
ASHBY:
What can I do to help?
To the women and children
you bombed.
ASHBY:
What can I do to help?
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
Now I know that there were a lot
of innocent North Vietnamese,
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
but they sure as hell
aren't carrying weapons
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
to the south in
the middle of the night.
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
You believe that?
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
Then you believe in the war
that cost you your freedom?
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
Don't you know that?
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Uh, listen, the only thing that
I hit was the Ho Chi Minh trail.
Are you trying
to tell us something?
I'm telling you,
the food stinks.
Are you trying
to tell us something?
And don't swallow
that crap about us
getting the same as them,
not true.
And don't swallow
that crap about us
They don't get the cabbage
with the maggots in it
And don't swallow
that crap about us
or with the human--
And don't swallow
that crap about us
But who cares about food
when you're being tortured?
I'm telling you, guys are
getting killed down here.
But who cares about food
when you're being tortured?
You tell everyone.
But who cares about food
when you're being tortured?
We were told that you asked
for an early release
of your own free will.
We were told that you asked
for an early release
Yes, that's more
or less true.
We were told that you asked
for an early release
More or less?
We were told that you asked
for an early release
Uh, I'm sorry.
There is no equivocation.
We were told that you asked
for an early release
I asked to go on.
We were told that you asked
for an early release
Were you tortured
for this request?
Uh, no.
What are your
views on the war?
Uh, no.
I hate it. I hate war.
All war.
Captain, do you think our
country should be in this war?
I hate it. I hate war.
All war.
No. No, I don't.
Nope. I don't.
It's all right.
You're famous now,
aren't you?
I don't think that
that's important.
You're famous now,
aren't you?
Heh, why do you think these
bastards let you in here?
You're famous now,
aren't you?
They're movie fans,
I can tell you that.
The fact is,
They're movie fans,
I can tell you that.
they just wanted a way to get
the press all hot and bothered.
They're movie fans,
I can tell you that.
They are using you.
I think we can handle
the politics of the situation.
I think we know
what we're doing.
I think we can handle
the politics of the situation.
[CHUCKLING]
Are you hungry,
captain?
Like you couldn't
believe it.
Are you hungry,
captain?
I suppose you're
no stranger to hunger.
Are you hungry,
captain?
Not after three years
in this joint.
Are you hungry,
captain?
How do you feel about
the Democratic Republic?
Are you hungry,
captain?
Democratic Republic?
Are you hungry,
captain?
Oh, heh,
you mean the gooks.
Are you hungry,
captain?
Heh, you're safe with us,
Eric,
Are you hungry,
captain?
there's no need to use
that word.
Are you hungry,
captain?
You call me captain, lady.
Are you hungry,
captain?
I worked hard for that rank.
And I use the word gook
Are you hungry,
captain?
because I can't think
of anything worse
Are you hungry,
captain?
I'd use in front of you.
Are you hungry,
captain?
I'm just trying
to help you, Eric.
Are you hungry,
captain?
Why don't you shove it?
Are you hungry,
captain?
I don't need help.
Never from you.
Are you hungry,
captain?
You don't even know
when you're being used.
Are you hungry,
captain?
So I'm sorry,
but you got the wrong nigger.
This has been
an amazing two days.
Obviously, you are doing
everything you can.
This has been
an amazing two days.
Although some of the amended
complaint about the food.
This has been
an amazing two days.
I can sympathize,
none of us like to eat
This has been
an amazing two days.
when we're forced to.
However, it is war.
This has been
an amazing two days.
[BOTH SPEAK IN FRENCH]
This has been
an amazing two days.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
Only Ashby, really,
but he can't help it.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
He's a product of
his environment.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
He's used to having
his own way.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
I don't think this is
his idea of a country club.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
Yes, yes.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
And, as a sign of
our enduring friendship
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
for the American people,
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
I will parole
three prisoners to you.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
That is wonderful.
Thank you, merci.
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
[BOTH SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
I presume only a few of the men
complained about the food?
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
Your people did not have
will to fight no more.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
President Nixon
is withdrawing 25,000 troops.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
Be smart,
take early release.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
At this moment,
insider at Hanoi,
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
three of your countrymen,
three of your fellow prisoners,
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
you too can be watching
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
Baltimore beat Cincinnati,
in World Series.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
Say goodbye to
the wise ones amongst you.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
[BOTH SPEAK IN VIETNAMESE]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
And you two are to be
congratulated.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
I'm sure Major Doc
will miss you.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Hey, black criminals,
things are changing.
No doubt.
But we shall do our best.
What?
Take it easy, all right?
I would have ended up
like all of them.
What?
Take it easy, all right?
Is that what you want,
huh?
What?
Take it easy, all right?
[SPITS]
What?
Take it easy, all right?
Oh.
What?
Take it easy, all right?
I'm supposed to die here?
Is that it? Is that right?
What?
Take it easy, all right?
Was I supposed to die,
huh?
What?
Take it easy, all right?
Am I supposed to die?!
For what? For what?
[WHISTLING "OLD MACDONALD"]
[GONG BANGING]
[GUARD SPEAKING IN VIETNAMESE]
No, I have to wait
for my gong.
Come on, Miles, move.
Move it!
No, I have to wait
for my gong.
[ALL SHOUTING]
No, I have to wait
for my gong.
Okay.
What, what, what?
You move!
Let's go.
Okay.
What, what, what?
Now look, you got him upset?
My fault, I suppose.
Okay.
What, what, what?
I told you move!
Okay.
What, what, what?
[ALL CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING]
Okay.
What, what, what?
[¶¶¶]
Okay.
What, what, what?
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
You think you can handle it?
Okay, here we go.
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
You should have
known better!
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
It was our duty to escape.
As prisoners of war.
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
War criminals!
Criminals! Criminals!
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
War Criminals! Criminals.
Major, please--
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
[GUN COCKS]
Okay, 10 feet to a buttress,
it's under the ground.
And you,
since Murphy was moved,
you pretend to be senior
ranking officer, huh?
And you,
since Murphy was moved,
Major, please, be reasonable,
they're just kids.
And you,
since Murphy was moved,
They didn't have a chance!
You got them.
And you,
since Murphy was moved,
[BOTH GRUNT]
And you,
since Murphy was moved,
We stood out in the crowd,
heh.
And you,
since Murphy was moved,
No.
FISCHER:
There's nothing to
be accomplished
No.
by doing anything rash, major.
GREGORY: It was my fault!
No.
There's nothing to be gained
by doing any of this.
No.
It was my idea.
So you're the leader.
No.
You useful to us
if controlled.
No.
He's a follower.
He's of no use to us!
No.
[SHOUTING IN VIETNAMESE]
[GRUNTING]
No.
Soles! No! Soles!
Don't. No, you're going
to kill him. No!
Soles! No! Soles!
No, you're gonna kill him!
[¶¶¶]
Soles! No! Soles!
[ALL GRUNTING]
[YELLS]
Oh, no!
You killed him!
You shit!
[YELLS]
I will take you
from your cell,
[YELLS]
personally,
to your execution.
[YELLS]
FISCHER:
You will...
...not see me after tomorrow.
Important message
to wife and family.
...not see me after tomorrow.
I'm sorry
I did this to you.
...not see me after tomorrow.
I love you as life itself.
But I would have to do it
again, if necessary.
...not see me after tomorrow.
Soles' last words were,
"we stood out in the crowd."
...not see me after tomorrow.
That is the apology of a man
who wants only to be ordinary.
...not see me after tomorrow.
But none of the men here,
and especially not Soles,
...not see me after tomorrow.
are ordinary.
They are the bravest
of the brave.
...not see me after tomorrow.
People who go on,
even when deserted
by friends and countrymen.
...not see me after tomorrow.
What they carry
inside of them
...not see me after tomorrow.
is something
very extraordinary.
...not see me after tomorrow.
It is the spirit that makes
all human beings unique.
...not see me after tomorrow.
It makes them heroic.
[SIGHS]
I do not believe my death
will help end the war.
It seems that people at home
no longer care, anyway.
I do not believe my death
will help end the war.
I die, not so much
for love of country,
I do not believe my death
will help end the war.
as for love of countrymen.
I do not believe my death
will help end the war.
God bless you all.
I do not believe my death
will help end the war.
To me, you all stand out
in the crowd.
I do not believe my death
will help end the war.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[KEYS JINGLING]
[¶¶¶]
For the time being, your fate is
being decided by other events.
Yes, Fischer, circumstances and
things have changed matters.
For the time being, your fate is
being decided by other events.
Your execution is
to be delayed.
For the time being, your fate is
being decided by other events.
I do this personally,
For the time being, your fate is
being decided by other events.
because I do not wish
for you to think
For the time being, your fate is
being decided by other events.
I have relented
on my anger with you.
For the time being, your fate is
being decided by other events.
In time,
you will be informed.
[GONG BANGING]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
The light from our lives
has gone.
President Ho Chi Minh
has died.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
The light from our lives
has gone.
Thank you.
From all us Isaacs.
[LAUGHING]
Thank you.
[ALL CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING]
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
Hey, some break.
How about that?
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
Let's wait and see.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
What? You don't know?
What?
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
Man, you Hilton guys
are really in the dark.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
Special forces raided
the camp at Son Tay.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
The guys were gone,
but they made the point.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
And, with old President Ho dead,
they're gonna ease up on us.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
They're putting us
all together, here in Hanoi.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
He's saving his bargaining
chips for Paris.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
FISCHER: Paris?
What's up, Doc?
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
DOC:
Do not assume your good
fortune, Miles.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
Show me respect or you will
deeply regret your folly.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
[DOC SHOUTS IN VIETNAMESE]
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
Easy, easy, we just want
to know what's going on.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
Simply, we are showing
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
our humane and lenient
treatment.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
You will all be
put in one cell,
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
you will be forbidden to do
anything until ordered.
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
And you?
You look like hell.
The Asian flu!
I am being reassigned.
Your failure to
take early release
was considered a significant
propaganda defeat.
Your failure to
take early release
And you, commander,
you did what you had
to do to survive, eh?
No, to win.
We won.
you did what you had
to do to survive, eh?
One knows,
we all know it, remember?
you did what you had
to do to survive, eh?
Tell him to fuck himself, Pat.
you did what you had
to do to survive, eh?
Atten-hut!
Right face!
Forward march.
Atten-hut!
Two, one, two,
one, two, three, four,
Atten-hut!
hut, hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut...
Atten-hut!
Where were you?
It seems kind of indecent,
sleeping in the same room
as other people.
Where were you?
How's Fischer?
He made it through
perfectly.
How's Fischer?
God, that was some speech about
standing out in the crowd, huh?
How's Fischer?
Wasn't it?
Heh.
How's Fischer?
You think this means
real change,
How's Fischer?
like maybe we'll get mail
or Red Cross?
How's Fischer?
I hope so.
Cigarette?
No, you know,
I think I quit.
Cigarette?
[LAUGHING]
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
You're so goddamn uptight.
MILES: You son of a bitch.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
Don't tell me Hubman's
doing okay.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
You gonna fight
this war forever?
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
You'd go to war with
your goddamn zip code.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
You're damn right I would!
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
What's a zip code?
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
Okay, look, I apologize,
I'm sorry.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
I know it's been
hard on you old men.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
Old men?
Watch who you say that to.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
I haven't seen
a mirror for nine years.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
I'm not an old man.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
Do I look like an old man
to you?
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
No. Do I look like
an old man?
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
Huh, I don't know.
My teeth as bad as yours are?
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
Are my teeth bad?
He's an old man.
SHAVICK:
What the hell's the matter
with you guys?
[CHUCKLING]
Excuse me,
are you Barry Ashby?
[CHUCKLING]
Yeah.
I'm Charlie Cummings.
[CHUCKLING]
I went to Greenwich High School.
You're a hero there.
[CHUCKLING]
An alum, heh.
Hey, come over here.
[CHUCKLING]
Pretty crummy high school
if Ashby's a hero.
[CHUCKLING]
[ALL LAUGH]
Of course some students
call you fascist.
[CHUCKLING]
Is that true?
The hippies.
[CHUCKLING]
Not just the hippies.
Most people, I guess.
[CHUCKLING]
Most people?
Yep. By now.
[CHUCKLING]
People are tired of a war
you're not trying to win.
[CHUCKLING]
Especially when things
at home are so good, you know?
[CHUCKLING]
No, I don't know.
Explain.
[CHUCKLING]
Are they going to put us on
trial like the VC say?
[CHUCKLING]
CUMMINS:
Nah, I doubt it.
[CHUCKLING]
People are kind of into
themselves now, you know,
[CHUCKLING]
self-awareness,
sensitivity training,
[CHUCKLING]
consciousness-raising,
you know?
[CHUCKLING]
What the fuck
are you talking about?
[CHUCKLING]
Well, heh,
you'll have to see it.
[CHUCKLING]
Maybe to live through it
to understand it.
[CHUCKLING]
Right.
Cummings, come on.
[CHUCKLING]
We need a fourth
for hearts.
[CHUCKLING]
It was a real honor
to meet you, sir.
[CHUCKLING]
A real honor.
Thank you.
[CHUCKLING]
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
they don't play
the national anthem.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
They sing
"God bless America."
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
Why do you think they do that?
Because it's hockey.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
All this time, what
finds its way here?
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
A past due notice for
my Playboy subscription.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
Just my luck,
my Little League team
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
goes to the state Finals
without me.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
Damn, my little sister
got into Harvard.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
[ALL CHATTERING]
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
Goddamn, son-of-a-bitching--
Fucking perfect!
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
She waits until now! Now!
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
From his daughter,
his wife divorced him.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
Move out!
You heard the man.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
It's not your problem.
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
[¶¶¶]
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
[CRYING]
I gotta apologize for
my hockey team,
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
GREGORY:
These guys are my ticket
to law school.
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
At your age?
What if they bomb us?
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
SHAVICK:
No sweat, we've improved
bomb sites
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
since they got you, major.
They don't come near this place.
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
You never heard of
a wild shot?
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
No way.
Matter of fact,
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
I'll bet the Vietnamese are
sleeping in our courtyard.
[EXPLOSIONS
RUMBLING IN DISTANCE]
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Shh!
What do you think?
I don't know.
If we were going home, them
planes should've been here.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Just hope I'm home in time for
opening day at Dodger Stadium.
Just wait until you see
the pilot, lieutenant.
Just hope I'm home in time for
opening day at Dodger Stadium.
If he's an American,
Just hope I'm home in time for
opening day at Dodger Stadium.
I'll buy you a ticket
to the World Series.
Just hope I'm home in time for
opening day at Dodger Stadium.
You guys are paranoid.
Just hope I'm home in time for
opening day at Dodger Stadium.
They wouldn't go through
all this for nothing.
Just hope I'm home in time for
opening day at Dodger Stadium.
It wouldn't be
the first time, pal.
Just hope I'm home in time for
opening day at Dodger Stadium.
Atten-hut!
Lieutenant Commander
Patrick Williamson reporting
to return to
the United States, sir.
Lieutenant Commander
Patrick Williamson reporting
Where in the world
have you guys been?
Lieutenant Commander
Patrick Williamson reporting
We've been here all along.
Where the hell have you been?
Lieutenant Commander
Patrick Williamson reporting
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Lieutenant Commander
Patrick Williamson reporting
[ALL CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
Lieutenant Commander
Patrick Williamson reporting
[¶¶¶]
¶ You seem to stand out
In a crowd ¶
¶ Without meaning to
Without talking loud ¶
¶ You seem to stand out
In a crowd ¶
¶ There's something extra
In your appeal ¶
¶ You seem to stand out
In a crowd ¶
¶ Oh, what makes
You so special ¶
¶ What makes you so smart ¶
¶ How can you seem
To know my thoughts ¶
¶ What makes you so smart ¶
¶ Before they even start ¶
¶ What makes you so different ¶
¶ What makes you so smart ¶
¶ Is it hidden in your heart ¶
¶ You're a friend of mine
And a special breed apart ¶
¶ What makes you so smart ¶
¶ That's why it always
Make me proud ¶
¶ Just to be here with you
Standing out in the crowd ¶
¶ That's why it always
Make me proud ¶
¶ What makes it happen
What makes it feel ¶
¶ That's why it always
Make me proud ¶
¶ Oh what makes
You so special ¶
¶ That's why it always
Make me proud ¶
¶ What makes you the best ¶
¶ You seem to tower ¶
¶ Head and shoulders
Over all the rest ¶
¶ What makes you the best ¶
¶ What makes you a somebody ¶
¶ That sets you far apart ¶
¶ What makes you the best ¶
¶It must be that you have
A hero's heart¶
¶ What makes you the best ¶
¶ What makes
You so special ¶
¶ What makes you the best ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ I can put the finger
On the answer ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ And might be the one
Who really knows it all ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ Knows it all ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ Really knows it all ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ What makes you
So beautiful ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ Living work of art ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ Must be that to have
A hero's heart ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ What makes you so special ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ You never take a fall ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ I can put my finger
On the answer ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ And I might be the one
Who really hears your call ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ Hears a call ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ I wanna hear you call ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ What makes you
So wonderful ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ So high you're off
The charts ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶
¶ It must be that
You have a hero's heart ¶
¶ What makes you stand
So tall ¶