[Explosions In Distance]
[Incoming Shells Whistling]
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Panting]
[Droning]
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Explosion]
[Chattering]
- Up! Up!
- Push!
- Come on!
[Man] Move out of the way!
Clear the way!
- [Shouting, Indistinct]
- [Neighing]
[Man]
Move! Move!
That was a full bottle,
Herr Leutnant.
Yes!
[Brakes Squeal]
[Droning In Distance]
[Klaxon Blaring]
[Blaring Continues]
[Loud Droning]
- You've just met Willi von Klugermann!
- Yes!
- I see you've heard of him!
- Oh! Yes, I have!
- [Man] Look at him!
- You must be the new...
- He's tearing the wings off that plane!
- Let him celebrate, Ziegel!
He shoots them down!
Your job is to keep him up there!
You must be
the new replacement... Stachel!
Bruno Stachel,
Herr Oberleutnant.
- Are you the adjutant?
- I fly a desk now!
Anti-aircraft fire!
Still, it could've got me
higher up, couldn't it?
- Yes!
- [Chuckling]
Wait here!
I'll tell the C! O! You've arrived!
And if I were you,
I'd button up that jacket!
Ziegel! How soon
can you have us ready again?
Depends on how many of the others
have been hit, Herr Hauptmann.
I wasn't the only one!
I can't keep these barges flying forever!
I'm a mechanic, not a magician!
No, you are a magician,
whether you like it or not!
- Only 11 back, Herr Hauptmann.
- Yes! Mueller went down!
- He didn't last long!
- [Airplane Approaching Quickly]
Fabian, how did we
come to lose him?
I gave him the usual
instructions!!!
But he wouldn't
stay with me!
Too, uh!!!
Too keen!
- By the way, Scholte's replacement's here!
- [Boot Heels Click]
Leutnant Bruno Stachel reporting
from 104 Training School.
Your commanding officer...
Hauptmann Heidemann.
Ah, yes! Stachel!
Come inside!
[Men Chattering, Laughing]
Herr Hauptmann.
- Stachel!
- Yes, sir!
- [Boot Heels Click]
- Two years in the infantry!
- Any rank?
- Corporal, Herr Hauptmann.
What made you transfer
to the Air Corps?
To fly,
Herr Hauptmann.
Are you a good flyer?
I am!!!
Comfortable in the air!
"Comfortable!"
Are you?
- Interesting!
- [Man] Willi!
- [Excited Chatter]
- Willi!
[Men Laughing]
Very pretty flying!
I wish you would stop it!
You'll live longer!
[Chattering,
Laughing Continue]
Sorry about that!
I see you are
from Wiesbaden!
I've done some hunting
around there!
- Who are your people?
- Herr Hauptmann?
I want to know something
of your background!
What does
your father do?
He works in a small hotel,
Herr Hauptmann.
- Five bedrooms!
- [Scoffing Sighs]
Corporal, see the new officer's bags
are taken up to the mess!
- Herr Hauptmann.
- Come into my office, Stachel!
[Chattering]
Close the door,
please!
I'm sorry if it bothers you
about what your father does!
It doesn't bother me,
Herr Hauptmann.
Then why are you
so touchy about it?
Well, you're an officer now! Your
social problems are no concern of ours!
Take a look at the map, Stachel!
Our operating area is between Arras
and Saint-Quentin!
The British also operate the area,
as you'll find out!
Uh, what did you
train on?
The usual machine, Herr Hauptmann...
an out-of-date Pfalz!
- That's what you'll fly here!
- But, at flying school, they told us...
"Flying school!"
[Laughing]
At flying school,
they'll tell you anything!
Up-to-date machines
go to experienced pilots!
Those are in short supply!
It's a cruel world,
Stachel, huh?
Yes, Herr Hauptmann.
Welcome to the squadron! The truck will
take you to the mess with the others!
[Boot Heels Click]
And, Stachel!
Let's hope
you get to like us!
Of course, he could've
been lying about the five bedrooms!
[Chuckling] His father
was probably only a waiter!
- Just another snob, in fact.
- [Chattering]
Willi, there's something
I haven't told you!
I have an uncle
in the hotel business!
I admit he's a baron and
the hotel has 500 bedrooms!!!
But you do see the position
it places me in!
[All Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
[All Chattering, Laughing]
[All Laughing]
¶ There was a town
in Poland ¶
[All] ¶ And there
a girl we found ¶
- ¶ Lovely was she ¶
- Want a cigarette?
- Thank you!
- ¶ She was the haughtiest maid ¶
¶ That ever we beheld ¶
¶ But do not kiss me
please, she said ¶
¶ I never kiss ¶
- You've got 18, haven't you?
- ¶¶ [Humming]
Squadron rule number one,
Stachel...
gentlemen never parade
their military achievements!
¶ She was the loveliest maid
that ever we beheld ¶
Any rule against saying
how long it took you?
- ¶¶[Continue Singing]
- I would say that was covered
by the same rule!!!
Wouldn't you?
No, I wouldn't!
How many rules are there?
I don't know!
None of them have been written down!
¶She was the haughtiest maid
that ever we beheld ¶
¶But do not kiss me,
please, she said ¶
¶ I never kiss ¶
[All Laughing]
¶ She was the haughtiest maid
that ever we beheld ¶
- ¶ But do not kiss me, please, she said ¶
- [Horn Honks]
¶ I never kiss ¶¶
¶¶ [Humming]
[Laughing]
- [Laughing]
- Oh!
[Chattering]
[Laughing, Chattering Continue]
Seems you're next to me
in Scholte's old room!
- That's, uh, number 11!
- Scholte?
Oh, your predecessor! He, uh...
He didn't last long, unfortunately!
- Unhappy young man!
- Yes! He forgot to keep
looking over his shoulder!
It's worth remembering!
They come fast, out of the sun!
[Imitating Zooming Noise,
Knife Cutting]
- Thank you!
- [Chuckling]
[Men Chattering, Laughing]
Willi, what do you
think of him?
Hmm?
Gonna have a drink?
- Ah!
- [Chattering]
[Footsteps]
Oh! They haven't removed
poor Scholte's card!
Very tactless of them!
I just thought you should know
we, uh, don't dress for dinner here!
Von Richthofen, I see!
Your hero?
He's done it all!
Two more kills,
and you'll have one of those!
Hmm! A pretty medal,
the Blue Max!
It's the only one worth having!
People respect it!
The medal or the man?
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Birds Chirping]
The usual routine, Fabian!
You know what they are like
the first time in combat!
- Of course!
- Keep your eye on him!
Here! Isn't it nice to hear the birds
again, Herr Hauptmann?
- [Birds Chirping]
- Listen to that!
They won't
be here long!
When our offensive starts...
[Spits]
- Good luck, Fabian!
- Herr Hauptmann.
What is it?
Stachel!
Fly on Fabian's left!!!
And a little behind him!
- And watch for his signals!
- Yes, Herr Hauptmann.
And relax! Get the balloon
and come straight back!
- You'll find balloons burn beautifully!
- [Loud Rap]
[Engine Starts In Distance]
Switches on!
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Machine-gun Fire
Continues]
[Artillery Fire]
[Artillery Fire
Continues]
[Machine-gun Fire]
Is that army observation?
Adjutant, Squadron 11 here.
One of our pilots claims
an SE5 shot down in sector five!
- Yes!
- Can you confirm, please?
Yes, about, uh,
0700 hours!
- Perhaps Fabian made a forced landing!
- I don't know!
Yes? Sector five,
on our side of the line!
You did? Fine!
Go on! Uh...
In midair?
- Did yours explode?
- No!
Yes, we do have
a pilot missing!
- That will be him, I'm afraid!
- Ask him!
Thanks!
Good-bye!
- But...
- Only Fabian! He never got out!
- No SE5!
- But somebody must have
seen my SE5 go down!
Not necessarily!
[Sighs]
It often happens!
No confirmation, no claim!
- That's a squadron rule!
- But I saw it! It was a kill!
Then you have the deep satisfaction of
knowing you have served the fatherland!
It went down here...
our side of the line!
Why couldn't
the army look for it?
They have other things to do!
Somebody must have seen it!
Fabian might have
seen it!
[Men Chattering]
- Corporal Rupp!
- Herr Leutnant.
We're going to search sector five!
Get your motorcycle!
- But, Herr Leutnant...
- Be at the mess in five minutes!
- Herr Leutnant.
- [Thunder Rumbles]
[Thunder Continues]
[Lowing]
[Starts Engine]
Back to the mess,
Herr Leutnant?
No! I'm going to search
that wood over there!
- You already have, Herr Leutnant.
- What?
You searched that wood
an hour ago!
Well, we're going
to search it again!
What's the matter, Rupp?
Too close to the guns for you?
[Engine Revs]
[People Chattering,
Laughing]
- Thank you, Corporal!
- It's been a pleasure, Herr Leutnant.
[Boot Heels Click]
[Footsteps]
You have finished
your wild goose chase, I hope!
- Yes, Herr Hauptmann.
- Found nothing, huh?
No!
If every pilot were to go
careering around France!!!
Looking for
unconfirmed aircraft!!!
There'd be no air force left!
And Corporal Rupp has
more important things to do!
- Do you understand?
- Yes, Herr Hauptmann.
Unconfirmed by army
means unconfirmed, and that's final!
Good night, Stachel!
- ¶¶[Piano]
- [Chattering, Laughing]
Stachel!
Come and join us!
- Ah!
- [Laughing]
I'll get the next one, Willi!
- Brandy, please!
- Champagne, Herr Leutnant.
Willi got his 20th kill today!
- He's being awarded the Blue Max!
- Uh-huh!
I see you've had
a hard day!
No one's ever done that before
about an unconfirmed kill!
Quite novel!
You must be in a hurry!
To your Blue Max!
- Blue Max!
- Willi!
- [Men Chattering]
- [Billiard Balls Clacking]
I don't suppose you've ever had
an unconfirmed kill!
Oh, but I have!
I've had, uh, three!
Then you've shot down 23!
No!
- Twenty!
- [Laughing]
By the way, Stachel!!!
There's an impression
around that!!!
You care more about
your unconfirmed kill!!!
Than you do
about Fabian's death!
[All Quiet]
Perhaps it's force of habit!
In the trenches,
we couldn't even bury the dead!
There were too many of them!
I've never had the time!!!
To discuss them over
a glass of champagne!
[Chuckling]
Well, never mind, Stachel!
To your unconfirmed victory!
Next time,
you must have witnesses!
- Witnesses!
- Good evening, gentlemen!
- [Man] Good evening.
Pairings for next week's sorties!
- Let's have them, please!
- I'll fly with Becker!
- [Man] Heller and Braun!
- [Second Man] I'll fly with Lindorf!
[Third Man] Von Klinger and I
will do the ground strafe!
Good!
Who'll fly with Stachel?
I'll fly with Stachel!
[Machine-gun Fire]
He's...
He's bringing her in!
[Crash]
[Klaxon Blaring]
[Men Shouting, Indistinct]
This one is dead,
Herr Leutnant.
- Easy, easy!
- [Man] Bring a stretcher!
Quick! Quick!
- Get over there!
- Quickly!
What happened, Stachel?
The observer, he was
going to open fire!
Then we are to assume
he was either very brave!!!
Or very foolish!
Confirmed!
It's a cruel world, Herr Hauptmann.
You said so yourself!
[Man Shouting, Indistinct]
Willi!
I've read your report, Willi!
What really happened?
As I said, Otto, the observer
made a move for his gun!!!
So Stachel
shot him down!
You wish to stand by
a comrade!
- I appreciate that!
- What I reported is what I saw!
We are German officers!
We'll fight this war with chivalry!
- You know that as well as I do!
- Of course!
The observer was blinded!
Did you know that?
No! It could have happened
when Stachel opened fire over the airfield!
- But did it?
- I don't know!
You know how Stachel behaved
when his first claim was disallowed!
If he shot down
a helpless enemy in cold blood!!!
It's something I won't tolerate
in my squadron!
All right, I agree!
There is some measure of doubt!
But I have no reason
to change my report!
All right, Willi!
The incident is closed,
officially anyway!
Is everyone here?
All except Leutnant Stachel,
Herr Hauptmann.
Someone inform him
this is a parade!
He is ordered
to attend!
[Knocking]
We're about
to honor your dead!
So I see!
Well, aren't
you coming?
It's an order!
Why?
Because our commanding officer
has made it one!
He believes in chivalry, Stachel.
Chivalry?
To kill a man!!!
Then make a ritual
out of saluting him?
That's hypocrisy!
- They kill me!!!
- [Glass Clinks, Drink Pours]
I don't want
anyone to salute!
- [Glass Slams]
- They probably won't!
All right!
Let's get it over with,
shall we?
Stachel!
Thank you!
You know, there's something
of the cobra in you!
I'll have to watch you!
Mm-hmm!
[Chuckling]
¶¶[Martial]
Leutnant von Klugermann!
Parade, stand at!!! Ease!
I assume you've talked
to the other pilots about this, Holbach!
Yes, Herr General. I'm making a thorough
inquiry into the whole incident!
Good!
When the opportunity arises,
point the man out to me!
Yes, Herr General.
- Ah, Otto!
- [Boot Heels Click]
The squadron's drawn up,
Herr General.
We were discussing the pilot
who brought this in!
Air headquarters
is quite excited about it!
What's the man's name again?
- Leutnant Stachel, Herr General.
- Mm-hmm!
Is he a good flyer?
Yes! Yes, he is!
Glad to hear it! We mustn't
keep my nephew waiting any longer!
Not to mention my wife!
¶¶ [Continues]
[Man]
Parade, front!
Left... turn!
Sorry to have been so long!
Were you bored?
With all these men around?
Look beautiful for them, Kaeti!
Look at Willi!
Doesn't he look splendid?
The Blue Max
will go so well with his eyes!
He is rather vain!
He'll probably wear it in bed
the first few days!
Oh, how uncomfortable
for the girl!
- [Man] Parade... attention!
- Excuse me, Herr General.
- Yes?
- The second one on the left!!!
Front row... that's Stachel!
- Ah!
- ¶¶[Concludes]
"To Leutnant Wilhem von Klugermann!!!
"For bravery
of the highest order!!!
"In action against the enemies
of the German Empire...
"and for exceptional services
to the fatherland...
"in that he has destroyed
single-handed 20 enemy aircraft...
"the order Pour Le Mérite!
"By imperial decree...
Wilhem, Emperor!"
I'm afraid it's rather
a small medal, Willi!!!
But it's the highest
Germany can give!
Thank you!!! Uncle!
[Boot Heels Click]
- ¶¶[Orchestra]
- [Laughing]
[Loud Chatter]
- ¶¶[Men Singing]
- [Cork Pops]
Otto!
This pilot of yours...
Stachel!
Humble origin, risen from the ranks,
et cetera, et cetera!
Two years'
front-line service, hmm?
Yes, that's right!
To deliver the final blow over your own
airfield... on the doorstep, so to speak!
- It was splendid, wasn't it?
- "Splendid"?
Otto, if this young man
lives long enough!!!
He could be very useful
to our propaganda department!
The common people of our country
are war-weary, restive!
They need to be provided
with a hero of their own!
Von Richthofen, Willi,
are of our class!
That fellow Stachel is common as dirt!
He's one of them!
- You understand?
- Yes, I understand!
But I don't agree with
killing helpless men!
Otto, this is 1918!
Things have changed!
Unrestricted submarine warfare!
Bombing of civilians!
Poison gas!
Ask your wife... she's a nurse!
Ask Elfi about
the mustard gas casualties!
So you approve
of this kind of ruthlessness!
- We fight to win, Otto!
- Yes, of course!
Excuse me, Herr General.
[Holbach]
Herr General!
May I present
Leutnant Stachel!
[Boot Heels Click]
I saw the plane
which you brought in!
Very!!!
Interesting exploit!
It proves that our young men
still have vitality!!!
Courage and the will to win
at all costs!
Yes, Herr General.
Thank you!
I'm sure we'll hear
a lot more of you!
[Boot Heels Click]
[Loud Chatter, Laughing]
Kaeti, you haven't met
our Leutnant Stachel!
Stachel.
May I introduce
the Countess von Klugermann!
[Boot Heels Click]
My aunt!!!
By marriage!
You appear to have caught
my uncle's interest!
Interest from high places
is always welcome!
May I get you a drink,
Countess?
All right!
Champagne!
Pink champagne!
[Laughing]
- Pink champagne?
- Yes!
Yes, Countess!
[No Audible Dialogue]
- May I have two glasses
of pink champagne, please?
- [Loud Chattering]
[Louder] May I have two glasses
of pink champagne, please?
- ¶¶[Waltz]
- Well, I say...
My glass, hmm?
- ¶¶[Men Vocalizing To Music]
- [Laughing]
¶La-la-la la-la-la ¶
¶La-la-la la-la ¶
¶ La-la-la la-la-la ¶
- ¶La-la-la la-la-la ¶
- [Laughing]
¶ Yam-pah-pah
yam-pah-pah ¶
That champagne
is getting warm, Stachel!
¶¶[Vocalizing Continues]
Not yet!
[Laughing]
¶La-la-la-la
la-la-la la-la-la-la ¶¶
Silence, please!
Silence!
- Please, silence!
- ¶¶[Stops]
Gentlemen!!!
In a few hours!!!
The horizon will be lit up
by the flashes of 7,000 guns!
Our guns!
[All Cheering]
[Cheering Subsides]
They will herald
the greatest offensive in history!
Our defeat of Russia
has released a million men...
for the Western Front!
I need hardly tell you!!!
That if we destroy the British
and French armies...
before the Americans
can intervene effectively!!!
We shall have
won the war!
- [All Cheering]
- God be with us! God be with us!
¶¶[Martial]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Light Footsteps]
[Door Opens]
[Hushed]
Oh! Willi, darling!
- [Door Closes]
- Mm-hmm!
I'm sorry I'm late!
[Yelps]
[Chuckling]
I'm sorry!
Well, I'm not!
If you're looking for your nephew,
he's next door!
Yes!
I realize that now!
[Clears Throat]
As long as you're here!!!
Perhaps I can
get you that drink!
Yes, do!
I'm afraid
I'm out of champagne!
- Then whatever you have!
- Schnapps!
Mmm! Horrible!!!
But quite stimulating!
So that's you... Cobra!
- "Cobra"?
- Yes! That's what Willi calls you!
Has he been talking
about me to you?
I asked!
He says you're quite,
uh, deadly!!!
In sort of a quiet way!
[Chuckles]
He's a romantic!
- And you're not!
- No!
No!
Tonight is a!!!
Family affair!
[Laughing]
- Are you shocked?
- No!
- You see, my husband is a very civilized man!!!
- Mmm!
And we are great friends!
It must be nice to have
an understanding friend!
Oh, yes, it is!
Willi must be
getting impatient!
Shall I announce you?
Please do!
[Pounding]
Thank you!
[Laughing]
- [Faint Knocking]
- [Door Opens, Closes]
[Countess Laughing]
[Artillery Fire In Distance]
[Artillery Fire Continues]
[Machine-gun Fire]
- [Gunfire, Explosions]
- [Shouting, Indistinct]
[Man] Fire!
[All Shouting, Indistinct]
- [Machine-gun Fire]
- Come on, lads! This is it!
[Man]
Follow me!
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Incoming Shells Whistling]
[Man]
Here they come again!
[All Shouting, Indistinct]
[Screams]
[Groans]
[Man] Come on, boys!
Come on now!
[Whistle Blows]
[Airplanes Droning]
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Machine-gun Fire
Continues]
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Explosion]
The oil pressure's
still too low!
That's all you'll
get out of her!
She wasn't made yesterday!
Oh, is that what it is?
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Neighing]
[Engine Stalling]
[Airplane Droning]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Explosions In Distance]
- [Groans]
- You'll feel better in
a few days, Herr Leutnant.
- We've taken Bapaume!
- Bapaume!
Bapaume!
[Groans] It means
we're closer to Paris!
Thank you!
Herr Leutnant, I'm here
to take you back to the squadron!
In there, Herr Leutnant.
What are we celebrating?
Your survival, of course,
and your tenth victory!
You're moving up fast,
Stachel!
Too fast?
[Artillery Fire Continues]
Does it hurt?
Yes!
Then I'd better
open the bottle!
Tell me, uh...
never having
suffered it personally...
what does it feel like
to be!!! Shot down?
- I'd rather you found that out for yourself!
- [Chuckles]
¶¶ [Humming]
Prosit.
You know, l... I was
quite pleased at first...
when you were posted
missing, I mean!
Thank you!
Oh, it was just that, uh,
all of a sudden!!!
The war seemed
a bit more!!! Peaceful!
And then... this is the odd thing...
I had a sense of loss!
- I'm touched!
- No, no! Uh, seriously!
I suppose I've had everything
in my life too easy!
I'm inclined to be lazy!
I have to have a challenge!
I need someone around me who is, uh!!!
Hard to beat!!!
And you fulfill that role!
- How's the countess?
- The countess?
- Mmm!
- Oh!
Your aunt by marriage!
- Is she well?
- I think so!
I should have thought
you'd have known!
Oh, yes! She told me about
coming into your room that night!
I knew you'd have
to bring it up sooner or later!
The countess!
- [Smacks Lips]
- There's a fascinating subject!
I believe you have aspirations
in that direction, Stachel!
You should forget them!
I'll try!
But if the impossible happens!!!
I'll buy you
a bottle of champagne!
Will you?
It's vintage 1903!
You'll find it!!!
Hard to get!
[Chuckles]
1903? I'll remember that!
[Gears Shifting]
[Brakes Squeal]
Thanks for the champagne!
[Groans]
That's the damn fool
that almost got me killed today!
I believe he's a friend of mine!
Why don't you
take it up with him?
I hope it'll be
a longer visit next time!
Yes, of course! Stachel!
May I introduce!!!
The Baron von Richthofen!
It is an honor,
Herr Rittmeister.
And I'm very grateful!
Hmm!
1903 again!
- [All Chuckling]
- You'll never change, Willi!
I'd like to have some
of Willi's champagne with you!!!
But I must get back
to my squadron!
I'm glad to see
you haven't had to pay!!!
Too high a price
for my life!
I only lost an old Pfalz,
Herr Rittmeister.
Perhaps now I'll get
a better plane!
Oh, yes, you will!
My squadron is going to be equipped
with the new monoplane!!!
Berlin's been
promising so long!
I don't understand,
Herr Rittmeister.
The baron wants you
to join his squadron, Stachel!
I have no objection!
Well, what do you think?
I am!!! Very flattered by your offer,
Herr Rittmeister.
Thank you!
But I'd prefer
to prove myself here!
Oh, I see!
Well, I admire loyalty!
You're lucky to have
this fellow, Otto!
[Man]
Switches on!
[Engine Starts]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Thank you!
[Chattering]
Holbach!!!
Bring me that report
from Von Richthofen again!
Yes, Herr General.
You're not
shoeing a horse!
Get out!
Herr General.
Stachel!
I want him brought to Berlin
immediately!
- Yes, Herr General.
- There is some difficulty?
[Chuckling] I don't know
what you have in mind!!!
But with the offensive
at its height!!!
There'd have to be
some legitimate excuse!!!
To order him
from the front.
- He's wounded, isn't he?
- Yes, Herr General.
Hmm!
A mentionable wound?
In the arm!
Good! The people like soldiers
to be shot in the right places!
Order Stachel to Berlin
for special hospital treatment!
I want you to ensure that all
our newspapers give full prominence!!!
To this!!!
Gallant episode!
Photographs!
Everything!
Yes, Herr General.
Yes!
I think I can get the field marshal
to see things my way!!!
With luck!
[Wind Rushing]
- [Man] Stop!
- [Wind Machine Shuts Down]
So what you're telling me
behind your jargon!!!
Is that this machine
is unstable!
Exactly!
Herr Field Marshal!!!
We require at least three more months
to perfect the design!
By then, the war
may well be lost!
Well, Franz, what more have you
to say to the experts?
With your permission,
Herr Field Marshal!!!
I would like to produce
an expert of my own!
[Man] Stachel!
We would like the benefit
of your experience, Stachel.
You'll have read in this morning's papers
about Von Richthofen!
- This is the pilot concerned...
Leutnant Bruno Stachel!
- [Boot Heels Click]
This way!
[Stachel]
The new monoplane!
Is it as fast
as we've heard?
Faster!
What about
its maneuverability?
Only one wing...
will it take the stress?
It will out-turn any Allied plane
present in the air!
It could even turn the tide
of the air war!
Then we must have it!
What would your reaction be if I told you
that these gentlemen believe!!!
That there will be risks for you pilots
if we hurry it into production now?
Well, we're used to risks,
Herr General.
One more wouldn't
make any difference!
- Hmm!
- Leutnant Stachel!
- [Boot Heels Click]
- Tell me!
Do you think that your opinion would
be shared by your comrades?
I am certain of it,
Herr Field Marshal!
- Let me see it again!
- [Wind Machine Starts]
[Car Horn Honking]
[Man Groaning]
Nurse!
[Man] Nurse!
Nurse, come quickly.
Come along,
Herr Leutnant.
Frau Heidemann,
Leutnant Stachel!
- [Boot Heels Click]
- Yes! I remember you!
- I'm due back in a few minutes!
- It won't take long!
The jacket, please, Herr Leutnant.
And your shirt!
Frau Heidemann!
Those flowers, please!
Thank you!
Sit down, Herr Leutnant.
Excuse me, please!
Mm-hmm!
Excellent!
[Footsteps Leaving]
I saw how busy
you were outside!
- Yes!
- I'm sorry!
[Holbach]
Come along, gentlemen.
Along here!
Now, Frau Heidemann,
if you please!!!
It is just
this one pose, hmm?
What are you going
to put under the picture?
- "Squadron commander's wife
nurses wounded hero"?
- Yes!
Please!
Oh, very good!
[Holbach]
Now move a little closer.
Thank you!
Now!!! Hold still!
[Chattering]
- The playacting is over?
- Yes, Herr General.
We have finished!
Elfi, my dear!
How good of you to have found time
to come and help us!
It was an order, Herr General,
wasn't it?
Of course!
It was a very important
piece of playacting!
I see!
Well, Stachel, by morning,
you'll be quite famous!
How do you feel
about that?
- Lucky, Herr General.
- Hmm.
- Tomorrow, you will be making
your way back to your squadron!
- [Boot Heels Click]
And tonight, my wife
would like you to dine with her!
That's!!! Very kind of her,
Herr General.
Not at all!
She likes heroes!
8:00!
[Door Closes]
¶¶[Piano, Softly]
You don't convince me
for one moment, Colonel!
Herr Leutnant, may I ask you, please,
do you envy the birds?
It may surprise you,
General, to know!!!
Is that what makes men
want to fly...
- jealousy of the birds?
- That I'm a serious student
of military strategy!
No, Baroness, I am not
really surprised!
Jealousy of the birds!
I've never heard it put better!
[All Chattering]
[Woman] Herr Leutnant,
about the birds.
[Chattering]
- Good night!
Good night!
A most successful party!
[Woman]
Absolutely wonderful!
- Bless you, Kaeti!
- Good night!
Hans!
¶¶[Drum Beating]
What's that?
It sounds like a drum,
Countess!
¶¶[Drumming Continues]