##[Military March]
##
## [March Continues]
Armies, for the most part,
are made up of men drawn
from simple and peaceful lives.
In time of war,
they suddenly find themselves...
living under conditions
of violence,
requiring new rules of conduct
that are in direct contrast...
to the conditions
they lived under as civilians.
They learn to accept this
and to perform their duties
as fighting men.
But some begin to perform,
as military language puts it,
"at the risk of life,
above and beyond
the call of duty."
Military histories are filled
with incredible examples
of individual courage...
that are only made more
incredible by the fact that
they were everyday events.
As Senior Staff Officer
at Supreme Headquarters
in World War II,
it was my privilege to know
the records of many such men.
The story you are
about to see is theirs:
The true story
of the foot soldier,
as seen through the eyes
of one of them, Audie L. Murphy.
He received
every decoration for valor
that his country could award,
and he became
the most decorated soldier
for combat action...
in the military history
of the United States.
In 1937, in northeast Texas,
at the age of 12,
Murphy was already
a fair rifleman.
I don't suppose you girls have
had time to fill the wood box.
Uh-uh, Audie.
Hey, Audie, look at me!
Get off that woodpile,
Preston. Do you want
to break a leg?
Did you get another
rabbit today, Audie?
Yeah.
Now you come with me.
You sit down
right over there.
You watch that
until I get back, okay?
Okay.
It'll keep you
off the woodpile.
Now, you watch it.
Hi, Mom.
[Mrs. Murphy]
Audie.
I saw Mr. Huston today.
He said he'd get
the window fixed.
- That's good of him.
- He was askin' about Pa.
No word today.
But we'll be hearing
from him real soon.
[Doors Closing]
[Horn Honking]
Hi, Mr. Brooks!
Hi!
[Mrs. Murphy]
Any mail for us today,
Mr. Brooks?
Nothing today,
Mrs. Murphy. Sorry.
Thank you.
Maybe tomorrow.
Bye.
Why does Mom
get so worried
when no mail comes?
Because
we got no money.
Here, take these
to the house.
Where are you goin'?
I just made my mind up
about something.
When he makes up his mind,
he sure does it sudden.
Where is he goin'?
[Sawing]
Hi, Mr. Huston.
Hello, Audie.
That was a first-rate job
you did on that chicken coop
the other day.
Thanks.
Hi, Mrs. Huston.
Hello, Audie.
Sir, I know you don't
hire any steady help
except at picking time,
but could you give me
a full-time job?
A full-time job?
I wouldn't want much money,
and you could keep half until
we pay back what we owe you.
What does your ma say to that?
I wanted to talk to you
before I said anything to her.
It's not right.
Why, you'd have
to quit school.
Yes, ma'am,
but I need the money.
What about your sister
in Farmersville?
Can't she help?
Edna.
Corinne's helped all she can,
but, well, she's got a family
of her own to take care of.
A boy your age!
You can't do it, Ben.
This is man's talk.
Will you please
go to the house,
and let me run the farm?
[Rooster Crowing]
Seems like
she's forgot, Audie,
I never finished school neither.
A couple years older than you,
I quit to go in the Marines
when we was in the big war.
Sometimes I wish
I'd stayed in.
Probably be retired by now
on more money than I make
out of the farm.
Now about that job...
I guess the best thing to do
is leave it to your ma.
Thanks a lot, Mr. Huston.
Ma, I got a full-time job!
I'm gonna work for Mr. Huston
in the morning.
But you've got
to go to school.
I don't care for school.
I don't like it anymore.
You can't stop
your education now.
I'll learn, Ma.
I'll read books.
We can't go on without money.
We can manage
a little longer.
Your daddy's doing
the best he can,
and we can wait...
We can't keep waitin'
for some old letter that
maybe won't ever get here.
- What's the matter, Mom?
- Nothing, dear.
Audie and I were just
talking things over.
[Boy]
Something bad?
Of course not.
We just decided who the head
of the family is.
It's your turn.
I did them
yesterday!
You did not!
Gene keeps saying...
Shh!
Gene keeps saying it's my turn
to do the dishes today.
Who did them yesterday?
I forget.
[Sister]
Beatrice and I did them,
and he knows it.
Then you do them today,
and you won't forget
tomorrow.
Besides,
your hands could use
a little soap and water.
Smarty.
I told you so.
Time for breakfast, Mom.
Oh, thank you.
All the kids are home
from Sunday school.
They can do
everything that needs
to be done today,
so don't you try
to get up.
Yes, sir.
I'm gonna take a run
over to Mr. Huston's.
But this is Sunday.
This is not about work.
Jim, their nephew, is
on leave from the Marines,
I haven't seen him
since he went in.
Oh, I see.
You try to eat.
I won't be long.
All right.
[Radio Announcer]
TheJapanese bombers
swept over the island...
Come in, Audie.
At 7:55 this morning,
Honolulu time.
Pearl Harbor has been attacked.
[Announcer Continues]
The attack was without warning,
and launched
from aircraft carriers
standing off Hawaii.
Casualties among naval personnel
will run into the thousands.
At Hickam Field, the barracks
sustained a direct hit.
Details are at a minimum,
but we will continue
to interrupt broadcasts...
as more information
reaches us.
[Turns Off Radio]
Ben, we're really at war.
We sure are.
[Murphy]
How does this affect you, Jim?
I'll probably be ordered back
to base right away.
It'll be an honor to serve,
and don't you ever forget it.!
You've got the best training.!
I've had a lot of it, anyway.
[Ben]
Why, you leathernecks...
will have this war won
in two months.
Just wish I was young enough
to help you do it.
Biggest mistake I made
was gettin' out.
Why, I might have been
a general by this time.
I'll bet you...
Never mind, General.
War or no war,
you boys are gonna eat
the doughnuts I fixed.
I'll get
a pitcher of milk.
I was too optimistic, Audie,
but so was a lot of folks.
War is gonna last longer
than most of us figured.
How aboutJim?
You heard from him lately?
He's doin' real good.
Up to sergeant now.
Audie!
You gotta come home!
It's Ma!
All of a sudden
Ma got worse!
How about Doc Snyder?
Is he with her?
I called him.
He should be by now.
Doc, is she...
She went peacefully.
I should have
been with her.
She didn't know, Audie.
She was happy and proud
of you and her family,
right up till the end.
[Crying]
[Doctor]
I'll telephone Corinne...
and make
all the necessary
arrangements.
[Continues Crying]
If you don't let
the children come into
the church orphanage,
Social Welfare
will place them in some
public institution.
I took care of'em
for a long time.
I can take care of'em now.
He's right, Audie.
All right...
if that's the way it has to be.
As soon as I can,
I'm gonna get them out.
I know this must seem like
the end of the world, Audie,
after taking care
of your family
all these years,
but look at it another way.
You've got
no responsibilities left now,
except to yourself.
It's time
you were thinking
about your future.
I have been. That's what
I wanted to tell you.
After all the talk you and I
had about it, I've decided
to go into the service.
I was hoping
you'd say that.
It'll be a great chance
for you to catch up
on your education.
Yeah. The only thing is,
I hate running out on the kids.
They've had enough of that.
You can do more for 'em
with your service pay than
you can by staying here.
I guess I hadn't
thought of it that way.
Course, being under age,
you'll have to get
a letter of permission.
I'll get Corinne
to write one for me.
Good-bye, Mr. Huston.
Thanks.
If I were you, Audie,
I'd think about it
for a career.
You stay in 20 years,
and you can retire
on good money.
Don't make the mistake
that I made. I might
have been a general...
Yes, sir.
I'll remember that.
It'll take more than a letter
from your guardian to get you
in this outfit, sonny.
We separate the men
from the boys, but we like
to have something to start with.
Why don't you
try the Army?
[Others Laugh]
I'm sorry.
The Navy makes men
out of boys,
but you're too much
of a job for us.
Why don't you
try the Army?
[P.A. System]
Attention!
Attention, please!
This being
our fourth day at sea,
it is now permissible...
to report
our destination as being
French North Africa,
which we will reach
in approximately
five more days.
According
to the last communique
on the fighting in Tunisia,
the Axis forces
are still retreating
toward the coast.
Their losses in men
and equipment are reported
to be extremely high.
Further bulletins will be
announced as received.
That is all.
Sure picked a beaut for acting
platoon sergeant, didn't they?
Huh?
[Men Chuckling]
Murphy, here you are.
Baker Company.
Well, what do you know?
We're being reinforced.
Wonder what Boy Scout troop
they dug him out of.
Don't let
them old soldiers
eat you alive.
Man, that's really
fresh meat, huh?
[Men Laughing]
Sergeant?
Hmm?
I'm supposed to report
to Captain Marks.
All officers and noncomms
are at division briefing.
You're the replacement?
That's right.
Let's have your orders.
Hey, Sergeant,
send him over here.
I need somebody
to help carry
my Purple Hearts.
[Men Laughing]
At ease
over there!
Fall in for inspection.
You go to 3rd Platoon.
Hey, wait a minute.
I see you were acting sergeant
on the trip across.
Ain't that nice?
I think you should see the way
some real tough veterans
handle their equipment.
You inspect
the 3rd Platoon!
Acting Sergeants,
take over and inspect
your platoons!
[Acting Sergeants]
Platoon, attention.!
What's this man's Army
coming to?
Ayardbird replacement,
already he's taken over
the platoon.
[Acting Sergeants]
Open ranks.!
Open ranks, march.!
Platoon,
attention!
Open ranks,
march!
Ready, hut!
How did you collect
all those Purple Hearts?
Did your rifle blow up?
[Soldier With Foreign Accent]
... promote the general welfare
and secure the blessing...
of liberty to ourselves
and our poster-ity...
Posterity.
Ah, that's what I said.
...do ordain and establish
this Constitution...
for the United States
of America.
By George!
I know that, all right!
That's pretty good.
Now, what date
was it adopted?
Uh, 1774.
Oh.! Six.!
No, no, no.
What was signed
in 1776?
Oh, the Declaration
of Independence.
Right.
That other was 1774.
No, it wasn't.
Chief, he doesn't want
to be an American citizen.
He isn't even trying.
Uh, 1780...
1787.
That's right.
But don't just guess.
Memorize it.
Yeah, I do that.
Hey, Chief, coffee ready.
You have some, huh?
# From Casablanca to Bombay
So send me... ##
Hey, Johnson!
What do you got this time?
Bonded date juice.
"Bonded date juice"?
You're gonna go blind
drinking that native stuff.
I might as well with nothing
but you Joes to look at.
That reminds me
of an old gal I met in Omaha.
She was colorblind.
Took her out to buy her
a red dress...
Never mind.
We've all heard that one.
You and your dames.
It's the dyin' truth.
Here.
Oh, no, not me.
I wouldn't touch that
with a bayonet.
- What are you doing
with my rifle?
- Now, drink!
[Coughing]
[Coughing Continues]
Now hold it on me
so I can have one.
This stuff don't smell right.
You don't suppose that
connivin' first sergeant...
He knew I had it.
Knock it off so a guy
can get some sleep, will you?
##[Bugle Call]
Mail call! Mail call!
Here we go
for the "DearJohn" roundup!
Stevens.!
Right here.!
Arthur.!
Yo.!
Jacobs.!
Here.!
You know about mail call?
Casano.!
Yep.!
I don't think my mail...
has caught up
with me yet.
Oh, too bad.
Brooks.!
Here.!
Cooper.!
Yeah.
Gomez.!
Here.
Eisenburg.
Uh-huh.
Davis.!
Oh, Brandon.
Dugan.!
Yo.!
You dropped
something.
Everett.!
[Murphy]
Family?
They were once.
Harper.!
Roger.!
Sir, Private Murphy reports
to the company commander
as ordered.
Lieutenant Harris,
3rd Platoon leader.
Murphy.
We've been
looking over your file.
"Spent the first week
of basic training
in the hospital:
Reaction
from inoculations. "
Yes, sir. L-I'd never
had any shots before.
"Spent most of the trip over
in sick bay."
Yes, sir.
L-I'd never been
on the ocean before.
Well, there were a lot
of other guys in there with me.
"Requested transfer
to paratroops.
Denied due
to physical deficiencies."
It was a mistake assigning you
to a rifle company,
and I'm going to see
that you're reassigned.
But, sir,
I asked for a combat outfit.
I don't want anything else.
Well, except for the jumps,
duty with us is just as rugged
as a paratrooper's.
The captain's trying
to do you a favor.
I know that, sir, but...
I don't want any favors.
I don't want to be transferred.
All right.
I believe in giving
a man a chance.
Especially if he wants one
as bad as you do. That's all.
Feisty pup,
isn't he?
Yeah, but he's got
a good side to him.
Did you notice?
Practically all his pay
goes for bonds in the name
of an older sister.
It looks like he signed
for every educational course
we've got during training.
He's got the spirit,
but, in action,
it's gonna take
two strong men
to take care of him.
# I wouldn't give a bean #
#To be a fancy pants Marine #
# I'd rather be
a dogface soldier like I am #
# I wouldn't trade my old O.D. S
for all the Navy's dungarees #
# For I'm the walking pride
of Uncle Sam #
# On all the posters
that I read, it says #
#The Army builds men #
# So they're tearing me down
to build me over again #
# I'm just a dogface soldier
with a rifle on my shoulder #
#And I eat a Kraut
for breakfast every day #
# So feed me ammunition #
# Keep me in the 3rd Division #
#Your dogface
soldier boy's okay ##
[Cheering]
[Men Laughing, Talking]
Hey, that connivin'
first sergeant must have
been here too!
[Men Laughing]
[Johnson] Come on, honey,
have a slug of this stuff.
It won't hurt you a bit.
Honest. This is good for you.
It picks up your whole attitude.
[Soldier]
A toast to the one and only
3rd Division.!
[Men Cheering]
Turn on the radio
so we can dance!
Can you jitterbug?
- [Soldier] Little Texas.!
- One day, I was drivin' along...
Hey, Little Texas,
where you been?
I went to Alaska
on a vacation.
Hey, that's great.
You must need something
to warm you up.
Come on. I got
just the thing to do it.
Hey, Cleopatra!
Come here! Come here!
I want you to meet
a friend from Alaska.
He owns a gold mine.
Would you like
to dance with me?
[Laughing]
I'm not very good at it.
If Cleo can't teach you,
nobody can!
##
[Radio Announcer
Speaking French]
[French Continues]
[Women Cheering, Shouting]
What's all
the excitement
about?
The Germans have surrendered
in Tunisia!
Did I hear right?
Africa's all ours?
That's what
she said!
Hey, talk about luck!
With us about to move
into the line!
All that training for nothing!
We'll be goin' home!
[Men Cheering]
"Goin' home," he says.
That's where
we're goin'.
I just didn't know
we had to take Sicily
to get there.
To hell and back,
that's where this
outfit's goin'.
General Patton was just
tellin' me the other day,
[Imitating Patton]
"You boys think that Fedela
landin' was somethin',
"you just wait
till the next one.
It'll be so rough,
they'll be haulin' dog tags
back by the truckload."
Shut up, Johnson.
You're scarin' us to death.
It's the dyin' truth, son.
Hey, Murphy...
I'd unfasten
that chin strap
if I were you.
Why?
The first time a shell
goes off anywhere near you,
the concussion
will blow your helmet off,
your head with it.
How do you keep it on?
[Brandon]
Half the time, you don't.
One of us better stick with him
when we hit the beach.
The way I see it,
after we take Sicily,
we'll hit the Italian mainland.
That's when this war
gets real personal with me...
because I'll be liberating
my ancestral home.
Home? Weren't you
born in Flatbush?
Sure, I was.
But my mother was born
in Naples. I promised her
I'd look up the family.
If I get there in one piece,
I'll bet they'll greet me
like a conquering hero.
Sure, they'll put your statue
right next to Mussolini's.
[Laughs]
I'm gonna fix you guys spaghetti
like you never had before,
with my own Valentino sauce.
Hey, Kovak, will you
let me use your stove?
By George,
you get your own.
Everybody think they're
so smart they throw
their stoves away.
I keep mine.
No, this is for Chief and me.
[Officer]
All right, you guys,
check your gear and get ready.
Come on, Little Texas.
You stick with me.
How did you like
the rough landing
Johnson was yellin' about?
He never got the right dope
in his life!
Murphy, you see
how lucky you were
to land in the 3rd?
When theJerries heard
this division was comin',
they headed for Berlin!
Yeah, I'll bet.
I never thought the first day
would be this easy.
[Murphy]
They got the lieutenant.!
Steiner,
take three men and see
what we're up against.
Right.
Johnson, Brandon, Murphy.
[Gunfire Continues]
Is it rough enough
for you yet, Murphy?
[Gunfire Continues]
I figure there's only one
machine gun up there.
Right?
Yeah.
I'll get word
back to Klasky.
Keep 'em busy.
[Gasping]
[Gunfire Continues]
Where does he think
he's going?
I'm supposed
to take care of him?
Hey, you think you got
a private war?
No, I think there's enough
to go around.
[Enemy Gunfire Continues]
Keep low, Brandon!
[Gunfire Continues]
[Enemy Gunfire Resumes]
Stay there!
This more the way
you figured the first day
would be like, Murph?
Somewhat.
Relax.
Get through the first
three or four days,
you'll be just like us.
That's what it means
to be a veteran:
You're scared all the time.
I didn't notice you
being too scared.
Just crazy,
standing up like that.
I had to take care
of you, didn't I?
[Laughs]
[Narrator]
War, to the foot soldier,
is a continual fight
for a few yards of dirt...
that always seem
to lie ahead ofhim,
to be taken from the enemy
or to be held at all costs.
Why? As often as not
he doesn't know...
in regard
to the overall campaign.
On Sicily,
all he knew was that he took
the entire island in 38 days.
What he had accomplished
gave the Allies...
a giant base of operation
close to the Italian mainland.
Hey, you guys,
you know what we've been doing
the last few weeks?
I want to forget.
We've been "advancing
against light resistance...
and squeezing the last
of the enemy forces off Sicily."
What do you know!
And our spirits are high!
Speaking of high spirits,
you know what this jug cost?
In Tennessee, I could have
gotten a fifth of bourbon...
3rd Platoon.!
On your feet!
We got a new lieutenant.
I hope he's luckier
than the last one.
As you were, men.
I'm Lieutenant Manning.
I've been told that
Sergeant Klasky here...
has been handling the platoon
for quite a while now.
He's been doing a good job
so there won't be any changes,
at least for the time being.
Any news from up above,
Lieutenant?
Yeah.
The 36th Division
and the British 10th Corps
has landed at Salerno.
They're having a rough go of it.
Looks like we're a cinch
to be going across too.
Why us? We took
enough beatin' already.
The 36th is a Texas outfit.
Somebody's gotta
give them a hand.
[Men Laughing]
They were doing all right
till they started
draftin' you Yankees.
[Men Laughing]
At ease. I've got
a special order here.
One promotion.
Murphy to corporal.
I don't want
any stripes.
I didn't hear anybody ask you
if you wanted them or not.
All right, that's all.
Why'd he pick on me?
You ought to get the promotions.
You've been in this outfit
longer than I have.
When you've been
in the outfit
as long as we have,
you learn how to avoid
these things, Corporal.
Don't feel bad, Murph.
We recommended you, so you
could lead us on to victory.
[Laughing]
Hey, you guys,
welcome to sunny Italy,
the beautiful home
of my ancestors!
How come there wasn't
any brass band to meet you
back at the beach?
When we hit Naples, I'll get
the big greeting, and you'll
get your spaghetti dinner.
[Johnson]
How's it been going, Mac?
Been a bit sticky.
Glad to let you chaps
have a go at it.
Looks like
Jerry's making his stand
at the Volturno River.
How do you know?
The blokes blew out
the blasted bridges!
Have a good time.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
Sure looks peaceful,
don't it?
That's what
I don't like about it.
LfJerry's over there,
he's sure invisible.
He's over there, all right.
They've already blown
the bridge, Lieutenant.
[Klasky]
Hey, Lieutenant.!
They want you
for battalion briefing.
After dark we'll move down
close to the river and dig in.
Gentlemen, our mission here
is a diversionary one.
We're to make the enemy
think that the main effort
will take place here.
Actually, the 7 th Regiment
will be the attacking force.
They'll go across
upriver from us.
Captain Marks, Baker Company
will start things off.
River like this
reminds me of an old gal I knew
in Perth Amboy, New Jersey.
Had a pet seal.
She was a beautiful thing.
- The seal?
- No, the girl.
[Murphy]
Sure is quiet.
Jerry must know we're over here.
Be more natural if he opened up.
Why open up tonight
and get ten of us...
when they can catch a hundred
in the middle of the river?
It's none of my business,
but you got something
on your mind?
It's nothin'.
Thinkin' about home?
Yeah.
About my little girl,
my ex-wife.
Sometimes I think I got
my mind rid of her, but...
when it gets quiet like this,
she keeps coming back.
How come you busted up?
We were still in school
when we got married.
Then the baby came.
I had to give up school
and work full-time.
I began blamin' them for all
the big things that I'd planned
that weren't pannin' out.
I just walked out on them.
"Walked out on them"?
A guy with your guts?
I sure did.
Did she get married again?
I don't know why,
but she hasn't yet.
Sounds like maybe you ought
to try patching things up
when you get back home.
Maybe it's better
if I don't make it.
Oh, knock off that kind of talk.
I fouled up once.
Who can say
I wouldn't foul up again
if she gave me another chance?
I'll say you wouldn't.
Thanks, Murph.
Say, what are
your postwar plans?
I think I'll let the Army
do my planning for me.
Think I'll stay in.
[Klasky Whispers Loudly]
Hey, Murphy.!
The lieutenant
wants to see you.
That Klasky...
Learned to whisper
in a sawmill.
We gotta get a combat patrol
across the river
and stirJerry up.
Do you think that squad
of yours can cut it?
Give it
a good try, sir.
All right.
Move out as soon
as you're ready.
What's goin' on?
Nothin' much.
What do you mean,
"Nothin' much"?
Oh, I almost forgot.
Klasky wants to see you
at the C.P.
What about?
I don't know, but you better
get yourself up there.
[Soldiers Speaking German]
[Murphy]
Get that flare.!
Back out of here!
Open up!
[Gunfire Continues]
Klasky didn't want me.
How come you left me behind?
'Cause I got sentimental?
No, 'cause you take
too many chances.
"Too many chances"?
Look, you take care of you,
and I'll take care of me.
Remember?
I ought to let you
freeze to death.
I might anyway.
[Vehicles Approaching]
[Engines Idling]
Sounds like the patrol
worked, Murph.
They're really moving
motorized stuff in.
At 0500 we'll open up
with small arms fire.
The 7 th will move across
at the same time.
I'm sure theJerries will
throw some entertainment
our way too.
You can count on it,
Lieutenant.
Yeah.
Just sitting here
being a target isn't my idea
of how to start a day.
You ever think of resigning?
Who'd win the war if I did?
[Chuckles]
Baker Six,
this is Baker Three.
[Gunfire Continues]
[Shell Explodes]
[Gunfire, Shelling
Continue]
[Shell Explodes]
[Gunfire Continues]
Medics!
[Gasping]
Get Klasky.
He and Jones
are both dead, sir.
[Marks On Radio]
Baker Three.! Baker Three.!
Baker Three,
this is Baker Six.!
[Shell Explodes]
Baker Three!
Corporal Murphy speaking!
Isn't Manning
down there now, Murphy?
Lieutenant Manning's
been hit pretty bad, sir,
and Sergeant Klasky's dead.
You'll have to take charge
of the platoon.
We're still taking
a pretty bad pounding, sir!
Shall we pull back?
Stay where you are.
Increase your fire if possible.
The 7 th is about ready to cross.
[Shelling Continues]
[German]
TheJerries have shifted
the artillery onto the 7 th.
However, they are across
and in good shape,
so get moving!
Yes, sir!
The 7 th made it!
Come on!
[Narrator]
For the next couple of months,
the 3rd Division
continually engaged the enemy.
As usual, the foot soldier
wasn't concerned with why.
His greatest concerns were
a vicious German defense,
the fact that Italy was
one mountain after another...
and that weather conditions
were impossible.
These elements, combined,
finally brought the Allied
advance to a stop at Cassino.
Hey, watch what you do!
Why don't you
put a sign up?
I put a sign on your face!
All right,
break it up, you two!
We got enough trouble
without this kind!
You clumsy fool.
Kick over my stove.
We better
keep an eye on Kovak.
He's gettin' a little edgy.
He any different
than the rest of us?
Who isn't?
[Soldier]
Look who's here.
Lieutenant Manning.!
Hello, Lieutenant.
It's good to see you.
Kerrigan.
We figured
you'd be married
to a nurse by now.
Good to have you back, sir.
Thanks, Murphy.
Nice to be back.
I've got some good news
for you men.
We're moving back
to a rest area near Naples.
Naples!
I was beginning to think
we missed it for good.
Do they think we're
getting soft, Lieutenant?
We've only been in the line
two months solid.
I know.
After medical inspections,
there'll be some passes.
What do they think
we got, mud sores?
[Laughing]
A few weeks
of easy soldiering...
while we get replacements
and new equipment.
Then we're going to practice up
on amphibious tactics.
- What you think this is?
- [Men Chuckling]
I've got some more news
for a couple of you.
Promotions.
Murphy to sergeant.
Hey, Sarge!
Johnson
to corporal.
Did you buck me
into that?
I have a request, sir.
What is it?
I'd like to change
to another squad.
With Johnson
heading this one,
the war is lost.
[Chuckling]
Oh, yeah?
Forget the war.
Imagine, 12 hours
in bella Napoli.!
Oh, at the speed
of one woman per hour!
Yow!
You guys can have the town.
I'm gonna stay in camp and see
what some real sleep is like.
Would you like
my mashed potatoes?
There will be trucks
leaving this corner for camp
tomorrow morning at 6:00.
If we're not here,
don't wait for us, Mac.
We've got ground to cover.
I sure wish I could
do the town with you,
but I promised my mother
I'd look up her family.
You really got
relatives here?
Sure.
You don't think
I'd give my extra G.I. Shoes
to anybody else, do you?
These are worth
their weight in gold.
Take it easy.
I'll see you in the morning.
Good luck, Val.
All right, let's move out.
Oh, pardon me!
Sergeant Murphy,
CorporalJohnson.
[Groans]
[Johnson Laughs]
I can see Valentino now.
Big family reunion.
Valentino kicks open the door,
tosses in the grenade...
and then counts ten
before he enters
the old homestead.
By George, he do that!
That only way he know how go
in house anymore!
It should be right down
the end of this street
and around the corner.
Hey, Joe, no papa, no mama.
Hey, Joe, you want a fried egg?
You want a beef steak?
No, thank you.
Hey, you got
a cigarette?
You give me
one cigarette?
You're too young
to smoke.
For my papa.
One cigarette for my papa.
Hey, "no papa."
Remember?
No cigarette?
No cigarette.
How about this?
How about you?
You want a chocolate?
No grazia.
Boy, they sure picked
a great time to be born,
didn't they?
By George, they no start
Hitler's war. Look!
Look what it does
to them.!
Well, we didn't
start it either.
Let's get rolling.
I don't want
see this no more.
It makes me
think of Poland.
I go back camp.
It'll do you good
to blow off steam!
Come on, Kovak!
I know what I want do!
Got him pretty good,
hasn't it?
Let's not let it
spoil things.
Let's go!
You stick with me,
Little Texas.
Man, I invented women!
##
[Crowd Laughing,
Chattering]
##
Hey, what is this?
These fly-boys got a corner
on all the livestock?
"Livestock"?
Oh, aye!
They're stationed here.
And they got the medals
to charm 'em.
Maybe the infantry
can tear that charm
down a little.
Hey, dogfaces!
[Whistles]
##
# Into the air, Junior Birdmen #
#Into the air
Boy Scouts too #
Junior Birdmen #
#And keep your nose
up in the blue #
# Up in the blue #
- #And when they make
that presentation #
- [Speaking Italian]
#And hand out
those wings of tin #
#You, too, can be
a Junior Birdman #
[Italian]
# If you'll send
your box tops in ##
Charge!
[Soldiers Clamoring]
Hello.
[Women Screaming]
[Blowing Whistle]
Break it up!
Come on!
[M.P. Blowing Whistle]
Break it up.! Come on.!
I said, "Break it up!"
What's the matter?
Don't you guys get enough
fighting at the front?
All right,
who started it?
He did.
He didn't like
our singing.
[Italian]
All right, all right!
If he started it,
how come you were mixed up
with the Air Corps?
"Mixed up with the Air Corps"?
Why, they're our pals!
Yeah.
That's right. We've been
sittin' here drinking.
After he started
the trouble, we were so
anxious to stay out of it,
we all headed for the door
at the same time
and got tangled up.
Don't let it
happen again.
Grazia.
Man, that's what I call
a real joint operation!
Drinks on the house!
[Soldiers Cheering,
Chattering]
##
[Soldier]
I can't find my hat.!
Seven and three-quarters!
[Italian]
No, I don't think so.
Come here, baby.
He doesn't
understand women.
Here.
She reminds me
of an old gal
I knew back home.
She was a real beaut.
Comes up to me in a U.S.O.
Club in Nashville.
Takes me ridin'
in a yellow roadster.
We hit a curve doin'
65 miles an hour...
and the cops
take after us.
Says she, "Don't..."
"Don't say a word
while I lay the charm
on these boys."
Hello there.
Can I have a shine,
please?
All right.
I don't seem to have
any money, but, uh...
how about this,
huh?
Grazia.
Vincenzo!
My brother
do not beg,
soldier.
He wasn't begging.
He did a job for me,
and I paid him.
I see what you call job.
You do not let him finish.
Oh, why don't you
let him have it?
Here, I have enough
for all the children.
No.
Well, we tried anyway.
Wait.
There is no begging here,
but...
if you would like to share
our food, then the children
can have your chocolate.
You don't have to do that.
If you are nice to the children,
my mother and I want
to be nice to you.
- Please stay.
- All right.
It's a deal.
[Italian]
[Italian Continues]
I sure wish I knew
what she was saying.
It was nothing.
She was...
[Mother] Maria.
[Air Raid Sirens Blaring,
Mother Shouting Italian]
[Sirens Continue]
Come.
You go with us.
Oh, no.
I'm not spending my first pass
in some bomb shelter.
[Sirens Continue,
Mother Speaking Italian]
[Italian]
Please,
you can't stay here.
You run along.
As soon as the streets clear,
I'll head back for camp.
[Mother]
Maria.!
[Sirens Continue]
[Door Closes]
[Chuckling]
Oh, this is just
what I've been needing.
[Chuckling]
[Italian]
No, no,
don't get the wrong idea.
I've been looking
for a long time
for somebody I could talk to,
and you are it...
because you can't understand
a word I say.
Si, si.
[Sighs]
I want to talk about my girl,
the real one.
She's gonna be my wife
if I get home.
You see, I can't tell my buddies
about the real one.
They'd have to make cracks
about her and say things that
I don't want to hear,
even if they are joking.
Naw, I gotta make up
some wild ones...
for the entertainment
of my buddies.
But you,
I can tell the truth to.
Can't I? Can't I?
[Italian]
[Chuckling]
You just keep it that way,
'cause I'm gonna talk
about my girl all night long.
[Laughs, Sets Down Bottle]
I got an awful lot
to get off my chest.
[Sirens Continue]
Well, what do ya know,
a rug.
I haven't rested
my poor dogface feet
on a rug in two centuries.
Man, I gotta lay my feet
on that rug.
You sit down.
I pour your wine.
I sure will.
[Distant Explosions]
[Sighs]
Man, this is really livin'.
[Shelling Continues]
[Shelling Continues, Louder]
You are crazy
to stay here.
How about you?
Why did you come back?
I do not know.
I'm sorry
I could not talk
to you before,
but my mother
does not like for me
to speak English.
The English have killed
my older brother
in Africa.
Then she must
have hated me too.
No, she do not hate.
But when she hear English,
she think of her son
she love very much.
[Shelling Continues]
I'm sorry.
I'm not anymore.
What good is it?
One cannot feel sorry
for all who die.
It's too much.
[Shelling Continues,
Louder]
My little brother,
Vincenzo, he like
that sound.
He say he is going
to shoot big gun
when he grow up.
I hope he doesn't have to.
Where is your father?
He went away
when bad times come.
He never come back.
Well, I guess we all
want to quit sometimes.
It's hard not to take
the easy way out when it's
right there in front of you.
Why do we talk
of bad things?
It is no good.
[Shelling Continues]
Are you afraid?
All the time.
I, too, am afraid,
but I am glad
I come back.
I am too.
It can be so lonesome
when the bombs fall.
When war is close,
a woman wants someone
to hold.
[Valentino]
The family wanted you guys
for the spaghetti dinner...
after we got back
from the bomb shelter,
but I couldn't find you.
Hope we get you into camp
before the M.P. S spot you...
or you're gonna
be in trouble.
Be in trouble?
Man, where do you
think I've been?
I was rolled by an expert.
Takes an expert to get
old Kerrigan's shoes.
I told you they were
worth their weight in gold.
Hey, Johnson, how come
you're not bragging up that
old gal you were with?
Lost my voice.
Must have been bad wine.
Hey, to keep you
from talkin', I wish
I had a truckload of it.
You should have stuck
with me, Murph.
You've gotta just quit
being scared of women.
[Narrator]
There wasn't much time
to think about women...
because, in a few weeks,
the combined force...
of British, Canadian
and American units
was landed at Anzio...
to bypass and cut off Cassino
and open the road to Rome.
A beachhead only seven miles
in depth was consolidated.
It took everything,
including naval gunfire
support, to hold it...
because five crack
Nazi divisions
were thrown against it, :
Divisions that otherwise
would have opposed the impending
invasion of Normandy.
[Shelling Continues]
Hey, who's Sergeant Murphy?
I'm Murphy.
We're your replacements.
I'm Thompson.
This is Saunders.
I'm Sanchez.
Well, you men picked
a good time to come up.
Find yourself some cover.
I'll be right with you.
[Shelling Continues]
They're blasting Johnson's
squad out of that house,
Lieutenant.
And thoseJerries will be
right on his tail.
Bronson, bring that gun
up here with me!
You men over there, cover 'em!
Give 'em fire!
[Machine Gun Firing]
[Gunfire Continues]
[Shelling Continues]
[Firing Guns]
[Gunfire Continues]
[Shelling,
Gunfire Continue]
Let's get out of here!
[Gunfire Continues]
[Shell Explodes]
We'll never get
out of here!
Take it easy!
We'll never get out of here!
Get down!
[Gunfire Continues]
Jennings, huh?
Yeah.
Didn't last long, did he?
That farmhouse cost us
five casualties already.
Who wants it anyway?
Some general lookin'
for a place in the country?
Why don't you be clever
someplace else.
With Jerry holding
all the high ground,
every company in the line...
fights for a two-story building
for observation purposes.
Just asking.
Sergeant Murphy!
Thompson, Saunders
and Sanchez, Johnson.
Best I can do
for your squad.
What difference does it make?
I'm not gonna be here
to watch over them.
Feel like I'm gonna walk
into one for sure this time.
Knock it off.
Ten to one,
wejump off again.
To hell and back,
that's where we're
jumping off to.
We've been in that
farmhouse five times,
got knocked out six.
The law of averages
got to catch up
with you sometime.
This is Lieutenant Lee,
our new forward observer.
Just in from the beach.
How are things
going there, sir?
It's under artillery fire
and dive-bombers all the time.
Men and equipment gettin'
to shore any better?
It's pretty rough.
We've got to hit that
farmhouse again, Murph.
German tanks have
been spotted moving
into the area.
Wouldn't take many to push us
right back into the ocean.
If we can take that house
in one piece, we might be able
to keep those tanks off you.
We haven't had
too much trouble with them.
They've been held to the road.
The fields have been too muddy
to support them.
If it starts to rain
again, I'll feel better.
We'll get ready to go, sir.
I never thought I'd hear
a foot soldier ask for rain.
I make some coffee,
then, by George, I go back,
I kill all Germans.
You better make it
good and strong.
All right, you guys,
we got to hit her again.
Again?
What did I tell you?
You new men
drop your packs here.
Oh, sure.
[Shell Explodes]
[Shelling Continues]
You all right?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
When it cuts loose,
stick with us older men.
"Older men"?
A couple of days,
you'll be as old
as we are.
Okay, on your feet.
Let's go.
[Shelling Continues]
Set your gun up
behind that wall over there.
Yes, sir.
[Machine Gun Firing]
You men stick
with the first squad.
[Shelling, Gunfire Continue]
Keep working on that
second-story window.
Murph! Murph! I'm hit!
Murphy!
[Gunfire Continues]
Where is it?
My back!
I'm bleedin' to death.
I can feel it!
You clown, get moving.
Murph, you can't leave a man!
They shot my back clean off!
All they did was
spoil your lunch.
Well, I'll be a dirty name.
[Both Laughing]
Hey, give me back
my Thompson, will you?
All right,
you guys over there,
get ready to go!
You stay here and make sure
those artillery people
get up there all right.
Hey, wait a minute!
Cover us, Johnson!
We're going in!
[Firing Gun]
[Gunfire Continues]
All right, you men!
Get moving! Come on!
[Groans]
[Machine Gun Firing]
[Gunfire Continues]
[Pipe Clattering]
[Hinges Creaking]
Man, that's the first time
I ever saw a Texan beat himself
to the draw.
You say one word about this
to the other guys, and I'll
turn this loose on you.
Don't you
go blabbing either.
[Gunfire Continues]
That machine gun's
on the other side of the house.
Let's go get it!
[Machine Gun Firing]
[Gunfire Continues]
Kovak, hurry up!
[Firing Gun]
[Gunfire Continues]
[Gasps]
It's no use, Chief.
You'll get yourself killed too.
What's going on?
He'll be all right
in a minute. Kovak.
[Gunfire Continues]
Must be the same gun
that got Lieutenant Manning.
We'd better get it, Murph.
Stay right where you are.
Our orders were to take
this house and hold it.
Why did Manning have
to come back anyway?
He didn't have to come back.
I guess he figured
the platoon needed him.
[Shell Explodes]
[Tanks Firing]
Crank that thing up before
they blast us out of here!
[Shell Explodes]
Red nine! Red nine!
Five tanks attacking
near eastern junction!
Coordinates: 4-1-8-6-0-3!
Situation urgent!
[Shelling Continues]
Fifty short, 200 right!
One hundred right!
[Explosions Continue]
That's good shootin',
Lieutenant.
[Shelling Continues]
With that tank blocking
the road, they can't get to us,
as long as the field's muddy.
I sure wish it would rain.
Kovak was sure
a good soldier.
You'd have thought
he was fightin' a holy war.
Maybe he was.
Are you nuts?
What did he have to save?
Not even a citizen.
His whole family liquidated
in Poland.
Then maybe he didn't mind dyin'.
Maybe that's what fightin'
for a cause means.
Something none of us
really understands.
[Door Opens]
Look what I found!
A stove! Now we can
have some coffee!
Takes a new guy
to take care
of you fellows.
Wait a minute!
Let him alone!
You expect me to take
that kind of stuff?
What's the matter
with him?
You'll find out... sometime.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Clanking]
Sarge, can you hear
that clanking noise
out there?
[Clanking Continues]
Yes, sir, Jerry was sure nice
to let us borrow the house
from him for the night.
Now tomorrow, if he wants it
back just a little bit,
he'll wake us up with some
of that 88 millimeter stuff;
you know, small caliber.
If he wants it back real bad,
he'll open up old Annie.
Rumor says
its barrel is just short
of a quarter of a mile long,
can use old railroad cars
for shells and a pile driver
for a ramrod.
Did you tell them
about that bean can that
won you the Purple Heart?
[Men Laughing]
Um, yeah, I was just
gettin' around to it.
Three machine guns
lined up on me...
You three guys
just volunteered
to go fight a tank.
What?
I heard them working
on that one that got hit.
If they get it off
that road, we're sunk.
Anything to get away
from this guy.
I better tag along
so you won't miss the ending.
Oh, no, you don't.
Probably see
that theJerries
heard it too.
I'll go, Sarge.
Me too.
We don't need you.
What's eating him?
He was friendly enough
this morning.
Does he have to snap
our heads off just 'cause
we offer to go with him?
He doesn't want you for friends.
That's why he did it.
You see, when you guys have been
in the line as long as we have,
you find out
it's no good to make friends.
Because when a friend gets it,
well, it's rough on you.
The buddies that come with you,
you're stuck with, but you
don't make no new ones.
It's the dyin' truth.
[Clanking]
[Clanking Continues]
They've got
a machine gun
on the right.
You stay here and cover me.
Less chance of noise.
[Whispers]
Hey...
Shh.
As soon as I open up
on those tracks,
let 'em have it.
[Loud Clank]
[German]
[Clanking]
[Clanking Continues]
Hey, you guys
keep your eyes open.
Those fields are really
drying up out there.
Captain.
Nice work
last night,
Murphy.
I'm recommending you
for a decoration.
Well, there were
three other men
with me, sir.
Yes, I know.
They told me the story.
Coffee, Captain?
Hope you can
take it black.
Thanks.
I've been talking
to Colonel Howe.
We want you to take
a battlefield commission.
Oh, no, sir.
I couldn't do that, sir.
You couldn't?
No, sir.
I'm not qualified.
What do you mean?
Education, for one thing.
Another is I'd have to transfer
from the outfit.
That's the rule in this
division, but I still
think you should take it.
I couldn't transfer, sir.
Why not?
It's a hard thing to answer.
Murph, they're moving up
tanks and infantry!
They're trying
to use the fields!
[Shell Explodes]
[Marks]
Lousy break,
those fields drying out.
Pull back
to the old positions.
I'll contact
the other platoons.
Yes, sir.
[Shelling Continues]
Lieutenant Lee,
we're pulling out of here!
Come on!
Get ready to go!
[Explosions Continue]
You did right
turnin' down lieutenant.
Don't ever take it.
If you do, I hope you
get your can shot off!
Thanks a lot!
[Guns, Tanks Firing]
Hey, Murph, looks
like you'll be up
for retirement...
before we get off
this beach.
[Murphy] Don't bank on it!
[Explosions Continue]
What's the matter
with Johnson?
Don't this remind him
of some old gal
he used to know?
Hey, what is wrong
with you?
Just a scratch.
[Coughing]
A silly, little scratch.
It's the dyin' truth.
[Rain Falling]
For one lousy farmhouse.
The trouble is
makin' friends,
learnin' to love guys
like Kovak and Johnson.
Well, isn't it?
I'm sure you'll all agree
that the four months
here on Anzio...
have been the longest
of your lives.
The enemy has played host
with a vengeance.
Every time we've gotten
a division ashore,
he's moved two in to face it.
But we've finally gained
the balance of power over him.
The 1 st Armored Division's
been landed, and we're
going to break out.
We're going
all the way to Rome.
We'll have strong air cover.
We'll mark our own position
with red smoke.
H-Hour is 0500.
Good night, gentlemen.
Captain Marks?
You're still short
a second lieutenant.
I'll see what I can do about it.
I'd rather not have
a new man, sir.
Murphy's one
of the best platoon
leaders I've ever had.
Then why won't he
take a commission?
Something about not wanting
to take responsibility.
He's mixed up because,
instinctively, he does
take it all the time.
The main reason
is he doesn't want
to be transferred.
Maybe we can do something
about that.
Good luck, Marks.
Thank you, sir.
[Airplane Engines Droning]
Look what's coming!
[Kerrigan]
Oh, you beautiful dolls.!
[Gunfire, Shelling Continue]
[Sanchez] I'll lay you
two to one, the Chief traps one.
[Kerrigan] You got a bet.
Hey, you guys,
get a load of this.
"Normandy beaches
fully consolidated.
Allied forces
continue advance."
They're doing all right.
It figures
we'd miss that landing.
Must have been a breeze.
I heard a couple
of officers talking.
With things going so good
in Normandy, we're gonna stay
right here and garrison Rome.
No kiddin'?
What's the matter
with going home?
Home? With all
these Rome women?
Here comes Murph
and the new
90-day wonder.
Men, this is
Lieutenant Burns.
Rest.
You picked a good time
to join us, Lieutenant.
Oh?
I got it from a good source,
we're gonna garrison Rome.
I've got it
from a better source,
we're on orders to move
to the coast tomorrow
for amphibious training.
More of that?
I feel like I got
webbed feet now.
I thought the Marines
were the amphibious experts.
They are, but we're
the only Marines in Italy.
Any idea where
we're goin', sir?
Could be southern France.
[Narrator]
It was southern France.
For the fourth time
in World War II,
the 3rd Division
was about to land
on a hostile shore.
[Bells Ringing]
But this time the foot soldier
knew why he was there.
He knew the enemy, being closed
in on from two sides in France,
was now falling back
toward his own border.
He knew the sooner the enemy
was pushed into Germany,
the sooner the war
would be over.
And this was all he lived for.
[Machine Gun Firing]
[Groans]
[Gunfire Continues]
How bad is he?
He'll go home.
You got
the million-dollar
wound, Chief.
Hey, you timed that just right.
You only had one left.
See what chance we
have to flank that hill.
Yes, sir.
Take a radio so we can be
in contact.
Yes, sir.
You three men right here,
you with the extra radio,
come with me.
[Gunfire]
[Gunfire Continues]
Brandon, this is Burns.
Over. Brandon!
I can't contact Brandon.
Do you think I ought
to send up another patrol?
Why don't you give me
about ten minutes
to check first?
All right. Go ahead.
Sure caught us cold,
Murph.
Yeah.
See if you can get him
on down the hill.
[Gunfire Continues]
Are you trying to win
yourself a wooden cross?
I told you to get down the hill.
Thought you might need this.
Think you've got a corner
on this real estate?
Come on. They can kill us,
but they can't eat us.
That's against the law.
[Firing Guns]
That did it!
Get down Brandon!
[Laughing]
[Shouting]
Why didn't you stay down?
Murph...
[Machine Gun Firing]
[Gunfire Continues]
Come on, Murph, before the rear
echelon catches up with us.
We're being pressured
by Division for being held up.
We've got to get that
German artillery off of us
so we can push through.
They have an observation post
somewhere on Hill 481.
I can back you up
with a couple
of pieces of armor.
Send a platoon out,
and get rid of it.
Right, sir.
You sent for Murphy?
He's on his way, sir.
He can't turn it down this time.
Did you know
he was turned down...
by the Navy, the Marines
and the paratroops?
[Chuckles]
It's not so funny, sir.
I tried
to get him transferred
out of the company...
as being unfit
for combat.
[Soldier]
Sergeant Murphy's here, sir.
Sir, Sergeant Murphy reports
to Battalion Commander
as ordered.
At ease, Murphy.
- How would you like
to go to West Point?
- West Point?
He means it.
Quite a few men
who have shown special
qualifications are being picked.
I talked it over at Regimental,
and we think you ought
to be one of them.
You'll never find
a better break than this.
Sir, it's true I've decided
to stay in the Army, but...
West Point.
I'm not qualified for it, sir.
I didn't even
finish grade school.
The courses you took...
and the coaching
we can give you
will get you through.
After we move
through the Colmar area,
we'll get things rolling.
In the meantime,
you'll take a commission.
But, sir, how about...
You won't have
to transfer.
With the replacement
shortage being what it is,
the rule has been waived.
You are now a gentleman
by act of Congress.
Take a bath, shave...
Well, anyway, take a bath
and get back into the lines.
Thank you, sir.
Congratulations.
Thank you, Captain.
Why is it always
the 3rd Division that
takes the beating?
Yeah, and the closer
we get to the German border,
the tougherJerry's gonna be.
You mean they
can get tougher?
With somebody moving in
on the States, wouldn't you?
[Jeep Departs]
You see what I see?
Well, what do ya know!
Well, congratulations.
It's time you took it, sir.
Shavetail.
I still say you're gonna
get shot right in the...
At ease.
[Chuckling]
Take your cotton-pickin'
hands off me.
From now on, there'll be
a little more respect shown
second lieutenants.
Yes, sir.
And another thing,
I want to thank you two for all
the buckin' you've been doing
for me over the past two years.
Ah, don't mention it, Murph.
Ah, forget it, Murph.
Forget it? Just when
I'm in a position to repay you?
You take over the platoon,
Sergeant Kerrigan.
But I don't want the rank.
I don't deserve it. Give it
to one of the other guys.
I didn't hear anyone
ask you, soldier.
[Sighs]
All right.
That's what I like
in enlisted men: Spirit.
[Laughing]
Sergeant Kerrigan.
What are you laughing
about, Corporal?
Huh?
Oh, not me, Murph.
[Tank Approaching]
Get the platoon ready
to move out.
Yes, sir.
[Engine Idling]
[Idling Continues]
I'm Murphy.
Pierce.
They brief you
back at headquarters?
Just generally.
That German observation post
that's breaking our back...
seems to be located
along this ridge
about five miles up.
It's up to us
to take him out of there.
All right, you men,
from here on down,
get on the first tank.
The rest of you
take the second.
As Platoon Sergeant, I will
assume my proper position.
Your hand, please.
Be my guest,
Corporal Valentino.
Thank you, Sergeant Kerrigan.
Hey, Lieutenant, you tankers
have really got it soft.
This is the way to travel,
with a hundred thousand dollars
worth of machinery under you.
If we run into German Tigers,
you won't think so.
This thing's only got
about four inches of armor.
Oh, yeah?
Say, how thick do you think
this G.I. Shirt is?
[All Laughing]
[German]
Sergeant Kerrigan,
have the men dismount.
All right, you guys,
bail out!
Valentino,
get those men out of here!
Move out!
[Explosions Continue]
See what promotion
does to you.
You lucky son of a gun.
Looks like somebody
just handed you a ticket home.
Who wants to go home?
And I was getting used
to the rank.
[German]
[Engine Idling]
Just to the right
of those trees!
Can you get a few rounds
in there?
[Gunfire]
[Gunfire Continues]
[Engine Idling]
Murphy. Lieutenant Black.
I brought him down
to help you out.
Black.
How are you?
You're gonna
take over the company.
Captain Marks, sir?
His jeep hit a mine.
He's busted up pretty bad.
We're moving
into the Colmar area
immediately.
The battalion objective
is this wooded area...
on the outskirts
of Holtzwihr.
It's heavily defended
because it's Jerry's
last foothold in France.
You can expect them
to throw everything
they've got at you,
but it's got to be taken
at all costs.
When this city's reduced,
there's nothing between us
and the German border.
Able Company will be
on your right flank,
Charlie on your left.
Be in position here
at 0600 and ready
to jump off.
Yes, sir.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
[Phone Rings]
[Tank Idling]
Colonel Howe?
Sir, we're on our objective,
but I haven't been able
to contact the companies
on either flank.
Artillery's delayed them
temporarily.
Any change in orders?
No, you'll attack
in ten minutes.
You'll get
your support.
Yes, sir.
Get the men ready
to jump off.
Yes, sir.
[Shells Exploding]
Should we dig in?
Too late for that now.
We'll never be able
to stay here with 30 men.
Pull back and tie in
with "A" Company.
What about you?
I'm gonna see if I can get
some artillery working.
[Shelling Continues]
Better knock on it.
You two get out of here.
Artillery, I need
a round of smoke...
at coordinate
3-0-5-6-0-1!
What are you
up against?
Five tanks that I can see...
and two reinforced
rifle companies.
Tell thoseJoes
to get the lead out!
One hundred short, 50 right,
and fire for effect!
You're right on the nose!
Keep it coming!
That's good shootin'!
The tanks are heading
for cover!
Give me a correction!
Let's stay on those tanks!
Never mind the tanks!
Let's keep after that infantry!
[Firing Guns]
Are we too close
to you?
Keep firing for effect!
[Gunfire Continues]
How close are they?
Hold the phone,
I'll let you talk to them!
[Gunfire Continues]
He's got more guts
than sense!
That tank is loaded
with gas and ammo!
It'll blow up!
Murph, get outta there!
Murph!
[Gunfire Continues]
[Firing]
[Continues Firing]
[Gunfire Stops]
Murphy, are you...
Keep 'em rollin', Black!
Medic!
Medic, over here!
I'm all right, Val.
Get movin'.
You crazy Irishman,
you ought to be dead!
Well, I'm not,
so get movin'!
Okay, I'll see you, Murph.
Take care of yourself.
And you still owe me
a spaghetti dinner!
Hey, Murph... uh, sir.
You aren't supposed
to be in this ward.
I know, sir, but I've got
to see my old buddy.
You're liable
to get into trouble.
Sir, if I have to,
I can prove I'm a bird colonel
from Intelligence in disguise.
You shanty Irishman.
I figured you'd be
on your way back to the States.
No, not for a while yet.
Where'd you get it?
In the hip.
Wha... But where
did it come out?
[Laughing]
You know where it came out.
I told him where he
was gonna get it.
Didn't I tell ya?
[Laughing]
Sergeant,
you'll have to leave.
Look, sir,
he's a friend of mine.
When he goes to West Point,
I'm gonna open a bar right
across the street.
What's the matter?
What's wrong with a bar?
His wound's going to keep him
out of West Point.
It will probably
put him out of the Army.
Gee, I'm sorry
to hear that, Murph.
It doesn't matter.
You're probably better off
anyway. Let 'em bust you
right back to civilian.
You'll be in big demand
back in the States.
You can pick off a man
at 500 yards with an M-1,
[Chuckles]
You can toss a grenade
further than anybody
in the neighborhood...
and you can bathe
in ditch water!
[Both Laughing]
Sergeant,
roll up your sleeve.
At least I can quiet you
down so my patients
can get their rest.
Okay, sir.
I was just leaving.
I'll be back
and see you later,
Murph, uh, sir!
[Narrator]
On August 9, 1945,
a little more than three years
after his enlistment...
and shortly
after his 19th birthday,
Lieutenant Audie L. Murphy
had fought in seven major
campaigns of World War II.
He had been awarded
three Purple Hearts,
a Bronze Star Medal,
a Bronze Star Medal
with a Bronze Service Arrowhead,
a Legion of Merit,
two Silver Star Medals,
the Distinguished Service Cross, :
And, from the French government,
two Croix de Guerre with Palm
and the Legion of Honor
Chevalier.
On this memorable day
in his life,
he was awarded his country's
highest decoration,
the Congressional
Medal of Honor.
##