kristin:
hey, meredith, it's kristin.
you have to tell me
what happened last night.
call me.
brad:
hey, meredith. brad calling.
listen, do you want
to hook up later?
well, i'll talk to you then.
give me a call. thanks.
brock: hey, meredith,
what's going on? this is brock.
i just wanted to let you know
the gang is gonna get together.
we're gonna go to the garage.
we're gonna have some beers
and some shots.
all right, dean,
this is the place.
i've got to say
dad and me did just fine
without these
stupid costumes.
i feel like
a high-school-drama dork.
what was that play
that you did?
what was it --
"our town"?
yeah, you were good.
it was cute.
look, you want to
pull this off or not?
i'm just saying these outfits
cost hard-earned money.
whose?
ours. you think
credit-card fraud is easy?
thanks for letting us
look around.
the police said they were done
with the place, so...
you guys said
you were with the alarm company?
that's right.
well, no offense,
but your alarm is about
as useful as boobs on a man.
well,
that's why we're here --
to see what went wrong,
to stop it from happening again.
now, ma'am,
you found the body?
yeah.
right after
it happened?
no, a few days later.
meredith's work called.
she hadn't showed up.
i knocked on her door.
that's when i noticed...
the smell.
any windows open?
any sign of break-in?
windows were locked.
front door was bolted.
chain was on the door.
we had to cut it to get in.
and the alarm was
still on?
like i said. bang-up job
your company is doing.
did you see
any overturned furniture,
broken glass,
signs of struggle?
everything was
in perfect condition...
except meredith.
well, what condition
was meredith in?
meredith was all over,
in pieces.
the guy who killed her
must have been a whack job.
but i tell you,
if i didn't know any better,
i'd have said
a wild animal did it.
ma'am, you mind
if we take some time,
give this place
a once-over?
go right ahead.
knock yourself out.
so the killer walks in and out
of the apartment --
no weapons, no prints,
nothing.
i'm telling you,
the minute i found that article,
i knew this
was our kind of gig.
i think
i agree with you.
so, you talked
to the cops?
uh, yeah,
i spoke to amy --
a, uh, charming,
perky officer of the law.
what did you find out?
well, she's a sagittarius.
she loves tequila.
i mean...whew.
oh, and she's got this
little tattoo. dean!
what? yeah.
nothing we don't
already know,
except for one thing they're
keeping out of the papers.
meredith's heart
was missing.
her heart?
yeah, her heart.
so, what do you think
did it to her?
the landlady said
it looked like an animal attack.
maybe it was.
werewolf?
not a werewolf.
the lunar cycle's not right.
if it was a creature,
it would've left
some kind of trace.
it was probably
a spirit.
hmm.
see if you can find
any masking tape around.
ever see
that symbol before?
never.
me, neither.
i talked
to the bartender.
did you get anything...
besides her number?
dude, i'm a professional.
i'm offended that...
all right.
you mind doing
a little bit of thinking
with your upstairs brain,
dean?
hmm? there's nothing
to find out.
meredith worked here.
she waited tables.
everyone here is her friend.
everyone says she's normal.
she didn't do or say anything
weird before she died.
what about that symbol?
did you find anything?
nope. nothing.
it wasn't in dad's journal
or in any of the usual books.
i just have to dig
a little deeper, i guess.
there was a first victim, right,
before meredith?
right, yeah.
his name was, uh...
his name
was ben swardstrom.
last month he was found
mutilated in his town house.
same deal. the door was locked.
the alarm was on.
is there any connection
between them?
nothing i could tell.
ben was a banker.
meredith was a waitress.
they never met,
never knew anyone in common.
they were practically
from different worlds.
so the only successful intel
we've scored
is the bartender's
phone number.
what?
sam?
meg.
sam!
sam, is that you?
oh, my gosh!
[ sighs ]
what are you doing here?
i'm just in town --
visiting friends.
where are they?
well, they're not here
right now,
but what about you, meg?
i thought
you were going to california.
oh, i did.
i came. i saw.
i conquered.
oh, and i met
what's his name --
something michael murray --
at a bar.
who?
it doesn't matter.
anyway,
the whole scene got old,
so i'm living here
for a while.
you're from chicago?
no, massachusetts --
andover.
gosh, sam,
what are the odds
we'd run into each other?
i know. i thought
i'd never see you again.
well,
i'm glad you were wrong.
dude, cover your mouth.
yeah, i'm sorry, meg.
this is, um --
this is my brother, dean.
this is dean?
yeah.
so you've heard of me?
oh, yeah,
i've heard of you.
nice -- the way you
treat your brother like luggage.
sorry?
why don't you
let him do what he wants to do?
stop dragging him
over god's green earth.
meg...it's all right.
[ whistles ]
okay. awkward.
[ chuckles ]
i'm gonna get a drink now.
sam, i'm sorry.
it's just, the way
you told me he treats you,
if it were me,
i'd kill him.
it's all right.
he means well.
we should hook up
while you're in town.
yeah.
i could show you
a hell of a time.
that sounds great.
why don't you
give me your number?
312-555-0143.
you know what?
i never got your last name.
masters.
masters?
so you better call.
scout's honor.
i hope to
see you around, sam.
who the hell we he?
i don't really know.
i only met her once.
meeting up
with her again?
i don't know, man.
it's weird.
what was she saying --
i treat you like luggage?
were you bitching about me
to some chick?
look, i'm sorry, dean.
it was when
we had that huge fight
when i was in the bus stop
in indiana.
is there any truth
to what she's saying?
am i keeping you
against your will, sam?
no, of course not.
now, would you listen?
what?!
i think there's something
strange going on here, dean.
tell me about it.
she wasn't even into me.
no, man, i mean,
like our kind of strange.
maybe even a lead.
why do you say that?
i met meg weeks ago literally
on the side of the road.
now i run into her
in some random chicago bar --
the same bar
where a waitress
was slaughtered
by something supernatural.
you don't think that's
weird? it happens.
well, yeah, it happens,
but not to us.
look, i could be wrong.
i'm just saying there's
something about this girl
that i can't
quite put my finger on.
but i bet you'd like to.
but maybe
she's not a suspect.
maybe you got
a thing for her, huh?
you're thinking too much
with your upstairs brain, huh?
do me a favor.
check and see if there's
a meg masters from massachusetts
and see if you can't
dig anything up on that symbol.
what are you gonna do?
i'm gonna watch meg.
[ laughs ] yeah.
i just want to
see what's what.
all right,
you little pervert.
i'm going. i'm going.
hey.
you're lurking outside
that poor girl's apartment,
aren't you?
no.
yes.
you've got a funny way
of showing your affection.
you find anything
on her or what?
there's a meg masters
in the andover phone book.
i even pulled up
her high-school photo.
now, look, why don't you
go knock on her door
and invite her
to a poetry reading
or whatever it is
you do, huh?
what about the symbol?
any luck?
yeah, that i did have
some luck with.
turns out
it's zoroastrian.
very, very old-school,
like 2,000 years before christ.
it's a sigil for a daeva.
what's a daeva?
it translates
to "demon of darkness" --
zoroastrian demons,
and they're savage, animalistic,
nasty attitudes --
kind of like demonic pit bulls.
how did you
figure that out?
you don't have a corner
on paper chasing around here.
name the last book
you read.
i called dad's friend caleb.
he told me, all right.
anyway,
here's the thing.
these daevas,
they have to be summoned.
so someone's
controlling it?
yeah,
that's what i'm saying.
and from what i gather,
it's pretty risky business, too.
these suckers tend to
bite the hand that feeds them...
and the arms
and the torsos.
what do they look like?
nobody's seen them
for a couple of millennia.
summoning a demon
that ancient,
someone really
knows their stuff.
i think we've got
a major player in town.
why don't you go give that girl
a private strip-o-gram?
bite me.
bite her.
don't leave teeth marks,
though.
sam? are you --
no, no, i'm just --
pervert!
what a creep!
i don't think you should come
because the brothers --
they're in town.
i didn't know that --
yes, sir.
yes, i'll be here...
waiting for you.
what the hell?
dude, i've got to
talk to you.
so, hot little meg
is summoning the daeva?
it looks like
she was using that black altar
to control the thing.
so sammy's got a thing
for the bad girl.
and what's the deal
with that bowl again?
she was talking
into it --
the way witches used to scry
into crystal balls.
she was communicating
with someone.
with the daeva? no, you said
those things were savages.
no, this was
someone different,
someone who's
giving her orders,
someone who's coming
to that warehouse.
holy crap.
what?
what i was gonna tell you
earlier.
i pulled a favor with my...
[ clears throat ]
...friend amy
over at the police department.
complete records
of the two victims.
we missed something
the first time.
what?
the first victim --
the old man?
he spent his whole life
in chicago,
but look where he was
born. lawrence, kansas.
mm-hmm.
meredith --
the second victim?
it turns out
she was adopted.
and guess
where she's from?
holy crap.
yeah.
i mean, that is
where the demon killed mom.
you think meg's tied up
with the demon?
i think
it's a definite possibility.
what's the significance
of lawrence?
and how do
these daeva things fit in?
i say we trash
that black altar, grab meg,
and have ourselves
a friendly little interrogation.
no, we can't.
we shouldn't tip her off.
we've got to stake out
that warehouse.
we've got to see who...or what
is showing up to meet her.
i'll tell you one thing.
i don't think
we should do this alone.
we think
we've got a serious lead
on the thing
that killed mom.
so, uh, this warehouse --
it's 1435 west erie.
dad, if you get this,
get to chicago
as soon as you can.
voice mail?
yeah.
jeez. what'd you get?
[ sighs ]
i ransacked that trunk --
holy water, y weapon
that i could think of.
exorcism rituals from about
a half-dozen religions.
i'm not sure
what to expect,
so i guess we should
just expect everything, huh?
it's a big night.
yeah.
you nervous?
no. no, are you?
no. no way.
god, could you imagine
if we actually
found that damn thing,
that demon?
let's not get
ahead of ourselves, all right?
i know. i'm just saying...
what if we did?
what if this whole thing
was over tonight?
man,
i'd sleep for a month,
go back to school,
just be a person again.
you want to
go back to school?
yeah, once we're done
hunting the thing.
why? is there something wrong
with that?
no, no, it's great.
good for you.
i mean, what are you gonna do
when it's all over?
it's never gonna
be over.
there's gonna be others.
there's always
gonna be something to hunt.
but there's got to be something
that you want for yourself.
i don't want you to leave
the second this is over.
dude,
what's your problem?
why do you think
i drag you everywhere, huh?
i came and got you at stanford?
'cause dad was
in trouble.
'cause you wanted to
find the thing that killed mom.
yes, that,
but it's more than that, man.
you and me and dad --
i want us
to be together again.
to be a family again.
dean, we are a family.
i'd do anything for you.
but things will never
be the way they were before.
they could be.
i don't want them
to be.
i'm not gonna
live this life forever.
dean,
when this is all over,
you're gonna have to let me
go my own way.
guys. hiding is a little bit
childish, don't you think?
that didn't work out
like i'd planned.
why don't you come out?
sam, i have to say,
this puts a real crimp
in our relationship.
yeah,
tell me about it.
so, where's your
little daeva friend?
around.
and that shotgun's
not gonna do much good.
oh, don't worry,
sweetheart.
the shotgun's
not for the demon.
so, who is it, meg?
who's coming?
who are you waiting for?
you.
hey, sam,
don't take this the wrong way,
but your girlfriend...
is a bitch.
this, the whole thing,
was a trap.
running into you
at the bar,
following you here,
hearing what you had to say --
it was all a setup,
wasn't it?
and that the victims were
from lawrence.
it doesn't
mean anything.
it was just to draw you in,
that's all.
you killed those two people
for nothing.
baby, i've killed a lot more
for a lot less.
you trapped us.
good for you.
it's miller time.
why don't you kill us
already?
not very quick on the uptake,
are we?
this trap isn't for you.
dad.
it's a trap for dad.
oh, sweetheart,
you're dumber than you look.
'cause even if dad was in town,
which he is not,
he wouldn't walk
into something like this.
he's too good.
he is pretty good,
i'll give you that.
but you see...
...he has one weakness.
what's that?
you.
he lets his guard down
around his boys,
lets his emotions
cloud his judgment.
i happen to know
he is in town,
and he'll come
and try to save you.
and then the daevas
will kill everybody --
nice and slow...
and messy.
well,
i've got news for you.
it's gonna take a lot more
than some...shadow to kill him.
oh, the daevas
are in the room here.
they're invisible.
their shadows are
just the only part you can see.
why are you
doing this, meg?
what kind of deal
you got worked out here, huh...
and with who?
i'm doing this
for the same reasons
you do what you do --
loyalty, love.
like the love you had
for mommy...and jess.go to he
baby, i'm already there.
[ sighs ]
come on, sam.
there's no need
to be nasty.
i think we both know...
how you really feel
about me.
you know...
...i saw you...
watching me...
changing
in my apartment.
it turned you on,
didn't it?
get a room, you two.
i didn't mind.
i liked that
you were watching me.
come on, sammy,
you and i can still
have a little dirty fun.
you want to have fun?
go ahead, then.
i'm a little tied up
right now.
now, were you
just trying to distract me
while your brother
cuts free?
no.
it was because
i have a knife of my own.
sam!
get the altar.
[ chuckles ]
so, i guess the daevas
didn't like
being bossed around.
i guess not.
hey, sam?
hmm?
next time
you want to get laid,
find a girl that's
not so buckets of crazy, huh?
why don't you just
leave that stuff in the car?
i said it before,
and i'll say it again --
better safe than sorry.
hey!
dad.
hey, boys.
hi, sam.
hi, dad.
dad, it was a trap.
i didn't know.
i'm sorry.
it's all right.
i thought it might have been.
were you there?
i got there just in time to see
the girl take the swan dive.
she was the bad guy,
right?
yes, sir.yes, sir.
good. well,
it doesn't surprise me.
it's tried
to stop me before.
the demon has?
it knows i'm close.
it knows i'm gonna kill it.
not just exorcise it
or send it back to hell,
actually kill it.
how?
i'm working on that.
let us come with you.
we'll help.
no, sam.
not yet.
listen,
try to understand.
this demon
is a scary son of a bitch.
i don't want you
caught in the crossfire.
i don't want you hurt.
you don't have to
worry about us.
of course i do.
i'm your father.
listen, sammy,
the last time we were together,
we had one hell
of a fight.
yes, sir.
it's good
to see you again.
it's been a long time.
too long.
no!
these things
are shadow demons,
so let's light 'em up!
dad!
over here!
come on!
all right, come on.
we don't have much time.
as soon as the flare's out,
they'll be back.
wait, wait!
sam, wait.
dad, you can't come
with us.
what? what are you
talking about?
we'll be all right.
dean, we should stick together!
we'll go after those --
sam, listen to me!
we almost got dad killed
in there.
don't you understand?
they're not gonna stop.
they're gonna try again.
they're gonna use us
to get to him.
i mean, meg was right.
dad's vulnerable
when he's with us.
he...he's stronger
without us around.
dad...
no.
after everything,
after all the time
we spent looking for you,
please.
i've got to be a part
of this fight.
sammy, this fight is
just starting,
and we are all gonna have
a part to play.
for now, you've got to
trust me, son.
okay? you've got to
let me go.
be careful, boys.
come on.