Previously on The Strain...
Looks like a dead animal.
There have been 200 people
sitting there silently,
- absolutely no movement.
- Oh, my God...
- Are you seeing this?
- They're all dead.
- No signs of struggle.
- (Gasping)
- We've got survivors!
- I've seen this disease before.
If you have the coffin,
then you still have him?
You will cross the bridge back
into Manhattan before daybreak.
You will be let through.
Seal off the perimeter of the airport.
Got it. I said let him through.
(growling)
Ah!
_
♪♪♪
(meowing)
(making kissy sounds)
Hi. Mm-hmm!
(rap song in Spanish)
_
Hey yo, Waxy Boy!
Waxy Boy, I got your box!
Oh!
What you got there, white boy?
(rumbling noise)
(growling)
♪♪♪
sync and corrected by caioalbanezi
www.addic7ed.com
- (helicopter sound)
- _
His lanyard says his name is Peter Bishop,
an ATC supervisor. You knew him?
Where is his head?
That is his head.
I thought you guys were
used to shit like this.
He's not a doctor.
It would take a lot of pressure
to crush his skull like
that. What did this?
The tower said he came down here with you.
He was helping us look for a large cabinet
from Regis 753 that went missing.
What was in it?
We think it was some
sort of infectious agent.
You mean whatever killed
the people on that plane?
We don't know that.
I mean, it's just a theory
at this point. Right?
Ammonia.
- Just like on the plane.
- Hey, one of you got an ALS?
Kill the work lights.
What is that stuff?
Biological discharge.
Closest analogue is guano.
That or tick shit.
That's one hell of a tick.
(cell phone ringing)
Goodweather.
Jim, what's the matter with you?
Long night. No sleep.
Maybe too much coffee.
Goddamn it! I don't care
what he said! Just stall them.
Lose their clothes. I don't
care, just keep them there
till we get there. We have to go.
This crime scene is
now under CDC authority.
Nobody touches that body.
Barnes just released the four survivors.
You don't need a cab. My
driver will drop you off.
I'm sorry, folks, but
you're not going anywhere.
Spare yourself the crucifixion.
You don't have a chance in
hell of making that stick.
You still think it's some super flu, Doc?
Haven't you seen the news?
Someone leaked the Regis Air
documents to the internet.
It's carbon monoxide
poisoning. All of it covered up
by the airline's CEO, Daniel Flaxton.
You should be relieved, Doctor.
It's out of your hands.
Now if you don't mind,
- I've got a lawsuit to file.
- You believe everything on TV?
Holy Jesus, is this man
annoying. We're fine.
We're all fine. No thanks to you, Doc.
Feeling fine at this moment
does not mean you're not sick.
- Diseases incubate.
- Look, I get it.
This is your time in the spotlight.
To snag a promotion. Love to help,
but I've got a major concert
on the day of the eclipse, so...
I need to go. I do.
If it were up to me, I'd stay,
but my union lawyers want me out, so...
We're going around in circles
here. Let me be very clear:
you're all staying here under
quarantine on my authority.
Director Barnes said we would be released.
And I say you stay. I
don't care what Barnes said.
According to the Health Powers Act,
it only takes two physicians
to issue a quarantine order.
It's on. One phone call, I get your job.
- And Little Miss Muffet's.
- You better start dialing then.
Dialing. Katie, it's Joan.
Get me the Secretary of Health
and Human Services, Margaret Pierson.
At a press conference last night,
Dr. Ephraim Goodweather,
chief medical officer
with the Centers for Disease
Control in New York City,
said it was too early
- in his investigation...
- This could be a problem.
The CDC has closed the airport.
They have still not released the survivors.
If they continue to
treat this as an epidemic,
- it will delay our timetable.
- In an hour,
nobody will be talking about an epidemic.
And I'll have the four
survivors on the street.
You will accomplish this how?
Disinformation.
A good story always trumps the truth.
Just give the press a villain to hate.
Now that this is done,
when do I see him?
Soon.
He's across the river. That was our deal.
You will see him soon.
Where are you going?
To see an old friend.
I personally read all 250 pages
of the Regis documents.
As sh
by the airline's flagrant disregard
for the safety of its passengers.
Abraham Setrakian.
Your lawyer's here to see you.
I have no lawyer.
You've grown old,
A230385.
Eichorst...
- Surprised to see me?
- It has been many years.
You look exactly the same.
Your heartbeat is irregular.
I can hear it, Jew,
clear as a bell.
Did the coffin cross the river?
What do you think?
And where is your Master now?
Watching you through me.
The great game is over, Jew.
Not while I still breathe.
Amazing.
Despite all evidence to the contrary,
you cling to the delusion
that you will prevail.
Don't tell me you still believe
in that God of yours.
So where is He?
Why has He done nothing?
Face the truth.
He is nothing but a
figment of your imagination.
Your arrest report says
you were apprehended
with an antique sword.
- Is it Sardu's?
- Don't worry.
I will give it back to
your Master in due time.
That is amusing.
And her heart...
Do you still have that as well?
Oh, you are such a sentimentalist.
You might like to know this.
She struggled at the very end,
but she never cried out.
I thought that strange. Not even a whimper.
Only a single word.
"Abraham."
But you were not there
to help her.
Do you feel great regret?
I will avenge her.
You will not avenge anyone.
You're not a hero or a savior.
You're just a number.
I took your name and gave you that number.
That's all you are.
It's good for you that you are in here.
It's the only place you can feel safe.
Safer than the streets will be very soon.
You might survive
a little longer.
I want you
to watch it unfold, unable to do anything
to stop it.
And when you die,
it will be the Master's eyes
you see last...
Remember your old friend,
Dreverhaven?
Would you like to know why
he isn't here to share your glory with you?
Because I cut him to pieces with that sword
and dumped his parts
in the North Sea.
I'll see that you're reunited with him
very soon.
Until next time...
A230385.
- (news bulletin on TV)
- _
(door opening)
Mama, I home!
She's getting ready for Mass.
Why don't you clean your shit up?
Shh! Listen.
- Plane coming in wit those stiffs on it?
- What did I say?
Huh?
- You think I'm playing with you?
- Hola, mijo.
Hola, mami!
Como estas? Mira, que
linda! You look beautiful.
You look... terrible.
Oh, mijo. I don't like you
working nights like this.
It's not good for you.
- I know.
- Come to Mass with me.
Father Cortez has been asking about you.
I can't, Mama, I gotta get some sleep.
Next week.
Did you see what Crispin got me?
No, I didn't see it.
(chuckling excitedly)
Wow...
That's a nice piece.
Where'd you get it, bro?
Flea market.
Was a real steal. Old lady
didn't know what she had.
So good to have my two kids together again.
Your both will here for dinner?
- Si, Mama.
- I'll make something special.
- OK.
- Bye!
- Bye, Mommy, I love you.
- I love you too!
Where'd you get it? Huh?
Where d'you get it? The truth,
you junkie piece of shit!
Huh? Huh?
The pawn shop a couple blocks
down! The Jew who buys silver.
You don't bring stolen shit into this house
- and involve Mom on it.
- OK!
- You hear me?
- Yes!
You know, Gus, you got some balls
talking to me like that.
Two years.
Two years I listened to her
cry herself to sleep at night
while you were upstate.
I was the only one who was here for her!
You were shooting her
paychecks up your arm.
- OK, you got me.
- Yeah, I got you.
OK. But what about you, Gus, huh?
- What about me?
- How you long is it gonna be
before you get busted again
and break her heart? Huh?
I'm taking this clock back.
That's not gonna work you ***  , altar boy!
You contradicted my explicit orders
and declared them quarantined.
You can't release those survivors.
Not till we know what we're facing.
We do know. Let me introduce you
to the Secretarof Health
and Human Services,
Margaret Pierson.
Pleasure to meet you, Dr. Goodweather.
Dr. Martinez. Let me
bring you both up to speed.
These Regis Air documents
point to a systems
failure aboard flight 753.
So I've had the FAA ground
the entire Regis Airline fleet
until the NTSB completes its investigation.
It's not a CDC case anymore.
The NTSB has the ball now.
With all due respect, Madam Secretary,
these people didn't die
from a faulty air system.
- They didn't?
- Everything in my investigation
points to a virulent pathogen.
We're far from understanding
exactly what did happen,
but we need to shut down this
airport so it doesn't spread.
- Eph, please.
- Dr. Goodweather,
I appreciate ur zeal.
But you need to step back
for a moment and consider
the impact of a medical quarantine.
It would immediately stop all exports
from New York to he rest of the world.
Do you want to crash a $70 billion economy
and send the stock markets
into a free fall on a hunch?
Eph, I know you've been
under a lot of stress
in your personal life, that's
a big part of the cause.
- But don't bring your baggage...
- My personal life
has nothing to do with this.
It's about saving people.
It's that simple. Eph...
Sorry, Everett. I shouldn't have done that.
No, you shouldn't have.
Here's what's going to happen.
You're going to take a few days off.
Then once this all blows
over, we're going to revisit
your situation.
Go home.
You've reached the office
of the Chief Medical
Examiner of New York City.
No one is available to take...
I can't reach Bennett, or anybody.
Why aren't they picking
up at the coroner's office?
They got 206 dead bodies,
they're probably a little busy.
(soft music playing)
(news bulletin on TV)
Captain Redfern? Thanks
for agreeing to meet us.
You bet.
My passengers and crew trusted
me to get them to JFK safely.
But I didn't. I'd like to know why.
You look a little pale.
I'm OK. A bit of a headache.
There's that humming in my ears.
We do have a non-medical question for you.
A large piece of cargo has
gone missing from the plane.
You know about the box?
I was doing my pre-flight
walk around on the plane.
Four officials in suits show up
in a government van with this huge crate.
We've carried last-minute high-
security cargo in the past,
so I didn't think much of it.
This box, it was maybe
nine foot by four foot?
Yes.
Do you know what government
office? Who they were?
They got down onto the tarmac to my plane,
they had suits and badges...
I figured it had to be official.
Who am I to question this?
But because I didn't,
206 people are dead.
Other people are still in
danger. You can help save them.
Here's what you can do:
go to the emergency room
at St. Sebastian's.
A Dr. William Lester will meet you there.
Who's he?
He's the best diagnostician I know.
He'll admit you as a private patient,
as a favor to me, and run some tests.
He'll find out what's
causing the sound in your ears
- and your headaches.
- OK.
Unbelievable. Jumping
through all these hoops
because those bastards don't
want to face a quarantine.
And the airline's worried
about their liability,
my union is worried about theirs...
Everyone's first priority
is covering their asses.
And no one gives a shit about the truth.
I do, and you do,
and that's the best
shot we've got right now.
Oh, my God...
Its buccal cavity has serrated projections.
So it can latch onto or cut through tissue.
I want to try something.
Make it quick.
Before someone asks what
the hell we're doing here.
If these worms did infect the victims,
then human blood should
produce a tropic reaction.
Look at that...
(beeping)
It's Zack. I'm supposed
to stop by to talk about
- the custody hearing.
- You better go then.
No, this is important. He'll understand.
He'll understand he's not
as important as your work,
which is exactly what he hears
from his mother every day.
You want the judge to
give Kelly full custody?
Of course not.
Take a moment.
Redfern's test results won't
come in for a couple of hours.
I'll finish this.
Thank you.
See you at the hospital.
_
- What are you doing in here?
- Vasiliy Fet.
- Inspector, City Pest Control.
- On a Sunday?
No! You're not doing an inspection now.
There's no time... this
is our champagne brunch.
Busiest service of the week.
- Sorry. We had a complaint.
- You want breakfast?
Give the order to one of the line chefs.
But I am not giving you any cash.
Is that what you think I'm here for?
Ha! Look.
You see that?
That's rat urine.
Ridiculous! OK,
two hundred dollars, but you get
the hell out of here right now.
- No.
- You're making a big mistake.
I make many mistakes, but not about vermin.
Move.
That was a $300,000 offer
for a 30-minute
on-camera interview.
- And you hang up?!
- Whatever they're offering,
it's gonna be chump change
compared to what we'll
get from the airline.
This may go in the category of "too soon,"
but ticket sales are way up.
That's what I love about you, Ruby.
Here's to being alive.
Moments like this... As an artist,
they make you take a step back
- and look at the big picture.
- There's no answer
to "why us." It's just
random luck, but I'll take it.
- (whirring sound)
- There's that... hum again.
You hear it still, don't you?
It's almost like an echo.
Like an echo of a voice,
maybe your own voice, when
your ears and nose are stuffed.
- It's weird.
- I'm not hearing it,
but Gabe, if that voice
has a tune, write it down.
Reminds me of my first acid trip.
You ever done acid, Joan?
Nope, no acid.
Not my thing.
What is your thing?
You want to take this party someplace else?
Like?
Townhouse above my new theater.
We can celebrate
our escape from the abyss.
No, I better get home
and see my kids. And my husband.
Maybe another time?
I'm going to be getting
together our legal team
at the firm tomorrow.
We'll talk soon, Gabe.
I need to get my pipes cleaned, Ruby.
Pick out a couple of hot ones.
Everyone stop what they're doing.
No more food goes out of the kitchen.
As of right now, you start cleaning...
if you ever want this
place to open up again.
You can't shut us down!
Councilwoman Shankar
eats here every Wednesday.
Oh yeah? You gonna serve her this?
Attention, everybody!
By order of the health
department, this establishment
is now closed. All right?
Everyone must leave.
- Hey, hon.
- (Screaming)
- (all screaming)
- Time to go!
I'm guessing we don't have to pay.
(screaming)
Dr. Moise called with some good news, sir.
The liver's young and healthy.
It belongs to a laborer.
No family. He won't be missed.
Moise would like to move
ahead with the acquisition.
I'm not sure I'll need it anymore.
With all due respect, sir,
if these other people can't
deliver what they've promised...
They can. And they will.
Even so, you should have a backup.
Keep in mind: it's a
five-hour flight to Bogota.
Minimum of eight hours
to harvest the organ.
Five more to return.
Your liver functionality is
already well below normal.
It could fail at any time. If it does fail,
it will be a challenge to keep you alive
until we receive the replacement.
All right. Fine.
- Do it.
- I'm not sure it's wis
to leave the building, sir.
My ability to withstand surgery.
Yes, yes, yes. I'm going.
There is no debate.
In fact, I've never felt
more excited about a meeting
in my entire life.
_
I agree, Nora: 101 degrees
is not cause for alarm,
but I don't like that
his temperature's rising.
Fine. I'll meet you back
at the hospital by the time
Redfern's path report gets back.
Good.
Talk soon. Sorry.
- It's the airplane case.
- Yeah, I've been watching.
But why are you involved?
They say something was
wrong with the plane.
That's total bullshit. Nobody
wants to deal with the truth.
What is it?
I don't know.
Nothing's adding up.
- That's scary.
- It is.
Well, I'm glad you're handling it.
That means whatever needs
to be done will get done.
Thank you.
Oh, come in.
Matt's here.
- Hey, Eph.
- Hey...
Diane. My name's Diane. I've met you, like,
five times. I drive your kid
to school every other day,
and you can't even remember my name.
I remember your name,
Diane. I just drew a blank.
Funny, I've never drawn a blank about you.
Not once. Why is that, Eph?
Diane. Zack's in the back,
- helping Matt.
- Do what?
We're converting your old office
into a game room.
Hey, Dad.
- Hey, Zack.
- How's it going, Eph?
OK.
So you're rebuilding this place, huh?
Yeah. Giant screen TV
over here. Perfect size
for a room like this.
Speakers here, and here.
This'll be a great new space for us.
Listen... I know this is awkward,
but I don't want it to be.
Um...
Just make her happy.
Just make them happy. That's all I ask.
You got it.
Oh. Oh, OK.
Great.
Mind if I speak with my son?
No, of course. You know, in time,
I bet you and I will become good friends.
Maybe.
Hey, Zack, Zack, I gotta go.
Because of that plane. I know.
I wanted to talk about
- the custody hearing tomorrow.
- OK.
- Just don't be late.
- I won't. I won't be.
- I mean it.
- So what about it?
Uh...
It is a weird situation,
huh, for all of us?
Mom says the judge will
ask all kinds of questions.
Yeah, he will. Or she will.
Whoever it is, they will.
Have you thought about
what you were gonna say?
Mom says I should just say how I feel.
K from your heart.
- What are you gonna say?
- Me? Same thing.
My feelings. I'm gonna say
you're the most important person
in the world to me, because you are,
- and that I want joint custody.
- What's that?
That means...
that you get to spend as much time with me
as you do with your mother.
And I know that's what you want, right?
Yeah... But if you're always so busy...
I won't be, not after
I put this case to bed.
You always say that.
And I know you mean it,
- but it's never true.
- Zack, Zack, look at me...
This time,
it will be.
I didn't think you were gonna show.
Keeping commitments is...
Is part of my recovery process.
Hi, my name's Eph.
- I'm an alcoholic.
- (Greetings)
I've been sober one year
and eleven days.
I'm in therapy.
Learning about myself.
It's a journey of discovery. Uh...
I'm passive-aggressive
and actively aggressive,
which is a rare combination, I'm told.
Let's see, what else? I'm
controlling. I'm self-centered.
I'm emotionally distant for my family.
Oh, and the greatest sin of all:
I love my work.
But I'm taking it all in,
you know, I'm owning it.
And it's really making a difference.
My wife's divorcing me,
and screwing this new dude...
in my bed. In my house,
on which I'm still making payments.
There I go again, right,
Richard? My sponsor says
that I use sarcasm to
avoid my real feelings,
that if I truly loved Kelly,
I would be happy for her,
I wouldn't resent her...
I'm trying, Richard.
But it is a very steep hill.
I saw them right before I came here.
All three of them together.
Doing things I never had time to do,
still don't have time to do...
I wanted a drink.
I passed a bar after I left there.
But I came here.
Because I can't blow it with Zack.
Ecse that I have left.
He's my whole world.
(applause)
(muffled music)
(hard rock music)
Are you ready to party with me?
Yeah!
(giggling)
You smell beautiful. I
bet you taste even better.
- You okay, Gabe?
- Yeah, yeah.
I'm still on German time.
Keep the beat going. I'll catch up.
(sound of blood pumping)
- (screaming)
- You bit me, you bastard!
- Bullshit.
- I'm bleeding. He bit me hard!
Get out.
Get out! Out!
Out! You're crazy!
(sound of blood pumping)
- _
- What's wrong?
Redfern just went into a tailspin.
Lester's with him. Here's the path report.
I've never seen anything like it.
This is crazy: Aberrant, foreign cells...
nuclear pleomorphism.
Biphenotypic appearance...
It's like something
shanghaied his cellular machinery
and is creating something
totally different.
We've sedated him for the
pain, started fluids, but...
- Antibody studies back in yet?
- No.
- How you feeling, Doyle?
- Boiling.
Skin's crawling. I feel like
I swallowed a razor. UV light.
Watch your eyes.
A scar. Same place as the airline victims.
It just healed so fast
we couldn't see it without UV light.
Eph, look!
Jim, find Barnes. Tell him
that Redfern's gone critical.
He's gonna be really
pissed when he finds out
you've been treating him. I
don't give a shit! Tell him
that one of the survivors is very sick.
Tell him we need to corral
the rest of the survivors
and anybody they've had contact with.
Now. Yes, sir.
The autopsies should have
turned something up by now.
Dr. Bennett is still not answering.
It went straight to voice mail again.
Well, if the mountain
won't come to Mahomet...
We're going to the morgue.
Dr. Goodweather? This is
Laurie from the CDC exchange.
- There's a Gary Arnot calling.
- Yeah, OK.
Hello? Yes, Doctor,
this is Gary Arnot.
- I'm Emma's...
- I know who you are, Mr. Arnot.
First of all, I just wanted to say
that I'm sorry for what I did,
and to thank you for sending
my little girl home to me.
What? Are you saying someone
released her body to you?
No, not her body.
Emma's alive. She showed up
on my doorstep this morning.
Uh, Mr. Arnot, I'm a little confused.
- Are you telling me...
- You don't believe me?
You know what? Fine, whatever.
- I'm just trying to...
- My daughter's home safe.
That's all that matters.
Thank you very much.
Do you think it's possible she's alive?
He's in shock. He's seeing ghosts.
I examined her in her seat, she's dead.
When we boarded that plane,
everybody looked dead.
Then four of them woke up.
Could these worms somehow induce
some sort of state of hibernation?
Like tsetse flies?
We'll find out in ten minutes.
If she's dead, she'll be at the morgue.
Sir?
I know you don't wanna hear this,
but I've been with you
a long time and listened
to a lot of doctors
promise you a lot of things.
I've seen what can be done and what can't.
These people... They're deceiving you.
These people have power
beyond anything you can imagine.
In time, you also will
benefit from that power.
Stay with the car.
I need to do this alone.
The sun has fallen.
You are very fortunate, Mr. Palmer.
He has chosen you to
bear witness to his glory.
(growling)
Welcome to the New World.
You brought me all the way here.
Aren't you going to look at me?
(whimpering)
(creature growling)
- Hello? Anybody here?
- (Phones ringing)
Dr. Bennett?
Dr. Bennett, you OK?
Hello?
(clanking)
Every bag is empty. Every single one.
(I Love You song from
Barney playing faintly)
_
- _
(low growling)
_
(screaming)
sync and corrected by caioalbanezi
www.addic7ed.com