Last week, my best friend came back
to life. The day before, he died.
A few days before that, he emerges
as the most powerful member
of this tribe called the Angelics.
He acquires magical powers
they didn't even think was possible.
People used to think he was mad.
They were wrong. He's special.
But him being special's
been a tumultuous time.
And that's not even half of it!
There's these dead people...
the Fades ... and they're
trying to come back to life,
led by this dude called John,
who died in 1943 and has come back
to life by eating human flesh.
And now he's got a taste for it,
he just can't stop. Yeah, I know.
He tricked Paul into helping him rescue
this girl, Natalie, from the Angelics.
And with her help, he's bringing a whole
army of dead people back into our town.
We've got to fight. Meanwhile,
the Angelics have their own plan.
How?
By having one of our team on theirs.
Those of us in the middle of it ...
me, my history teacher,
Paul's mum, Paul's sister, Paul's
girlfriend ... just stick out our chin,
grin and try and pretend we
understand what's going on. Scary.
Now, who's seen my Matrix box set?
I'm pretty sure I've worked out
who the Architect is a metaphor for.
Na-Nu, Na-Nu.
HE BREATHES LUSTFULLY
I've been waiting for over an hour!
'For those with
missing persons enquiries,
'a crisis centre has been set up
at St Barnabus School.
'I repeat, a missing persons crisis
centre has been set up at the school.'
THEY LAUGH
I don't even know if he's all right
or if he should be here!
The doctor didn't even
want to discharge you.
I am allowed to be worried.
He's fine. Watch this.
Lord Of The Rings.
Why don't they just fly in and out of
Mordor on the back of a giant eagle?
Boom! They didn't want to
discharge him because he's too well.
That's ridiculous.
Mission Impossible 2.
Cruise finds a face
mask of the bodyguard
without having seen or met him?
Likely(!) Kaboosh.
Very few people actually come out of
a coma healthier. It's... odd.
My name is Dr Mac the Movie Doctor and
I pronounce a clear bill of health.
He's got a good recall
of basic facts. "Basic facts"?
The Matrix.
'This is Steve... '
Where do I start? Direct hit.
Steve! Call me back!
Boom! Ssh! Boom!
Home run.
"Got well soon."
See what you've done there.
I'm OK, Mum. Good to have you home.
Steve's still not
answering my calls.
Yeah, the school's going to be
a secondary location,
we're completely swamped
on missing persons.
Armstrong wouldn't know a suspect
if one bit him on the arse.
Look, Carol, I need to go, right?
Hello.
KNOCK ON DOOR
We come in peace.
Oh, do you now?
That must be nice.
Sarah?!
So why are you here? Paul's back.
What?
Back from the dead? Sarah?
Are you OK? So has he eaten, then?
No, He hasn't eaten.
He just... came back.
He closed an ascension point but..
The point's closed?
That's what happened, isn't it, eh?
Sarah...
Sarah's eaten, hasn't she?
Hasn't she? It was my idea.
At least we're trying
for a solution to this mess.
Sarah eats, she'll be reborn.
Immortal, just like him. The boy,
he came back. The boy's the answer!
The answer to what?
People have died.
The boy's a joke.
We can beat them, we need to try.
With Sarah's help
we can start to fight back.
You're going to destroy her, Neil.
I'm not staying to watch.
RUMBLING AND RATTLING
What's happening?
I don't know.
Must be him.
We've got to get
everyone out of here.
We've got two more.
Good.
I love this.
I love you.
I've never been happier
than I am right now.
Thank you...
for what you did.
Tried and failed to save you?
Tried and failed to save me.
Pleasure. I came back from the dead.
What I am, who I am
has got to mean something.
It probably does.
MAC SPITS AND GARGLES
I was ready to ascend.
I'd let everyone down,
and I was ready to leave this...
rock for ever.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
so you came back to life.
But can you do this?
Can you though? No. Can you?
Well, then you're nothing to me.
THEY LAUGH
Shut up!
Paul.
Don't tell anyone but there's
a real live girl in your room.
Are you wearing identical pyjamas?
Yeah, they were... they were
the only two I had clean.
Likely story.
So your mum was pretty clear
I should sleep in Anna's room.
Yeah.
But I don't want to.
No?
Oh. I get it.
Oh, don't mind me.
I'll just be quiet in the corner.
You do anything you want to.
I won't listen or watch.
Sofa downstairs it is. Yeah.
Night.
You're not even scarred.
The doctor thinks me
a medical miracle.
The doctor thinks you're a freak.
You're my freak, though.
Yeah.
You... Are you the man in charge?
How did you get in here?
You need to get everyone out
of town. It's not safe.
Full scale evacuation? Great!
You're just what I need(!)
You need to leave. Now. You're
going to die here. All of you!
If you don't get out,
you'll be arrested, understand?
Men with power. You think you can
scare me, you little, little man?
I'm actually average height.
Any news on Clement?
Nothing.
When do we add him to that?
What now?
There's only one thing to do,
we've got to try and find Paul, eh?
Alice?
Rargh!
What's she?
The girlfriend?
Yeah.
Pretty.
Neil, what are you doing here?
BREATHES HEAVILY
'You were dead.'
I know. And now you're back.
Alice thinks
that makes you important.
What do you think?
Oh, I think I should have a knife
at your throat right now.
SHE SHIVERS
Why did you do it?
Why did you help him?
He promised he wouldn't hurt you.
And you believed him?
A murderer?
You were cutting Natalie up.
You were torturing her.
He told me that's what the Angelics
had always done.
Suppressed, policed.
That's what I believed.
What we did, we did for
the good of everyone.
We thought they could be dangerous.
It turns out, we were right.
GROWLING
SHE PANTS
The past is a hole
and it's full of what-ifs.
And I live in the present.
You? Don't know where you live.
You confuse me.
GROWLING
HER NECK CRUNCHES
'One thing I do know... '
is that you are going to matter.
And when we find out why that is...
you'll have to pick a side.
Just make sure
you pick the right side, kid.
SHE BREATHES HUNGRILY
BLOOD DRIPS
Hello, Sarah.
Welcome.
I can't...
You want to.
One time, during the war...
I was fighting alongside this NCO
called Richard... something.
They brought a man
with his guts ripped out
into the hole that we were in.
Then someone shouted
for medical support...
and Richard raised his hand
in the air
"I'm a medic."
And then I watched him...
as he went and held
this man's guts together
and then watched him till he died.
And afterwards I said to him,
"Richard, I didn't know
that you were a medic."
And he turned to me and he said...
"I'm not.
"I just wanted to know what
the insides of a man felt like."
SHE PANTS
Urges are OK.
They're human.
Just eat.
And you'll be reborn.
Don't fight it, Sarah. We win.
SHE FEEDS NOISILY
Sarah?
Sarah! Oh...
WIND HOWLS
GLASS SHATTERS
Oh, shit. Mum?
MUM!
HE SNARLS
HE PANTS
Bad dream?
Yeah.
I didn't wet the bed, though,
so that's a bonus.
We're going to school. Are we?
They've set up a crisis centre.
Steve's not answering my calls.
I think he's missing and Mum says
she'll drive me but only if you come.
Paul, I'm not asking. I'm telling!
I don't know whether there's
enough people...
Hi. Excuse me?
My name's Mark Etches.
I was told to report to you.
Not unless you're in need of help
and guidance you weren't.
Peter. Peter Tremlett. Doctor.
I'll be running
a counselling service.
Right. Well, thanks for coming in, Mark.
We're going to need everyone we can get.
Now, let's see if we can find someone
to show Mark around, all right?
OK.
You really don't have to show me
everywhere, you know. I want to.
And just round here, we're starting up
an online database of missing persons.
Steve? What you doing here?
Didn't you know?
I'm dead civic-minded, sir.
I work with the elderly, too.
Wiping their arses and everything.
We've actually had a remarkably good
response to our request for volunteers.
I've got a clipboard and all.
Hi, hello. We're looking
for missing persons.
Who are you missing?
Steve. Steve McEwan. Steve?
He's not missing. He's a volunteer.
Steve's a volunteer? He's helping
with the online databasing.
Anna, wait. Anna!
I think I could be of more use here.
Yes, join me.
Hello, stranger.
Oh... Hello, stranger still.
Surprised to see you here.
My housemate's mum has gone missing.
I'm... moral support.
Is your wife still missing?
Um...
Pretty much officially dead.
Pink suits you.
SHE LAUGHS
What's so funny?
What? What's so funny?
Sorry, who are you? Oh, Vicky,
this is... Dr Tremlett, right?
No, no, no, sorry.
I'm just kind of interested...
in what's so funny right now, yeah?
It was just a private joke.
Yeah, and we're actually quite busy,
so unless you want something?
Yeah.
Yeah, I want something.
Oh!
Oof.
Argh!
"Volunteering"?
He's seen some opportunity to
seek out some new pussy, more like.
If I had you, I'd never let you go.
In order for you to
have me, I'd have to be
gagged, blindfolded and
locked in a chest.
That could be arranged.
Why's this door locked?
Oh, speak of the fucking devil.
Where have you been?
Being a devil, I guess.
Are you dribbling?!
Course I am.
I've missed you, sweetness.
Tch! Does that work?
Does that work in your head?
"Haven't seen my
girlfriend in days, I'll
flob on myself and
she'll forgive me."
Anna. Stop. That's not normal dribble.
He's one of them. One of what?
Yeah, one of what?
Don't come any closer. Or what?
He's my boyfriend.
Yeah, and now he's dead.
He used to be dead, now
he's come back to life!
What?! Babe, that's not true.
Anna, trust me.
He wants to kill you.
Go.
Steve, what the fuck are you doing?
Steve?
HE CHUCKLES
THUD AND SCREAM
Have to keep feeding...
Sarah. Sarah!
They're coming for them so quickly.
Sarah. It's me.
Sarah, Where were you?
We need to keep killing.
They can only eat flesh.
What did you see? Did you find him?
I've done... It's OK, you'll be fine.
Some things.
Tell me where you've been.
Sarah, you're going to be fine.
Listen to me. It hurt. So bad...
Too badly. I know it did.
There were bodies. So much blood.
Why is every door... locked?!
Steve's dead? My boyfriend's dead?!
Surely more important
is the fact that he's a zombie?
He was dead. Now he's not.
That makes him a zombie.
It's more complicated than that.
In fact, you were dead
and now you're not.
Makes you a sort of zombie.
Mac, this is real.
This is dangerous. This...
There you go.
So, er...
so your children are at this school?
Yeah, Paul and Anna Roberts.
Anna, well, you've met her.
She's loud. Paul...
Well...
Well, he's...
Paul's quieter.
More contemplative.
If you ever want to talk
to anyone, Dr Tremlett
runs a counselling
service in the gym.
OK, thank you.
What are you doing with us?
We... are...
keeping you.
Keeping us for what?
Keeping us for what?!
A WOMAN SCREAMS
THE SCREAMING CONTINUES
Come on!
THEY GASP
How'd you know where the key was?
I volunteer here sometimes.
You're a library monitor?
My boyfriend's dead,
and you're a library monitor?
Paul, what the fuck
has happened to Steve?
What is he?
If I make an educated guess,
he died, OK?
He became a ghost.
A Fade.
Then this guy called John, he's
from the 1940s, he used
to be a Fade ghost,
he's probably taught him how to
eat flesh and grow a new body.
This is serious, Paul.
I am being serious.
We are in so much danger.
Trap him or something.
You ain't afraid of no ghost.
No, no, you're mental.
You're both mental.
Steve's mental, you're mental...
and Jay's a fucking library monitor!
I'm sorry, Anna. My brother?
My stupid pissing brother?
Little pig, little pig, let me in!
Anna, let me in!
Let me in right now.
BANGING
That's it. That's it.
Dad, Dad?
Aw, it's gone to answerphone.
The one time having a dad who's a
policeman might be useful. School. Now!
There's...
Fuck.
I'm going to rip your fucking
head off and spit down your neck.
I'm not afraid of you, Steve.
No-one could be that scary
with a dick your size!
We're going to die here.
I knew this would happen.
Death before life.
I'm going to die and I haven't
even felt a breast in my hand.
Haven't even seen a breast.
That's your excuse
to flash me, by the way.
Flash this! Hmm.
We need weapons.
Weapons are no use.
Can't kill them. They're immortal.
I don't even know
how many there are.
What about Mum?
She's still in the hall.
We need to get out of
here, get back to her.
Shit, fuck, shit.
Paul, what are we going to do?
Right. Who's first?
Me!
That's for scaring my... Argh!
See? Now he's de...
This is your mess. I shouldn't be
cleaning up your mess!
He'll be back. Let's go.
Where's Jay?
Jay. Jay?
Jay? Jay?
Jay!
SHE GROANS
Ah!
You have 30 seconds to tell me
everything I need to know about Paul.
Start with what he can do.
He came back for a reason.
To stop you. Wrong answer.
Me?
No, take one of the others.
I can be useful.
I can be useful,
I can show you where things are.
I don't want to die yet!
THWACK!
Fuck!
OK. I'll try again.
Paul.
The boy that was, that now is.
How has he dragged himself
back to life? Did he eat?
No.
He's important.
Eeny.
Meeny.
Miny.
Mo.
You.
Are.
It.
No, no, no... It's OK, it's OK.
Phil! PHIL!
PHIL!
MUMBLED SINGING
SINGS QUIETLY
HALTED BREATHING
I went to them. Yeah?
I didn't mean to, but I went to them.
I was drawn there.
Where? Where, Sarah?
I fucked up, Neil. I fucked up.
Jay...
JAY WHIMPERS
You're pretty. You've got hair
like a boy, but you're pretty.
Do you think I'm pretty?
SIGHS
Don't cry.
This life is going to be
better for all of us.
I was never happy as a human.
But when the change happens to you,
and it will...
the world just... opens up.
Natalie.
Don't worry, he'll come for you.
Jay. Have, er... Have you seen Jay?
Jay? I'm sorry.
She was the last one they took.
They took Phil.
Where? Where did they take her?
Paul!
Hello, Paul.
Dr Tremlett.
How's the nightmares?
Still wetting the bed?
He's one of them.
Dr Tremlett.
I need to leave.
Are you going to get out my way?
Paul...
Don't pick a fight with it. You
should listen to your friend, Paul.
He's afraid.
I'm surprised you're not.
You used to always
be afraid of everything.
I'm still afraid.
I'm afraid
of letting my friends down,
I'm afraid of not being good enough,
I'm afraid
of not doing the right thing.
But you?
I'm bored of being afraid
of things like you.
Do you remember I told you once
that you reminded me of me?
You remember I told you once
to get out of my way?
They've got my girlfriend.
I need to get back to her.
You always were...
such a whinging little shit.
And all that talking, whining...
"I can't control my bladder."
Well, fuck you and fu...
HE SPLUTTERS AND GROANS
We may not be able to kill you but
we can keep you from doing damage.
This was a mistake! I'm losing me.
I've got this hunger. This hunger.
No. You're strong.
You're strong.
You're stronger than you know.
Listen to me.
You need to go to the school.
I'm not leaving you.
No way am I leaving you.
You did this for us.
For me.
Neil, that's not true.
I did it partly for you,
and partly because...
I was frightened of what was going
to happen to me, but mostly...
mostly...
I did it because Mark didn't want
me around any more and I couldn't...
You always did see the best in me.
Mark.
Please, please leave me.
Leave me.
You need to go to the school.
You need to stop him.
For me.
For everyone.
The boiler room.
OK.
I'll always see the best in you.
DISTANT WHIMPERING
DOOR SLAMS
WHIMPERING GROWS LOUDER
JAY SOBS LOUDLY
You're all right.
It's all right.
SHE CRIES
Paul! Paul!
This is a school.
Not a fucking... fridge.
It is... what it needs to be.
SHE WHIMPERS
MACHINE GUN FIRE
PAUL! Neil, NEIL! Paul, go!
SHE SCREAMS
HE SCREAMS
What did I do?!
What did I do to him, Neil?!
You killed him, Paul!
You can kill them.
Where is he? Where's the killer?
He's getting away!
MACHINE GUN FIRE
I need you, Paul!
I can only slow them down.
Paul!
PAUL!
SCREAMING
I'm a freak.
But I'm your freak, remember?
Paul! Come on!
Oh, shit.
Paul?
No, no, no. Stay back. Stay back!
Paul, you need to kill him.
I can't see him. I can't see him!
It could be any of them. Kill them
all! My mum's in this room!
He's there. Do it! Do it, Paul!
SHE YELLS IN PAIN
SLITHERING
COUGHS AND SPLUTTERS
SHE YELLS
SHE WAILS
My name is Detective
Chief Inspector Armstrong.
But I'm not here as a policeman.
I'm here as a citizen,
as a man,
as a father...
to tell you I think
you should leave town.
We don't know what's happening,
we don't know how it's happening,
and we have no idea how to stop it.
Not the murders,
the attacks, or the tremors.
We need to evacuate now.
Now!
SIRENS WAIL
This can't be why I came back.
No.
I killed Steve.
And that... girl.
Natalie.
They burnt up.
But they were dead already, right?
I don't want to be a killer.
You don't have to be one.
Superman could crush Lois Lane after
an argument about the washing-up.
He could melt the Daily Planet
after a bad day at the office.
He doesn't.
He uses his powers for good.
That's all you need to do.
Got to go.
SIRENS WAIL
It's you and me, then.
We start a clean up, Paul, now.
And identify them? How?
I can't tell them apart from
ordinary people, can you?
We don't even know how many of them
there are. Well, we'll find a way.
A way that doesn't involve me
killing everyone?
Look after him, won't you?
Paul?
I think he can look after himself.
Look after your mum.
That I will try to do.
Look after yourself.
You want me to look after me?
Yeah.
Give me your hands.
You've got three seconds. OK.
Three.
Two. One.
OK? OK.
Look after yourself, too.
Yeah.
You ready?
Probably not.
Come on.
A 17-year-old boy, Neil.
And if these powers have been
given to me for a reason, then...
maybe it's not to kill everyone.
Maybe it's because I can see past
your shit and his shit.
Is that the shit
that just saved your life?
If all the world
needed was more death...
then you'd have been given these powers.
If I had one-tenth of your powers,
I'd be giving you
such a fucking kicking.
I'm going to find a better plan.
Another way.
Ascension is broken,
I'm going to put it right.
Better? You think you can do better?
You're signing a death
warrant for everyone here.
There's going to be
reborns everywhere.
DON'T WALK AWAY FROM ME!
DOORBELL RINGS
Hello.
Hi.
Can I come in?
You've got no time. No time.
Dad, I have things here worth
thousands of pounds on eBay.
I refuse to rush.
Yeah. Why rush?
Tortoise always wins.
I'm here to take you with me, Mac.
Where?
Somewhere I can persuade Paul
to follow.
You're taking me hostage?
Yeah.
That's about the most efficient
way of putting it.
Why?
Because he's stronger than me
in every way...
except one.
He has people he cares about.
I'm his weakness?
Yep.
And I intend to take
full advantage of that fact.
MAC'S DAD: Come on, Mac. Hurry up.
Don't make me hurt your dad, Mac,
because I am this close.
Get a move on.
Mac!
Paul, kitchen.
Anna, get some clothes.
Jay, call your mum.
You've got five minutes.
Paul.
What I saw you do...
Best to forget about that, Mum.
Sometimes, I'd sit outside your room
listening to you have nightmares.
I'm scared.
That's understandable.
I don't know whether to be
scared for you or scared of you.
I'm going to make you
proud of me, Mum.
I hope so.
I'm a teeny tiny bit claustrophobic,
so if you could leave the light on...
Shut up.
Can you knock?!
Erm, where's that
stripy hoodie of yours?
Have you packed all the food?
We need to move quickly.
DOG BARKS
I'll kill you.
Now!
You make one move towards my family.
Jesus. That almost
sounded grown-up, then.
That was very manly, very good.
I meant...
I mean it. You know,
it's interesting, isn't it?
When I kill,
people can come back.
But then when you kill,
people are wiped from existence.
Yeah? Why's that interesting?
Because I'm the one
people think is the monster.
And today, you killed the one
person I had left that I loved.
And I wanted you
to feel similar pain.
Me and you, we're the same.
I'm the chosen one of my people.
You're the chosen one of yours.
Nah, we're not alike.
I will find a way...
to hurt you.
To kill you.
I didn't come back to be a monster.
D'you hear me?
I'll find a way to help you.
Free you. No, good luck with that.
You have been NOTHING
but helpful so far.
Subtitles by
Red Bee Media and APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com