Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
We are not supposed
to be doing this.
We are!
He chopped the guy's head off
with a sword!
Get these people on the bus.
- Be ready to drive. I'll be right back.
- What if you're not!?
Beth!?
Where is Beth!?
Maggie...
I'm just trying to find the
kids to get them on the bus.
We gotta go, Beth.
We gotta go.
Beth's voice: Hey.
I know it's been a while.
I'm gonna be honest,
I forgot about you.
After the farm,
we were always moving.
But something happened.
Something good.
Finally.
We found a prison.
Daddy thinks that we can
make it into a home.
( snarling )
He says we can grow crops
in the field,
find pigs and chickens,
stop running, stop scavenging.
Lori's baby is just about due.
She'll need a safe place
when it comes.
( walker snarling )
( gun clicks )
The rest of us,
we just need
a safe place to be.
I woke up in my own bed
yesterday.
My own bed in my own room.
But I've been keeping
my backpack.
Keeping my gun close.
I've been afraid
to get my hopes up
thinking we can
actually stay here.
The thing is, I've been
starting to get afraid
that it's easier
just to be afraid.
But this morning
Daddy said something.
If you don't have hope,
what's the point of living?
( panting )
So I unpacked my bag
and I found you.
So I'm gonna start
writing in you again.
And I'm gonna write
this down now
because you should write
down wishes
to make them come true.
We can live here.
We can live here
for the rest of our lives.
( theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
We should do something.
We aren't the only survivors.
We can't be.
Rick, Michonne,
they could be out here.
Maggie and Glenn could have
made it out of A block.
They could've.
You're a tracker.
You can track.
Come on.
The sun will be up soon.
If we head out now, we can--
Fine. If you won't
track, I will.
( birds screeching )
( blows )
Could be Luke's.
Or Molly's.
Whoever they are,
it means they're alive.
No. This means they were alive
four or five hours ago.
They're alive.
They picked up
the pace right here.
Got out in a hurry.
Things went bad.
Wouldn't kill you
to have a little faith.
Yeah, faith. Faith ain't
done shit for us.
Sure as hell didn't do
nothing for your father.
They'll be hungry
when we find them.
( sighs )
What?
That ain't walker blood.
The trail keeps going.
They fought them off.
No. Got walker tracks
all up and down here.
At least a dozen of them.
( twig snaps )
- ( snarling )
- ( gasping )
( panting )
Come on.
( flies buzzing )
( Beth crying )
Beth's voice:
We're not gonna die.
None of us.
I believe now.
I believe for Daddy.
If this doesn't work,
I don't know how
I could keep going.
( crying )
Don't cry.
I want Carol.
Well, she's not here.
Here, put this on your belt.
It's gonna get dark soon.
Where are we going?
Farther.
Come on.
Is everybody dead?
- ( crying )
- They're gonna hear her.
We shouldn't be out here.
We'll find a safe place soon.
We will.
Here.
( crying stops )
-  ( leaves rustling )
- Walkers!
Here, come on.
Let's go.
It's okay.
I'll find you something to eat.
All right, go.
( Judith crying )
Look, grapes.
It's okay.
- Can we eat them?
- Yeah, they're good.
Here, Lizzie, have some.
Shh.
- Come on, baby girl.
- ( fussing )
Shh.
Lizzie, hand me a diaper.
- ( crying )
- It's okay. All right.
Bear with me, Judith.
Okay, that's it.
Okay.
Mica:
They're gonna hear her.
( crying continues )
You're all right.
Come on.
It's all right.
I know. I know.
All right, what do you want?
What do you want, hmm?
Shh. Shh.
Okay, come on.
- Shh.
-  ( leaves rustling )
- They're coming!
- Ah! I heard it, Mica!
Don't yell at her.
She doesn't understand walkers.
You're the one who
doesn't understand them.
Come on.
Watch the baby.
( crying continues )
- ( wings flapping )
- ( gasps )
Mica!
- Tyreese: Mica.
- She's gone.
You yelled at her
and now she's gone.
Mica.
Are you okay?
I got scared.
That's okay.
We all get scared.
You did the right thing
running.
- What?
- She did.
You hear or see
a walker, you run.
But when you're in a group,
you got to try to stay
close to them, okay?
You're bleeding.
Did I hurt your arm bad?
It was a lot worse
at the prison. No big.
I'm sorry.
I know I'm not like Lizzie.
Don't be sorry. You each
do things your own way.
- But you both get it done.
- Like you and Sasha?
You're not like Sasha.
Why not?
Because you're still here.
Sasha isn't.
( woman screaming )
- Here.
- What are you doing?
Come on.
I'm making sure you can see
in both directions.
You stay like this
and keep watch.
- You're leaving us?
-  ( woman screams )
They may be from the prison.
- I need to help them.
- We need you.
Mica, tuck your shirt
behind your knife
so it's easier to grab.
- We'll be okay.
- Okay.
( woman screams )
What do you do
when you see a walker?
- Run.
Together, towards me.
Only fire if you have to.
You stay right here
until I get back, okay?
Please, please don't go.
Mica, look at me.
You can handle this.
You're tough.
( woman screams )
( walkers snarling )
- Chris, head for the woods.
- I can't.
( Judith crying )
Come on, Judith.
Be quiet.
She's not stopping.
Please, Lizzie, do something.
They're gonna hear us.
- Shh.
- ( muffled crying )
( leaves rustling )
( snarling )
Lizzie.
- Ah! Dad!
-  Christopher!
- Dad!
( Mica muffled )
Lizzie, we have to run.
( Judith crying, muffled )
Mica:
Lizzie?
Lizzie.
( gunshot )
- Watch out!
- ( screams )
Carol:
Tyreese.
How-- how...
How'd you find us?
Where were you?
How'd you--
( man sobbing )
Stay here, girls.
Stay on the tracks.
That was my mistake.
But the woods have more cover.
No, you don't understand.
There's a place up the tracks.
It's safe. You can take
the children there.
Trust me.
Please.
Follow the tracks.
( sobbing )
Tyreese.
I didn't run.
I didn't leave Lizzie.
See that?
Tough little lady.
Hey, there's some
water in there.
- And some food.
- Yeah.
Here you go.
I didn't see you get out.
I thought you--
I wasn't there.
I hadn't gotten back yet.
Rick and I found a car.
He took what we had
back to the prison
while I...
kept looking.
Did you see it?
I saw the end.
And then...
I saw you running
into the woods.
You were far away.
I lost you, but...
You found us.
I knew you would.
Hey, maybe we can circle
back and find your car.
The walkers
and the fire--
you can't go back
to a graveyard.
Look.
"Sanctuary for all.
Community for all.
Those who arrive
survive."
( knife scraping )
( fabric ripping )
Sorry.
You can smile.
You're alive.
I get it.
That's not it.
Okay.
Tyreese could have
made it, Sasha.
We don't know
if anybody got out.
No.
We do.
How's he doing?
Bleeding stopped.
He'll be all right.
Got the water to our backs.
Decent vantage points
from the bank.
I'm thinking we camp
here for the night.
That's good.
You should both be safe here.
The bus got out.
Glenn got out.
- I'm gonna find him.
-  Maggie.
With any luck, the bus is gone.
It was heading east down the main road.
If I follow in that direction,
- I might be able to pick up its tracks.
- Alone? With just that?
I'm out of ammo, so, yeah.
I couldn't find Beth.
I know Glenn got out
and I know which way he went.
I'm gonna go get him and I'm
gonna come back for you.
- We both are.
- Sasha: Maggie.
- I'm going.
- We cannot split up. Not now.
I'm going.
You said it.
We can't split up.
_
Sasha: You could have
helped me stop her.
If you're trying to make me feel
sorry for you, it's not working.
Damn, it means I let myself
get shot up for nothing.
The odds of us finding him...
We should be out looking
for food, shelter.
Yeah, why is that?
So we can live.
- Then what?
- What?
Maybe we didn't survive
just to keep surviving.
Shit happens.
Not everything
has to mean something.
No, it doesn't have to,
but it can.
If you make it that way, and that's
what it seems like we're doing.
And I'm down with that.
Maggie.
Maggie!
( snarling )
You should go.
- Maggie, stop.
- Maggie. Maggie.
I have to know
if he's in there.
Fine, but we do it together.
Smart.
We'll let them out
one at a time.
Two of us should be
at the door...
in case they stack up
against it.
I have to be here.
I need to see their faces.
-  ( pounding )
-  ( snarling )
( knife thuds )
I can't hold it.
( muffled gunshots,
knife pierces )
( growling )
( gunshot )
I'm sorry.
But they got away.
They were good people.
All of them.
You should let me.
( flies buzzing )
( gurgling )
( snarling )
( growling )
( crying )
( laughing )
( walkers growling )
( groans )
Maggie?
Maggie!
( door squeaks )
( bottle clinks )
( coughs )
( sighs )
( crying )
( sniffles )
( walkers growling )
( Glenn shouting )
( shouts )
( breathing heavily )
( knife pierces )
It's full.
Did you even fire a shot?
All right.
Let's go.
Are you just gonna
stay here, huh?
- You're just gonna die?
- I was part of this.
I know.
So what are you doing?
I need your help.
We're gonna run out of bullets.
Take this and take this.
- ( lighter clinks )
- Back up.
All right. I need you to
stay ahead of me, okay?
All right. I'll cover you,
but I can't do it alone.
You ready?
Let's go.
Go.
Go, go, go, go, go.
- ( gunshots )
- Shoot! Shoot! Come on!
( gunshot )
_
( panting )
Did you see if any
of my people got out?
All I saw was my sister
in that field.
She wasn't supposed
to be there.
She had a gun,
but they just swarmed her.
She wasn't
supposed to be there.
I did it for him.
I trusted him.
And then he just
killed that old man.
Hershel?
Was his name Hershel?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Brian, that man, told
us you were bad people.
I know it's not true.
I can see it's not,
so what we did, what I did...
I mean, I'm a piece of shit.
Why would you want my help?
I don't want it, I need it.
I have to find Maggie.
Who's Maggie?
She's my wife.
You guys got separated?
I was on the bus and then I got off
to help and she didn't see me.
How do you know if she made it?
I don't know.
But Hershel,
Maggie's father,
was a great man.
And he told me all I
had to do was believe,
and that's what I'm gonna do.
Neither one of us
should be alive right now.
She got out, so you're
gonna help me find her.
Things aren't over.
They're not over.
I want to believe that.
I want to.
( walkers growling )
You have to.
( gasping )
Glenn.
Hey, Glenn.
( snarling )
( vehicle approaching )
( panting )
Hope you enjoyed
the show, assholes.
( doors open )
You got a damn mouth
on you, you know that?
What else you got?
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com