Strange.
Who would do something like this?
Maybe someone got upset about
their roaming charges.
Stealing satellite phones makes sense,
you can hawk 'em.
You can write up charges
on somebody else's account.
But burning them?
Youngsters?
...pulling some prank?
No. They would have left a note.
"Fuck you", to their parents....
....or the world or whatever
Not a bad idea though.
I brought Peggy here on our
first date.
Yeah, we all did.
Not Peggy of course.
I gotcha.
Last sunset of the month.
Always works.
Well, uhm, let's go to the sign.
You okay, Eben?
Yeah.
Why  even bother with that, nobody's
going to see it for a month.
It's condition.
Kind of put this off til the last
minute didn't ya?
There's a lot of small towns in this state.
My boss wants all this gear inspected
and certified by the 31st.
Yeah, I noticed it says barrel for the last.
Are you sure you don't wanna stay?
Me and Jane were kind of hoping...
that you and Eben would rethink this
separation thing.
Thanks.
I, uh...
...gotta meet the plane.
Okay sweetie.  I know you can handle ????
Promise I won't live on Oreos and Snapple.
I'm going to Seattle.
Yes you are Kristen,
call me when you get there.
You got a problem?
Nothing I can't handle
my fucking self.
Is this for generators?
Yeah, yeah most.
Beau, I'm going to have to cite
you for it. I can't have it leaking all
over the street.
What?
For that?
...you don't have to cite me.
You don't have to do anything.
Isn't that why we live out here?
You know, for a little freedom?
Happy motoring.
Yeah, I'll add it to my collection.
You know, Beau's not so bad.
Why'd you bother writing him up?
He lives all alone out there
on the south ridge.
A little citation now and then lets
him know he's a part of this town.
Eben? Come in Eben.
Yeah Helen?
Something bad happened to John Reese's dog.
[Radio] : Well folks, you're listening to KBRW,
Marrel, Alaska.
...today's the last day [fade out].
And we've been to get the last plane
out of here.
Hey Stella, are you okay?
????? Malachi.
Didn't you know what "right of way" means?
I'm sorry Stella.
The brakes jammed and....
...Eben wanted this back before
the storm hit. And I was trying to...
Oh shit!
Was going to meet you at the airport.
Wouldn't Eben?
Well, my mom could come down and give you
a tow, but you know she don't move
too fast.
Fuck, where's my phone?
It's me.
Surprise!
I uh, need a ride to the airport.
What?
You're in town and you didn't want to talk?
I had fire marshal work here,
..and I just had a little accident.
I'm stuck on Ransom and 355 and the airport
will close, and I'll never get to Anchorage.
I mean, if you wanna talk,
we can do it on the drive.
Billy.
Stella's stuck at Ransom and 355.
She needs a ride to the airport.
Can you go get her?
Stella, John Reese needs me for something,
so Billy's going to come get you.
Let me know if the day comes
and you do wanna talk.
What sick jerk would do this?
Every kennel, every dog we had.
Did you fuck with anyone recently John?
I'll kill them....I'll kill them.
This wasn't done long ago.
I'll find him.
It'll be okay Malachi.
Where have you been?
Uh, I couldn't find the damn car keys.
And then I was like..wait, is that like Rogers
and 355 or Ransom?
Yeah, never mind, let's go.
It would be a lot easier,
if you would just play grandma.
Oh, I don't really care for those sort of
games, if you want to know the truth.
Try your brother.
- Tessek?
- Eben, do you want to play?
Oh, I can't right now Jake, I'm sorry.
While you were busy with John Reese,
Carter Wilson called.
about a vandalism problem at the
utilidorf.
Thanks.
You know, call Point Hope and Wainwright
and see if they have any troubles.
No!
I am not trapped here for a month.
There will be someone you can bunk with.
Uh, don't start Billy.
Peggy and me and the 2 girls in one room.
Place of your own.
I can't stay here..I've got bills to put and
my plants will die.
It will work out.
Of course the process of staying at my place...
...is you can explain to me and Peggy just
what is wrong between you and Eben.
I don't have enough time this century
to cover that Billy.
Eben, how you doing?
Good to see you.
Boy, it's gotta be 10 below out here.
- Eben
- Wilson.
Can't your wife bring you out
a sweater or 2?
Bring the whole tribe up,
while she's at it?
When they're ready I guess.
So...
I found all kinds of garbage
over the years.
Blue jeans...bikes.
Sometimes I can yank them out before
the muffin monster chews them
to shit.
The muffin monster?
That's old Wilson's helicopter logo,
pulled that stuff out before it got
totally trashed.
You keep a copy of your lock and key,
don't you Wilson?
Yeah, I put it in dry-dock, with
tourists headed south.
Haven't looked at it for days.
They ripped out the throttle, the rotors...
half the fucking helicopter.
It's my life Eben!
Why would someone rip the hell out of
my ??????
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Who are you people?
No whiskey?
No rum.
Alcohol's illegal this month.
Folks have a hard enough time in the dark
without booze making it worse.
Well forget about the liquor..
...Lucy.
Just bring me a bowl of...
...raw hamburger.
You only get meat 2 ways around here...
frozen or burnt.
You don't bring me what I want to eat
what I want to drink.
That's enough pal, leave the lady be.
Hey, what do you say the 2 of us go
outside and have a little talk, huh?
Now what's wrong with a man
wanting a little fresh meat?
Come on. You and me, let's go.
Taking you outside.
I would like to see that.
I would too.
And Lucy would have to clean up after
Eben kicked your ass.
More trouble than you're worth.
Hey hey
That's enough.
Stay down.
Fire marshals office will take care of ????
It's a funny thing, you never asked.
So you missed your flight?
That sucks, where you gonna stay?
Billy and Peggy are putting me up.
Well, I'll talk to you sometime I guess.
Hey listen, um...
...maybe I'll come along and say hi
to Jake and Helen.
Bye Lucy.
I haven't seen vandalism like this
in a long time.
You don't know how to take care
of this town without me.
Malachi totaled my car.
Hell of a day.
Just you wait.
-Where are we going?
-Headed back to your house.
My landlady doesn't want a bunch of
pipeline workers keeping her up all night.
That's right.
- Let's head back to my place.
- Neither of you are getting me alone.
Neither!
Share, right?
None of us have to be greedy.
Ahh, come on, we'll be good.
Oh, you will?
- Where's ????
- Oh you bad little bitch.
Okay, rock, paper, scissors.
Whoever wins, we go to his place.
- Good idea, do it.
-Hurry up, let's get moving.
On 3.
One, two..
Gabe?
Let me tell you what I got.
You don't work at the refinery.
You didn't fly in.
Somebody would have seen you.
You're definitely not from around here.
How did you get in?
Alright.
We got a long time to figure this out.
Nobody's coming for you for a month.
Jake, come here a second.
What the hell is that?
Oh, it's pot.
It helps her with her cancer.
Didn't tell you I have a little greenhouse
at home, didn't want you arresting me.
Now I know why you wanted to
go live with grandma.
No, I just thought you and Stella would just
want some privacy.
It worked out.
Ah, computer's down.
I'll call Gus.
Strange.
The phone's down too.
Mr. and Mrs. Sheriff.
Soooo, sweet.
So...
...helpless against what is coming.
He's just trying to freak us out.
It's working.
We have more important things to
think about.
I'll check on Gus.
Check on Gus.
Bar the windows.
Try to hide.
They're coming.
This time they gonna take me with them.
Honor me.
Yeah, for all that I have done.
They?
Who are they?
Our generator's kicked in.
- I meant ????
- We have to stay here with him?
Sure. We'll keep an eye on him.
As soon as the lines are back up,
get Billy over here, stay on the walkie-talkie
with me until the power gets back.
Gus!
Gus?
This is sheriff Eben Olson, stay in your homes.
...lock your doors, and
load your firearms.
- Is your genny up and running?
- yeah.
Anyone with a genny should go
home immediately just to be safe.
If you don't have one, you should
meet at the diner.
I heard gun shots Eben.
What the hell is going on?
I don't know.
Just go home, I'll let you know
when I find out, okay?
Let's just have dinner John.
Please?
John! John!
Ally!
No! John!
John!
Ally!
Oh my God!!!
No way out of town.
No one to come help.
- Shut up!
- Ignore him Jake.
You can feel it?
That cold ain't the weather.
That's death approaching.
Who do you think they gonna
take first, hmm?
The girl who takes a gun, will help her?
A kid, a sheriff's kid?
Shut up!
Oh, yeah.
Thank you for the plastic.
I can split it apart and pick the lock.
No it won't.
Jake!
Oh, sheriff.
Helen, get the first aid kit.
All right, time to talk!
Who are you here with?
Who are you here with?!
Who did that to Gus?!
You are dead man.
Where are they!?!
I don't talk to dead men.
I DON'T TALK TO DEAD MEN!!!
Well if I'm dead, no one's getting loose
from here.
You're all dead!
I can take care of that for now, but Doc Miller should...
No.  Wait til the power's back, call Doc Miller then.
This fucker doesn't deserve anything til then.
Billy and I will work our way from the south
street to the pipeline.
His friends don't have many places to hide.
I'll join you.
Oh I got it.
Only you, me and Billy are the authorities.
It's stupid not to take more help.
We got walkie talkies, we'll be fine.
There's a tazer in the back...
if he gives you any trouble....
...use it.  Okay?
You drive, I'm riding shotgun.
Stop the car.
What?
Stop the fucking truck!
I thought I saw something.
- Get in the truck.
- What?
Get in the fucking truck!
Jesus Christ!
- Holy Shit!
What was that?
Who is that?  Where was that?
Where was that?
No...no!
- Helen!
Helen! Helen, come in!
Jake?
Helen?
Are you here?
Oh shit.
They didn't take me.
Who did they take?
Did they take my brother?
Finish me off.
Eben.
Eben, look at me.
No.
What are they?
We don't know.
Wilson, I wanna go home.
It's okay Dad, it's okay.
You keep shooting and they....
...they just keep coming.
How is that possible?
I don't know.  They're all coked up on PCP
or something.
They don't feel any bullets.
They killed every sled dog in town.
They took Aaron and Gabe.
They took my grandma.
- Lucy, is back there alive?
- Oloft
Jake?
Eben!
Who the hell are these people Eben?
What do they want?
We'll figure that out.
We'll get you guy some place safe.
There's a generator at the ??????
No, it's way major out of town, we need
some place close to hide.
Now.
Charlie Kelso's attic?
It has a pull down ladder, you
can't tell it's there.
He would've boarded up his home
before he left.
Which is exactly why it's a good idea.
We'll pull down a board to get it,
and then tack it back.
Carter.
I want you to stay as close to the building
as possible.
If you hear anything, go through a crawl
space and go strait to Kelso's attic.
I'll meet you there.
What are you gonna do?
Something's gotta slow them down.
I'm coming with you.
Okay.
Go on, get out of here!
What the hell is going on?
- I don't know.
We gotta lose this thing.
And go where?
We know a place.
Go!
They seem to work.
Looks well hidden.
...the feet of grandma Helen.
Like...
...vampires, you know?
Vampires don't exist, Jake.
They don't fall when you shoot them.
Well neither do I.
Well, I don't care what they are.
I just care what we do about them.
What are we gonna do about them?
We'll sleep in shifts.
We'll ration our food, and then
we'll figure out the next step.
We have 2 advantages...
We know this town...
...and we know the cold.
We live here for a reason...
...because nobody else can.
Yeah, right.
Gondunk lesz rád.
I guess it's good you didn't want
kids huh?
Imagine...
Where, where's Catherine?
Dad, dad.
Mom died a long time ago.
Isaac...
You should go to sleep now.
That's right, that's right.
Go to sleep.
Thank you.
They're ransacking the Clark's place.
They're tearing through everyone's home.
We have to move!
When do you suggest we do that?
Now...
...while we have the strength.
Until we have some way to stop them,
it's suicide Lucy.
We can stay here til they find us and then....
and they can kill us all,, or we can
run like hell.
Now, some of us won't make it, but it's better
than all of us dying.
- Shut up.
- You should sit down.
So, maybe Denise or Lucy dies, but that's okay
as long as you still have a chance?
Hey.
If we start to fight, that will get us killed
a lot faster.
We go to the general store, and get supplies,
then we go to the utilidorm.
We'll never make it there without cover.
If we get there, we can last the month.
The next blizzard, we'll be ready.
Somebody!
Help!
Please!
Anyone....
We need to get her in here
before they find her.
- Wait.
- What?
Look at the rooftops behind her.
They're using her as bait.
Please!
Please no.
No, I tried.  There isn't anyone there.
God.
No God.
I've known Kirsten my whole life.
I'm going out.
Why are we waiting here for Eben?
...We can make a run
for it and give it all we got.
- Shhhh
- If I can kill anything, I can kill these things.
We'll die in here otherwise.
- Eben doesn't know what he's doing!
- Just move
- Beau.
We agreed to ???????
- Just move!
- We need you here.
Okay, okay.
John.
How long you been under there?
I'm not sure.
Where's Ally?
They took Ally.
Couldn't follow.
You okay?
My leg hurts.
I know a safe place.
I'm going to pull it out.
But stay quiet.
Come on.
I'm really hungry.
We'll get you something to eat.
[Howling noise]
What happened here?
Shit.
Eben.
Carl.
John! Stay back!
Stay back!
John.
Are you hurt?
- There's blood.
- Can't breathe.
I'm okay, I'm okay.
Where's your inhaler?
I lost it.
Oh, shit.
John Reese became one of them.
Isaac!
I'm walking to Wainwright.
It's 80 miles, there's no way to
get there.
- Go upstairs.
- Wilson.
Come on. We need to get out of here.
Bring your mother too.
- We'll die if we go out there.
- No.
I'll die if I stay here, that's what will happen.
Leave me alone.
What's he doing?
Just keep quiet.
- I'm sorry.
- It's alright.
Let's just go back upstairs.
Is there a bathroom?
Just open the valve afterwards.
Who would've thought we'd make it
this long, huh?
We're ahead of the curve.
Everyday they need more food,
they'll be back.
Dad?
No noise.
- Wait, you can't just rush out there.
- He's my father!
No, wait!
Stella, you alright?  What happened?
Isaac went to Wainwright.
Wilson went to find him.
How long have you been down here?
Dad!
We should've fought harder...
...kept Wilson here.
It's hard to stop someone,
when their family's at stake.
The things you'll do to save your home.
We were like that once.
Weren't we?
Let's go on.
It's snowing.
As soon as it's safe, we have to move.
Canned goods, Stella ?????
Uh, propane, and batteries.
Jake, better get supplies.
We meet back here in 2 minutes.
- Let's go.
My wife and I wouldn't live on these things
while she was gone.
I'm done playing with this one.
Do you wanna play with me now??
What?
She was just a girl.
You did the right thing.
It's okay.
Who was she?
Does anybody recognize her?
The white-out is over.
We can't stay here.
But the utilidorm's too far without cover.
Eben?
Can you make it to your station,
if someone created a diversion?
How?
These things can't survive the sun.
What if we brought the sun early?
Helen had that operation at home.
Yeah, she used an ultraviolet light
to grow the stuff.
We can run for her place,
let them follow me.
And hit them with the sunlamp, while
the rest of you beat it to the sheriff's station.
Just because something stopped
Bella Legosi, doesn't mean,
...it can stop these things.
Why would they send that
stranger to cut us off?
...into the light?
And what if it doesn't work?
It has to.
I'll do it.
- I'm the fastest.
- Bullshit!
I weigh less than you, and I
know grandma's house.
You've got a wife, people need you.
Jake.
I saw you in the back with the ax.
You think you're up to doing that
3 or 4 more times?
You don't think this plan will work.
Yeah, but you do.
I'm going.
See you at the station.
You'll need to start the genny first.
See you soon.
- Okay.
- Goodbye.
Hey...come on motherfuckers!!!
Come on!!
Come on Stella.
Are you there?
Yeah, yeah it worked.
But they're gonna cut off the power
so.....
Stella.
We got em.
Oh, it's good to hear your voice.
Don't wait for me.
Eben, run for Rogers Avenue, towards
the trencher.
It's my turn.
Fuck off!
Open the barrel.
Top of the world.
You ain't gonna eat me.
Beau
and Doug.
Now there's 6 of us.
And then there will be just 5.
The little girl in the store.
Changed.
Just so thirsty now.
I couldn't tell you.
That photo is all I got left of my family.
Martha was taking the kids
to visit her mom.
They were hit....
...by a drunk driver.
Anna wanted to be with me so much.
I couldn't bring myself to do it.
But, I know they're waiting for me.
I can't live forever.
I can't.
Don't let me.
No Carter.
He told us what he wants.
Do you see that?
Yeah.
It's Billy.
Billy.
It's Peggy and the girls.
I heard the screams.
I didn't want them to die like the rest.
I was about to shoot myself too...
when the fucking gun jammed.
I shouldn't have signaled you.
I just couldn't stand being on my own.
You have a family.
You don't ever hurt them!
You don't ever hurt them.
Maybe they tried the utilidorm.
Gail!
No, Stella!
I'll meet you at the utilidorm.
No, Billy, stay there!
Eben!
Jake!
Stella?
Gail Robbins?
We don't know.
Stella, this is Eben, come in.
Chocolates, vitamins and vodka.
Stella, come in, this is Eben.
We should celebrate.
One day til sunrise.
You did good getting everybody here.
Eben.
Stella.
???? is walking around.
Just had to hear your voice.
Like you're there with me.
Where are you?
Are you okay?
???????
I'm freezing Eben.
I can see the car,
the rack on the right.
We're coming to get you.
There's way too many of them.
They'd kill us before we got to her.
We have to cut off or they'll hear you.
I'll call you back when it's safe.
The sun comes up tomorrow.
We're going to watch it together.
I'm so sorry baby.
I should never have left you.
The street's filling up with oil.
They broke into the pipeline.
They're burning down the town.
Nobody will know what happened.
They'll just think it was some
horrible accident.
Next time, they'll take out Point Hope,
Wainwright.
Wait, wait.
This building's strong.
Can't we just ride it out here?
They'll kill her if she runs.
She'll burn if she stays.
If you go out there, won't they come
after all of us?
Oh dear God.
When they're all watching me...
...get on the walkie talkie.
- And tell Stella to run for it.
- What are you talking about?
When John Reese and Carter changed....
they were only bitten, they stayed who
they were for a while.
We can't fight them the way that we are.
Thanks, little brother.
Take care of Stella for me.
- Are you fucking crazy?
- That's somebody else's blood.
He's one of them.
- How do you know?
- He won't attack us.
- Maybe we should stop him now.
- Shut up.
Shut up!
Nobody touches him.
I can smell your blood.
You can't fight them all Eben.
Stella, it's Jake.
Get out of there now. Run!
Go!
What did you do to yourself?
What I had to.
Should I go after them?
It's almost dawn.
We made it.
The dawn.