CLIF: All right.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- All right, I'm Clif Prowse.
- And I'm Derek Lee,
and tomorrow we're going on a
year-long trip around the world!
(ALL CHEERING)
This is the trip that I've been
waiting to do my entire life.
Clif and I, six continents,
over 30 countries.
We're gonna see the Eiffel Tower,
the pyramids, the Great Wall.
It's gonna be epic.
My parents stalled me traveling
when I was really, really young,
and up until the day
that I graduated,
I pretty much spent every
spare moment on the road.
And then, I don't know,
I got what I thought was a
great opportunity in I.T.
Next thing I know,
five years have gone by
with me sitting behind a desk,
and I'm thinking to myself,
"What the hell did I
just do with my life?"
DEREK: Hey, buddy. Are you okay?
(TOILET FLUSHES)
CLIF:
Hello. My name is Clif Prowse.
I am a filmmaker and documentarian.
I have known the
aforementioned Derek Lee
since we were both, uh,
pimple-faced teenagers,
and I basically forced him to be
in every single one of my movies.
Am I nervous? Hell, yes.
Okay? I don't like planes.
I don't like heights.
I don't like the Ebola virus.
I don't even like spicy food.
But this is gonna make for
some spectacular footage.
We are going to film
the entire thing.
We are going to post it online
as the world's greatest
video travel blog ever.
We're calling it
"Ends of the Earth."
And we wanted this to be as
interactive as possible.
So you guys post suggestions,
anything you want us to do.
The craziest shit. I don't care.
You want us to go eat live
crickets in Cambodia,
we will do that.
Derek will do that, and I
will film him doing that.
- MAN: Whoa!
- Everybody. Everybody.
This is a very important
Chinese tradition.
Jade is to ward off evil spirits. It
can never be bought for yourself.
It must be given by
another. So, Clif...
(ALL LAUGHING AND WHOOPING)
Going away for an entire year,
I am going to need someone
to watch my back.
I need someone who has seen
me puke my brains out.
I need someone who's seen
me at my absolute worst.
I need someone who would
take a bullet for me.
That's Clif.
I am so envious that you
guys are about to take off
on this awesome trip
around the world.
Most of us experiment in college.
You guys take until now,
but we're thrilled.
We're thrilled you guys are
finally taking this leap.
To Clif and Derek.
(ALL CHEERING)
I think that Derek's decision to
go on this trip is courageous,
but there are some people
who think it's a mistake.
- Hey, man, how's it going?
- DEREK: Good.
Uh, we're leaving,
uh, soon. Very soon.
What does, uh... What does
Mom think? You talk to her?
- Yeah, I...
- She's starting to get a bit concerned
because if something goes wrong on
the road, it's really hard to...
Look, if anything does happen,
there's only really, like,
a 4 percent chance of any...
A 4 percent chance
in some shit-box town
on a long-distance bus
is a hell of a lot different
than falling on the floor
in your kitchen, where your
roommates will pick you up,
call the hospital and say,
"He's somebody who has AVM."
DEREK: A few months ago, I started
getting really bad headaches.
Um, I went to the doctors.
They took an MRI.
And they told me I have something
called an arteriovenous malformation,
Or AVM,
which is basically like a tangle
of screwed-up blood vessels
in my brain which if it ruptures,
can cripple or kill me.
REDEKOP: Look, Derek, I'm not gonna
tell you not to go on your trip,
but if you develop severe
headaches, weakness in your limbs,
loss of the ability to write,
it could be a sign that
your AVM has ruptured,
and it's really important that you
seek medical attention right away.
DEREK:
I have to go, dude, so it's, uh...
She's not gonna understand,
and she's never gonna understand.
And she's my mom, so
she's not supposed to.
- I get that. That's cool.
- Whatever, dude.
I don't think you have to...
Yeah. Whatever. Okay.
CLIF:
Given everything he's dealing with,
I think it's pretty incredible
that Derek is going on this trip.
Um, he is a normal guy who
got dealt a shitty hand,
and in spite of that, he's
not letting it stop him
from doing the things
that he loves.
I'm going on this trip because
I wanna be there for Derek,
and I'm documenting it
because I want to share his
story with everyone back home.
DEREK:
I don't know how much time I have,
and I don't wanna regret anything.
I don't wanna look back on my life
and wish I had done
something bigger or better.
I just wanna travel.
And if I'm gonna see the world,
I kind of have to go right now.
DEREK: Okay, here we go.
Clif has entrusted me
with the B cam here
to get some establishing shots.
That's really lame,
so instead, you guys get to
see what crazy looks like.
- Hello.
- Hello, people.
- DEREK: My God.
- Come. Come see my studio.
DEREK: What are you
doing with all this gear?
- Are you ins...? Oh, man.
- This is where the magic begins
that is "Ends of the Earth..."
That will be "Ends of the Earth."
DEREK: That's a lot of gear,
dude. What exactly is this?
CLIF: That is a strap-on.
- DEREK: A what? Ha, ha.
- Strap-on.
Basically, I put that on,
this thing clicks in, I can
put the camera right here,
which means I can shoot
multicameras at the same time.
One man, multicamera shoot.
Up to three cameras, in fact.
- It is, in fact, amazing.
- DEREK: Ha-ha-ha.
Um...
This is gonna be
awesome, by the way.
- What up?
- All right, we are here
in beautiful Barcelona, Spain, in front
of the Christopher Columbus statue,
about to start our year-long
trip around the world.
Derek, can you explain to us,
why are we starting here?
You mean other than that?
Easy. Rock stars.
CLIF: Edo Van Breemen and Zach
Gray are two friends of ours
who are here on tour with
their band, Unalaska.
We're gonna hang out with
them here in Barcelona
before joining them in Paris
for their final show.
CLIF: Oh, there he is.
- How's it going?
- EDO: Voyeurism, monsieur.
- I can't believe I'm seeing you here.
- Hey.
Has he been doing this for however
long you guys have been here?
ZACH: Did you guys check in or not?
CLIF:
Yeah. No, this is the camera gear.
Heh. You're kidding. Ha-ha-ha.
- CLIF: Okay. Guys.
- Oh, no.
CLIF: We're here. Check it out.
- EDO: The GoCar.
- CLIF: The GoCar.
So I have to say, we're already
having a hard enough time
because we're naturally less
cool than all Europeans,
and now this.
EDO:
It'll provide for some bonding time
- between the two of you, I suppose?
- Yes.
- CLIF: Everyone...
- Wait. Why am I in this thing?
CLIF: Why are you guys not excited?
- It's cool.
- CLIF: What the hell...?
You're gonna pick up
a lot of girls today
riding this thing around town,
especially at the beach.
Fine. No one else gets
it, but I get it.
And we're gonna have a
damn good time today.
I don't really care
what these guys say.
All right. B camera right here.
Two cameras, baby. Two cameras.
ZACH:
This is the best city in the world.
The only two factors that determine
how good a time you have
in a new city are the
weather and the people.
And I don't think we
could ask for much more.
We've had an amazing two days.
The footage is phenomenal.
Probably the coolest thing is just
seeing Derek looking so happy
for the first time in
a really long time.
A weight has been lifted
off his shoulders,
and I can't wait for the
next couple of days,
because things are gonna
get even crazier.
(LAUGHING)
Whoo!
Holy shit. Holy shit!
It was way more scary than
I thought it was gonna be.
Oh, my God.
Group hug. Group hug.
Oh, I love this. Feel the love.
CLIF:
Okay, Derek. If we can find you
a suitably drunk French girl
with low enough standards,
do you think you can take her home?
Let's take a quick poll.
I think that he's gonna
succeed in, uh...
In getting her where
he wants to get her,
but I think that she's gonna
have a horrible time.
(ALL LAUGHING)
With that Canadian vibe, he's
not going anywhere tonight.
Actually, with you guys at my
wing, I'm pretty much screwed.
CLIF: I'll be impressed if he
just talks to a girl tonight.
ZACH: Clif will be filming.
That'll add a certain
amount of pressure.
- CLIF: We have to get this on film.
- EDO: No, I'm on your side.
- CLIF: This is important.
- Can we not...?
Let's not encourage this,
okay? You gotta...
You gotta not be filming
the whole night.
Actually, I have something for you.
It's condoms.
I think this is the lucky one.
Actually, I'll give you all of them.
They're all lucky ones.
Oh, this is very optimistic
of you. Ha-ha-ha.
They're French condoms, so they're
probably the best in the world.
(EDO SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
(IN ENGLISH) We're Unalaska.
We're gonna play
some songs for you.
(ALL CHEERING)
(SINGING) I'm the brother
That you never meet
I'm an anchor
When you swim in the sea
Oh, a life sentence
Like a battery beast
And I only see the light
When you smile with teeth
CLIF: No luck?
No luck?
Have you been telling them
obnoxious travel stories?
- Yep.
- CLIF: You need to lead with
"I have a brain aneurysm."
Okay, that might be a little
bit too close to home.
Dude, there are tons
of cute girls in there.
We are gonna go find
you one right now.
Too hot for Derek?
Possibly. I don't know.
Derek, I got one! Derek!
Aw.
Hell has frozen over.
Derek Lee has found a lady.
CLIF: Hi.
Hi. I'm... I'm Clif.
Buddy, hey, back off
with the... Buddy.
(SINGING)
I'm the skeleton in your body
You will never get a glimpse of me
CLIF: Attaboy, Derek.
I knew you could do it.
And now I'm filming
my friend making out.
Good stuff.
DEREK: So I'm supposed to
act natural while you're...
EDO:
Act natural. Just talk to Clif.
We are leaving, so...
- EDO: Oh, yeah, okay.
- If you wanna come party with us,
- call this, my number.
- CLIF: Holy rock star moment.
We're trying to figure out what
we're doing with our hotel tonight
because our friend went back
there with a girl, so...
Okay, that's fine. So you don't
sleep and, like, party all night.
I have to say congratulations
for him doing it with a girl
because I always congratulate
my friends for that.
- EDO: We don't know...
- It's hard to do.
We don't know if he's
actually doing it.
- CLIF: There's one way to confirm.
- We could find out.
CLIF:
There's only one way to... Exactly.
What you're suggesting is the, uh...
The Turkish cock block.
CLIF: I believe that
that is what it's called.
I think we should
elaborate on that point.
The Turkish cock block is not
in the spirit of friendship.
But it is something
that friends do.
- CLIF: And it is hilarious.
- It's hilarious.
CLIF: I think we really need
to do it. Edo, confirmation?
(IN FRENCH ACCENT)
Operation Cock Block is a go.
(CLIF LAUGHS)
(GUYS LAUGHING)
This is... This is hands
down the shittiest thing
I've ever done to a friend,
but we're gonna do it,
because it's in the
spirit of Paris.
- CLIF: In the spirit of Paris. I like that.
- Yeah.
CLIF: Can I just say,
because we're filming this,
that I am against this
completely because it's mean?
Yeah, well, you can go
sleep in the lobby.
- We're not.
- CLIF: I'm independent.
One, two, three.
ALL: Cock block!
(EDO SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
- CLIF (IN ENGLISH): Holy shit.
- EDO: Derek?
- CLIF: Fuck me.
- EDO: Derek, Derek.
- ZACH: Hey, man.
CLIF: Derek? Derek?
- EDO: Dude...?
- CLIF: Call an ambulance.
- Call an ambulance!
- EDO: What happened here?
CLIP: Call an ambulance!
Derek, wake up.
Wake up!
- Derek, are you okay?
- EDO: You're bleeding, man.
CLIF: Shit, it's on his head.
(GROANS)
CLIF: What the hell happened, man?
What did Audrey do to you?
I don't know. I don't remember.
CLIF: Is she running around
the city naked right now?
I mean, she left all her clothes.
Look, I just said I
don't remember, man.
Like, she comes in, she...
She hits me in the head,
everything goes hazy,
and the next thing I know,
you guys are rushing in, so...
CLIF: We shouldn't be taking
you to the hospital, right,
like, given your condition?
No, I don't think so.
- CLIF: You're sure?
- Yes, I am sure.
Like, look, this looks way
worse than it is, all right?
I just wanna keep going.
CLIF: Are you groggy? Are you okay?
- DEREK: I'm okay.
- CLIF: All right.
- We gotta go.
- This is it.
- All right.
- See you.
Take care, dude.
- Take care of this guy.
- CLIF: Yeah.
- See you, man.
- Take care of your wife.
All right, bye.
CLIF: Okay.
I guess that'll be your place. Heh.
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
CLIF: What the hell, man?
You're still asleep?
CLIF: Get up. Come on, man. Get up.
This is ridiculous. You've
been asleep forever.
Come on, seriously, man. Come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
- How long have I been out?
- DEREK: A while. Way too long.
- Come on. Come on, come on.
- Okay. Okay.
CLIF:
Let's go. Contacts, clothing.
Emerging into the outer world
where you can interact
with other humans beings.
Why are you...? Why are you so...?
Why are you so annoying?
CLIF: Because we're supposed
to be on this trip together.
- What the hell?
- Yes. I am here.
(STOMACH GROWLS)
- Guess I'm hungry. Sorry.
- CLIF: Yes.
Well, I know exactly
the place we can go.
Good.
DEREK: Yeah. Two, please.
CLIF: This place is amazing,
man. Look at this place.
Little sleepy boy here has
been sleeping the days away
and missing this
Mediterranean paradise.
Seriously, look at that.
I'm starving. What are you having?
Um, pesto.
All right, look at that.
Oh, jeez. Thank you.
- Looks amazing.
- CLIF: Look at that.
This food looks so
good, man. This...
Aw. Heh. I am...
(STOMACH GROWLS)
Are you even listening
to me right now?
Oh, Jesus Chri...
Derek.
(CROWD GASPING)
CLIF: Derek. What the hell?
Derek, wait.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
CLIF: Hey.
Hey, man, how are you feeling?
Better.
CLIF: Look, I just think
that with everything that's
been going on with you,
that we should go talk
to somebody about this.
Clif, I'm not going
to the hospital.
Okay, it's probably just
food poisoning, so...
CLIF: What are you talking about?
What are you doing, man?
You got hit in the head.
This isn't something to
fuck around with, man.
DEREK: Clif.
If I go,
okay, and they find something,
they might not let me leave, okay?
And I don't wanna spend
another second in a hospital.
I feel fine.
So, like, we're not
stopping the trip.
DEREK: Are we doing this or not?
CLIF: Yes, I'm rolling, okay?
- Go.
- Okay, uh...
Clif has arranged a tour with
a local vintner named Bartolo
here at his... At his, uh, cantina.
It's Cheo Wines.
Let's go.
- Hello.
- Oh, good morning.
- Hi. I'm Derek.
- Oh, nice to meet you.
- My name is Bartolo.
- Bartolo.
This is our cellar.
We have the largest cellar in town.
- CLIF: Really?
- This doesn't mean so much,
because in Vernazza
the cellars are very tiny.
Everybody has his own cellar.
CLIF: So how do you feel
about, um, showing us the
vineyard, the vines, the...?
Going up on the mountain?
BARTOLO:
Okay, is not so far. Is very easy.
CLIF: You missed this cute pig.
What are you...?
BARTOLO: This is Judita, my pig.
Judita.
CLIF: He's very cute.
BARTOLO: In this area, the main
production is white grapes.
There is a little bit crazy because
this environment, to me...
DEREK: Clif. We gotta go down.
- We gotta go down the mountain now.
- CLIF: Shit.
Clif! I have to go down
- the mountain now.
- CLIF: What's wrong with your skin?
- BARTOLO: Go in casa.
- CLIF: Just go.
Derek, just go. Go! Go!
Shit.
Derek! What do...? What do
you need? What do you need?
(DEREK WHIMPERING)
- DEREK: Water! Water!
- CLIF: Okay, okay, okay.
What the hell is going on?
Here it is! Here it is!
(DEREK SHOUTING)
(WATER SIZZLING)
CLIF: Are you okay?
- DEREK: Aah!
- CLIF: Are you okay?
(DEREK GASPING)
- CLIF: What...?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
CLIF: Jesus.
(GROANS)
Look.
What the fuck is wrong with me?
CLIF: Jesus.
I need your guys' help.
Because seeing what I saw
at the vineyard today,
with Derek and his skin, I don't
think I've ever seen anyone
in as much pain as
I saw Derek today.
And, you know,
I know we talked about doing
this thing for a year,
but, like...
I need to convince
him to come home,
and he's not gonna listen to me.
He's only gonna lis...
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
I'm... I'm really sorry,
but I'm worried about you.
You're... You're sick.
And I don't think you're
being honest with me
or with yourself about this, okay?
You're really sick.
Like...
What happened at the
vineyard was...
And you're still not eating.
And...
I...
I'm your friend, and I
feel responsible for you.
And I can't in good conscience just
let you stay here and hurt yourself.
We have to go home,
okay? It's the right...
- Agh!
- Jesus Christ.
Fuck. Fuck.
Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm good. I'm good.
- CLIF: You just broke the wall.
DEREK:
What is this wall made out of?
It's like... It just disintegrated.
CLIF: It's made out of rocks, man.
Are you...? Did you...?
Did it hit you? Are you okay?
CLIF: Yeah, I'm okay, but
you just broke a rock wall.
Like, look at... Look at this.
It's, like, crumbly and
dry and old and shitty.
- CLIF: Wait, wait.
- DEREK: And I need to go
- to anger-management classes.
- CLIF: Try this one.
DEREK:
What do you mean, "try this one"?
CLIF: I want you to break this
like you did the last one.
(CLIF GASPS)
CLIF: That is awesome.
CLIF: All right, I'm rolling.
(PANTING)
CLIF: Just do it, man. Just do it.
Come on, man. You can do it.
(GRUNTS)
CLIF: Holy shit.
Oh, my God.
(CLIF CHUCKLING)
You just... Are you okay?
- I will be.
- Oh, my...
Oh, shit.
- CLIF: All right, I'm rolling.
- Uh, strength test.
- One, two...
- CLIF: Go at three.
Three.
(CAR ALARM WAILING)
- Go, go, go.
- CLIF: Oh, shit.
CLIF: Holy crap.
Holy cow.
What is it like to be a superhero?
Oh, my God. Let's go, like,
fight some bad guys. Heh.
I don't know if you guys
saw that or not back home,
but that was absolutely
unbelievable.
I hope I got it on tape.
I think I just broke
the sound barrier.
CLIF: What's it like?
You just... You just
lifted a car. Come on.
I don't know. I don't
know what's going on.
(MOTORCYCLE ENGINE ROARING)
CLIF: All right. Are you ready?
- Just go.
- CLIF: All right, here we go.
CLIF: Okay. I'm at 20.
CLIF: I'm at 40.
CLIF:
I am at 60 kilometers an hour!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
CLIF: Whoa!
Holy shit!
CLIF: You were going 60K, which
is like 4O miles an hour.
- How do you explain that?
- DEREK: I don't know.
CLIF: Is there any way this
could be related to your AVM?
(SIGHS)
- CLIF: Derek, are you okay?
- DEREK: Oh, my contact.
Fuck.
- CLIF: What is it?
- I don't know, man.
Can you just...? Can you
just turn that off?
- Just turn off the camera.
- CLIF: What?
Our, just... Clif...
Look, I don't wanna be a dick,
but turn off your camera.
There's something
wrong with my... Ugh.
CLIF: Are you okay?
(GROANING)
CLIF: What the fuck?
Fuck.
What are you doing?
Dude... Dude, don't.
- Stop pulling.
- Clif... Clif...
- CLIF: Derek.
- DEREK: Did I just pull out my eye?
- CLIF: What the...?
- Did I just pull out my eye?
CLIF: Oh, my God, your eye.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- What are you...?
CLIF: I don't know. I don't know.
I just saw it for a second. I mean...
- DEREK: Oh, the other one.
- CLIF: Derek.
Oh, my God, are you okay?
Holy shit.
CLIF: Jesus Christ.
What the hell is wrong with you?
(RETCHING)
CLIF: Shit.
He's ignoring my mom's e-mails.
He's ignoring my e-mails.
- What do I do?
- You're the only person...
If he's not listening to anybody,
what the hell am I supposed to do?
Yeah, but you're the only
guy who's physically able
at this point to do
anything about this.
You know how it is.
He's freaked out.
He does not know what's going on.
You need to be the one who gets him
to somebody who can
take a good look at him
and understand what
this is all about.
Because I certainly
can't do it from here.
I'm just worried if we don't
get him somewhere soon, um,
it's gonna be beyond the point
where I can do anything about it.
CLIF: Derek?
Look, man, I... We need to talk.
Derek?
- Aah!
- CLIF: Jesus!
- What the hell? That's not funny.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- DEREK: Yes, it was.
- CLIF: You need to go to a hospital.
- DEREK: No.
- CLIF: What do you mean, no?
DEREK: I mean no. I feel fine.
CLIF: You are not fine.
You are clearly not fine.
DEREK: What do you need me to do?
You want me to prove it?
- Are you rolling?
- CLIF: I hit the record button.
- Okay.
- What the hell are we doing here?
DEREK:
Okay, I'm super strong. Right?
And super fast.
- Jump test number one.
- CLIF: What are you talking about?
(DEREK GRUNTS)
CLIF: Holy shit.
(DEREK CHUCKLING)
- CLIF: Derek, please just come down.
- Whoo!
I told you I was okay.
CLIF: That's great, but you're
being ridiculous, okay?
Can you just please
come down from there?
You're such a baby.
(GRUNTS)
- Okay, look, I'm fine, all right?
- CLIF: You're not fine, okay?
- Let's just go home.
- No, we're not going home.
We're not going anywhere.
We're staying right here.
Let's test. Come on, let's test.
- CLIF: Shit.
- Ugh.
CLIF: Derek, what are you doing?
Derek, you're freaking
me out right now.
Just stop. Okay?
Come down from there.
DEREK: Okay, Clif, here it is.
If I make this next jump, that
proves that I am not sick.
CLIF: What?
No, this isn't gonna
prove anything.
- DEREK: Aah!
- CLIF: Oh...
Oh, my God. Derek?
Proved it. Okay?
(STOMACH GROWLS)
- Ugh.
- CLIF: Oh, shit.
Are you okay?
(GROANS)
Okay. Okay.
Hospital.
Okay, we're here in
downtown La Spezia.
It's about 20 minutes from Vernazza.
It's the closest place with a hospital.
Derek, you okay?
Okay, well, maybe the doctors
can finally figure out
what the hell's going on. Oh, shit!
(CAR HORN HONKS THEN TIRES SCREECH)
CLIF: Jesus.
(MAN SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
CLIF: Whoa!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
DEREK: Don't touch my...
CLIF: Holy shit.
(MAN CONTINUES SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
CLIF: Oh, my God.
Derek, what the...?
(DEREK GRUNTS)
CLIF: Oh, shit. Holy shit.
It's okay. It's okay.
Okay, he's still breathing.
He's still breathing.
Let's get out of here.
I don't know what I was
thinking. I just, uh...
I uploaded the footage, um,
and Mike posted this.
CLIF: Shit.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
CLIF: Derek?
Derek, I need you to explain to me
exactly what happened on
the way to the hospital.
Did you lick blood off your hand?
Oh, my God.
Okay, so, um...
What are we saying about this?
Look, I won't post it,
but if this is what we think it is,
then we have to document it.
Right?
It says here that, uh, you should
have the ability to turn into mist,
sometimes maybe even a bat,
you have command
over certain vermin,
such as rats and wolves,
and you are unable to enter
into someone's homestead
unless specifically
invited, which is...
- That's a weird one.
- It's fucking useless. Heh.
CLIF: I'm just trying to harness
the power of the Internet
to help you with your
vampire problem.
How do you think this happened?
Oh, my God.
CLIF: Audrey.
It's gotta be, right?
CLIF: What are we gonna
tell people about this?
I don't know.
CLIF: I mean, we're going to have
to tell them something, right?
Clif...
Blood.
Where are we gonna get the blood?
DEREK: Cow's blood?
CLIF: Yeah, I just...
I went to the butcher.
Okay.
CLIF: Shit.
(DEREK RETCHING)
(DEREK COUGHING)
CLIF: Fuck.
That smelled awful.
CLIF: Um...
I think it might need to be fresh.
- CLIF: What did you get?
- Some sausage, I think.
CLIF: You know we're
going to hell, right?
- Like, this is disgusting.
- Oh, my God.
- You eat meat, right?
- CLIF: What? Yeah, I eat meat.
Do you have a pet cow?
People don't sleep with
cows in their beds
and name them and...
These dogs are owned by people.
These are like members
of their family.
So...
(PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
CLIF: Are you serious? That's the
cutest dog I've ever seen in my life.
- That's the one you want?
- Fuck off.
CLIF:
There's no feral dogs around here.
They all have owners.
CLIF: Oh, my God, I can't
believe we're doing this.
- Derek, just...
- Shh. Quiet.
CLIF:
Promise me you'll make it as quick
- and painless as possible, okay?
- DEREK: Shut up.
(SQUEALING)
DEREK: No, no, no.
(PIG CONTINUES SQUEALING)
CLIF: Christ.
Derek.
Oh, my God, oh, my God.
(PIG SQUEALING)
(DEREK GRUNTS THEN PIG STOPS SQUEALING)
(DEREK GRUNTING)
(RETCHES)
(COUGHING)
CLIF: Dude, shit.
Clif is, um...
Clif isn't dealing well
with what just happened.
It has to be human blood.
We've been through everything else.
So, uh, yeah, we're gonna have to
do something very, very stupid.
Okay. We're here outside
the hospital in La Spezia.
Derek has gone inside
the blood bank
to see if he can bribe
an orderly or something.
(CRASHING)
(ALARM RINGING)
- CLIF: Did you get it?
- DEREK: No, no, no, just run! Just run!
CLIF: What the hell happened?
DEREK: I didn't get it, okay?
Jesus, I had to show
them my ID, Clif.
They know who I am.
(DEREK GROANS)
(DEREK COUGHS)
What are we gonna do?
DEREK: Wait. Listen. Listen.
- CLIF: Listen for what?
- DEREK: Okay.
(SIREN WAILING)
- CLIF: What are you doing?
- DEREK: Oh, yes. Yes.
(HORN HONKING)
DEREK: Unh.
EMT: Hey!
(EMT SCREAMS)
DEREK: Get in the ambulance, Clif.
We gotta get out of here.
- CLIF: What are we doing here?
- DEREK: Oh, shit.
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
DEREK: Um...
CLIF: Worst idea ever, Derek.
DEREK: Blood. I need blood.
Do you have any blood?
I need blood! Do you
have any blood?
CLIF:
She does not speak English, Derek.
DEREK:
Clif, it's not working. Help me.
- Clif. Clif, help me.
- CLIF: You're talking in English, idiot.
You're talking in English.
(DEREK SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
- DEREK: Goddamn it!
- CLIF: What are we gonna do?
I don't even know how
to drive this thing.
- I don't know how to drive stick, man.
- DEREK: Just keep driving.
CLIF: Where are we going?
(SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
CLIF:
Derek. Derek, what are you doing?
(DEREK GROWLING)
- CLIF: Derek, stop!
- EMT: Aah!
(THUDDING)
(EMT SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
CLIF: Just go.
DEREK: Clif... I almost killed her.
- CLIF: I know. Just go.
- DEREK: I almost killed...
CLIF: The cops are coming. Go.
Go, go.
(DEREK GROANING)
(DEREK WHIMPERING)
- CLIF: Oh, my... Come on, Derek.
- DEREK: No, Clif, listen.
Promise me if things get
any worse, you will leave.
- Come on, man. We have to go.
- DEREK: Clif. Promise me.
Okay, I promise. Just come on.
CLIF: Derek?
Derek, is that you?
Fuck.
(RUSTLING)
(CLIF GASPS)
CLIF: Derek?
Derek, wha...?
What the f...?
(DEREK SQUEALS THEN CLIF GASPS)
CLIF: Oh, my God. Derek?
Oh, my God, oh, my God.
Derek, just bite on this.
(STICK CRACKS)
CLIF: Oh, shit. Derek.
CLIF: Derek has been
unconscious for 11 hours.
I can't take him to the hospital,
because the cops are
gonna be waiting for us.
He's mostly unresponsive,
except...
I think he can smell my blood.
The, uh... The thing is,
it's still Derek.
I... I know there's a part of him
that's still in there, and...
I'm not gonna leave him.
(DEREK MOANING)
CLIF: Derek?
(HISSES)
(GROWLING)
CLIF: Derek...
Get away from me.
(CLIF PANTING)
CLIF: Derek. Derek, I got it.
Derek?
Derek!
Where the hell are you?
Shit.
Derek?
(RUSTLING)
CLIF: Shit. Someone in there?
Derek?
(CLIF GASPS)
(CREAKING)
CLIF: Derek, is that you?
CLIF: Jesus!
I brought you something.
I know... I know it's not much.
Just... Just take it.
Take it!
(DEREK SQUEALS THEN ROARS)
(CLIF GRUNTS)
(DEREK ROARS THEN CLIF GRUNTING)
(DEREK GULPING)
(ROARING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SOBBING)
Clif...
I'm sorry.
(WHIMPERING)
(SQUEALS)
The, um...
suicide...
was pointless.
It didn't solve anything.
Clif,
you sacrificed everything for me.
And I will never forgive myself
for what I did to you.
There has to be a way to fix me.
So I need to find Audrey.
Everything starts with her.
She has to have an answer.
A cure, something.
Do you hear me, Audrey?
Why? Why would you do this?
Where...? Why...?
You just can't do this to
somebody and just take off.
Like, wha...?
What the hell's...?
I'm coming to Paris,
and I'm gonna find you,
and you are going to fix this.
You're gonna fix this,
or I'm gonna kill you.
Clif is gone.
How that's ever gonna
be okay, I don't know.
But I am going to honor his memory
by keeping the cameras rolling,
by documenting this in the
hopes that somehow some good
can come of this.
It's what Clif would have wanted.
We never officially tested this.
Um...
Sun test number one.
(GROANS)
Okay, that's good.
(GROANING)
Okay.
Audrey is in Paris.
Which has, like,
a population of like
12 million or something.
I just don't have a plan.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
DEREK: Hello?
MAN: Mr. Derek Lee?
- DEREK: Yeah, who is it?
- MAN: I'm from Interpol.
Open the door.
DEREK: Shit.
MAN: I'm Inspector Barbiero
with Italian Interpol.
- Is Clifton Prowse here?
- DEREK: No, he's left.
BARBIERO: Mr. Lee, we
have video footage of you
breaking into a hospital.
Then you stole an ambulance
and endangered lives.
- DEREK: My God.
- You have to come with me.
- The Canadian embassy...
- DEREK: Unh.
(DEREK GRUNTS)
DEREK: Oh, shit.
(DEREK GRUNTING AND WHIMPERING)
DEREK: Unh.
(CROWD SCREAMING)
- Interpol.
- DEREK: Oh, shit.
(DEREK PANTING)
(YELLING)
(GUNSHOT THEN DEREK GRUNTS)
(MEN SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
(DEREK GRUNTING)
DEREK: No, no, no, don't shoot!
(GUNSHOT THEN DEREK GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOT)
DEREK: Stop it! Stop shooting me!
Stop shooting!
(GUNSHOTS)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
DEREK: Sorry.
(DEREK PANTING)
DEREK: Okay. Okay.
DEREK: I am
somewhere east of Nice.
Good thing is my face
stopped bleeding.
Managed to get out of that place
with, um, just my clothes on my back
and the camera bag.
No wallet, nothing,
which means Interpol has
everything they need.
So I better figure something out,
because I'm starting to get hungry.
DEREK:
So I finally made it to Paris.
And I managed to find
this place as a shelter.
It has water
and power and everything
I could possibly need.
Except everyone back
home is freaking out
because Interpol has just
issued warrants for our arrest.
And now I need to find Audrey
before they find me.
Uh, um...
I was going through the footage,
and, um, I was just looking for clues.
I was looking for anything,
just something to help, and...
Shit, you have to check this out.
Okay, here we go.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's it. That's her cell phone.
That's Audrey's cell phone.
It's at the hotel.
I just have to go get it.
Clif, I've never been so
grateful in my entire life
that you shoot everything.
You document everything.
(PANTING)
Thanks.
DEREK: I'm really hoping that
Audrey's stuff is still at the hotel.
Okay, fingers crossed.
Uh, hi.
Um, do you have, like,
a lost and found?
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
DEREK: Okay, okay, okay, thanks.
(DEREK LAUGHS)
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Okay.
- Jason?
- Derek?
DEREK: What are...?
What are you doing here?
- Hey, man.
- DEREK: You can't be...
Please. I got the cops outside.
DEREK: You can't be here.
You can't be around me.
Like, it's not safe.
- Gotta come in.
- DEREK: No, no.
Please, we can sort
this out together.
DEREK:
No, you can't be around me, man.
- It's not safe.
- Please, Derek.
- DEREK: You can't be around me!
- JASON: No, please!
- Derek, stop!
- DEREK: Unh!
(PANTING)
Shit.
Jesus.
Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
(OFFICER YELLING IN FRENCH)
(DEREK GRUNTS)
Unh.
(OFFICERS YELLING IN FRENCH)
(DEREK GRUNTS)
Unh.
(OFFICER SPEAKING IN
FRENCH ON BULLHORN)
OFFICER 1: Stop! Police!
DEREK: Oh, shit.
Oh, no, no, hold on, hold on.
I don't have you. Just hang on.
Grab my arm! Grab my arm!
Grab my arm! Grab my...!
No!
(OFFICER YELLING IN FRENCH)
(GUNSHOTS)
(DEREK GRUNTING)
Unh.
(GUNSHOTS)
I'm so sorry.
It was an accident.
I tried to save him.
I really tried.
I'm not a murderer.
DEREK: Jason.
I just... I just need more time.
And then I promise
I will come home.
Um...
I am not sure
how much longer I'm gonna
be able to hold out.
But I got her phone.
So this is what's gonna happen.
I'm gonna text all the
numbers in this phone
a message to come meet me.
Maybe I'll get lucky.
Call me, you bitch! You
know I have your phone!
I've been posting online.
I gave you my fucking e-mail.
You can contact me. I know
you can, so just do it!
Just do it!
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERING)
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
I finally got a text.
And if this doesn't work...
I'm so screwed.
Audrey?
DEREK: I got you.
(YELLS IN FRENCH)
(DEREK PANTING)
DEREK: I got you.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR CREAKING)
DEREK: Audrey.
(MAN GRUNTING)
DEREK: Okay.
Okay, welcome to an
"Ends of the Earth"
live-streaming event.
Tonight we have a very special
guest in Maurice Behar.
Now, Maurice here is 56 years old,
living right here in Paris,
and he has a very unusual pastime.
Now, what the fuck are you
doing with this, Maurice?
It is covered in blood.
All right, Audrey, here it is.
I have your fucking plaything.
It's been about two weeks,
so I tell you what,
I'm gonna stay right here
until either you show up
or I can't hold out any longer.
So where is she, Maurice?
Where's Audrey? I know you
know where she is. Look at...
(DEREK GRUNTS)
DEREK: Jesus.
MAN: Fifty years, and you are
the first one she's turned.
DEREK: What?
What are you talking about?
I mean, who are you?
You have to run now.
DEREK: What?
You have no time.
- She will come.
- DEREK: Good. Good.
I want her to come.
(SCOFFING)
You know what?
Just kill me,
you ungrateful little shit.
I can't believe she
give this to you.
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
DEREK: Jesus.
(GUNSHOT THEN MAN GASPS)
(MEN YELLING IN FRENCH)
(THUDDING AND GRUNTING)
DEREK: Get off me! Get off me! Unh!
(MAN YELLING IN FRENCH)
(DEREK PANTING)
(GUNSHOT THEN DEREK GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(MAN YELLING IN FRENCH)
DEREK: No, no, no!
(GUNSHOTS)
(MEN YELLING IN FRENCH)
(MEN CONTINUE YELLING IN FRENCH)
(MAN SPEAKING IN FRENCH OVER RADIO)
(MEN CONTINUE SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
(DEREK SQUEALING)
(MAN 1 SCREAMS)
(MAN 2 YELLING IN FRENCH)
(DEREK SQUEALING)
(MAN 2 GRUNTING)
(DEREK ROARS)
(MAN SPEAKING IN FRENCH OVER RADIO)
(MEN WHISPERING IN FRENCH)
(DEREK ROARS)
(MEN SPEAKING IN FRENCH OVER RADIO)
(MAN 3 SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
(GUNSHOTS)
(DEREK SQUEALS)
(DEREK ROARING)
(YELLING)
(DEREK GRUNTS)
(GULPING)
(ROARING)
(GROWLING)
(PANTING)
Wait. Wait.
Please.
(PANTING)
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
(THUDDING)
(SQUEALING)
(DEREK COUGHING)
Don't come near me or
Maurice ever again.
DEREK: What?
What are you looking at?
You're not feeding enough.
What the hell's that
supposed to mean?
Please, you have to help me.
Listen to me.
You must eat.
- Your body will not let you starve.
- Are you insane? You want...?
I can't keep killing people.
You have to be able to fix this.
You have to have a cure.
- A cure?
- Yes, a cure.
This isn't a disease.
There is no cure. You must kill.
(GRUNTING)
Fine. I'm gonna kill you. Unh!
You don't get it!
You can't kill me!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(DEREK GROANS)
(AUDREY SQUEALING)
(DEREK COUGHING)
(PANTING)
DEREK: Do it.
Please.
Kill me.
(AUDREY GRUNTS THEN DEREK GROANS)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHING)
Don't you think I would
have cured myself
if there was such a thing?
Don't you think I would have
ended my life if I could?
You were a mistake.
I will never create another.
I can't... I can't kill
someone every ten days.
- I can't.
- Ten days?
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
(IN ENGLISH)
Your eyes are changing already.
You need to be feeding
every four to five days.
DEREK: No. No.
If you do not choose to feed,
you will become something worse.
You will lose control.
You will kill every day.
Every single day.
And you will not stop.
No, no, no.
You can't choose not to kill.
But you can choose who you kill.
It makes a difference.
DEREK: So why did you choose me?
AUDREY: You were dying.
I thought I was being kind.
Mom, Dad, Jason.
I know you haven't heard
from me in a while.
I needed time to figure this out.
I hope seeing this helps you
to understand what happened.
I just want you to
know that I love you.
And I am very sorry for everything
that I've put you through.
But look.
If Audrey is right and I can't die,
then what I am and the
things I have to do,
you can't be around.
It's not safe.
I'm not the person you remember.
MAN: Hello?
Look, whoever you are,
please, don't hurt me.
(GASPS)
What? What? No. Please.
Let me go. I won't tell anyone.
Please. Why are you doing this?
DEREK: Is this your phone?
- Uh...
- DEREK: Is this your phone?
(GIRL CRYING OVER PHONE)
DEREK: That's what I thought.
Wait. Wait.
What are you going to do?
DEREK: I don't know.
But I'm gonna give you the same
chance you gave that little girl.
(RUSTLING)
(WHIMPERING)
(DEREK ROARS)
DINA:
What are you doing with the camera?
I'm looking for the light.
Just don't put it on the Internet.
JEFF: So, what are we doing here?
We are gonna make your first
night in Italy a memorable one.
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
CHIARA: Whoo!
JEFF: Come on, it'll be fun.
- All the lights are off.
- Okay.
JEFF: Nobody's home. Heh.
- Where's Chiara?
- JEFF: What?
- DINA: Where is she?
- JEFF: What the fuck?
- DINA: Chiara!
- JEFF: Dina, calm down.
- Chiara!
- JEFF: Dina, we'll find her.
- Aah!
- JEFF: Din...!
(JEFF PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, God. Oh, my God.
(PANTING)
Oh, my... Aah!
What the fuck? What the...?
What the fuck is that?
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
What the fuck?
Fuck!
(JEFF PANTING)
(SQUEALS)