Hey. Hey, hey.
Come here. Take a look at this.
What?
- What is it?
- It's a data stream from PS12.
- Where is she?
- Right above sector 14.
There isn't anything in sector 14.
There is now.
- Hello?
- Miss Woods. Pleasure to speak to you.
- Who is this?
- My name's Maxwell Stafford.
I represent Weyland Industries.
- Let me guess. He's suing us again?
- You misunderstand.
Mr Weyland has offered to fund your
foundation for a year, if you'll meet with him.
When?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow's gonna be a problem.
Take me a week to get back to the world.
Yes, I told Mr Weyland that.
He said he didn't have a week.
We must be right on top of it.
What is it, Sebastian?
The burial chamber is here.
I know it. We are gonna find it.
I know it too, but without a crew
and a permit we're out of business.
Hold the team together for two days.
I'll go to Mexico City and I'll talk to the bank.
I'll get us more money.
I might be able to help you
accomplish that, Professor.
Do I know you?
In exchange for a little of your time.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I should've switched the flash off.
There's your magazine. Excuse me.
That's OK.
I'm documenting the trip for my boys.
This is them.
Jacob and Scotty.
Would you mind taking a picture?
Thank you.
Just wanna show them
that their dad wasn't always so boring.
- Smile.
- OK.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
I'm Graeme Miller. I'm a chemical engineer.
Alexa Woods,
environmental technician and guide.
- Do you work for Weyland?
- Oh, no.
No, I split my time between working
for a small environmental group
and taking scientists
on expeditions on the ice.
Lex. Buckle up.
We're gonna hit some turbulence.
Thanks, Jack.
- Is he a friend of yours?
- Of my dad's.
He trained most of the pilots here.
- Just passed the PSR.
- Oh, damn. I wish I'd got a picture.
- Of what?
- The PSR.
I wish he'd called it out before we passed it.
The PSR is the point of safe return.
It means we've used up half our fuel,
so we can't turn back.
Right, but if something went wrong,
we could land, presumably.
- We could ditch.
- Yeah. Ditch.
But the temperature of the water
would kill us in three minutes.
Welcome aboard, everybody. Please.
Some of you may be wondering
why this team has been assembled.
Your host will give you the answer now.
Mr Weyland.
Seven days ago, one of my satellites
over Antarctica hunting for mineral deposits
discovered a sudden heat bloom
beneath the earth, which outlined this.
The red lines indicate solid walls.
Through thermal mapping, we've generated
a three-dimensional image of the structure.
It's massive, containing hundreds of rooms,
all built around a central core.
My experts tell me it's a pyramid.
What they can't agree on
is who built it and when.
One expert tells me this has features
reminiscent of the Aztecs.
Another tells me it's probably Cambodian.
What they all agree on is that
the smooth side is definitively Egyptian.
- I think your experts are right.
- Which one?
- All of them.
- Meaning what, exactly?
This pyramid contains
the features of all three cultures.
This might be the first pyramid ever built.
- But built by whom?
- By the first civilisation.
Thank you.
But how could anyone possibly
build a pyramid out here?
Ancient maps show Antarctica free of ice.
- It's likely the continent was once habitable.
- I can't tell you who built it.
But if I could take a sample from it,
I can tell you how old it is.
Dr Miller, I'm offering
to put you right next to this thing.
- What caused the heat bloom?
- I don't know.
- Where exactly on the ice is this?
- Bouvetoya Island.
But it's not on the ice. It's 2,000ft below it.
- Mr Quinn?
- Mr Stafford.
You're looking at the best drilling team in the
world. We'll chew to that depth in seven days.
Add three weeks on top of that
to train everyone here.
We don't have that kind of time, Ms Woods.
I'm not the only one
with a satellite over Antarctica.
Others will be here soon.
Maybe I wasn't clear.
No one in this room is ready for this trip.
That's why I asked you here.
Bouvetoya is one of the world's most isolated
places. The nearest land is 1,000 miles away.
- There's no help if we run into trouble.
- You're right. It's a no-man's-land.
But the train has left the station.
And I think I speak
for everyone aboard this ship.
This is worth the risk.
Find another guide.
I've spoken with Mr Weyland.
Money's been wired to your account.
Chopper's refuelling to fly you home.
Who'd you get?
Gerald Murdoch.
- Come in.
- Murdoch has two seasons of ice time.
He's not ready.
- Don't worry about it.
- What about Paul Woodman?
- We called him.
- He gave the same bullshit answer you did.
"Bullshit"?
What I told you in there wasn't bullshit. If you
rush this, people will get hurt. Maybe die.
I don't understand.
We're not asking you to take us up Everest.
We need you to take us from the ship
to the pyramid, and back. That's it.
- What about inside the pyramid?
- Don't worry about that.
Once we're on the site, we have the best
technology and experts that money can buy.
- Is this new?
- It's the latest.
Mr Weyland, when I lead my team
I don't ever leave my team.
I admire your passion.
I wish you were going with us.
You're making a mistake.
It's in the upper atmosphere.
Streams of protons
and electrons from the sun
being deflected by the earth's magnetic
field, causing a solar radiation storm.
Shackleton called Antarctica
"the last greatjourney left to man".
It's the one place left in the world
that no one owns.
It's completely free.
Me, I'm sort of partial to the penguins.
I wish you'd reconsider coming with us, Lex.
Come on, don't make me pull out
pictures of my kids again.
Your kids aren't that cute.
What if we got pictures
of other people's kids?
Want my advice?
Stay on the boat.
OK. Let me ask you something.
Do we stand a better chance
of surviving with you
or with the number-two choice?
Miss Woods, your helicopter's refuelled.
They're waiting for you.
Everybody, listen up!
Gather round.
Told you she'd stay.
She can't resist my animal magnetism.
Laugh it up, Miller. Laugh it up.
Gentlemen?
It is my job to keep you alive
on this expedition,
and I need your help to do that.
Since I don't have time to properly train you,
I'm laying down three rules.
One. No one goes anywhere alone, ever.
Two.
Everyone must maintain
constant communication.
Three. Unexpected things are gonna happen.
When they do, no one tries to be a hero.
Understood?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Good.
Seven seasons on the ice
and I've never seen a gun save someone's life.
- I don't plan on using it.
- Then why bring it?
Same principle as a condom.
I'd rather have one and not need it
than need it and not have one.
I'm glad that you decided to stay.
Move the trucks out on the ice.
Move that. OK, let's move.
- What's with the bottle cap?
- What?
What's with the bottle cap?
This is a valuable archaeological find.
When I was a kid growing up in Italy,
you know what they call a moon that big?
La luna del cacciatore.
Brava.
- What's that?
- Hunter's moon.
Hunter's moon.
Hold it, guys.
- Keep those engines running!
- Set it down.
Move over a little further. Connors.
It's an abandoned whaling station.
According to your satellite imagery,
the pyramid is located directly beneath it.
All right, bring it up. Come on.
Spread out.
We'll use this place as a base camp. Mr Quinn,
begin drilling operations as soon as you can.
I'm on it. OK, guys, let's move out.
- What are these?
- Whale bones.
This station was abandoned in 1904.
Everyone just disappeared overnight.
It was a big mystery back then.
One for National Geographic.
- Lex.
- No one goes anywhere alone.
There's something there. Listen. Listen.
Careful. They bite.
Over here. Over here.
What is it?
Can you believe that?
It's drilled at a perfect 30-degree angle.
- How far does it go down?
- All the way to the pyramid.
There it is. Clear as day.
And the same time yesterday...
- Nothing.
- How was it done?
- Thermal equipment of some kind.
- Like yours?
More advanced. Incredibly powerful.
I've never seen anything like it.
There's no team and no machine in the world
that could cut to this depth in 24 hours.
Well, the only way we're gonna know for sure
is to get down there and find out.
Look at that. Change it. Now!
OK, guys, what's taking so long?
There's a storm coming.
There's no room for sick men
on this expedition.
- My doctors tell me the worst is behind me.
- You're not a very good liar, Mr Weyland.
Stay on the ship.
We'll update you at the top of every hour.
When you get sick, you think about your life
and how you're gonna be remembered.
You know what will happen when I go?
Ten per cent fall in share prices.
Maybe 12. That's it.
I've heard this speech before.
My dad broke his leg
700ft from the summit of Mount Rainier.
He was like you.
He wouldn't go back or let us stop.
We reached the top,
and he opened a bottle of champagne.
I had my first drink with my dad at 14,400ft.
On the way down, he developed a blood clot
in his leg that travelled to his lung.
He suffered for four hours
before dying 20 minutes from the base.
You think that's the last thing
your dad remembers? The pain?
Or drinking champagne
with his daughter 14,000ft in the air?
I need this.
Come on, move.
Shit.
Mr Weyland!
Man down!
Get him! Somebody get him!
Move it!
Now!
I don't understand it.
No equipment. No sign of another team.
Well, that tunnel didn't dig itself.
Move it. Connors, get those lights up.
We have power.
Congratulations, Mr Weyland.
Looks like you'll be
leaving your mark after all.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you all for this.
Let's make history.
Thomas.
What is it?
- I recognise the Egyptian...
- The second symbol is Aztec.
Pre-conquest era. The third is Cambodian.
Then you were right.
The pyramid contains all three cultures.
- That's what it looks like.
- "You may choose to enter."
"Those who choose may enter."
Who taught you to translate?
Funny. Kinda looked like you.
Well, it's not "choose".
It's "chosen".
"Only the chosen ones may enter."
Quinn, is that you out there?
Mikkel.
What is all this?
This is the sacrificial chamber.
Like the Aztecs and the Egyptians.
Whoever built this pyramid
believed in ritual sacrifice.
This is where the chosen ones
were offered to the gods.
Those that were chosen would lie here.
They weren't bound or tied in any way.
They went to die willingly.
Men and women.
It was considered an honour.
Lucky them.
"They gave their lives
so the hunt could begin."
What happened here?
It's common in ritual sacrifice
to take the heart of the victim.
That's nice.
But that's not where your heart is.
Besides, it looks like the bones
were bent straight out.
Something broke out of this body.
- What have you found, Max?
- It's a shaft to another level.
Looks like there's another room down there.
- Let's move to that lower room.
- We're moving on, everyone.
Ms Woods.
You, stay here. Rousseau, you stay with him.
Keep a team with you.
Catalogue everything.
Professor.
This should be directly below
the sacrificial chamber.
Sebastian.
It's a sarcophagus.
This is the Long Count.
This is the Aztec calendar.
And this, it's some kind of combination lock.
"Days."
"Months."
"Years."
The dials are set for...
1904.
Someone opened this 100 years ago?
- What's today's date?
- October 10.
10/10/2004.
- Are you sure this is gonna work?
- I don't know.
Back up!
Oh, my God. Take a look at this.
- Any idea what these are?
- No.
- You?
- It's a good thing we brought the experts.
- Well, yeah. It is a good thing.
Cos this is like finding
Moses' DVD collection.
Weyland?
A little too much excitement.
We've been out long enough for today.
We'll set up base camp at the whaling station
and get back at it tomorrow morning.
Well, you can go back to the base camp,
Ms Woods, but we're staying here.
No. You wanted to leave
without proper prep. We did.
You wanted to be the first here. We are.
You've claimed the find. It's yours.
Now, we move as a team,
and we're done for the day.
You heard her.
- What do you wanna do with these?
- Take them.
We'll run further tests on the surface.
No. No! Don't touch them.
- Watch out!
- The doors!
The door!
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Slab's gotta weigh two tons.
We'll never move it.
What did you say this room was called?
Sacrificial chamber.
- Rousseau.
- Tommy, come in.
- Come in, Rousseau.
- Come in.
- Is there anything you didn't tell me?
- Nothing. Your guess is as good as mine.
Whatever it is, we're not prepared.
We're gonna round up the rest of the team
and get to the surface. Let's move!
- What are you doing?
- My job. Yours is over.
My job is over when everyone
is back on the boat safely.
And that gun doesn't change anything.
This bearing should take us back to the
entrance. We'll regroup at the whaling station.
What about Thomas? Rousseau?
- We'll find them on the way up.
- Max?
Stone, Verheiden. Cover our backs.
The heat bloom your satellite detected
makes more sense now.
What do you mean?
A building this sophisticated
requires an energy source.
I think that's what your satellite detected.
A power plant for this pyramid firing up.
- Preparing.
- Preparing? For what?
Gentlemen?
Keep close.
- Recognise what's on their shoulders?
- Yeah.
- We worshipped these things?
- According to this, we did.
And the artefacts you removed from
the sarcophagus seem to be their weapons.
Let's keep moving.
Only another 200 yards to the entrance.
Take cover.
Where's Stone?
Stone!
The pyramid's shifting again.
The doors are closing. Get out.
Come on.
OK. Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go.
Hey! Verheiden!
Verheiden!
Somebody!
Run! Let's go!
No!
Quickly!
No! No!
Hey! Can you hear me?
It's Connors! Where are you?
We're never getting out of this place.
Have you got any children?
- Got a son.
- Yeah, I've got two.
That means that we do not have
the luxury of quitting.
We're gonna make it outta here.
We're surviving this
if I have to carry you the whole way.
There's no way out back there.
- What's that?
- Just a theory.
The Aztec calendar was metric.
Based on multiples of ten.
I'm guessing the pyramid
reconfigures every ten minutes.
Let's stick together.
Weyland.
It would seem that we are rats in a maze.
Sorry.
Connors? Connors!
Verheiden? Verheiden?
- Oh, God.
- Dr Miller! Get me outta here!
It's OK. I'm gonna find a way
to get down to you. OK?
Verheiden!
No!
You want a piece of me?
You ugly son of a bitch!
Oh, God.
Weyland.
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Leave it. They can only slow us down.
Too much has been lost
to leave here with nothing.
Give it to me.
Max.
Hold on.
Look out!
Come on. We have to get Weyland.
Weyland, come on.
- What were they?
- You're the expert.
I've got to stop. I've got to stop.
Take it easy. Weyland.
Look at me.
You have to slow your breathing down.
Slow, steady breaths.
- Weyland, come on.
- I can hardly stand.
I'm not gonna let you die down here.
You didn't.
- There's another one. We have to go. Now!
- Weyland.
- Come with us.
- Get her outta here.
- Now!
- Come on.
Run!
Don't turn your back on me.
Wait.
This way.
Go! Go!
Look over here.
- He's marking himself.
- What?
Ancient warriors would mark themselves
with the blood of their kill.
It's a rite of passage.
This is starting to make sense.
The hieroglyphs are
a little difficult to make out.
But the story is all here.
Thousands of years ago,
these hunters found a backwater planet.
They taught humans how to build
and were worshipped as gods.
Every hundred years the gods would return.
And when they did,
they would expect a sacrifice.
Humans were used to breed the ultimate prey.
The hunters would battle
with these great serpents
to prove themselves worthy
to carry the mark.
But if the hunters lost,
they made sure nothing survived.
An entire civilisation wiped out overnight.
So...
the humanoids, the hunters -
they brought those creatures here to hunt?
And they use us like cattle.
We're hosts for them to breed in.
The heat bloom was the sign
to lure us down here.
This whole thing was a trap.
Without us, there could be no hunt.
Shit!
Verheiden!
Oh, shit.
When that door opens, we're dead.
- Not if we set things right.
- What do you mean?
This pyramid is like a prison.
We took the guards' guns,
and now the prisoners are running free.
To restore order, the guards need their guns.
When that door opens,
we're gonna give that thing his gun back.
Are you crazy? During a big-game hunt, the
animals being hunted don't arm the hunters.
They're not hunting us.
We're in the middle of a war.
- It's time to pick a side.
- We are on our side.
We have to consider the possibility
that we might not make it out of here.
But we have to make sure
those serpents don't reach the surface.
Because if they do,
everything everywhere could die.
The enemy of my enemy...
is my friend.
Let's go find our friend.
How do you say "scared shitless" in Italian?
Non vedo I'ora di uscire con te da questa
piramide perché mi sto cagando addosso.
More or less.
Move!
Lex.
Hold on.
Come on, Lex.
Oh, no.
Wait. Wait. Please, wait.
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
I'm coming with you.
You hear me, you ugly creature?
What are you doing?
Miller!
Sebastian.
- Help me, Lex.
- I'm gonna get you out of there.
- It's too late. It's inside me.
- I'm gonna get you outta here.
- You can't...
- No!
No. No. No! No!
I have to help him.
Lex!
They mustn't reach the surface.
I know.
Do it!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's a bomb.
Well, I hope it kills every fucking one of 'em.
You are one ugly mother...
Got it!
Visiontext Subtitles: Margaret Burke
ENGLISH