CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
NEW LINE HOMEVIDEO
AND NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
[Gasping]
Police found her in the street.
Looks like she was bitten.
Some kind of an animal.
WOMAN: Jesus!
Her water's broken!
She's going into
uterine contractions!
We'll have to do
a C-section!
[Heart monitor beeping]
[Baby crying]
[Flat line tone]
What you got down there,
little man?
Oh, that's
my heat seeker.
I'll bet it is.
Aah!
Ha ha ha!
So, where are we going?
It's a surprise,
baby.
Yeah, I like surprises.
Yeah.
DENNIS: Whoo!
Oh, my God!
What the fuck
are we doing here?
Whoo! Look at all that.
Ha ha ha!
What the fuck is that?
Hey!
[Speaking
Slavic language]
What did you just say?
[Techno music playing]
Wow.
Whoo! Hey, what's up?
Unh! Man!
Whoo!
All right.
Ha ha ha!
Yeah.
Whoo!
Ha ha ha!
What's happening?
Unh!
Whoa!
Man.
Fuck.
Fuck. I need a drink.
Ahh!
[Cheering]
No! No!
Aah!
What's wrong, baby?
Aah! Aah!
No! No!
[Growling]
Aah! No!
Ha ha ha!
[Cheering and clapping]
Is that him?
Jesus, that's him.
It's Blade.
It's the daywalker.
[Snarling]
Come on, daywalker!
[Screaming]
Aah!
Hey! I'm gonna rip
your fucking head off!
Unh!
[Click]
Aah!
That's him!
That's him! Get him!
Fuck him up!
We're gonna jack you up.
Make him hurt bad.
Whoo!
Yaah!
[Screaming
in Slavic language]
Quinn...
I'm getting a little tired
of chopping you up.
[Beeps]
Thought I might try fire
for a change.
[Speaking
Slavic language]
Give my regards to Frost.
[Screaming]
No! Please don't!
[Radio crackles]
Put him out.
Yes, sir.
Paramedics.
Got a charred cadaver here
for you. Still warm, too.
1, 2,3.
[Sizzling]
Oh, Jesus, that's rank.
Paramedics said
he was still screaming
when they found him
stapled to a wall.
That's very pretty.
CURTIS: Did you check
the chem count?
His blood sugar's
3 times norm,
phosphorus and uric acid
are off the charts.
KAREN: You took this
off a D.O.A.?
Yeah.
But this doesn't
make any sense.
The red blood cells
are biconvex,
which is impossible.
Look at the polys.
They're binucleated.
OK, Curtis, it's 3.00
in the morning--
This is not a joke.
I've got the body sitting
in the morgue right now.
I thought you promised
to give me some distance.
I just want you to come down
and take a look.
OK. Show me the body.
And I don't want to hear
a word about us.
Done. We've had
that conversation.
You haven't started on
the internal organs yet?
Just a blood sample
through the pericardium.
The maxilla looks
a little deformed.
There's some odd muscle
structure around the canines.
I'm going
to start the "Y"
and check
the tracheal mucosa.
Let me ask you
something.
Honestly...
you ever have second
thoughts about us?
[Sighs]
Sometimes.
But then I remember how much
of an asshole you were.
Want to cut me
some slack here?
You asked for some time off,
I gave you some time off.
Look, Curtis--
I'm trying.
It's over.
Yaah!
[Snarling]
Aah!
KAREN:
Call security!
Aah!
Came back
to finish you off.
Get out of my way,
you freak!
Freeze!
Motherfucker, are you
out of your damn mind?!
Aah!
Yaah!
[Siren]
Aah!
[Snarling]
Hey, you! Freeze!
Aah!
Freeze!
Hold it right there!
[Gunshot]
Aah! Aah!
My shoulder.
It's dislocated.
Aah!
Uhh!
[Power tool whirring]
[Radio playing
rock music]
BLADE: Whistler.
Whistler.
[Turns off machine
and radio]
Bringing home
strays now?
She's been bitten.
Should've
killed her, then.
Yeah, I know.
But I didn't.
You watch her close.
If she starts to turn,
you finish her off.
Or I will.
KAREN: Uhh.
She's borderline.
Another hour, she'd be
well into the change.
Dr Karen Jenson,
listen close.
I'm going to inject you
with Allium sativum--
garlic.
This is going
to hurt--a lot.
It was Quinn.
Frost's little
errand boy?
You get
a lead on him?
No.
Too bad.
Uhh!
Hold her.
[Laboured breathing]
I give her fifty-fifty
if she makes it
through the night.
[Radio playing
rock music]
Blade...
the daywalker--
still pursuing
his ridiculous crusade.
How many died?
We don't have
an exact count.
Apparently, he used
a lot of silver.
We're having
difficulty--
Send in Frost.
Deacon Frost.
You can come in now.
[Sniffs]
[Speaking Slavic language]
These nightclubs of yours
are dangerous.
Are they?
They draw needless
attention to our kind.
You know our policy.
Your policy,
not mine.
GITANO:
Our livelihood...
depends on our ability
to blend in
and our discretion.
Maybe it's time we forgot
about discretion.
We should be ruling
the humans,
not running around
making back-alley treaties
with them.
For fuck's sake,
these people are our food,
not our allies.
You're out of line, Frost.
Am I?
Or maybe I'm just
the first to say out loud
what we've
all been thinking.
We have existed this way
for thousands of years.
Who are you
to challenge our ways?
You're not even
a pureblood.
Like it matters.
I was born a vampire,
as was every other member
of this house,
but you, Frost...
you were merely turned.
The world belongs to us,
not the humans.
You know that.
Do we have any other
business to discuss?
Well, uh...
there's the matter of
our offshore accounts.
We're having
difficulty--
And have you made
the transfer to the--
Gitano...
you may wake up one day
and find yourself extinct.
[Door opens]
You're a week early.
Yeah.
Whistler says I'm building up
a resistance to the serum.
Yeah, I figured
that might happen.
You take care, all right?
[Mechanical whirring]
WHISTLER: I must be getting
soft in my old age,
letting you bring home
a stray like that.
It was damn stupid of you.
Might've lucked out,
though.
I checked her background.
It turns out
she's a haematologist.
She might be useful to us.
I doubt it.
I'm serious.
I took a look
at that notebook of hers.
She's onto something.
I had to increase
the dose.
It's over
50 milligrams now.
That's getting
dangerous.
Just do it,
old man.
Ahh.
Uhh...
[Groaning]
[Laboured breathing]
Wander off
the beaten path, Doctor?
Who are you people?
My name's
Abraham Whistler.
[Lands silently]
You've met Blade.
So, am I
a prisoner here?
[Exhales]
Not at all.
We just had to take
certain precautions
before we let you go.
You got to understand,
they're everywhere.
Vampires--
the Hominus nocturna.
We hunt them, you see--
moving from one city
to the next
tracking
their migrations.
They're hard to kill.
They tend to regenerate.
And I'm supposed
to believe all this?
Well, you already met
Mr. Crispy at the hospital.
What do you think?
So, what do you use, then?
Stakes? Crosses?
Crosses don't do squat.
Some of the legends
are true, though.
Vampires are severely
allergic to silver.
Feed them garlic,
and they go into
anaphylactic shock.
Then, of course,
there's always sunlight,
ultraviolet rays.
I got this sucker
running.
You want to give it
a try tonight?
It's still heavy.
Well, you're so big.
If you want to live
to see another day,
you'll be out of town
by nightfall.
So where am I
supposed to go?
You've been exposed to them.
One way or another, somebody's
going to take you out.
There's a war going on
out there.
Blade, myself,
a few others,
we've tried to keep it
from spilling over
onto the streets.
[Car engine starts]
Sometimes,
people like yourself
get caught
in the crossfire.
I have blood samples.
I can go to the police.
They own the police.
You have to understand,
they're everywhere.
Chances are you've
seen them yourself
and didn't know it--
on the subway
or in a bar.
So that's it?
You guys just patch me up
and send me on my way?
Here.
Vampire mace...
silver nitrate,
essence of garlic.
You keep your eyes open.
Be careful.
One other thing...
buy yourself a gun.
If you start getting
sensitive to daylight...
if you find
you're thirsty
regardless of how much
you had to drink,
then I suggest
you take that gun
and use it on yourself.
Better that
than the alternative.
[Music playing
at low volume]
You have been warned
before.
These archives
are restricted
to members
of the House of Erebus.
[Scoffs]
You are wasting your time.
It's a dead language.
The ancient texts
can never be translated.
You wouldn't even
understand them.
Damn it, Frost!
I'm talking to you!
Shh.
Keep your voice down,
Gitano.
[Turns off music]
We're in a library.
You don't need
to shout.
What are you up to,
Frost?
[Sighs]
What are you
going to do, hmm?
What?
You bore me.
[Turns music back on]
[Sighs]
[Tyres squeal]
Hey!
BLADE: Remember
what we told you.
You keep your eyes open.
They're everywhere.
[Tyres squeal]
But it's daytime!
[Elevator bell dings]
How you doing?
[Buzzer sounds]
Hi there. Hey.
I'm sorry. Whoa, whoa!
Whoa. Hold on,
hold on, hold on.
Police officer.
I'm sorry, OK?
Police officer. I didn't
mean to scare you.
The front door was open.
What are you doing in here?
I'm just here
on a routine check.
Look, I'm--
I'm Officer Krieger,
42nd precinct.
You're Karen Jenson,
right?
Yeah.
Your co-workers
at the hospital
said that you were
kidnapped last night.
Are you OK?
KAREN: What happened to
the other doctor I was with?
Curtis Webb?
Um, he died.
No, look,
don't worry about that
right now, OK?
Why?
Because you're dead,
too, you bitch.
Aah!
Bitch!
What is it?
[Sniffs]
[Laughs]
What is this, garlic?
Yeah. He said it would
work against vampires.
Vampires?
Who said I was
a vampire, huh?
Nobody.
[Groans]
He's a familiar--
a vampire wannabe.
If he's loyal enough
and he proves himself, maybe
his master will turn him.
Wait a minute.
You used me as bait?
Get over it.
Is all that necessary?
BLADE: That's a glyph--
a vampire cattle brand.
It means that Officer Krieger
is somebody's property.
Another vampire tries
to bleed this little hooker,
then they have to answer
to his owner.
Deacon Frost.
We've been tracking him
for a long time.
All right.
Officer Krieger,
you going to be a good
little bloodhound, huh?
Tell us what your master's
been up to.
Oh, great,
now you're robbing him.
You going
to rob me, too?
How do you think that we
fund this organization, huh?
We're not exactly
the March of Dimes.
It's fake.
Well...
Looks like our friend here
has been blood running, huh?
Hillbarn Clinic.
I know this place.
It's a blood bank.
Owned by vampires,
and there's one
in every city.
And they always deliver.
So, where were you
taking it?
I don't know what
you're talking--aah!
Ooh!
Look, take it easy.
I'm only going to ask you
one more time.
Where were you taking it?
Go fuck yourself.
Fuck me?
No, you fuck this.
[People screaming]
You better wake up.
The world you live in is
just a sugarcoated topping.
There is another world
beneath it--
the real world.
And if you want
to survive it,
you better learn
to pull the trigger.
Wait a minute.
I'm coming with you.
You're useless.
I have to stick with you.
It's the only way that
I'll stay alive long enough
to find a cure for myself.
There is no cure.
He's not going
to come back.
Nobody's that stupid.
When you understand
the nature of a thing,
you know what
it's capable of.
[Car engine starts]
It's Krieger.
I'm at 16-0-0-9.
DISPATCH: Yes?
Get me through.
[Tyres squeal]
KRIEGER: I got a delivery
in progress here,
and I just had a run-in
with Blade.
I got to clear out
that clinic on Hillbarn now!
[Roars]
BLADE: Looks like
we hit pay dirt.
That's a vampire mark.
It means that
there's a safe house
around here somewhere--
a place they can go
with donors coming.
See the valets
over there?
They're vampires.
So is the doorman
and the whore
on the corner.
How can you tell?
By the way they move...
the way they smell.
Psst.
It's like a bad dream.
There are worse things
out tonight than vampires.
Like what?
Like me.
OK, Vampire Anatomy 101.
Crosses and holy water
don't do dick,
so forget what you've seen
in the movies.
You use a stake, silver,
or sunlight.
You know how to use
one of these?
Nope...
but I'll damn sure
learn quick.
The safety's off,
rounds already chambered--
silver hollow point
filled with garlic.
You aim for the head
or the heart.
Anything else is your ass.
[Speaking
Asian language]
Do you have
an invitation?
[Speaking
Asian language]
[Dance music playing]
[Women rapping
in Asian language]
What you got?
Kenji!
[Chef speaking
Asian language]
Ohh!
Where's the entrance?
I can't tell you
that, man.
Uhh!
I'm going to ask you
one more time.
Where's the entrance?
OK. OK.
It's in the freezer.
Come on, man!
I told you!
It's in the fridge!
OK.
You give Frost
a message from me.
You tell him it's
open season on suckheads.
Some kind of archive.
This must be where they keep
most of their records.
Isn't this just
a little high-tech?
They've got their claws
into everything--
politics, finance,
real estate.
They already own
half of downtown.
[Dance music playing]
Frost throws a good party.
WOMAN: Yeah...
but where is he?
Come on, baby.
Don't keep everyone
waiting.
MAN: Deacon,
there's someone here
to see you.
I got to talk to you,
Frost.
KRIEGER: I'm sorry.
I had to come here.
It's a mistake
going to Pearl's.
I know that.
Dumb fucking me.
I know you're
disappointed.
Am I that
transparent?
You want
to meet him?
Yeah.
I can get you guys
in with him,
because we're tight.
We're like brothers.
Fuck.
Aw, fuck. Frost.
Hey.
Yeah.
Deac. Deac.
I've been telling these
bitches all about you, man.
They've been dying
to meet you.
They are so psyched.
Bad ass bitches.
They--
Hi.
Deac?
Frost, it's about Blade.
Aw, he's busy, you know?
Because, like, when
he's focused on business...
Look, Frost,
this is important.
Blade was waiting for me,
using the girl as bait.
WOMAN: And you were stupid
enough to take it.
Shut up, bitch.
I didn't know he was
going to be there.
It was a trap, see?
But don't worry
about it.
It's no problem. We can
still get the girl.
[Grunting]
Yeah!
[Quinn laughs]
Whoo!
[Grunting]
[Squeaks]
Forget the girl.
I want Blade.
WOMAN:
I know you do.
You hear me, Quinn?
I want him alive.
What?
Wait a minute, man.
[Laughs]
You want him alive?
KAREN: What's that smell?
HIGH-PITCHED VOICE:
...image carefully, Frost.
You will need 12 purebloods
to make the ritual work.
Krieger, is that you?
He--he's here!
He's here!
BLADE:
This must be Pearl,
the record keeper.
[Loud flatulence]
He's going to kill me!
You need me, Frost!
You need me!
Pearl, you're history.
Have the good grace to die
with some fuckin' dignity.
PEARL: Frost.
Ruthless bloodsucker.
Congratulations, Blade.
Frost.
I hear you've
been lookin' for me.
I'm flattered.
It'll pass.
Fuck.
[Snap]
[Pearl moans]
What is that?
That, biscuit boy,
is a U.V. lamp.
We're gonna play
a little game
of 20 questions.
Depending on
how you answer,
you may walk out
of here with a tan.
What's that?
Oh, that?
Oh, it's nothing.
It's routine research.
Heh heh.
Actually,
it's a video game.
[Shrill screaming]
That must've hurt.
It's a fragment,
a piece of the prophecy!
What prophecy?
Oh, I'm not really sure.
There are so many out--
[Screaming]
And there is nothing you
can do about it, daywalker!
Is that so?
Well, that's
what Frost says.
Then you won't mind me
borrowing this
for a while, will you?
If he moves, fry him.
What's in here?
Nothing.
It's a--a storeroom.
But you're
wasting your time.
There's nothing
of importance to anyone.
Then you won't mind
if I take a peek.
No!
[Screaming]
[Flesh bubbles]
[Sizzling]
[Whimpering]
He moved.
What is this?
These are the pages
from The Book
of Erebus,
the Vampire Bible.
It contains everything...
their entire history.
La Magra must be
one of their legends.
Why is Frost
so interested in La Magra?
Shh!
[Footsteps]
Give me your hand.
Do you remember me?
QUINN: Give it to him!
QUINN: Hey! Hey!
Nice one.
Heh.
Well, well, well.
You took my arm, man.
Remember?
But it's cool.
I got a new one.
[Laughs]
Think I'll ever
play piano again?
[All laugh]
You can slice him,
you can dice him,
but the Quinn man
just keeps on comin'!
Check it out.
I've got his pigsticker.
Ah ha ha ha--
Ohh! Aah!
You're a fuck up, Crease!
Ha ha ha ha!
[Snarls]
You're a fuck up!
"l got his pigsticker!"
Ohh.
You're just
full of surprises,
isn't you, chief?
[Panting]
Stay with me, sweetness...
'cause I'm not finished
with you yet.
Ah, looky here.
Silver.
Nice craftsmanship, huh?
Probably cost you
a pretty penny.
Now, this here is a man
who takes his job...
just a little too seriously,
don't you think?
Come to think of it, Blade,
I owe you one.
Actually, if you want
to get technical, Blade...
I owe you two.
[Laughing]
Oh, what's so funny,
bright eyes?
I'm expecting company.
[Muffled radio
transmission]
Catch you fuckers
at a bad time?
No! No guns!
No! No! No!
No! Fuckin' this way!
Drop the guns!
I need him!
He wants Blade alive! Go!
KAREN: You've been
listening in the whole time?
Keeping
radio contact.
Think I'd let him run loose
without a chaperon?
Christ!
I'm too old for this.
Somebody get me
a god-damn wheelchair.
[Beep beep beep]
[Screaming]
Whistler!
He can take care
of himself.
Jump!
[Rail hums
with electricity]
[Train brakes]
[Horn blows]
Aah!
QUINN: Aah!
What are you
gonna do?
Oh, my God.
What's wrong?
It's dislocated.
Ah!
Let me help you.
Aah!
Let me give you--
No! Get away.
[Injects needle]
You're one of them,
aren't you?
No.
I'm something else.
WHISTLER: I found him
when he was 13.
He'd been livin'
on the streets,
feedin' off
the homeless.
His need for blood had
taken over at puberty.
I took him
for a vampire at first.
Almost killed him, too.
Then I realized
what he was.
Blade's mother was
attacked by a vampire
while she was pregnant.
She died, but he lived.
Unfortunately,
he'd undergone
certain genetic changes.
He can withstand
garlic, silver,
even sunlight,
and he's got
their strength.
This time tomorrow,
all those wounds of his
will be healed.
He still ages
like a human, though.
See, vampires
age slower than us.
Unfortunately...
he also inherited
their thirst.
I thought the serum was
supposed to suppress that.
Time's runnin' out.
[Sighs]
His body's
startin' to reject it.
So far, all my efforts
to find a cure have failed.
Why do you hunt them?
I had a family once--
wife and two daughters.
Then a drifter came
callin' one evenin',
a vampire.
He toyed with 'em first,
tried to make me decide
which order
they'd die in.
We kill as many of 'em
as we can find,
but it's gettin' worse.
Because of Frost.
There's somethin'
happenin'
in the vampire ranks.
It's somethin' big...
and I'd stake my life
that son of a bitch
is at the center of it.
KAREN: Blade.
Whistler told me
what happened.
He told me
what you are.
You don't know me.
You don't know
anything about me.
I'm not human.
You look human
to me--
Humans don't
drink blood.
That was
a long time ago.
Maybe you should
let that go.
I have spent
my whole life
looking for that thing
that killed my mother.
It made me what I am.
And every time I take
one of those monsters out,
I get a little piece
of that life back,
so don't you tell me
about forgetting.
...my fault he took us
by surprise!
Two of them against your
entire security force?
Don't put that shit on me, OK,
'cause you were there, too!
I'm sure Deacon
will appreciate--
...stabbed in the balls
for it, all right?!
Aah! You little skeez!
Don't see the lifestyle
really suits you.
I should put this stump through
that shit-eating grin of yours.
Face it, angel.
You were sloppy.
You got
what you deserved.
QUINN: Deac, let me
take this guy out, man.
Look. Look what
he fuckin' did!
He took my hand again!
Listen to me.
I want him alive.
What the fuck
are you talk--
you want him alive?
We've been tryin' to kill
this motherfucker for years.
Are you out of
your fuckin' mind? Shh.
Big guy, relax.
CAPTIONED BYAUTHORITY OF NCI
COPYRIGHT 1991
FALLS CHURCH,VIRGINIA
Be patient.
Now, we got a lot
to do here.
I need you, man.
Heh.
I need you.
Yeah.
[Muffled grunting]
Morning.
How you feelin'?
Look at that.
Whew. Gettin' a little
toasty out here, huh?
Heh heh.
[Clears throat]
When was the last time
you stopped to appreciate
a good sunrise?
Oh, that's right.
You were born a vampire,
so you never had
the pleasure, have you?
That's OK.
It's all right.
Least we're here together.
Share the moment,
which means a lotto me,
by the way, really.
I mean that.
[Groans]
'Cause actually, you know,
when you get to know me,
I'm a fairly
sentimental type of guy.
Bit of an innocent,
you might say.
[Gasps]
Do what you want,
Frost.
Doesn't make
any difference.
You just don't
fuckin' get it.
You're never
gonna be a pureblood.
Hold him.
You will never rule us.
[Groaning]
Aah!
Ow.
Jesus Christ.
Have a nice day.
Sorry, you old dog.
You just got a little
too long in the tooth.
[Quinn laughs]
What, man?
That was funny.
"Long, tooth."
Funny.
Did I tell you
the one about...
Aah!
[Screaming]
What have you done
with Dragonetti?
Let's get down to business,
shall we?
I need 12 volunteers.
Tkktkk.
Whistler.
What is this?
[Sniffs]
Smells like a vampire
wiped his ass with it.
I took it
from the archives.
It's written in blood.
It's from
The Book of Erebus.
I think it's what Frost
has been workin' on.
It's somethin'
about the Blood God,
the spirits of the 12.
I--I don't know.
I can't make out
the rest of it.
Maybe this'll help.
I'll figure out something.
So what's all this?
Took a trip to
the hospital last night,
borrowed some equipment.
For your
miracle cure?
This is E.D.T.A.
It's an anticoagulant.
We use it
to treat blood clots.
Now look what happens
when I introduce it
onto a sample
of vampire blood.
Take a step back.
The reaction's
energetic.
[Snickers]
Some cure.
I didn't say E.D.T.A.
was a cure.
But maybe
you could use it
to explode
some vampire heads.
Wait a minute.
I need a sample
of your blood.
Later.
Gotta go downtown.
Need some serum.
Serum can wait.
This is important.
[Coughing]
[Whistler coughing]
Is he sick?
Cancer.
You have a lot of love
for him, don't you?
We have
a good arrangement.
He makes the weapons.
I use 'em.
You know,
my mother used to say,
"A cold heart
is a dead heart."
[Footstep]
You don't look so good.
I'm just a little tired.
You know we've been...
workin' all night.
I guess we didn't
catch it in time.
You got another day,
two at the most.
For what it's worth,
I'm sorry.
You make it sound
like I'm already dead.
Blade.
How you doin', chief?
Easy.
[Soft sobs]
Wouldn't want
our little friend here
to wind up on the back of
a milk carton, now would we?
Ah, it's nice
to finally meet you, man.
Had my eye on you
for years.
I know all about you--
your serum, Whistler--
everything.
Sunblock.
Hey, it's a start, right?
The goal, of course,
is to be like you,
the daywalker.
You got the best
of both worlds, don't you?
All our strengths...
none of our weaknesses.
Well, maybe I don't
see it that way.
Oh, so it's back
to pretending we're human again?
Come on. Spare me
the Uncle Tom routine, OK?
You can't keep denying
what you are, man.
Heh. You think the humans
will ever accept
a half-breed like you?
They can't.
They're afraid of you.
And they should be.
You're an animal.
You're a fuckin'
maniac.
Look at 'em.
They're cattle,
pieces of meat.
What difference does it make
how their world ends?
Plague...
war...
famine.
Morality doesn't even
enter into it.
We're just a function
of natural selection, man,
the new race.
Looks like
your mascara's running.
I'm offering you a truce.
I want you with us.
What do you think,
I'm stupid?
You're familiar
with the Blood God.
Frost...
you're nothing
to me...
but another
dead vampire.
You're an idiot.
You know that?
I came down here
offering you an easy way out,
and you spit it right back
in my fuckin' face.
Careful.
What do I care?
They're nothing
but cattle...
just like you said.
If you want to take
the hard road, be my guest, pal,
but I promise you
by the time this is over,
you're gonna wish they never
cut you from your mother's--
aah!
Go home.
It was simple.
Why do vampires
need to drink blood?
'Cause their own blood
can't sustain haemoglobin.
Right. So it's
a genetic defect,
just like
haemolytic anaemia.
That means that
we have to treat it
with gene therapy,
rewrite the victim's DNA
with a retrovirus.
They've been using it
on sickle cell anaemia.
Are you sure
that's safe?
I have no idea,
but I don't have
a choice, do l?
You actually think
this could work?
On me...
yes.
On Blade,
I'm not so sure.
See, he didn't
contract vampirism
from a bite
like I did.
He was born with it.
It's--it's part
of his DNA.
I'm sure I can cure
his thirst,
but it's gonna
take time.
Ah, we're out of time.
You saw what was
on that disc.
[Laughter]
[Laughs]
Damn.
Get out of here.
[Laughter]
[Chuckle]
I said get out of here!
Nice place.
Took us a while
to find it!
Bite me
and get it over with.
I ain't gonna bite you.
Do your thing.
Whistler.
Ohh.
Frost took her.
Listen to me.
The disc.
He decoded it.
Frost is trying to...
trigger a fuckin'
vampire apocalypse.
There's some kind of...
Vampire God he's trying
to resurrect.
La Magra.
You're the key.
He needs
your blood.
The blood
of the daywalker.
You're the chosen one.
Listen to me, Blade.
You can't
go after him.
Bullshit.
If Frost gets
his hands on you,
it's all over.
There'll be armies
of the motherfuckers.
[Groan]
Shit.
You're gonna have
to finish me off.
Don't want me
coming back.
We can treat
the wounds.
It's too far gone.
You know that.
Give me your gun.
No.
Give me
the god-damn gun.
Now walk away,
you stupid
son of a bitch.
Walk the fuck away.
[Gun blast]
By the time you watch this,
your friend Whistler
should be dead.
If it makes any
difference to you,
he put up
quite a fight.
You can find us
at the Edgewood Towers.
You seem a bit...
tense.
A bit pent-up maybe,
like you need to
release something.
You know?
Blade not...
givin' it to you
maybe.
I don't know.
I just...
I see such
a beautiful woman.
Great skin.
I'd like to see you
happy, that's all.
Is this the part where
you offer to turn me?
Well, it's either that
or a body bag.
Go ahead.
Bite me.
I'll just cure myself.
I did it before,
and I can do it again.
There is no cure,
baby.
There is if you've
been bit,
if you were once human.
How'd you get
that scar, Deacon?
A born vampire
would have the power
to regenerate from birth.
You must've gotten scarred
before you were turned.
Isn't that right?
Vampires like you
aren't a species.
You're just...infected,
a virus...
a sexually transmitted
disease.
I'll tell you
what we are, sister.
We're the top of
the fuckin' food chain.
The Blood God's coming.
And after tonight,
you people
are fuckin' history.
He's a hurricane,
an act of God.
Anyone caught
in his path
will instantly
be turned.
Everyone you've
ever known,
everyone you've ever
fucking loved.
It won't matter
who's pureblood
and who's not.
How are you gonna cure
the whole fuckin' world?
Hmm?
And Blade's blood
is the key.
We got an intruder.
[Elevator bell]
[Motorcycle engine
revving]
[Revving loudly,
all around]
[Tyres peeling]
Deac, I don't think
you understand.
I mean, this dude
is fuckin' bad. What?
He's, like, he had
20 guys around him--
and he's got shit
he throws at you--
Yeah, the swords.
Throw it in the air,
catch it underneath.
Yeah. Shut the fuck up!
[Over radio] There's no
intruder where we are.
Look, make it happen,
all right?
It's one guy on foot.
That's him!
Get him!
Why am I hearing
gunfire? Huh?
Did I tell anybody
to start shooting?
I need him alive.
No!
Please!
I just work for them!
Jesus Christ.
Lock this place down.
Yes, sir!
Aah!
Aieee!
Eric?
But you died.
I came back, Eric.
That very same night...
when Deacon welcomed me
into his arms.
[Shock blast]
Uhh!
Jesus Christ. I thought
you'd be happy.
You're finally being
reunited with your mother,
and you act like this?
Blade, give it up.
It's over.
She belongs to me,
buddy.
Uh! Uhh!
Don't look so surprised.
You spent your whole life
looking for the vampire
who bit your mother.
Well, here I am.
Who would ever guess
you'd survive
your mother's death?
But you did.
And here we are--
one big happy
fuckin' family.
I need my serum.
Maybe when we
get outta this,
I'll take that
miracle cure of yours.
There's one catch.
If it works,
you'll lose
your strength
and your ability
to regenerate.
You'll be
completely human.
Uhh!
FROST: Blade, Karen,
glad you could make it.
Hey, man. Thanks
for the shades.
Our ancestors
called this place
the Temple
of Eternal Night.
Nice, isn't it?
Apparently, these geniuses
forgot it ever existed.
Fortunately for us...
I'm what you
might call a...
student of history.
Why are we here?
This temple was built
for one glorious moment--
this night,
for the Blood God.
Thanks.
Let's see
this sword of yours.
Well.
Titanium, right?
Acid-etched?
I'll get used
to a weapon like this.
What?
You look surprised.
I told you, Blade,
I know everything
about you.
Hold out your arm,
Quinn.
Why, man?
These are--they're,
like, all better.
Hold out your arm.
Now.
Deac, l--
Just kidding.
Ha ha ha ha!
He was fuckin'
with me.
He was, like,
fuckin'...
Blade.
He can't hear you,
honey.
The thirst has
got him now.
What do we have here?
The precious serum.
Mm. How long's it been
since you shot up?
12, 13 hours maybe?
I bet you're just
dying for a drink,
aren't you?
What's it feel like?
Is your blood on fire?
Try some.
You might like it.
Thanks, but I prefer
the real thing.
In any event,
I don't think you'll be
needing these any more.
It's a shame, you know?
When I think of what
you've become,
what you should
have become.
I guess
I don't blame you.
I mean, with everything
that's happened,
it's the human
side of you
that's made you weak.
You should've listened
to your blood.
Say what you want,
but I promise you,
you'll be dead by dawn.
Ooh.
Get him outta here.
Get these fucks
downstairs. Now.
Come on. Let's go.
Let's go.
Don't worry,
sweetheart.
We haven't
forgotten about you.
QUINN: Oh, no, baby.
We got something real
special planned for you.
QUINN: That surfer boy
had a nice ass.
I sucked him dry.
And you'd figure
he'd turn, man.
Yeah, but he didn't
turn, did he?
No. He turned into
some kinda zombie.
It happens
sometimes, cutie.
[Imitating zombie]
He was fuckin'
tripped out.
FROST: Pathetic.
QUINN: Yeah. These guys
are complete scums, man.
They'll eat anything--
animals, rodents, corpses,
and sometimes...
They'll even
eat vampires.
That's a plus.
And bearing that
all in mind,
I'd like you to meet
an old friend of yours.
Uh!
It's too bad.
I kinda liked her.
What a waste.
[Moans]
I don't know what's
happening to me.
No pulse.
And, of course,
there's the question
of lividity.
Curtis?
Ahh.
Karen?
Karen.
I never thought
I would see you again.
Tell me, Karen,
do you ever have
second thoughts about us?
[Roar]
Karen!
Karen.
Poor child.
You're so sick.
So thirsty.
Don't touch me.
Eric, look at me.
Vampires are
my people now.
I'm one of them.
Can't be.
Yes, it can.
Try to understand,
Eric.
Your mother died
a long time ago.
I've hunted...
I've killed...
and I've enjoyed it.
Haven't you?
I know you have.
Sooner or later,
the thirst
always wins.
Come on.
Spread them out.
One on each glyph,
under the towers.
Make it perfect.
Yeah.
FROST:
Bring the elevator up.
[Thunder]
VAMPIRE:
You stupid girl.
What do you think
is going to happen?
La Magra?
The Blood God?
That's nothing more
than a fairy tale
for pretty
little vampires.
Then why are you
sweating, pureblood?
You're afraid we're
gonna steal your soul,
your pureblood spirit.
You should be.
Read the prophecy.
It's time you fucks
contributed something
to the cause.
SECOND VAMPIRE: Even
if Frost is right,
you really think
he cares about you?
You're gonna die,
just like
the rest of us.
Waah!
Blade.
Tonight, the age of man
comes to an end.
No more compromises.
We're gonna be gods.
Of course we are.
Yeah!
I'm gonna be naughty.
I'm gonna be a naughty
Vampire God.
Ha ha ha!
Gotta stop...
stop...
Save your strength.
Blue.
You're hypovolemic.
You're bleeding
to death.
Need...
serum.
[Gasping]
Blade.
Listen to me.
I want you to take
some of my blood.
No.
Look, just do it.
Is everybody thirsty?
I hope you're all
very fucking thirsty.
[Sucking]
[Panting]
[Wind blowing]
KAREN: Ohh...
don't stop.
Don't stop.
[Karen moans]
Aah!
[Low-pitched roar]
How was it?
Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Uhh!
Aah!
[All screaming]
[Roaring]
Aah!
[Babbles]
Eric...
I'm your mother.
You wouldn't hurt
your mother...
would you?
Come here.
I must release you.
[Screaming]
Fuck!
Aah!
[Groaning]
[Screaming]
Uhh!
Unh!
Deacon?
Not anymore.
[Growls]
Frost!
Kill him.
Wait! I owe you, man.
I got two new hands, Blade.
I don't know which one
to use to kill you with!
Aah!
Yaah!
Frost.
I got struck
by lightning
Aah!
[Kicks]
[Laughs]
I'm really going to
enjoy this now. Haah!
[Shrieks]
Yaah!
Aah!
FROST: Hey, Blade.
Let's do this.
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
You're too late, Blade.
My turn.
[Laughs]
Look at you.
You're a little bitch.
What, your serum?
It can't help you
now, stud.
Nice shot.
BLADE: Aah!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Some motherfuckers
are always trying
to ice-skate uphill.
Uhh!
[Serum bubbling]
Aah!
KAREN: Blade!
Let's get out of here.
[Wind blowing]
I need to get back
to the lab
if I'm going to cure you.
It's not over.
You keep your cure.
There's still
a war going on,
and I have a job to do.
You want to help,
make me a better serum.
[Woman speaking Russian]
[Speaking Russian]
Uhh!
[Blade speaking Russian]
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
NEW LINE HOMEVIDEO
AND NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.