Radio host:...million of
you guys out there.
- Host: What's going on?
- Man: Something I wanna do.
- Host: What do you wanna do?
- Man: I wanna kill myself.
Well, that doesn't--
- Man: I have a gun.
- Host: Have you loaded it?
Host: I'm sorry--
I'm sorry. I just--
I just can't take
these things seriously.
A lot of you guys phone in,
half the time you guys are cranks.
Host: Hello?
Host: Well it takes all kinds.
We're gonna take another caller.
- Host: You're on line two.
- Man #2: I'm here.
Host: Are you all right?
Man #2: Like you give a shit
whether I live or die!
Host: I'm a regular guy,
I know what it's like.
Man #2: Regular guy,
my ass!
They don't pay me a million dollars
to sit there and talk to people.
Host: Well, they're not paying me
for that either.
They pay me to stir it up,
to try and get some dialogue going.
That's why I'm here, I just
wanna get dialogue going with you.
I don't want you
to shoot yourself.
Man #2: My old man drops dead,
that's the point.
Host: I'm sorry,
I didn't know that.
Man #2: He leaves
me his house.
40 years he's been in this house,
that's all he's got.
Host: Yeah, well you lived--
Man #2: He leaves it to me,
and what happens?
Inheritance tax, land tax,
school tax,
you're-lucky-to-be-alive tax!
- Man #2: I lost the place.
- Host: You never--
Man #2: The bank sold it
out from under me.
Host: Oh man...
Man #2: The guy spends
his life working,
paying what he owes,
doing what he's supposed to do.
Can't leave his house
to his only kid...
what kind of mark
has he made?
Host: Listen, chief,
we can all go home and listen
to our own ranting and ravings--
Man #2: You shovel
sh--( beep ) all your life,
and you don't even leave
a mark?
It's like...
you shouldn't bother.
It's like you've
never been here at all!
Host: No man, he left his mark.
He left you.
I don't think your old man's
gonna appreciate you kicking off--
- ( gunshot )
- Host: Obviously--
Host: Hello?
Hi... hello?
We got a...
we have a line?
66QRZ, we're taking a break.
We'll be right back.
Babe?
Janine?
God, you're so...
( dog barks )
( gasp )
Christ!
Is it morning already?
- I'm sorry I woke you.
- Shut the drapes.
( whispering )
Go back to sleep.
I'll be home...
regular time.
No, we're supposed to go
to the thing.
- What thing?
- Barbecue.
Oh.
Jesus, he's your boss,
Henry.
Did you shut the drapes?
I still feel light on my face.
The light.
I got it.
Bye.
You know, it's incredible.
Some guy just killed himself
on the radio.
It takes all kinds.
Shit! Now I'm awake!
Wide awake.
( dog barks )
( barks )
This is people food,
not mouse food.
( saw starting )
Janine: She learned
how to do that.
Oh, it's cute.
Would you mind
callin' her, please?
Janine: All you have to do
is unplug the stupid thing.
( saw stops )
Janine, do you mind
calling her?
Please.
Henry: Janine?
Man: ( chuckle )
Why walk when you can fly, baby?
- Jimbo, what is that?
- My new ride. Get in.
I tell you, if I could fuck a car,
I'd never leave my garage.
- Jimbo: What do you think?
- Oh, she's hot.
She is hot!
- Wanna see what she can do?
- Guess I'm gonna.
Oh yeah, you're gonna.
Whoa...
Come on baby, whoo.
Jesus Christ,
could you just slow down?
d I've got everything I need...
almost d
- d But I don't got you... d
- ( honk )
d You're the one I need
the most. d
Always wanted
one of these babies.
Cost me a bundle,
but I tell you,
some things are just worth it.
Best money I ever spent.
- Jimbo: So I dumped Consolidated.
- Henry: Westerman?
Uh... sold.
You took a bite on it.
Graves was up 1/8th,
but remember you bought high...
against my recommendation.
You did all right
on Stimper though.
Cut to the chase.
What am I getting?
You already got it,
it's in your account,
- 1 2 and change.
- 1 2?
I already told you,
the market's in the toilet.
Even so, I figured...
Ah, shit! That's just my luck.
I expected to net--
Christ! You make it sound like
I shortchanged you.
No, no, it's not that.
I just expected it
to be more.
I always expect it
Look Jimbo,
I'm house-poor.
I don't even own
the house yet.
I'm stretching the work
to afford it.
You get the report
at the end of the month.
I should pay more attention.
Janine looks after the finances.
I told you
this was a bad idea.
Money and friends
just don't mix.
Stop it!
Who better to trust than
my oldest and best buddy, huh?
Huh?  Come on.
Jimbo: 1 2:30, the club.
Call what's-her-name my secretary.
- Betty.
- Right. Work it out with her.
Excuse me.
You--
Man: Hey!
What the hell
are you doing?
Good mornin', Rita.
Rita?
Do you ever listen
to the Larry Case show?
No, but Frank told me.
Some asshole blew
his brains out.
I tell you,
it takes all kinds.
Good morning.
Did anyone hear the Larry--
- Did you watch Elsa last night?
- The Deevers Collection?
Oh, God. The last creative
thing Rip ever did,
was to get himself
a breast implant.
I have a friend who knows him,
like really well.
She says he wanted tits
so he could see
how his clothes would
hang on a person with tits.
Oh yeah.
- Coffee?
- Definitely.
Woman: Hey, morning.
Rosemary?
What are you doing here?
September cover. Milo asked me
to pick out some new faces.
- I like this one.
- Yeah?
- Which one's your candidate?
- Milo's gonna go with that one.
Henry: Number seven.
My lucky number.
- But you haven't even seen her.
- I don't need to.
- Your choice is my choice.
- I didn't say she was--
Buon giorno, bruisers!
Are you okay?
Listen up, guys.
All right...
( all clap )
- Milo: Bruisers!
- All: Bruisers.
Milo: All right!
We've been paying close
to $300,000 for a face...
just because it's hot!
Milo: That's insane,
isn't it?
Milo: I mean, we're hot,
and we make heat.
So, from now on...
Rosie's got the cover.
( cheer and applause )
I'm not actually
gonna be on the cover--
Oh, you ought to be, babe!
You'd knock 'em dead!
- ( gasp )
- ( laughs )
Man: You're the number one
photographer.
I asked Rosie, "Pick me faces
from the street,
that I can own,
and that I can buy...
for nothing."
Milo: I have never seen
any of these chickies before.
But in a minute,
I'll pick September's cover!
It's instinct, you know?
You've heard of that?
Impulse?
Those lima beans
hanging between your legs,
those are balls!
Maybe you forgot
what they look like?
Huh!
- Man: Hello?
- ( laughs )
Milo: Now if you find nothing
down there in-between your legs,
stay home.
But if you find
a pair of maracas,
get your ass over here
and start shaking!
Yeah, get fired.
Show any kind of balls
around here, you get a pink slip.
Let's rock and roll.
We've got 1 0 candidates,
one to 1 0.
So who do you pick?
Who do you like?  Come on.
- Number seven.
- Who said that?
- Henry, sir. It's me.
- Oh, Henry.
So we've got one vote
for number seven from Henry.
- Come on, who else?
- Number two.
- Milo: Number two?
- Man: Number three.
- All right?
- Woman: Number ten.
- It's gotta be number ten.
- Man: She's great.
Oh for--
have you seen her teeth?
Bad teeth.
No way, no way.
Come on, we've seen this face
a hundred times before, haven't we?
This is like
yesterday's pizza.
- Cold!
- Woman: '80s.
We've got number seven, we've got
number nine. Who do you like now?
I'm still going for
number seven, sir.
Oh, Henry, stickin' with
number seven!
I have to admire him.
Because I admire him,
I can be honest enough to tell him...
your taste is in your ass.
( laughs )
Number seven is
a fuckin' skunk!
You want her?
Keep her.
Now this is what
I call a bruiser!
( groan )
You're perfect.
Now what
the hell is she, Rosie?
Milo: Chink or Jap?
She's American.
She was born here, Milo.
Her father's from Korea,
her mother's Puerto Rican.
- Dominican.
- She's a spick.
Yes sir, she's
half hispanic and part--
Milo: Nip?
She's a spick-nip!
- ( woman laughing )
- Or a pic-nic...
I don't care!
Can you imagine this face
on a be-like-me cover,
among all the white bread
in the fucking supermarket?
Milo: Whooo!
Rosie, great job.
And remember, bruisers,
we make heat.
Man: We make heat, yes!
All: We make heat!
We make heat!
Milo: Whoooo!
- Milo: And put a spin on it!
- Spin on this.
Here, here.
Guess my lucky number's
not so lucky.
I thought he'd pick her for sure.
She's his kind of cheap.
You said she was your choice.
I said I thought
she'd be Milo's choice.
I know you picked her
because of me.
You're very sweet.
Other guys should take a lesson.
- You know, Milo is--
- The boss!
- And bosses are--
- Jerks.
( chuckle )
- I was gonna say entitled.
- Milo's entitled himself.
What happened to him?
He was never like that before.
No, I know.
He was a communist.
He was a fuckin' refugee,
for Chrissake!
Milo's been good to me.
He's given me a lot of breaks.
He's given me a career.
I can't just forget that.
I want you to know,
I wanna tell you--
Milo: Creedlow!
- You're one of--
- Milo: Henry, get your ass in here!
Like I said, other guys
should take a lesson.
You're one of the only friends--
- the only true friends--
- Milo: Creedlow!
I know.
No, you don't know.
You don't understand.
What I'm trying to say
is why you and I--
Henry?
- Asshole wants you.
- ( groan )
- Yes, sir?
- What's the fuckin' matter with you?
- A problem with your ears?
- No, sir I was just--
We're talking about the party.
Is everything cool?
The barbecue is--
Why the fuck should I talk to you
about my own barbecue?
- I'm talking about the--
- The masquerade, sir.
You're right, Henry.
That's what we should be
talking about, isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
- So, everything's copacetic?
Sir?
Come on, entertainment, food,
the laser show, the freak show?
- Everything's under control?
- I think it's gonna be a blast, sir.
- Are you coming?
- I'm helping organize everything--
I'm talking about
the fuckin' barbecue, Henry.
Yes, sir.
Yes, I'm coming.
You know it's one of those
bring-your-wife things?
I'll bring my wife, sir.
Good, Henry!
I love it
when it clicks up there.
- Man: Mr. Styles, specifically--
- Milo: Come on.
He's in a staff meeting.
Can I take message?
Who is it?
- It's a Mr. Wynn.
- Oh, put him through.
He'll be right with you.
- Good morning, Mr. Wynn.
- Wynn: Good morning.
I'm calling about
your application.
You were interested
in platinum I believe, not gold?
No, I already have
a gold, but uh...
my wife wasn't impressed,
so I wanted to upgrade to a platinum.
Wynn: Yes, well... a platinum card is
like a blank check, Mr. Creedlow.
It has no cash limit,
as you know.
Your credit history has been
impeccable, but your assets...
We found your estimates
were a bit high.
High?
By 1 0, 1 5 grand?
The market goes up
as well as down. You know that.
- Wynn: We know about the markets.
- Your costume.
But given your limited
equity holdings,
we're a good deal further off
than 1 0 or 1 5,000.
That much?
Jesus, I must have miscalculated,
but that much?
So, my buddy is sitting
at the bar
and these two guys come in
carrying a third guy
and they just leave him there.
The guy just flips off the stool,
and lands flat on his ass.
- Out!
- This is the shaggy dog story?
No, I swear it's true.
So my buddy scoops him up,
puts him back on his stool.
The guy goes... bam!
Flips right off the stool
and lands flat on his ass, again.
My buddy's looking at him thinking,
"Oh, man he's shitfaced."
He goes through his wallet,
gets his license
puts him in his car,
drives him home, rings the doorbell,
his wife comes to the door,
he says, "Look, I got your husband."
She says,"Thank you very much."
He turns to go,
and she turns to him and says,
"Where's his wheelchair?  "
( Larson laughs )
"Where's his fucking wheelchair?  "
Come on, Henry. Jesus Christ.
Do us all a favor, go out with
some of the money I make you,
buy yourself
a fucking sense of humor.
Fuck!
40-30.
I got one for you: A guy wakes up
one morning and he's miserable.
His life sucks.
He's at the end of his rope.
- So, he calls the--
- He calls the Larry Case Show,
It's about that guy that
blew his brains out, right?
Christ, I can't tell
that story to anyone.
Power of the media.
You should know.
I'm not in the media.
I'm in the face business.
- Oh, just out.
- No!
Six inches, man.
Game, set and match.
- You guys are up.
- Great. Thanks.
What I want to know is,
why would someone do that?
So what if your life sucks?
Whose doesn't?
No one's, man.
Except maybe mine.
They turned me down
on my platinum card.
So what?  Who needs it?
Iced tea, please.
- Henry, have something stiffer.
- No, just an iced tea, thanks.
They said it's my assets.
That my assets have come up short.
It makes you wonder.
No shit it makes you wonder.
You don't think there
could be any tampering?
- By who?
- I don't know?  Who's got access?
It's not Janine.
It's probably some
computer glitch.
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
In the meanwhile, Henry,
do us all a favor and
don't get worked up, okay?
Like your friend on the radio,
he gets himself all worked up.
Over what?  Nothing.
I guarantee you, if I ever get
cheesed enough to shoot somebody,
the last person
I'm gonna shoot is me.
Man: Hey, how's it going?
Hey, I just had to do that, man.
You know?
It's a fucking pool party!
No hard feelings, eh?
How are you doing, kiddo?
Listen, thank you, Milo,
This is-- this is the best.
- Huh?
- Yes. Great.
Great party.
Great house.
It's a great house. Great house!
She thinks I'm gonna give it up.
Not a fucking inch of it, Rosie.
I'd rather chop an inch off my dick.
- You have a good lawyer, I hope?
- The best. Me.
- Are you okay?
- Mmm.
Have you filed yet?
You don't file until
you have a term sheet.
All Rosie has to do is not move out.
- She has to live with the creep?
- Not with him, just near him.
It doesn't look anything like him.
- Sure it does.
- Cheek-bones.
- The nose.
- The mouth, maybe the mouth.
Amazing, isn't it?
It's an exact replica,
yet you'd never know who he was.
He's a total blank.
- Who's blank?
- You are, cutie pie.
- Come and take a look.
- That's me?
No.
That's you.
I don't know. I think it's cool.
I can see myself.
Yes, but can you
make other people see you?
- What do you mean?
- Paint it. Color it--
whatever you think might
make people recognize that it's you.
They're great,
but who are they?
The only one I can recognize
is Wilson.
- How could you tell?
- The beak.
You ever do one of yourself?
- Yeah.
- How'd you decorate it?
No, that's no fun.
I know who I am.
Oh. And Milo?
It's enough she has
to look at his real face.
Gloria, most of the time--
I think we all know how
Milo spends most of his time.
- And with whom.
- All you have to do is prove it.
- That's you, isn't it?
- Please. Stars and Stripes.
Not until they elect
a female president.
You never told me you were
a sculptress.
I'm not.
I never had the balls,
as Milo would say,
to do anything original.
My little garden of lost souls.
No matter how they're decorated,
or what their make-up
or what they're wearing,
as soon as they're gone,
they're gone.
They fade from memory completely.
- People are forgettable.
- Most people.
Not all people.
Sorry, you have...
a little plaster.
We should stop hiding.
People will wonder
where we are.
Yes, I should make
an appearance.
You go and see if you can
work on your image.
( growls )
The new cover girl you
picked this morning--
Oh, you like this doll, Ted?
Tom.
You're afraid I'm gonna pull
her pants down, aren't you?
Uh, no.
I mean, yes.
I like her a lot.
But no,
I never thought that you--
Sure you did.
Come on.
No. I'm not going to do it.
Not tonight.
Tomorrow night,
she's fair game.
A month from now, when she's been
all over the newstands,
she'll be everybody's date.
Tonight's your only chance to prove
to her that you're the man.
Right. Yes.
Well, thank you, Mr. Styles.
I appreciate your advice.
Fucker.
You're a total sleaze.
What the hell are you?
Why do you have to fuck
with people all the time?
Because there's nothing else
you can do with them.
Look at them.
Fucking pathetic crowd.
I don't even know
half of them.
The only thing
I need to know,
is that they're busy.
And what's keeping
them busy is me,
Milo Styles.
You're a bastard.
That you are.
Everybody needs a bastard
in their life.
You see,
it gives them...
a yardstick
to measure themselves by.
Your yardstick is out there.
Play with it.
Come on, you're a grown-up.
Don't pop off, okay?
I never met a guy who
popped off as fast as you.
Old guys lose
their patience quickly.
You're not old.
Ooh, I caught a brass ring.
Does it mean I get a free ride?
Nothing's free, Milo.
This is a pay as you go world.
( Milo moans )
Ma'am?
Fill it with the best you've got.
Switch seats. I'll drive.
- I am not drunk.
- Yes, you are,
but that's not what I said.
Say what you think.
Give me a clue, please?
Some reason why I should still
be interested in a dick like you.
Oh, no reason. Especially when
there's so many more
interesting dicks
under the liquor bar.
You noticed.
Thank God,
you're not brain-dead.
- Cash or charge?
- Charge.
I try my best, I go out there
every day, and I--
Let people walk all over you.
Yeah, if that's what
it takes, yes.
- There are rules.
- I know the rules better than you.
Man: Sorry, no smoking near
the pumps. Can I check the oil?
The car's fine. Check his oil.
No. Just gas, thanks.
You hear about women who
fuck their way to the top.
Me...
I have been fucking
my way to the bottom.
Six years and what do we have
to show for it?
A life?
Jesus!
When I first met you I thought
you were on the fast track.
Man, was I wrong.
You swallow your emotions.
You eat whatever shit is served up.
- That's not fair.
- You saw me jerking a guy off,
for Chrissake!
Did you slug him?  No.
Did you slug me?  No.
( knocking on window )
- Yeah?
- Your credit card, sir.
I want to go someplace, Henry.
You are going no place.
You're nothing.
Nobody.
I'm not going in.
Get out.
Get out of the car.
Treat me like shit.
...everything I've got.
What more do you want?
Suddenly I'm nothing.
Fuck you!
Aargh!
Janine: Don't wait up.
Did you hear me, asshole?
I said, don't wait up.
( tires screech )
Radio host: We're taking calls
from everybody around the city.
And we're gonna take one
from John on line two.
- John: Larry?
- Larry: Yeah. Hi, go ahead.
John: I'd like to talk about
the guy that shot himself.
Larry: Yes, what about Mr. Stupid?
John: I don't think he's stupid.
I mean--
Larry: Well, I don't know.
John: He made his point.
He made an impression.
Larry: The only thing he made
an impression was on his skull.
John: That's a good one. He made
headlines in every newspaper.
Larry: He did it on my show,
and that's what everybody remembers.
John: To get attention. For the first
time in his life, he's been noticed.
Larry: What's good about being
dead and noticed?
I mean, dead ain't sexy.
At six feet under,
you think anyone's gonna
notice him in his grave?
- John: He's not in a grave.
- Larry: What do you mean?
John: He's sitting in a rocking chair,
sipping a cold one,
talking to some pimp
on the radio.
I'm him, asshole.
I'm the guy.
Just this regular guy,
my own man and everything,
and I'm risen from the dead.
And this time around,
I'm not taking any-- ( beep )
from rat bastards like you.
You treat us like garbage.
Like we're nothing.
Like we're not even here.
You can't turn a man into nothing.
You try, you're the one that's
gonna pay. You're the-- ( click )
Henry: This isn't happening.
This is just a dream.
Woman: Hello.
Señora, the garage is open.
Is anybody home?
Janine's not here, but I am.
You left the garage open.
The door open.
This is bad city, señor.
You leave house open
it's trouble.
( woman speaks Spanish )
I'm sorry, what was that?
( speaks Spanish )
What did you find, Katie?
What did you find in my pocket?
Find, señor?  Nothing.
I was fixing your jacket,
and fold it out, make it nice.
- ( Katie speaks Spanish )
- You stole money, didn't you?
Money?  No, never.
No?  How about silver?
I steal nothing.
( speaks Spanish )
( Henry speaks Spanish )
You speak Spanish, señor?
Oh, yeah.
I'm full of surprises.
You must have a lovely home, Katie,
with all the things you've stolen.
I steal nothing.
I take nothing.
( silver clanks )
If you take nothing, then there's
nothing in this bag.
Take that!
Henry: It's just that
she made me so angry.
It's real. It's all real.
( tires screech )
Janine: Henry?
The dog is out.
That's a good dog.
Henry, are you home?
Henry?
The dog was out.
Go on now.
Henry...
( saw buzzes )
( yelps )
Pupsie, come here.
I know it's a bad old thing,
bad old saw.
I told your daddy to unplug it.
He doesn't even know what to do
with an extension cord.
Yeah. Hi, it's me.
No, he's not here.
- ( Pupsie barks )
- Pupsie, stop that.
I turned it off.
Come here.
Come here, baby.
That's it.
Huh?
He's not here.
If he was, you think I'd tell him
I'm going away with you?
When you're ready to get serious,
then I'll talk to him.
Until then, I've got to
make a living, too.
( laughs )
Oh, yeah,
like you give a shit.
So where are you taking me?
Really?
How'd you work that out?
Hold on a minute.
Okay.
Come here.
Come on. Come on.
A weekend in the sun.
I'll take it.
Even if you are
just fucking with me.
Hey, Pupsie.
Come on, Pupsie.
Look at this.
Come on.
Yeah, good.
( car engine starts )
- Janine: Milo.
- Milo: I'm hiding.
Milo: Getting warmer.
Getting warmer.
Ooh, you're getting hotter.
Ow!
Hey, got to keep up
your energy, honey.
Some English muffin?
Sable on a bagel?
I told you, I'm not hungry.
Something more substantial?
( latin music playing )
Are we leaving or what?
This is not my idea of a good time,
standing around watching
you eat sable on a bagel.
Adios.
What about some jelly
on the belly?
Oh, God.
Is your dick on steroids?
We spent all last night in bed.
And we're gonna spend
the whole weekend in bed.
Bed...
is a blessing given to us
by the gods.
Come on.
But how often do you get
to make it on a
$40,000 fucking
conference table, honey?
Yeah, wait.
Milo: I'm gonna come.
Oh God, it's so beautiful.
( Janine laughs )
That's good. Give it to me.
Give it to me. Give it to me.
- Oh, yes!
- ( mechanical door rumbles )
Wait! Wait!
Gotcha, dickhead!
Milo!
Hey, Rosie.
Come on, you're spying on me?
That's beneath you, honey.
Just trying to keep track
of who's beneath you, Milo.
You wanna ruin me?
Is that what you want?
I just want what's fair.
- What?
- What's fair, Milo!
Shit!
( rattling )
- ( clanging )
- Milo.
( crashing )
Milo, is that you?
( screams )
What's the matter?
You shocked by my appearance?
- Henry?
- Well, let me tell you,
I'm shocked by yours.
Look at me.
Look at me!
You're crazy, Henry.
You've gone fucking crazy.
Not crazy. No, gone.
All gone.
You took the only thing
that can't be replaced.
My identity.
There's nothing left.
Nothing!
Where am I?
Huh?
Come on, come out.
Where am I?
Hello.
( screams )
God, is that blood?
Yeah, and you know what?
I'm getting a taste for it.
Ow!
Now, I may be a loser,
but I know exactly what to do
with an extension cord.
( Janine screams )
You can't do this to me, Rosie.
Rosie, that was a fucking
private moment, you understand?
Don't you have any ethics?
We're partners--
( glass shatters )
Boo.
Don't-- don't hurt me.
Please, Henry.
You know me?
I heard you talking.
You and Janine.
Well, that puts you at
an unfair advantage, doesn't it?
You know who I am. So, we'll have
to pull back the curtain
so I can know who you are.
Please, just let me go.
Pull back the curtain.
Jesus, Henry.
What's happened to you?
What are you doing here?
Nothing. I came to catch up
on some work, that's all.
Come out here, Tom.
Please, Henry.
You're not going to--
Just come out here, Tom.
I can't fucking check her pulse,
she's hanging 20 feet up
with a fucking cord around her neck.
There's no panic,
the cops are on the way.
There she is, sir.
I don't know what the hell--
What the fuck is--
Sir, she came out from
there, the fourth floor.
Out of fool's mouths.
- What do you mean?
- Janine was right.
I've been eating whatever
shit was served up.
Don't develop a taste for it, Tom.
You'll wind up looking like me.
They saw what happened.
Ghandi knows everything
that happened. He saw everything.
And the guy with the saxophone,
he's fucking blind.
Just relax, all right?
Just take it easy.
- I'm going to check it out.
- We need an ambulance.
I don't know
what's happened to me, Tom.
And I'm not sure
I know exactly what to do.
You and I have got
to come to an arrangement.
Tom: Of course.
Whatever I--
Anything you--
You don't tell anyone
that you saw me.
I won't.
You tell anyone...
anyone that I was here today,
and I'll have to take unpleasant
measures, you understand?
Yes. I swear, Henry.
I'll never--
Don't disappoint me.
I've been disappointed enough.
You have my word, Henry.
You have my word.
Mr. Styles?
- Yeah, who's asking?
- Detective McCleary, Homicide.
You want to tell us
what happened?
Can't you see
what the fuck happened?
Aside from the obvious.
Why are you looking at me?
I didn't do anything.
I was down here on the street,
and she jumped.
The uniformed officers on
the scene don't think she jumped.
What?
They think it was a murder.
Well, you should ask them.
They saw everything.
They can tell you what happened.
Why don't you go
and talk to them?
I'd rather talk to you.
There's some shit here,
kimosabe.
- These things record, right?
- Yeah, sometimes they run a tape.
Hey, boss!
Check this out!
Oh, that was good.
See if you can mess up
the crime scene some more.
Fuckin' chadrool.
I'm embarrassed
to ask this, sir, but...
did you recognize either
one of those garments?
Oh, what do you think, Columbo?
I'm fucking standing here
in my underwear
in the middle of the street
and one of your chadrools
is waving an empty pair
of pants out my window.
We were having an affair,
me and that girl.
It doesn't mean I threw her
out the window, you understand?
Was there anybody else
around up there?
Yeah, of course. I always invite
an audience when I fuck.
Cheerleaders, crackerjacks...
my wife-- ex-wife.
She was here?
What?  As a member
of the audience?
Yeah, very funny.
She's working for me.
She's working for the magazine.
She's a photographer.
You saw her leave?
The building?
You mean she was still
in the building?
You mean she was hiding?
Oh, come on.
No fucking way! No way.
My Rosie, she's an angel.
You don't understand.
She's--
No. No, it's impossible.
That's a fucking
horrible thing to say, sir.
( Pupsie barks )
( car approaching )
( doorbell rings )
- Man #1 : Call him again.
- Man #2: I've been calling him.
Then you know the number.
Call him again.
( phone rings )
( Henry and Janine's voices )
You've reached the Creedlow residence.
Leave a message for
either Henry or Janine,
Henry: and we'll get back to you.
Janine: Maybe.
( giggles )
Henry: We've got to go.
Janine: Come on, we are going.
( Henry and Janine laugh )
( machine beeps )
Yeah, this is
Detective Rakowski again.
It's about your wife,
Mr. Creedlow.
We've got to talk to you.
( machine beeps )
Man #2: Still no answer, man.
I'm telling you the guy's not there.
- You think we should go in?
- No. No. It's too soon.
Maybe he's lying in there.
Maybe something happened to him.
Man #1 : Yeah, maybe.
Man #2: If we make our move,
we should go in.
Man #1 : We have no real cause.
If we pop the door,
they're gonna have our asses.
Man #2: No, no. Come on,
maybe he skipped.
Man #1 : Why would he skip?
Man #2: Wild guess.
Maybe because he killed his wife.
Man #1 : No, no, no.
He didn't do it.
The other dame did it.
Yeah?
You mean Styles' ex?
What ex?  They're not divorced.
She had motive, she had opportunity.
Styles admitted she was there.
Nah, this dame was
not waxed by another dame.
You know how much strength
it takes
to pitch somebody through
a closed window?
That's why the chair.
To break the glass.
This could be the guy.
What about this other guy, Burtram?
I'll bet you 1 00 the dame did it.
- I'll raise you 50.
- You are on.
You go dig up
this Burtram character.
I'll go visit Styles
and his ex.
You're not gonna just let
this guy go, are you?  The husband?
No, no, we're not just
gonna let this guy go.
You call in for a warrant.
And the dame did it.
No, no.
The dame did not do it.
( beeps )
Man's voice: Henry, I just saw
something on the news, and...
it's Jimmy, around 3:00.
Listen, the only thing you can do
wrong right now is freak out.
If Janine is--
I can't even say it.
If it's true, there's ownership,
there's joint holdings,
there's all kinds of legal shit.
Before you do anything,
call me.
( machine beeps )
Henry. Shit, it's 3:30.
It's Jimmy here, I'm dying.
Call me, okay?
Call me.
I thought there'd be more.
I always think--
that there ought to be more.
( Pupsie barks )
You have been the most annoying
thing in my life.
Reporter: Locally,
police report no suspects
in this morning's murder
of a woman on Newmarket Street.
Traffic was snarled
for several hours
as police closed off the scene,
causing a surge of complaints
from the area's
tony business owners.
The victim, whose name is being
withheld pending notification
of next of kin, apparently strangled
to death when she dropped out
of a fourth story office window
suspended on a length of cord.
The city's bravest joined the city's
finest outside the building...
Henry: Yes, is this
the San Juan Agency?
One of your domestics was supposed
to be with us this morning.
Saldano?  I think her first
name was-- is Katie.
Well, she didn't show up.
And I'll let you know
if I hear anything.
What are you saying?
Yeah.
Umm-hmm.
( doorbell rings )
No. Hold on.
Inga!
Stay on the line.
Can you get the fucking door?
( doorbell rings )
Inga!
Where is she?
( phone rings )
Rosie: Whoever it is,
I'm not here.
( doorbell rings )
Milo: You're all wet,
so you'll get the phone,
and I'll get the door.
Maybe I'll get wet, get the phone,
and you get the door.
Okay, I'll get the door.
Just answer the fucking phone,
will you?
- Leave me alone.
- Rosemary, don't go to the door.
- What?
- Don't go to the door.
- Milo went to the door.
- Shit! It's the police.
- Who is this?  Henry?
- They think you did it.
- Did what?
- Be careful. Whatever you say.
- This is crazy. How did you--
- Don't come out here.
Come out where?
- Henry, where are you?
- Outside.
You're outside my house?
You know how it is, right?
You look like a guy who's been
around the block a few times.
With your job,
you must have been out there
salami-ing around
on the side, huh?
No. Of course,
if I had cutie pies
hanging all over me
the way you do--
What are you talking about?
I never touch the chickies.
Word gets out, I'm fried.
The magazine's fried.
The whole shebang
goes Kentucky.
I never touch the chickies.
If I wanna go salami-ing around,
I look for a grown-up.
I think you understand what I mean?
Yeah, well...
I understand what you mean,
"grown-up"...
- Yeah.
-...Iike somebody else's wife.
Fuck you, Pope Pius.
Like you never stuck your dick
up another man's sandwich?
Come on, give me a break.
We're two guys talking here.
Rosemary, there are only two people
who had a reason to kill Janine.
You and me.
- Henry, it wasn't me.
- Listen to me.
Henry, I swear,
I didn't do it.
Listen to what I'm trying to say,
one of us did it.
- No...
- It wasn't you.
- It had to be someone else.
- Milo: We got the cops here.
Henry: I did it.
It was me.
Sorry to bother you, ma'am.
I know this has been tough.
Hey, Rosie's tough, right babe?
One tough piece of flesh.
- What do you want me to say?
- What do you mean, "what"?
I've got nothing to hide.
I've told them everything already.
You caught us in the office,
took some pictures, remember?
All that means
is that I was there.
You were there.
I also told him, didn't I, sir?
I told you specifically,
I told him there's no fucking way
Rosie had anything to do with this.
No, I left.
I told him you fucking left.
Come on, Rosie.
Would you shut the fuck up?
You don't fucking talk to me
like that.
Styles! The lady just asked you
to shut the fuck up!
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
Is there anything you might like
to say without his interference?
Rosemary: No. No.
- McCleary: These masks...
- They're weird, eh?
- The little lady's hobby.
- Can we go inside, please?
Officer, you want to step inside,
and watch some of her other talents?
I'll bet you they're more interesting
than these boring masks.
You never know
what might figure in.
What tape?
What tape are you talking about?
Excuse me.
You guys know anything
about a tape?
Oh.
The security camera
down at Bruiser.
Some asshole leaked it
to the press.
It's got to be a mask, right?
I mean, obviously.
- Yeah.
- It's Creedlow. The husband.
Uhn-uh.
Come on. Anyway,
it's a guy, right?
Give me that.
Obviously, it's a guy.
What's so obvious about it?
That could be a dame.
That Newley dame,
she makes them.
- Makes what?
- Masks. She's got a million of them.
Yeah, and maybe
she killed Creedlow, too.
Something else
I don't know about?
Well, we executed
the warrant on the house.
The place is a mess.
Blood on the floor,
his I.D. stuck to it.
Nine mil slugs in the walls.
And a shirt with a buttonhole where
there ain't supposed to be one.
- What's the word on the blood?
- We're still typing it.
So, Fadush, who's your friend?
She's our only witness.
You interrogate her, huh?
You have the right to an attorney,
if you cannot afford an attorney,
Fadush will finance your attorney.
Reporter:...alarmed
by the recent trend
and views it as greatly exaggerated
in the local media.
The suspect remains at large,
leading to increased speculation
about the identity
of the mysterious assailant.
Police continue
to refuse to comment
about the motive
for the brutal slaying,
saying only that detectives
view it as an isolated incident.
( reporters ask questions )
I don't know what
you're talking about...
The murder,
the 56th in the city this year,
has caused renewed attacks
on the administration's
crime policy,
which has resulted
in an increase
in per capita violent incidents,
up 57% from the same period
last year...
All right...
that's very cute.
Who's there?
Nobody that matters.
Jesus, come on.
Henry?
Are you fucking with me here?
Henry: No no no.
You finish off, I just wanted
to talk about my portfolio.
You know the 1 2 and change that
I thought oughta be more?
Okay, it's better.
Better that
it's on the table.
Better that you
finally found out.
Found out?  What could I have
possibly found out?
Uh...
Oh, you mean the money.
The money that you stole from me.
How long have we
known each other, Jimbo?
A long time, Henry.
A long, long time.
And do you think it's right
to steal from people
that you've known
for a long, long time?
That shiny new car of yours?
I bought it for you, didn't I?
Guys! Anybody?
Walter?
Paul?
Anybody?
( door closes )
Walter?
Is anybody...
is anybody in here?
Henry?
Jesus!
Arrgh! God!
I think I broke something.
Something's broken.
Thanks.
You signed this, didn't you?
Right where it says
authorizing agent?
What are you, nuts?
Are you fucking crazy?
Arrgh!
Okay, okay! Fuck, Henry!
Fuck...
I did it, all right.
It was 30 some grand
over two years. That's it.
That's all I took.
It was Janine's idea.
She took all the rest.
I swear to God I'll give you--
I'll give you
every penny back, Henry.
My briefcase...
my briefcase, it's in my locker.
I'll write you a check
right now.
Looks like you pissed yourself,
there, buddy.
Must be the stress--
the stress of high finance.
You fucking prick.
You're actually enjoying this,
aren't you?
Henry, your face...
- you look--
- Different?
I am, Jimbo.
No more Mr. Nice Guy.
Argh! God!
Why did you do it?
I fucked up, Henry.
I fucked up and I'm sorry.
Now I'm going
to write you a check,
and I'm going to make us square.
I'm going to make us even.
No no no!
Not nearly even!
Not nearly square!
Damn it, Henry, you were
never supposed to notice!
Notice?
You thought because
you didn't notice me,
that I wouldn't notice you?
Really?
Yes!
So if you're going to go
fucking shoot somebody,
shoot yourself, Henry.
Not me!
No, I'm gonna to take
your advice, Jimbo.
The only bit of decent investment
advice you ever gave me--
if I ever get cheesed enough
to shoot someone,
the last person
I'm gonna shoot is me.
Shit...
You fucking lunatic.
Some things are worth it.
Best money I ever spent.
The man had gone to market
To buy a diamond ring
The man who never noticed
That he was not a king
He choose the brightest sparkle
A diamond made of glass
The setting bright and gold
Was crafted out of brass
The man spent all his money
The jeweler was a cheat
He told the man that royals
Wore diamonds on their feet
The man went proudly walking
Inside his shoe, the ring
And no one ever told him
That he was not a king.
So you saw the guy,
but you can't describe him.
You want me to write that down?
Am I a suspect here?
Fine, if I'm a suspect,
I'd like to consult a lawyer
before I answer any more--
Did the I hear the "L" word?
Relax, Mr. Burtram.
Have yourself a cup of joe.
I brought extra.
This Nazi shows up at my house.
I didn't have to come down here
with him, did I?
No, sir, you did not.
So why did you?
Just wait here,
we'll get you a lift home.
- All right.
- You guys, drive this guy home?
- Okay.
- It's this car over here.
Thanks.
He'll tell you where to go.
You're still not hard.
Sorry.
( garage door opens )
Girl: What was that?
Nothing. It's okay.
Come on, let's try again.
I'm ready.
I guess...
I'm not.
Girl: You used to say I got you going
more than anyone ever got you going.
Burtram: You do.
And I had hopes for us,
babe, I really did.
But I have to get out.
What do you mean?
Out of the tub?
Out of town.
Out of the rat race.
Just... out.
Are you wanted or something?
Are you on the lam?
The woman who died?
The police think
I might have killed her.
I didn't.
But I know who did.
Jesus, who?
Another guy.
Another... ordinary guy.
You sold him out
to the cops, right?
No, I told them
I had no idea who he was.
Not far from the truth--
I barely know him.
But in the end,
he might turn out to be
the best friend I ever had.
Come on,
you expect me to pack up
and run away with you
when I'm gonna be
on the cover of Bruiser?
I didn't ask you
to come with me.
I got the cover, Tommy!
I didn't ask you
to come with me.
You expect me to leave town
when I got the cover?
Hey! Creep!
You want a free peek?
Here it is, baby!
Tomorrow it'll cost you more
than you could ever afford!
Larry: 66WQRZ.
The 66th caller wins a T-shirt
with a picture of nobody on it.
Caller, who do you think
Faceless is?
Man: My brother.
He has a problem with authority.
Larry: So spank him. Next.
Woman: I think it's you, Larry.
- That's very funny.
- No one ever sees your face.
You're just a voice
on the radio, anomalous!
Larry: Anon-- anonamis--
anonymous, you idiot.
Which is one thing I'm not!
- This is Frank Himmelfarb.
- Who the hell is Frank Himmelfarb?
My point exactly.
Larry: Why don't you
kill yourself?
This is WKILL.
Phone in and kill yourself.
Himmelfarb!
Frankenfarben.
We're gonna take a break.
We'll be right back.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to startle you.
That's a lie--
actually, I did.
- What are you doing here, Henry?
- I'm going away.
But first I have
accounts to settle.
- Milo!
- He's not here.
I saw him drive away
about an hour ago.
An hour?  So the accounts you
have to settle are with me.
I didn't want to wake you,
so I used the time to finish this.
That's not a cast I made.
Nope, it's all me.
I've been working on my image.
For the world's greatest wuss,
I'm becoming a pretty good
second-story guy.
I got in the back window.
I had to.
There's a police car outside.
I can't let you go out there.
Henry, I'm sorry.
I'm truly sorry
about what happened.
You sound guilty. What have you
got to feel guilty about?
Because I was part of it.
I knew.
You knew?
About Milo and Janine?
How long?
Not long, just... Henry, please,
you're scaring me.
We get so used
to the lies and deceit.
It makes you do things
that you don't want to do.
- I tried to tell you.
- I know.
When you said that it was only the
two of us that could have done it,
I was so sure you thought
it was me,
- I couldn't imagine...
- Imagine that it was me?
That it was Henry?
Henry what's-his-name?
That mouse?
That mouse-dog crawling around
in an unfinished house?
Trying to make it
look like this?
Who would want to live like this,
except a glutton like Milo?
Why don't you just kick it over?
Get out?
Get away from him
and all his fucking garbage!
I am trying.
It's not that simple.
In your head, it's not.
But out here, where your feet
touch the ground, it is.
As simple as murder?
What's in your head, Henry?
Shhh.
It's okay.
I can understand what you did.
I can't forgive it,
and I can't forget it.
But I can understand it.
I know what it's like
to feel so betrayed.
What you don't understand is that
if you let them betray you,
you're betraying yourself.
I've done it my whole life.
And it's what you'll be doing
if you stay with that creep.
What else do I have?
Look at me.
I'll hold.
- What do you see?
- A beautiful woman.
Someone of value.
Someone I value.
No, I'm still here.
We should have spoken.
We did.
You weren't listening.
At the office.
You said you owed Milo a debt.
You were saying,
that if it weren't for that debt,
maybe you and--
Is that the Larry Case Show?
Am I on air?
I'm phoning about Faceless.
I know who he is.
Me, Henry Creedlow.
I murdered my wife.
- For God's sake.
- And another woman.
Katie Saldano.
That wasn't murder...
well, not premeditated.
But I killed her anyway.
I dropped her body
off the 9th Street pier.
Henry, stop it!
And my good friend,
Jimbo Larson.
He's in the river, same place.
He'll be the one
in the fancy new car.
The police are also talking
to a guy named Burtram.
He had nothing to do with any
of this. He's a good guy.
And there's another good guy.
Rosie.
Rosemary Newley.
She had nothing to do with
any of this, either.
And she won't have anything
to do with
whatever happens later tonight.
I'm cutting you loose, Rosie.
( people laughing )
Man: Where the hell
are we going?
Woman: I don't know.
That's half the fun.
Woman: Milo's idea
of a good time.
Pack us in a cattle car
and take us down to the ghetto.
Come on down!
Man: This is the pits.
Actually, we haven't
gotten to the pits just yet.
Oh, I believe I found your switch.
Mind if I turn you on?
Miss Jones, you're beautiful
without your glasses.
I wanted contacts, but
they didn't have my size.
Man: All right,
let's make this quick.
Y'all got some good shit.
Toss it up.
- I don't have anything.
- Let's see what this is about.
You're right.
You ain't got shit.
Not no more.
Arrgh!
Help me.
Hey! Let's party!
Why don't we grab a cab
and go home?
May I have your name, sir?
Mr. Styles likes the names of
those who do not choose to attend.
Man: I think we could,
maybe, for a few minutes.
All right.
You guys stay close to me.
Buddy, can you spare
some change?
It's Henry.
Henry, I hired you, Creedlow.
Going okay?
So far, so good.
Three trucks unloaded,
nobody spotted us as fakes.
Good.
I'm the new cover girl.
Are you somebody I should know?
I don't think so.
I voted for number seven.
Want to see how
fucking crazy I am?
We're the wrong dudes.
Jester: Different strokes
for different folks.
Different rooms for
different dooms.
Feel the coldness.
Feel the coldness of dead flesh.
( rock music plays )
d The silence where you hide d
d Till you scream d
d Till you scream... d
Football player: Touchdown!
Dancer: Extra point.
I didn't think it was
gonna be this nuts.
Call the cannery.
Six cars, signals off.
If Creedlow is here,
I don't wanna scare him away
with sirens and shit.
Two-ninety in a jar.
Strip district, Canal Street.
Number 1 2,
requesting backup.
What the fuck is wrong
with you people?
Milo: She's a bruiser!
Who designed your costume?
Mommy and Daddy.
I'm fuckin' freezing, though.
This is an interesting touch.
What do you mean,
it's fucking real.
That fucking thing is real.
I love it.
It's going to be
a whole new thing.
It's hotter than silicone,
dames with mustaches.
Whooo, I'm gonna change
September's cover.
No! You can't change
your mind.
I told everybody
I got the cover!
Get out of here, you freak!
- Milo?  How's it hanging?
- What the heck was that?
What are you doing here?
Keeping an eye on things.
- Chester?
- Yeah?
Henry Creedlow.
We spoke on the phone.
Oh, yeah.
How ya' doin', man?
So what is all this shit?
Mixers, we got sequencers,
with manual over-rides.
Of course, of course,
manual override.
We've got the nub unit
over there.
That picks up the signals
so we can do the music.
It's gonna be amazing,
you've gotta see this,
Iike it's confetti flying and,
shit, it's gonna be great.
And that thing,
that's a little freaky, though,
because I've never really done
a show before where I had to,
honest to God, deal with
a blaster like that.
- Cool.
- No. Hot. Don't touch it.
This fucker is twice as hot
as the fuckin' sun.
Really?
We'd better be careful then.
Very careful.
Bruiser.
Fuckin' bruiser, man.
( grunting )
( snake rattling )
I think you should
get out of here.
Henry could walk right by and
you'd never recognize him.
He's painted his face.
Only I've seen it.
Everybody here is faceless.
We don't know what
his real face looks like.
We're wasting our time looking
for Creedlow. We gotta find Styles.
Stick with him so nobody
jumps his ass.
Die!
Girl: Hey,
where are we going?
Man: All right,
take him up.
Next victim.
McCleary: Shit! This way.
Come on!
Son of a bitch!
Don't shoot!
You might wax the dame.
We gotta go up.
No, listen,
he's gotta come down.
- Where's the goddamn backup?
- I don't know.
You cover down here,
I'm going up.
Damn!
You called them.
You called the police.
No I didn't.
They followed me here.
They won't stop me.
You won't stop me.
Not until I've finalized
your divorce.
There are other ways
to do this.
To do what?
You still live with the bastard.
He probably still gets
to fuck you in the shower
whenever he's got
the leftover energy.
Am I wrong?
Yes you are!
Don't do this.
They know who you are.
The whole world knows
who you are!
You told them!
I told them because I didn't
want them thinking it was you.
I would have
gotten away with it!
Gotten away with what?
You didn't do anything.
You don't get it!
You said you were
gonna leave.
Go now while you
still have the chance.
I've lost you anyway.
Whatever we had is finished.
Whatever we had?
When you told me you killed
all those people,
I knew there was no chance
of having you as a--
As a what?
Friend?  Soulmate?
Someone to hold your hand,
tell you it's gonna be all right?
You want a companion,
get a fucking dog,
as long as it's not a poodle.
This is where we get off.
Don't worry, it's safe.
Henry, please,
I'm begging you.
Really?
Nobody ever begged me before.
It feels kind of good
to be begged.
We could leave together,
go now...
You're only saying that
to save Milo's ass.
Take advantage, Rosemary.
Do what everyone else does,
and take advantage.
Henry, wait!
They'll catch you if you go!
Rosie, they won't know me.
I'm invisible--
I've always been invisible.
( elevator doors open )
( bat screeching )
Rakowski?  Rakowski?
I'm right here.
I think I got him, third floor.
Stop! Stop or I'll--
( gunshots )
Henry: Jesus, I could have hit you
if I'd wanted to.
You son of a bitch.
d All I give is hate
it seems to them d
d I thought they could make
things evil... d
Girl: Get lost! I don't get
paid enough for this.
Any of you guys seen Styles?
Check the John Does over there.
Come with me.
I wanna give him a taste
of his own medicine.
Okay.
( girl screaming with pleasure )
What the fuck!
Are you trying
to scare somebody?
No.
I'm just waiting my turn.
You're my kind of guy,
aren't you?
That's why I always tell them,
"Bring me a handicapper."
Because nobody uses it,
it's nice, it's clean, it's tidy,
and there's plenty of room
to salami around. Know what I mean?
You mean you had
a woman in there?
Hello?
What do you think?
That I had a shit of a lifetime?
I have to tell you, Milo,
that in my opinion,
you're just about the lowest
thing that ever crawled.
We all mean nothing to you.
That's right, you mean
nothing to me. You know why?
Because you are fucking nothing.
An ant-- a fucking ant,
with no mind and small balls.
That's what you all are,
and I'm a fucking anteater--
- Fuck!
- Milo, relax,
it's all part of the show.
Part of the show?
All right!
We're fucking with you.
We're just fucking with you,
- like you fuck with us.
- I like that.
We've got something planned
for you, sir.
A grand finale?
Yeah, I mean how could we have
a grand finale without you, sir?
- Exactly. Come on!
- Take him away.
Milo: The grand finale,
that's great!
Woman: Milo?
Milo?
He's gone. Party's over.
And if you know
what's good for you,
you'll find yourself a shirt
and get out of here.
Go on!
Yeah! Woo-hoo!
Yeah!
( trumpet blares )
Got it, hit it--
What the fuck was that?
Cool.
Man: Armageddon,
ladies and gents.
Armageddon!
I can fly! I can fly!
Where the hell is Tinkerbell?
Bam!
So what's happening next?
This is fucking hilarious!
I love you,
Romans and countrymen!
Woman: I love you!
I love you, too!
Thank you everyone, everybody!
Aghhh!
God, get me down!
Woman: Yeah, Milo!
This is really happening!
You hear?  This is happening!
What are you doing?
- Woman: Dance, Milo, dance!
- Come on, you want to play?
You little fucking hack!
You're nothing but a hack.
We... make... heat.
( crowd cheers )
Henry?  I didn't realize
you were here.
Henry: You can see my face?
Yeah, Henry,
I can see your face.
My face is back?
Did it go somewhere?
Yeah... but I stood up.
I stood up for myself!
Henry, you are a whacko.
But you are such a cute whacko.
Come here and dance with me.
Come on, come on.
Freeze!
( gunshot )
Masked person:
It's nothing, see?
The mask. My mask.
It's a total blank.
Just like yours used to be.
I can't hear you!
McCleary: Freeze!
Wait a minute, over here.
I'm the killer.
This isn't right!
It's me you want.
No, it's me. You thought
it was me all along. It's me!
It's me!
- It's me!
- No, it's me!
- Me!
Man: This man's dead!
Dancer: That's it, I quit.
No, doll, you're fired.
- Are you all right, miss?
- Yeah, yeah.
Sorry to hear about it.
Rakowski: I need everybody,
listen man, all the way downtown,
we're gonna flood
the fucking warehouse district.
We got a brown Volvo leaving.
A Volvo!
He's gone.
No, he's somewhere.
Somewhere, and I'm going
to find him.
It's my job to find him.
Why'd you do it?
Do what?
Lady, I've been skunked here tonight,
and I've gotta answer for it.
So help me out--
why'd you do it?
I have absolutely no idea
what you're talking about.
Hey.
If you change your mind--
if you catch up to him
before I do, gimme a call.
Okay.
Paula Fleet. That's you.
What are we gonna do
about the Steelers, man?
Here we go.
Here you are, sir.
Apple a day
keeps the doctor away.
Man: Because it's crap,
that's why I don't like it!
Your taste is
up your ass, folks.
What is it with you?
Does nobody have a fucking brain?
I take it back.
You don't need a brain.
What you need is some
fucking cojones, folks!
Some lima beans,
for God's sake!
What the fuck
are you staring at?
Me, sir?
"Me, sir?  " Yes you, dickhead.
Something here interest you?
Not particularly.
Then what the fuck
are you staring at?
Nothing, sir. Nothing.
Get back here--
I'm talking to you, Jack!
I'm talking-- Jesus Christ.
You people are all assholes,
you know that?  You're dicks.
I can't even find a fucking
messenger boy around here
who knows what end is up.
I'm not done with you, asshole!
Get back here!
Coming, sir.
d We're talking away d
d I don't know what I'm to say d
d I'll say it anyway d
d Today's another day
to find you d
d Shying away d
d I'll be coming
for your love, okay d
d Take on me d
d Take me on d
d I'll be gone in a day or two d
d So needless to say d
d I'm odds and ends bother me d
d Stumbling away d
d Slowly learning
that life is okay d
d Say after me d
d It's no better
to be safe than sorry d
d Take on me d
d Take me on d
d I'll be gone in a day or two d
d La la la la la la d
d La la la la la la... d
d Oh oh oh d
d Eeeeeeee d
d Ohhhhhhh d