(GROWLING)
(HISS)
(SNARLING)
Help me.
Up here. Look up here.
You've got to find it.
It's after me.
You've got to get back and find it.
You've got to stop it.
Please, help me. You've
got to help me. Please.
Nice little pussycat, yeah. You're
gonna save me a trip to the pound.
What are you so excited about, huh?
What am I, a cat psychologist?
- Well, this is the place.
- I don't know about this, Jim.
- You said you wanted to quit these.
- Yeah, I know, I know, I know.
- But I'd just like to know what they...
- Go on, Dickie, before you lose your guts.
Well, why don't you come
up with me at least?
It doesn't work that way.
Against the rules.
What is this? A quit-smoking
clinic or the CIA?
It's gonna turn your life
around, Dick. I guarantee it.
That's what Jim Jones said
when he spiked the punch.
(MEOW)
(WHIMPERING)
I guess this is where you
come to quit smoking, right?
- Fill one of these out, please.
- No, no. I have a pen.
(SOBBING)
Honey!
Are you all right?
Sweetheart.
Darling. No, no, no!
Precious. My precious.
- It's all right. You're gonna be fine.
- Take me home.
Home? I'll take you
home. Hang onto me.
I've been a smoker
for a long time...
Since I was sixteen.
It is very hard.
Uh, come on, now. Here.
Come on. OK.
The elevator is down here.
One step at a time.
- Hi. Excuse me.
- I'll take that for you.
Well, you know, actually,
I think I've changed my mind.
- Mr. Morrison?
- Yeah? Yes?
- Sorry to keep you waiting.
- No, really. It's all right.
- I was just saying...
- Come with me.
- We're about to change your life.
- For the better, I hope.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- The founding father?
- Please, Mr. Morrison.
I see you have a daughter who's 10.
Uh... Alicia.
You left the space for
her school blank.
Where my daughter goes to school really
has no connection with whether or not
your organization can help me
to quit smoking, Mr. Donatti.
Ahem. So...
- Are we gonna get down to it or not?
- Yes, of course.
In fact, we've already
started getting down to it.
(BEEP)
Do you have cigarettes with you?
Does a bear shit in the woods?
May I have them, please?
Our methods here at quitters incorporated
are rather radical, Mr. Morrison.
Well, as a treatment,
Mr. Donatti, they suck.
There's a newsstand down in
the lobby. They sell all brands.
- You know what I mean?
- Availability is only part of the problem.
The fall-back rate
for reformed smokers
is higher than the fall-back
rate for heroin addicts.
You can spare me the Reader's
Digest lecture, my friend,
because... I've changed my mind.
Will you open this door?
You've got a hell of a
problem, Mr. Morrison,
but we here at quitters incorporated
have developed a hell of a solution.
Look, you're gonna develop a hell
of a problem with my lawyers
if you don't open
this goddamn door!
Relax, Mr. Morrison.
Here's something that
might interest you.
(BEEP)
Watch closely, Mr. Morrison.
Nothing up either sleeve.
And you'll notice at no time
does my hand leave my wrist.
("TWIST AND SHOUT" PLAYS)
- The music is part of his conditioning.
- Shake it up, baby
Shake it up, baby
Twist and shout
Boogie down, baby.
Come on, baby
Come on and work it on out
Yeah, work it on out, honey
Work it on out
Yeah, you look so good
What are you doing?
Stop it. You're killing him!
Kill the nice kitty?
No, no. He's fine.
Maybe a little crispy around the
paws, but otherwise, he's fine.
Damn it. You barbecue
all the cats you want.
If you don't have me out of
here inside of 15 seconds
I'm gonna call the cops on you faster
than you can say Marlboro man.
You better listen to the
big picture, Mr. Morrison.
Quitters incorporated was endowed
by a very important person.
After he died of lung cancer, we realized
that there were certain techniques
that he had developed
in the family business
that we can now use to
stop people from smoking.
Actually, this is a
very nice tax gimmick.
But mainly, we're interested
in helping our fellow man.
For the first month, our operatives will
have you under constant supervision.
You may see some of them all of the time.
You may see all of them some of the time.
But believe me, Mr. Morrison, you'll
never see all of them all of the time.
If you smoke, they'll see you.
And bring me down here and stick
me in the old cat room, I suppose.
No... We'll bring your wife down
here and stick her in the cat room.
You'll get to watch.
I'm a man of medicine.
I'm expected to save lives and
ease suffering, and I love people.
Therefore, I would have no choice...
but to kill the son of a bitch.
Kill the son of a bitch. Good idea.
- What did you say?
- What?
- Huh?
- Nothing. I was...
- I can't believe this is happening.
- Oh, it's happening, Mr. Morrison.
First offense, your
wife gets the juice.
Not too much. Just enough to hurt.
Second time, we bring your
daughter Alicia here.
Imagine, Mr. Morrison, your daughter
in there instead of the cat.
The third offense, I'm afraid I have
to send someone out to rape your wife.
There's a rather disturbed
individual we keep around here
just for such distasteful jobs.
In the meantime, content yourself
knowing that only 2% of our clients
ever fall from grace a fourth time.
And if they do?
Then we give up, Mr. Morrison.
- Oh, God... God!
- What's wrong?
- Well, I spilled my drink!
- Well, I'm sorry, Dick...
but as long as you keep using your left
tit for a coaster, that's gonna happen.
Shit! I have no idea what's going
on in this damn movie anyway.
I don't know who writes this crap!
- Dick.
- What?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
You're like a bear
tonight. What is it?
It's nothing! Well, it's everything.
I mean, I quit smoking today.
Since when? Five minutes ago?
Since 3:00... quarter
to 3:00 this afternoon.
You haven't had a
cigarette in six hours?
Uh, 6 hours and 23 minutes.
Cindy, I'm trying to get
some ice cream here, OK?
What in the world made
you decide to quit?
I'm doing it for you...
and for Alicia.
That's the sweetest
thing I ever heard.
Even if you don't make it,
we both thank you.
I think I'll make it.
Shit!
Jesus! God!
(NOISE)
Hello.
Is somebody in there?
I didn't smoke it, see?
If you're in there, would you tell
Donatti that I didn't smoke it, see?
I actually was just, uh...
coming to get my golf clubs.
- Want some coffee?
- Jesus!
I assume that's a yes.
Talk about aversion therapy.
Jesus.
That's it. That's it.
Daddy!
Hi, baby. Whoa!
(RING)
OK, eyes closed and there we go! OK,
now, we're skipping with eyes closed.
(INDISTINCTLY)
We're gonna skip over to...
Here. Are those eyes closed?
Are they closed?
I think they're open.
- Are they real tight?
- Yeah.
We don't want to spoil
any surprises, OK.
I think now it's time to open them.
Ah.
Thank you, daddy!
- Thank you! Thank you!
- OK, I'm glad you like it, honey.
You know what? I love you, Alicia.
- What's its name?
- His name...
I think it's right here on the tag.
Its name is Norma Jean.
- Nor-ma...
- Norma...
- Jean.
Huh?
I love Norma Jean!
I'm glad, baby.
OK, honey, come on. You got
Norma Jean, you got her shoe,
and you got her little adoption papers.
Look after the kid and be a good girl, OK?
Sister?
OK, bye, honey.
- Bye.
- Bye, dad.
You love her a lot, don't you?
One of your men was in my
closet last night, in my home!
- Really?
- Yes, really.
That's possible, I suppose.
Constant supervision for the
first month is what we promise.
Constant supervision is
just what the client gets.
- You're a son of a bitch.
- Yes, I'm a son of a bitch.
It takes a son of bitch
to beat the habit.
People who are unable to turn into sons of
bitches on their own behalf, come to us.
We give them what they
need. Believe me, we do.
I didn't smoke. I don't know what your
hoods told you, but I didn't smoke!
If you had lit that cigarette in your
mouth, you wouldn't be here right now.
You'd be down at my office watching your
wife hop around in the little room.
You love your wife, you love your kid,
unfashionable these days, but useful.
I think you're gonna make it,
Mr. Morrison. We'll be watching you.
("EVERY BREATH YOU TAKE" PLAYS)
Every breath you take
Every move you make
Every bond you break
Every step you take
I'll be watching you
An asshole like me
could stay in business.
I said it wasn't easy, but with
assholes like him around, I got by.
Not bad, huh?
No. Not bad at all.
Can I get a bourbon?
So he says, "what do you think the S.E.C.'s
gonna say when they hear about this?"
Two things... First they're gonna
say they heard it all before.
Second, they're gonna say
P.T. Barnum was right.
There's a sucker born every minute.
Earth to Dick. Earth to Dick
Morrison. Come in, Dick!
I'm sorry. I'm just a little tired.
Kind of under the weather.
- Have a cigarette.
- Yeah... no! Thanks. Sorry. I quit.
I did, really.
Sure.
No. Two weeks ago. Done.
Two weeks, two months,
two years. It doesn't matter.
A big presentation comes along,
a make-or-break meeting,
a marathon sales conference...
boom, you'll be right back on it.
Come on. Have a cigarette.
Come on. Have a cigarette!
No, really. I gave those babies up.
(TRAIN WHISTLE)
Hey, gang! The smoking
lamp is lit again!
Every word you say
Every game you play
Every night you stay
I'll be watching you
Oh, can't you see
You belong to me?
Dickie.
Why don't you shove
it up your ass, Hal.
Every step you take
What? Lit?
(MUSIC PLAYS)
(MUSIC WARBLES AND STOPS)
(SEMI HORN HONKS)
(HORN HONKS)
Shit!
Cindy!
Cindy! Cindy!
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
(RING)
Cindy?
Hello, Mr. Morrison.
It seems we have some business to
attend to. Will 5:00 be all right?
You know, it was just a slip, Mr. Donatti.
It was just a little, small slip.
You know? I mean... really,
I swear it won't happen again.
You know, it's funny...
it didn't even taste good.
I'll count on you
for 5:00, shall I?
No, no! Donatti! Donatti!
You son of a bitch!
- Where's my wife, you turd?!
- Hello, Mr. Morrison.
He tried to get smart with his fists, but
unfortunately, he's got very dumb fists.
Where's Cindy?
(BEEP)
Don't, you idiot!
Oh, fiddlysticks!
Here, kitty, kitty,
kitty! Here, kitty!
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty!
Forget the cat, you
hemorrhoid! Get the gun!
Get up, Mr. Morrison. Let's not
have any more of this foolishness.
Open the door!
I understand your agitation.
It will not be held against you,
- at least not by me.
- Please, Mr. Donatti, please!
You be a good boy, Mr. Morrison,
and don't provoke Junk again.
I will make this as brief as possible.
Your wife will not be hurt this time.
Watch him, Junk.
(BEEP)
(MUSIC PLAYS)
Too many teardrops
For one heart
To be cryin'
Too many teardrops
For one heart
To carry on
Remember, it just like getting
a shot at the doctor's office.
You're way out on top now
Since you left me
You're always laughin'
Ow! Stop!
Way down at me
But watch out, now
I'm gonna get there
We'll be together
Stop it! Would you stop it?
You're killing her!
Take it easy, Mr. Morrison.
She'll be fine.
Way down here...
I think you've got some
explaining to do, don't you?
Hey, boss, ain't you
gonna turn the sound up?
There's no reason to.
When you been in the business as long
as I have, you get to know every line.
In 30 seconds, she's either gonna squeeze
this guy hard enough to give him a hernia,
or she's gonna slap him
in the face and walk out.
- 10 bucks says she slaps him.
- You're on.
Oh, darn.
(WHISTLE)
(MEOW)
- No, back about there.
- No, no.
- See, look.
No, that's eight pounds in six months,
Vinnie. I don't think that's so bad really.
An ounce of prevention is worth a
pound of cure. We gotta watch it.
73% of our clients get a weight
problem the minute they quit smoking.
Now, I want you to get dressed,
and you and I will have a talk.
- You gotta watch it.
- OK.
Junk, you think eight pounds
is bad in six months?
I think it's great.
So remember, now, some of
these diet pills are highly illegal
so I want you to
use them sparingly.
Now I'm setting your maximum
weight at 165 pounds.
If I go over it, you'll send a guy to my
house with a flamethrower or something?
No, I'll send a guy to your house and
cut off your wife's little finger.
You kill me.
- Have a good day, Dick.
- Take it easy, huh?
(LAUGHING)
Cut off my wife's little finger.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I think a toast is in order.
A toast is in order.
OK, no throwing the glasses
in the fireplace, though.
- We don't want to wake Alicia.
- The ladies are entitled...
The ladies are entitled to throw
glasses in the fireplace.
To quitters incorporated.
Quitters incorporated.
Beat it! Go on! Scat! Go on! Scat!
Come on, Darcy. It's gobbler time.
Now you just sit right there.
Gobblers is all that Darcy eats because
it's her mostest, mostest favorite.
Listen to me carefully.
It's still looking for me.
You've got to get back and find it.
You're my only chance.
- Lucky night, Mr. Cressner.
- Don't jump to any conclusions.
The night ain't all lucky.
- Good night, Mr. Cressner.
- Good night, sweetheart.
- Richards!
- Yeah, boss?
- Cash these.
- OK. You got it.
- Buona notte, Mr. Cressner.
- Buona notte. Buona notte.
Oh, so nice, Mr. Cressner.
Thank you.
- Good night, Mr. C.
- Good night, Henry.
- Hey, have you spoke to Ducky?
- Yes, sir, Mr. Cressner.
He's got my wife and
her friend in view?
Yes, sir, she and the tennis guy are
in a white mustang convertible.
Ducky's right on 'em.
He's right behind 'em.
Good, good, good, good. Good man.
So, folks, what's it gonna be?
Dean Martin's at the golden nugget,
and I haven't seen Dino Martino
since I was a little girl.
Have you taken care of
your domestic problem?
- I got everything well in hand.
- Good.
The golden nugget will be fine, OK?
- Oh, good. Thank you so much.
- OK. Let's go.
(HORN HONKS)
Oh, my gosh. Look at that... a cat.
(HORNS HONK)
You know, my daddy used to say
that all cats should be drowned, after
they stop playing with spools and stuff?
Is that what your daddy said?
Your father must have been
a great humanitarian.
(MEOW)
(HORN HONKS)
Oh, my gosh, I bet that
cat's gonna get run over.
I got 2,000 says he can make it.
- You're kidding?
- No.
- You're on.
- 2,000 that he can make it.
- Cat's dead. You're on.
- Here you go.
You say he makes it,
I say he's dead.
- Yeah, all right.
- I can do anything I want?
- Sure, so can I. Anybody can.
- You won't say a word?
- Go ahead. Yeah.
- You got it. Watch.
- Anybody can do anything they want.
- Watch me.
- I'm watching.
Come on, cat. Come
here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Come on, kitty, kitty.
Come on, little kitty, kitty.
- You guys would bet on anything.
- Yeah. That's what it's all about.
Come on, kitty, kitty.
Come here, little kitty.
- Come on, little kitty. Come on.
- Come here, kitty. Come here, kitty.
- For 2,000, you're on my side now?
- Yeah.
You're the one whose father
was drownin' cats, remember?
- Come on, kitty. Come to mama.
- Come on. kitty. Come on, kitty.
(HORN HONKS)
Don't worry about these big
things. That's special effects.
- Come on, kitty.
- Here, kitty.
OK, OK. OK, OK.
OK, OK, OK. OK!
Now! Come on.
- Come on! Come on!
- Come on!
- Come on, kitty, kitty.
Hey, there he is. There he is.
Yeah, there's the guy.
There's the guy. Look at him.
He was just lucky.
Lucky? I think he knows
you bet against him.
You win some, you lose some.
You guys go on. Go see Dean Martin.
I'll take this guy home, give him a bowl
of milk. I think he just earned it.
- Good-bye, sweetheart.
- You sure you're not coming?
I got to finish that business
I was talking about.
Right. OK.
- You wanna get me a cab, please.
- Have a good time.
Get Ducky on the radio.
Tell him to nail the bastard.
Good night.
Thanks.
Thank you. I still don't see
why you can't come with me.
Because we're broke. If you
decided to leave with me,
you'd be sent into a whole new plane
of financial existence, my dear.
I'm just trying to... make the
decompression as painless as possible.
- I don't care.
- But I do.
The Armbruster Hotel in New York.
- I'll see you there tomorrow night.
- Johnny...
I've got to wait till the banks open, so
I can crack open one of my piggy banks
to get us some money. We gotta
have something to live on.
Look, Johnny, you don't
know how dangerous he is.
- You don't even have a clue.
- I know exactly what he is.
And that's why you're getting on
the bus, after you give me a kiss.
All passengers bound for Philadelphia, New
Hope, and Harrisburg, please report to...
- Johnny.
- Go.
All passengers for Philadelphia...
Hey!
It's for horses, sometimes for cows. Pigs
don't eat it 'cause they don't know how.
Get him.
Get his keys, Dom. Come on.
You're in grade-A trouble,
buckaroo. Come on. Move. Move!
Come on.
Come on!
OK, blow.
- Come on, kid.
- Hey!
Pigs don't eat it 'cause
they don't know how.
When Ducky says that,
it means shut up.
- Does it?
- Yeah. It's like a joke, you know?
Close the door, close the door.
I've set you up, Mr. Norris.
In 10 minutes, Albert
will call the police
and tell them a tale of
heroin, 1970 mustangs...
aging tennis pros with drug records.
You'll be eagerly sought after, Mr. Norris.
Unless I tell you where Marcia is.
With you gone, she'd come back.
She's got nowhere else to go.
Now as for you, when
you get out of jail...
you'll be more concerned with
your arthritis than your libido.
Unless you take the wager
I'm offering. Hmm?
Hey, come here.
Come on.
I want to show you something.
Now look down there, and tell me
what you see. Look. Go ahead.
- The street.
- No. There, there.
The ledge.
- The ledge.
- Look, what is all this about?
The wager I'm proposing
is very simple.
The top of the building is sort of
an architectural monstrosity...
All little nooks,
crannies, weird winds.
You walk all the way around, scab
will be removed from the car,
you get the money,
and you get my wife.
You're crazy.
Lose your balance, lose
your balance once...
That's the bet, Mr. Norris.
You get the girl, you get the
gold watch, you get everything.
Or you get a lot of straight
time in Rahway Prison.
You welsh on your bets?
I've never welshed
on a bet in my life.
(MEOW)
Hey, Sebastian. Hey, Sebastian.
Sebastian appears to like you.
Maybe that's a good sign, huh?
Huh?
Good. Good. Well
begun is half done.
The ledge is about 5 inches wide.
But once you're on it, it looks
more like 3, doesn't it?
Or two. two, yeah.
One?
How the hell would you know?
Mr. Norris, you know what I think?
I think you're gonna just stand there
for a while, then climb back up, huh?
I mean if your arms still got
the strength left to do that.
I... don't think you got the guts.
I just don't think you got the guts.
Boogie! Boogie! Boogie!
You bastard!
I just want to keep
you on your toes.
Ha ha ha!
(MEOW)
Oh, get out of here.
Boingo.
(HORN TOOTS)
You bastard!
Just keeping you on your toes!
Oh, Jesus.
Hey, what's the matter with you? Knock it
off, huh? Where's your sense of humor?
Hey.
Buzz off.
Hey!
Shove off.
Ow!
Oh!
God.
Oh, God!
Ow, you little pecker.
Try this, you...
You flying shithouse.
Mr. Norris!
What do you think, Mr. Norris?
Is this more fun than human beings
should be allowed to have, or what?
- I'll kill you!
- No, Mr. Norris.
But I will most assuredly kill you if
you don't get moving in 30 seconds.
The valve was only
half-open that time.
If I open it all the way, I'll
blow you out of this hole. Move!
I'll kill you.
I'm going insane.
Oh, God. God!
God!
Put it in the shopping bag.
- On top of the money?
- Put it in the shopping bag.
Put that down.
Now you come in when I say, "all right,
all right, Mr. Norris." You got that?
- Yeah, I got it. "All right, Mr. Norris."
- No, no...
"All right, all right, Mr. Norris."
- I got it. "All right, Mr. Norris."
- Forget it. Go ahead.
All right, all right, Mr. Norris.
I told you I don't welsh.
- No?
- No...
I'm just an extremely poor loser.
I promised you three things...
You have your car clean,
you have the money,
and, of course...
You have my wife.
Jesus!
How do you like that, Mr. Norris?
God!
Albert! Albert!
Albert!
Shit! Shit!
The money... Nothin'. Nothin'.
Chicken feed.
I can get you a 100,000. 500,000.
A million, Norris...
In a Swiss bank account. How
about that? How about that?
A million dollars.
I don't think so.
Two million. Two million!
No. I got an idea.
I'll make you a little
bet. It's not a wager
'cause I'm not a big,
fancy hood like you.
I'm just an over-the-hill
tennis bum...
with a dead girlfriend. Now,
it's just a simple little bet.
Five million. Five million, huh?
I'll give you... I'll give you
anything you want, huh?
You're right, Mr. Cressner.
This is a lot fun.
You got to be joking,
Norris, come on. It's a joke.
Tell me it's a joke. Tell me it's a
joke, for Christ's sake! Don't shoot!
Just keeping you on your toes,
Mr. Cressner. Keep moving.
The next one might be a lot closer.
Move!
Norris, you son of a bitch!
Hey!
Get out of here!
Get out! Get out!
(HORN TOOTS)
(PANTING)
Ohhh.
Don't splash daddy when
daddy's got the hose.
Come on, you two. Lunch time.
Let's get some of that soap off.
A cat!
Hey!
Can we keep it? Can we keep it?
No. He probably belongs
to somebody else.
Amanda, wait till I get a broom.
Amanda, wait a minute! Amanda!
Amanda, don't touch that
cat. It could bite you.
He's not gonna bite
me. It likes me.
I want to keep... No, don't!
Amanda, we can't keep every single
stray that comes into this house.
- It could have disease.
- What if we have the vet check him?
If the vet checks him out and says
there's nothing wrong with him
and no one comes to get him,
then can we please have him?
Please? Pretty please
with sugar on top?
What's your name?
I can't hear you.
Gonna guard me? Hope so.
But, mom, can't General
stay in my room tonight?
- No.
- Please?
No. His trial lease in this house
does not include bedroom privileges.
- But, mom!
- Come on, now. Bedtime.
Oh, mom. Good night, General.
(CARTOON ON TV)
Amanda, would you turn off that
TV set? I'd like to talk to you.
That cat was in your bedroom
last night, wasn't he?
Uh-huh. I found cat hairs
all over your bedspread,
and a lot of your dolls
were knocked over.
Was he? I dreamed he was. Far out.
Yeah? Well, he's really
gonna be far out
if that happens again because I'm
gonna send him to the animal shelter.
But, mom, you can't do
that! That's not fair.
Have you given one
minute's thought to Polly?
General loves Polly.
They get along great.
Birds and cats do not
get along great,
in case you haven't watched Sylvester
and Tweety Bird on television.
General wouldn't do a think to
hurt Polly. He's nonviolent.
(BIRD SCREECHES)
Well, I think it's really early to decide
that, and I just wish you'd understand.
Also, your mom just happened to have a
conference call with Nana last evening.
And Nana told your mom
that... cats steal kids' breath.
Why would General take my
breath if he has his own?
(GERMAN ACCENT) You have to put
all the animals outside in the night,
I mean, especially the cat
animals. Because if you don't...
they climb up and sit on your chest and
suck all your breath out like this.
- That is very, very helpful, Hugh.
- Thank you very, very much.
Come on. Sit down and
have your breakfast.
No! No. Jokes about my
mother's accent in the morning
just have this way of
killing my appetite.
Nonviolent, my ass.
Mom.
I'm sorry we laughed at Nana.
- But couldn't you...
- No. The subject is closed.
Bus in fifteen minutes.
(MEOW)
- Mama, can't General just stay with me...
- No. No.
Don't forget those back teeth. That's
where most of the food gets stuck.
Get the back.
Hi, doll.
Hi, daddy.
You know, Amanda, it would be a lot easier
for me to get General back in the house
if I knew what these bad
dreams were all about.
Why?
Why? Because when you play
the violin, little girl,
everybody listens, including
your mom. So, come on. Tell me.
Well, I can only remember
that there's a monster in it.
A monster? What's he like?
Do you know that story
about the goats?
- The Three Billy Goats Gruff?
- That's the one.
Well, this one lives in
my wall right there.
But General kept those
dreams away last night.
Can't he come in for
good, daddy, please?
You know, Amanda, your mom
is really serious about this.
Yeah, I know. Just like
getting your back teeth.
That's where all the food gets stuck,
and cats stealing kids' breath.
Well, my making fun of nanny's accent
at the breakfast table this morning
probably didn't get us
off to the best of starts.
But I might be able to bring your mother
around. No promises, but maybe.
No promises.
You know, Amanda...
there are no real monsters.
Yeah. I guess I do.
OK. Go to sleep now.
- No bad dreams.
You know, I think she was beginning to cry
when I kissed her good night tonight.
Come on, Hugh.
What do you say we talk about
it just a little bit more, huh?
Hugh, I just don't trust that cat.
(FOOTSTEPS)
(SNEEZES)
(BIRD CHIRPS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(JINGLE)
(MUTTERING)
(CHEWING SOUNDS)
(LAUGHING)
(JINGLE)
(SCREECHING!)
(LAUGHING)
- What was that?
I don't know. I'll go.
General, is that you?
Meow!
(GIGGLING)
Meow.
Polly!
Mandy?
Polly's dead.
- The monster in my wall killed Polly.
- Oh, no.
I knew it. I knew it!
It's OK.
I told you this would happen.
Look at this!
It's OK. It's OK.
- She's convinced the cat didn't do it.
- Yes, I know.
She's convinced that it was a troll
that got tired of living under a bridge
and is now living in her wall.
But she is 8, and you're 38.
And that cat's tracks were on
her windowsill in Polly's blood.
Now, are you gonna take care
of Polly, or do you want me to?
Well, here he goes, killer.
You know, I would have thought that you'd
have cleared out of here by now, too.
You know, your welcome's getting
pretty threadbare. Hmm?
Come here.
What have we got here?
Who did that to you? Hmm?
Hey, the cat's got a
wound on his shoulder.
- So what?
- I don't know...
Seems like a big wound.
Yeah, well, Polly got in one good peck
before that cat killed him. Good for Polly.
Uh-huh. I certainly never realized
that Polly had such a... big pecker.
You know, you better get ready
for work. You're gonna be late.
(MEOW)
You stay right there.
Come on. Looky look. Good food.
Come on.
Come on, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Mama's got your favorite food.
Come on, you furry little
bastard. Come on. Come on.
OK.
Going.
Your bird-killing days
are over, my friend.
(THUNDER)
General!
(JINGLING)
(JINGLE)
(DOGS BARKING)
(CATS MEOW)
Tomorrow's your big day, fella.
Do you think General ran away because
you thought he killed Polly?
Honey, cats don't think.
General does, and he knows that you
think that cats steal kids' breath.
Blech!
(GIGGLING)
(CAT SCREECHING)
Hey!
(COUGH)
(COUGHING)
(SHOUTING IN TROLL)
What was that?
Mommy!
(COUGH)
- Mommy!
- Amanda!
- Get out of my way!
Amanda! Amanda!
Get him, General! Get him!
Oh, no!
Come on! Don't let him get away!
Please! Amanda!
Mommy and daddy. We're not angry.
Hugh! What is wrong?
Why won't this door open?
Come on, General! Get him!
(LAUGHING)
Uh-oh. No!
Come on, General! You can do it!
Cream him! Cream him!
Watch out, General! Watch out!
Come on, General!
Amanda!
General is fighting the monster!
("EVERY BREATH YOU TAKE" PLAYS)
Play it faster!
(MUSIC PLAYING FASTER)
- Play it faster!
- (SPEEDED UP) Every breath you take
Every move you make
Every bond you break
Every step you take
I'll be watching you...
General!
Amanda!
Where did he come from?
Give me that cat!
- Give me that cat!
- Quiet!
It wasn't General that was trying to
take my breath! It was the monster...
and General fixed him!
You've gotta believe me!
Amanda, where did it go?
General played him on the
record player and swoosh! Zoom!
Into the fan and got smushed.
- Oh, my God.
- Yuck.
Hugh, what do you think it is?
That's where he came from.
Right there! Right there in
my wall, just like I told you!
Amanda, whatever it was that was
in the wall, was... was it alone?
I mean, did it have any friends?
I only saw one.
Hugh, we're not gonna
tell anybody about this.
Are you kidding?
Amanda, promise me...
promise me that you won't tell any
of your friends about this, OK?
- Well, that depends.
- Depends? Depends on what?
On whether or not I can keep General
and sleep with me at night.
Amanda! That's blackmail.
Hi.
("CAT'S EYE" PLAYING)
I didn't know I was
under your spell
I couldn't know
There was no way to tell
I took the step
I slipped up and I
didn't know why
Deep in the dark,
it was too hard to see
That in the night,
it had come over me
You stole my soul
Imprisoned me with your cat's eye
- Cat's eye
- How you caught me unaware
- How you hold me in your stare
- Cat's eye
- Going to hide, but tell me where?
- You've got me spellbound!
- Cat's eye
- How you stole my breath away
- How you kept me night and day
- Cat's eye
- I can never get away
- I am spellbound!
It's like a dream,
only when do I wake?
Can't even scream
Every breath that I take
Belongs to you
What can I do?
Why should I try?
I walk around like
a boy in a trance
You pull the strings
I'm a puppet, I dance
You're holding me eternally
In your cat's eye
- Cat's eye
- Took my heart with just a look
- Every stare is like a hook
- Cat's eye
- Just one look is all it took
- You made me spellbound!
- Cat's eye
- How you stole my breath away
- How you kept me night and day
- Cat's eye
- I can never get away
- I am spellbound!