(Doll's electronic voice)
'Action Man patrol, open fire!
'This is your Commandant speaking.
'Mortar attack, dig in!'
What are you reading?
I was trying to find the answer
to a question Christine was asking.
"If the world's round,
why is a frozen pond flat?"
It's a good question.
Ah-ha!
"Lake Ontario curves
more than 3 degrees
"from its easternmost shore
to its westernmost shore."
Frozen water isn't flat.
- Nothing is what it seems.
- My cigarettes...
Did you put
all the slides together?
No, I put the duplicates in my tray.
(Doll) 'Action Man patrol, fall in.
'Enemy in sight. Range 1,000.'
(John) Oh, shit!
(Laura) What's the matter?
Nothing.
Dad! Dad!
(Screams)
(Guttural moan)
(Speaks Italian)
- Hi!
- Hi.
- What are you doing?
- Writing to Johnny.
- What did you say?
- Oh, it's just a letter.
- How did it go?
- Oh, God!
The deeper we get,
the more Byzantine it gets.
I'm restoring a fake.
And you can't change your course?
Not enough bread.
The options are: Restore the fake
or let it sink into the sea.
What did you say?
I said, "Daddy's still hard at work
on the windows of St Nicholas,
"our beautiful 16th-century church.
He's done incredible stuff.
"I can't tell the difference
between his and the originals.
"I'm going to send some slides to you.
Maybe you'll know the difference.
"Hope Ellis is being
reasonable this term."
That's his group captain
or something.
"I'm enclosing money
for your gym shoes.
"Buy the ones
with the padded soles.
"Ask Matron for those.
Be kind to yourself."
Just another boring letter.
God, it's cold.
(Howling wind)
Oh, dear,
I've got something in my eye.
It's all right.
Want me to put something
on the end of that?
No. Why don't you send him
a card yourself?
It's so cold in here
the waiters don't come.
I must take some time off.
- What do you want?
- I'll have what I had last night.
(Speaks Italian)
- Did you see the bishop this morning?
- No.
I'm terribly sorry.
Sorry.
- What?
- She's got something in her eye.
(Man shouts in Italian)
(Lady #1) I don't know
what he's talking about.
I think I'd better go and help them.
Excuse me.
- Perhaps I can show you where it is.
- That is kind of you.
Thank you so much. How kind.
I hope you don't think us rude.
Rude? Why?
I mean, staring at you out there.
We're frightful starers.
Comes from living in the country.
Country people stare more.
- I'm frightfully sorry.
- I didn't notice it even if you were.
- (Lady #2) Which eye is it?
- The left one.
- Let me help.
- How can you help?
- I can try.
- No.
You nearly put Jocelyn's eye out
the last time you tried poking about.
Well, perhaps...
Perhaps I can help, do you think?
That's awfully kind of you.
Oh, dear. Oh...
My sister is blind, you see.
- (Laura) Oh, I see.
- Yes.
That's it.
It was a tiny black speck.
- I think I've got it.
- Well done.
Thank you very much.
Goodness,
you do remind me of my daughter.
- Oh, really?
- Only her hair is darker.
Oh, really?
Well, here, take your handkerchief.
You're sad.
You're so sad,
and there's no need to be.
- My sister's psychic.
- She wants you to know...
I've seen her and she wants you
to know that she's happy.
I've seen your little girl sitting
between you and your husband
and she was laughing.
Yes.
Oh, yes, she's with you.
She's with you, my dear.
And she's laughing.
I'm sorry if we stared.
She's wearing a shiny little mac.
Christine...
But she's laughing, she's laughing.
She's happy as can be.
Oh, you're very like her.
The forehead, the eyes...
- Is that better?
- Yes.
- Shall I fetch your husband?
- No, no, I'm all right, thank you.
Good. Jolly good.
If you just leave me alone,
I'll be fine.
All right, my dear.
Did you?
Did you really see her?
She was there.
I felt you were right.
I felt we should.
(Cash register rings)
Oh, I sent your food back
to get it warmed.
- The mastic that works is number 3.
- Oh, God. I've got to stand up.
I'm sorry.
(Man speaks Italian)
(Siren wails)
(Laura laughs)
(Children scream and laugh)
There's nothing but children here.
- It was the nearest hospital.
- I've been playing with them.
- I talked to the doctor...
- John?
Christine is still with us.
Christine is dead, Laura.
- Christine is dead.
- Of course, of course. I know.
But you know the two ladies
in the restaurant?
They were watching us eating.
They kept staring. They told me.
They could see
Christine sitting between us.
This is two people
who we don't even know!
Listen, listen...
There's one who's blind.
She's the one with the second sight.
She's blind and she described to me
Christine's red plastic mac.
Laura...
John, listen,
I'm perfectly all right.
I haven't felt as good as this
in months and months.
I feel really fine.
I don't need pills,
I'm not going crazy.
I feel really great.
When did the doctor say
you could leave?
Any time. I only fainted.
John, I wish you'd believe me.
I really feel fine.
- I really feel good at last.
- I believe you.
Seeing is believing. I believe you.
Put your shoes on.
(Horn blasts)
(Shouting in Italian)
(Speak Italian)
- What did he say? Homicide?
- Yes.
(Horn blasts)
I thought this was the place...
Isn't this where you were?
No.
I want to stop at this church.
(John) It's closed.
Why that one?
I just wanted to...
I want to say a prayer.
Oh, Laura!
(? Organ music playing)
- I don't like this church at all.
- Well, I do.
- Do you have any change?
- Yep.
- I'm going to light a candle for her.
- How much are candles?
Fifty.
I don't have any fifties.
Maybe I'll light six.
(He sighs)
Thank you, my love.
(Man)... the Madonna is
by Antonio Rizzo in about 1490.
The grille work is also by Rizzo.
Note the flowers woven into...
Ah!
- Jesus!
- You hypocrite.
The bishop!
I'm an hour and a half late.
(Speaks Italian)
How are you, John?
Forgive us, it was entirely my fault.
Nothing to do with John.
A woman to share your sins with.
Laura, you're looking much better.
- I'm really terribly sorry.
- Please.
The workmen took me
around the church.
You have made
some great advances.
I'd like you to look at the mosaics
that need to be refired.
I've already been much too long.
Now, when are you both
coming to stay with me?
Thursday, if that's all right?
I look forward to it.
I've taken samples from the pilings.
We're in trouble down there, too.
The churches belong to God,
but he doesn't seem
to care about them.
Does he have other priorities?
We have stopped listening.
Are you a Christian, Laura?
I don't know.
I'm kind to animals and children.
St Nicholas is the patron saint
of scholars and children.
An interesting combination,
don't you think?
We must talk, John.
- Thursday. I'll have your room ready.
- (Laura) Thank you.
I'll have the mastic samples by then.
The acidity is breaking down
all the adhesives.
I look forward to hearing about it.
Thursday.
- Ciao.
- Bye!
He doesn't give an ecclesiastical
fuck about the church.
- Why did he ask if I was Christian?
- Because you kissed his ring.
What in God's name made you do that?
(Speaks Italian)
No, seriously.
You know?
Your bishop really makes me
feel quite uneasy.
He probably makes God
feel less than immaculate.
- No, no. I don't mean that.
- (Speaks Italian)
(Speaks Italian)
(Radio on)
I'm going to get down
to some work tomorrow.
Enough of this idling around.
(John) What?
Are you sure we don't have
to book at this place tonight?
I don't want that same performance
as happened last time.
- What place?
- Oh, John!
The place we're going to be eating at.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Where's my Neutrogena? OK.
(John laughs)
You'll have to read this.
What are you doing?
- I can't hear what you're saying.
- I'm shouting!
- I still can't hear.
- What are you doing?
I'm having a bath.
You heard me that time.
Those lumps are coming back
on the side of your waist?
See?
I weigh 85 kilos,
which is 190 pounds.
- You OK?
- Yes, I'm OK.
(Knocking)
Come in.
(Speaks Italian)
Isn't it a miracle I didn't hurt myself
when I fainted today?
The unconscious body reacts faster
than the mind ever can.
Perhaps.
You've got toothpaste
all over your mouth.
Eat it off.
I can't get it off.
This.
- (Laura) It was.
- It wasn't.
- Was it?
- Mm-hm.
You will be eating here
tonight, I hope?
No, thank you.
We're going to eat out tonight.
(Speaks Italian)
(Clock chimes)
(Laura) Hey.
Come here.
I think I've found the way.
(John) We've been
over this bridge already.
Well, I never mind
being lost in Venice.
Down here.
We take the second left...
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
A nice dark little alley.
- (John) Yes, this is it.
- It isn't.
- Yes, it is.
- It isn't, John.
- Come on.
- Oh, it isn't.
(Laura gasps) Oh, rats!
I'm getting out of here.
I know this place.
This is it.
It's the Ponte Giretto.
- What?
- It's this one.
No, I...
(Hoarse gasping)
(Scream)
(Screaming)
What's that, John?
It's OK, I've found the real world.
It's down here. Come on.
- What on earth was that?
- It was a cat or a rat.
- Maybe it was something...
- What, a rat?
This was just around the corner
from where we were.
I know where we are now.
(Speaks Italian)
Hello.
- Hello.
- Hello!
How extraordinary to see you.
Oh, it's Mrs Baxter.
- Yes, I know.
- My husband's restoring this church.
(Speaks Italian)
Yes, I do.
I remember her hair.
Light hair and silky soft.
She tossed it as she laughed.
- Did she die suddenly?
- Heather, you have no right to...
No, I really wouldn't mind
talking about it, actually.
I'll get my coat.
Would you mind waiting?
I won't be a second, all right?
Thank you.
(Laura) Sunday afternoon.
We'd just finished lunch.
Oh, I used to smoke then.
And I remember I had this cigarette.
You know something strange?
John just suddenly got up
and rushed down to the pond,
almost as if he knew
something was going to happen.
Well, it was too late,
but it was strange.
- Yes, of course.
- What?
Of course. He has the gift.
That's why the child was trying
to talk to him. He has the gift.
Even if he doesn't know it,
even if he's resisting it.
It's a curse as well as a gift.
(Speaking Italian)
It's off centre.
You can't...
ever contact people, can you?
We're often asked.
She's quite famous round Elgin.
They want a lot of mumbo-jumbo
about ectoplasm
and holding hands.
Second sight is a gift from
the good Lord who sees all things.
It's impertinent to call
his creatures back from rest
for our entertainment.
It wouldn't be for my entertainment.
Would you come for tea
when your husband's finished?
Just for a little while?
Yes, I'd like that. Thank you very much.
Is that all right?
I make no promises.
No.
- It's ridiculous.
- They want to meet you.
I'm not getting involved with two
neurotic old women in mumbo-jumbo.
I've been trying very hard
to hang on to myself,
to forget about what happened,
to get rid of this emptiness.
It's been with me like some pain,
and finally...
Finally through these two women
I've discovered how.
They disapprove of mumbo-jumbo, too.
They used that very word.
- Of course they do.
- They just want to help, that's all.
- Laura, do you not see?
- She's going to try and reach her.
OK, Laura, that's enough.
Now, listen to me.
I've listened to you.
You said let the children play
where they want to.
- You let her go near that pond.
- Thanks for the memories, Laura.
You said you'd give your life
in exchange for hers.
Well, you can't do that.
- Jesus H Christ!
- John.
She's trying to get in touch with us.
Maybe to forgive.
OK, go on.
Go on to your crazy women.
They can have their victim. Go on.
Here, drink this. Whisky.
Thank you. I don't really need it.
You may, child, you may.
I'll be back in a jiffy.
Here you are.
- Where are you?
- Me? Oh, I'm here.
Oh, the children.
- Who are you looking at?
- Um...
There's a boy here
with rolled-up shirt sleeves.
- Difficult to tell how old he is.
- Yes, that's Anthony.
And then there's Charles
next to him in his uniform.
- And then the three girls.
- Mm-hm, yes.
- And then there's Angus.
- What, this little bust?
Yes.
Oh, that's lovely.
Yes, he was a gentle child.
Oh, you haven't touched your drink.
Er, no.
Was that Angus?
I was just looking
at the pictures of your family.
They're wonderful.
It jars you, losing one like that.
But I had two more.
So can you, I daresay.
Nothing can take the place
of the one that's gone.
Now, then.
(Baby crying)
It's all right.
It's all right!
(Clock chimes)
Are your legs crossed?
Yes.
Switch the light out.
(Moaning)
Yes.
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
- (Speaks Italian)
- English.
John! Yes!
- (Speaks Italian)
John! Yes! Yes!
English.
(Wailing)
- English.
- (Speaks Italian)
Yes! Oh!
(Shouting in Italian)
(Dog barking)
(Wailing)
(Moaning)
- Oh!
- Here.
What did she say?
Oh, what did she say?
I got scared for you.
I told you it was all right.
Those two sisters...
- How much have you been drinking?
- You got scared for me, eh?
- God, you're not going to be sick?
- Screw them!
- You're just not listening.
- I am not going to be sick!
Listen, Heather, the blind one,
she is really psychic.
She has second sight.
I mean, you'd understand
completely if you'd...
Today when I was there, she...
She went into the most
incredible trance. Really...
- Concentrate.
- Now, John?
Yes?
She said that your life is in danger
while you're in Venice.
- She kept on and on saying it.
- I am going to be sick.
(Vomiting)
(Groaning)
(Toilet flushes)
I wouldn't go in there
for a couple of minutes if I were you.
I haven't thrown up for ten years.
John?
I really think
we have to leave Venice.
It was a warning.
It was Christine.
She was trying to warn us.
How can I?
We must leave, John.
Do you hear what I say?
It was Christine, our daughter.
My daughter is dead, Laura.
She does not come peeping
with messages back
from behind the fucking grave!
Christine is dead.
She is dead.
Dead, dead, dead, dead, dead!
You must think I'm ill, then.
Yes.
If I'm ill,
I should be seeing Dr Jameson.
Yep.
Maybe I am.
Maybe I left England too soon
or something.
Maybe... Maybe those women
were influencing me.
Maybe I shouldn't see them again.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Yep.
Maybe I should start
taking my pills again.
They're on the desk right there.
Here.
Now...
You could get about a couple of weeks
or so off, couldn't you?
Yeah.
Could you?
Yes.
Do you really think you could, John?
(Bells chime)
All right, Laura.
All right.
(Phone rings)
- Hello.
- (Speaks Italian)
- (Laura) Jesus! Who on earth is it?
- Hello?
- Hello.
(Laura) What's the time,
for God's sake?
Operator?
- Operator?
- What's the time?
Operator!
Hello!
Operator,
where is this call coming from?
Hello?
Hello!
Where in England?
- Oh, hello. Is that Mr Baxter?
- John Baxter, yes.
Oh, good.
Look, this is Anthony Babbage here.
- Yes?
- Headmaster, Porton School.
Yes, that's right.
I'm awfully sorry
to get you so late at night, but...
What time is it with you out there?
Oh, I see.
We got your telephone number
from your London people, you see.
Yes, well, the fact of the matter is
there's been a bit of an accident.
It's your son, Johnny.
He's been to the san
and he's in very capable hands,
but Matron thinks that just possibly...
Hello, Mr Baxter?
It's Mandy Babbage here.
Yes, poor little Johnny.
It was an accident
during fire practice.
There's nothing to worry about
but we did think you ought to know.
Good. Yeah.
Mm-hm.
Tell them I'm catching
the next plane home.
What was that?
My wife will be there this morning.
Yes, well,
that's very kind of you, Mrs Babbage.
Thank you.
Yes, good night.
Good morning.
Bye.
This is what they meant, John,
about leaving Venice.
This is it. This is what they meant.
You see?
(Speaks Italian)
Will you get me Alitalia, please?
Well, get me the airport, then.
What time do they open?
Oh, Christ!
Thank you. Yes, good night.
Darling, she said that she's sure
that he'll be OK.
(Speaks Italian)
(Continues speaking Italian)
A charter flight.
We got the last seat.
Oh, fantastic!
He's just finding out
where they go from.
Don't forget to ask the bishop
what we talked about last night,
about staying over in England.
- Oh, yeah. Three weeks?
- Whatever you can do.
I really feel I need time in England
away from Venice.
- I'll tell him today.
- You can't come with me now?
You call me tonight
and I'll get away by the weekend.
10 minutes.
The boat leaves in ten minutes
from Riva Schiavoni.
Mr Baxter? You are coming back?
We are closing.
I'll collect everything this morning.
(Speaks Italian)
Give Johnny my love.
Hold tight.
I'll call you tonight, OK?
(Speaking Italian)
- Hello, John.
- Morning.
Morning.
I'm sorry, but this church
means a great deal to him.
You have all worked so hard.
- Are those the mosaics?
- Yes, they arrived this morning.
Is something the matter?
Our son had an accident and...
Laura flew to London to see him
at four o'clock this morning.
- I will pray for you.
- Oh, he'll be OK.
Laura's had some complications
since...
...Christine...
You should have gone with her.
- Can I see the mosaics?
- Of course.
They're marvellous.
The firm has worked
for my family for over 200 years.
- Will they be able to match those?
- Sure.
May I compare them?
Lower me down.
(Speaks Italian)
(Creaking)
(Shouting in Italian)
(John cries out)
(Clanging)
(Shouting in Italian)
(Banging)
(John cries out)
(Shouting in Italian)
(Applause)
(Groaning)
(Speaking Italian)
(Speaks Italian)
Would you like
to sit for a few moments?
No, I'm going to walk for a bit.
- May I walk with you?
- Please.
- My father was killed in a fall.
- Yes?
Yes.
It's unbelievable.
What?
My wife was warned
that I was in danger.
Warned?
It was...
It was like a...
It was a kind of prophecy.
I wish I didn't have
to believe in prophecy.
I do, but I wish I didn't have to.
(Child calling)
(Speaks Italian)
I hope it's not another murder.
(Children laughing)
We should go.
(Speaking Italian)
(Speaks Italian)
The bishop's driver will come by
and pick up my things.
Thank you.
Laura!
(Man speaks Italian)
- Where is the manager?
- (Speaks Italian)
(Whispering)
Ah, Signor Alexander.
Has Mrs?
Signor Baxter. I thought you'd...
The end of the season,
you understand. It's my holiday.
Has Mrs Baxter come back here?
- (Speaks Italian)
- My wife, yes.
- Has she come back here?
- Come back?
- But she left this morning.
- No, no, no.
I just saw her on the Grand Canal.
Has she?
- Has she come back here?
- She missed the plane?
No, I'm just asking
if my wife has come back here.
No, signore. We are closed.
We are closed.
Momi!
(Shouts in Italian)
- Did my luggage get away all right?
- Yes.
- You didn't see my wife, did you?
No.
(Speaking Italian)
(Speaks Italian)
Hello.
Sit down, Mr Baxter.
This is your wife,
and these are the sketches.
- How are they?
- I guess you'd recognise them.
Age makes women grow
to look more like each other.
Don't you find that?
Old men decay
and each becomes quite distinct.
Women seem to converge, eh?
I hadn't thought about it.
The skill of the police artist
is to make the living appear dead.
You are no longer staying
at the Europa?
No. No, it closed for the winter
this morning.
Now, tell me what happened,
from the beginning.
My wife met these two women
a couple of days ago and...
One of them, the blind one,
claimed to have seen Christine,
our dead daughter.
She said Christine was happy.
My wife collapsed.
When she came round,
she was changed.
She was happy.
She had come to terms with the death.
She... She was her whole self again.
Did you have a row?
A row? No. Well, yes.
I was only trying to protect her.
It was...
It didn't make any difference,
because she went
to see the women anyway.
And when she came back,
last night,
when we went to bed,
there was a call from England.
Our son goes to school in England
and the school phoned to say
that he had an accident.
My wife said that
she had been warned.
So I put her on the first plane
to England this morning.
And I saw her go.
I mean, I put her on the boat.
I saw her leave at 8.30.
Have you called the airport?
Yes. The plane was full.
That's all I know.
Please go on.
Then I saw her.
Between 10.30 and 11.00 on a boat.
I was on a Vaporetto.
She's here in Venice
with those two women.
What is it, Mr Baxter?
I do not understand.
If she's in Venice,
surely she will get in touch with you.
If she can.
What is it you fear?
The killer on the loose, the murderer.
My wife is not a well woman.
Yes.
Yes, of course.
I just thought...
There must be more.
No, no, there is nothing more.
My wife got something
from these two women,
something doctors couldn't give her,
I couldn't give her,
something that she needed,
so she went with them.
Where?
Where? I don't know.
I was outside...
inside the pensione last night,
where they lived.
And today before I came here,
I went to look for it.
But it's vanished.
So now she's with them.
Why should one criticise you
for being worried?
Thank you, Mr Baxter,
for talking to me.
I am grateful.
OK, I'll be at the Palazzo Vendori.
I want you to help me, Mr Baxter.
Try again.
Try and find the pensione.
It will make me feel we have
your cooperation in a real way.
I... er...
I don't even know where to start.
Start from where
you saw them the last time.
OK.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Where did you say?
San Nicolò dei Mendicoli.
Ah, yes.
(Speaking Italian)
Hello!
(Speaks Italian)
Thank you, Mr Baxter.
Murder squad.
They're not here.
Yes, very nice, very nice.
(Speaks Italian)
Mr Baxter? Yes, of course.
He's got some people with him.
- I'll go and tell him you're here.
- Thank you.
(Speaks Italian)
- Sister.
- He won't be long.
I have to make a telephone call
to England which is urgent.
- Could I use that phone?
- Certainly.
- You just have to complete this form.
- Thank you.
- Can I use this one?
- Yes.
(Speaking Italian)
Mrs Babbage? John Baxter.
'Mr Baxter. I'm so glad you called.
I've been trying to reach you.'
But the wires are down
or some such silly nonsense.
Now, the main thing is
Johnny's absolutely fine.
Right as rain. He woke up this morning
with no headache, no after-effects.
Fit as a fiddle!
The doctor's let him get up,
and now he's playing around.
'The doctor doesn't think
it's concussion.
'Johnny's aware
of all the events that led up to it.'
That's marvellous.
That's something
they have to watch for, apparently.
I expect you'd like
to speak to your wife.
- Sorry?
- Here she is.
- 'I've lost you.'
- Hello, darling. What?
- Laura?
- 'John, isn't it ridiculous?
'He's perfectly all right.
There's nothing wrong with him.'
Absolutely nothing. He just has
this little bump on his forehead.
John, are you all right?
Where are you?
- I'm at Alberto's.
- 'I'm catching the 9 o'clock plane.'
I don't know what time it gets in,
but we can have a late dinner.
- 'I thought I saw you in Venice.'
- Everything is very good.
John's fine and I'm OK. OK?
I thought I saw you here.
I thought I saw you
with the two sisters, the two women.
I was certain. I swore it.
'Darling, it's all right.
Don't worry, sweetheart.'
I've just found the flight number.
It's...
- Laura, where are you?
- I'm at Porton, John.
Johnny and I just got back from tea.
'My arrival time is 11.00.'
Just a second, I'll get a pencil.
'You stay at Alberto's.
I'll come there.'
- OK, I'll wait...
- 'Stay there.'
I'll see you about 11, all right?
John, is that all right?
- OK.
- 'John? Are you all right?'
- Yes. I love you. Bye.
- 'All right, darling. Bye.'
(Speaks Italian)
John, are you feeling all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
Excuse me, Alberto.
I think I just...
I have some things to...
- May I use your telephone?
- Sure.
I don't blame you moving in here.
- I would have done the same.
- It's very nice.
Do you want to see Johnny again?
- To say goodbye?
- No, I've already said goodbye.
- It would probably be quicker.
- Oh, yes, much quicker.
(Speaks Italian)
Wendy?
Answer me!
It's me, John Baxter.
Laura's husband.
What's happened to Wendy?
Where is she?
I don't know. I'll find out.
Are you all right?
- I don't know what's happening.
- Yes, I know.
(Speaks Italian)
- She's at the British consulate.
- Yes, but that was hours ago.
It's half past nine now.
I don't know this room.
I want to go home,
back to the hotel.
This is a police station.
I don't want to stay here, Mr Baxter.
I can't tell you how sorry I am.
It was a misunderstanding...
They took us out of our hotel.
We were arrested.
Then they asked us about your wife.
I know. I'm truly, truly sorry.
I'm going to take you back to your hotel.
- Yes, please. Take me back home.
- Can you?
- If I could just take your arm?
- Please.
You see...
you can't understand the noises
in a place like this.
I'm so sorry.
I just feel that...
If you could just take me back.
(Speak Italian)
One of the things I love about Venice
is that it's so safe for me to walk.
- Steps.
- Thank you.
The sound changes, you see,
as you come to a canal.
And the echoes from the walls
are so clear.
- My sister hates it.
- That's too bad.
She says it's like a city in aspic,
left over from a dinner party,
and all the guests are dead and gone.
It frightens her.
Too many shadows.
- We are almost there.
- Yes.
Milton loved this city.
Did you know that?
No. That's interesting.
This isn't the right way, is it?
(Speaks Italian)
This is the wrong way.
I was told to take you
to Signor Baxter.
- Yes?
- He is at the police station.
It is just on the way.
Puss, puss, puss, puss.
- (Meowing)
- Puss, puss, puss.
I've tried to keep them.
They never stay.
They're very wild in Venice.
- Do you like cats, Mr Baxter?
- Oh, yes.
Yes, I like them all right
but they don't like me very much.
It's all right.
- Here's the hotel.
- Thank you.
- These are swinging doors.
- I remember.
I'll keep them open.
It's so reassuring to have a man.
We changed hotels. Wendy said
there were prowlers and it was dirty.
- Careful of the steps.
- Thank you.
- Here's the key, Mr Baxter.
- Room 307.
- 307, yes.
OK, it's here.
They said you'd left
at the police station.
Wendy, you're back.
Mr Baxter has been looking after me.
- Oh, has he?
- Yes, she was at the police station.
She had been there quite a while.
I thought that the best thing...
- They found your wife, then?
- Yes.
- With the killings...
- He's explained everything to me.
Have we a drop of whisky
to offer Mr Baxter?
- You will stay a minute?
- Yes.
There's the miniatures
we got for Jessie.
We're leaving tomorrow.
The aeroplane's arranged.
- Have you put the photographs out?
- They're on the dressing table.
None of that for me.
Just a glass of water for me.
I'll fetch it.
Do take a seat, Mr Baxter.
So...
you will be able
to find it quite easily.
Thank you.
- It doesn't really look like her.
- It doesn't matter.
- No?
- No.
Please, your photograph.
What?
My God!
Thank you very much.
Thanks for your help. Bye-bye.
Goodbye.
Thank you.
- You're wearing odd socks.
- You put out my clothes.
- I was merely informing you.
- Thank you.
- Laura's plane gets in. I'd better go.
- Let Mr Baxter be off.
Wait. Wait!
- Is there anything I can do to help?
- No, it's quite all right.
It'll be all right.
(Yelling)
Wait! Wait!
- Fetch him back!
- Wait!
Please, please!
Let him not go!
Please, fetch him back!
Please, let him not go!
Fetch him! Fetch him!
- Fetch him back. Fetch him!
- No!
Fetch him! Fetch him!
Fetch him back! Fetch him back!
Fetch him!
Mr Baxter! Mr Baxter!
Mr Baxter!
Mr Baxter?
(Rapid footsteps)
- Hello. Is John here?
- Come quickly!
- What is it?
- Quick! Quick!
What is it?
- Hurry!
- Is this it?
- Mrs Baxter, please.
- Is it Heather?
- It's Mrs Baxter.
- Where is he?
- I couldn't find him.
- Christine. I saw Christine.
- He left. He just left.
- Find him. Warn him.
You must find him.
You must warn him.
- She told you.
- When did he leave?
- Where did he go?
- I don't know.
You must know where he went.
- She told you to leave Venice.
- Oh, God!
She told you.
Beware! Beware!
(Dog barking)
Laura! Mrs Baxter!
Hey, hey, hey!
(Shouts in Italian)
(Man shouts in Italian)
(Footsteps)
(Whimpering)
(Speaks Italian)
I'm coming.
(Man shouts in Italian)
It's OK.
(Crying)
I'm a friend.
I won't hurt you.
Come on.
Darlings!
Wait.
- No!
- Wait.
(Bell tolls)
Laura!
(Bells toll)