After a reign of hideous terror
spanning more than a century
the king of the "undead" was
finally traced to his lair
high in the Carpathian Mountains
Through the decades, many had
sought to destroy him. All had failed.
Here, at last, was an
adversary armed with
sufficient knowledge of
the ways of the vampire
to bring about the final and
absolute destruction.
This then was his fate.
Thousands had been enslaved by
the obscene cult of vampirism.
Now, the fountainhead
himself perished.
Only the memory remained
of the most evil
and terrible creature who ever
set his seal on civilization.
There, there, Frau Koenig. Calm yourself.
Stay with me.
Frau Koenig. You know this
is for the best!
The risk is too great to
allow for any other way.
You do understand.
You must understand.
- Frau Koenig - tell me you agree.
- Hurry, Father. It'll be dark soon.
Please, Frau Koenig!
So be it. Then it must be done
without your consent!
No, you mustn't do it! You can't!
She's my daughter! My baby! No!
(gunshot)
Barbarians!
This is none of your concern!
Would I ride 50 km in this filthy
weather if it were none of my concern?!
You shame the cloth you wear.
- We can't take any chances!
- Chances? What chances?!
This child died. You understand that
"Man of God"?
She died. Nothing more!
- You can't be sure.
- Of course I'm sure!
Take her to the churchyard.
She will be buried properly.
- I will read no service over her.
- I will bury her.
Now, do as I say.
Do as I say!
You're out of your jurisdiction.
I'll complain to the bishop.
You?! And tell him that I stopped you
from performing an act of blasphemy?!
Or would you prefer that I told him?
Well... we have to be sure.
You are an idiot, Father.
Worse than that - you are a
superstitious, frightened idiot!
Take care I don't have cause
to ride this way again.
That's right - take it steady!
No time for a breather, though!
Very good.
- That's as much as I can manage.
- Very good, sir!
- Drinks all 'round again.
- Thank you, sir.
- He just bought drinks for everyone.
- I know.
- Charles is far too extravagant.
- A few shillings - we can afford it.
But that's not the point.
You've got your disapproving expression
on again, Helen. What is it this time?
Well, I know it's
none of my business,
but that was the 3rd time you
supplied everybody with drinks.
I know!
They don't appreciate it - they
just think you're a fool.
Helen, what I do I do
for my own satisfaction.
What about you, Alan - do you disapprove
of your younger brother's generosity?
- I gave up approving of what you do.
- There's a sensible fellow.
You see Helen, Alan knows
that I'm incorrigible.
He accepts the fact. Why don't you?
Foolishness is foolishness.
And now, as we all have to
get up early, I suggest we go to bed.
I think that's a very good idea.
- What can I fetch you, Father?
- Mull me some claret.
It's not fit for a beast
out there tonight.
Well, what are you all looking at?
Garlic - to keep out the Boogy man.
There is no Boogy man, and if
there was this wouldn't keep him out.
Can't you get it into your thick skulls
it's been over these past 10 years?
- May I warm myself by your fire?
- Of course.
- Charles, let him sit by the fire.
- I prefer to stand, thank you.
It's easier to warm
one's self this way.
Ah! That's better.
Fortunately, my calling still allows
me the luxury of a warm posterior.
One of the few pleaures left in life.
You strike me as a man who
takes his pleasures seriously, Father.
I do, my son - indeed I do.
Pleasure in this life is important.
What are the alternatives?
Hellfire and brimstone.
No, I'm sure the warming of one's
backside before an open fire
and mulled claret aren't
part of the Grand Design.
No, these are earthly pleasures
we enjoy while one is able.
And what, may I ask, are four charming
English people doing in the Carpathians?
My name is Charles Kent.
This is my wife Diana,
my brother Alan and his wife Helen.
Father Sandor, Abbott of Kleinberg
at your service.
Please, be seated.
Father...
Kleinburg must be a dangerous
journey for you to go armed like this.
Another of my earthly vices.
Each time I leave the monastery,
I bring this with me.
The bretheren think it's a bundle of
prayer books for the heathen.
I'm sure they truly believe
that the venison I bring home drops
dead by the divine Will of God.
- You too are hunting?
- No, no. Some climbing, some sightseeing.
- Travel broadens the mind.
- Admirable.
But I question your choice of locale. You
won't have your mind broadened by this lot.
You don't seem to have a very
high opinion of your flock.
Not mine - dear me, no.
I wouldn't tolerate them.
I wouldn't tolerate them!
You will find things very
different in Kleinberg
I hope you will visit us there.
You can stay at the monastery.
- The brothers will make you very welcome.
- Thank you Father - that's a fine idea.
Our programme won't allow for it.
Tomorrow, we go to Carlsbad.
Well, I suppose we
could change our plans.
I suggest that you do so.
It's very kind of you to invite us, but...
...as my wife points out, we do
have our programme to stick to.
I don't care whether you go to Kleinberg or not,
I'm just saying you shouldn't go to Carlsbad.
- I've heard it's very beautiful.
- So is a drop of belladonna.
Deadly nightshade.
- We're all experienced climbers, Father.
- Climbing's got nothing to do with it.
You may think me an eccentric old cleric
and not much credit to my cloth.
Perhaps I enjoy shocking
people's susceptibilities,
but I can be serious.
and when I tell you not to go
to Carlsbad, I want you to take note.
- Landlord?
- Yes, Father?
Have my horse brought 'round.
Well, I'm delighted to
have met you all.
And if you disregard my advice,
at least stay well clear of the castle.
Castle? But there's no castle
marked on the map.
Because it is not on the map
doesn't mean it does not exist.
Stay away from it.
Ladies.
- Very strange.
- The Father made a mistake.
If there was a castle,
it would be marked.
Well, right or wrong - we'll
find out tomorrow.
I don't care how much money you
give me. I ain't going to go no further.
Don't be ridiculous. You contracted
to drive us to Carlsbad.
You can walk. It's bare 2 kilometers.
- Walk?! You must be mad!
- You're the ones that are mad.
- Come on, man - it'll be dark soon.
- Aye, it will. That's why I'll go no further.
It's not our fault that you slipped
a wheel and we're 4 hours late.
I'm not saying it is. I'm just
saying I'll go no further.
Look. Up there. The castle.
- What's that place?
- What place?
- The castle.
- I don't see no castle.
That's because you're
not looking, idiot!
Alright - you've had enough
argument. Get the women out!
Now! Get 'em out!
You'd better do as he says.
Leave it, Charles. He's a highway
robber. He just wants our luggage.
I'll be back here 2 hours
after dawn tomorrow.
If any of you are here then,
I'll take you on to Carlsbad.
Hyah!
He wasn't a robber. We should be
grateful for small mercies.
- Why did he say he'd be back after dawn?
- He's frightened of the dark.
- You don't mean that.
- Of course not.
- He should be reported to the authorities.
- We're not in England now, Helen.
I doubt that there are any
authorities to report him to.
And it wouldn't help us
if there were, would it?
Why wouldn't he look at that place?
Well, Sandor was right in any event.
But why does everyone else deny the
existance of the place? Even the map?
- Maybe we could stay there.
- No - let's stay away from there.
I agree with you.
Well - there's the alternative.
I prefer that.
So would I.
Very well - let's take a look.
There's no driver!
- Can we stop it?
- We can try.
- Charles, be careful!
- Watch it, Charles!
Well - you're the most welcome
horses I've ever seen. Both of you.
This is a bit strange, isn't it?
Haven't you heard? Never look
a gift horse in the mouth.
Especially when there
are two with a coach.
- Alan's right. The whole thing is strange.
- I agree.
Well, all I can see is, we won't have
to spend the night in that hut.
All aboard?
- Alright.
- Let's see to the luggage.
Helen, hold the horses, will you?
Diana, you hold them.
Alright, Darling.
- Carlsbad?
- Carlsbad.
Gitup!
Whoa! Whoa! Come 'round!
They're taking the wrong road!
Come back! Whoa! Whoa!
- What's wrong?!
- They're going the wrong way!
I can't turn them!
Come back! Whoa!
Come back! Whoa! Whoa!
Alright, my beauties,
you're calling the tune!
He can't control them!
Well!
Let's see if your master is
as hospitable as you are.
What do you think?
I don't think they're horses at all,
but St Bernards in disguise
rescuing travelers who are
stranded at the crossroads.
We made enough noise arriving - you'd
think somebody would come out
if not to welcome us, to chase us away.
Well, it's no good standing
here debating the situation.
Let's pay our respects.
Ladies?
No, Charles.
Surely, it can't be as bad as
spending the night in that hut.
It's eerie.
Well, let's find out just how eerie.
It's open.
Well?
Hello?!
Anybody there?!
You're right Helen - it is a bit eerie.
- I don't think we should go in.
- We've got to now. Come on!
Hey! Stop!
- What now?
- I don't know.
If you'd listened to me back at the
crossroads we wouldn't be in this state now.
If we'd listened to you, Helen,
we'd still be in England.
- Would that be bad?
- You wanted to broaden your mind!
I suppose you call this
educational, now?
I'm sure it would be very educational
if we knew what it was all about.
Stop it, both of you.
I'm sorry, Helen.
Look at this!
What is it, Darling?
The table is set for four persons.
Don't you see? First the coach brings us
to the castle, and now the dinner table.
We're expected.
- Ridiculous. How could that be?
- I don't know - but we are.
No, Alan's right, Darling.
Any moment now, four perfectly normal,
respectible people are going to
come down those stairs for dinner.
Well, if there's anybody up there,
they must be stone deaf.
There's one way to find out.
No!
No. We can't stay here.
We must leave this place now.
- Steady, Darling. It's alright.
- It isn't!
It isn't.
Come... sit down.
Charles!
- Charles, you mustn't go upstairs.
- He's only going to see if anyone's home.
I'll be back before you know it.
Charles!
It'll be alright, Helen. You'll see.
Hello?!
(knocks)
Alan!
Come up here, will you?
- Someone's bedroom.
- Come here.
Whose cases are these?
They're yours, aren't they?
I'm going to look next door.
Alan!
Our things are in there.
Sorry if I startled the lady, sir.
It was unintentional.
Why didn't you make your
presence known sooner?
I was unpacking your cases.
I trust the rooms are satisfactory.
Yes, admirable. But I don't
understand - none of us do.
My master's hospitality is renowned.
- But...
- If you are ready, I will serve dinner now.
Thank you, sir.
- I still don't understand it.
- Please, let's leave here.
- Dinner sounds like a splendid idea.
- I agree.
- Diana, you can't.
- But why not?
Ten minutes ago we were stranded in
the cold miles away from anywhere.
Now we're warm - we're going to be fed,
If that man's master is anything like I think
he is, we're going to be entertained as well.
Yes, Diana's right. Let's get down.
What's your name?
Klove, sir.
Well, Klove, isn't your master
joining us for dinner?
No, sir. I'm afraid not.
- Is he indisposed?
- He's dead.
I'm sorry if we appear a little
dense - perhaps you could explain.
- Explain, sir?
- Yes, you seem to have expected us.
This dinner, our rooms,
the carriage, everything.
Well sir, my master is dead, but
instructions were left
that the castle should always
be ready to receive guests.
- I am merely carrying out his wishes.
- I see.
Who was your master?
His name was Count Dracula.
An old and distinguished famlly.
That is the coat of arms,
over the fireplace.
Does no one hold the title now?
My master died without issue, sir...
...in the accepted sense of the term.
Now if you will excuse me.
The soup's delicious.
What a marvelous man he must have been,
to keep the castle always ready for travelers
- Perhaps we'll get a bill tomorrow.
- No, surely not.
No, no. I didn't mean it.
If only that coachman knew it, he
did us a favor when he deserted us.
I think it's frightening.
The unexplained is always
a little frightening.
Even you must admit,
this is preferable to
spending the night
in a woodcutter's hut.
I'm still frightened.
I don't know why.
I'm just frightened.
I admit it was a little
strange at first, dear,
but now it's all been explained.
Father Sandor tried to
warn us about this place.
- Helen.
- He tried to warn us!
That's because he wanted us to
go and visit him in Kleinberg.
It's my belief that we're
all extremely lucky.
Now, I think we should take advantage
of the late Count's hospitality,
and enjoy ourselves!
Here's to him.
May he rest in peace.
- Count Dracula!
- Guess who.
- Horace Peabody.
Right first time.
Did you enjoy your port,
cigars, and man's talk?
No, not very much, but then it
takes female company for me to...
- Who is Horace Peabody?
- An old beau of mine.
Before your time, Darling.
There was no before my time.
You were a schoolgirl in pigtails.
Even schoolgirls have their moments.
Hurry up. I'm cold.
- Is the bed comfortable?
- Not really. Lumpy.
Maybe you've got Horace Peabody
in there somewhere.
He was far too much of a gentleman.
It is lumpy.
Fine, that'll give Helen something
else to complain about.
Funny about Helen.
Darling, she's always the same - 2 miles
outside London and nothing is ever right.
She wasn't complaining.
She really was frightened.
- She hardly touched her dinner.
- It was a damn fine dinner, too.
Did you notice how she kept
looking over her shoulder all the time?
Klove frightened the life out of her.
He's not a particularly comforting
person to have around, I'll grant you.
I'm glad you noticed it.
I thought it was just Helen and I.
What was it about him?
I don't know. I suppose he's
a bit like the castle - sort of dusty.
He's not particularly clean, either.
- You suppose he cooked the dinner?
- I haven't the faintest idea, Darling.
The place isn't exactly
swarming with servants, is it?
(knock)
Yes, Klove?
Is there anything further
you or Madam require, sir?
No, thanks.
Then I wish you goodnight.
- He's a strange one.
- He's frightening.
I wouldn't go so far as to say that.
I can't get through to any of you that
it is frightening. Everything
about this place is evil!
You're tired dear. We've all
had a most trying day.
It's not that.
This whole situation is like a bad dream.
I expect any moment to
wake up and find it didn't happen!
- Oh, Helen.
- It's true!
The worst part of it is that
I'm the only one that can see it.
- Oh, Alan, let's go. Please!
- Don't be ridiculous.
- I mean it!
- I know you do.
You'll forget about all of this
in the morning. You'll see.
There'll be no morning for us.
What's the matter?
- You called me.
- No. Go to sleep.
- You said "Helen".
- I did not.
- Something called my name.
- You dreamt it.
Alan... what is it?
Well?
- It's Klove.
- Klove?
- What's he doing?
- I don't know.
Seems as if he was pulling
a trunk down the corridor.
- Let's find out.
- Alan!
Don't leave me.
I'll only be a moment.
Lock the door.
(thunder)
Madam... your husband.
Will you come quickly?
I'll wake the others.
Klove?!
Klove!
- Have you found them?
- No.
- All their luggage is gone.
- They must be here somewhere.
We've looked everywhere.
- I want to leave.
- Darling, we can't leave without them.
Please, Charles. I'm frightened.
Alright, come on.
- No, Charles, I won't allow it.
- Darling, I've got to go back there.
At least go to the
village first and get help.
What help? As far as the villagers
are concered, that castle doesn't exist.
- Then, I'm coming with you.
- No. I want no argument.
You stay here, I go to the castle.
That's all there is to it!
Is that clear?
Alright.
It's 2:30 now.
I'll be back before 6:30.
- It's dark by then!
- You're not frightened of the dark.
- I am here.
- You'll be quite safe in there, Darling.
I'll try to be back soon.
Take care.
Yes, of course I'll take care.
Klove?!
I hope I haven't startled you, Ma'am.
Klove - what are you doing here?
Your husband sent me to
fetch you in the carriage, Ma'am.
- Why?
- He will explain everything to you.
He's been waiting for you, Diana.
He's been waiting for you.
Helen!
Where is Charles?
There's something wrong, isn't there?
- Where is Alan?
- Nothing's wrong.
Come, sister.
Where's Charles?
You don't need Charles.
Stop!
Let her go!
Dear Charles. Let me kiss you.
- Charles!
- Diana! Get away!
Charles!
Diana!
I warned you not to go
anywhere near the castle, Mr Kent.
I read about vampires years ago.
I always thought it was the product
of an over-fertile imagination.
Would that it were, Mr Kent.
Here in the Carpathian Mountains,
vampirism was an undisputed fact.
And the fountainhead of this
obscene cult was Dracula himself.
I hoped we had seen the last of him.
The last record we have of him is...
...here it is... ten years ago.
From what you tell me,
it was your unfortunate brother
who provided the life force
for his resurrection.
Then...
...I must kill him.
Not kill... he is already dead.
He is "undead", Mr Kent.
He can be destroyed, but not killed.
- How... destroyed?
- There are a number of ways.
He can be traced to his resting place
during the daylight hours
and there staked through the heart.
He can be exposed to the
direct rays of the sun.
Running water will drown him.
The cross will burn him.
He is not invulnerable.
You make it sound
comparatively simple.
To skin a cat - first catch it.
It is not simple.
To the contrary, it is a difficult
and dangerous undertaking.
You see, there are people who help him.
Apparently normal human beings.
who are not vampires themselves
but who, for reasons
we don't understand
are in his power.
This Klove is such a man - spending
his life at the castle,
waiting for such an opportunity
as you gave him last night...
...a chance to resurrect his master.
- How is she?
- Admirable. Another 24 hours
and she'll be as good as new.
Ludwig would like to see you, Father.
Come with me Mr Kent.
Ludwig should interest you.
He was a traveler, like yourself.
I found him one night
near Castle Dracula.
Something he had seen
or heard unhinged his mind.
He lost his memory completely.
We brought him here. And here he
has remained these past 12 years.
Oh, he's a contented enough soul,
and a brilliant craftsman.
- Good day, my son.
- Good day, Father.
- What can I do to help you?
- I seek shelter for the night.
I'm sorry, my son, but I have
orders to let no one in tonight.
You are welcome to rest here.
I'll have the kitchen
send you out some food.
Thank you, Father.
Exquisite. Magnificent.
Fly away, Peter. Fly away, Paul.
Flies, Ludwig?
A small aperitif, Father Sandor.
It will soon be dinner.
- You wanted to see me?
- I finished the cover of the third folio.
I wanted your opinion on it.
Is it exquisite or merely magnificent?
- Exquisite, eh, Mr Kent?
- Beautiful.
Good.
You may go now!
- Goodbye, Ludwig.
- Yes, I'll send for you when I want you again.
- Why the security?
- He's a harmless enough soul,
but he has been known to erupt.
Come, we have things to discuss.
We are in agreement, then.
As soon as your wife has
recovered sufficiently
we will send her home to England.
Then, you and I will do
what has to be done.
We will pull that castle down
stone by stone if necessary.
We will find him wherever he is.
I still don't see why we
can't start immediately.
No, it is better to wait until
Mrs. Kent is safely away.
Last night Dracula was
robbed of his prey - your wife.
He has seen her and touched her.
He considers that she
belongs to him already.
He will want her badly.
- He won't come here?
- It is unlikely.
And even if he does,
he will not get in.
What the inhabitants here don't realize
is that a vampire cannot cross a threshhold
unless he is invited by
someone already inside.
And if he is,
all the garlic flowers in
the world won't keep him out.
Yes, master, yes.
Darling, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to wake you.
- Are you alright?
- Yes, of course.
You're the one we
have to worry about.
The important thing is to get
you well enough to go home.
Home... that sounds marvelous.
When do we leave?
I won't be coming - not just yet.
Why not?
There's something I have to do here first.
Oh, Charles - you're not
going back to that castle.
- I have to, Darling.
- No you don't!
Please Charles, promise
me that you won't.
- We'll talk about it in the morning.
- No... now.
- Darling.
- I'm not leaving here unless it's with you.
Now Mrs Kent, no more talking.
It's important that you rest.
Father, you tell him. It's madness
to go back to that place.
I think your husband is right, my dear.
We'll talk about it in the morning.
Now, Mr Kent, please.
Diana!
Good night.
Charles!
She'll be alright in the morning.
She'll understand
what has to be done.
I hope you're right.
I think you will find everything
you need. Goodnight, my son.
- Goodnight, Father, and thank you.
- God be with you.
(tapping)
Diana!
- Helen.
- Please let me in. It's cold out here.
So cold.
Everything is alright now.
I got away from him.
Oh, please, Diana, let me in.
I'm freezing.
Darling, what's wrong?
What's wrong?
Alright. Alright.
What happened?!
Tell me, what happened?!
Get her down.
Hold out her hand.
For pity's sake, enough!
Brother Mark.
Bring some salve and bandages.
- Well?
- We were just in time.
Are there any strangers
in the monastery?
Only a tinker, Father. He's spending
the night outside the main gate.
Why wasn't I told this before?!
Spread some salve on her wrist,
bandage it and remain with her.
Come with me, Mr Kent.
She'll be alright now. Come!
That will prevent them from
returning here at daylight.
If we haven't caught them
by that time, they will be
exposed to the sun and destroyed.
We have caught the woman.
She was hiding in the stables.
- Dracula?
- No.
Take her to Ludwig's cell.
If you wish to see the destruction
of the horror spawned by Count Dracula
come with me. But I warn you -
it is not a sight for the sqeamish.
Take Ludwig out.
Go with Father Peter, Ludwig.
It will be alright.
Now, bear in mind that this woman
is not your sister-in-law.
She's dead. This is a shell, and
what it contains is pure evil.
When we destroy it,
we destroy only the evil.
Mr Kent... have a look.
(Latin rites)
Ludwig? What are you
doing out of your room?
My room is being used for
most important matters.
Father Sandor sends his
compliments, Madam.
Would you do him the honor
of joining him in the study?
- But...
- Everything is under control, Brother.
There's no cause for concern.
Diana!
No!
- Horses! Quickly!
- We will go after them.
- But my wife!
- Not in panic!
Come.
Take him back to his cell.
Come, Mr Kent.
Come along now, Ludwig.
Come along. Come with us.
He will head for the castle.
Once there, he will be safe,
and your wife will be lost forever.
We must stop them
before he gets there.
- It's more than a day's ride.
- I know. This is to our advantage.
How?
It will be daylight soon. Already he will
be thinking of returning to his coffin.
Your wife will be safe
until sunset tomorrow.
Here.
It would be better if you kept it.
It's your rifle. You're used to it.
No. We will not be shooting
animals, Mr Kent. Klove is a human being.
I may bend the laws of my office at times,
but there is a limit to what even I will do.
Come. We must saddle the horses.
We've a hard day's ride ahead of us.
He's making for the castle.
- Will we be in time?
- We've got to be.
- We'll never make it!
- No.
We'll cut across country!
That's far enough!
Get down from there!
Get out of the way!
Come on Mr Kent!
Hurry, Mr Kent!
Diana!
God be praised.
No! You look after her.
I'll take care of him.
You must hurry! The light's going!
It's too late, Kent!
Get away from there!
It's too late!
- Why don't you shoot him?
- It would do no good, my dear.
Running water.