[ Choir Vocalizing ]
[ Vocalizing Continues ]
[ Soprano Vocalizing ]
Oculus Deum.
[ Speaking Italian ]
[ Whispering ]
She must be killed !
[ Speaking Italian ]
She was chosen
to bear his child.
lf she lives
to bring about the End of Days,
there will be no redemption.
All our souls
Will perish.
[ Italian ]
Tomaso.
[ Speaking Italian ]
[ Male Doctor ]
Okay, now give me
a big push.
That's it.
You're doing great.
Okay, stop pushing.
...five, six, seven--
I have the baby's head.
[ Rapid Puffiing ]
Don't push yet.
One little push
oughta finish this off.
One little push.
[ Shrieks ]
[ Baby Crying ]
You have
a beautiful baby girl.
Oh !
[ Laughs ]
She's so beautiful !
[ Crying ]
Just gonna take her
and clean her up.
Not yet.
[ Nurse ]
Hospital rules.
Please.
You'll have her back
before you know it.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
[ Baby Crying ]
[ Crying ]
[ Rattling ]
[ Speaking In Latin ]
[ Latin ]
Here she is.
[ Baby Coos ]
All fresh and clean.
[ Chuckles ]
You thought of a name
for her yet ?
Christine.
Her name is Christine.
Happy birthday,
Christine.
[ Man ]
WBAZ time is 8:06.
Three more nights, New York.
Three more nights left
in the century.
in the millennium.
Three more nights
until every computer fails.
until the biggest celebration
in the history of this city...
starts in Times Square.
Where will you be ?
[ Man ]
Hey, Bobby, come over here.
Something weird's goin'on.
What do you got there,
Charlie ?
I don't know.
Pressure's climbin'
off the gauge.
[ Rumbling ]
[ Alarm Blaring ]
[ Shouting ]
Go the other way !
[ Christmas Music ]
[ Car Horns Honking ]
[ Music Continues ]
Excuse me.
[ Grunting ]
[ Gagging ]
- [ Growling ]
- [ Grunting ]
[ Growling ]
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
[ Gasping ]
What the hell are you--
Mmm.
[ Man ]
You're on Gotham Talk.
Say something interesting.
[ Woman ]
I'm trying to figure out
what everyone'spredicting here.
ls the world going to come
to an end at exactly 12:01
on New Year's, or--
[ Radio Show Host ]
I'll tellyou what.
You should play it safe,
not quit your job
just yet.
Tell you something else.
in two more nights,
this place is gonna see
the wildest party ever.
We're gonna be there
with the first hundred callers,
we'regonna make the most noise,
and we'regonna be the craziest,
and if the world
comes to an end,
what the hell,
we're all gonna be together!
And if it doesn't,
and i don't think it will,
then we'll all have
the best time
anybody has ever had.
[ Radio Sound Fades ]
[ Banging ]
[ Pounding On Door ]
[ Man ] Let's go.
We'regonna be late.
Honey, i'm home.
[ Heavy Breathing ]
[ Groans ]
I Was just
pulling myself together.
[ Chuckles ]
It's gonna take
a lot more pulling.
[ Groaning ]
You are looking
very sharp this morning.
- Thanks.
- You're Welcome.
You got about five minutes
to get ready. Here.
There's enough caffeine in this
to kill an elephant.
Oughta get you
started.
- So What's today ?
- Transport.
Anyone special ?
No, just some
Wall Street scumbag.
Why the hell does he need
all this protection ?
Well, I guess he fucked
With some people...
that didn't like
being fucked with.
Personally, I like scumbags.
They pay better.
They say breakfast
is the most important
meal of the day.
No, I'm good.
Thanks.
[ Radio Dispatcher ]
Striker One, F.D.R. Drive--
[ Man ]
Follow Three,
F.D.R. south bound.
[ Dispatcher ]
Striker One, stay close.
Striker Four--
[ Man #2 ]
Okay,you zeroes.
These people are
paying us good money.
Get your heads out
of your asses and start
earning those paychecks.
[ Man #1 ]
Follow Three,
give me a visual sweep.
[ Pilot ]
Striker One,
rooftops 125 to 136 clear.
- Keep them clear.
- Striker Four,
advise and contact the--
[ Man #1 ]
Follow Three is on approach.
E.T.A., two minutes.
Striker One,
Follow Two and Three to report
tight formation. Do you copy ?
- [ Man #2 ]
Air One, make a final sweep.
- [ Air One ] Roger that.
[ Man #1 ]
Follow Three.
We have nest in sight.
[ Dispatcher ]
Air One, westbound
overzone two.
[ Muttering ]
[ Driver ]
Ten seconds out.
[ Dispatcher ]
Roger. Ten seconds.
[ Man #1 ]
Follow Three,
we have arrived.
Keep everyone close.
- We're exposed.
- [ Pilot ] Roger.
Sky Two,
fire escape, southwest corner.
Fire escape's negative.
You're Wrong ! Shooter !
Evac ! Evac !
Get in the car !
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
Call N.Y.P.D. !
Get me an ambulance !
- What the hell's goin' on ?
- [ Man ] i see him !
i see him !
[ People Shouting, Screaming ]
Shit !
Oh, shit ! Tell me
You remembered ! Come on !
Get up,
you pussy.
[ Groans ]
Where's the shooter ?
- Headed for the roof.
- So are we.
Sky Two, get the fuck
down here, now !
Come on ! Hurry !
Take us up there !
Move in ! Move in !
- Set us down ! Hurry !
- There's too much crap
on that roof !
- We'll tear off the main rotor.
- Then get us down
as low as you can !
Hurry now! Go !
Strap me in !
You're good !
- [ Hollering ]
- He's gonna jump
off the roof ! Shit !
- [ Hollering ]
- He's gonna jump
off the roof ! Shit !
[ Hollering ]
He's got him !
Gun ! Gun !
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Gunshot ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Groans ]
Oculus Dei !
The thousand years has ended!
The Dark Angel is loosed
from his prison !
Get down on the ground and
put your hands behind your head.
You don't know
What you've done !
- Get down,
or I'll put you down !
- The thousand years has ended !
You don't know
What you've done !
[ Groaning ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
Priest that drinks.
Can't be all bad.
I think the police
may want that at some point.
- They call it evidence.
- I like to get a head start.
- No reason to make it
easy for them.
- Yeah.
[ Priest Muttering ]
All right.
Watch the lines.
Go through here.
[ Police Officers Chattering ]
She doesn't look happy
With the statements.
Should've just killed that son
of a bitch. Less paperwork.
Yeah.
Hey, Detective.
Bobby. Hey,Jer,
it's been a while.
Hey. How are you,
Marge ?
Can't complain.
You ?
It's a nice day
to jump out
of a helicopter.
Well, just doing
my job.
Now, listen.
Something I
gotta ask you.
[ Jer ]
Yeah, what is it ?
You still drinking ?
[ Bobby ]
Oh,yeah, we got all
liquored up this morning.
-We start every day that way.
-I'm just reading his statement.
You said here
the guy spoke to you.
Yeah. So what ?
The guy doesn't
have a tongue.
- What ?
- He has no tongue ?
Why don't I just leave
that little detail out for now.
No big deal, right ?
Are you saying that
limagined all this ?
No, I'm just saying.
I saved a life today.
What the hell
did you do ?
All right, let it go.
- No, no. I know what i heard.
- All right.
[ Marge ] Those people
who don't belong here,
get them out of here.
Make sure this place
is secure.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
A drunk hangs out
in a neighborhood bar,
passes out enough times,
people would know
where he lived
from carrying him home.
I mean,
it's one thing I know.
Yeah, well,
it's important to be
an expert at something.
Oh, it took years
of research.
This must be it.
[ Bobby ]
What do you want to bet
it's rent-controlled ?
[ Door Scraping ]
[ Water Dripping ]
Well, I don't think
this is paint.
A real art buff.
[ Bobby ]
I don't go for this look.
It's just too damn busy.
Listen to this.
"I have seen the Earth
laid to Waste.
"I have seen the horror to come.
lsit a sin to wish
you were never born ?
"The thousand years
have ended.
Twenty... seven."
it ends in
a football score.
That's nice.
[ Jer ]
Hey, i found something.
Can you see
What it is ?
His tongue.
He must have
cut it out himself.
Okay. And why is it
someone would cut out
their own tongue ?
To keep
from talking.
Right.
Well, I could eat.
- [ Screeching ]
- Ah !
- Shit !
- What ?
All right, I knew
that was gonna happen.
No, it's all right.
There's something
in here.
Have you ever
seen her before ?
Nah.
[ Jer ]
This guy
is no ordinary hit man.
No, this one's
extraordinary.
Let's get the hell
outta here. This place
is making me itch.
- Drop it ! Don't move !
Don't move ! Freeze !
- Don't move ! Freeze !
Oh. It's us.
jesus! How the hell
did you two find this place ?
Lucky guess.
So what did
You fiind out ?
His name's
Thomas Aquinas.
He's a priest.
Why don't you tell us
something we don't know ?
- A homicidal priest.
That's good.
- Yeah ? well, it gets better.
He studied at the Vatican.
He was one of their
alleged visionaries.
Came here in '81
to St.john's Church
downtown.
Six months ago,
he disappeared.
Priests there say he was
having a spiritual crisis.
Oh, yeah.
That's What this is about.
Spiritual crisis.
Doesn't make
any sense.
What's a priest doing shooting
at a Wall Street banker?
A Wall Street banker,
by the way,
who suddenly disappeared.
Maybe we should ask the girl.
What girl ?
Uh, the guy.
The guy. Priest guy.
[ Jer Clears Throat ]
[ Jer ]
There's five million women
living in New York City.
How we gonna fiind her
without a name ?
Here.
Look, I already
gave you some money.
Can you just move on, please ?
He's comin' for you.
He's comin' for you, Christine.
How do you know
my name ?
He's gonna fuck you.
He's gonna fuck you, Christine.
Can you see him ?
- [ Chuckles ]
- Who are you ?
Can you see him ?
How do you know
my name ?
[ Screaming ]
- [ Glass Tinkling ]
- [ Gasps ]
-He's gonna fuck you, Christine.
-[ Screaming ]
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Panting ]
I'm sorry.
[ Gargling ]
[ Groaning ]
Ohh.
[ Groans ]
The thousand years
have ended.
Thousand years have ended.
[ Classical Tune Plays ]
[ Music Continues ]
"When the thousand years
are ended,
Satan shall be loosed
out of his prison.''
"Twenty... seven. "
[ Woman ]
Christine ?
I'll be there
in a sec !
[ Phone Ringing ]
Doctor's offiice.
Hello.
Is Dr. Abel in, please ?
Who's calling, please ?
It's Christine York.
Christine, listen to me.
We've been over this before.
It's a terrible thing
to lose your parents.
I know it was a long time ago.
The holidays always make
something like that
feel much Worse.
Understand,
these dreams are your creation.
There's nothing real about them.
You control them.
They don't control you.
Take another Xanax
to relieve your anxiety.
You are fine. Trust me.
Another vision ?
Why didn't you tell me ?
I didn't want you to worry.
i'm your step mother.
it's my job to worry.
No big deal, really.
just someone on the subway car
turned into porcelain
and shattered.
What's wrong with me ?
Why do i see things ?
Why am i so different ?
Oh, you don't know
how special you are.
You're better
than everybody else.
Just remember that.
I don't want to be
better or worse.
I want to be normal.
I want a normal life.
You have to have patience.
All good things will come
to you. You'll see.
Oh, excuse me.
I'm sorry,
we're closed.
I would like
to talk to you
about Thomas Aquinas.
Father, please,
I need you down stairs.
Just take these.
Father, please.
Go.
I've already told the police.
Thomas was a friend of mine
and a colleague.
He had nothing to do
with what happened today.
There was no one else
on that fire escape.
You don't understand.
I understand getting shot at,
and I don't like it.
He shot at you ?
No, he shot
at my client.
- I happened to get in the way.
- Who's your client ?
That's irrelevant right now.
What I want to know is why would
a priest try to kill someone ?
You've been drinking.
I've got 14 years sober,
and I can spot that.
Well, good for you.
Your friend and colleague,
was he working for someone ?
Yes, he was working for God.
So God ordered a hit
on an investment banker ?
There's a lot that you
don't know. You think
You've seen everything ?
You haven't. There are
things you never dreamed of.
There's another world
out there. Thomas saw it,
and it destroyed him.
I've seen a lot too,
but there's nothing that would
make me cut my tongue out.
Yeah, well,
wait a few days.
what happens
in a few days ?
Did Thomas tell you
about a girl?
- No.
- I see. Do you
believe in God ?
Maybe once,
but not anymore.
what happened ?
We had a difference of opinion.
I thought that my wife
and daughter should live,
and He felt otherwise.
I'm sorry to hear about
the loss. Maybe it's time
for you to renew your faith.
This girl.
Is she in trouble ?
Does she need help ?
I have a lot ofthings
to do here. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
I have more questions,
if you don't mind.
I've got a question for you.
If you don't believe in God,
how can you understand
his adversary ?
Now I have to believe in God
in order to solve a crime ?
I'm sure that you
can fiind your way out.
[ Woman Chanting ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
[ Chanting ]
- How many have received
the stigmata ?
- She's the third this week.
[ Screaming ]
- What is shesaying ?
- For your own good, get out
and forget what you've seen !
Was Thomas part of this ?
There are forces at work you
couldn't possibly comprehend !
Now, please,
leave!
[ Recording Over P.A. System ]
[ God rest ye, merry gentlemen ]
Let nothing
you dismay
Remember Christ--
No, it's just I hate
the fact that they put
finals after the holiday.
It ruins
the whole meaning
of vacation.
I wouldn't worry.
You always do fine.
Besides, a bad grade
isn't the end of the world.
isn't the end ofthe World.
[ Door bell Rings ]
[ Pants ]
It's you.
I didn't--
Where is she ?
The girl is safe.
And what of the world ?
Everything is
as planned.
Our acts go unnoticed,
unquestioned.
- We're everywhere.
- Daddy, who is it ?
- Is this your daughter ?
- Yes.
- And this is your wife ?
Mm.
[ Rock ]
Oh,you insist
you gotta talk that shit
You gotta keep
that dog ass breath
All up in my face
And i remember when
You would never lie
to a friend
'Cause you were so high
you were so shy
You were
so fucked up anyway
Life keeps on tickin',
tickin', tickin', tickin'
[ Song Fades Out ]
[ Screaming ]
- [ Heavy Footsteps ]
- [ Gasps ]
What's wrong, baby ?
What's wrong ?
It was a dream.
He came
for me again.
It's only a dream, angel.
It felt closer.
[ Panting ]
[ Female Newscaster ]
Through out the country,
the National Guard...
has been put on alert
as a precaution--
[ Male Newscaster ]
Mayor Giulianiurged
all citizens and police...
to stay calm
during this holiday season.
[ Female Newscaster ]
No explanations for how blood on
the hands of the Christ child,
depictedin Michelangelo's
famous sculpture of the Pieta--
[ Male Newscaster ]
...atmosphere of fear and panic,
random acts of violence...
are being attributed
to satanic cults
who seem determined...
to disrupt
New Year's celebrations
throughout the world.
Here in New York--
Sorry, pal,
You can't come in here.
Ahh. The young boys
that you seduced have left
their scent upon you.
Remember who it is
that you serve. Hmm ?
Open your eyes, Thomas.
[ Gasping ]
[ Grunting ]
Look. Look at the face
that has haunted your dreams
for a thousand years.
[ Grunting ]
They say you can
see the future, Thomas.
Then you must know exactly
What I'm going to do to you.
[ Panting ]
[ Bobby ]
i don't know what we hope
to get from this guy.
He's got no
fuckin' tongue.
He can write.
Fuck me.
[ Female Newscaster ]
There is still no explanation...
for the devastating explosions
that rocked midtown
two nights ago.
In the wake
of Tuesday night's explosion,
investigators from the New York
City Fire Department are still
at a loss to explain...
why the restaurant
suddenly burst into flames,
killing at least 35 people.
- Hey, asshole,
watch where you're going.
- Hey, I like the shirt.
Screw you, man !
Hey, kid.
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
Nice shirt.
I'm tellin'you,
no one entered the room.
Maybe he did it himself.
Then how did he get
the last scalpel in !
[ Doctor ]
Oh, my God.
- It just keeps getting better.
- [ Doctor ] I've never
seen anything like this.
[ Police Officers, Nurses Chattering ]
i think this
is written in Latin.
"When the thousand years
has ended,
Satan shall be loosed
out of his prison.''
Uh, this next part
is not clear. I-I-I
think it's in English.
lt says, "Christ--
Christ in New York."
- [ Thomas Shouts ]
- [ Screaming ]
- Christ !
- [ Nurses Whimpering ]
Well, it's offiicial.
I'm never sleeping again,
ever. You okay ?
A guy cuts words into
his chest. Someone else
nails him to the ceiling.
What's not okay ?
[ Sighs ]
So where we going ?
The girl.
I gotta talk to her,
find out what she knows.
W-W-Wait.
We don't have a name.
That would help.
Maybe we do.
Maybe it's not
"Christ in New York."
Maybe it's,
"Chris in New York,"
"Christine in New York."
"Christine York." Let's run
a D.M.V. check and find out
if any of those names come up.
[ Bobby ]
Hello, Christine York.
Sometimes you border
on competent.
-I know. It's scary, isn't it ?
-[ Bobby Chuckles ]
[ Speaking Italian ]
Christine ?
Mabel called.
She'd like you to get dressed
and join her for lunch.
Grazie, Carson.
No !
[ Screaming ]
Shit !
[ Christine Grunts ]
No ! No !
Ahhh ! Goddamn it,
get off me !
Go downstairs
and watch the front door !
Please!
Help !
There is no sanctuary
but heaven.
- [ Grunting, Gasping ]
- You must go there now.
- What are you doing ?
- I commend you to Almighty God
and entrust you--
[ Bobby ]
At what point
is this considered...
interfering with
a police investigation ?
Hey, we are private citizens
having a conversation
with another citizen.
I mean, I don't think they've
found a way to outlaw that.
At least not yet.
[ Christine ]
Please! No !
May you return
to Him who formed--
Go down there. Do whatever
You can. I need more time
to finish the last rites.
- [ Shrieking ]
- May Christ,
the true shepherd--
[ Christine ]
Help !
Stairs.
Covered.
Help !
May you see
Your redeemer--
- ...forever, amen.
- [ Yelling ]
- [ Christine ]
Son of a bitch !
- [ Groaning ]
[ Grunting ]
You all right ?
Yeah. Check the body
down the stairs.
What body ?
Call the police,
and get an ambulance.
[ Jer Panting ]
Take it easy.
We're the good guys.
All right ?
What happened?
Carson.
Those men--
Th-Those men--
They tried
to kill me.
[ Panting ]
Why ?
Eight jets, variable speed.
That's what i call
dying in style.
What kind of girl
lives in a house
like this, anyway ?
Oh, she's an orphan.
Both parents deceased.
After the mother died,
the home nurse married
the father.
Now the nurse is
the sole guardian.
I think it's adorable
the way you talk
like a real cop.
Yeah ? So you think
after they clean up
this mess, we could...
[ Marge ]
Don't tempt me.
soak a little ?
They relax me.
You want one ?
Oh, no, thanks. I drink.
My little girl had one
just like it.
Really ?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah ? You snoop through
her stuff without asking too ?
When I was looking
for something.
What are you
looking for ?
A connection.
Most days, I don't feel
connected to anyone.
I noticed a lot
of religious books outside.
Mm. They're
my stepmother's.
- Is she a big believer ?
- No, not really.
It's mostly just kind of
like a hobby with her.
Do you know
a priest by the name
of Thomas Aquinas ?
No. Is that
Your connection, religion ?
I've seen a lot
of attempted murders,
but I've never seen anyone
perform the last rites before.
[ Mabel ]
Christine ?
In here !
Are you all right ?
Oh, my God, I just
heard what happened !
Did they
hurt you ?
I'm okay, but Carson--
I know. Oh.
I'm just so glad
You came along
When you did.
Thanks.
[ Sighs ]
I didn't realize you knew
Where the library was,
let alone had a card.
Well, there's a lot
about me you don't know.
[ Mabel ]
They're right outside.
[ Dr. Abel On Telephone ]
You must bring her.
He is waiting for her.
No, that's impossible !
They'll follow me
and find the temple !
I couldn't
convince her
to come here.
Yuck ! Then I shall
have to go to her.
Did i mention
i had a date tonight ?
Not just
the inflatable kind.
A real live girl.
Did you break up
With the inflatable one ?
Yeah. She was
just too needy.
Everything
was about her.
It's just that this
is starting to feel
a lot like work.
Normally, l wouldn't
mind work because,
well,you know,
we'd be
getting paid.
Watching rich people
for free. It just
seems odd, doesn't it ?
Okay, I'll wait here.
- Change your mind
about the pill ?
- I found something.
Christine,
what are you doing ?
why is that man here ?
I'll be
five minutes.
She loves me to death, but she's
a little overprotective.
I took this from one
of your attackers.
Did you show that
to the police ?
No.
If I did, it would end up
in a plastic envelope
on one of their large shelves.
That's pretty cynical.
well, I've put a few
of those envelopes...
up on that
large shelf myself.
I used to be a cop.
Now, this amulet
is from a Masonic order...
in a former sub-herald
ofthe Vatican knights.
[ Jer ]
The Knights
of the Holy See.
They await the return
of the Dark Angel to Earth.
So, the men
that attacked me
are devil worshippers ?
No. This says
they're the good guys.
They're the ones
that are supposed to stop
the devil worshippers.
Those were the good guys ?
What does that
have to do with me ?
Those were the good guys ?
What does that
have to do with me ?
- [ Humans Shrieking ]
- [ Screams ]
[ Panting ]
I'm sorry. I have
a medical condition.
- Sometimes I see things
that aren't there.
- No. I saw it too.
[ Zipper Unzipping ]
[ Urinating Continues ]
I've been having visions
ever since i can remember,
but I've never
shared one before.
There must be
an explanation.
I hope so.
I've been waiting
all my life to hear it.
[ Flicking Open Cigarette Lighter ]
[ Whistling Sound ]
- [ Christine Shrieks ]
- [ Jer Grunts ]
Let's get
out of here !
Come on !
[ Gasps ]
You're not
going anywhere.
- What are you doing ?
- There's no time
to discuss this.
After all these years of
waiting, it's finally happening.
What's happening ?
You can't run away now!
- [ Christine ] Stop it!
- Let her go !
- No !
- [ Grunting ]
Don't you love me ?
Didn't I give you
everything ?
- [ Grunting ]
- Haven't i been
a mother to you ?
[ Groans ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Groaning ]
[ Screams ]
No-o-o !
- Christine.
You know who I am.
- Oh, no.
- I've come for you.
- Let's go. Come on.
[ Moaning ]
[ Whimpering ]
You only had one simple job,
and you couldn't even do that.
[ Gurgling, Grunting ]
[ TiresScreeching ]
[ Siren Chirps ]
[ Police Radio Chattering ]
Hey, Marge ?
Marge, over here !
we need your help !
Easy with the hardware.
Jesus, Marge !
what the fuck ?
[ Marge ]
lt's okay, Jer.
We just want the girl.
Okay, tell me. What the hell
is going on here ?
I don't know.
I don't believe you.
- All right. I'm coming out.
- Throw out the gun.
Please don't don't
leave me here. Please !
[ Cop ]
Hands on your head.
- What ?
- Hands on your head.
Now!
What do you want
With her, Marge ? Huh ?
-why is she so important ?
-just the girl.
You can kill him.
[ Gasps ]
Come on !
Quickly !
You, i don't need.
But you--
Call your people.
Find them.
Over here.
[ Pills Rattling ]
Goddamn it !
Get up !
Come on. Get up !
My best friend is dead.
Everyone is trying to kill us.
I just shot two cops.
Why is everyone
after you ?
I don't know.
I swear. I don't know.
why is this happening ?
i know it's my fault.
i just don't know why.
That man on the stairs,
what do you know about him ?
Nothing.
Come on.
I saw your face.
You recognized him.
I don't talk
about it.
[ Softly ]
Tell me.
I need to know.
I've seen him before...
in my dreams.
- In your dreams ?
- They're-- They're
nightmares really.
He takes me, and--
and he makes love to me.
I've been making love
to him my whole life.
I thought I was crazy,
but he was never real
before tonight.
Oh, he's real.
I've seen him before.
- I'm afraid.
- Don't be afraid. I won't
let him do any harm to you.
I'm afraid of me.
I'm afraid that if I see him,
if he tries to take me,
I'm gonna
want him to.
- [ Woman Chattering On Police Radio ]
- Let's go !
Where we going ?
To get
some answers.
[ Knocking On Door ]
- [ Gun Cocks ]
- You don't need that.
You have no enemies here.
I'm not so sure about that.
This girl Was just attacked
by your people.
- Your Vatican knights
almost killed her !
- Vatican knights ?
Oh, my God.
Well, they're not
my people. They think
they're doing God's work.
-But they're not.
-I Want to know What's going on,
and I want
to know right now !
Put the gun away.
Did anybody
see you come ?
No.
Good. We should
be safe here.
According to the Scriptures,
he can't see inside
of the house of God.
Who can't ?
Maybe now you're
ready to believe.
[ Woman Chanting in Ancient Language ]
[ Computer Beeping ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
Her hands are healed.
That's the power
of faith.
- Who is she ?
- She's a Polish peasant.
She fell into a trance
about two weeks ago,
and then she began to speak
in a language she couldn't
possibly have known.
- She made a prophecy
about End of Days.
- "End of Days" ?
Of man's destruction
and the unholy's reign
upon the earth.
Why don't you stop all
this church talk and tell us
What the hell is going on.
- Who's after her ?
- Well, if you'll excuse me,
I'll try to explain.
[ Kovak ]
You know anything about
the number of the beast ?
Revelation of St.john ?
From his dream ?
- Six-six-six ?
- The number ofthe beast
is not six-six-six.
Often in dreams,
numbers appear upside down
and back wards.
So, six-six-six
becomes nine-nine-nine.
Like in 1 999,
the year of his return.
What does that
have to do with me ?
Regressus diaboli:
The return of Satan.
Does any of this
look familiar to you ?
She's been chosen.
He's in her blood.
The Holy Church
has been searching for you
since the day you were born.
Chosen for What ?
Every thousand years,
on the eve of the millennium,
the Dark Angel comes
and takes a body,
and then he walks the Earth,
looking for a woman who will
bear his child.
lt allhas to happen
in that unholyhourbefore
midnight on New Year's Eve.
lf he consummates
your flesh
with this human body,
then he unlocks
the gate of hell...
and everything
as we know it
ceases to exist.
So, the Prince of Darkness
wants to conquer the Earth,
but has to wait until
an hour before midnight
of New Year's Eve ?
- Is this Eastern time ?
- It's got nothing to do
With New Year's Eve.
It has to do
With a temporary
celestial alignment.
The Gregorian monks
studied the heavens.
They were able to calculate
the precise moment
of this event.
They created our calendar
by mapping this event...
and counting backwards
from that moment.
- It was a mistake to come here.
- It doesn't matter
Whether you believe or not.
He's real, and he won't rest
till he finds this girl.
- Why did he pick me ?
- Because the stars were
right When you were born.
A man's body
was also chosen,
just like yours.
lf the devil does exist,
why doesn't your god
do anything ?
It's not my God.
It's our God, and He doesn't
say that He Will save us.
He says that
We will save ourselves.
Save myself?
What am i supposed to do ?
Get a restraining order?
- We have to have faith.
- Faith.
Yes, faith.
it's an interesting concept.
If you read the Bible,
You can't miss it. Faith !
Between your faith and
my Glock nine millimeter, I take
my Glock. Come on. Let's go.
I'm afraid it takes
a person of pure heart
to defeat pure evil.
You did your job. You brought
her here to people of faith.
We'll protect her.
- We'll hide her.
- You know, you live
in a different world.
We have some
real serious problems here,
and this is not solving them.
Satan's greatest trick
Was convincing man
he didn't exist.
I don't, uh--
This all feels
true to me.
You'll be safer with me.
At least I can fight this guy
With something real.
You know what to do.
You feelit.
[ Softly ]
I'm sorry.
Let him go.
[ Priest Speaking In Italian ]
It gets easier when you
accept what you are.
A fallen soul.
Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk.
[ Chuckling ]
Door's locked,
no windows broken.
- [ Whispers ]
How did i get in here ?
- Who the fuck are you ?
Oh, I think
You know who i am.
You just don't
want to believe it.
I took a bullet for you.
I protected you.
Oh, no-no-no.
You didn't protect me.
You protected this body.
Am I-- Am I getting
a pattern here ?
So much pain.
"Not to be taken
With alcohol."
Remember that.
Oh.
To lose a wife and child.
I can't even imagine
What that must be like.
- What do you want ?
- To make you happy again.
[ Nat King Cole Singing ]
jack frost nipping
at your nose
Yuletide carols
Beings ungby a choir
And folks dressed up
like Eskimos
A gift
from you daughter?
Hmm ?
[ Continues ]
[ Water Splashing, Child Giggling ]
[ Splashing Continues ]
Amy ?
Don't stayin there too long.
You'll turn into a prune.
- Emily !
- Come on, darling.
It's time to get out.
Gotta get you dressed.
Your daddy's gonna be home soon.
[ Amy ]
I have the best daddy
in the whole world.
Yes,
You certainly do.
[ Laughing ]
But i don't think
he'll be home.
[ Emily ]
Now, what makes you say
a silly thing like that ?
- He never comes home.
- Well, honey,you know
your daddy workshard.
It's not about
how much time you're there.
It's about "quality time."
Now, he'll be home
just like he promised.
You'll see.
He keeps his promises.
I can give it all back to you.
Everything that He took away.
Everything.
You can hold
your wife again.
You can watch your daughter
walk through the door
in her prom dress.
All you have
to do is tell me
where the girl is.
Come on.
She's a nobody to you.
You don't even know her.
You're in the middle
of something you don't
really understand.
You think you're
saving her from me ?
She wants to be with me.
- You know that.
- What did you do
in school today ?
You think i'd harm her?
[ Scoffs ]
i'd treat her like a queen.
Turn around, sweetheart.
You told me you'do anything
to get yourfamily back.
You want them ?
This is your chance.
They're not real.
Does that matter?
- Oh, yes.
- i think you need
to be reminded...
of how painful
reality is.
No !
Oh, shit !
[ Snarls ]
[ Jer Yelling ]
[ Screaming ]
Don't hurt my baby !
- Daddy!
- Let my daughter go !
[ Screaming ]
Daddy !
- Let go of my baby !
- [ Screaming, Shotgun Blasts ]
No !
[ Panting ]
Oh, it's true.
It wasn't your fault.
- I wasn't there.
- No, you were just--
You were out doing your job.
- I wasn't fucking there !
- Oh, look at you.
Torn apart by guilt.
You didn't do anything wrong.
You were an honest cop.
You didn't take money.
You had to testify
against them even after
they threatened your family.
Most people Would never
testify against those guys.
They're not like you.
You had to do
the right thing.
And where was God, hmm ?
He could've stopped it,
but he didn't. He fucked you.
Then He made you feel guilty.
Me, I don't do guilt.
I didn't do what happened here.
He did.
Now you just
think about that.
Then you tell me
Who's really your friend.
I can make it like
it never happened.
All for the price
of a stranger's address.
No !
You will never see the girl !
Now, you see--
Now you're upsetting me.
You don't want
to see me upset,
believe me.
Oh, you want to fuck with me ?
You think you know bad, huh ?
You're a fucking choirboy
compared to me ! A choirboy !
You're in touch with your anger.
I really like that.
I don't know about you,
but I'm going
to have a drink.
You and I are
so much alike.
We're nothing alike !
Nothing !
Look at yourself. Look at this.
Look at what you are now.
You walked away from the light,
just like me. You want one ?
- You need to get out, now.
- Come on. You know
What's in your heart.
We're on the same side.
I'm not on your side,
and I never will be.
[ Laughs ]
You're on His side ? He's the
one who took away your family.
Let me tell you
something about Him.
He is the biggest underachiever
of all time.
He just had a good publicist,
that's all. Something good
happens: "It's His Will."
Something bad happens:
"He moves in mysterious Ways."
You take that--
that overblown press kit
they call the Bible.
You look for
the answer in there,
what do they tell you ?
"Shit happens."
[ Scoffs ]
Please.
He treated you like garbage.
You walked away.
I'm not the bad guy.
What about the End of Days ?
Think of it
as a new beginning.
A change of management.
And you'll be right there
With me on the ground floor.
It Will be
so cool.
Tell me what you want.
Tell me what you really want,
and I'll give it to you.
I'll tell you
what I want.
I want you
to go to hell.
[ Sighs ]
You see, sometimes
the problem is...
[ Neck Bones Cracking ]
- hell...
- [ Gasping, Choking ]
comes to you !
- Don't fuck up the coat.
- [ Groans ]
I've wasted
too much time on this.
You see those insignifiicant
little dots down there ?
Huh ? Do you see them ?
That's what you mean to me.
Now, give me the girl !
[ Gasps ]
Not today.
[ Groans ]
Look down.
Now, look in your heart
and tell me you don't
Want to die.
All you got to do
is take my hand.
[ Grunting ]
And I'll give you back
everything that He took away.
[ Groans ]
- Come on.
- Okay.
[ Panting ]
Okay. Okay. Okay.
[ Grunting ]
Fuck... you !
[ Car Alarm Blaring ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
[ Knocking ]
[ Knocking Continues ]
Hey.
Hey !
- I thought you were dead.
- Couple of seconds,
I would've been.
All i remember is steppin' out
of the van, then I woke up
in the fucking gutter.
What the hell
are you doing here ?
What are you talking about ?
I've been lookin'
for you allnight.
What the hell happened to you ?
- Hey. Hey. Hey.
- I can't trust you.
I don't know how much you had
to drink, okay, but let's not
point the gun at me ?
I just need to know.
You need
to know What ?
That you are you.
Of course I'm me ! what
the hell are you talking about ?
You took his body.
All right.
You're ill.
Okay ?
You need some help.
All right ?
Oh, fuck !
Jesus !
- Fuck.
- You're bleeding.
Ofcourse I'm bleeding !
You fuckin' shot me !
I just needed
to find out !
You found out, okay ?
Stop being such a pussy !
It's just a scratch.
Pussy ? Come on !
Oh, Christ.
Does it hurt ?
What do you think ?
Jesus.
What the hell's
the matter with you ?
What's going on here ?
I can't explain it.
I shouldn't have left
her alone like that.
I should be with her.
[ Bobby ]
Tell me what to do.
I gotta
get back there.
[ Panting ]
Got to get her
as far away
from him as i can.
Okay, We'll leave town.
You get her.
I'll get a Striker car.
Just tell me
Where to meet you.
St.john's Church...
in one hour.
How much longer, Father?
Well, he has to sire his child
between 11:00 and midnight
tomorrow night.
So, We must keep you hidden
until that hour passes.
[ Banging ]
We've come to help.
Your Eminence.
In this hour of darkness,
We need all the help We can get.
How's the girl ?
The girl's fine.
Thanks.
No.
No. Father !
Father, they're the ones
Who tried to kill me !
[ Groaning ]
- No !
- Your Eminence,
what are you doing ?
We cannot allow
this union to takeplace.
No ! No.
Please !
You can't!
You mustn't!
- [Christine] Let go !
- She is only one life.
How many lives are you prepared
to end if we do nothing ?
- That's not who we are.
- Of course it is.
We are doing God's work.
We are preventing
the End of Days.
But you can't prevent evil
by doing evil.
- There is no time !
- No !
- [ Chanting ]
- It's the only way.
- No-o-o !
- [ Screaming ]
- May God forgive us!
- Amen.
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Blade Clattering ]
- [ Groaning ]
- I can do this all day long.
- Now, let her go.
You must let us finish.
lf she is slain,
his hope of creating a kingdom
on Earth dies with her.
- Her death is God's will.
- It's not God's Will.
lt's your will, and it will
lead to our destruction.
Jericho.
She must be removed.
lt's the only way to defeat him.
For a thousand years,
We prepared ourselves for this.
We're not
afraid to die.
Good.
Because I'm
not afraid
to kill you.
Let her go.
[ Rumbling ]
Go. Go.
Get out of here.
[ Kovak ]
Go !
God help us.
We're too late.
- I've come for my wife.
- Let's go.
This is the house
of the Lord, our God,
and you are not welcome here.
I can stand the pain
of being in church.
How much pain can you bear ?
Christine !
Come to me.
I am the one
you've been waiting for.
I am the answer
to your prayers.
In the name of God,
I order you to leave here now !
[ Kovak ]
May the wrath of God destroy--
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Screaming ]
A thousand years
You have waited for my return.
And behold, you have failed.
And with your last breath
You shall bear witness
to the End of Days.
[ Bones Cracking ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Gasps ]
No ! Jericho !
[ Tires Screeching, Horn Blaring ]
- [ TiresScreeching ]
- [ Grunts ]
Get in the car !
Run !
- [ Groans ]
- [ Honking Horn ]
Jesus ! Come on !
Bobby, What the hell
are you doing ?
[ Engine Accelerating ]
What are you doing ?
Open the door !
Open up !
- Come on ! Open up !
- Open the door !
Jer--
Please, stop the car !
Please !
[ Grunts ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Horn Blaring ]
-Jer !
Jer !
[ Jericho Grunting, Groaning ]
You should
have taken my offer.
At least you would have
been happy once in your life.
[ Groans ]
Let her go,
or I'll kill you.
Ooh, so much anger,
so much hatred.
You're almost there.
I'm gonna hurt you so bad,
You're gonna beg to die.
But I'm not gonna let you.
It's not gonna be that easy.
You're mine, and I want you
to see what's gonna happen.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Female Newscaster ]
World religious leaders
have asked their followers...
to prepare
for the new millennium not
with celebrating and partying...
but rather with acts
of kindness, compassion--
[ Male Newscaster ]
This is it, New York. The last
day of the first 2000 years.
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Speaking In Italian ]
[ Crowd Roaring ]
[ Whispering ]
[ Screaming, Groaning ]
- How long have I been out ?
- You almost slept the whole day.
- You're lucky to be alive.
- [ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
The time ?
It's almost 7:00.
It's not too late.
He has the girl.
But it's not too late.
ln nomine Patris,
et Fili, et Spiritus Sancti.
[ Crowd Roaring ]
[ Man ]
jesus, what did you do ?
Get hit by a truck ?
No, the truck missed me.
[ Door Lock Beeping, Buzzing ]
[ Door Buzzes ]
Where the hell
are you goin' ?
Doing my job.
[ Computer Keys Clacking ]
You know,
the cops are after you.
[ Jericho ]
They have to wait.
I've got to do something.
[ Beeping ]
That son of a bitch.
- [ Engine Off ]
- [ Door Opens ]
[ Door Slams ]
[ Cocks Gun ]
[ Gasps ]
Yes.
You wish entrance ?
[ Grunts ]
You have much hatred
and vengeance in your heart.
You may pass.
[ Distant Chanting ]
[ Chanting GrowsLouder ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
[ Loud Chanting ]
Angelus obscurus.
[ Follo Wers ]
[ Priest ]
Princeps finis dierum.
Princeps finisdierum.
[ Chanting Continues ]
You know
this is what you want.
[ Chanting Continues ]
Angelus obscurus.
You can't resist, can you ?
"Cause you don't Want to.
I didn't come here to hurt you.
I came here to love you.
Relax.
Give yourself to me.
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Followers Shouting ]
[ Automatic Weapon Firing ]
- No one move,
or I kill the girl.
- What are you doing ?
- [ Whispers ] Trust me.
- You're not gonna kill her.
You said it your self.
i have a darkheart.
- Then stand With me.
- I'll tell you What.
You let us both out of here,
and i'll stand
wherever you want.
- Step back,
or I'll pull the trigger.
- I didn't want to kill you.
But now you
leave me no choice.
Let her go, Jer.
Oh, don't look at me
like that.
You'd be amazed
what you agree to
when you're on fire.
Don't do it, Bobby.
You're better than this.
- You're better than him.
- You know, considering
how you've lived your life,
when this is all over,
what makes you think you're
going upstairs anyways, huh ?
Come on,Jer.
This is the main event.
It's gonna happen.
- Why shouldn't you have
the best seats in the house ?
- You will never get a shot off,
and you know it.
Don't do it.
Bobby.
I thought we had a deal ?
Well, I guess
the deal's off.
[ Screaming ]
- No !
- [ Screaming Continues ]
You son of a bitch !
- [ Panicked Shouting ]
- [ Muffled Cries ]
Here !
This way !
Up here.
Shit !
- [ Christine Shouts ]
- [ Train Horn Blares ]
[ Wheels Screeching ]
- Oh, thank God.
I thought I hit you.
-just get us out of here !
Let's go.
Give me a minute.
I'd feel better
if you'd show me how
to use one of those things.
- I want to do something.
Let me help.
- All right. Here.
You take the gun. Line up
the sight with your target.
Uh-huh.
Beware of the recoil.
Here's the magazine.
Put it in. Load.
- Only pull the trigger
When you're ready--
- [ Groans ]
Like that ?
Yeah, like that.
He's on the tracks !
Shit !
- Don't stop ! Don't stop !
- What are you doing ?
[ Screams ]
He's gone.
[ Screaming ]
Oh, God.
Go on.
- We must separate the cars.
Separate the cars.
- What ?
-Jericho !
- [ Yelling ]
Jericho !
[ Shouting ]
[ Grunting ]
Jericho !
[ Christine ]
That's it. Come on.
Jericho !
Here. Hold on !
[ Man ]
How can you expect to defeat me
when you are but a man...
and I am forever !
[ Cheering ]
We must lock the doors !
- Deliverus, O Lord.
- [ Jericho ] Everyone, out!
Get them to a safe place!
Get them out of here!
[ Screaming ]
[ Man ]
Lady, come on !
[ LoudBanging ]
[ Banging Stops ]
What are We gonna do ?
Hide. just hide !
No.
Please, God, help me.
Give me strength.
[ Rumbling ]
[ Rumbling Continues ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Growling ]
- [ Snarls ]
- [ Jericho Gasps ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Growling ]
[ Grunting ]
- [ Jericho Grunting ]
- [ Satan Growling ]
[ Cheering, Horns Honking ]
Christine.
Christine ?
Jericho ?
Are you all right ?
[ Panting ]
What happened ?
It's over.
We won.
Let's go.
Huh ?
- What's wrong ?
- Nothing is wrong.
- [ Grunts ]
- Everything is the way
it should be.
No ! Jericho ! No ! No !
No, please !
What are you doing ?
Jericho !
No !
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting, Gasping ]
No ! Stop it !
You died for nothing.
You just bought them time.
Please. You have
to fight him, Jericho.
lknow you.
- You're stronger than he is.
- [ Clothes Tearing ]
That's why you came back for me.
Don't let him win.
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Panting ]
[ Bell Tolls ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Jericho Grunting ]
Run.
- Run.
- [ Gasps ]
[ Grunts ]
- Yah !
- No !
[ Screaming ]
[ Crowd Shouting ]
Six, five, four,
three, two, one!
[ Screaming ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Shrieking ]
[ Amy Whispering ]
Daddy ?
[ Grunts ]
Thank you.
[ Sirens Wailing ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Soprano Vocalizing ]
[ Vocalizing Continues ]
[ Choir Vocalizing ]
[ Soprano Vocalizing ]
[ Boy Chanting ]
Oculus Deum
[ Soprano Vocalizing ]
[ Tubular Bells Ringing ]
[ Heart Beating ]
[ Distorted Shout ]
[ Eerie Chanting ]
[ Rock ]
lt's not how you're thinking
As you've been mine
You been living a dream now
Believe you're a bad jump
Believe you're in favor
And drain out your soul
And what can i do
when there'so many liars
That crawl through your veins
Like millions of spiders
And seek out their victims
And who is the wiser
Watch out
Gotcha
Oh my God
i can't deny this
I've been taught
just to kill and fight this
Don't bury it deeper
where nobody can find it
Like nobody wanted to know
So give it away like
they're not gonna fuck you
How long can you beg them
to come back and haunt you
To run past your demons
and carry you to some place
You're startin'to bleed
And they don't give up
Before it's too late
What will you offer
in ways of healing
Oh, i'm so confused
Confused
Misused
Oh my God
i can't denythis
I've been taught
just to kill and fight this
Don't bury it deeper
where nobody can find it
"Cause nobody wanted to know
Ooh, if it opens your eyes
Well,just bet on
a strong compromise
I was willing
to be lost in the shuffle
lf only you had let me know
Ooh, if it opens your eyes
Well, then just bet
on a little less compromise
I was willing
to be lost in the shadows
lf only you had let me know
And they won't give in 'cause
they know what they're after
I'll give you them days like
it'sall that would matter
And
[ Screaming ]
Oh my God
i can't deny this
I've been trying just
to murderand fight this
Don't buryit deeper
where nobody can findit
Well, nobody wanted to know
Ooh, if it opens your eyes
Well, then you can bet
on a little good compromise
I was willing
to be lost in the shuffle
lf only you hadlet me know
Ooh, when they're done
with the show
Like the tide
out on the ocean
The wave'sal ready
set in motion
The only one in the game
who's lost is you