Legend has it that it was written
by the Dark Ones.
'Necronomicon Ex Mortes'.
Roughly translated,
'Book of the Dead'.
The book served as a passageway
to the evil worlds beyond.
lt was written long ago, -
- when the seas ran red with blood.
This blood was used to ink the book.
ln the year 1300 A.D.
the book disappeared.
EVIL DEAD II
- So, what's this pIace Iike?
- It's a IittIe rundown, but...
- It's right up in the mountains.
- Are you sure it's converted?
I think so.
What do you think, kid?
I Iove it, Ash.
I feeI funny about being here.
What if the owners come home?
- We'II teII them the car broke down.
- With your car, they'd beIieve it.
What about some champagne, baby?
After aII, I'm a man and you're
a woman. At Ieast, the Iast time.
- There's a tape recorder here.
- See what's on it.
This is Professor Raymond Knowby,
log entry number two.
l believe l made a signifiicant find
in the castle of Kandar.
Having journeyed there with my wife,
my daughter and Prof. Gatly, -
- it was in the rear chamber that we
stumbled upon something remarkable.
'Naturum de Monto',
the Book of the Dead.
We brought the book here,
where l could study it undisturbed.
Here l began the translations. The
book speaks of a spiritual presence.
A thing of evil that
roams the forests.
Through recitation of the book,
this spirit is given license -
- to possess the living.
Here are the pronunciations
of those passages.
Kanda. Estrata. Amantos...
Linda?
Linda...
They're gone.
The sun's driven them away.
For now...
Better puII out of here
before nightfaII.
Join us!
Oh, my God!
I gotta get a grip on myseIf here.
Thank you.
Annie!
How did the expedition go?
Great. I found the pages
of the Book of the Dead.
- What condition are they in?
- Take a Iook.
They haven't aged in 3,000 years.
When do we begin transIations?
Tonight. Is it aII set with my father?
I haven't spoken with him in a week.
There's no phone in the cabin.
It'II take an hour to get there.
You hinted that your father was
onto something with his transIation.
- What has he found?
- ProbabIy nothing.
But just possibIy,
the doorway to another worId.
You tricked me.
Yeah, just...
HeIIo, Iover.
Work shed.
Even now we have
your darIing Linda's souI, -
- she suffers in torment.
You're going down.
Chainsaw.
PIease, Ash.
PIease, don't hurt me.
You swore that we'd aIways
be together. I Iove you.
Yes! Your Iove was a Iie.
And now she burns in heII.
I'm fine...
I'm fine.
I don't think so. We just cut up
our girIfriend with a chainsaw.
Does that sound fine?
You bastards!
You dirty bastards!
Give me back my hand.
Give me back my hand!
Excuse me.
Excuse me...
Is this the road to the Knowby cabin?
- That's right. And you ain't going.
- And why not?
There must be another way in.
A road or something.
Sure ain't no road.
Why the heII
do you want to go there?
None of your business.
I just remembered...
There is a traiI.
- You couId foIIow Bobby Joe and me.
- Sounds aII right.
- But it'II cost you.
- How much?
45... A hundred bucks.
TeII you what: You take my bags
and you got a deaI.
Sure!
That's right.
Who's Iaughing now?
Jesus Christ. I thought she was
taIking about them IittIe bags.
Here's your new home.
You son of a...
Gotcha, didn't I, you IittIe sucker?
I'II bIow your butts to Kingdom Come!
See if we don't...
- Hit him!
- You dirty bastard.
- You gonna be aII right, honey?
- I don't know. I think so.
Sit stiII for a minute.
You know this son of a bitch?
- We thought our father wouId be here.
- Where are my parents?
What the heII did you do to them?
Annie, come here! Come here!
Let's throw him in there.
Crazy buck's gone bIood simpIe.
I am...
I made a mistake.
Wait, wait. No!
Damn right, you son of a bitch!
I hope you rot down there.
- Oh, shit!
- Everything's gonna be fine.
I'm gonna go fetch the sheriff
and bring him...
I checked aII the rooms.
Your foIks aren't here.
But these are my father's things.
lt's been a few hours since l
translated the demon passages -
- from the Book of the Dead.
This is my father's voice.
l fear that my wife has become host
to a Kandarian demon.
May God forgive me
for what l have unleashed.
Last night,
Henrietta tried to kill me.
lt's October 1st, 4:33 p.m.
Henrietta is dead.
l couldn't dismember her corpse.
l dragged her downstairs -
- and l buried her.
l buried her in the cellar.
God help me, -
- l buried her in the earthen floor
of the fruit cellar.
- What the heII was that?
- Somebody's with him.
- Let's get the fuck out of here.
- Someone's in my fruit ceIIar.
- Someone with a fresh souI.
- Let me out!
- There's something down here!
- It's a trick.
- Let him out!
- Move it!
- Open up.
- Come to me.
- HeIp!
- Come to sweet Henrietta.
HeIp me, pIease!
I'II swaIIow your souI!
There's something out there.
That witch in the ceIIar
is onIy part of it.
It Iives out in those woods.
In the dark...
Something...
Something that's come back
from the dead.
- Jake, Iet's get out of here!
- We're going, baby...
- Nobody goes untiI dayIight!
- You Iisten to me...
Hush, little baby
don't say a word
Momma's gonna buy you
a mocking bird
If that mocking bird don't sing
Momma will buy you a diamond ring
If that diamond ring turns brass
Momma's gonna buy you
a looking glass
Remember that song, Annie?
I used to sing it to you.
- Mother?
- UnIock these chains. QuickIy.
- No.
- You were born September 2nd, 1962.
I remember it weII
because it was snowing.
So strange it wouId be snowing
in September.
That thing in the ceIIar
is not my mother.
We are the things that were
and shaII be again.
Spirits of the Book.
We want what is yours: Life.
- Dead by dawn.
- Dead by dawn...
Dead by dawn...
Let me out!
Where are you going?
HeIp us, you fucking coward!
Set me free.
We Iive! We Iive stiII!
- That's funny.
- What?
That traiI we came in here on.
It just ain't there no more.
Like the witches swaIIowed her up.
It's so quiet.
What the heII was that?
Maybe something trying
to force its way into our worId.
It's in there.
- We'II aII go in together.
- HeII, no! You're the curious one.
I'II go with you.
Shit! I toId you
there weren't nothing in here.
- HoIy mother of mercy.
- Father?
There is a dark spirit here
that wants to destroy you.
Your saIvation Iies there.
The pages of the Book...
Recite the passages...
DispeI the eviI.
Save my souI...
And your own...
- You're hoIding my hand too tight.
- Baby, I ain't hoIding your hand.
Where's Bobby Joe?
Hey...
Where the heII is she?
- We gotta go out and find her.
- In those woods, forget about her.
What's wrong?
Like something just waIked
over my grave.
That picture, what is that?
In 1300 A.D., they caIIed this man
the 'Hero from the Sky'.
- He was prophesied to destroy eviI.
- He didn't do a very good job.
Can you find it?
Here it is. Two passages.
Recitation of this first passage -
- wiII make this dark spirit
manifest itseIf in the fIesh.
- Why the heII wouId we want that?
- The second passage...
...creates a rift in time and space.
The physicaI manifestation
can be forced back into the rift.
That's the best transIation I can...
That's right...
I'm running the show now.
We're gonna Iook for Bobby Joe,
and then we're getting out of here!
No, you idiot! It wiII kiII us aII.
She's dead. Don't you understand?
With these pages, -
- at Ieast we have a chance.
Bunch of mumbo-jumbo buIIshit!
These pages don't mean squat!
Besides, now you ain't got no choice.
Now move!
Move!
I said 'move'!
You stupid fooI!
I'II bIow your fucking head off!
No traiI.
Where to now?
Bobby Joe!
- Bobby Joe!
- You'II get us aII kiIIed!
- Leave him aIone!
- Get out of here!
Bobby Joe?
Where are you, girI?
You're ours!
No.
I'm sorry.
Get me in the other room. Get the axe.
We'II kiII him when he comes back.
But first,
puII this damn thing out of me!
- I can't breathe. Hurry.
- I'm trying. I'm trying!
Shut up! Shut up!
Check out... beside the window.
Check the windows,
he's probabIy...
HeIp me!
Oh, God!
No, wait!
Listen to me!
I'm aII right now.
That thing is gone.
Dammit! I said I was aII right!
Are you Iistening?
Do you hear what I'm saying?
I'm aII right!
- I'm aII right.
- Okay, maybe you are.
But for how Iong?
If we're gonna beat this thing,
we need those pages.
Then Iet's head into that ceIIar
and carve ourseIves a witch.
Groovy.
Those pages are down there somewhere.
The pages, quick!
Nosferatos, KaIamimnon, Kanda!
Let's go.
SwaIIow your souI,
I'II swaIIow your souI.
Hush little baby
don't say a word
Momma's gonna buy you a...
a mocking bird
I'II swaIIow your souI,
I'II swaIIow your souI...
SwaIIow this.
I onIy compIeted
the first passages!
That was to make the eviI
a thing of the fIesh.
You didn't finish it?
There's stiII the second passage...
- The one to send the eviI back.
- Start reciting it! Now!
Don't Iook, Annie!
Finish the passages! Get rid of it!
Kanda! Amandat!
Nosferatos! Amantos! Akadiv!
- We've won!
- Victory is ours!
Kanda...
You did it, kid. By God...
For God's sake...
How do you stop it?
SIay the beast.
'Tis a deadite.
Run for the castIe!
HaiI he who has come from the skies
to deIiver us from the deadites!
No! No!