[thunder clapping]
[woman whispering]
[Marie whispering]
I WON'T LET ANYONE COME BETWEEN US ANYMORE.
ARE THEY RECORDING?
[panting]
[grunts]
[continues panting]
[foliage rustling]
[groans]
[panting]
[tires screeching]
[brakes squealing]
[engine stalling]
HELP ME!
[moans]
CIGARETTE.
LIGHT.
[Alex sighing]
(Alex)
WE'RE ALMOST AT MY PARENTS' HOUSE, SLEEPYHEAD.
I DON'T BELIEVE THE DREAM I JUST HAD.
I WAS IN A FOREST RUNNING BAREFOOT.
I WAS HURT,
AND I WAS BEING FOLLOWED BY SOMEBODY, AND...
WELL, THE MORE I RAN,
THE MORE I COULD SENSE HIM COMING CLOSER.
WHO WAS THE GUY STALKING YOU?
IT WASN'T A GUY, IT WAS ME.
THAT'S THE WEIRDEST PART.
IT WAS ME RUNNING AFTER ME.
DON'T YOU EVER HAVE NORMAL DREAMS?
NO.
BEING LIKE EVERYONE ELSE IS A BORE.
WE SHOULDN'T HAVE PARTIED SO MUCH.
I FEEL SHITTY.
TAKE A REST.
I'LL WAKE YOU WHEN WE GET THERE.
REAL FUNNY.
I'LL DRIVE IF YOU LIKE.
[scoffing]
LIKE LAST FRIDAY
OH, COME ON,
IT WAS LATE, AND I WAS TIRED.
TIRED? MORE LIKE WASTED.
WELL, IT WAS YOUR FAULT FOR DUMPING ME FOR 3 HOURS
AND DISAPPEARING WITH GOD KNOWS WHO.
[chuckles]
I HOPE AT LEAST, THAT HE WAS WORTH IT.
HE WAS UNBELIEVABLE.
[chuckles]
[in French]
WHAT A SLUT!
ASSHOLE!
BIMBO!
BITCH!
SKANK!
YOU'RE A PIG.
[sighs]
ARE THERE ANY COOL PLACES TO GO OUT HERE IN THE COUNTRY?
I'M AFRAID THE TOWN HALL IS ABOUT THE ONLY PLACE.
WOW, IF I HAD TO LIVE HERE ALL YEAR ROUND,
I THINK I'D SHOOT MYSELF.
WELL, IT'S JUST A DIFFERENT LIFESTYLE.
BESIDES, REMEMBER
WE'RE HERE TO STUDY,
NOT TO PARTY.
[music blaring on stereo]
HEY, WE ARE NOT DEAF, HUH?
(Alex)
CHILL OUT, MARIE.
OH.
[music playing softly]
[music playing loudly]
[both singing in Italian]
(Tom)
COME ON, HENDRIX.
COME ON. COME ON.
I'M GONNA GET YOU.
BOOM, BOOM.
I'LL GET YOU, HENDRIX.
TOM, STOP SHOUTING.
GO INSIDE.
YOU'RE GIVING ME A HEADACHE.
I'M JUST WAITING FOR ALEX TO GET HERE.
SHE'LL BE HERE BY THE TIME YOU TAKE YOUR BATH.
NO, I CAN'T.
ALEX HASN'T SEEN THE COWBOY.
ALL RIGHT,
GO INSIDE, TAKE YOUR BATH,
THEN PUT THE COWBOY SUIT ON AGAIN.
COME ON, HENDRIX.
[Hendrix barking]
COME ON. LET'S GO.
[insects chittering]
[man muttering]
[train horn blaring]
[grunting]
[man moaning]
[engine starting]
[I Believe by Jamie Dunlap playing]
THOUGH I CAN'T SEE YOU FACE TO FACE ?
SOMEDAY I'LL BE WITH YOU, I KNOW
AND I BELIEVE
EYES ON THE ROAD.
YOU'VE STILL GOT SOME SARCASM, YOU KNOW.
AND I BELIEVE
THAT IT'S REALLY GONNA COME TO BE
ARE YOU SURE IT'S THIS WAY?
OF COURSE. JUST UP AHEAD.
YOU TURN RIGHT AT THE CORNFIELD.
OH, LOOK, LOOK.
THERE IT IS. TURN RIGHT.
NOW YOU GO STRAIGHT FOR ABOUT 4 KILOMETERS.
WOW, EASY TO GET LOST.
NOBODY USES THIS ROAD EXCEPT FOR TRACTORS.
4 KILOMETERS OF THIS,
AND IT'S GOODBYE, CAR.
[crickets chirping]
[engine humming]
(Alex)
YOU CAN'T ACT THAT WAY
EVERY TIME A GUY TRIES TO TALK TO YOU.
(Marie)
I DON'T ACT THAT WAY WITH EVERYONE.
COME ON, MARIE,
IT'S ALWAYS THE SAME STORY.
AND YOU KNOW IT.
STOP!
WHAT'S WRONG?
I THINK I SAW SOMEONE.
HEY, THAT'S NOT FUNNY ALEX.
I'M NOT KIDDING.
I SAW SOMEONE IN THE CORNFIELD.
STOP SCREWING AROUND LIKE THAT, WILL YOU?
ALEX, COME BACK, PLEASE.
ALEX!
I BELIEVE
THAT IT'S REALLY GONNA COME
[music stops]
[owl hooting]
[hand brake clicking]
SHIT.
ALEX.
[foliage rustling]
[in French]
IF THIS IS A JOKE,
I'LL MAKE YOU REGRET IT.
ALEX, WHERE ARE YOU?
ALEX?
WHERE ARE YOU?
[in French]
I'LL GET YOU FOR THIS,
DAMN IT!
[owl hooting]
ALEX, CUT IT OUT.
ALEX?
[engine starting]
ALEX!
STOP, BITCH. COME BACK.
[gravel rumbling]
[Italian song playing]
COME BACK!
[Alex laughing]
COME ON, I AM SICK OF YOUR LITTLE GAME.
DAMN YOU.
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
[Alex laughing]
I COULD HAVE LEFT YOU OUT HERE, YOU KNOW.
YEAH, VERY FUNNY.
YOU SCARED THE HELL OUT OF ME.
[laughing]
NO.
GO ON, LAUGH YOUR HEAD OFF.
VERY FUNNY.
(Alex)
MARIE, REMEMBER,
MY FAMILY JUST MOVED HERE 6 MONTHS AGO.
THEIR FRENCH IS WORSE THAN MINE.
HERE WE ARE.
[music stops]
ALL RIGHT.
I SEE WHY YOU PASSED YOUR EXAMS SO EASILY.
YOU SPEND ALL YOUR TIME HERE.
THERE IS NOT TOO MUCH ELSE TO DO EXCEPT STUDY.
THAT'S RIGHT. THE ONLY REAL EXCITEMENT AROUND HERE
IS WHEN A TRAIN RUNS THROUGH.
[panting]
TAKE IT EASY, HENDRIX.
EASY, BOY.
[Hendrix whining]
HI.
HELLO, DAD.
[dog growling]
HOW ARE YOU?
DON'T WORRY, HE DOESN'T BITE.
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ME OR THE DOG?
[laughing]
MARIE, THIS IS MY POP.
POP, MARIE.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
SO NICE TO SEE A PERSON AND NOT JUST A PHOTO OF YOU.
PHOTO?
YOU KNOW, THE ONE I TOOK IN SPAIN.
IT'S ON THE FIREPLACE.
YOU'RE PART OF THE FURNITURE.
AND THIS IS TOM.
HELLO, COWBOY.
AH.
[Alex laughing]
AREN'T YOU HAPPY TO SEE ME?
OF COURSE HE'S HAPPY.
HE INSISTED ON WAITING UP ALL NIGHT FOR YOU.
AND YOUR MOTHER HAS BEEN WORRYING THE WHOLE DAY, OF COURSE.
MOM ALWAYS WORRIES FOR NOTHING.
I THINK SHE LEFT YOU SOMETHING IN THE OVEN.
OH, I TOLD HER SHE DIDN'T HAVE TO DO THAT.
WELL, SHE WASN'T SURE IF YOU WERE GONNA HAVE TIME TO EAT.
OH, MOTHER.
[kissing]
I'LL PUT TOM THUMB TO BED,
AND I'LL SHOW MARIE HER ROOM.
RIGHT. ALL RIGHT, THEN.
I STILL HAVE SOME WORK TO DO.
GOOD NIGHT, GIRLS.
GOOD NIGHT, POP.
GOOD NIGHT, SIR.
SWEET DREAMS.
(Marie)
SO, WHAT WAS THIS PLACE BEFORE?
IT WAS AN OLD FARM THAT MY FATHER RENOVATED.
THERE'RE LOTS OF THEM IN THE AREA.
MOST OF THEM ARE IN RUINS.
IT'S TOO BAD.
THEY'VE LIVED HERE HALF A YEAR NOW.
DID THEY HAVE ANY PROBLEMS WITH NEIGHBORS?
YOU MEAN THE REDNECKS? YEAH.
THEY FIRST THOUGHT MY PARENTS WERE HIPPIES
HERE TO MAKE GOAT CHEESE,
BUT THINGS ARE FINE NOW.
WELL, HERE'S MY ROOM.
MMM-HMM.
YEAH?
OK, FOLLOW ME.
MY PARENTS' ROOM IS ON THE RIGHT.
UH-HUH.
THIS IS TOM'S ROOM.
YOU'RE UPSTAIRS IN THE GUEST ROOM, OK?
I'M JUST GOING TO PUT HIM TO BED.
OK, ALL TUCKED IN.
[muttering]
[Alex shushing]
[kissing]
NIGHTY-NIGHT.
(Mom)
IS THAT YOU, ALEX?
[Alex sighs]
MY MOTHER.
I'LL MEET YOU UPSTAIRS.
(Alex)
HI, MOM.
(Mom)
IS YOUR FRIEND ALL SETTLED IN?
SHOW HER WHERE THE BLANKETS ARE.
OK.
CLEAN TOWELS ARE IN THE CLOSET.
DON'T WORRY.
[Alex and Mom chattering]
[door creaking]
[wind howling]
[creaking]
YOUR VERY OWN BATHROOM,
HUH?
THE HEATER'S ELECTRIC.
DO YOU WANT IT ON?
(Marie)
NO, I CAN DO IT IF I GET COLD.
WELL, THEN WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S LIKE A DOLL'S HOUSE, VERY PRETTY.
[music playing]
[whistling]
(Alex)
THE PROBLEM IS,
HE'S GOT A GIRLFRIEND
HE DOESN'T WANT TO SPLIT UP WITH.
WHY ARE YOU SO INTERESTED, THEN?
SOMEONE WHO'S TAKEN MUST BE WORTH IT.
I'M SKEPTICAL OF SINGLE GUYS.
HERE. FINISHED?
THANKS.
I THINK IT'S TOO EASY TO BE A WOMANIZER
WHEN YOU'RE ALREADY TAKEN.
WELL, COULD BE RIGHT, I GUESS.
[Alex sighs]
[plates clinking]
MAYBE HE DOESN'T EVEN LIKE ME.
WHAT'S HIS GIRLFRIEND LIKE?
SHE'S BRAZILIAN.
THEY'VE BEEN TOGETHER 3 MONTHS.
A BRAZILIAN?
WHAT, IS HE INTO EXOTICISM OR SOMETHING?
WHATEVER. I NEED TO GET A TAN, QUICK.
AND I GOTTA WORK ON MY ASS.
I TELL YOU, THAT GIRL IS BUILT.
IF YOU DO SALSA, I'LL GO WITH YOU.
GO EASY ON THEM, ALL RIGHT?
OR THEY'LL BE UP ALL NIGHT, CHIRPING.
AND YOU, MARIE?
ARE YOU GOING TO FINALLY TAKE THE PLUNGE?
DON'T START WITH THAT.
YOU'RE GONNA END UP ALONE.
I'M NOT A SLUT LIKE YOU.
[scoffing]
YOU'RE SO SCARED.
WELL.
I'M GONNA HAVEA SMOKE OUTSIDE.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
I'M BEAT.
I'M GOING TO BED.
DON'T BE TOO LONG.
I'LL WAKE YOU AT 9:00.
WHAT'S THE GAME PLAN?
I WAS THINKING
INTERNATIONAL LAW TO START.
OK.
GOOD NIGHT, ALEX.
GOOD NIGHT.
HEY, ALEX?
I'M GLAD THAT I FINALLY MET YOUR FAMILY.
[crickets chirping]
[sighs]
COME ON, HENDRIX. LET'S GO.
[foliage rustling]
[owl hooting]
[swing squeaking]
[exhaling]
[keys clinking]
[in French]
GOOD NIGHT, HENDRIX.
[whimpers]
[squeaking]
[crickets chirping]
[wind howling]
[sighs]
[wood creaking]
[Runaway Girl by U. Roy playing]
SO YOU GOT TO REMAIN A LITTLE GIRL YOU KNOW?
JUST ANOTHER GIRL
THAT'S WHAT YOU ARE
YOU ARE JUST ANOTHER GIRL
YOU MAY BE NICE, BUT YOU'RE NOT THAT SMART
I LOVE YOU
AND REMEMBER, YOU'RE JUST ANOTHER GIRL
GIRL
JUST ANOTHER LITTLE GIRL
BUT BABY, YOU'RE STILL MY FIRST
AND ANYWAY YOU'RE RUNNING AWAY
YOU'RE TRYING TO GO
I SAY YOU'RE JUST ANOTHER GIRL
AND THAT YOU'LL REMAIN THE SAME
YEAH
JUST A LITTLE TEENY-WEENY LITTLE GIRL
[moaning]
[panting]
[crickets chirping]
[engine humming]
[bed creaking]
I WANT TO TELL YOU THIS
YOU KNOW WHAT KIND OF WAY
THERE'S ONE THING
[engine revving]
[music playing]
[roaring]
[moaning]
[barking]
[squawking]
[Hendrix barking]
JUST ANOTHER GIRL IS WHAT YOU ARE
[moaning]
JUST ANOTHER GIRL
YOU MAYBE NICE, BUT YOU'RE NOT THAT SMART
I LOVE YOU
AND BUT REMEMBER
YOU'RE JUST ANOTHER GIRL
[Hendrix barking]
GIRL
JUST ANOTHER GIRL
[doorbell rings]
[gasps]
[Hendrix barking]
[doorbell ringing]
(Daniel)
I'M COMING.
[bell rings]
QUIET, HENDRIX.
WHO IS IT?
[Hendrix growling]
[Daniel screaming]
[screaming]
[keys clinking]
[barking]
[growling]
[glass shattering]
[Hendrix snarling]
[panting]
[groaning]
[Daniel shouting]
[objects clanking]
[exclaiming]
[doorknob clicks]
WHAT'S GOING ON, MOMMY?
NOTHING MUCH.
NOW GO TO SLEEP.
BUT WHAT'S THAT NOISE?
TOM, DID YOU HEAR WHAT I SAID?
I TOLD YOU TO GO TO SLEEP.
(Alex's Mom)
DANIEL?
DAN?
[Alex's Mom gasping]
[Alex's Mom retching]
[Mom quivering]
[Alex's Mom screaming]
[muffled screams]
[Alex's Mom panting]
[objects thudding]
[Alex's Mom screaming]
[panting]
[creaking]
[Marie grunting]
[panting]
[quivers]
[blade swishes]
[shoes squeaking]
[man panting]
[man chuckling]
[sniffles]
[creaking]
[gasping]
[crickets chirping]
[gasps]
[shushing]
[Marie quivering]
[Alex screams]
[muffled screaming]
[man grunting]
[shuddering]
[Alex screaming]
[man grunting]
[panting]
[Marie grunting]
[in French]
SHIT, THE T.V. PLUG.
[sighing]
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
[sobbing]
[Marie panting]
[shuddering]
[panting]
[chains rattling]
[muffled screams]
[man grunting]
[Alex screaming]
[panting]
[man grunting]
[chains rattling]
[muffled groans]
[panting]
[footsteps thudding]
[footsteps approaching]
[panting]
[screams]
[gasping]
[muffled gasp]
[body thudding]
[body wriggling]
[man panting]
[man grunting]
[squishing]
[sighs]
[Marie sobbing]
[gasps]
[gasping]
WHY ME?
[gasps]
[gasping]
[sniffling]
[static]
[in French]
OH, SHIT!
[thudding]
[footsteps pattering]
[door shutting]
[panting]
[crickets chirping]
ALEX?
[quivering]
[chains clinking]
[muffled sob]
ALEX!
[sobbing]
HOLD ON.
[groaning]
IT WON'T COME OFF.
[chains clinking]
WAIT.
(Tom)
MOMMY!
MOMMY! MOMMY!
[Alex sobbing]
[panting]
[gun firing]
[sobbing]
[gun fires]
TRY TO CALM DOWN, ALEX.
IF HE WANTED TO KILL YOU, HE'D HAVE ALREADY HAVE DONE IT.
NOW LISTEN TO ME, ALEX.
LISTEN. LISTEN TO ME.
SHH. LISTEN TO ME, FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
TELL ME WHERE I CAN FIND A TELEPHONE.
IN THE KITCHEN
IN THE KITCHEN?
ANSWER ME, ALEX.
LOOK, I NEED YOUR HELP.
I CAN'T DO ANYTHING ALONE.
I NEED YOU. HUH?
I'LL BE BACK.
[Alex sobbing]
I, ALEX. I SWEAR.
HE COULDN'T KNOW IF ANYONE ELSE IS IN THE HOUSE
OK?
[in French]
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
[phone clicks]
[chain clinking]
[muffled screams]
[footsteps thudding]
[screaming]
[Alex sobbing]
[tools rattling]
[swishing]
[man breathing heavily]
[fire crackling]
[owl hooting]
[grunts]
[glass shatters]
[crickets chirping]
[Marie panting]
THE PHONE'S BEEN CUT.
I'M GONNA GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
I PROMISE.
[panting]
[Alex sobbing]
[footsteps approaching]
[shutter closing]
[Marie panting]
[engine starting]
[truck revving]
[radio buzzing]
[French song playing]
[sobbing]
YOU HAVE TO STAY QUIET
[wailing]
YOU MIGHT HAVE A CHANCE TO GET AWAY. COME ON.
[Alex wailing]
ALEX.
[chains rattling]
ALEX,
WE'RE GONNA GET OUT OF THIS,
I PROMISE YOU.
EVEN IF WE HAVE TO FIGHT OUR WAY OUT,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT.
[shushing]
LISTEN, ALEX,
THOSE OTHER GIRLS WERE ALONE,
BUT THERE ARE 2 OF US.
[clinking]
(Marie)
IT'S GONNA WORK. IT'S GOT TO.
[clanging]
[grunts]
[panting]
JUST A LITTLE MORE.
ALEX, I GOT IT OPEN.
[music stops]
[door creaking open]
WE'RE IN A GAS STATION.
THIS COULD BE OUR ONLY SHOT.
THE KNIFE.
IN CASE I DON'T COME BACK.
[meter clicking]
[whirring stops]
[in French]
MISS?
PLEASE CALL THE POLICE.
(man speaking in French)
WHAT?
MISS.
[door opening]
[music playing on radio]
[in French]
HEY, JIMMY.
HOW ARE YOU?
[in French]
GOOD.
ON YOUR OWN TONIGHT?
YEAH, WEEKENDS ARE SLOW.
SO, THY LEFT YOU TO MIND THE STORE?
I GUESS.
(man)
THIS IS THE IDEAL PLACE
TO BRING GIRLS.
DON'T TELL ME IT'S NEVER HAPPENED.
IF I DID, MY BOSS WOULD FIRE ME.
[chuckles]
(man)
COME ON...
THE OLD RICH LADIES THAT DRIVE THROUGH,
DON'T TELL ME THEY NEVER ASK FOR YOUR SERVICES.
AIN'T THAT RIGHT, JIMMY?
YEAH, I GUESS.
[titters]
HOW DO I LOOK?
DO THEY SUIT ME?
YEAH. THEY LOOK GOOD ON YOU.
THEY ARE GOOD PROTECTION?
FROM WHAT?
FROM THE SUN.
YEAH, THEY ARE SUNGLASSES.
THEY'RE GOOD PROTECTION.
HOW MUCH DO I OWE YOU?
ARE YOU TAKING THE GLASSES?
I DON'T THINK SO.
BUT I NEED SOME BOOZE.
CAN YOU GIVE ME A BOTTLE OF J&B?
[keys clinking]
DO YOU HAVE CAMPBELL?
I'M NOT SUPPOSED TO SELL ALCOHOL THIS LATE.
DON'T TELL THE BOSS, OK?
I PROMISE.
[screaming]
[glass shattering]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[music stops]
[rattles]
[panting]
[rattling doorknob]
[latch rattling]
[man speaking in French]
WHAT WERE YOU LOOKING AT JIMMY?
WHAT WERE YOU LOOKING AT?
[panting]
[footsteps approaching]
[door squeaking]
[water running]
[door creaking]
[metal clanking]
[man urinating]
[sighs]
[sniffles]
[toilet flushing]
[water running]
[panting]
[sighing]
[truck engine starting]
[tap squeaking]
[phone ringing]
[in French]
FUCKING COME ON! PICK UP!
COME ON!
(man speaking in French)
STATE POLICE.
[in French]
PLEASE HELP ME.
CALM DOWN.
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
THE SORALS,
THEY HAVE A FARM,
I'M A FRIEND OF THEIR DAUGHTERS.
SOME GUY BROKE IN AND KILLED THEM ALL!
HE'S TAKEN ALEX IN HIS TRUCK GOD KNOWS WHAT HE'LL DO.
HE AXED THE GAS STATION GUY.
THE GAS STATION GUY?
ARE YOU IN A GAS STATION?
WHICH ONE?
HOLD ON I'M LOOKING.
I DON'T KNOW.
I WAS IN HIS TRUCK.
I COULDN'T SEE.
IT'S AN OLD RUSTY TRUCK.
DID YOU GET THE LICENSE PLATE NUMBER?
NO, I WAS INSIDE.
I COULDN'T SEE.
YOU KNOW HOW MANY TRUCKS THERE ARE ON THE ROAD?
IT CAN'T BE FUCKING HARD TO SPOT AN OLD TRUCK
AT THIS TIME OF DAY!
STAY CALM AND SIMPLY TELL WHERE YOU ARE.
THE BASTARD'S GETTING AWAY.
SEND A CAR OR ALEX DOESN'T STAND A CHANCE.
I NEED YOUR LOCATION TO HELP YOU.
IF I BLOW UP
THIS FUCKING PLACE WILL YOU FINALLY SEE IT, ASSHOLE?
KEYS...
[tires screeching]
[New Born by Muse playing]
[sobbing]
LINK IT TO THE WORLD
LINK IT TO YOURSELF
STRETCH IT
LIKE A BIRTH SQUEEZE
THE LOVE FOR WHAT YOU HIDE
FOR BITTERNESS INSIDE
IS GROWING
LIKE THE NEW BORN
WHEN YOU'VE SEEN
SEEN TOO MUCH
[sobbing]
TOO YOUNG
[chuckles]
SOULLESS
IS EVERYWHERE
[chuckling]
[grunting]
HOPELESS TIME TO ROAM
THE DISTANCE TO YOUR HOME
FADES AWAY TO NOWHERE
HOW MUCH ARE YOU WORTH?
YOU CAN'T COME DOWN TO EARTH
YOU'RE SWELLING UP
YOU'RE UNSTOPPABLE
'CAUSE YOU'VE SEEN
SEEN
TOO MUCH
AND TOO YOUNG?
[in French]
WHERE ARE YOU GOING YOU BASTARD?
[bird cawing]
[lock rattling]
[sighing]
[in French]
FUCK.
WHERE DID HE GO?
[thudding]
[chuckles]
[panting]
[thudding]
[metal clanking]
[Marie groans]
[exclaims]
[groaning]
[groans]
[foliage rustling]
[panting]
[breathing heavily]
[thunder rumbling]
[Marie grunting]
[grunts]
[plastic rustling]
[panting]
[thunder rumbling]
[gasps]
[screaming]
[choking]
[gasping]
[Marie gasping]
[in French]
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ALEX?
SHE TURNS YOU ON?
SHE TURNS ME ON, TOO.
SHE TURNS ME ON.
[panting]
[grunting]
[man chuckling]
[groans]
[grunts]
[both grunting]
[Marie panting]
[gasps]
[choking]
[gasping]
[shrieking]
[grunts]
[panting]
[screaming]
[sobbing]
(policeman speaking in French)
ALL LIGHTS ARE OUT.
THE STATION LOOKS CLOSED.
WE'LL TAKE A LOOK ANYWAY.
[in French]
FERNAND, GO AROUND THE BACK.
BE CAREFUL.
[in French]
YES, SIR.
[flies buzzing]
(Fernand speaking in French)
SIR, THE BACKDOOR IS LOCKED WE NEED--
[in French]
CALL THE D.A.
(Fernand)
THIS IS FERNAND.
WE GOT OURSELVES A HOMICIDE.
OH, MY GOD.
[clanging]
[shuddering]
IT'S ME, ALEX. IT'S ME.
[grunts]
[chuckling]
[sobbing]
[sighing]
IT'S ALL OVER.
[both panting]
[chuckling]
[chain rattling]
[birds chirping]
[Marie laughing]
OH!
THERE.
DON'T YOU TOUCH ME!
DON'T YOU TOUCH ME, I SAID!
IT'S ALL OVER.
HE'S DEAD, ALEX.
HE'S DEAD. IT'S OVER.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
HE IS DEAD.
JUST LEAVE ME ALONE!
IT'S OVER, ALEX.
GET OUT!
[Alex sobbing]
ALEX.
GET OUT!
[panting]
IT'S OVER, ALEX.
I KILLED HIM.
ALEX.
PLEASE, COME DOWN.
DON'T COME NEAR ME!
COME ON, ALEX. COME.
IT'S ALL OVER.
NOW HE CAN NEVER DO ANYTHING TO YOU AGAIN.
YOU BITCH, YOU'RE CRAZY.
I'M GONNA TEAR YOU TO SHREDS!
IT'S ME.
IT'S ME, MARIE, YOUR FRIEND.
I'M ON YOUR SIDE.
I KILLED HIM, ALEX.
IT'S FINISHED. HE'S DEAD.
YOU MURDERER,
YOU MURDERED MY FAMILY.
GOD DAMN IT, MY FAMILY!
THERE WAS NOTHING I COULD DO TO SAVE THEM.
THERE WAS JUST YOU.
ALEX.
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE OK FROM NOW ON.
PLEASE, ALEX, TRUST ME.
CALM DOWN.
[grunts]
[screaming]
[in French]
YOU CAN'T ESCAPE FROM ME, BITCH!
[saw whirring]
I'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU, ALEX!
[panting]
I'M GONNA TAKE CARE OF YOU, ALEX.
[grunting]
[tires screeching]
[man panting]
PLEASE!
SHE'S NOT FAR.
COME ON! COME ON!
[in French]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[Alex sobbing]
[engine puttering]
HURRY!
[screaming]
[man groaning]
[Alex screaming]
[in French]
I'LL RIP YOUR HEAD OFF.
[screaming]
[screaming mockingly]
[pants]
Alex.
[groaning]
[saw motor revving]
[groans]
[saw whirring]
[sobbing]
[in French]
YOU'D DRIVE A WOMAN CRAZY.
YOU LITTLE SLUT.
[in French]
YOU'D DRIVE A WOMAN CRAZY.
YOU LITTLE
[sobbing]
DO YOU LOVE ME?
YOU DON'T LOVE ME, DO YOU?
[screams]
YOU DON'T.
[in French]
YES, I DO.
YES, I LOVE YOU.
YES, I DO LOVE YOU.
[Alex sobbing]
[panting]
[gasping]
[sobbing]
[grunting]
NOBODY WILL COME BETWEEN US, EVER,
EVER AGAIN.
I WON'T LET ANYONE COME BETWEEN US ANYMORE.
I WON'T LET ANYONE COME BETWEEN US...
[New Born by Muse playing]
LINK IT TO THE WORLD
LINK IT TO YOURSELF
STRETCH IT
LIKE A BIRTH SQUEEZE
SHE CAN'T SEE ME, RIGHT?
FOR BITTERNESS INSIDE
IS GROWING
LIKE THE NEW BORN
WHEN YOU'VE SEEN
SEEN
TOO MUCH
TOO YOUNG
YOUNG
SOULLESS
IS EVERYWHERE
HOPELESS TIME TO ROAM
THE DISTANCE TO YOUR HOME
FADES AWAY TO NOWHERE
HOW MUCH ARE YOU WORTH
YOU CAN'T COME DOWN TO EARTH
YOU'RE SWELLING UP
YOU'RE UNSTOPPABLE
CAUSE YOU'VE SEEN
SEEN
TOO MUCH
AND TOO YOUNG
YOUNG
SOULLESS
IS EVERYWHERE
DESTROY THE SPINELESS
SHOW ME IT'S REAL
WASTING OUR LAST CHANCE
TO COME AWAY
JUST BREAK A SILENCE
CAUSE I'M DRIFTING AWAY
AWAY FROM YOU
KINGDOM ROCKS!!!!!!!