Translation: Peter Petrelli
www.divxplanet.com
Help!
Eddie!
What the hel....
Eddie, wake up!
Don't move.
Okay, listen to me. Don't lean forward.
-What's going on?
-No!
Hello.
I want to play a game
The devices on your
heads are symbolic
of the shackles you
place upon others
You recklessly
loan people money
knowing their
financial limitations
Counting on
repossessing more than
they could ever pay back
You are predators
Well today, you become the prey
and you will give the amount
of flesh that I demand
This is your fault!
The scale before you is your
only path to freedom
However, only
one of you may pass
and the toll is the
ultimate sacrifice
The sacrifice of flesh
Before you are the
instruments to exact this flesh
Move with haste now,
for when the 60 second timer hits zero
the one who has given
the most flesh will release their bindings
while the gears on your opponent's
head will engage,piercing their skull
Who will offer the most flesh
in order to save their life?
The choice is yours
I will not die because of you, bitch!
Saw VI
Translated by Peter Petrelli
I ask you, Special Agent Strahm
have you learned enough to trust me?
However, if you choose not to
you will never be heard from again.
Your body will never be found.
And my legacy will become yours.
Make your choice.
Hey,baby
Well, listen, I am so,
so sorry.
but I can't make dinner
I have to work late.
I have a meeting with
my lawyer
and this will keep me busy
for the rest of the afternoon.
I know it's your birthday,and I'm going to
make it up to you. I promise.
love you.
-Uh, what were we talking about?
-We're talking about your deposition.
So worried about me, Debbie
Some small-time lawyer trying to squeeze us is not
going to get me to say anything I don't want to say.
I have no doubt about that,
but as lead counsel for this company
if you screw up,
it comes down on my ass,so
what do you say we prep your deposition?
-Oh, Christ.
-Do you remember dealing with a Mr. Harold Abbot?
William, I have a Casey Patterson
on Line One.
Take another message, Addy,
I'll get back to her this week.
Sometime... Keep going
When opposing counsel asks about
Mr. Abbot, how will you respond?
I am going to respond by saying, as Senior
Vice-President of Membership and Claims.
it is my job to review.
every terminated policy
As a matter of fact, Mr. Abbot
was sitting right where you are now
when we discussed his appeal.
I... I just don't get it.
I've been with this insurance
company for over 10 years.
I know, Harold, but unfortunately,
when we reviewed your claim.
we discovered that you failed
to mention a previous condition.
What condition?
There's no condition
It says here you had oral surgery
to remove a cyst from your jaw.
This is absurd!
I have heart disease
It has nothing to do with some oral surgery
- that I had 30 years ago!
- Any type of oral surgery
is going to leave scar tissue
Scar tissue can lead to gum disease
and as you well know,
gum disease can cause heart disease.
.
You know what?
You're-You're a criminal
You are goddamn criminal
I've paid my monthly premium for
10 years without so much as a cold
and now that I'm actually sick,
you're gonna deny my coverage?
- I have a family!
- Those are the rules, Harold!
I'm sorry, but your own
actions have caused this.
You've just given me a death sentence,
I mean, who's gonna cover me now?
You just killed me
I have a family too, so
I can empathize with his argument
But basically, the guy lied
on his application
- Whoa, watch it, Will.
- What?
Do you think he did that on purpose?
It wasn't my job to assess
what his intentions were
It was my job to check
the accuracy of his claim.
Everybody thinks we're the bad guys.
Nobody mentions
the millions of people we help
every year without incident
Or the millions of dollars
we donate to charity every year
Or all the free clinics we support
Short answers, Will.
Short answers.
The assets for one of history's
most notorious serial killers
John Kramer, were distributed
They were mainly in
real estate holdings
but in my time...
One more question:
Who found the error on his application?
The Dog Pen. They work as a team
If there's a discrepancy to be
found on an application,
the six of them will find it.
- Lord, are waiting in the conference room.
- very good.
How is going today people?
I found two errors in the application for a client.
This practice had now been closed for some time.
- Terminator strikes again!
- Be back in a few hours.
Farewell, Hank.
the one who has given the most
flesh will release their bindings
The choice is yours
Yeah
I'm on my way
- What's going on?
- Feds took over the crime scene
They're requesting you ASAP.
Erickson!
I didn't know you ever made
it out from behind the desk.
I make exceptions when fingerprints
are found at a Jigsaw murder scene
Have a look
We also got a right index off the scale.
- Been IDed yet?
- Yeah.
They're Agent Strahm's
When I learned he and Perez
were being targeted by Jigsaw
I should have been more aware,
but I didn't see this coming
-Not from Peter Strahm
-It was a shock to all of us.
Yeah, But...
we've got something
he doesn't know about
Follow me.
Lindsey.
Detective Hoffman
Perez?
It was my call, Detective.
I knew that Jigsaw wasn't working alone
but until I knew for certain
who was helping him
I couldn't guarantee her well-being
So you let me think she was
dead?
Well, I did not know
who I could trust.
What else have you been
keeping from me?
We know that Agent Strahm knew
the 5 people in the real estate scam
The victims in the traps that Erickson found
- How do you know?
- Strahm and I investigated them after the house fire
It was arson.
All five people were accountable
but after our lone witness went
missing,
no charges were ever filed.
Strahm couldn't let them get away
so he put them in a trap in which slaughtering
each other was the only way out
So what are you telling me?
He's a vigilante?
Call him whatever you like.
But he has to be found.
We would like to work
together on this.
You led me to believe that she was dead,
and you want to work with me?
Look, we're offering full disclosure, detective
So from now on, everything
we know, you know
Is that fair?
Detective Hoffman.
How about a quick word?
Pamela Jenkins,
the resident Jigsaw sensation
- Just reporting the facts, detective.
- Is that what you're doing? John Kramer: Conundrums of Carnage
If you'd like to make a statement on the record,
I'd be more than happy to take it.
You're twisting the facts to
make a better story
It's irresponsible
Excuse me. Nice catching on
I know more about John Kramer
than you might think
- Somehow I doubt that
- Kramer left his wife a box in his will
- Did you know that?
- Maybe I did, maybe I didn't
- How do you know it?
- Probate court
It's public record for those
who know where to look.
All right. What do you really want?
Jill Tuck
Help me get to her, and I will
dial down on the sensationalism
Really?
I'll see what I can do
I do not know how I got there.
I just opened my eyes ... e.
He did this to me
Who did this?
Jigsaw.
You didn't cut your own arm off?
I did. I did.
But he made me do it.
And why is that?
Because what Eddie and
I were doing was wrong
We were ruining people's lives.
He wanted us to learn
And did you?
Look at me!
Look at my goddamn arm!
What the fuck am I supposed
to learn from this?! Huh?
Look at my arm!
What am I supposed to
learn from this?!
Look at me!
Hello Gideon!
I'm sure I put here, somewhere.
Look here.
This gives happiness to the family.
We love you more than ourselves son.
If you're watching this Jill
I'm long gone from this world.
I'm leaving you a box today,
and its contents are of grave importance.
Now I'm not at home, but, please,
leave a message.
Sig.na Tucker, are still
Pamela Jenkins.
hoped it would clarify one thing
the relationship with her husband ...
Are you there, detective?
By hearing this tape
some will assume that this is over.
You feel you now have control,don't you?
You think you will walk away untested?
think to be able to get out before he risked his life?
Look here ...
These are the Jigsaw pieces
carved from previous victims
This is the piece taken from
the latest victim
-It looks like all the rest
-Yeah, that's what we said, too.
The skin abrasions, they're indicative of a knife
of a partially serrated edge.
So?
So all the other cuts were made with
a near-perfect blade of surgical quality.
Obviously, Strahm used a different
knife than John Kramer.
Right, but it got us curious,
so we pulled the files to compare
That same knife was used
on only one other victim
That victim was Seth Baxter
The man who killed your sister.
You're telling me that
you can tell a different knife
was used from a photo?
No, but I can
I was the one who examined that body.
I've examined every body of the Jigsaw Killer.
Good work.
The tape from the latest victim was missing,
so we're looking into the Seth Baxter tape.
Why is that?
Well, maybe if a different person cut the piece,
then maybe a different person made the tape, too.
- Strahm?
- Yeah, maybe.
Strahm's voice on the tape
would be our smoking gun.
We have that, we could
go public with his involvement.
Jane , Jane, it's allright , ok?
take it easy
I didn't expect to
see you here so soon.
Change of plans.
The game begins tonight.
Why?
Because somebody knows
about the box that shouldn't.
- Who?
-That's not your concern.
All you need to know is
that:from now on
I control all aspects of the game.
That's not what John wanted.
Give me the envelopes.
That's not a request.
Here.
That all there is?
- Yes
- From now on, I work alone.
I know
I'm only carrying out John's final request.
Well, John's dead.
And his work is almost done
- Who's this?
- Unfinished business.
When I'm done,
we no longer speak.
Methadone is only a masking agent.
It doesn't heal; it just simply numbs the senses
I found a better way.
These people,
they will continue to hurt you,
and let you down.
They're addicts, John.
Recovery is a process.
Maybe addiction is just
a part of human nature.
But what about these people,
Jill, who come here every day
and use you?
They bide their time
They're avoiding prison sentences
They're getting hooked on masking agents,
Do you call that recovery?
- It's not that simple.
- Addiction is not simple! JILL!
WAKE UP!
These people have no respect
for the lives that they're destroying
Once you see death up close,
then you know what the value of life is
the value of life,do you know that?
And that's my way. And I
brought proof that I want you to see.
- Amanda?
- Hello, Jill.
Jill, you once told me that she
was a lost soul
But here she stands
She's clean, and whole.
- And she has new appreciation for her life.
- It works
It's real. He helped me.
Okay, John.
Do you know police , what had you believe?
John Kramer (Jigsaw) has dead.
prorpio last week claimed to have discovered
a new game with terrible implications.
the victims are all connected
the life of John Kramer ...
Jigsaw [killer] that may be dead,
But the murders continue.
Fuck!
Hank, are you still here?
Don't fucking move!
Oh... shit!
O God!
Someone will take care of you.
Where is the key?
And in the left pocket?
Hello, William.
Oh, Jesus--
You've probably been wondering
when we would see each other again.
- Today is that day.
- No!
For years, your probability formula
has decided the fate of others.
The healthy have benefited while
the potentially sick have been unjustly rejected.
However, this formula does not take
into account the human will to live.
When faced with death,
who should live versus who will live
are two entirely separate things.
Today, your policy
will be put to the test
There are four straps around your limbs
and you have four tests you must complete.
For if you don't, the straps on your arms
and legs will detonate
Look closely.
You have 60 minutes to complete
your tests and avoid this fate.
Starting now.
You are not alone in this game,Just as you
have taken loved ones away from their families
if you don't reach the end before the timer hits zero,
you will never see your family again.
Mom?
Mom!
Wake up,Mom!
Mom?
Where are we?
I don't know
- What's that?
- I don't know.
Look ...
Oh, my God!
Here is your first test.
Your health and military background puts
you in the highest category of success.
However, the same cannot be
said for your adversary.
At only 52 years of age, this man has continued to smoke even
though he has a history of high blood pressure and heart disease
This demonstrates his appreciation
of the blessings of his own life
Your game will focus on a simple element.
From there, once this game begins,
every time you take a breath,
the clamps around your chest
will close in and crush your body.
The only way to escape is in the other's failure.
So I ask you, when faced with death,
who will survive?
Live or die, William.
Make your choice.
- Fuck you!!
- Who the hell is that?!
Hold your breath!
Fuck you!
Jesus Christ!
Come on! Come on!
Shit
Please help us!
Please!
Help!
Someone help us!
Please!
Help!
anybody!
"Live" ?  "Die" ?
What the fuck?
Connected to that thing.
- HF , What is that?
- Hydrofluoric acid.
This substance can corrode the flesh
in seconds.
- What do we do?
- I do not know.
you want live , dont you?
What about the timer?
Must mean something.
I have no idea. I do not know
why we are here.
We are here because of your father.
- Ms. Jenkins
- Please, this will only take a second
We can help each other.
What makes you think you can
come to my door like this?
Because I found something
you'll want to see
Go on.
Where did you get this?
It was at the location where John died.
Does it mean anything to you?
No.
Goodbye, Ms. Jenkins.
If you think of anything.
I want to thank you for
sponsoring this party, William,
And I know how much the clinic appreciates it.
John Kramer.
William Easton. Kramer.
You're Jill's husband, right?
- I am.
- Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Sounds like we're in
a similar business, John.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
Well, you try to predict people's behavior.
So do I.
People count on us for coverage,
and we have to analyze each person
for the probability of success.
- How do you do that?
- Well, it's a formula.
It's pretty complicated, actually,
but in essence
it breaks down to monthly payments
multiplied by lifespan,
minus the probability of illness,
and if its sum is positive,
we consider coverage.
- Who devised that formula?
- Me.
So, in a sense...
you choose who lives or dies?
No, I, uh... No, I'd say I decide
which people have the potential
to live long, healthy lives.
But you're not taking into onsideration
the most important human element of all.
Which is what?
The will to live.
Until a person is faced with death,
it's impossible to tell
whether the have what it takes to survive.
Fuck that!
Shit!
Hello, William.
Standing on the platforms behind me
are two of your colleagues.
One is your file clerk:
A healthy man with no relatives or relations.
The other, a middle-aged woman
with a family history of diabetes.
According to your policy, your secretary is older
and weaker and,therefore, less worthy to survive.
But you know the loss that
she will be to her family,
while young Allen will disappear
without a blip on the world's radar.
Only one can exit this room,
and the choice of whom falls upon you.
You must let go of the one to
save the life of the other.
As you can see, the choice is not so clear
when you're face-to-face with
the people whose blood will stain your hands.
Let the game begin.
Wait! Wait!
No! I won't do it! I won't do this!
I won't do this!
Help me!!
It's a business!
No! I'm not going to do it!
I'm not going to do it!
-Stop it!!
-Help me...please..
S..Stop it...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry...
Thank you. Thank you!
You try and find a way out of here, Addy.
I have to keep going. Be careful.
Why not throw acid on the bars
iron corrode?
With what they threw it on the bars?
With your hands?
What are you looking at?
Thought ...
Look at that mirror.
What?
Somebody's watching from behind the glass.
What do you want?
Why are you doing this?
Somebody help me, please.
Please help me.
Hello, Pamela.
You've sensationalized my life,
twisting the truth
and exploiting my message
for your benefit
Hoffman.
It's Erickson.
We found the Seth Baxter tape.
Yeah?
But there was something else
we wanted to discuss with you.
- What's that?
- Better to talk about it in person.
- It's, uh, time sensitive.
- I'll be right there.
The device Timothy is strapped
to is my personal favorite.
I call it The Rack.
Last-minute tweaks?
Told you he'd fuck with it.
If you switch the gear ratio,
you have to change the gear
grease to match the increased friction.
Maybe you should stick to the heavy lifting.
You will need this [gun] .
Check with me next time.
How many next times are there gonna be?
However many there needs to be.
That's a human being.
Do you like how brutality feels, Mark?
Let's be honest.
You want him to suffer
just as much as I do.
- So when's your test, detective?
- I don't need one.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Because I don't take life for granted.
You're still dragging
your knuckles on the ground.
What do you know about life?
Get used to me,
cause I'm not going anywhere.
You sure about that?
Time is short.
You okay?
Now it's time to get
Dr. Denlon from the hospital.
Ok.
I'll take you back.
Go.
I'll be quick.
- Why'd you come here?
- John.
Please, stop.
- Don't do this.
- I promise you
when all this is done
I will provide a way out for you.
don't you that, time was now.
I have something for you.
What is it?
You will discover that in it's time ...
you know , what to do.
final decision.
I came to talk to you, Will,because
I've found a treatment for my cancer
that I think holds a lot of promise,
but my requests for coverage
have all been turned down.
So I was hoping that maybe
if I came and explained it to you,
that you might be able to get
that overturned for me.
Well, the buck starts here,
John,Fire away.
This is a doctor in Norway
He's got a 30-40%
success rate with gene therapy
He injects what he calls suicide genes
into cancerous tumor cells,
then any inactive form of a toxic
drug is administered and it...
Yes, I'm familiar with the therapy
you're talking about.
Right.
And a new trial's starting.
He's looking for new patients,
-and he seems to think that I'm the perfect candidate.
-John,
if your primary physician, Dr. Gordon,
thought you were a suitable candidate,
he would have pursued it.
Dr. Gordon is a specialist, you know.
He's making money on his specialty.
He's not a thinker,I mean, the man has his hand on
the doorknob half the time that I'm there..
I'm going to be straight with you.
At your age, and with
the development of your cancer,
it's simply not feasible for your--
Wait, wait, wait.
What's unfeasible?
By whose mathematical
equation is this not feasible?
It's policy, John.
It's policy.
And if you go outside the system to seek out
this treatment, which has been deemed ineffective,
you will be in breach of policy
and dropped from coverage completely.
I'm sorry.
Did you know that in the Far East,
people pay their doctors when they're healthy.
When they're sick,
they don't have to pay.
So basically,they end up
paying for what they want,
not what they don't want.
We've got it all ass-backwards, here.
These politicians, they say the same thing,
over and over and over again.
Healthcare decisions should be made
by doctors and their patients,
not by the government.
Oh, now I know they're not made by doctors
and their patients or the government.
They're made by the fuckin' insurance companies.
Piranha.
John...
please. If you do this,
then you'll be on your own
and the subsequent cost to
you will be staggering.
Don't talk to me about money.
I have money.
This is about principle.
You see, Will...
this is my life
we're talkin' about.
You remember?
What about Jill's life?
How's she going to be taken care of when you're gone?
You let me worry about Jill.
The type of cancer you have
is malignant and inoperable.
That rolled off your tongue real smooth.
Even if the treatment works,
the cancer will return eventually.
It's an unwinnable battle.
That was even smoother.
As a matter of fact,
that was downright slick.
You think it's the living that will
have ultimate judgement over you,
because the dead will
have no claim over your soul.
but you may be mistaken.
Hello, William
You have seen the flaws in your policy.
But what you have not seen is the extents
only fools will go to when faced with death.
-The lawyer from your firm
-Debbie!
has 90 seconds to cross this room
or the device attached to her chest
will discharge and pierce her brain.
It's going to be okay!
You're going to be okay!
She will find that the journey across
this room is filled with danger.
In order for her to make it,
you will need to be there for her
as it is you who ultimately
holds the key to her survival.
When faced with death,
will she have the skills to live?
Let the game begin.
Okay, listen!
-What the fuck is this?  Get me the fuck out of here!
-Listen to me! Debbie! Hey!
Okay, you're gonna get through
this maze as fast as you can
Go. Go! Now!
Come on! You can make it!
You have to keep moving.
Will, this is madness.
Go ... Come on,
you can do it to get out of here!
Wait a minute,
I think I can help here.
We must work concomitantly!
We must work concomitantly to succeed!
- Are you ready?
- Yes!
Go!
Keep moving, do not stop!
Come on!  , Go! Go! Go!
I can not! It's a fucking trap!
There is no way out.
It's a fucking trap.
I can not get out!
No!
No, there is a ladder at the end!
If you get there, be able to help.
Are you ready?
Go!
Come on!
You're almost there.
Go! Go! Go!
Search for a key, there should be a key.
Come on!
- What are you waiting for?
- It is inside you.
- What?
- Is within you!
Shit.
Ok.
Or wait ... Wait what are you doing?
I can take it!
God, no!
Hello, Pamela.
Well, today, you will experience
the meaning of sacrifice and you
will see the consequence for those
who unjustly hurt others.
Fuck you!
Someone's there.
They're watching us.
Why?
Why would someone do this?
Thanks for coming.
What'd you find?
- An abnormality with Strahm's fingerprints
- What?
Take a look
See, the human fingerprint leaves an oily residue
Depending on how long it's been
exposed to the elements
it's highly susceptible to contamination.
So what's the problem?
Well, we found trace amounts of Halomethane R-12.
She means Freon
Production of R-12 ceased in 1994, so the question is,
was the contaminant we found at the sight already,
or did Strahm bring it to the facility with him?
We controllamo inside the 'edifício
before it was abandoned.
Did anything come off of the Seth Baxter tape?
Uh, yeah, actually.
We might be on to something.
The tape was in pretty rough shape when
we found it, but we were able to authenticate it.
The voice was intentionally distorted,
but it didn't match John Kramer's.
It's currently being analyzed.
-Through what?
-Well, we're trying to descramble the tape
to find the original voice.
He's on with the tech now.
You timing something?
Your watch.
Oh, I was before I got your call.
We got it.
This is our smoking gun.
The lab's off-site. Come on.
You're coming, right?
Of course.
Hey! Who's in there?
- Sr. Easton, was you?
- Ms. Shelby?
Who's in there with you?
We are all here, sir, all 6.
What the hell is going on?
What to see?
Nothing at all, it's dark.
- What is that sound?
- I do not know, but we are bound to something.
- turns.
- Take us out of here!
Please
Get us out of here.
Help,
Sr. Easton, help us.
Sr. Easton, please.
Help us get out of here.
Mr. Easton, what is this?
It's a game.
game?
What the hell are you talking about?
Hello, William.
Before you are six of your most valuable associates.
The ones who find errors on policies.
Their findings result in over two-thirds of all applications
denied or prematurely terminated.
Now you must apply your "analysis" to them
and be able to find their errors.
Six ride the carousel,
but only two can get off.
The decision of which two will survive
falls upon you,
but remember: the mounted gun will continue
to fire until all six rounds are spent.
And if no decision is made on your part,
all six will perish.
To offer the two reprieves, you must press
both buttons at once in the box before you.
However, in doing so,
you will give a sacrifice of your own.
Two can live. Four will die.
Your decision is symbolized
by the blood on your hands.
Wake up!
You've got to get us out of here!
Listen to me!
I am the one who should live.
Fuck!
Jesus!
Please! Mr. Easton!
Please! Follow policy, Mr. Easton!
Follow the policy! Please!
Do it!
Please!
Follow the policy, Mr. Easton!
Mr. E!
You always said we're only
as strong as the weakest link!
-I'm the strongest! You can't let me die!
-Fuck you!
I'm healthy! I'm healthy!
I have two kids!
You know them, Will!
Please, they can't get on without me!
They need me!
-Thanks....thank you...
I do not even know Mr. Easton.
My parents are sick! They need me! I'm all they have!
-You fucking liar! Your parents hate you! They cut you off!
-What?! That's not true!
I'm pregnant! I'm pregnant!
No she's not! She's lying!
-She's fucking lying! Mr. Easton, she's lying!
-No,I'm not!
Please! Please! Push the thing!
Seriously!
-I'm pregnant!
-She's fucking lying!
No! , no! , no!
Oh, please! Forget that!
Mr. Easton! My parents are loaded!
They'll give you whatever you want!
But if you do not see them for years!
Dave!
Fuck you!
Christ! Mr. Easton, come on!
Mr. Easton, please.
Okay, listen to me, Mr. Easton!
Mr. Easton! I'm on your side
and I can help you.
-You cannot trust this bitch!
-What?!
She is all lies! You cannot believe her! She has
already lied and she's going to continue to do it!
-You know it! Trust me!
-What about you?!
It's me, Josh.
Help me!
Fuck!
-Oh, well that's it, isn't it?!
It's over!
-You motherfucker!
-Stop it...
You spineless, pussy-whipped
MOTHERFUCKER!
That's all it takes, huh?!
Bitch says one thing and its all over!
You know what, William?!
Your policy is
BULLSHIT!
Fucking bullshit!
Will you listen to me, you son of a bitch?!
I did everything for you.
Look at me!
When you're killing me, you look at me!
Oh My god...
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
This is the same helplessness
you bestowed onto others.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
How's it going?
Good.
This is it.
Whoever made this tape had access to
some very impressive audio filtration equipment.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
Fortunately, we have some tricks of our own, here.
I can turn his algorithm upside-down and let us
hear what he really sounds like.
Let's hear what you got.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
-You okay?
-Huh?
You seem a little... preoccupied.
I'm just anxious about the tape.
You know, there are still a couple of things
I can't quite wrap my head around.
Like, I don't understand Strahm's motivation.
He was my partner for 5 years.
I mean,
we all knew he was a bit of a hothead,
but I never saw any indication of psychotic behavior.
You can't really tell when
someone's so good on the inside.
...helpless.
Hear that?
I'm getting there.
Come on. I thought you had something to show us.
It's just I never really
thought of him being vengeful.
You know. I mean,
all the facts are there.
Something doesn't sit right.
Listen. It's getting closer.
You know, there is an alternative.
Let's say that, Strahm killed Seth Baxter specifically
to set you up as an accomplice to Jigsaw.
...Okay.
Well, there's a problem with that, though.
On further analysis of Strahm's fingerprints,
it was found that the uric acid levels
were inconsistent for an individual with
an active epidural metabolism.
In other words?
In other words, when you left
his fingerprints on the latest victim,
Strahm was already dead by then!
There it is.
Right now, you are feeling helpless.
Who else knows about me?
Who knows about me?
Everyone!
You lie.
You're a fucking liar...
Because I found something you'll want to see
It was at the location where John died.
Does it mean anything to you?
What are you doing?
I'm trying to finish this
as soon as possible.
We do not know what will happen.
Do not just sit here doing nothing.
We must make a decision,
Don't you understand?
Ok.
You can pull it.
I love you.
I love you,too.
Departed.
No. I do not know what will happen.
At the three draft.
No. No.
One ...
Two ...
Three!
What the fuck?
This thing not working!
This thing does not work...
What the fuck?
I think I know what it is used.
Get used to me, 'cause I'm not going anywhere.
You sure about that?
Amanda will fail you.
We'll see
Amanda, you were with Cecil
the night Jill lost Gideon.
I can't fucking do... I don't want to get--
What do you mean you don't want to--
Run, fucking pussy! Go! Go! Go!
Cecil? What're you doing!
You killed their child.
You know it, and I know it.
So do exactly as I say:
kill Lynn Denlon,
or I will tell John what you did.
She doesn't deserve to go free!
Amanda, Lynn is more important than you know.
-I did it. I made it.I made it!
I've done it!!
-If you fail, you will never see your family again.
- What are you doing here?
- Will!
Pamela.
Yes
I know it's your birthday, and I'm going to
make it up to you. I promise.
You're really standing up your sister for work?
I'm your only family.
Are you okay?
Let her go!
I made it! I won!
Shit, I followed your fucking rules.
Now let it go.
You son a bitch.
You've just given me a death sentence,
I mean, who's gonna cover me now?
You just killed me.
You're the man who killed my dad.
Hello, Tara.
My apologies for exposing you
and your son to this kind of treatment,
but I can assure you it is not without reason.
The man before you just made the
sacrifices to save the life of a loved one.
However, when given the opportunity
to save your husband's life,
he chose not to.
Now, you will be given the power
to save a life.
Will you grant this man
the opportunity to continue living,
or will you dispense the same death
sentence he issued your husband?
Live or die.
The choice is yours.
It's not my game.
I'm leaving you a box, today
and its contents are of grave importance
Ms. Tuck, what's in the box?
Please. Forgive me.
Please!
Have mercy, please!
Did he show mercy
When my husband was suffering?
John left you 5 envelopes.
The sixth one was for me.
This is John's will.
- He had no choice!
- He always had a choice!
Please, no.
The only reason I'm doing this is not because
I can't forgive you for what you did to me.
The reason I'm doing this is because
I couldn't forgive myself for
what you might do to someone else.
Please, no.
- You'll never kill again.
- Please. Please. Please don't.
I can't...
I can't kill him.
I can.
No, Brent!
You killed my father, you motherfucker!
Now you burn in hell!
Those are the rules, Harold!
You've just given me a death sentence.
So, in a sense...
you choose who lives or dies?
It's policy, John. It's policy.
Who devised that formula?
You think it's the living
that will have ultimate judgement over you,
because the dead will have
no claim over your soul.
But you may be mistaken.
Game over.
No! No!
So when's your test, detective?
I don't need one.
Oh, yeah?
You know why you're here, don't you?
I want to know if you have
what it takes to survive.
You feel you now have control, don't you?
You think you will walk away untested?
I'm only carrying out John's final requests.
Do you like how brutality feels, Mark?
From now on,
I control all aspects of the game.
That's not what John wanted.
You want a chance?
I'll give you a chance.
Translation: Peter Petrelli