[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
GIRL: I need a drink.
BOY 1: Here you go.
BOY 2: Okay, all right.
Katie Cumming?
Shaved.
BOY 3: Very bad.
Nice.
What about Molly Simmons?
Trimmed neatly.
BOY 3: I like it.
I like that.
Holly fucking Dwyer?
Full bush,
with a little treasure trail.
Fucking treasure
turn pike.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Fucking treasure freeway
with a car pool lane.
Oh!
BOY 3: Here we go.
BOY 4: Yes.
Who invited you freaks?
So he walks up to her,
he goes, "Open the vagina."
BOY 3: Come on.
I never said that.
No, no wait.
She slaps
the shit out of him,
and so he says,
"Open the vagina, please."
Sarah Voizon?
Shaved.
[GUN CLICKS]
Timmerman's sister?
Dude, she's seven.
Timmerman's mom?
Buckwheat in
a scissor lock.
Janie Smith?
[GUN FIRES]
Trimmed.
You study for
that history exam?
No.
BOY 4: Dude, that scared
the shit out of me.
[GUN FIRES]
MAYBEL: I can't see.
I can't see.
[PHONE RINGS]
Popular kids, from what
we're getting upstairs.
Jocks.
Football or basketball?
Football.
They had
a game tomorrow.
Nobody heard
the gun shots?
They had music
cranked up pretty good.
Who found them?
Pizza guy.
Pizza guy?
They ordered pizza?
Two.
Pizza guy strolled in
at 11:05.
So they commit suicide
en masse,
the night
before the big game
and they ordered pizza.
En masse?
My vocabulary
is expanding.
Must be the literature.
Here's what
I think happened.
Junior got a hold of
papa's gun,
started to have a friendly
game of Russian roulette.
Things just
got out of hand.
First kid commits suicide,
blows his brains out.
That'd bring the game to a
screeching halt, don't you think?
[GUN FIRES]
Can you feel it?
But all the elements
are there.
BOY 3: Trimmed.
Then why can't we
feel it?
The project takes time.
But everyone else
feels it.
I feel it.
Liar.
Seriously.
There, the way
he tilts his head.
No. It's in his eyes.
RITA: Bedtime, boys.
Five more minutes.
OWEN: You heard
your mother.
BOY 4: That scared
the shit out of me.
[GUN FIRES]
SETH: Well,
maybe next time.
I didn't feel it.
I know.
Trial and error, that's the
nature of the project.
It's the genius
of the project.
Exactly.
Goodnight.
[MUSIC BOX WINDING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Mmm.
Now I got to run.
Booked all morning.
You'll be home
in time for dinner?
Word of honor.
Do you know how
much I love you?
This much?
Not even close.
FATHER ZINSELMEYER:
It is with great regret
that I've summoned you
here today.
The loss of these
four fine young men
has come as an abrupt
and unexpected shock.
They were friends,
scholars, athletes.
But above all,
they were the embodiment
of the phrase,
"Men for others."
Let us pray.
"Our father, who art in heaven.
Hallowed be thy name.
"Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done."
[EXHALES]
Detective Lampkin.
Sorry to have
kept you waiting.
Good book?
Yes, well,
it does have its moments.
Poetics?
You mind if I...
Of course,
for as long as you like.
Please.
Well, so far,
most of the guests
at the party
don't remember
a goddamn thing.
I was wondering if I could
open it up a little bit.
Interview some friends,
girlfriends,
that sort of thing.
They were
very popular boys.
I always wondered
what that was like.
You heard anything?
Just a lot of
teenage gossip.
That they were
in a suicide club.
Some sort of
satanic ritual, drugs.
Were they on drugs?
One of them tested positive
for weed and that's about it.
Who?
Yes, well, I just hope
that you can help us
understand why they
would kill themselves.
If, in fact,
they did kill themselves.
What are you saying?
That someone...
Suicide and homicide.
One can be made
to resemble the other.
Hmm.
My uncle has diabetes.
He never takes care of it, though.
He's always losing toes.
I'm new.
What's your excuse?
Reactive hypoglycemia.
I'm Eve.
Jonah.
Jonah, I'm looking for
room 408A.
I had no trouble
finding 401 through 407.
It's in the Dorsey Annex.
And where might that be?
Far from here.
You know, you strike me as a
New Testament kind of guy.
Are you familiar with The
Parable of the Good Samaritan?
Luke 10,
verses 30 to 37.
Great.
Let's pretend that you are
the Good Samaritan
and I'm on
the side of the road.
Show me a little mercy,
it's my first day.
All right, follow me.
[STUDENTS CHATTERING]
[BELL RINGS]
TEACHER: Pencils down.
They didn't even ask about
the Great Western Schism.
So, should we focus
on the next project?
Who?
The one who
made you late.
No.
We should stick
to the program.
Lay low for
a while and then...
Feed the birds?
Yeah. Feed the birds.
All right, Vargo.
Back to class.
Ms. Dunn.
Ms. Dunn, I know this must
be real difficult for you.
Lots of people.
Lots of people what?
You're gonna ask me the same thing
that you've asked everybody else.
Do I know anybody who
would wanna hurt those boys?
I know lots of people.
They're jerks.
Including Derek?
Especially Derek.
How long did
you two date?
I saw them
kill a dog once.
Derek and his friends?
A chow chow.
They look like lions,
don't they?
They do that
to your arm, too?
No, I was in a movie once.
[MOANING]
[SCREAMS]
They like making movies.
Who likes making movies?
Were they at the party?
Even if they were,
nobody would remember them.
Twins with the camera. How do
you forget something like that?
[PIANO PLAYING]
Jonah Trimble?
Seth.
Good enough. Let's say we
talk for a little while?
Is this seat taken?
Gum?
It's not allowed.
[CHUCKLES]
That's a keeper.
It's a shame what happened
to them boys, ain't it?
Friends of yours?
We don't have any friends.
You know
Elvis had a twin?
I didn't.
Brother was stillborn.
Elvis was the first,
then came the dead one.
You imagine that?
Two Elvises.
Wow.
What do you want?
So my real name
is Kristen,
but if you ever call me that,
I'll have to kill you.
I'm from Salem.
Massachusetts?
Oregon.
Vancouver before that.
British Columbia?
Washington.
Before that, Hollywood.
California?
Florida.
My mom relocates a lot.
For work?
For love.
I mean
she thinks it's love.
It looks like love on paper,
but it never really works out.
I'm just trying to
make sense of this tragedy.
Maybe you should see
one of the grief counselors.
Maybe you should.
I'm not
experiencing any grief.
Really?
Not even...
What's it called when you
question God and what not?
Existential.
Right.
Not even that.
That a crime?
Not in this state.
Good. So I guess
we're through.
Now, withholding evidence,
that's a crime.
We've known each other
ever since we were eight.
She was the only other kid
on my block, besides me,
who knew the words
to American Pie.
Where?
Kansas City.
Missouri?
Kansas.
[LAUGHS]
Now, neighbor lady says
she saw twin boys,
about your age,
head into the party,
with the video
camera rolling.
Now what I can't
figure out
is how come none of the guests
recall you being there.
When you're not
popular in high school,
you might as well
be invisible.
So you were there.
Never said I wasn't.
But we left before
anything happened.
I think we gonna have to let the
video camera speak for itself.
Oh!
I'm sorry but
there is no video.
I mean, there would have been,
but my brother, dumbass,
forgot to put the memory
card in the camera.
Seems like a real
simple mistake
for boys with such high
SAT scores, don't it?
I'm gonna have to
talk to your parents.
They're out of town.
Where?
They're in Aspen.
Your brother says Vail.
My brother
wouldn't say that.
Why not?
Because they're
in Aspen.
My God.
It is uncanny.
How far apart?
Ninety-three seconds.
You're the older one,
I bet, right?
Younger.
Taller by
a few inches, though.
Shorter by less than one.
What can you tell me
about the video camera?
Your brother says
that you, dumbass,
forgot to load the memory
card in the camera.
There you have it.
Don't get mad at me.
I'm just repeating what he said.
I'm not mad.
No?
You're the sensitive one.
Gum?
I'm diabetic.
Not so funny
second time around.
JONAH: Dumbass?
Cops dig the vernacular.
Puts them at ease.
How considerate of you.
Come on. You know what
they're trying to do.
He was smart
to keep us apart.
Just lucky.
Lying about the neighbor,
that was kind of clever.
Are you worried?
Not at all.
We covered our tracks.
He's fishing.
Yeah.
But somebody
told him something.
So let's find out who.
[GASPS]
What in God's name
are you two doing here?
You said you had
an open door policy.
It's after 8:00. How the
hell did you get in here?
You said if anyone had a
problem they can come to you.
Anytime, 24/7.
Not now. No...
I thought I saw...
Rats?
You're more likely to find
those among the student body.
What are you
talking about?
Who ratted us out, Frank?
How dare you?
In Africa, they get to be
the size of small dogs.
Is that why you left?
I'm gonna have you little
bastards expelled, you hear me?
Now get out.
Out!
You were just hitting your
stride as a missionary.
Why'd you leave?
I got...
I got sick.
With what?
[STUTTERS]
Dracu...
Dracunculus.
The Guinea worm.
I find parasites much more
interesting than rats.
Did you know we spent a whole week
on parasites in biology class?
The Guinea worm
is our favorite.
By far.
Infection can be caused by
drinking contaminated water.
The worm matures in the host's
body, growing up to six feet long.
After about a year, it
migrates towards the surface.
In 90% of the cases...
The worm will emerge
from the leg or the foot.
The worm needs to be rolled
out onto a small stick.
Caution must be
exercised during removal,
Frank.
If it breaks...
What happens
if it breaks?
Crippled.
Right, you can lose a leg.
Or worse.
[GROANS]
Now back to my
original question, Frank.
Who ratted us out?
I can't hear you.
Katie.
Really?
Guess we didn't make enough
of an impression on her.
Please, please.
No.
Looks like you'll have to
dig it out yourself.
Dig out? No!
I found this
in the contraband drawer.
[SCREAMING]
[SIREN WAILING]
[CAMERA CLICKING]
He cut an artery.
Bled out in minutes.
You get a shot of this?
Maybe he was trying
to get to the phone.
Maybe he was trying to
tell us something else.
[CAMERA CLICKING]
LARRY:
How you doing, Lampkin?
Larry, I want you to
be the first to know,
this is my last
pack of cigarettes.
Yeah, I heard
that one before.
Oh, man.
Seriously, my wife says
she's gonna divorce me
if I don't quit.
Figure I'm gonna have
two on the ride home,
park a block away,
have one in the car
and two on the porch.
Shit, maybe three.
How many that make?
Fuck 'em all but nine.
Come again.
We used to say that
back in Nam.
Six for pallbearers.
Two for the road guards.
One to count cadence.
Fuck 'em all but nine.
Maybel?
Maybel!
MAYBEL: I can't see.
I can't see.
WOMAN:
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Welcome to pain management for
the new millennium, Detective.
Distract the mind from
what's happening to the body.
Send you on a little trip,
while we scrub you down.
[PANTING]
SETH:
We need to escalate.
JONAH: Haven't we done
enough lately?
They're just trying to make
sense out of this tragedy.
We need to talk about Katie.
No.
Morning, Katie.
She's a loose end.
The quicker we
take care of her,
the quicker we can
get back to the project.
I think we should
take a break for a while.
Why? What about
feeding the birds?
EVE: Holy shit.
I can tell the difference.
You can?
You have a scar
by your eye.
And you have a squiggly
thing on your iris.
I do?
It's kind of cool.
I'm Seth.
Eve.
Nice to meet you, Eve.
You know, Jonah and I have been
working on this little project.
Seth.
What kind of project?
It's a movie.
You wanna be in it?
No.
Sure.
I mean, how do we
even know she can act?
Audition me.
Sounds pretty
reasonable to me.
Don't we have
someone else in mind?
Do we?
Yes. We do.
I want her.
Good, let's have her.
No, just me.
All to yourself?
Yes.
You wouldn't know
what to do with her.
I know what not
to do with her.
I've learned
from our mistakes.
[MAN INSTRUCTS IN SPANISH]
[KATIE REPEATS IN SPANISH]
MAN: Katie.
Katie.
Daddy?
Yes, Katie, it's me.
How's my little angel?
Daddy, I miss you so much.
I miss you, too.
How's my little girl?
[SOBBING]
It's okay.
I know about
the abortion.
How you can't
have children.
I'm so sorry.
Sweetheart, do you
know where I am?
Heaven.
Would you like to
be with me?
Yes, I would.
I wanna see you.
[MAN BREATHING HEAVILY]
Daddy?
[BREATHING CONTINUES]
[KATIE SCREAMING]
Katie?
Stay the fuck away from me.
Put the glass down.
[LAUGHING]
No!
HARDESTY:
Another suicide.
LAMPKIN:
And you believe that?
This time, we got
a bunch of witnesses.
Including our boys?
Trimble, Jonah and Seth, they
were sitting right there.
What makes you think
they're witnesses?
What's your point?
My point is maybe they had
something to do with it.
[SCOFFS] Well,
your point is moot.
Moot?
I'm expanding
my vocabulary.
Books?
Books on tape.
Look, Detective,
I got 15 witnesses
says those boys never
laid a finger on her.
Maybe they didn't have to.
SETH: She's as same
as the others.
JONAH: No. She's better.
I feel it.
Liar.
Maybe it's your blood sugar.
I'll make you a sandwich.
I'm not hungry.
LAMPKIN: Where's Jonah?
I don't know.
Not your
brother's keeper, huh?
You know the game
Hacky Sack?
Me and my buddies used
to play it in college.
I remember this one time we were
playing and this feeling came over me.
Sadness.
Found out my father
died that day.
While you were
playing Hacky Sack?
I've been reading up the last
couple of nights about twins.
And a lot of people say that
twins have a special connection.
Started to think you and your
brother have a special connection.
Like you and your wife?
My wife?
What were you doing when she died?
Playing canasta?
Don't talk about my wife.
Were you
freaked out?
Not really.
What about
the blood?
There wasn't
that much blood.
You know what I mean.
Someone offs themselves in front
of you, there's an effect, right?
There's supposed to be.
I've been to five schools in three
years and I can honestly say,
I've never met
anyone like you.
Really?
LAMPKIN:
Well, well, well.
I need to borrow your
boyfriend for a minute.
I'm not her boyfriend.
She didn't seem to
mind the label much.
Seth, on the other hand,
did not look happy
because he felt
left out.
God with the football team
this year?
God was always
with our football team.
Not so much
the water polo team.
I was never much
into sports myself.
Too much like you.
Too damn sensitive.
Your interrogation
technique sucks.
See that's not you talking.
That's Seth.
Seth must have
really gotten to you.
He said some hurtful
things about my wife.
I lost control.
Hell, I think
any man would.
I think you
would have stood up
for somebody
that you care about.
She met your parents yet?
No.
Think it's about time
I did.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
OWEN:
May I help you?
Oh. Excuse me. I...
[MUSIC PLAYING SOFTLY]
I knocked loud, twice, and
no one came to the door.
I'm Detective Lampkin.
Detective Lampkin.
Our sons told us about you.
I'm sure they did.
Nice home.
You know, my mama,
she used to...
She used to work as a housekeeper
in a beautiful home.
Like this.
How long you've
been living here?
Oh, this house has been in
my family for many years.
You mind if I...
No.
You know, I couldn't
afford this place
with my salary
and my pension.
What kind of square footage
are you looking at?
About 4,000.
You know,
my house right here,
I'm standing
in my kitchenette,
and I take two steps, little
steps, I'm in the alley way.
[CHUCKLES]
Sounds claustrophobic.
Like a jail cell.
Where are your boys?
Upstairs.
I am sure that they have informed
you about the recent tragedies.
We're still in shock.
I'm advising
all the parents
to communicate
with their children.
Help us sort out
this mess.
We did and we have.
We have great communication
with our boys.
They mention the video?
Unfortunately there is no
video, Detective Lampkin.
I wish there had been.
Perhaps it could have helped
you make sense of things.
They ever talked to you
about their gift?
I should hope they have
more than one gift.
Gift I'm referring to is
less conventional.
I'm not sure
I'm following you.
How was Aspen?
I don't see what
this has to do with it.
We stayed at
a little bed and breakfast.
Which one?
I'm sure you've
never heard of it.
Try me.
Elsa's Landing.
Honeymoon suite.
RITA: Do you know it?
We even brought back
a little souvenir.
Right over there.
My wife and I
used to go there.
OWEN: It's lovely,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Anything else, Detective?
No.
Thank you for your time.
Ma'am.
RITA: Oh, and Detective.
You lay a hand on
one of my boys again
and you can kiss that little pension
of yours goodbye, understood?
Yes, ma'am.
[EVE HUMMING]
You're on work study?
I just needed
to get away.
The police asked me
about you.
I know.
Should I be worried?
Maybe.
[LAUGHS]
Do you play?
No.
Here.
[EVE SINGING]
That's good.
Good job.
Yeah?
So where do you live?
Santa Maria, by Dunham.
Fancy.
Do you want to
hang out there?
I'm not allowed to
have guests over.
Then we'll go
to my house.
MAYBEL: I can't see.
I can't see.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SETH: Excuse me,
so sorry to bother you.
Can you help us out?
We are kind of
stranded here.
Uh...
I...
I just parked my wheels
right over there.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Thought I was seeing double
back there for a second.
I guess you guys get that a lot, huh?
Twin jokes?
Less than you think.
[LAUGHING]
So, Kirby, do you?
What?
You know,
feed the birds.
Did I say
my name was Kirby?
Uh-huh.
This isn't the way
to Grandma's house.
Yeah, we blew past that
like three miles ago.
Don't worry.
I know a way.
You ever hold a little
bird in your hand?
It's so light.
Deceptively light.
It's an aerodynamic thing,
I guess.
Well, boys at your age
are like little birds.
I guess you realize I do at the
carnival, but you pick one up...
[THUMPING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Mother?
KIRBY: Mother?
It's okay.
Mother.
Kirby, help.
[KIRBY SOBBING]
Mommy.
Mom!
Here it comes.
Hey!
LAMPKIN:
Why did you get in the car?
We needed a ride.
LAMPKIN:
You needed a ride where?
The mall.
We told him to stop
but he just kept going.
Jonah grabbed the wheel
and the car started swerving.
JONAH: Then I pulled
the emergency brake.
And the rest
is on video. Why?
Evidence.
Figured we could show it to
the police when we got away.
We didn't see the truck
coming until it was too late.
The driver says, he's been
taking that same route
every Saturday morning
for the last five years.
Company log says
he ain't lying.
Neither are we.
I think you knew
that truck was coming.
I think you tricked that man
into giving you a ride.
And I think you used your
unique talents to kill him.
Oh, right, you think we
have these weird powers.
You know, my dad called
his lawyer last night.
Not because you hit me.
It's no big deal.
You were upset.
It was just to see
what our rights are.
He says what you're
doing is harassment.
This is not Salem.
It's what he said.
Wormwood wants you.
What the hell are
you doing in there?
Interviewing suspects.
We have our suspect,
right here.
Kirby LeFleur.
Busted in '91
for indecent exposure.
Graduated to criminal
misconduct with a minor in '94.
Did a seven-year stretch
for accosting a child.
As far as I'm concerned,
those kids were abducted
by a sexual predator
who should have invested
in a AAA membership.
That's what they
want you to think.
They can get inside of people's heads.
I've seen them.
Did I bring you back
too soon?
Let them go, Detective.
This isn't Salem.
This time he deserved it.
He's a goddamn pedophile.
Then why didn't it
make a difference?
Why didn't we feel
a fucking thing?
It's the nature of the project,
all right? Trial and error.
It's the genius
of the project.
It's just not working.
Come on. You know we have
it in us, all right.
Remember when we were little
before the babysitter?
I think that part
of us is broken.
Why?
I'm done wasting my time.
It's her, isn't it?
No.
You can't
abandon the project.
I just did.
He just doesn't get it.
I can't do this.
Do what?
The project.
We're not the same anymore.
I'm not making any sense.
No, it's okay.
You're just upset.
I'm glad you called me.
Hi, honey.
Hi.
Who's your friend?
Jonah Trimble.
Hi, Jonah Trimble.
I'm Brenda.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.
EVE: Okay, Mom.
All right, honey,
I'm gonna go lay down.
I'm sorry about my mom.
She's much more interesting
when she's sober.
I liked her.
Not too much,
I hope.
No.
I bet you have
the perfect parents.
I used to think so
as a kid.
What does
your dad do?
He was a doctor.
What does he do now?
He's a doctor.
You said "was."
I wasn't. I was just...
I don't wear thongs.
I mean, I know most girls do but
I don't like the way they feel.
Do you know, one time,
a boy broke up with me
just because I didn't wear one.
Can you believe that?
I bet you wear boxers.
Ask me another question.
I didn't ask you anything.
On a boat.
What?
My first time was on a boat.
On the Lake of Ozarks.
You know where that is?
Ask me another question.
I can't think of any.
Some football player,
some jerk.
What was it like?
It hurt.
Here.
That's what
I like to listen to.
How old were you?
Fourteen.
Listen.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON EARPHONES]
It's beautiful.
What's wrong?
I should go home.
You're not into me?
No. I am.
It's just I...
Wanna take things slow?
Yeah.
You're weird.
I know.
I'll see you later?
Here.
So I can tell you apart.
I know you feel it
with her.
Of course not.
It's why you don't need
the project anymore.
I need some protein.
Maybe I should go see her.
Stay away from her.
Nice ring.
OWEN: What's going on
up there?
Nothing.
MAYBEL: Hold me.
I can't see.
LAMPKIN: Linda,
I need to go back there.
I don't see any fresh
burns on you, Detective.
Anyway, we're done
for today.
Please, I just need
to escape.
I'm sorry it's just...
My wife and I
used to go here.
Yeah.
[LAUGHING]
RITA:
Happy birthday, Jonah.
Happy birthday,
you two!
RITA: Happy birthday,
my two sweet boys.
[LAUGHING]
OWEN: That's the way, boys.
Good job.
It's about a girl,
isn't it?
At your age,
it's always about a girl.
Or God.
I don't believe
in God.
You were always
my favorite.
Really?
Is she beautiful?
Yeah.
I used to be beautiful, too.
You still are.
You're the most beautiful
mother in the entire world.
Having twins,
it ruined me.
See the stretch marks?
I'm sorry.
Touch it.
It's okay.
You sucked
the life out of me.
Oh, look,
the babysitter.
She's so beautiful.
Remember the babysitter?
[CRUNCHING]
Things really seem
to be falling apart.
Yes.
It's strange.
Time for your shot.
[HAMMERING]
Dr. Elder?
Dr. Elder is dead.
I'm Detective Lampkin.
I'm Dr. Houska.
We used to be partners.
Well, they came
here to get pregnant.
That's what we do.
Or it's what we did.
How does that work? Drug?
Well, it depends on the patient.
Depends on the couple.
I'm asking about
the Trimbles.
Can I see your credentials
again, please, Detective?
About that time,
isn't it?
Excuse me?
I don't mean to compare you
with the local street addict
but a jones is a jones,
ain't it though?
Listen, I have a consultation
I have to make.
So please. Hey! Hey!
Get your hands...
I'm not asking you to compromise
your high ethical standards.
Just allow me to
compromise mine, okay?
All right, Detective,
you're on your own.
What happened?
You went to instant shock because
you've been eating like shit.
Come on, time for school.
[BOY SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[ALL CHUCKLING]
[CONTINUES IN SPANISH]
Sorry about last night.
Catholic guilt?
I fell asleep.
Me, too. I was out like a light.
Why did you leave again?
What?
You could have
stayed the night.
My mom's cool.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
What's wrong?
I never do that.
I mean, I try to get
to know the guy first.
Listen, if some of
the stuff that I said...
I hope I didn't
scare you away.
I haven't been scared
since I was little.
[SCHOOL BELL RINGS]
I take it you're pissed.
Fuck you! Why?
To keep you in your place.
Shut up!
We're the same!
Jonah!
Couldn't tell the difference,
you fucking idiot!
[SCREAMING]
Well, I'll be damned.
MAN 1 ON TV: ...color of television and
radio as well as stereo recording.
This fabulous home entertainment
center will be yours
if The Price Is Right,
priced authority.
MAN 2: Thank you, Don.
And thank you, ladies.
Mr. Ritner, we begin with you.
Minimum is 50. You may start anywhere.
Oh, my God.
[SCREAMING]
RITA: Did Seth do that?
No. I did it.
Owen.
Does it hurt?
Now they'll be
able to tell us apart.
MAN 2: ...Fifty,
that's the minimum. $1500.
Mr. Ritner, you're picking
up where you left off.
Thank you. Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm your favorite right?
Sweetie, I love you
both just the same.
No. No.
You said I was your favorite.
Did I?
I can't remember.
He says we're just the same,
but I'm not like him, right?
We're all special
in God's eyes.
I've got the scar.
Sweetie, it's just
a tiny little scar.
He fucked my girl!
Poor thing.
His heart's broken.
Son.
It'll all come out
in the wash.
What kind of parents
are you?
LAMPKIN: Good question.
It's okay, Jonah.
It's gonna be okay.
You're not like him.
Mommy. Make him leave.
Mommy's not too
talkative right now.
Especially when
Seth's not around.
Where is he?
I don't know.
It's harder to do when
he's not around, isn't it?
Get out.
It's harder to pull the wool
over your own eyes.
Daddy?
Make him leave.
I see what's happening.
You know what's happening,
Jonah?
I remember now.
It started
with the babysitter.
[CRUNCHING]
Open your eyes.
What is this?
I did this to protect us.
Excuse me.
I had knocked loud twice,
but no one answered so...
I'm Detective Lampkin.
Nice home.
You killed them?
No.
I'm sorry.
[SOBBING]
Listen.
They're ruling
this as suicide.
[WHISPERS]
We know differently.
They killed her.
We just need to
keep them apart.
[THUDDING]
[WHISPERS]
It's just the house.
I'm scared of them.
They wouldn't hurt us.
Then why are we
whispering?
Do you remember
how badly we wanted a child?
How we prayed?
I went to those doctors...
It's not our fault.
It's my fault.
I let them put
those drugs in me.
We just need to
keep them apart.
Do you know
how much I love you?
This much?
Not even close.
[KNIVES SLICING]
This much?
I can make things right, now.
Trust me. I can protect us.
Like the way
I always have.
No. It needs to end.
Right now.
I don't need you anymore.
What are you doing?
Stop!
Stop it!
You fucking need me.
You need me.
[GUN FIRES]
Get away from him.
Wow.
Where was that enthusiasm
last night?
'Cause I thought I was fucking a glass
of water but, hey, I'm willing...
[GUN FIRES]
Please get up.
Seth.
Get up.
Stay away!
[COUGHING]
[SCREAMING]
This is your fault!
You fucking whore.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
I'm gonna make you watch.
[COUGHING]
EVE: Help!
I can't see.
Can you feel it?
Yeah.
Finally.
[SIGHS]
It's beautiful.
I'm scared.
Me, too.
[SNIFFLING]