[HARD ROCK MUSIC]
[ELECTRICAL BUZZING]
[BUZZING]
[MUSIC VOLUME LOWERS]
Police are sure only
of the following:
He is male and savagely powerful.
In almost all cases he has
battered his way to his victims
through locked doors,
and he is so intelligent
he has managed not only to allude
police for these nine months,
but escape identification
of any kind.
And now it has happened again.
In the early hours of this morning,
the killer struck once more.
Again killing an entire family,
again escaping without being seen.
And this city's descent into
frustration and terror deepens.
[TV CHANNEL CHANGES]
Jonathan?
Schneider caught five touchdowns
against Dallas last night.
What are you watching this crud for?
Where's my Coke?
I haven't had a good night's sleep
in over a month because of that creep.
If you don't like the news, Doreen,
change the channel.
I hope you don't play football
like you live your life.
- Hey, Jon.
- Get a job, Carson.
Go. Hut!
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
GO, go'
I'm very good.
Way to go, Jonathan.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Keep looking at the girls, Romeo.
- You're making me look good.
-It was a lucky shot, Rhino.
What the hell has happened
to your concentration, Jonathan?
Are you staying in training,
or what?
Huh?
Or are you sneaking
out at night?
Training, Coach, I swear to God.
You know, you could be one
for the record books, Jonathan.
You come up the hard way,
you got great talent,
but I don't know if
you got greatness.
In order for you to be great, you gotta be
able to concentrate your will to greatness.
Otherwise when you look
the other way,
someone's gonna come up
and help cream your ass!
Like that poor young lady sitting over
there in the stands with no shirt on.
You see?
That's what I'm talking about.
It won't happen again, Coach.
I promise.
Now get the hell on back to the huddle.
Get back to the huddle, let's move it!
Looks like you've been
up all night screwing, boy.
No, man, I just haven't been
able to sleep, that's all.
You get more ass than a toilet seat.
Don't lie to your man Rhino.
Just do me a favor.
Shut up and fix your laces
before you kill yourself.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
Go. Come on!
Sorry, Rhino.
Where there's a will there's a way.
[CLANG]
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Are you okay?
- Instant karma.
- Karma? I got hit by a karma?
[LAUGHTER]
That's more like it, Jonathan.
That's concentration.
That's using your will
and your head.
Oh, you look like shit, incidentally.
Come on, get up.
Take it in for the rest of the day.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
You okay?
No problem.
All right. You guys,
back to the huddle.
You could have a
mild concussion, Jonathan.
Do you wanna see the doctor?
No, I'm okay, Pac Man.
I'm all right.
[SHOUTING]
[CLATTER]
Oh, God.
Christ.
- Hey, are you okay?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Are you sure you're okay?
- I'm all right. Go ahead. Seriously.
Are you sure you're okay?
- Do I know you?
- Alison. Alison Clement?
I sit next to you in chemistry.
We've been going out
on and off for a year.
You once told me you
wanted me to bare your children.
- Did you?
- Did I what?
Did you bare my children?
I mean, maybe we--
We haven't had children yet.
We haven't even slept together.
That's good. I wanna be
respected as a person first.
That's good.
Come on, I'll walk you home.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
- Straight to bed with you.
- Now we're talking.
You're crazy, you know that?
What?
Something...
[SCREAMING]
Jonathan, where are we?
I was raised on this street.
My family still lives here.
That's their house right there.
Who's working on a
TV at this hour?
[NATIONAL ANTHEM
PLAYING IN DISTANCE]
[WIND BLOWING]
Alison, I don't think you should-
Bobby?
No!
[SCREAMING]
Jonathan, help us!
You get away from her.
What are you doing here, dipshit?
- Do you wanna watch?
- Jonathan, do something!
Shut up, bitch!
Do you wanna watch?
Watch this.
- Get him out of here!
- Diane!
Come on!
[THUNDER CRASHING]
No!
Jonathan, are you okay?
Where am I? What happened?
Remember, you ran into the goal post?
You whacked your head.
- What are you doing here?
- I stayed. I was worried about you.
Are you sure you're okay?
You seem different.
Something's different.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello.
Hello, Lt. Parker. Hold on.
It's your father.
Don.
Don, is the family all right?
Jonathan?
Okay, I'm gonna need
another ambulance here.
It's gonna be okay.
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[SIRENS IN DISTANCE]
You don't wanna go in there.
I mean it.
Jonathan, hold off. Don't.
Just listen to your dad.
Bobby?
Hey, guys, come on, let's go.
Let's make this snappy.
Sally and Mom?
They're all gone. I tried to tell you,
there's nothing you can do here.
Hey, get that reporter out of there.
Get her out.
Come on, we got a
gurney coming in.
Donnie, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
She was the best.
- Lt. Parker?
- I knew this was gonna happen.
Lt. Parker, with the killer now murdering
your own family, will this intensify
phantom-like devastator of families
struck again late last night.
This time, killing the wife
and two foster children
of the detective leading
the search for the killer.
Local college football star
Jonathan Parker, seen here
was also a foster child
raised by the couple.
After being found beaten and near
death when he was just 7 years old.
Well, for a while this
rainy afternoon,
the city took time to
mourn its latest loss
as the close friends of
Lt. Donald Parker and Jonathan Parker
gathered with them
to lay their loved ones to rest.
As yet, Parker and his police have still
not so much as identified the killer
who has claimed seven families to date.
Almost 30 souls.
And left an entire city
afraid to sleep.
Who is this man?
What motivates him?
And more importantly-
Oh, God! Change the channel.
[HARD ROCK PLAYING ON TV]
Can't go anywhere without
hearing about the son of a bitch.
Hi, Jonathan. What'll you have?
- Jack Daniel's on the rocks.
- I'll have a Coke, please.
I guess you're wondering
why I called you here?
Yeah, I guess I am.
I dreamt of the murders, Don.
Just the way they happened.
Things like this happen,
people get bad dreams.
I've had a few of my own lately.
Don, no, I dreamt of it
the night it happened.
Before you called me.
I saw what happened
in the house.
You don't know
what happened in that house.
You don't wanna know.
Bobby was killed in
the living room.
The flashlight was
laying right next to him.
The fingers on his right
hand were broken.
These three.
Diane and Sally got it up in Sally's room.
- What is this shit?
- That's how it was, isn't it?
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
This is so crazy.
I knew it was more
than a dream, Don.
It was so real.
I could smell the blood.
I know what this guy looks like.
I even know he has a limp.
Just because I'm your father doesn't
mean I have to listen to this crap.
Don, just hold on a second.
Hey, what the hell's with you?
Are you on drugs, or what?
Did you find tracks of a van
in front of the house?
How'd you know that?
I saw it, Don. I saw him.
I saw his van.
I saw his name on the van.
I bet I can take you to
where he works.
All right, you tell me,
I'll check it out.
No, I'm in on this. I'm there.
That way or no way.
That's against procedure,
you know it.
Yeah. Well, fuck procedure, Don.
Do you want this guy or not?
I didn't even know
this place was here.
This is it.
This is it?
- Mike, come here.
- I can feel him.
This is screwball beyond belief.
It's just like the dream.
- You two go around back.
- Okay.
- What's all the lights inside?
- Televisions.
[KNOCKING]
Look at them all.
Look, if I get a chance, we'll come back
when the place is open. Okay?
He's in there.
Break it.
Now, wait a minute.
We don't have a warrant.
This is breaking and entering,
you know that.
The place has already
been broken into.
We're investigating
an apparent burglary here.
Right. You're right.
This is all because
he had a dream?
[DOOR BREAKS OPEN]
I thought you said he was here?
I thought he was.
Keep dreaming, Lieutenant.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[EERY MUSIC TONE]
Don?
- Wasn't one of your guys just here?
- How the hell should I know?
Sarge?
He was just there.
Jesus Christ.
Call for backup.
Call for backup!
[CLATTER]
Parker gonna keep us
here all night, or what?
Really. I could use a cold one.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[SIGHS]
Judas.
You scared the crap out of me, Sarge.
Did you find anything?
[SCREAMING]
[LAUGHTER]
[TRAIN ENGINE]
- I can find him again.
- You stay out of this!
This is my business,
police business!
And this fucker just
killed four of my men!
You think you can mess
with a guy like that?
You get the hell home
and let me deal with this!
[LOUD MACHINERY]
Good morning, Maryville.
Although the sun
has finally come out today
it doesn't help for a city
afraid to unlock its windows.
Last night, a man thought to be
the long sought after slasher
was surrounded by police, only to
escape in a burst of new killings
that left four officers dead
and a police department in shock.
His name is Horace Pinker.
- A virtual phantom until yesterday
- Dammit!
He was described for this police drawing
through a most unusual means.
According to the police report
Jonathan Parker, foster son of Maryville
Police Department's Lt. Donald Parker
dreamed of the killer.
A junior at Mid Western Tech, Jonathan
apparently was able to find
Pinker's name in a local phone book
after recalling it from a dream
he had the night of the murders.
Now, strange as it-
[GROANING]
Twenty.
[CHAIR VIBRATING]
Jonathan?
Aren't you forgetting
your 9:00 practice?
No. No, no, no.
I'm going.
I'm QOWQ-
Where the hell's my
philosophy book?
It's under your jacket.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
I'm just worried about this exam.
Your dad's gonna catch him
now that he knows who he is.
He's never seen him, Alison.
Only I have.
I almost forgot.
Happy birthday.
Jonathan, in the middle of all this
I can't believe you'd even remember.
It's beautiful.
Thanks for sticking around.
You'll be late.
. Are you okay?
- I'm haPPY-
Go. I'll see you at practice.
- Bye.
Jonathan Parker,
I love you so much.
[DOOR CLOSING]
[DREADFUL MUSIC]
Suggest a man with
a shaven head.
The storm continues to
remain in the area.
Last night, pouring three inches
of rain in outlying districts
accompanied by high winds.
In local news, Maryville's college
football hero, Jonathan Parker
has pledged to play in
Saturday's game
despite his harrowing brush last
night with the Maryville Slasher
now known by name
as Horace Pinker.
A man who apparently, from evidence
uncovered in a hidden room in his TV shop
practiced black magic and
animal sacrifice.
Police Lt. Donald Parker described the place
as a "Hell hole filled with evil instruments
strange symbols,
and hundreds of mummified cats."
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
He apparently struck again
early this morning
killing a family of five in
their sleep.
In this, the latest work of what is thought,
because of distinctive patterns
police refuse to make public,
to be the Family Slasher.
[RADIO TURNS OFF]
Although Pinker was thought to have
escaped a police dragnet and left the city
recent evidence suggests he
has mysteriously doubled back--
[TV sl-luTs OFF]
Please, God, keep him safe.
[SCREAMING]
Red 18!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
All right!
That's more like it. Okay.
Take five!
- You guys seen Alison?
- No!
Hey, Jonathan.
Come here.
- You better go home, son.
- Why's that?
You better go home.
[INDISTINCT POLICE CHATTER]
Jonathan.
Who let him in here?
Uh, kid, uh...
Jonathan, you don't wanna
go in there.
Go outside and see if
you can find his dad.
Somebody go get him!
Right this way. In there, sir.
[GASPING]
Come on. You don't want to see this.
What the hell did you
let him in there for?
For Christ's sake!
Baby.
I'll love you forever.
[EULOGY BEING READ IN DISTANCE]
- When our Lord takes us
all to be with Him.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
And now, may Alison Clement
rest in peace.
Do you know what to do?
Yeah. I think you're tripping
but I know what to do.
Good. Fasten your seat belt.
[DISTANT SCREAMING]
[CLATTER]
- Don't leave me hanging.
- Son of a bitch!
No!
[SCREAMING]
- No, help us!
- Pinker!
How you doing, Horace?
Why don't you let her go?
Come take me on!
You wanna play,
you little piss-ant?
For God's sake, do something!
Do you wanna play
in this game, boy?
Huh?
Rhino?
[GROANING]
- Rhino?
- Rhino.
[SCREAMING]
You got it, asshole!
Rhino!
Yo, yo!
- Shit!
- I do it right?
You did it perfect,
Rhino. Perfect.
Maddalena and Wagner.
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
[TIRES SQUEELING]
[BRAKES SCREECHING]
Yeah. This looks like the place.
I think.
You swear this
ain't a put on, right?
[POLICE SIRENS APPROACHING]
All right. Hold it. Don't move.
You heard what he said.
- Lieutenant?
- Yeah?
Evening, Jonny.
- What are you doing here?
- My job. What are you doing here?
[SCREAMING]
- It's coming from upstairs.
- Keep these two guys here!
- Back it up, boys.
- Let's go, move it!
No!
[SCREAMING]
Freeze!
You bastard.
I'll blow your head off.
Go ahead! Take your best shot!
She won't mind!
I see you had to bring
Daddy along, huh?
Hey, you boys hungry down there?
Huh, you hungry?
Well, eat this!
- Jonathan!
- Come on.
No!
[LADDER CLATTERS]
- There he is.
- Yeah.
All right, back down.
Cover the other building.
All right, let's go.
[POLICE SHOUTING]
Jonathan, forget it, man.
Oh, Jesus!
[DOOR CLANGING]
[GLASS BREAKING]
Come on!
[SCREAMING]
Drop it!
Drop it! God damn it, I mean it!
On the ground!
[KNIFE CLANGS ON GROUND]
All right. Cuff him and
get him out of here.
Go ahead, man, shoot me.
And by the way, boy,
she died real hard, you know?
Your girlfriend?
[LAUGHTER]
I'll see you dead,
you son of a bitch!
You like killing, too, squirt?
It's in the blood.
- You and me, we're killers.
- You'll die, you motherfucker!
I'll see you die! You fucker!
You're breaking my fucking heart!
[LAUGHTER]
Easy now. You want him gone,
let the State do it for you.
He'll fry for sure. He's history.
I wanna be there.
What?
If they give him the chair,
I wanna be there.
Don't be crazy.
It's over. Now let it go.
I wanna see him die, Don.
I've earned it. I wanna see him die.
Yeah, maybe we've both earned it.
I'll get box seats.
[HARD ROCK MUSIC]
[MUSIC FADES]
[DOOR SLAMS SHUT]
Where is he?
Choking on his
last meal, I hope.
Do you know what
his last wish was?
TV set in his cell.
Can you believe that?
He must like his soaps, huh?
All right, my son, it's time to-
[ELECTRICAL BUZZING SOUND]
Pinker!
You all right?
Stay away from the bars!
Get up!
Come on, give it to me!
[STATIC SOUND]
You got it, baby.
[SCREAMING]
Get those cables off him.
What the hell was that in the air?
Did you see it?
Smoke, I guess.
Must have fried his fucking brains.
Asshole.
Put him down here.
God damn this!
God damn this blasphemy!
[TV SPARKING LOUDLY]
You better do mouth-to-mouth.
My ass. You do mouth-to-mouth.
This guy's an animal.
The Warden hears
we let him zap himself,
we're gonna get our
asses canned.
- No way.
- Shit!
[SCREAMING]
Open up!
Finger-licking good.
[LAUGHING]
Fucking animal!
Shut the fuck up!
Get those men down
to the infirmary!
Is the fucker alive?
I don't know.
[GASPS]
Well, I'm fine, boys. Just fine.
[LAUGHING]
Let's get on with the killing.
Okay, pretty boy.
You come to look death in the face,
school boy?
Strap him in.
It isn't right. It just isn't right.
They're treating him
like some kind of animal.
Why give animals such a bad rap?
Would you like to pray with me, my son?
I'm no son of yours. Go pray
with your choir boys, you little pederast!
[LAUGHTER]
[DOOR SLAMS SHUT]
Ladies and gentlemen.
As warden of this facility,
I'm directed by the State
to request that you all bare witness
to the execution of Horace Pinker
in accordance with the laws
of this great state.
In most cases, this is a duty
that I'd rather not be mine.
However, today,
I feel justice is being served.
Does the prisoner
have any final words?
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I do.
Your pitiful little memory's
wiped it all out, hasn't it?
I used to beat you good, boy.
I was beating you good when your
mama tried to stop me with a gun.
You shut your mouth, you fuck!
The witness will sit down
and remain silent.
[LAUGHTER]
- The prisoner has a right to speak.
- That's right.
I was beating you real good when
your mama tried to stop me with that gun
that she brought into our happy home.
You saw me kill her.
Don't you remember how she screamed?
And how clever you were
grabbing that gun
and shooting me right through
the fucking knee, you little peckerhead!
Such a big gun
just blasting away at your daddy
with murder in your eyes.
Like father like son, huh?
[LAUGHTER]
What are you waiting for, dickhead?
You wanna fry me?
Then do it, you fucking insect!
You heard the man.
The chair is armed.
Repeat: The chair is armed.
The inner chamber is now sealed.
[LAUGHTER]
[ELECTRICITY SURGING]
[SCREAMING]
Get the lights!
[MACHINE POWERS DOWN]
Oh, my God.
[GASPING FOR BREATH]
Shit.
[CROWD MURMURING]
Get in there, Doctor,
and check him out.
[LAUGHTER]
[ELECTRICITY SURGING]
[SCREAMING]
God damn it!
All right, everybody.
Keep your seats. Keep your seats.
The guard will show you out.
Lieutenant, the executioner's fried.
- Get me a backup and get your ass back!
- You got it.
- Go, Pastori!
- I'm right behind you, Lieutenant.
I need backup in the chamber! Now!
The guy's had it.
- Help me. Get me to a hospital.
- All right, she's alive.
- Sergeant!
- Yeah?
Call the ambulance.
I can't. It's already gone
with two of our guys.
Get me a car and get
this doctor to a hospital!
- Yeah, hold it down here.
- All cell blocks sealed.
UP here!
Come on, move it, move it!
Check that corridor.
He's not in here.
He's gone, sir!
Seal the cell block off!
Hurry! Move!
He couldn't have gone far
after taking a hit like that.
[SECURITY ALARM BLARING]
Lock down all units.
Forget what he said, Jonathan.
Was it true?
It's been in the papers
you're a foster kid.
He was messing
with your mind, that's all.
Forget it.
Jon, relax.
He's not going anywhere.
They'll find him.
Are you all right?
Oh, Christ!
Jesus! That chair really kicks ass.
[ALARM BLARING]
Yo, get that car in here!
[BRAKES SCREECHING]
I've got her. I'll get her in.
Leave me alone. I'm fine.
I just need to lie down.
Get her in. Let's go!
What the hell's with her?
I didn't touch her.
What do you expect?
She just got knocked on her ass.
Open up!
[SIRENS WAILING]
How's she doing?
Is she gonna make it?
Yeah. She looks good.
Sleeping like a baby.
Great.
[SCREAMING]
- What the hell are you doing?
- Just feel like a little head, sport.
Let go of him!
[BONES CRUNCHING]
[LAUGHTER]
[HORN HONKING]
What the hell do you mean,
"Where's the doctor?"
She's in there.
You got an asbestos mask?
Go take a look!
Hey, what are you doing?
What are you, crazy?
Listen. How come you're so interested
in the doctor all of a sudden?
Pinker is dead, Jon.
Go home, get drunk or something.
- I don't think he's dead.
- What are you, crazy?
Yeah, all right.
I know it sounds crazy Don
but when I saw that
body back there,
I didn't feel anything
like I used to. Nothing.
It wasn't him any more.
He wasn't there.
That's right! It's nothing but
a bunch of fried meat. And good riddance!
It's just too bad he took so
many people with him, that's all!
Lieutenant? Lieutenant, over here!
- Come on.
- Keep on it, keep it on there!
- He must have been thrown clear.
- Oh, thank God.
- He's lucky.
- Is he gonna make it?
- Yeah, I think so.
- All right, Pastori, hang in there.
Now, we're gonna get you help.
You're gonna be all right, you hear me?
Hang in there now.
- Watch his arm.
- Get him back first.
Okay, get that mask on. Let's go.
Hey, what are you doing?
That's one of my guys.
Watch that bump, push hard.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
You go home!
This is enough of this shit!
You gotta trust me,
I know something! You ask him!
You ask him. What happened
to the doctor? Go ask him!
What happened to him?
You ask him! You ask him!
[AMBULANCE SIRENS]
What the hell's
with that kid, anyway?
[WATER DRIPPING]
[DRIPPING SOUND STOPS]
[DRIPPING SOUND RESUMES]
- You've gotta stop him, Jonathan.
- Pinker.
Alison, he's gone. He's dead.
He's learning how to move.
He's gonna be uncatchable soon.
It'll be slaughter.
Alison, he's gone. I stopped him.
No. No, he's not.
He's on the move.
You've gotta stop him.
Remember our love.
Use this.
It'll drive him out. Keep him away.
Alison, please go back.
Just go back.
Hold me. I'm so cold, Jonathan.
- Hold me.
- Stop, Alison. You gotta stop!
Alison!
[SCREAMING]
[TV STATIC]
[KNOCKING]
If you're here to see the house,
go next door to the landlord's.
Jonathan, police.
Jonathan, your father, Lt. Parker,
wants to see you down at the station.
I got a car out here.
[PHONE RINGING]
Jonathan?
This is Jonathan. I'm not home.
Leave a message at the beep.
[BEEP]
Jon, this is your dad.
Jonathan, you hear me?
I thought I'd call and tell you,
Pastori, my cop
that survived the car
wreck yesterday?
Well, he's disappeared
from the hospital.
I wondered if you knew
anything about it.
JQn?
Jon, you there?
Open up!
Jonathan?
Pastori?
[GUNFIRE]
If you won't open up, I will!
[GUNSHOT]
Jesus!
[GUNSHOTS]
Hold it right there, Jonathan!
[nos BARKING]
Why don't you just
calm down and--
Jesus!
[GUNSHOT]
What's your problem, Pastori?
You shut your
fucking face, shithead!
Get down on the ground! Now!
Pinker?
- And let you shoot me like a dog?
- Then eat this, asshole!
[GUNFIRE]
Running out of gas, Pinker?
You should've picked a better body,
you gimp.
[YELLING]
Jonathan, help me, please.
Pastori?
How did I get out
of the hospital?
Oh, Jesus, help me.
Feeling yourself, Pastori?
Hey, man, is he all right?
Yeah, he's all right.
He's a little under the weather.
[GUNSHOTS]
- Oh, mother.
- Come here, kid.
I didn't do anything.
Got you.
[SCREAMING]
[BICYCLE BELL]
Oops, sorry, mister.
It's all right, sweetie,
you just banged my funny bone.
You ought to try being a little
more careful with that thing.
I will. Sorry. Bye.
[BICYCLE BELL]
Excuse me, sir.
Have you seen a little girl,
blonde, on a bicycle?
Sorry.
No, I saw her. She was up
by that light pole up there.
Well, thank you. Amanda!
Help me. Please help me.
Please, help me.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Come on, you fucker! Move!
Christ.
Come here, you little-
Come here!
[SCREAMING]
Get away from my daughter!
Pinker?
I'm gonna rip your lungs out,
you son of a bitch!
Get away from her!
[SCREAMING]
What the hell are you doing?
Amanda!
Stop, Mandy!
Come here.
Get out of her, Pinker.
Get out of her, you bastard!
Mandy.
Oh, God.
Is this creep
bugging you, ma'am?
No!
- No!
- Eat your heart out, sucker.
[SPLASH]
[SWITCHBLADE FLIPS OPEN]
How do you like
this body, Jonathan?
I don't get it.
Are you saying
that Pinker is alive somehow?
And he just jumps in and out of people
like a goddamn crab or something?
I know it sounds crazy,
but that's exactly what he's doing.
Maybe he's using electricity or something
because of the way he died, I don't know.
All I do know is that
I saw him do it five times today.
- Well then, let's go just grab the fucker then.
- And break his neck.
- I'd love to break his neck.
- You can't do it that directly, Rhino
or you'd be killing whoever it is
that he's inside of, that's the whole point.
Then, why don't you just do
like you said you did with this cop?
I mean, you can outrun anybody
Pinker gets into
and then, when they're out of
energy Pinker's just forced out.
- Then we'll break his neck.
- It doesn't work that way, Coach.
You don't force him out of the body until
he's used up the life of the body he's in.
We can't go killing people
just to get Pinker out, you know.
But there is something we can use,
to get him out before he kills the body.
Well, what is it?
I mean, I'll get you 10 of them.
There's only one of them.
It's in the bottom of the lake.
The bottom of the lake?
I know pretty much where it is.
I think we can find it.
I have a diving mask in
my closet at home.
I just need you to go and get it, Coach.
I can't go back to that house.
All right, I'll go get your mask.
- Meet me at the lake in half an hour.
- I'll go with you.
I'll get you some fresh clothes
and something to eat, too.
- You guys be careful.
- You be careful.
I'm not letting you
out of my sight.
Where the hell is he?
Coach isn't coming.
He's out laughing it up with
Pac Man somewhere right now.
No way Coach would jerk you around.
He's an hour and 15 minutes late,
Rhino, an hour and 15.
Does that sound like
Cooper to you, huh?
I mean, for all I know
the cops are all over my place.
God knows, enough people saw me
running from Pastori.
Pinker's gonna start killing again
tonight if I don't stop him.
I can feel it.
I gotta get that thing, Rhino.
- I just gotta get it.
- Hey, Jon. Jon, wait.
Man, what are you doing?
Jon, wait, hold it. Okay.
All right, maybe if I go look.
Tell me what it is.
But you can't see a thing in here,
Rhino, without a mask. No one can.
- I gotta go back to my place.
- What are you doing?
I gotta go back to the house.
You gotta go?
What the hell you talking about?
- We gotta go. I'm with you on this.
- Get lost, no deal.
Fuck you, you need a friend.
That's Rhino, that's the deal.
What are you, God? Hey!
You know what I could do to you
if I wanted to, right?
But that ain't what I'm about.
What about you? What you about?
You're not my friend on this, Rhino.
Look, I already got one person
I love killed, I'm not gonna do that again.
I gotta do this by myself.
You wanna be my friend,
leave me be.
[WATER RUNNING]
Alison?
Coach.
Good evening, Jonathan.
Alone now, huh?
What are you doing?
If someone ever gets
in your way, Jonathan,
you gotta run right through them.
Understand what I'm saying?
Remember what I told you?
I'm gonna rip your
lungs out, Jonathan!
[YELLING]
No more Mr. Nice Guy.
[STRUGGLING]
Coach, please, not you!
Coach Cooper's bye-bye, asshole.
And the closet, don't look.
I made a mess on the floor.
[LAUGHTER]
[SCREAMING]
God, no more!
Pac Man liked
you too much, Jonathan.
He wouldn't let me in.
That's a no-no.
Time to die, sweetie!
Don't even
think about it, Pinker.
Cooper, for your own sake,
fight him.
Don't let him take your soul.
It's like you say, Coach!
Coach, it's like you say,
I know you're in there!
Everything is a matter of will.
Will him out.
[SHOUTING]
Jonathan, he's too strong.
I can't will him out.
Yes, you can.
I can eat this wimp's will power
for breakfast, Jon-ho!
No.
I want to tell you, Jonathan,
to get this bastard!
- Coach.
- No!
No!
No, Coach! No!
[YELLING]
Get out of my way, bitch.
I need a body.
Go back to hell
where you belong, Pinker.
[YELLING]
Jonathan. Jon.
Jonathan.
[KNOCKING]
I have something very
important to tell you.
Listen very carefully.
[KNOCKING]
Wait a minute.
There's a little power.
[KNOCKING]
- Why not?
- Jonathan?
[KNOCKING]
I think I can.
[ELECTRICITY SURGING]
[YELLING]
Contact!
Jon, what's going on in there?
Jonathan, open up.
Jonathan.
[nos BARKING]
It smells like the goddamn
electric chair in here.
Don.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
- Hold it!
- Oh, jeez, you scared-
What the hell's going
on around here?
It's been a bad day, Don.
You'd never believe me.
It may interest you to know
there's an APB out on you.
Half a dozen people witnessed
Pastori chasing you in the park.
He's dead now, too.
Yeah, well, what the hell was
Pastori doing out of the hospital
wearing his uniform?
What have you been up to?
I wanted Pinker dead so bad,
when I got my wish
it just made him stronger.
You think I killed that cop.
You're talking crazy enough, that's for sure.
If you did,
you must've scared him to death.
What do you mean?
I mean, there wasn't a mark on him.
He was just dead.
You're family a long time, Jonathan.
Been through a lot of
tough times.
I saw you turn a screwed up
childhood into straight A's.
Football scholarship.
I've been proud to be your father.
I can't see you a killer.
Besides, Pastori's body was just a...
- A husk, just like--
- Just like Pinker's.
Shit.
Is that how you knew
about Bobby's fingers?
I gotta take you in, kid.
Don't do that, Don.
Called for backup when I
heard the fighting in here.
What do you want?
- Read him his rights.
- Yes, sir.
Jonathan, you're under arrest.
"You have the right to remain silent.
"Give up the right to remain silent
"anything you say
can and will be used against you."
Shit!
What is it with the
electricity around here?
Put him in my car,
I'll take him back myself.
Yes, sir.
"You have the right to have an
attorney present during questioning.
"If you so desire and cannot afford one
"one will be appointed to you
without charge."
Do you understand these rights
as I've read them to you?
Sure as shit can't tell
a book by its cover, huh, boys?
All right, boys, wrap it up.
I got something to do here.
- Check that car.
- Yes, sir.
Hey; Smitty, you got a key for this thing?
- Yeah, inside.
No. Shit!
Shit!
[GLASS SHATTERS]
Move. Come on, Jon, get on your feet.
Let's move! Move, boy.
Come on. Go! Explain later, go!
[GUNFIRE]
Jesus!
- Freeze!
- Shit!
Get him!
No, I'll get him! I'll get him!
This one's mine!
[HARD ROCK MUSIC]
[POLICE SIRENS]
Don! Can't we just talk about this?
[GUNSHOT]
Guess not.
- Don, you gotta fight him.
- Eat shit and die, you little fuck.
[GUNSHOT]
That's nice.
[MUSIC FADES]
Dead end, asshole.
[LAUGHTER]
[GUNFIRE]
Motherfucker.
Hey, kid, eat this.
[GUNFIRE]
Come on.
Where you gonna go now?
Don, you gotta fight him.
You can't let him do this to you.
You gotta get him out!
Don't let him do this, Donnie!
Don't let him do this!
You gotta stop it! Stop him!
[GASPING]
What's going on?
Don, are you there?
- Talk to me.
- Oh, God.
Jonathan, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
[SCREAMING]
My heart. I-
[YELLING]
Jonathan, help me!
All right, asshole,
I'm nationwide now.
[CHUCKLING]
Donnie, give me your hand.
Gimme your hand.
Give me your hand!
Donnie, give me your hand!
I got you. I got you,
Okay.
Donnie, I never even knew
you had a bad heart.
I don't.
I knew that. You knew that
but Pinker didn't.
[SIRENS APPROACHING]
With the arrest of Jonathan Parker
who was increasingly implicated
in the copy-cat murders following
the electrocution of Horace Pinker
the horrors seemed to be over.
But last night, while Jonathan Parker
was in the city jail
the copy-cat murderer struck again
killing an entire Maryville family
and leaving a grizzly threat
to Jonathan Parker scrawled on the wall,
signing the name Horace Pinker.
Police are further baffled because
there were no signs of forced entry.
The family apparently awake and
watching TV at the time the killer struck.
Meanwhile, Jonathan Parker
has been released by authorities
following the testimony of his
father, Police Lt. Donald Parker.
Indeed, police lab reports confirm
that the deaths of Coach Sydney Cooper
and Student Assistant Coach
Roy "Pac Man" Stewart
now appear to be
the results of a murder-suicide.
[TURNS TV DOWN]
Coach didn't do it, you guys,
neither did Pac Man.
You still up for this?
- We're friends, right?
- Yeah, we're friends.
- And we're a team, right?
- Right!
So we'll do what you ask us to do.
Just make sure you do
it exactly at midnight.
Give me enough time, okay?
Right.
- All right, let's go!
- All right. Come on. Let's do it.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Come on, 17 minutes and counting.
- This is crazy.
- Sometimes crazy is what it takes.
Shut up and get in there. Let's go.
[THUNDER CLAPS]
Come on.
- You all set?
- Yeah.
Let's go.
The stuffs all set up and ready,
just like you asked for.
Okay, let me get this straight.
You want me to go on the air
live at five minutes to midnight
and if I do, you guarantee
you'll deliver the guy
responsible for the
copy-cat killings last night?
That's right.
[THUNDER IN DISTANCE]
Don't make a fool
out of me, live.
I'm gonna make you a
network anchorman.
You're ready for that, aren't you?
Where're you going?
I'm gonna go get the killer for you,
bring him right here.
All you have to do is make sure
this camera's on
feeding the station by
five to midnight.
No way I'm doing what you tell me,
with you not here.
Really?
Well, we'll just let the other networks
get the story first, I don't care.
- Do you want us to pack back up?
- No, leave it.
I have a feeling this kid's for real.
I wish Pac Man were here for this.
A maze.
[THUNDER CLAPS]
There it is.
[THUNDER]
The central unit should be in there.
Too bad it's locked.
Let's get out of here.
Pick it.
- That's a felony.
- No, that's a lock, pick it.
[THUNDER CLAPS]
[RAINFALL]
Come on.
Please! Please!
[ECHOING]
Please.
Jonathan.
[SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[TV POWERS ON]
The red-crested nuthatch is one of
the largest arboreals found in the British--
[GASPING SOUNDS FROM TV]
[LAUGHING]
[YELLS]
- Don't be afraid, Jonathan.
- You're not alive, Alison.
So? I'm here.
All right.
That's it.
- Give me the crowbar.
- Crowbar.
- Mask.
All right, move it. Move.
Get back.
[STATIC SOUND]
Jonathan.
Jonathan, stop sleeping.
- Please.
- Wake up, Jonathan.
- Don't let him catch you sleeping.
- Watch your ass, boy.
Don't get caught napping.
I don't wanna go through with this.
Why should I go back?
Why should I be away from you
in that madness?
You've got to, Jonathan,
or you'll die.
Then I die. I don't ever wanna
be away from you again.
You'll never be apart
from me again, ever.
$5,000, praise the Lord,
for a total
a grand total of $1,542,000.79
But glory be, we hear you, Lord.
The Lord wants more.
We still need more cash for Christ.
Let it rain, let it rain
dollars for Christ.
More. More. More.
And the beast shall rise out of the
pit and walk among the world
and great will be the devastation
and desolation.
And I tell you woe to the man
who is without the Lord.
And woe to the man
and woe to the woman
who has not given generously
to this ministry.
Who has not dug deep
and sent cash
or check to this
anti-beast brigade
of true believers
who are girding now for battle.
I beg you, send your
dollars to Jesus now!
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
Beware! Beware of the beast!
He's among you! Prepare!
Check your perimeter!
[SINGING ON TV]
[SCREAMING]
[LAUGHTER]
Die!
[YELLING]
This Barcaloungefs gonna
kick your ass, boy.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[ELECTRICITY OVERLOADING]
It's hard to outrun
Recldy Kilowatt, asshole.
In the last 80 years alone,
over 125 million people have been killed
in warfare between civilized nations.
This total is the equivalent
of murdering the entire population-
[ELECTRICAL SURGE]
Come on, boy, let's take
a ride in my Voltswagen.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[GROANING]
[YELLING]
Alison, if you're in me,
give me the power to do this.
[YELLING]
[GUNFIRE]
[EXPLOSION]
[HARD ROCK MUSIC]
Bastard!
Who the hell's that guy?
Take cover!
Do as your father asks.
Roll up the window.
He)!' hey! Beaver!
Well, it's all out in
the open now.
So we still have no word from our
reporter at the home of Lt. Parker.
However, incredibly, we have begun
to receive unconfirmed reports
of unexplained appearances
of Jonathan Parker
and a man who looks very much like
executed mass murderer Horace Pinker
-fighting at least what appears to be
- Kick his ass!
The programming of several local stations
during the last several minutes.
[YELLING]
And that's the way it is.
Did you get that?
My kind of town!
Move it out.
- Come here, you shit!
- Dial 911!
[EXPLOSION]
[YELLING]
We got any cheese spread?
Now wait a minute,
that's my drink.
Honey.
Do we have any
cheese spread, or what?
Come on!
Get him, honey.
[CLATTER]
Now watch out.
Now wait a minute.
[MUSIC ENDS SUDDENLY]
I've heard of audience
participation shows,
but this is ridiculous.
- Give me that!
- You can't take that.
He's taking our remote.
Sweet Jesus!
Shut up!
[SCREAMING]
Come here.
Brother, are you all right?
Get up, you shit!
Holy shit! It's him!
Horace Pinker.
What are you staring at?
Get the camera on him!
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
A special bulletin, huh?
I'll give you a show!
Let's get out of here!
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
I killed your mama
and your little sister here.
Right about there.
I'll do you here, too.
Say your prayers, squirt.
I'm gonna do you real slow.
Hey, what the fuck?
It's show time.
What the hell are you doing?
You bought into TV, Pinker,
now you're bound by its rules.
I'm gonna show you something.
Remember Bobby, my little brother?
My mother? My baby sister?
Let's try and remember
all the other families, Horace.
Fathers, mothers, sleeping
defenseless in their beds.
Try. Try to remember
the pain. No?
Then get up on the bed.
Up' up! up!
- God damn you little bastard, stop it!
- Just freeze.
- That's good.
- And what the fuck?
I just showed you
what you can never remember.
What it feels like to victimized.
Give me a violin, why don't you?
At the mercy of
some guy's hate. Weapon?
- Doesn't feel so good, does it?
- Go ahead, do it.
You know you wanna do it.
Go ahead, you little pussy, do it.
[YELLING]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
- It's not my style.
- It is your style.
You're a chip off the old block,
like it or not.
No good, Pinker,
Alison told me the secret.
Maybe you were my father,
but you know who my father is now?
Know who's responsible for me?
Me, no one else.
I get down from here and you're dog meat.
Three minutes to
midnight, Pinker.
Rhino blows the
Maryville Power Station
we'll see who's clog meat.
Town power goes, TV goes
and anybody in this TV room's
gonna go right with it.
Anybody who gets out first
might just survive.
Wait a minute,
it was three minutes before.
Your watch has taken a licking.
And I don't think it's
ticking no more.
- Rhino, no!
- Three, two, one, hit it!
[ELECTRICAL EXPLOSION]
You should've killed me
when you had the chance, prick.
Shit. It's working!
[CHEERING]
Shit!
[ELECTRICITY SURGING]
- It's sign off time.
- No!
"O, no, no!
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[ELECTRICAL EXPLOSION]
[FAINT YELLING]
[ELECTRICAL SPARKING]
You bastard, come back in here.
Come back in here, you shit!
Don't ever turn the TV on,
boy, I'll be there.
I'll be there waiting for you.
I'll look over your shoulder,
you little bastard.
Come back in here! Come back!
[TV sl-luTs OFF]
[REMOTE CLATTERS ON GROUND]
Bob, you got any
lights in your place?
Looks like the
power's out all over.
- Beautiful.
- Look at that sky.
- Look at that.
-Isn't it beautiful?
Jon, I just saw you on the tube.
- Was that real?
- Yeah, it was real enough.
Howard?
Wow, what a storm that was.
And look at that sky.
Are you there,
you see those stars?
- Absolutely beautiful.
- It sure is.
[HARD ROCK MUSIC]
[MUSIC FADES]
[SOMBER BALLAD]