♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's waiting ♪
♪ Christmas Eve is slowly fading ♪
♪ Can you hear him in the night? ♪
♪ Close the door,
turn out the light ♪
(MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN ON RADIO: This is KSCZ Radio
wishing you the joy of the season.
The weather looks good
for Santa Claus tonight
with a full moon and a starry
sky to help him find his way.
The temperature right now
here in Bartlesville...
21 degrees. Ooh.
Well, let's listen to
"Christmas Fever."
♪ What a night of cheer this is,
how grand it is to feel so merry ♪
♪ Life is very gay when people
catch the Christmas fever ♪
♪ How delightful on this eve ♪
♪ When saints and
angels sing along ♪
♪ With holly hung just right and
faces bright with Christmas fever ♪
♪ What a night of cheer this is,
how grand it is to feel so merry ♪
♪ Life is very gay when people... ♪
Mom, what time is it?
It's almost 4:30, honey.
We're going to be at
Grandpa's pretty soon.
- Mom?
- Yes, Billy.
What time does Santa Claus come?
Not until everyone is
asleep in bed, hon.
Can't I stay up and see him?
I wouldn't if I were you.
It's naughty to stay
up past your bedtime.
Santa Claus doesn't bring
presents to naughty children.
What if we don't get
home by my bedtime?
We will, hon. Don't worry.
Santa Claus is going to bring
you a big surprise tonight.
You just wait and see.
MAN ON RADIO: That was
always one of my favorites.
Give us a call at KSCZ for something
special we haven't played for you yet.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
I've had your father brought
to the recreation room.
Right this way.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (BABY CRIES)
Dad.
Can you hear me?
It's me, Dad, Jimmy.
Dad, it's Ellie.
We have Billy here
and little Ricky, too.
Why doesn't Grandpa say something?
He doesn't hear us, honey.
He doesn't even know we're here.
Then what did we come for?
Billy, shh.
He's gotten so much worse.
I have your father's
records, Mr. Chapman.
We can review them in my office.
Wait right here, okay, honey?
Daddy and I are going
to be right back.
Don't worry. Grandpa's
not going to hurt you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Grandpa?
- Mom.
- Shh.
Quiet.
What do you want her for?
She can't help you.
Nobody can.
You're scared, ain't you?
You should be.
Christmas Eve
is the scariest damn
night of the year.
I'd be scared, too, if I was you.
You know what happens on
Christmas Eve, don't you?
You know all about Santa Claus?
He brings presents to all
good boys and girls.
(LAUGHS) Your daddy told
you that, didn't he?
Well, I'll tell you something...
Santa Claus only brings presents
to them that's been good all year.
To the ones that ain't
done nothing naughty.
Naughty.
All the other ones,
all the naughty ones,
he punishes.
What about you, boy?
You been good all year?
If you see Santa Claus tonight,
you better run, boy.
You better run for your life!
(LAUGHING)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- Time to go home, Billy.
Dad, we have to go now.
We'll come back and see you soon.
Come on, son.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'll be good from
now on, I promise.
Mommy, were you ever naughty
when you were little?
Hmm, once or twice.
Did Santa Claus ever punish you?
Where did you get an
idea like that, hon?
Grandpa.
Grandpa?
Grandpa said Santa Claus
was going to punish me.
Do you think Dad could
have talked to him?
I don't see why Billy would lie.
Maybe we ought to call Dr. Conway.
I don't want him to
come. I'm scared.
- Of who, honey?
- Santa Claus.
Honey, there's nothing
to be scared of.
Grandpa said Santa Claus
was going to punish me.
Billy, calm down.
Grandpa is nothing but
a crazy old fool.
(GASPS)
Mommy, you shouldn't
have said that.
It's naughty to say bad
things about old people.
Santa Claus will punish you.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BELLS JINGLE)
Ho, ho, ho.
I don't get enough of
this shit on the radio.
It has to come into my store now.
(CHUCKLES)
What's the matter, you
don't like Santa Claus?
It's good for business,
bad for my stomach.
A lot of phony sentiment,
you know what I'm saying?
What charity are you with?
What the hell are
you doing that for?
I'm holding you up, asshole.
- Put the money in the bag.
- All right, all right.
So it's not all phony
sentiment, is it?
A lot of it's genuine greed.
- All right, you!
- (GUNSHOT)
31 bucks. Merry fucking Christmas.
- (CAR STARTS)
- (TIRES SQUEAL)
MAN ON RADIO:
Steve Carlson here at KLOX FM
where the temperature
this Christmas Eve
is still holding in there
at 21 degrees at 7:00.
Well, we hope Santa is dressed
warm tonight, don't we?
♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's waiting ♪
♪ Christmas Eve is slowly fading ♪
♪ Can't you hear him
in the night... ♪
How's it going, hon?
Got a ways to go yet.
What's that?
Hmm?
I thought I saw something
out there on the road.
There it is again. See?
JIM: There's something
up there, all right.
ELLIE: What would anybody be doing
stopped out here in the middle of the...
(LAUGHS)
- Do you see what I see?
- He must be on his way to a party.
Do you think we
should wake up Billy?
Santa Claus!
JIM: Looks like you get to see
him tonight after all, Billy.
No, Daddy, I don't want to see him!
Keep going! Don't stop!
(BELLS JINGLING)
- Need a ride, Santa Claus?
- Well, no, not exactly.
- What's the problem?
- Oh, there's no problem.
It's just that I ran into a
little bit of lousy luck.
ELLIE: Oh.
Jim, go!
- Go!
- (TIRES SQUEALING)
- No!
- (BABY CRYING)
Oh, no! (SCREAMING)
Never hit me!
(GRUNTS, MUTTERS)
Where are you, you little bastard?
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Sweet little baby ♪
♪ This pretty little baby ♪
♪ So, so sweet ♪
♪ Sweet little baby ♪
♪ Pretty baby ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
- ♪ Ooh ♪
- ♪ Sweet little baby ♪
All right, now, who's next?
Oh, yes. We haven't seen
your drawing yet, have we?
Billy?
Billy, answer me.
Okay.
Let's go, Billy. Come on up here.
Put your drawing up on
the board with the others.
You put it in place and
I'll put the tape on it.
(SCREAMS) Sister, look.
Billy, take that down!
Young man, you go
find Mother Superior
and you show her what
you've done. March.
Explain this, William.
I'm sorry, Mother Superior.
Are you?
I don't think so.
But you will be.
You will learn what
it is to be sorry.
- Now go to your room and stay there.
- Yes, Mother Superior.
Until I tell you to come out.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Well, you finally have what you've
been asking for, Mother Superior.
- Proof.
- Of what, Sister Margaret?
What I've been saying.
That it's all still inside him.
All that terrible violence he saw.
His drawing clearly shows that.
I am not interested
in what you think.
I thought you finally
understood that.
Simply because something unfortunate
happened to his parents,
which he knows nothing about,
is no reason to allow
him to run wild.
He must be taught.
But the memory is still there,
Mother Superior,
waiting to come out.
And if it does, and if he has
received proper training,
he will know how to cope with it.
But if he keeps going on
like this much longer,
it may be too late.
It seems to get worse for
him every Christmas.
Well, it won't go on any longer.
I will take charge of
that child personally.
He needs help, Mother Superior.
He'll get it.
Good day, Sister.
Good day, Mother Superior.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(CHILDREN PLAYING)
I think you've been locked
away up here long enough.
Why don't you come out and
help us build our snowman?
I can't.
Look, Billy,
Mother Superior only wants
what's best for you.
And I think what's best for you
is to come out and play with
the other children, okay?
- Hmm?
- Yes, Sister.
Okay.
(MAN AND WOMAN MOANING)
(SCREAMS)
You filthy devil!
(DOOR SLAMS)
You'll pay for this.
Punishment.
You little devil,
take your punishment.
- Devil!
- (BELT WHIPPING)
- WOMAN: Sorry! Please, stop!
- (MOTHER SUPERIOR GRUNTING)
MOTHER SUPERIOR: Take it! Take it!
William!
Don't blame him, Mother Superior.
I told him he could...
Stay out of this, Sister Margaret.
William, come here.
Billy, what's wrong?
Your brother's a nutcase,
that's what's wrong.
No, he's not! Take it back!
Boys.
What did you see upstairs, William?
Nothing, Mother Superior.
Do you know what they were doing?
No, Mother Superior.
Good.
What they were doing was
something very, very naughty.
They thought they could do
it without being caught.
But when we do something naughty,
we are always caught.
And then we are punished.
Punishment is absolute.
Punishment is necessary.
- Punishment is good.
- Yes, Mother Superior.
- You left your room, William.
Very, very naughty.
(GROANING, YELPING)
Now go to bed and stay there.
(BILLY GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
Please, let me up.
Sister Margaret.
- Let me up!
- Leave him alone.
Please, let me up.
Let me up, Sister Margaret.
Let me out of here!
Let me out. Let me out.
Please, let me out. (CRYING)
Sister Margaret.
Let me out of here! Please!
Ow. (CRYING)
Please, let me up, Sister Margaret.
(CHILDREN PLAYING)
I see nothing but greed when
there should be gratitude.
What is it? Can I see it?
Are you ready to behave
properly, William?
Yes, Mother Superior.
Good.
Go find your present.
You will have no more
trouble with him.
You will see how well
my methods work.
Of course he'll improve
once Christmas is over.
He always does.
Well, it isn't over,
Sister Margaret.
We still have our annual Christmas
visit from Santa Claus.
William will sit on Santa
Claus' lap and behave.
You'll see.
(BILLY SCREAMING)
No! No! No!
- No!
- Get him out of the way.
- You will learn gratitude.
- Say thank you to Santa Claus.
- No! No!
(GRUNTING)
Billy!
What the hell's wrong
with that kid?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be naughty.
Don't punish me.
Please.
(FOOTSTEPS)
WOMAN: William.
SISTER MARGARET: Please, Mr. Sims,
every store in town
has turned us down.
There must be some job that
you can give this boy.
- Why, he just turned...
- I'm sorry, Sister,
but I only have one job open
and it's for a man, not for a boy.
It's in the stock
room hauling crates.
It's just not a job for a kid.
I suppose not.
Sorry I couldn't help.
Well, you wouldn't expect some kid
to haul heavy crates all
day long, would you?
- Glad you understand.
- Oh, here's Billy now.
- Maybe you'd like to meet him, Mr. Sims.
- That's not necessary.
Billy. Billy, meet Mr. Sims.
Oh.
Well, uh, um...
I'm always happy to
help the church, Sister.
He starts Monday
morning. 9:00 sharp.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Sims.
♪ I'm looking for ♪
♪ The warm side of the door ♪
♪ Where the fire's bright ♪
♪ And it's burning every night ♪
♪ Everybody will be there ♪
♪ And they'll be smiling at me ♪
♪ And I won't need no more ♪
♪ On the warm side of the door ♪
♪ My brother's there ♪
♪ He'll call to me ♪
♪ The way he did before ♪
♪ There'll be thunder
and lightning ♪
♪ But we're safe and sound ♪
♪ And I won't need no more ♪
♪ On the warm side of the door ♪
♪ There's always
people who love you ♪
♪ That will kiss you and hug you ♪
♪ And it's always Christmas on
the warm side of the door ♪
♪ There's always
people who love you ♪
♪ That will kiss you and hug you ♪
♪ And it's always Christmas on
the warm side of the door ♪
♪ There's always
people who love you ♪
♪ That will kiss you and hug you ♪
♪ And it's always Christmas ♪
♪ On the warm side of the door. ♪
What the fuck do you
think you're doing now?
I'm... you know, you
shouldn't talk like that.
Oh, well, excuse me, Ann Landers.
You know, what is it
with you lately, Billy?
Nothing.
I'm going to level with you.
When you came here a
couple of months ago,
you were an all right kid.
But all of a sudden, you got
this fucking attitude problem.
Snapping at me all the time.
You're staring off into
space like some moon goon.
Will you just... just leave
me alone, all right?
When I leave you alone, asshole,
none of your fucking
work gets done.
Look, I don't care
about my fucking work.
Oh, is that so, wise ass?
Look, just leave me alone.
Merry Christmas,
everyone. Ho, ho, ho.
Merry Christmas. Ho, ho, ho.
Come here, you little bastard.
- Pamela.
- Are you all right, Billy?
Yeah.
Yeah, I...
You don't look so good.
No, I'm fine.
Really, I...
Don't worry about this stuff.
I'll straighten it up for you, okay?
- (SHUDDERING)
- Are you sure you're all right, Billy?
Yeah, yeah.
I never felt better in my life.
(PAMELA'S VOICE) Billy, are
you sure you're all right?
(BILLY'S VOICE)
Never felt better in my life.
(SCREAMS)
No! Don't!
No!
I want to be good.
I didn't mean to be naughty.
- (YOUNG BILLY'S VOICE) I'm sorry.
- Don't punish me.
Don't punish me.
(YOUNG BILLY'S VOICE) Please.
Christmas Eve.
Only one more day and this
Christmas crap is history.
I hate to ruin your
party mood, Mr. Sims,
but a teensy problem has
arisen personnelwise.
Well, do something
about it solutionwise.
It ain't that simple, Mr. Sims.
I just got a call from
one of the employees.
Seems he went ice-skating last
night and broke his ankle.
He'll be out for the
remainder of the season.
Lucky him.
Call the temporary agency
and get a replacement.
Do I have to think of
everything around here?
Well, then think of this.
The agency's only got women.
This job requires a person
of the male persuasion.
- Oh.
- A big, fat, jolly one.
- You're receiving me?
- Oh, no.
Ho, ho, ho. (LAUGHS)
You pull another disappearing
act like yesterday, Billy,
and I'm going to go
straight to Sims.
I don't think you realize this,
but I'm giving you a break.
That's a hell of a lot
more than he'll do.
Sims is nobody's friend.
Remember that.
- Ah, Mr. Sims.
- Billy boy.
How are you?
I've been meaning to come around and
see how you're enjoying yourself.
Well, everything okay?
Uh, yeah. Yes. Fine.
Everything's fine, Mr. Sims.
Good, good. Good boy.
Ah, listen, Bill.
The reason I dropped by,
I've got a little problem
maybe you could help me with.
I mean, if you'd like to.
Well, of course, Mr. Sims.
Anything you want. You just tell me
what it is and I'll be glad to help out.
Good. Good boy. Thank you.
That's very good.
Very realistic. Isn't
it, Mrs. Randall?
He's definitely fat and jolly.
Take a closer look at yourself
in the mirror, Billy.
Now just remember, be jolly.
Lots of ho, ho, ho.
Try not to scare the
little bastards.
Sometimes they cry their heads off.
I guess they think
the old guy's scary.
Silly, isn't it?
Yeah.
Silly.
- (CHATTER)
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (GROANING)
- Stop it.
Please, stop it.
What's the matter with you?
Stop it. Stop kicking.
Do you have any idea
what you're doing?
You're being naughty.
Right on Santa's lap.
I don't bring toys
to naughty children.
I punish them.
Severely.
That's right. Stop it.
Or I'll have to punish you.
He sure knows how to handle kids.
He's great, isn't he?
Mommy!
(PHONE RINGING)
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Christ, keep your head on.
Stock room. Andy speaking.
Who?
No, no. Billy don't
work back here no more.
Sure, sure. I can
tell you his new job.
Ho, ho, ho.
He's playing Santa Claus for
a bunch of snot-nosed kids.
7:00. It's over!
Time to get shitfaced!
(LAUGHS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Christmas is a feeling... ♪
Merry Christmas, Helen.
How about a cheap thrill?
(LAUGHS)
Hey, Santa Claus,
come join the party.
MR. SIMS:
Santa Claus, come on over here.
There you go, there
you go, there you go.
Drink up.
Stick with me, kid.
By the time this party's over,
you'll think you are Santa Claus.
♪ We wish you a merry Christmas ♪
♪ And a happy new year ♪
♪ Good tidings for you ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
♪ We wish you a merry Christmas ♪
♪ And a happy new year... ♪
Hey. Hey, Santa Claus.
Hey, what you doing, huh?
I was, uh...
thinking about my parents.
Oh, good, good.
Good, that's fine. That's fine.
A boy should think about
his parents at Christmas.
- Good boy, good boy.
- They're dead.
Oh, God.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I forgot. I'm sorry.
Hey, Santa.
Santa, you better sober up.
You got a long night ahead of you.
(LAUGHING)
Huh?
Well, you remember what Santa Claus
does on Christmas Eve, don't you?
Yeah.
Yeah, I know what he does.
Better get started.
Ow.
Fuckin' party's dead anyway.
Ah. Go get 'em, Santa.
Go get 'em.
If you got me a present, Andy,
I don't see why you don't just bring it
out there where everybody can see it.
(CHUCKLES)
Pammy, this, uh,
this particular present
really isn't for everybody to see.
It's something I've been wanting
to give you for a long time.
- Oh.
- Come on, it's just right back there.
Hey, trust me, huh?
You are going to love it.
Come on.
BOTH: ♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's creeping ♪
♪ Soon you're nodding,
now you're sleeping ♪
♪ Were you good for Mom and Dad? ♪
♪ Santa knows if you've been bad ♪
♪ There might be a treat for you ♪
♪ In Santa's bag of toys ♪
♪ But Christmas won't
be fun and games ♪
♪ For naughty girls and boys ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's waiting ♪
♪ Christmas Eve is slowly fading ♪
♪ Can you hear him in the night? ♪
♪ Close the door,
turn out the light ♪
♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's creeping ♪
♪ Now you're nodding,
now you're sleeping ♪
♪ Were you good
for Mom and Dad... ♪
PAM: Stop it.
Come on, don't do that.
No, no. Don't do that.
Come on, let's go back now.
Andy, stop it.
Please, Andy, no.
Come on, let's go back.
No. No.
- (GASPS)
- (LAUGHS)
You goddamn little bitch.
No!
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS) No!
Run, you little bastard!
(SCREAMING) No! Please! No!
Ho, ho, ho.
(ANDY LAUGHING)
- ANDY: You little tease, huh?
- Naughty!
(GROANING, GASSING)
(PAM CRYING)
My God, you're crazy.
Oh, stop it, Pamela.
You bastard! You're crazy!
Get the hell away from me!
Did you hear something?
I don't hear anything, Mr. Sims.
It must have been your imagination.
(SCREAMING)
Punishment is necessary, Pamela.
- It is good.
- (GROANS)
I heard something, by God.
Anybody in here?
(BELLS SOFTLY JINGLING)
Sims, you're drunk.
You're hearing things.
(LAUGHING)
Yoo-hoo.
(SCREAMS)
Mr. Sims?
Oh, Mr. Sims?
Ooh.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Mr. Sims?
Come out here and see this.
It's lovely.
Mr. Sims?
Mr. Sims, are you hiding in there?
(SCREAMING)
Oh, God.
Answer.
Thank God.
(SCREAMS)
'Twas the night before Christmas
and all through the house...
not a creature was stirring...
not even a mouse.
No!
(GROANING)
Hello?
Anybody there?
Billy, are you in here?
(SCREAMING)
♪ ...on this eve when saints
and angels sing among us ♪
♪ Holly hung just right and faces
bright with Christmas fever ♪
♪ Happy eve of happy day ♪
♪ Candles burning, tables full ♪
♪ Drawers are spilling
wrapping paper ♪
♪ Closets stuffed with
down and woolens ♪
♪ Now's the time to make your vow ♪
♪ To help your friends and
love your neighbors ♪
♪ Joyful neighbors where the
Christmas fever lends us here ♪
♪ On the warmest winter... ♪
Shit. I can't concentrate
with that racket.
Hold on.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Mama, won't you give me... ♪
- (GIGGLES)
- (LAUGHS)
♪ And I'm missing all
the Christmas parties ♪
♪ What'll I do... ♪
GIRL: Denise?
Denise, I want to stay
up to see Santa Claus.
Cindy, go back to bed
right this minute.
But I can't sleep.
Holy shit. She's coming down.
Cindy, um, don't come down here.
We're, um, we're
doing our homework.
Cindy, if, uh, you
don't go back to bed,
Santa won't come.
He's not the only one.
He won't?
No, um, you're being bad,
Cindy, now go back to bed.
Well, okay.
Back to our studies.
- Two ball in the corner pocket.
- Mm.
♪ Merry Christmas, baby ♪
♪ This isn't what I planned ♪
♪ I was going to buy
you a diamond ring ♪
♪ Take you out, jump and shout ♪
- ♪ But I can't give you anything... ♪
- (BELLS SOFTLY JINGLING)
Oh, shit.
What?
Sorry, Tommy, I've got to
go upstairs for a minute.
- What for?
- Um, the cat wants to come inside.
How do you know?
I heard her collar
jingling at the door.
♪ And I'm trying to be
jolly, good golly ♪
♪ But I got the blues ♪
♪ I got the blues ♪
♪ I got the Christmas blues ♪
♪ Baby, I've got the blues... ♪
I'm going to kill her.
(SIGHS)
Woody? You out there?
Woody? Kitty, kitty, kitty.
(SIGHS) Kitty?
Where'd you go?
Okay, you're on your
own until morning.
- Merry Christmas.
- (BELLS JINGLING)
- (MEOWS)
- There you are, you bad kitty.
- Punish!
- (SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
Ah!
(SCREAMING)
No!
Tommy!
Punish.
- Punish!
- No!
(GROANING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ I guess I really tied one on... ♪
Hey, Denise!
What are you doing?
♪ I love you, baby,
but you made me mad ♪
♪ You were the best
Christmas I've ever had ♪
♪ Merry Christmas, baby ♪
♪ I guess I really tied one on... ♪
(CAT MEOWS)
Holy shit.
(MEOWING)
Denise?
Where are you?
Are you okay?
If this is some kind of joke,
I'm going to kill her.
(SCREAMS)
Operator.
Operator, I need the police.
Punish.
(SCREAMS)
CINDY: Santa Claus!
I knew you'd come. Did
you bring me a present?
Have... have you been good
or have you been naughty?
Good.
You haven't done anything naughty?
No, Santa Claus.
Are you sure?
CINDY: Denise?
Denise?
OFFICER: Can you believe this?
It's Christmas Eve and we got
orders to bring in Santa Claus.
Hey, Miller, what do you think the captain
would do if we brought in the real one?
He's never satisfied.
He'd send us back out to
pick up the Easter Bunny.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Peter Pan maybe.
Hey, look.
What are you doing?
What do you think you're doing?
Hold it. Stop right there.
Daddy.
Daddy?
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
Look at this hill. Virgin, man.
- The only kind you'll ever get.
- I'm going down first.
(BELLS JINGLING SOFTLY)
Go on.
What's the matter, you afraid?
Shut up a second.
Are you having a
religious experience
or did you pee your pants?
Somebody else is out there.
Who'd be out here at this time of
night on Christmas Eve? Go on.
Be quiet for a minute.
I feel like somebody's watching me.
Like who? Santa's little elves?
Well, maybe it was
just my imagination.
Yeah, it would be if you had one.
Now ride your stupid sled.
My sled ain't stupid.
I'll show you. Watch.
Well, if it isn't Bob and Mac.
Now why don't you guys just
get the fuck out of the way?
Glad to, little man.
But, uh, we're going
to go sledding.
- Oh, that's the plan.
- Yeah.
You guys are going
to take our sleds.
Oh, you guys are great.
You know, I want to grow
up to be just like you.
Ugly and very stupid.
Do you want to take
that back, fuck face?
- Drop dead.
- I said take it back.
All right! All right, I'm sorry.
Now get out of here!
- Go on, go!
- Get out of here!
- (BOTH LAUGH)
- Yeah.
- All right.
- All right, let's go.
- You go first.
- Okay.
(BELLS JINGLING SOFTLY)
Hey, what if I hit a tree?
Just go.
(YELLS)
(LAUGHS) Whoo!
(YELLING)
Okay, I'm right here, man.
That's beautiful.
All right.
Now watch this.
(YELLING)
- Naughty.
- (SCREAMS)
Oh, God!
(SCREAMING)
Oh, God! Oh, shit!
Oh, God!
- (CHATTER ON DISPATCH)
- (PHONE RINGING)
Oh, Captain Richards.
I'm sorry, I must
have fallen asleep.
Any news?
All bad, Sister.
(SIGHS)
Three more murders.
(GASPS)
Been eluding my men all night.
Kid may be nuts, but
he's not stupid.
No, he's not stupid.
In fact, everything he's been
doing has a kind of logic to it,
once you understand
what he's gone through.
If that's true,
there ought to be a way we
can predict his next move.
Oh, my Lord.
(CHATTER)
I want those papers
folded and stacked.
Not tossed about.
And I want each one of you to
write a nice thank-you to Santa
for his visit later.
Are you listening?
Better say good-bye now. Mother Superior
wants us to write a note to Santa Claus.
(DIAL TONE)
(BUSY TONE)
Is that the only line
out there, Sister?
- I'm afraid so.
- Still busy.
I can't imagine who'd be
on the phone so long.
We can't wait any longer.
I'm going down to the dispatcher
and you and I are going out
to the orphanage together.
Sister.
CAPTAIN RICHARDS ON RADIO:
I need every available car
to go out to the
orphanage on the double.
The Santa Claus Killer may be
headed that way there now.
Responding officers are ordered
to shoot to kill if necessary.
If you get wet or start to
feel cold, come back inside.
Wow.
Cut it out!
Can't you see who's coming?
This is Officer Barnes. I'm
approaching the orphanage now.
Everything looks okay.
There's a bunch of kids
playing in the yard.
Holy shit.
Hey! Hold it!
Get out... get away from him!
(GUNSHOTS)
Oh, my God. Children,
inside. Hurry.
- Santa!
- What happened?!
Ricky! Come away from there.
MAN ON RADIO:
A man dressed as Santa Claus
was shot and killed
at Saint Mary's Home.
Ambulance is on the way.
I'm sorry, Sister.
But at least it's all over.
Captain, we got a problem here.
The description of the
dead man, it's all wrong.
What do you mean all wrong?
Barnes says the guy's about
50, under six feet tall.
My God.
It's Father O'Brien.
He was our Santa this year.
Kid we're looking for is 18.
Barnes wanted the guy to stop,
Captain. He didn't respond.
But of course not, he's deaf.
He couldn't hear it.
You tell Barnes to
stay at the orphanage.
The killer may still
be on his way there.
10-4.
We've got to help him.
We've just got to.
I don't understand how you could
have mistaken Father O'Brien
for the murderer in the first place.
He was dressed as a Santa Claus.
Captain Richards can explain
everything when he gets here, ma'am.
I'm sorry for what happened, but
there is a killer on the way here.
Oh, the children.
No harm must come to the
children. Do you understand?
That's why I'm here, Sister.
I am Mother Superior.
And so far, all you
have done is harm.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to check out the grounds.
In the meantime, you make sure
everyone stays locked up inside.
Don't let anybody come in unless
you know exactly who it is.
No one is going to get in
that doesn't belong here.
Poor things are scared to death.
Hmm? Oh, yes.
They need something to
keep their mind off it.
Richard.
Yes, Mother Superior.
Will you please get my pitch pipe?
Thank you.
Such a good boy.
Not at all like his
older brother William.
Children, listen to me.
I know that you're very
upset and I understand,
but I want you to stop that moping.
We're going to sing. Thank you.
- (PITCH PIPE HUMS)
- Ooh.
Ready, Sister?
"Deck the Halls."
And a-one and a-two and a-three.
♪ Deck the halls with
boughs of holly ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly ♪
♪ Don we now our gay apparel ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ Troll the ancient
Yuletide carol ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ Deck the halls with
boughs of holly ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly ♪
♪ Don we now our gay apparel ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la... ♪
- Punish!
- (GROANS)
♪ For the king of angels ♪
♪ Oh, come let us adore him ♪
♪ Christ the Lord. ♪
MOTHER SUPERIOR: All right, let's
try now "Jingle Bells." All right.
Andrew, where do you think you're
going? Come on. We need altos.
No, don't!
GIRL: It's Santa.
Chrissie, stay away.
Stay away from him.
But, Mother Superior,
it's Santa Claus.
Chrissie, stay away from him.
Hello, Santa.
Chrissie, come here.
Come here.
Andrew, come here.
There's no Santa Claus.
There is no Santa Claus.
Naughty.
BILLY: Naughty!
(GUNSHOTS)
You're safe now.
Santa Claus is gone.
Naughty.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- ♪ Do do do do ♪
- ♪ Dodo ♪
- ♪ Dodododo ♪
♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's creeping ♪
♪ Now you're nodding,
now you're sleeping ♪
♪ Were you good for Mom and Dad? ♪
♪ Santa knows if you've been bad ♪
♪ There might be a treat for you ♪
♪ In Santa's bag of toys ♪
♪ But Christmas won't
be fun and games ♪
♪ For naughty girls and boys ♪
♪ Oh, Santa's watching,
Santa's waiting ♪
♪ Everybody's celebrating ♪
♪ Did you do your best this year? ♪
♪ Too late now
'cause Santa's here ♪
- ♪ Dodo ♪
- ♪ Dodododo ♪
♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's creeping ♪
♪ Now you're nodding,
now you're sleeping ♪
♪ Were you good for Mom and Dad? ♪
♪ Santa knows if you've been bad ♪
♪ There might be a treat for you ♪
♪ In Santa's bag of toys ♪
♪ But Christmas won't
be fun and games ♪
♪ For naughty girls and boys ♪
♪ Santa's watching,
Santa's waiting ♪
♪ Everybody's celebrating ♪
♪ Did you do your best this year? ♪
♪ Too late now 'cause
Santa's here. ♪