¶¶
(Gasp)
ELAINE!
AAAARRRGH.
(screams and slashing sounds)
(gun being loaded)
(gunshot)
(engine revving and screaming)
(eerie music)
(Anderson) YOU'RE
NEVER GONNA SLEEP AGAIN.
(Hallaway) THAT'S THE POINT.
RIGHT.
LET ME KNOW IF YOU WANT TO SWITCH SEATS.
WE'RE CLOSE.
NO, THIS SHOULD'A BEEN
ALL OURS ... FUCKIN' FEDS
COME IN HERE; WE DON'T
EVEN MAKE THE LOCAL NEWS.
I'M JACKED!
THREE SURVIVING WITNESSES...
FEDS....I'M FUCKIN' JACKED!
WOW...HANDSOME...LOOKIN' GOOD.
COFFEE'S ON.
N'N'N'N'NO...THIS IS
FOR THE LITTLE ONE...
HOT CHOCOLATE.
HERE'S WHERE WE COME IN ?
EASY NOW, UH?
BOTH OF YOU...
(Anderson) OH...AND A LITTLE
GIRL, SHE'S EIGHT OR NINE
...AN' I GUESS GUESS SHE'S
NOT SAYING MUCH RIGHT NOW.
THEY'RE GUESSING.
WITH KIDS, IT'S DIFFERENT.
I'LL BE FINE BY IT. HOW 'BOUT YOU?
UH-HUH.
SHE'S GONNA BE A MESS.
AH, WE DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE SAW.
FUCK, ANDERSON! WE KNOW.
LISTEN...
THEY CALL 'EM WITNESSES
BECAUSE THEY'VE SEEN THINGS.
SO WE GO IN, FIND OUT.
YOU GOOD?
I'M GOOD.
YOU REAL GOOD?
YOU KNOW IT.
BILLINGS...
AGENT HALLAWAY.
AND THIS IS OFFICER
DEGRASSO...OFFICER WRIGHT.
AGENT ANDERSON.
AH.
UH, UP-TO-DATE WITNESS
FILES, THEY ALL DESCRIBE
THE SAME THING. HASN'T
GOTTEN US MUCH OF ANYWHERE.
WE'RE PRETTY SURE WE KNOW
WHAT WERE DEALING WITH HERE.
AND THEY ALL ARRIVED
TOGETHER, LATE YESTERDAY?
YEAH, THAT'S THE WAY IT HAPPENED.
ONE OF OUR OFFICERS BROUGHT THEM
IN, UH HE'S IN THERE TOO, HE...
HE'S ALSO A WITNESS.
I UNDERSTAND ONE OF
YOUR OFFICERS WAS KILLED?
YEAH. JIM. JIM CONRAD.
NOW, UH THE YOUNG WOMAN...
SHE SEEMS TO BE INTOXICATED
OR IN SHOCK; THE CHILD...
THE 'YOUNG WOMAN' IS
HIGH AS A FUCKIN' KITE.
AS I WAS SAYING...
THE CHILD HASN'T SAID MUCH OF ANYTHING.
HOWEVER, SHE HAS BONDED
WITH THE YOUNG WOMAN...
BOBBI...BOBBI PRESCOTT.
AND IS THIS ALL SHE SAID?
UH, YEAH, ONLY WHAT WE TOOK NOTES ON.
THE...THINGS THAT HAVE HAPPENED
TO HER, YOU CAN'T BLAME HER.
AND YOU HAVE NO FEMALE
OFFICERS HERE, IS THAT RIGHT?
HAVE TWO OF YOU ALWAYS BEEN PRESENT?
WELL I WAS THERE... HI, I'M JANET.
WELCOME, I COULD, CAN
I GET COFFEE FOR ANY...
YOU KNOW, THAT LITTLE GIRL'S
NAME, HER NAME'S STEPHANIE...
'CAUSE OFFICER BENNETT TOLD ME
THAT HER NAME WAS STEPHANIE...
WE'LL NEED TO SEPARATE
THEM FOR THE INTERVIEWS.
THEY REALLY SHOULD HAVE BEEN
KEPT APART DURING THE NIGHT...
I TRUST MY OFFICER.
I NEVER SAID I DIDN'T...UH...
YOU KNOW...I'M SURE THAT
PROPER PROCEDURES WERE FOLLOWED,
AGENT HALLAWAY.
IT'S JUST...INTERESTING...THAT
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT BROUGHT UP
THE TRUST THING.
GREAT. UH, SAM?
I'M GONNA TAKE A MINUTE
WITH THE LITTLE GIRL, SAM.
TAKE A FEW MINUTES...YEAH...
SO, WE BROUGHT EQUIPMENT WITH US,
WHILE I'M IN TALKING
WITH HER, YOU GUYS SET IT
UP...ROOMS...CAMERAS.
EVERYBODY WORK TOGETHER,
WE'RE GONNA GET GOING FASTER.
RIGHT-RIGHT IN HERE?
DO, DO YOU THINK IF I
BROUGHT IN SOME COFFEE...
WHY DON'T YOU ASK HIM...
HEY, STEPHANIE, MY NAME IS
ELIZABETH...AND WE'RE GONNA TRY
AND TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED, OKAY?
AND IT'S GONNA HELP YOU FEEL BETTER.
YOU F.B.I.?
YEAH...YEAH...
YOU GONNA BUST ME?
FOR NOW, NO.
THE ONLY ROLE YOUR NARCOTIC
USE PLAYS IS IN HOW IT MAY HAVE
AFFECTED YOUR PERCEPTION
OF THE EVENTS...
I KNOW WHAT I SAW.
YEAH.
SO WHATCHA GOT THERE,
STEPHANIE? A VIDEO GAME?
YOU LIKE PLAYING GAMES? HMM?
SO...
THERE'S A...
PAIR OF PANTS UNDER THAT SKIRT, HUH?
UH, YOU KNOW THE EQUIPMENT
SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT...
IT'S IN THE TRUNK OF MY CAR.
(Wright) I'M ON IT!
ACTUALLY IT'S QUITE A BIT OF
EQUIPMENT, CAPTAIN, SO...MAYBE,
DEGRASSO.
GIVE WRIGHT A HAND.
C'MON NOW.
AGENT, CAN I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
UH...IT'S JUST PROCEDURE,
I LIKE TO SEPARATE 'EM, PUT 'EM ON TAPE.
I KNOW ONE OF YOUR OFFICERS IS IN THERE,
BUT...THERE'S ONLY ONE
WAY TO UNFOLD A NOTE,
SO TO SPEAK...WITHOUT TEARING THE PAPER.
YEAH THAT'S WHAT I FIGURED.
SO LET'S LOOK AND SEE WHAT WE'RE....
WELL THAT'S NOT WHAT
I WANTED TO ASK YOU.
UH... YOU GOT A CIGARETTE?
NO, SORRY.
AH.
¶¶
STEPHANIE?
WE'RE GONNA TALK, RIGHT?
I WANT TO GO HOME.....
I KNOW YOU DO, STEPHANIE...
I KNOW.
ARE YOU FUCKING KIDDIN' ME?
JANET!
COULD YOU GET US A LIGHT IN HERE?
IT IS FUCKING DARK IN
HERE. THERE'S NO LIGHT!
RIGHT...YEAH, THESE WERE....
(Hallaway) THESE SHOULDN'T
BE BE HERE, TAKE 'EM DOWN.
(Billings) YEAH...
YOU GUYS GIVE ME A
HAND WHEN YOU'RE DONE?
DO YOU HAVE SOME CRAYONS IN YOUR BAG?
THEY WERE IN THE CAR.
I HAVE SOME CRAYONS,
I THINK, IN THE OFFICE.
OH, GREAT. COULD YOU GET THOSE, JANET?
YEAH. AND, UH, SOME PAPER... AND...
I THINK I'M GONNA BRING BACK
SOME MORE MARSHMALLOWS, OKAY?
STEPHANIE?
SO WHILE WE'RE TALKING YOU COULD
DO SOME DRAWING FOR ME, YEAH?
I GOTTA...I GOTTA GO TO THE BATHROOM.
OKAY. IN A MINUTE.
THAT AGENT LADY, YOU KNOW, SHE
WANTS THESE FOR THE LITTLE GIRL.
CRAYONS?
HOO! ...BOY
THOSE F.B.I. AGENTS...THINK OF
THINGS NO BEAT COP EVER WOULD.
(goofy laugh)
WHAT...IS THE MATTER?
WHAT, ARE YOU TWO YEARS OLD?
SO YOU KNOW, RIGHT?
I'M SORRY?
THESE TWO...
FUCKING...MASKED FUCKERS...
OFFICER?
I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH
A REALLY ROUGH TIME...
BUT LET'S WORK TOWARDS
MAKING THIS A SAFE SPACE.
I'M GONNA ASK YOU TO
WATCH YOUR LANGUAGE.
HUH, HUH, SAFE...
I REALLY HAVE TO USE THE BATHROOM.
OKAY, BOBBI, YOU CAN GO.
GO ON.
HI.
USE THE TOILET.
SO HOW WE DOIN'?
WE'RE ALL JUST FUCKING SWELL MR. F.B.I.
OFFICER BENNETT?
AGENT HALLAWAY.
MM.
I GATHER YOU TWO, UH, SWOOPED
INTO TOWN ALL SUITED UP TO
FINISH WHAT I STARTED?
I SEE THE TENSIONS BETWEEN OUR
DEPARTMENTS ARE ALIVE AND WELL.
MY PARTNER AND I, WE HAVE MANY
MONTHS INVESTED IN THIS CASE...
MY PARTNER INVESTED
HIS LIFE IN THIS CASE.
HIS AND YOUR INVOLVEMENT
IN THESE INCIDENTS WILL NOT
GO...UNCREDITED.
THE HAND...
HOW YA DOIN'?
LIKE I SAID...'
WE'RE ALL JUST FUCKING SWELL'.
NEXT TIME YOU NEED TO PEE...
SOMEONE GOES WITH YOU.
I'M A WITNESS, NOT A SUSPECT.
I KNOW WHAT YOU ARE.
AND I ALSO KNOW HOW TO
PERVERT A CAVITY SEARCH.
WOW, I HAVEN'T DONE A
GIRL SINCE ART SCHOOL.
OH! IT'S JUST LIKE RIDING A BIKE.
YES, MA'AM.
OKAY, GIRLS, UHHH, WE'LL DO
THE INTERVIEWS SEPARATELY, SO...
JANET AND THE OFFICERS
WILL SHOW YOU WHERE TO GO.
JACK...
SAM, GO EASY.
EASY?
YEAH. REMEMBER WHY WE'RE HERE.
I REMEMBER WHY WE'RE HERE...
AGENT.
I'M GOOD.
REAL GOOD.
JANET WORKED THE MUSHROOM
LAMP FOR THE AMBIENCE.
REALLY LIVENS THE PLACE UP, DOESN'T IT?
IT'S ALRIGHT, SWEETHEART.
IT'S JUST A CAMERA.
(growl) F.B.I.
CAN WE PLEASE HAVE OFFICER
BENNETT TAKE HIS SEAT AT
THE TABLE, PLEASE?
C'MON JACK. TAKE A SEAT IN THE CHAIR.
EVERYONE?
WE'RE GONNA BE STARTING
WITH YESTERDAY MORNING.
JIM AND I ...WERE HAVING COFFEE...
RICHARD RAMIREZ!
OH.
JEFF 'HUNGRY-MAN' DAHMER...
OH. DIED IN PRISON!
AMEN, BUDDY.
YEAH. THAT'LL TEACH YA TO SWEEP.
JOHN WAYNE GACY.
FUCKIN' MANSON FAMILY.
WE'LL GET OURS...
YEAH...
I'M STILL KINDA DRUNK.
I DO SO LOVE THE LADIES.
FAITHFUL LADIES.
WE PULLED THE DRIVER OVER...
HE SAID HE'D BEEN DELIVERING
GROCERIES ON CAMROSE...
SAID HE'D SEEN SOMETHING...
SOMETHING TERRIBLE.
WASN'T LIKE YOU'D THINK...
SO JOHNNY AND I DROVE ALL THIS WAY
TO SEE THIS GUY ABOUT A JOB...
¶¶
HEY.
WHAT'S UP, BUCKET?
MISTER HORNS?
WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
HEY. HAVE A SEAT.
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND?
THIS IS BOBBI.
HI.
HI...
YEAH, I AM...
(Laughter)
SPEAKIN' OF...CAN I GET THE USUAL?
AND...
WE HAD OUR INTERVIEW...
YOU UH, YOU WANT A DRINK?
GOT SOME, UH, LEFTOVERS
IN THE REFRIGERATOR.
GOD NO, UM, WE'VE ACTUALLY,
WE GOTTA GET GOIN'.
SO...WE'LL SEE YOU LATER.
(coughs and wheezes)
JESUS CHRIST...JUST A SEC.
BUCKET...YOU ALRIGHT?
RAISE YOUR HANDS ABOVE YOUR HEAD...
NOT YOU.
JESUS CHRIST...
(vomits and chokes)
BUCKET!
OH SHIT...
THE INTERVIEW...
ENDED PRETTY ABRUPTLY.
WHATEVER DOESN'T FIT IN YOUR
POCKETS GOES IN MY PURSE.
GOT IT.
SHIT.
GET THE LIGHTER.
LIGHTER. GET THE PIPES.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELL, I'LL TALK TO YOU SOON.
C'MON.
SEE YA!
WE WERE PRETTY SURE
WE DIDN'T GET THE JOB.
WAIT WAIT WAIT WAIT WAIT...
YOU MEAN HE DIDN'T JUST...
HIRE YOU ON THE SPOT?
OH. NO. WE WEREN'T
INTERVIEWING TO BE COPS.
ALRIGHT ALRIGHT...
LET'S...GO ON.
THAT'S IT. WE LEFT.
HE TOOK FOUR DAYS OFF
OF WORK, PLUS A WEEKEND,
SO WE COULD HAVE A VACATION.
EVERYBODY DOIN' OKAY?
YEP. YEAH.
I THINK YOU WEAR THIS
'FATHER' THING PRETTY WELL.
WELL WITH THESE KIDS, IT'S EASY.
THANK YOU.
MY MOTHER KEPT SAYING OVER AND
OVER WHAT A NICE THING IT WAS
FOR HIM TO DO.
(Anderson) IT'S GOOD FOR
PEOPLE TO GET AWAY SOMETIMES...
(Stephanie) I GUESS.
BUT I LIKED WHERE I WAS TO BEGIN WITH.
MOMMY.
YEAH.
LOOK WHAT I DREW.
OH! LOOK AT THAT! OH, HONEY.
YOU ARE SO TALENTED.
THANK YOU.
IT'S GREAT...THE ANTS...
NO, HONEY, THEY'RE BEARS.
...THE BEARS...
(Stephanie) BEAVERS.
THE BEAVERS.
OFFICER BENNETT...?
YEAH.
YEAH...UM...YOU AND YOUR
PARTNER WERE FIRST ON THE SCENE,
AM I CORRECT ABOUT THAT?
THAT'S CORRECT.
RIGHT, UH, AFTER THE
GROCERY DELIVERY MAN...
IF YOU COULD CONTINUE,
PLEASE, OFFICER BENNETT?
KEEP GOING.
THE GUYS FROM
'CRIME-SCENE' SHOWED AN'...
WE LEFT.
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING?
SHE'S GOOD-LOOKING.
HE USED TO BE, TOO.
SO... WE'RE DRIVING ALONG...
GOOD GIRL!
(laugh) YEAH.
OOF!
YES!
AW, THAT IS SOME GOOD SHIT.
OK, OK, C'MON!
SHIT! SORRY ...I FORGOT WHO'S DRIVIN'!
WHO AM I?
NO, IT'S COOL.
LET'S SEE...WE...
STOPPED. TO STRETCH.
THAT'S GOOD...
STRETCHING.
IT'S GOOD.
AND THAT'S WHEN WE FIRST SAW
THE LITTLE GIRL, STEPHANIE.
STOP! SERIOUSLY! GOD DAMN IT, STOP!
WHY, WHADDYA HAVE TO PEE?
DON'T ACT LIKE AN
ASSHOLE. THERE'S A FAMILY.
HEY, IT'S THE ELEPHANT AT THE
REST STOP NOBODY TALKS ABOUT.
OH, OK, 'BILL W.' OH. HELLO.
(Snorts)
(Television Reporter) WHERE
A GRISLY DISCOVERY WAS MADE.
POLICE FEEL CERTAIN THAT
THIS IS THE WORK OF THE TWO,
AS YET UNIDENTIFIED SUSPECTS,
WHO HAVE LEFT A SERIES OF
VICTIMS ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
A PRESS CONFERENCE IS SCHEDULED
FOR LATER THIS AFTERNOON AFTER
FURTHER EXAMINATION OF THE SCENE
AND THE BODY DISCOVERED INSIDE.
POLICE URGE ALL CITIZENS OF THE AREA TO
KEEP THEIR DOORS LOCKED,
AND TO IMMEDIATELY REPORT ANY
ACTIVITIES THAT APPEAR OUT
OF THE NORMAL...AS WELL AS ANY
SIGHTINGS OF THE MISSING WOMAN,
ELAINE MEYER, PICTURED HERE.
I'M NOT ALLOWED TO
WATCH THE NEWS AT HOME.
SOME THINGS CHILDREN SHOULDN'T SEE.
THAT'S WHAT MY MOM SAYS...
I MEAN...SAID.
I'M SO SORRY, STEPHANIE.
OH.
THAT POOR LITTLE GIRL...
CHILDREN CAN BE VERY RESILIENT.
I THINK IT'S A SHAME MAKIN G
HER RE-LIVE ALL THOSE THINGS...
NO, I MEAN, I KNOW, OF COURS
E YOU'RE JUST DOING YOUR JOB,
I KNOW THAT...IT'S JUST...YOU
HAVE TO DO THIS, RIGHT?
I HAVE TO KNOW WHAT THEY'VE SEEN.
UH...
EVERY DETAIL, RIGHT?
OH YEAH...OH YEAH. EVERY DETAIL.
OH GOD, I JUST...I JUST...OH.
YOU NEED THE INFORMATION
AND SPEAKING OF...
IT'S THE CORONER'S REPORT.
I'M 'FRIENDS' WITH THE CORONER.
YEAH.
WELL...THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
UM...NO LAB RESULTS?
NO, NO, HE'S RUSHING THOSE BUT
HE SAID IT'S JUST GOING TO TAKE
HIM A LONG TIME TO COLLECT IT ALL.
DID HE SAY WHAT HE'S COLLECTING?
I MEAN, DID HE MENTION...
BALLISTICS?
NO. BUT YOU KNOW HE IS
BIG ON HAIR AND FIBERS.
IT'S KIND OF HIS...SPECIALTY.
APPARENTLY THEY LEFT A LOT OF THAT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M WONDERING?
WHY WOULD THEY BE SO SLOPPY?
THEY'RE LIKELY TO IMPROVE.
OH. OF COURSE. YEAH.
UNLESS, MA'AM...
THEY JUST DON'T GIVE A SHIT.
OH MY GOD...
WHAT WE DO TO EACH OTHER, HUH?
MMH.
WHAT ARE YOU TWO DOIN' IN HERE?
THE UH, THE GIRL...BOBBI?
SHE HAD TO PISS.
AH.
WHY DON'T YOU GO AND MAKE
SURE SHE GETS BACK IN THE ROOM?
GO ON NOW...
OKAY!
AND WHY DON'T YOU GO KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
ALRIGHT. THEN?
WE HAVE, UH, AREAS WE PATROL.
OOOOOH!
NICE SHOT!
LOOKIT HIM!
ALRIGHT.
PICK YOUR FUCKIN' PERSONALITY.
I GET TO PICK?
I AM CLEARLY 'GOOD COP.'
MMM...THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
FRIEND TO THE PEOPLE!
'GOOD COP'!
WE PATROLLED THEM.
I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING WITH YOU
HELLO OFFICER, LOOKS
LIKE I HAD A TIRE BLOW...
THAT'S WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE, HUH?
I GOT A SOLID SPARE, SO...
YEAH, WELL, I'M AFRAID I'M GOING
TO HAVE TO ASK YOU TO GET BACK
IN THE VEHICLE FOR THE MOMENT.
IS THERE A PROBLEM, OFFICER?
WELL, SIR...UH.
UH, KEITH.
OH. KEITH. OKAY. HI.
UM.. THERE'S NO PROBLEM WITH ME...
BUT YOU SEE MY PARTNER BACK THERE...?
YES SIR...HE LOOKS UPSET.
YEAH.
WELL...
WE GOT A COUPLE OF KILLERS
LOOSE...EVERYONE'S WOUND UP
PRETTY GOOD ABOUT IT BUT JACK THERE;
HE'S WOUND ESPECIALLY TIGHT.
UH, WE HEARD SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT ON THE RADIO...
OH NO NO, IT IS WORSE THAN
THEY'RE SAYING ON THE RADIO.
TRUST ME. AND JACK THERE
IS, WELL, LIKE I SAID,
PRETTY WOUND UP AND WE SAW
YOU GUYS COMING DOWN THE ROAD,
AND HE SWEARS THAT YOU WERE
PULLIN' TOO MUCH SPEED...
OH, JEEZ, I WASN'T
SPEEDING, OFFICER, I, I,
REALLY I WAS GOING...NOT
SPEEDING...SIR...
NO. NO. NO. RELAX,
KEITH. THAT'S WHAT I SAID.
YOU'RE 'PREACHING TO THE
CHOIR'. THAT'S WHAT I TOLD HIM.
IT WAS JUST A NORMAL SPEED, I
WAS GOING DOWN THE ROAD AND HAD
A TIRE BLOW OUT, I'M NOT...
YEAH, I KNOW. I TOLD HIM. AN
D HE DIDN'T LIKE IT WHEN I DID.
HERE HE COMES... ACT CASUAL.
GET DOWN ON THE FUCKING GROUND.
WHOA...UH...
GET DOWN ON THE FUCKING GROUND! NOW!
(Woman) GET DOWN, KEITH!
GO!
OH. WHOA, WHOA, WHOA... MA'AM!
PLEASE RETURN TO THE VEHICLE.
KEITH, HONEY...?
(Keith) PLEASE DON'T SHOOT ME!
I'LL BE IN THE CAR, HONEY....
PLEASE OFFICERS!
I'M GOING TO ASK YOU TO GET YOUR WALLET
AND GIVE IT TO MY PARTNER.
KEITH, IT'S BEST TO DO WHAT HE SAYS,
BECAUSE WHEN HE GETS LIKE
THIS...IT'S JUST REALLY CRUCIAL
THAT HE FEELS LIKE YOU'RE LISTENING.
I'M LISTENING.... PLEASE
DON'T SHOOT ME, OFFICER!
WE LET HIM GO WITH A WARNING...
(Gunshots)
YOU KNOW HOW PEOPLE
GET OUT HERE, CAPTAIN...
YEAH.
THE WAY THEY START DRIVING
IN THE DESOLATE STRETCHES...
LIKE THE RACECAR DRIVERS
THEY ALWAYS WANTED TO BE.
SPEEDING IS THE NUMBER ONE CAUSE
OF TRAFFIC FATALITIES, YOU KNOW.
NOT THIS WEEK.
I'LL BE, UH, GETTIN' BACK TO IT NOW.
THAT'S AN EXCELLENT PLAN, WRIGHT.
YOU GETTIN' COFFEE?
LIGHT AND SWEET FOR ME, THERE, CHIEF.
SOMETHING I CAN DO FOR YOU, DEGRASSO?
JUST, UH, ENJOYING YOUR WORK.
HOW ABOUT YOU LET ME
ENJOY SOME OF YOURS?
GO ON...
I THINK MAKING HIM ANGRY
IS A REALLY BAD IDEA.
OH, GEE MOM....TELL DAD
I'M REAL FUCKIN' SORRY.
HEY. AN ATTITUDE CHANGE, PLEASE?
IS THERE ANY MORE HOT CHOCOLATE?
UH, OF COURSE THERE
IS...CAN I KEEP THIS?
I DREW IT FOR YOU.
IT'S GREAT...
ALRIGHT, I'LL GO GET YOU
THA T HOT CHOCOLATE...
YOU'LL BE BE ALRIGHT, ON YOUR OWN?
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
¶¶
HAVIN' FUN?
YEAH!
YEAH...
THIS IS WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
BEAUTIFUL DAY.
YEAH!
YEAH, IT'S PERFECT.
HEY...
I'LL BE DAMNED....
YEAH, I THOUGHT IT WAS
PRETTY AMAZING MYSELF.
SHE HASN'T SAID MUCH.
WELL, I'M WORKING ON IT.
YOU'RE GOOD WITH HER.
YEAH.
WELL, I WAS ONCE A
SAD LITTLE GIRL MYSELF.
DON'T GO GETTING EMOTIONALLY INVOLVED...
THAT'S NOT WHAT THIS THIS
IS ABOUT AND YOU KNOW IT.
IT... IT'S BRINGING UP A LOT OF STUFF...
A LOT OF...
YOU CAN'T SAVE HER...
I KNOW.
HERE YOU GO...
THANK YOU.
WATCH...IT'S KIND OF HOT.
(Bobbi) YOU LIKE BEIN' A COP?
YOU LIKE BEING A FUCK-UP?
HEY, DEGRASSO...
I DON'T LIKE THIS ...LADY.
...REALLY?
MM-NN.
(Intercom) LET'S KEEP
THE PACE, OFFICERS.
YEAH.
LET'S...KEEP THE PACE.
YOU HEARD THE AGENT, BOBBI...
CHOP! CHOP!
SO, WE WERE JUST DRIVING ALONG...
ONE FOR YOU...
NO, I DON'T WANT ANOTHER ONE!
DO YOU WANT ME TO BE ABLE TO
DRIVE THE CAR OR DO YOU WANT ME
TO, LIKE, GO INTO CARDIAC ARREST?
OKAY... ONE MORE.
OKAY... I'M NOT DOIN'
ANOTHER ONE, NO WAY...
YOU... UH-UH, YOU DO IT. YOU DO IT.
YOU'RE DOIN' IT.
I'M NOT DOIN' IT.
I'LL GRAB YOUR FUCKIN' TITS RIGHT NOW...
I SWEAR TO GOD I I WILL...
OH THEN I'M REALLY NOT
DOIN', I'M, I'M DONE.
I'M SO NOT DOIN' IT.
BRING IT ON!
PROMISES, PROMISES...
OH, SHIT!
OWWWWWWW!
I'LL DO IT...
WHOOOOOO!
(Bobbi) I LOVE THIS SONG.
(Johnny) YOU LOVE EVERY FUCKIN' SONG.
¶¶
MOM!
MOM, I SAW SOMETHING!
(Mom) OH, NOW WE'RE TALKING!
(Dad) OLD SCHOOL!
MOM!
¶¶
¶¶ WHY CAN'T I GET JUST ONE KISS? ¶¶
¶¶ THERE MAY BE SOME THINGS
THAT I WOULDN'T MISS. ¶¶
¶¶ BUT I LOOK AT YOUR
PANTS AND I NEED A KISS ¶¶
¶¶ WHY CAN'T I GET JUST ONE SCREW? ¶¶
WATCH THE ROAD... WATCH THE ROAD!
¶¶
SEE NOW THIS IS MUSIC, DAVID.
THIS IS ROCK!
THIS ROCKS, BABY.
WHOA!
(gasp!)
JUST ONE DUCK!
COVER YOUR EARS...
YOU GUYS ARE GREAT.
ONE DUCK!
NO ONE HEARD ME.
PEOPLE JUST WEREN'T
THEMSELVES YESTERDAY...
FINISH UP, JIM.
WE GOT ONE.
WHADYA' KNOW...MOTHER
FUCKER IS SPEEDING.
YOU GONNA TAKE THAT?
GUESS.
OHHHHHHH!
WHOO HOO HOO!
UNBELIEVABLE!
THAT'S SUPERNATURAL.
I'M A LITTLE HARD RIGHT
NOW, I GOTTA TELL YA.
¶¶ SHOOT SHOOT SHOOT
THAT THING AT ME. ¶¶
¶¶ YOU KNOW YOU'VE GOT MY SYMPATHY ¶¶
¶¶ BUT DON'T SHOOT SHOOT
SHOOT THAT THING AT ME. ¶¶
¶¶
NEAT.
SO LET'S TRY IT AGAIN .
WELL THIS IS THE REAL THING.
WE STOPPED TO HELP...
(gasp!)
(scream) SHIT! FUCK!
I ALMOST JUST HAD A HEART ATTACK.
LIKE THIS.
SO CLOSE.
MMM. THAT IS CLOSE.
YOU SHOULD'A SEEN BOBBI'S FACE...
SHE WAS SO SCARED.
I'LL BET YOU WERE ALL SCARED.
FLATS SUCK.
I DON'T WANNA SEE ANYONE
ELSE DIE TODAY, PLEASE HON'?
NO SHIT...
GOD...
THE LADY...IS A FUCKIN' SAINT, RIGHT?
YEAH...SHE IS.
WE STOPPED.
THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
WE GAVE 'EM A HAND.
THEY WERE FUCKIN' STRANDED.
OH GOD...
WHERE YOU GOIN'?
AH, I WAS GONNA GO START
THE PAPERWORK ON LITTLE MISS
SHITTY'S GOOD DEED AWARD.
WOW...HE NEEDS A WOMAN.
HMM.
ME TOO.
LET'S GO DO SOME BAD.
IT COULD HAVE BEEN A REAL MESS, CAPTAIN.
I'M TELLING YOU...
HELLO, DADDY!
OH MY GOD, HIS SHIRT
SAYS MISCHIEF SAUSAGE.
NO, IT DOES, LOOK AT IT.
IT SAYS MISCHIEF SAUSAGE.
WHATEVER, MAN.
LOOK AT HIM!
(gasp)OH MY...
OH MAN...
OH WE'RE FUCKED.
OH MY GOD.... FUCK...
FUCK FUCK FUCK FUCK FUCK...
HAND OUT OF NOSE!
FINGER OUT OF NOSE!
WANT ANOTHER ONE?
JUST KEEP IT REAL.
JUST BE COOL.
DON'T LOOK BACK.
DON'T LOOK BACK!
IT'S OKAY, OFFICER, IT'S A...
IT'S A FLAT. THAT'S ALL.
(Chortling)
(On speaker) LISTEN UP, FOLKS.
GET BACK INSIDE YOUR VEHICLE...
AND LEAVE THE ENGINE ENGINE OFF.
WE'RE GOING TO FUCK IN THE CLINK.
YOU KNOW IT.
(Anderson) YOU'RE
DOING GREAT, SWEETHEART,
I KNOW IT'S NOT EASY.
I DON'T KNOW HONEY...IT'S
PROBABLY PROCEDURAL.
OFFICER...HI...FINE...
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
DON'T LOOK BACK!
I'M NOT!
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO KNOW IF
I'M NOT ALLOWED TO LOOK BACK?
JUST SHUT UP!
FUCK. NOW THE CHARGE IS DYING. GREAT.
DAVID, WATCH YOUR LANGUAGE.
DO I GOT SHIT UP MY
NOSE? DO I GOT CHUNKS?
DO I? NO, LOOK!
'NOTHER ONE?
YEAH...
DAD?
IT'S OKAY, HONEY. JUST SIT TIGHT.
I SAW SOMETHING...
WELL I SEE SOMETHING TOO, BEAN.
HONEY, PASS ME THE INSURANCE
AND REGISTRATION WILL YA?
I'LL TAKE THE STATION
WAGON, YOU TAKE THE DUSTER,
AND THEN WE'LL SWITCH.
OH, DIG IT. ALRIGHT...
I CAN'T FUCKING BELIEVE THIS!
WATCH YOUR LANGUAGE, MOM.
ALRIGHT.
YOU REALLY WANNA POKE THE BEAR, DAVID?
OKAY SETTLE DOWN!
WHERE THE HELL IS HE?
OH SHIT!
HI.
HI...HOW YA DOIN'?
GOOD.
KINDA SNUCK UP ON YA, DIDN'T I?
YOU DID!
YOU KNOW, YOU WERE PULLING
A PRETTY BIG NUMBER.
I'M SORRY, YOU KNOW, I JUST...
I, I DIDN'T EVEN NOTICE.
YOU GUYS WERE DRIVIN' PRETTY FAST.
NO... OH.... SHE'S PRETTY.
BUT WE WEREN'T DRIVING FAST.
OH... COME ON...
I'M SOFT WHEN IT COMES TO TH E
SPEED LIMIT...I GREW UP HERE...
PULLED A FEW RACE CAR
MOVES OUT HERE MYSELF.
WE'RE AWFULLY SORRY, OFFICER.
YEAH I GOT THAT, AND I UNDERSTAND.
UH, SEE, THERE IS ONE ISSUE, THOUGH.
MY, MY PARTNER.
YOU'RE TIMING'S BAD
BECAUSE MY PARTNER...
LAST YEAR HE LOST HIS FAMILY
IN A TRAFFIC INCIDENT LIKE THIS.
HE LOST HIS WIFE AND SON
TO A SPEEDING COLLISION.
AW, IT WAS HORRIBLE!
HE HAD A WIFE.
HAD A COUPLE O' KIDS.
AND NOW HE GOES HOME...
AND HE EATS A TV DINNER.
AND YOU CAN'T IMAGINE..THE
DEPTH OF GRIEF...
NO...
HE WEPT...IN A FETAL
POSITION FOR OVER A YEAR.
I HELD HIM TIGHT.
OH, IT'S HYSTERICAL, ISN'T IT?
NO. IT'S NOT.
YEAH. GIVE ME YOUR FUCKIN' WALLET.
MY I.D.?
NO, I'LL NEED YOUR WALLET.
WE'VE MOVED PAST I.D. TO WALLET.
I'LL NEED YOUR WALLET AS WELL.
YEAH. OKAY.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY ABOUT
GUYS WHO DRIVE RED CARS?
NO.
I'LL BE BACK IN A MINUTE, ALRIGHT?
OKAY...
THEY DON'T SAY THAT ABOUT
GUYS WHO DRIVE RED CARS...
FUCK, BUT WHAT THE FUCK,
WE SHOULD GET RID OF THIS...
BAD NEWS. SPEEDER KILLED YOUR FAMILY.
YOURS, TOO.
HEY, SINGLE AGAIN.
THOSE KIDS ARE HIGH.
YOU KNOW, YOU MIGHT
WANNA SEARCH THE CAR.
YOU SMELL MONEY?
NAW... JUST BEER.
AW FUCK IT, THEN.
CHECK OUT THE MOM.
SHE LOOKS LIKE THAT
SKIRT FROM WOOD SHOP.
OH! ALRIGHT...
SHIT.
WHAT?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
HERE COMES MY PARTY.
GREAT...
WHERE'S THE FUCKIN' FIRE?
HEY...HEY...HEY...HEY...HEY!
OH SHUT UP! OH 'HEY' WHAT?
GET YOUR FUCKIN' ASS ON THE GROUND.
ALRIGHT.
NOW YOU BE REAL FUCKIN'
QUIET...OR ELSE I'M GONNA BLOW
YOU A NEW SHITTER. YOU UNDERSTAND?
OH FUCK...
PUT YOUR HANDS ON THE WHEEL.
LOOK AT HIM.
TELL YOUR JUNKIE BOYFRIEND, TELL HIM...
TELL HIM YOU DON'T LOVE LOVE HIM.
I DON'T LOVE YOU.
MEAN IT.
FUCKING MEAN IT!
I DON'T LOVE YOU!
FUCK...HE DRIVE LIKE THIS ALL THE TIME?
NO, NO, NEVER, I SWEAR...
AW, YOU'RE PROTECTING HIM.
THAT'S SWEET. I GET IT.
YOU SETTLED, DIDN'T YA?
WHAT?
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, YOU GET SCARED...
I GET IT.
SAY...
'I HATE YOU'.
I HATE YOU.
FUCKING MEAN IT!
I HATE YOU!
MEAN IT! ! !
FUCK...
LOOK THE OTHER FUCKING WAY.
ALRIGHT. C'MON. GIMME A LITTLE SUGAR.
C'MON.
GIMME A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S OKAY.
DON'T CRY. IT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE GONNA BE ALRIGHT.
EESH...
WHAT A DAY!
YOU DON'T FUCKING MOVE.
AND YOU GET YOUR FUCKING
ASS OUTTA THE CAR, WHORE!
IT'S BEAUTIFUL OUT HERE, HUH?
SOMETIMES I COME OUT
HERE JUST TO THINK...
Y'KNOW, GET MY HEAD STRAIGHT.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE IN THIS SAD PREDICAMENT
BECAUSE YOU DRIVE TOO FUCKIN' FAST.
RIGHT?
NOW, I'M COOL...
BUT I'M FAIR.
RIGHT?
SO WE'LL LET IT GO.
MM! YOU SMELL GOOD!
WHAT IS THAT?
LOUDER.
FIFTY-FIVE SAVES LIVES.
OKAY CALM DOWN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO ONE LAST THING,
JUST SO I'M THE BOSS GUY, RIGHT?
I WANT YOU TO PUT THIS RIGHT
IN YOUR FUCKIN' MOUTH...
C'MON, OPEN YOUR MOUTH.
FUCKIN' OPEN UP YOUR MOUTH.
HUH?
OPEN UP YOUR FUCKIN'
MOUTH! DO IT. DO IT.
NOW SLAP ME IN THE FACE.
WHEN YOU GET BACK IN THAT CAR,
YOU'RE GOING TO DRIVE
AT A SAFE SPEED, RIGHT?
OKAY.
I'M ALL ABOUT SAFETY.
THAT'S HOW I DO IT.
OKAY.
NOW I BET THE KIDS ARE
A LITTLE WORRIED, RIGHT?
SO LET'S MAKE A 'SNOW
ANGEL' RIGHT NOW, GO AHEAD.
SNOW ANGEL!
C'MON. YOU AND ME. SNOW ANGEL?
NO! FUCK...
GET BACK IN THE CAR.
DON'T!
ARE YOU OKAY?
YEAH...
FUCK...
I DIDN'T MEAN IT, YOU KNOW THAT, RIGHT?
LOOK AT HIM, EVEN HIGH IN
HIS DRIVER'S LICENSE PICTURE.
THEY'LL BE GONE IN A FEW MINUTES.
IT'S ALMOST OVER.
STEPH JUST GOT OUT OF THE CAR!
OH SHIT!
GET BACK IN THE CAR, SIR!
MY MOM SAID YOU'D BE
GONE IN A FEW MINUTES.
WELL YEAH...IN A FEW MINUTES.
I TRIED TO TELL MY PARENTS
BUT THE MUSIC WAS TOO LOUD.
TRIED TO TELL THEM WHAT?
I SAW SOMETHING BAD...
WHAT DID YOU SEE?
THERE WAS A WHITE CAR AND A BLUE CAR.
AND THE BLUE CAR HAD SMASHED-UP
WINDOWS AND BLOOD ALL OVER IT.
YOU BEEN WATCHING SCARY MOVIES?
MY MOM DOESN'T LET ME.
ALRIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR TELLING
US THAT, SWEETHEART.
AND WE ARE GONNA TAKE CARE OF THAT OKAY?
HOW ABOUT YOU AND ME
GO BACK TO YOUR CAR?
YOUR DAD LOOKS WORRIED.
I KNOW WHAT BLOOD LOOKS LIKE.
YOUR DAUGHTER'S A BRAVE LITTLE GIRL.
GOOD NEWS.
WE WON'T BE TICKETING YOU FOR SPEEDING.
ALRIGHT? I TOOK CARE OF THAT.
YOU KNOW, I COULD REPORT YOUR PARTNER.
BUT HE WON'T!
I WOULD JUST LET THIS GO,
SIR...WITH MY APOLOGIES.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU
SAID TO HIM BUT WHATEVER IT WAS
IT REALLY DID THE TRICK, BECAUSE
HE IS GRINNIN' LIKE A MONKEY!
YOU FOLKS GOT A GOOD SPARE IN THE TRUNK?
WE SURE DO, OFFICER.
WE'LL BE JUST FINE.
SO THANK YOU FOR THAT, Y'KNOW,
'CAUSE I GOTTA RIDE WITH HIM ALL
DAY. WELL HERE YOU GO...
WELL YOU ALL HAVE A GREAT DAY, ALRIGHT?
ALRIGHT. TAKE CARE.
FUCKIN' ASSHOLE...
STEPH, HONEY...WHAT DID YOU
SAY TO THE POLICE OFFICERS?
I TOLD THEM I SAW SOMETHING.
YOU WEREN'T LISTENING.
YOU COULD HAVE REALLY GOTTEN
YOUR FATHER IN TROUBLE...
HE'S NOT MY FATHER.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEANT.
FUCK.
MOM, 'ARE WE THERE YET?'
ALRIGHT.
THIN ICE, DAVID.
WANNA DO ANOTHER ONE?
YES...I DO...
STEPHANIE, WHERE IS YOUR FATHER?
WE SHOULD CONTACT HIM.
MY FATHER'S DEAD.
SOCCER MOM'S THIRSTY.
BRING HER A BEER.
I'M FINE, I'LL BE OUT IN A MINUTE, OKAY?
OKAY.
HERE YA GO.
THANKS.
CHEERS!
HOW'S THE VACATION GOING?
I'M NOT REALLY HAVING A VERY GOOD TIME.
YEAH...
OKAY...
I'M SUING THEM...
NO YOU'RE NOT, STEVEN.
I AM SUIN' THEM...THAT IS UNBELIEVABLE.
STEVEN, WE'RE LUCKY TO BE ALIVE.
THEY'RE ALL CORRUPT.
YEAH, NO, YEAH...
I MEAN, I WAS PETRIFIED!
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S THE
UNIFORM, OR THE GUN...
HEY MOM...MAYBE I'LL BE A COP.
DAVID, GROW UP!
PROBLEM?
AH, THIS FUCKIN'...TAKE THE
WHEEL A SECOND, WOULD YOU?
JESUS...SHOW OFF.
DAMN IT!
LOOK AT THAT.
TIGHT-ASS PANTS.
WHAT, DO YOU HAVE TO FEED
THAT THING MICE? RIDICULOUS.
BABY FUCKIN' DEER-FAWN.
UNBELIEVABLE...IT'S LIKE A PUPPET.
AH...WHATEVER...
CHEERS!
THIS IS A GODDAMN BULLET HOLE!
SO YOU THINK OFFICERS BENNETT AND CONRAD
SHOT OUT THAT MAN'S TIRE...
I DUNNO, I GUESS IT COULD
HAVE BEEN A BULLET...
ARE YOU FUCKING STUPID?
NO, I'M TELLING YOU, THAT'S
WHAT THE GUY THOUGHT IT WAS.
WELL, THE GUY'S A FUCKIN' ASSHOLE!
YOU'RE THE MAN WHO'D KNOW.
HA HA HA HA HA HA HA.
ARE THOSE...LITTLE FLOATING DEAD PEOPLE?
YEAH.
(Dad) IT'LL IMPRESS THE GIRLS.
YOU GOTTA COME HELP AND
CHANGE THE TIRE...C'MON...
HEY SWEETIE...
WE'RE ALMOST FINISHED.
I WANNA GO HOME.
WE'RE NOT GOIN' HOME, SWEETIE!
WE'RE, WE'RE ON VACATION.
WE'RE HAVIN' A GREAT GODDAMN TIME, OKAY?
WE GOT BLOOD!
AW FUCK...
THEY WERE RIGHT BEHIND US.
YOU SHOT THE TIRE OUT.
THE GIRL... TOLD US,
YOU KNOW, ABOUT THE CARS.
SHE SAID THERE WERE TWO CARS.
YEAH, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE'RE MISSIN' THE WHITE ONE.
AND WHAT HAPPENED TO UH,
KEITH, OR 'CANDY PANTS'?
YOU'RE DESCRIBING THE
TAURUS THAT YOU PULLED OVER
EARLIER IN THE DAY?
UM, MY PARTNER AND I PULLED
THAT TAURUS OVER EARLIER, YES...
THEY WERE SPEEDING...BLEW A TIRE...
AND THEN YOU, THE TWO OF YOU,
LEFT THE SCENE WITH THE COUPLE
ALIVE AND WELL.
IS THAT YOUR STATEMENT?
I SEE WHAT YOU'RE DOIN', AGENT.
SO THEN IT WAS JUST
MOMENTS AFTER YOU LEFT
THAT THE UNKNOWN KILLERS
CAME AND TOOK ADVANTAGE
OF THE COUPLE'S PREDICAMENT?
FINE. THAT'S YOUR STATEMENT.
KEEP GOING.
HEY, IT'S HIS JOB TO SHAKE ALL OUR TREES
AND SEE WHAT FALLS OUT, HUH?
FUCK 'IM.
A VAN JUST PASSED US.
A WHITE VAN.
I DIDN'T WARN MY
STEPFATHER ABOUT THE VAN.
NO ONE BLAMES YOU, STEPHANIE.
I DON'T BLAME YOU.
EVEN IF YOU DIDN'T TELL HIM ON PURPOSE.
STEPHANIE, WHERE YA GOIN'?
STEPHANIE!
(Loud crashes)
DAVID?
DAVID!
MOM?
I GOT YOU ?
MOM!
I GOT YOU.
I'VE GOT YOU.
HEY FUCK FACE!
YOU JUST KILLED MY BEST FUCKING FRIEND!
GET OUT!
WHAT THE FUCK IS YOUR PROBLEM?
(Female Hostage whimpers)
OH SHIT.
YOU ALRIGHT?
WAIT, LADY, I'M COMIN'.
I'M COMIN'! OH GOD.
I THINK IT'S THE MISSING WOMAN.
IN HERE!
STAY RIGHT THERE!
HOLD ON, I'LL BE, I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
GET OFF THE VAN!
OKAY, ONE SECOND.
OKAY...
BACK UP, MOM.
FUCK!
(Female Hostage whimpers) SHIT!
HEY, GET AWAY FROM THE VAN CRACK-HEAD!
FUCK YOU.
AW, JESUS, JACK...WHERE
ARE OUR FUCKIN' GUYS?
FUCK! DAMN IT...
HEY!
HEY, GET OUTTA THE WAY.
HANG TIGHT, MA'AM!
AW FUCK! I COULD'A KILLED YOU!
WHAT! I'M DOIN' MY JOB.
GO AROUND THAT SIDE AND
GET THAT WOMAN OUTTA THERE.
I'LL CHECK AROUND.
ALRIGHT, PRETTY FUCKIN' GREAT HUH?
YEAH...
POLICE OFFICERS!
HIS HANDS...WERE TAPED TO THE WHEEL.
THE GUY FROM THE TAURUS.
AND HIS HEAD CAME UP...
(Gunshot)
YOU'RE SAYIN' BENNETT JUST DOVE IN?
MINUS ONE GOOD HAND, YEAH.
COOL...
FUCK!
AWW!
MOTHER FUCKER!
GET TO THE BACK!
GET TO THE BACK, JIM!
FUCK!
- SHUT UP!
AHH!
AW FUCK!
THIS IS MY FUCKING SHOOTING HAND, KEITH!
FUCK!
GOD DAMN IT!
IT WAS LIKE A FUCKING BUILDING
HAD JUST DROPPED ON ME.
SO WAIT A MINUTE...SHE,
UH, ON TOP OF YOU?
OHHH... JESUS, LADY!
IT'S NOT HER!
AND I CAN, I CAN HEAR BOBBI
YELLIN' THAT IT WASN'T THE
WOMAN, AND...
HOSTAGE IS A SUSPECT!
(Gunshots)
SO THE MOM AND THE KID JUST GO DOWN.
IT'S FUCKED UP.
HEY LITTLE GIRL!
C'MERE C'MERE C'MERE QUICK QUICK
QUICK C'MERE, WE'RE GONNA HIDE,
C'MON OKAY GET IN GET IN, HEAD
DOWN, HEAD DOWN, HEAD DOWN...
AND I WAS ALMOST OUT
THE BACK DOORS...AND...
JACK.
JIM TOOK A BULLET.
UH, I WENT TO HIM...
NO!
NAW, OH SHIT. OH FUCK.
OH. NO. JIM.
(whispering)YOU'RE GONNA BE OKAY.
YOU'RE GONNA BE OKAY.
YOU'RE GONNA BE ALRIGHT.
OH SHIT. OH SHIT. NO. JIM!
(screaming)FUCK!
FUCK! FUCK!
ONE OF 'EM CLOCKED ME FROM BEHIND.
(Crack)
I KNOW YOU'RE KEEPING A SECRET, BUDDY.
HMM?
OH YEAH.
I HAVE TO GO TO THE BATHROOM.
I CAN GO ALONE. I'M ALMOST NINE...
ALRIGHT, YOU CAN GO.
HEY, YOU...
HI.
GET GOIN...
YEAH, UH HUH,
YOU SHOULD SEE IT, IT'S AMAZING.
THEY'RE JUST SO GOOD AT WHAT THEY DO.
I'M SAD, OF COURSE...
THE LITTLE GIRL. BUT IT'S EXCITING.
EVERYONE'S SO NICE, YEAH.
I JUST WANT TO BE HERE Y'KNOW
IN CASE ANYONE NEEDS ANYTHING.
UH, I'LL KEEP WHAT YOU SAID IN MIND.
YEAH. I'LL DO THE SAME.
C'MON.
(Housekeeper) HOUSEKEEPING!
(Hysterical scream)
BLUE?
D
- BLUE DOVE?
OK. BLUE DOVE MOTEL, UH HUH.
3 BODIES? OH MY GOD.
TWO MEN. ONE WOMAN. RIGHT.
RIGHT. AND THEN... OKAY.
LESS THAN...24 HOURS, UH HUH, OKAY.
OK. I WILL. I'LL GIVE IT
TO THE CAPTAIN RIGHT AWAY.
'K BYE.
HUH!
THERE GOES MY DINNER DATE...
JANET.
I'LL TAKE THAT.
GREAT. I'D BETTER DEAL WITH THIS.
MM-HMM LADIES AND GENTLEMEN...
WHY DON'T YOU GO AHEAD AND
STRETCH YOUR LEGS AND WE'LL MEET
IN THE CORRIDOR?
THERE'S BEEN A DEVELOPMENT.
AGENT ANDERSON, I'LL NEED TO
SPEAK TO YOU FOR A MOMENT BEFORE
I UPDATE THE OTHERS.
AH, THIS IS UNFORTUNATE.
YEAH...BOY...
YOU LIKE THAT MAN YOU WORK WITH.
AGENT HALLAWAY?
YOU CALLED HIM 'SAM'.
I D
-... I DID?
UM, WELL, WE'VE WORKED
TOGETHER FOR A LONG TIME.
THAT'S THE WAY MY MOM
LOOKED AT MY STEPFATHER,
BEFORE THEY WERE MARRIED.
THEY THOUGHT IT WAS A SECRET.
BUT IT WASN'T. I KNEW.
CAPTAIN?
YEAH, I'LL HAVE EVERYONE SIT TIGHT.
UH...HERE YOU GO, AGENT.
YOU GONNA TELL US WHAT'S HAPPENING?
APPARENTLY A MAID HAS DISCOVERED
BODIES AT THE BLUE DOVE MOTEL.
WHO'S GOIN'?
UH, I'M GONNA TAKE WRIGHT AND DEGRASSO,
SEE IF IT'S RELEVANT TO THE CASE.
GET YOUR STUFF.
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN NOW?
I'M GOING TO HAVE TO GO SOMEPLACE, OKAY?
YOU'RE GONNA STAY IN HERE WITH ME.
WE CAN FINISH THIS LATER.
NO, WE'RE GONNA FINISH IT NOW,
I HAVE SOME QUESTIONS FOR YOU.
JUST DO AS YOU'RE TOLD
AND EVERYTHING'LL BE OKAY.
BYE.
C'MON LADIES, I HAVE SOME
QUESTIONS FOR YOU SO IF YOU
COULD STEP INSIDE, PLEASE?
COME ON, JACK.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH...
WHERE'S JANET?
SHE'S UH, TALKING TO THE CORONER.
WELL, THAT COULD TAKE AWHILE. C'MON.
SHOTGUN!
LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE GONNA
BE RIDING IN THE BACK.
YEAH, I'LL DO THAT.
UHH....NICE WORK,
DEGRASSO. PICK IT UP...
OOOOOH. BUSTED.
FUCK YOU, TEACHER'S PET.
WHOO-HOOOOO!
AH, SHIT, BUDDY!
WOULD YOU JUST SIT DOWN?
YOU'RE DRIVIN' ME FUCKIN' CRAZY.
(impersonating Hallaway)
YOU GOTTA STAY HERE.
FUCK YOU!
C'MON JACK... TAKE A LOAD OFF.
(Clears throat) HEY...
I'M GONNA BE IN THERE IN
A MINUTE, STEPHANIE, GO ON.
I DON'T WANT TO BE IN THERE.
LOOK.
IT'S ALMOST OVER, KID.
IT'S ALMOST OVER.
JUST LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING, FIRST.
WHAT?
(Whispers)
YOU KNOW, I FIGURE WITH
THIS UNDER MY BELT...MM,
PRETTY GOOD CANDIDATE
FOR ANY JOB I WANT.
OOF, MY MOTHER'S GONNA
SHIT HERSELF WITH PRIDE.
SHE'LL BE REAL PROUD OF YA.
I HOPE SO...
WELL...OKAY...
GIVE ME YOUR PIECE, BENNETT.
YEAH, I... NEED YOU TO
GIVE ME YOUR GUN, OFFICER.
FUCK YOU YOU NEED MY FUCKING GUN.
I NEED THE OFFICER TO
GIVE ME HIS WEAPON...
NOW.
GIVE HIM YOUR WEAPON, JACK.
I'LL GIVE IT BACK TO YA
AFTER I FINISH TALKIN'.
THIS IS FUCKING BULLSHIT.
IT'S CRAZY BULLSHIT.
REALLY.
NOT...REALLY...
ALRIGHT.
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE A SEAT, JACK?
'CAUSE I WANNA GO BACK TO THE
CRASH...RIGHT...JUST BEFORE YOUR
PARTNER WAS...ALLEGEDLY,
BRUTALLY MURDERED.
DON'T YOU FUCKING TALK ABOUT MY PARTNER.
HEY. C'MON.
I THINK IT'S GONNA FEEL GOOD
TO GET IF OFF YOUR CHEST.
AGENT HALLWAY, LOOK...I'M
A LITTLE CONFUSED.
YOU SHOULD BE USED TO THAT BY NOW.
LOOK, IF THERE'S ANY QUESTION
AS TO HOW JIM CONRAD DIED...
THERE'S NO QUESTION HERE, THAT
OUR OFFICER JACK CANNOT ANSWER.
NONE.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT, JACK?
HOLD THAT.
HOLD THAT THOUGHT...
BECAUSE I THINK WE ALL
OUGHTTA HAVE A SMOKE.
MM?
LET'S ALL JUST HAVE
A SMOKE NOW, ALRIGHT?
YEAH.
MISSY?
NO THANK YOU.
YOU NEVER SMOKE?
NO...
ALRIGHT...I GUESS SO....CAPTAIN?
HE QUIT.
YEAH BUT THIS IS A SPECIAL OCCASION.
C'MON.
YOU LIED...
SMOKER'S PRIVILEGE.
C'MON YOU CAN QUIT
AFTER YOU HAD THIS ONE.
YEAH...
MMMMMM.
MMMMM...
OH YEAH.
MMM.
ALRIGHT.
JACK?
SMOKING KILLS.
NO.
YOU DO.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
DON'T I? HMM?
YOU WEREN'T THERE.
OH WAIT.
I WAS THERE.
YEAH.
MMMMMMM.....HELP....HELP.....
HMM?
SURPRISE!
YOU WERE A LITTLE OUT OF IT
'CAUSE YOU HAD YOUR HAND OPENED
UP, AND ...BOBBI...
THAT WAS GREAT, ALL
THAT SCREAMIN' STUFF,
THAT SET THE WHOLE DEAL UP.
THAT WAS, THAT WAS, THAT WAS
GREAT, IT WAS A LOTTA DRAMA,
AND THEN YOU WERE REALLY GOOD, TOO.
REALLY.
YOU JUMPED RIGHT BACK INTO THE GAME.
YOU GOT A LOTTA GAS IN
YER TANK, DONTCHA, HUH?
NOW I WANT YOU, I WANT YOU
TO TAKE IT FROM THERE, HUH?
HMM?
FUCK----AHHH!
YOU THINK THERE'S A MEDAL IN THIS?
I HOPE THERE IS.
IT'D BE SWEET...
(Drawing gun, gunshots, squealing tires)
FUCK!
YOU FIRED INTO YOUR PARTNER
AND YOU OPENED HIM UP
LIKE A CAN OF SODA.
POP! PSSSSSSSSSSSSSSS
SSSSSSSSS SSSSSSSSST!
HEAD RUSH, CAPTAIN?
YEAH.
IT'LL PASS.
(Gunshot) FUCK!
POW!
(laughs, deep breaths, screams)
SIT ON THE CHAIR, MISSY.
THANK YOU.
JACK...
C'MON.
LET'S GO BACK.
OKAY?
WHAT'S THAT SMELL?
DON'T YA HATE THAT SMELL, HMM?
OHHH.
QUITE A SMELL OHHHHHHHH.....
(Cellphone rings)
OH YEAH......
I GOTTA TAKE THIS. BABY?
ARE YOU SMOKING?
WHEREVER YOU ARE, I WANT
YOU TO COME BACK TO ME,
I WANT YOU TO COME BACK...
AND BRING THE BUTTER,
WE'RE HAVIN' TOAST.
JUST THE WAY YOU LIKE IT.
(Whispers) SHE'S WAY
TOO HOT TO BE F.B.I.
HELLO...
FUCK.
WHAT WAS THAT?
C'MERE...
I DIDN'T HEAR THAT.
WHAT WAS THAT YOU SAID?
I SAID SHE WAS WAY TOO
FUCKABLE TO BE F.B.I.
THERE WAS SOMETHING ELSE...
I SAID SHE SMELLED LIKE YOU.
I LIKE THAT, AND I WANT YOU
TO TELL HER THAT WHEN SHE COMES
BACK IN.
OKAY.
LET'S GET BACK TO
WHERE WE WERE, ALRIGHT?
C'MERE. YOU WANNA HEAR THIS.
LET'S GO BACK.
WANNA GO BACK TO THE POINT
WE WERE TALKING ABOUT?
'CAUSE THIS WAS MY
FAVOURITE PART OF THE DAY.
YOU AND YOUR BITCH
CAN GO FUCK YOURSELVES.
WHOA.
HEY.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING AT,
WE'RE GONNA DEAL WITH THE GUN
LATER, ALRIGHT?
IT'S FUN NOW.
OKAY?
'CAUSE FIRST OF ALL,
EVEN THOUGH, REGRETTABLY,
THE CAPTAIN HERE IS UNABLE
TO HEAR YOUR ADMISSION,
AND THAT WOULD'A BEEN PERFECT, BUT...
I WANT YOU NOW TO
ADMIT THAT YOU KILLED...
YOUR OWN PARTNER.
FUCK. YOU.
NO.
THAT'S NOT THE RIGHT ANSWER.
BYE BABY...
YOU KILLED MY PARTNER.
(laughs) OH, PLEASE.
(Jim) JACK, YOU OKAY?
IT'S, IT'S NOT THE MISSING WOMAN;
IT'S ONE OF THE FUCKING KILLERS!
UGH! JACK!
HOSTAGE IS A SUSPECT!
(Gunshots)
I MAY HAVE ORCHESTRATED IT
BUT THEY WERE YOUR BULLETS.
THIS IS KIND OF AMAZING.
FUCK YOU, YOU FUCKING
DRUG-ADDICT WHORE.
HEY, NO, SHE'S IMPRESSED!
THE LITTLE GIRL WAS IMPRESSED, TOO.
(Gunshot)
NO!
NO! NO! NO! NO!
I'M NOT...HAVING...A VERY...
GOOD TIME.
(Gunshot)
IT'S HARD TO IMPRESS CHILDRE
N WITH THAT SHIT THEY GET ALL
SLOBBERY AND UNCONTROLLED AND EVERYTHING
BUT SHE DIDN'T GO THAT WAY.
BUT YOU, HEY, MISSY...ARE
YOU FUCKING SOFT OR SOMETHING?
C'MON, SHE'S GONE...SHE'S GONE.
YOU WERE GONNA SAY SOMETHING,
GO AHEAD, SPIT IT OUT, PLEASE.
I'M A GOOD COP!
OH...THAT'S A TOTAL OXYMORON.
AND REMEMBER, I WAS THERE.
WHEN YOU REALIZED WHAT YOU'D DONE.
OH FUCK...FUCK...
YOU WENT ALL 'CRAZY COP' FUCK!
YOU STARTED SHOOTING AT EVERYTHING.
AND, OF COURSE, YOU FIRED AT MY GIRL.
FUCK...
WELL I WISH I HADN'T MISSED.
UGH!
OH SHIT!
WELL THAT'S THE SECOND
TIME I'VE KNOCKED HIM OUT.
YOU'D THINK HE'D SEE ME COMING.
HUH? OH. BUT HE'S STILL WITH THE PARTY.
GOOD.
YOU WANT A LITTLE NAP, TOO?
NO...
RIGHT.
(Disconnect tone)
(Hangs up phone)
YES...GO AHEAD.
YOU EVER LET ANYONE GO?
YOU PROBABLY READ THE END
OF A BOOK FIRST, DONTCHA?
YEAH...
THAT IS NO WAY TO LIVE.
(Intercom) HONEY...I'M HOME.
HEY...
COME ON, BABY...COME ON.
OH YEAH...
HOW WAS I?
HOW WERE YOU?
WE KNOW YOUR EARS WORK.
HOW THE FUCK WAS I?
WAS I SCARY?
WILL FLATTERY SAVE MY LIFE?
DON'T BE STUPID.
HOW 'BOUT A BLOWJOB?
ANSWER ME.
YOU WERE SCARY AS SHIT, HEY MAN...
JUST THE WHOLE
THING WAS AMAZ---
I JUST WISH I COULD TELL PEOPLE.
MAYBE IN YOUR NEXT LIFE.
BABY!
OH...
I FUCKIN' LOVE YOU.
BABY...WE CAN START THE PARTY.
HEY!
HEY.
GOD...
LOOK AT YOU...
YOU SMELL SO GOOD.
Y-YOU DON'T HAVE TO HURT ME.
WE'RE NOT HURTING
YOU...WE'RE LOVING YOU.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA FUCKING LOVE THIS.
SHE'S SO FUCKING PRETTY, JESUS...
LOOK AT THESE....OHHH...THEY'RE NICE.
DO YOU LIKE THESE?
D'YOU LIKE 'EM?
YEAH...
OKAY...
MM, WOULD YOU TOUCH MY TITS?
OH, GOD...THAT'S RIGHT.
YEAH, C'MON, THAT'S RIGHT.
OH GOD, YOU'RE...
JUST LET IT GO, IT'S OKAY, JUS
T LET IT GO, JUST LET IT GO YEAH,
LET IT GO...
YEAH...
SHE'S READY!
YEAH!
(whispered) GET IT!
GET IT!
OH YEAH, BABY.
(Moaning)
(Gunshot)
(Gunshots)
(Hysterical laughter)
SURPRISE!
OH I LOVE A...
(Phone rings)
I ALWAYS WANTED TO BE BLONDE.
C'MON, WE GOTTA RIDE...
(Ralph) YEAH, HEY, IT'S RALPH,
I'M STILL AT THE BLUE DOVE.
UH, I'VE IDENTIFIED THE
MISSING WOMAN, UH ELAINE MEYER.
BUT I'M LOOKING AT SOME F.B.I. BADGES.
UH, HOW MANY AGENTS
ARE WE SUPPOSED TO HAVE
IN TOWN RIGHT NOW?
ARE YOU HURTING MUCH, BABY?
MM, NO... JUST FEEL JABBED.
HMM.
OH!
STEPHANIE...
(whispered) I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
BABY...
AH, SHE WAS ON TO US,
SO...I THOUGHT 'THAT'S FUN'.
LET HER GO FREE.
I THINK THAT'S THE MOST ROMANTIC
THING EVER, IN THE WHOLE WORLD.
OH BABY...
BABY, OH...
¶¶