[silence]
[dramatic music]
[door opens]
[engine revving]
[sobbing]
[baby crying]
[crying continues]
[footsteps approaching]
- Well, what do you think?
- Jesus Christ.
I fuckin' told you these movies
would be shit
and they are pure shit,
literally, they stink.
I can tell you why you insisted
to show me this trash
you vain dumb-ass.
Shave off your stupid brush
and you'll look precisely
like this retarded pervert.
Ouch!
Are we fuckin' done?
- I kinda like these movies.
Everyone's talking about them.
Bill doesn't like when things
are more insane than he is.
[laughing]
- Watch it, tits!
[gasps]
Having the privilege to fuck,
suck me dry
still doesn't give a woman..
[sniffs]
The right to an opinion.
- Sir, I'm sorry,
it was just a joke...
- Shh, shut your pussy mouth
and go answer my fuckin' mail.
[sniffs]
Why do you look so damn pleased?
- Well, sir, I think I've found
the solution to
all our problems.
[telephone ringing]
- What?
- Mr. Boss, we've got a code 6 in block 4.
- Not again. Dammit!
[dramatic music]
- Sir, our prison
relatively has
the highest personnel turnover,
violence rates,
legal and medical costs
than any other institution in
the US correctional system.
Things will have to change fast
or Governor Hughes
will replace us.
- Uh-huh? Over my dead body.
[indistinct chatter]
Get a load of Billy Boss.
- What, you think you're
a fucking lone ranger?
[laughs]
- I'm no ke-mo fucking
sah-bee, bitch!
- Please, sir?
I think I have the solution.
- Doors, for the boss.
[buzzing]
[indistinct chatter]
- Scheiss, Nazi.
[dramatic music]
- I'm gonna rape you..
To fucking death..
And it scares you.
I can see it..
You motherfucker.
- What's his number?
- Prisoner 297, sir.
- Make a note.
I'll treat this walking
skin cancer later on.
[chuckles]
[buzzing]
[screaming]
- Stop moving!
Medic's coming.
- Which cocksucker did this?
- Hold his arm down, goddammit.
- 178, sir.
- By the way, doc,
I need my physical check up.
See you in an hour,
at your office.
- Sir?
[screaming]
- Did you hear me?
- Yes, sir!
[indistinct chatter]
- Fuck you!
- Look.
[groaning]
- Death, rape
will be your destiny!
- What's the ape nigger's
masturbation arm?
- Uh, he's right handed, sir.
- God!
[grunting]
[screaming]
- Turn him around, belly down.
[grunting]
[screaming]
[dramatic music]
[grunting]
[screaming]
You want more?
- Please, sir, no more.
Think of the medical expenses.
- You..
- When your little monkey bones
are healed..
I'll come by for a follow up.
[screaming]
[buzzing]
[groaning]
- Oh, you..
[screaming]
[indistinct chatter]
- I'm gonna kill you, you wait!
- You wanna rape me to death?
- Death trap, death trap,
death trap!
Come on, motherfuckers!
[gunfire]
On your knees!
I want respect!
[gunfire]
I deserve respect!
Respect!
[gunfire]
[gasps]
[sighs]
[sobbing]
- Oh, God.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[sighs]
[beeps]
- Ow!
[banging]
160 to 120.
Heh!
Sweet bleeding Jesus.
- Listen, Bill, my plan...
- Shut the fuck up.
I need to relax
for a few minutes!
- How can you relax
with such problems at hand?
I... I believe...
- I believe..
In bringing back
medieval torture methods.
Reverse hanging, Spanish boots,
and the good old rack!
- Statistics show
that the system
as it is now
just doesn't function.
- Poisonous Spiders..
For prisoners with
arachnophobia.
Massive force feeding
with raw slaughterhouse waste
of pork
for Muslims and Jews.
Beat them crippled
with their Torahs,
Korans or Bibles.
- More than $50 Billion a year
are spent on corrections.
Yet more than 4 in 10
offenders nationwide
return to prison within three
years of their release.
- Eyes for eyes.
[laughing]
Ugh!
Teeth for teeth, times 100!
A prison should
be a real deterrent
not a goddamn nursing home.
- I agree!
But medieval torture
ain't gonna be the answer.
Something else will.
[knock on door] That's why...
- Mr. Boss..
I have a special
delivery for you.
- Don't bother me, tits.
Goddammit!
I have to think!
- Sorry, sir.
- No, wait.
Give it to me.
Your rolling ass cheeks tell
me what it must be.
By the way I need my ball sack
emptied before lunch.
Holy shit.
- What is that?
- Tribe leaders in Africa
chew them for unbelievable
strength.
- Yeah, but what exactly is it?
- Dried clitorises.
- What?
- Clit-o-ris-es!
[telephone ringing]
What?
- We are comin'.
- What?
- We are comin'
to your office, bitch.
- Who's this?
- Oh, you don't know who I am?
[laughing]
It's your death squad coming
to rape you to pieces,
you fucking white trash!
- Give me a guard on the line
this instant!
- Somethin' wrong?
- Ugh.
They are coming.
- Who's comin'?
- It's a code 8.
[knock on door]
[groaning]
- What's going on?
- Fuck off!
- Hey!
[heavy breathing]
- This time... it is real, jerk!
Really real!
- Oh, no. Not again.
[dramatic music]
[dial tone]
- Yes, sir?
- What's goin' on?
- Sorry, Mr. Butler,
346 must have used his
once a month family phone call
to call Mr. Boss.
Won't happen again.
[sighs]
- False alarm!
[heavy breathing]
[knock on door]
- Why didn't you let me in?
What's going on?
- This goddamn heat
is drivin' me insane.
- Sir, Doctor Jones called
about your physical...
- Whoever did this is..
Fucked!
[buzzing]
- Well, your heart is racing.
Have you been under
a lot of stress?
- Stress is for pussies.
[inhales]
- I also hear a heart murmur.
- Listen, I'm not fuckin'
paying you to give me bad news.
- I would like to draw some
blood and do an EKG as well.
- I demand some
fuckin' good news..
Or your ass will be fired.
[inhales]
There's nothin'
wrong with me, right?
- You're in
perfect health, sir.
- Great.
I knew it.
Back to work!
- Fuck! Fuck!
[grunting]
Billy Boss, good that you
joined the party!
- Are there any regrets,
you little phone-action Tonto?
[grunting]
- I would scalp you if you
had any fuckin' hair.
Fuck..
Fucker.. [foreign language]
[speaking in foreign language]
- What is this?
- Water, sir.
[groaning]
[grunting]
- I said boiling water..
Fuck face!
- Yeah, get some teabags
with that too, Earl Grey.
[laughing]
- Please, sir, just think
of the outrageous medical costs.
It's our jobs on the line here.
[grunts]
- Sir, Governor Hughes
will be arriving in 20 minutes.
- What?
Today?
- I thought that lobby whore
would come in on Thursday?
- Uh, sorry, it's... it's
in the agenda for today.
- Shit!
Try to make him touch your ass
so we can sue his ass
for sexual harassment!
- I will, sir.
Will you be attending
the execution tonight?
- You fuckin' know..
I never go to these
wellness executions
by injections.
Sister Dwight will attend
the feel-good penalty.
- Get me out of here!
- Shut up!
You, timber nigger!
[indistinct radio chatter]
- Uh-huh. Uh!
[grunting]
- Guantanamo Style XXL.
- Fuck you, you Nazi!
- Boiling water boarding..
By Bill Boss!
[groaning]
- Eyes for eyes!
[screaming]
Teeth for teeth.
Yeah!
[screaming]
- Times 100!
[dramatic music]
- You lost your soul,
William Boss.
[engine revving]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[buzzing]
- Oh, excuse me, sir.
Um, I'm...
[instrumental music]
- Hmm.
- May I offer you a
top of the line
Dominican cigar, governor?
- Hmm, I only smoke
Cuban cigars
the world's best.
- You are..
A native-born citizen
of the glorious
United States of America.
The greatest nation on earth.
And you are not ashamed to smoke
communistic cigars from Cuba?
I'm only a German American
from Schweinfurt.
But I feel..
Deeply ashamed for you, sir!
Ah!
I apologize.
The heat... is driving me crazy.
- Right, the heat.
I guess it's your...
depressing statistics.
- Statistics are
Mr. Butler's department.
- I... I... I know things
aren't going so well.
Um, we are running
costs inefficiently.
- That's true!
I'm afraid... I have to fire
poor Mr. Butler.
- Poor Mr. Butler. Your accountant...
has nothing to do with it.
Answering violence with violence
is not the way of a real leader.
You Bill are no Boss.
You have managed one
thing however..
To damage me
in an election year.
I'll return in two weeks.
When I return, I want changes.
And if I don't get them..
I will replace you..
And your accountant,
understood?
- Very well, sir.
Sure thing.
No problem, sir!
- Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck you!
Fuck yourself!
You imbecile,
communist, zombie cunt.
Nobody insults me like that.
I'll stuff your
baggy homosexual shithole
with Cuban Cigars
up to your throat!
Don't mess with Bill Boss!
- I... I did everything
I could, I swear to God!
- Please, Boss, will you just
listen to my idea?
- Shut the fuck up!
Fuck the sissy psychological
leadership bullshit!
My leadership balls
are atom bombs!
A 100 megatons each!
I'll teach him leadership!
I'll do what I wanted
to do since ages!
Castrate them all!
- No, it won't work
besides it's permanent!
- Send the cockroaches
to the yard!
- But it's 120 degrees outside
that's irresponsible!
- Great.
Let the pork roast!
[speaking in foreign language]
- Good morning pigs!
Good to smell
your acid stink again.
A prison is like a swine farm
and I'm your Almighty Lord
and swineherd.
My grandfather owned
a big one in Germany
He castrated thousands of pigs.
Why?
Because they have
too much testosterone.
That's what makes
'em so aggressive.
You might wonder,
why I'm telling you
this touching little story.
One of you lucky cock-suckers
will have the privilege to
experience first as a prototype
the transformation
into a sissy eunuch.
Castration will return
all of you back into society
as sweet, harmless, submissive
pussy schnitzels.
And the winner is..
Our awesome tattoo wasp!
Sister prisoner 297! Congrats!
Take him to the special cell.
Enjoy your sunbath!
- Allahu Akbar!
Allahu Akbar!
- Yeah! Yeah!
[dramatic music]
- Hey, warden, I like my men
bald. I think it's sexy.
Why don't you come over here
and suck my dick.
[indistinct chatter on radio]
- No worries!
As a child..
I've seen it a hundred times
trust me.
[dramatic music]
Turn him around..
Facing the wall!
[yawning]
[music continues]
- Oh, no. Please.
Don't!
[music continues]
[moaning]
[dramatic music]
[music continues]
Ah! You bitch!
Ah!
- Bring these little fuckers
to the cook!
I want 'em medium rare
for lunch!
Hmm.
[screaming]
Have him stitched up!
Yeah!
Yeah, yeah!
[rattling]
[moaning]
- Oh.
- Hmm.
Oh!
[groaning]
- Uh, I'm sorry, sir.
I... I can't do it
with Dwight in the room.
- Go ahead for Christ's sake!
Dwight is my pet.
[groaning]
Ah!
Whoa.
Good. Oh.
Yeah. Yeah.
[groaning]
[thud]
[groaning continues]
[exhales sharply]
Come on. Swallow it!
I didn't get
your asshole of father
out of prison for nothin'!
Swallow it, bitch! Swallow up!
God damn it!
[groaning]
- Sir, could I please have
a candy for the taste?
- Help yourself!
- Don't Daisy, don't.
- Shut up!
- Gross, this is salty.
- Back to work, office slut.
Where is my lunch?
I'm fuckin' hungry.
Ah.
[indistinct chatter on radio]
- Here is your lunch, Mr. Boss.
- Hmm.
Energy Food!
Ah!
- Daddy, I promise you
nothing's wrong.
No. I've just been so busy.
[praying in foreign language]
- I... I did talk to him
about the hours.
He said that
it's gonna get better.
[clears throat]
- Look..
We are positively
in the papers.
"Craig Sinner executed
in George H. W. Bush
state prison at 1:00 A.M."
Did you get off last night?
- Well, he called for Satan
before he died!
- Putting the cockroach
gently to sleep
with a sissy needle.
Is that the way
he killed the kid?
No!
Torture castration will be
the final solution.
- No, it won't!
- Why is this shit on my desk?
- Please, please, please, Bill
will you just listen to my idea?
- Not when I'm eating
my health food!
[phone ringing]
What?
- Sir, prisoner 297
is about to wake up.
- The moment of truth.
- You white fuck!
[screaming]
- Crimson red, thoroughbred.
- I'm still a red man,
you fucker. You white fuck.
- When I'm walking free,
I'm gonna stab in your eyes.
- Time for the follow up
as I promised!
[screaming]
[speaking in Hebrew]
- Well, he's still a bit weak
from the incident
but we have given him some
morphine to manage the pain.
- I personally castrated him.
- Yes, we all are aware.
- And tomorrow
we'll start
a fuckin' mass castration
doing them all!
- Thanks, doc,
for fixing everything.
- I owe Mr. Boss big time.
This is the only hospital
that will let me work
without my license.
- You better believe it!
Glad you appreciate it.
[monitor beeping]
Hey, man.
How do you feel?
Feel submissive.
Even thankful, I bet.
[sighs]
- Ah!
You took them, that's okay.
I don't need them.
When I get loose
I'm gonna find some barb wire
and I'm gonna fuck you
in the ass with it.
And then I'm gonna dig up
your German Nazi parents
and I'm gonna
fucking rape them too.
Sieg heil, motherfucker!
- Yeah, I told you
it wouldn't work.
- Shut your filthy mouth!
[grunting]
[flatline]
[sighs]
[coughs]
[dramatic music]
- I'm not getting a heartbeat.
- Resuscitate him.
Quickly! Hurry up!
- I need
a crash cart over here!
Alright, it's charging.
Alright, everybody, clear?
Shocking now.
Alright, charging.
Shocking now!
[gasps]
[coughs]
- I'll kill
this creature twice!
[grunting]
[sighs]
[dramatic music]
- I do not accept this heat!
[monitor beeping]
- I want you to watch these.
- Oh, I've seen those.
They're really good.
[heavy breathing]
[dramatic music]
[door creaking]
[sighs]
- Where have you been?
- I'm gonna shoot all
the malignant cock sockets.
Then you.
And then myself.
What's the goddamn
point of living
when even the castration program
doesn't work..
And I get fired?
- Seriously?
It's also my job,
and my life on the line!
- How dare you,
ugly piece of mutant shit
talking to me like that?
- I have been trying to
tell you for days now.
I have the answer
to all our problems!
We've got to make a human
centipede of our prisoners.
Sewn ass to mouth
sharing one digestive system.
No more prison fights, no more assaults
on guards, no more disrespect.
They will literally be
on their knees
begging for your mercy
and it's the ultimate deterrent
for those considering
a career in crime.
It's brilliant!
We don't gotta to deal
with their shit no more.
They just gotta deal
with each other's.
- What?
That B movie shit?
Impossible!
- No! It is possible.
That's why I let Daisy make
an appointment with Mr. Tom Six
creator of these films.
He claims that it's 100%
medically accurate!
- The man is still
in his potty stage.
A poop infatuated toddler.
You call him now
and tell him I don't speak
with a stupid filmmaker
about his poop fetish!
- Fine then, we'll get fired!
- You..
Are fired!
Right now!
- You know, Bill Boss,
I used to look up to you.
I used to idol-worship you.
I worked 10 years for you
and I grew this stupid
mustache to look like you.
But I know what you are.
You are a sadistic,
vile, asshole.
- Get out of my face.
You malignant midget!
[sobbing]
[sighs]
I just saved your fuckin' life!
[coughing]
[groaning]
[screaming]
[grunts]
I hate..
Human beings!
[glass shatters]
[exhales]
Black, chicken slave niggers..
Mother fisting, baby raping
Mexican lowlifes.
Me cago en la madre
que te pario.
Circumcised, ugly
Jewish goat fuckers.
Pubic hair bearded
Islamic halal pigs.
Jesus fuckin'
bleached assholes.
Impotent, yellow faced,
narrow eyed coons!
[megaphone screeching]
[sighs]
[intense music]
Guards?
Dwight!
[laughing]
How you all..
Got out of your cells?
Go back to your cells,
immediately.
I only follow orders.
I just try to do my job.
Please forgive me and let me go.
I will pardon all of you!
No!
I just let you go..
Immediately, you can go.
Go, go!
See your fuck..
See your loved ones.
I have a heart problem..
And diabetes mellitus!
Under stress
I could get a severe attack..
That would kill me!
[screaming]
[grunts]
- Today is your day
to be fucked
like the rest of us.
But I'm not gonna do you
in your stinking ass.
I'm gonna cut me a fresh hole
in your soft kidney tissue.
- Belly down!
[crying]
Death rape!
[screaming]
- Death rape!
- Oh, shit, this shit
feels good.
- Death rape!
- You like that, daddy?
Oh, yeah. Ooh.
- Death rape!
- Don't move, here it comes!
[grunts]
[gasps]
[groans]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[telephone ringing]
- What?
- Sir, Mr. Tom Six
is at the gate.
- Send him in.
[instrumental music]
- Dwight!
- Didn't I fire you?
- I'm gonna give you
one last chance
and if you don't like
what you hear
then I'll quit myself!
- Uh-huh.
- Mr. Tom Six!
It's so great to meet you.
My name's Daisy, uh, I was
wondering if you could sign
an autograph for me
before you go in.
- Sure, babe.
- Thank you.
You're even more
handsome in person.
- Thanks.
- Uh, let me show you in.
Gentlemen, Mr. Tom Six.
- Ah, Mr. Six,
it's nice meet you.
- Hello, sir.
- My name is Dwight Butler.
This is my boss,
Mr. Bill Boss.
- Sir.
- Please take a seat.
- First of all, Mr. Six,
I'd like to say
congratulations on your movies.
They've become
a... a cultural mime.
I mean, there is
the "South Park" episode
of the Human Centipede.
And then there's the LA porn
parody, and the cat toys.
- I don't have
the time for this..
Fan shit shat.
[knock on door]
- Well, I'm sorry I'm late.
Prisoner 297 had a heart attack
and I had to resuscitate
him again.
But, um, he's stable now.
I.. Mr. Six, this is a big
pleasure 'cause I'm a big fan!
- Uh, thank you sir.
[groans]
- Well, we are gathered
here today.
Glad to investigate
the possibility
of applying Mr. Six's human
centipede idea to our prison.
I mean, is it
100% medically accurate?
- This is my desk!
In my headquarters!
At my penitentiary!
Wake up!
We're not in a movie
here playing some idiots!
- Well, it is 100%
medically accurate.
I consulted a real surgeon
in Amsterdam
and he made a very detailed
operation report for me
and he said he could
actually make
a human centipede
in his hospital.
I brought the, uh,
operation reports
and the drawings..
So maybe you can
have a look at that?
[clears throat]
- Okay, uh..
- What do you think, doc?
- Well, from what I see here,
uh, it looks..
Medically accurate.
- You're sure?
- You would have to give
anti-rejection medication
and there is always
the risk of infection
during the healing
process, but, uh..
Yeah, I'm sure.
- But what about the excretia?
- Well, the feces wouldn't be
contaminated by outside bacteria
because it would be going from
one digestive tract to another.
So it wouldn't be harmful.
But there wouldn't be
much nutritional value.
On the other hand if you gave
a series of, uh, injections
of fluids with plenty
of vitamins and minerals
I don't see why
someone couldn't survive
a lifetime in this position.
- Aah! Gentlemen.
[instrumental music]
This is a historical moment.
This is beyond
medieval torture!
Beyond castration!
The ultimate correction
nationwide.
We have business
on hand, gentlemen.
We start immediately.
- No, the surgery can't be done
like in Tom Six's movies.
We have to take into account
of the fact that
at the end of their sentence
the prisoners have
to be released
without being mutilated.
So I've been
thinking about this.
What we have is instead of
the pulling of the teeth
we have a gastro-intestinal
bite-ring
that holds the mouth open,
so they can't stop the feces
from coming into their system.
Instead of the cutting
of the knee ligaments
we simply inject
to induce temporary paralysis
in that joint.
Then, to attach the head
to the buttocks
of the person in front
we have a system
of leather straps
which can be adjusted,
pulled in tight and then undone
for when we release.
At the end of their sentence
and taken out of the centipede
there's only a slight scar
round their mouth and anus.
Well, doctor,
what do you think?
Is it possible?
- Very clever, Mr. Butler.
But this, all of this
is beginning to be
in serious conflict
with my Hippocratic oath.
If I back out of this,
I'm gonna get fired, aren't I?
- Very clever thinking,
Mr. Jones.
- You know, my original idea
for the Human Centipede films
was sewing a child molester's
mouth to the anus
of a fat truck driver, as
a punishment, so I love this.
- I just got
an even better idea
for our life-time-trash
and the death-row-scum.
But I'll talk
to my loyal doctor first.
- Gentlemen, you may use my human
centipede idea, but on one condition.
I have witnessed all the fake
latex stuff on my movie sets.
Now I insist on attending
one of your real
mouth to anus operations.
- Deal.
I put you in charge
of the whole operation, doctor!
Soon you'll lead..
Surgical teams all over
the States.
- Fantastic!
Uh, we are going to need
a much bigger surgical team.
We have to run blood workups
on all the prisoners,
uh, test their stool samples
for parasites.
- Whatever you need, doc.
I've another brilliant idea.
We'll show the cockroaches
the two Human Centipede films
back to back
at their monthly film night
and then..
I'll announce them their fate.
- The prisoners will tear
this place apart.
We have to do this without the
fore knowledge of our clientele.
- Shut up, pooper.
- How dare you
turn your back on me?
[indistinct]
[groans]
- Oh!
- Yo, what the fuck is this?
- This trash occupies a world
where the stars don't shine.
- Come on, swallow it, bitch.
- No!
- Swallow.
[speaking Arabic]
[laughing]
- What the fuck?
[screaming]
- Oh, man!
- These films risk
causing harm.
They should be banned!
- Ha!
- Turn that shit off!
[screaming]
[machine gun firing]
- Hey cockroaches
did you like these films?
I handpicked them for you
as an instructional
and mental training.
The world's first
human-prison centipede
will finally teach you
how to become humans.
- I don't think
this is a very good idea.
- Literally
on your fucking hands and knees.
[screaming]
- Your ugly pussy mouths
sewn to an unwiped asshole
feeding of the diarrhea
from your fellow inmate.
I can't wait
to see..
Your pure
agony!
[screaming]
[alarm blaring]
Help!
[screaming]
[alarm blaring]
[indistinct yelling]
- What's going on?
What's going on?
- Shut up!
- Don't hurt me,
Bill Boss is in there.
I have nothing to do with
this, I swear to God!
[grunts]
- Special forces immediately!
[grunting]
[coughing]
[glass shattering]
- Get the fucking door!
[screaming]
[helicopter whirring]
- It's time to fuck!
[gunshot]
[indistinct chatter on radio]
[machine gun firing]
[indistinct yelling]
- Bill!
- Here.
I'm here.
- Where are you?
- Here.
Over here, I need help.
- Got eyes on Bill Boss.
- Thank God, I just
couldn't find you.
The situation's
under control now.
But they, they
really hurt Daisy.
- Can't you see I'm hurt?
Get the medical team for me!
Hurry up!
It's an emergency!
[groans]
Now it's
hell on Earth!
Do you hear me?
Scum of the..
Universe!
Ah!
The "Silence of the Lambs."
Sedation rifle!
- Fuck!
- No worries.
It's only a sedation rifle.
[screaming]
[gunshot]
- No!
- Fuck you!
[gunshot]
- Gentlemen.
Unleash..
Hell!
[buzzing]
Ugh!
Their submissiveness
gives me a huge erection.
Death rape, death rape
rape, rape, rape.
Eyes for eyes
teeth for teeth.
Get the fucking scum
on their fucking knees.
On your fucking knees
on your fucking, fucking knees.
Get the fucking scum
on their fucking knees
on their fucking, fucking
fucking, fucking knees.
Ha ha ha.
I'll explain.
This spectacular operation
only once.
We start
with injections into the lig...
- Ligamenta patellae.
Paralyzing the ligaments
of your kneecaps.
So knee-extension
is no longer possible.
Your lips and anuses
are cut circular
along the border
between skin and mucosa,
the muc...
- Mucous-cutaneous.
- Mucous-cutaneous zone.
Then we combine
those circular mucosa
and skin parts
of anus and mouth
creating a human centipede
connected via
your gastric systems.
Gentlemen.
Put them to sleep.
- By the way,
what are your plans
for the life sentenced
and death row prisoners?
- Wait and wonder, peepheart.
How's it going, doc?
- Right on schedule,
five surgical teams
working round the clock.
Those teams creating
centipede segments
of three prisoners each,
which are then taken outside
to the hospital tents
and then they are sewn
into the final
larger human centipede chain.
- Marvelous, doc.
- Since I have you here..
What do you want to do
with this prisoner?
He has Crohn's disease.
[farting]
- What the fuck
is Crohn's disease?
- It's an inflammatory
bowel disorder.
The prisoner has
constant diarrhea.
- Who'll kiss his ass?
Our awesome..
Tattoo wasp!
The white, anal
sexing prostitute.
- Please.
One more chance.
Please don't sew me
into a human centipede.
I beg you.
- Yeah yeah.
[sniffles]
Your whining
makes my dick even harder.
Revenge is so sweet.
Take it into your sleep.
- We have another
problem at hand.
- That's fuckin' gross!
- I have a stoma
and you have a problem.
Thank God.
[speaking in foreign language]
Now I finally discovered
why they blessed me
with a lifetime stoma. Ha ha ha.
[laughs]
- This guy is repulsive.
Maybe it's a fake.
With Mexicans, you never know.
[grunts]
No fake.
No way to integrate him, doc?
- His rectum is sewn shut, no.
- Finish him off then.
- I'm sorry.
But I have cooperated
with you and I will..
Continue to cooperate.
But I will not
just kill prisoners!
- Jesus Christ.
Chicken shit!
- Excuse me.
I have work to do.
- My friend, you don't match.
I have to kill you.
Take it fucking personally!
[gunshot]
Ooh.
Ugh!
Take my gun.
Wash it, oil it, disinfect it.
If I sniff the tiniest stink
you'll suck a bullet out of it.
- And what do you
want to do with him?
- I am sick and tired
of your vegetables.
[screams]
[gunshot]
- What the fuck!
- Please, sir, can we go
and see Daisy now?
Just look at her.
She is the only beautiful and
sweet thing about this place.
I think she should be treated
in a regular hospital.
- No.
I want my cock socket close.
Beaten up women
make me so horny.
- Please, Bill, don't.
- Jesus Christ.
- I beg you.
I...I love her.
- Even the corpse of a spastic
would turn you down.
Fuck off!
Ah!
[intense music]
I'll make you
squirt even in a coma.
- Alright, we're all done.
- Good job.
[indistinct yelling]
I want you to make sure
that the world premiere
of the first
human-prison centipede
is guaranteed
to take place the moment
our communist governor
appears at the gate
to destroy us!
- Well, there is only
16 more prisoners left
to undergo the procedure.
After that
the human-prison centipede
will be finally complete
on time and under budget.
- They did their magic.
[sniffles]
Thank God for Africa!
Thank God for female
circumcision!
Private rehearsal!
Let's hear what
our zombie governor
will have to say.
- May I offer you a genuine
Dominican Republic cigar?
- I only smoke Cuban cigars
best in the world.
No! Just kidding.
After having seen the miracle
of the first
human-prison centipede
I'll never again touch
a communistic cigar from Cuba
because you, Sir William Boss
you are the new American hero.
You are in the Hall of Fame
with George Patton
Neil Armstrong
and Muhammad Ali.
Thanks to you.
Our glorious nation
will be the example
to the world again.
A proud, safe nation
with hardly any crime.
Your idea, Sir William
is of absolute genius.
You will be honored personally
by the President of
the United States of America.
[whistling]
- Actually, it was
my accountant
Mr. Dwight Butler
it was his brilliant idea.
- Oh, yeah.
You did it.
You fucking..
Fucking did it.
[horn honking]
[telephone ringing]
[laughs]
Mr. President.
It's me,
William Boss, call me Bill.
- Sir, Mr. Tom Six
is at the gate.
Sir?
- What?
- Sir?
[instrumental music]
- Oh, man, I am so excited
to see the real
mouth to ass operation.
Prove all the skeptics wrong.
It is 100% medically accurate.
I'm gonna be so rich and famous.
- You owe me big time, mister.
- I'm already
eating my own shit.
I want to be
in the prison-human centipede.
[laughs]
[gun cocks]
- Wait, can't we use him
in the media conference?
- No.
[gunshots]
I don't want anyone
liking this!
- Oh, man, this is so wrong.
- Come on.
- Wash, please.
- Wash.
Yeah.
- Marker.
- Marker!
Yeah.
My hands are shaking
with excitement!
What about you, Six?
Having a hard-on?
[laughing]
Look at this.
Oh, yeah, oh..
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Six, I am gonna show you
some Human Centipede
improvement.
Copyright, Bill Boss.
Follow me!
♪ Bang bang bang bang
bang bang bang bangin' ♪♪
- Oh, oh.
- What a poor pussy, huh?
- What in the hell is this?
- Wait and see, Dwighty.
♪ Wait and wonder ♪
♪ Wait and see ♪
♪ Mr. Dwighty ♪
♪ Wait and wonder ♪
♪ Wait and see ♪
♪ Mr. Dwighty ♪♪
[instrumental music]
[laughing]
No.
120/80.
Perfect!
- The pede looks perfect.
The last few prisoners
have just been attached
and although the wounds
are still fresh
you get the idea!
- Perfect!
[telephone ringing]
What?
-  Sir, Governor Hughes
is on his way.
- Perfect!
We are ready for the cunt!
Dwight!
I repeat
you are really
the cunt!
Hello, sir.
- Why do you two assholes..
Look so pleased
with yourselves?
The both of you
are fucking fired.
I should have done it years ago.
- All problems
are history, sir.
I took your advice.
I've learned
from your strong personality.
You are the ultimate leader.
You are my role model.
And now the prisoners
are like obedient slaves
begging for mercy.
I got them down on their knees.
Literally.
Your last visit inspired me
to such an extend
a brilliant idea!
I'll show you the result
that tells more
than a thousand words.
The last ones have
just been attached.
So it is show time.
- Attached?
Attached?
A-T-T-A-C-H-E-D, attached?
- Yes.
- What does that mean?
- Wait and see.
- You talk so much shit,
your ass must get jealous.
[laughing]
- Great, governor, I love that.
[dramatic music]
- What the hell is this?
[screams]
The black panther
made it to the lead!
This burger-killer is feeding
the whole humanitarian
system behind him.
Don't cry.
Tomorrow, you'll get
your hamburgers.
[laughs]
- Why?
- Because he loves junk food.
- No, no, I don't mean that.
I mean, what..
What is this?
- Dwight..
Tell the governor my vision!
And this black whiner here
has to become a middle piece.
Fuck!
- Well, sir
more than 50 billion dollars
a year are spend on corrections.
Yet more than 4 in 10
offenders nationwide
return to prison within
three years of their release.
This, despite a massive
increase in state expenditure.
- Shit!
- But, not anymore.
This human-prison centipede
will reduce crime dramatically.
It will be
a deterrent to anyone
considering a career in crime
and no more recidivism.
[grunting]
- Feed him!
Feed him!
Digestion in progress!
No, it's not halal
it's not kosher!
A Jew behind a Muslim
a Muslim behind a Jew!
A Republican behind a Mexican
a crip behind a blood.
"Peace on earth
good will to men."
- Oh, my God.
This is too much.
[grunting]
Bill Boss..
Isn't that your secretary?
[groaning]
- Oh.
Yeah, uh, uh, yeah.
That's, uh..
Only a short, uh..
Gender-test!
Come on, sir!
[crying]
Dwight!
Tell our beloved governor
about the money savings!
- The savings would be
in the billions!
We can make savings
on prison staff
food and drinks.
On books and television,
housing.
Heck, we don't even
need fences no more.
- We can even save more money
if we attach them in a circle
like a perpetuum mobile.
Feces going round and round.
Food isn't needed anymore.
Only cheap liquid
and vitamin injections.
- And that money
could be spent on schools
and the hospitals
and nursing homes
and road improvements.
Whatever you want.
And the tax payers,
they'll love you for it.
[grunting]
- His anus is not very clean!
I want perfection
in my penitentiary!
Inmates shall feel well
and clean, understand?
Wipe it!
- I apologize.
- Oh, oh, oh.
- In the beginning
things are not always perfect.
Please follow me
for another interesting insight.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah.
- Tat-ta-ta-ta-taa!
The human caterpillar!
For the lifetime convicts
and our friends on death row.
Now..
Is that a deterrent?
This man..
Has just
finished his sentence..
And already checked out
of the centipede chain.
Ready to go home.
All what is left
are a few little scars
around his mouth and anus.
Another big advantage
because other people can see
by these little stigmas
that he was integrated
in a prison centipede.
Another huge deterrent, right?
How are you doing?
[speaking in foreign language]
Good luck, my friend.
Stay clean!
You see?
It really works.
What do you think, sir?
- This..
This is a violation
of human rights.
It's certainly
a violation of federal ethics!
Oh, God, I am fucked.
You insane freaks will get
the death penalty for this.
- Sir, you're dead right.
But in fact,
it was Mr. But..
- This is heights.
This is too much.
- You got the wrong man!
Fuck!
[dramatic music]
[music continues]
- Please, don't.
- What an epic
glorious moment, huh?
When do you think we can start
the national surgical campaign
'cause I am so fucking ready.
What is the matter?
[gunshot]
[dramatic music]
[groaning]
[gunshot]
[crying]
[dramatic music]
- Gentlemen..
This is exactly
what America needs.
This may even
get me elected president.
You've convinced me.
It's genius.
Don't change a goddamn thing.
My pals in DC..
They won't believe
their near-sighted eyeballs.
[laughing]
[instrumental music]
- Yep, my idea!
- You are..
Absolutely right, Dwight.
You're indeed a genius.
You came up with the idea.
You deserve every credit.
Give me a hug, Dwighty!
[instrumental music]
[gunshot]
[screaming]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]