(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
ON CASSETTE PLAYER)
(CASSETTE DISTORTING)
(SCOFFS)
(GASPS)
Jeez!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
SUSANNE:
With the community still shaken
from last year's
Slater's Quarry tragedy,
here in Boreham,
it's fresh heartache.
As the search for
the missing women
moves into the end
of its second day,
hope is fading for Senator Kaplan's niece,
Juno, and her 5 friends.
Just behind me I can see
one of the cave rescue teams
emerging from the caverns.
Good luck, guys.
Thanks.
Chimney's pretty tight.
You all be careful in there.
RESCUER: Will do.
SUSANNE: Sir,
any signs of the missing women?
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Do you think you'll
find them alive?
How does this compare to
Slater's Quarry?
That's enough now.
Move back.
Do you think you responded
quickly enough this time?
Greg, leave it!
Greg!
DAN:
We're back on in 4 hours.
Get some sleep.
You too, boss.
GREG: Hey, you want to
share a sleeping bag?
(SNIFFING)
What's that cologne you're wearing?
Yeah, 6 hours of sweat and dirt
and all other kinds of shit.
I think I'll pass.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Lynch? What's up?
What?
Where?
Look, get a tracker dog
out there.
See if you can find
where she came out.
Yeah, all right, and...
Let's keep the lid on this.
All right, I'm on my way to the hospital.
VAINES:
Right, Doc, how is she?
She's resting.
We had to sedate her.
I've got 5 girls missing
and you put the one person
who knows where they are to sleep?
She was hysterical.
Besides, she has no memory
of the last 2 days.
Whatever happened to her,
she's blanked it.
Injuries?
Well,
it's only some minor cuts and bruises.
But her clothes were completely
stained in blood.
So it's not her blood?
No.
But she's been in
a fight, all right,
because judging
by her fingernails,
she scratched some
big chunks out of somebody.
Test her clothes,
get the blood type.
Get the blood type of
the other 5 girls.
Mmm-hmm.
All right, let's see
what you can do.
RIOS:
Hello, Sarah.
I'm Jenna Rios from Hyde County
Sheriff's Department.
This is Sheriff Vaines.
How you feeling?
Where am I?
You're safe.
You're at Hyde County hospital.
We've been searching
for you and your friends.
2 days ago
you all set off on a caving expedition
and you never came back.
We've been following your
Boreham Cavern flight plan
but we found nothing.
Can you tell us what happened to you?
I don't know.
I can't remember anything.
Sarah, your friends
are still missing.
We need you to
help us find them.
Beth.
RIOS:
What happened to Beth?
What can you remember?
What about Juno?
Jessie.
Where's Jessie?
Your daughter?
Sarah, Sarah,
I need you to
listen to me carefully.
Your daughter
isn't here, Sarah.
She died.
A year ago,
in Scotland.
No.
I know how hard
this must be for you,
but you have to try...
No, no. No! No.
DAN:
Come on.
(DOG BARKING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
This looks like the
end of the trail.
What's that?
That there's
Chapel Mine.
Cuffs, come here,
come here.
Go find them, boy.
One of these days
I'm gonna come up here
and help myself to
some of this shit.
What you found, boy?
What you found?
Cuffs?
(GROWLING)
Holy shit!
(WHIMPERING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Sheriff.
Dan.
Keep it under your hat,
but we found one of the girls.
Dog picked up her scent
near the old Chapel Mine.
That's the other side of the county.
I know.
Jeez.
Don't tell me we've been looking
in the wrong place.
Listen, I don't want to shift
the whole goddamn circus.
I just want a couple of volunteers
to pick up where the dog left off.
All right, give us an hour.
DAN:
Cath, Greg, rise and shine.
Blood on Sarah Carter's
clothes, A-positive.
Juno Kaplan is A-positive.
So? I'm A-positive.
Half the state is A-positive.
Can she walk?
Sure.
Wait, wait, you're not seriously
gonna take her out...
Rios, get her dressed
and get her in the car.
(GRUNTING)
ED:
My granddaddy used to work down there.
One time, him and 2 of his buddies
broke into a whole new cave system.
Really big.
Company bosses figured there
should be some rich pickings to be had,
so they sent my granddaddy back down
to have a good look-see.
He never come back.
Folks reckoned they must've broke
clean through into hell.
The devil was mighty pissed.
So you're telling me that there's an
uncharted cave system down there?
Cool.
There's a map of
the mines here.
If the caves are uncharted,
we won't even know where to begin.
Bring the girl.
Come on, Dan, she's the only
one been down there.
All we gotta do is get a nod from her,
left or right.
Narrows the search.
There's a mountain full of caves
and fuck-all time.
Could piggyback on
the elevator cables.
(CHUCKLES)
You planning to go down there,
why not go down there in style?
What, this old shit
still works?
Sonny, let me tell you,
this old shit-bucket
will be working
long time after
that MP3 of yours.
Whatever.
All right, Ed,
get it going.
RIOS: I'm sorry, but Mommy's
got to help people tonight.
Chica, when Grandma tells you to go to bed,
you go to bed, okay?
Honey, I love you.
Okay, baby, I'll see you
tomorrow, okay?
Rios, get yourself kitted and
get her kitted. We're going down.
RIOS:
Okay, Sarah, I know this is difficult,
but if you do this,
it could help jog your memory.
Your friends could still be alive.
You have to help us find them.
(WHIRRING)
CATH:
Hey, Sarah, this might fit you.
DAN:
You want to lose that heavy metal.
Gun blast down
there'd be like dynamite.
Come on, I'll put them in the car.
My gun stays with me.
This is a missing
persons case.
What the hell do you think
you're gonna find down there?
(ENGINE STARTING)
GIRL: (WHISPERING)
Mummy.
Right, let's get moving.
Come on.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
You all ready to ride?
Yeah, let's do it.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MACHINE CREAKING)
(THUDDING)
(GASPING)
Whoa!
(EXCLAIMING)
(CREAKING)
VAINES:
Jesus.
DAN:
Hang on, just wait up a second.
(COUGHS)
Here, drink this.
She's okay.
Let me worry about her.
Come on, Dan,
let's get to the goddamn cave.
Listen. Down here,
I call the shots.
Is that understood?
Loud and clear.
Let's go.
(GASPS)
DAN:
Should be a ladder down there.
How long have I
been teaching you?
Your light is your life.
Hey.
All right. Okay, we've gotta go
down another level.
Greg.
You gotta be
fucking kidding me.
(CREAKING)
Is it okay?
You know what's good?
Modern mines have metal props.
Miners prefer
these old wooden ones.
Why's that?
The metal ones don't give you any
warning when they're about to go.
(RUMBLING)
(SCOFFS)
After you.
DAN: Okay, we should hit the
cave system somewhere up here.
Greg, go scout ahead.
You got it.
DAN: And Cath, you're next.
Deputy.
GREG:
I think I've found it.
What the hell is that?
It's a pit pony.
Always a good sign.
(CHUCKLING)
(CRASHING)
GREG:
Check it out. This is awesome.
Greg, T.I.
Hey, hey. Don't...
Don't touch anything.
This place is
thousands of years old.
Well, you're hot.
(SCOFFS)
Get away.
Sarah, do you
recognize anything?
(GASPS)
What?
(SCREAMS)
It's okay. It's okay,
she just got spooked.
Calcium deposits.
Let's keep moving.
It's okay, come on.
Come on.
Come on, Sheriff,
you can do it.
I ain't that old yet.
Which way?
You recognize this?
Cath, have a listen.
(STATIC)
Anything?
I don't know.
I think I hear something.
(GASPS)
Jesus!
Oh, my God!
VAINES: Shit!
Fuck! Sarah.
Look at me.
VAINES:
She's moving.
No. There's no body heat.
It's not possible.
(CATH SCREAMING)
Deputy.
(SARAH VOMITING)
Okay.
Sarah.
She's been butchered.
6 girls came down to this cave.
One came out.
Covered in her friends' blood.
Now, you tell me what the hell
happened down here.
(STAMMERS) Wait a second. You think
she had something to do with this?
This is fucked up!
Dan, get your team out of my face.
Man, you brought her down...
Get off my back!
Greg! Save it.
I thought she was a victim here.
What are you saying now,
she's a suspect?
VAINES:
I think she knows something.
I still got missing girls down here,
so let's keep our goddamn focus.
I should never have
let you bring her down here.
Dan, I think she came through here.
All right, Greg,
take point. Take point!
This is fucking bullshit.
DAN:
Deputy, look after her.
It's okay.
Come on, you're gonna be...
(GRUNTING)
Sarah, what is it?
I think there's something down here.
We were attacked.
By what?
There's nothing down here that
could have done this to a person.
Sarah, what can
you remember?
Sarah?
We shouldn't stay here.
You've got to try and think rationally.
You're scared.
Your mind's
playing tricks on you.
GREG: (OVER RADIO)
I'm through.
It's about a 50-foot crawl with some
tight spots, and then it opens out.
All right, copy that.
Sheriff, get your team together.
Greg, we're coming through.
Look out for them at the other end.
Okay, Rios, you go first.
I want you
in front of her.
She's not getting out of my sight
from now on.
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTS)
Come on, you're
almost there. Come on.
Hey! Whoa, come on.
You need to breathe with me now.
You need to breathe, okay?
VAINES:
Come on, keep it moving up there.
Get a move on,
you're slowing down.
(SCREAMING)
Why have you stopped?
Get a move on!
How are you feeling? All right?
Hey, hey, hey.
WOMAN:
Sarah... Sarah...
Rios!
Sarah!
For Christ's sake, Rios.
Which way did she go?
Which way?
Shit!
It's okay. It's okay.
That lady's a fucking
psycho, Dan. Jesus.
You okay?
I'm fine.
Look at me. How's it feel?
You want to kiss it better?
He's fine.
Where's Vaines?
He took off after Sarah.
Oh, fuck! He doesn't
even have a radio.
5 minutes in these honeycombs,
they'll both be lost.
Okay, listen to me,
listen to me.
We've gotta catch up on them
before they get too far ahead.
This time, we stick together.
You understand? Okay, let's go.
Yeah, come on.
(PANTING)
Okay.
Okay, there's
falling rock here,
which, as you know,
means the roof's unstable,
so we have to
tread carefully. Rios?
You stick with me, okay?
Let's go.
(LOOSE STONES CLATTERING)
(GASPS)
(GUN FIRING)
(RUMBLING)
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
Cath, can you hear me?
Take it easy,
that's gotta last.
Cath, come in.
Cath, speak to me.
CATH: (OVER RADIO)
Dan, are you there?
I'm here, I'm here.
I'm here. Are you hurt?
I'm stuck in a boulder choke.
And I need something
to support the rocks.
All right, all right.
Don't you panic, don't you panic.
Listen to me.
I'm gonna get you. Okay?
We'll work at this end, all right?
You listen to me.
You sit tight,
we'll get to you.
Okay.
Jesus. Come here, come on.
Come on.
Come on, come on,
come on. Jesus!
Dan.
(DAN GRUNTING)
Come on. Come on!
Fuck!
Fucking trigger-happy Americans.
Dan.
Fucking only answer they've got
to anything is a fucking gun!
Dan, don't let her
hear you this way.
There's a fucking ton
of rubble between us.
She couldn't hear
a fucking rock concert.
Dan.
Okay.
Okay. Okay, Cath.
CATH:
Yes?
DAN:
We can't get through to you.
Well, can't you drill it or det it?
You know we can't.
It's too risky.
You're gonna have to
work yourself free.
I can't, Dan, it'll crush me.
I need you here.
(SIGHS)
Okay, I'm gonna find
another way around to you.
Okay.
I'll get to you.
I'm scared, Dan.
That's good, yeah?
Fear keeps you alert,
it keeps you alive, it's...
I promise you,
I won't stop till I get to you.
I know.
Maybe I should stay with her.
You know we can't help her here.
You hang in there, teammate.
No worries.
Okay, Cath.
Are you dry?
Yeah.
DAN:
So you'll keep warm.
You keep drinking.
You stick with the drill, okay?
Okay.
DAN: We're gonna have
to move off now.
So you'll probably lose the signal.
You stay positive.
Okay.
DAN:
We're walking away.
You stay on channel 1.
CATH:
Okay. I'll be on channel 1.
You got your chance now.
(CRYING)
(RUMBLING)
(COUGHING)
Shit!
Fuck!
DAN:
What the fuck?
Are these animal bones?
Jesus.
Dan! Dan!
Here we are, morning
after the night before.
Here we go. Look at this face.
WOMAN 1: Yeah.
Wake up, ladies.
I feel like a pig.
WOMAN 2: Now there's
some water. It's not nice.
WOMAN 2: We all ready for
this big, exciting day?
Yeah.
That's Juno.
WOMAN 2:
I'll believe that when I see it, all right?
WOMAN 3:
How you doing?
Yeah, I feel good.
Good.
WOMAN 2: Recording for...
WOMAN 4: For National Geographic!
WOMAN 2:
For National Geographic.
WOMAN 4:
Once again...
WOMAN 2:
Recording our trip...
To Boreham boredom Cavern.
How do you think Sarah's doing?
Do you think she's ready for this?
I mean, she just seemed a little bit...
You cut the camera?
(GIRLS EXCLAIMING)
WOMAN 4:
Sarah?
Put it away for, like, 2 minutes!
Where is that?
I don't know.
WOMAN 4:
Holly! Could you take a break?
HOLLY: I just want to
take a few more shots.
This cave's a lot
cooler than I thought.
This wasn't in the book.
Good.
Maybe that last jelly custard
wasn't a really good idea.
(LAUGHING)
(HOLLY LAUGHS)
How much further, do you think?
Thank you very much.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Okay, guys?
Do you hear that?
Is that it?
WOMAN 4:
Dead animals, hundreds of them.
That's here.
SARAH: This is not good, guys.
Can we get out of here?
Which way? That's this place.
JUNO:
Come on. I don't know.
SARAH:
What do you mean you don't know?
JUNO: There's no breeze! It could be any
one of these tunnels! Take your pick!
(CLAMORING)
JUNO:
Fuck it!
Hello!
Please!
Is there anybody there?
Hello?
(SCREAMING)
What the fuck is that?
Greg! Greg!
DAN:
Greg! Greg, where are you?
(EERIE HOWLING)
(SOFT GROWLING)
Dan!
DAN:
Rios, you there?
Dan, I'm here!
Where are you?
Dan! Where are you?
(GASPS)
Dan!
(GROWLING)
Rios!
Rios! Where are you?
Let me know where you are!
I can't hear you!
Sarah.
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(CHOKING)
(SOFT GROWLING)
(CRYING)
You let him die.
(SOBBING)
What the fuck
was that thing?
Don't worry.
It's just your mind
playing tricks on you.
(ECHOING)
Dan? Greg?
Dan, is that you?
Can you hear me, Dan?
(GROWLING)
(CATH GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
(PANTING)
(CRAWLER EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(TREMBLING)
Sarah.
I...
I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
They're blind.
They track sound.
You're louder.
(SCREAMING)
Greg! Greg!
Cath!
(GREG SHUSHING)
Where's everyone else?
We got split up.
What the fuck
are these things?
I don't know.
I want my fucking torch.
Shit. Sorry. Here.
Is this okay?
Okay? Okay. All right.
(GROWLING)
Run. Run! Run!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
Jesus!
Dan!
Jesus Christ, Dan.
Fuck. Fuck!
(SCREAMING)
(SNIFFING)
VAINES: (OVER RADIO)
Are you there?
Can you hear me?
Is there anybody out there?
Come in! Anybody?
Up! Up!
Up!
(SCREAMING)
Dan's dead.
Turn it off.
Turn it off!
VAINES:
Come in. Anybody?
Are you there?
Can you hear me?
Come on, can you pick this up?
(SHUSHING)
(WHISPERING)
Dan? Dan, come in.
Dan, it's Cath. Come in.
Dan's dead.
Dan. Come in, Dan.
Vaines had his radio, Cath.
We don't know that.
We... He wasn't clear.
(NORMAL TONE)
Dan? Dan, come in. Dan?
(SHUSHING)
Give me that. Give me.
I left him there.
Those... Those fucking things
attacked us and I left him there.
No. No, he promised he'd come back.
He promised he'd come back.
I heard him scream, Cath.
I heard him scream.
He's gone, Cath, okay?
No. No.
(SHUSHING)
I ain't gonna run out on you.
You even try, and I'll kill you myself.
(GROWLING IN DISTANCE)
We gotta move.
Stay quiet. Come on.
(CATH GASPS)
Jesus.
(GROWLING IN DISTANCE)
Fuck.
GREG:
Fuck!
You'll have to jump.
It's too far.
Use her to get across.
(GROWLING IN DISTANCE)
Go.
Fuck!
We have no choice.
Fuck! Fuck!
Go!
All right, push forward!
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIRRING)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Greg!
(SOFT GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(WATER RUNNING)
Got washed out by
the water last time.
I... I can't go
down there.
The water's flowing.
There's a way through.
No, no. Wait. Wait, please.
Wait. Please. Wait!
(GROWLING)
(SHIVERING)
(BOTH GASPING)
Sarah. Sarah.
Sarah! Sarah!
Oh, God.
No, no, no. Sarah!
(SCREAMS)
Come. Come.
All right.
It stops here?
It's a dead-end.
There's no way through?
No.
Fuck!
Fucking water.
Hi, baby girl.
Hiya. It's Mommy.
I... I just wanted
to let you know...
That I love you.
I want you to be good.
And kind.
And caring.
I want you to
be a good person.
You're so special, baby.
Te quiero, te extrano, baby.
My daughter's dead.
I know.
Everything you just said,
you tell it to her face.
We're not dead yet.
Come on.
We'll keep moving.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
Juno!
Juno, I'm here to help you.
Get you out. You hear me?
I'm here with Sarah.
(SOFT GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
Sarah!
(SHRIEKING)
Oh, God.
What the fuck
is this?
SARAH:
I don't know.
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
Now I wish I was
back in the water.
(SOFT GROWLING)
(GROWLING)
What are these things?
Death.
Your friends,
they're all dead?
Yeah.
How the fuck did you
find this hellhole?
Juno brought us here.
She wanted us all to discover it.
She said she wanted
to name it after me.
Why?
Guilt.
What happened
between the 2 of you?
My husband.
She had an affair
with my husband.
What happened to her?
It was just
Juno and me left.
Those things
were coming for us,
so I hurt her so
I could get away.
She left my friend
Beth dying.
Alone.
When I found Beth,
I had to put her out of her misery.
Save your torch.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
No, Juno,
wait! Wait!
We came to get
you out! Juno.
Sarah brought us back down here.
She brought us back.
Juno. Sarah is your friend.
(SCREAMS)
So you're the
rescue party?
We're what's left.
(SOFT GROWLING)
Come on.
We gotta get out of here.
Okay, listen to me.
Listen. Those things hunt
above ground.
I think I know
which way they go.
They must have
a route to the surface.
So, let's go.
Wait a minute, so what?
We go to where they feed?
Are you fucking
kidding me?
Do you want to live?
Silence is your best weapon.
Follow me.
We're following
the water.
I ain't going in no goddamn water.
Juno knows the way out.
So how come
you're still here?
Because my light died,
I had no equipment,
and my climbing
partner put a pick
through my leg
and ran out on me...
There isn't time
for this, God damn it!
We want to get out of here alive,
we follow Juno.
No fucking way.
God damn it! I brought you
into this hellhole, I'm taking you out.
Wait!
What? It's no good.
Chief!
Shut up, Rios.
Let's move.
Come on.
It's...
We'll have to
go single file.
Spread your weight.
Keep it steady.
Easy, easy.
We really should do
this one at a time.
You ran out on her,
but you ain't running out on me,
so let's get going.
(SCREAMS)
Shit!
Help me!
Give me the bag.
Juno, help me, please!
Juno!
My arm! Pull me up!
Grab my pick.
Okay. Okay.
Cut.
What? Cut what?
Cut it,
or they'll both die!
Just fucking cut it!
(GROWLING)
SARAH:
Do it now!
VAINES:
Wait! Wait!
(SCREAMING)
Hurry!
(EXCLAIMS IN PAIN)
Fuck. Okay.
We gotta move.
We gotta go.
Rios.
Sarah.
Let's go.
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(SLURPING)
(GASPING)
(GROWLING)
(GROWLING LOUDLY)
(SCREAMS)
Come on. Come on!
(SHUSHING)
I can't...
No.
(CHOKING)
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
(GROWLING)
RIOS:
Sarah.
Sarah, we can't stay here.
Sarah. We have to
get out of here now.
(SARAH CRYING)
Sarah.
Please.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
Subtitles: Arigon
(GASPS)
(DIALING)
Come on.
(SHRIEKING)