[ Exorcist theme plays ]
[ Eerie music ]
[ Glass shatters ]
[ Thumping ]
[ Wind blowing ]
[ Rumbling ]
VOICE: Preacher.
[ Heavy breathing ]
[ Eerie music ]
MAN: I have dreams of a rose,
and then, falling down
a long flight of steps.
[ Thumping ]
MAN: Catch.
Catch.
[ Helicopters chopping ]
MAN: A light shall
shine upon this day,
for the Lord
has been born unto us.
And He is called wonderful.
God, The Prince of Peace.
MAN ON HELICOPTER RADIO:
Dockside Hunter,
sweep completed,
negative finding.
MAN 2: Roger, River.
Repeat, acknowledge.
Peace, I give you.
My peace, I leave you.
As the world gives,
do I give to you.
Let not your heart be troubled.
MAN ON HELICOPTER RADIO:
Proceeding northeast,
approximate, uh,
location near...
The Lord is my light
and my salvation.
Whom shall I fear?
The Lord is
the defender of my life.
[ Police radio chatter ]
[ Helicopters chopping ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Birds chirping ]
TIM: So, how'd I do
on my theology quiz?
FATHER: I recommend you change
your name to Rajneesh.
Really?
"God is like a power mower"?
[ Tim laughs ]
No kidding.
Father, everything's relative.
Is it?
Or maybe not.
FATHER: I like a man
who knows his mind.
Well, that's it, I'm, uh--
I got to go now.
I'm driving to Philly.
FATHER: Speed kills.
- TIM: Who's to say?
- Not me.
You know, Father,
you mentioned a Damien Karras
in your prayer for the dead.
Yes, I did.
- Father, isn't he the one who--
- Yes.
Died in a fall on those steps?
Yes, that's right, Tim.
15 years ago today.
- I hear a lot of--
- Feldman, get lost, will you?
All right.
All right, I am flight.
[ Door closes ]
[ Glass shatters ]
[ Thumping ]
MAN: Hep, hep, hep, hep,
hep, hep, hep, hep,
hep, hep, hep.
[ Wind blowing ]
MAN: You know that
you did that.
Here's more potatoes, Father.
MAN:
Could you pass the salt, AJ?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
FATHER: Joey, what did you say
that offended Tom Lowery?
He's our biggest benefactor.
Oh, he is?
What did you say to him?
"Jesus loves you.
Everyone else thinks
you're an asshole."
JOHN: Sounded pleasant.
Good morning, John.
Back aches.
Do we really have to have
our own Olympics?
Any plans today, Joe?
This afternoon,
I'm at the flicks.
It's A Wonderful Life.
Very nice.
Seen it 37 times.
That's commendable.
Do you have a favorite picture?
The Fly.
You going alone
or with the usual keepers?
I'm taking Bill Kinderman
with me.
The cop?
Yeah.
Yeah, every-- every year
on this day, he gets depressed,
so I-I try to cheer him up.
Dress more appropriately?
Do you know what Macbeth
is about? I'll tell you.
It's a play about the numbing
of the moral sense.
I tell Ryan that we have
nothing to go on in this case.
You know what he says to me?
"Win some, lose some."
You're a racist, Ryan.
Did you know that?
On the entrance exam
for new policeman,
they ask, "What are rabies
and what would you do for them?"
Ryan said,
"Rabies are Jewish priests,
and I would do anything
I possibly could for them."
What was the murder weapon,
Stedman?
I'd be guessing.
Well, if not us, who?
And if not now, when?
All right. Something like
garden shears, maybe.
We're abandoned.
I didn't get you.
I was signaling beings on Mars.
Sometimes they answer.
Funny.
So, you enjoying
your luxury cruise
aboard the Patna, Lord Jim?
I want you to telex Richmond
right away and most urgently
for the file
on the Gemini Killer.
The Gemini Killer's
been dead for 15 years.
- Who was speaking to you?
- But he's dead.
He should live so long.
And the autopsy?
When, please?
Tomorrow.
And tomorrow, and tomorrow.
I am leaving you.
Ryan, Stedman, go home.
Go home to your families.
Talk about wops.
OLD WOMAN: What kind
of job is that, a detective?
All hours. He's out
eating Danish with hoods.
MARY: You know, Ma? When
you're right, you're right.
OLD WOMAN: Oh, is that so?
Now, look, darling.
Please, don't patronize me.
It hurts old people
when they vomit.
MARY: Is that you, honey?
- Starving?
- Not really.
Just some coffee.
Hey, you've been up
since 5:00 in the morning.
I have this.
How was your tour of Virginia?
Neat. We stopped at a diner,
and instead of potatoes,
they served Mama grits.
So, she says right out loud,
"These Jews are crazy."
They are! They're all wackos.
- Next, they'll wanna eat papaya.
- My God.
How was your day?
Fabulous triumph.
Our trackers at long last
brought in Mushkin,
the Georgetown terrorist
and scourge of society
who breaks into people's homes
and completely redecorates.
You okay, Bill?
Hi, Daddy.
- And goodbye?
- Uh-huh, off to dance class.
Pocahontas with the hair.
Watch out for red shoes.
So, you're home now.
BILL: No, gotta go again.
Today is my day to cheer up
our friend, Father Dyer.
[Approaching police sirens ]
[ Car screeches,
sirens turn off ]
What are you doing out here?
Founding an order
called Lurking Fathers?
I've been standing out there
for centuries.
Four new popes
have been elected.
That's a lot of white smoke.
Official business.
So, all right. So, I'm late.
So, I know it.
So, I'm sorry.
I got...
You want butter on it?
No. And could I have
two Cokes, please?
- Medium or large?
- Medium.
- What are you doing?
- I need some lemon drops.
We'll be late
for the start of the picture.
I once spent a year
hearing children's confessions,
and I wound up
a lemon drop junkie.
Little weirdoes
keep breathing it on you
along with all that pot,
and between the two of them,
I've got a feeling
it's probably addictive.
[ Background chatter ]
Now, I suppose you have
all sorts of rosary biz
and the like.
No, no. Loose as a goose.
Maybe you should go home
and rest.
I can't go home.
- Why?
- The carp.
You know,
I thought you said...
My wife's mother is visiting,
Father.
And Tuesday night,
she's cooking us a carp.
It's a tasty fish, I--
I have nothing against it.
But because it's supposedly
filled with impurities,
she buys it live.
And for three days,
it's been swimming up and down
in my bathtub.
Up...
and down.
And I hate it.
I can't stand the sight of it.
Moving its gills.
You're standing
very close to me, Father.
Have you noticed?
Yes.
I haven't had a bath
for three days.
I can't go home
until the carp is asleep.
[ Laughs ]
Because if I see it swimming...
...I'll kill it.
[ Background chatter ]
- And a salad.
- Okay.
BILL: Nobody could
do that scene
like Jimmy Stewart, Father.
No one.
What a film, huh?
So innocent, so good.
It fills your heart.
Yeah, well, you said the same
thing about Eraserhead.
[ Chuckles ]
Most Jews pick a priest
for a friend.
It's always someone
like Teilhard de Chardin.
What do I get?
I get a priest who calls
children little weirdos
and treats all his friends
like Rubik's Cube,
always twisting them around
in his hands,
trying to find colors.
What's the matter?
You're not eating.
It's too spicy.
I've seen you dip Twinkies
in mustard. Come on.
Eat something, Gandhi.
Stop fasting.
The teeming masses
need your strength.
You're so stubborn.
I know, I know.
Me too.
What a wonderful man he was,
Bill.
So loving, so terribly kind.
The whole world
is a homicide victim, Father.
Would a God who is good
invent something like death?
Plainly speaking,
it's a lousy idea.
It's not popular, Father.
It's not a winner.
There you go, blaming God.
Who should I blame,
Phil Rizzuto?
You wouldn't want
to live forever.
- Yes, I would.
- No, you wouldn't.
- You'd get bored.
- I have hobbies.
In the meantime,
we have cancer,
and mongoloid babies,
and murderers,
monsters prowling the planet.
Even prowling
this neighborhood, Father.
Right now,
while our children suffer
and our loved ones die.
And your God goes waltzing
blithely through the universe
like some kind of cosmic
Billie Burke.
Bill, it all works out right.
When?
At the end of time.
- That soon?
- No, we're gonna be there.
We're gonna live forever, Bill.
We're spirits.
How I would love
to believe that.
It's that kid that got killed
on the dock, isn't it?
I heard it on the news.
You wanna talk about it?
You knew him.
A little bit.
Police Boys Club.
His name was Thomas.
Thomas Kintry.
Black boy, about 12 years old.
The killer...
...drove an ingot
into each of his eyes...
then cut off his head.
WOMAN: Is this okay, Father?
I can get you something else.
Some more coffee?
In place of his head
was the head
from a statue of Christ,
all done up in blackface,
like a minstrel show, you know?
The eyes and the mouth
painted white.
Mr. Bones.
The boy had been crucified...
...on a pair of rowing oars.
[ Church bells tolling,
background chatter ]
May the Lord be in your heart
and help you
to confess your sins.
Yes?
OLD WOMAN: I have a...
a scrupulous conscience,
Father.
This need to confess...
...so many things.
If I step on two straws
in the shape of a cross,
I feel
that I have to confess it.
It torments me.
Try to make a good confession.
And remember, Christ
forgives us all of our sins.
OLD WOMAN:
Only little things, nothing.
Seventeen of them, Father.
The first was that waitress
near Candlestick Park.
I cut her throat
and watched her bleed.
She bled a great deal.
It's a problem
that I'm working on, Father.
All this bleeding.
[ Maniacal laughter ]
[ Screaming and sobbing ]
[ Thunder rolling ]
[ Humming ]
[ Police radio chatter ]
I don't know. I don't know.
He was such a good...
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
[ Thunder rolling,
police radio chatter ]
You know,
I've been thinking, lieutenant--
This is new.
Do we really need prints
from the inside
of the sliding panel?
I mean, all you're gonna get
are the prints of the priest.
Yes, I know.
Then, what's the point?
I'm padding the job.
[ Clicking pen ]
[ Thunder rolling ]
[ Eerie music ]
[ Women laughing ]
[ Eerie music, wood sliding ]
[ Wood sliding continues ]
[ Window slams open ]
We've got an autopsy
on the boy.
[ Sighs ]
Yes.
Kintry didn't die
from the decapitation.
He was injected with a drug
called succinylcholine.
They use it
in electroshock therapy.
But injecting 10 milligrams
for each 50 pounds
of body weight
causes immediate
and total paralysis.
The kid couldn't move or scream
while the killer
was nailing and cutting him up.
He was conscious?
Yes.
He was fully aware.
The drug attacks
the respiratory system.
He died from slow asphyxiation.
INTERCOM: Ms. Scott,
please report
to West Wing nurses' station.
Father Dyer,
Joseph Dyer, D-Y-E-R.
- He's in room 411.
- 411.
INTERCOM:
Dr. Miller, line 118.
What's this nonsense?
Well, nothing's really wrong.
They're just doing some tests.
You mean
they couldn't find a rabbit?
I don't know you.
You're reading
Women's Wear Daily?
So what? Am I supposed to give
spiritual advice in a vacuum?
Is that for me?
Oh, I found it in the street.
I thought it suited you.
[ Coughing ]
I thought you told me there's
nothing really wrong with you.
There isn't, my brother Eddie
had these same
stupid symptoms for years.
Your brother Eddie died
at the age of 30.
So what?
He got killed in Vietnam.
There could have
be some connection.
A connection?
Are you sure
this isn't serious, Joe?
- Well, with Eddie, there was--
- You shut up about Eddie!
- With my brother, it was nerves.
- You make people a lot nervous.
- Only sinners.
- Everybody!
Is everything all right
in here, guys?
We're fine!
I'm just tired.
Well, call the desk
and book a room.
I brought you a hamburger,
Father.
I'm not hungry.
Eat half. It's from Clyde's.
Where'd the other half
come from?
Space, your native country.
I've come to take
a little blood from you, Father.
- Again?
- What's again?
Somebody already took it
not 20 minutes ago.
Are you kidding me?
There's a hole.
There it sure is,
hell, goddamn, rat shit is.
Who stuck this guy?
Nice and peaceful here,
isn't it?
Idyllic.
Those things will kill you,
incidentally.
They're quiet.
Mr. Horowitz?
Nope.
This is 409?
411.
Never mind.
Go in peace, my child.
May the Schwartz be with you.
It's a drug cart.
Why not?
Almost anyone
could steal something from it.
I heard about what happened
at the church.
I beg your pardon?
Father Kanavan.
Oh, yeah. Well, we found
some kind of drug in him.
He didn't feel a thing, Father.
He had no pain.
Ah, well, that's good.
Shouldn't you be reading
from the Gospels or something?
They don't give you
all the fashions.
- Oh, this is true.
- Damn right.
Look at the gooey gowns,
they're getting boring.
Couldn't you get me
something serious to read?
I've got to be going.
No, can't you pick me
something up?
My God, the grammar.
No, I want The National Enquirer
and The Star.
There are Jesuit missions
in India, Father.
Couldn't you find one
to work in?
Now look, these are all
last week's editions.
I've read every one of them.
If you will forgive me,
I will leave
this mystical conversation.
Too much of aesthetics
always gives me a headache.
Is it something I said?
Mother India is calling you,
Father.
INTERCOM: Dr. Kincaid
to Orthopedics, please.
EKG stat to ER.
STEADMAN: Father Kanavan's
vocal cords were paralyzed.
He couldn't make a sound.
He couldn't cry out for help,
so the killer was
able to take his time.
Succinylcholine again?
In precisely the proper dosage
to cause the paralysis.
A fraction too little
has no effect.
A fraction too much
causes instant death.
Our friend
has medical expertise.
Did we find a hypodermic
at the crime scene?
No syringe.
What about
the fingerprint analysis?
Most of the prints
were the priest's.
You said most?
We've got something else.
Right here, on the inside
pull of this panel.
It's strange.
Nobody touches this pull
but the priest.
And the killer.
See, he wants the panel closed,
so that the next person
in line for confession
doesn't know
that Father Kanavan is dead.
So he puts his hand in
and slides it almost shut.
Then he has to pull
his hand back out
and finish the job
from the outside.
So the prints on the oars
from the crucified boy
match the prints on the panel,
correct?
They're one and the same.
Well, aren't they?
Two different people
committed these murders?
BILL: Where's Julie?
MARY: At dance class.
BILL: So late?
MARY: Bill, it's only 10:00.
BILL: It's very late.
[ Clock ticking ]
[ Music box chiming ]
[ Ominous music ]
MAN: Your attention, please.
Your attention.
The 12:18 to Elksberg
now departing from track 11.
All passengers boarding
proceed to the gate.
Let me out
of this damn casa blanca!
[ Eerie classical music ]
- BOY 1: No, it isn't!
- BOY 2: Yes, it is!
No, it isn't. If it hits
the line, it's out of bounds.
- BOY 2: The line is in bounds!
- No, it's not, it's out!
BOY 2: It hit the dirt!
WOMAN: Earth, come in, please.
Can you hear us?
We are attempting
to communicate.
Come in, please.
The living are deaf.
We come here first.
Lieutenant.
How you doing, lieutenant?
I'm so sorry you were murdered,
Thomas. I miss you.
I miss you, too.
[ Smooth big band playing ]
You know, I wonder
if both of us are dreaming this.
No, Bill.
I'm not dreaming.
[ Big band music builds ]
[ Ominous music ]
[ Phone ringing ]
BILL: Kinderman.
What are you telling me?
Hold it.
[ People whispering ]
[ Police radio chatters ]
I've just never seen
anything like this in 20 years.
Call it.
- What's her name?
- Ellen.
[ Police radio chatters,
camera clicking ]
[ Camera continues clicking ]
INTERCOM: Dr. Bartlet,
please call the operator.
Dr. Bartlet,
EKG stat to ER.
please call the operator.
Dr. Bartlet,
Ugh...
[ Thunder rolling ]
What are these?
What are they?
What's in them?
Father Dyer's
entire blood supply.
What?
All of his blood?
And not a drop of it spilled.
All neat.
There's not even a smudge
on the jars.
There's only the writing
in his blood.
Writing?
On the wall.
[ Thunder rolling ]
[ Ominous music ]
INTERCOM:
Dr. Hoffman, line 412.
- Lieutenant.
- Dr. Hoffman, line 412, please.
Take a squad of men.
Make sure all the hospital doors
are locked.
Make a pattern search.
No one in.
No one out.
Except for emergencies.
No one.
All right.
INTERCOM: EKG stat to ER.
EKG stat to ER.
Now...
What time was
the body discovered?
At 6:00.
By whom?
You saw him at 5:00 a.m.?
Yes, that's right.
He was awake?
He was awake.
I came to give him medication.
How long did it take you?
About a minute.
And then what?
I came back to the desk.
And you were here
until you went
to see Father Dyer again
at 6:00, is that right?
Yes, that's right.
Were you here
or inside in the office?
I was inside the office.
I was writing up reports.
So, if someone had entered
Father Dyer's room
between the time you left
and the time you returned,
you might well not
have seen them.
That's right.
Did you see anybody else
go into the room?
No, I didn't.
Or leaving the room?
Did you see anybody
in the hallway?
Mrs. Clelia.
You saw Mrs. Clelia
walking around?
No, not exactly.
Not exactly?
I found her lying
completely unconscious.
When was that?
On my way to give the Father
his last medication.
The 5:00 or the 6:00?
The 6:00.
Mrs. Clelia is a patient?
Yes, she is.
In Neurology?
INTERCOM: Dr. Randolph
to examining bay two.
Dr. Randolph
to examining bay two, please.
[ Moaning ]
NURSE: How we doing today?
They're all harmless.
Well, some more serious problems
here, too, though, of course.
Some catatonics,
some with Alzheimer's, autism.
Are you my son?
I'd be very proud to believe so.
You're not my son.
[ Eerie growling ]
There's your girl over there.
[ Humming ]
Mrs. Clelia?
- My name is William Kinderman.
- Yes.
Would you help me, please?
What about my radio?
Pardon me?
I said, my radio.
Aren't you gonna fix it?
Ugh, nothing ever gets fixed
around here.
Just a bunch
of pies and anchovies.
Go away!
I don't ever talk to strangers.
I'm the radio repairman,
Mrs. Clelia.
Well, fix it.
Well, what's wrong with it?
Dead people talking.
INTERCOM:
Lab technician to Oncology.
It's right here.
Do you see it?
Yes, I see it.
I just knew you weren't really
a radio repairman.
That's a telephone I'm holding.
It's all right.
A lot of people wouldn't know
the difference either.
It's all right.
You have a very kind face.
You will do well.
[ Humming ]
You caught her
on a talkative day.
You being funny?
No, she's quasi-catatonic,
in and out.
What's this?
The disturbed ward.
[ Door slides shut ]
To get out,
...you punch
a four-digit combination
that sends a signal out
to the control booth.
The inner door opens.
The control booth operator
visually checks
through the one-way glass.
And every day,
there's a new combination.
I'd like to look around.
VOICE: Bill.
[ Door slides open ]
ATKINS: Lieutenant.
Dr. Freedman's
gone ballistic, sir.
I think you need to come.
[ Inaudible dialogue ]
MAN: Death, be not proud.
Though some have called thee
mighty and dreadful,
thou art not so.
Though soonest
our best men with thee go,
death of their bones
and soul's delivery,
but those thou dost thinkest
thou dost overthrow,
die not, poor Death.
Nor canst thou kill me.
We're a hospital here,
not a war zone.
How do you expect us
to keep people calm
when you're running
around here--
[ Phone ringing,
yelling muffled ]
You need a court warrant
in order to be here
doing what you're doing!
Look, I fully appreciate
your trying to prevent
further tragedy.
But think of the state
of our patients' minds
when you've got
these policemen here--
Lieutenant wants fingerprints
taken of all the hospital staff.
He said fingerprints!
Not on your life, goddammit!
No sir, no way, Jose!
No, he's standing right here.
I don't want 100 lawyers
running up and down the halls.
Do you want to talk to him?
You ever heard
of malpractice suits?
of the Gemini Killer?
- Have I what?
- I said--
Yes, of course
I've heard of him. So what?
He's dead.
That's right,
he died in the electric chair.
And so why
are we talking about that?
Just a minute, I'll explain.
Yes, the Gemini is dead.
We all know that, but do you
recall all the stories
in the papers and on television,
about the Gemini's strange MO?
I'll remind you.
Supposedly--
supposedly, the middle finger
of the victim's left hand
was always found severed,
always missing.
In addition,
on the victim's back,
we were told,
the killer carved out...
...a sign of the zodiac.
The Gemini symbol, the twins.
- That was 15 years ago.
- Go ahead, lieutenant.
Temple, why are you
encouraging this?
Would you shut your mouth?!
Excuse me.
Um...
INTERCOM: EKG stat to ER.
EKG stat to ER.
The Gemini MO...
...that you heard about
is false.
The missing finger was not
on the victim's left hand,
but on the right
It was the index finger,
this one.
And the sign of the Gemini
was carved
not on the victim's back,
but on the victim's
left-hand palm.
Only Richmond Homicide
knew that, no one else.
A misinformation
was fed to the press
in order to weed out
all the crackpots
who were coming in
saying everyday
that they were
the Gemini killer.
"How did you kill him?"
"Well, first I cut off
this finger," the loony says,
"And on their backs
I made my mark."
Next case.
But,
in this case, gentlemen,
in this...
three decapitations,
three victims,
with this finger severed,
the correct one,
and the sign of the Gemini here.
Here!
One more thing.
The Gemini wrote letters
to the newspapers,
bragging about his murders.
And he always doubled
his final L's,
whatever the word,
two L's, as in "wonderfull".
Yes.
And the victims' names
always starting with K,
like Karl, his father,
the famous evangelist
whom he hated
and wanted to shame.
And whom he wanted to kill,
and keep killing and killing.
But the priest,
Father Dyer, Joseph Dyer.
Father Dyer's middle name
was Kevin.
Kevin.
[ Eerie wind blowing ]
Even that could do it.
Would it take
a lot of strength?
No, not at all.
Very little, in fact.
Spring-activated.
Open it,
and it closes on its own.
Takes strength just to open it.
Oh?
It's a little stiff.
It needs adjustment.
- What's this?
- What?
This label.
Just a shipping tag.
Is it new?
Just came in.
A replacement?
Where's the old one?
[ Clock ticking ]
BILL: Two priests
and a crucified boy,
Father Healey.
There's clearly
some religious connection,
but what is it?
I don't know
what I'm looking for.
I'm groping.
[ Sighs ]
But,
besides being priests,
what might Kanavan and Dyer
have had in common?
Where's the link?
I don't know.
Dear God.
[ Clock falls silent ]
It could be that exorcism.
The MacNeil kid, Regan MacNeil.
The exorcism
over on Prospect Street
that Damien Karras did.
The one that killed him.
[ Soft sobbing ]
[ Door creaking ]
[ Whispering
in foreign language ]
[ Soft thump ]
[ Door creaking ]
[ Whispering ]
[ Ominous rattling ]
[ Whispering
in foreign language ]
[ Dramatic echoing ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Whispering continues ]
[ Growling ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Laughing ]
Excuse me.
FATHER: Alice!
The speech!
Will you give this to Father,
please, lieutenant?
I got to run.
What's the matter
with these lights?
FATHER: Good night, Alice!
Good night, Father.
[ Door slams ]
Your speech, Father.
Thanks.
That's all right.
Need a drink?
I do.
Do you believe in possession,
Father?
Who cares?
I've got enough to do
worrying about kids
who need scholarships.
Well, you mentioned
that exorcism.
As a connection.
To the people
who were murdered, you mean.
That's right.
Joe and Damien Karras
were very close.
Yes, I know.
Joe was also a friend
of the MacNeils.
And Father Kanavan?
Kanavan had my job back then.
He gave Damien permission
to investigate the case.
That leaves us
with the Kintry boy, Father.
Does it?
Damien gave
our School of Linguistics
a tape he wanted them
to analyze for him,
the voice of the MacNeil kid,
supposedly possessed.
He wanted to find out
if the sounds on the tape
were a language
or just a lot of gibberish.
He was looking for proof
the MacNeil kid
was speaking in a language
she couldn't possibly
have known.
And was she?
No.
The tape was really English
in reverse.
But the expert
who figured that out--
Was Kintry's mother.
[ Beeping ]
This is impossible.
[ Thunder rolling,
rain falling ]
Do you remember coming in here
when the priest died,
Mrs. Clelia?
You're the radio man.
Yes, that's right.
Do you remember coming in here?
Do you remember coming in here
and touching those jars?
Why did you touch them,
Mrs. Clelia?
Was there anyone else
in this room?
Who was in here?
That radio isn't mine.
Mine is newer.
DR. TEMPLE: That man
in the isolation tank...
You know,
the one you looked in on?
[ Clears throat ]
You know,
the one you looked in on.
Yeah...
Well, the police brought him
in here 15 years ago.
They picked him up
wandering the C&O Canal.
Uh, no, no, no.
Down around Key Bridge.
Yes, total amnesia.
The man in the isolation tank...
You know,
the one you looked in on.
The police brought him
in here 15 years ago.
They picked him up
wandering the C&O Canal.
- Down around Key--
- [ Door rattling ]
You had something to tell me?
Please, sit down.
There's a paper drive?
Haven't had a chance yet
to read them.
I just keep them till I do.
I hate to miss
the science articles.
They're good.
[ Thunder rolling ]
That man in the isolation tank,
you know,
the one you looked in on?
Yes.
The police brought him in here
15 years ago.
They picked him up
wandering the C&O Canal,
down around Key Bridge.
Total amnesia, no ID.
They brought him to us here,
and his condition grew worse.
He ended up catatonic,
completely withdrawn.
But recently...
Well...
About six weeks ago,
he slowly started
to come out of it.
Every day he got better.
Just a little, but better.
And then, all of a sudden,
he got violent,
really bad news.
We've been giving him
electroshock therapy,
and as of two weeks ago,
he's been in isolation, but...
The thing is, lieutenant...
Yes?
He says he's the Gemini Killer.
[ Eerie music ]
I want the file on that man.
Get it.
Now!
This file is thin, Dr. Temple.
Thin. No age, no description
of what he was wearing.
Were you here when this man
was brought in?
- No, I wasn't.
- Who was?
Nurse Allerton, I think.
I'll go get her for you.
Yes, get her.
You wanted to know
about the man in cell 11.
Stretch your memory.
What was he wearing
when they brought him in?
Do you recall?
That was quite some time ago.
Was he dressed like a priest?
Like a priest?
Were there any signs
of injuries? Blood, lacerations?
That would be in the file.
It is not in the file!
It is not!
Two men on every ward.
- Rotate them 24 hours a day.
- Mm-hmm.
On the disturbed ward,
one man inside
near the entry door,
one man outside the door.
Ask the Jesuits in Georgetown
for the dental records
of a Father Damien Karras.
Find out if he ever had
a saliva test.
Might help us get
a positive identification.
What for, sir?
- Sir, are you all right?
- Mmm...
INTERCOM: IV team to NICU.
IV team to NICU.
Phew.
You all right?
Yeah.
Father Karras...
...was a Jesuit psychiatrist
at Georgetown University.
The man was a saint.
He was my best friend,
I loved him.
Fifteen years ago,
he jumped or was pushed
to his death
down that long flight of steps
next to the Car Barn.
Atkins...
I saw it.
I watched him...
...die.
I think...
...the man in cell 11...
...is Damien Karras.
It's a wonderful life.
BILL: You know what
the physicists
are saying now, Atkins?
Hmm?
That there are no such things
as things.
That matter is kind of
an illusion.
That electrons can travel
from place to place
without having to move
through the space in between.
Could even travel
backwards in time...
...in such a world.
Maybe there shouldn't be
a thing like surprise.
It isn't him.
[ Water dripping ]
BILL: Who are you?
Who are you?
No one.
Many.
Do you know me?
I can do imitations. Listen.
[ Imitates horse ]
Who are you?
You know.
Are you Damien Karras?
Ah, haven't any medical records
for him, have you?
No tedious fingerprints.
Are you Karras?
I am the Gemini Killer,
James Venamun.
The Gemini is dead.
No, not quite.
Not quite.
I'm at the station.
[ Imitates train ]
Your attention, please.
Your attention.
The 12:18 to elsewhere,
now departing
from track 11.
[ Laughs ]
Which is the dream world,
lieutenant?
Here...
...or there?
Why do you call me lieutenant?
Ah, don't play games with me,
fool.
Remember Karen?
Little ribbons in her hair?
Yellow ribbons.
I killed her.
After all, it was inevitable,
wasn't it?
A divinity shapes our ends,
and all that.
I picked her up in Richmond.
And I dropped her off
at the city dump,
at least some of her.
Some of her I kept.
I'm sentimental.
It's a fault, lieutenant.
Who's perfect? Not me.
In my defense, I kept her breast
in my freezer for a time.
I'm a saver.
Pretty dress she was wearing.
Little peasant blouse, pink,
white ruffles.
I still hear from her
occasionally, screaming.
I think the dead should shut up
unless there's something to say.
Yes, I killed the black boy
by the river.
And the priests.
Oh, yes, their names began
with K.
That little modicum, at least,
I was able to insist upon.
But they were off
my beaten track, you understand?
I kill at random.
That's the thrill of it.
No motive, that's the fun.
But the black boy
and the priests were different.
I was...
...obliged...
...to settle a score...
...on behalf of a friend.
What friend?
You know, a friend...
...over here...
...the other side.
I'm so cold.
And afraid.
There is suffering over here.
It isn't easy.
No, not easy.
They can sometimes be cruel.
Very cruel.
Who is "they"?
Never mind.
I cannot tell you.
It's forbidden.
[ Loud growling ]
I do that rather well,
don't you think?
Why not?
After all, I've been taught
by the master.
Who's that?
The one.
There is only one.
By the way,
did you know that you're talking
to an artist?
I sometimes do special things
to my victims.
Things that are creative.
Of course, it takes...
...knowledge and pride
in your work.
Did you know, for example,
that decapitated heads
can continue to see
for approximately 20 seconds?
So, when I have one
that's gawking,
I always hold it up
so that it can see it's body.
It's a little extra I throw in
for no added charge.
I must admit,
it makes me chuckle every time.
But why should I have
all the fun?
I like to share.
Of course, I got no credit
for that in the media.
They only want to print
all the bad things about me.
- Now, is that fair?
- Damian!
Don't shout, please.
There are sick people in here.
Observe the rules,
or I'll have you ejected.
Incidentally...
...who's this Damien
you insist that I am?
You know.
I know nothing,
except I must go
on killing daddy.
I must shame him.
Are they calling these
Gemini killings in the paper?
It's important. You must
get them to do that, lieutenant.
The Gemini is dead.
No, I am not, I am alive!
I go on, I breathe!
See to it it's known,
or I will punish you.
Punish me?
Yes.
Do you dance?
What--?
[ Female voice singing
in foreign language ]
I like plays.
The good ones, Shakespeare.
I like Titus Andronicus
the best.
It's sweet.
Life is fun.
It's a wonderful life,
in fact...
...for some.
It's too bad
about poor Father Dyer.
You know, I killed him.
An interesting problem,
but finally, it worked.
A bit of the old succinylcholine
to permit one
to work
without annoying distractions.
Then, a three-foot catheter
threaded directly
into the inferior vena cava,
or, in fact,
the superior vena cava.
It's-- it's a matter of taste,
I think, don't you?
Then the tube
moves through the vein,
from the crease under the arm,
into the vein
that leads into the heart.
Then, you hold up the legs
and squeeze the blood
manually into the tube
from the arms and the legs...
...shaking and pounding
at the end for the dregs.
It isn't perfect.
There's a little blood left,
I'm afraid.
But regardless...
...the overall effect
is astonishing.
And isn't that really
what counts in the end?
Yes, of course.
Good showbiz, lieutenant,
the effect!
And then,
off comes the head
without spilling
one single drop of blood.
Now, I call that showmanship,
lieutenant.
Then, of course,
no one notices.
Pearls before--
[ Hand smashing face ]
Oh.
A few boos from the gallery,
I see.
That's all right.
I understand. I've been dull.
I shall liven things up for you
a bit, lieutenant.
The master is throwing me
a scrap from his table.
A little reward
for faithful service.
Something fun.
Something random.
Something...
...my way.
Good night, moon.
Good night, Amy.
Telling her beads...
Her beads...
[ Pressing button repeatedly ]
[ Dinging ]
- BILL: He passed out.
- ALLERTON: Again?
My God, he's hemorrhaging.
The man in that cell
knows the details of a murder
of a girl named Karen.
It happened years ago.
Yes?
It was a Gemini killing
that never appeared
in the papers.
ALLERTON: His goddamn nose
is broken!
When I told you that the man
in cell 11 fell unconscious,
you said something.
Really?
Yes, I think you said, "Again?"
Might have done.
Does that mean
that it's happened before?
Yes, it has.
Many times?
No, not really.
It's just been this week.
I think the first time
was Sunday.
And again?
The next day.
If you want exact times, it's--
On your chart. Yes.
Yes, that's right.
Any other times?
Early yesterday morning,
just before we found--
Yes, that's all right.
I'm very sorry.
When this happens,
does it seem
like a normal sleep?
Nothing's normal about that man.
You seem a little pleased
about that.
Well, it's quite unusual.
His autonomic system
slows to a crawl.
His heartbeat,
his temperature...
...his breathing,
but his brain-wave activity
accelerates.
Accelerates?
Okay, keep that on
until the weekend.
You're most kind.
I'm a bitch.
Have you ever told
the man in cell 11
what happened to Father Dyer?
No, of course not.
Might anyone else have told him?
Why would they?
I don't know.
I don't either.
BILL: Alright, he was buried
the next morning.
Closed coffin, the usual.
But who was the last person
ever to see him?
Would you know?
- Brother Fain.
- I beg your pardon?
Brother Fain.
At least, I think it was.
Wait a second. Hold on.
Yeah, that's right.
That's who it was.
Brother Fain.
He was left to dress the body
and seal up the coffin.
And then, no one
ever saw him again.
It was a sad case.
He always griped about The Order
not treating him well.
Well, he has family in Kentucky.
He was always asking
for an assignment
someplace near them.
He never got it.
- Toward the end, he was--
- Toward the end?
Oh, he was elderly, 80, 81.
He always said
that when he died,
he'd make sure he died at home.
We always figured
he'd just split
because he sensed
the end was coming.
He'd already had a couple
pretty bad coronaries.
What's the matter?
Brother Fain...
...had two heart attacks,
precisely?
Yeah, two.
Was he tall?
Yes, he was very tall.
The man we found
in Damien's coffin,
you remember,
was dressed like a priest.
Yeah.
His vital organs
were remarkably preserved.
Is that so?
We did an autopsy, Father,
and discovered, well...
He was elderly,
perhaps in his eighties.
Very tall.
No teeth.
We made out the scarring
of three major heart attacks.
Two before,
plus the one that killed him.
Yes.
We have every indication
to believe that he died of...
...fright.
BILL: "And Jesus said
to the man who was possessed,
"'What is your name?'
"And he answered, 'Legion,
for we are many.'''
Many.
[ Door closing ]
- Good night, Daddy.
- Good night, Julie dearest.
It's so late.
Yes, it is.
Very late.
[ Rattling ]
[ Door creaks ]
[ Thud ]
[ Rattling ]
[ Ice cracking ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Screams ]
God Almighty,
can't I get any sleep?
- What the hell do you want?
- Sir, I'm very sorry.
Bad enough you wake me up
at half past 5:00 for breakfast.
- Sir, I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
I think you do this on purpose.
What's your name?
I'm going to report you.
My name is Amy Keating.
Good night.
[ Sighs ]
MAN: Angels of mercy,
horseshit.
[ Noisily rattling at desk ]
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Yes, I'm fine.
I'm just a little jumpy,
that's all.
Okay.
[ Grinding ]
[ Keys jingling ]
[ Door creaks open
light clicks on ]
[ Light clicks off ]
[ Dramatic music ]
She was slit down the middle.
Cut open.
And all her vital organs
were removed.
Then, the killer
stuffed her body with...
...other materials,
and sewed her back up.
Other materials?
Rosaries.
Catholic rosaries.
ALLERTON: Lieutenant!
[ Ominous rumbling ]
GEMINI: Did you get
my message?
I left it with Keating.
Nice girl, good heart.
BILL: You killed her?
You must put it in the papers,
lieutenant.
You must tell them
that these are Gemini killings.
In the meantime...
About this body of mine.
Friend of yours?
[ Laughs ]
Well, there I was,
so awfully dead
in that electric chair.
I didn't like it.
Would you?
It's upsetting!
There was still
so much killing to do,
and there I was, without a body.
So unfair.
But then, along came,
the master.
He thought my work
should continue,
but in this body.
In this body in particular,
in fact.
Oh, let's call it revenge.
A certain matter of an exorcism,
I think,
in which your friend,
Father Karras,
expelled certain parties
from the body of a child.
Certain parties
were not pleased,
to say the least.
To say the very least.
And so, my friend,
the master,
devised
this pretty little scheme
as a way of getting back,
of creating a stumbling block,
a scandal,
a horror to the eyes
of all men who seek faith,
using the body
of this saintly priest
as an instrument of my...
...work.
But then, that's a perk,
a bonus, a little extra.
The main thing
is the torment
of your friend, Father Karras,
as he watches while I rip,
and cut,
and mutilate the innocent,
his friends,
again, and again,
and on, and on!
He is inside with us!
He will never get away!
His pain won't end!
Oh, gracious me, was I raving?
Please forgive me.
I'm mad.
Where was I?
Oh, yes, the master.
He was kind, see?
He brought me to our mutual
acquaintance, Father Karras.
Not too well at the time,
I'm afraid.
He was passing on
in the dying mode, as we say.
So, as Karras was
about to slip out of his body,
why, the master
was slipping me in.
Slickly done.
I mean, he was dead.
His time was up.
He wanted out, but I was in.
A little traumatized, true.
I mean, after all,
his brain was jelly,
lack of oxygen and all,
that sort of thing.
It took a maximum effort
that at last got me out
of that cheap little coffin.
Vow of poverty, disgusting.
Never mind.
Toward the end,
a little slapstick
and comic relief
when that old Brother Fain
saw me climbing from the coffin.
[ Laughing ]
It's the smiles
that keep us going,
don't you think?
The little giggles
and bits of good cheer.
After that, it was all
blue Mondays for a while.
So much damage
to Karras' brain cells.
So many lost.
It took me 15 years
to bring them back.
Fifteen years.
So many years.
Who are you?
Just a traveling man.
One who moves.
How can I believe
that you're the Gemini Killer?
Oh, you are issuing a clear
invitation to the dance.
What do you mean?
- We shall see.
- Please, explain that.
We shall see.
Incidentally, don't blame me
for Temple.
That was suicide.
The man was a lunatic,
a weakling.
Still, he helped me.
Are there services?
I'd like to attend.
- Temple helped you?
- Yes, of course!
He brought you to me.
I told him that if he failed
to convince you to come to me
that he would suffer
in unspeakable ways.
Poor superstitious fool,
he believed me.
And you came.
But he couldn't take
the pressure, it would seem.
What pressure?
The pressure of inimitable me.
Some other tasks
I said I had for him,
things, little things.
You know, I think perhaps
you really are the Gemini.
- Oh, good.
- But I can't be sure.
- Not sure?
- No.
I don't think I'll ever
really be convinced
until I know how you managed
to get out of this cell.
Does someone help you?
I see.
Who helps you?
Just friends.
Old friends.
You know, lieutenant...
There are so many possibilities.
Maybe I really am your friend,
Father Karras.
And after the fall,
I revived at a terribly
inconvenient moment
and wandered through the streets
without knowing who I was,
and still don't,
for that matter.
Needless to say, of course,
I'm quite naturally
and hopelessly mad.
But sometimes,
I have dreams of a rose.
And then, falling down
a long flight of steps.
And other times,
I dream I'm the Gemini Killer.
And these dreams are very nice.
They feel so comfortable,
so right.
But I can't sort out the dreams
from the truth.
Am I Karras?
There's so many
other possibilities.
Perhaps the Gemini
had an accomplice
who is still at large
and very active.
Maybe I am that old accomplice.
Perhaps I'm telepathic
or have psychic powers
that give me all my knowledge
of the Gemini killings.
The new ones,
the old ones,
the ones still to be.
Tell the press
that I am the Gemini,
lieutenant,
final warning.
Incidentally, I can help.
Help what?
Your unbelief.
Little Jack Horner.
Child's play, lieutenant.
I'm tired.
I'm so tired.
Damien?
No!
MAN: A transfer up
from pediatrics.
NURSE: Let's see where we're
gonna put you up for the day,
my little man.
Let me to Father Healy, please.
It's urgent.
NURSE: 410.
BILL: Will you
expect him soon?
NURSE: Jimmy,
I can't read this.
Korner, K-O-R-N-E-R.
BILL: I'll call again.
See you later, alligator.
NURSE: Come on sweetheart,
let's go back to your room.
Just take your time.
That's it.
Take it easy.
BILL: How do you get
out of here?
GEMINI: Old friends,
old friends.
I'm a traveling man,
one who moves.
Old friends, one who moves.
One who moves, one who...
[ Indistinct chatter ]
I-I didn't hear it.
Say it again, will you?
Yeah.
[ Mumbling ]
[ Ominous rumbling ]
[ Ominous music ]
- Hit the light!
- Mommy!
ALLERTON: God Almighty!
What the hell do you think
you're doing? Are you crazy?
What on Earth
is the matter with you?
I want my mommy.
Just toys.
Is that a crime?
He's after someone. Who?
You treat your own family
like this?
Aren't you leaving?
Please leave.
I cannot wait for you to leave!
Oh, you are issuing
a clear invitation to the dance.
To the dance, to the dance...
Julie.
[ Phone ringing ]
Hello.
Bill.
Hiya, honey. Where...
Uh-huh.
[ Busy signal beeping ]
Okay, sweetheart.
That was Bill. There's a nurse
coming over with a package.
Danny, get in the car!
Roll it, roll it,
move it, move it! Go, go!
[ Engine turns over ]
[ Sirens blaring,
wheels squealing ]
[ Ominous music ]
[ Sirens blaring,
wheels squealing ]
[ Ominous music ]
[ Sirens blaring,
wheels squealing ]
Go around!
Ram it if you have to! Ram it.
Back up, you son of a--
Get out!
Go!
[ Doorbell ringing ]
That must be the nurse.
[ Machine ticking ]
[ Growling ]
[ Tires screeching ]
Go around the back!
Oh, hi, Dad.
Mother, Daddy's home.
What's this?
Billy, what's going on?
I'm crazy,
that's the only explanation.
- Well, you're honest.
- Let's start from the beginning.
[ Phone ringing ]
- It's all right.
- No, it isn't alright.
What's this nurse thing?
- What nurse?
- I'm so tired.
Oh, hi, Stevie!
Yeah, how'd it go?
- Julie!
- Daddy, I'm talking.
Sorry, Steve, I missed that.
Bill, what kind of a nurse
is this?
I open the door
for the woman, she faints.
And then, when she wakes up,
she says, "When is it bedtime?"
Please help me.
Is it bedtime?
So, is she staying for dinner
or what?
It's okay, Danny, we're good.
DAMIEN: Catatonics
are so easy to possess.
I've been waiting for you,
lieutenant.
I wanted you to see this.
- No!
- Julie!
[ Screaming ]
[ Growling ]
- No!
- Daddy!
[ Growling ]
[ Screaming ]
Grandma! Daddy!
[ Growling ]
[ Screaming ]
Damien.
I was just about to check him.
Never mind, he's awake.
How do you know that?
Just open up,
and then lock it behind me.
All right.
- Will you be long?
- No.
Wasted effort.
Don't worry, we'll get her.
Pray for me, Damien.
You're free.
[ Gunshots ]
[ Groans ]
[ Cocks gun ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Singing in foreign language ]