Mr. Falk? James Sandin.
I talked to John over at repairs...
and he took care of it.
It's all fine
The system is working without a hitch,
you're going to be locked in tight tonight.
- Thank you, sir.
- All right, Mr. Falk, safe night.
- James Sandin's Office.
- Sue, I took care of Falk.
What do you know?
You hear anything?
You're number one, Mr. Sandin.
You got it, sir.
- You come out on top.
- Thank you very much.
Thank you.
- Congratulations to you too, Susan.
- You don't have to say that.
No, Susan, it's a team win.
Thank you.
- Okay, safe night.
- Safe night, Mr. Sandin.
Radio:   The poor can't afford
to protect themselves.
- They are victims.
- We all have our opinions.
That is what makes this country great.
Holly, line 4. What's are your Purge plans?
I'm going to hide behind my new
security system.
Pete from Northern Virginia.
What's your Purge plans?
I'm gonna hunt down my boss.
That son of a bitch has it coming.
Clearly more people will be
purging this year than ever before.
American streets will be
running red tonight...
when people "release the beast"
in record numbers.
Mr. Cali!
- Getting in one last walk in before lockdown?
- Yes.
Did you do the systems check
I recommended?
- Of course, there are no problems.
- OK, it's the same one I use.
I only sale the best.
Nobodies bothering us tonight.
Well, you have a safe night,
Mr. Sandin.
Thank you.
Now don't forget to buy your blue Baptisia's,
just wear those flowers proudly, OK?
Show your support for
this important evening.
A safe night to everyone.
- McGander, McGangee, Jim...
...Release the beast and
Purge the streets...
Hey Honey, I'm home!
Wife: I'm in the kitchen.
What a day! What a day. Everybody
is doing security checks. It's crazy.
Traffic is even worst than last year
Something smells good.
Great!
I'll put them in the water,
they look dry.
- Where are the kids?
- In their room, of course.
- We got about an hour before commencement.
- Dinner isn't going to be ready for a while...
OK, good.
Well, I have to make a few phone calls.
- One thing.
- Yeah.
Zoey's is getting worse.
She has been pouting all day.
So, you're gonna have to do something
about the Henry situation. I can't stand it.
There's nothing to do with her. He is 18,
he's not getting any younger
She is going to have to sulk,
get over it
But I have some good news for all of us.
I'll tell you at dinner.
History has proven over and over again.
We are a inherently violent species,
Wars, genocide, murders, the denial of our
true selfs is the real problem.
The Purge not only contains societal
violence to a single evening.
But the countrywide catharsis
creates a  psychological stability...
by letting us release the aggression
we all have inside of us.
I love you.
- Let's growl.
- What?
- Growl.
- Why?
Because, everyone says
I love you and it's used...
and we need to find our own thing.
- No! I'll look silly.
- Come on.
- No.
- Do it. It's our way of saying " I love you".
Try it.
Seriously.
I think my dad's home.
I'm sorry, baby,
but you have to get going.
I'm sorry.
And you have to get home
before lockdown.
Come on.
[Growls]
- Really?
Someone is getting ready for tonight.
Be careful.
Mary!
I'm so glad I caught you.
I come bearing gifts.
What have I done to deserve
a gift, Grace?
I was baking and I made way too many cookies.
Hi Grace!
- Hi!
- Ohhh cookies! I hope you're hungry.
Those cookies are crazy good.
They're lovely.
To have a safe night,
ladies.
- Bye!
- Goodbye!
Thank you, Grace.
Just as I needed more cookies, right?
The new edition to your house.
It's just amazing.
- Thank you.
- You know not everyone is happy you build it, Mary.
Whatcha you mean?
You know your husband sold a new
security system
to almost every home in this community.
Some people are actually saying that...
this neighborhood paid for...
that new edition on your home.
Are people really saying that?
Relax, it's just some good ole
neighbor gossip. Don't worry about it.
You're too sensitive.
So, are you having your
annual party, Grace?
No, too much trouble. We just going to
lockdown, and watch some Purge event special...
Thanks for the cookies.
Goodnight.
You're welcome.
- Have a safe night, Mary.
- And you, Grace.
Jesus.
You scared me to death.
You can't keep creeping up
on me like that, Charlie.
So, quit playing with Timmy,
and help me set the table.
Okay?
Now.
Christ!
Charlie, that's twice today.
You're gonna give me a heart attack?
I'm sorry, Mom.
Check it out. I made some adjustments, look!
I installed a night vision program...
and I insulated this motor so
you can now barely hear him.
And you can now play music to
accompany him on his missions.
[ Playing:   "Is he an Aussie, Is he Lizzie?",
by Mr Flotsam and Mr Jetsam ]
See?
- He like songs from olden times.
- Mmm-hmm...
It's very, very cool.
What is it?
What's bothering you?
It's tonight, isn't it?
Just remember all the good
the Purge does, OK?
It's all that matters.
You hungry?
- A little bit.
- Good. Tell you what, take Timmy away...
and come help me finish up.
- OK?
- OK.
Honey, this is so good.
Isn't it amazing?
And not one carb.
Great.
Well, I want like to hear about every bodies day.
Zoey, you go first.
Charlie, what are you doing?
Sorry, I forgot to take
my vitals earlier.
By the way, there is a slight deviation
in the heart rate.
But other than that...
- nothing to worry about.
- Okay, thank you.
Zoey, your day.
I don't want to do this anymore.
It's stupid.
Great! Fine. Pop test, piano,
a normal day.
- Who cares?
- I do. I care, very much.
And what about practice?
Are you ready for your recital?
Of course you are, because you're
always ready to make sure ...
your left hand cooperates
in the third movement.
I'm not saying,
that justs what I hear.
Well, I can say what I did today?
I did it.
All sales are final...
and I'm on top.
My division sold
most upgraded security systems.
- Congratulations, Dad.
- Congratulations, baby.
Thank you. It was a team effort,
you know.
All right, Charlie. You're next.
Well, we studied history
of tonight in History.
And in English I wrote a story about
a man whose love was so powerful,
that it can kill people.
Cuts out his own heart.
That is so sweet.
You know he should have cut off his own penis.
- Zoey!
- We're eating dinner!
Zoey, that's not funny...
- Don't encourage her.
- We're trying to eat.
We are not living in a dormitorium.
- It's just a story.
[Everyone talking at once]
Guys, look what time it is.
Well, it's later than I thought.
Alright, it's time to lockdown.
Let's go.
- Hon, give that back.
- Give it back.
All right.
Check this out.
Mr. Sabean and Mr. Bapaora
are going hunting this year.
I didn't know they were on a purge together.
Are they friends?
The Ferrins are having a party.
Grace said she wasn't having
a party this year.
Just thank God we weren't invited.
She's nice, but wow, she is annoying.
Well, get ready for the night.
As always,
just for precaution.
Alright, Mr. Cali has started
to lockdown.
OK.
We ready?
Alright, let's hit it.
Okay, Charlie, it's almost time.
Hit it.
TV:   ..Release the beast and
purge our American streets.
Your new Founding Fathers
encourage your participation.
[Emergency Broadcast alarm sounding off]
This is not a test.
This is your emergency broadcast system.
Announcing the commencement
of the annual Purge
sanctioned by the
U.S. Government
Weapons of Class 4 and lower...
have been authorized for use during the Purge.
All other weapons are restricted.
Government officials of ranking 10...
have been granted immunity from the Purge.
and shall not be harmed.
Commencing of the sirens...
any and all crime, including murder,
will be legal for 12 hours.
Police, fire and
emergency medical services...
will be unavailable until tomorrow
morning at 7 a.m.
...when the Purge concludes.
Blessed be our New Founding Fathers
and America, a nation reborn.
May God be with you all.
[Siren goes off]
[Siren stops]
OK, kids, I know bad things
do happen tonight,
but we can afford protection,
So, we'll be fine, just like always.
No worries,
Okay?
Can I go now?
I would prefer to be miserable in my room.
Of course, and thank you
for being here.
- Charlie...
- Where are you going, bud?
Charlie!
Why don't you guys kill?
Because we don't feel the need too,
Charlie.
That's all.
So if you felt the need too,
you would kill someone too?
Look, I know this is difficult to
understand at your age,
But tonight...
allows people a release...
for all the hatred, and violence,
and aggression they keep inside.
Okay, and ...
Yes! If your mother and I were so inclined
we would participate.
Because it works.
You don't remember how
bad it was, Charlie.
The poverty,
all the crime.
This night saved our country.
Why don't you go rest.
We're all done here.
I've got some paperwork
here to process.
To get my bonus.
Maybe we should watch a
movie later with the kids.
Oh, Jesus, Henry.
You scared the hell out of me.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to surprise you.
So, I snuck in here.
Baby, you can't be in here.
My Dad would lose his mind
if he sees you here now.
Come on...
Aren't you happy to see me?
Of course.
TV:   "We're looking at a live feed
from around the country,
and discussing the Purge with criminologists, Tommy Ayeguard.
Thanks, Nicole.
Now is the Purge really about releasing aggression,
and containing violence.
Or is it something else?
Purge distracters often postulate it is about
the elimination of the poor,
the needy, the sick.
Those unable
to defend themselves.
The eradication of these so-called...
non-contributing members of society.
Consequently, unburdening the economy.
Is the Purge really about money?
Anyway, crime is down.
The economy is flourishing...
I can't do this.
- Did I do something?
- No, I...
It's just...
I didn't come to see you.
- I came to see your father.
- What?
- Why?
- To try and straighten this out.
He cannot prevent you from seeing me.
It's crazy.
It might be crazy,
but he isn't going to change his mind.
He thinks you're too old
for me.
Talking to him will only make him more angry...
and make it more difficult for us.
I promise...
everything is going to be OK.
TV:   America was collapsing. A quadruple dip recession...
followed by a whole market crash.
Skyrocketing debt, multiple awards,
and significant dollar devaluation.
All precipitating the worst economic disaster
in the history of the United States.
Crime and poverty rosed exponentially.
And The New Founding Fathers just months
after being elected...
came up with this audacious notion...
decriminalization of murder for one night.
A lawful outlet for American rage.
With the continual decline in crime,
the undeniable fact is, this is working.
[Machine gun fire in the distance]
I thought I heard gun shots.
A couple of streets back, maybe?
Well, gun shots are going to happen tonight, OK?
It nothing. It's probably  somebody just
firing off a few rounds before going hunting.
C'mon, let's go to relax.
Hold on.
Look, he can't kick me out.
He's going to be forced to listen
to what I have to say.
I don't know...
One on one, man to man.
No BS.
I'm going to explain to him,
sure I'm older...
but you're also very mature.
So, age difference
is not a problem.
I'll tell him how much
I love you.
Ten years ago we could barely afford rent,
And now we are going to buy
a boat.
Crazy.
This one has a car garage.
Who needs a car
on a boat?
Help me!
Someone please help me!
They're coming after me!
Please!
Can anybody help me?
I ask you.
I just need to get somewhere safe.
Can anybody hear me?
I won't hurt you!
I don't want to die.
I don't deserve this.
Why won't anybody help me?
I need somewhere to hide.
Please, somebody open a door!
They're coming, they're coming.
Please! They're going to kill me!
Come here!
Let's go! This way!
Come on, hurry!
Hurry, hurry!
What the hell?
Charlie! Charlie!
This way! Hurry!
Go! Go!
Faster!
What's going on?
Mr. Sandin?
Jesse he has a gun!
Henry has a gun!
Henry!
Henry! Oh, God!
Are you hit?
- Is Zoey alright? I didn't hit Zoey, did I?
- No, she's fine.
Zoey! Zoey!
- Mom, what's going on?
- Charlie...
Where is he? Where is the man?
I don't know.
I don't understand. Who is he?
Why did you let him in our home?
He was hurt. He called for help.
No one was helping.
Charlie, Jesus Christ, what the hell?
We have no idea what this man is capable of.
James he's gone, we don't know
what Henry might do...
we're not safe here,
and we don't know where Zoey is.
You're right, let's go.
Come, come, come.
Let's go.
Henry!
Henry, you're...
Why?
Henry!
OK.
Here's the plan.
You two stay put here
and I'll just...
I'll go out there,
and I'm going to find Zoey...
and I'm going to bring her back here.
- Henry tried to kill you.
- Mary...
I've got to make sure she's OK.
Okay? I have too.
He didn't shoot me.
I'll find her.
- I'll go.
- I can't let you go...
with that man out there.
OK, I can't let you do that.
Let me go get her.
You just stay here with Charlie.
- OK?
- You be careful, okay?
I will.
Zoey!
Zoey! Listen to me!
You okay, sweetheart?
Yeah.
[Zoey calling outside]
Charlie! Mom!
Charlie you wait here, I will be right on
the other side of the door.
Baby!
Zoey!
[Machine gun fire down the street]
Mom?
Zoey.
Are you okay? Is Charlie OK?
- Father all right?
- Everyone is fine.
I didn't know Henry
was going to do that.
I didn't know that he wanted
to kill him.
- Why would he do that?
- Mom?
Charlie, give me a second....
He's died.
Mom?
Charlie, give me a second.
- Zoey, let's see what Charlie wants.
- Mom, now!
What is it, baby?
- You wanna see this.
- Tell Dad that I'm sorry.
Zoey!
Henry is dead.
I killed him.
I know, I saw Zoey.
- Is she OK? She alright?
- She's not hurt.
I couldn't get her to come with me.
What are we going to do?
I have to show you something.
Oh, god.
Now that one is saying something.
Good evening, Mr. Sandin.
Your home tells me that you are
good folks, just like us.
One of the haves.
And the blue flowers tell me
that you support the Purge.
We willing to treat you fairly,
so, listen closely.
Let me introduce us!
We are some fine, loyal, very educated,
guys and gals.
We have gotten gussied up these terrifying disguises...
as we do every year...
ready to violate,
and annihilate,
to cleanse our souls.
But things took a turn.
Our target escaped us, and...
So, one of your good neighbors
informed us that you...
the Sandin's...
have inexplicably given him sanctuary.
The man you shelter is nothing
but a dirty, homeless pig.
A good testimony of a just society who
has audacity to fight back.
Killing one of us as
we attempted to execute him tonight.
The pig doesn't know his place,
and now he needs to
be taught a lesson.
We need you to return him to us.
Alive.
So that we may Purge
as we are entitled.
Here's the plan, Sandins!
You have to provide us with permission
to break into your home.
If you don't...
If you don't, we're going to come in
and release the beast on him
And on you.
And ah...
We can enter any home we want.
And we will want...
As long as we want
on this fine night.
Don't force us to hurt you.
We don't want to hurt one
of our own.
Please, just let us Purge!
Toodaloo, Sandins.
Cut it, cut it now!
C'mon, let's work on the back-up.
The powers down
over the whole house.
They can't get here, right?
They can't get into our house.
I don't know, it's hard to say.
You don't know?
You sell these security systems.
What do you mean you don't know?
We have tested the system.
It works 99% of the time.
It looks good. It's strong,
it keeps people away.
It looks good.
It's not built for
worst case scenarios.
It is impenetrable?
No, nothing is impenetrable.
Things like this are not suppose to
happen in our neighborhood.
But they are happening, James.
They're happening right now.
Do you see this?
Listen, sit down, just sit down.
Please, we've got to calm down.
Okay, sit down, sit down, listen.
To answer your question,
Yes, they could get into here.
OK, they could tunnel underneath us.
They could smoke us out.
Improvise a battering ram.
OK, I'm sorry, but it's true.
So, here's what we're going do.
We'll gonna give them
what they want.
We'll find that man
And we're gonna force him outside.
Now...
we have guns...
And he doesn't.
But they'll kill him.
Why should he die?
It's either him or us, Charlie.
[Girls outside taunting, shooting guns]
I bet the boys won't let us go inside.
Not killing anyone wouldn't be any fun, please!
Fuck!
Where is he?
There he is.
Look at me.
Come on,
look over here.
Where are you?
Come on!
Polite Leader:
Hey, Mr. Sandin!
Sorry to interrupt,
but I must have a word.
Anybody at the front door?
I just need a moment of your time.
[Knocks on door]
There you are.
Thank you for accepting my invitation.
Tell me, why haven't you delivered
the filthy swine yet?
Are you protecting him?
I certainly hope not, Mr. Sandin.
No, of course not.
I just can't find him.
You see, this is a misunderstanding.
My son let him in, he's a young boy
who doesn't know better.
But I support what occurs
here tonight, 100%.
OK? I sell security equipment.
So, I would never deny yours
or anybodies else's right to Purge.
You see...
Give us the homeless pig,
you fuck...
Sorry about that.
I don't condone that
kind of behavior.
Just keep in mind, Mr. Sandin...
he was my friend, and you...
...are not.
Our equipment is arriving soon.
And we will get him.
Soon after that...
we will need him.
- I'll go get him.
- You should do that.
Hey, Charlie.
I don't know what going on here.
There are people outside.
Henry is dead.
I'll be OK, I have his gun.
Stay where you are.
Please be safe, okay?
I'm gonna go hide
in your secret spot.
No.
I love you.
Don't.
Zoey?
Get back.
Into the hall. Let's go.
Drop your gun.
Dad, please.
Drop it.
Don't hurt her.
Zoey, I will not let him hurt you.
Leave her alone.
No, you son-of-a-bitch. I will let her go
when this night is over.
You're gonna get us all killed,
you know that
They're going to come in here,
and they are gonna kill us all.
They are coming here!
You have got to leave my family
out of this, OK?
If you don't drop your gun,
I will hurt her.
- and I will hurt you.
- We didn't do anything to you.
- I don't deserve this.
- I don't deserve this, either.
Now listen, I don't want
to hurt any of you.
But I am "NOT" dying tonight!
Drop the gun, please.
Drop it.
Please.
Listen to me, okay?
You are going to die tonight.
And you can either you die like a man and
walk outside there by yourself...
or you can die like a coward,
And get my wife and my children
killed along with you.
OK? So, take that gun away from
my daughter's head.
Shoot it, Mary!
Shoot it!
Oh, shit.
Mary! Mary! Zoey!
She's unconscious.
Okay.
- We gonna need some rope.
- What?
Mary, we have to get some rope,
and we have to tie him up,
and get him outside.
And we're gonna end
this goddamn night.
Alright? Do you hear me?
OK.
Alright Charlie,
c'mon, help me.
Sweetheart?
Sweetheart.
I'm almost done here.
As soon as we get the legs secured.
Let me see.
You're doing great.
Here's what we're gonna do.
I'm gonna roll him into that chair
and drag him outside.
Okay? You got it?
You ready?
Charlie, concentrate
on your sister, OK?
In case she wakes up.
Charlie, I need the light.
Thank you, son.
Alright, okay.
Good job. You're doing great.
Alright, great. I'm gonna get the chair here.
Okay? We are almost done.
I'm gonna pick him up on the count of three.
You can help...
Keep the light on us, Charlie.
OK, one, two...
Three!
OK. Alright, get the tape
and tape him in there.
Hey, hey, hey! Quiet down, quiet down!
I got it. I got it, OK!
Alright, alright! You gotta calm down!
He's gonna break the tape!
- Cut his wound.
- What?
Get the letter opener and open his wound!
Get the letter opener,
I said!
- Grab the letter opener!
- No! Mom!
I'm just trying to protect my family.
Calm down!
- Mom!
- Come on, Mary, do it!
Do it, Mary! Do it!
Right on his wound!
Yes, yes.
Want to do it again?
Mom!
Stop!
Do it!
Alright, alright!
Cut!
You gonna sit in the chair?
Now he's ready,
help me up, help me up!
Alright, alright.
OK, OK,
I got it.
Stay right there, alright?
Stop it.
Just let me tape you
to this chair, alright?
Mary, where's the tape?
You are making it much more difficult...
than it needs to be.
Do you understand me?
Alright,
alright.
Look at this! Look at this man!
Look at what we're doing to him.
Come on Mary,
let's get this over with.
Come on, Mary!
- Look at me!
- I can't.
Yes, you can, baby.
Baby, I need you right now.
OK. Hey! Look at me! Huh...
Mary!
Mary?
We don't have no other choice.
This is so wrong.
Baby!
- This is so wrong.
- We don't have no other choice.
Don't touch me.
OK, look at you!
No, no.
Don't touch me.
When did this happen?
James, look at you.
What the hell happened
with us, James?
Charlie!
Baby, where did you go?
Charlie, where... ?
Charlie!
Zoey.
Hey, are you alright?
Sit down, sit down. You hit your head.
Are you okay?
Good!
I'm so sorry about Henry.
Okay?
I'm so sorry.
But we're going to make it through tonight
We will and ...
everything is going to be OK.
No, it...
What?
Look at what you doing.
Nothing, is ever going to be OK again.
Don't say that.
Save your children.
Take me outside.
Charlie!
[Car horns honking outside]
I want all these barricades down!
Polite Leader: Get everybody to cover
every door and every window.
James, where's Zoey?
I don't know, she ran out here.
The street thugs outside are coming in.
They've got chains on the door
and the windows.
They're going to pull them,
and come inside.
- Baby you were right.
- No, I wasn't right about anything.
You know what, they're right outside.
I have another idea.
What are you gonna do?
Charlie! Charlie...
listen to me! Listen to me.
You take this gun, alright?
You want me to go outside?
No.
You gonna go and hide in the basement and
you'll not come out for anybody, alright?
-OK.
- You got that? You're a good boy.
Alright!
Go! Go!
You just gave our son a gun.
What the hell are we doing?
We're gonna fight.
Why don't you take this one as well.
The safety is off.
- We have a lot of rounds.
- What do I do?
You will cover the other
side of the house.
This is our home,
our kids live here,
If anyone tries to come in, you blast him,
you will not hesitate.
Polite Leader:
Hey, Mr. Sandin!
I'm sorry to tell you,
but your time is essentially up.
And you failed!
You failed to deliver
the homeless swine.
I am very disappointed that you fine folks,
should know better,
that piece of filth,
that you are protecting,
exists only to serve our need to Purge!
So, I bid thee sweet farewell, Mr Sandin.
Release the beast, boys...
let the purge commence!
Go!
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
No, I'm OK!
Charlie: Let's go!
James: C'mon, c'mon
Cooper!
Come look for the little lady Sadin.
Jesus...
Send her to me.
Dad!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm OK.
Okay.
- Mom and Zoey, OK?
- Yeah, they're gonna be fine.
It's okay.
Your soul has been cleansed,
Mr. Sandin.
You've purged.
Just one question for you.
Was his life really worth yours?
Your family's?
Thank you for this unforgettable Purge,
Mr. Sandin.
No!
No! No!
Do not do that!
Leave me!
No! Leave me alone!
No! No!
Please! Don't do that!
I'm sorry!
No!
James!
James?
Charlie! Charlie! Zoey!
It's okay!
Dad!
Thank you for your sacrifice.
You have a lot of heart, Mr. Sandin.
Bless the New America.
A Nation Reborn.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
I saw that you were having some trouble.
And decided to help you.
I don't know what to say.
Don't thank us too much,
Mary.
The truth is you're ours,
not theirs.
What do you mean "yours"?
What do you mean?
- Dad!
- No!
- Wait!
- He's gonna die!
James is dead.
Mary and the kids,
will have to do.
Let's tie them up,
we'll kill them right here.
No! No! No!
Wait!
- No! No! No!
- Mom!
No!
Give me the tape!
Don't you...
Don't even thinking about touching them!
Shut up!
Let go of me!
- Get your fucking hands...
- Shut up, Mary!
- Fuck you!
- Shut up!
I swear to God
I will shoot him right now.
Do you hear me?
Grace, why are you doing this?
Why do this now?
When your barricades came down,
I saw an opportunity
to cleanse ourselves from the hatred.
You made so much money off of us,
and just flaunt it in our faces.
You all think you're so damned perfect.
Listen, Grace.
I begging you right now.
Don't do this to my children.
Please, they're my children.
Please, not my children.
You, Mary,
is what this night is all about.
I'm begging you.
I'm really begging you!
I can't believe you'll do this.
They will be better people.
Until you sacrifice yourselves
to make the world
a better place.
Mom!
Please don't!
Please let me hold my children!
Mary. It's over.
- Untie me!
- It's over.
Please.
Time for your quiet time, Mary.
Let us do our duty
as Americans.
Look at me.
Just look at me.
Chanting "Blessed be the New Founding Fathers...
[Indistinct dialog]
"Bless America
"A nation reborn. "
I'll go start first and then
we'll take turns.
[ Song:   "Is he an Aussie, Is he Lizzie?",
by Mr Flotsam and Mr Jetsam playing]
Timmy?
Don't move!
Drop your weapons,
right now!
Untie them, let's go!
Right now!
Your call.
Just get it over with.
Kill us quickly.
Oh, for God sake, just do it!
Come on!
- Mom, they were going to kill us.
- Doesn't matter.
We'll get through the rest of this
night in fucking peace.
Does anyone have
a problem with that?
Did you enjoy Grace's Purge party?
Mr. Halverson...
- Fuck yourself!
- Sorry, I can't hear you.
- It was very nice.
- Good.
I'm glad you all had a grand time.
Did you hear what I said?
No more killing tonight!
Is that so hard to understand?
[End of the Purge siren going off]
Now get the hell out of my house.
Wait.
Are you gonna be OK?
Thank you.
Your welcome.
[Police and Ambulance sirens in the background]
Female Reporter 1:
Countdown, at 7 a.m.,
March 22.
The Annual Purge has
just been concluded.
This is your American morning news program.
And reports are coming in from all around the country.
as Police, firefighters and paramedics and...
Male Reporter 1: The new founding fathers
have released a early statement saying
this was most successful Purge...
Man Reporter 2: I am walking,
I should say stumbling,
through downtown Los Angles.
There are literately bodies everywhere...
Eyewitness 1: I witnessed a group of young men
breaking into the tavern next to me...
and they still were dragging people out
and executing them on the street...
Female Reporter 2: Hundreds have gathered
in Time Square for a public vigil...
thanking all those who were killed
last night for their sacrifice...
to make this country a safer place.
Male Reporter 3: They are 3 deep lined up
outside the Emergency Room,
and there is simply no more room...
Economist: The market was up this morning as
both gun and home security system...
quarterly sales reports were released announcing
profits in both sectors...
Female Reporter 3:
...We have 364 long days until the next Purge...
so let's get all our Purge talk and analysis in
today while our thoughts are still fresh.
According what I've been readings, it seems like
Dallas had the most participates.
I did get a chance to see some live
surveillance footage out of Dallas/Fort Worth,
and there had to be 200 people in the town
square purging at the same time.
Caller: I lost my 2 sons last night, my boys.
Yeah, I was a proud American,\i0}
not any more. This country has taken
everything away from me...