[Birds Chirping]
[Shouting]
[Whistle Blowing]
[Cheering]
[Announcer Over P.A.] That's a first down.
Huskie ball
at the 35-yard line. ♪♪ [Band Playing]
[Cheering]
[Shouting, Grunting]
- [Whistle Blowing]
- [Cheering]
[Announcer]
Touchdown! Paul Taylor. 17-yard pass from Terry Stokes.
Look at her, man, look at her!
I think she wants your body.
You gotta ask her out, Paul.
Isn't she datin' Pulver?
Yeah, but that's goin' nowhere.
Take a shot, for Christ's sake.
God.
Hey, I'm gonna ask her out.
Bullshit.
When, when, when? When the timing's right.
Yeah, right.
Timing's everything.
[Cheering Continues]
[Whistle Blows]
No-no-no-no.
Hit him! Hit him!
Yeah! All right!
Whoo-hoo!
[Announcer]
Wildcat fumble, Huskie ball. First and 10.
♪♪ [Band Plays]
[Cheerleaders]
Go, Wildcats, let's go!
Seven-yard pass,
complete to Paul Taylor.
Meg, got any plans this evening?
[Chanting]
Go! Go!
[Chanting Continues]
- [Engine Revving]
- Go!
Go! Go!
[Chanting Continues]
- [Engine Sputtering]
- Go!
Go! Go!
- Go! Go!
- [Sputtering Continues]
[Crowd Cheering]
[Groaning]
[Man Applauding]
[Laughing]
♪♪ [Country]
Looks like the game put you outta business.
Don't worry. When they're
through screamin' their heads off, they'll be in here like a flood.
More iced tea?
Please.
It's good that this town's
got up on its hind legs about somethin'.
Well, it takes people's minds
off their troubles.
It's been a lean year
for most folks.
Well, ski season's about to start.
There'll be tourists.
You know, there's a new band
out at the Tin Palace tonight.
Is that right?
Supposed to be pretty good.
That's nice.
You like country music?
Herb, are you askin' me out?
Yeah, well, I‒
I guess I am, yeah.
I don't know. Uh‒ [Sighs]
I'm kinda stuck here.
You know,
I gotta earn a livin'.
Yeah. Yeah, it must be tough
tryin' to get away.
- [Horns Honking]
- Shoot.
George, here they come.
[Kids Shouting, Whooping]
- That my check?
- Mm-hmm.
Now, if you do get
any free time to yourself,
that's my number there
down at the station.
[Chattering]
Okay.
Okay, okay.
One at a time.
[Shouting, Cheering]
[Shouting, Cheering Continue]
Flagg, congratulations.
- For what?
- Well, I hear you have a birthday comin' up.
No more juvie hall, right?
Yeah, right.
Now, you mess up now,
and you're in the majors.
I'll see ya around, Flagg.
Moss, what's happening?
You look like hell.
Hey, it's
a fashion statement, man.
Only statement
them clothes got to make is, "I look like hell."
My bike's broken down
at Elkin's Grove.
I was thinkin', uh,
maybe I could borrow your ratchet set?
The Summit's got me
overhauling six damn Ski-Doos,
three Cats, and two flatbed
snowmakers... by Monday.
What's the hurry?
It must be 70 degrees out there.
It's injun summer, boy.
Before you know it, winter gonna be
tear-assin' through this town with no apologies.
Aw, come on.
It barely pissed snow the last couple years. This whole town's ready to fold.
[Clears Throat]
Yeah, well, see, this year's gonna be different.
Is that right?
Mm-hmm. Take my word.
You're gonna wish your piece
of shit excuse for a motorcycle was one of these sweet rigs.
So, uh, Moss, how 'bout the ratchet?
All right, maybe I'll put in
a couple hours over the weekend, lighten things up a bit.
[Sighs]
There's 12 sockets
in that set... 12‒
and they better all be there
when I get it back too.
You got it, buddy.
You got it.
Thanks a lot, Moss.
Hey, I owe ya one.
You owe me too damn many.
[Sighs]
Oh, bombs away!
[Whimpers]
[Growls, Barks]
[Barking Continues]
What the‒
[Gasps]
[Mutters]
[Dog Whimpers]
Holy cow!
[Barking]
[Bell Tolling]
Uh, lend me five bucks
just till tomorrow, okay?
What for?
You know, you're not the only one with a date tonight, pal.
I'm gonna score with Vicki tonight.
I want to invest in a little protection. Come on.
Let's go, boys.
It's closing time. All right. Here.
Thanks.
Make it quick.
Uh, look, pal.
Give me a pack of Trojans and a Binaca spray.
- Scott Jeskey.
- Reverend.
Good game today!
Uh, thanks.
Thanks, Reverend.
How are ya?
Well, my hay fever's acting up a little bit, but I'll live.
Yeah.
Haven't seen you at the Sunday services lately.
Oh. Yeah, well, I‒
You want the ribbed or the regular?
Ribbed, I-I guess.
They're not for me,
you know.
They're for my friend.
Oh?
There's this-this-this sort of
naive girl that he's planning on‒
Well, you know. And, uh, I insisted
that he take precautions.
Why doesn't he pay for them?
I had to drag him down here as it is.
The guy is totally irresponsible.
Hey, come on, Scott.
What's the holdup? I can't keep this girl waiting.
The boy doesn't need condoms.
He needs a muzzle.
[Slimy Gurgling]
[Growling]
- [Gasps]
- [Whimpers]
- [Screaming]
- [Slurping]
Kevin, don't eat with your face.
Mom, we're in a hurry.
We're gonna go bowling with Anthony.
And then to the movies.
Ow! [Kicking]
What movie?
Garden Tool Massacre.
It's your basic
slice-and-dice. Your basic what?
Well, this guy in a hockey mask,
he chops up a few teenagers.
But don't worry.
There's no sex or anything bad.
They won't let you kids
into a movie like that.
No problem.
My brother's an usher.
[Scoffs]
No. Absolutely not.
Mom, come on.
Kevin!
I will not have you seeing
that kind of trash, and that's final. Do you understand?
Yes, ma'am.
[Girl] Mom, have you seen my pink sweater?
Uh, it's on the hamper,
honey.
I meant to talk to you
about that.
Why did you do that?
What did I do?
We, uh, had
a little accident.
What happened?
It got mixed up in the wash.
Interesting look.
Why don't you wear my cashmere sweater?
Are you serious?
Sure.
[Doorbell Rings]
Oh, my God, that's him.
- What do you want?
- Hi. I'm here to see Meg.
- What for?
- Uh, just to see her.
Is she home?
Just a minute.
[Door Slams]
[Scoffs]
I'm terribly sorry.
You must be Paul.
I'm Meg's mother.
Hi. Nice to meet you, ma'am.
Well, come on in.
Meg'll be right down.
Uh, where do you think
you're going? Sleeping over at Eddie's.
Oh, right.
But you're not going anywhere without your jacket.
Oh, Mom, it's boiling out.
Well, it's October.
It's nighttime. You're wearing your jacket.
[Sighs, Grunts]
Stupid coat.
No, here, let me.
Okay. Bye-bye, honey.
Enjoy yourself. Bye, Mom.
Bye, Eddie.
Oh, yeah.
Won't you sit down?
[Phone Rings]
Oh, excuse me.
Hi, Paul.
Hi.
Are you surviving
my family so far? Yeah. You look great.
Thank you.
You wanna go?
Sure. I just want you
to meet my dad really quick. It'll just take a second.
Sure.
Daddy, I'd like you
to meet my friend Paul.
Ribbed.
[Birds Chirping]
[Twig Snapping]
[Rustling]
[Screaming]
[Grunting]
Hey!
I'm really sorry about my dad.
I've never seen him like that before.
Th-That's okay.
It was just a misunderstanding.
[Laughing]
I've made better
first impressions though. That's for sure.
Well, no harm done,
I guess. No, wrong.
Scott Jeskey is gonna die.
- Paul, watch out!
- [Tires Screech]
Flagg! Jesus Christ!
What did you do to him?
Hey, I'm not the one
who bounced him off my car, pal. You ran him in the road!
Stop it!
Let's get him to a doctor. Hey, watch out.
He's got some kind
of corrosive shit on his hand.
Come on.
Take it easy, mister.
We're gonna get some help,
all right?
Let's go. Come on.
[Whimpering]
- The sky. It fell from the sky.
- What's he sayin'?
He's in shock.
Let's just go.
Hey! Get in the car.
What for?
There's gonna be a lot of explaining to do,
and you're part of it.
Now, are you gonna get in the car,
or am I gonna make you get in?
What's the matter, Taylor?
You worried about
a little insurance claim on Daddy's car, huh?
Maybe I will come along...
just to make sure you don't
blame this whole thing on me.
Are you two finished?
Whenever you're ready.
[Engine Starts]
Right here.
Excuse me, Nurse?
One moment, please.
- Now, how may I help you?
- We've had a car accident. This guy needs a doctor.
He has something on his hand too‒
some kind of acid or something.
Does he have Blue Cross?
I don't know.
Medical insurance of any kind?
- I don't believe this shit.
- Look, we don't even know who the guy is.
[Sighs] The doctor's with
another patient right now. [Buzzes]
Could you put this gentleman
in room three, please?
You'll have to
fill these out.
Okay. Come on, up. Up.
[Groans]
Hey, take it easy,
old dude.
These guys are gonna
fix you right up.
Hey, where you goin'?
These people don't give a shit
about explanations.
If you need me,
you know where to find me.
[Sighing]
[Sighs]
I bet you've had
better first dates, huh?
I don't mind.
Want a soda?
Yeah, sure.
That'd be great. Something diet.
[Man]
Absolutely. At this point the prognosis is very positive.
In cases like this,
the question is always
the quality of physical therapy.
The follow-up to any operation
is to a great extent...
[Slimy Gurgling]
Doctor, come in here quickly!
I'm with a patient...
There's a man dying in here! Hurry!
Excuse me a moment.
Is this the hand injury?
- What is this?
- That thing on his hand.
Nurse!
Sheriff's Department.
Get me the sheriff! It's an emergency.
Paul?
Geller speaking.
Sheriff, this is Paul Taylor.
Paul, what's wrong?
I'm at the Arborville Hospital. An old man's been killed here.
You said "killed"?
Yes, sir.
Okay, you sit tight. I'll be right down.
Now, who else is involved?
- I'm with Meg Penny,
and Brian Flagg was here earlier. - Flagg? Where is he now?
[Screaming]
Paul?
[Slimy Gurgling]
[Muffled Screaming]
[Screaming]
Paul!
[Dispatcher Over Radio, Indistinct]
But I did see it, Dad.
It killed Paul.
Shh.
Sheriff.
How 'bout it, Herb?
Can we take her home now?
Yeah, you may as well, Tom.
Make sure she gets a good sleep, huh?
We're not gonna get anything
out of her tonight. She's hysterical.
I got a call in to Paul Taylor's folks.
They haven't heard from him.
Well, let's face it, Bill.
They're not going to.
You get that to Sacramento tonight.
I want the autopsy pronto, not next week.
[Car Engines Starting]
"Jesus wept."
Herb, you okay?
Taylor was a good kid.
I want the son of a bitch
who did this.
Maybe we already got him.
♪♪ [Radio: Rock]
Scott, cut it out.
I told you.
Come on, Vicki.
You're wearin' my ring. That makes you my girl.
[Giggling]
Doesn't that count for something, huh?
Hey, what are all those
lights down there?
Isn't that the hospital?
Yeah. It's probably
a promotional gimmick.
They're giving away
free tonsillectomies or something.
[Giggles]
Say, young lady,
I think you're about ready
for another one of my famous cherry coolers.
I think I've had enough.
Nonsense. You've never had enough.
My very own blend
of special imported liqueurs.
[Radio]
♪ And you feel my love ♪
♪ All my love ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
[Slimy Gurgling]
♪♪ [Continues]
Vicki?
Okay.
It's like a steam bath in here.
Here's your drink, Vicki.
Vicki?
Yep.
Hot as a dog
out there tonight.
Vicki?
[Coyote Howling]
That's, uh‒
That's a nice blouse.
Nice material.
Must be hot though, huh?
Yeah.
I'll‒ I'll just
undo one of these for you.
Ah. That's better, huh?
Oh, no? Oh, well,
I'll-I'll just...
I'll undo another one then.
There! Okay.
[Sighing]
Oh.
[Gasping]
[Screaming]
Vicki!
[Father]
I knew I shouldn't have let her go out with the son of a bitch in the first place!
[Mother]
Lower your voice. That poor boy's probably dead.
I wanna know what happened
out there tonight.
Whatever it was, you can bet
that Flagg kid was behind it.
It's about time they nailed
that little psychopath.
His ass is gonna fry
this time, believe me.
[Sighs]
Here. Take this.
I don't want it.
No, come on, honey.
You have to get some sleep.
[Sighs]
That's my good girl.
Now, just... let it alone.
I'm sure that the police will have
this whole thing settled by the morning.
Come on.
Mom?
You don't believe me either, do you?
You're home now.
You're safe.
That's all that matters.
[Slimy Gurgling]
[Dispatcher Over Radio, Indistinct]
Look at him.
He's too stupid to know how much trouble he's in.
Why don't you wise up?
I told you everything.
I'm gettin' tired of hearing myself talk.
We're not boring you, are we‒
a bright kid like you?
Hey, am I under arrest?
Because if I am, I want a lawyer.
Man wants a lawyer.
Yeah, that's right.
And if you're not bookin' me,
I'd like to leave.
- Either way, I want you outta my face.
- Oh, yeah, hard-ass?
Well, I'm in your face to stay.
What are you gonna do about it?
- Go ahead, hit me!
- Bill.
Go ahead.
[Chuckles]
[Footsteps]
Any luck with his mama?
- I can't seem to find her.
- That's not unusual, is it?
She takes little vacations
with her pal Johnnie Walker Red and anyone else who happens to be around.
Of course, we could call his dad,
if anyone knew who he was.
Hey, call a shrink.
I'm a broken man.
You think this is a joke?
Turn him loose.
Herb, we got eyewitnesses
placing him at the scene of the crime.
No motive, no evidence.
He hasn't got
a drop of blood on him.
Hell, Flagg's a punk,
but he's no killer. I think it's a mistake.
Well, your objection is duly noted.
Now, turn him loose. We got work to do.
Go on.
[Handcuffs Click]
Take a hike.
Brian,
I need to talk to you.
Brian.
What the hell are you doin' here?
Look, I came down
to bail you out.
What do you think they are,
Neiman-Marcus? They don't take plastic.
Hey, I appreciate the thought.
Now, go home, okay?
I need to talk to you.
Hey, I'm sorry about your boyfriend.
I really am.
But I'm tired and hungry,
and I'm not in the mood for conversation. Okay?
George. Franny.
¿Qué pasa?
Hey, hotshot, we're closed.
Aw, come on, Fran.
I've been dumped on all day. Give me a break.
Oh, what's the matter, dear?
Tough day at the office?
[Scoffs]
Well, grill's shut down.
- How 'bout a sandwich?
- Beautiful.
Geez, you don't give up, do you?
I need your help.
For three years in school
you haven't said shit to me.
Now all of a sudden, what...
you need my help, and we're best friends, right?
Nobody believes me
about what happened tonight.
- What did happen?
- You were there. You saw.
All I saw was an old man with a funky hand.
That's all I saw.
Thanks.
Can I get you somethin', hon?
No, thank you.
The thing on that man's hand
killed him, and then it killed Paul.
And whatever it is,
it's getting bigger.
Is that what you told the cops?
Do you mind if I ask you
a personal question?
I know you're
the homecoming queen type and all, but, uh,
are you strung out
on somethin', or what?
[Chuckles]
[Scoffs]
You're just the same.
What are you talkin' about?
You act like you're different.
You put on this big show.
But you're just like
everybody else in this town. You're full of shit, Flagg!
Hey, wait a second.
Hey, calm down, all right?
I'm sorry, okay?
Come on, sit down.
[Sniffling]
You okay, huh?
You want somethin' to eat?
Here. Go ahead.
It'll make you feel better.
[Scoffs]
Unbelievable.
No, it's just I've never heard
you say the word "shit" before. What was that like for you?
[Chuckles]
[Laughs]
We're comin' up empty here.
Do you want us to head into the foothills?
[Sheriff Over Radio]
Negative. No, I'd rather have you patrolling the streets.
We'll start all that at first light
when the state police come in.
Ten-four.
You look exhausted.
It's been a long night.
Thank you.
It's gonna be even longer.
That's the truth.
One deputy and six volunteers.
I feel like the one-legged man
in an ass-kicking contest.
Well, you're doing all you can, Herb.
This isn't your normal Friday night trouble.
Something wrong?
I'm, uh‒
I'm just worried
about a friend of mine.
I guess I'm worried
about everybody tonight.
- Dessert?
- Oh, Fran.
That sandwich busted me.
On the house. Last two pieces.
Eat up, or
I chuck it in the garbage.
[Meg]
Thanks.
[Gurgling]
[Sighs]
Shit.
Here, here.
I'll get that.
I'll get it!
[Chuckling] Here.
Knock yourself out.
Well, thanks.
Geez.
[Sighs]
What is this?
[Screaming]
George? George!
George!
[Screaming Continues]
Fran?
[Screaming]
George!
Don't touch him! Don't touch him!
Fran, come on!
In the freezer!
[Screeching]
[Panting]
Oh! Oh!
Hear anything?
I'm okay.
Hey.
I'm gonna get us outta here.
I promise.
[Line Ringing]
Come on.
Come on, answer!
[Gasping]
[Recording]
Your call cannot be completed as dialed.
Please check the number
and dial again.
[Whimpering]
[Woman]
Sheriff's station. Help me. Get me Herb.
Get Herb Geller.
He went down to the diner.
[Line Disconnects]
[Screaming]
Oh, Herb!
You ready?
[Hinges Creaking]
Okay.
Franny?
Franny!
Great. I killed
the strawberry jam.
Let's get outta here.
The front door's locked.
That's okay. I got a key.
[Bell Tolling]
[Slimy Gurgling]
[Gurgling Continues]
Merciful God.
[Cat Yowling]
Hello?
Is anybody... hurt?
[Cat Meowing]
[Electricity Arcing]
[Meowing]
We need to see the sheriff.
I don't know where he is.
[Phone Ringing]
Sheriff's Department. Please hold.
- What about Briggs?
- I can't raise anybody. All I'm getting is static.
[Ringing Continues]
Sheriff's Department. Please hold.
The last I heard from the deputy,
he was on his way up to Elkin's Grove.
Elkin's Grove.
That's where I found the old man.
Come on, let's go.
[Phone Continues Ringing]
Looks like he left
in a hurry.
Yo, Briggs!
[Coyote Howling]
He's gotta be
around here somewhere.
In the woods.
In the dark woods.
Right.
We could wait here.
[Sighs]
Never thought I'd go
out of my way to find a cop.
[Coyote Howls]
Hello?
I feel like fuckin'
Hansel and Gretel here.
Should have brought
some bread crumbs.
Wait. I think
I hear something.
[Low Rumbling]
What the hell is that?
Put those weapons down.
We're here to help you.
Name?
Meg Penny.
Are you a resident
of Arborville, Meg? Yes, I am.
Have you experienced
any vomiting, nausea or diarrhea?
Hey, back off, huh?
Hey, pal, you wanna fill us in?
Who the hell
are you people? I'm Dr. Meddows.
We're a government-sanctioned
biological containment team.
"Biological containment"?
We're microbe hunters,
young lady. Flagg?
What are you doing here, boy?
The men from Glad here
are showing us how to keep our leftovers fresh.
These people are here on serious business.
They don't have time for your bullshit, understand?
Colonel, has the deputy
been briefed in detail? Yes, sir.
I'm just heading back to town now
to get things started.
Splendid. Colonel Hargis
will arrange an escort.
What is going on over there?
That's the source of our worries‒
a troublesome souvenir
from space. What?
A meteorite.
Don't get too close.
There's danger
of contamination.
[Meg]
I don't understand. Let me tell you a story.
The dinosaurs ruled our planet
for millions of years,
and yet they died out
almost overnight.
Why?
The evidence suggests
that a meteor fell to Earth bearing an alien bacteria.
Plague? Is that what
this whole thing is about?
Prevention.
And you think this meteor
brought some kind of a killer germ?
It's something I've expected
and prepared for all my life.
Well, your meteor
brought somethin', all right.
But if it's a germ,
it's the biggest son of a bitch you've ever seen.
[Small Engine Revving]
What's the matter?
Isn't it awfully late
to be trimming the hedges?
Maybe this guy's
a Peeping Tom or something.
So let's give him
something to peep at.
[Engine Revving]
Wait a minute.
Hockey season ended months ago.
[Chuckling]
Watch this.
He's gonna get
the camp counselor with the hedge trimmer.
[Screaming]
I'll bet
the girl gets away.
Ooh, watch. She's gonna
run in the lodge and hide, but he's gonna get her anyway.
[Screaming]
Please be quiet.
- You shut up.
- Hey!
You guys gotta shut up.
If you get caught in here, Mom's gonna kill me.
Get your feet off the seat.
Anthony, come on.
What a jerk.
What a wimp.
Check out the body
on the blonde.
[Muffled Gurgling]
Wonderful.
[Man Over Intercom] Yeah?
It's Hobbs. Listen, it's boiling up here.
The air conditioning on?
It's on full blast.
Yeah, well, it must be
blocked up or somethin'.
There's nothing wrong
with the air conditioning. Come up and see for yourself.
[Slimy Gurgling]
[Screaming]
Hobbs?
Hobbs, are you in here?
[Gasps]
[Groaning]
[Screaming]
I can't begin
to thank you both.
This information
is incredibly valuable.
Please, get in.
Where are we going?
Back to town.
Arborville is under quarantine
until we've isolated that organism...
and checked every living soul
for signs of infection.
- In the meantime, we're your prisoners.
- Not at all. You're my patients.
Sounds like
the same thing to me.
- Brian‒
- Young man, please, step into the van.
Look, thanks for
the offer, Doc,
but my bike's right back there
and we can make it back on our own.
Hey, by the way, I love your tailor.
I gotta get me one of those.
- [Barking]
- Get in the van.
Van ride sounds nice.
[Engine Starts]
Clear.
It's locked.
So what?
Brian, what is with you?
You're acting like a complete jerk.
I have a problem
with authority figures.
- What are you doing?
- I think we ought to get out of here.
We oughta take my bike
and blow this town.
It's gettin' a little thick
around here, don't you think?
That's crazy.
These people are here to help us.
Come on, Meg.
We don't even know who they are.
NASA? C.I.A?
The Royal Canadian Mounties?
All I know is I saw
a bunch of unmarked trucks.
- I think this whole thing stinks.
- Well, we can't just run out.
Let's just think of it
as looking out for our best interests, huh?
You coming?
Brian, I have to go back.
My family's there‒ people that I care about.
I'm goin'. If you're smart,
you'll come with me.
Then go.
Take care of yourself.
It's the only thing
you're really good at, isn't it?
No one else ever volunteered for the job.
Christ, Flagg.
A cheerleader.
[Man]
Clear out. Come on through here.
All right, back it up.
Come on, ma'am.
[Woman Over P.A.] There is no cause for alarm.
I repeat:
There is no cause for alarm.
This is
a precautionary quarantine...
due to a potential
biological hazard.
This is a precautionary measure.
They're just gonna ask a few questions,
and maybe give you a shot.
Mom! Dad!
Meg!
Oh, Meg!
Oh, thank God you're all right.
Honey, is Kevin with you?
No. Isn't he staying
over at Eddie's house?
Eddie said they were
staying at your house.
Oh, God!
He must've snuck off to that damn movie.
What movie?
You didn't tell me about any movie.
Sir? Excuse me, but I think
that my little brother is over at the movie theater on Main Street.
Miss, we're going by sectors.
We'll get there shortly. But you don't understand‒
We'll handle it, okay?
Now get back in line.
I don't see you handling
much of anything. You on a coffee break?
Look, mister...
Don't "Look, mister" me. I'm a taxpayer. I pay your salary.
What are you gonna do
about finding my son? I understand you're upset.
But if you just get back in line,
we have the situation under control.
Did you know that
ten years ago tonight,
there was a horrible murder
in this house?
No. No way.
[Man Chuckling] You'll love this.
He hot-curls her to death.
[Chuckling]
Mister, we're trying to watch a‒
[Screaming]
[Screaming, Shouting]
Kevin!
[Yelling]
- Kevin!
- Meg!
Meg! Meg!
[Screeching]
[Gasping]
My zipper!
[Pounding]
Come on! Hurry!
Your feet!
[Screaming]
No! Aah!
Hurry!
Here!
Get it up!
Eddie!
[Gurgling]
[Screeching]
Hurry! Go!
[Screaming]
[Kevin]
Come on, Meg!
Meg, come on!
[Man]
Alpha Team, do you copy? [Man #2] Affirmative.
Status report.
Highway 31 closed.
Phone lines down.
We've got this town locked up tight.
On up.
[Chattering Continues]
[Mechanical Whirring]
[Meddows]
We suspected that conditions in space...
would have a mutating effect
on bacteria, but this‒
[Man]
This activity must be what threw the satellite out of orbit.
[Meddows]
Correct. Our little experimental virus seems to have grown up...
into a plasmic life-form
that hunts its prey.
A predator.
It's fantastic.
Sir, the organism is growing
at a geometric rate.
By all accounts,
it's at least a thousand times its original mass.
This'll put U.S. Defense
years ahead of the Russians.
You don't understand.
At this rate, by next week there may be no U.S.
[Meddows]
Nonsense.
All we have to do
is contain it properly.
As far as the locals are concerned,
this is simply a medical quarantine.
Nobody gets in or out.
Dr. Meddows.
Just for the record,
I don't agree with any of this.
Those people's lives
are at stake.
Don't you think I know that?
This isn't one of
your textbook exercises, Mr. Jennings.
This is an experiment
in biological warfare. Or hadn't you noticed?
That organism is potentially
the greatest breakthrough in weapons research...
since man split the atom.
What we do here
will affect the balance of world power.
Of course there are
lives at stake‒ whole nations, in fact.
And that's far more important
than a handful of people in this small town.
And that is my cross to bear,
Mr. Jennings.
Now, carry out your orders.
Yes, sir.
Colonel! Colonel,
we've got a sighting.
Hargis here.
Colonel, we've got an eyewitness
who says the organism pursued some civilians into the sewers.
It's got Kevin and Eddie
and Meg down there! You gotta do something!
Excellent! We need a schematic
of the sewer system.
We'll contain it down there.
I want that organism alive.
What about the civilians?
They're expendable.
- [Rifle Cocks]
- Get up.
[Gunshot]
Stop him!
Attention!
We have an infected civilian trying to escape!
Stop him before he reaches
a populated area!
[Man Over Loudspeaker]
Halt, or we will open fire!
I repeat:
[Gunfire]
[Woman Over P.A.]
Handicapped persons or persons in need of special assistance...
may report to the blue station
located on the north lawn.
Dr. Sims and Dr. Divatni,
please report to Med Unit One.
Are these the schematics?
Yes, sir.
The whole town's sitting
on a system of aqueducts‒ runoff from the mountains.
Can the organism
be contained?
There seem to be three main junctions‒
here, here and here.
If we close off those valves,
I think we got it.
Is it still after us?
I don't think so.
I'll-I'll be good, I swear.
I'll-I'll never see a movie ever again.
It's gonna be okay.
Let's just find a way out of here.
This way.
[Man Over Radio]
Baker Team, we place you 80 meters south of valve two.
[Rat Squeaking]
Come on.
That's our way out of here.
Watch out for the rat.
What rat?
Run!
Get up the pole! Go!
Come on! Climb! Go!
[Screaming]
- Eddie!
- Meg, no!
Get out of there!
No! Meg!
Meg!
[Gasping]
[Screams]
[Screeching, Bellowing]
I can't get through!
You can make it, Meg!
Come on!
Run, Kevin! Run!
[Gunfire]
We have orders not to shoot.
[Screaming]
Run, Kevin!
Go to town hall!
- No! But Meg‒
- Do it, now!
[Screaming]
Meg!
Brian!
What are you doing?
Hang on!
Brian!
You all right?
Yeah.
Forget about it, Brian.
Let's go! Forget about it!
[Panting]
It got 'em‒ Bigelow and Wilson.
How do we get out of here?
They were trying to scream.
Inside it, trying to scream.
Listen to me!
How do we get out of here? Listen to me!
Brian, he's hurt!
[Slimy Gurgling]
I think... we'd better... go now.
[Man Over Radio]
Baker Team, what the hell's going on down there?
We're coming up!
Close the manhole.
That's my man
down there!
We've got to contain that thing.
Now, close it off! That's an order!
Do it.
Hey!
No! Hey!
You son of a bitch!
[Man Over Radio]
Colonel, you can't!
Colonel, that thing's
down here with us!
Meddows!
You hear me, Meddows?
Talk to me, man!
Meddows!
The water's rising.
It's comin' for us.
I thought you were gonna
take care of yourself.
I guess I blew it, huh?
I'm sorry, Meg.
I really am.
Brian.
This thing work?
This thing work? It won't do any good.
Not against that thing.
All right, Meddows.
If you won't listen to me, listen to this.
Shit!
Fire in sector two!
Charlie Squad to sector two!
All right, people,
please stay where you are!
Stay out of the street!
Mobile weapons unit
to sector two!
We got a man down in
sector two! On the double! [Siren Wailing]
Mobile units to sector two!
Flagg! Drop it!
Stay back!
It's a lie!
All of it!
I said, put it down.
I'll blow you out of your shoes, boy.
- Shoot him.
- Freeze, mister!
All right, hold on.
Everybody...
just lower your weapons.
[Man]
Hold your positions.
[Man #2]
Don't come any closer.
He's infected!
Contagious!
He'll spread a plague
through this place...
and kill all of you!
[People Gasping]
Listen to me, Briggs.
Think for a minute.
Do you suppose an army of guys
in plastic suits show up every time a meteor falls?
Shoot him.
That's a direct order!
How do you think they got here so quick?
How did they even know when to come?
- Shoot, damn it! Shoot!
- I'll tell you how!
That meteor is man-made!
It's some kind of a germ warfare test
they fucked up!
[Bill]
Don't try it!
[Screaming]
Let's scrag that son of a bitch.
Sensor charge!
Short fuse!
[Beeping]
[Gasping, Exclaiming]
Chew on that, slimeball.
[Rumbling]
[Rumbling Continues]
What's happening?
I think you pissed it off.
Go!
[Gunfire]
My God.
The day has come.
You don't understand! Reverend, come on!
This has all been prophesied.
Come on, move!
Get out! Everybody, back! Back! Everybody, back!
Brian!
He ran for it, Meg. Let's go! Go! Move!
You're hot.
[Screaming]
[Meg]
Reverend! [Screaming]
Meg, look out!
It's the cold!
It can't stand the cold!
[All Screaming]
Barricade all the entrances!
Get some more CO2 over here!
Look out!
I'm comin' through! Comin' through!
It's empty, Meg!
Get back!
Stay here.
And the great voice spoke
to the seven angels, saying‒
There! There!
Right there!
- It's out!
- Find some more!
[Screaming]
Brian!
[Gasping]
Help me.
Come on!
You can do better than that!
Come on, you son of a bitch.
[Beeping]
[Beeping Continues]
Meg!
Brian?
What a rush.
Whoa!
Hey, man.
I told you we'd get snow.
You gotta have faith.
I wonder if I'm covered
for this sort of thing.
Dave, bring in
the dump truck.
We better get this thing
to the icehouse before dawn.
[Reverend]
The will of God is written in the sky...
in fingers of flame!
Wormwood falls from heaven,
consuming sinner
and saint alike.
Who shall be lifted up
to rapture...
when the judgment trumpet blows?
None but the faithful,
brothers and sisters.
None but the faithful.
[Shouts Of Affirmation]
♪♪ [Piano]
♪ Soon I will be done ♪
♪ With the troubles ♪
♪ Of the world ♪
♪ The troubles ♪
When, Reverend?
Ma'am?
The Day of Reckoning.
How far off?
Soon, madam. Soon.
The Lord
will give me a sign.
♪♪ [Rock]
♪ She took a chance
and led with her heart ♪
♪ Passion played
and she took the part ♪
♪ In her eyes
I could see the flame ♪
♪ She heard my silent call
and came ♪
♪ And in the midnight
she held to beauty ♪
♪ Wild and eager innocence ♪
♪ Minute to minute
she took the lead ♪
♪ In our shadow dance ♪
♪ With her brave new love ♪
♪ She gives it up
like it's never been done ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪
♪ And in the dark
she's as tough as they come ♪
♪ She touched a place
I tried to hide ♪
♪ Found her way
past the warning signs ♪
♪ Fearless in battle
defending me ♪
♪ Though her surrender's my victory ♪
♪ I want to hold her
but not to tightly ♪
♪ She could crowd too easily ♪
♪ I gotta wait
till her lightning strikes to ♪
♪ Set me free ♪
♪ With her brave new love ♪
♪ She gives it up
like it's never been done ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪
♪ And in the dark,
she's as tough as they come ♪
♪ She's as tough as they come ♪
♪ Inside my dreams
I hear her calling me ♪
♪ I feel the need,
I know she'll be there ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ With her brave new love ♪
♪ She gives it up
like it's never been done ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪
♪ And in the dark,
she's as tough as they come ♪
♪ She took a chance
and led with her heart ♪
♪ Passion played
and she took the part ♪
♪ In her eyes
I could see the flame ♪
♪ She heard my silent call
and came ♪
♪ And in the midnight
she held to beauty ♪
♪ Wild and eager innocence ♪
♪ Minute to minute
she took the lead ♪
♪ In our shadow dance ♪
♪ With her brave new love ♪
♪ She gives it up
like it's never been done ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪
♪ And in the dark ♪
♪ She's as tough as they come ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪
♪ She gives it up
like it's never been done ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪
♪ And in the dark ♪
♪ She's as tough as they come ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪
♪ With her brave new love ♪
♪ Brave new love ♪♪