[projector clicking, ♪...]
[♪...]
>> man: [sighs]
you're available to start
right away?
You're available to start
>> yes.
Right away?
[♪...]
>> yes.
>> I'm not really seeing
[♪...]
a lot of restaurant experience
>> I'm not really seeing
on the, uh, resume.
A lot of restaurant experience
>> I've always had, um, summer
On the, uh, resume.
jobs, but, yeah, mostly retail.
>> I've always had, um, summer
[♪...]
Jobs, but, yeah, mostly retail.
>> so, did you drop out of
[♪...]
school, or... Why'd you come
>> so, did you drop out of
all the way back here?
School, or... Why'd you come
>> oh, no, um...
All the way back here?
Well, this is my home, and there
>> oh, no, um...
was an accident, so I have to
Well, this is my home, and there
take care of my brother.
Was an accident, so I have to
[♪...]
Take care of my brother.
>> well, I'll tell you what
[♪...]
I can do, um...
>> well, I'll tell you what
I'll talk to the owner.
I can do, um...
Uh, I know they were looking
I'll talk to the owner.
for, uh, wait staff with
Uh, I know they were looking
experience, but... Obviously
For, uh, wait staff with
you're smart, so maybe they'll,
Experience, but... Obviously
um, work with you, so...
You're smart, so maybe they'll,
>> sure, that'd be,
Um, work with you, so...
that'd be great.
>> sure, that'd be,
>> maybe you could do, um, host,
That'd be great.
if nothing else.
>> maybe you could do, um, host,
>> oh, sure, definitely.
If nothing else.
>> o.K., I mean, I can't
>> oh, sure, definitely.
promise anything, but, um...
>> o.K., I mean, I can't
>> oh, no, yeah.
Promise anything, but, um...
>> maybe I'll let you know by
>> oh, no, yeah.
the end of the day.
>> maybe I'll let you know by
>> thank you so much.
The end of the day.
Nice to meet you.
>> thank you so much.
>> nice meeting you.
Nice to meet you.
[♪...]
[toaster clicks]
>> I can make you some eggs
if you want.
>> yeah, I can make 'em, too.
If you want.
>> I'm gonna go back to the
>> yeah, I can make 'em, too.
clinic for a little while today.
>> I'm gonna go back to the
Will you be o.K. Here alone?
Clinic for a little while today.
>> something wrong?
Will you be o.K. Here alone?
>> dr. Barden thinks that he can
>> something wrong?
help us cut some of the costs.
>> dr. Barden thinks that he can
>> how?
Help us cut some of the costs.
>> I... I have no idea.
>> how?
But I'll find out.
>> I... I have no idea.
>> so there'll probably be some
But I'll find out.
of this... Yeah?
>> so there'll probably be some
>> yeah, probably.
Of this... Yeah?
Thank you.
>> yeah, probably.
[car whooshes, ♪...]
Thank you.
[car alarm beeps on]
[car whooshes, ♪...]
[♪...]
>> woman: Oh, thank you.
Thank you both.
[knock on door]
>> um, dr. Barden?
The nurse said that I--
>> man: Of course, come in.
Iris, good to see you.
>> iris: Hi.
>> dr. Barden: Iris,
shepard lambrick.
>> iris.
Shepard lambrick.
Dr. Barden's told me much
>> iris.
about you.
Dr. Barden's told me much
>> iris, please, have a seat.
About you.
Shepard.
>> so...
Your brother.
He's quite sick, correct?
>> you can help him?
>> well, let's just say that my
foundation has the ability to
improve his situation.
Foundation has the ability to
>> the lambricks have funded
Improve his situation.
the building of clinics all over
>> the lambricks have funded
the world.
The building of clinics all over
Haiti, uh, afghanistan...
The world.
>> schools, too.
Haiti, uh, afghanistan...
>> well, my brother doesn't need
>> schools, too.
a school.
>> well, my brother doesn't need
>> you're right.
A school.
Absolutely right.
>> you're right.
Because we're not talking about
Absolutely right.
that today.
Because we're not talking about
Not at all.
That today.
My family also believes in
Not at all.
creating opportunities for...
My family also believes in
Everyday people.
Creating opportunities for...
People who just haven't received
Everyday people.
a fair shake in life-- people
People who just haven't received
like you and your brother.
A fair shake in life-- people
>> what do we have to do?
Like you and your brother.
>> I'm hosting a dinner party
>> what do we have to do?
tomorrow night, and I'd like you
>> I'm hosting a dinner party
to join us.
Tomorrow night, and I'd like you
>> just me.
To join us.
>> just you-- oh, but there'll
>> just me.
be other guests there.
>> just you-- oh, but there'll
Individuals that we'd also
Be other guests there.
like to help.
Individuals that we'd also
And the evening will culminate
Like to help.
with a game, of sorts, and
And the evening will culminate
the winner...
With a game, of sorts, and
Will be taken care of.
The winner...
Bills, school, house,
Will be taken care of.
everything.
Bills, school, house,
>> a contest.
Everything.
What if I don't win?
>> a contest.
>> [chuckles] well, then,
What if I don't win?
you just don't win.
>> [chuckles] well, then,
That's it.
You just don't win.
>> um, I'm sorry, dr. Barden.
That's it.
No, no offense to mr. Lambrick,
>> um, I'm sorry, dr. Barden.
but is this legit?
No, no offense to mr. Lambrick,
This is for real?
But is this legit?
>> [chuckles]
This is for real?
>> very real, iris.
>> [chuckles]
[♪...]
>> very real, iris.
mr. Lambrick saved my life.
[♪...]
Not long ago, but before I met
Mr. Lambrick saved my life.
you and your brother, I was in
Not long ago, but before I met
the same position.
You and your brother, I was in
I'd already lost my wife.
The same position.
I was on my way to losing
I'd already lost my wife.
everything-- this practice,
I was on my way to losing
everything.
Everything-- this practice,
I had no place to turn.
Everything.
I was invited to this event,
I had no place to turn.
so I went.
I was invited to this event,
>> you won?
So I went.
>> he did, and I am proud to say
>> you won?
that the lambrick foundation
>> he did, and I am proud to say
came through on its promise.
That the lambrick foundation
>> tenfold.
Came through on its promise.
>> you see what we might be able
>> tenfold.
to do for you.
>> you see what we might be able
>> well, money would definitely
To do for you.
help, but my brother needs a
>> well, money would definitely
bone marrow transplant.
Help, but my brother needs a
So, do you mind if I think
Bone marrow transplant.
this over?
So, do you mind if I think
Um, it's just--
This over?
>> short notice.
Um, it's just--
It is, you're right.
>> short notice.
Of course, yes.
It is, you're right.
Think it over.
Of course, yes.
Do that.
Think it over.
>> well...
>> but r.S.V.P. By eight o'clock
tonight, if you do decide to
join us.
Tonight, if you do decide to
And my staff will make
Join us.
arrangements to pick you up.
And my staff will make
>> iris: Thank you.
Arrangements to pick you up.
>> mm-hmm.
>> iris: Thank you.
When I say that we have the
>> mm-hmm.
ability to dramatically improve
When I say that we have the
your brother's situation, iris,
Ability to dramatically improve
it's not just the money
Your brother's situation, iris,
I'm talking about.
It's not just the money
You win the game, and we can
I'm talking about.
bypass any waiting list and
You win the game, and we can
locate a donor, immediately.
>> I will let you know.
Thank you.
>> she's perfect.
[crickets chirping]
>> iris: This is the special du
jour, is pasta a la vegetables.
>> brother: Um, o.K., wow.
Jour, is pasta a la vegetables.
Iris, um, that's a terrible
>> brother: Um, o.K., wow.
italian accent.
Iris, um, that's a terrible
And if it's french, "monsieur"
Italian accent.
is not pronounced "man sewer".
And if it's french, "monsieur"
>>   monsieur>> monsieur.
Is not pronounced "man sewer".
>>   monsieur.
>>   monsieur>> monsieur.
>> yes. Come on, seriously,
>>   monsieur.
like, it's not gonna kill me to
>> yes. Come on, seriously,
have some protein now and then.
Like, it's not gonna kill me to
[cell phone buzzing]
Have some protein now and then.
>> hello?
[cell phone buzzing]
Uh, speaking.
>> hello?
Uh-huh?
Uh, speaking.
Oh.
Uh-huh?
O.K.-- Well, uh, wait, um,
Oh.
what about the hostess position
O.K.-- Well, uh, wait, um,
that you, you...
What about the hostess position
Oh.
That you, you...
O.K., well, thank you.
Oh.
Thanks again.
O.K., well, thank you.
[♪...]
Thanks again.
>> brother: You mad at me or
[♪...]
something?
>> brother: You mad at me or
>> why would I be mad at you?
Something?
[♪...]
>> why would I be mad at you?
I thought I would be a match.
[♪...]
I feel like I let you down.
>> brother: You can't always be
the hero.
Sometimes you have to let go.
The hero.
>> like let go of you?
Sometimes you have to let go.
[♪...]
>> man: Get down, get down!
Give me cover!
[gunfire and man shouting]
>> killing lots of aliens?
>> nope, terrorists.
>> killing lots of terrorists?
>> straight up murderin' these
terrorists, yo.
What's up?
Terrorists, yo.
>> so, um, I'm gonna go out
What's up?
tonight.
>> so, um, I'm gonna go out
>> with who?
Tonight.
>> I... I ran into a couple of
>> with who?
friends from high school and,
>> I... I ran into a couple of
and I thought, you know what?
Friends from high school and,
I should go and unwind.
And I thought, you know what?
>> yeah, let your hair down
I should go and unwind.
and shit.
>> yeah, let your hair down
>> yeah, just go crazy.
And shit.
>> yeah, cool.
>> yeah, just go crazy.
>> so, you're gonna be o.K. Here
>> yeah, cool.
alone for the night?
>> so, you're gonna be o.K. Here
>> yeah.
Alone for the night?
Got my meds, emergency contact.
>> yeah.
I'll just play video games or
Got my meds, emergency contact.
whatever.
I'll just play video games or
I could really use the quiet.
Whatever.
>> great.
I could really use the quiet.
Cool.
>> great.
[kiss] love you.
Cool.
[♪...]
[birds chirping, ♪...]
>> aren't you sick of this?
Taking me back and forth to
the clinic.
Bills, taking care of me,
The clinic.
like, don't you want a life?
Bills, taking care of me,
>> no.
Like, don't you want a life?
I mean, yeah, I...
>> no.
It's hard.
I mean, yeah, I...
But, raleigh, you're my brother.
It's hard.
This is my life.
But, raleigh, you're my brother.
It's gonna be fine.
This is my life.
We'll get through this.
It's gonna be fine.
[car door opens]
We'll get through this.
[crickets chirping...]
>> this way, please.
>> iris: Thank you.
[music plays in distance]
pretty.
>> yes.
Pretty.
>> does the lambrick family
>> yes.
live here?
>> does the lambrick family
>> not exactly.
Live here?
Property's owned by the
>> not exactly.
foundation.
Property's owned by the
It's used for holidays and
Foundation.
special events like this.
It's used for holidays and
Dinner will begin shortly.
Special events like this.
You can wait in here with all
Dinner will begin shortly.
the other guests.
You can wait in here with all
And please, help yourself to any
The other guests.
of the provided refreshments.
And please, help yourself to any
[♪...]
Of the provided refreshments.
our eighth and final guest.
>> lucky number eight.
>> iris: Does everyone get an
introduction like that?
>> oh, yeah, it's been
Introduction like that?
very formal.
>> oh, yeah, it's been
>> it's nice to meet you guys.
Very formal.
I'm iris.
>> it's nice to meet you guys.
>> lucas, and this is, uh...
I'm iris.
>> cal, how you doin'?
>> lucas, and this is, uh...
>> hi.
>> cal, how you doin'?
Have you guys been here long?
>> hi.
>> not long.
Have you guys been here long?
Couple minutes for some.
>> not long.
Hour or two for the rest of us.
Couple minutes for some.
>> are you both from the area,
Hour or two for the rest of us.
too?
>> are you both from the area,
>> no, they flew me in from
Too?
seattle.
>> no, they flew me in from
>> iowa.
Seattle.
>> would you like a little
>> iowa.
something to drink?
>> would you like a little
>> um, no, I'm o.K., not yet.
Something to drink?
So, what do you know about
>> um, no, I'm o.K., not yet.
the others?
So, what do you know about
Anything?
The others?
>> mm, a little.
Anything?
As you can see, they're not
>> mm, a little.
exactly gregarious.
As you can see, they're not
>> big guy over there is peter.
Exactly gregarious.
Supposed to be some sort of
>> big guy over there is peter.
high stakes gambler from vegas.
Supposed to be some sort of
>> not that any of us have
High stakes gambler from vegas.
actually heard of him.
>> not that any of us have
>> it's the way he made it
Actually heard of him.
sound. >> yeah.
>> it's the way he made it
>> lady in the wheelchair is
Sound. >> yeah.
linda.
>> lady in the wheelchair is
She barely speaks.
>> kid in the corner is travis.
He's an iraq vet.
>> yeah, he's got that
thousand-yard stare.
>> what about the girl?
Thousand-yard stare.
>> her name is amy.
>> what about the girl?
And, yeah, she's a real charmer.
>> her name is amy.
>> and the older gentleman?
And, yeah, she's a real charmer.
>> I don't think I'd call him
>> and the older gentleman?
that.
>> I don't think I'd call him
>> older.
That.
>> "gentleman".
>> older.
>> why?
>> "gentleman".
>> conway's a bit of a sourpuss.
>> why?
>> yeah, he's, um, he has some
>> conway's a bit of a sourpuss.
conspiracy theories about the
>> yeah, he's, um, he has some
lambrick foundation.
Conspiracy theories about the
Don't get him started.
Lambrick foundation.
>> maybe I will have a drink.
Don't get him started.
>> good.
>> maybe I will have a drink.
My very own specialty, b.L.T.
>> good.
[glasses and ice clanking]
My very own specialty, b.L.T.
>> thank you.
[glasses and ice clanking]
To the lambrick foundation.
>> thank you.
>>   salud.
To the lambrick foundation.
[glass shatters]
[♪...]
>> shepard: She's perfect.
Case?
Case.
>> I'm not sure she's right
for this.
>> what?
For this.
She couldn't be more perfect.
>> what?
She's fighting for her brother,
She couldn't be more perfect.
herself, she has no relatives,
She's fighting for her brother,
no family.
Herself, she has no relatives,
No one to ask questions.
No family.
>> shep, she is not right.
No one to ask questions.
>> let's just say I've
>> shep, she is not right.
appreciated your discretion over
>> let's just say I've
the last couple of years.
Appreciated your discretion over
Should I be concerned about this
The last couple of years.
moment of weakness on your part?
Should I be concerned about this
>> dr. Barden: [chuckles]
Moment of weakness on your part?
...Of course not.
>> dr. Barden: [chuckles]
I'm fine.
...Of course not.
>> bevans has informed me that
I'm fine.
the last guest has arrived.
>> bevans has informed me that
We ought to get downstairs soon.
The last guest has arrived.
>> man: Do we have to sit
We ought to get downstairs soon.
through an entire dinner?
>> man: Do we have to sit
Why can't we just get it
Through an entire dinner?
over with?
Why can't we just get it
>> shepard: Julian!
Over with?
That's not the way it works,
>> shepard: Julian!
as you know.
That's not the way it works,
There is a process involved.
As you know.
>> [chuckles]
There is a process involved.
of course.
>> [chuckles]
>> I trust that you will be on
Of course.
your best behavior tonight.
>> I trust that you will be on
>> I'm not even drinking.
Your best behavior tonight.
>> I'm serious.
>> I'm not even drinking.
The integrity of the game
>> I'm serious.
requires minimal participation
The integrity of the game
on our part.
Requires minimal participation
We must remain an objective
On our part.
observer, even if one of these
We must remain an objective
people is eliminated.
Observer, even if one of these
Do you understand?
People is eliminated.
And if one of them has to be
Do you understand?
removed from the game, bevans
And if one of them has to be
will be the one to handle it.
Removed from the game, bevans
Your job, as a lambrick,
Will be the one to handle it.
is simply to observe.
Your job, as a lambrick,
You can engage these people with
Is simply to observe.
questions and conversation, but
You can engage these people with
you will not so much as touch
Questions and conversation, but
any of these people tonight.
You will not so much as touch
>> I know.
Any of these people tonight.
>> julian.
>> I know.
Look, I appreciate that you've
>> julian.
taken an interest in the
Look, I appreciate that you've
foundation-- I do-- but what
Taken an interest in the
happened last year was
Foundation-- I do-- but what
unacceptable.
Happened last year was
>> [sighs] for the last time,
Unacceptable.
I understand.
>> [sighs] for the last time,
>> o.K., o.K., o.K.
I understand.
I won't bring it up again.
>> o.K., o.K., o.K.
And you're underdressed again.
>> we have one small matter to
clear up before we begin.
In the interest of discretion,
Clear up before we begin.
and eliminating distraction and
In the interest of discretion,
unfair advantage, we ask that
And eliminating distraction and
you leave all possessions here
Unfair advantage, we ask that
during the game...
You leave all possessions here
Phones, keys, et cetera.
During the game...
>> I don't like this.
Phones, keys, et cetera.
I don't like it.
>> I don't like this.
>> I assure you they will be
I don't like it.
safe.
>> I assure you they will be
These are the rules.
Right.
If you're ready, I'll escort you
through to the dining room.
This way.
[♪...]
Please, take a seat.
Place cards have been provided.
>> thank you.
>> cal: Of course.
>> and good evening, everyone.
I apologize if I've kept anyone
waiting.
Welcome to the lambrick house.
Waiting.
Oh, this is my son, julian.
Welcome to the lambrick house.
>> hello.
Oh, this is my son, julian.
>> [chuckles]
>> hello.
now, you've all met our butler,
>> [chuckles]
bevans, and his staff, yes?
Now, you've all met our butler,
Bevans.
Bevans, and his staff, yes?
Let's start with some wine,
Bevans.
shall we?
>> dinner tonight is seared
foie gras and rib eye steak with
a red wine reduction, served
Foie gras and rib eye steak with
with asparagus and garlic leek
A red wine reduction, served
mashed potato.
With asparagus and garlic leek
Enjoy.
Mashed potato.
>> haven't had a meal like this
Enjoy.
in so long.
>> haven't had a meal like this
>> cal: Never had a meal like
In so long.
this, you kidding me?
>> cal: Never had a meal like
>> mm, yes?
This, you kidding me?
>> I probably should have
>> mm, yes?
mentioned this before.
>> I probably should have
Um, I'm a vegetarian.
Mentioned this before.
>> [scoffs]
Um, I'm a vegetarian.
>> well, this is interesting.
>> [scoffs]
We don't have anything else in
>> well, this is interesting.
the kitchen, iris.
We don't have anything else in
>> o.K.
The kitchen, iris.
I, I don't mean to be a bother.
>> o.K.
Uh, the potatoes are fine.
I, I don't mean to be a bother.
I'll be fine.
Uh, the potatoes are fine.
>> so, have you always been a
I'll be fine.
vegetarian?
>> so, have you always been a
>> most of my life, yes.
Vegetarian?
Long time.
>> most of my life, yes.
I just can't imagine eating--
Long time.
>> I think... That we have just
I just can't imagine eating--
found our first opportunity to
>> I think... That we have just
award some money tonight.
Found our first opportunity to
Iris.
Award some money tonight.
I would like for you to eat the
Iris.
steak and the foie gras.
I would like for you to eat the
I really would.
Steak and the foie gras.
>> I can't do that.
I really would.
>> you can... But you won't.
>> I can't do that.
Yet.
>> you can... But you won't.
>> no, I really, I can't do it.
Yet.
I'm not trying to be rude.
>> no, I really, I can't do it.
I just, I won't do it.
I'm not trying to be rude.
>> listen, I, I understand that
I just, I won't do it.
it's not going to be easy.
>> listen, I, I understand that
But I refuse to accept...
It's not going to be easy.
That you don't have a price.
But I refuse to accept...
$5,000 to eat the steak
That you don't have a price.
and this decadent foie gras.
$5,000 to eat the steak
[chuckles] mmm!
And this decadent foie gras.
Make it 10,000.
$10,000.
What could you do with that?
>> you should eat it.
Just close your eyes.
It's a lot of money.
[iris exhales]
>> shepard: [chuckles]
eat it with some of the liver.
>> [chuckles]
Eat it with some of the liver.
>> I can't believe I'm
>> [chuckles]
doing this.
>> I can't believe I'm
>> yeah, but $10,000 though.
Doing this.
>> [sighs]
>> yeah, but $10,000 though.
>> a lifetime of discipline and
>> [sighs]
commitment to cause wiped away
>> a lifetime of discipline and
by a mere $10,000.
Commitment to cause wiped away
[laughing]
Well, that is nothing compared
to what's really at stake
tonight, I can assure you
To what's really at stake
of that.
Tonight, I can assure you
[chuckles]
Of that.
you don't like the wine?
[chuckles]
>> well, no, it's not that.
You don't like the wine?
>> we can get you something
>> well, no, it's not that.
else. >> mmm.
>> we can get you something
>> we have some wonderful
Else. >> mmm.
scotch.
>> we have some wonderful
>> no, no thanks, I don't drink.
Scotch.
>> oh...
>> no, no thanks, I don't drink.
Oh, I see.
>> oh...
You're a recovering alcoholic.
Oh, I see.
Aren't you?
You're a recovering alcoholic.
>> it's not your business.
Aren't you?
>> [chuckles] on the contrary.
>> it's not your business.
You are here essentially begging
>> [chuckles] on the contrary.
me for money.
You are here essentially begging
How is that not my business?
Me for money.
[♪...]
How is that not my business?
how long has it been?
[♪...]
>> [scoffs]
How long has it been?
[sighs] it's been 16 years, and
>> [scoffs]
I turned everything in my life
[sighs] it's been 16 years, and
around.
I turned everything in my life
>> [laughs]
Around.
but you haven't.
>> [laughs]
Look at you.
But you haven't.
You're still mired in a pit of
Look at you.
poor health and crippling debt.
You're still mired in a pit of
I'd hate to see what you looked
Poor health and crippling debt.
like 16 years ago.
I'd hate to see what you looked
I mean, really.
Like 16 years ago.
What's the point?
I mean, really.
>> please.
What's the point?
Why are you doing this?
>> please.
>> because I want to help you.
Why are you doing this?
Look...
>> because I want to help you.
It's safe to say that drinking
Look...
is what ruined your life in the
It's safe to say that drinking
first place, isn't it?
Is what ruined your life in the
So what if... Drinking again
First place, isn't it?
could help you save it?
So what if... Drinking again
>> what? >> I will give you
Could help you save it?
$10,000 if you drink that
>> what? >> I will give you
glass of wine.
$10,000 if you drink that
>> [chuckles] oh.
Glass of wine.
No.
>> [chuckles] oh.
No, no way, no.
No.
You don't understand.
No, no way, no.
You have no idea how hard
You don't understand.
I've worked.
You have no idea how hard
>> ah, but iris here, uh, she
I've worked.
just devoured a pile of meat,
>> ah, but iris here, uh, she
and she's a devout vegetarian,
Just devoured a pile of meat,
and you won't drink
And she's a devout vegetarian,
a little wine.
And you won't drink
>> it's totally different.
A little wine.
Why are you doing this to me?
>> it's totally different.
>> $50,000.
Why are you doing this to me?
If you won't drink...
>> $50,000.
This decanter of the finest
If you won't drink...
scotch that money can buy,
This decanter of the finest
right now.
Scotch that money can buy,
50,000.
Right now.
>> this is what, a test?
50,000.
It's not real.
>> this is what, a test?
>> oh, no... [chuckles]
It's not real.
I am deadly serious, conway,
>> oh, no... [chuckles]
and you know that I am.
I am deadly serious, conway,
The glass of wine or the whole
And you know that I am.
damn decanter.
The glass of wine or the whole
Now, it seems to me that the
Damn decanter.
wine is... That's pretty simple,
Now, it seems to me that the
isn't it?
Wine is... That's pretty simple,
But the scotch.
Isn't it?
Well, we could consider that a,
But the scotch.
a momentary lapse to...
Well, we could consider that a,
Change your life.
>> [softly] I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
>> shepard: So what would you
rather do?
[♪...]
[laughing]
>> [grunts]
>> that's a good man.
>> thanks.
>> bevans.
That was brilliant, as usual.
My compliments to marcel.
Regarding tonight's game.
Please allow me to alleviate any
concerns you have.
>> we haven't already been
Concerns you have.
playing?
>> we haven't already been
>> oh, no, the game has yet to
Playing?
officially begin.
>> oh, no, the game has yet to
>> what exactly is the game?
Officially begin.
>> well, it is not a quiz or a
>> what exactly is the game?
trivia contest, nor is it a test
>> well, it is not a quiz or a
of brute strength or
Trivia contest, nor is it a test
athleticism.
Of brute strength or
At its core, it's just a
Athleticism.
children's game, and I would
At its core, it's just a
wager that some of you here this
Children's game, and I would
evening have played "would you
Wager that some of you here this
rather?" at some point.
Evening have played "would you
So, how do we play?
Rather?" at some point.
In each round, each player
So, how do we play?
will be given a choice between
In each round, each player
"a" or "b", uh, and usually, uh,
Will be given a choice between
neither choice is very
"a" or "b", uh, and usually, uh,
attractive.
Neither choice is very
Let's see if I can give you
Attractive.
an example: Travis.
Let's see if I can give you
Travis, would you rather...
An example: Travis.
Kiss iris or peter?
Travis, would you rather...
[scattered chuckling]
Kiss iris or peter?
[chuckles]
[scattered chuckling]
>> guess I'd kiss iris.
[chuckles]
>> very good.
>> guess I'd kiss iris.
Now, this is where our version
>> very good.
of the game is different.
Now, this is where our version
Whatever you choose, you must
Of the game is different.
act upon, so in this case,
Whatever you choose, you must
travis, you must walk over and
Act upon, so in this case,
kiss iris.
Travis, you must walk over and
>> you're gonna make us kiss
Kiss iris.
each other?
>> you're gonna make us kiss
>> [chuckles] no, no, no,
Each other?
nothing like that, my dear.
>> [chuckles] no, no, no,
No, that was just off the top of
Nothing like that, my dear.
my head.
No, that was just off the top of
Now, as the game continues,
My head.
with one dilemma after another,
Now, as the game continues,
eliminating players as we go
With one dilemma after another,
until we have a winner.
Eliminating players as we go
>> and how are players
Until we have a winner.
eliminated?
>> and how are players
>> well, if a player is no
Eliminated?
longer capable of continuing--
>> well, if a player is no
well, for whatever reason--
Longer capable of continuing--
then they are eliminated.
Well, for whatever reason--
>> what if someone refuses to
Then they are eliminated.
make a choice?
>> what if someone refuses to
Like, if travis didn't want to
Make a choice?
kiss either of us?
Like, if travis didn't want to
>> ah, if you refuse to choose.
Kiss either of us?
Well, I am afraid that that
>> ah, if you refuse to choose.
would be grounds for
Well, I am afraid that that
elimination.
Would be grounds for
And one more thing.
Elimination.
The dilemmas are timed.
And one more thing.
And you must make your decision
The dilemmas are timed.
in 15 seconds or you will be
And you must make your decision
eliminated.
In 15 seconds or you will be
>> hold up.
Eliminated.
Is all this necessary?
>> hold up.
I mean, couldn't you help
Is all this necessary?
all of us?
I mean, couldn't you help
Why does this have to be a game?
All of us?
>> because, as simple as the
Why does this have to be a game?
game is, it's all about
>> because, as simple as the
decision-making in its rawest
Game is, it's all about
form.
Decision-making in its rawest
And there's no better window
Form.
into a person's character than
And there's no better window
the decisions that they make
Into a person's character than
and how they make them and how
The decisions that they make
one applies rationale and ethics
And how they make them and how
and reason while under duress.
Tonight...
Will test your limits.
And ultimately, prove...
Whether you deserve our help.
If anyone no longer wishes to
play, now is your opportunity
to leave.
Play, now is your opportunity
We have cars waiting outside.
To leave.
Anyone?
We have cars waiting outside.
>> [grunts] mm-hmm.
Anyone?
[sniffles]
>> [grunts] mm-hmm.
[money thumps on table]
>> [laughs] all right.
We have a full house.
And so.
Here...
We...
Go.
[rumbling...]
Our man bevans, ladies and
gentlemen.
[keys jingling]
Gentlemen.
did you know he was formerly an
[keys jingling]
agent with m.I.-5?
Did you know he was formerly an
>> many years ago.
Agent with m.I.-5?
An interrogator.
>> many years ago.
>> is this one of your old toys,
An interrogator.
bevans?
>> is this one of your old toys,
>> [gasps]
Bevans?
>> it is, sir.
>> [gasps]
Car batteries with some
>> it is, sir.
after-market configurations.
Car batteries with some
>> shepard: Ah.
After-market configurations.
>> what, what the hell is this?
>> shepard: Ah.
>> oh, no, I see where this
>> what, what the hell is this?
is going.
>> oh, no, I see where this
>> conway?
Is going.
>> I knew this was too good
>> conway?
to be true.
>> I knew this was too good
This is a joke.
To be true.
You just wanna hurt us.
This is a joke.
You people, you're gonna sit
You just wanna hurt us.
here and you're gonna let this
You people, you're gonna sit
sick, perverted son of a bitch
Here and you're gonna let this
debase you?
Sick, perverted son of a bitch
Be my guest.
Debase you?
>> someone's had a little too
Be my guest.
much to drink.
>> someone's had a little too
>> that's right!
Much to drink.
That's right, and I'm
>> that's right!
going home.
That's right, and I'm
>> no, you've already been given
Going home.
that chance.
>> no, you've already been given
>> I don't care!
That chance.
I'm done with this!
>> I don't care!
>> ah, you were warned.
I'm done with this!
>> you go to hell, you sick
>> ah, you were warned.
motherfucker!
>> you go to hell, you sick
[screaming]
Motherfucker!
[no voices, ♪...]
>> I would like to go home.
>> well, obviously,
participation is no longer
voluntary.
Participation is no longer
I believe we just made that
Voluntary.
perfectly clear.
I believe we just made that
Bevans, shall we?
[lucas sighs]
[battery hums]
>> what's this?
What are we doing?
>> cal, you're up first.
So, cal.
Would you rather...
Electrocute yourself or would
you rather electrocute amy?
The blue button is for you.
You rather electrocute amy?
Press the red button if you'd
The blue button is for you.
rather zap amy.
Press the red button if you'd
And you have... 15 seconds to
Rather zap amy.
decide, beginning now.
And you have... 15 seconds to
[timer ticking...]
Decide, beginning now.
>> w-wait. >> iris: Wait.
[timer ticking...]
>> stop, stop, don't push it.
>> w-wait. >> iris: Wait.
O.K., wait, wait, stop.
>> stop, stop, don't push it.
Don't push the button.
O.K., wait, wait, stop.
Wait.
Don't push the button.
[ticking becomes louder]
Wait.
[screaming, buzzing]
>> shepard: Moving on.
[iris gasps]
>> you're not serious.
>> no!
Oh, no. >> oh, come on!
>> blue is for linda.
>> no, no, no, no, no, please!
>> amy.
You're next.
Would you rather electrocute
yourself or...
>> wait-- [screams]
Yourself or...
>> oh!
>> wait-- [screams]
>> take it easy!
>> oh!
>> we're competing, right?
>> take it easy!
>> no timer needed.
>> we're competing, right?
>> bevans: Linda.
>> no timer needed.
>> shepard: Linda!
>> bevans: Linda.
Bevans, is she ready?
>> shepard: Linda!
Linda.
Bevans, is she ready?
Can you hear me?
Linda.
Your turn.
Can you hear me?
>> I can't do this.
Your turn.
>> well, you have to do it,
>> I can't do this.
linda, you must make a decision.
>> well, you have to do it,
It's the game.
Linda, you must make a decision.
>> red is for peter.
It's the game.
>> I don't think I can do this,
>> red is for peter.
either.
>> I don't think I can do this,
[gun clicks]
Either.
all right.
[gun clicks]
>> what was that?
All right.
>> christ.
>> what was that?
>> would you rather electrocute
>> christ.
yourself, again, or shock peter?
>> would you rather electrocute
15 seconds.
Yourself, again, or shock peter?
[timer ticking...]
15 seconds.
>> [groans]
Fuck!
>> [clapping]
well done, both of you.
Next.
Well done, both of you.
[♪...]
>> [sighs]
[engine revs, ♪...]
[travis grunts]
[buzzing]
>> [gasps]
>> iris: Are you o.K.?
>> stall 'em.
>> are you o.K.?
>> I can do one more.
>> what?
>> I said stall 'em.
I'm not gonna shock you.
>> iris.
What have you seen in the last
10 minutes that leads you to
believe you don't have to
perform in this round?
Believe you don't have to
Keep... Still.
Perform in this round?
Much better.
Keep... Still.
>> bevans: Red is for iris.
Much better.
>> now, lucas, what would you
>> bevans: Red is for iris.
rather do?
>> now, lucas, what would you
[timer ticking...]
>> [screams]
[pounds on table]
>> [gasps]
>> bevans: Red is for cal.
>> iris, would you rather
electrocute yourself, or cal for
the second time?
Electrocute yourself, or cal for
>> you do what you gotta do.
The second time?
>> go.
>> you do what you gotta do.
[timer ticking...]
[buzzing]
>> [breathing heavily]
>> that's an interesting choice.
[iris sniffles and gasps]
right.
[thumps on table]
Right.
[clapping] well done,
[thumps on table]
everyone.
[clapping] well done,
Very well done.
Everyone.
Now...
Very well done.
I'm gonna give you a moment,
Now...
all, to compose yourselves while
I'm gonna give you a moment,
we prepare for the next round.
>> travis: Listen, we just need
a moment, some kind of
distraction-- if we all move
A moment, some kind of
at once, we can overpower 'em.
Distraction-- if we all move
>> cal: It seems like they're
At once, we can overpower 'em.
all packing, so that's not much
>> cal: It seems like they're
of a plan.
All packing, so that's not much
>> travis: If we can disarm one,
Of a plan.
I can shoot-- that'll even the
>> travis: If we can disarm one,
odds pretty fucking quick.
I can shoot-- that'll even the
>> iris: But what about the
Odds pretty fucking quick.
doors? They have us locked in.
>> iris: But what about the
>> lucas: I saw a couple of 'em
Doors? They have us locked in.
with sets of keys.
>> lucas: I saw a couple of 'em
Here comes another set
With sets of keys.
right now.
Here comes another set
>> hi, everyone.
Game's getting pretty intense
already, right, hmm?
>> why are you doing this?
Already, right, hmm?
>> "why are you doing this?"
>> why are you doing this?
[chuckles]
>> "why are you doing this?"
>> you're fucking crazy.
[chuckles]
>> you know...
>> you're fucking crazy.
You agreed to be here.
>> you know...
You're basically asking my
You agreed to be here.
family for a handout.
You're basically asking my
The least you could do, pig, is
Family for a handout.
show a little fucking respect.
The least you could do, pig, is
>> travis: Psycho little bitch.
Show a little fucking respect.
>> excuse me, what?
>> travis: Psycho little bitch.
>> lucas: Shh, shh.
>> excuse me, what?
>> you heard me, bitch.
>> lucas: Shh, shh.
>> I'm sorry, we didn't get
>> you heard me, bitch.
formally introduced.
>> I'm sorry, we didn't get
>> well, now we have.
Formally introduced.
How 'bout you show us a little
>> well, now we have.
respect, huh?
How 'bout you show us a little
>> stop.
Respect, huh?
What's your name?
>> stop.
Name, pig!
What's your name?
>> travis schulke!
>> o.K., travis.
Travis.
You're the soldier, right?
Well, allow me to thank you for
your bravery and your service.
Really.
Your bravery and your service.
But, um, yeah, that said...
Really.
[scoffs] opening your mouth was
But, um, yeah, that said...
a big mistake.
[scoffs] opening your mouth was
>> lucas: Easy, easy.
A big mistake.
>> julian: So.
>> lucas: Easy, easy.
[clears throat]
>> julian: So.
cover the walls and the...
[clears throat]
Area around the table.
>> wait, what are you guys
doing?
>> that was incredibly stupid,
Doing?
travis.
>> that was incredibly stupid,
>> I will fuck that guy up if I
Travis.
get the chance.
>> I will fuck that guy up if I
>> but you won't.
Get the chance.
>> cool it.
>> but you won't.
They want us to turn on
>> cool it.
each other.
They want us to turn on
>> if we stay logical, we can
Each other.
turn the tables on 'em.
>> if we stay logical, we can
She's on her own.
Turn the tables on 'em.
>> look around you.
She's on her own.
>> travis: Yeah, we're fucked.
[crickets chirping, ♪...]
[car door opens]
>> and so we begin again.
Oh, does anyone need to use the
restroom or anything?
[laughs]
Restroom or anything?
I'm just joking.
[laughs]
I know you're probably all just
I'm just joking.
as eager to keep playing
I know you're probably all just
as we are. [laughs]
As eager to keep playing
now in this round, you will each
As we are. [laughs]
get 30 seconds in order to make
Now in this round, you will each
your decision, all right?
Get 30 seconds in order to make
So, let's begin with...
Your decision, all right?
Iris.
So, let's begin with...
Iris, would you rather...
Iris.
Stab cal in the thigh with an
Iris, would you rather...
ice pick?
Stab cal in the thigh with an
>> what?
Ice pick?
>> shepard: Or strike travis
>> what?
three times with this african
>> shepard: Or strike travis
whipping staff, a sjambok?
Three times with this african
>> linda: Oh, my god.
Whipping staff, a sjambok?
They're gonna kills us!
>> linda: Oh, my god.
>> look, iris, three whacks from
They're gonna kills us!
that, I'll be o.K.
>> look, iris, three whacks from
>> if I stab him, I could kill
That, I'll be o.K.
him, right?
>> if I stab him, I could kill
>> and it's only three.
Him, right?
>> it's gonna hurt though, man.
>> and it's only three.
>> I know, just get it over
>> it's gonna hurt though, man.
with.
>> I know, just get it over
>> the clock is ticking.
The sjambok it is.
Now, iris, you have to put your
back into this, hmm?
There's no just tapping him.
Back into this, hmm?
That doesn't count.
There's no just tapping him.
And, uh, travis.
That doesn't count.
This is going to hurt, so
And, uh, travis.
make yourself comfortable.
This is going to hurt, so
[laughs]
Make yourself comfortable.
>> bevans: Like this, ma'am.
[laughs]
Across the back.
>> bevans: Like this, ma'am.
>> [breathing heavily]
Across the back.
travis?
>> [breathing heavily]
>> go ahead, iris.
Travis?
>> [breathing heavily]
>> no, no, no, no, no, no.
That won't count.
>> [breathing heavily]
>> [gasps]
[slap]
>> [grunts]
>> fuck.
[slap, travis gasps]
>> shepard: All right.
That looked like it hurt,
travis.
>> well, it did.
Travis.
>> [softly] are you o.K.?
>> well, it did.
>> I've been through worse.
>> [softly] are you o.K.?
>> shepard: Lucas.
>> I've been through worse.
You're next.
>> shepard: Lucas.
Would you rather stab iris
You're next.
in the thigh...
Would you rather stab iris
Or...
In the thigh...
Give travis three more strikes?
Or...
>> oh, come on!
Give travis three more strikes?
[timer ticking...]
Look, it's a really dangerous
place to stab somebody.
There's a major artery there.
Place to stab somebody.
You know what I'm saying?
There's a major artery there.
>> I do.
You know what I'm saying?
Let's just get it over with.
>> I do.
[sighs]
Let's just get it over with.
[iris sighs]
[sighs]
>> shepard: The sjambok again.
[iris sighs]
[travis breathing heavily...]
[slap, travis grunts]
[whimpers]
[slap, travis yelps]
[slap, travis grunts]
>> sorry, man.
[travis breathing raggedly...]
>> travis, you're probably
relieved to find out that
it's your turn.
Relieved to find out that
>> something like that.
It's your turn.
>> all right, then.
>> something like that.
Let's get it over with.
>> all right, then.
Travis...
Let's get it over with.
Would you rather... Stab lucas,
Travis...
the man who just whipped you,
Would you rather... Stab lucas,
or... [tapping on table]
The man who just whipped you,
a drum roll, please...
Or... [tapping on table]
Take three more lashes, this
A drum roll, please...
time administered by bevans?
Take three more lashes, this
>> ser-- seriously, man.
Time administered by bevans?
I can't... I can't do this
>> ser-- seriously, man.
anymore.
I can't... I can't do this
>> I wonder why you're being
Anymore.
singled out.
>> I wonder why you're being
>> [laughs mockingly]
Singled out.
>> what the fuck is the matter
>> [laughs mockingly]
with you people?
>> what the fuck is the matter
What did I ever do to you, huh?
With you people?
[screams] what?
That's, that's what I thought.
>> travis, we need a decision.
>> yeah.
Yeah, fucking whip.
I'm not stabbing anybody.
>> we have to stop this,
we have to.
>> yeah, wait.
We have to.
Wait, stop-- stop.
>> yeah, wait.
Travis, just stab me in
Wait, stop-- stop.
the thigh, o.K.?
Travis, just stab me in
We can't watch this go on.
The thigh, o.K.?
>> I'm not stabbing anybody.
We can't watch this go on.
>> travis, come on.
>> I'm not stabbing anybody.
>> lucas, this is admirable,
>> travis, come on.
but it's against the rules.
>> lucas, this is admirable,
>> but I'm o.K. With it.
But it's against the rules.
>> he can't go back.
>> but I'm o.K. With it.
His first choice is final.
>> he can't go back.
>> just hold on a second,
His first choice is final.
I said I'm o.K. With it!
>> just hold on a second,
>> it's o.K.
I said I'm o.K. With it!
>> lucas: Come on.
>> it's o.K.
>> shepard: Lucas.
>> lucas: Come on.
>> it's o.K.
>> shepard: Lucas.
>> shepard: This is all very
>> it's o.K.
admirable.
>> shepard: This is all very
His decision.
>> it's o.K.
>> it's just like life,
isn't it?
There's no do-overs.
>> [whimpers]
[muffled screams]
[whimpers]
>> travis, travis, travis,
travis.
>> lucas: Hey, hey, hey.
Travis.
>> [grunting and retching]
>> lucas: Hey, hey, hey.
>> he's in trouble.
>> [grunting and retching]
He needs medical attention.
>> he's in trouble.
[crickets chirping, ♪...]
>> peter...
I'm awfully sorry, but I'm
afraid it's your turn.
You know the drill by now.
Afraid it's your turn.
The pick or...
You know the drill by now.
Give travis three more.
>> if I do the pick, who does it
have to be?
>> I'm sure you've already
Have to be?
worked the angles on that one,
>> I'm sure you've already
haven't you?
Worked the angles on that one,
>> well... I don't wanna stab
Haven't you?
a lady.
>> well... I don't wanna stab
I'm not mr. Manners or anything,
A lady.
but I think there's some common
I'm not mr. Manners or anything,
decency considerations here.
But I think there's some common
>> shepard: 30 seconds.
Decency considerations here.
>> [sighs]
>> shepard: 30 seconds.
on the other hand, travis is
>> [sighs]
in real bad shape.
On the other hand, travis is
We can't really hit him anymore,
In real bad shape.
can we?
We can't really hit him anymore,
Honestly, linda.
Can we?
You're paralyzed, right?
Honestly, linda.
Your leg wouldn't feel this,
You're paralyzed, right?
anyway.
Your leg wouldn't feel this,
>> no, please.
Anyway.
>> if I whip him with this
>> no, please.
thing, he's going to die.
>> if I whip him with this
And haven't we all been saying
Thing, he's going to die.
this whole time that we have to
And haven't we all been saying
work together?
This whole time that we have to
Well, unfortunately, you're
Work together?
gonna have to take one for the
Well, unfortunately, you're
team, linda.
Gonna have to take one for the
I'm sorry.
Team, linda.
[sighs]
I'm sorry.
you're gonna be o.K., I promise.
[sighs]
Just close your eyes.
You're gonna be o.K., I promise.
>> in and then out, o.K.?
Just close your eyes.
Don't push it too far.
>> in and then out, o.K.?
>> [exhales deeply]
Don't push it too far.
fuck.
>> [exhales deeply]
[breathes deeply]
>> linda: Ugh.
>> oh, shit.
>> lucas: Holy crap.
>> I think I hit that artery.
>> lucas: Do you have a belt?
>> iris: Tie it, tie it, hurry.
>> what happened?
>> peter: You're o.K.,
you're o.K.
Can we not take her to a
You're o.K.
hospital or something here?
Can we not take her to a
This isn't good.
Hospital or something here?
>> people, we're playing a game.
This isn't good.
Linda, it's your turn.
>> people, we're playing a game.
Now, would you rather whip
Linda, it's your turn.
travis or give your neighbor amy
Now, would you rather whip
down there the old in and out?
Travis or give your neighbor amy
>> what?
Down there the old in and out?
>> can we not give her a sec?
>> what?
>> peter, what's going on, man?
>> can we not give her a sec?
>> is the tourniquet supposed to
>> peter, what's going on, man?
go above or below the wound?
>> is the tourniquet supposed to
>> above, above! >> o.K., o.K.
Go above or below the wound?
>> my god, tighten it!
>> above, above! >> o.K., o.K.
>> I got it, I got it.
>> my god, tighten it!
>> lucas: Tighter!
>> I got it, I got it.
>> linda has not made a decision
>> lucas: Tighter!
yet.
>> linda has not made a decision
Linda!
Yet.
Travis or--
Linda!
>> ugh, bitch!
Travis or--
Fucking scratched me.
>> ugh, bitch!
>> linda.
Fucking scratched me.
Stupendous.
>> linda.
Well, then, come to think of it,
Stupendous.
[chuckles] she didn't have
Well, then, come to think of it,
another choice.
[chuckles] she didn't have
She couldn't whip travis
Another choice.
even if she wanted to.
She couldn't whip travis
She can't walk. [laughs]
Even if she wanted to.
so let's... Change things up
She can't walk. [laughs]
a little bit here.
So let's... Change things up
Amy.
A little bit here.
Would you rather whip travis or
Amy.
stab any player of your
Would you rather whip travis or
choosing.
>> in case any of y'all haven't
figured this out yet...
This game isn't about helpin'
Figured this out yet...
each other.
This game isn't about helpin'
It's about eliminating the rest
Each other.
of you.
It's about eliminating the rest
>> bevans.
Of you.
Huh.
>> bevans.
>> this one's probably gonna
Huh.
bleed to death.
>> this one's probably gonna
>> peter: You're o.K.
Bleed to death.
>> amy: Duck.
>> peter: You're o.K.
Duck.
>> amy: Duck.
Goose.
Duck.
>> hey, hold on a second.
Goose.
O.K., o.K.
>> hey, hold on a second.
>> shepard: She's made her
O.K., o.K.
decision.
>> shepard: She's made her
>> don't do this.
Decision.
Please don't do this.
>> don't do this.
>> can I stab her anywhere?
Please don't do this.
>> that's a new one.
>> can I stab her anywhere?
>> [crying]
>> that's a new one.
>> just from the shoulders down.
>> [crying]
>> [screams]
>> just from the shoulders down.
>> ooh! >> lucas: No!
>> [screams]
[iris moans]
>> ooh! >> lucas: No!
>> [laughs]
[iris moans]
>> let me see, let me see.
>> [laughs]
>> [moans]
>> let me see, let me see.
>> lucas: Can you breathe?
>> [moans]
I think she missed the lung.
>> lucas: Can you breathe?
Put some pressure on it.
I think she missed the lung.
Can you breathe?
Put some pressure on it.
>> [gasps]
Can you breathe?
>> lucas: Tighter.
>> [gasps]
Tight.
>> lucas: Tighter.
Travis?
Tight.
>> [laughs]
Travis?
>> shepard: Bevans.
>> [laughs]
[crickets chirping, ♪...]
[dr. Barden breathes heavily]
[metallic clang]
>> still breathing, sir.
Remarkable.
>> guys, she hasn't moved for
a while.
>> stabbed an old woman, peter.
A while.
>> peter: Linda.
>> stabbed an old woman, peter.
See, she's unconscious.
>> peter: Linda.
>> she's not unconscious.
See, she's unconscious.
She's dead.
>> you guys saw what happened,
right? I tried to help her.
>> oh, yes, peter, we all saw
Right? I tried to help her.
what happened.
>> oh, yes, peter, we all saw
You made a decision and there's
What happened.
a consequence.
You made a decision and there's
And now... Cal is the one to
A consequence.
make a choice.
Finish off travis here or...
Stab lucas.
>> stab lucas like the others?
Like linda, that's what you're
saying?
>> shepard: 30 seconds.
Saying?
[timer ticking...]
>> shepard: 30 seconds.
>> o.K., come on.
[timer ticking...]
Let's get it over with.
>> o.K., come on.
>> maybe amy is right.
Let's get it over with.
Eliminate a player.
>> maybe amy is right.
That's what this is about.
Eliminate a player.
>> no, cal, amy's crazy.
That's what this is about.
>> well, maybe he wants to
>> no, cal, amy's crazy.
end it, too.
>> well, maybe he wants to
>> that's not your choice to
End it, too.
make, man.
>> that's not your choice to
>> but it is.
Make, man.
[cries]
>> but it is.
they're making it my choice.
[cries]
>> cal, come on, I'm giving you
They're making it my choice.
an opening here!
>> cal, come on, I'm giving you
>> shepard: Time.
An opening here!
>> o.K., I choose...
>> shepard: Time.
>> god, no, cal, don't do this.
>> o.K., I choose...
Don't do that.
>> god, no, cal, don't do this.
>> you can't do this.
Don't do that.
>> no.
>> you can't do this.
Don't look.
>> no.
>> oh, jesus.
Don't look.
[cries]
>> shepard: Nicely done.
[cal breathes heavily]
And now...
On to the next round.
>> it had to be done, right?
Right?
>> you didn't have to do that.
>> so, how long would you say?
>> he may live for several more
hours, days even, I don't know.
But he's in no shape to continue
Hours, days even, I don't know.
play, that much is certain.
But he's in no shape to continue
>> all right, let's move him
Play, that much is certain.
out.
>> all right, let's move him
[clears throat]
Out.
ladies and gentlemen, I regret
[clears throat]
to inform you that travis is
Ladies and gentlemen, I regret
unable to continue playing.
To inform you that travis is
>> julian: [sarcastic] aww.
Unable to continue playing.
>> shepard: [softly] do not
>> julian: [sarcastic] aww.
do that.
>> shepard: [softly] do not
Keep your sarcasm to yourself.
Do that.
[plastic rustling]
Keep your sarcasm to yourself.
[travis gasps]
[plastic rustling]
[footsteps receding]
[travis gasps]
>> I'm thinking...
[footsteps receding]
We don't have much time here
>> I'm thinking...
with these delays.
We don't have much time here
[indistinct whispering...]
With these delays.
>> [whispers] can you run?
Now!
[scuffling, grunting...]
[gasping] iris, run.
>> [screams]
[grunts]
[gunshot]
>> get back!
All right, everyone back to
the table.
Get up.
The table.
Everyone, get up.
Get up.
Julian, get up on your--!
Everyone, get up.
Back to your seats.
Julian, get up on your--!
Well, that was some unexpected
Back to your seats.
excitement, wasn't it?
Well, that was some unexpected
Everyone, sit down.
Excitement, wasn't it?
>> where's iris?
Everyone, sit down.
>> what? >> iris!
>> where's iris?
>> bevans!
>> what? >> iris!
The door was unlocked?
>> bevans!
>> stay here!
The door was unlocked?
Keep an eye on them!
>> stay here!
>> bring her back to the game!
Keep an eye on them!
>> I should help him.
>> bring her back to the game!
>> fine, go, go.
>> I should help him.
Remember what we spoke about.
>> fine, go, go.
I believe I said sit down.
Remember what we spoke about.
>> [coughs]
I believe I said sit down.
[♪...]
>> [whistling]
>> [screams]
[grunting]
[♪...]
[iris screams in distance]
[iris screaming...]
[iris grunts]
>> [laughs] little pig tried to
run away, didn't she?
What, you gonna go tell on us?
Run away, didn't she?
Well, no one is gonna believe
What, you gonna go tell on us?
you, o.K.?
Well, no one is gonna believe
No one.
You, o.K.?
[kissing, iris grunts]
No one.
[julian screams, grunts]
[kissing, iris grunts]
[screams]
[julian screams, grunts]
>> iris.
[screams]
Get back.
>> iris.
I'm getting you out of here.
Get back.
I made a mistake.
I'm getting you out of here.
I should've just told--
I made a mistake.
[gunshot]
I should've just told--
>> [screams]
>> shoot her, bevans.
She attacked me.
[breathes raggedly]
>> your father will be
disappointed.
>> after all she did, she
Disappointed.
doesn't get punished?
>> after all she did, she
>> I need to take her back to
Doesn't get punished?
the game.
>> I need to take her back to
Take him upstairs and leave him
The game.
there.
Take him upstairs and leave him
I'll inform his father.
There.
I'm sorry, iris.
I'll inform his father.
But we're not through playing.
>> shepard: Ahh.
Welcome back, iris.
Bevans, what took so long?
Where's julian?
>> bevans: [whispers] your son
tried to rape iris.
She-- >> shepard: What?
Tried to rape iris.
>> stabbed him in the thigh.
She-- >> shepard: What?
He's been taken upstairs, sir.
>> stabbed him in the thigh.
>> let me handle that.
He's been taken upstairs, sir.
Excuse me for a moment,
>> let me handle that.
everyone.
Excuse me for a moment,
Lock that behind me.
Everyone.
>> where's cal?
Lock that behind me.
>> they shot him.
You gonna be o.K., iris?
Iris, talk to me.
How far did you get?
Is there a way out?
>> do you get it now?
They're not gonna let us
just leave.
>> she's right.
Just leave.
She's absolutely right.
>> she's right.
[knocking on door]
She's absolutely right.
[door slides open]
>> shepard: [softly] iris.
I am dreadfully sorry for what
took place in the basement.
Since the loss of his mother,
Took place in the basement.
my son lacks...
Since the loss of his mother,
Restraint.
My son lacks...
Well, please.
Restraint.
My apologies.
Well, please.
All right.
My apologies.
Let's continue.
All right.
>> that's it?
Let's continue.
Why is this bitch allowed to
>> that's it?
stay in the game?
Why is this bitch allowed to
You're lucky you didn't get us
Stay in the game?
all killed.
You're lucky you didn't get us
>> crazy girl has a point.
All killed.
>> this is my game.
>> crazy girl has a point.
I make the decisions here.
>> this is my game.
Keep your petulant mouth shut.
I make the decisions here.
She will play.
Keep your petulant mouth shut.
The game will continue.
She will play.
[bangs on table]
The game will continue.
final.
[bangs on table]
Now...
Final.
My son, julian, is unable to
Now...
continue.
My son, julian, is unable to
>> what a shame. [scoffs]
Continue.
>> excuse me?
>> what a shame. [scoffs]
Thank you.
>> excuse me?
So, on to the next round.
Thank you.
Now, when all of you were
So, on to the next round.
deciding whether or not to
Now, when all of you were
accept our invitation to play
Deciding whether or not to
the game, you were, in essence
Accept our invitation to play
making a choice between the
The game, you were, in essence
known and the unknown.
Making a choice between the
You could continue to deal with
Known and the unknown.
your problems, the known, or
You could continue to deal with
possibly solve your problems in
Your problems, the known, or
the unknown, our game.
Possibly solve your problems in
This round uses that same
The unknown, our game.
concept.
This round uses that same
[rustling]
>> what's this for?
You gonna let us clean up?
>> [chuckles] uh, no, peter.
I'm sorry.
The barrel of water is for the
next round.
Envelopes are being placed
Next round.
randomly in front of you.
Envelopes are being placed
They each contain a card with a
Randomly in front of you.
punishment on them.
They each contain a card with a
Some of them, quite harsh.
Punishment on them.
Others, relatively harmless.
Some of them, quite harsh.
You must decide between what
Others, relatively harmless.
lies inside the envelope
You must decide between what
or the barrel.
Lies inside the envelope
The known or the unknown.
Or the barrel.
>> what's with the barrel?
The known or the unknown.
>> two minutes.
>> what's with the barrel?
Two minutes held underwater.
>> two minutes.
That's the barrel.
Two minutes held underwater.
And you will have 30 seconds
That's the barrel.
in this round to make
And you will have 30 seconds
your decision.
In this round to make
Let's begin, shall we?
Your decision.
Peter.
Let's begin, shall we?
>> fuck.
Peter.
>> we will begin with you.
>> fuck.
So what will it be?
>> we will begin with you.
The barrel...
So what will it be?
Or what is in that envelope?
The barrel...
>> huh, well, I already know
Or what is in that envelope?
what I'm choosing.
>> huh, well, I already know
>> do you?
What I'm choosing.
Really.
>> do you?
Do tell.
Really.
>> this is gambling 101
Do tell.
right here.
>> this is gambling 101
You just gotta look for the
Right here.
patterns.
You just gotta look for the
It's all patterns,
Patterns.
it's psychology.
It's all patterns,
And drowning does sound
It's psychology.
pretty bad.
And drowning does sound
So, I'm guessing you think
Pretty bad.
I'm gonna choose the envelope to
So, I'm guessing you think
avoid "duggins" holding me
I'm gonna choose the envelope to
underwater for two minutes and
Avoid "duggins" holding me
drowning, is that it?
Underwater for two minutes and
>> bevans.
Drowning, is that it?
>> whatever.
>> bevans.
If you were facing a normal
>> whatever.
player, that's exactly what
If you were facing a normal
you'd do.
Player, that's exactly what
Put something really shitty in
You'd do.
that envelope, so all the other
Put something really shitty in
players think twice.
That envelope, so all the other
But I know you.
Players think twice.
You've looked into my past.
But I know you.
So you know all about my
You've looked into my past.
gambling experience.
So you know all about my
So you probably have anticipated
Gambling experience.
that I was gonna figure
So you probably have anticipated
this out.
That I was gonna figure
>> come on, come on, come on,
This out.
make a decision.
>> come on, come on, come on,
Your time is running out.
Make a decision.
>> the envelope.
Your time is running out.
Obviously.
>> the envelope.
[paper rustling]
Obviously.
>> and the envelope says?
>> [sighs]
what is this?
>> oh.
What is this?
You have to light off a
>> oh.
firecracker in your hand.
You have to light off a
That's it.
Firecracker in your hand.
>> [sighs] good.
That's it.
[chuckles]
>> [sighs] good.
see?
[chuckles]
Gambling 101.
See?
Why are you pointing a gun in
Gambling 101.
my face?
Why are you pointing a gun in
I'm agreeing to this.
What the hell is this?
>> you have to light it, peter.
It's what the envelope says.
>> but it's not a firecracker.
That's a quarter stick.
>> you know, you're right.
Maybe you ought to move away
from the table.
You're gonna make an awful mess.
From the table.
>> let it go before it goes off.
You're gonna make an awful mess.
Don't hold it too tight.
>> let it go before it goes off.
>> no, he must hold it tight.
Don't hold it too tight.
Bevans?
>> no, he must hold it tight.
Secure it to his hand, if you
Bevans?
would, please?
Secure it to his hand, if you
[tape ripping]
Would, please?
>> peter: Fuck.
[tape ripping]
You know, peter, maybe it's
a dud.
Did you think about that?
A dud.
Did you consider that?
Did you think about that?
And of course, we won't know
Did you consider that?
that until you light the fuse.
And of course, we won't know
Use the lighter!
That until you light the fuse.
And light the fuse!
Use the lighter!
Now!
And light the fuse!
>> if this is a dud, do I have
Now!
to go again?
>> if this is a dud, do I have
>> nah.
To go again?
>> [breathing heavily]
>> nah.
[fuse stops fizzing]
>> [breathing heavily]
[sighs]
[fuse stops fizzing]
[explosion]
[sighs]
>> oh, god.
[explosion]
>> lucas: Oh, god.
>> oh, god.
>> iris: Oh, my god.
>> lucas: Oh, god.
[iris cries, lucas whimpers]
>> iris: Oh, my god.
>> wow!
[iris cries, lucas whimpers]
That was loud.
>> wow!
We're lucky we didn't break
That was loud.
any windows.
We're lucky we didn't break
And see what we have here.
Any windows.
[peter screaming]
And see what we have here.
>> ooh.
[peter screaming]
>> I think he's having a
>> ooh.
heart attack, sir.
>> I think he's having a
>> really.
Heart attack, sir.
>> bevans: Peter?
>> really.
>> shepard: Peter?
>> bevans: Peter?
>> peter.
>> shepard: Peter?
Now he's dead.
>> peter.
>> [chuckles]
Now he's dead.
oh, well.
>> [chuckles]
[lucas and iris crying]
>> lucas.
It's your turn.
So, what is it?
The barrel or the card?
What would you rather do?
>> two minutes held underwater.
[breathes heavily]
I don't think I can do that.
I don't think I can.
>> shepard: We're running out of
time here.
>> no.
Time here.
I'll take my chances with card.
>> no.
>> shepard: O.K.
What do we have?
Oh.
>> what is it?
>> oh, well, that's--
>> well, what is it?
>> this, this is, um...
[chuckles] is very interesting.
You... Must...
Slit open your eye.
You can use this mirror,
if it helps.
>> no.
If it helps.
>> shepard: That's it.
>> no.
>> that's it?
>> shepard: That's it.
No, that's not it.
>> that's it?
No, I can't do this.
No, that's not it.
>> lucas.
No, I can't do this.
>> I can't.
>> lucas.
>> you made your decision.
>> I can't.
This is how the game is played.
>> you made your decision.
Pick up the razor blade.
This is how the game is played.
>> [softly] please.
Pick up the razor blade.
>> pick it up. >> please don't.
>> [softly] please.
You sick fuck!
>> pick it up. >> please don't.
>> I will give you...
You sick fuck!
30 seconds to do this.
>> I will give you...
>> I can't do that!
30 seconds to do this.
>> 30 seconds.
>> I can't do that!
>> I can't do it!
>> 30 seconds.
>> 30 seconds to do it...
>> I can't do it!
>> I can't do it.
>> 30 seconds to do it...
>> or bevans...
>> I can't do it.
>> I can't do it!
>> or bevans...
>> ...Will dispatch you.
>> I can't do it!
Do you understand?
>> ...Will dispatch you.
And, by the way, you can pick
Do you understand?
whichever eye you want.
And, by the way, you can pick
It's completely up to you.
Whichever eye you want.
Go.
It's completely up to you.
>> ha!
Go.
[timer ticking...]
>> shepard: 20 seconds.
>> fuck!
[cries] I can't do it.
>> 10 seconds.
Listen, lucas.
He will eliminate you,
I am telling you.
Five, four, three, two, one.
[lucas screams]
[iris screams]
[lucas screaming, crying]
>> there.
[lucas screams]
all done.
>> [screams]
All done.
[crying]
>> [screams]
>> iris.
[crying]
Are you interested in seeing
>> iris.
what's in your envelope?
Are you interested in seeing
>> no.
What's in your envelope?
>> oh... Of course. [chuckles]
>> no.
you're not the gambling type,
>> oh... Of course. [chuckles]
are you?
You're not the gambling type,
Oh, no, no, no.
Are you?
No, you prefer the sure thing.
Thank you.
Lovely.
So.
Two minutes, yes?
>> [breathes heavily]
>> shepard. Go.
[timer ticking...]
[♪...]
>> raleigh: I keep having this
dream that I'm on a boat.
Suddenly, the boat tips over and
Dream that I'm on a boat.
throws me into the water.
Suddenly, the boat tips over and
You and all these people are
Throws me into the water.
pinned under it...
You and all these people are
And you're drowning.
Pinned under it...
>> lucas: Come on, come on.
And you're drowning.
>> and I keep trying to pull
>> lucas: Come on, come on.
myself up, but the more and more
>> and I keep trying to pull
I do...
Myself up, but the more and more
The more the boat comes down
I do...
with me.
The more the boat comes down
And you are trying to grab my
With me.
hand, trying to help me, but
And you are trying to grab my
we're sinking faster and faster
Hand, trying to help me, but
and faster until...
We're sinking faster and faster
I just finally...
And faster until...
[exhales]
I just finally...
[crashing]
[exhales]
>> [gasping]
[crashing]
>> yes!
>> [gasping]
>> whoo, two minutes!
>> yes!
[laughs]
>> whoo, two minutes!
iris!
[laughs]
Very impressive.
Iris!
You know... [chuckles]
Very impressive.
this is designed to actually
You know... [chuckles]
drown people.
This is designed to actually
[iris coughs, shepard chuckles]
Drown people.
>> what was in her card?
[iris coughs, shepard chuckles]
>> I have no idea.
>> what was in her card?
Find out.
>> I have no idea.
Set of lungs. [laughs]
Find out.
>> [coughs]
Set of lungs. [laughs]
>> oh.
>> [coughs]
Oh... [chuckles]
>> oh.
that was a close call, iris.
Oh... [chuckles]
All your teeth extracted.
That was a close call, iris.
Sorry, bevans, maybe next year.
All your teeth extracted.
Is amy ready?
Sorry, bevans, maybe next year.
So, how long can you hold your
Is amy ready?
breath, amy?
So, how long can you hold your
How long did it take your
Breath, amy?
husband to hold your little girl
How long did it take your
while he drowned her?
Husband to hold your little girl
[amy cries]
>> what is this?
>> it's another barrel.
With a four.
Well, that four stands for, uh,
four minutes.
>> that isn't possible.
Four minutes.
>> no, technically, it is
>> that isn't possible.
possible.
>> no, technically, it is
Not even close to the world
Possible.
record, by the way.
Not even close to the world
[amy cries]
Record, by the way.
>> well, I guess...
[amy cries]
Beggars can't be choosers.
>> well, I guess...
>> I guess so.
Beggars can't be choosers.
[iris cries]
>> four minutes.
Ready, bevans?
Go.
[amy grunts]
>> iris: She wasn't ready!
[water bubbling]
>> shepard: Shh, shh, shh.
[amy kicking and thumping...]
[water bubbling]
[plastic rustling]
[shoes squeaking on floor...]
[silence]
>> shepard: At the beginning of
the night, I would have pegged
her as the odds-on favorite
The night, I would have pegged
to win.
Her as the odds-on favorite
>> you never know, sir.
>> and then there were two.
Iris, I would like for you to
sit across from lucas, if you
would, please.
Sit across from lucas, if you
Thank you.
Hmm.
We're in the final stretch now.
Now... Before we begin the
final round, I'd like to say a
few words, if I may.
Final round, I'd like to say a
I know that this evening has
Few words, if I may.
been difficult.
I know that this evening has
For all of us, really.
Been difficult.
But it has also been one for
For all of us, really.
the books.
But it has also been one for
And I speak, not only for
The books.
myself, but for bevans and his
And I speak, not only for
staff and the entire lambrick
Myself, but for bevans and his
family when I say, "well played,
Staff and the entire lambrick
both of you."
Family when I say, "well played,
personally, I'd be happy if
Both of you."
either one of you won.
Personally, I'd be happy if
Truly.
Either one of you won.
[sighs]
Truly.
to the final round then.
[sighs]
Now, in all likelihood, the game
To the final round then.
will end with the very first
Now, in all likelihood, the game
question in this round.
Will end with the very first
We have found that the player
Question in this round.
who goes first in the final
We have found that the player
round has a decided, uh,
Who goes first in the final
advantage.
Round has a decided, uh,
Therefore, we will flip a coin.
Advantage.
Bevans.
Therefore, we will flip a coin.
Heads, iris.
Bevans.
Tails, lucas.
Heads, iris.
Bevans, if you would, please.
Heads it is.
Iris...
You're up.
[inhales deeply]
the final question.
Would you rather...
The final question.
"a"-- end the game, right now,
Would you rather...
you and lucas free to leave.
"a"-- end the game, right now,
Empty-handed.
You and lucas free to leave.
But alive.
Empty-handed.
>> [chuckles]
But alive.
or "b"--
>> [chuckles]
with this dueling pistol
Or "b"--
with a single round in its
With this dueling pistol
chamber...
With a single round in its
>> [sniffles]
Chamber...
>> eliminate lucas.
>> [sniffles]
Claim victory and salvation
>> eliminate lucas.
for your brother.
Which?
[timer ticking...]
>> iris.
Iris.
[chuckles] it's over.
We're done.
We can... [laughs]
we can go home.
[timer ticking...]
Iris.
I never told you why
I came here tonight.
I think you should hear it,
o.K.?
I think we have some things in
O.K.?
common.
I think we have some things in
You're here for someone else,
Common.
right?
You're here for someone else,
Your brother.
Right?
I'll bet you'd do anything
Your brother.
for him.
I'll bet you'd do anything
I know exactly how you feel.
For him.
I have three sisters--
I know exactly how you feel.
[gunshot, ♪...]
I have three sisters--
>> [laughing]
[gunshot, ♪...]
[clapping slowly]
>> [laughing]
oh!
[clapping slowly]
[♪...]
Oh!
we have a winner.
[♪...]
[iris cries]
We have a winner.
brava! [laughs]
[iris cries]
>> bevans: Bravo!
Brava! [laughs]
>> [cries]
>> bevans: Bravo!
[♪...]
>> [cries]
>> bravo!
>> this is yours.
There should be enough in there
to cover any debts that your
parents left behind you,
To cover any debts that your
plus enough for you to go
Parents left behind you,
back to school.
Plus enough for you to go
We had previously located a
Back to school.
suitable donor in romania.
We had previously located a
Arrangements are already being
Suitable donor in romania.
made as we speak, and your
Arrangements are already being
brother will be undergoing the
Made as we speak, and your
procedure before the week
Brother will be undergoing the
is out.
Procedure before the week
You see?
Is out.
We keep our word.
I believe a "thank you" is in
order.
>> thank you, mr. Lambrick.
Order.
>> oh, please.
>> thank you, mr. Lambrick.
No, no, no, call me shep.
[♪...]
[birds chirping...]
[iris sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[birds chirping, ♪...]
>> raleigh.
Oh, my god.
Oh, my god, oh, my god...
What did you do?
[cries] what did you do?
Oh, my god.
[♪...]
what did you do?
[music ends]