RAGNAR: I've had no message
from my brother,
but I still believe in my heart
that he will not betray me,
for he has no reason.
Who needs a reason
for betrayal?
One must always think
the worst, Ragnar,
even of your own kin.
That way, you avoid too much
disappointment in life.
(Bird cries)
(Harsh wind blows)
(Wind whistles)
(Expresses water forcefully from nose)
(Horn bellows in the distance)
(Horse snorts nervously)
There is the
treacherous one.
I was right, Ragnar.
(Inhales forcefully)
I was right.
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com
Resync for WEB-DL by Norther
♪ More, give me more ♪
♪ Give me more ♪
♪ If I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ After the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see what
tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I... ♪
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing ♪
(Horse gallops, panting hard)
(Horn bellows)
Rider approaching!
(Horse nickers and snorts)
What is it you want?
ARNE: I'm here on behalf
of Ragnar Lothbrok.
I want to speak
to his brother.
JARL BORG:
Then speak.
Rollo,
you and I fought
together many times.
I don't suppose
you've forgotten.
I think of you
as a brother...
but over there is
your real brother,
your own flesh and blood.
Are you sure you want to
raise your axe against him?
Did Ragnar send you?
(Exhales)
What answer shall
I give him?
(Exhales slowly)
Tell him I shall
answer him with blood.
(Wind howls)
(Inhales and exhales forcefully)
Shield-wall!
WARRIORS:
(Roar fiercely)
JARL BORG:
Shield-wall!
BORG'S WARRIORS:
(Roar fiercely)
Spears!
(Forceful breaths)
Charge!
JARL BORG:
(Yells battle command)
BORG'S WARRIORS:
(Scream fiercely)
(Ground rumbles)
(Spears clack, shields smash)
(Bodies crash, axes clank)
(Grunts of effort)
(Fierce grunt)
Hold the wall!
Aggghhhh!
(Axes whip through air)
Ungh!
FLOKI:
Ungh! Ungh!
(Shields clank and thud forcefully)
Aggghhhhh!
(Fighting grunts, punching thuds)
(Blades and shields clash)
(Forceful grunt)
ROLLO:
Your death is on its way!
Agghhhh! Agghhhh!
Agggghhhhhhhhhhhh!
(Blade rings on impact)
Ungh! Unnngh!
(Fighting grunts, weapons smash)
Ungh! Aggghhhhh!
Ungh! Ungh!
(Hard smash)
(Struggling grunts)
(Straining grunts)
Ungh!
(Hard blows)
(Distorted breathing)
- FLOKI: Ungh!
- JARL BORG: (Grunts)
(Hard whack)
Ungh!
- ROLLO: Yah!
- FLOKI: (Groans)
(Fighting grunts)
(Gasping for air)
Ungh!
(Charging cry)
(Sickening crunch)
Aggghhhhhh!
Ungh!
(Hard blow)
Agh!
(Weapon slices)
(Heavy distorted breath)
TORSTEIN:
Floki!
Ungh!
(Weapons clank and slice)
(Warriors grunt and yell)
Aaggghhhhhhh!
(Hard blows, fighting grunts)
Ungh!
- ROLLO: Ungh!
- ARNE: Agh!
(Pained grunt)
(Charging cry)
(Grunting with effort)
Aggghhhhhh!
(Charging cry)
- ARNE: (Screams in pain)
- ROLLO: (Growls, straining)
(Grunts in pain, gasps for breath)
Aggghhhh!
(Grunting and choking in pain)
(Screaming and yelling fades out)
(Ear-ringing silence)
(Men yell and scream)
(Weapons clank and slice)
(Readying breaths)
Is this what you
really want, brother?
(Threatening grunt)
(Breathing hard)
(Threatening grunts)
(Men scream)
(Weapons clash all around)
(Spear clatters)
I cannot fight you.
(Weapons clash)
(Warriors grunt and scream)
(Sighs deeply)
(Breathing hard)
(Footsteps crunch, weapons clank)
FLOKI:
(Groans weakly)
(Wind blows)
KING HORIK:
Without being defeated,
we have grown weary of the slaughter
of our young men. So, Jarl Borg,
I offer you...
one third of the profits
from the disputed lands.
Unless you continue to
dispute my claim to it.
I would rather go back fighting,
than receive such scant justice.
(Weary, frustrated sigh)
So, you'll not accept
my fair offer?
No.
Why do we continue
looking inwards?
(Shouts)
Why?!
Why do we fight each other about
this piece or that piece of land?
Why are we not looking
outwards to the West?
If we raided together,
we would not need
to fight amongst
ourselves.
We would not need to kill
anymore of our young folk.
But instead,
offer them land,
land that they can farm.
WARRIOR: (Quietly)
He speaks the truth.
My mind tends the
same way as Ragnar's.
It is my intention to join
with him and sail West.
What do you say, Jarl Borg?
Yes,
I will raid with you,
and so I accept
your offer.
(Warriors talk quietly)
Not that you'd
care, brother,
but your niece,
Gyda, is dead.
Time to go home.
(Spits in disgust, groans)
(Water churns)
(Shouts of surprise in the distance)
(Cries of excitement)
(Chain clanks)
(Torstein grunts with effort)
(Women weep openly)
Floki! Floki!
Don't die.
- Please don't die.
- WOMAN: What's happened to them?!
TOWNSPEOPLE:
(Shout angrily)
One Eye died.
Arne?!
Rollo killed him.
And Floki may not survive
for he is so badly wounded.
LAGERTHA:
This was not your quarrel.
You should not have
become involved.
Look what has happened!
No man can walk through life without
things happening to him, Lagertha.
You chose.
Yes. I chose, and
Rollo chose.
And Rollo's choice led to all this!
BJORN:
Don't argue you two.
I am weary
and I'm blood-sickened,
and that is the truth.
(Bites food)
(Quietly)
Who is Aslaug?
(Grunts angrily)
(Plate strikes floor)
Stop.
Who is Aslaug?
She's a Gotaland princess.
We met her over there.
You just met her?
SIGGY: (Warningly)
Lagertha.
What has the boy told you?
What did you
tell her, boy?
LAGERTHA: It doesn't
matter what Bjorn says.
What do you say?
I say...
(Chairs crash)
we should not wash our dirty
clothes in front of others.
(Water splashes and drips)
(Doors crash open)
Ungh!
(Object smashes)
Did you have sex with her?
Yes, I had sex with her.
(Object clatters)
How many times?!
Once.
Ungh!
(Struggling grunts)
(Panting)
I don't love her.
(Sharp gasp)
How can I make
you let this go?
- Never see her again.
- Done.
Never again.
(Passionate gasp)
BJORN: Why are there such
problems between you?
RAGNAR:
You know why.
But I don't want there
to be problems.
Can't you just say sorry
for what you've done?
(Laughs)
It's not so easy
with your mother.
And what will
happen to Rollo?
RAGNAR: I cannot judge
my own brother.
We will have an assembly and
the Law-Giver will judge.
We will take Rollo
up to the Law Rock
and that is where his
fate will be decided.
What's that you have?
A gold coin.
From England.
You see?
It even has King
Aelle's face upon it.
So it's worth a fortune?
(Townspeople chatter, seagulls cry)
(Approaching footsteps)
TORSTEIN:
What do you want?
To talk to him.
(Whispers)
Rollo...
Rollo, it's me.
Don't bother.
You cannot warm
up a dead man.
(Angry shouting and jeering)
MAN:
He is without honor!
- MAN 2: Kill him!
- WOMEN: I spit on you!
MAN AND WOMAN:
Traitor! Traitor!
WOMAN 2: Now he'll pay
for what he's done!
- WOMAN 3: Kill him!
- MAN 2: Traitor! Traitor!
WOMAN 4:
Kill him!
WOMAN 5:
Shame on you!
(Bangs staff)
LAW-GIVER: People,
as your Law-Giver,
I have been asked to determine
the fate of this man.
This man chose to fight
with our enemies.
Chose to fight
against his brother.
MAN:
Traitor!
LAW-GIVER:
He killed many of our sons,
brothers,
fathers.
What hope is
there for him?
TOWNSPEOPLE:
(Angry jeers)
TORSTEIN:
He has no defense!
MAN:
LAW-GIVER:
This man deserves to die.
TOWNSPEOPLE:
Yeah!
We all know that.
But...
I have decided
to spare him.
(Shouts of disagreement)
LAW-GIVER: I have taken
the advice of the gods.
If they had
wanted him dead,
he would have
died in battle.
But they spared him.
He came forward
and threw himself upon the
mercy of his brother.
He behaved in an interesting
and unexpected way,
and therefore,
I conclude...
that the gods have made
their own judgment,
which I cannot overturn.
LAW-GIVER: I therefore order
this man be set free.
CROWD:
(Shouts angrily)
MAN:
Kill the traitor!
TORSTEIN: We should kill him
anyway. You are the Earl!
No. We must obey the law.
Who is the Law-Giver?
Just an ordinary man.
Not when he stands
on the Sacred Stone.
(Ships creak, dog barks, seagulls cry)
(Goats bleat, geese honk)
(Sighs heavily)
I wanted to step out
of your shadow.
You understand, don't you?
But when I stepped out
of it, there was...
there was no sunlight,
no sunlight at all.
(Ships creaks, seagulls cry)
(Door creaks open)
What are you doing?
Leaving.
Everyone hates me here...
with good reason.
I have betrayed them.
There is no point
in my staying.
But you are going to leave and
not even say goodbye to me?
I thought you would
prefer it that way.
Do you really know
me so little?
I have nothing...
to offer you.
It would have been better for
you, for me, for everyone
if I had been executed.
So you take no
account of the gods?
What would you say the
gods have offered you?
A lifetime of humiliation.
SIGGY:
No! That is not it!
The gods have offered you
a chance to be reborn,
to be redeemed,
to gain Valhalla.
That is what they
have offered you.
But you, you want to run away. You
want to hide in a hole somewhere.
Where else can I go?
Why do you have
to go anywhere?
(Birds chirp and cry, fire crackles)
RAGNAR:
Gyda,
I have come to say
goodbye to you properly.
I have been thinking about you,
about when you were small.
You were so lively, you could
run as swiftly as the wind.
You were like quick-silver.
But then, before
I knew it,
you stopped running here
and there and everywhere
and you became still.
At 12-years-old,
you had the stillness and
the calm of a fine woman.
What children you
would have produced!
What joy...
that would have
brought to all of us.
Dear child,
Gyda,
you are not gone because you
are always in my heart.
They say that a man must
love his sons more,
but a man can be
jealous of his sons,
and his daughter can always
be the light in his life.
I know very well that
you are with the gods,
but I will wait
here awhile,
and if you want to come and
talk to me, then come and talk,
and I will gently stroke your long
and beautiful hair once again
with my peasant hands.
(Waves lap gently)
(Waves lap against the ship)
(Ship creaks)
(Low hum of chatter, wind howls)
(Running footsteps)
BJORN: Father!
Father!
- RAGNAR: What?
- BJORN: There's someone coming.
(Buzz of excited chatter)
CAPTAIN:
Keep steady! Take the oars!
Pull in the ropes!
(Buzz of excited chatter)
RAGNAR: You must believe
me, I had no idea.
I did not ask her to come.
(Sheep bleats)
(Low hum of chatter)
(Excited whispers)
(Boisterous chatter)
(Music fill the hall)
(Goat bleats)
Bjorn told me that your mother
was the shield-maiden, Brunhilde,
of whom we've all heard?
It's true. Although she
died when I was very young.
And your father?
My father was Sigurd.
Sigurd...?
Just Sigurd?
ASLAUG:
No, I mean the Sigurd
who, according to the sagas,
killed the dragon Fafnir.
Then your father
is also a hero.
People talk about him, it's true, and
I'm proud that he was my father.
But I never knew him.
What about your parents?
LAGERTHA:
Hmm.
They were just farmers.
Surely nobody is
just a farmer.
Believe me, princess,
that is exactly what some people
are, and are happy to be.
Forgive me.
Do you remember me, Bjorn?
Do you remember we stood
in front of the Tree of Life?
It wasn't Yggdrasil.
It was just a tree.
ASLAUG: You're right.
We both know that.
It creates a bond between us.
BJORN:
I don't think so.
We don't have any bond.
I don't want any
bond with you.
(Uneasy silence)
BJORN: Why don't you just tell
her that she has to leave soon?
She can't stay here.
She is carrying my child.
She brings unhappiness
and difficulty.
Can't you see that?
Are you blind?
I know it is hard
for you to accept,
but unhappiness is more
common than happiness.
Who told you you
should be happy?
You've come to an age
where you must be grow up
and be responsible
about such things.
When I was your age,
I had many friends.
All are dead.
The happiness is neither
here nor there.
SIGGY: How much do you
know about this woman?
Only what Bjorn told me,
which was not much.
He did not wish to be
disloyal to his father.
(Sighs heavily)
I did not know she was
carrying his child, though.
And you believe it?
LAGERTHA:
Ragnar believes it.
What of all her stories
of Brunhilde and Sigurd?
I suppose so. She is
clearly different from us.
(Women chatter nearby)
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
I must do what is
right for my son.
(Water splashes)
(Geese honk, people chatter)
Oh, Floki!
I'm not dead yet, Bjorn.
No thanks to you, Ragnar.
RAGNAR: Oh.
Say what you'd
like about me,
I'm just glad that the gods
were stupid enough to save you.
FLOKI:
The gods...
and Helga.
You must regain your strength.
There's much to do. A whole
fleet of boats to be built.
You and I have
seen nothing yet.
Our journeys have just begun.
FLOKI:
It's true!
I thought I was dead
and while I was dead, I was
dreaming of other places,
the places that you and I
shall sail to, Ragnar.
(Laboured breath)
(Exhales in pain)
Rest.
Come on, boy.
(Wind blows fiercely)
(Loud chatter fills the hall)
(Fire crackles)
(Doors bang open)
- BJORN: Floki!
- MAN: Hey, Floki!
- FLOKI: Hello, Bjorn.
- MAN: Floki!
(Doors latches)
(Loud chatter resumes)
(Everybody quiets down)
ASLAUG: I hope you will accept what
I have chosen and prepared for you?
(Hushed whispers and laughter)
WOMAN:
Generous!
I did not expect you to
go to so much trouble.
It is no trouble, if
it is pleasing to you.
(People laugh and chatter)
To tell you the truth,
I did not imagine
you could cook!
I can't. My women cooked,
I just bought the
ingredients.
Looking at both
of you here,
in my home...
I see no reason why you two
should not get on together.
You two are very different,
yet both strong.
I have heard that similar arrangements
exist all over this country.
What arrangements?
That an Earl can live
with more than one woman.
In fact, it is not unusual.
It works to the
benefit of everyone,
especially the children.
Of both marriages, of course.
It's true. I know of
many such instances.
Yes.
Is that what
you're suggesting?
If I were,
what would you say?
I'm sorry, but this woman
is carrying my child.
I must take care of her.
You must accept.
When we lost our
unborn son,
it broke my heart.
I had failed and I
will not fail again.
I cannot turn
this woman away.
I have to take
care of my child.
(Sighs heavily)
Don't forget the axe.
You are leaving then?
Of course I'm leaving.
TORSTEIN:
Is Bjorn going with you?
That's up to Bjorn.
Bjorn, you have a
big choice to make.
I admire your mother.
We all do.
But you have to stay
with your father.
If you don't, you will regret
it for the rest of your life.
Remember,
your father is
Ragnar Lothbrok.
(Townspeople chatter)
Bjorn.
You have to choose.
Say it now.
I... I choose my father.
(Emotional)
Very well.
(Tearful, shaky breaths)
(Light kiss)
(Shaky, emotional breaths)
(Quiet whimper)
(Cart rattles, tack jingles lightly)
(Weeping)
(Hooves thud)
What?
Mother's left.
(Horse whinnies)
Move!
(Hooves thud)
(Water splashes)
(Galloping hard)
(Cart rattles to a stop)
You're really going
to abandon me...
without even
saying a word?
You insult and
humiliate me.
I have no choice but to
leave you and divorce you.
I don't want you to go.
It's fate.
(Running footsteps)
(Panting)
I've changed my mind.
I'm coming with you.
(Panting)
(Emotional exhale)
(Shaky, emotional breath)
(Shakily)
Look after your mother.
(Emotional exhale)
LAGERTHA:
Come on.
(Sniffs)
Move on.
(Cart rattles away)
(Emotional exhale)
(Bleating)
(Horse neighs softly, goats bleat)
(Footsteps crunch in the dirt)
(Retreating footsteps)
Sync and corrected by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com
Resync for WEB-DL by Norther