♪ ♪
(crowd cheering)
ANNOUNCER: It looks like our first
female competitor
is about to hit the beach.
WOMAN:
Bring it on in, Jen!
(cheering)
CROWD (chanting):
Jen! Jen! Jen! Jen!
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
here she comes.
After nearly six grueling
hours of paddleboarding,
let's give a big aloha to
Honolulu's very own Jen Hassley!
(cheering and applause)
ANNOUNCER:
Way to go, Jen.
Folks, you've just
been witness to history.
With an official time
of five hours, 52 minutes
and 47 seconds,
at 15 years old,
Jen Hassley's just become
the youngest
female competitor to win
the Molokai 2 Oahu
Paddleboard World Championship.
How you feeling?
Great, Mom.
Okay. Are you sure?
Yes. Yes.
Nothing to worry about.
I'm fine. I'm good.
Give her a few minutes.
She'll be back to answer
all your questions.
I'm going to go rinse off.
I'll meet you
at the medal ceremony.
Okay. All right.
That's our little girl.
(cheering and whistling)
And finally, the moment
we've all been waiting for,
in first place,
with a time of five hours,
52 minutes and 47 seconds,
Jen Hassley!
(whooping, cheering)
Jen Hassley.
Jen Hassley
to the podium, please.
Why don't you go check
the changing tent?
Okay.
Jen?
Honey, where are you?
JEN: Mom!
Mom!
(car door opens and closes)
Jen!
Jen! No!
Mom!
(panting)
Mom...
Somebody help! Please!
They took my daughter!
(Hawaii Five-O
theme song plays)
♪ Hawaii Five-O 2x02 ♪
Ua Lawe Wale (Taken)
Original Air Date on September 26, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
(phone ringing)
RECEPTIONIST:
Yes, sir.
Okay.
I'll let him know.
I'm sorry,
Commander.
The governor will be
with you in a few minutes.
Mahalo.
(footsteps approaching)
Hello. Officer Lori Weston here
to see the governor.
Thank you,
Officer Weston.
The governor will be
with you shortly.
Okay. Thanks.
(chuckles)
I have, uh, clearly
been here for a while.
(chuckling)
You want the sports section?
I already read it.
Yeah. Sure.
Thank you.
I'm Steve McGarrett, by the way.
Hi. Lori Weston.
- Nice to meet you.
RECEPTIONIST:
Commander McGarrett.
Officer Weston.
The governor
will see you now.
Together?
Yes. Follow me.
(Steve clears throat)
Come in. Come in.
Have a seat.
All right.
Commander, have you met
Officer Weston from
Homeland Security?
Yes, we, uh... we just met.
LORI: Yes, sir.
Sir, does this have
anything to do
with Victor Hesse's murder?
No. I called you here
for a different reason.
Have a seat.
Commander, I thought you
and I had an understanding.
When I told you there was
going to be accountability,
I wasn't saying it just
to hear myself speak.
Um, I'm... I-I don't know
what you mean, sir.
You let a dangerous felon
go last week in hopes
that he would lead
you to Wo Fat.
You thought
you could slip
that one by me,
didn't you?
With all due respect, sir,
the objective
is to catch Wo Fat,
not the little fish under him.
With all due respect,
Commander, you broke my trust.
And there's
going to be
consequences for that,
as I said there would be.
- What kind of consequences?
- Officer Weston.
- Sir.
- I'm sure you thought,
coming here, you were
going to be appointed
my new public
safety liaison,
but actually, I have
a different position
in mind for you.
- Wait a minute.
- Sir, if this has something to do...
That's right.
Officer Weston,
welcome to Five-O.
Sir, we're not really
recruiting new people right now.
- No offense.
- None taken.
Commander, you're going to
find Officer Weston to be
an incredible asset
to you and your team.
She spent six years
with Homeland Security
as a profiler.
LORI: Sir, I actually
STEVE: If this is about
really do appreciate you thinking
of me replacing Officer Kalakaua...
for this position...
- Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
- I'm not looking to be a babysitter.
- Time-out! Time-out!
Babysitter?
Time-out.
This is not about
Officer Kalakaua,
and I'm not asking
you to babysit.
I'm asking you to
be a part of a team
(cell phone buzzing)
that is vital to this state's safety.
And frankly, I am not asking;
I'm telling.
I need to take this.
- Then you should take it.
- Excuse me.
McGarrett.
Yeah, go ahead.
Yeah. I'll be right there.
Okay, there's been a kidnapping,
so, uh, I have to go.
Then get on it.
- Sir, I really don't...
- What are you still doing here?
You've got a case.
Go.
Yes, sir.
I know neither of
us expected this,
but let's just try and
make the best of it.
You ever work
a kidnapping case before?
I started my career
with the FBI.
- That's not what I asked.
- I was in profiling.
- You're avoiding the question.
- Five cases.
And how many of those cases
ended successfully?
Three.
I'll drive.
I'll follow you.
(keyless lock chirps)
Wow. Look at you.
You clean up nice, babe.
You got all dressed up
for the new governor?
- Win you any points?
- Not exactly.
Danny Williams, this is
Officer Lori Weston...
- Hi. -Hi.
- Our new partner.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet...
- Our new what?
- Partner.
Governor Denning assigned me
to your Five-O task force.
- To do what?
Uh, assist you in any way I can.
STEVE: I'm sorry.
I'm pretty sure the word
you used earlier was "babysit."
You're going to babysit us.
DANNY: Oh, okay, I'm-I... I apol... I...
I apologize. He, uh...
he lost his manners
somewhere between the
womb and kindergarten.
You will fit right in.
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Come on, GQ.
Duke's over here.
LUKELA:
Vic's name is Jen Hassley,
15 years old.
Abductor drove off
in a red sedan.
Her mother got a
partial plate.
We got a MAILE Alert out?
Just hit the wire
a few minutes ago.
- Run that.
- Teenage girls
are usually kidnapped
for one of two reasons:
ransom or a sex crime.
- Where are the parents?
- Over there.
DANNY:
Any strange phone calls?
Anything at all
out of the ordinary
last couple weeks?
No.
LORI: In over half of all
kidnapping cases,
the abductor
is usually a relative
or an acquaintance
of the victim.
Is there anybody you can think of
that would have reason
to want to take Jen?
No.
All right. I'm going to send
some of our people
to your house--
they're going to set up
phone taps in preparation
for a ransom call.
Okay? Officer Weston
is going to
accompany you home.
She's going to supervise
the whole thing, all right?
Okay?
CHIN: Got something.
- Oh, my God.
- I found this outside the changing tent.
Does it belong to Jen?
Jen was born with
a heart condition.
She has to take this
medication twice a day.
If she doesn't
get this
within 24 hours,
she could...
She could die.
(sobbing)
That's not going to happen.
STEVE: Hey.
- Good. You're here.
What do you got?
HPD reports all
registered sex offenders
within five miles
of the abduction site
have been accounted for.
They're expanding
the search now.
Okay.
Uh, what about Jen's
personal life? Anything?
I scanned Jen's cell records
and social network profile.
Everything's clean--
no suspicious messages,
no strange calls,
nothing to indicate
a potential threat.
DANNY: All right, see,
this is strange.
All right,
she's got nothing personal
on her home page, right?
It's all generic
publicity stuff.
I mean, kids use
these sites to vent,
all right, share secrets,
talk trash to each other.
It's like Jen
doesn't want anyone
to know who she really is.
Okay, well,
maybe she had
a secret profile somewhere.
- Keep looking.
- Get Jen's laptop, okay?
Mine it and see if you can find
anything that she was trying
to keep away from her parents.
- Got it.
CHIN: Hey, just got off
the phone with HPD.
MAILE Alert lines
are ringing off the hook.
I'm going to have
to head back to the station
to coordinate a grid search.
- Keep us posted, all right?
Yeah.
Hey. So what do we know
about the new hire?
She's cute.
- She's very cute.
- She's attractive.
- She used to work for Homeland Security.
- That could come in handy.
Yeah, if she lasts.
What? Why wouldn't she last?
Well, let's see
what she looks like
when she gets done with
Sergeant Slaughter's boot camp.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Let's just try
and not get the new girl
blown up, kidnapped, shot
on her first day, that's all.
Can we do that, Steven?
I can't guarantee that.
(gun cocks)
Hands on your head.
Turn around slowly.
Do you hear me?
I'm not gonna ask again.
Shh.
Wow.
You seem to have a lot of people
who really, uh,
cared about you.
That's nice.
Who the hell are you?
You might want to sit down.
KAYE:
Danny was right.
Jen was hiding something.
She has a second
social network profile.
I managed to extract
all of the deleted e-mails
and private chats
and I found a bunch of
exchanges with a guy named
Brant Cunningham.
What do we know about him?
Not much.
But everything about it
screams predator.
The account is brand-new,
the only e-mails he sent were
to Jen, and that profile picture
is a stock shot
of a male model
I identified through
facial recognition.
All right, when was the last
time they exchanged e-mails?
Last week.
He asked for her address.
Said he wanted to
send her something.
Guys, I'm not seeing anything
from a Brant Cunningham here.
And the parents don't remember
Jen getting
anything from that name, either.
Okay, it's got to be there.
Well, it's not in her fan mail,
which means she's hiding it.
Wait, this is a girl who's
deleting her private e-mails
from this guy, right?
Yeah. Most likely
she didn't want
her parents to find it.
Huh. Which rules out the sock
drawer and under the mattress.
Check for loose
floorboards.
No.
The room's carpeted.
This is a good kid.
According to her mom,
she's perfect.
She does what she's told,
keeps her room clean.
I mean, she's about to go on
a 32-mile race
and still remembers to make
her bed in the morning.
Clearly, appearances
are important to her.
Along with her accomplishments.
I found something.
What do you got?
Guys, the Hassleys
aren't Jen's parents.
MRS. HASSLEY:
"This is your birth mother,
"and she would
like to meet you.
"If you want to know more,
meet me behind the changing tent
after your race
on Saturday."
Jen has always known
she was adopted.
We've been very open
with her about it.
MR. HASSLEY:
Jen's real mother
died in childbirth.
It was in the adoption records.
Jen knows that.
I just can't believe
she arranged
to meet this person
and didn't say
anything about it.
I don't know
why she'd lie to us.
LORI:
Yeah, well, my guess is
Jen's abductor
found out she was adopted,
fabricated information
about her birth mother
and used that into luring her
to meet up him.
Okay, so it had to be someone
who knew she was adopted.
Well, she talked about it
in her interview
for Aloha Life magazine.
I mean, thousands of people
could know.
I'm gonna go take this letter
to the crime lab,
see if I can get
a print off of it.
STEVE:
All right, hold on, hold on.
Let Kaye take the letter.
Lori, I need you to
stay with the
family, okay?
Okay.
And, Lori...
Yeah?
Nice work.
Thanks.
And nice work to you, too.
That's good.
What?
"I want you to stay
with the family."
I mean, you're keeping
this woman at arm's distance.
Is it because she's
the governor's hire or is it
something else? Just curious.
Hey, MAILE Alert paid off.
Found our abductor's car.
Kam Highway,
southern edge of Wheeler.
(siren wailing)
(tires screech)
Nobody.
It's empty.
Check the trunk.
I got blood.
And Jen's jacket.
STEVE:
What do you got, Max?
The amount of blood I found
on the jacket and in the trunk
is quite troubling.
Approximately
six to seven pints.
The odds of anyone surviving
after that much blood loss
is quite low.
Okay, but you're saying,
I mean, it's possible
she could still
be alive, right?
How old is the girl
you're looking for?
She's, uh, 15.
About 90 pounds.
About.
If this is her blood,
I find it highly doubtful
that she could
have survived.
Listen to me, Max.
I need you to
run this, okay?
Because I can't
talk to the parents
until I know what we
have, you understand?
I'm on it.
DANNY:
Suspect's VIN number:
17Q4378OI95
39572.
Got it.
Running it now.
(computer beeps)
Here we go.
Your car is registered
to a Matt Porter.
4810 Loho Street in Kailua.
Matthew Porter! Five-O!
Clear.
All clear here.
No Porter, no Jen.
But you guys should see this.
That's Jen right there.
Who are these
other women?
Victims.
Yeah. Or potential victims.
Take a look at these.
Sam Baker, Todd Kilgore,
Charles Tetchy.
He's got, like, 30 of these.
This guy's been at it awhile.
Yep. And he knows
how to disappear.
(phone beeps, recording):
Message two.
WOMAN (on voice mail):
Hi, Julie, it's Beth.
Yeah.
That's great.
Okay, thank you.
That was the TSA;
they have an alert out
on all the names that
Porter's been using.
- All right, we check plane tickets?
- Yes, we did.
There's nothing been purchased
under these names.
Okay, good. So Porter
might still be on the island.
Right. Unless he got off using
an alias we don't know about.
We're running out of time
to get Jen her medication.
- Come on!
What do we got?
Something, something.
I'm working as fast as I can.
You putting pressure on
an already stressful situation
is not gonna make me
work any faster.
I can't even verify
that Matt Porter
is his real name.
- Okay, whoa, whoa.
Look, I don't know
what his real name is, either,
but I do know that one of his
aliases, Todd Kilgore, is wanted
for questioning in a 2009
kidnapping case in Nebraska.
Okay, good, good, good.
So Jen isn't his first victim.
Or his last.
What do you got?
Julie Nells.
I managed to get into her voice
mail and found a message that
Porter left for her yesterday.
He asked her to meet him.
Tomorrow morning, 9:00 a.m.,
Wailana Coffee House.
All right.
Hey.
Hey, you're supposed to
be at the Hassleys'.
What's up? You all right?
Yeah, yeah.
You got a second?
Yeah, sure.
Good work.
How are the Hassleys doing?
They're a mess.
I mean, they're waiting
on a ransom call
that you and I both
know isn't coming.
What are you talking about?
Look, I get that
you don't want me here.
It's your team,
I wasn't your choice.
But sidelining me is just
a waste of your resources.
Okay, first of all, I put
my resources where I need them.
- I needed somebody on the phone.
- Come on.
I looked into
the Hassleys' financials.
They don't make any money.
Jen hasn't signed any
endorsement deals.
Her kidnapping was never
about ransom, and you know that.
You just wanted me
out of your hair.
Fine.
- Fine?
- Yeah.
Fine.
I sidelined you.
Well, at least you're man enough
to admit it.
Lori, we met this morning.
You expect me to trust you
the way I trust
these people out here?
I've been in the field
with these people,
they've had my back,
I trust them with my life.
The Hassleys are trusting me
with Jen's life,
and I promised them I'd bring
their daughter home.
- Okay, well, there's your first mistake
right there.
- Excuse me?
We don't make promises
like that around here.
Oh, really? Well, I do.
Those two kidnapping cases
that went south--
did you make the same promise
to those families?
Yeah. I did.
And I don't regret it.
Sometimes you make
all the right moves and
it just isn't enough.
You know, the Hassleys
are no different.
I intend to keep
my promise to them.
Hey, wait.
Tomorrow morning, 9:00 a.m.,
Wailana Coffee House.
Meet me there, okay?
Wait a minute.
So you're saying
he was in your house?
Yeah.
This is Captain Fryer, the
head of Internal Affairs?
What did he want?
He, uh, he asked me
a lot of questions
about the asset
forfeiture locker
and the money
that they said I stole.
I don't understand. You answered
all those questions already.
Yeah, well, he wanted
to see my face.
See if I was
a good liar.
There's something else,
isn't there?
IA's ruling on my case tomorrow.
Here, come here.
It's gonna be fine, okay?
They got nothing.
Porter's late.
Yeah. ' show.
Thank you.
Don't you just hate that?
Hate what?
The top off.
You know, you get
just the right mix going--
coffee, cream, sugar--
all working in perfect harmony.
Then, when you're not looking,
waitress comes, tops you off.
Ruins a perfectly good
cup of coffee.
That's why I switched to tea;
they don't mess with that.
What?
I'm just saying.
(groans)
Told you.
When you're right, you're right.
You know, I expected
somebody who graduated
top of his BUD/S class
would take his coffee black,
but mm-mm.
Did you pull my file?
Mm-hmm. Last night.
Which is when I assume
you pulled mine.
You graduated with
honors from Penn State,
but you switched from
bio to criminal justice
in your sophomore year.
- Mm-hmm.
What happened,
you couldn't hack the sciences?
Uh-huh, something like that.
Hmm.
Yeah, phys ed was
more my style.
Phys ed?
You care to
elaborate on that?
Uh-uh.
Maybe when I know you better.
- Okay.
Hey, any sign
of Porter out there?
No.
How's the date going,
buddy?
Chin?
You didn't answer
Danny's question.
I will take that as
no sign of Porter.
I think she's done waiting.
Let me see if I can stall her.
Hey, you're Julie Nells, right?
I'm Lo...
Julie, wait!
She's running, she's running.
Move, move.
(car horn honks)
(tires screech)
Whoa!
Hey!
Julie!
Whoa, whoa, come here,
come here.
Get away from me,
I'm not going back!
Julie, it's okay,
we're not here to hurt you.
Where's Matt?
What did you do to Matt?
Listen to me,
hey, hey, we're Five-O.
Look, okay,
we just want to talk to you.
- What do you want from me?
We're just looking
for Matt Porter.
Why?
DANNY: Because we
think he might
be trying to hurt you,
that's all.
Matt?
He wouldn't hurt me.
He saved my life.
Matt Porter rescued me from
a cult in Northern California.
What do you mean "rescued"?
That's what he does.
He's an extractor.
Two years ago
I joined this religious movement
near Mount Shasta.
When things changed, I tried to
leave, but they wouldn't let me
and they've been
after me ever since,
so I called Matt.
He was supposed
to meet me this morning
to help me disappear for good.
So why did you
run from us?
Matt said they might send
some people after me.
I'm scared.
I won't go back there.
Okay, okay.
When was the last time
you spoke to Matt?
Two days ago.
Okay, how did you contact him?
Matt's got a private number
he only gives out
to people he's helping.
Okay, we're going to need
that number, okay?
LORI:
Thanks.
Excuse us.
This doesn't make
any sense.
I mean, Jen wasn't
in a cult.
She didn't need
to be saved.
Why would Porter kidnap her?
- I don't know.
DANNY: I just got
off the phone with Max
and he ran tests
on the blood we found
in the trunk of Porter's car.
It's not Jen's.
LORI:
Oh, that's great news.
Okay, so she
could be alive.
Well, that's the good news.
The bad news is that the blood
we found in the trunk
was a match
to a John Doe gunshot victim
HPD found
this morning.
Max ran some DNA
and got that hit.
That's Matt Porter.
So where's Jen Hassley?
(groaning)
According to Max,
Matt Porter was killed
and placed in the trunk
of his car
somewhere between 8:00 p.m.
and 11:00 p.m. on Saturday
and more than likely
dumped along the Kamehameha
Highway shortly thereafter.
Okay, well,
Porter's not our guy.
Jen was abducted
on a Sunday morning.
KAYE: Guys, I just got a
strange hit on an alias
that Porter was using.
Which one?
James Westerfield-- it says here
in Jen's adoption records
that he was the one
who delivered Jen
to the Hassleys
15 years ago.
Okay, wait a minute.
If Porter
was an extractor
back then,
maybe Jen's biological parents
were actually
in a cult.
What if her parents
found out where she was
and they just
wanted her back?
LORI: This could be how
they found her.
She's been in the
press a lot lately.
- Maybe somebody put two and two together.
- All right, we need to find out
which cult Porter extracted her
from because that's where Jen is
right now.
We're ready for you.
I think I found something
that may help narrow down
where Jen was extracted from.
- Okay.
She was born with a
heart valve condition
that required emergency surgery.
Those symptoms
would have presented
hours after
she was born.
Now, a lot of cults don't allow
their members to see doctors
or take modern
medicine.
So if Jen was born
into a cult,
her only chance
of survival
would actually be
getting extracted.
That's what I'm thinking,
so I-I ran a search
on the list of known cults
that prohibit
medical treatment.
That is the
preliminary list.
I'm cross-referencing it
right now with Porter's files
to see if we can narrow it down
even further.
That's excellent work,
that's great.
Um, anything else?
That's all I got, boss.
Hey, hold up a sec.
Is there, is there
anything else you want to,
you want to talk
to me about?
What do you mean?
I mean,
you seem distracted.
I want you to know that
if something is going on,
you can come to me.
Well, um...
I didn't want to bother you
in the middle of a case,
but...
I received a phone call
yesterday from Langley.
My old boss at the
CIA said he picked up
on some chatter he thought
I should know about.
What are you talking about?
My fiancé might be alive.
How accurate is this intel?
They can't say, but I can't
stop thinking about it.
Okay, uh,
when are you leaving?
I was hoping as soon
as we found Jen.
If there's any chance
he might be alive,
Steve, I need to be there.
Yes, you do, and if there's
anything that we can do,
you, uh, you come
to us, okay?
(knocking)
You're gonna want to hear this.
WOMAN (over recording):
Matt, it's Rhea.
I know you said
it wasn't safe to contact you,
but I need your help.
I think my father knows
what happened.
Jen's in danger.
I need you to make sure
he doesn't get to her.
So I ran that
private number
the girl from the
diner gave us.
Turns out it has a
voice mail account.
This was the
only thing on it.
Do we know who Rhea is?
She could be the birth mother.
I'm running
the name and cross-referencing
with everyone in Jen's life.
Do we know
where the call originated?
Came from an unlisted number
on Lanai
a couple
of days ago.
Wait, uh, there's a commune
on Lanai that's been red-flagged
by several
government agencies.
They're the only ones
on that island.
That's got to be where Jen is.
MAN: About 20 years ago
they bought an old plantation
at the end of the Kaena Trail.
Who runs it?
Haole by the name
of Steven Carver.
This Steven Carver?
Yep, that's our island's
Jim Jones.
Nice.
How many people
drinking his punch?
MAN: Carver started with
about two families.
Now he's got about 50 people
on that property,
mostly militia types,
isolationists living
off the grid,
thinking modern-day society
and all its trappings
is the work of the Devil.
This island is not only
their home,
it's their
Garden of Eden.
They'll do anything
to protect it.
I assume they're armed.
I wouldn't bet against it,
but I know someone who's been
on the other side of those walls
who might be able to give you
a better picture.
MAN:
Yeah, I've been in there.
It's barely living.
Carver's got them thinking
it's paradise.
Do you know
if one of his followers
is a woman named Rhea?
Yeah, she's
Carver's daughter.
Okay, please, if you can, when
was the last time you saw her?
Oh, a couple days ago.
She came in
to use the phone.
Okay, uh, is this her?
Yeah, it's an old one,
but that's Rhea.
Okay, so Carver's been the one
exchanging the e-mails with Jen.
He wasn't lying;
this is her birth mother.
That makes Carver
Jen's grandfather.
Does Carver have
weapons up there?
He has rifles,
uses 'em to hunt.
Okay, I'm gonna need you
to draw me a map
of that compound.
Sure, absolutely.
Uh, can I help you?
- He one of them?
- Yeah.
Danny.
Okay, he made us.
Wait, whoa.
LORI: Listen, he's gonna
go back to the compound,
tell Carver we're here,
Carver's going to run.
What's the fastest
way up there?
There's only
one road in.
Unless...
Unless what?
This is the only way in--
on an animal?
We couldn't have got
an ATV
or a golf cart or something like...?
- Did you say ATV?
- I did.
They wouldn't hear an ATV from
a mile away, would they, Danny?
But you know what? Your whining
is probably louder than an ATV.
Whining?
STEVE:
Yeah, you're whining.
How long have
you two been married?
- Horses.
- Whoa,
whoa, whoa, that's it,
that's it right there.
(Jen groaning)
(sobbing)
What are you doing?
I told you
to keep away from here.
She's, she's not well.
That's none of your business.
It is my business--
she's my daughter.
And she's my granddaughter
and you told me she was dead.
You threw her away
like trash.
Go on, go to your room.
I'll deal with you later.
Here.
Uh, drink this.
There's herbs
in here.
It's good for your heart.
I don't want your tea.
I just want to go home.
Please.
This is your home.
I know this is hard
for you to understand,
but this is my fault.
I-I didn't raise
your mother right.
But I'm not gonna make
that same mistake with you.
You're my family.
I'm not gonna let them
take you
away from me.
You're not my family!
Now, listen
to me. Listen.
Those people...
are the ones that have been
poisoning you.
Now, I can make
you better.
You have to trust me.
(sniffles)
Just drink your tea.
(door opens)
We've got a problem.
All right.
According to this,
Carver's cabin is right in
the middle
of the compound, okay?
If Jen is here, that's where
he's gonna be holding her.
Wait, I think that's her.
Come on, we got to move.
(grunts)
Down on your knees. Now.
Face down, face down.
Hands behind your back.
It's okay.
Get them inside.
Jen, we're not
gonna hurt you.
We're the police.
We're Five-O.
Get down.
It's okay.
Where's Jen?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean,
you don't know?
My father found out
you were coming,
and he took her.
STEVE:
We got company.
Everybody down!
(grunts)
Whoa! Please.
Can we try
not to kill
everybody in the
compound, okay?
One of these hippies might know
where Jen is, all right?
Fine.
(gunfire continues)
One, two, three!
(grunts)
What'd I tell you?!
Go, go, go, go!
Stay here and stay down.
Down!
Drop it.
(grunts)
Where's Jen?
Where did Carver take her?
Don't make me
ask you again.
He has a plane.
Where?
Where is the plane?
Two miles west of here.
But you'll never catch him.
♪ ♪
Ho!
(tire pops, hisses)
Get out of the plane.
Show me your hands.
Show me your hands
right now!
Get out of the plane.
I just...
On your knees.
Leave her alone!
That's my granddaughter.
(handcuffs click)
Jen.
Jen, you hear me?
Everything's gonna be okay,
all right?
We're gonna get you
back to your parents.
(sirens approaching)
Okay?
I knew as soon as
Jen was born
that something was wrong.
She needed
medical treatment.
With real doctors.
But my father
would never allow it.
He said,
"Medicine makes us weak.
We have to empower our bodies
to fight."
But her little body--
it just...
It just didn't have
anything to fight with.
I-I knew we were
losing her.
So that's why you
gave her away?
The only way to save her life
was to let her go.
So I faked her death.
But a few weeks ago,
my father was in town
and saw a magazine article
about this amazing girl
with a heart condition...
...and he just knew it was Jen.
Hmm. So you
called Porter.
I tried to warn him
that my father was coming.
And he said
he'd take care of it.
And...
now he's dead because of me.
No.
You were looking after Jen.
You did what any mother would
do to protect their child.
She's not my child.
The Hassleys raised her.
And I'm just thankful
for everything they've done.
Rhea, there's someone
who'd like to meet you.
♪ ♪
(laughs)
Oh, you're leaving?
Kid's got a plane
to catch in an hour.
Yeah, so I guess
this is good-bye.
For now.
Come on.
(cell phone ringing)
Thank you.
Hey, cuz, how'd it go?
Mm-hmm.
WOMAN:
Sir, you can't go in there.
We need to talk.
We have nothing to talk about,
Lieutenant Kelly.
You're about to kill the career
of a good cop just because
you think she did
something wrong.
I know...
she did something wrong.
Apple doesn't fall far from
the family tree, does it?
This isn't about me.
You're right.
It isn't.
The governor wants to make it
very clear that there's
a zero-tolerance policy with
regard to crime and corruption.
He's tasked me with
cleaning up this department,
which is exactly
what I am going to do.
(taps desk)
Starting with your cousin.
After a lengthy investigation by
the Internal Affairs Department,
Officer Kono Kalakaua has been
stripped of her badge and is
no longer a member of Five-O
or the Honolulu
Police Department.
Her case has been handed over
to the prosecuting attorney,
who is officially moving forward
with charges.
I'll take your questions now.
(reporters clamoring)
I'm not at liberty
to say right now.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==