[GUNSHOT]
[GASPING]
[SIREN WAILING]
[METAL CLINKS]
Jesus.
MAYOR:
"To the city of San Francisco.
I will enjoy killing
one person every day...
...until you pay me 100,000 dollars.
If you agree,
say so tomorrow morning...
...in personal coining,
San Francisco Chronicle...
...and I will set up meeting.
If I do not hear from you...
...it will be my next pleasure
to kill a Catholic priest or a...."
"Scorpio."
-What goes on in their minds?
-Kooks.
Where the hell does he expect me
to find a hundred thousand dollars?
You're not-- You're not thinking
of paying him, are you, Mr. Mayor?
The city of San Francisco does not
pay criminals not to commit crimes.
Instead, we pay a police department.
Chief, who's in charge of this case?
Inspector Callahan. He's waiting outside.
Send Inspector Callahan in.
Callahan?
Mr. Mayor, Inspector Callahan.
All right. Let's have it.
-Have what?
-Your report. What have you been doing?
Well, for the past three-quarters of an hour,
I've been sitting on my ass waiting on you.
Damn it all, Harry.
That's the mayor you're talking to.
Won't you sit down, Inspector Callahan?
There's a madman loose.
I've asked you what's being done.
Fair enough?
We've got a dozen men
checking identification files.
Checking on all known extortionists,
rooftop prowlers...
-...rifle nuts, peepers--
BRESSLER: Mr. Mayor?
We've arranged for rooftop
surveillance and helicopter patrols...
...especially around the Catholic churches
and schools and in the black area.
Ballistics is checking on the slug.
We're pretty sure it's a 30-06.
-Seven lands and grooves, right-hand twist--
-Sir?
We're running a computer check...
...on everybody in the files
whose birthday falls between...
-...October 23 and November the 21st.
MAYOR: Why?
Natives of Scorpio.
Thank you, inspector.
Have any of you
mentioned this note to anyone?
How about you?
-Nobody.
-Your wife, sweetheart? Press?
Nobody.
All right.
Give the message to The Chronicle.
We'll agree to pay. But we need time
to get the money together.
Wait a minute. Do I get this right?
-You're gonna play this creep's game?
-It'll get us more breathing space.
It might get somebody killed.
Why don't you let me
meet with the son of a bitch?
None of that.
We'd end up with a real bloodbath.
I agree with the chief.
We'll do it this way, all right?
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
Come on, Callahan, let's go.
-Callahan?
-Sir?
I don't want any more trouble like you had
last year in the Fillmore district.
Understand? That's my policy.
Yeah, well, when an adult male
is chasing a female...
...with intent to commit rape,
I shoot the bastard. That's my policy.
Intent?
How did you establish that?
A naked man is chasing a woman through
an alley with a butcher knife and a hard-on...
...I figure he isn't out
collecting for the Red Cross.
I think he's got a point.
[MOTOWN MUSIC PLAYS
ON CAR STEREO]
Thank you.
JAFFE: Inspector Callahan.
-Jaffe.
Usual.
-So, the usual lunch or the usual dinner?
-Well, what difference does it make?
Not much.
Hey, Jaffe...
...is that tan Ford still parked across,
in front of the bank?
Tan Ford?
-Mm-hm. Yeah, tan Ford.
-Engine running?
I don't know. How can I tell?
-Exhaust fumes coming out of the tailpipe.
JAFFE: Ooh, that's awful.
Look at that pollution.
Yeah.
Do me a favor, will you?
Call this telephone number.
Police Department?
Yeah. Tell them Inspector Callahan
thinks there's a...
-...2-11 in progress at the bank. Got it?
-Two-eleven.
Got it.
Be sure and tell them
it's in progress, right?
In progress. Yes, sir.
Now, if they'll just wait
till the cavalry arrives.
[ALARM RINGING]
[GUNSHOT]
Oh, shit.
Halt!
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
HARRY:
Uh-uh.
I know what you're thinking:
"Did he fire six shots or only five?"
Well, to tell you the truth, in all this
excitement I kind of lost track myself.
But being this is a .44 Magnum, the
most powerful handgun in the world...
...and would blow your head clean off...
...you've got to ask yourself
one question: "Do I feel lucky?"
Well, do you, punk?
MAN:
Hey.
I got to know.
[CLICKS EMPTY]
[SIREN WAILING]
[CHUCKLES]
You son of a bitch.
Well, Harry, it looks like
we can save that leg.
HARRY: I've got a couple
under my knee here too.
-Did you ever consider another line of work?
-I really appreciate this. You know, Steve?
It's okay. We Potrero Hill boys
have to stick together.
Nothing fancy now, huh?
You know, just a little tweezers
and Mercurochrome.
Do I come down to the station and tell you
how to beat a confession out of a prisoner?
-Come on, I haven't got all night.
-You might experience a little discomfort.
But if you do,
just have your wife fix a....
I'm sorry, Harry.
-What are you gonna do with those?
-Cut your pants off.
-Oh, no, no. We'll pull them off.
-It'll hurt.
For $29.50, let it hurt.
You can turn your back
if you're embarrassed.
-Good morning, inspector.
-Maria.
You wanted to see me, lieutenant?
Yeah.
Hey, when the hell
you gonna get a haircut?
HARRY:
Well, whenever you do.
Look, who's got time? I was up till 3 a.m.
checking the search patterns.
-Well, put in for overtime.
-That'll be the day.
That was a good pinch you made.
Chief was pleased.
HARRY: He was, uh?
BRESSLER: Yeah, he really was.
-He wanted me to tell you, "Well done."
-I can't tell you how deeply moved I am.
I pass along a compliment....
You could at least be a little bit polite.
It might not even kill you to say thanks.
I'd much rather say thanks to a raise.
Hey, Harry, check communications.
Something from Chicago. A gun nut.
HARRY: I’ll get right on it.
-Now wait a minute. Wait a minute!
I'm putting somebody with you.
-What are you talking about?
-You need a partner.
-What's the matter with the partner I've got?
BRESSLER: He's in the hospital.
-He'll be out in a couple weeks.
BRESSLER: Say hello to Chico Gonzales.
-He'll be working with you.
-Al, you've gotta be kidding.
I haven't got the time
to break in newcomers.
-Why don't you do this boy a favor?
-What do you mean?
You know what happens to guys I've
worked with. Deitzick's in the hospital...
-...and Fanduchi's dead.
-So?
So if I need a partner, I'll get me someone
who knows what he's doing.
-What's the matter with Frank De Georgio?
-No way.
You're working with Gonzales
or you don't work.
That's straight from the fifth floor.
You got it?
I got it.
If you see De Georgio, send him in here.
You from around here?
Yeah, but I went to school
at San Jose State.
-You play ball?
CHICO: No, I boxed. Light heavyweight.
HARRY:
Just what I need, it's a college boy.
-Haven't found one thing you like about me?
HARRY: Well, it's early yet.
-Get your degree?
-Sociology.
Sociology? Oh, you'll go far,
that's if you live.
-I intend to.
-Inspector Callahan.
Don't let your degree get you killed.
I'm liable to get killed along with you.
CHICO:
I'll remember that.
-Hey, hero. Nice work yesterday.
HARRY: All right, fatso.
Bressler wants to see you.
You're a sweet man, Harry.
There is one question,
Inspector Callahan.
Why do they call you Dirty Harry?
Now, that's one thing about our Harry.
Doesn't play any favorites.
Harry hates everybody: limeys, micks,
hebes, dagos, niggers, honkies, chinks.
You name it.
-How does he feel about Mexicans?
-Ask him.
Especially spics.
[BELL TOLLING]
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
Hey! There's a guy
on the roof over there.
On Stockton Street
by Washington Square.
OFFICER [OVER SPEAKER]:
You, on the roof.
You there.
Yes, you. Stop what you're doing.
Turn around
and put your hands in the air.
CHICO: l don't understand
how the helicopter boys lost him.
How did they let him get out
of the building without seeing him?
They were probably talking instead of
looking, like they were supposed to.
That's possible.
DISPATCH: Attention, all units.
-Turn that thing up a little louder, will you?
--on the rooftop prowler. Last seen
in the vicinity of Washington Square.
He is an adult male Caucasian.
-Repeat, adult male Caucasian.
MAN 1: There goes a satisfied customer.
When last seen,
the suspect was wearing tan chinos...
...a pale blue shirt, brown coat
or sweater, dark gloves.
He was carrying a tan suitcase...
...which probably contains a 30-06 rifle.
This man is wanted on suspicion....
These loonies, they ought to throw
a net over the whole bunch of them.
I know what you mean.
-There.
-What?
Tan suitcase.
-Where?
-I lost him.
There he goes, over there.
Does that bag look tan to you?
I don't know,
I haven't even seen him yet.
CHICO:
Let's go to Filbert and hang a left.
Look out for these people!
MAN 2: Hey, fruitcake, what are you doing?
-Get out of the way, hammerhead.
CHICO: It was a tan suitcase.
I know it was. I know it was.
I saw him. I saw him.
-There he is. Right over there.
HARRY: I see him.
Okay.
DISPATCH:
Car 2, the license number...
...at 10-32 on that Chevrolet,
Colorado plates.
-How do you wanna work this?
-You find another entrance. I'll go in here.
-Okay.
-Car 2, what's the model of that Chevrolet?
MAN 3:
Car 2. It's an Impala convertible.
DISPATCH:
10-4.
MAN 4: You can cancel that 10-25.
There's three cars here.
MAN 5:
Anybody home?
[CLATTERING]
-I brought you a nice present.
WOMAN: Let me see it.
It's beautiful! Why don't you go get
a nice container of egg rolls?
Lousy peeping Tom.
You getting an eyeful?
You goddamn pie hawker!
MAN 6: We ought to call the police.
-I am a police--
[GUNSHOT]
CHICO:
All right, hold it!
Up against the wall. Right now, move.
-Let them go.
-Let them go?
-You heard me.
-They were assaulting a police officer.
A police officer? Why, he was
standing on that can peeking in...
...on Hot Mary and her boyfriend.
Beat it. Get out of here.
-How about the man with the suitcase?
-Wrong number.
-You know, I just had another thought.
-Yeah? About what?
Oh, about why
they call you Dirty Harry.
[SIREN WAILING]
DISPATCH:
Inspector 71. Inspector 71.
Inspector 71,
please respond to your call.
Inspector 71, do you read me?
-This is Inspector 71.
-I've got an 8-0-4 in progress.
California Hall at Polk and Turk streets.
10-4. We're on our way.
[SIREN WAILING]
MAN 1: There's some idiot up there.
MAN 2: Where? l don't see him.
MAN 1: There he is.
MAN 2: Oh, yeah. Now I see him.
DISPATCH:
I have a 10-29 and a 10-28.
The 600 block of Baker. On a Chevrolet.
California license: D-dog,
C-Charles, V-Victor 4-7-2.
FIREMAN:
Sorry to bring you in.
We thought it was your sniper, inspector,
but it turns out to be a suicide attempt.
HARRY: Anybody try to talk him down?
-Yeah, no luck. But now that you're here....
HARRY: You mean, I go up.
FIREMAN: We'd sure appreciate it.
MAN 3:
Please cooperate--
MAN 4:
Come on, now.
MAN 1:
Don't you try to get me.
Not me, no. You're the one who
wants to get yourself killed, not me.
Always happens with you guys, you know?
The last minute you always want to...
...grab onto somebody,
take somebody with you.
Down you go. Not me, brother.
Aren't you gonna try to grab me?
A friend of mine was up about 20
floors with a jumper a few years ago.
The jumper grabbed him and they went off.
And 20 floors down, just mashed all over.
Couldn't tell which legs were with which,
which arms were with which.
And it was a terrible mess.
I tell you, I almost threw up myself.
I'd just like your name and address,
that's all.
-Why?
-Like I said...
...it's such a mess down there afterwards.
It makes identification impossible.
Even if they find your driver's license,
all that blood and everything....
I think--
I think I'm gonna puke.
Oh, now don't do that, son. I mean,
all those people down there looking up.
The fire chief looking up. His face....
You rotten bastard.
Set me loose!
MAN 2:
He hit the poor man. He hit him.
MAN 3:
Why'd you hit that guy?
MAN 2: Why'd you hit him?
You didn't have to.
MAN 3: A wonder he didn't let go of you.
MAN 2: Probably would have liked to.
MAN 4: Okay, folks, come on, move out.
Give him room.
MAN 5: I got him, I got him.
Here, sir. Let him go now.
-Come on up here.
MAN 6: Easy, now. Easy, easy with him.
-Give me some help.
MAN 5: Get the stretcher.
Get the stretcher up here.
Now you know
why they call me Dirty Harry.
Every dirty job that comes along....
DISPATCH:
Inspector 71. Inspector 71.
This is Inspector 71.
Got something for you. Corner of
Sierra and Texas. A young boy, Negro.
What about him?
MAN:
Shot in the face. Blew part of it away.
Anybody know who the boy is?
WOMAN:
His name was Charlie Russell.
I'm his mother.
He's only 10 years old.
MAN 1 [OVER RADIO]:620 Pennsylvania.
MAN 2: 620 Pennsylvania. 10-4.
Ingleside, 4-Nora-Ida-Charles-5-9-2
is 10-32.
Inspector, this officer--
Oh, Jesus Christ!
-You'd better go check on the mother.
MAN 3: Lanakey. Inspector Lanakey.
Yeah. What do you have?
There's a 30-06 shell casing.
He was up here, all right.
Welcome to Homicide.
You know, the man who designed blue
serge uniforms for police departments...
...has to sell these for a living.
Well....
.458 Magnum, huh?
-This thing will stop an elephant.
-Yeah.
-Apparently you like a little edge.
-All I can get, sir.
Well, there's no elephant, Harry.
He's no animal of any kind. Remember.
What you got, lieutenant?
As you know, the blue flags represent the
units that will be on duty by dark tonight.
-Double shifts and overtime.
-Just at nighttime.
Daylight hours, the helicopters
will keep him off the roofs.
We're going for high visibility. Units
will make themselves very noticeable.
CHICO: Yeah, except in here.
BRESSLER: Right. The North Beach area.
We're saving that for him.
-Have you found a good stakeout?
-I think so.
It's a building that overlooks the roof
where they spotted him yesterday.
Something bothering you, Gonzales?
-No, no, nothing.
-Well, speak up. You're among friends here.
It seems like a long shot
that he'd come back to the same roof.
I mean, there are a lot of rooftops
in San Francisco.
Most of them are locked.
This particular one'll be open for him.
You see, these sick guys
have behavior patterns.
We know for a fact they'll rob the very
same store three, four times in a row.
It must appeal to their
superego or something.
Scorpio strikes again.
They like that feeling.
There's one other reason
why he might pick the same rooftop.
It's got a very clear view
of the St. Peter and Paul's Church.
And they're having a novena tonight.
-Well, go on.
-Well...
...the note. He threatened
to kill a Catholic priest or a Negro.
The Russell boy was black.
He may just figure
he owes himself a padre.
HARRY:
Inspector 71.
We're in position
to start our surveillance.
CHICO:
How about that priest?
-Does he know he's being set up for bait?
-Yeah, he wanted to.
We told him we had a volunteer
who was wiling to take his place.
Who?
You'll never guess.
Yeah, I know. "Welcome to Homicide."
You owe it to yourself
to live a little, Harry.
[DOOR SQUEAKING]
That son of a bitch took the bait.
When l say "now,"
you hit him with the light.
Now!
[GUNSHOTS]
-You all right?
-Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
[LAUGHING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE]
MAN 1:
Call an ambulance, will you?
Officer Collins
never knew what hit him.
MAN 2: All right. Let's go. Clear the alley.
There's nothing to see.
Call headquarters.
He's loose in North Beach.
MAN 2:
Let's go.
Now, move it, move it.
Well, it's a whole new ball game, fellas.
He grabbed a 14-year-old girl.
Ann Mary Deacon.
The bomb squad got a call this morning.
Suspicious object in Golden Gate Park.
It was addressed to the mayor. The lab
just sent it over to us with this letter inside.
"Ann Mary Deacon, buried alive."
Right. The poor kid went to the movies
last night and she never came home.
"Double-crossing San Francisco police
made me do this.
Now ransom $200,000,
in used tens and twenties.
One man with yellow bag.
South side Marina. Green East Harbor.
Nine p.m. She has oxygen
until 3 a.m. tomorrow morning.
Red panties and bra. Nice tits.
Mole on left thigh. Anything cute
and you will force me to let girl die...
...of slow suffocation."
Signed, Scorpio.
-Anything else in there?
-Yeah.
The mother identified the bra...
...the hank of hair...
...and that. The dentist identified that.
He said it was pulled out
with a pair of pliers.
You know she's dead, don't you?
All I know is the letter says
she'll be alive until 3 a.m.
The mayor's out trying to
put the money together now.
He's using up a lot of favors, Harry.
He wants to pay.
No tricks.
We're looking for a bag man.
You want the job?
-Yeah.
-Okay, you got it.
-Now, be in the chief's office at 6 p.m.
-All right.
-Wait a minute. What about me?
-You're out.
No cover? Not even one man?
Are you sure that's the way to do it?
No, I'm not sure.
But those are my orders. All right?
No wonder they call him Dirty Harry.
Always gets the shit end of the stick.
One more word out of you and
you're chopped off at the ankles.
Al, let's split the difference, huh?
Give him the night off.
Get the hell out of here, both of you.
-Testing one, two, three--
-Ow!
-What the hell are you yelling for?
-All you have to do is whisper.
Mary had a little lamb,
its fleece was white as snow.
-Okay, okay, that's better.
-It's good for two or three blocks.
But, like, in a tunnel, forget it.
All right, Sid. What do I owe you?
Bring it back in one piece.
Two hundred thousand dollars.
Count it and sign for it.
HARRY:
Did you count it, Al?
Did you count it, chief?
It's not my responsibility.
Oh, boy. Well, always knew
I'd get rich on the police force.
Just make sure
nobody takes it away from you.
God knows how he'll contact you.
He’ll probably run you all over town.
You just go where you're told,
do what you're told.
-Play it straight down the line. Okay?
-Okay.
Nothing cute. Nothing fancy.
Just pay the ransom money
and report back.
Okay.
You wouldn't mind if I borrowed
a little Scotch tape, would you?
It's disgusting that a police officer
should know how to use a weapon like that.
Okay.
[PHONE RINGING]
Yeah?
SCORPIO: You got a yellow suitcase?
-Yeah, I got it right with me.
-What's your name?
-Callahan.
-What are you?
-Police officer.
Hello? Hello?
All right, police officer...
...this is how we play.
I bounce you all over town
to make sure you're alone.
If I even think you're being followed,
the girl dies.
If you talk to anyone-- I don't care if
it's a Pekinese pissing against a lamppost.
--the girl dies.
-Is the girl okay?
-Just shut up and listen.
No car.
I give you a certain amount of time
to go from phone booth to phone booth.
I ring four times.
If you don't answer by the fourth ring...
...I hang up
and that's the end of the game.
The girl dies. What time you got?
-9:30. Now listen--
-You listen.
I'm watching you.
Not all the time,
but you’ll never know when or where.
Now get to Forest Hills Station
as fast as you can. Understand?
[ENGINE STARTS]
-Cop?
-Yeah?
I hope you're not stupid.
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
[PHONE RINGING]
Callahan.
SCORPIO:
Downstairs. Take the "K" car.
Get off at Church and 20th.
Hurry up, or you’ll blow it.
[PHONE RINGING]
Callahan.
SCORPIO: Yeah. you sound like
you had a good rest.
You’ll need it. I'm gonna give you
a nice little run this time.
And you better make it,
because if you don't, dead girl. Yeah.
Public phone,
hamburger stand, Aquatic Park.
[LAUGHING]
Hubba-hubba-hubba, pig bastard.
What's in the bag, man?
-You dudes get lost now, you hear?
MAN: Screw the bag.
Yeah, just give us a wallet now.
[GRUNTING]
[COCKS GUN]
You don't listen, do you, asshole?
[PHONE RINGING]
Hey! Don't answer that!
Hello. Hello?
Hello? What the--?
Callahan.
SCORPIO: Who picked it up?
-Just some old guy. I never saw him before.
[LINE CLICKS DEAD]
Oh, Christ.
Chico, he hung up.
[PHONE RINGS]
Callahan.
SCORPIO: You know Mt. Davidson Park?
-Yeah.
Go to the cross.
I'm at the entrance to the park
on Lansdale Street.
I'm going up.
I see a couple people.
Just a couple of kids necking.
Boys or girls?
I'm Callahan.
My friends call me Alice.
And I will take a dare.
Well, Alice, when was the last time
you were busted?
If you're a vice, I'll kill myself.
Well, do it at home.
SCORPIO:
Freeze.
Just like a statue.
That's right.
One wrong move, anything,
I don't care.
I'll kill you and the girl both.
You understand?
Yeah.
SCORPIO:
Drop the bag.
Left hand.
Let's see the gun.
My, that's a big one.
Left hand. Throw it.
Easy.
Raise your hands.
Come on, get them up.
Now turn.
Face the cross.
Come on.
Put your nose right up
against the cement.
[GRUNTING]
Oh, no. You lift that hand once more and
I won't let you know where the girl is.
Do we understand each other, huh?
Do we understand each other?
Don't pass out on me yet. No, no, no.
No, no, no. Not yet. Not yet.
Don't pass out on me yet,
you rotten oinker!
Do we understand each other?
If you care what happens to the girl,
you'd better answer me. All right?
-Yeah.
-All right. Now listen to me carefully.
I've changed my mind.
I'm going to let her die.
I just wanted you to know that.
You understand? l just wanted to make
sure you knew that before l killed you.
Goodbye, Callahan.
[SCORPIO LAUGHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
Chico, don't kill him!
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[SIREN WAILING]
The hospital report on Gonzales
looks okay, chief.
Yeah. Well, he's a pretty tough kid.
Harry Callahan, he's right here.
He's got two cracked ribs.
They wanna do some more tests
on him in the morning.
Well, the son of a bitch really
kicked him a couple of beauts.
I'm sending him home. Right, chief.
Chief says beat it, and that's an order.
Yeah.
Harry, the chief wants to know
if I misunderstood his orders.
Meaning, am I just plain stupid
or did I deliberately disobey him?
He wants to know
what Gonzales was doing up there.
why we screwed everything up.
Now, what the hell am I gonna tell him?
Why don't you just start
by telling him the truth?
Tell him Gonzales was obeying orders
from a superior. Me.
Tell him you didn't know
anything about it.
And when this mess is over, if he wants
my badge, well, he can have that too.
Hey, you wouldn't have a belt of booze
around here, would you?
[PHONE RINGS]
Lieutenant Bressler's office.
Yeah.
-Put him on.
-What is it?
It's Park Emergency. They just treated
a guy who has a knife wound in the leg.
Yeah, doctor?
What'd this guy look like, huh?
Long blond hair...
...medium build, about 150 pounds.
Pale complexion.
-He didn't give you his name, huh, doc?
-Nope.
They usually give a phony name,
in any case.
But I've seen him someplace.
Look, doc, it's important you remember.
There's a 14-year-old girl who's suffocating.
I'm trying to think. I'm trying to think.
It was....
I believe he works around here.
Doctor, could you give him something?
He's in terrible pain.
Yes, just a moment.
-For Christ's sake, she'll be dead in an hour.
-I'm trying to remember.
I've got who he is.
When they had football,
he used to sell programs at the stadium.
I think the groundskeeper
lets him live there.
-Live where?
-There.
Kezar Stadium.
Thanks.
Illegal entry. No warrant.
Looks like we climb.
Too much linguine.
I'll find another way.
[CLATTERING]
Stop!
SCORPIO:
No, no, no!
Don't do anything more!
No, you tried to kill me!
DE GEORGIO:
You need any help, Harry?
-Go on out and get some air, fatso.
SCORPIO: Please! No more!
I'm hurt. Can't you see I'm hurt?
You shot me! Please, don't!
Don't! Let me have a doctor.
Let me have a doctor.
Please, get me the doctor.
Don't kill me!
-The girl, where is she?
-You tried to kill me!
If I tried that, your head'd be splattered
all over this field. Now, where's the girl?
-I want a lawyer.
-I said, where's the girl?
-I have the right for a lawyer.
-Where's the girl?
I have the right to a lawyer!
Need to go to the doctor. Please!
I have rights. l want a lawyer!
[SCORPIO GROANING]
Harry Callahan. He said it was urgent.
Oh, yes, inspector. The district attorney
has been wanting to talk to you.
-It's Inspector Callahan.
MAN: Have him come in, please.
Will you come this way, inspector?
-May I bring you in a cup of coffee?
-No, thanks.
ROTHKO:
I'll be done in a minute.
Have a seat.
I've just been looking over
your arrest report.
A very unusual piece of police work.
Really amazing.
Yeah. I had some luck.
You're lucky I'm not indicting you for
assault with intent to commit murder.
-What?
-Where does it say...
...you've got a right
to kick down doors, torture suspects?
Deny medical attention and legal
counsel? Where have you been?
Does Escobedo ring a bell? Miranda?
I mean, you must have heard
of the 4th Amendment.
What I'm saying is,
that man had rights.
Well, I'm all broken up
about that man's rights.
ROTHKO: You should be.
I've got news for you, Callahan.
Soon as he's well enough
to leave the hospital, he walks.
What are you talking about?
He's free!
-You mean you're letting him go?
-We have to. We can't try him.
And why is that?
Because I'm not wasting a half-million
dollars of the taxpayers...
...on a trial we can't possibly win.
The problem is,
we don't have any evidence.
-Evidence? What the hell do you call that?
ROTHKO: I call it nothing.
Zero.
Are you trying to tell me Ballistics
can't match the bullet up to this rifle?
It does not matter what Ballistics can do.
This rifle might make a nice souvenir.
-But it's inadmissible as evidence.
-Who says that?
It's the law.
Well, then the law is crazy.
This is Judge Bannerman
of the appellate court.
He also holds classes in constitutional law
at Berkeley. I've asked him for an opinion.
Your Honor?
Well, in my opinion, the search
of the suspect's quarters was illegal.
Evidence obtained thereby,
such as that hunting rifle, for instance...
...is inadmissible in court.
You should have gotten
a search warrant. I'm sorry...
-...but it's that simple.
-Search warrant? There was a girl dying.
She was, in fact, dead
according to the medical report.
But I didn't know that.
The court would have to recognize...
...the police officer's legitimate concern
for the girl's life...
...but there is no way they can
possibly condone police torture.
All evidence concerning the girl,
the suspect's confession...
...all physical evidence
would have to be excluded.
There must be something
you can get him on.
Without the evidence
of the gun and the girl?
I couldn't convict him
of spitting on the sidewalk.
Now, the suspect's rights...
...were violated...
...under the 4th and 5th...
...and probably the 6th
and 14th Amendments.
And Ann Mary Deacon,
what about her rights?
I mean, she's raped and left in a hole
to die. Who speaks for her?
The district attorney's office.
If you’ll let us.
I've got a wife and three kids. I don't want
him on the streets any more than you do.
Well, he won't be out there long.
What is that supposed to mean?
That means sooner or later,
he'll stub his toe and I'll be there.
This office won't stand
for any harassment.
You're crazy if you think you've heard
the last of this guy. He's gonna kill again.
How do you know?
Because he likes it.
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
[MUSIC PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS]
MAN: Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Step right in here.
Don't leave, boys.
You sure you ain't been tailed, man?
Yeah.
You really want $200 worth.
Every penny of it.
You might as well be comfortable.
Go on, sit.
Relax.
Take it easy.
It's gonna be all right.
[GRUNTING]
You sure you want the rest of it?
SCORPIO:
Every penny's worth...
...you black son of a bitch.
This one's on the house.
MAN:
That's gotta be him.
-Come on.
-Sir. Excuse me, sir.
Are you claiming the
San Francisco Police did this to you?
I swear it. As God is my judge.
Why would they do that?
Why harass you?
I don't know.
They tried to frame me with the murder.
Now they're trying to murder me.
Look at me. Just look at me.
I'm supposed to be innocent until proven
guilty, and look at what they did to me.
Everywhere I go cops follow me.
And just look at me.
Just a minute, nurse. Please,
let me ask him one more question.
-Did you see who did this to you?
-Yes, I did.
-Can you identify him?
-Yes.
His name is Callahan. He's a big cop.
Works Homicide. Callahan.
Now, that's the rerun
from the 4:00 news.
Since then he's given
a statement to The Chronicle.
And he claims you have been
following him. And you beat him up.
Well, what about it, Harry?
-You want my star?
-I want an answer.
Have you been following that man?
Yeah, I've been following him
on my own time.
-Anybody can tell I didn't do that to him.
-How?
Because he looks
too damn good, that's how.
Now, before I let you go,
let's get one thing straight.
I don't want any more surveillance.
Well, neither does he.
What does that mean?
Good night, sir.
HARRY:
Go ahead. Try them.
Guy makes them
at the place I eat all the time.
CHICO:
Thank you.
HARRY: I talked to Bressler about
being on permanent with me.
So at least you know
you got a spot when you get out.
Yeah, well, I don't know
if I am coming back, Harry.
Nah. Doing a lot of thinking
about it and....
Well, I have a teaching credential.
And I figure...
...what for? You know?
Yeah.
-Time for therapy.
-You hang in there now, huh?
Goodbye, honey.
See you tomorrow. Same time?
NORMA: It's my fault, you know.
HARRY: What?
His leaving. l thought I could take it.
No class.
HARRY: Don't ever say that.
-What?
HARRY:
Just don't ever low-rate yourself.
What I meant was, whatever it takes
to be a cop's wife...
...I'm just not sure I'm making it.
He really tries, and these bastards...
...you know, "pig" this, "pig" that.
But maybe it's when I watch him
walk out that door at night.
And I think...
...what if this is
the last time I ever see him?
Look, am l the only one?
I mean...
...doesn't it drive your wife crazy?
HARRY:
No.
NORMA:
You mean she got used to it?
HARRY: No, she never did, really.
NORMA: Well, what, then?
She's dead.
Oh, please forgive me.
She was driving home late one night
and a drunk crossed the center line.
No reason for it, really.
-I'm so sorry.
-That's okay.
Look, I want you to tell Chico...
...that I understand him quitting.
I think he's right.
This is no life for you two.
-Why do you stay in it, then?
-I don't know.
I really don't.
-Hi.
-Yeah?
Um.... Yeah, let me have
a fifth of Seagram's, please.
What the hell happened to you?
SCORPIO:
My wife's brother.
I hit her...
...so he hit me...
...several times.
Five sixty-nine.
You're the guy that's been
robbed all these times, aren't you?
Fourteen times the last three years.
Last two times, I sent them
out of here on platters.
-Yeah?
-I'm getting to be a pretty good shot.
And I always keep it right here.
Right where it's handy.
Please, l scare easy.
[LAUGHS]
MAN:
You dirty son of a bitch!
-Goodbye.
-See you tomorrow. Bye.
BOY 1: Gotta get my lunchpail.
WOMAN: Bye. Get your lunchpail.
Okay.
BOY 2: Goodbye.
WOMAN: Bye. Bye-bye.
-Everybody out who gets out here?
BOY 3: See you tomorrow.
SCORPIO:
School bus inspector. Hi, kids.
Just one minute.
I'm not allowed to have anybody--
I'm authorizing it, so let's go.
What are you doing?
I don't know you.
Hear me, old hag. I'm telling you to drive
or I’ll decorate this bus with your brains.
-Where?
-Just get started. I'll tell you where.
All right. Let's have some fun now.
Who knows a song, huh?
Everybody knows a song. How about you?
You must know a beautiful one.
Come on, sing for us.
[SINGING "OLD MCDONALD
HAD A FARM"]
[PHONE RINGING]
BRESSLER: Millie, this is Inspector Callahan.
-Oh, yes. The mayor is waiting for you.
[BUZZES]
HARRY: What's up?
BRESSLER: Another note from our boy.
HARRY: Who's he grabbed now?
-That's the trouble, we don't know yet.
MAYOR: The jet must be fueled and
ready to go in a half an hour.
Skeleton crew. They must be volunteers.
Tell them the man is dangerous.
Well, here you are.
I'll read you this note which
was delivered at 8:00 this morning.
"To the city of San Francisco.
You have double-crossed me
for the last time.
I'm warning you to have my $200,000
in a jet airplane ready and waiting.
I will call the mayor's office at 1:00
and tell you about the hostages...
...who I will be happy to kill if you don't
do exactly what I say. Scorpio."
Well, you better
have somebody standing by.
Don't count on it being a false alarm.
MILLIE: Mr. Mayor?
There's a call for you on Line 2.
I think it's the one
you've been waiting for.
MAYOR:
This is the mayor.
SCORPIO:
I've got seven kids from Park Street School.
All right, now listen.
I got the bus and I've--
Come on, honey, now, back in the bus.
That's a good girl. Back in the bus.
And I've got the bus driver. Here she is.
Just tell him.
-Wasn't my fault, he had a gun--
-Just tell him your name.
PLATT:
This is Marcella Platt.
SCORPIO: You can check up on that
if you want. But l don't see any point.
I'm not bullshitting, and you know it.
It's very simple.
I've got the kids. And you start screwing
around, the kids start dying.
Is the plane ready?
MAYOR:
The jet is being fueled and ready to go.
-Money will be there when you get there.
-All right, listen.
And listen very carefully.
I'm gonna be driving nice and easy.
Just me and a busload of kids.
I’ll turn off at Sir Francis Drake
on my way to Santa Rosa Airport.
I don't wanna see any police cars...
...helicopters, whatever.
You got the guts to play this game by the
rules, the kids will have a nice plane ride.
-Where are you going?
SCORPIO: I'll tell the pilot...
...when I get on the plane.
No alerts. Nothing.
I guarantee you, you will not
be molested in any way.
I give you my word of honor on it.
Marcella Platt. It checks.
CHIEF:
Callahan?
You willing to take the money to him?
When will you people stop messing around
with this guy? He's gotta be stopped now.
He's got a busload of kids
and I can't take that chance.
I gave my word of honor on it
and he will not be molested!
That's a direct order, Callahan!
Well, you can just get yourself
another delivery boy.
[CHILDREN SINGING
"ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT"]
Where are we going?
-This isn't the way we're supposed to go.
-We're going to the ice cream factory.
Anybody doesn't want to go can get off.
I wanna go home to my mother.
I wanna go home.
You wanna go home and see what?
Now, sing! Sing again!
[SINGING
"ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT"]
What's the matter? Don't you sing?
Are you sick? Are you sick? What is it?
All your mothers will die
if you don't sing!
I'm gonna kill all your mothers
along with the rest of you!
All right,
now get in the right-hand lane.
-It's not right to do children that way.
-What?
-You can hurt them.
-Just drive the goddamn bus.
And get in the right-hand lane.
I want my mother.
There's the sign, Sir Francis Drake Blvd.
Make a right there.
Goddamn it, there's the sign
to Sir Francis Drake Boulevard!
Not this one. Not this one.
BOY:
I want my mother.
SCORPIO:
Shut up!
Just get to the right! To the right!
Jesus.
What the hell is he doing up there?!
[CAR HORN HONKING]
What the hell are you doing?
Pass the V.W. Pass it, will you?
[SCREAMING]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[CHILDREN CRYING]
MAN:
Hold it, hold it. You can't go in there.
You drop the gun, creep!
[SCORPIO LAUGHING]
I'll blow his brains out.
Drop the fucking gun!
[SCREAMS]
[COUGHS]
Uh-uh.
I know what you're thinking, punk.
You're thinking,
"Did he fire six shots or only five?"
Now, to tell you the truth, l forgot
myself in all this excitement.
But being this is a .44 Magnum, the
most powerful handgun in the world...
...and will blow your head clean off...
...you've gotta ask yourself a question:
"Do l feel lucky?"
Well, do you, punk?
[LAUGHING]
[GUNSHOT]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[ENGLISH SDH]