♪ My flesh and bone,
not my own ♪
♪ You have changed me
to my core ♪
♪ Took control of my soul ♪
♪ I am not me anymore ♪
♪ I'm gone ♪
♪ Now you live on ♪
♪ I, I'm among the dead ♪
♪ Blood don't reach my head ♪
♪ Suffering
what you made me become ♪
♪ Seepin' in my skin ♪
♪ Darkness deep within ♪
♪ Can I come back
from among the dead? ♪
♪ I, I'm among the dead ♪
♪ Blood don't reach my head ♪
♪ Suffering
what you made me become ♪
♪ Seepin' in my skin ♪
♪ Darkness deep within ♪
♪ Bring me back
from among the dead ♪
How are thing's back there?
Oh, it's fine. Slow.
I'm glad we're
only a quarter full.
Same up here.
Did you hear something
about the weather front?
Yeah. These things
used to bother me.
The weather?
No.
That we're gonna be delayed
getting into Paris.
Ha ha ha!
Please tell me you plan
on getting some sleep tonight.
Oh, I can promise you
we'll be in bed early.
Emily, why don't
you go out with us?
It'll be so fun.
Wow. Paris at night.
Zee Champs Elysees,
zee clubs...
- zee mademoiselles.
- I will be busy.
Now, if you'll
please excuse me, ladies...
I've got some work to do.
Okay.
That's a hint.
- Yaah!
- Aye, aye.
So what's the deal
with the special cargo?
It was
some last-minute, top-level...
government contractor shipment.
This says there's
an armed guard in the hull.
That's a first.
What are we carrying?
I'm not sure I want to know.
Well, looks like
all the signatures check out...
so we are free to drop it
with the S.O.C.
All right, it says here if there
are any abnormalities...
involving the cargo area-
Abnormalities?
We're to contact a Dr. Bennett
and Dr. Sebastian.
These were the guys
that secured the cargo.
They're in first class.
Abnormalities.
I'm glad this is my last flight.
Yeah.
Lucas, you need to settle down.
No, you're not listening!
We could lose Kelly,
and I won't let that happen.
- Do you underst--
- Would you calm down?
You're makin' a scene here.
Now, I told you, I will
bring Kelly out of stasis...
when we have
a controlled environment...
not before.
We all know
this is highly unorthodox.
We had to move quickly.
This is our--
our only way out.
Unorthodox?
Hey, she would have died,
and we saved her.
If we hadn't intervened,
she'd be dead.
You goddamn well know that.
Now, were we able
to reach our friend?
Kolinsky's made
all the arrangements...
for the transport,
and we'll see him in Prague.
In Prague?
I thought we had a lab
set up in Toulon?
Crazy.
Our files have been hacked.
That'll be
the first place they look.
We are running out of time!
There have always been risks...
but think of the good
we are doing.
We will save loved ones.
We will bring them back.
It's why we all have sacrificed.
Kelly knew the risks
goin' into this.
Ah, that's easy for you to say.
That's not your wife
down there, is it?
Is it?!
Shh. Calm down.
Sit down. Sit down.
Come on. Come on.
That's it.
Now, listen,
I know how you feel.
I really do.
But do you, for one minute,
think I don't know...
what's at stake here?
My entire company depends on
the success of this project...
and I am less concerned
about losing one life...
than I am of saving thousands.
So I'm not gonna
let you or your wife...
or some petty little bureaucrat
jeopardize this project.
So shut the fuck up
and get back to your seat...
because this subject
is closed for good.
Are we clear on this, doctor?
We're clear.
Excuse me.
He's not gonna let this go.
Don't worry about it.
Dr. Thorp will
not be leaving Paris...
not with us at any rate.
Excuse me, Miss...
I'll, uh, take
a rum and Coke, please.
Oh, sorry, Burrows.
Rude of me. Make that two.
Right.
How about a Coke?
If a little bit of Bacardi were
to find its way in there...
it would be
our little secret, huh?
Uh, yes.
Anything for you, Mr...
Uh, Burrows, Truman.
But, no, thank you.
And I'm Frank,
Frank Lee Strathmore.
It's a name rich with tradition.
MY, uh...My family--
She doesn't need to know
your family history, Frank.
Look, I don't expect
to be tied up long.
Just a couple of parking ticket
kind of things, really.
I mean, how about you and I...
meet at the Eiffel Tower
around midnight?
I'm sorry to disappoint you...
but, uh, Frank here,
he's gonna be a little busy.
That's okay.
Truman, if you guys need
anything, let me know, okay?
Thank you.
Okay.
Truman?
Truman, hmm.
I guess that pretty well
does it for me.
Looks like if you
play your cards right...
she could be cuff in' you later.
Mmm.
You're gonna shut up
and drink your Coke.
HEY, guys.
Hey.
My God, you are are lovely.
Stewardess, do you think...
I could get some sugar
with my coffee?
Down, boy.
So, is Ally packed?
Aw, she's been packed
for five years.
The legendary Ray Bashore
retiring.
So, why isn't she with you
on your final flight?
She insisted on staying home...
to get things
ready for our trip.
Oh. So, where are you two going?
Summer vacation
with the grandkids...
then we're on a slow
ocean cruise to Alaska...
just the two of us.
That's so romantic.
Yeah, the ocean cruise maybe,
but the kids?
Ooh, sounds like a nightmare.
Hey, that's great Ray, really.
Thank you.
Looks bad ahead, huh?
Oh, not to worry.
Boring flight, boring flight.
So, I can't wait to go shopping
at Chanel in Paris.
Courtney says that we have
to go to Cartier first...
and then we can go to--
Yeah. Well, I can't wait
to go surfing in Biarritz.
Surfing?
Oh, yeah, we're goin' surf in'.
You can go surfing.
Good.
You and that slut Jackie
can go surf in' all you want.
Whoa. Hey, Tony's
my friend, all right?
Mm-hmm.
We're here to surf,
and you know that.
And, hey, his girlfriend's
a total bitch...
and you know that.
What the hell is it
with you two?
I don't like her, okay?
Whatever, okay.
Whatever yourself.
Hey, yo, Tone.
- Yeah?
- Gotta go long, buddy.
Oh.
Nice.
Oh, Oh!
- It hurts to get scored on.
- Geez, Peter, stop it!
Thank you.
Child.
Whoa. Nice toss.
Hey!
I'll give it back to you
when I'm done playing with it.
Hey.
Dude, she cannot take the ball.
Obviously, she can.
Nice toss.
- Uh, excuse me, Mr. Freeman?
- Yeah?
Uh, could I--
Could I get your autograph?
Oh, yeah. Sure, sure.
That--That final putt
on the last day of The Masters?
Man, that was poetry.
Oh. poetry, huh?
Yeah.
All right. Here you go.
Thank you.
- Thanks, Mr. Freeman. Thanks a lot.
- No problem.
Why can't they
just leave us alone?
You told me this was
a trip away from golf...
and everything
that goes with it.
I know, and it is.
Look, I promise
that for the rest of the trip...
I'm just gonna be
plain old Billy, all right?
You won't even know
Long Shot exists...
I promise you that.
Okay.
Love that smile.
Excuse me, Mr. Freeman.
Yeah?
Captain Bashore
would love to meet you.
When he has a break
later in the flight...
would you mind
if he stops by for a visit?
Yeah. It's not a problem.
Thank you.
Great.
You know, while you're at it...
if you're done fawning
over my husband...
I'd love another Bloody Mary.
Anna.
William, I'm on vacation.
I'll get your drink
right away, Mrs. Freeman.
Yeah, and make sure you put
some vodka in it this time...
'cause that's
how I like to tee off.
Hey.
There's no reason
to be so rude, all right?
Oh.
You know, I'm sure there's
someone back in coach...
that hasn't got
your autograph yet.
Well, maybe I'll go back there
and give it to him.
You knew what you were gettin'
into when you married me.
I thought I did.
Yeah, you just keep twirling
that little putter of yours...
'cause that's all you're gonna
be twirling on this trip.
Wasn't so little
last night, was it?
You know you've
got the wrong man.
Yeah.
That's why Interpol
has your picture...
all over the Internet.
It's a classic case
of mistaken identity.
Yeah.
Hey.
Burrows, you can't
treat me like this.
I'm not guilty.
It's not fair, bouncing me
all over the world...
to stand trial here and there
for something I did not do.
I'm not guilty.
No, I have a clear conscience.
I'm--I'm not guilty.
Yeah.
What is it going to take
to convince you I'm innocent?
An act of God.
Now shut up
before I make you eat...
that flotation device
you're sittin' on.
Mmm.
Here we go.
We can fly around it,
but not above it...
and this is a huge system.
It's about 150 miles
east and west of course...
so it looks like either way
we go, we are screwed.
It's either that, or we fly
all the way back around...
but that's gonna add 30 minutes
to our flight at least.
Hmm...Paris weather
is not good for our arrival.
I'm gonna deviate left
and thread the needle.
That gap might be our only shot
at getting around this system...
without landing for fuel.
Folks, looks like it's gonna
get a little bumpy ahead.
Like you to remain in your seats
and wear your seatbelts.
Probably be through this
in ten or fifteen minutes.
Thank you very much.
Oh! Ow! Ow!
Ow!
Oh, God!
Did you hear that?
Something must have
shifted and fell.
As you know, Mr. Madison...
a combined strike team
of the CIA and FBI...
seized the headquarters
of Medcon Labs in Los Angeles.
A number of arrests were made...
but we've been
unable to determine...
the whereabouts
of four key individuals.
The first one,
Dr. Leo Bennett.
He's a head research scientist
and founder of Medcon...
known for his work
with retroviruses...
and synthetic biology.
He was investigated
two years ago...
for illegal cloning research.
Unfortunately,
that investigation...
failed to produce
any indictments.
So far, I've seen nothing...
that warrants
disturbing the President.
Can we get to the point here?
Look, we're
trying to reconstruct...
Bennett's hard drive...
and we think there
is cause for alarm.
We believe Leo Bennett
is responsible...
for the development of a new
strain of the malaria virus...
and the containment
and transportation...
of Dr. Kelly Thorp.
Malaria?
Initially,
we thought it was malaria.
However, we discovered
that it's something new...
something different.
Bennett obtained a DNA sample
from a mosquito...
native to a remote area
in Vietnam...
which had a 100 percent
mortality rate within seconds...
which then regenerates
that same organism...
for a few seconds or longer...
depending
upon the subject organism.
What Bennett has
developed is a mutation...
of this same mosquito virus
to restart major organs...
for an indefinite period
of time.
So, what you're saying is
that his virus kills organs...
and then brings them
back to life?
Not just organs.
He apparently was experimenting
on the resurrection...
of the entire human body
after death.
Oh, impossible. I can't go
to the President with this.
Jerry, come on.
From what we've uncovered,
we believe he's succeeded.
Ohh! Ohh!
Help me.
Oh...Oh!
Aah.
Hello?
What--
What is going on?
What is happening to me?
Aah!
Aah-haa!
Aah! Aah!
God damn it.
Jesus.
What now?
We got electrical
and communication problems.
And we just had
a temperature drop...
in the cargo hold.
This is Concord 2-3-9 to base.
Great. No radio and this crap
for the next hour.
Perfect.
What the hell
is wrong with you?!
I'm sick.
I need help.
I need help!
I'm a scientist
with Medcon Labs.
Where the hell is Dr. Bennett?
Aah! Aah!
I need to talk to someone!
I'm coming out!
Don't shoot!
Come out. I won't shoot.
Aah!
What the fuck? Fuck.
Where is she?
Oh, God! Help!
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
Okay.
Hey, will you grab me
a Diet Coke on the way back?
Sure, honey.
Thanks, babe.
Check out that dime.
Wow. That is
one hot little be-otch.
Uh-huh.
Ow! Fuck, that hurt!
Oh, hi, honey.
Busted.
So, I guess
that mid-flight blowjob...
is out of the question?
Such a Pi!!-
Sweetheart?
What?
Did you see that?
Come here.
Um...
Hey, hey, hey, he!!-
What?
What's wrong?
I mean, what
if somebody sees us?
What are you talk--
We're in a bathroom.
What are you talking about?
No. I--
You know what I mean.
You're Peter's best friend.
So what?
Oh! I'm sorry.
Oh, pardon me, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
- No. It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
I wasn't paying attention.
Sir, you actually,
you need to take your seat.
The "fasten seat belt" sign
is on.
Yeah, yeah, um...
Can I get you
some more coffee? Okay.
Yes, thank you.
You're welcome.
Uh, "Mee-gan,"
rhymes with vegan.
- I was a vegan...
- Yeah?
For two days.
"Mee-gan" Vegan...Ha!
It's actually "Meh-gan."
"Meh-gan."
Oh, no, I know that. Um...
Sir, you actually need
to take your seat.
Okay. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I just--You need to be
more careful.
I mean,
people sneakin' up on you.
There's strange people here.
You never can tell...
what's gonna happen
on these flights.
Sir, you need
to take your seat.
Okay. Thanks, thanks.
- You're welcome.
- Buckle up.
Yes.
Jesus.
Ha! Wow.
Cool, huh?
Yeah.
Maybe this little diversion...
will keep my mind off
your tasteless, cheap suit.
Would you feel better...
if I was in a bitch-ass
orange jumpsuit...
like the one
you're gonna be wearing...
the rest of your life?
There you go
getting nasty again...
when I am merely
offering a criticism...
of this sartorial horror show
you call a suit.
However, I do like the shirt.
Does it come in a man's style?
And for your information,
the jumpsuits in France...
are a sort of burgundy, yeah.
Oh, you should look nice
in that color.
Now I know what color corsage
to get you...
when big Pierre
makes you his wife.
Someone sounds
a wee bit jealous.
Yeah.
.Aah!
Aah!
- Ow!
- Ha!
Ow!
Anna.
I'm gonna descend a little.
Is it over yet?
Let's find out.
This is Randy.
It's Stacy.
I--I think
some of the passengers...
might have been hurt.
How bad?
I don't know.
It's a mess down here.
Well, we'll do the best we can.
Just stand by.
Looks like we're okay
for a few minutes.
Give 'em the go-ahead to check.
Let me know what's what.
Well, folks, we apologize...
for the heavy turbulence
we just experienced.
It appears as though
we're clear for the moment.
However, we're traveling
through some unstable air...
so, as a precaution,
I would like you...
to remain in your seats
for the time being.
At this time, I would only
like our flight attendants...
up and about the cabin.
Thank you.
Would you make sure
everyone's all right?
Then have
one of the doctors...
uh, Bennett or Sebastian...
check the cargo
situation out with you.
The cargo?
I'll get my tools.
Is she okay?
It's her head.
Looks like Tony got hurt.
Damn.
You all right, dude?
You take one?
Fucking bag
hit me in the head.
Come on, that was fun.
It's just turbulence.
My God, don't be such a baby.
It didn't hit you.
Relax.
What is your problem, girl?
Oh, are you scared
we're gonna crash?
Relax, bitch. Enjoy the ride.
Whoa, Jesus,
pipe down, you psycho.
Shut up.
What the hell's wrong
with you?
- Hey!
- What?
You are a psycho.
You know, and you're
a fucking skank.
I am so sick of your shit!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Bring it.
- Fuck off!
Stop it! Hey, come on!
Everyone just calm down.
Take your seats.
And you take your seats, too.
What is wrong with you?
We have
several warning lights...
we don't usually get,
even with this weather.
It's probably nothing,
but we should look just to see.
I agree.
Why don't you two go with him?
Both of us?
Right.
Well, whoever's going,
meet me by that exit door.
It usually takes a few minutes
to get down there...
and there's no easy way to go.
God damn it. I told you.
I told you both.
Hey, hey, hey, calm down.
Just go check on our passenger.
If it was a malfunction,
Kelly might be dead.
Yeah, listen,
don't take your eye off him.
Make sure he doesn't
do anything stupid.
Are you guys Okay?
I'm fine.
But, uh, do you think we can
move up to business class?
I mean, the plane's
really empty and all.
He's kidding. We're fine.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Hey, I am trying
to help you out here.
She wants you. Make your move.
Go, boy, go.
I'm sorry if this is a problem.
No problem.
We'll take care of it.
It could be dangerous.
Only if you're afraid
of the dark.
Come on, bro.
I need to go to the sandbox.
What?
I gotta pee.
No.
You heard the P.A.
Sit down and hold it.
Fine.
Oh, if you should happen
to feel something warm...
just move
a little to your right.
You're like a five-year-old.
Come on, let's go.
Oh!
Easy. Take it slow.
Yes, of course!
Burrows?
Mr. Burrows?
Truman.
Oh, my God.
All right, gentlemen.
Here we go.
Oh, my God. Truman.
Ohh.
Truman?
Mmm?
What?
Mmm...
Oh.
Aw, that little shit.
Flight deck.
Captain, this is Megan
at door four-L.
We've got a problem back here.
Okay. How bad is it?
Mr. Burrows, the cop who brought
the prisoner on board...
was knocked out cold,
and his prisoner is missing.
Excuse me.
You guys seen a, uh,
funny-lookin' skinny guy...
blue sweatshirt, turtleneck,
walk through here?
No.
No? No? All right.
Well, that explains
the communication problem.
Frey? Dr. Thorp!
Kevin!
Frey's not in the jump seat.
My God.
This can't be happening.
We need to get out of here now!
Come on!
We need to seal the hatch now!
- What's wrong?
- Come on!
Lucas.
Kelly. Oh, God.
No! Aah!
Aah!
No!
Run!
Aaah! Aaah!
Tony?
Asshole.
Ah ha ha ha!
Don't scare me like that.
What? Where the fuck
are you goin'?
Ow, that hurts.
And don't use that kind
of language around me, either.
Over here. Come over here.
Hey, you two.
You need to be in your seats
with your belts fastened.
Why don't you make yourself
a fuckin' sandwich...
while you're at it?
What have you done?
You son of a bitch, what
have you brought on board?!
Take your seats, everyone!
Please take your seats!
Okay, if everyone
could just calm down.
Please take your seats now.
Do you know what's goin' on?
Ray, open up!
What's wrong? Randy!
Ray, bring the plane down!
Bring the plane down right now,
or we're all gonna fuckin' die!
Oh, shit.
Tell me what the hell
happened down there.
It's the fucking...
The fucking--
The fucking scientists...
they let something
out of the cargo hold.
What are you talking about?
Where are the doctors?
They're dead!
All right, they're dead!
Settle down!
Look at me, man!
Everyone's gonna fuckin' die!
They killed 'em!
Sit down and calm down!
Sit down!
Now! Sit down!
What happened to you?
Listen to me.
Just listen to me, Ray.
- If you don't land this plane now...
- Slow.
You, me, Emily...
everybody on this
fucking plane is gonna die.
You know I can't bring
her down without warning...
and no place to land.
Think about it!
There is something...
that's not human
down there, man...
and it's gonna kill
everybody on board...
unless we land this plane.
So whatever you do,
I don't care how you do it--
- Look, I need you to calm down.
- Just find a place, Ray,
and land the fucking plane!
Find a piece
of straight fuckin' road!
This storm isn't
helping our situation.
If it's clear,
we can try to cross...
but I'm turning around
and heading back.
There's a TSA man aboard.
Find out which passenger he is
and get him up here!
Now!
Ray...
Are you sure that's the guy?
Okay, they're dead...
and you say whatever
killed them wasn't human.
I know it sounds insane.
I saw this happen.
I mean, those things...
I mean,
they ripped those men apart...
and they were eating them.
You said there was
a fugitive on board.
Is it possible
you saw him down there?
No. I told you,
there were two of them...
and these--
These things aren't human.
You know what?
I'm gonna go find out
what was in those containers.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go talk
to that asshole, Bennett...
because he knows.
Sit down.
I'll check it out.
I'll report back.
Everything okay? Okay.
Any sign of him?
No.
How's your head?
Uh, better than my ego.
Aw, come on,
he can't hide forever.
As soon as
the turbulence settles...
I'm gonna look for him
some more.
Don't go alone.
Why? ls he dangerous?
Well, he's probably
never owned a weapon before...
but he's more of a con artist
than anything.
What did he do?
Can you tell me?
Um...
He posed as an accountant...
skimmed $35 million
off the Russian mob...
stole their jet,
crash landed it,
and we finally caught up to him.
Everybody wants him.
Wow.
Why are you taking him
to Paris?
Oh!
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
You should take your seat.
Okay. Be careful.
- Okay.
- All right.
Hey, take a look at this.
I think I found Concord 2-3-9.
Nobody's been able to reach them
for over an hour.
Los Angeles dispatch,
this is Yellowknife Center.
I believe I have
your Concord 2-3-9 on my screen.
It's in the middle
of two huge weather fronts...
and transponder indicates
it's off course.
No. No radio contact yet.
I'll try now.
Concord 2-3-9,
Yellowknife Center.
Los Angeles dispatch.
I need you to put this
on speaker-phone right away.
Yes, I understand.
I repeat, you must tell 2-3-9
to return to U.S. airspace.
The Canadian government
will not permit them to land...
or continue to fly
in their airspace.
This decision has come...
from the highest level
of the Canadian government...
as well as the U.S. State
Department and the CDC.
Is that clear?
Can you tell me what it is...
you're transporting
in the cargo hold?
I'm sorry.
My cargo is
a highly classified project...
linked to
our nation's security...
and you don't have
the necessary clearance.
I'm with the TSA,
Federal Air Marshal.
I need to know
what's down there.
Well, how fortunate for us...
to have a man of
your obvious talents aboard.
You seem a bit nervous, doc.
Is everything all right?
I just don't like flying.
Isn't it true
your two colleagues...
accompanied the co-pilot
down to the cargo hold...
because there was some problem?
No, no problems.
No problem?
Just a routine
in-flight inspection.
Routine.
What I can tell you, while
my cargo isn't dangerous...
it is highly perishable
and extremely valuable...
so the cargo area is off-limits
to unauthorized personnel.
Well, can you tell me--
No, I'm sorry.
I've said more than
I should have already.
You Burrows?
Yeah.
I'm Paul Judd, TSA.
I believe your prisoner's
in the cargo hold.
Ready?
Hey, Frank!
Frank!
Frank, get out here!
Dr. Thorp! Dr. Sebastian!
Anybody out there?
That's a lot of blood.
Somebody was in trouble.
Yeah, if it's Frank's,
he needs help now.
Check that out.
Looks like he escaped
through the ducts.
I don't know.
That's an awful lot of blood...
for a skinny little shit
like Frank.
You go that way.
I'll go this way.
Meet back in five.
All right.
Hey, Frank?
You there, buddy?
Now, why don't you come on out
and talk to me, man?
Everything's all right.
It's cool.
We can just talk.
It's just me.
Frankie?
I'm gonna kill that little shit.
All right!
I'm comin' up.
Yes?
You're sure?
Outstanding.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
We have located
Bennett and his team.
Hallelujah.
Aw...
Ohh...
Ohm
You know, Frank, sometimes
this job is really boring.
This is not
one of those times, bud.
You're makin' this
real exciting.
Ohm
Son of a bitch.
Paul?
Frank?
Raah!
Get off!
Aah!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God,
I'm gonna be sick!
Oh, my God!
Cara, where the fuck
are you goin'?
Where are you--
What the fuck?
Tony, this bitch
just got shot, dude.
There's fuckin' bullets
comin' from somewhere.
Oh, no. Oh, my God.
Oh!
Please take your seats.
Everything's fine.
Take your seats, okay?
Please take your seats.
We're gonna be fine.
Thank you.
Ray, it's total chaos down here.
There were gunshots or something
that freaked out the passengers.
Aah!
Aah! Aah-Ha! Aah!
Emily!
Go. Take the gun.
Oh.
Ohh...
Ohm
Oh, God,
this can't be happening.
Get back.
Go back to your seats
and stay there!
Go back!
Aah!
Move, move, move, move!
Get out of my way!
Cara! Cara!
Cara, open the door!
What's going on here?
Move! Cara!
Aah! Aah!
Hold on, Cara!
I'm coming! Cara!
Aah!
Go!
Oh, shit.
Dude, what the--
Get back!
Get back! Get back!
Get out of here!
Oh, my God!
Cara! Cara!
Stay right there!
Stay back there!
What the fuck, dude?
What is this?
Christ!
Holy shit!
Get off him!
Get off him! Get off him!
Aah! Aah!
What is this shit?!
Help me!
Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Fuck! What the fuck?
What the fuck was that?
Please, please!
Please go back to your seats!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, Tony,
what happened?
What the fuck happened?
Please take your seats.
Flight deck.
Ray, something's
happened down here.
Something attacked
one of the passengers...
and he's dead.
You got to get us down, Ray.
Oh, my God.
Megan, listen to me.
No, no, you don't understand.
There's blood everywhere,
and--and--and Stacy...
and one of
the other passengers was hurt.
How did it happened?
Who attacked?
I don't know.
Maybe the escaped prisoner?
I can't think of anyone else.
Look, Megan,
we've turned around...
and we'll land
the first place we can find.
And the only way back is
through the center of the storm.
You need to get the passengers
back to their seats now.
Okay.
Ow.
Oh.
I'm scared, Meg.
Aah!
Oh, God!
God!
.Aah!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Aah! Aah!
Aah! Fuck!
Get out!
Help! Help me!
Help me! Help me!
Oh, shit!
They're gonna kill us all!
I should go check
on the passengers.
Open the door! Help me!
For Christ's sake,
they're gonna kill us all!
Open this fuckin' door!
God damn it! Help me!
Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Bill!
Hey, hey, what's goin' on?
- Oh, shit!
- Doc, what's goin' on, man?
Oh, shit! I can't explain!
We got to get out of here!
They're gonna kill us!
Wait! Calm down!
Calm down. What's goin' on?
I don't want to die.
We're gonna die!
Be very quiet.
Don't let them come get us!
Aaah!
Come on.
What happened?
Bill, where are you going?
Come on, come on! Go!
Where?
The back galley-
the floor's two-feet thick.
It's the only safe place.
No, I can't. I can't.
My wife is upstairs.
Oh, shit.
Well, get her and get back there
as soon as you can.
Come on, now! Come on!
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Come on!
Aah! No!
- Hey, hey, you go.
- Tell me something.
- Help me get this open.
- What's going on?
It's the only place
we can find.
Hey. shh! Shh!
Tell me something.
Be quiet.
Good, good, good.
Hey, you, you get in there.
- Wait!
- See if you can see anything.
Go on. Get up. Get up.
Do you see anything?
Okay, be very quiet.
Come on, baby.
Gimme a hand.
God damn it.
You know you fucked up, right?
Asshole.
Stacy?
No--oh!
Ohm
- Duck!
- Aah!
Aah!
Oh, my God.
You all right?
No bites? No--
We thought...We thought...
What? That it was me gnawing
on all the passengers?
No. I'm a vegetarian.
Ugh!
Hey!
Let go of me!
The overall feeling among the
scientists working on this...
is that we're dealing
with a serum transfer virus.
This virus is without
a known vaccine or cure...
but this type virus transfer
is only through bodily fluid...
and then most effectively...
blood from an infected victim
enters a cut or saliva.
The Medcon scientists believed
they could make this work...
despite the side effects...
that are being brought back
from the dead.
In fact, they looked upon
these side effects as a benefit.
Mm-hmm.
Let me paraphrase these notes...
that we found
on Dr. Bennett's desk.
They wanted this virus
as a bioweapon...
to keep soldiers fighting after
they were mortally wounded...
to release a captive enemy
infected with the virus...
and let him infect others
until they all kill each other.
I'm going to recommend to you
and to the President...
that we destroy
Flight 2-3-9...
before it can reach
a populated area.
Let me get this straight.
You want our forces to follow
a shoot-to-kill order...
regarding
this civilian aircraft?
We've had no communication
with the aircraft.
We must assume the cargo
has been breached...
and that the virus has spread...
throughout
the passenger section.
The only chance we have to
contain this is to vaporize...
every living thing
aboard that aircraft...
before the virus can reach
a major population center.
Do you concur?
I'm afraid I do.
Can you get me
the President, please?
Dear God...
Oh!
Get off of her! Get off!
Get off!
Oh! Oh, my God.
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Get her up!
Oh, my God.
- Oh!
' Shh!
Why? Why'd you do this, huh?
Hey, I'm talkin' to you, man!
It wasn't me.
I was just following orders.
They told me it was
an experiment to extend life.
I had no idea there'd be
these crazy side effects.
Well, look around you, asshole.
Your side effects have
eaten half the passengers.
Hey. Hey, I don't have
to listen to you.
You were
the one that seemed like...
you were givin' all the orders.
You were the one that
the cop was talking to...
and you were the one
that sent the others below.
I heard all of that.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
It wasn't me, I tell you.
Hey, keep your voice down.
Yeah, well,
you just keep talking.
You'll draw their attention.
Aaah!
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Oh!
It's startin' to get
really tight in here.
Yeah, yeah.
I think we're getting closer.
Ray! Ray, I'm hurt!
Open up! Hurry!
Ray!
Hurry!
God!
Aah!
Oh, my God.
I don't know
if that's gonna work.
It has to work.
Oh, God.
Oh!
Let's get the other side, hmm?
Okay.
Two in the chest,
one in the balls...
that's what I say.
It's barricaded.
Ah, Frank, I see you!
He did that?
Busy little beaver.
Raah!
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Come here, Frank.
Aah!
Where have you been?
Where have I been?
Where have you been?!
I have been up and down
this plane!
So have I!
Back off!
Oh, my God.
Aaah!
- Shit! Aah!
- Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Statistically speaking,
the tail section...
is the safest place
to be in a crash.
Of course--
Frank, not now.
Help me with this.
Yeah, man.
Go! Get something else!
Get something else!
- I am!
- Do it!
Right there! Right there!
I can't lift--
There's a--Wait.
Frank!
Wait, wait, wait. Shh.
Quiet, quiet.
Listen.
I don't hear anything.
Go.
Hold on! Hold on!
- Ohhh!
- Aah!
Bennett!
Oh, my God, Tammy!
- We got to go. We got to go.
- Huh?
We got to go. We got to go.
GO. Go! go'
All right,
we need to find anything...
that can be used as a weapon.
Does anyone have anything sharp?
They confiscated
my toenail clippers...
pearl handle,
with matching tweezers...
quite lovely.
Damn, Frank.
You should have brought those.
You could have saved the day.
You never know.
How much ammunition
you have left?
I got five in here
and one clip.
What about you?
One full clip, five more.
Shit.
Hey, maybe we could
electrocute the bastards.
No, don't do that!
Aah!
I guess that
could have gone better.
Frank, you stupid shit.
Please tell me you're dead.
Megan!
Aaah!
Where'd you find him?
The auxiliary lights.
Oh, my God.
The auxiliary lights will come
on any second...l hope.
Frank, fix 'em.
We need to find weapons.
Still no answer
from the cockpit.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe everyone's dead.
Oh, my God, we're gonna die.
Megan, listen to me.
Listen to me.
We're not gonna die.
No. Okay.
No, we're not gonna die,
I promise you.
- I need your help.
- Right.
- I need you to be strong.
Oh! Oh!
Unh!
Did you see that?
What the hell was that?
Listen.
Someone's up there.
Don't shoot!
Aah!
We need to have a plan
to get this plane down safely.
Does anyone know if
the pilot's still alive?
I tried to reach him.
Try him again.
Okay.
Nothing?
No, no.
The captain's dead.
We're on autopilot.
So, what? We just fly
around until they get us?
Or until we run out of fuel.
Actually,
that might be preferred.
Run out of fuel?
Yeah!
Hey, hey, hey, we got to get
to the flight deck...
and check on the captain.
We got to do this now before
they start coming at us.
I don't think
you have enough bullets...
to make it to the cockpit.
The guard down below
has a weapon.
We need that weapon.
That's our only chance.
So, what?
You're just gonna go down there?
- Down there?
- Yes!
How do we know he didn't
use all the ammo already?
We don't know, Frank.
It's good to know you
still have a sense of humor...
at a time like this.
I know it's not much to look at,
but with any luck...
it's gonna buy me enough time
to get that weapon...
and get back here
without tearing the plane apart.
Why are you doing this?
I made a promise to someone.
I keep my promises.
I have radar contact
with Concord 2-3-9.
Should have visual
in two minutes.
Burrows, in case this blows up
anything, uh, important...
do you mind if I take
out your new girlfriend?
Hey, Bennett!
Got something for you!
Aah!
Roger. Try to establish contact.
You have three minutes
from my mark.
Mark minus three minutes.
Roger that. Minus three minutes.
Try to establish contact.
I'm gonna circle and signal.
Look.
I'd like to think
that's the cavalry, but, um...
What do you mean?
We don't have much time.
Aren't they gonna save us?
No, they're not gonna save us.
There's just us.
Unless we let him know
we're alive...
he's gonna shoot us down.
They can't do that.
He's right.
Unless we answer them...
they're gonna fire
the missile at us.
What do we do?
We answer 'em.
Someone needs to get to
the cockpit and signal that jet.
Does anybody know
how to fly a jet?
Anyone? Anyone?
You can fly a jet?
Well, not officially,
but I know most of the basics.
Basics?
Course, it's been awhile.
We just need to get
to the radio and use it.
We need to go now, Frank.
Aww.
All right. Count me in.
No, no, no,
Billy, don't leave me here.
I'll go. I'll go
No, no. You stay here.
I'm gonna do my part.
- Why?
- I'll see you soon, baby.
I'll see you soon.
Let's go.
I got such a big mouth.
Nice drive.
Command, this is 4-3-1.
Go ahead.
Two-three-nine has no one
in control that I can see.
Repeat. Two-three-nine...
has no one
in control that I can see.
Aah!
Billy! Billy!
- No, wait!
- Let me go!
Billy!
Aaah!
Come on, baby!
Aah!
Get out of my way,
you stupid bitch!
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Yah!
You don't know
who you dealin' with!
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
No, no, no, that's it.
That's it, I'm done.
You guys go. You guys go.
I gotta wait for Anna.
Go! Go!
No response to my signals.
You are clear to engage 2-3-9.
Command, please repeat.
Roger that.
Clear to engage contact 2-3-9.
L 901 you.
Aaah!
Aah!
Aaaah!
Hold on, baby.
I love you.
I love you, too, baby.
I always have.
Is that you, Bennett?
Shit.
Come on, motherfucker.
I want to make sure you keep...
that shit-eating grin
on your face...
all the way to hell.
Aaah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aaah!
Aah!
Command, this is 4-3-1.
It appears that
engine number three is burning.
Aaah!
Aaah! Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
She's gummin' me to death.
Damn you! Ohh!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Where's the autopilot?
I don't know!
You're asking me, Frank?
This is different!
Don't yell at me!
I'm not yellin'!
I have lock.
Um...uh, we're alive.
Repeat, we're alive.
Abort. Abort.
Missile away.
Incoming object.
They must have launched
the missile.
Frank, we got seconds!
I know!
Where is the autopilot?!
I don't know!
Collision imminent.
Here, here.
Autopilot off.
All right.
What are you doin'?
- Ready?
- Uh.
We got live civilians.
Aborting. Repeat, I am aborting.
I'm out!
Aah!
Hold on!
Pull up.
Aah!
Aaah!
Hold on! Hold on!
Aah!
Aaaah!
Jesus!
Pull up.
You did it, Frank.
Whoo!
Sure.
Oh, shit.
Frank?
Frank!
Yes!
Mountain!
Pull back!
Back!
Mountain!
Ohm
We did it.
We did it, my friend.
Would you ever consider
goin' out with an ex-cop?
I went out with a cop once.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. The only thing
he was good for...
was scratching my back
when I couldn't reach.
Do you ever get
that itch anymore?
All the time.
Aaah!
♪ Don't blink, baby ♪
♪ Look out, baby,
there's no time to waste ♪
♪ Bite down, baby,
or they'll take your taste ♪
♪ Right now, baby,
'cause tomorrow's too late ♪
♪ Can't afford to wait ♪
♪ Right behind you, baby,
ready to strike ♪
♪ Anytime it wants
and not when you like ♪
♪ Best not let your party
be a surprise ♪
♪ A word to the wise ♪
♪ Picture's not so pretty
when they've printed your last ♪
♪ Especially when your monument
says "over too fast" ♪
♪ Don't blink, baby,
it's gonna pass by ♪
gotta live till you die ♪
♪ Don't blink, baby,
don't even try to fight it ♪
♪ Time is gonna shrink
in a blink, blink ♪
♪ Blink of an eye ♪
♪ When it's over, baby,
where will you be? ♪
♪ Lookin' back
upon your whole history ♪
♪ Shocked, regrettin'
everything that you see ♪
♪ Total disbelief J'
♪ Mi came y mis huesos
ya no me pertenecen ♪