-Valik's here!
-He's here?
They've found another one.
There's going to be not a treasure left
by the time she gets here.
Mark the location!
That's the French mast!
And over there, crystals!
They're all coming.
All except one
All right, follow Crystals.
When he dives, we dive.
Maybe we'll get luck and find what it is down there.
Hey! Look at that, Jimmy, look!
Why isn't she slowing down?
-You ask her.
-No way.
Hello, boys! You're wet!
Half the world's trade is already here.
And you make us wait.
But you know I can't resist to be defied.
Lara, tell us, what's all this fuss about it?
What does everyone think is down there?
I don't know what everybody thinks is down there, but
I think it's the Luna Temp.
The Luna Temp?
My sons, if it is not on television, forget it.
It's a temple built by Alexander the Great.
who was Greek, in case you don't know.
-Yeah, yeah.
Alexander collected treasures from all over the world.
He stored them in two places.
The majority went to his library in Egypt.
But his most priced possessions,
went here,
the Luna Temple.
By law, no one was allowed to record its location.
And in 330 B.C., it was...
swallowed by the sea...
destroyed, during a volcanic eruption,
lost forever,
until yesterday.
Even half the temple is intact,
it would still be the greatest find
since the pyramids.
The others heading to this area here
along the shore
-That's based on the currents.
-Yes.
-Oh. This is it goes, it's why I was late. -Oh.
It's geological.
Take him two hours after the quake.
The epic enter was here,
five miles northeast of us.
But, look at the current along the shore now
Wait, they've shifted.
So, while they're all diving there,
the wind will actually be...
Here.
Let's go!
Something wrong?
First Alexander doesn't report the temple's location.
Then God washed it from the earth
with a volcano.
Now even the currents changed.
Lara, maybe this temple is not meant to be found.
Everything lost is meant to be found.
Don't worry!
Incredible!
It's unbelievable!
God!
It's huge.
Wonderful!
Jimmy, this is wonderful
-Do you see what I see?
-Oh my god!
Oh my god!
-It's incredible!
Nicky, look at these!
We're going to be rich!
Hey, Lara!
What do you say to two handsome Greek partners?
When you find two, let me know.
Heard? She's talking about you. -No, you
Luckily gold coins...give me that...
Lara, what is that?
It's mine.
What is she doing?
Lara! That column is collapsing!
After shows.
I think that's the sign leave!
Two minutes.
Lara, we need to leave now!
We've got to go!
-Keep packing! -Do you think it's going to collapse?
-You take those two.
We have to hurry up!
We're going to go,
we're going to go now. Come on!
They're coming up!
Lara!
Lara, it's us, Hillary and Bryce!
She's disorientated, that's normal after three days.
Nice day for a dip?
Gentlemen, there is an expression,
"It's not nice to fool mother nature."
Yet that is precisely what
I've been doing for some time now.
The will be sorren gas for Mr. Zap.
improved typhoid for Mr. Croft to use in the Balkans...
enhanced colorof for Mr. Devalia
But, while these weapons served their purpose,
there have always been limitations.
Stable diseases aren't lethal.
deadly ones burn out too quickly.
Mother Nature can only be fooled so much.
Deploy my weapon, and your enemies, however great,
will collapse...
not unlike Mr. Monza is collapsing right now
What the hell is going on?
Monza told MI-6 about this meeting.
That's why the changed orfication
He was going to turn me over
to the menasic asylum of the West
A smart man would have known
I was onto him.
would never have got on the plane
but I knew you would, Mr. Monze
because you actually thought you could fool me.
That, gentlemen,
is the sound of a traitor dying.
That was an accelerated form of Ebola,
the deadliest disease known to man
highly contagious
However, as with all known diseases
there exist dog piles of anti serums in the West.
There is no anti-serum for what I'm offering you
no treatment
no vaccine, no cure.
The modern world has never seen
anything like what I've uncovered.
Uncovered?
Yes, I branched that.
Archaeology.
07744681, that is the account at the
largest bank in Bonn.
$100 million dollars each, if you please.
[Hong Kong Chai Wan Private Airport]
Where's Chen Lo?
He's got the orb, but MI-6 is onto him.
How?
He doesn't he know,
but rather than risk bringing it to you,
he's waiting.
I have just told a cabin full of men
about Pandora.
the clock cannot be researched
Tell Chen Lo to bring the orb to me at once.
Find the killers,
don't take it out on me
Bryce, what have we got?
I haven't even finished loading
the images from your camera yet.
We've got references to an orb.
I took the liberty of checking.
Historic inventories of the Luna Temple
do not list any ore.
I want you both to list
every orb ever mentioned in Greek history.
Ah
That's a...libel...to be.
Thousands
Then we'll read thousands
Start with that one.
Perhaps you gentlemen would like
some tea while you're waiting?
No, they wouldn't.
Tea is for guests.
The door is for intruders.
Lara, these men are from MI-6.
Yes, I can tell from their soft hands and pressed suits.
that these are the men who made decisions
and leave the dirty work for others
I have no interest in...
His name is Chen Lo
along with his brother Xien,
he run a gang of Chinese bandits
known as Shay Ling.
They deal in gun, diamonds and antiquities, anything that
Chen Lo can sell them in the black market.
They've followed you the moment
you arrived at Santralina.
where they killed your friend Gus
and sank his boat.
Why?
For this.
After you were picked up in sea
our listening post in Mota intercepted that fax
it was sent from Chen Lo to a
man named Jonathan Reiss.
What, a scientist?
won a Nobel Prize.
He is now the foremost designer of
biological weapons in the world.
His creation has been in the heart of
every active bio-terror in the past 15 years.
Reiss's disdain for life is legendary.
He has no political agenda,
He doesn't care who his weapons kill or why.
A modern-day Dr. Mengelen.
We know Chen Lo followed you
in order to obtain the orb.
we also know he'll deliver it to Reiss.
What we don't know is why.
Candidly, that terrifies us
Pandora's box.
Reiss is going to use the orb
to find Pandora's Box.
Do you mean the Greek myth?
Pandora was given a box by God,
told not to open it, she does
and unleashes pain into the world.
That's the Sunday school version, yes.
How do you think life began?
Shooting stars, primordial ooze.
In 2200 B.C.. an Egyptian pharaoh
found a place he named the
Cradle of Life
where, we life, we began
and there he found a box
the box which brought life to earth
the pharaoh opened the box
but all that was left inside
was ramonte, or empty life,
the plague which came as the companion to life.
Companion?
Nature is about balance.
All the world comes and passes.
yin and yang, right and wrong, men and women,
what's a pleasure with pain?
What did this plague do?
It leveled the pharaoh's army.
The pharaohs's son dispatched
the finest soldiers to take the box,
and transport it to the end of the world.
2000 years later, Alexander the Great reached India
where his army was ravaged by a plague.
After one of his men found a box
among some of the men
India, that's what the pharaoh's men wrote it.
Alexander felt that
the box was too powerful to be trusted to
any man
so he returned it to its home
the Cradle of Life.
And it has not been seen since.
And this Cradle of Life is where?
No one knows.
Alexander found it using a map
that was with the box.
a map he then hid from the world
But the name he gave this map
was Mati and the literal translation for
the word Mati is "eye".
it orbits the map
hidden in the Luna Temple by Alexander
And Reiss will use it to find
Pandora's Box
And when he does he opens it
The markings definitely form a pattern, but
even if I figure out what they represent
we still can't read the whole map
because we're going to get past
the view of these, see?
We have to figure out how to read it.
Right, thank you.
On behalf of her Majesty, we firmly request
that you find and recover this box before Dr. Reiss.
Oh! Now that I have her Majesty's permission
Tell me where to find the orb.
The last we heard, it was somewhere in China
with Chen Lo and Sha Ling
finding them would be never to impossible
we'll assign two of our best agents to help.
I don't want them.
With due respect, your expertise is archaeology, doesn't...
I didn't say that I don't need help
But your agents would never get me to Chen Lo in time
I need an insider
someone who knows the Shei Ling
their methods, their hideouts.
I need Terry Sheridan.
Not in a million year
not if you're the last man on earth.
Terry Sheridan, former commander of the Royal Marine
turned a mercenary, and a traitor.
You don't honestly expect me to put that man
on a trail to hold weapons
you can turn around and
sell to the highest bidder?
[Kazahkstan, Barla Kala Prison]
Open!
I'm your host, Armika.
Welcome to Fantasy Island!
Croft.
Hello, Terry.
So what do you think of my new place?
Not quite Croft manner.
What, a key to your heart?
To a flat in Zurich.
You can pick another city if you want.
Your record will be expound, your citizenship restored.
Why?
MI-6.
Now, without meet me first with devil?
Well, you can pick one.
because MI-6 would also arrange a new identity
Oh yeah, do you think I need their help?
Oh, having two faces doesn't count.
So what do I have to do?
You need to take me to the Shay Ling.
She who?
There's a man named Chen Lo
who took something from me and
I want it back.
Yeah. Is that you, or MI-6?
Also, I've arranged the government
to wire you 5 million in sterling
when we succeed.
you can call it second chance, man.
All right, then insurance for you?
I don't need any.
You and I working alone?
And it's easier to see through you, that way.
So what if afterwards
MI-6 decide that me back in the world
isn't such a great idea?
Then I'll feel sorry for whomever
they get to come after you.
Do you have authorization to kill me, Croft?
Any time, for any reason.
So why don't you just do it now?
What is it they see?
Hell have no fury.
You're not that good.
Shay Ling and the groove's Croft.
They move constantly.
And they're in almost the most
remote mountain region in China.
Region?
You have to do better than that.
Get me into China, and I'll get you to them in a day.
No guns, no women, no weapons, when you come.
Shay Ling has spies all over China.
We have to get into country undetected
so we'll slip into Beijing, and we go by truck.
Truck?
I wasn't thinking about
something a little faster.
A little faster?
Well, this is a little faster.
But the Chinese will pick the part.
There won't be any part to find.
Will there be any of us to fight?
-Ready? now!
-Ready for what?
What you did was good, Croft.
I'll give you that.
But we're never going to feign
the equal of a place like this
ni3 hao3
It's lovely to see you
So is everything ready?
Yes. Your clothes, guns, and knives, are over there.
And I took the liberty of tuning your bike.
-May I?
-Yes.
Lara.
Ah, what is the happy couple up to?
Accessorizing.
Where are we all on reading the orb?
All maps have a key, Lara, scale or legend, yes?
The orb's key is not on orbit,
it must have been lost.
or somewhere in the temple
Go through every image I took
start with the ones near the orb.
key must have been linked to it in some way.
Right, well then...
It's unlike Lara to take a partner.
Where are you two going?
We're taking a nice little trip.
breathe some fresh mountain air
stop by my friends the Shay Ling
Shay Ling watch all the roads.
We have to go around the back.
We'll go straight.
Maybe you didn't hear me
Shay Ling have men on every road
from here to Luo Yang.
Not every road.
Getting rusty, are we?
Oh, I think it's coming back.
I expect the move is gone.
I don't expect anything from an English woman.
Good, cause you're not going to get anything.
Party's over.
From now on it's by foot.
I see you can reconsider that no gun rule.
No.
And don't be looking at my ass.
So where do I fit in?
What do you mean?
You'll the guide.
I mean...when you think back
on the vast scheme of hugely adventurous life
where do I fit in?
Is that a love of your life?
Or just another bump on the road?
Was that time well spent?
Four months, whether good or bad.
Come on I had to be more than that, am I right?
All right.
It was five months.
You're not laughing at me?
No. It's the fact that I used to find you charming.
I am charming.
You're late.
The bank, do it.
You won't see again in a hour, maybe.
What's this?
It's not there.
There's no orb.
Is it anything you can tell me about this?
Hello.
I take it you don't like your messenger
I didn't, but I did like the men lost in a temple.
You underestimated Lady Croft.
I underestimated how much this orb is worth.
So many horrible diseases in the world
things that are particularly susceptible to our children
You'll never know when you'll be holding a little sheal or
or tie by the hand with the mysterious illness in their bodies
If you kill them,
and I'll give your orb to Lady Croft.
My men tell me, she's a few miles away from here
as we speak.
I wonder how much she would pay
I'll pay you an additional $12 million dollars.
It will be yours when she has delivered the orb to me
along with Lady Croft's body.
I don't think you know where they are.
You're impossible you know that.
I think you pretended to know
so I would get you out.
This isn't a tomb Croft,
and Shay Ling aren't mummies.
They're killers.
But if you don't trust me,
I'm sorry I have to do this
but you're wasting time.
You want to shoot me, shoot me.
Personally, I'd rather you do it than them.
bu xu dong (Stay right there!)
Well, Terry, what part of "never come back again"
didn't you understand?
You wanted to fight the Shay Ling.
The only way to get into their place
is as their prisoners.
You want to tell me that in jail before.
Would you have believed me?
Make Chen Lo a better offer than his buyer
you cross them.
Even if his buyer is Jonathan Reiss.
You may have told me that lot in gem before.
Were you really going to kill me?
Oh, I bet you would have
I've seen her in action.
Didn't Terry tell you?
The last time any of us saw him,
he was riding away with a truck
full of my many vases
and sitting next to him, was his sister
Oh, how is she?
You
shouldn't come here
They got me out of prison
this here lady has a good offer
better than Reiss.
Really?
Should I take it?
Take it.
Or better yet,
you and I run some horrendous thing
back to the British for triple.
Let's talk.
Not you, Terry.
Lady Croft and I.
You wait here.
Catch up.
There will be four minute.
Terrific!
There's something I think you will have appreciated
This is the largest terracotta warriors I've found.
The king of Qin made them
for use in the afterlife
to fend off enemies he may
Sounds like we could both use it there.
I'd be happy to sell some to you.
I hope you're as entrepreneurial with the Orb.
You've lost men, I've lost men
I see no reason we should both lose again.
If I want double, would Reiss offer it to me?
Is it here?
It's worth a lot.
Well then, if you know that,
you'll know Reiss will also kill you
the moment you give them to him.
And your government would guarantee my safety?
No.
But I will.
That must hurt, saying that to me.
Take the offer.
You presume to give me orders?
Take the offer before it expires.
No.
Then I would have to force you.
Then I would have to kill you.
Has it been four minutes yet?
Loverboy,
It's too bad, you're on the wrong side
Tell me where the orb is,
and I'll spare your life.
The Flower Pagoda in Shanghai, 9 PM.
This is mine.
Now, we're even.
Freeze! Put your hands up!
Remember that no gun rule? I reconsidered.
Lara, there was a staircase we could have used.
Lorie, are you all right?
rushing, I'm on my way to Shanghai
And I need you to look at something for me.
It's in the Luna Temple near the orb.
And I'm betting it's key to those markings.
She's holding some sort of musical instrument.
It's sound.
That's brilliant.
Key must have linked into it some way
I'll start decoding the images we have.
-Good.
-You give us the rest, bye, Lara.
-Miss you.
-Bye.
[Shanghai]
Flower Pagoda, 8:50 pm
Trouble is coming, let's go.
well.
Just like old times.
I think that's the first time you've
actually smelt because of me
Why did you do it?
I started thinking.
I was...tired of doing things for somebody else's way
and it was always going to be somebody else's way.
So you abandoned your men and
betrayed your country.
Leaving my men and my country
that didn't actually hurt as much as I thought.
Believe me you would do it.
that hard to follow Croft.
Do you know why you and I got
along for a while?
No.
We are two of a kind, me and you.
We are nothing alike.
-I don't think we're alike.
-Um hm.
But do you think we're a pair?
say it's the same coin.
My men have the roof covered.
Why don't you set down at the square instead.
That way, my men would also have things covered.
Okay, fine.
Okay, so, let's go!
We're arriving at the square.
We're in the wrong position.
-Steels? -No time.
-Wet tapes?
-No.
I've got a plan!
Stay here, wait for my signal.
Here's your money, come and get it.
Wait for my signal, pal.
Give me that box!
You give me the money first.
Get out of here.
Go, run her over!
-Yeah.
-We tried it your way,
now we'll do it mine.
Bring it...now.
Okay!
Come on, come on! Hold it up!
Now we're going to your brother.
We're too late.
Lara, what are you doing?
Take us up!
Move! Go!
Let's go, move!
I'm getting tired of you
pointing that thing at me.
-Are you okay?
-Never better.
It looks like we've lost the orb.
Actually you don't think I'd go
vaulting in the thin air for nothing, do you?
I've put a tracer on the crate.
Got it!
Look!
Impressive!
[Hong Kong]
Our weapons...in the middle of the city, no way.
He must have dumped that in the crater
No, it's here
One of the buildings?
No.
It's exactly where we're standing.
There's part of me that always
allow for the possibility
that Pandora's Box was just a legend.
But now I know it's there.
She escaped.
She has no idea where we are.
We take no chances.
Have everything we need
to manufacture an antidote transferred to the jet.
I need an orb for two people
Mid city, soon.
What? Are you crazy?
Who is that?
Piece of cake
Wang Jie, come in.
Hello.