Keep going.
How long do you got? Good.
Here comes security.
You've got three seconds.
Yo.
We had them.
All right. It was a good run.
That was close.
Better than coming in third.
Next week. Next week.
Yeah, all right.
Are you ready, baby?
What's up?
There's Michael.
Here we go.
MAN: I know you're looking for
some good company tonight.
Say hello, dear.
Hey, ladies.
WOMAN: Hello.
The Latina.
Man, that's Miss Cuba.
Hi.
Hi. How are you?
And the tall Jamaican,
who's she? Miss Jamaica?
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, yeah.
One for three
or two for five K.
All right. Let's go for three
and bring them to the
after party at the mansion.
(NUMB/ENCORE PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
Hey, darling.
Two Bacardi mojitos
and a gin and tonic.
Lemon or lime?
Lime.
Where you from?
Lisboa. That's in Portugal.
But you got your tan in Miami?
What's your name?
Rita.
Rita. Sonny.
See you later, Rita.
Hey, Michael.
(LAUGHS)
Neptune.
Here are your dates.
Hey, baby.
Here you go.
Let me hit you now.
No, no, no.
Please, put it away.
Be cool.
Come on.
Hit me later.
What's with number three?
She's sick, man.
That's cool. I'll go with two.
Let's go, sweetheart.
NEPTUNE: Do you know how much
I'm losing tonight?
GIRL: No.
(GROANING)
(NEPTUNE SPEAKING CREOLE)
BOUNCER: Where you going?
SONNY: Easy. Easy.
Neptune should ease up
on the merchandise.
Flip the girls upstairs
and we got him.
His day will come.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
SONNY: Hello?
ALONZO ON PHONE: Sonny?
Yeah. Who's this?
Sonny?
Alonzo?
Alonzo, I can't talk.
We're in the middle
of a deal right now.
Take care of Leonetta for me.
Ask Ricardo to do that.
I gave up nothing on you.
They're on their own.
It's all their deal, anyway.
Fuck them.
(CAR HORN BLARING)
Alonzo, what are you
talking about?
I'm falling by the house,
and then I'm gone.
So whatever you can
do for her, okay, Sonny?
Alonzo.
Goodbye.
What is it?
Alonzo Stevens.
Something's wrong.
He told you to
look after Leonetta for him.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
FBI Miami.
This is Detective Crockett,
Miami-Dade PD.
Patch me through to your SAC.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
RICO ON MACHINE: Leonetta,
it's Rico. Give me a call back
as soon as you get a chance.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPING)
This is ASAC John Fujima.
Detective Crockett.
What's your Miami-Dade
badge number
and date of birth?
447-Charlie-1292.
SONNY ON PHONE: 07-02-70.
FBI OFFICER ON PHONE:
Miami-Dade PD Tech.
Bobby G., it's Rico.
Hey, that transponder we had
on Alonzo Stevens' Bentley,
it still running?
When's the last time
we used it?
I don't know.
We ain't worked him
in six months.
Okay. So?
SONNY: One of your deals
may be going bad.
Confidential informant
we cut loose to you guys.
CI's name is Alonzo Stevens.
He called us.
We haven't spoken to him
in six months.
How do I discuss this over
an open phone line?
How the hell do I know?
We got the phone call
from Alonzo on an open line.
That is the hand
we have been dealt
at 11:47 on Saturday night.
Now, I do not know what case
you have him on,
but whatever it is,
it is going bad,
and it sounds like
it is going bad right now.
It's a preliminary
meet and greet.
RICO ON PHONE: Meet and greet?
You flash me yours,
I'll flash you mine?
FUJIMA: Who are you?
Ricardo Tubbs.
My partner.
Yeah, deal goes down
another time, another place.
So, what?
No HRT weapons team out there?
FUJIMA: That's right.
Colombians? Russians?
White supremacists.
And that tape is not gonna
look good in court.
Aryan Brotherhood? Mongols?
Nazi Low Riders? What?
We think Aryan Brotherhood,
but we don't know for sure.
What's up?
Get Michael out of there.
What about Neptune?
It's Neptune's lucky night.
What else
did Stevens tell you?
He said that it went bad,
that he didn't give us up.
Told us goodbye.
ZITO: Rico,
we got the Bentley.
Hey, he just got
on the 95 southbound
from the 195 causeway.
We got meth,
ice, glass, Es, Ks, ex,
Mitsus, Ames, Colombian H.
Ice.
Party down with the coke.
You're looking at 92% pure.
Not like that jumped-on powder
they sell up in Nuyorico.
Never seen green?
You got the green.
We got the goods.
We party.
Larry'll call you in the a.m.
About quantity and money,
time and place.
Hey, lvan!
My brother.
How long have you been working
with the FBI?
(ENGINE STARTING)
Alonzo, pull over!
Pull over!
Stay back!
What'd you do?
I fronted their undercover
team to these guys like usual,
you know?
They're Feds,
Russian speakers.
I was the middleman.
What, 15%?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
to set up the meet.
They grabbed Leonetta.
They took Leonetta.
I gave them up, man.
Gave up the Feds. Everything.
Everything I knew.
Rico, I got to go home.
Got people there now.
How did they
get onto you, Alonzo?
How the hell do I know?
They knew one Russian was FBI
from the get-go, so...
They knew I knew.
Rico, I gotta go.
Alonzo. Alonzo.
(RICO DIALING PHONE)
(RINGING)
Rico, I got to go.
I got to go.
Alonzo. Alonzo!
I gotta fucking go!
Hello?
(HANGS UP)
You don't...
You don't need to go home.
They said
they wouldn't hurt her, man.
They lied.
RICO: Alonzo!
SONNY: No!
Prints on the fridge.
Hold on.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah.
CASTILLO: Where are you?
What's your QTH?
Just a couple blocks away.
We can see the lights.
Turn around.
Turn around?
Look, we know these people.
Meet me in 15 minutes,
Standard Park.
What the hell just happened?
What was that?
Who's this?
He needs to talk to you.
I'm Fujima.
We talked on the phone.
So, this was your operation?
Yes, at command level.
We trusted our informant,
Alonzo, to you, and you
got his whole family killed?
What, did you
jump some amateurs into
a game they ain't ready for?
What the fuck happened, man?
Three men got killed!
SONNY: And so did our...
Cool down.
They discovered
my guys were undercover,
and we don't know how.
This was an interagency
task force, DEA, ATF,
U.S. Customs.
The leak could have come
from any one unit.
I gotta assume
my operational security
is compromised.
Compromised? Your whole
op sec is blown. You're
stone cold dead in the water.
Meanwhile, it does not track.
White supremacist gang?
White prison gangs is tweakers
and meth labs
and trailer parks.
Bouncing the old lady around
until they get busted back.
And how did they get
all high tech with
sophisticated counterintel?
And what we here
talking to you for, anyway?
Miami-Dade wasn't
part of the task force.
Oh.
They don't know you.
So, you want to recruit us?
Identify them. Who are they?
How did they cut into us?
How do we cut into them?
How do we get
all close and personal
with them?
Make a buy. That worked well.
Sell to them? We supply them?
No, they got
a steady stream of supply.
Colombian named José Yero,
midlevel trafficker.
Okay. So what about Yero?
Can we get to them
through Yero?
FUJIMA: Possible.
What does he need?
Money laundering? Transpo?
Transpo.
He outsources
his transportation.
Okay.
Do we run an undercover
on José Yero?
So we transport
a load for Yero
into this group?
So can we run a load for Yero
It's a question.
He transships out of Haiti.
Flies his product in from
Colombia, hires someone to
run it from Haiti into here.
This is a FLIR image
of someone's go-fast boats
running in a Yero load.
FUJIMA: AWAC shot it.
That's all we got.
All right. If they do this,
I'd like them deputized
as federal under OCDETF
for the purposes of this case.
Fine by me.
Because your op sec is blown,
your agency can't know
anything about how they do
whatever it is they do.
That's why I came alone.
Thank you.
Sorry about your men.
What'd you spot?
Go-fast boats running
that close? On radar
they look like one, not two.
Total darkness?
Plus, who runs four 250 Mercs
off a deep-V hull?
Sal Maguda.
He that good?
Oh, yeah.
SONNY: Bleaching it down.
Must have just unloaded.
RICO: Who are we?
How's your Creole?
(RICO SHOUTING IN CREOLE)
Do you know
whose load this is?
It's José Yero's.
What are you doing?
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Hey, Nicholas, my ace.
What's up?
Everything's good. You?
RICO ON PHONE: We good.
We all good.
As a matter of fact,
we're looking to charge up
your cash flow. Hold on.
Nicholas, how you doing?
Sonny. What's up?
Somebody's something's
got to go somewhere,
some when.
Not too distant in the future.
Except he had
transpo problems.
Call Colombia.
Man, that's José Yero.
Really?
NICHOLAS: He is AUC, you know.
Colombian right-wing
paramilitaries.
You know who they are?
They are vertically
integrated. They are...
You mean, they walk around
with constant erections?
No. They farm, process,
produce, export...
I know what it means.
No, see,
it gives them attitude.
A player negotiates too hard
and you never hear
from him again,
'cause these guys
kill everything!
I gotta know
what's the skinny.
It's none of your
fucking business.
It can come back on me, baby.
It can't come back
on you, baby.
Am I assured of that?
Hey, sunshine.
When has Rico or Sonny
ever lied to you, huh?
I mean, when has anything
Rico told you not happened
exactly like he said?
RICO: You saying I lie to you?
NICHOLAS: No,
I'm not saying that...
Yes, you are.
NICHOLAS: It's just
there's variables, you know?
Randomness, see? That's why.
"That's why," what?
Well, why, like,
if you can't deliver,
this group goes from zero
to high-order violence
like that.
You made a 15% commission
off three money-laundering
prosecutions
I put you into,
you know, which is why
you live in your $4 million
condo.
And you question
Rico and Sonny?
Fuck that. I will cap your
skanky ass and throw it
off that goddamn balcony.
Yeah, then we can kick back
and watch Marlins highlights
on this 65" plasma.
After we clean this place up.
Don't you ever
put anything away?
Plus he's gonna commission
José Yero for putting you
to José Yero.
Anybody looking at
his ill-gotten gains?
IRS looking into his shit?
SONNY: Any reason
this does not go down?
That's the sound of
air rapidly filling the vacuum
created by your departed body.
On account of how fast
I remanded your ass
back into custody.
Why is this happening to me?
Because you
lead a life of crime.
Can't do time,
don't mess with crime.
SONNY: He's cool.
He'll make the call.
NICHOLAS: All I know,
these guys are quiet,
they do big volume
with a lot of product.
Can you vouch for them?
Yeah. Of course
I vouch for them.
All right. Check them out
and you better be right.
Hey, you.
Wake up.
What happened to you?
Aren't you excited to see me?
I can't talk about it.
This is all right.
(GRUNTS)
I'm just joking.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Go to sleep.
Go to sleep right here.
That's it.
Any word?
RICO: Nothing.
Hey, Trudy. Hey, Sonny.
Hey, Trudy.
How you doing, darling?
Who are we here?
It's the same fabricated
fundamentals as before.
TRUDY: Rico.
3-to-5 on assault,
Folsom B-wing,
Pelican Bay.
Sonny, Marine Corps,
Chicago, and 10 plus weapons.
Five out of eight,
and jumped parole.
Pelican Bay,
where you guys hooked up.
And then it goes cold,
'cause presumably you're both
too smart and too fast
to get jacked again.
What about this place?
It'll show up
leased under these aliases.
How'd they test?
And who tested them?
TRUDY: Helene in NYPD.
And she worked through
your false identities,
and then she found your
deeper, hidden,
more criminal selves.
(PHONE RINGING)
SONNY ON PHONE: Yeah.
He's in.
You're on.
The meet's in Haiti.
NICHOLAS: He'll negotiate
the price in person.
Call me after you've landed
in Port-au-Prince,
'cause only when you're
on the ground will he tell me
where you are to go.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Be careful. Be cool.
Approaching.
Turning to heading 340
down to 6,000 feet.
Clear to the ILS runway 1-0
for the approach
to Port-au-Prince.
Why do I get the feeling
everybody knows
we're here 15 blocks out?
'Cause everybody knows
we're here 15 blocks out.
Sit.
José.
Sonny Burnett.
That's my partner, Ricardo.
Thank you for coming down.
So, let's lay it out.
Nicholas say you
run a tight group.
That's nice, 'cause we got
product that's got to move.
Real tight.
We move as fast as FedEx.
Move to where?
To New York,
through South Florida.
Move when?
Right now.
That's kind of all of
an instant.
RICO: That means
only one thing, real fast.
So, the price, is it right?
Price is right.
But how I know if you
any good at this shit?
What's that?
Yeah, your business.
How much volume you do?
Whose product you move?
Who you work with?
Other than Nicholas,
who the fuck knows you?
Well, my mommy
and daddy know me.
And we don't talk about
who we work with.
And we didn't come down here
to audition for business.
Business auditions for us.
And knows all about us,
before they call Nicholas.
That way we don't waste avgas
or our motherfucking time.
(ALL CLAMORING)
SONNY: You want us to be
telling you about our shit?
You can't find out
on your own?
Why do I not buy that?
You with DEA?
The Feeb? What's up?
They targeting
our transpo line?
You with the Man?
You wearing a wire?
RICO: I'm gonna tell you
what's gonna happen.
People gonna come in here,
and you know what
they gonna say?
They're gonna look around
and they're gonna go...
"That's some crazy
motherfucking wallpaper.
What is that?
"Jackson Pollock?"
"No, viejo. That was
José Yero, who got splattered
all over his own wall."
So, we can close
each other's eyes
right now, real fast.
But then ain't nobody
gonna make no money.
ISABELLA: José.
(ISABELLA SPEAKING SPANISH)
So let's talk equipment.
Adam A500s, carbon composite,
real stealthy.
1,400 nautical-mile range,
low and slow.
We like Caravelles and 727 s
to move the product
from source countries
to transshipment
places like here.
Big loads, we like containers.
Smaller loads
into South Florida,
we do go-fast boats.
So, what's the weight?
First, let's talk logistics.
Okay.
You pick up a load,
you fly it in the hole,
we tell you the drop point,
and our people then
move it on up the road.
Now, not so fast. People
at the drop point are
our people, not yours.
You know,
so there's no tweakers,
dopers, first-timers,
people we don't know.
They didn't do time with us,
they ain't doing
crime with us.
Once we pick up the load,
the next time you hear from us
it'll be a date, time,
and a place.
Like, "There's a 18-wheeler
in a parking lot
in north Miami with the keys
in the ignition."
You pick it up,
you drive away.
Smooth, that's how we do it.
So, when you
looking to move it?
Never.
'Cause how you drop loads,
I don't like,
so maybe this don't work.
Then it don't work.
Red light, green light, José.
They also call me Cochi Loco.
That means "crazy pig."
'Cause I run security
and counterintel.
I get people to tell me
what they don't ever
want to say.
And I have eyes everywhere.
That part of what I do,
you never want to
find out about.
Other people negotiate money,
and go and no go.
Yes, no, maybe so.
Not me.
So, what the hell
are we talking to you for?
I had to lay my eyes on you.
Why is that?
To see if you go meet the Man.
And?
You seem okay.
But him,
I don't like how he looks.
Do you want to
fuck my partner, or do you
want to do business with us?
'Cause I don't give a shit
how you think he looks.
Wait by the phone
in the hotel.
You get a call,
or maybe you don't.
And then you can piss off
back to where you come from.
Yero said New York
through South Florida.
Then this load
does not go
to the Miami group.
That may take load number two.
(PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
That was fast.
Full signal, no service.
They're jamming the phones.
This is the type of stuff
the CIA does. In Baghdad.
Yeah. What's it doing
on a dope deal?
Out of the car.
MAN: See the three trucks?
Move there now.
SONNY: Where'd
all the people go?
Ready, boss?
Excuse me,
because I am very busy.
I have many things to do,
so this will be brief. Yes?
I will try you out
on one load to build trust.
1,000 ki's out of Colombia.
Your end is $3 million.
In all matters,
when you work for me,
you must do
exactly what you say
you will do.
In this business with me,
I do not buy a service.
I buy a result.
If you say
you will do a thing,
you must do
exactly that thing.
Then you will prosper
beyond your dreams and live in
Miami millionaire-style.
You will contact and work
through José Yero
on logistics,
communications, security.
To do with money and terms,
you will work
through my Isabella.
I look forward
to our doing
more work together.
Whether we do or do not,
it is unlikely
that we will meet again.
I extend my best wishes
to your families.
Thank you for
making this trip to see me.
Signal's back.
TRUD Y: Hello?
Hey, what's up? You okay?
Sure.
You sure?
Yeah.
Yeah. What's up?
Yeah. Just saying what's up,
hi, you know. Seeing
what's up with you.
I'm bored.
Bored, okay. All right,
so we'll be there soon.
Yeah.
Hey.
Thanks for the flowers.
Flowers? What flowers?
The bouquet here.
It's $500 worth of roses.
Yellow.
Was there a note?
You mean with the flowers?
Was there a note
with the flowers?
What did the note say?
"Salutations from your friend
in the South."
I thought it was from you.
Okay, we're on our way.
We'll grab a bite.
TRUDY: The lease is under
two layers of false
identities. So are the phones.
It'd take the FBI a week.
How long did it take them?
About three hours, four.
Yes, I am impressed.
They're too goddamn fast.
The flowers? They mean,
"We know where you live,
"where your dog lives,
your dog's veterinarian.
"We can reach out
and touch you,
we had Teleflora..."
Listen. Even if
they would have cut through,
the only thing they're
gonna find is more layers
of our fabricated identities.
Trust what you built.
That's quality.
All right? We're cool.
You trying to reassure me?
You're worried about me?
Don't be.
I got Gina on back up.
Dial 911, whatever.
You and Sonny
are in denied territory.
Not me.
If your focus is on me,
if your attention
is distracted,
you will miss something
coming at you.
I'd die if anything
happened to you
on account of me.
You worry about you.
You and Sonny. And I'm fine.
They sent us some flowers.
Big deal.
Thanks for the flowers.
Flight 000 is airborne.
PILO T: This is November
1206 Sierra. Roger that.
CONTROLLER: Good afternoon.
Radar contact.
Climb and maintain 7,000.
WOMAN: November 636
is coming your way
from the northwest.
636.
CONTROLLER:
Opa-locka Departure,
good afternoon.
Radar contact.
Climb and maintain 7,000.
King Air 1206 Sierra,
you see anything
off your right side?
This is November 1206 Sierra.
Negative, Opa-locka.
I got a double hit.
I think there's
another plane there.
Let me see.
CONTROLLER: Go down to 220.
Ghost. One blip, one plane.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yeah.
Oye, Burnett. Our client
got delivery. Product's
on the road. Good work.
Yeah, but we had a problem
before your client showed up.
SONNY ON PHONE:
Somebody tried
to rip off the load.
You know a detail shop
on Second and Overtown?
I do.
Across the street
we found a stash house.
10:00 a.m. Be there.
Here we go.
Only two.
RICO: They tried to
jack your load. We brought him
home and discovered this.
YERO: Haitians stole
this two weeks ago.
That's my load.
This is my product.
RICO: How'd they know
where the drop was?
How'd they know?
I find out.
See you later.
YERO: I see you,
I see a load
we lost two weeks ago
all in the same place.
Well, you don't like us
finding your load,
we can go ahead
and lose it all over again.
What other suspicions
did you mastermind today?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
We want our product back.
Sure.
How much?
How much...
For what?
For recovering that.
Nothing.
Nothing?
Consider it an investment
in the future of
a fine business relationship.
That is because it's yours.
What's yours is yours.
So is this a one-time deal?
Or is something else
coming up?
Give them the shipment
on the 17th.
RICO: Conveyance?
By ocean. Out of Barranquilla.
José has details.
Lay it out.
You're gonna get
the longs and lats
for a transshipment point.
Ma'am.
Do me one favor.
Yeah?
In return for the risks
we took in recovering
your load,
allow me to buy you a drink.
How fast does that go?
Goes very fast.
Show me.
Where would you like to go?
What do you like to drink?
I'm a fiend for mojitos.
I know a place.
RICO: Partner.
I know what I'm doing.
All right.
The secured satellite comms,
longs and lats
for the transshipment points,
that's all cool.
But I need a vector,
not a location.
Ships move, that's why
they call them ships.
Ship stops,
it's trying to impersonate
an apartment building.
At sea, that is
very suspicious.
Brings about attention.
AWACS, Coast Guard,
U.S. Customs, that's all bad.
I take you to
the best place for mojitos.
Where is that?
Bodeguita del Medio.
Oh, the Keys?
Havana.
Havana?
Cubans don't like my business.
And they don't
like my passport.
It's okay,
the harbormaster is my cousin.
Grab the wheel.
You do business in Cuba
with your husband?
I never do business in Cuba.
And Jesús is not my husband.
I'm a businesswoman.
I do not need a husband
to have a house to live in.
(SEATBELT CLICKING)
(CUBAN MUSIC PLAYING)
You like the mojito?
Mojito's great.
Do you dance?
I dance.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
My aunt. She old.
Now she live here.
This was my mother house.
You grew up in this house?
Yeah.
And then we went to Angola.
She was a surgeon.
She's still in Africa?
No.
She died there
of typhus when I was 16.
(ISABELLA SPEAKING SPANISH)
You will like it.
Allman Brothers.
You know Allman Brothers?
No.
Lynyrd Skynyrd? Free Bird?
No Skynyrd.
Well, that was
the music back then.
And he played
all those Atlanta bars.
But his luck was...
Well, my dad never got lucky,
so he started trucking.
Yeah, I didn't see
a whole lot of him.
But we were close.
You look like your mother?
Why?
I show you photograph.
It's from wedding.
This is a bad idea.
This is past a bad idea.
And it has no future.
That's right.
So, then there's
nothing to worry about.
Come here.
See?
Lucinda somebody's wedding.
Everybody is with couples.
Husbands and wives,
they all pose.
But she is the most special.
Let's talk
a different kind of deal.
You pay us zero.
Is it December?
Why?
Did Christmas
come early this year?
No.
We become partners
on the loads we run.
What we want is
25% of that load in product.
And why, you're thinking,
would I be crazy enough
to cut in these gringos
like that?
It's because Sonny and Ricardo
can deliver to me
what no one else can.
We guarantee loads.
Comes up short, we make good.
Your operation will run
from now on out risk-free.
And you are the 25% partner?
You?
What if I tell you
your ideas are too big
for your skin?
And merely to propose this
is a dangerous thing.
Then I would say to you,
this has been fun.
Okay. So?
Think of the cash
you don't have to front.
Cash is not difficult.
Seventeen.
I would say you're
five percentage points
away from a deal.
Maybe I'm only one.
You've convinced me.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
RICO ON PHONE: What's up?
Where are you?
I'm on my way back.
The meeting with Castillo
is in 45 minutes.
What's up, Sonny. You okay?
Fine, darling.
So, where you been?
Hit a couple of jazz clubs,
fell back to her place.
Where?
Vedado.
Where's Vedado?
Suburbs outside Havana.
You went to Havana, Cuba?
No, Havana, Louisiana.
Don't we have a meet?
You making moves
on Montoya's woman?
No.
You're not
making moves on her?
We're making
moves on each other.
Oh, so that's supposed to
make it all right?
Something like that.
So what happened
to the first load?
Went to Dominicans
in New York.
We think load number two's
going to our guys.
South Florida.
Their big buyer.
Okay, that's great.
Yeah.
But we wanna go
beyond load number two.
Why are we going exploring?
Who's the "we"?
Only thing you've
contributed so far to this
is bad intel.
How's that?
José Yero, cocaine producer?
Yero's middle management,
part of a bigger
transnational operation
run by
Arcángel de Jesús Montoya.
Montoya's the new news.
Globalized.
Moving?
Colombian coke and H,
arms from the Ukraine,
E from Holland,
pirated software
from China into Brazil.
What's this got to do
with the price of tea
in China?
We're seeing their ops.
Transpo. You know,
money-laundering networks.
It would take years
to put together
a deal like this.
We want to stay under,
run in load number two
and keep going,
and hold off busting
the ABs or Yero.
We illuminate Montoya's
operations from the inside.
No one has ever tread before
where we are now.
Well, the answer's no.
We take the Aryan Brothers,
the shooters,
pressure them for the leak.
It's a bird in the hand.
I'm not changing my op plan
for speculation
masquerading as intel.
Look, I know undercover
requires aggression,
some outlaw attitude.
You know, how else do you
lie down with dogs?
Okay, but that...
Go fuck yourself.
Chill. Sonny, chill.
You know what
this prick's game is?
He'll get his picture
in the Miami Herald
off a quick bust,
save his punk-ass career
at the slug farm in DC.
We are not backing off this.
That's it.
Where you on this?
100% with Sonny.
Change the mission statement.
I have to run it
past my ADO in DC.
Hey, slick.
Don't try and shine me on.
You don't have the time
or the skill.
If I close this down,
I will close it down
right now.
And you can
sink in Washington.
All right, do it.
You fucking better be right.
So, what's going on?
As in?
As in, there's undercover
and then there is,
"Which way is up?"
Oh, you think
I'm in so deep, I forgot?
I will never doubt you.
(FEMALE NEWSCASTER
SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
Did you find it?
Yeah.
Dominion or Blackstone
hedge funds?
Through Hong Kong bank?
Yes.
Ukrainian shipment?
Eight tons,
small arms and RPGs
on the 27th.
Tell me about
the deal in South Florida.
They want 18% of the product
to bring in loads.
They guarantee them.
Our risk goes to zero.
And Burnett?
What does your
intuition tell you?
My intuition about Burnett?
I slept with him in Havana.
And?
A serious man.
Ambitious,
but he has to be watched.
After a few good runs,
he will renegotiate
the deal upwards.
That's my girl.
But José Yero thinks
you are wrong.
On the next load, he wants
to front them silver,
but pay them in lead.
What do you wanna do?
I like the diminished risk.
I like businessmen who are
competent because you can
predict their behavior.
On the other hand,
if what you wish is el plomo,
the lead, then do that.
After the load is received,
we will close
their eyes forever.
We will try a few runs
with these partners.
I will tell José.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hey, what's up?
This is Trudy, my girl.
It's a pleasure.
Hey, nice club.
I redid it.
And I got places in Medellín,
Foz do Iguaçu, and Rio.
You like clubs?
Oh, yeah. I'm a disco guy.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
In the back.
In Colón, in Panama,
a Malaysian freighter
will transfer eight tons.
Crates with Russian marking.
Do not open them.
The 4,000 ki's you move
into Miami, you keep
and release when we say.
So long as
delivery goes down our way.
Sure.
But the crates,
they come back
to Barranquilla.
You want us to break down
the load for different buyers?
No. It's one,
my main South Florida guy.
RICO: José, my ace.
Skies are crowded, man.
AWAC's, ICE,
DEA spies in the sky.
Do you have any counterintel
you could contribute
to the good and the welfare?
YERO: Sure.
Check your e-mail.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
BODYGUARD: Hello?
It's José.
José, what is it?
YERO ON PHONE:
I don't like the Americans.
Why?
Too good at what they do.
MONTO YA: So?
They are wrong.
Somehow,
somehow they are wrong.
You ran them.
Did you run them?
YERO: Yes.
Do they check out?
Yes.
We made their deal.
And Isabella
disagrees with you.
ISABELLA:
Once I had a fortune.
It said, "Live now.
Life is short. Time is luck."
You got assets somewhere?
Insurance?
Why?
Things go wrong.
The odds catch up.
Probability is like gravity.
You cannot negotiate
with gravity.
One day...
One day you should
just cash out, you know.
Just cash out and get out.
Yeah?
Yeah. As far
and as fast as you can.
Would you find me?
Yes, I would.
This is very Cuban.
The protective male talking.
It's the talk of a man.
If he were your husband,
he would never
put you at risk.
And he would never put you
within 1,000 miles of anything
that could hurt you.
And where would you be?
A while longer still
in this business,
and then I'd find you.
Would you?
Yes, ma'am.
If you couldn't,
I would have left
the only thing I know
since I was 17.
But none of this will happen.
Because what do you
see around?
Look around you.
It's controlled
by Arcángel de Jesús Montoya.
RICO: Let me talk to Fujima.
FUJIMA ON PHONE: Who's this?
Ricardo.
Okay, go ahead.
Listen, I want you to
issue an alert.
An informant
has revealed that a freighter
departed Barranquilla
for South Florida with plans
to transship contraband
to go-fast boats
in broad daylight
one day next week
off the coast of Miami.
Okay.
For Customs, you say Monday.
For FBI operations in DC,
you say Tuesday.
FBI Miami, you say Wednesday,
DEA on Thursday,
Coast Guard on Friday.
And keep it classified,
keep it discreet,
keep it out of
interagency communications.
Yero hit me back.
He says U.S. Assets expects
our transshipment load
on Tuesday day.
Tuesday day only went out
to FBI Operations
planted in DC.
So what's up?
Anything could be in
those crates out of Odessa.
This one has too many
moving parts,
too many unknowns.
It's your call.
Where you at?
The message from Yero
locates the agency
and the office
where the leak is coming from.
I call that progress.
So, let's take it
to the limit one more time.
(MEN CHATTERING)
RICO: Move!
We got to go. Rápido.
Let's go. Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
How we looking?
MAN: I can take one more.
RICO: Good. Let's move!
That's it. Take off.
Let's hit it.
All right, Julio,
break the lines
and straighten the load.
Break the lines.
We'll rendezvous
in about eight hours.
(TRUDY GROANING)
WOMAN ON TV: If there's
any place where most people
feel at home,
it's right
in their own backyard.
And that's why today,
more than ever,
homeowners are asking,
"What can we do to make
our backyard a paradise,
"a vacation destination
you can visit anytime,
"without the hassle
of air travel,
or even starting the car?"
We'll answer these questions
and much more.
Be loaded up in a minute.
(DIALING ON TELEPHONE)
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
ARYAN BRO THER ON PHONE:
Want you to listen to this.
Who are you? Who is this?
Shut up and listen.
ANCHORWOMAN ON TV: Developing
news in weather today, there's
new activity in the tropics.
We turn things over to
meteorologist Ryan Phillips.
What's developing?
WEATHERMAN ON TV:
Coincidentally, three years
ago today, July 24th,
that's when Hurricane Danny
formed out across
the Atlantic Basin.
And now we have our own
tropical troubles as Hurricane
Ernesto, a category...
Somebody's proving
it's right now.
Yeah.
ANCHORWOMAN ON TV: All right,
Ryan. Thanks.
And we've got
some good news
about your electric bill.
Your rates
will not be going up.
Say hello, honey.
Some nice friends you got.
Urban trailer trash with B.O.
And a noisy fucking...
MAN: Yeah.
They know.
It's me. We're on.
Pay attention.
I will now tell you
when and how this load
will get dropped.
This is happening our way.
COLEMAN ON PHONE: You have
30 minutes from right now
to enter Government Cut.
Head up the Miami River.
You have 15 minutes
to make it to
the First Avenue bridge.
When you're there,
I'll call you with
the exact drop point.
You fuck up, we fuck her up.
What's the deal?
For doing the deed,
30% off the load.
RICO: J.C.!
RICO: Zito!
Zito, you copy?
ZITO ON RADIO: Don't hear you.
Go again.
Zito, do you copy?
ZITO ON RADIO:
Go to marine 78.
RICO ON RADIO:
They took Trudy hostage.
What's the ask?
What do they want?
RICO: They want us to drop
the load their way.
They got eyes on us.
We're on a timetable.
The next call that
we get will be
at the First Avenue bridge.
Where do we hook up?
Hook up at the Port bridge
ahead of that.
RICO: Port bridge.
GINA: I got it.
ZITO: What did Trudy say?
Urban trailer park.
Did you hear the roar?
Was it near the freeway?
No, no, no. Airport.
ZITO: Sonny, Rico,
where is the drop site?
RICO: We'll know last minute.
They got Trudy.
Maybe in a trailer park
near an airport.
Look for antennas.
These guys manage
a lot of signal traffic.
They will not kill her
until they've got the goods.
Once they've got the goods,
she is dead.
When they see the boat,
we slow this down.
Buy some time.
Did they prove she's alive?
That's the first thing
they put through.
Try Paradise Trailer Park
near the airport.
Sonny, I got a possible.
It has three HF antennas.
It's on the corner lot
at the southeast end.
For you.
Hello?
Where are you?
ISABELLA: Geneva.
Yero's buyer
jacked one of our people.
What the fuck's going on?
ISABELLA: What's he want?
SONNY:
To control the delivery.
It's Yero, not the buyer.
ISABELLA:
Yero's acting on his own.
I do not know
what shit he's pulling, okay?
But whatever
he tells you to do,
do not do it.
So?
It's José Yero.
Be a hit and a rip.
SWITEK ON RADIO: Slow as we
can go. Two and a half minutes
before we hit the drop site.
Copy that.
Hold it.
Clear.
CASTILLO ON RADIO:
Sonny. Ricardo.
Copy.
I'm approaching
on a west parallel street.
It's clear. Sonny's
in position on the east.
Four people. Two shooters.
Milano's Pizza.
ARYAN BROTHER 2:
You order pizza?
No.
GINA: Hold it!
Hold it!
Drop the detonator!
WOMAN: Leon, no.
Shoot me, she dies.
Shoot me. Go ahead.
Fuck it. We can all go.
That's cool.
That's not what happens.
What will happen is...
What will happen is,
I will put a round
at 2,700 feet per second
into the medulla
at the base of your brain,
and you will be dead
from the neck down
before your body knows it.
Your finger won't even twitch.
Only you get dead.
So, tell me, sport,
do you believe that?
Hey...
Get down!
Be still.
We got her.
TRUDY: Motherfucker!
RICO: He's dead.
All right?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
COLEMAN ON PHONE:
José.
Those guys and your product
are a no-show.
Stay here until we clear.
Do you hear me?
Our QTH is C-33.
We are in the northeast corner
of the trailer park.
SONNY: Clear!
(BEEPS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Get out of the car.
I already called the medic.
Get out!
Open the door.
Come on.
You know what gets me?
The prospect
of her losing her life.
Of her losing her life
over this bullshit
line of work.
Is that what she thinks?
No, it's what I think.
She'd tell me,
"Rico, I ain't playing.
This is real.
"Same as you.
No less than you."
Yeah.
Hey.
She's in recovery.
She has burns to
15% of her body.
We're gonna keep her totally
sedated with a complete
muscle relaxant.
She's in a coma.
And her right lung
is collapsed, burst spleen.
So what's her chances?
The brain swelling
worries us the most.
You relieve the pressure?
Not surgically.
It's too diffuse.
And any complication,
an infection, and she's...
She's in bad shape.
I will recover the load,
but all I know
is we don't have our load.
The Americans have our load.
So I plead with you
to look at this.
Go ahead.
Do you see this?
This is not casual.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yeah.
YERO ON PHONE: You okay?
I heard some bad shit happened
with the crazy whites
at a trailer park.
Cut the crap.
You got my product, man.
SONNY: You got my money.
That's right.
Here's the deal.
We have a deal.
Here's a new deal, cash money.
Three a ki
times 4,000 ki's is 12 mil.
And we ain't waiting
for a back nine.
We had a different deal.
This is the only deal,
or else I offload your shit
to some other buyer.
Mail you a refund, maybe.
Okay, man. Let's do this.
And I want you there.
None of your peckerwood
proxies.
I'm out of town.
I'll wait.
Why?
'Cause if you're there,
guarantees it's for real.
Tomorrow night.
I be there.
We call you with the place.
You got my number.
Yeah, well, follow up
with the ME,
identify off the DNA samples.
Yero's coming back to the U.S.
To recover his product.
He's coming back himself.
How do we deal?
How do we do a deal?
I mean, how's anybody
gonna believe anybody
after tonight?
Nobody does. He's compelled.
We got his 4,000 ki's,
worth $60 million
at wholesale.
That's right.
All right. Now, here's
what's gonna happen.
They will change out the place
at the last minute
so we can't set up on them.
And it'll be
an L-shaped ambush.
I run it.
They won't initiate
until they got eyes
on the product.
And I won't let the product
come in until we've got
their shooters in our sights
and you have cover.
Okay.
I don't care how much
we want this guy.
Clear?
Yeah.
What shit have you pulled?
You know what
Jesús will do, right?
Yes, I do.
Do you wanna call him?
You're all mine now.
It's that time.
Yeah.
RICO: Badges get flashed,
guns come out.
Arrests get made.
That's what we do.
So?
So, fabricated identity
and what's really up
collapses into one frame.
You ready for that
on this one?
I absolutely am not.
So, where you at with that?
I'm with her 100%.
She could be a white collar
money manager.
She may even be true love.
But she's with them.
Like Trudy would say,
I ain't playing.
ZITO: Time.
Let's do this.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yeah.
ARYAN BRO THER: I'm on them.
They're clean.
What's up?
The location got changed.
Bojean shipyard,
27th and the river.
I can't find the shooters.
Stall.
Copy that.
Where's the product?
Where's the money?
How do I know
what you say is there,
is there?
Here's how that works,
somebody from my side
lays eyes on the money.
Only then do we
call in the dope.
Then somebody from your side
can go look at the product.
The money's right here,
so send somebody over.
CASTILLO:
Can't find the shooter.
Where's Yero?
YERO: Right here!
And I brought your friend.
Oye, 'mano, she mine now.
Jesús gave her to me
to ask questions
and find out
interesting things.
We a couple now.
After work, she and me go
catch a movie and grab a bite.
When I get tired,
I throw her away.
Her leg in one place,
her head someplace else.
You guys ever see that?
Anyway, she here now
to make sure
everything go right.
CASTILLO: Still no shooter.
My guy, show him the money.
I don't want him!
Why?
What difference
does it make, Sonny?
Listen to me, asshole,
I do not want that
motherfucker near me.
You wanna see your dope?
You send Isabella.
Or it travels.
Stay here, bitch.
Let her go.
Check the dope,
then come right back.
Got one.
On the container. Hold it.
I got number two.
Port side, third deck,
middle of the superstructure.
Fire.
(GUNS FIRING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
Go!
GINA: Go!
Move it, man. Run, run, run!
Crockett. I'm on your right.
Who are you?
Get up.
Get in. Get in!
Zito?
Yeah, he's okay.
Fuck you.
What is this?
It's a house we use.
Gloria? Sonny.
Is Frank around?
All right. Just get him
to call me right back.
A man named Frank
is going to come in a boat.
He will run you
into Cayo Sotavento.
And from there,
you can find your way
to Havana.
And nobody will follow you.
Including me.
Remember,
I said
time is luck.
Yeah.
Luck ran out.
This was too good to last.
Nurse?