Whoo-hoo!
- Come on, we're outta here!
- Easy, Rocky.
All right, guys,
we're 15 seconds from the drop zone.
All right, pinheads,
the Stealth Eagle's about to fly.
Ditto for the Swooping Swallow.
Well, lead on, flyboys.
- That's a lotta air!
- After you, Skull!
What are you? Crazy? This was your idea!
Hey, guys. You might wanna slip those on.
Good idea.
We're three seconds away
from the target zone. Aisha, you're on!
Yes!
Stylin'!
On your tail! Whoo!
All systems go!
Banzai!
Whoo-hoo!
- Show 'em your stuff.
- You got it. Surf's up!
Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
Catch you on the flip side.
( # "Higher Ground" by Red Hot
Chili Peppers )
# Soldiers #
# Keep on warrin' #
# World #
# Keep on turnin' #
# Cos it won't be too long #
# Powers #
# Keep on lyin' #
# While your people #
# Keep on dyin' #
# World #
# Keep on turnin' #
# Cos it won't be too long #
Yeah! All right!
All right, guys, let's break!
# Gonna keep on tryin' #
# Till I reach the highest ground #
PA: With the arrival
of Ryan"s Comet two days away,
the Angel Grove jump-a-thon will
breathe new life into the old observatory.
Tickets to see the comet
are at the Fire Department booth.
Now, folks, raise your eyes to the skies, cos
here comes the team from Angel Grove High!
All right, Dad, pay close attention.
This is how the pros do it.
- I didn't do so bad.
- You landed in the parking lot.
- It was embarrassing.
- Well...
PA: The first of the team
is beginning his final approach. It"s Adam!
As he rounds the turn, he looks awful low...
but he pulls up just in time
and hits the target dead centre.
Right behind him is skydiver Billy...
who manages a perfect landing!
Skydiver number three is Kimberly!
Her landing is flawless!
And here comes Rocky...
who lands right on target!
Here comes Aisha! She makes it a perfect five
out of five landing and ties the 1986 record.
So now it"s all up to Tommy Oliver.
Can he make it six for six?
Yeah! Go, Tommy!
PA: He"s making his final approach.
Looks a bit wide, but still OK.
Almost to the ground now. Can he do it?
He does! The Angel Grove team
sets a new city record! Way to go, guys!
- Let's go.
- OK.
PA: Remember, folks, Ryan"s Comet
will be passing in just two days.
- Looking good up there.
- Thanks. Maybe next time you can join us.
Really? Could l?
Yeah, well, we'll talk about that, Fred...
in about 10 or 1 2 years, all right?
Congratulations, Tommy.
The observatory just got a new lease on life.
- Yeah. Thanks, man.
- FRED: Awesome.
- Ryan's Comet is passing over in two days!
- Guys, we did it!
- That was awesome, Tommy.
- Wonderful.
- Thanks, guys. You too, man.
- Hey, has anybody seen Bulk and Skull?
Ernie's is serving a free dessert with lunch.
They probably landed on the roof.
- PILOT: Hurry up. We're runnin' out of fuel.
- BULK: I gotta be the eagle.
I'm gonna be the eagle!
Be the swallow!
- Be the swallow.
- Come on, baby!
- BULK: Let go of me!
- SKULL: I want my mommy!
TOMMY: Rock and roll!
# The mountain is high #
# The valley is low #
# And you're confused on
which way to go #
# So I've come here to
give you a hand #
# And lead you into the promised land #
- Air time!
- Up and away!
# Come on and take it be my side #
# Come on and take a tree ride #
- Let's take a shortcut.
- Right behind you!
# Come on and take a free ride #
# Come on and take it by my side #
SKULL: Hey, this doesn't look like the target
landing zone! Where's the free food?
You idiot! Your screaming threw off
the Stealth Eagle's sense of direction.
Stealth Eagle? Lame duck is more like it.
- Hey!
- Uh-oh.
- You guys, what do you think you're doing?
- Uh...
We're from the Angel Grove
Building lnspector's office.
Yeah. That building's
supposed to be over there!
And what's that man doing
without proper foot protection?
- Who's in charge around here, huh?
- Huh?
Hey, Dave! Come and have a look at this.
Go on, Dave.
- That was a close one.
- Uh-huh.
- You hungry?
- Always.
What in the world is this?
It sure as heck ain't DWP.
Let's get a crane in here.
OK, take it up!
Incredible.
What do you think it is?
No... idea.
Aaaaarrgghh!
John, you all right?
ROCKY: Let's get somethin' to eat.
(bleeping)
TOMMY: Hang on.
Let's go over there.
- What's up, Alpha?
- Rangers, Zordon needs you. It"s urgent.
We're on our way.
Aye-yai-yai-yai! The subtronic
interphasers are short-circuiting.
I have to find a way to alternate
the frequency modulators.
What's goin' on?
A massive surge of evil energy is
overloading our sensors. Aye-yai-yai-yai-yai!
Rangers, you must act swiftly.
- The planet is in grave danger.
- Danger from what?
6,000 years ago a morphological being
known as lvan Ooze ruled the world
with a reign of unparalleled terror.
He was on the verge of completing
construction of his ultimate weapons:
the Ecto-Morphicon Titans, twin machines
capable of enslaving the entire universe.
What happened to him?
A group of warriors like yourselves
lured him to into a hyperlock chamber
and buried him deep underground.
But now the chamber
has been accidentally uncovered.
You must return it to the depths
before it is opened and lvan is released.
His Ecto-Morphicons were buried near
the chamber. If lvan escapes, he'll find them.
Use extreme caution, Rangers. You're dealing
with an evil that is beyond all imagination.
( snoring )
- What do I care about some stupid egg?
- This is no ordinary egg!
- Well, I say we hard-boil the thing!
- I'm with her. I'm hungry.
- That's cos you're a pig!
- Hey, Kurt, take a look at this.
No need to wake him. In fact,
why don't you take a little nap yourself?
PIG: Yeah, I could do that.
I just choose not to.
Zip your lips.
After 2,000 years of searching...
you are finally within my grasp.
And now... Iet's crack this egg.
Excellent.
Yuck!
What?! You spent 2,000 years
looking for a tub of snot?!
Patience, motor-mouth. Watch.
( laughs )
Yes!
Cool!
( yawns loudly )
Ladies and gentlemen!
The Ooze is back!
Yeah!
- He's so handsome!
- Why, thank you.
I am Lord Zedd, sworn enemy
of all that is good and decent.
- It is a supreme honour to finally meet you.
- How can I ever repay you?
Do you recall the name Zordon of Eltar?
I think he's heard of him.
I want you to destroy Zordon... so that
my evil may once again reign supreme!
I will not only destroy him...
I will obliterate his entire legacy.
It will be as if Zordon of Eltar never existed!
- Finally, a real man!
- ( growls )
We shall leave you to weave your evil ways.
Let's go, Rita.
What is that odious stench?
Smells like...
teenagers.
Anybody see anything?
Let's take a look up there.
Ugh!
- AISHA: What is it?
- ROCKY: It reeks.
Hey! What are you kids doin' here?
You haven't seen a morphological being
lurking around here?
- A morphological being?
- Yeah.
What the heck is that?
Wait a second.
Did it look something like this?
- Ew, gross!
- Too kind. Allow me to introduce myself.
I am the galactically feared,
globally reviled, universally despised...
They call me lvan Ooze.
Well, pack your bags, cos we're sending
you back where you came from.
Gee, a teenager with a big mouth.
Not much has changed in 6,000 years.
You obviously don't know
who you're dealing with, Mr Raisin Head.
- Really?
- Yeah. We're the Power Rangers.
Where's my autograph book? Ha!
Power Rangers, huh?
So Zordon's still usin'
a bunch of kids to do his dirty work.
Well... meet my kids!
Ew.
From this moment forth
the world as you know it shall cease to exist!
Welcome to my nightmare!
Bye-bye, kiddies!
He's gone.
- What are we gonna do?
- ROCKY: There's plenty of room down there.
Go, guys!
- Let's take these beasts!
- Spread out!
( # "Are You Ready?!" by Devo )
Welcome to my nightmare.
# Action boy now #
# Action girl now #
# Be prepared to climb
another mountain #
Ever play Kick The Can?
# Action boy now #
# Action girl now #
# Be prepared to surf across
the ocean #
Kiss and make up.
# To fill your plate #
# Be prepared #
# Don't hesitate #
# For a great big bust #
# Be prepared #
# To do what you must #
# To take a hit #
Let me get the door.
# Be prepared #
# For a sneak attack #
You ooze, you lose.
Sit down!
See ya!
Right behind you, Kimberly.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
Adam!
- AISHA: They got us cornered!
- BILLY: We can't hold them off!
- BILLY: There's too many of 'em.
- Let's do it, guys! It's morphin' time!
Pterodactyl!
Triceratops!
Tyrannosaurus!
Mastodon!
Sabre-toothed tiger!
White tiger!
# Go, go, Power Rangers #
# Mighty Morphin Power Rangers #
- Where'd they go?
- Keep your eyes peeled.
Heads up, guys! Over there!
- Careful. It could be a trap.
- Right.
Let's go.
Alpha, my sensors tell me
the Rangers were too late.
- lvan is on his way here.
- Don't worry.
Nobody enters the command centre
without a power coin.
( squelching )
Well, almost nobody.
Hey, pretty fancy-schmancy.
I guess if you invest
your money well over 60 centuries,
you can buy something pretty nice.
Uh-oh.
( laughs )
Aye-yai-yai-yai-yai-yai-yai....
You haven't changed, Ooze. You're still
picking on creatures smaller than yourself.
Put a sock in it, Z! 10 minutes out of the egg
and I'm listening to one of your lectures.
You locked me into your
stuffy hyperlock chamber
and tossed me away in the depths
like yesterday's trash.
You any idea what it's like to be locked up
in a rotten egg for 6,000 years? It's boring.
Not to mention I've had a charley horse
since the Renaissance.
- You won't get away with this, Ooze.
- You robbed me of my prime.
I was the supreme ruler
of the most foul empire in the universe.
And now... it's time to pay the piper.
Oh, the things that I have missed!
The Black Plague!
The Spanish lnquisition!
The Brady Bunch reunion!
( laughs )
- BILLY: This place gives me the creeps.
- AISHA: I heard that.
TOMMY: I've got a bad feelin'
about this place.
( squawking )
- KIMBERLY: Anybody see anything?
- We need some light.
Activating power beam.
- They gotta be around here somewhere.
- Activating power scope.
TOMMY: Talk to me, Rocky. What do we got?
I don't know what these purple creeps
are made of, but I can't lock 'em down.
TOMMY: All right. Stay alert.
- Over there!
- Let's power up!
- ALL: Right!
- AISHA: Here they come!
You guys make me sick, sick, sick!
Back off!
Have a nice flight!
Later, dudes.
It's gonna be one messy night.
- Up and over?
- Let's do it!
ADAM: Rocky, behind you!
Goin' airborne!
These guys don't know when to quit.
Double whammy?
You're on.
Uh-oh!
Whoaaaa!
That does it. Stegastinger!
Did you miss me?
Pterodactyl Thunderwhip!
Have a nice trip! See you next fall.
Bye-bye.
Gotta love it.
Hold on, Aisha!
One, two, three, four, five, six!
Aisha!
- You OK?
- They're tough.
- Let's finish these purple parasites.
- You said it.
I want you guys to meet Saba.
ALL: Uh-oh!
ALL: Yeah!
TOMMY: Now let's go find lvan.
KIMBERLY: Hey, what's happening?
BILLY: We're losing power.
- What's goin' on?
- Alpha, come in.
- Something's wrong.
- We'd better get back. Let's go, guys.
BILLY: Oh, no.
- Ooze.
- TOMMY: Let's get it open.
TOMMY: Look at this place.
TOMMY: I can't believe it.
AISHA: What happened here?
KIMBERLY: Oh, no.
ADAM: Zordon!
What's happening to him?
Outside of his time warp, he's dying.
BILLY: He needs power.
Rangers.
Thank goodness you are safe.
Come on, we gotta get you back inside.
I'm afraid that is impossible.
The power has been destroyed.
It is gone.
The Zords...
the weapons...
all of it.
The Power Rangers are no more.
Ivan Ooze has won.
- We're losing him.
- Zordon, you can't leave us!
Ever since you came into our lives,
you've been like a father to us all.
You must be strong.
Rangers!
TOMMY: Alpha.
- Are you OK?
- I'll be fine.
There may be a power
that can save Zordon.
- What power?
- It is on the distant planet of Phaedos.
It's very dangerous.
All who have tried for it have perished.
- But we have to try, Alpha.
- Zordon's life force will not last long.
- You won't have much time.
- How can we get it?
Maybe if I can download the last plasmatic
morphing gem into the transport core,
I might have just enough power
to get you there.
- But there won't be any left to get you back.
- So, how do we get back?
We have to hope that the power is there.
Zordon's life depends on it.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
We may not have our powers,
but we're still the Power Rangers.
Remember, Rangers,
Zordon doesn't have much time.
Oh, no! Aye-yai-yai-yai-yai!
Please hold on, Zordon!
I can't believe it! How could he
let them slip through his hands?!
He's no better than the rest of the hired help!
Oh, give it a rest.
- Hi, honey, I'm home!
- You egg-sucking purple pinhead!
The Rangers are going after the great power!
I thought you said this guy
was the master of disaster!
He's nothing but
a slime-infested jelly doughnut!
Finally someone shut her up.
Your feebleness is staggering.
You obviously need a vacation.
I think circumstances
force us to choose a new leader...
and I pick... me!
Who does this clown think he's dealing with?
The bogeyman is taking over.
No one double-crosses Lord Zedd and lives!
Oh, stop it! It tickles!
My turn.
- RITA: (squeaky voice) Way to go, bonehead!
- ZEDD: You can't trust anyone in this galaxy!
- I love snow globes.
- RITA: Earthquake! Earthquake!
Now you have a choice. You either serve me...
or you can join these
insufferable dingledorks!
- Goldar, get us out of here!
- Don't listen to that purple booger!
ZEDD: Don't you dare betray me!
- We never liked those dingledorks.
- PIG: You said it. They stink.
So... what are we going to do about
the Power Rangers, oh my hideous one?
Ah, yes.
The Power Rangers.
( snorts )
- Good distance.
- Yeah.
( squawking )
Shut your beaks! Now,
my Tengu Warriors, you will fly to Phaedos,
you will find the Power Rangers
and you will tear them apart!
- GOLDAR: Go sic 'em, Tweety!
- PIG: Happy hunting!
Wow.
My gosh. Look at this place.
AISHA: You guys! Over here! Quick!
AISHA: Whoa. Looks like
somebody had a bad day.
- What is it?
- I think the question is "What was it?"
Definitely not the welcoming committee,
that's for sure.
Come on, guys, we got a job to do.
Taking over the world is one thing.
Finding good help to run it for you,
that's the killer.
Would you like me to make a few calls?
No need. I'm going to recruit
the parents of Angel Grove.
No offence, boss,
but they might find you a little disgusting.
( belches )
Well, I suppose you'd be the experts on that.
- You forget. I'm a master of disguise.
- How could I forget? I never knew.
First I'll turn them into zombies
and then order them
to dig up my Ecto-Morphicons.
How you gonna do that?
By showing them the wonders
of being wicked with a little bit of lvan's ooze.
( laughs )
Ooh!
Finally I get to finish
what I started 6,000 years ago!
Little do they know my weapons of
destruction lie buried beneath their feet.
( all laugh )
- Stop it! Get to work!
- PIG: Yes, Your Royal Heinous Highness.
Hey.
You OK?
I was just thinking about Zordon.
You know, everything
we've been through together.
Look, he's gonna make it.
We'll find this power
and then send that slimeball lvan Ooze
back to the sewer he crawled out of.
Come on.
What the heck was that?
BILLY: Get down!
TOMMY: Let's move!
ROCKY: Look out!
They're everywhere!
Take cover!
Back off.
- Know the funny thing about morphin'?
- What?
You don't appreciate it till you can't do it!
TOMMY: Kimberly, behind you!
Hang on, Kimberly!
Somebody help me!
- They're too strong!
- We need our powers!
Let me go, Big Bird!
( whistling noise )
( whistling noise continues )
That was amazing. Thanks.
If you want to thank me,
go back to wherever it is you came from.
- We can't.
- We were told there was a great power here.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
The ground is littered with the bones
of those who have tried for it and failed.
Well, we're different. We won't fail.
Leave Phaedos... before it's too late.
Look, we don't want any trouble.
Our leader Zordon got hurt...
Zordon?
Did you say Zordon?
You know Zordon? Who are you?
I am Dulcea, master warrior
of the planet Phaedos.
What has happened to Zordon?
He was attacked by
this cosmic being named lvan Ooze.
- lvan Ooze is free?
- You've heard of him?
Ivan Ooze is a monster.
If we don't hurry, your planet is doomed.
Follow me.
Alpha, I am deeply concerned
about the Rangers.
Please, Zordon, save your strength.
You need to rest.
We must try to communicate with them.
It is possible I can help them.
If I could locate a vertical deflector, we could
make contact through the viewing globe.
Please... please hurry.
Aye-yai-yai-yai-yai! Hold on.
Guys and girls, girls and guys,
gather round and feast your eyes.
I promise you all, you just can't lose,
when you've got
your own supply of lvan's ooze.
- BOY: What are we supposed to do with it?
- Show it to parents, show it to friends.
When you've got your ooze,
the fun never ends.
This is kinda gross.
You may have heard
that looks can be deceiving.
I'm sure that when you've tried it,
you all will be believing.
And did I mention it's free?
- I'll take some.
- Here you go. Who else?
OK, there's enough for everybody.
Take it home in boxes, take it home in cases.
If your parents try to stop you,
just throw it in their faces!
BILLY: Dulcea, where are you taking us?
You shall know soon enough.
KIMBERLY: We have to hurry.
Zordon won't last much longer.
TOMMY: Wow.
- AISHA: Amazing.
- TOMMY: What is this place?
DULCEA: These are the ancient ruins
of the Ninjetti Temple.
There, beyond the Niola Jungle,
is the monolith.
Inside awaits the power of the universe.
The monolith
is heavily guarded against intruders.
No one has ever survived
an attempt to reach it.
Then how can we?
You were chosen by Zordon.
I have faith in his wisdom.
Can you help us?
We will call upon
the sacred animals of the Ninjetti for help.
Fred!
There, that should do it. Let's give it a whirl!
Police have been fielding
hundreds of calls from concerned citizens
as the number of missing parents
continues to grow.
Hi, folks. Ivan Ooze here.
Are you bored with your work?
Are you bored with your life? Then come on
down to Ooze City and let"s get sticky!
Aye-yai-yai-yai-yai!
Ivan's evil plot is taking shape.
I just hope they're not too late.
Buried deep within each of us
is an animal spirit waiting to be released.
Close your eyes and look deep inside.
Aisha, you are the bear,
fierce and unstoppable.
Rocky, powerful, smart,
you are the mighty ape.
Billy, you are the wolf, cunning and swift.
Agile Kimberly, light as a feather,
you are the crane.
Adam...
- Adam, what's wrong?
- I'm a frog.
Yes, a frog. Like the one you kiss...
to get a handsome prince.
And you, Tommy, are the falcon,
winged lord of the skies.
To be in harmony with a sacred animal
spirit is to have the force of the Ninjetti.
To those who are Ninjetti,
anything is possible.
But... I am afraid
you must do this on you own.
You're not coming with us, Dulcea?
If only I could.
One step beyond this plateau and I would
begin to age as rapidly as Zordon is now.
The strength is inside you. Trust it.
Your sacred animals will be your guide.
May your animal spirits watch over you.
Dad?
Dad? Where are you?
IVAN: I forgot how slow parents are.
I thought my Ecto-Morphicons
would be dug up by now.
Oh, Goldie, I'm bored.
Let's have some fun. Hey, you!
Dance.
( rock and roll music )
Do the swim.
- Ballet!
- (ballet music)
( Ivan and Goldar laugh )
Hey.
Hey, boss! They're back!
Ah!
My Tengu.
(squawking)
Stop your screeching.
- How did you fare?
- It couldn't have gone better.
Threw one of 'em off a mountain,
one into a ragin' river.
So, they've all been destroyed?
- Well, we were about to destroy them, but...
- What?
You didn't kill them? You call yourself Tengu
warriors? You're more like Tengu turkeys!
I'll have you all stuffed and roasted!
But, master, there was this monster with
these huge sticks and it kept twirling them...
Sticks? Did these sticks
have a whistling sound?
It was more like nails on a chalkboard.
Dulcea.
That miserable, manipulating,
loathsome she-devil of a witch!
If she leads them to the great power,
everything will be ruined.
- Do you want us to take another whack at it?
- How about takin' another quack at it?
No time to waste. My Ecto-Morphicon
machines must be unearthed by sundown.
It's time.
BILLY: Man, this jungle goes on for ever.
TOMMY: We've gotta keep movin', guys.
Zordon's time is runnin' out.
Dad!
Hey, Dad!
Dad, what's wrong with you?
It's me - Fred.
Dad, we gotta get outta here!
Hey, you!
Get back to work!
PIG: Yeah! Pick up those rocks!
Tote that barge! Lift that bale!
GOLDAR: Put your weak backs into it!
PIG: Yeah, I had a weak back
about a week back.
Feast your eyes on the exoskeleton
of the Barbaric Hornitor!
The Dreaded Scorpitron
should be close by.
Once my lovely little Ecto-Morphicon
machines are up and running,
spreading ooze throughout the world,
I shall annihilate Angel Grove,
and then... the universe!
PIG: # We're takin' over the world!
We're takin' over the world #
- AISHA: What is this place?
- BILLY: Looks like some kind of graveyard.
- KIMBERLY: I wonder what happened.
- ADAM: Personally, I'd rather not find out.
- Welcome to Jurassic Park.
- AISHA: Very funny, Adam.
TOMMY: Aisha, get outta there!
Rocky!
Uh-oh.
Wait for me!
- Tommy!
- Hang on!
Tommy!
All right, bonehead!
- Tommy, hang on!
- Whoa! Whoa!
Tommy!
Whoa!
Hold on tight, Tommy!
Yo, fossil head!
I've got a bone to pick with you!
Huh? Whoa!
Are you OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Biology finally paid off for you, huh?
We should get outta here
before he pulls himself together.
Yeah.
GOLDAR: You there! Let's show a little
initiative! And you, get your rear in gear!
Pick up the pace! We haven't got all day!
- Hey, boss, construction is completed.
- PIG: Yeah, when's lunch?
Parents of Angel Grove!
You have completed my Ecto-Morphicons!
But, frankly, I'm sick of your ugly faces
and your dull personalities.
- Yeah!
- (giggles/snorts)
You will return to the construction site
and leap to your doom.
- Leap to your doom.
- Bye-bye.
- GOLDAR: Bye-bye!
- GOLDAR: Aloha!
GOLDAR: Arrivederci!
- Dad!
- IVAN: Hasta la vista, baby.
GOLDAR: See ya! Wouldn't wanna be ya!
Ciao.
See ya later, alligator.
Finally, the moment of truth!
Mordant, let the ooze flow!
Comin' right up.
Ooze, give my creatures life!
Life, I tell you! Life!
Excellent!
Now my machines will destroy the city!
ADAM: Wow.
Hey, guys, check this out.
BILLY: lncredible.
Let's go, guys. Nice and easy.
What do you think?
Wait here.
Tommy!
- What now?
- Ninjetti!
- Falcon!
- The frog!
- The ape!
- The crane!
- The wolf!
- Bear!
These things are made of rock.
These guys are strong.
Yikes.
Back off, boulder breath!
Hang tight, Adam!
Ever play leapfrog?
- Adam!
- Hang on, Rocky!
Hey, lava head!
Thanks, Adam. Thought I was finished.
That's one down, and three to go.
Whoa!
Somebody help!
Let's talk about this.
Guess not.
Come on, roll!
Hang on, Kimberly!
They're strong, but they're not too smart.
Help me push.
Right.
KIMBERLY: Let's rock his world.
What is this, pick-on-the-frog day?
- Hey, Adam, could you use a hand?
- The thought crossed my mind.
Adam!
Elevator goin' up.
BILLY: Elevator goin' down.
Talk about a splitting headache.
Whoa! That was close.
- All right. Ready?
- Yeah.
Go!
Ninjetti corkscrew kick!
Eightball, corner pocket!
What now?
- Whoa. What's happening?
- TOMMY: Look.
The great power.
The sacred animals.
ROCKY: New Zords!
- We did it!
- Our morphers are on line.
- We got the power!
- Hang on, Zordon!
- We're on our way.
- Let's do it.
DULCEA: Good luck, Rangers.
Citizens of Angel Grove,
how do you like my friends, huh?
The boys are back in town!
Long live the King of Ooze!
The mayor has declared a state of emergency.
He"s asked that the city
be immediately evacuated.
Angel Grove has never before known...
Aye-yai-yai-yai-yai! Ivan's evil machines
are destroying Angel Grove!
Alpha...
keep trying.
TV: Where are the Power Rangers?
I love the smell of destruction in the evening.
Me, too.
What's that smell?
Inconceivable.
The Power Rangers!
- Oh, man! Look at this mess.
- This is lvan's handiwork.
- Let's get back to the command centre.
- Wait. What was that?
I think we're about to find out. Look!
- Whoa. What is that thing?
- lvan's been busy while we were away.
Whoa!
- What's that?
- AISHA: There's another one.
KIMBERLY: And it's even uglier.
- Whoa.
- We've gotta stop these things.
- We've got new Ninja Zords. Let's use 'em!
- Right!
Ninja crane Zord!
Ninja wolf Zord!
Ninja frog Zord!
Ninja ape Zord!
Ninja bear Zord!
Ninja falcon Zord!
GOLDAR: Uh-oh!
- Check it out!
- Ninja Zords!
Cool!
- Yes!
- Awesome!
Oh, no! It's the Zords!
Ah, Zords, schmords.
I'll crush 'em like roaches.
- Let's do it!
- Right! Ninja Zords power up!
Ready to ride. Yes!
- All systems on line.
- Activating weapon systems.
- Nice stereo.
- We're outta here!
(parents chanting) Leap to our doom.
Leap to our doom.
# Uh-oh, we're in trouble #
# Something's come along
and it's burst our bubble #
# Yeah, yeah #
Hey, everyone!
Listen up! You all think
this is one big party, don't you?
- Yeah!
- Well, you've all been brainwashed.
Ivan's taking over the planet
and he's using all of us in his plans!
- And he's got our parents.
- What are you talking about?
Look, lvan Ooze is evil.
And if you don't come with me right now, our
parents are gonna die! You gotta believe me!
TOMMY: Rangers, I'm over the east quadrant.
My sensors are pickin' up a disturbance.
I'm goin' in.
Somebody call for an exterminator?
I've got a lock.
Rockets away!
I've been hit! I'm pullin' out!
Don't worry, Tommy, Frog Zord is in position.
We got 'em now, boss.
Touch me again,
you'll be chicken wings in the morning.
ADAM: Tongue-tied and twisted.
Yee-hah!
Bad move, sparky.
You play with fire, you're gonna get burned.
- I need backup!
- BILLY: l"m on my way!
Wolf Zord approaching target.
Keep him tied up. I'm loading hydraulics.
ADAM: I'm losin' him!
Here goes!
All right! Got him.
Time to boogie with the bear.
Whoa!
I've been hit hard!
Ape Zord locked on target.
Yee-hah!
Ride 'em, cowboy!
- Hang in there, Rocky!
- I'm hangin'! I'm hangin'!
FRED: Come on! We'll take the monorail!
Let's get down to the construction site!
All right, guys,
I've got a lock on the ooze man.
Ah!
Here comes that cute
little Pink Ranger to the rescue.
Oh, you think she's cute too, huh?
(lvan growls)
- One order of toasted slime comin' up.
- So, you wanna play, huh?
Ivan's got me in an electromagnetic deadlock!
I can't break free!
TOMMY: Hang on, Kimberly!
I'm getting airsick up here!
My stabilisers have ruptured!
I can't hold on much longer!
- I'm burning up in here!
- AISHA: Kimberly, use your thrusters!
Right! Now, which button?
Aaaaaggghhh!
- I'll deal with you later.
- Yeah, later.
Ah. Oozed.
I'm losing my grip!
I can't hold on much longer!
Falcon Zord is back in the game.
Adam, disengage. I've got a clear shot!
He's all yours.
All right, big guy, it's lights out for you.
Rockets away!
- He's outta there!
- Target neutralised. Let's get the other one.
He's too strong! I can't take him down!
Everybody close in. This street's a dead end.
IVAN: They've destroyed
my beautiful creation.
Now I'm beginning to get really angry!
Oh, I'm gonna be sick.
IVAN: I feel big again!
Go get 'em, booger man!
Whoa. Somebody call a plastic surgeon.
Oh, no!
I'm outta here!
Time for a little swordplay.
- He destroyed the monorail track.
- We need Ninja Megazord power now!
Ninja Megazord, power up!
Monorail's in trouble.
I'll complete docking sequence later.
KIMBERLY: We"ll take care of lvan.
# Go, go, Power Rangers #
# Mighty Morphin Power Rangers #
Crane Zord locked on.
Checking out.
Ninja battle mode now!
- Activating Ninja Megazord battle mode.
- Power Sword, now!
Shall we tango?
- Oh, no.
- What is that?
- The track's broken!
- Oh, no!
Hang on, kids.
- Falcon Zord is comin' in for a landin'.
- Everybody hang on!
All right! Yeah! Whoo!
Good luck, kids.
Power Sword has been destroyed.
- Pressure's dropping!
- Negative control!
- Tommy, we need your help!
- Hang tight, guys. I'm on my way.
- Everybody hang on!
- IVAN: Next stop, Angel Grove First National.
Whoaaa!
ADAM: Brace for impact!
- All systems down!
- He's closing in!
- Tommy, get your butt down here!
- Comin' in to complete the sequence.
Ninja Falcon Megazord!
Let's get Ooze outta here
before he destroys everything.
- I'll set a course for outer space.
- Good idea.
Let's do it!
You can run, but you can't hide.
Yee-hah!
(chanting) Leap to our doom.
Leap to our doom.
It's our parents!
You guys try and stop them.
And you two come with me.
- Guys, I think I know a way to get rid of lvan.
- Really? How?
- Ryan's Comet.
- Billy, that's brilliant!
- What?
- We get lvan in the comet's path...
And kaboom! He's space dust.
- All right, guys, main thrusters.
- Right!
- We can't hold 'em back!
- We have to keep on trying!
Turn it on!
Well, if it isn't that
double-dealing dough head!
I hope those Rangers
put that lousy lowlife out of my misery!
- Go, Rangers! Go, Rangers!
We're approaching the comet's coordinates.
All right, guys, this is it.
We'll wait here and lure him in.
I'm gonna rip you apart Zord by Zord.
TOMMY: Here he comes. Brace yourselves!
(lvan laughs)
- Micropressure's in the red!
- We're imploding!
Bearing 009. We're in the comet's trajectory.
We need to break free.
IVAN: Have you hugged your Zords today?
- Here it comes!
- We have to break his grip!
Desperate times
call for desperate measures.
- What are you doing?
- Taking care of business.
- We're outta here.
- Right!
Oh, no.
Yeah.
- Skull!
- Bulk...
Dad!
- Fred!
- Dad!
I love you, son.
Alpha!
Rangers, you made it!
But... I'm afraid you're too late.
BILLY: Too late?
This can't be happening.
Remember what we learnt?
To those who possess the great power,
all things are possible.
Come on.
Zordon!
Rangers!
He's alive! He's alive! He's alive!
- We thought that you had...
- It is good to see you again, too.
( # The Power" by Snap )
- SKULL: We were awesome.
- BULK: lncredible!
Ivan and his 50-foot monsters
had us surrounded.
- There was no escape.
- We knew we were facing death in the eye.
- We could smell death's breath.
- And death could use a mint.
Can you believe those guys?
I'm so hungry.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, Fred!
- Hey! Rumour has it you're quite the hero.
- That's my man!
I helped a bit.
The Power Rangers did most of the work.
Hey, things got tough, you didn't panic.
You, my friend, demonstrated true bravery.
It's like what you taught me about martial
arts: use your head, and above all, stay calm.
I heard you're in line to be
a Ranger yourself one of these days.
- Nah, that's impossible.
- Hey, anything's possible.
- You really think so?
- I know so.
- Fred Kelman, the Silver Ranger.
- It does have a certain ring to it.
Fred Kelman the Gold Ranger.
Check it out!
# We'll get higher and higher #
# Straight up we'll climb #
# Leave it all behind #
# So, baby, dry your eyes #
- All right!
- I don't believe it.
- Power Rangers?
- Bulk and Skull!
# Cos we belong #
# In a world that must be strong #
# Oh, that's what dreams are made of #
I am King Goldar,
the ruler of the universe!
Uh-oh.
Captioned by Grantman Brown