(WIND WHOOSHING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(BOXING SOUNDS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Are you seriously trying
to rope-a-dope me?
That's an old man's move.
I am an old man.
No, you're not.
But you box like one.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Not bad.
Come on, keep your guard up.
Come on!
(GROANS)
Come on, Ben,
you're telegraphin'.
(PANTING)
Mr. President.
Ten minutes, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you, Forbes.
Hey. You're not supposed
to hit the President.
Yeah. I know.
(CHUCKLES)
I'll get you next time.
Yeah.
I'm sure you will.
AGENT 1 ON RADIO: Perimeter secure.
AGENT 2 ON RADIO: Weather's
getting worse out there,
but we're advised
it's drivable.
Post vehicles to standby.
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Good evening, Mr. President.
Five minutes, sir.
Thanks, Mike.
Evening, ma'am.
Merry Christmas, Mike.
President gets us off our
dependence on foreign oil
yet he cannot help a
wife choose an earring.
Nah, small one. Classic
look for a classic lady.
Good chat.
(QUIETLY) Kiss ass.
Well, I love you both but
I am going with the long.
(SIGHS) I hate going
to these fundraisers.
Why don't you go for me?
(LAUGHS) Oh, honey.
You're perfect.
God forbid people know we kiss.
(GUN FIRING ON TV)
(CHRISTMAS MUSIC PLAYING)
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES ON TV)
Now the real bloodbath starts
when your mom catches
you playing this.
(SIGHS) You suck.
You suck worse.
Come on.
MAGGIE: Well, he likes it
when you call him Dries
because it makes him feel like, I
don't know, you're pals or something.
Hey, love. You wanna open
a gift before we go?
It's not "love,"
and I'm gonna wait till
everyone else is here.
(WHISPERING) Keep forgetting.
Sorry.
Do I really have to
come with you guys?
I mean, I've been on so many.
Re-election's
hard work, buddy.
MAGGIE: Sorry, pal.
Can I at least ride with Mike?
You'll have to ask him.
He's the boss.
Mike, do I get
to ride with you?
Okay. All right.
Okay, Diaz.
You're riding
in The Beast tonight.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you, sir.
You okay to stay back and
watch the fort tonight?
You kidding me?
In this weather?
Get out of this monkey
suit, sit by the fire,
watch Breaking Bad?
Fine by me.
My own little retirement party.
Leave the babysitter
alone, all right?
Are you going to wear that hat?
I like the hat.
I think it's fine.
It's age appropriate.
You take it off
when you get inside.
No, the girls dig it.
Mustang, this is Big Top.
Bringing out the full package.
Let's go.
AGENT ON RADIO:
Package is on the move.
ETA to Morgan
residence, 22 minutes.
Keep it tight, everybody.
Hey, Connon Come on.
Scoot back.
Put your belt on.
What if I don't?
Then O'Neil here's gonna
punch you in the nuts.
Come on.
(ROMA CHUCKLES)
You keeping 180
degrees awareness?
I thought you said it was 360?
Yeah, just checkin'.
Setting me up
is what you're doing.
All right. So, how
many emergency exits
in the West Wing?
Eight.
How many feet from the Oval
Office to the P.E.O.C. elevator?
116.
From doors closing
in the elevator,
how long does it take
to get to the P.E.O.C.?
Four minutes.
Security cameras?
How many have audio?
Only the ones
in the common areas.
Not bad.
Kid's got it, huh?
Yeah, we're gonna make a Secret
Service agent outta you yet.
You just need to remember
to keep your seatbelt on.
(LAUGHING) That's right.
(CHUCKLES)
(WIND HOWLING)
Gosh, it's really coming down.
Hmm.
I've been thinking
about shaving my head.
That sounds good.
AGENT ON RADIO: It's getting worse out there.
Bring it down to five.
Merry Christmas,
Mr. President.
You shouldn't have.
My God. It's my
grandfather's watch.
How did you find this?
Just have my ways.
Thank you.
Mmm.
You're just welcome.
Now, let's talk about
that shaved head idea.
(LAUGHS) You were listening.
You didn't think I was listening, did you?
Very clever.
You ever been to a billionaire's
Christmas party before, Diaz?
No, sir.
They're overrated.
Yes, sir.
Oh, my gosh.
Look what I found.
Where'd that come from?
Merry Christmas.
(WIND HOWLING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GRUNTS)
Stop, stop, stop!
(GROANS)
Hey, Connon stay right there!
Clear communications, Diaz.
First Lady's injured.
Connon
Get some weight on the back!
O'Neil, get on the back!
I'm gonna get this door!
Don't anybody move inside.
Don't move!
Maggie!
(AGENTS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
AGENT ON RADIO: Eagle Number
One is hanging off the bridge.
Route 117.
Get the birds out.
(AGENTS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Sir?
Seatbelt's stuck!
Sir, get out of the car!
I'll take care of her!
Keep your weight
on the back, O'Neil!
Roma, open the fucking door!
It's jammed! It's fucking jammed!
Pull her out that side!
It's going down.
ROMA: O'Neil, God damn it!
Hold it down!
Mike, it's going!
ROMA: Hold it back!
ASHER: Mike, take Maggie!
Shit.
Sir, I'm sorry.
ROMA: Watch out, it's going!
It's going! ASHER: Maggie!
No, Mike!
(CRASHING)
No!
Dad!
Mom!
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
(WATER RUNNING)
(WATER STOPS)
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
I don't like going to barbecues
by myself, you know?
(SIGHS)
NEWSCASTER: North Korean
maneuvers along the DMZ continue
to ring alarm bells
throughout Pacific markets,
even as President Asher
is set to meet
this afternoon
with South Korean...
Babe,
we out of coffee?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
Are we?
All right, just...
I thought you said
that anything...
(WHIRRING LOUDLY)
(CLEARS THROAT)
You were saying?
I was saying, I'll get
some more coffee.
Great.
Yeah.
So, how was the
barbecue I missed?
It was actually kind of fun.
You might have enjoyed it.
Yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
Paula's got this new
boyfriend who's very sweet
but he's working in the same
department as her ex, Alex.
Remember Alex?
Anyway, Alex ended up
showing up at the party,
which was really weird
for Paula, who was...
(SIGHS) Overwhelmed.
Mike, you're
not listening to me.
Yeah.
I was listening.
You were talking about
Patty's boyfriend and...
No. Paula
and Paula's boyfriend.
You've met Paula.
(SCOFFS) It's okay, Mike.
We'll talk about it later.
All right, babe.
I'm sorry.
But I tell you what.
Why don't we go see
a movie tonight?
Okay? Just
the two of us.
Or you can bring
Paula and Patty
and their boyfriends.
You know what
I think we should do?
I think we should
take that holiday
that we've been talking about.
All right?
You, me, the ocean.
Come on. It'll be like the
honeymoon we never had.
We didn't have a honeymoon?
(GIGGLES)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Thank you.
BANNING: Thanks.
So, how was your Fourth?
My fourth what?
Fourth of July.
Don't be an ass.
Some people do take
holidays, you know.
Yeah, it was quiet.
You know, we stayed in.
We?
Okay. I stayed in.
She went out.
I'm shocked.
ROMA: Ms. Jacobs?
JACOBS: Good morning.
Morning, Director.
How are you, buddy?
Hey, Roma.
Good to see you, partner.
How's the family?
The kids are good. Thank you.
Yeah. Yeah?
O'Neil.
Hey, Banning.
You're looking sharp.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
ROMA: So, we missed you
for poker, uh, last week.
Where were you? Missed
taking your money.
Yeah, I know. I've been
working the late shift.
Yeah, non-stop action over
there at the Treasury.
You gotta do what
you gotta do, right?
Yeah. You guys got a big
day coming up, huh?
You got the Koreans coming in?
Nah, I mean, you know.
Business as usual.
Hey, I wanted to introduce you.
This is Agent Jones.
You've heard of Mike
Banning, haven't you?
JONES: Yeah, yeah. The guy who
told the Speaker of the House
to go fuck himself.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Don't you guys
have somewhere to be?
Yes, ma'am.
Hey, Mike. Good seein' you.
Yeah, you too.
Come Thursday night, all right?
Okay.
ROMA: 7:00.
Not getting any easier, huh?
No.
I want back in.
Desk job is killing me.
Mike. Everybody knows you did
the right thing on that bridge.
Hell, even the President knows.
He just doesn't want
to see you and have
to be reminded of it every day.
He never even stopped
to grieve properly.
Just give it some time.
How's Connor?
President's son,
misses his mom.
Hell of a gig.
Misses his buddy, though.
Yeah, he's a good kid.
Is he still sneaking around the White
House, making everybody crazy?
Oh, I wonder
who taught him that.
You know, the first
time you walked
into my office
out of the darkness
you needed therapy then.
Never mind now.
And you don't exactly
do yourself any favors.
Where are you going with this?
Mike. Look, you gotta learn how
to get back into the real world.
That's good, Jacobs.
Let me write that one down.
(SIGHS)
Hey, Jacobs.
Thanks.
I'll be in touch.
ASHER: Hey, buddy.
What do you
think of this? Hmm?
Which one do you like?
I don't know.
Okay, you take that one.
I'll take this one.
ASHER: Maggie! Maggie!
BANNING: I'll take care
of her.
No, Mike!
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
Deb.
Mr. Foss came in, chest
pains, about an hour ago.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
ANSWERING MACHINE: Hey, it's Leah.
You've reached my phone.
You know what to do.
(BEEPS)
Just checking in.
Uh...
(EXHALES) Listen,
I'll call you later. Bye.
ASHER: Get some fishing in.
Hit the bag together.
It'll be fun.
I hate Camp David.
Do we really have to go?
Can't we go somewhere else?
You know, the beach?
Yeah.
The beach does
kinda sound better.
Hey. I've got
three minutes.
Let's run down to the kitchen
and get some ice cream.
Yeah.
Hmm?
Chocolate chip or rocky road?
I'm gonna have rocky road
before you eat it all, like
you did the last time.
I don't remember it that way.
Yeah, you did.
(CHUCKLES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in.
Mr. President,
we're ready for you.
Already?
Yes, sir.
(SIGHS)
Sorry, buddy.
It's okay, Dad.
All right.
I'll see you soon.
TRUMBULL: Minister Lee is
going to want you to issue
a joint statement,
Mr. President.
Threatening military action
to get the North Koreans
to stand down from the border
and stop their missile tests.
Which I think
we should give them.
Ruth?
Provided that the
North Koreans are rational
which is dicey, at best.
We bluff. They call it.
Then what?
Well, who says
we'd be bluffing?
Personally, I'd like
to try to avoid a war.
(SIGHS)
Charlie?
I think I agree with Ruth
on this one, Mr. President.
Thank you for
sitting in, Mr. Speaker.
Yes, sir.
I won't hold you up any longer.
Hello, Mr. Speaker.
Hello, Janie.
What time is Minister
Lee due to arrive?
McMILLAN: 7:00 this evening.
(SIREN WAILING)
(MAN SPEAKING KOREAN)
Our guests have arrived.
Prime Minister Lee.
I'm Special
Agent-in-Charge Roma.
I'd like to welcome you
to the White House, sir.
Thank you. May I introduce my Head of
Security and Chief Aide, Mr. Park.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
A pleasure.
Prime Minister,
after you, please.
Agent Davis will be taking care
of your security team outside.
Prime Minister, if you would
follow Agent O'Neil, please?
Ma'am?
Private sector looks
good on you, Dave.
Yeah, something
to look forward to.
Yeah. How you been?
Ah, I tell you, I miss
the Secret Service.
Best years of my life.
ROMA: It misses
you too, old man.
I could still kick your ass.
(LAUGHS)
At what? Dominoes?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
It's good to see you,
my friend.
FORBES: You, too.
F-22 PILOT ON RADIO: Unidentified
flight, this is flight leader,
U.S. Air Force aircraft
at your starboard wing.
You've entered
restricted airspace.
Unidentified flight,
you must divert immediately
to vector 0-2-0. Acknowledge.
I'm sorry to have
disrupted your vacation.
(LAUGHS) Please.
I'm glad you could come.
Mr. Lee, we have
a mutual problem.
And I think together, I'm
confident we can find a solution.
Thank you, Mr. President.
That's why I'm here.
As you know, North Korea has a
one million man standing army
less than 50 kilometers
from our capital.
The threat is real.
F-22 PILOT: Unidentified flight,
you must divert immediately
to vector 0-2-0.
This is your final warning.
You will be shot down.
Acknowledge.
(BEEPING) Anti-aircraft.
We're taking fire.
Mr. Lee, I'm sure you can
appreciate that this is...
Sir? There's been an incursion.
Please stand up.
Let's go.
Move.
Mr. Lee,
please join us.
That's not protocol, sir.
He's coming with us!
ROMA: Move, move!
AGENT: Get him to the elevator.
(ALARM BLARING)
ROMA: Go! Go!
Find Connor!
MAN ON PA: Code 999.
ROMA: Go, go, go! Move!
Get that elevator open now!
MAN ON PA: Code 999.
Give me four minutes,
Mr. President.
Harden down on Olympus.
MAN ON RADIO: Air support on the way.
ETA four minutes.
Code Red. Air space 1
and 2 compromised.
Bravo, Delta, ready one.
Move to west corner.
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
This way, please.
This is not a drill.
Evacuate immediately.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
MAN ON PA: All units, 999.
I repeat.
All units, 999.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(BEEPING)
Let's move!
Find my son.
It's O'Neil. Find
Sparkplug immediately.
AGENT: You okay,
Mr. President?
O'NEIL: Sir, right this way. Over here, sir.
Right this way.
Go on! Get down!
Get down!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(PLANE ENGINE ROARING)
Stay down!
Don't move!
Get down!
Get out of the way!
Take cover!
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
PPD Command, this is Wolfhound Six.
Have bogey in sight.
PPD COMMAND: Wolfhound Six, fire at will.
Repeat, fire at will.
Acknowledge.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(FAINT CHATTER ON EARPIECE)
Mr. President?
(QUIETLY) We have confirmation
that the bogey is down, sir.
Thank you, Jones.
Activate Com Plan One.
I want open lines
to the Pentagon,
Homeland Security and NSA.
Charlie.
Coordinate with
the Air Force and FAA.
Find out if that's a lone aircraft.
Yes, sir.
Half hour at the most.
Ruth. Where the
hell is my son?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Just go.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Hey!
Hey, get the fuck down!
(EXPLOSIVE POWERING UP)
(EARS RINGING)
(GROANING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Thirty-three, thirty...
(GRUMBLES)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(GROANS)
Mr. Lee.
We've had a problem.
Please have patience with us.
Mr. President.
Yes?
It's a critical message.
The White House
is under ground attack.
(GROANS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
MAN: Officer on deck!
Rapid Response Team from
Andrews, get 'em moving!
At ease.
How bad is it?
Front fence has been breached.
We've got a C-130 burning
on the South Lawn
and a gunfight
raging on the North.
Fucking shitting me.
Where's the President?
In the bunker.
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(BARKING)
(GROANING)
(GUN FIRING)
(DOG WHIMPERS)
(GROANS)
Get me the Pentagon
on the line now!
AGENT: Yes, sir.
YU: It's happening.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(YELPS)
Mr. President!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
AGENT: Forbes,
what are you doing?
Move!
For God's sakes, Forbes.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(FORBES GRUNTS)
You are not to run.
Sit down!
Forbes, what are you doing?
FORBES: Shut up!
(GROANS)
(MAN SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
(GASPING)
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(GROANS)
(MACHINE GUN FIRE CONTINUES)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(OFFICER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(BEEPS)
Come on, Tim.
Come on.
Come on, hang in there!
Shit.
(BULLET RICOCHETING)
Where's the President?
I don't know!
God damn it! Where's
that response team?
MONROE: They're five
minutes out, sir, but...
But what?
We may have a hostage
situation on our hands.
P.E.O.C.'s
gone offline.
(AGENTS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Go back!
Go back! Go!
(ALL GROANING)
No!
Ahh!
(GROANS)
Shit.
Fuck!
RPG!
(SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
Kenny, get inside!
Get inside!
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(GROANS)
Come on!
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING
IN KOREAN)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(CONTINUE SPEAKING KOREAN)
(GUN FIRING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Video monitoring off.
Initiating external lockdown.
(BEEPING)
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Go, go! Move!
ROMA: Fall back!
Fall back!
(GROANING)
AGENT 1: They're down the hall.
AGENT 2: Shit, we've only
got four guys left!
AGENT 3: You hold your
position, you understand?
I got this door.
Cover the other one.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Ahh!
(GROANS)
(SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
(MACHINE GUN FIRING) Fuck!
Oh, shit! Son of a...
(PANTING)
Olympus has fallen.
(GRUNTING)
Fuck you!
They've taken the White House.
(BEEPING)
SOLDIER 1: Move, boy!
Let's go! Let's go!
Move! Move!
SOLDIER 2: Let's go,
let's go!
SOLDIER 3: Go, go, go!
(SIREN WAILING)
SNIPER: Command, Sniper
Team 1 in position.
(BEEPING)
(MAN 1 SPEAKING
KOREAN ON RADIO)
East Wing is secure.
(MAN 2 SPEAKING
KOREAN ON RADIO)
West Wing is secure.
Control override complete.
Air vents sealed.
White House systems secured.
All outside networks
locked out.
ARMY OFFICER: They're coming
from the White House.
So far,
the perimeter's been set.
We're waiting on more intel
to come in right now,
and once we do,
Bravo team's gonna breach.
Wait for my command to execute.
Yes, sir.
Not since the British
burned down the White House
in the War of 1812
has an enemy force occupied
the center of American power.
The White House, the most protected
building on Earth, has fallen.
AGENT ON RADIO: Sir, we have
a hot feed from the P.E.O.C.
(BEEPS)
Minister Lee.
Sir, are you safe?
Are you with the President?
Sir, can you hear...
My God.
Don't negotiate.
Sir?
I have your
commander-in-chief.
Now, stand down.
Who are you?
I am the man in control
of your White House.
Now, stand your men down.
Stand down!
MONROE: Sir.
All units, stand down!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are at DEFCON 4.
How could you?
Put your hands up.
Fuck you.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(WOMAN BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SCREAMING)
Let go of her, she's a nurse!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
No!
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(CHO SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
McMILLAN: Bastards!
There is a reason
I never voted for you.
MAN: Don't do it, Forbes.
(CHO SPEAKING KOREAN)
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(CHO CONTINUES
SPEAKING KOREAN)
(PLANE WHIRRING)
(MAN SPEAKING KOREAN
ON RADIO)
The drone has been deployed.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(POWER SHUTTING DOWN)
(TYPING)
KANG: It takes 15 minutes
for your Armed Forces
to reach the White House.
(CHUCKLES)
We took it down in 13.
(DOOR OPENING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(BEEPS)
(BEEPING)
(BOTH SPEAKING KOREAN)
Mr. Kang.
Can you get them back?
Pull up the
surveillance archives.
DOCTOR 1: Hurry,
we need a wheelchair.
In triage, do you want me to
color-code them or number-code them?
Color-code 'em.
Okay, Fran, we still need
to take his vitals.
DOCTOR 1: Fran, we got to
take this one to CT.
DOCTOR 2: Let's go!
Let's go!
DOCTOR 3: He's gone.
(WAILING)
Oh, Mike. Mike!
(AMBULANCE SIREN BLARING)
OPERATOR: The cellular service
in the area you are calling
has been suspended temporarily.
EMT: I got a head trauma, six-year-old girl.
She's fading!
DOCTOR 4: CT scan, now!
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
Bring Mr. Asher here.
What are you doing,
for Christ's sake?
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Oh, sir!
I have no interest in
your nuclear launch codes.
By now your Pentagon
has changed them, no?
Sit.
You from the North?
You sure as hell
are not from the South.
(RESTRAINT TIGHTENING)
I'm working for justice.
To give millions of starving
men, women, and children
a chance at more
than just subsistence.
To end the civil war your country
interrupted so long ago.
And yes,
for a united, prosperous Korea.
It's a whole new world, baby.
What's the going rate
for souls these days?
What'd you say to me?
I never would have taken
you for a traitor.
Me?
What about you?
You sold this country out
long before I ever did.
Globalization and
fucking Wall Street.
What's it cost to buy a
presidency nowadays anyway?
Huh?
$500 million?
I'm a fucking rookie
compared to you!
(GROANS)
Gotta keep
your gloves up, Forbes.
Enough! (SPEAKING KOREAN)
Find the boy,
his name is Connor.
What about Connor?
What the fuck are you
gonna do with my son?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Mr. Speaker.
As both the President and the Vice
President of the United States
are unable to discharge
the duties of their offices,
I'm officially placing you under
Secret Service protection.
(CLEARS THROAT)
You are the Acting President
of the United States.
Are they alive?
They are.
Sir, North Korea is denying any
involvement in the attack.
We've secured the perimeter
of the White House
and cleared
a 10-block radius.
Sir, they've also assassinated
the South Korean Prime Minister.
(BEEPING)
(DIALING)
(RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(WHISPERING)
We have contact
from inside the White House.
Trace confirms it's
the President's sat phone.
Put it through!
Mr. President?
BANNING: Negative.
Identify yourself.
Echelon Four.
It's one of yours?
Designator?
Oscar Zulu 309.
Jesus. Banning?
Where are you?
I'm in the Oval Office.
Is the President in the bunker?
He...
Can we trust him?
Banning was one
of our best agents.
Mr. Speaker, I just have to
say, this is Mike Banning.
Is this the same guy that was
removed from the President's detail
after the accident when we lost
the First Lady? Ray! Ray! Ray!
What's he doing in the White House?
You wanna add something?
I suggest you get
your facts straight.
How do we know
we can trust this guy?
Banning is ex-Special Forces,
Ranger battalion.
He will move mountains
or die trying.
I know him.
Does anyone else
in this room have
any intelligence coming out
of the White House?
Then we have no choice.
(CLICKS)
Yes. The President's
in the bunker.
He's being held hostage.
What do they want?
We're trying to find out.
Who's in charge?
Trumbull.
Are there any
survivors with you?
Negative, sir.
They wiped us out.
They have commandos
roaming the hallways
with enough explosives
to take out an army.
Looks like the doors and windows
are rigged with C-4 explosives.
Who knows what other tricks
they have up their sleeves.
Any team coming in is gonna be ringing
the front doorbell pretty loud.
They shut the power down.
Lights off. And I assume
they closed the air vents.
I killed the surveillance, but I don't
know how long that's gonna last.
Where's Connor?
We have no status of his location, but
he's presumed to still be inside.
Well, they're looking for him.
They have his photo.
Sir, I'm here. Use me.
Okay, Banning. Sit tight.
We'll get back with you.
(CLICKING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(GROANS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
MAN: What part of expedite
do you not understand?
MAN ON RADIO: Sir, we have a
hot feed from the P.E.O.C.
Mr. Speaker.
What is it you want?
Recall the Seventh Fleet
from the Sea of Japan,
and withdraw all 28,500 American
troops from the Demilitarized Zone.
If you do not comply, if you attempt
any operation to retake this building,
if you deviate
from my instructions...
Wait a minute. We can't just
recall the Seventh Fleet.
Then I will execute your
officials one by one
and their blood
will be on your hands.
You have until dawn.
I suggest you move quickly.
Who is that guy?
Well, sir, we're running facial
recognition on him right now.
Well, he cleared as part of the
South Korean security detail.
If we recall the Fleet
and leave the DMZ,
Seoul and all of South Korea
could fall within 72 hours, sir.
But if we do nothing, they kill
Asher, the Vice President,
and his entire
National Security team.
And Connor, if he's in there.
Mary, get me some coffee.
Half-and-half,
three Sweet'N Lows.
In a real cup, not one of those
paper or Styrofoam things.
All right.
Let's secure all nuclear sites.
Get me our expert
on North Korea.
Then I want to speak with
the Premier of North Korea
on a secure line.
After that, I wanna speak
with the Russians,
the Chinese, the British,
and the French.
And set up a press conference.
In that order.
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
United States of America doesn't
negotiate with terrorists.
Who said anything
about negotiating?
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(KANG SPEAKING KOREAN)
Bring him.
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING KOREAN)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Admiral Hoenig,
your Cerberus code.
You kill him,
you won't get the code.
I will not ask again.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
Give it to him, Joe.
Mr. President...
Shh.
ASHER: You'll never get mine.
Tango-Juliet-1
9-3-3-4.
Louden
Tango-Juliet-1-9-3-3-4.
(TYPING)
(BEEPS)
(ALARM BEEPING)
MAN: What the hell?
Get me Homeland
Security. No, now!
Sir, NORAD reports
a Cerberus code
has been entered.
CLEGG: Jesus.
Jacobs, I got something coming your way.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
I got a Korean commando
in front of me.
TRUMBULL: What is that?
JACOBS: Is he alive?
Ask me a serious question.
Anybody around the table?
We don't recognize it.
Well, whoever they are,
they're fucking good.
They're well-trained
and they're well-organized.
But I guess you
know that already.
Get that over to Langley.
Yes, sir.
So, what have you got?
Talk to me.
They want us to recall the Seventh
Fleet and pull our troops out.
Oh, is that all?
A Cerberus code
has been entered.
(GUN COCKING) What's Cerberus?
That's classified.
Classified?
Really?
Well, right now I think I have the
proverbial need-to-fucking-know.
Cerberus is a highly
classified military protocol.
A three-pronged fail-safe in the case
of an inadvertent nuclear launch.
It allows us to access the self-destruct
mechanism in our ICBMs in-flight.
So even if one of our nuclear
warheads was launched
and we wanted to abort...
TRUMBULL: Cerberus is
the only way to stop it
from reaching its target.
No one person has
all three codes.
It's parceled out
to the President,
Secretary of Defense and the
Chairman of the Joint Chiefs.
All of whom are in the
President's bunker right now.
With those codes, they can destroy
any long-range nuke that we fire.
And that will make America
vulnerable to a nuclear strike.
So, change the codes.
MONROE: We can't.
Cerberus was designed as a
self-contained, total-isolation system.
The only way to change the code is
physically on the computer itself.
Which is located in
the President's bunker.
So, now we know why they
wanted the President's son.
The President will hold
out as long as he can.
But if they get his son,
if they hurt him...
Well, nobody could hold out
under those circumstances.
So, find Connor,
get him the hell out of there.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Forbes.
Who is that?
(KANG SPEAKING KOREAN)
Show him.
(BEEPING)
Mike Banning.
And who might that be?
He was on the President's
protection detail for a few years.
Are we worried about him?
Hell, no.
No.
(SCOFFS)
(WHISPERING) He should be.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Find Banning now!
(MEN WHISPERING IN KOREAN)
(SHUSHING)
(WHISPERING IN KOREAN)
(CLOSES DOOR)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
He's not here.
We've completed search
of the living quarters.
Did Truman gut the White House
interior in 1948 or '49?
I believe it was '49.
Steel frame over
the old stone walls. Yes?
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
He's in the walls.
(WHISPERING IN KOREAN)
(CREAKING)
(WHISPERS) Connor.
Shh!
How are you doing?
You okay?
Yeah, I'm all right.
I see this is still your
favorite hiding place, huh?
Two seconds.
BANNING: I've got Sparkplug.
Finally, some good news.
BANNING: He's safe.
I'm bringing him out.
What about my dad?
Your dad's gonna be fine, okay?
Nothing bad's gonna happen.
We're gonna get him outta here.
(FLOORBOARD CREAKS)
(WHISPERING IN KOREAN)
(INAUDIBLE)
(SHOUTS IN KOREAN)
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Okay?
Yeah.
All right.
Let's get outta here.
You ready to haul ass?
Yeah.
Okay, stay close.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Come on.
Okay, come on.
(PANTING)
All right, kiddo.
Keep an eye out, okay?
Watch my six.
Jacobs.
Okay, I have Sparkplug.
He's coming out in a ventilation
shaft in the northwest corner,
ground floor.
Have the green party waiting.
We'll be there.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
How are you gonna
fit through that?
You're coming with me, right?
I gotta go get your dad.
All right?
Now, listen, you can do this.
Now, you remember the chimney climb I
taught you on the Rose Garden wall? Yeah?
So, that's all it is. Okay?
It's one foot against the front
wall, one foot against the back.
Now, all the way to the top.
Mike?
Yeah.
I'm scared.
Yeah, me too.
But you're gonna
get through it. (SIGHS)
You're one of us now.
It's yours. Put that on.
Now, I'm counting
on you, kiddo.
Okay.
Good man.
All right. Let's go.
(GRUNTS)
There you go, kiddo. I'm
gonna push you on up, okay?
I'll see you on the other side.
CONNOR: Okay.
Now, keep movin'.
Sparkplug is on his way up.
(MAN SPEAKING KOREAN)
Whoa, Jacobs, hold on.
Connor, wait up.
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(CRACKING)
False alarm. Go.
Okay.
He's coming out, Jacobs.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
SNIPER ON RADIO: Hold your position.
Hostiles in the area.
Go, go, go!
It's clear.
SOLDIER ON RADIO: Set one. Going in.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
SOLDIER: You okay?
ON RADIO:
Coming out. Cover us.
SNIPER: Hostile moving
toward the ledge. Hustle up.
WOMAN: Oh, my God.
Sparkplug received.
(SIGHS)
TRUMBULL: Good job, Banning.
Now, let's see if we can
get the President out.
(WHISPERING) Roger that.
I want to reassure
all Americans
and everyone around the world
that despite today's events,
our government
remains 100% functional.
We know that
the President is alive.
To our friends, we are grateful
for your loyalty and support.
As a nation, we are never
stronger than when tested.
We will remain
united and strong.
God bless you all, and God bless
these United States of America.
(ALL GRUNTING)
(KOREAN SOLDIERS PANTING)
BANNING: Okay, asshole. Yo. Hey.
Who's running the show?
Hmm?
Oh, you speak English? They teach
you that where you come from?
'Cause you know
what they teach me?
Is how to extract information
from people like you.
(CHUCKLING)
(ALL CHUCKLING)
That's funny, huh?
No, it's funny.
I know. I get it.
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SIGHS)
Yeah.
I guess I'm a little rusty.
I liked your friend, though.
He seems like a funny guy.
What's your leader's name?
Oh, I'm sorry. Here.
How many men you with?
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
In English.
BANNING: His name is Yeonsak Kang.
He's the head of the KUF,
the paramilitary organization.
No surprises there. 40
commandos breached the gate.
28 are left.
How do we know we can
trust the information?
I just asked them nicely.
Kang Yeonsak?
Sir, this is one of the most
wanted terrorists in the world.
He was brought across the DMZ as a
child after his father was executed
for crimes against
the North Korean state.
While they were crossing
the border, his mother was
killed by an American landmine.
This guy masterminded the 2004 bombing
of the British Embassy in Seoul.
And he funneled Pyongyang uranium
enrichment technology from Pakistan.
He's never before been
photographed or identified
by any Western
intelligence agency.
Well, Jesus Christ, nobody
ever thought to look for him
inside the South Korean
government.
Look, I don't care who he is.
With a force that size,
I have men who can
sweep 'em out in short order.
Sir, this is not
going to be a cakewalk.
These sons of bitches
are pretty fucking tough.
I've got the toughest
fuckin' guys in the world.
What we need to know is how
to get into that bunker.
Once those blast doors close, you don't.
It's nuclear hardened.
Now, there used to be some old tunnels,
but they were sealed up years ago.
Sir, your men need to know
what the hell
they're dropping into.
Do not launch anything
until I do some recon.
(POWERING UP)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
KANG ON RADIO: Agent Banning.
Yes, I know who you are.
Welcome to my house.
(BEEPS) Hey, asshole.
What took you so long?
You're the one that let
the First Lady die, no?
And soon, the President.
Failure seems to be
a habit with you.
Yeah, well.
Maybe I owe you
for giving me the chance
for making up for that today.
I admire you for
acknowledging your failure.
But there's no going back.
Nothing you try and do
here tonight can atone.
Yeah, maybe not.
But I reckon fucking your shit
up will be a pretty good start.
You may wanna take a headcount.
The bodies are piling up.
I have more than enough
men to finish the mission.
Oh, and by the way, if
you're looking for Connor,
he's on his way
to the baseball game.
How's your wife, Michael?
Leah. She's a nurse.
Saves lives.
Too bad she will
not save yours.
You know what? Why don't you
and I play a game of fuck off?
You go first.
(BEEPS)
Go kill him.
(SOLDIER SPEAKING KOREAN)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Madam Secretary.
Your Cerberus code.
No!
(GRUNTS)
Ruth!
Your code!
You'll have to kill me.
As you wish.
(GROANING)
(SPITS)
There's a saying in Korea.
(WHIMPERING)
Seeing something 100 times
is not as good as
living it once.
Fuck you.
(GROANS)
ASHER: Stop!
Enough!
(GROANS)
Enough! Stop!
(GROANING)
ASHER: Enough!
(GRUNTS)
(MCMILLAN GASPING)
(WHEEZING)
Give it to him, Ruth.
It doesn't matter.
They won't get mine.
(WHEEZING)
ASHER: Ruth.
(GROANING)
ASHER: Give it to him!
That's an order, Ruth.
Sir...
Give it to him, Ruth.
Yes, sir.
Echo-Mike
6-0-2-8...
(TYPING)
Five, sir.
(BEEPING)
Get your fucking
hands off of me!
(GRUNTS)
(SOBBING)
Sir, NORAD reports that the second
Cerberus code has been entered.
My God.
Mike! Mike. Mike, it's me.
Dave?
You scared the shit out of me.
Jesus, what the fuck?
Yeah, just put that thing down.
Jesus, I almost blew your fucking brains out, man.
What are you doing here?
I was with the
South Korean delegation.
What the fuck
are you doing here?
I thought you were working
at the Treasury. Yeah, I am.
Believe it or not, I came
in through the front door.
Oh, fuck, Mike.
I saw my life
flash in front of me.
Look at my hand. Fucking shakin'.
Jesus Christ.
It's good to see you, buddy.
You got a funny
way of showing it.
Is the President okay?
He's alive for now.
(CLEARS THROAT)
They got him in the bunker.
Oh, man.
It's a fucking shit show, huh?
Yeah, that's for sure.
Did Roma make it?
Fuck.
We gotta keep movin'.
(PANTING)
You got a plan, Mike?
Yeah.
But it hasn't worked
out so far.
(CHUCKLES) Fuckin' Mike.
You always were a hardass.
You never change.
Hey, Dave.
This place is getting me rattled, man.
I can't think straight.
You okay?
No. Not for real.
This fucking Kang guy,
he's crazy.
How do you know his name?
Hey, Mike, do you remember
that time in New York?
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
(CHOKING)
Oh, Dave.
Why'd you do it?
Fuck, Mike. Fuck.
(SOBBING) I lost my way.
You make up for it now.
Tell Kang I'm dead.
And help me save the President.
(BEEPS)
Kang. It's Forbes.
I got him. All clear.
KANG: Good.
(BEEPS)
Okay?
(WHISPERING) Ruth.
Mr. President, sir?
Rough day.
Could be worse.
How's my hair?
(CHUCKLES)
Not a strand out of place.
Any regrets?
None. You?
A few.
Like running for President.
(CHUCKLING)
The office is lucky
to have you, sir.
We all may meet
our maker today,
but the one thing I do not
want on my tombstone,
"She went down
without a fight."
(CHUCKLES)
No danger of that.
Pull up your satellite feed.
CLEGG: Give me eyes on.
Looks like there's only
four sentries on the roof.
With the Air Defense grid gone, they're
vulnerable to an aerial insertion.
Wait. Let me get there
first and check it out.
CLEGG: We're not waiting.
We have to secure Cerberus.
Oh, fuck.
Send in the SEALs, General.
We're going through the roof.
PILOT: Command,
Tiger flight inbound.
SEAL TEAM LEADER:
Tiger team, standby.
TRUMBULL ON RADIO: The
assault team is on the way.
About fucking time.
Yes, sir. Copy.
(CAMERA WHIRRING)
(LIM SPEAKING KOREAN)
Here they come.
Command, Tiger flight's three minutes out.
Team, go green.
Go green.
Cho. (SPEAKING KOREAN)
Is the Hydra assembled?
Weapon is ready.
Stand by to repel boarders.
(MACHINE POWERING UP)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Two guys to the left.
Two to the right.
SEAL TEAM LEADER: 60 seconds to target.
I want a clean deployment.
Fuck.
(CLANGING)
Tell them to hold.
We aren't holding shit!
Fuck.
(BEEPING)
Jacobs. You gotta
abort this mission.
They've got the Hydra 6!
What's that?
Next generation
weaponry. Ours.
JACOBS: How the hell
would they get that?
CLEGG: It doesn't matter.
We'll take it out.
I said abort
this fucking mission!
Let's go get our goddamn
house back, Captain.
Tiger 2, Tiger 3,
you're cleared hot.
PILOT 2: Tiger 2, roger.
PILOT 3:
Tiger 3, roger.
SEAL TEAM LEADER: All birds, be on the
lookout for possible advanced weaponry.
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SHOUTS IN KOREAN)
(GROANS)
PILOT: Approaching rooftop.
Negative on the four sentries.
SEAL TEAM LEADER: Tiger
flight is on station.
We got him.
Go, go, go!
PILOT: We have a radar log
source for the target.
(SCREAMING)
Tiger 2 is taking
fire from the rooftop!
SEAL TEAM LEADER: Tiger
team, go combat flight.
SEAL 2: Tiger 2 is hit,
he's going down.
SEAL 5: Tiger 2
is going down hard!
He's hit.
Evasive, evasive.
SEAL TEAM LEADER: Tiger
3, fly behind the target.
Tiger 4, adjust approach.
Hang northwest
and flank from there.
Tiger 5 and 6,
begin formation Charlie.
Take out that gun!
PILOT: Damn it, drop altitude!
(SCREAMS)
Tiger 1 gunner just got hit!
(SHELLS CLATTERING)
SEAL TEAM LEADER: Three, on your three.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
SEAL TEAM LEADER:
Tiger 6 is down!
Tiger 5 is hit!
(SCREAMING)
Tiger 5 is going down.
Reset formation.
Tiger 1 taking lead.
PILOT: Roger that.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Need backup.
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
SEAL TEAM LEADER: Two birds up.
Only two birds remain.
Abort! Abort!
WATCH OFFICER:
Pull out. Clear the area.
SEAL TEAM LEADER: Roger. Clearing the area.
(ALARM BEEPING) Tiger 1 is hit!
Losing control!
Tail rotor failure.
Mayday, mayday,
we're going down!
(GRUNTING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING) Oh, no!
WATCH OFFICER: Five out
of six birds are down.
Request a QRT.
Permission to launch
second squadrons.
SEAL TEAM LEADER:
Negative, negative.
We don't have any intel about what other
surprises they could have for us.
Return to base.
Return to base, over.
WATCH OFFICER:
Roger that.
Banning, are you there?
Banning!
Half the White House
is just gone.
The residence, the roof,
all destroyed,
and the remainder of the
historic building now trashed.
Speaker Trumbull, that was
a very foolish undertaking.
(ALL GASP)
'(our President is next.
You now have one hour
to recall the Seventh Fleet
and your troops.
Once you do so, I want a helicopter
on the North Lawn fueled and ready.
60 minutes.
(GROANING)
Fuck.
It's Banning.
Patch him through.
Mike?
BANNING: Yeah.
We've been trying to reach you, son.
Are you okay?
Mr. Speaker, sir, if we ever
get out of this shit storm,
you can hold me
for insubordination.
But your team needs
some serious fucking help.
This is General Clegg,
Army Chief of Staff.
I am ordering you
to stand down.
BANNING: Remove your only eyes
and ears from the ground.
That's fucking brilliant.
CLEGG: We need to pull you out of
there before we lose another hostage!
I am giving you a direct order.
Newsflash, asshole.
I don't work for you.
General Clegg.
I'm the Commander-in-Chief.
If I didn't absolutely need you,
I would relieve you right now.
I will not let this asshole
blow up America, sir! General, I
don't wanna hear another word
out of you unless
I ask you a question!
Sir.
Mr. Banning.
Mr. Banning, are you there?
Yes, sir.
What's the plan?
We're recalling
the Seventh Fleet,
pulling our troops
back from the DMZ,
and giving them the helicopter.
Sir, you cannot do that. You cannot
give this guy what he wants.
I've dealt with these
types of men before.
Give me sometime.
Let me flush him out.
We are talking about the safety of
the President of the United States!
We're talking about a hell
of a lot more than that, sir.
With all due respect,
you're Acting President now.
And I'm the best hope
you've got.
Okay, Mike.
You've got 30 minutes.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
Leah, call for you
on the landline.
The emergency line.
(GROANING)
Can you make sure he gets
some morphine? Yeah.
Mike?
Hey, I was just checking in.
(SIGHS) Babe.
How's your day been?
Yeah, it's been busy.
It's good, you know.
How about you?
Yeah. Busy.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, I just... I've had to stay
a little later than I expected.
(SNIFFLES)
Yeah, me too.
You're gonna come
home tonight, right?
Yeah. Sure.
I got a date, remember?
Hey, I gotta go.
All this, uh,
paperwork's piling up.
Okay.
I love you.
(DIAL TONE)
(GROANS)
(TYPING)
(BEEPING)
What's the matter, Kang?
You look like
you've seen a ghost.
I guess you don't know
who you can trust, huh?
It's over. No more
televised executions.
No chopper.
No more negotiating with you and the
United People's Front of Who Gives a Fuck.
I will send the President out
one piece at a time.
It won't matter.
Because whatever you
think you accomplished,
you won't be alive to see it.
Shut him down.
Ah, you're not shutting
me down, Kang.
I'm here to stay.
I underestimated you.
It will not happen again.
There is no again. You're
gonna die down there alone,
cut off from the
rest of the world.
My advice? Save the last
bullet for yourself.
'Cause if you don't,
I'm gonna stick my knife
through your brain.
Don't worry. I'm gonna leak the
photos of your body to the press.
You know, 'cause I know
you like that kind of shit.
(BEEPS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
He's locked out
our video access.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Secure the entrance.
Leaving now!
Her!
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
I pledge allegiance to the flag
of the
United States of America!
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Your leader is out of his mind.
You fucking idiots!
(GROANING)
Go.
Walk.
Move!
(WHIMPERS)
(SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
(MAN SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Sir, there's movement
in front of the White House.
Ours or theirs?
Looks like
Secretary McMillan, sir.
Any bulges, wires?
Negative.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
MAN ON RADIO: Sir, ground reports
activity at the White House.
Is that...
McMillan.
Get a team out there now.
And another to cover! Go!
(SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
NEWSCASTER: It looks like Secretary McMillan.
Yes, yes, it is.
(GUN FIRING)
(GASPS)
Yes!
Mike?
Hey.
He got away.
He's back in the bunker.
TRUMBULL: You gave it a good shot, Mike.
You saved McMillan.
North and South Korean military
forces are on high alert
in response to rumors of an impending
American pull out from the DMZ...
NEWSCASTER 2: ...India, China and Russia
have declared a state of emergency and have
mobilized military forces.
NEWSCASTER 3: In the Middle East,
the response to the attack
on the White House is jubilant.
Crowds of thousands are
celebrating in the streets and
American flags are burning.
NEWSCASTER 4: The power
vacuum created by
a U.S. departure could spark an
immediate and full-scale conflict
and that any conventional war in this
heavily armed corner of the world
could easily escalate
into nuclear confrontation.
TRUMBULL: The hour's up.
Send the helicopter.
Let's recall the Seventh Fleet.
Pull the troops out of the DMZ.
We just lost South Korea.
Our Pentagon sources are now
saying that U.S. ground troops
have been given the order
to withdraw from Korea
for the first time in 60 years.
We're also hearing reports
that the U.S.' Seventh Fleet
has been directed
to pull back in the region.
Although unconfirmed,
this historic turn of events
seems to be motivated by today's
attack on the White House,
which began as the Prime Minister of
Korea was meeting with President Asher.
(TYPING)
(BOTH SPEAKING KOREAN)
They're recalling the fleet.
Of course.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
What are they doing?
(SOLDIERS
SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(BEEPING)
TRUMBULL: Mike.
We have to get Kang
and the President out in the
open and take our best shot.
Copy that, sir.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
SEAL TEAM LEADER: Bravo
team is in position.
Sir, we are ready.
All units are in position.
(SHOUTING IN KOREAN)
Here come the hostages.
We count 11 targets, sir.
One of them's gotta
be the President.
That's their ticket out.
Hercules Six in position.
Can you I.D.
the President?
Negative.
FBI AGENT:
Can you I.D. Kang?
Negative.
Targets unclear.
Sir, all ground units
are im position.
Do we have the go-ahead
to take them?
We're gonna go,
we gotta go now, sir.
Do we have the go-ahead, sir?
No. Too risky. They could
kill the President.
Yes, sir.
It's okay. We have a tracking
device on the chopper.
MAN: Holy shit, what was that?
Was that us?
OFFICER 1: Negative, negative.
That wasn't us.
OFFICER 2: Where's the QRT?
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Though it is not confirmed
yet, President Asher
is believed to have been among those killed
when the Black Hawk helicopter went down
in flames on the
White House North Lawn.
And certainly, today's events
will be recorded in history
as one of this country's darkest hours.
Oh, my God.
JACOBS: The President's gone.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Mike?
BANNING:
What the hell happened?
I'm sorry to report
the President was
on that helicopter.
And Kang?
TRUMBULL:
Kang killed himself.
And all the other hostages.
Wait. This doesn't add up.
It doesn't make sense.
What doesn't make sense?
Kang would not
go out like that, sir.
That's not who he is.
I think he's
still in the bunker.
And he has the President.
He's gonna try and slip away.
If Kang is still on the premises with
the President, you can't let him leave.
He won't.
(SOLDIER SPEAKING KOREAN)
I read your Bible,
Mr. President.
It says, "The wages
of sin is death."
You better keep that in mind.
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
(TYPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
What are you doing?
AUTOMATED VOICE: Cerberus
has been activated.
We haven't launched
any missiles yet.
KANG: I don't need
to launch them.
The explosive force within each hardened
silo will detonate the missiles.
Tens of millions
of Americans will perish.
Your country will be a cold,
dark nuclear wasteland.
Now, too, America shall
know suffering and famine.
South Korean officials are saying now
that they've called up the reserves.
And they're mobilizing additional
armored units in response...
Sir? Cerberus
has been activated.
What?
NORAD confirms.
How did it come to this? We
lost Korea and now our nukes?
They couldn't have
broken the code.
That would be impossible.
They'd be on the bunker computer
for days to break three codes.
He only needed to
break one code.
But we haven't
launched any missiles.
They're gonna detonate
them in their silos.
How many?
All of 'em.
He's just opened
the gates of hell.
(BEEPING)
Time to go, Mr. President!
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
You really think you're
gonna get out of here alive?
The world thinks
we're both dead.
And with you as insurance...
(BEEPS)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
To the tunnels.
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(CRACKING)
(GUN FIRING)
(GASPS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(CERBERUS TIMER BEEPING)
(SPITS)
(GASPING)
(CHOKING)
Come on, Mike.
(GRUNTING)
Looks like you
failed again, Mike.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(BONES CRACKING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
Sir?
Sir, look at me.
Sir. Sir.
Okay, it's gone through.
You've lost a little blood.
I'm gonna get you
outta here, okay?
Now, you know what to do.
Ben, Ben, come on!
Cerberus.
What?
Cerberus activated.
Cerberus.
Keep that pressed in.
Sir! Ben!
You're gonna be okay.
All right.
(BEEPING)
This is Banning. I have the President.
He's hurt, but alive.
How do I switch
this fucking thing off?
Hang on.
TRUMBULL: Deactivation code!
Find the control panel
marked, "Countermand."
(PANTING) Countermand.
Got it!
Flip a blue-white switch
marked, "initiate Recall."
Initiate recall.
(TYPING) Okay.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Deactivation
sequence initiated.
Please enter abort command.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on!
November-India.
Lima.
Wait, wait. Yep.
MONROE: Five-Oscar-hotel.
Oscar, hotel.
Backslash. Niner.
Backslash.
Victor. Kilo.
Hashtag.
What?
Shift-3!
Holy fuck!
MONROE: Echo.
Sierra.
Foxtrot.
Is that it?
JACOBS: That's it.
(BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Cerberus has been deactivated.
(SIGHING)
(CHEERING)
(SIGHS)
Sir,
NORAD confirms Cerberus
has been shut down.
Good.
Now get me Seoul
and Pyongyang on the line.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
(BOTH PANTING)
Are you ready,
Mr. President?
Sorry about the house, sir.
It's okay. I believe
it's insured.
(CHEERING)
ASHER: We've lost good friends.
Family.
All good people.
Heroes, every one of them.
Dad!
Our hearts and prayers
go out to their families.
And they will be remembered.
Nor will we forget
those who serve out
of the spotlight,
to whom we owe
our highest gratitude.
Our foe did not come only to
destroy our things or our people.
Are you okay?
They came to desecrate
a way of Hie.
To foul our beliefs.
Trample our freedom.
And in this,
not only did they fail,
they granted us
the greatest gift.
A chance at our rebirth.
We will rise. Renewed.
Stronger and united.
This is our time.
Our chance to get back
to the best of who we are.
To lead by example,
with the dignity, integrity, and
honor that built this country
and which will build
it once again.
May God bless you.
And may God bless the
United States of America.