You know the economy is going
to crash. That's why I'm here.
The problem is
the bail-out plan.
It's only going to make the
problem worse
and exacerbate things.
The politicians have
to resist the urge...
Coast Guard and environment
cleanup organizations
are working overtime
to clean up the disastrous
53,000-gallon spill
that left over 30 miles
of pristine coastline
soaked with sludge and oil.
It's still unclear how long it
will take to clean up this mess
and what long-term effects it
will have on the environment...
We need to do
something fast.
Adjustable rate mortgages
have already done enough damage
and we have not seen
anything yet.
...just like President Richard
Nixon did to the Vietnamese
back in the late '60s...
Osama bin Laden,
al Qaeda,
these people are out
to kill us. People don't--
All of these things
contribute to
the problem
of overpopulation...
People don't comprehend
the danger
that this country
creates for the world...
If just 15 millilitres is
released and becomes airborne,
this chemical could kill
a million people...
Oil is not only one
of the reasons,
but the main reason
to go to war in Iraq,
despite what federal
governments are saying.
Thousands of Australian
troops have been sent--
As mentioned in that story,
the soaring prices of oil is
a world-wide problem...
Efforts to reduce emissions
and pollution are required
immediately to reduce the
effects of global warming.
If we do not react soon...
Monetary policy allows
American citizens
to borrow trillions of dollars
without the ability to
pay any of the money back...
What were the beachgoers
thinking
when they left ten tons of
garbage behind on the beach
this Labour Day weekend?
The bottom line is...
The shooting happened in a
supermarket parking lot
in broad daylight with
dozens of people around.
Yeah, I couldn't believe it.
I was shocked.
I was just standing there,
and he came up shooting.
I saw him fall...
He's killed
a lot of people here.
Bill, are you up?
Come and have breakfast.
TV:
Beautiful woman's ring,
straight out of Africa.
Retails at $699.99...
Hey, darling.
Hey, honey.
How are you doing?
Did you sleep okay?
I did. You were
a tiger last night.
Oh, did you put
milk out already?
Yeah.
Okay.
I want to see if there's a
mirror I can--
Hey, honey. How are you doing?
Good.
Oh, you've already got
everything.
Sweetheart, you're
taking care of business.
That's fantastic.
I've got your coffee.
Let's move things along.
Sweetie, I just want to mention
that these should have
been put away, okay?
I mean,
you've got to chip in.
I thought I--
I thought I did that.
Okay, but find
a way that's not--
because you know what--
I don't want to do this
on a rush,
because it's an important thing.
But your mother and I were
talking last night.
We didn't get a lot of sleep--
not for the reason you think.
That's gross.
We think it's time you
moved on and moved out.
Fuck!
Oh, don't worry about it.
Okay.
I'll get a napkin.
I'm sorry.
Help your father.
You got it, Dad?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sorry, Mom.
No, it's okay.
But it's just that,
look, you're 23...
You've got to get your
own place, right?
I know. You keep saying that.
You just spilt more on me.
I'm sorry.
But you-- I know you
guys keep saying that.
Sorry.
You keep saying that,
but it takes time,
because I have to, obviously,
raise the money
for my own post-education,
right?
So the deal was is that
I would do that by own,
do my best to
save up that money.
In the meantime,
I would stay with you guys.
How about putting some of that
money into some rent?
What did I do last month?
We talked about the fridge.
Remember, when you
first suggested it?
I said I didn't--
Honey, what did--
And then you said that that
would buy me some--
That's a classic guilt trip by
the way, and I appreciate that.
No, but he did say--
I know what you're doing.
You learned from the best.
If you guys want me
to go back to school,
then obviously I have to have a
little bit of money
to do that too.
Look, honestly, Bill,
you don't want to be the--
We shouldn't have
gotten into it now,
because you and I--
we have to go.
Yeah.
I'm just saying--
I'm just saying, okay--
Five o'clock, mister,
we're going to have
a roundtable discussion.
Do me a favour.
Do me a favour. Do me a favour.
--you guys need to
help me out a little.
Give me a call at work.
We're going to-- we're going to
have a bite to eat.
We'll grab some lunch.
We'll grab a newspaper.
We'll go look at some
apartments,
and we'll have you in a new
place by the end of the week.
Okay, just as long as you're
paying for the lunch, because--
Wow, man.
Now, you guys.
You can push each other's
buttons like no one,
birds of a feather.
I'm fine. I thought we had a
good situation, but obviously--
We have a good situation.
But let's not make it a bad one.
That's what we're saying.
We're going to help you out
for the first--
for the first couple
of years, okay?
We will help you out.
I'm not saying that we're
going to pay 100 percent,
but we will help you out.
Okay, here's what
we're going to do.
We're going to meet here. I'm
going to pick up some pizzas,
and then we're going to sit
and have a nice discussion.
But I have to go.
I mean, if you guys are willing
to help me out, I'm cool.
Yeah.
Okay?
We still love you, man.
It's not to, you know--
I know.
Okay, have a good one today.
Okay?
Okay.
Give me a call at work.
Be safe.
There you go, enjoy.
Hey, how are you doing?
Good, man.
A double espresso macchiato
with extra foam.
Sure, that will be $4.50.
There you go.
Thanks, man.
Extra foam, man.
You got it.
There you go.
That's not what I ordered, man.
Yeah, it is.
That's not a macchiato.
There's no foam in there at all.
Yeah, there is.
There's some right there.
No, no, no.
No, a lot of foam,
a lot of foam.
Dude, look,
this is like half milk.
That's not a macchiato.
Look, there's--
there's foam in there.
There you go, more foam.
Yeah, but take-- take some of
the milk out of it, man.
I'm not taking any
of the milk out.
That's a perfectly good
macchiato.
Give me back my money, man.
I'm not giving you--
Give me back my money.
I'm not giving you
your money back.
Just take your coffee.
I'm not paying for something
that I didn't order, man.
Give me back my money.
I make the best
coffees in this town.
Take your coffee and go.
I don't give a f--
what you make, bro.
But I didn't-- I didn't order
this, so I don't want it.
I don't care.
That's a good coffee.
Take it.
You know, just take it and shove
it up your ass, all right?
Fucking idiot, man.
Hey, man, you don't want
to give me back my $4.50?
You don't want to give
me back my $4.50?
No.
No?
All right, man.
Here, take a--
take a fucking roll while you're
going out the door.
Fuck.
Bill!
Yeah, what?
Come on. Your lunch has been
over like 15 minutes ago.
What do you mean? I took my
lunch break 15 minutes ago.
Bill, take the mask off.
I've got tons of cars in there,
and you're wasting
time on this van?
All right?
I already finished
three cars today, Jim.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Three cars?
Come on. Get in there.
Okay, the clock says work, work.
Okay, you should check
your clocks, though.
Maybe I should clock you, eh?
I don't think you should treat
your best worker like that, Jim.
Bill, just get in there and make
some money for us, okay?
How about a raise?
Yeah, Bill?
Why don't you fuck off?
Nine bucks.
Yeah, nine bucks.
That's it, yeah. Right.
It's all prepped and ready.
RADIO:
The stresses from war do not
make a man do this.
What makes a man do this are
shame and rage.
What do you do when
the sun sets?
Gonne get down
when the sun sets.
Yeah!
Late.
Sorry, I'm late.
The funniest thing is that you
and this piece of shit--
only you would do a burn out
coming into a
shit hole like this.
Yeah, it's $300.
I know you've got to work for
six months to make that, but...
Hey, I got you a present.
Why? What the fuck, man?
Read up.
Listen, by the way, you've got
to stop having these things
sent to my fucking house, man.
Yes, these are
the last ones, man.
Yeah, but my dad
is getting pissed, okay?
And what the fuck is in this?
What did he say?
He was asking what it was.
What did you tell him?
To mind his own
fucking business.
Good, good.
No one can know.
It's a surprise.
Piece of shit.
Watch your head.
Fuck. Yeah!
Let's go eat.
Do you really want
to fucking eat
in this shit hole Chicken Den
piece of shit?
This is America, man.
This is what we eat, okay?
I love it.
Dude, Chicken Den?
Do you know what they do with
these animals?
It's all-American.
This is America, baby.
They sit in cages,
sitting in their shit all day.
You're such a fucking prick.
How are you doing?
Welcome to Chicken Den.
How may I help you?
Give me, uh...
Give me the four-piece,
a four-piece mixed meat.
Do you want the combo?
Combo.
Fuck.
A salad, a garden salad.
A four-piece combo?
Hi, sorry.
A four-piece combo,
you said?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay.
You're just going to have salad?
Draw cartoon chickens
saying, "Eat me."
$10.70, please.
Yes, ma'am.
How is your day, love?
Perfect. How is yours?
Sunshine and rainbows.
A combo and a salad.
She seem a little bit
pissed off, huh?
Yeah.
Thank you.
High-five.
Don't leave me hanging.
This is a fresh, fresh salad.
I'll bet they went out and
picked it this morning.
That looks disgusting.
Your salad probably has bugs
crawling all over it.
Dude, move this.
You're going to knock
it off the fucking edge.
So tomorrow, 1:00.
Yeah. Tomorrow, 1:00.
Paintball, right?
No problems with work?
Dude, I've got to call in sick.
You haven't done that yet?
Well, dude, I have
to call it on the day.
I'm not going to
call today and say,
"Listen, tomorrow I'm not going
to be in, because I'm sick."
I talked to you about
this two weeks ago.
Yeah, I have to call in
tomorrow.
I said, you said--
Can I have the tray?
I took the day off work too.
We have to play.
Holy shit!
Crap!
Would you get me a napkin?
Like, she didn't even say
anything.
She didn't go, "I'm sorry."
No like, "I'm sorry."
Hi!
You brought napkins.
No, no. We'll probably need
like-- I don't know-- a mop.
Are you going to apologize?
I mean, you fucking got
this shit all over us.
Look, I'm sorry.
I'm laughing because you got it
on him, and he's a prick.
Could you
get me more chicken,
because this is right
all over the place.
Yeah, I'll make that.
What's your problem?
I don't have a problem.
I'm sorry.
Is there something
wrong with you?
Look, I'll get
this replaced. That's fine.
She's upset with her life.
Jesus!
Can I get my money back?
Look, I'll get you more stuff,
but I'm not giving
you your money back.
I don't want more stuff.
I'm sorry I dumped stuff on you,
but I'll just have
it replaced, okay?
Lady!
It's okay.
Do you have a manager?
Hey, it's okay. It's all right.
Don't worry about it.
Hold on. No, no, no.
Do you have a manager?
Don't worry about it. It's fine.
It will dry.
This is why I don't want to eat
in these fucking places, man.
Look at this shit.
Do you think she likes it?
Dude, do you think that I like
having whatever-the-fuck this
kind of salad is,
this salad dressing,
extra ranch?
Is this quality service?
Hello? Hello?
Yeah, don't forget
the tray, right?
That's great. It's all clean.
Thank you.
Like, take this guy.
You see him walking
down the street?
Smile on his face.
He's got nice clothes on.
What's he doing? What do you
think he does?
I don't know. What's he do?
Maybe a banker.
He's delirious, though.
Maybe a travelling salesman?
He's delirious, why?
That guy helps to
wreck the economy.
He helps to wreck the world.
He eats in Styrofoam
fucking cups.
He's terrible, delirious.
That's not what the world needs.
What does the world need?
The world needs change, man.
What kind of change?
Who is going to do it?
Dude, the problem is--
As one person,
what could you do?
--that this fucking world grows
by like 70 million people a
year. That's the problem.
There's too many people.
And so our natural resources
are running out.
And no one, and no one--
look, we have trains.
We have-- we have cars,
tons of cars
that are just burning up gas and
making this place disgusting.
We've got a hole in the ozone.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
You have chicken that looks
like-- yeah, of course, man.
It's just disgusting.
That's all.
It's just absolutely
fucking sick.
It makes me just sick.
But what are you supposed
to do, stop living?
There's two kinds of people--
leavers and takers.
And the leavers coexist.
We need people that coexist.
And the takers is the
society of the world.
The takers is the
people that fucking--
that just, like, drive
Ferraris not caring.
Because people
have to make money.
No, people don't
People have to make money.
That's the thing. That's what
I'm talking about, man.
People don't have to.
That's the thing that society
drills in your head
over and over and over since
you've been fucking 5-years-old
that you have to have
a big bank account.
You have to make a lot of money.
You have to have a fast car.
It makes life a lot easier,
doesn't it?
Dude, but what happens--
Would you want to be poor?
Do you want to be poor?
Do you want to have no money?
You keep going down this road.
Do you know where it's going?
So you just think just keep
going down the reckless path,
just fucking-- pile straight
ahead, because there's no--
We're all just fucked.
What's the point?
That's the most pessimistic
point of view
I've ever heard in my life.
You're a prodigy of the world,
my son, a prodigy of the world.
You're all talk, buddy.
You're all talk.
Oh, snap.
All talk?
All talk, no action.
That's helping. I stood on my
feet all day today.
Not to change the subject,
but when is dinner?
No-- hi.
Hey, hey, hey.
Yeah?
No phone call?
Sorry.
Where have you been?
What are you guys doing?
What do you mean,
what have we been doing?
We've been waiting for you?
Remember, we had this meeting
planned, right?
I was going to pick up pizza--
How long is
it going to take?
Oh, come on.
It's just going to
take as long as it takes.
No, no, no, no.
Can we do it tomorrow morning?
I've got some very exciting
news for you guys,
and I actually ate at the
Chicken Den--
Oh, come on, Bill.
We organized this.
I know.
We talked about it this
morning, remember?
It was like nine hours ago.
Tomorrow--
Oh, jeez.
We'll talk about
it at breakfast,
and I've got very, very exciting
news for you guys, okay?
Okay, are you going to
be on time for once?
Yes, on time.
That's exciting news.
Okay, well, I will make a
special breakfast.
No-- no coping out this time.
No, absolutely, I'll see you
tomorrow morning.
You promise?
Promise. Good night, guys.
Wow, I kind of figured
that would happen.
Yeah, that's typical.
That's typical, every,
every time.
Why is he resisting
this so much?
I don't know.
Do you think he's hiding
something? Is he okay?
I just think he's--
...Psychiatrist Michelle His tow
has a theory about Kyle.
When I saw him, he had already
murdered seven people.
Our work is gripping and
unpredictable.
This is not the way
conventional psychiatry works.
Up next, an interview with
Michelle His tow.
We have the right to drive
whenever, wherever,
and whatever we want, but we
need to understand the effects
of the carbon footprint
and realize the
environmental damage
cars are causing
to our planet.
Al Qaeda is all over Iraq.
The administration
of the U.S. president
will likely
double the bounty on...
The BTK killer has confessed
to killing 10 people and
tonight...
The United States will deploy
30,000 additional troops...
EVAN:
The global population grows by
over 70 million people a year.
At the same time, our natural
resources are dwindling--
coal oil, gas, water.
Okay, and with the development
of the third world
we're just creating a ticking
time bomb,
and even though we know that
forests are essential
to reducing carbon emissions,
we continue to cut them down,
whether it's for housing,
farming, alternative energy,
or just useless furniture
instead of truly getting
together and fighting
for something, fighting
against global warming,
against political
and social unrest.
Our politicians are using the
same lame band-aid techniques
up for re-elections,
over and over.
What we need is change.
We can't stand
for this anymore.
Any why do we accept this?
Because we're a society
built on wants.
Not needs.
What are we taught
to want from childhood?
Hmm? Big bank accounts.
Fast cars, plasma screen TVs,
liposuction.
Okay, facelifts.
Does this help anyone? No.
What is this? This is ego.
This doesn't help the world.
We need to bind together.
We don't need to be
individuals.
We need to become whole as a
country, as world.
We need someone who
will stand for something.
believes in what they say
and believes in actions
changing the way
that we view our world.
We can't survive with our
politicians focusing their time
on fighting religious wars,
fighting over control
of natural resources.
Can anyone do this?
Well, I don't know.
Do you have any thoughts?
We're so precious, aren't we?
Everyone has got to live.
Everyone has got to be happy.
It's a joke.
It's an absolute joke.
Humanity can't survive
over the next 100 years.
The facts don't lie.
We need someone who will
stand for something.
We need someone who
believes in what they say
and believes in action,
believes in positive action.
It's an absolute joke.
Evan, that's what
you didn't get.
That's what you didn't get.
You think people are equal.
They're not.
¶
...just like President Richard
Nixon did to the Vietnamese
back in the late '60s--
Osama bin Laden, al Qaeda,
these people are out
to kill us. People don't--
All of these things
contribute
to the problem of
overpopulation.
People don't comprehend
the danger
that this country
creates for the world.
If just 15 millilitres is
released and becomes airborne,
this chemical could kill a
million people.
--About society and people
in the humanitarian sense.
We need to changes
to protect the--
Thessalonians 3:10 says,
"For even when we are with you,
this we commanded you,
that if any would not work,
neither should he eat."
The global population grows by
over 70 million people a year.
And why do we accept this?
Because we're a society
built on wants.
Not needs. What are we taught
to want from childhood?
Hmm?
Big bank accounts.
Fast cars, plasma screen TVs,
liposuction.
Okay, facelifts.
Does this help anyone? No.
What is this? This is ego.
We need someone who
will stand for something.
believes in what they say
and believes in action,
believes in positive action
and changing the way
that we look at things,
changing the way that
we view our world.
BILL:
So that's what I'll do.
My name is Evan Drince.
Why not?
Bill?
Breakfast is ready, Bill.
What?
I said breakfast!
I'll be up in 15 minutes!
I'm working out!
Good morning, honey.
Morning.
That smells really good.
I'm glad we're actually having a
nice breakfast together,
because yesterday
was a bit tense.
Well, you guys dropped a--
dropped a bomb on me.
I know, but I feel like--
I think we've reached some
kind of agreement, right?
And today, what I'm
going to do for you guys
is that I'm going
to be proactive.
And today, I'm going to stay in.
I've got the day off.
I'm going to fill out some
college applications,
and I'm thinking--
What did my ears just hear?
That I'm going to fill out some
college applications,
mechanical engineer.
Honey!
Who kidnapped our son?
What's going on?
That's fantastic!
Yeah, it makes sense, right?
Okay, you know, I--
That's fantastic. Good job.
So are you guys happy?
I've got to say
I'm really proud of you.
Uh-huh.
Well, I think it's
about time, right?
I think our little talk maybe
got in there somewhere, huh?
You guys kicked my little
tushie out the door.
With love.
Absolutely.
You know what?
Here's the thing.
You're going to feel better
about yourself
once you have, like, goals.
I know. I do have goals, Mom.
Look, I've got to go.
We'll talk about
it more later.
Okay, chin up.
Okay. Bye, Dad.
Sweetheart, I'll see you later.
Okay, we'll talk at dinner.
I'm really, really
proud of you.
I think what you're
going to feel
is that you have goals in life
now and a direction.
Right.
Yeah.
Yeah, I woke up today
feeling enthusiastic.
My little boy,
he's growing up.
Come here.
It's out of love that we kick
your bum-- your bum.
Sorry about the language.
Have a good day at work, okay?
I will, sweetheart.
I'm very excited for you,
and I want to see how this turns
out with the applications.
Okay.
I'll see you tonight.
Bye, honey.
All right.
BILL:
Evan, you think
people are equal.
They're not. They're not.
Evan, Evan, Evan, Evan.
You're such an idiot.
They're like a drop in a bucket.
I just poured the bucket out.
Yeah, you couldn't do anything.
All you could do is talk--
meaningless.
Do anything.
Well, I guess I did.
...shot about five or six
times and everybody...
...most of the shooting right
here at this location
where most of the
bullet casings are...
BILL:
In nature, there's
survival of the fittest.
What separates us
from the animals?
It's our consciousness.
It's our ego.
It's our sense of self...
So, all of a sudden, we care
about ourselves too much.
We care about our
fellow man too much.
We have to do anything that
we can to keep them alive.
You know, the animals
just want to eat.
They just want to eat.
They'll kill you
so they can eat.
EVAN:
Can anyone do this?
I don't know.
Do you have any thoughts?
BILL:
Let's face it.
If we could just kill everybody,
you know, in the third world,
people with cancer, you know,
people that are sucking up
our resources,
maybe we could survive.
The Bible says
we must not kill.
The bible says we must not
commit adultery.
...Most of the shooting right
here at this location
where most of the bullet
casings are,
and then ran off
in that direction
while still shooting...
Survival of the fittest is
really, is a real theory.
That's a way to create balance.
I don't believe in god.
I believe in what I see,
the pain and suffering I see.
I believe that when I go out in
the street
and I see a mother who can't
feed her child...
Described as a loner who never
fit in with his classmates...
Couldn't do anything.
All you could do was talk...
Meaningless.
¶
RADIO:
Don't forget Bingo at
Centerville Bingo Hall.
Now back to the local news...
EVAN:
The world needs change, man.
BILL:
What kind of change?
Who's going to do it? You?
How long is it going to take?
EVAN:
Can anyone do this?
I don't know.
Do you have any thoughts?
All talk, no action.
Start up.
Here we go.
Jesus.
Oh, fuck.
Come out with your hands up!
Open the back.
Whoa...
Get down, you piece of shit!
Get down!
On the ground!
Down on the ground!
Shit!
Oh, hi.
You're scared as shit, huh?
Here we go.
Please...
¶
Hey, man, how are you?
Oh, hey, man,
you remember me?
Uh...
Why don't you make me
a double espresso macchiato
with extra foam?
You got it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Why don't you make it like
your life depends on it?
With extra foam!
You like to take your sweet
fucking time, don't you?
There you go.
Why is this so difficult?
I mean, how hard can it be?
I'm going to give you
five seconds
to get the fuck out of here.
I'm going to start counting
right now.
One...
Are you serious?
Yeah, yeah!
I'm pretty fucking serious!
One...
Two... hurry up, motherfucker!
Run, Forrest!
Now you're getting it!
Five, bitch!
TV:
Again, we are strongly advising
people to stay inside,
as early reports indicate that
chaos in downtown Centerville
is caused by a
heavily-armed individual
firing randomly
at innocent bystanders.
Hello, beautiful ladies.
Whoa, hold on a minute.
No, calm down. No, no.
You get over there.
Hey, ladies. Out of the kitchen.
Go join your pretty friends.
You too.
Come on.
Let's go.
There you go. Come on.
You too, Blondie.
Who else is here?
There's no one else here.
No one?
It's just us here.
What about this door?
Come on, ladies.
Come over here. Get down.
It gets so hot in this thing.
I have my cell phone here.
Chirp, chirp, chirp, chirp,
chirp, chirp, chirp...
I've got--
I've got two kids at home.
I've got a husband.
I've got--
Chirp, chirp, chirp, chirp,
chirp, chirp, chirp...
Please! Let us go!
What is it you...
I feel nauseous.
Come on...
Shh...
Oh, my God!
Is everybody okay?
What a fucking dickhead!
Are you guys okay?
Holy shit!
Oh, my God! Does anybody have--
Where's the phone?
Everyone over here!
Over here!
Get down!
Get down! Get down!
Please!
BILL:
I don't know why I did that.
Maybe I shouldn't
have taken off my mask.
Please, don't do it. Please!
BILL:
I have to.
CALLER:
O-67. Six seven.
G-54. Five four.
G-48. Four eight.
N-32. Three two.
G-60. Six zero.
O-68. Six eight.
N-35. Three five.
I-30. Three zero.
B-4. Number four.
G-6. Six.
Hey, buddy,
I'm a little bit peckish.
You got something to eat?
Why don't you get me the best
sandwich you've got?
The best, tastiest
sandwich you've got.
What have you got
to drink, iced tea?
That looks like shit.
Here you go.
That's a nice hairnet.
Do they make you wear that?
Yeah, thanks.
Free of charge. Just--
Oh, good. I completely
forgot my wallet.
Right.
Thank you.
Have a good day.
Thank you for coming to
Centerville Bingo
where everyone is a winner.
B-10. One zero.
G-49. Four nine.
G-56. Five six.
O-61. Six one.
B-1. Number one.
B-4. Number four.
G-59. Five nine.
G-46. Four six.
O-63. Six three.
O-62. Six two.
N-37. Three seven.
O-70. Seven zero.
Excuse me! Sir, I need that!
I-27. I-27!
I need that back, please, sir.
It's I-27!
Excuse me...
I-27! Bingo!
Bingo?
No Bingo.
You guys don't need
my help at all.
Wow...
I-27. Two seven.
RADIO:
And we are still getting
reports that a brown van
was seen smashing into the
front of the police station
just moments before
the massive explosion
that woke Centerville
residents up this morning.
Everybody get
behind the counter.
Ladies, back the fuck up!
Nobody presses the alarm!
Let's go!
Ladies, back the fuck up!
Don't touch those alarms!
You too.
Let's go, big shot.
Don't be scared, big shot.
Let's go. Come on.
Ahh!
Get him!
What the fuck was that?!
Anybody else want
to play hero, huh?
No?
Knock, knock, knock,
Mr. Manager.
What are you doing in here?
Give me your fucking phone!
Everyone is out there.
What are you doing in here?
Get the fuck out here! Come on!
Come on!
What do I want?
What do you think I want?
Money.
Come on,
quick.
Money, money.
Money? Oh, you're
a smart one, genius.
Get in the back!
It's in the safe.
Where? In the safe? Go!
I don't have the key.
You don't have the fucking key?
Where is the fucking key?
In my office.
Go get it.
Don't fuck around!
You, you work here or do you
just dress like an idiot?
Empty the registers, fuck face.
Empty the registers.
You look like a fucking idiot
when you're scared,
you know that?
I have the key.
I've got the key!
Come here!
Hurry up!
Open the safe. Open the safe.
Hurry up. What are you,
retarded?
Give me-- give me the bag.
Give me the bag.
Keep it.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Bro, calm down.
Calm down, all right?
Everything is going to be okay.
I'm not going to kill you.
I don't know why I'm not.
Is this your first time?
Is this your
first time?
What the fuck is wrong
with you, huh?
Punch in the code!
I got it! I got it!
There you go.
There it is.
Fill it up.
You see? You see?
It's money.
It's about as
worthless as you are.
Hurry up.
I'm hurrying.
Please, just don't shoot.
That's it. That's all of it.
Give me the fucking bag.
Stay there.
Thank you.
Pinhead.
Your fucking money
doesn't mean anything,
because all you use it for
is stupid and senseless shit!
What is he doing out there?
Say goodbye!
Lock the door!
Have a nice day!
Just stay inside.
RADIO:
Once again,
please stay indoors.
Do not go outside
until local authorities
have told you that
it's safe to.
Sheriff Malvoy.
The blaze is keeping all
available fire trucks
and fire-fighters
extremely busy
with no news on any survivors
in the collapsed building.
...individual went amok in the
downtown shopping district,
seemingly killing random people
without motive or reason.
I don't know how this
could happen here,
or anywhere, for that matter.
Centerville? Centerville,
this is Sheriff Malvoy.
Come back.
Centerville,
this is Sheriff Malvoy.
Clark and Bradley has been
robbed by an armed assailant.
We're heading back into town on
Cross Road.
30 minutes out. Over.
What the hell is going on, Ray?
RADIO:
Again, please be advised
of the location of a suspected
armoured and armed terrorist.
Therefore, we still
strongly recommend
that everyone stays indoors.
MOM:
Oh, honey. Hi, sweetheart.
Are you okay?
Hey, Mom. Yeah, I'm okay.
Do you know what's
going on right now?
You haven't--
you haven't seen anything?
What happened?
No, turn on the
television, Honey.
There's, I guess,
one guy, they think,
killing people all over town.
What do you mean?
Yes, yes! Killing people!
What do you mean
he killed people?
It's crazy, but you're fine.
You're at home working
on your stuff, right?
I'm fine. I'm just--
I'm at home. Where are you?
I'm watching it on the news at
work, and it's terrible.
You're at work?
You're going to stay there?
No, I don't think so.
You're not going to come home?
No, not just yet, sweetheart.
I'm going to go meet your dad,
and we're going to wait there.
Okay, when are you
going to be back?
Well, sweetheart, as soon
as we can get there, okay?
Just please stay safe.
Okay, I'll be back--
I'll be here.
Sorry, honey,
you're breaking up.
I'll be back--
I mean, I'll be here.
Yes, stay there, okay?
Sweetie, I love you.
Please be safe, okay?
Okay, stay safe.
All right, baby. I love you.
Bye-bye.
Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck, man!
Evan.
Billy.
Hey.
Yeah, where are you?
I'm running some
errands right now, man.
What errands?
I'm coming right now, Bro.
Don't go anywhere, okay?
Yeah, I'm not going.
Don't go anywhere. I'm getting
in my car right now. Okay, bye.
Oh, I'm going fucking nuts.
Yeah, who's the winner, Bill?
Who is the winner?
No, I'm not going to shoot you.
Oh, I'm just fucking kidding.
Seriously, though, seriously.
Have you ever seen
a fucking cowboy?
Fuck this kid.
Fucking...
Hello!
Evan.
I'm leaving.
I'm fucking leaving!
No, you're not, man.
Dude, you're taking
for fucking ever!
I've had a lot of shit
to do today, okay?
It's been a fucked up afternoon.
I'll be there in ten minutes.
Don't go anywhere.
I've been wait--
Dude, I've been waiting.
Ten minutes, my fucking ass.
I've been waiting here for
fucking 45 minutes.
Paintball. Paintball.
Paintball, bro.
So?
We're going to play paintball.
Give me a fucking good reason--
and I want a fucking articulate
reason-- why I should stay.
Why should I stay?
I'm going to fucking
kill you, man.
Listen, you're the one--
You're going to be needing
some fucking target practice,
all right?
You're not going to
go anywhere, right?
Just stay there for ten
minutes, okay?
I'm coming. I promise.
I love you, man.
All right. I'll see you soon.
Okay.
We can go a little faster, Ray.
Closer, Ray.
¶
Shit.
Bump him.
This is Sheriff Malvoy.
I'm at the roundabout
in the County Park.
I've got two more
deputies down.
I'm pursuing the
suspect on foot.
You got blood on me.
60 to 80 seconds.
You ready?
What the fuck?
Is that what you took two
fucking hours doing?
I'm glad you
didn't leave, buddy.
I brought you a gift.
What the fuck?
Check it out.
Dude!
Dude, this is real money.
It's a shit-load of money.
Where the fuck did you get all
of this fucking money?
Hey, Evan?
Yeah?
Check it out.
You all right?
Give me your hand.
Hold this. Hold this.
You kind of asked
for it, right?
I kind of made you the martyr
you always wanted to be.
EVAN:
You are a prodigy of the world,
my son, a prodigy of the world.
DAD:
We'd like you to...
EVAN:
Stop having these things
sent to my fucking house.
BILL:
Last ones, man.
You're making me pay
for my own post education.
EVAN:
I've been waiting
for fucking 45 minutes.
BILL:
I made you the martyr
you always wanted to be.
MOM:
Okay, sweetie.
I love you. Be safe.
WOMAN:
You're going to pay for this!
Do you hear me?
BILL:
What do you think I want?
Come on, quick.
MANAGER:
Money! Money! Money!
EVAN:
I don't know.
My name is Evan Drince.
Do you have any thoughts?
BILL:
Your fucking money
doesn't mean anything!
TV:
...dozens of Centerville
residents and police officers
earlier today, during what can
only be described
as a massacre.
The rampage began with
a massive explosion
that destroyed Centerville
police station.
MOM:
Oh, God, honey.
There you are, sweetheart.
This is just so awful.
I'm so glad you're here.
You're okay, though, yeah?
I'm so glad you
weren't out in this. This was--
Are you okay, Bill?
You were back here
when this started?
I drove by the bakery,
and the whole glass was
shattered out of the bakery.
This is the forest.
Look, this is where
they found the guy.
They found the shooter already?
Yeah.
Wait a second.
One guy did all of this?
It was Evan.
Evan got shot?
Did Evan get shot?
No, Mom. Evan did it.
My friend, Evan.
Oh, my God.
Shot all of the--?
Have they announced his name or
you just recognized him?
They just said it,
Evan Drince, Evan Drince.
Breaking news.
Unbelievable.
How did they find him? Like,
what? Did he give himself up?
They just found
him in the woods.
He shot himself in the head.
He's dead?
He committed suicide.
This is insane.
This world is a crazy place,
isn't it?
He was a fucked up kid.
Oh...
I thought he was--
I thought he was a bit odd,
but I didn't think
he was a--
Psychopath?
He looked like he had secrets.
I mean, I'm just
an armchair psychologist,
but a mother knows.
Like, you just intuit.
Yeah.
Nevertheless, it must be a shock
for his parents.
Have you spoken to them?
Uh, yeah.
I don't even want to ask you
about the college
applications now.
It all seems
so trite, I guess.
I'm glad you guys
are okay, right?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, we're fine.
Presently, the only
thing we know...
This is where I drove by.
I told you I saw
that poor woman.
Do you think
it's Mrs. Blakeslee?
I didn't want to stay around
long enough to find out?
Guys, I'm so tired.
I'm going to go to sleep.
Oh, of course, honey.
I'm really sorry
about your friend.
I'm really sorry.
You give us a shout if
you need anything, okay?
All right.
Take care, guys.
Get some sleep.
Yeah, sweetheart. Bye-bye.
I think he's
holding it in.
Maybe we should take
him to see somebody.
Well, for sure after this.
He's going to have
to go talk to someone.
Yeah.
Just, I don't want anyone to
know that we're taking him.
Yeah, fair enough.
I don't want people to know and
think he's crazy or something.
Oh, my God.
This is awful.
Let's have a drink
or something, huh?
Yeah, make me a
double, something.
TV:
Stay tuned to this station for
an update of this tragic story
as more details
become available.
Centerville resident
Lloyd Drince,
the father of Evan Drince
was arrested at his home
when local authorities
attempted to enter the
premises.
Close sources reveal that Lloyd
Drince used to be a radical
and extreme protester
in the '60s and '70s,
especially at the height
of the war in Vietnam
and has always been
strongly outspoken
against the government.
With the current evidence that
his son, Evan Drince,
has been identified as being
behind the massacre
in downtown Centerville today,
it appears that
radical measures
to get your opinions
out runs in the family.
To recap, the offender
has been identified
as 21-year-old Centerville
resident Evan Drince,
who took his own life
in a nearby forested area
after completing his
destruction and killing spree.
LLOYD DRINCE:
You've got the wrong kid!
My kid wouldn't do this!
My kid's innocent!
Bill Williamson!
Bill Williamson did this!
Check Bill Williamson's house!
My kid is not a murderer!
My son is innocent!
Bill Williamson!
NEWSCASTER:
The authorities have not
pressed any charges
or revealed information
about suspects
since they feel a thorough
investigation is needed...
BILL:
It's a...
It's a downward spiral
to the end of all times.
And there's no chance
that we can survive.
I mean...
70 million
people every year
are brought onto this Earth.
What are they doing?
Sucking up our resources.
There's too many people,
so what do we do?
Just keep them around?
Let's kill them.
Let's get rid of them.
Good, thank you.
Thanks for--
thanks for coming out.
But you know what?
We're at capacity.
We're at capacity now.
So... sorry, no more.
No more.
So that's what I'll do.
Why not?
That's my plan.
That's what I want to do.
Let's just clean the world,
so maybe the rest of us can
sustain a little bit of life.
So maybe that's what
I'll do in the future.
I'll help you out.
I'll help you out,
and I will cleanse,
make more room for you.
I will exhibit my own brand of
population control...
for you.
That's it.