Look at that fellow over there.
I have never seen anything
so disgusting in all my life.
I'll tell you something, he's staring.
I think he's looking at us.
I think we're being picked up.
- Oh, it's too awful.
Can you believe
they allow creatures like that in here?
Really.
(White noise humming)
Uh...
Uh-uh-uh...
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh...
Oh, help, someone, please.
(White noise intensifies)...
...(White noise fades)...
...(Man) She's going to be all right.
It's all right. Stand back.
Ugh.
Damn it.
You're 35 years old, Mr. Vale.
Why are you such a derelict,
such a piece of human junk?
The answer is simple.
You are a scanner, which you don't realize.
That has been the source of all your agony.
But I will show you now
that it can be a source of great power.
Let them in.
(People's thoughts echoing)
Hurry up.
(Muttering intensifies)
(Distorted, haunting voices)...
...(Distorted voices fading)...
...(Distorted voices end)
You can talk now.
I would like to scan all of you
in this room, one at a time.
I must remind you that the scanning
experience is usually a painful one,
sometimes resulting in nosebleeds,
earaches, stomach cramps, nausea,
sometimes other symptoms
of a similar nature.
There's a doctor present. Dr. Gatineau.
I know that you've all been prepared for this
but I thought I'd remind you just the same.
There is one other thing.
No one is to leave this room,
once the demonstration has begun.
At this point I'd like to call for volunteers.
(Audience muttering)
Anyone. It doesn't matter.
Fine.
Just sit right here, please.
Now, I'd like you to think
of something specific,
that will not breach
the security of your organization,
and that can be disclosed to this group.
Something personal, perhaps.
- All right.
I have something. Shall I close my eyes?
- It doesn't matter.
All right, yes, I have something.
(Screaming)
Get everybody out, now.
Call ConSec leader.
I want you to come with me.
- I didn't do anything.
I said I want you to come with me.
Come on.
Gatineau, come with us.
Down there. Quick.
Move it.
Get down.
Give him a shot of Ephemerol.
Come on.
OK.
(Thunderclap)
Take it easy.
All we need is to get stopped by a cop.
It would serve him right. Why the hell
do they have to send us to the old factory?
If this guy's a scanner, they don't want him
down at Central. They're afraid of him.
He is a scanner.
Hey, where's Security 2?
He's moving up fast on the left.
Hey, man, what's happening?
Ray. What the hell's the matter with you?
You gotta pull back behind him, man.
Come on.
Ray, I'm gonna kill you if you don't do it.
Ray.
Oh, my God.
Don't stop. Move it.
No, we gotta get him out of there.
(Shouting in distance)
Come on now, let's go.
There are people inside.
Get up.
Let's get out of here, man.
Do you want to get us killed?
All right, now. Pipe down. All right.
Last night, we at ConSec
chose to reveal to the outside world...
...our work with those telepathic curiosities
known as scanners.
The result, six corpses...
...and a substantial loss in credibility
for our organization.
So this morning we have a new director
of internal security, Mr. Braedon Keller.
Thank you.
Mr. Trevellyan, gentlemen,
we're in the business
of international security.
We deal in weaponry and private armies.
We do not trade
in fantasy and pipe dreams.
Let us leave the development of dolphins
and freaks as weapons of espionage...
...to others.
With all due respect to Dr. Paul Ruth.
I recommend that we drop
our scanner programme immediately, sir.
Dr. Ruth, what's your response?
Mr. Keller, who composed
our audience last night?
We had 25 financial and political VIPs
from all over North America.
Were these VIPs carefully screened?
The screening process used
was very sophisticated, yes.
Yet an assassin managed
to infiltrate this group.
Yes.
- And kill six of our people?
- How did he kill them?
We have reason to believe
he used scanning techniques.
Then do you suggest, Mr. Keller,
that this highly skilled
assassin, very deadly,
who embarrassed us all in front of
the community we were trying to impress...
...was himself a scanner?
We believe so, yes.
That, gentlemen, is my response.
The weapons capability
of these telepathic...
Curiosities?
...is obvious.
If I may, Doctor? Your programme is based
on a list of 236 known scanners, is it not?
It is.
Of that number... Of that number,
how many are now working with us?
As of last night, none.
Well, then, we don't even have
a programme to drop, do we?
It shouldn't be very painful for anyone.
ConSec Surveillance has gradually lost
contact with all the names on our list.
I submit that this is not an accident.
I think we've lost them to a programme
far in advance of ours.
(Muttering)...
You might elaborate, Dr. Ruth.
- In my study of the situation
I've come to the conclusion...
...that there is a scanner underground
developed at North America.
It has an organization that's well motivated,
it has a leader.
That's ridiculous. You can't get
two of them to sit in the same room...
...without going berserk.
You're making
a very provocative allegation, Dr. Ruth.
Who controls this group?
If you study the descriptions in this report,
you'll find that you probably met him
last night.
His name is Darryl Revok.
And he was on our list.
This is total fiction. Mr. Trevellyan...
One moment, Mr. Keller.
What do you suggest?
Eliminate the competition.
- How?
Contact a scanner who is as yet
unknown to the underground,
convert him to our cause, and then send
him out to infiltrate the underground.
(Keller) Convert him, Doctor? How?
They're all pathetic social misfits.
Unstable, unreliable.
That is because their unique gifts
are not understood, Mr. Keller.
There's one point about which
there's no doubt at all,
and that is that ConSec was attacked.
For our own peace of mind,
we have to retaliate in some way.
And I think Dr. Ruth's suggestion
is a very interesting one.
Except that... we don't have
any scanners left to send into the field.
As a matter of fact...
I do have one still unaffiliated.
A very special one.
I don't suppose you speak much.
(Revok) No.
It's not surprising.
With all those other voices in your head,
how can you hear your own voice?
How can you develop a self, a personality?
How do you feel?
I feel... crystal clear.
How do you like it? Clarity.
I'm not sure.
I think I'm a bit afraid.
Why?
I feel so exposed.
I can hear myself.
You hear your own voice?
- Yes.
Good.
- You called me a scanner.
What is that?
A freak of nature,
born with a certain form of ESP.
A derangement of the synapses,
which we call telepathy.
It could be a disease, possibly.
Or a result of radiation.
We don't really know why.
Who are you?
My name is Dr. Paul Ruth.
I'm a psycho-pharmacist by trade,
specializing
in the phenomenon of scanners.
The woman in the shopping mall,
what were you doing to her?
I wasn't doing anything to her.
It was her.
She was... forcing me...
'To what?'
'To think about her.'
'The 50 people that were here
appeared to disturb you.
'Why was that?'
- 'They talked too loud.
'They talked, and they talked...'
- 'Really?
'I didn't see their lips move, did you?'
'No, it was the other voices, the ones
without lips. They were drowning me.'
I couldn't stop them.
The injection I gave you, with the needle,
what happened to the voices?
- They stopped.
The drug is called Ephemerol.
It's a scanner-suppressant.
It does nothing
when it's given to ordinary human beings.
When given to a scanner,
it prevents the flow of telepathy.
It stops the voices.
It can help you.
- How do you know these things?
It's my profession.
This is Mr. Keller.
Will my car be ready this evening?
'Tell us what you did, please, Darryl.'
'I drilled a hole in my head.'
- 'Where? '
'It's kind of obvious, isn't it? Right here.'
'Why did you do it, Darryl?
Why did you drill the hole?'
'Too much pressure.
'To lessen pressure.'
'You wanted to let the pressure out? You
wanted to let something out of your head?'
'Listen, I can't get anything past you, can I?'
'You wanted to let something
out of your head?'
'Uh-huh.'
- 'What?'
'People.
'The people in my head.
They're from the Devil.'
'You mean the voices?'
'No. All people. Arms, legs, hands.'
'What's that you've put over the hole?'
'It's a door. I put an eye on it so they won't...
...know it's a door and
they can't get back in...
'cos they'll see the eye, you know...'
- 'Do you think that will fool them? '
'Sure. Sure it will.
'I mean, sure it will, you know.'
- 'I mean, if that's the only way...'
'No.
'What do you know?
You don't know nothing, do you?
'You want to see if I can do it again?
Do you? You want to see how I did it?
'Aaaargh.'
'Darryl...'
- 'Get your hands off me.
'Get your hands... Get your hands off me.
'Get your hands off me.'
(Thunder in distance)
That's me, isn't it?
As you were...
...without Ephemerol, without guidance.
Is he still like that?
Worse.
- How could he be?
At the age of 22,
he was extremely self-destructive.
Now, at the age of 35,
he is simply destructive.
In many ways, Cameron, he is your enemy.
And mine.
But I don't even know him.
He... knows you.
Somehow he was able to gather
a master list...
...of all the scanners who were ever born.
He has sought them out, one by one,
asked them to join him
in an insane crusade...
...to destroy the society that created him.
And me?
He was looking for you but I found you first.
You can help me.
I don't understand.
All the scanners...
...who didn't agree to
join him were murdered.
These murders represent a loss to mankind
of the most spectacular human beings...
...that ever walked the face of this planet.
You, Cameron,
and your brothers and sisters,
can bring a glory and a brilliance to our
society that has never been seen before.
We must stop Revok. Now.
(Whistle)
ConSec are not ready
to give up their programme.
Paul Ruth... came up with a secret weapon.
What?
Someone you've been looking for, I think.
A scanner. Calls himself Cameron Vale.
I've seen him.
And Ruth knew exactly where to find him.
He's in indoctrination right now.
Can he do anything?
What kind of shape is he in?
He seems to function.
But he's nothing to worry about.
He's weak.
Very weak.
Welcome to our little psychic gymnasium...
...(Heart monitor beeping)...
...Cameron Vale.
And please meet...
...yoga master Dieter Tautz.
Mr. Tautz has kindly consented
to be your psychic sparring partner.
He has publicly demonstrated
on many occasions.
By the power of his will,
he can control his heart rate,
his alpha-wave rhythm,
and many other supposedly uncontrollable
functions of the human body.
Are we ready?
- Just about.
Proceed.
If you'd be kind enough
to sit facing this gentleman here.
I want you...
I want you to slowly release your scan.
Slowly, with focus.
I want it to touch... his heart.
But not his brain. You understand?
Telepathy is not mind-reading.
It is the direct linking...
...of two nervous systems...
...separated by space.
I want you to make a link...
...from your brain... to his heart.
I want your brain to make his heart...
...beat faster.
If his heart beats too quickly,
then he will take over control of his heart...
...and slow it down.
Don't worry about him. All you have to do...
...is make his heart beat faster.
Fast...
Fast.
Faster. Faster...
Faster. Faster.
Faster.
Aaargh.
End your scan.
End it.
Stop him.
- End it.
End it.
(Heart monitor beeping steadily)
You were right, Dr. Ruth.
It was easy.
This man's name is Benjamin Pierce.
These photographs were taken in a prison
for the criminally insane.
There's another one.
This is a plaster cast of him
at present on display...
...in the Crostic Art Gallery
He's our only lead.
A known scanner who may or may not
be part of Revok's underground.
Why was he in prison?
He tried to kill his entire family.
His father, his sister,
mother.
At the age of ten. That was in 1958.
A few years later, he was released.
They say here...
'Rehabilitation through art.'
The man has incredible power, doesn't he?
Power?
Oh, yes, he does.
I'm Arno Crostic.
I'm pleased you came to my gallery.
Are you an aficionado of Benjamin Pierce?
I'm interested in buying this piece
for my apartment in Paris.
Yes?
- I don't think it'll work out...
...unless I can get to meet the artist first.
I'm afraid, no.
I hope it won't prejudice you
against acquiring this piece...
...but I would lose Benjamin Pierce for good
if I even approached him with the idea.
You see, it's part of our agreement.
He will not meet his public.
Maybe you could just
tell me where he lives.
Then I could approach him myself
and you wouldn't be involved.
I'm afraid I can't.
Then maybe you could just
think about where he lives.
Excuse me.
I'm suddenly... feeling ill.
Arno, what's the matter?
Are you OK?
- I will be all right.
Let me take you back to your office.
You've got to lie down.
That's it, take my arm. I'll help you.
Benjamin Pierce?
Why don't you leave me alone?
I need some help.
You're the only one that could give it to me.
Is that right?
Me?
- Yes.
(Cackles)
Then I think you're in big trouble, chum.
I've heard you know
a man named Darryl Revok.
Who are you?
I was told...
...you were coming to
pay me a visit, Mr. Vale.
How did you know that?
How did I know that? Well...
I have friends.
I don't want them...
...but I have them.
Scanner friends?
What do you mean by that?
I'm one of you.
You're one of me.
- Yes.
You know what I think?
I think you'd better tell me
what you really want.
It's the voices in my head.
They're driving me crazy.
How do you stop them, your voices?
My art.
My art keeps me sane.
My art...
Sane...
I don't have anything like this.
That's why I have to find Darryl Revok.
You,
my friend...
...are a liar.
Get out.
- Look...
I'm not leaving until you tell me
where I can find Darryl Revok.
No?
All right. Well, then, I'll get out.
Aaaargh.
Aaargh.
Ow.
No.
(Groaning)...
...(Distorted voice) 'The eye of Revok...
The eye of Revok...
'They're zombies, robots, killers...
'They'll turn me into a zombie...'
'There are others...
'Other scanners...
'Kill Obrist... Kill Obrist...'
(Gasps)
Good evening, sir. Can I help you?
Are there any messages for me?
Your name, sir?
- Cameron Vale.
And your room number?
- 802.
Yes, this package is for you, sir.
(Distorted voices murmuring)...
...(Murmuring intensifies)...
...(Murmuring fades)
My name is Cameron Vale.
I've got to talk to Kim Obrist.
- Come on in.
Oh, God... They killed Ben Pierce.
Yes.
- Come on upstairs.
Just wait here a sec.
Kim, Revok got to Ben Pierce. He's dead.
This guy's name is Cameron Vale.
I scanned him. He's for real.
He was there when it happened.
Sit down.
I know you.
You were at the gallery.
You were looking for Pierce.
I need help.
'Scan together. Scan together and
our minds begin to flow into each other...
'until we become one mind.
One nervous system. One soul.
'One experience. Beautiful. Beautiful.'
'Beautiful and frightening.
Beautiful and frightening.'
'So frightening to lose yourself.
'So frightening to lose yourself to
the group, to lose yourself to the group will,
'to lose yourself to the group self.'
No.
Aaargh.
'The power...
'The power we can generate when
we focus our scans together is fantastic.
'Terrifying, supreme...'
- 'Terrifying, exhilarating...'
(Distorted voices overlapping)...
...(Voices continue)
Around the side, quick.
Hurry.
Get in.
Let's go.
Kim...
Kim.
Kim, come on. Kim.
Now I know...
...what it feels like to die.
Everywhere you go, somebody dies.
Who are you?
Who sent you?
I'm a scanner.
- Who sent you?
I was found by ConSec.
ConSec?
- They wanted me to find Revok.
I think they want to kill him.
But they never told me about you.
Tony.
(Horn blaring)...
...(Screams)...
...(Kim) Tony...
Oh, no...
Come on, we gotta get out of here.
(Police car siren)
Come on.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, outside, ma'am.
OK, let's move out.
Back to the street.
(Siren blaring)...
...(Woman) Let me get out.
Let's get out of here.
- (Fire alarm bell)
We'll be all right here for a while.
It doesn't matter.
It's finished.
And nothing can stop Revok now.
We're the dream, he's the nightmare.
There's still us. I can help you.
We can destroy Revok together.
You?
You're barely human.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, but you don't understand.
You don't know Revok,
you don't know how evil he is,
how powerful he is, you
don't know anything.
What are you doing?
He must have something
that will lead us to Revok.
Us? No, not me.
There it is.
That's it.
Dr. Ruth, telephone call, sir.
You can take it right here.
Yes.
'It's Cameron Vale.'
We missed you.
I made a breakthrough to Revok.
I want to come in. I want to bring you
an informant from Revok's group.
That's excellent.
I'll arrange for you to be brought in.
Can you call me back in about ten minutes?
OK. Goodbye, Dr. Ruth.
All set?
Ten minutes.
(Whistle)
We may have developed a serious problem.
Vale's coming in. He says
he has an informant from your group.
Now, is that possible?
No, he's lying.
Then why is he coming in?
Maybe he's homesick.
Vale must know something or his informant
does. It could be about me and you.
Then you'd better be the one
to interrogate the informant.
Ruth will talk to Vale.
I won't be able to prevent that.
If Ruth finds out anything,
anything at all... kill him.
Really?
I thought you didn't want...
- Kill him.
Really.
One-six, Central,
this is ConSec two-niner. Clear to land.
'ConSec two-niner, this is ConSec Central.
Security is in place. You are clear to land.
'Repeat, affirmative to land.'
I'm afraid I'm going to have to
give you both an injection of Ephemerol.
Well, Braedon, no apologies,
no vote of confidence,
and my man brought back the goods.
We save the party until
we've unwrapped the presents.
It won't take long.
I have a way with these creatures.
I know that.
So has Trevellyan.
That's why he's asked me
to take the informant.
You can do what you like with Vale.
What if that won't work?
Police-state tactics simply won't work, sir.
Really? Why don't you send a letter
to the Board about that, Doctor?
I'm sure they'd love to hear from you.
(Knocking on door)
- Come in.
Welcome.
Congratulations.
It's good to have you back home.
Where's the girl? She should be here.
She's in another room, being interrogated.
I thought it would be you.
So did I. That's why I
made sure the needles
I gave you both were harmless.
She'll be able
to protect herself if there's any problem.
Why did you do that?
Gesture of trust, dear friend.
I have my own methods.
And I've nothing to hide.
Nothing at all to hide.
Not even the RIPE programme?
The what?
Do you know of a drug laboratory
called Biocarbon Amalgamate?
Yes, of course. I founded it in 1942.
You?
- I sold it to ConSec. That's why I'm here.
Let's say that
we have a... genial working relationship.
Do you know what that lab does?
It's been so long
since I've been in touch with them...
As far as I know,
they make some sort
of chemical weaponry,
among other things.
It manufactures Ephemerol
for Darryl Revok.
It may even be run by Darryl Revok.
That's impossible.
No. I was there.
I took the place of one of Revok's men.
I saw Revok in the control room.
The production of Ephemerol
is computerized.
It's being manufactured
and sent out in huge tankers.
Ephemerol is being sent out?
Sent out where?
The answer is in your own computer.
The programme that controls everything
is called RIPE.
And it's a ConSec programme.
That means that someone,
here at ConSec, is a traitor.
That someone is working with Revok.
I want you to access the RIPE programme.
I do not have ConSec computer clearance.
Neither do I.
You do have a nervous system.
So does a computer.
And you can scan the computer
as you would...
...another human being.
Come.
Hello.
- Hello.
What a pleasant surprise.
You're very attractive.
OK, let's do it the formal way.
Your name.
Kim Obrist.
Your name?
Not relevant.
Now... Tell me everything you know
about Darryl Revok's organization.
Before I tell you anything...
I want to know
how you're going to protect me.
When Revok finds out that I've come here...
...he'll try and kill me.
Miss Obrist,
your best protection...
...is to tell us everything we need to know.
As soon as you do.
Revok will cease to be a threat to anyone.
Not good enough.
Revok's people are everywhere...
...and that scares me.
To be honest with you, Kim...
...the only one you should be afraid of...
...is me.
Why should I be afraid of you?
I came here of my own free will.
Because...
I know you're not what you say you are.
I want to see someone else.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
Now, I have acquaintances
in Revok's group. They tell me...
They tell me
that you have never been one of them.
Why are you here?
Why?
Goodbye, Kim.
(Alarm hooter)
It must be Kim. Where is she?
Where is she?
- This is more important.
No.
(Thinking) 'No, this is more important.
'The computer is more important.
'Access the RIPE programme.
'More important...
'But the RIPE programme is the past.
'Therefore to access the RIPE programme
is to access the past, no?
'Access the past...
'Access the past...'
(Alarm continues)
Security.
The scanners. Find them and kill them.
Put it on the air.
Find them and kill them.
It mustn't happen again.
It's always been there inside me,
lurking away, sucking out my joy
and rotting my successes.
Cameron...
Poor Cameron.
I have a way with you, Cameron.
It mustn't happen again.
RIPE. Ripe, indeed.
The RIPE programme... must be stopped.
This isn't the same thing, you understand.
Not the same thing at all.
It's different.
The first time was an accident.
Fortunate for some.
Unfortunate for others.
The RIPE programme is cold and cruel.
Very...
Very cold...
Very cruel...
...(Gunshot)...
What happened?
- Keller tried to kill me.
Keller? Then he's the one.
(Distorted) Oh, my God...
...(Distorted) Mom, what
are you doing here?
I'm sorry, Mom.
Mom...
I didn't...
I didn't mean...
Mom...
...(Distorted) I didn't mean it, Mom. Please...
There's blood on my hand.
Secure the computer room.
Blood on my hand...
What's going on?
What the hell is going on?
It's the scanners, sir. They're out.
Is this the only way we can do it?
If we don't plug into the computer now,
they're going to reprogramme it.
What does that mean?
It means...
...someone has reprogrammed
the computer...
...so that the RIPE programme
is locked away inside.
He threw away the key
and plugged the keyhole.
Try it again. Try it again.
OK.
That's as deep into it as we're going to get.
Hey, Lee, punch up your internal monitor.
Access is IM 863.
- Why, what is it?
Someone's inside this thing right now,
getting the RIPE programme.
How can this happen?
This room is max security.
We're plugged into the telephone system.
Anybody who has the proper access codes
could get in here long-distance.
Someone's getting in there right now?
- Yeah.
Damn.
It's him.
It's Vale. He's inside.
Is that possible?
- It's got to be.
It's got to be. I want to hurt him.
How can we hurt him before he gets out?
- Hurt him? I don't understand.
Vale's nervous system and the computer's
nervous system are joined.
He's scanning it.
I want to cripple them both.
Or maybe kill them both. How?
Well, I don't know if it's what you want,
but I could override
the max security self-destruct.
It blows all the circuits,
in case data is taken...
...by unauthorized and unfriendly forces.
Do it now.
- That would entail a total loss...
...of all programmes in the ConSec system.
I'd need written authorization
from ConSec Leader.
Mister, this is your authorization.
Sit down.
Do it now or I'll kill you.
Yes, sir, I'm doing it now.
Sir, I have to finish it over there.
Sir, this is the last step. Are you sure?
- Do it.
There's no need for that. It's all very quiet.
It's just internal switching.
Really? No one's ever switched off
a scanner before.
Oh, shit.
See? I told you,
no fireworks.
(Siren)...
I'll go find the doctor.
- All right, I'll keep an eye on the door.
Excuse me.
Is the receptionist coming back soon?
Erm, yeah, I guess so.
- Thanks.
Please. I'll be with you in a moment.
- I have to talk to you right now.
Would you please get out of here?
It's about this drug, Dr. Frane.
I understand
you've been prescribing it to some patients.
Excuse me. I'll be back in just a moment.
Just relax. Read a magazine.
Where did you get this?
What do you want with me? Who are you?
What happened?
I was scanned.
The woman in the... in the waiting room...
She scanned you?
No, not her.
Her child.
Her unborn child scanned me.
That's what the RIPE programme is.
The doctors on the computer list are giving
Ephemerol to their pregnant patients.
I don't understand.
- Ephemerol.
Ephemerol is creating new scanners.
Hold still.
- Ow. God...
- Oh, God... Ow.
OK. OK.
Oh, God...
- Come on, let's get out of here.
Come on.
Come on, you can make it. Come on.
Kim... Kim...
Vale.
Kim...
Sleeping beauty awakes.
Where is Kim?
The next room.
She'll be awake in a few hours.
We don't want anyone in here with us.
This is just between you and me.
Where's your partner, Keller?
He should be here.
Keller? It seems he died
when you blew up his computer.
By the way, that was very impressive.
Keller murdered Dr. Ruth.
He deserved to die.
You shouldn't mourn the doctor's death.
Celebrate it with me.
Dr. Ruth was a great man.
He tried to help us. He helped me.
Great man. There's only one person on
earth who tried to help you, and that's me.
You?. You sent your soldiers out to kill me.
Never. Never you.
I've spent years looking for you.
Then when Keller told
me Ruth had dressed...
...you up and sent you
out as an amateur spy.
I tried to take care of you,
look after you, guide you to me.
Now, why would you try to do that?
Who's your mother?
I don't know.
Who's your father?
- I don't know.
What was your first childhood memory?
I don't have any.
No, you don't.
And it's no accident that you don't.
You were kept on ice.
It wasn't till ConSec had trouble putting
me away that they thawed you out.
You've been monitored all your life,
allowed to live like garbage.
Scum. He knew where you were
but it wasn't till he needed you...
...that he hauled you out of the slime.
- Who?
Your father.
Dr. Paul Ruth.
Our father.
No...
You're my brother, Cameron.
My kid brother.
No...
Sit down. I want to show you something.
This was a test campaign
used in 1947 to market a new product.
The product was a drug,
a tranquillizer called Ephemerol.
It was aimed at pregnant women.
If it had worked,
it would have been marketed
all over North America.
But the campaign failed and the drug failed.
It had a side effect on the unborn children.
An invisible side effect.
It created scanners.
- Yes.
The man who invented Ephemerol was very
excited by this weird mutation it caused,
and so was ConSec.
They offered to finance his experiments,
so he sold them his company and himself.
And that man was Dr. Ruth?
That was Daddy.
I said the side effects of Ephemerol were
invisible but that's not completely true.
Daddy could see them.
He could see them in us.
He had given the prototype of Ephemerol
to his pregnant wife, our mother,
four years before it hit the market,
and then again a year later.
His children turned out to be difficult,
till he realized that the only thing that would
calm them down was his drug, Ephemerol.
That's why we're older than all the others.
Not only older, more powerful.
The rest of them,
they're nothing compared to us.
Then what did you need Keller for?
ConSec had hardware, it had contacts.
Keller could see the future.
The future?.
You murdered the future.
That's negative, Cam. Defeatist.
It disappoints me to hear you talk that way.
You're starting to sound like them.
A generation of scanner soldiers is a few
months from being born. We'll find them,
train them to be like us,
not like Obrist and her band of cripples,
bring the world of normals to their knees.
Build an empire so brilliant, so glorious,
we'll be the envy of the whole planet.
You sound just like him.
Like Ruth.
No, not like him. Like...
Revok. Darryl Revok.
No... Like him.
It's as though he's been
reincarnated in you.
You're not listening to me.
You're not cooperating, Cam.
You're not cooperating with me at all.
I've been counting on you
for years, Cameron.
Tell me you're not going to betray me
like all the rest. Tell me you're not.
No.
All right, we're going to do it the scanner
way. I'm going to suck your brain dry.
Everything you are is going to become me.
You're going to be with me, no matter what.
After all, brothers should be close,
don't you think? Hm?
(Distorted growling)
Cameron?
Kim.
It's me, Kim. Cameron. I'm here.
We've won.
We've won...