# No cigarettes, no sleep,
no light, no sound #
# Nothing to eat,
nowhere to drink #
# Sometimes all I need
is the air that I breathe #
# and to love you #
# All I need
is the air that I breathe #
# and to love you #
# All I need... #
- Watch where you're going.
# is to love you #
# All I... #
[urinating]
Hey.
[grunts]
(Man) Delta team check in.
Delta team (inaudible).
No, no, no.
[inaudible]
[inaudible dialog]
- Maybe the source is wrong.
- The source is good.
It's ten after. The source
said 4 a.m. on the dot.
Wait. Go back.
(music)
Creedence.
It's probably
just a radio station
someplace outside
of the city.
No. It's him.
[music continues]
Do we have to listen
to the whole song,
all seven minutes
and 40 seconds of it?
Why do you insist on
asking that every time?
Gum, I don't want to mess
with your superstitions.
God knows we don't wanna
fluck with the formula,
but how about a new band?
Over the last six years,
we have listened
the entire Creedence Clearwater
Revival songbook over and over...
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Hi, sweetie.
Why are you
up so early?
What?
Which one?
Which one? Oh, the Care Bears book.
Oh, okay. I thought you
were taking the even pages.
Oh, okay, I'm supposed
to color the evens.
Okay, well, I'll take my
turn as soon as I get home.
Save the purple crayon
for Daddy.
Well, I told you,
Daddy has to work.
But guess what?
When I get home, I'm gonna make
you those happy face pancakes
that you like so much, okay?
I love you, baby.
Okay, big kiss.
[kissing sound]
Don't.
What?
Actually,
you wouldn't understand.
- About Care Bears?
- Parenthood.
No, no,
you're totally right.
Every father talks
to his little girl
before he commits
a Class H felony.
Absolutely normal.
So sweet.
Hoyt's late.
Four minutes
is not late.
The sensors
are set in 20.
Four minutes
less from 20 is 16,
two to enter,
three for the wall,
ten to drill.
Puts us inside
in 15 minutes.
That's not enough cushion.
- Let's call it.
- Dude is running five minutes behind.
He's probably
just taking a dump.
We're not calling it.
We're good.
This is an ace boon swipe, Gum.
There's not another one of these
in the headlights for a long while.
I don't know. Suddenly
I'm not feeling so good.
Well, then relax.
Put on a little
"Bad Moon Rising."
This is Diamond Dog.
I'm in the mainframe now.
The blouse is open,
undoing the bra strap now.
Fire alarms are down.
Seismics are down.
Killing the cameras now.
Good to go when you are.
Go radio silent till I say.
[radio static]
The van's leaving.
[clanking metal]
Okay, fellas.
As ready to rock
as Riley's diaphragm.
Really, Hoyt?
Sorry, Sugar.
[swooshing, crashing]
Sir, I've got seismic.
Sounds like they blew a wall.
We got 'em.
Doesn't make any sense.
It's too easy.
This crew
doesn't do too easy.
Three minutes, guys.
Less than three, let's go.
Move it.
Dude, come on.
Okay, grab some extras.
[inaudible
background dialog]
Come on, move it.
We're in route now.
The proverbial hand is up
the skirt, heading straight
...for the moose knuckle. - Awesome.
That's why I love working with dudes.
For all the clever variations you can
come up with for the word "vagina."
Vagina.
I need some air.
[zipper sound]
[whirring]
Drill's up.
Three minutes down.
They started drilling.
Wait. On my go.
[whirring]
[sparking]
[bang]
Lock is out.
It's a go.
All right,
we'll take 'em.
(Vincent)
Come on, now, master at work.
- You got 30 seconds.
- Plenty of time.
(Gum)
Number one's down.
Gum, you have 15 seconds. Come on.
(Will)
Number two down.
Go!
- Clear.
What the hell's going on?
Doesn't make any sense.
They were casing this place
for three weeks.
Shit! Get someone in that toy store.
Now!
- We're in. - (Hoyt) They're in the
bank vault. Two minutes till we're rich.
Jesus wept.
It's like looking
into heaven.
Stay focused.
Alpha team
sweeping toy store now.
- Clear.
All clear.
Get a (inaudible) now.
Diamond exchange
has not been reached.
Repeat,
secondary wall is intact.
You know I like
bright shiny things, Gum.
- This is the ultimate bright shiny thing.
- How much weight can you carry?
Each one of those bars
weighs 27.5 pounds.
I played football.
We got our ten million right here.
Time!
Sir, I've got 500 meters of
dark empty tunnel in front of me.
Somebody screwed up.
We're on the wrong block!
They're robbing a bank!
Quick!
[siren]
[beeping]
All right,
let's do it.
[screeching tires]
[panting]
[sirens,
tires screeching]
Get that Brigadier
over here.
Get rid of this door.
Let's go! Let's go!
Let's go, guys.
Everybody out. Move it!
Pull the chains around
the right. Go, go, go!
Hook them up to the door.
I want this door gone.
It doesn't have
to be pretty.
Clear!
[chains scraping,
glass shattering]
Let's go, guys, come
on, move it! Let's go!
Go, go, go!
They'll be in the vault.
Hey, what are you
young fellas doing?
[man grunts]
Go on!
You should've
just kept moving.
- Did you have to hit him so hard?
- He saw our faces.
No. Put it down.
No homicide.
No, I am not going back
to prison. Not again.
In this bag is enough
for us to disappear.
No need for any more jobs.
Let's just go.
Come on, guys.
What the hell
are they doing?
Damn!
I have been to prison
and I didn't like it.
In fact, I fucking
hated it!
[gunshot,
yells]
Oh, shit!
Oh, my God.
Ah, you shot me!
Let's find the back
to this place.
- Ah, oh, my God!
- Be quiet.
- What are you doing?
- What happened?
He shot himself in the leg.
No! You shot me. Ah!
Oh, shit.
I left the money.
I have to get it.
What? No!
We're heated.
Let's go, guys, come
on, move it. Let's go!
God!
This sucks!
I want this guy nailed.
Now, everyone spread out.
What the hell
are you doing?
- He's on his own now, baby.
- No, Will!
Your ride is gone.
Hoyt!
[sirens]
Put your hands
in the air!
(Dispatcher) All units 217
on east side of Rampart.
Assault on
two police officers.
Suspect has fled the scene
In a police cruiser.
Oh, we got him.
There he is.
Straight ahead.
All units,
Iberville and Burgundy.
[tires screeching,
sirens]
[crash]
He's on the upward ramp.
[crash,
breaking glass]
Shit!
God damn it, Fletcher!
[screams]
Shit!
Come on, come on.
Cop. Let it go.
Shit, cop.
- Don't shoot, man!
- Get out of the way!
[police radio]
[sighs]
[zipper]
Will Montgomery. Bring out
the money and yourself, slow.
Real slow.
Stop.
Turn around.
On your knees.
My wedding day,
the birth of my twins,
and now this.
Highlights, Will.
I'm talkin' highlights.
Cuff him.
Hey!
Where's the money?
- Fletcher.
- How you doin', Will?
Hope you got
raped every day.
Harland wants
to give you a lift.
He's not asking.
Welcome home.
Harland.
So, where to?
Coronado and Prentiss.
So, how's
the federal penal system?
Not as tough
as they say, huh?
How's the wife?
- She's good, I guess.
- She left you?
Four years ago.
I'm sorry.
You ought to be.
Why'd you pick me up,
Harland?
I thought you might
pick up where you left off
now that you're
as free as a bird and all.
- No, it's all behind me now.
- You could probably afford to retire now
with that sizable withdrawal
from Parish Community you made.
You knew if you got caught
with money you'd be looking at
an extra ten years,
so you ditched it somewhere.
And now that you're out
I thought you're gonna
go get that ten mil.
Aren't you, Will?
Much like a squirrel
returning back to its horde
after a long cold winter.
I'm not the squirrel playing
with his nuts here, Harland.
I don't have the money.
You know that Vincent
is dead, right?
I don't think he knows,
do you, Agent Fletcher?
How does that
make you feel?
He was my friend.
Yeah. He had a tough
time of it after you left.
You being the brains
behind the operation.
I guess he owed money
to the wrong people.
- Your ex-wife's place, huh?
- I'm not here for her.
- You really think your kid wants
to see you? - I'm about to find out.
Grandma Harland used to say
love makes time pass,
but time is certain
to make love pass.
Can I enjoy my day now?
Thanks for the lift.
(Fletcher) Oh, happy
Fat Tuesday, Will.
I'm starting to think
you like the guy.
Admiring someone
doesn't mean you like them.
Let's go, Fletcher.
- Hi.
- What are doing? You scared me.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. I'm sorry.
When did you get out?
This morning. I know I should've
called. I didn't have a number.
You look like your mom.
She's not here, is she?
She's in Shreveport.
- With Mr. Loeb.
- Yes. With David.
This came for you
this morning.
It was just
left on the mat.
Thanks.
Can we talk?
- I really should get going.
- Just for a few minutes.
I have something for you. I saw it
on the way in. Reminded me of you.
Oh.
Cool.
No one sets out
to be a criminal,
but through...
I've had so many
conversations with you.
Now that you're
sitting across from me,
it's like my mind
is going blank.
No one sets out
to be a criminal, Alison.
But through circumstances,
bad choices, needs,
unforeseeable obstacles,
unreliable friends,
dishonesty,
life intervenes.
And I'm not trying
to justify it.
I'm not making excuses
for it. I was a bad man.
But I've had eight long
years to get rid of that man.
To ready myself
to get to know you.
I have to go.
Where are you going?
I told you, I'm late.
Late for what?
My shrink session.
- I go every Tuesday.
- Really?
Yeah. Apparently
I have abandonment issues.
Go figure.
I meant what I said,
Alison.
Keep it.
I'm not seven anymore.
- Alison.
- Just go, please.
[blues playing
on stereo]
[clears throat]
Thanks for
the visual massage, Pete.
Riley, you are just
too damn fine, girl.
When you gonna
give me the time of day?
Well, let me call your wife
and see when you're available.
Aah. Why you gotta bring her
up? Talk about a buzz kill.
- You have a good one.
- You too.
Now, how is it
that after eight years
you have
only gotten younger?
Oh, my God.
Will.
I can't believe it.
- When did you get out?
- This morning.
You should've let me know,
I would've picked you up.
That's all right. Agent Harland
was kind enough to give me a lift.
You're kidding. That guy needs
to get laid, like, yesterday.
[clears throat]
Hmm.
Let me get you a drink.
Tequila?
Yes, ma'am.
What the hell, Riley,
you're working in a cop bar?
Yeah, well, you know, it's a good way to
guarantee I don't go back to wrong.
Back to wrong?
Yeah. Self-restraint
was never my strong suit.
I'm honored
to be your first stop.
Actually, I dropped
by Alison's first.
Oh. And how is she?
Not as honored.
Don't worry, Will,
she'll come around.
I missed you, Will. I never got to
thank you after all that went down.
- Don't mention it.
- I wasn't allowed to come visit.
My lawyer wouldn't let me, and Harland
never really stopped sniffing around.
- So I just...
- I know. I know.
But you not ratting us out
really means something in my book.
Like I said...
You could've
ratted out Hoyt, though.
- That I wouldn't have minded.
- Hoyt.
Yeah, I'm looking
for that guy.
And I take it
you heard about Vince.
Yes. That's terrible.
I mean, he went really dark.
Well, I mean, do they
know who killed him?
No, I don't think so. He was
hanging out with the sketchy crowd.
Looking for the new you,
I suppose.
It's good
to see you again, Riley.
[phone ringing]
I think we woke up
your package.
(Man) Riley.
Can you change a tap?
Two beers.
Be right back.
Hello?
Hello, Will Montgomery.
[coughing]
Who is this?
You don't recognize
my voice, Gum?
- I wanted to be there for you
at the prison. - Vincent?
Give you a welcome
when you got out.
But you know how it is,
time just slipped away.
Well, hallelujah, man.
You're alive.
Shit. You know what? Everybody's
telling me you're dead.
I suppose that depends on your
interpretation of the word "dead."
'Cause I'm certainly not living.
[coughing]
Well, where are you?
Can we meet? How are you?
The years you've been gone
have not been kind to me, Gum.
Constantly running
from loan sharks,
the feds, broker than
a dead-dicked dog.
I couldn't get another swipe.
I am sorry
to hear about that.
You listen to me, Gum.
I have been waiting
eight years for this.
Go ahead.
I had to change my name,
erase everything.
And then there's that little
matter of the bullet in my leg.
A constant friendly reminder of the
partner who ruined my life that night.
Come on, man. Really?
We're gonna go back there?
You did that to yourself.
Semantics.
I want my share.
I want my share
of the $10 million
that was gonna
change our lives forever.
Vinnie, there is no cash.
[coughs] I had a feeling
you'd say that, Gum.
I burned it just before
Harland got to me.
No. Stop it.
It's true.
(Alison)
What's taking so long?
Hold on.
Wait a minute. Who...
That voice, who was that?
Oh, that's right, you don't
know. I'm a cab driver now.
My fare
is this sweet little girl
trying to get
to her shrink's office
so she can discuss
her daddy issues
and how they have manifested
into an unhealthy disdain
...for the world at large.
- Hey, what are you doing?
Hold on, please, Gum.
Sorry, Miss,
terrible Fat Tuesday traffic.
Be there in a jiffy.
See how it lays?
Now, Gum, this all
depends on whether or not
you're gonna stick to your story
about burned cash.
You touch her
and I'll take you
down the levy
and kick your fucking ass.
I don't know if you
heard what I just said,
but this all
depends on you.
Vincent!
He's on the move.
Where are we going?
What are we doing?
Why are we in here?
I hope you understand
this is not my preference.
Help me!
No! Help!
I mean,
considering your father,
I would never want
to add to your suffering.
But you see, Alison?
I've got a sickness.
I'm not well.
Your father abandoned me
in my time of need...
So I know what it is to be in the
position you're in. Really, I do.
I know what it is to be left
high and dry by Will Montgomery.
And you and me,
we're kindred spirits,
and I am going to make him
pay for the both of us.
Sorry.
[goofy sound,
grunts]
I love you too, man.
You don't gotta beat the...
[phone ringing]
Vincent?
- Gum.
- Where's Alison?
Did you change your mind or are you
still sticking with the bullshit story?
- Can I talk to her?
- Alison...
is waiting for you to decide
whether she's going to remain fine.
Vincent, don't do this.
- I'm hanging up now.
- No, no, wait, okay, wait.
I can get it.
I can get the money.
I just need time.
It's not here.
It's in Tuscaloosa.
My lawyer has it
in a trust.
- So I need 24 hours.
- You got 12.
The phone in your hand,
I'll be tracking you with it at all times.
Eight rings
and you pick it up.
You miss a single
phone call from me,
Alison doesn't live.
Vincent.
This is my last chance
to dance, buddy.
You haven't seen me recently.
Let's just say
I've got two left feet.
Hello?
Vincent. Hello?
Hi, I need to get a phone.
I'm sorry, sir,
you're gonna have to wait.
No, excuse me, ma'am.
I really need a phone.
Sir, I will be with you
in a moment.
How much is this one?
$29.99.
Do you want your change?
[texting]
(Announcer) Amtrak service to Tuscaloosa
is now boarding at Platform 2.
[texting]
[honking]
Help!
Get me outta here!
Fletcher, I can't hear you.
You lost him
on his first morning out.
- Shit!
- Will Montgomery is here to see you.
Send him in.
So your dead former partner, Vincent
Kinsey, has kidnapped your daughter
and is holding her
somewhere in New Orleans?
- In a cab. - The cab, yes,
that's right. In a cab, yeah.
And what does
he want in return?
- $10 million.
Remind me why that's a familiar figure.
I burned the cash.
Just before
you grabbed me.
(Harland)
William Montgomery.
That's the God's honest truth.
'Cause I knew I'd get less
time if I ditched the money.
I don't have it, but he has my
daughter and I need your help.
Why would I be here
if I had the money?
I would just pay Vincent off
and get my little girl back.
This is how
I see it, Will.
You're a thief,
a crook, and a scumbag,
but you're also
a very clever tree frog.
So you concoct this Kinsey-is-alive-
and-has-snatched-my-kid fantasy
so that, A, you can show
that you don't have the money,
otherwise, why wouldn't you
pay the ransom,
or, B, send us
running around all over town
searching for your daughter
and her abductor
to afford you the time
to dig up the dough
and jump onto
a cigarette boat
and zip down to the Bahamas
where you can sip rum
for the rest of your days
and listen to classic rock
played by bands with muscular
guitars and dead drummers.
Oh, my faithful bloodhound.
Couldn't find your couch
in the living room.
This is Vincent's file.
The prints match,
as you can see.
They cut his body up
before they burnt it.
We got the prints off the few
fingers that survived the fire.
We can visit
his grave if you want.
No, we can't, because he's
alive. He faked his own death.
Please. Tim.
I'm running out of time.
I'm not being played
by you again, Will.
- Fletcher?
- Yeah.
All right, let's go.
Please help me.
Escort our pal out of
the building, will you?
A little help, guys.
Well, Montgomery, on behalf of the
Federal Bureau of Investigation,
we'd like to thank you
for stopping by today.
Hold up. Hold up.
- Harland thinks you're some kind of
criminal mastermind. - Criminal mastermind?
I don't share this belief
because criminal masterminds
don't go away for
eight-year jolts, or do they?
[grunting, shouting]
One more, please.
Thank you.
We called Montgomery's
ex home and cell.
Both voicemails
say she's out of town.
Have you tried
his daughter's cell phone?
The account's been suspended
per request of the stepfather.
Get local PD on it.
If she has been kidnapped, we're
FBI, we do something about it.
You don't think
he's telling the truth?
No, I do not.
Hey! Is there
anybody out there?
Hello?
[phone ringing]
Jacobs.
Crap.
We have a problem.
[elevator ding]
[alarm]
That's good.
Alright,
keep tracking him to Tuscaloosa.
If he deviates from
the route, let me know.
Yeah, you are the exactly the woman
I want to see in clothes that tight.
The only thing
with any balls
to come to this town
was the hurricane.
Get away from the car!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Cab's off duty.
Good day, mate,
how are you doing?
- Look, I just gotta get to...
- Cab's off duty, man.
Yeah, mate. Look, I've just gotta
catch up with these chicks...
Hey!
Please?
Help!
Mate, I haven't had my donger
dipped since I got here.
[phone vibrating]
Ah, let's see.
Yeah, mate?
Mate, I'm trying.
One of them is preggers,
eh, yeah, I know.
Mate, I better
get off the blow
or this cabby's
gonna chuck a wobbly.
Hey mate, so let me tell
you about these sheilas, eh?
So the preggers one,
she seemed most interested.
Buggered if I know why, but
my willie's about as lonely
as bandicoot
on a burnt ridge.
I don't know
about these chicks.
They're quite different
in New Orleans, aren't they?
New Orleans
all comes back...
to a pudgy kid by the
name of King Louis XV.
King Louis XV,
he owned all this.
... fellow Frenchman
to cross the ocean and visit.
But it wasn't happening.
So in order to get
some use out of it,
finally he starts shipping over
boatloads of French prisoners.
What's crawlin'
up your ass, bugger?
Thieves, gamblers,
prostitutes, murderers,
pirates, gypsies,
pickpockets,
and psychopaths.
Is this me stop?
Those are the pioneers
of this land,
and the forefathers
of this town
that you casually dismissed.
[yells, growls]
(phone vibrating)
All the computers
In this building are tracked.
This is the page
that corresponds
to the exact moment in
the video where he stops.
This is Agent Harland. I need an assault
team at apartment 9,23 St. Claude.
(dog continuously barking)
Billy, shut up!
Stupid, stupid dog!
I'm gonna skin you and make
a pair of shoes out of you!
I hate you
and your owner!
Shut up!
- Jesus, Will!
- Shut up!
Drop the bag.
It's my lunch.
And that's my gun.
Drop the bag.
That's for the last
eight years.
- Where's Vincent?
- Vincent? Vincent's dead, man.
- Try again.
- I swear. I swear on my life.
- I haven't seen Vincent...
- Oh, that's right, I forgot.
It's not your brain
that you care about.
A bullet to the stomach
is the most painful.
And it takes
hours to die.
- Okay, look, man, what do you wanna know?
- What does he have you doing?
Nothing, baby. You know, bag
drops, recon, stuff like that.
He told me to drop off the phone
for you, so I dropped off the phone.
And my daughter?
My daughter!
The whole bottom fell out of our
operation when you went away, Will.
Look around you. Does it look
like I'm puttin' on the Ritz here?
We want our share.
Just our share.
[shouts,
Hoyt groans]
So help me God, Hoyt.
You tell me where she is or I'll
blow your lunch all over this carpet.
He's driving around with her
in the trunk of his cab.
- In the trunk?
- And I gotta be honest with you, Will,
'cause I didn't think the taking
your daughter part was right.
I mean, bad idea to steal from
America's greatest bank robber.
[Hoyt groans]
After he lost the leg,
something changed in him, Will.
He said he just
felt numb to everything.
Numb like a statue.
He blames that on you, Will.
He blames the leg on you. He said
he also blames the numb on you.
(screeching tires)
[grunting, fighting]
Go!
[dog barking]
[groaning]
Let the squirrels squabble,
and then we'll go
after their horde.
Hold it.
Come on, go!
Will, stop!
Stop!
Stop, stop, stop!
Street level.
Go.
What the hell
are you doing?
Man, you listenin', Tapioca?
Just go, please.
Medallion.
(siren)
License and registration, please.
Do you know why
I pulled you over?
- I do not.
- Brake light's out.
- What's funny?
- Nothing. It's just, it's Mardi Gras
and the streets are filled
with drunken lunatics
and you pull me over
for a broke brake light.
[pounding]
Help!
Reminds me of when my father
was dying of bone cancer,
all day he'd bitch about
the nick he got in his chin
from shaving that morning.
I know what you're thinking.
Why would a dying man shave?
No.
I wasn't thinking
that at all.
Get this vehicle
back to the barn.
Get that light
taken care of.
Please!
Can you hear me?
(Vincent)
'Cause he had tremendous vanity!
Sir, do you mind coming
around here to open the trunk?
He did not go gently,
my father.
He screamed a lot.
The pain was agonizing,
searing.
Eels squirming
through his veins.
Buddy, I really don't give a damn.
[silenced gunshot]
[trunk opening]
Somebody help me!
Help!
Somebody please help!
Gotcha.
[moans]
Come here.
You're more like him than I
thought. You don't remember me?
You were young, I guess, and
I did look a little different.
I had all my fingers then,
and both legs.
Ah, nice fingers,
sweetie.
You know, the FBI, they use they
little lines in order to find people.
That's how they were
looking for me anyway.
But one day
I came up with a plan.
Yeah, I dug up a body.
See, it wasn't hard.
Resemblance was reasonable.
Then I cut him up
into small pieces.
And added a little
of myself to the mix.
I was a golden boy,
doll face.
Now I'm a freakin' Picasso.
And don't ever mess
with my lights again.
What are you
looking at, shrimp?
Listen, brother, take the
cab, take the money in the cab,
I don't give a crap,
but don't take me.
- What is this?
- It's a meter.
No, I know what a meter
is, asshole. Not that, this.
It's a GPS. Everyone has 'em
in case the cars are stolen.
- Tells you their location?
- Within a few blocks, yeah.
All right,
call your dispatcher.
Man, you have got to clean out that
backseat before you sign off tonight.
Yesterday I had
to put on a biohazard suit,
hip waders and rubber gloves,
and I got the garden hoe
and scraped
that crap out there.
- Looked like boogers or jalapeno
jelly, Bertrand. - I got a question for you.
Nine inches, and can reload
after 14 minutes and a tickle.
- What else do you want to know?
- About the driver.
Is this about me docking your pay
again 'cause of the fender bender?
The same policy applies for
everybody, and I ain't lifting it.
- No, it's not about that.
- White guy with a fake leg.
- He's a white man with a fake leg.
- Maybe some missing fingers.
- Really?
- Tell him!
And maybe
missing some fingers.
Are you messing
with me today?
- (LeFleur) What you want him for?
- He cut me off at a light.
(LeFleur) And you think
I give a snot, huh?
Tell him he's stealing money,
you saw him pocketing fares.
He's stealing fares.
Pocketing.
Wait, are you saying
that the creepy limping bastard
be running around
sneetching my dough?
- Get his location.
- Where is he right now?
What you wanna
know that for?
I'll confront him for you.
Get the truth.
You would do that
for me, Bertrand?
You're a good boss.
- He in the French Quarter.
Burgundy and St. Philip. - Thank you.
Well done.
Get his
medallion number.
And his medallion number.
Man, he a freaky deak dude.
(Lefleur) You best be,
careful there, Berty-boy.
Get out.
It's all yours, brother.
(Lefleur)
Five-kilo-two-zero.
- Again, that's 5K20.
- Thanks, pal.
Looky here, did you just turn
white on me all of a sudden?
Who dat is?
Remember where
we dropped off Montgomery?
His daughter's address?
Yes,
Coronado and something.
- Prentiss.
- Hey, boss?
A guy matching
Montgomery's description
just jacked a cab
five blocks from here.
Get this, the cabbie said
he was sweating him
about a guy missing
a leg and his fingers.
They're tracking the stolen
cab back into the Quarter.
- Don't hurt me, man!
- Whose cab is this?
It's mine.
But that ain't my number.
Open the trunk.
There he is. We got him.
Whoa.
That's somebody else's GPS.
Montgomery! Get your God
damn knees on the ground.
Will Montgomery, you are under
arrest for violation of parole,
illegally accessing
confidential FBI records,
assaulting a federal agent,
and resisting arrest.
- We're bringing him back now.
- You've gotta listen to me.
- No we don't.
- He's gonna kill her.
(Tessler)
Oh, it's a neat story.
Vincent Kinsey has
come back from the dead?
(Matthews)
Yeah.
Me, if I were
coming back from the dead,
it wouldn't be
for daughter killing.
It'd be to go to Rick's Cabaret
to see some naked ladies.
(phone ringing)
- I gotta take that.
- Ah, you want me to take a message?
- I've only got eight rings to
pick up that call. - Hey, sit back.
(phone ringing)
(bones breaking)
Hello?
Hi, I'm here.
I'm here.
(resetting bone)
Really coming down to the
wire on this one, eh, Gum?
Have trouble getting it
out of your pocket?
I'm not.
I just, I just...
Sounds like
you're out of breath.
Tell me something, Gum.
What's the scenery like
down there in Tuscaloosa?
I always wanted
to take that ride along the Gulf.
I don't have it.
Or better yet, why don't
you tell me how Hoyt's doing,
seeing as that's
where you were anyway?
I don't have the money.
What did I say to you
about lying to me?
I'm sorry,
I just, I just...
- Your daughter's dead.
- No, wait! Wait!
You really
don't have it, do you?
- I'll get you the money.
- (Vincent) Good.
May I ask how?
By going back to wrong.
He got away on foot.
He went down the alley, okay?
We gotta
set up a perimeter.
Let's move.
Clear out!
(phone ringing)
Hello?
What's going on?
- Why are the feds after you?
- There's no time.
- Vincent's alive.
- What? What are you talking about?
He wants $10 million. He wants it
in three hours, and he has Alison.
Oh, my God.
The bank
we robbed that night,
there was something else
in the vault.
A gold reserve, there must've
been 100 million, easy.
There's no way
you can walk in there
and steal $10 million
worth of gold bricks
in the middle
of a business day.
But that's why
I need your help.
I already told you,
this isn't my life anymore.
- I know. I know.
- It's not yours either.
He's going to kill her.
I, I can hear it
in his voice.
He's not the same person.
He's going to kill
my little girl.
Okay.
(sirens)
Oh, man.
- You LeFleur?
- Yes sir, I am. LeFleur, yes sir.
A guy jacked your cab a little while
ago. He was looking for someone?
Well, he was looking for
that mope, Jimmy Morgan, sir.
Be a peach and show me
his hack license, will you?
Yes, yes, officer, sir.
I'll look it up
for you, inspector.
He been with us
two years.
Never any problem.
Although he do
scare my kids
when they come to visit
their daddy at work.
My kids
are in their 20s.
Vincent Kinsey.
Much obliged.
Let's go.
(sirens)
Fat Tuesday,
everybody go crazy.
We're six blocks away from
the bank, you do realize that.
- Have a little faith.
- Okay.
(Will) I've considered doing
this for the last 8 years.
(Will) Thirty meters, then we go left.
Montgomery doesn't have the
money, but he needs the money,
which means he's only got
one play left to make.
Get me a list of every bank that he's
stepped into in the city of New Orleans.
My guess is one of them
he's going to step into again.
We're through.
- Five minutes till the alarm.
- Think that'll be enough?
(Will)
Here it comes.
(alarm buzzing)
Fire alarm just went off
at Parish Community Bank.
(Harland) That's him.
Get us there now!
(Firefighter)
Let's go, boys.
The alarm will have
triggered by now. We gotta go.
I just want to see if I can get
a little more gold out of it.
Come on, guys, let's go!
Go, go, go!
Could you please
hurry up, sir?
(vault beeping)
Come on, Will,
we gotta go.
Come on!
Huh.
(Harland)
Well, what do you know.
So, you worked all this out from prison?
I was bored.
Boss, hey. Listen to this. Say again.
We have the two suspects.
They're in Rileys truck
on North Reters
headin' towards the ferry.
Do not take them
until they're off the ferry.
I repeat, do not take them
We take them now.
We got 'em boxed in.
(Harland) You don't corner a weasel
unless you wanna get bit.
I hope you know what you're
doing. Takes eight minutes
...to get across the river on that ferry.
- Wait for strength in numbers.
And when we get Montgomery,
he'll be as red-handed
as the boy who put his palm on the
gas stove to see how hot it really was.
Okay.
Don't make a move until all
four wheels touch Louisiana soil.
(Agent)
Copy that.
Hands in the air.
Hands in the air now!
Happy Fat Tuesday, officer.
Come on.
Come on, get out.
Get out!
(phone ringing)
(Vincent)
Time is up, buddy.
I've got it.
Ah, I am impressed.
You listen to a little
Creedence before you went in?
No, I didn't listen to CCR. That didn't
work out so well the last time, did it?
I missed you, old buddy.
I want to talk to her.
No, you'll talk to her
when you give me the money.
I wanna talk
to my daughter now!
I wanna hear her voice now!
It's your father.
- Hello?
- Alison.
Alison, did he hurt you?
No, but he scares me.
I'm gonna be there soon.
I'm gonna get you outta this.
(Will)
This is my fault.
Get my money
to the fairgrounds now.
Sorry, boss.
Finally starting to recognize the
skills of Will Montgomery, huh?
You got those listings
from the cab dispatcher?
GPS breakdowns?
Yeah, why?
I told you Kinsey
ditched his GPS
in the back of a cab
in the French Quarter.
I'm not interested in today's.
I wanna see the last few weeks.
Kinsey's gonna get the
money from Montgomery,
then he's gonna have to have
some kind of neutral rendezvous.
And if that's the case,
he's been casing it for weeks.
Uptown, Lakefront,
Beauvoir, Gretna,
- West Bank.
- Beauvoir?
- Is that the fairground?
- Yeah, I think so.
Twenty minutes
from out of town?
- That doesn't sound like a cab ride to me.
- Nicely done, boss.
We might actually
catch this prick.
Where's Alison?
In the trunk?
You look good, Will.
The same.
Where is she?
She's safe.
The money.
Hand her over.
I said, hand her over!
You got the money.
You win.
Vincent!
Over a janitor.
You piss away 14 years of
friendship over an old man janitor?
We're not killers.
Well, maybe not then.
None of this has anything
to do with my daughter.
But it does, Will.
Because you truly
love Alison.
And in that single act
of betrayal eight years ago,
you destroyed the only
thing I ever truly loved.
Me.
No! No!
Daddy!
[Alison calling
from trunk]
(Alison)
No!
Get me outta here!
(Alison)
Help!
Daddy,
get me outta here!
Help!
(screaming)
[screams]
[whimpers]
[choking, fighting,
yelling, groaning]
[yells]
[Alison coughing]
I've gotcha.
[yells]
[screams in agony]
Oh, my God,
you're bleeding.
I don't know what to do.
What do I do?
No, no, no.
Don't die.
Somebody help us!
No, no, no.
You can't die.
[groaning]
Just stay with me.
They're coming.
Just hang in there.
Over here! Over here!
(Harland)
There.
You're gonna be okay.
Oh, Jesus.
No, no, no. He can't die.
You've gotta save him.
Come on, let's
get him outta here.
[yells in pain]
Are you gonna
send him back to jail?
Now, why would I do that?
I'm sure that Vincent
Kinsey stole that gold.
Take her up.
Alison.
I'm here, Dad.
HI, Dad.
I'll call a Hazmat team.
- Why?
- You're cooking again.
Wake me up
if something happens.
Don't you ever
clean your truck?
Honey? Can you flip the
shrimp in three minutes?
- Let go of the control, Dad. I got it.
- Letting go.
Definitely more
than $300,000.
And the house can use
a new roof, kitchen...
He's got it. He's got that
missing ten pounds of gold.
That's what they're talking
about, somethin' enough for ya?
Yeah, that is something.
- Well, if you fence that gold...
- Oh, I know. I know. They'll nail me.
I can't see his lips.
- I'm gonna disappear it in the mud.
- Okay.
Here.
(Fletcher)
He's not gonna throw it.
He just might, and if he
does, you ain't got jack.
- Don't throw it.
- Throw it.
- (Fletcher) Don't do it.
- (Harland) Do it.
- Throw it.
- Don't do it.
- Do it. Throw it. Throw it.
- Don't do it. No, no, no.
Do it.
Sure, yeah,
keep it, sell it.
Get rich.
And then
go back to jail.
Okay. All right.
It's going in.
Oh, thank you, Will.
I'll return to my life now.