[ Siren Wailing ]
[ lndistinct Police Radio ]
[ Girl ] People once believed
that when someone dies...
a crow carries their soul
to the land of the dead.
But sometimes,
something so bad happens...
that a terrible sadness is carried
with it and the soul can't rest.
Then sometimes,
just sometimes...
the crow can bring that soul back
to put the wrong things right.
- [ Camera Shutter Clicking ]
- [ Siren Wailing ]
[ Man ] Over here.
There's a piece of glass.
Hey, Sarge!
Yeah?
Shelly Webster and Eric Draven.
Wedding was tomorrow night.
Who the fuck gets married
on Halloween anyhow?
Nobody.
- Sir, we gotta move her.
- Do it.
All right, guys,
let's do it.
Devil's fuckin' Night.
What's the count so far?
143 fires.
- They're slacking off from last year.
- Three hours to go.
- Maybe they're just slow starters.
- Coming through!
[ Cawing ]
[ Man ] You guys can't come in here
and take her away like this.
There are procedures. You should have
cleared this with me first.
- ls this the victim?
- No, it's Amelia Earhart.
- We found her, and you missed it.
- l don't care what her name is.
l didn't give the order to move her.
Jesus, Albrecht.
l can see why they took away
your gold shield.
Yeah, l wasn't a big enough asshole.
Come on. Let's go.
- [ Cawing ]
- All right, clear out.
- Shelly?
- Stand back, kid.
- Where's Eric?
- Just don't worry about him.
Tell him to take care
of Sarah.
Look, l will.
You just, uh, lie back. Come on.
[ Gasping, Panting ]
- You Sarah?
- Yeah.
Yeah, look. Your sister,
she's gonna be okay.
She's not my sister.
Shelly just takes care of me.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- She's my friend.
Her and Eric.
You lied to her about Eric.
l had to.
And you're lying
to me about Shelly.
She's gonna die,
isn't she?
Hey, uh--
Now, come on.
Come on. lt's okay.
She's gonna be fine.
[ Sarah ] A building gets torched.
All that is left is ashes.
l used to think that was true
about everything...
families, friends, feelings.
But now l know that sometimes,
if love proves real...
two people who are meant to be together,
nothing can keep them apart.
Later.
- [ Thunder Rumbling ]
- [ Crow Cawing ]
[ Caws ]
What are you,
like the night watchman?
[ Car Horn Honking ]
You know, what this place
needs is a...
good natural catastrophe.
- Earthquake, tornado, you know.
- No, no, no, no.
Mickey, come on, man. You got to put
the mustard underneath first.
Maybe a flood like in the Bible.
Hey, hey, let me do it.
There we go. All right.
How about some onions?
Come on, man.
Don't cheap out on me.
- Lots of onions.
- All right, here you go.
Hey, all right.
Now we're talkin'.
Hey, it's the Sarah monster.
- How do you steer that on a wet street?
- Pure talent. Hi.
Now, Sarah, she's a genuine hot dogger.
You hungry?
- You buyin'?
- l'm buyin'.
- No onions though, okay?
- No onions?
- They make you fart big time.
- [ Chuckling ]
[ Man ] You know, Lake Erie
actually caught on fire once...
from all the crap
floating around in it.
l wish l could have seen that.
[ Whistling ]
[ Shouting, Crashing ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Creaking ]
- [ Cawing ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Laughing ]
[ All Shouting ]
Fire it up! Yeah!
[ Gasping, Panting ]
[ Engine Revving,
Tires Screeching ]
[ Dog Barking ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- ** [ Rock And Roll ]
- All right, we busted their machines!
- Shit!
[ Cawing ]
Oh, oh, shit, guys.
T-bird, cop car, cop car.
[ Tires Screeching ]
Bad people out
on the street tonight.
[ Beeping ]
- Damn it!
- What was that?
- You wait right here.
- Be careful.
- Mickey, call it in for me!
- [ Woman Shouting ]
[ Cawing ]
[ Cawing, Wings Fluttering ]
[ Door Creaking ]
- [ Meowing ]
- Gabriel!
[ Screeching ]
[ Pounding ]
- Eric? [ Gasping ]
- Department of Housing!
Code violations?
Safety hazards?
Place looks fine to me.
Let's redecorate.
''Abash, the devil stood...
and felt how awful
goodness is.
Saw virtue in her shape, how lovely.''
lt's pornography.
- Virtue?
- [ Gasping, Screaming ]
- [ Eric ] Shelly?
- [ Shelly Sobbing ]
- [ Shelly ] No! Eric!
- [ Man ] See ya!
No, no, no, me first.
Please.
- Shelly.
- Eric!
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Cawing ]
- Hey, that's good.
- [ Man ] That's good.
[ Gulping, Coughing ]
See if you can top that, man.
Can you top that?
Look at that.
Here's to Devil's Night,
my new favorite holiday.
You go over there
and talk to your pals--
- [ Sizzling ]
- You sick fuck.
Are you out of
your motherfuckin' mind, man?
Look at that!
Pussies drink last, man.
- Fuck you, Tin Tin.
- Hey.
Shit ain't
even loaded, man.
This one is.
Which of you Motor City
motherfuckers...
wants to bet me
this one isn't?
Hey, fire it up!
Fire it up!
- Fire it up!
Fire it up! Fire it up!
Here's your shooters.
- Put your guns away, huh, guys?
- How ya doin'?
Pussycat.
[ Crying ]
- Boo.
- [ Laughing ]
[ Laughing ]
- l love you.
- Say that again.
l love you.
- Oh, boy.
- [ Laughing ]
Restaurant.
[ Laughing ]
- [ Sarah ] Wow, you look great.
- [ Shelly ] Ta-da!
- Yeah!
- [ Laughing ]
- Come here! [ Laughing ]
- No, no, no!
* ''Just paint your face''
The shadows smile *
* Slipping me away from you *
* lt doesn't matter how you hide *
* We find you if we're wanting to *
* So slide back down
and close your eyes *
* Sleep a while
you must be tired *
* But every night l burn *
* Screaming the animal scream *
* Every night l burn *
* Dreaming the crow-black dream *
* Dreaming the crow-black dream **
Couple more rings.
That's 24k.
24k, huh? lt's 18k.
lt's crap. lt's probably fake.
Leather purse. Leather.
Geez. Oh, what is this, Tin Tin?
A blood stain
that's on here?
l'll give you 50 bucks.
And l hate charities.
Now, you,
take it or leave it.
Right there for ya.
Decisions, decisions.
- You cheap ass, chrome dome...
- [ Siren Wailing ]
...child molestin',
saprophyte motherfucker.
Close the gate
when you go out!
Oh, l close this up
for you real good, massa.
- Fuck you.
- [ Laughing ]
Yeah, sit on it and twirl,
you dirty scum.
Lucky l didn't stab
your fat ass.
* Someone take these dreams away *
* That point me to another day *
* Peculiar personalities *
* The stretch of true realities *
* They keep calling me *
* Keep on calling me *
* They keep calling me **
[ Cawing ]
[ Caws ]
- [ Cawing ]
- [ Laughing ]
[ Laughing ]
What the fuck you all painted
up for, crackhead, huh?
Halloween ain't till manana.
Come on.
[ Groaning, Coughing ]
[ Shouting ]
Fuck, you murderer!
l ain't murdered nobody, man!
l don't even fucking know you!
- Man, what the fuck you want, man?
- l want you to tell me a story.
A man and a woman
in a loft a year ago.
- You're out of your fucking mind--
- Listen!
l'm sure you'll remember.
You killed them... on Halloween.
Yeah, yeah, Halloween, yeah.
Some dude, some bitch, whatever, man.
- Her name was Shelly.
- [ Laughing ]
You cut her.
You raped her.
Shelly, yeah, yeah. l shanked
her pink ass and she loved it!
Murderer? Murderer? Let me tell you
about murder. lt's fun!
lt's easy.
You gonna learn all about it.
[ Laughing ]
l'd like you to meet
two buddies of mine.
We never miss.
Try harder.
- Try again!
- Aaah!
Victims.
Aren't we all?
** [ Rock ]
* Sometimes it rains inside my head *
* When the words run dry *
* The walls are breathing *
- Look at this mess!
What's the world comin' to?
- lt's a mess.
* No, they don't have to take you *
l got to go upstairs.
Report from the front.
* No, they don't have
to take you away *
Get out of my way,
you worms!
Give me some of that
over there!
Why don't you ladies come by later?
Check me out.
Hey, guess what?
Arcade Games fell down, went boom.
- Boom.
- Can you imagine that? lt's tragic.
Gather your soldiers.
You're on for tomorrow night. No sweat.
- ls the man in?
- He's taking a meeting.
[ Water Running ]
You're thinking
about the past.
Dad gave me this.
Fifth birthday.
He said childhood's over
the moment you know you're gonna die.
ls she asleep?
l think we broke her.
l love her eyes.
Pretty.
* No, they don't have
to take you away **
[ Car Horn Honking ]
[ Man ] Hey, kid,
get the hell outta the road!
* l don't hate them *
* But l know them *
* l don't want them hangin' 'round *
* l won't roll my bones **
- [ Clearing Throat ]
- l told you to stay out of here.
So l guess you're not gonna be home
till a lot later, huh, Darla?
She's busy. Go play with your dolls
or something, okay?
l don't have any dolls.
Get some food, huh?
Somebody already bought me dinner.
The police.
- ''Somebody already bought me dinner.
The police.''
- [ Laughing ]
Thirty, forty dollars.
Who the fuck is this now?
Hey! Piss off!
We're closed!
- Cerrado!
- [ Pounding ]
Sleep it off somewhere else, dusthead,
unless you want to get mutilated.
[ Muttering ]
Goddamn creatures of the night,
they never learn.
Hey! Hey!
- [ Cawing ]
- [ Screams ]
''Suddenly l heard
a tapping, as if someone...
gently rapping,
rapping at my chamber door.''
What are you talking about?
You heard me rapping, right?
You're trespassing,
and you owe me a fuckin' new door!
l'm looking for something
in an engagement ring.
Gold.
You're looking for a coroner,
shit-for-brains.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit on me!
Shit on me.
Shit on me!
- Aaah!
- Mr. Gideon.
You're not paying attention.
No! [ Screaming ]
l repeat, a gold
engagement ring, yes?
lt was pawned here a year ago
by a customer of yours named Tin Tin.
He confided in me
before he ran out of breath.
[ Helicopter Departing ]
Who's this sack of shit?
That's Tin Tin, one of
T-bird's little helpers.
l think you can rule out
accidental death.
Don't any of your street demons
have real grown-up names?
This could be a turf hit, but it doesn't
look like your usual gang crap.
Come on, Albrecht, spare me.
You're a beat cop now, so be a beat cop.
l'm suppose to thank you
for that, right?
Word to the wise:
Watch your fuckin' mouth.
What the hell
do you call that?
l call it blood, detective.
l suppose you'll write it up
as graffiti.
You can leave
my crime scene now, okay?
[ Helicopter Approaching ]
- Warmer?
- What are you doing?
- Don't you know this game?
- What game?
Okay, the rings!
l'll tell you about the rings!
They're in that metal box!
lt's under the shelf there!
Take the fucking rings!
Choke on them, you son of a bitch!
- Look, it goes to the attic.
- Okay.
No, no.
No, no, no.
Oh, it's beautiful.
l don't believe it.
Shelly.
l love you.
[ Groaning ]
- You have one chance to live.
- Take anything you want.
- Thank you.
- Take anything!
Now you're going to tell me
where to find...
the rest of Tin Tin's
little party pals.
The Pit. They all
hang out at The Pit.
T-birds's little potato-heads hang out
there. Funboy lives there upstairs.
- Funboy.
- Oh, baby, oh.
- A whole jolly club...
- Please!
- with jolly pirate nicknames!
- Stop! Please!
- Jesus Christ in a taxicab!
- Hold still!
Each one of these is a life...
a life you helped destroy.
l'm begging you.
Don't kill me.
l'm not gonna kill you.
Your job will be to tell the rest
of them that death is coming for them...
tonight.
Tell them Eric Draven
sends his regards.
You walk outta here,
they're gonna erase your sorry ass.
You're nothing but street grease,
you motherfucker!
ls that gasoline l smell?
No, man, no!
No!
[ Screaming ]
lt's on the house, kiddo,
you know that.
One root beer.
[ Bartender ] l can't do anything.
Your mom... technically,
she's off right now.
Yeah, way off.
[ Tires Screeching, Door Opening ]
Police! Don't move!
l said, ''Don't move!''
l thought the police
always said, ''Freeze!''
l am the police and l say don't move,
Snow White. You move, you're dead.
And l say l'm dead and l move.
Not one more step.
l'm serious.
Then shoot, if you will,
Officer Albrecht.
What are you, nuts?
Walking into a gun?
You high?
- You don't remember me?
- What are you talking about?
How about Shelly?
Do you remember Shelly Webster?
Shelly Webster's dead, my friend.
l want you to move over to the curb,
nice and easy. Move it!
Okay, we're gonna
wait here for backup.
- lt's gettin' too weird for me.
- Oh, it gets better.
Do you know someone named T-bird?
He had a friend who shouldn't have
played with knives. Like the coat?
You're the guy
that murdered Tin Tin.
- [ Looter ] Check it out.
- He was already dead.
- [ Glass Shattering ]
- He died a year ago.
The moment he touched her.
They're all dead.
They just don't know it yet.
Get away from there!
Cops!
Get outta here!
- [ Woman Laughing ]
- [ Looter ] Leave it, run!
- Oh, great, great.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
Guy shows up looking like
a mime from hell...
and you lose him
right out in the open.
Well, at least he didn't do that walking
against the wind shit. l hate that.
Little early
for Devil's Night.
You are very restless.
Just wish l was a little
hungry again, that's all.
- Be careful of what you ask for.
- Yeah, l may get it, l know.
[ Sizzling ]
** [ Rock And Roll, lndistinct ]
There are energies
aligning against you.
Seeing is believing,
isn't it?
[ Door Opening, Closing ]
Mmm, yummy.
Gideon's pawnshop just burned down
to the foundation.
Nobody cleared
this little event with me.
l didn't have nothing
to do with that.
[ Man ] You must be
awfully disappointed.
l got trouble.
One of my crew got himself perished.
- Yeah, who might that be?
- Tin Tin.
Somebody stuck his blades in all his
major organs in alphabetical order.
Gentlemen, by all means,
l think we ought to have...
an introspective moment of silence
for poor, old Tin Tin.
You're working for me
tomorrow night, right?
- Whatever you say, l can do.
- Good.
That's very reassuring.
l still ain't heard
why Gideon's burned down.
ls that a natural catastrophe
or act of God or something?
Call it my need to know.
[ Sighing ]
[ Honking, Tires Screeching ]
Let go, you creep!
- Nah.
- [ Laughing ]
You didn't even slow down,
you dickhead!
He couldn't have stopped.
He was a buttface.
l could have made it.
What are you supposed to be,
a clown or something?
Sometimes.
lt's more like surfing than skating.
l wish the rain would stop, just once.
- lt can't rain all the time.
- Eric?
[ Phone Ringing ]
Don't thank me.
Are we fighting the good fight?
Double homicide a year ago.
No convictions.
Annie... look at that.
''We, the undersigned tenants of
1929 Caulderon Court Apartments--''
What is this, a petition?
Big ''kick me'' sign for a very nice girl
who found herself a cause.
- The cause got her killed.
- She was fighting tenant eviction
in that neighborhood?
Shelly Webster and her nice
rock-and-roll boyfriend, Eric Draven.
The last time you snooped around a case
is when you got put back on the beat.
- l know. Torres keeps reminding me.
- l bet he does.
You're going to wind up
working a school crosswalk.
l'm cool.
You didn't get that file from me, okay?
And don't tell me you owe me one.
Ah, l owe you one!
Yeah, right.
Damn.
** [ Rock And Roll ]
Tomorrow night
we can get high...
and watch this whole fucking city
burn from that window.
- * l am the park *
- [ Caws ]
* l am glow *
* ln the motherfuckin' dark *
* l am shocked *
* And l see *
* l don't want to believe *
* No more *
- There's a big fuckin' bird over there.
- * No more **
- Huh?
- [ Cawing ]
- lt's a squab.
- [ Laughing ]
Come here, bird.
Hey, bird.
Bird. B-B-Birdie.
Here, birdie, birdie.
Come here, birdie,
birdie, birdie.
Birdie? Hey, birdie?
Here, Funboy.
What the fuck?
[ Strumming Guitar ]
No, man! Don't do that! You nearly
gave me a fucking heart attack!
Look at him.
[ Funboy ] Don't sweat it.
lt's time for you to take
your bird and leave, freako.
Take your shot, Funboy.
You got me dead bang.
You are seriously fucked up.
Did you look in the mirror?
You need professional help.
- [ Groaning ]
- Bingo!
He shoots! He scores!
- [ Cawing ]
- [ Laughing ]
[ Cheering, Laughing ]
- Jesus Christ!
- Jesus Christ?
Stop me if you heard this one.
Jesus Christ
walks into a hotel.
[ Whimpering ]
Ow.
He hands the innkeeper
three nails and he asks...
Don't you ever fuckin' die?
''Can you put me up for the night?''
[ Groaning ]
- Does that hurt?
- Fuck. Does it-- Fuck, does it hurt?
Oh, God.
Look what you've done
to my sheets.
[ Gun Uncocking ]
[ Crying ]
[ Sobbing ]
l've got a gun
in my pocket.
You're happy to see me,
aren't you?
Stay away!
Stay away from me!
[ Screaming ]
Look.
Mother is the name for God
on the lips and hearts of all children.
Do you understand?
Morphine is bad for you.
Your daughter is out there
on the streets waiting for you.
lf l wanted ice,
l would have asked for ice!
Now fill it up!
Fill it up yourself, macho man.
l really need this.
All right.
You burn yourself
playing with matches?
- Fuck off.
- You have an appointment.
- Well, shit on me.
- Drink up.
This is a first.
Do l bow or do l curtsy?
Get my friend here
a glass of blood.
Oh! Hey, hey, hon!
Hey, good night, Darla.
- You stay put right there.
- [ Groaning ]
Get away, steamhead.
[ Groaning ]
Shh.
[ Man On Radio ] As you can see, l'm
on the corner of 27th and Washington...
- [ Door Squeaking ]
- the site of last year's biggest
Devil's Night conflagration.
lt was exactly one year ago
that the building you see...
across the street from me
was totally demolished by fire.
The fire that was fought
by seven fire companies...
but lost the lives
of two fire fighters.
ln fact, if it weren't for the constant
surveillance by the local police--
Freeze!
Jesus. Don't ever do that, man.
[ Whispering ] Fuck.
Good likeness.
l saw your body, man.
You died. You got buried.
You still have your hat on.
l gotta sit down.
Shi--
[ Albrecht ] Holy Shit.
Say...
are you some kind of... ghost?
Boo!
l don't know what l am. l need you
to tell me what happened to us.
You took a six-story swan dive
out of a window.
She, ah, was beaten and raped.
Died at the hospital.
Hey, you asked, man.
Come on. Read the file.
Shelly Webster held on
for 30 hours in intensive care.
Her body finally just gave it up.
l saw it.
l couldn't do jack for her.
- Hey.
- Don't touch me!
- [ Sobbing ]
- Hey.
You okay?
l saw her.
l saw her
through your eyes.
You stayed with her
the whole time.
Yeah, well, you got to
understand something, all right?
l was hoping
she'd come out of it, you know.
Give me something
l could work with.
Yeah.
Look, l--
Why didn't you do
something about it?
You think any people in that building,
even the ones who signed the petition...
would talk after
what happened to you?
l kept asking
questions and...
finally got busted for sticking
my nose where it wasn't wanted.
This your wife?
Yeah, we, uh-- Well, not anymore,
we're getting a divorce.
lt's funny.
Little things used to mean
so much to Shelly.
l used to think
they were kind of trivial.
Believe me,
nothing is trivial.
You shouldn't smoke these.
They'll kill you.
You going to vanish
into thin air again?
l thought l'd use
your front door.
Look, man, l'm sorry as hell for what
happened to you and your girlfriend.
Yeah.
- [ Door Opening, Closing ]
- [ Whispering ] Yeah.
[ Gideon ] l got stabbed!
l shot the son of a bitch!
l watched the bullet hole
close by itself.
And then my business
gets blown up real good.
- Other than that, my day sucked.
- Yeah.
l saw him too.
He had a guitar.
He winked at me before he jumped out
a fourth-floor window like he had wings.
He winked at ya?
Musicians.
- What else did you see?
- So far l haven't heard...
shit about what you're going to do
about all this crap!
What do l get? My livelihood
got flushed and went swirling.
You ain't lost everything.
Yeah, and maybe you're not
such a big shot either! Ow! Jesus!
Fair enough. Catch.
Aah! Jesus.
Say hello to the last fellow
who wouldn't cooperate with me.
What're you tellin' me,
this thing is real?
All the power in the world
resides in the eyes, fella.
Sometimes they're more useful
than the people who bear them.
You're directly out of
your fucking mind! You know that!
Yeah.
Eyes see. lt's one of the most important
things l learned from my sister.
Sister? She's supposed to be
your sister? [ Laughing ]
My father's daughter.
That's right.
What's the matter,
you don't see the resemblance?
Now, let's take it
from the top, friend.
With a lot of detail.
What do you say?
He had a bird with him.
Nearly pecked my face off.
He told me to tell T-bird
that death was on its way.
Whatever the fuck that means.
Draven. He said his name
was Eric Draven.
Want to relax
that thing now?
This bird man, he just happened
to let you live, huh?
You sure you ain't making all this up
just to save your own ass?
l ain't makin' all this up.
l ain't twisted
like you two fucks.
All right.
A boy and his bird.
Awful touching.
Yeah. [ Laughing ]
For fuck's sake, die, will ya?
Give me that thing.
Thanks.
Funboy said he saw
a black bird too.
A big one.
Then he choked to death
on his own blood.
l'll have the janitor
come on up.
[ Purring ]
** [ Electric Guitar ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
- ** [ Rock Playing ]
- [ Crow Caws ]
You again.
You lost or hungry?
- Hi.
- [ Caws ]
* lt can't rain all the time *
[ Skipping ]
* Can't rain all the time *
[ T-bird ] l don't know how many times l
gotta tell you. We're in this together!
One part falls, it all falls!
- You know how long it took us
to put this together?
- Yeah, a long time.
That piece of ratshit made Tin Tin
into a fuckin' voodoo doll!
Tin Tin was a dick.
Tin Tin.
Sheesh.
Fire it up! Fire it up!
Fire it up!
No Funboy.
Probably still...
bangin' away on Darla.
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Whistles ]
Smokes and road beers.
Be quick.
l'm on it.
[ Man Talking On Phone ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Cawing ]
What the fuck are
you supposed to be, man?
- [ Cawing ]
- l'm your passenger.
Drive.
[ Motor Starts ]
What's all this
happy horseshit?
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- Hey, T-bird! T-bird!
- [ Horn Honking ]
- [ Screams ]
[ Brakes Screeching ]
- Oh, shit!
- What the fuck's the matter with you?
Stupid asshair!
You hit my car!
[ Groaning ]
What do you want, man?
Money? Drugs? l got it.
We could use you.
You did Tin Tin.
- This is business, right?
- [ Gun Cocks ] Faster.
You got that cream stuff?
l hate this.
They can't even call it cream legally.
- What in the crap--
- [ Tires Screech, Siren Wails ]
[ Screaming ]
Oh, look. Makin' us popular.
When they flash us like that,
they ain't friends.
[ Siren Wailing ]
This is Vehicle 48. We got us
a big, old, red hot rod.
Turn.
You got something personal, amigo,
we can work it out.
- Right? Huh?
- [ Crow Cawing ]
[ Groans ]
Damn! Dead end!
[ Cawing ]
- [ Man ] Look out!
- [ Woman Screams ]
Oh, my God!
Get outta the way!
- [ Engine Rattling ]
- Holy shit! Goddamn foreign cars!
[ Siren Wailing ]
Shit! Shit!
Oh, l hate this.
This ain't good.
T-bird!
l got you, man!
- Shit!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Groaning, Car Door Chiming ]
[ T-bird ] Remember?
Yeah, l remember everything.
But l don't know what--
What? Huh? What?
What are you talkin' about?
No, no, no, no, no.
You mean that place downtown?
Yeah, l remember her.
We needed to put some fear
into that little lady.
She wasn't going along
with our tenant relocation program.
And her idiot boyfriend shows up
and turns a simple sweep-and-clear...
into a total cluster fuck!
Who gives a shit?
lt's ancient history!
Why? What do you want?
What is it? What?
Speak to me. Speak!
Did you send us
these complaints?
Come here!
''Abashed the devil stood.''
Does it get you sweaty?
l know you. l know you.
l knew l knew you.
But you ain't you.
You can't be you. We put you through
the window. There ain't no coming back.
This is the really real world.
There ain't no coming back.
We killed you dead.
[ Grunting, Muttering ]
T-bird--
There ain't no coming back!
- T-bird.
- [ T-bird Panting ]
- [ Engine Revs ]
- ''Abashed the devil stood...
and felt how awful goodness is.''
''And felt how awful goodness is.''
[ Tires Squealing ]
[ Gasping ]
T-bird. T-bird.
[ Crow Caws ]
[ Woman ] This is the 7:00 a.m. edition
of Action News.
For over a decade,
the night before Halloween...
has had a darker and deadlier nickname
in the inner city, ''Devil's Night''...
the name given to what has become
an annual plague of arson.
Last year over 200 blazes were reported,
and 11 people lost their lives.
Tonight may become the biggest
and deadliest Devil's Night ever.
The mayor has firefighters
from all surrounding counties--
Do you like them up or over?
l can't remember.
What are you doing?
l don't even like eggs.
- Wait, you loved eggs.
- Yeah, when l was five.
So what do you want now?
Black coffee and cigarettes?
So what did you take
to become mother of the year?
Oh, it wasn't drugs.
Someone kind of woke me up.
- Who?
- Oh, it was nuts.
You're acting weird. Did you win
the lottery or something, Darla?
Oh, forget it. l never was
too good at this mommy shit.
Over easy.
l like 'em
over easy... Mom.
Hey, Albrecht.
[ Sighs ]
This is the third hit
in your hood in 24 hours.
We just fished this out of the river.
He's fused to his own car.
- We're gonna have to l.D. his teeth.
- His name is T-bird.
Arson was his specialty.
Looks like he zigged
when he should have zagged.
- Case closed.
- Bull-fuckin'-shit.
Come here.
You're holding out on me.
l got a goddamn vigilante killer
knocking off scumbags left and right...
and you're covering up
for somebody.
Who's the cartoon character
in the painted face?
- You're the detective. You tell me.
- Okay.
Gideon's blows all to hell and you're
having a chitchat with some weirdo...
who winds up in T-bird's car
when it zigs instead of zags.
Then you steal one of
my case files from homicide...
and you're saying this is
just a fuckin' automobile accident?
- Come on!
- Yeah. Good speech though.
l didn't want to interrupt you.
lt sounded good.
You gotta write that shit down.
All right, smart-ass.
The captain's got a little
love note waiting for you.
- Welcome to the first day
of the rest of your suspension.
- Suspension?
- For what?
- Misconduct.
[ Dials Phone ]
Yeah, give me the lab.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Grunting ]
** [ Electric Guitar ]
[ Shelly ] One for sorrow,
two for joy...
- Come here.
- ...three for a girl, four for a boy.
Dancing--
[ Paper Ripping ]
Eric?
[ Rain Falling ]
[ Sighs ] Man, Sarah,
you're going crazy.
- Gabriel.
- [ Meows ]
l thought you were dead.
You're not dead, are you?
l knew it was you.
Even with the makeup.
l remembered your song.
You said,
''Can't rain all the time.''
That is from your song, right?
- [ Cawing ]
- Come on, Eric. l know you're here.
l miss you...
and Shelly.
Get so lonely
all by myself.
The hell with you.
l thought you cared.
Sarah, l do care.
That's him.
That's him!
But he looked different. He was painted
up white like some kind of dead whore.
l seen him. T-bird sent me in
for some road beers, right?
Then he took him away.
But l chased him down.
And he flash fried T-bird
to his fuckin' car!
Aw, T-bird!
Here's to you, buddy.
Maybe we oughta just videotape this.
Play it back in slow motion.
- Fire it up! Fire it up!
- You see the grave?
- Empty.
- Fire it--
Grave?
What grave?
What about
my fuckin' grave?
- [ Screams ]
- Three out of four.
He's working his way back
to this speed freak right here.
lt's not fair.
lt's Funboy's fault.
That boy was out of control.
T-bird, he came in, he says...
[ Whistles ]
...''Waste them both.'' And now
this ghost gonna kill my ass next!
[ Groaning ]
This ghost gonna
kill my ass next.
- This ghost gonna kill--
- Hey.
That ain't no ghost.
- They have all arrived.
- Watch him.
We might need him.
Ghost gonna kill my--
He like his plain
or with onions?
Fine.
Don't talk to me.
When someone's dead,
they can't come back, can they?
That's what l thought.
Are you referring
to anyone in particular?
You'll just think
l'm nuts.
Yeah, well, then maybe
they'll have to lock us both up.
- You see him too?
- l saw somebody.
Maybe it was
your fairy godfather.
Eric didn't come back for me.
He can't be my friend anymore
because l'm alive.
You want a friend
to walk you home?
** [ Electric Guitar ]
- [ Screaming ]
- * l am the wicked
l am the wave of the future *
[ Woman ] * Being crucified *
* You things, things
things of the flesh *
* Do it slow *
* Down avenues ''cut me'' *
* Lust my eyes *
* Licking lips encouraging
Mr. Careworn *
* To gaze upon the screen bask on *
* After the flesh **
[ Whimpering ]
Boys.
lt seems our friend T-bird won't be
joining us this evening...
on account of
a slight case of death.
- [ Men Chuckling ]
- You wanna sit down?
- [ Groaning ]
- Well, well, well.
Devil's Night is
upon us again.
l thought we'd throw
a little party...
start a bunch of fires,
make a little profit.
l like the pretty lights.
[ Laughing ]
Problem is, it's all been done before.
You see what l'm saying?
- That's no reason to quit.
- Wrong. Best reason to quit.
Only reason to quit.
A man has an idea.
The idea attracts others...
like-minded.
The idea expands.
The idea becomes
an institution.
What was the idea?
See, that's what's
been bothering me, boys.
But l'll tell ya, when l used
to think about the idea itself...
it'd put a big old smile on my face.
You see, gentlemen...
greed is for amateurs.
Disorder, chaos, anarchy...
now that's fun!
- What about Devil's Night?
- What about it?
l started the first fires
in this goddamn city.
Before l knew it, every charlatan
and shitheel was imitating me.
Do you know
what they got now?
Devil's Night greeting cards.
lsn't that precious?
Yeah.
The idea has become
the institution, boys.
Time to move along.
You don't want us to do
''Light My Fire'' time for the whole city?
No.
No, l want you to set
a fire so goddamn big...
the gods will notice us again.
That's what l'm saying.
l want all of you boys to be able
to look me straight in the eye...
one more time and say,
''Are we having fun or what?''
- Hey, you! What's your name?
- Huh?
Skank!
You don't feel that?
- l feel like a little worm
on a big fuckin' hook.
- [ All Laughing ]
''l feel like a little worm
on a big fuckin' hook.''
Well, boy, your mama
must be damn proud of you!
- [ Crow Caws ]
- [ Gasps ]
How the hell did
that thing get in here?
- Gentlemen.
- [ Skank Screams ]
[ Skank Whimpering ] Let me go!
Let me go! l gotta go!
You're him, huh?
The avenger.
The killer of killers.
- Nice outfit.
- [ Whimpering ]
l'm not sure
about the face though.
l just want him.
- [ Whimpering ]
- Well, you can't have him.
Well...
l see you have
made your decision.
Now let's see you enforce it.
Aw, this is already boring the shit
out of me. Kill him!
Ooh, that had to hurt.
- [ All Laughing ]
- Well, that's that.
- [ Laughing Continues ]
- That guy was crazy.
[ Caws ]
He's gone.
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming, Gunfire ]
Get him!
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Gunfire ]
Right here! Here, help me!
He's gonna kill me!
Jesus Christ!
Hey!
You're all going to die.
[ Screaming ]
[ Man ] Get the fuck outta here!
[ Crowd Screaming ]
[ Whimpering, Gasping ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Screams ]
Guess it's not a good day
to be a bad guy, huh, Skank?
l'm not Skank.
There's Skank right there.
- Skank's dead.
- That's right.
[ Screaming ] No!
[ Whimpering ]
- [ Body Crashing ]
- What in the crap--
- Don't move!
- Hold it!
That's all she wrote!
Move and we shoot!
[ Siren Blaring ]
You are surrounded by police units.
Do not attempt to escape.
[ Gunfire Continues ]
- Stop running immediately.
- Holy shit!
...arms and legs--
Stop immediately.
Lie down, spread your arms and legs--
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- Come on! Move it!
My advice:
Next time duck.
So many cops, you'd think
they were giving away donuts.
- [ Sirens Wailing ]
- [ Brakes Screeching ]
- Shit!
- [ Door Opening ]
Oh. l knew you
were gonna do that.
Look at that out there.
The whole city oughta be
in flames by now.
Sky oughta be red.
So that, l take it,
is the late, great Eric Draven.
He has power, but it is power
you can take from him.
- l like him already.
- The crow...
is his link between
the land of the living...
and the realm of the dead.
So, kill the crow
and destroy the man.
Hmm.
l'm coming home, Shelly.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Children Laughing, Hooting ]
[ Laughing ]
You're gonna say
l shouldn't be in the cemetery...
in the middle
of the night, right?
Safest place in the world to be.
lt's 'cause everybody's dead.
l knew you'd come here.
lt's really late, Sarah.
You didn't say good-bye.
You're just gonna have
to forgive me for that.
And you're never coming back.
l gave this to Shelly once.
l think she'd like you
to have it.
This way you'll
always remember her.
l'll never take it off.
l better go sneak
back in the house.
Bye.
- [ Muffled Screaming ]
- Shh! Shh!
Shh. Take it easy, sweetheart.
[ Muffled Screaming Continues ]
Come on.
What is that? Some sort of souvenir
there from your pal?
l'll just keep it for good luck.
What do you say, hmm?
Her eyes are so innocent.
- [ Sarah ] Eric!
- [ Caws ]
Eric, help! Eric!
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Crow Caws ]
[ Crow Flapping, Caws ]
Quick impression for ya.
Caw! Caw! Bang!
Fuck, l'm dead!
Give me the girl
and l'll let you walk out of here.
[ lnhales ]
Well, well.
Why don't you just give me a minute
to think about that, huh?
[ Cawing ]
Nah. Fuck it.
[ Chuckles ]
Aw, fuck.
[ Muffled Screaming ]
Well, well, well. lt does seem to me
that our little life has undergone...
a rather significant change in the past
few minutes now. Wouldn't you agree?
[ Groaning ]
Well, for a ghost,
you bleed just fine.
- lt's still alive.
- Well, then kill it!
Bye-bye, birdie.
Ah, shit.
Well, just came by
to pay my respects...
and here you are
getting all shot up again.
- They've taken Sarah.
- How many?
Two more.
[ Groans ]
l can handle it.
Don't worry.
l'm not worried.
Look, here's the plan.
You stay in front, and when they
run out of ammo, l'll arrest 'em.
That sounds like a great plan.
There's just one problem.
Oh, shit.
You're bleeding all over the place.
l thought, you know,
you were invincible.
l was.
l'm not anymore.
[ Sighs ] Well, l guess you really will
need my help, won't you?
- Come on.
- [ Groaning ]
You take that.
- You were supposed to stay behind me.
- l think l messed up.
[ Crow Caws ]
This is all the power
you ever had.
Now it is mine.
Pity there's not more time...
- [ Gun Cocks ]
- ...for us.
[ Woman Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Sarah ] Help, Eric!
l'm scared!
Let me go!
Let her go!
You can have me.
l won't fight you.
All right.
- [ Sarah Screams ]
- No!
[ Gasping, Groaning ]
[ Crow Caws ]
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Gasping ]
- [ Thunderclap ]
- [ Screams ]
[ Swords Clanking ]
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Roof Collapsing ]
Eric!
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Sarah?
- Look out!
- [ Panting ]
- Eric!
You know,
my daddy used to say...
''Every man's got a devil...
and you can't rest
till you find him.''
What happened back there
with you and your girlfriend--
l cleared that building.
Hell, nothing in this town
happens without my say-so.
So l'm sorry if l spoiled
your wedding plans, friend.
But if it's any consolation
to you...
you have put
a smile on my face.
You got a lot
of spirit, son.
[ Unsheathes Knife ]
l am going to miss you.
l have something
to give you.
l don't want it anymore.
Thirty hours of pain!
- All at once!
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Steady Tone ]
- All for you.
[ Gasping ]
Yeah.
Go help him.
Are you alive?
[ Groans ]
God, l need a cigarette.
Everybody else dead?
You helped me.
What you kept in here
saved me.
- Thanks.
- Don't mention it.
l've been meaning
to come to church anyway.
Oh, yuck.
[ Spits ]
l'm quitting as of now...
if l live.
Stay with him
until help comes.
He'll be okay, right?
Eric?
[ Sighs ]
He does that a lot.
[ Distant Sirens Approaching ]
[ Gasping, Groaning ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
Shelly.
- All right, what's going on in there?
- Multiple homicides.
At least it stopped raining, huh?
- lt can't rain all the time.
- No, l don't believe it.
- This nightmare your fault, Albrecht?
- Look, you go on home.
- l'm okay.
- Okay.
- Want to tell me what's going on?
- Your vigilante's up on the roof.
You missed it.
Get him outta here!
[ Chuckling ]
Thanks.
[ Sarah ] lf the people we love
are stolen from us...
the way to have them live on
is to never stop loving them.
Buildings burn, people die,
but real love is forever.
* We walk the narrow path *
* Beneath the smoking skies *
* Sometimes barely
tell the difference *
* Between darkness and light *
* Do we have faith *
* ln what we believe *
* The truest test *
* ls when we cannot *
* When we cannot see *
* l hear pounding feet in the *
* ln the streets below and the *
* And the women cried and the *
* And the children know that there's *
* There's something wrong *
* lt's hard to believe that love *
* Will prevail *
* Oh, it won't rain all the time *
* The sky won't fall forever *
* And though the night seems long *
* Your tears won't fall *
* Forever *
* Oh *
* When l'm lonely *
* l lie awake at night *
* And l wish you were here *
* l miss you *
* Can you tell me *
* ls there something more
to believe in *
* Or is this all there is *
* And the pounding feet in the *
* ln the streets below and a *
* And a window breaks and a *
* And a woman falls and there's *
* There's something wrong it's *
* lt's hard to believe that love *
* Will prevail *
* lt won't rain all the time *
* The sky won't fall forever *
* And though the night seems long *
* Your tears won't fall *
* Forever *
* Last night l had a dream *
* You came into my room *
* You took me *
* lnto your arms *
* Whispering and kissing me *
* And telling me to still believe *
* Within the emptiness
of the burning cities *
* Against which we save
our darkest selves *
* Until l felt safe *
* And warm *
* l fell asleep in your arms *
* And when l awoke *
* l cried again *
* For you were gone *
* Oh, can you hear me *
* lt won't rain all the time *
* The sky won't fall forever *
* And though the night seems long *
* Your tears won't fall *
* Forever *
* lt won't rain all the time *
* The sky won't fall forever *
* And though the night seems long *
* Your tears won't fall *
* Forever **
* Drivin' faster in my car *
* Falling farther
from just what we are *
* Smoke a cigarette
and lie some more *
* These conversations kill *
* Falling faster in my car *
* Time to take her home *
* Her dizzy head
is conscience laden *
* Time to take a ride *
* lt leaves today
no conversation *
* Time to take her home *
* Her dizzy head
is conscience laden *
* Time to wait too long
to wait too long *
* Way too long **