[Whistle Blows]
Hey, what are you doing?
You're supposed to be
upstairs sleeping.
Stanley keeps waking me up.
Oh, ho, ho. I get it.
Boy, are you getting heavy.
Don't let her pull more
than her usual nonsense.
Two stories,
two glasses of water.
Jack, you're going
to miss the plane.
OK. Cricket,
you listen to me.
Go upstairs with Mrs. Wheeler now
and go to sleep.
On my business trip,
I'll get Stanley
a little brother.
Will you promise?
I promise.
Can I get you anything, sir?
No, thank you very much.
If you try and get sleep,
the flight will go faster.
I can never sleep on a plane.
Turbulence.
Pardon?
Turbulence...
Solar radiation
heats the Earth's crust,
warm air rises,
cold airs descends.
Turbulence.
I don't like that.
Oh. Well, try to sleep anyway.
[Teacup Rattles]
Dr. Ryan?
Jack, boy,
get yourself in here.
Jesus!
You look like hell.
Thank you very much, Admiral.
Want coffee?
I think I need some coffee.
I'm not going to ask you
how your flight went.
When's the last time
you got some sleep?
Oh, I don't know.
This thing's still
on London time.
Milk and sugar?
Milk and sugar.
So how's Caroline?
Last time I saw her
was at your granddad's place
in Maine, wasn't it?
She's fine.
Sends you her best.
And Sally?
She's fine.
What is she now, 3?
Ah, no, she's
a very precocious 5.
She announced to Caroline
and I the other day
that her life would be
considerably less lonely
if we were to buy her
a baby brother.
But she decided
it would be enough
if we were to
buy one for Stanley.
Who's Stanley?
Uh... Stanley's a bear.
All right.
What's important enough
to get you on a plane
in the middle of the night?
British Intelligence obtained
these pictures two days ago.
She's the Red October,
the latest typhoon class.
Big son of a bitch.
12 meters longer than
the standard typhoon.
3 meters wider.
The captain's name is Ramius.
One of yours?
Yeah. I did his bio last year.
He's taken out the lead boat
in each new sub class
for 10 years.
Fairly good
political connections.
Trained most of their
attack boat skippers.
The Russians call him
Vilnius Nastavnic...
the Vilnius schoolmaster.
What are these doors?
Those doors, sir, are the problem.
I don't know what they are.
Neither do the British.
Perhaps our friends in Murmansk
have come up with something new.
With your permission,
I'd like to show these to someone.
Do you know Skip Tyler?
Sub driver.
Was. Clipped by a drunk driver.
Lost his leg.
He's teaching at the academy,
consulting for Navy labs.
Clearance?
Top secret or better.
Margie, have a car for Dr. Ryan
downstairs in 10 minutes.
A satellite caught Red October
in Polijarny Inlet this morning.
Do you hear it?
[Beep Beep]
No.
Beaumont, at Cal Tech
we used to do this
in our sleep.
You hear it now?
Wait a minute.
Maybe.
Um...
It's buried in surface clutter?
Yes.
I should go to SAPS?
Correct, Seaman Beaumont.
Signal algorithmic
processing systems.
Give it a week,
and you'll be
teaching at Cal Tech.
So...
like Beethoven on the computer,
you have labored to produce...
a biologic.
A what?
A whale, Beaumont.
A whale...
A marine mammal
that knows a hell
of a lot more about sonar
than you do.
Kill the SAPS.
Train over to 2-6-9
and let's try it again.
If he gets to ragging
on you too bad,
ask him about Pavarotti.
We don't have time
for sea stories.
I was in the middle
of teaching Seaman Beaumont
the intricacies
of modern sonar. Now...
I ain't chief of the boat.
I'm Sheena,
Queen of the Jungle.
Cob, please.
Come on, Cob. Tell me.
OK. Fine. Go ahead.
Ahem... Seaman Jones here,
he's into music in a big way.
He figures this whole boat
is basically just his own
personal, private stereo set.
He gets this
piece of Pavarotti...
Paganini.
Whatever.
This is my story, OK?
Tell it right.
Pavarotti's a tenor.
Paganini was a composer.
OK. So he's got this music,
and he's got it out
in the water.
He's listening
on his headsets,
happy as a clam.
Then all hell breaks loose.
A slew of boats
out of San Diego...
Including one
way out at Pearl.
All of a sudden,
they start hearing...
- Pavarotti.
- Pavarotti...
coming out of their asses.
[Sonar Beeps]
What do I do?
I got it.
Conn. Sonar.
New contact, bearing 0-9-7.
Designate contact
number Sierra 3-5.
Captain, aye.
What've you got, Jones?
Distant contact,
probably submerged.
It's a wild guess,
but I'd say we hit a boomer
coming out of the barn.
Could be a missile boat
out of Polijarny.
OK. Start your track.
I'll be there in a minute.
Sonar, aye.
[Speaking Russian]
...Armageddon.
And the seventh angel
poured forth his bowl
into the air,
and a voice cried out
from heaven, saying,
'lt is done."'
A man with your responsibilities
reading about the end
of the world. Huh.
And what's this?
"I am become death,
the destroyer of worlds."
It is an ancient Hindu text
quoted by an American.
American?
Mmm.
He invented the atomic bomb,
and he was later accused
of being a Communist.
You wrote and underlined
these passages?
No.
This book belonged to my wife.
I keep it
for sentimental value.
I'm sorry, comrade Captain.
Your wife was...
a beautiful woman.
Her death was... unfortunate.
I'm only doing my job.
It is my responsibility.
How many agents did the KGB
put aboard my boat?
Your boat, Captain?
Yes.
This vessel belongs to
the people of the Soviet Union.
Besides, if the KGB or the GRU
has agents aboard,
I will be the last to know.
I suggest we open
our orders, Captain.
Certainly, comrade.
"From commander...
strategic submarine forces
red banner northern fleet."
We're to proceed north
to grid square reference 54-90
and rendezvous with
alfa submarine Konovalov.
Captain Tupolev's boat.
You know Tupolev?
I know he descends
from aristocracy
and that he was your student.
It's rumored he has
a special place
in his heart for you.
There's little room in Tupolev's heart
for anyone but Tupolev.
Having made contact,
we are to run a series of drills.
Tupolev will hunt us
while we test our ship.
Having evaluated
the operational readiness
of the caterpillar drive,
we are to return to Polijarny
on or about the 16th
of this month.
Captain, this is
an historic moment.
I'd like to make a request.
Before you proceed, comrade...
I know it's not protocol,
but would you permit me
to post our orders
and inform the crew
of our mission?
Aah!
Where I'm going...
you cannot follow.
Dr. Petrov, report
to my cabin immediately.
There's been
a dreadful accident.
Hey, buddy!
Daniel, got any more rods?
More rods!
Listen to me.
There's no cradle underneath it.
Get it over.
Relax!
Stop being an old maid.
You want to come up here
and do it yourself?
All right. Bring her up.
What? What?
Ryan!
Who let you in here?
Hey, Skip,
what, have they got you
playing with models now?
Ahh!
Damn it, Bill!
Tell them to slow down!
I'm doing it.
Calm down, will you?
It's not a model. The DSRV.
Rescue sub.
I know what it is.
What are you doing with it?
We're rigging it
with a generic docking collar
so it'll mate with
British, German...
just about anybody's sub.
We can get it
anywhere in the world
in 24 hours.
How's your back?
It's fine.
Have you got a minute?
Bigger than
a regular typhoon.
What are these doors?
You don't miss much, do you?
Those are too big
to be torpedo tubes.
Would you launch
an ICBM horizontally?
Sure. Why would you want to?
They're symmetrical.
Right down
the long axis of the sub.
How about a towed sonar array?
Nope.
Too close to the screws.
I'll be...
This...
This could be a caterpillar.
A what?
Uh, a caterpillar drive.
Magneto-hydrodynamic propulsion.
You follow?
No.
It's like a...
a jet engine for the water.
Goes in the front,
gets squirted out the back.
Only it's got no moving parts,
so it's very, very quiet.
Like how quiet?
It's doubtful our sonar
would even pick it up.
And if it did,
it would sound
like whales humping
or a seismic anomaly.
Anything but a submarine.
We messed with this
a couple of years ago.
Couldn't make it work.
They really built this?
This isn't a mock-up
or anything?
She put to sea this morning.
When I was 12,
I helped my daddy build
a bomb shelter in our basement
because some fool parked
a dozen warheads
90 miles off the
coast of Florida.
This thing could park
a couple of hundred warheads
off Washington and New York,
and no one would know
anything about it
until it was all over.
Are you all right, Captain?
Oh, yes.
It's just to die for something
as petty as slipping on tea.
You're blaming yourself, Captain.
It was an accident.
You'll feel better
when we put in.
Put in?
Well, to base, Captain.
We cannot go on without
a political officer.
Doctor, this is a combat vessel
of the Soviet Navy,
and I'm a senior combat officer.
We do not cancel operations
because of accidents.
Seaman.
Come here.
Your name?
Cook's Assistant, Loginov, sir.
Good. I want you and the doctor
to witness this.
I'm removing
the political officer's...
missile key...
carry on...
and I'm keeping it myself.
Captain, I think
we should report this
to Red Fleet Command.
I'm afraid
that's impossible, Doctor.
Our orders are
for strict radio silence.
Orders, sir.
That's all, Loginov.
Yes, sir.
This is most unnerving,
Captain.
The reason for having
two missile keys
is so that no one man...
may...
May what?
May arm the missiles.
Perhaps I should keep the key.
Thank you.
That'll be all, Doctor.
Captain, l...
When I address the crew,
then you will understand.
Yes, sir.
Petrov.
Yes, sir?
I will try to forget
your comments
when I present my report.
Thank you, sir.
Holding steady on 3-1-0.
12 knots
at about 20,000 yards.
Have you got a make on him?
Computer's chewing on it, sir.
Twin screws.
The plant noise
sounds like a typhoon.
[Computer Printer]
I'd say we got
a new boat, sir.
Tommy, I miss something
on the boards?
Sub plant hasn't said
anything about it.
Hmm.
All right.
How many typhoons
we got in the computer?
Six, sir.
OK. Call this guy
Typhoon Seven.
Start a tape on him.
See if we can work
in a little closer.
Yes, sir.
Won't he hear us?
Not if we stay in his baffles,
Seaman Beaumont.
Not if we stay in his baffles.
Come in behind his propeller,
and he's deaf as a post.
Any sonar contacts,
Mr. Kamarov?
No contacts, Captain.
The sonar is clear.
Good. Do we have any
surface contacts, Mr. Borodin?
No contacts, sir.
Scope is clear.
Good. Then it is time
I explain our orders
to the crew.
[Lntercom Sounds]
Comrades, this is your captain.
It is an honor
to speak to you today,
and I'm honored
to be sailing with you
on the maiden voyage
of our motherland's
most recent achievement.
And once more,
we play our dangerous game,
a game of chess,
against our old adversary...
the American Navy.
For 40 years,
your fathers before you
and your older brothers
played this game
and played it well.
But today,
the game is different.
We have the advantage.
It reminds me of the heady days
of Sputnik and Yuri Gagarin,
when the world trembled
at the sound of our rockets.
Well, they will tremble again
at the sound of our silence.
The order is engage
for silent drive.
Aye, sir.
Ballast control,
open outer doors.
Yes, open outer doors.
Diving command.
Engage caterpillar
and secure main engines.
Doors opening, Captain.
Comrades, our own fleet
doesn't know
our full potential.
They will do everything
possible to test us,
but they will only test
their own embarrassment.
We will leave our fleet behind.
We will pass through
the American patrols,
pass their sonar nets,
and lay off their largest city
and listen
to their rock 'n' roll
while we conduct missile drills.
Then...
And when we are finished,
the only sound they will hear
is our laughter
while we sail to Havana,
where the sun is warm
and so is the comradeship.
[Cheering]
Cryogenic plant
coming on line, Captain.
A great day, comrades.
We sail into history.
[Singing Soviet
National Anthem]
Caterpillar engaging.
Caterpillar engaging,
Captain.
What happened?
I don't know.
Full rudder left.
Navigator.
New course, 2-5-0.
Yes, new course, 2-5-0.
Steering 2-5-0.
Yes, course is 2-5-0.
[Sonar Beeps]
[Singing Soviet
National Anthem]
Sonar contact, Captain.
Port quarter.
Close aboard.
American,
Los Angeles class.
American. Captain, we...
Course 3-1-0.
Is the American
turning to follow us?
No, Captain.
The American is continuing
in his original course.
He's continuing northwest.
He can't hear us.
And the singing?
Let them sing.
What are you talking about?
Check your gear.
Running diagnostics now,
Captain.
Sonar is working, Captain.
The Russian disappeared.
One minute, he was steady
4,000 yards off the bow,
and then he was gone,
and for a second,
I thought I heard...
Heard what?
I thought I heard singing, sir.
Singing?
Yes, sir.
[Speaking Russian]
Yah, yah.
Yah, yah, yah.
[Speaking Russian]
Yah, yah.
Good morning, sir.
I hope we had a lovely evening.
Yah, yah.
A little chilly this morning.
There's a letter there
from Marko Ramius.
Ah, Marko.
[Telephone Rings]
Yes?
No. This is Dr. Ryan.
What the hell happened?
Come on.
This is no longer
a research project.
I got a line on those doors.
You know what they are?
A nearly silent
propulsion system?
How did you know that?
The captain of the sub
following her radioed in.
Thing disappeared
right in front of him,
and that's only
the half of it.
Read.
Oh! I'm sorry.
Got your I.D.?
My God, this is unbelievable.
The Kirov, three Sverdlovs,
the Kiev, the Minsk.
They've sortied
their whole bloody fleet.
That's about the size of it.
Good afternoon, Admiral.
Afternoon, Matthew.
Where are we going anyway?
Briefing for Jeffrey Pelt,
President's National
Security Adviser.
Most of the Joint Chiefs
will be there,
along with a few other people.
Who's giving the briefing?
You are.
The yeoman will
have all the slides
laid out for you.
So all you got to do...
Look.
No one understands
this material better than you.
Just give him
a rundown on the sub
and a precis of the
stuff in your hand.
He's liable to ask
some direct questions.
Give him direct answers.
Tell him what you think.
Come on.
Ahem.
Uh, gentlemen,
the last 24 hours
have seen some extraordinary
Soviet naval activity.
The first to sail
was this ship,
we believe
called the Red October
in reference to
the October Revolution of 1917.
A variant
of the typhoon class,
she's some 650 feet long
and 32,000 tons
submerged displacement...
roughly the same size
as a World War II
aircraft carrier.
We believe that these doors,
here on the bow
and again on the stern,
enclose a unique
propulsion system...
a magneto-hydrodynamic drive,
or caterpillar,
that would enable the sub
to run virtually silent.
It is possible
that this new drive system
allowed the captain,
a man named Ramius,
their senior and perhaps
most respected commander...
Do we have
his picture available?
Allowed Ramius to elude
one of our attack boats,
the Dallas, which trailed Red October
from harbor this morning.
It is also possible
that this drive system,
if operable,
could render the Red October
undetectable to
our Sosus warning nets
in the Atlantic.
Mr. Ryan, would you
characterize this
as a first-strike weapon?
Uh, that is a possibility, sir.
It is designed
to approach by stealth
and to shower its target
with multiple
independent warheads
with little or no warning
before impact.
Goddamn thing's made
to start a war.
Proceed, Mr. Ryan.
About the same time
the Dallas lost contact,
there were additional sailings
from Polijarny and from
Leningrad on the Baltic
and from the Mediterranean.
There are now
some 58 nuclear submarines
headed at high speed
into the Atlantic.
This afternoon a satellite pass
over Polijarny
found heat blooms
in the engineering plants
at the Kirov, the Minsk,
and more than 20 other
cruisers and destroyers,
indicating they were
preparing to sail.
This constitutes the bulk
of the Soviet surface fleet.
Admiral Greer,
your conclusions.
Well, sir,
the data support
no conclusions as yet.
The absence of activity
in the Pacific
suggests this could
be just an exercise.
It may have nothing to do...
Suppose it's not an exercise?
Suppose this
is the beginning
of a move against NATO?
NSA can speak for that,
Mr. Pelt.
I must emphasize the extreme
sensitivity of this information
and that it not leave the room.
Before sailing, Captain Ramius
sent a letter
to Admiral Yuri Padorin,
Chairman of the Red Fleet
northern political directorate.
That's her uncle.
Whose uncle?
Ramius' wife.
Padorin's her uncle.
Now, the contents
of the letter are unknown,
but Admiral Padorin
immediately demanded
a meeting
with Premier Chernenko,
and within minutes
of that meeting,
the Soviet fleet sailed
with orders
to find Red October
and sink her.
Sink her?
My God. They've got
a madman on their hands.
If it gets within
500 miles of the coast,
we'll have less than
two minutes' warning.
Today's the 23rd, isn't it?
What?
Is today the 23rd?
Yeah.
You son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch!
You wish to add something
to our discussion, Dr. Ryan?
Well, sir,
I was just thinking
that perhaps there's another
possibility we might consider.
Ramius might be
trying to defect.
Do you mean to suggest
that this man has come...
Proceed, Mr. Ryan.
Well...
Ramius trained most
of their officer corps,
which would put him
in a position
to select men
willing to help him.
And he's not Russian.
He's Lithuanian by birth,
raised by his paternal
grandfather, a fisherman.
And he has no children,
no ties to leave behind.
And today is
the first anniversary
of his wife's death.
Come on.
You're just an analyst.
How can you read his mind?
I know Ramius, General.
He's nearly a legend
in the submarine community.
He's been a maverick
his entire career.
I actually met him once
at an embassy dinner.
Have you ever met
Captain Ramius, General?
Admiral Hollis,
how long before Ramius
could be in a position
to fire his missiles at us?
Four days.
All right.
I'll brief the President.
That will be all, gentlemen.
Dr. Ryan,
would you stay
for a moment, please?
I said speak your mind,
Jack, but Jesus...
You slammed the door
on the general pretty hard, Jack.
That was not my intention, sir.
Oh, yes, it was.
He was patronizing you,
and you stomped on him.
In my opinion,
he deserved it.
Listen, I'm a politician,
which means I'm
a cheat and a liar,
and when I'm
not kissing babies,
I'm stealing
their lollipops,
but it also means
that I keep my options open.
So let's assume for a minute
that you're right
and this Russian
intends to defect.
What do you suggest
we do about it?
We definitely
grab the boat, sir.
Hey, wait a minute.
We're not talking about
some stray pilot with a M.I.G.
We're talking about several
billion dollars' worth
of Soviet state property.
They're going to want it back.
Maybe it's enough then
just to get some people
onboard and inspect it.
Call it whatever
you want to...
a Coast Guard
safety inspection.
So how do we proceed?
First, we need to contact
the commanders
in the Atlantic directly.
The Russians get
one whiff of this
through the regular
communications circuits,
the game is up.
Second, we figure out
how we can help them.
We devise a plan to intercede,
ready to go at a moment's notice.
Third, somebody's got to
go make contact with Ramius
and find out what
his intentions really are.
OK.
When do you leave?
Ha ha ha!
Wait a minute.
The general was right.
I am not field personnel.
I am only an analyst.
You're perfect.
I can't ask any
of these characters to go.
They don't believe in it.
They'd never stake
their reputation
on a hunch, whereas you...
Are expendable.
Something like that.
I'll give you three days
to prove your theory correct.
After that,
I have to hunt down Ramius
and destroy him.
Will you do it?
Mother of God!
Secure the mast!
All ahead, 2/3!
Set depth to 900 meters!
What is it?
What's happened?
Mast secured, helm at 2/3.
Commence heading 2-0-5.
2-0-5, affirmative.
These orders
are seven bloody hours old!
Sitting on the bottom
like an addled schoolboy.
Captain...
Passing at...
All ahead, flank.
Inquire of the engineer
about the possibility
of going to 105%
on the reactor.
Seven hours.
The entire fleet is after him.
Leveling at 900 meters.
Very well.
Captain, Engineer reports
105% on the reactor
possible,
but not recommended.
Go to 105 on the reactor.
Captain, what is it?
Where are we going?
We're going to
kill a friend, Yevgeni.
We're going to kill Ramius.
If you like borscht,
perhaps,
but I've eaten better
in an oiler's galley.
My wife said to the waiter,
"Where did this man
learn to cook,
Afghanistan?"
So then we went
on to the Bolshoi,
the ballet,
to see this new girl
as Giselle.
You remember
how beautiful she was.
She just married
a factory manager.
Excuse me, Doctor.
Do you have the figures
for the latest batch
of radiation tests?
Now?
Now.
Perhaps you could bring
the preceding set as well...
for comparison.
Thank you, Doctor.
It will take him some time.
Before we begin, Captain,
I'd like to know
exactly what happened
to Putin.
He didn't slip
on his tea, did he?
I don't think I like
your tone, Slavin.
What the hell's my tone
got to do with it?
We're risking our lives here.
Putin could've caused
complications.
Did you think he would
just go away and sulk
while we carried out our plans?
Are you saying
he was murdered?
My God.
Stop whining, Yuri.
How can you justify murder?
So he was murdered.
The man was a pig,
but it's a decision
we should've all made together.
You are not in command here.
If the crew finds out,
we could have a mutiny.
What are you talking about?
They could kill us all.
Everything that happens
on this ship affects us all.
The Master-At-Arms
is already suspicious.
We could still go back.
There will be no going back.
Before we sailed,
I dispatched a letter
to Admiral Padorin,
in which I announced
our intention...
to defect.
In the name of God, why?
When he reached the New World,
Cortez burned his ships.
As a result, his men
were well motivated.
You have signed
our death warrants.
Padorin will send
the entire fleet.
Jesus, they'll find us.
They'll find us and...
No one's going to find us.
That's enough, Yuri.
You had to do it, huh?
You couldn't just
turn the submarine over
to the Americans.
You had to make
a political statement.
Or was it something
deeper, Captain...
something that made you
unable to slip away?
Was it ego, Captain?
We each have
our reasons, Victor.
My own began
the day I was handed
the blueprints for this ship...
a ship which had but one use.
And as for the rest,
well, those are things
that I alone
must carry the burden for.
Anatoli,
you're afraid of our fleet.
Well, you should be.
Personally, I give us
one chance in three.
More tea, anyone?
No?
Then you may report
back to your posts.
You heard the Captain.
Dismissed.
Captain.
Captain, I would never
disagree with you
in front of the men,
you know that.
But in this case,
Victor is right.
It would've been better
if you had not informed Moscow.
Oh, Vasily.
Moscow is not the worry,
nor the whole Soviet Navy.
I know their tactics.
I have the advantage.
No.
The worry is the Americans.
If we meet the right sort,
this will work.
We get some buckaroo...
Some turbulence,
eh, Commander?
You don't like flying, huh?
Oh, this is nothing!
You should've been with us
five, six months ago!
Oh! You talk about puke!
We ran into a hailstorm
over the sea of Japan, right?
Everybody's retching
their guts out!
The pilot shot his lunch
all over the windshield,
and I barf on the radio!
Knocked it out completely,
and it wasn't
that lightweight stuff either!
It was that chunky,
industrial-weight puke!
You want a bite?
Jack, next time
you get a bright idea,
just put it in a memo.
Sir.
[Knocks On Door]
That'll be all, Lieutenant.
Thank you.
That hawkeye
from Weymouth Trap?
Four wire.
Caught a gust over the fantail.
Well, not bad, considering.
The gentleman
is here to see you.
The gentleman?
What the hell
you talking about, Charlie?
I apologize
for the uniform, sir.
This is Admiral Greer's idea
of a low profile.
You work for Jim Greer?
That's right, sir.
Then I imagine you'll tell me
what all the hubbub's about.
Captain, you got a minute?
Jonesy's got something
I think you ought to see.
Martinez, get yourself
a cup of coffee.
Send me up some tea.
Aye, Captain.
Messenger,
get the captain a cup of tea.
Captain.
Sir, the moment
that sub went silent
and I thought I
heard some singing,
I heard something
in the background real faint.
After all those subs took off,
I caught it again
and got it on tape.
I washed it through the computer
and was able to
isolate this sound.
[Slow Pulsing]
When I asked the computer
to identify it,
what I got was
magma displacement.
You see, sir,
the SAPS software
was originally written
to look for seismic events.
I think when it gets confused,
it kind of runs home to Mama.
I'm not following you,
Jonesy.
Sir, I'm sorry.
Listen to it
at 10 times speed.
[Rapid Pulsing]
Now, that's got to
be manmade, Captain.
All right.
The first contact was at 09:15,
and the bearing was 2-6-9.
At 09:30, it was here.
I came back to it at 11:00
and 11:15, here and here.
Remember the dispatch we got
about Russian sub skippers
running the Reykjanes Ridge
at high speeds
because they had
hyper-accurate surveys
of the underwater canyons?
The front door to those canyons
was a formation
called Thor's Twins.
Yeah?
Look at that.
Right into Red Route One.
Captain.
You may think I'm crazy,
but I'll bet that
magma displacement
was actually some
new Russian sub,
and it's headed
for the Iceland coast.
Have I got this straight,
Jonesy?
A $40 million computer tells you
you're chasing an earthquake,
but you don't believe it,
and you come up
with this on your own?
Yes, sir.
Including all the navigation math?
Sir, I-I've got all the...
Relax, Jonesy. You sold me.
Tommy, I want you
to plot us a speed course
for the bottom end
of Red Route One.
We'll never find him
in those canyons.
First take us
to periscope depth.
This we got to phone in.
Aye, aye, Captain.
Hang on, Jonesy.
If I can get you close enough,
can you track this sucker?
Yes, sir.
Now that I know
what to listen for,
I'll bag him.
Carry on.
Yes, sir.
That's the craziest notion
I've ever heard...
a serving line officer?
An entire ballistic
missile submarine?
They can't all want to defect.
Even if it's only the officers,
it's extremely
difficult to believe.
What's his plan?
His plan?
Russians don't take a dump, son,
without a plan.
Senior captains don't start
something this dangerous
without having thought
the matter through.
What's he going to do,
sail into New York, pop the hatch,
and say here I am?
It might be just
that simple, yes.
Things may appear simple
in the cubicle at CIA,
but in the middle
of the Atlantic
with Soviet warships
bearing down on us,
they get more complex.
Smoke?
No, thank you.
And I don't think your notion
of a few days inspection's
going to wash either.
In order to be of any value,
you'd have to tear it apart.
The metallurgy would
take a couple of months.
Then we'd have to keep it.
What will you do with the crew?
Ones that don't defect will go back
and say we got the boat.
Or do you plan
to eliminate them?
We're not at war, sir.
So you have to get them
off the boat in such a way
that they think we don't have it,
and they'll report that
we don't have it to their bosses.
Otherwise, this whole business
is just academic, right?
Yes, sir.
I think I see your point.
When's the last time you slept?
A while.
The chief outside
will fix you up.
Thank you, sir.
Captain.
It'll be dawn
in a couple of hours.
We'll be in the CIC.
Things are liable to get
a little dicey around here.
Yes, sir.
You think he's crazy?
Certifiable.
No matter what
his credentials,
I don't care for him
wearing the uniform.
Did you see that ring
on his finger?
The academy, class of '72.
A marine.
You're kidding.
How did you...
Greer told me.
Summer of his third year,
he went down
in a chopper accident.
Bad. Pilot and crew killed.
That kid spent
10 months in traction
and another year
learning to walk again.
He did his fourth year
from the hospital.
It's up to you, Charlie,
but you might consider
cutting the kid a little slack.
Ah, Russians are
going to find that sub
before we get near it anyway.
Passing Thor's Twins, sir.
Very good.
Passing the twins now,
Captain.
Very good.
You may commence your run.
Call me at the first turning.
Aye, Captain.
Mr. Kamarov.
You may commence your run now.
Aye, sir.
First leg on my mark,
course 2-6-0.
Speed, 18 knots.
Depth, 270 meters.
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Mark.
Diving command, course 2-6-0.
Course 2-6-0, aye.
Speed, 18 knots.
Speed, 18 knots, aye.
Stop pissing, Yuri.
Give me a stopwatch and a map,
and I'll fly the Alps
in a plane with no windows.
If the map is accurate enough.
We're in the lane
and approaching first turn.
Come left to course 1-9-5.
In 30 seconds,
decrease depth to 200 meters.
Maintain speed.
Very good, Navigator.
Captain, we're approaching
the first turn.
25 seconds to course 1-9-5.
Increase speed to 26 knots
and recompute.
Aye, Captain.
Navigator, recompute
for 26 knots.
Turn on my mark.
5... 4... 3... 2... 1...
Mark.
Diving control,
come left to 1-9-5.
Come left to 1-9-5.
Up on the bow planes.
Course now 1-9-5
and maintaining speed
26 knots.
Mr. Kamarov?
Next leg, Captain,
come right
to course 2-4-0 now at...
8 minutes and 40 seconds.
Very good.
Maintain course and speed.
Too fast, Vasily.
Too fast.
Those charts are
laid out precisely...
so many knots
for so many seconds.
And this thing
handles like a pig.
Watch your bearing,
Mr. Slavin.
15 seconds to turn, Captain.
Should we decrease speed?
Negative.
Prepare to come right.
Aye, sir.
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1... Mark.
15 degrees down angle
on the bow planes.
Come right 2-4-0.
Move it!
We're in the lane.
Next leg 34 minutes
to the Neptune Massif.
Course 2-4-0.
[Boom]
What happened?
The cryogenic plant!
The magnets aren't cooling.
Temperature in
the caterpillar
is 15 degrees above red line
and rising.
It's going to melt.
Kill it! Shut it down!
Captain?
What happened?
The cryogenic plant failed.
Reactor damage?
There was a power spike,
but the reactor
scrammed automatically.
Was there any
radiation leakage?
I don't know yet!
How long will it take to fix?
I got to find
what's wrong first.
Could be the liquid helium
or the superconductors.
Captain, we will have to stop
until we can repair
the caterpillar unit.
Negative.
We'll run on normal propulsion.
Captain,
we will not be silent.
Make revolutions for 20 knots
and engage the propellers.
Aye, Captain.
Commence engine start-up.
He'll get us all killed.
The captain knows
what he's doing.
Doctor.
Naval activities?
I have no knowledge of this.
But then,
I never was a sailor.
Mr. Ambassador,
you have nearly
100 vessels operating
in the North Atlantic
right now.
Your aircraft have dropped
enough sonar buoys
that a man could walk
from Greenland to Scotland
without getting his feet wet.
Shall we dispense with the bull?
You make your point
as delicately as ever,
Mr. Pelt, but...
And what looks like an exercise
could be a prelude to war.
How can we tell the difference?
Prudence demands that we
deploy ships to observe yours.
Your government should consider
that having
your ships and ours,
your aircraft and ours,
in such proximity
is inherently dangerous.
Wars have begun that way,
Mr. Ambassador.
We have lost
one of our submarines.
Lost it?
We fear she may be down, and...
this is most embarrassing, but...
several of the officers
are sons of...
high party officials.
One is even the son
of a Central Committee member.
I cannot say which.
You're telling me this is
a massive rescue operation?
That is correct.
I'm terribly sorry.
How can we help?
I'm not sure that...
Perhaps a joint rescue mission?
That is very gracious of you, sir.
I'll pass your offer on.
But at this time,
I think we're doing everything
that can be done.
Captain?
Our strategy depends
on your answer.
The entire fleet
will know where we are.
Captain, Sonar.
We've been overflown
by a multi-engine turboprop.
Put it on audio.
Short transients,
close aboard.
Water entry of small objects.
Sonar buoys.
Battle stations.
Battle stations!
How long to Neptune Massif?
How long?
4 minutes, 10 seconds.
Should we bottom the boat?
No. Too late now.
We've run out of time.
Countermeasures.
Prepare to launch missiles.
Aye, sir.
Aircraft on computer guidance.
Request permission to launch.
You are authorized
to launch the weapon.
[Radio]
Weapon is away.
High speed screw!
Torpedo in the water!
Stand by.
Torpedo is active.
Torpedo has acquired.
Launch countermeasures.
Aye, sir.
We're in the lane.
How long till
the turn at Massif?
2 minutes, 9 seconds.
We have no room to maneuver
in these canyons.
Shut up.
Torpedo has reached
countermeasures.
Torpedo has lost contact.
Massif approaching.
Torpedo has reacquired.
Torpedo has reacquired
and is homing.
Give me the count.
Turn at Massif 40 degrees starboard
in 30 seconds.
Time to torpedo impact?
Torpedo impact, 35 seconds.
Increase to flank.
Full ahead flank.
Full ahead flank, aye.
Torpedo impact now 40 seconds.
35 seconds.
30 seconds.
Turn at Massif in...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...