[CROWD CHATTERING]
[BAND PLAYING POP MUSIC]
Only minutes away from midnight...
here at the fabulous Jade Park Hotel
in Hong Kong...
a star-studded event, typical of the man they
call the Donald Trump of Asia, David Chan.
Sir, what are your last thoughts
as the 20th century fades?
Tonight, we join the rest of the world
in celebrating the new millennium.
But next month we Chinese
begin the Year of the Dragon.
The year 4698.
Has it been that long?
But seriously, celebrating
the new Western millennium...
is quite a symbolic moment
for China, Hong Kong and myself.
Vitality and creativity of the West,
wisdom and experience of the East.
The fun's about to begin,
ladies and gentlemen. Please, join us.
[CHATTERING]
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
What is he waiting for?
What are you waiting for?
SHAW [OVER RADIO]:
Novak, I'm experiencing the moment.
He's gonna experience
a Chinese labor camp moment...
if he doesn't stick to schedule.
NOVAK: We are 10 minutes away,
and he's sight-seeing.
SHAW: Don't worry about it.
I'm always right on time.
All right, kids.
We're good to go.
[KEYBOARD CLACKING]
- Got it.
- Good stuff.
SHAW: Not so good.
Thought you said
he worked facing the window.
He does.
SHAW [OVER RADIO]: Not today.
He can't see where the infrared port is.
SHAW: Hold on. You can never
pay too much for good intelligence.
BLY [OVER RADIO]: Or a good hooker.
SHAW: We're good. The ball is up.
[WHIRRING]
We're receiving.
CHAN: Now, please, join with me
in counting us down...
CHAN: ...into China's new future.
Ready?
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[ALL YELLING IN CHINESE]
[IN ENGLISH] Three, two, one!
What...? What is it? What's wrong?
Is it Y2K?
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
Is it Y2K? No, never. It can't be.
[CROWD MUTTERING]
Not in my city!
Happy New Year!
[CROWD WHISTLING AND CHEERING]
Happy New Year. Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
Coming at you.
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Hey, happy New Year.
Okay, I got him.
[WOMEN LAUGHING AND CHATTERING]
- WOMAN 1: You like?
- WOMAN 2: You like this?
NOVAK: Thirteen-, 14-year-old girls.
Sick fuck.
That's good.
Did you get that?
- BLY: Okay?
- Yeah.
Let's do it.
Phone.
NOVAK: Here we go.
[PHONE RINGING]
[SPEAKS IN CHINESE]
- Happy New Year, Defense Minister.
- Who is speaking?
Well, you could think of me
as your conscience.
Huh?
Sending.
Maybe you should direct your attention
to the big screen.
Huh?
[GASPS THEN SPEAKS IN CHINESE]
Last month you took $90 million of U.N. aid
money, spent it on Chinese missile technology.
That money was for flood victims
and starving children.
I'm quite sure the North Korean
government won't mind...
but how do you think the world press
is gonna react to that?
- What do you want?
- You back at the negotiating table...
- ...with South Korea tomorrow.
- That is impossible.
NOVAK: Sending.
[BEEPING]
[IN CHINESE]
Oh? Well, just take a
look at your monitor.
Well, if it's still an impossibility,
press one on your keypad.
If it's a possibility...
[GROANS, THEN KEYPAD BEEPING]
Excellent choice.
Uh-oh.
I think I've been made.
NOVAK: Shaw, I'm picking up a lot
of chatter on the security channel.
[KEYBOARD CLACKING]
[BEEPING]
The man next to Chan
is Alex Wingate, media mogul.
United States, united Europe, united China.
There's no difference.
- Our blood is 68-percent Coca-Cola.
- WING-ATE: Opening China's doors...
to the West is more
complicated than that.
Oh, Alex, you know we'll try to
contribute what we can to make it easier.
And you, sir, who might you be?
Me? I'm Eddie Murphy.
[MIMICS EDDIE MURPHY'S LAUGH]
Would you hold this, please?
[MAN GROANS]
He hit me!
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[SPEAKS IN CHINESE]
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
SHAW: Okay, go to phase two.
Right. Yeah, yeah, yeah, I got it.
[CROWD YELLING]
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
[BLY LAUGHING]
[GRUNTING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Uh-oh. I know what's coming.
[MAN SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[GRUNTS]
Whoa!
[GUNFIRE]
SHAW [OVER RADIO]: I'm coming in. Hot.
BLY: Line up with the van.
Straight approach.
[ALL CHEERING]
[GRUNTING]
[CHATTERING]
REPORTER 1: Mr. Secretary-General...
do you have any comment on North Korea's
return to the, uh, peace negotiations?
How were you able to achieve this?
Common sense, patience,
mutual respect...
and an abiding understanding
that there are cultural differences...
and we're all gonna live with them.
REPORTER 2: Secretary-General
Douglas Thomas leaves the U.N...
after a successful return...
to peace negotiations
for North and South Korea.
Great.
I'm gonna become another one
of those famous Canadian peacekeepers.
Not famous. Do you know
how many Americans...
can name the secretary-general
of the United Nations? Three percent.
Well, that's all about to change...
because the press adore you,
and U.N. support is on the upswing.
Yeah, and there'd be hell to pay if
they ever found out about your tactics.
I know it's unorthodox,
but you cannot deny the results.
You know, if this treaty with China
could just go through...
the United Nations
could possibly become a world power.
It could.
Well, nonetheless, I think we should put a
cap on covert operations for the time being.
[SIGHS]
How's your fellow doing?
He needs a couple months to recover,
but, uh, he's in good spirits.
How do you give a medal to someone who
doesn't exist for something that didn't happen?
[GRUNTS]
Oh, Jesus.
- BLY: I wouldn't give up your day job.
- Well, well, well.
[BLY CHUCKLES THEN SHAW GRUNTS]
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought it was the other shoulder.
- Shoot. I thought you'd quit.
- Ha-ha-ha.
I did. This is my last one.
- It's a no-smoking court.
- Oh, okay.
So what? You come here to do what?
Force me into early retirement?
Well, you know,
the thought crossed my mind.
But, uh, to tell you the truth,
I was asked to check up on you.
Huh.
If Madam Hooks
wants to find out how I am...
why don't she come down here
and see for herself?
You know as well as I do
Madam Hooks doesn't do anything...
without gathering a
little intelligence first.
What, you?
You think you're qualified to test me?
Considering your, uh,
fragile condition...
I think I can kick your ass.
- Pfft.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Okay. All right.
- I'm ready.
- You ready? Yeah!
- Come on, you gonna shoot or dribble?
- What does it matter to you?
[GRUNTING]
- BLY: Oh.
- Ugh.
Goddamn it!
SHAW: Oh.
- Are you all right?
- Oh, yeah.
- Sorry. Oh, goddamn, man, you're bleeding.
- Oh, that's just great.
No, no, no, hold on.
Let me take a look. It's bleeding.
Damn. Argh.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You're gonna need some silk.
That should do it.
A nurse will be with you
in a minute to finish.
Thank you.
BLY: It's a good thing I'm an asshole.
Otherwise I'd feel guilty.
You should.
How is it?
Oh, he did a nice job.
Those people make good doctors.
What? Asians. Chinese. You know,
they're smart and well-educated.
And, uh, what about these people?
These people have gotta stop
getting shot on the job.
I can arrange that.
- Well, you're too young to retire, so...
- Yeah, I'm young, but I ain't dumb.
[SIREN WAILS]
- Don't that burn?
- Yes.
- Frank.
- What do you got?
Fucking thing
came off a Chinese freighter yesterday.
The longshoremen didn't think much of it.
Until the sun came up.
[INSECTS BUZZING]
[GRUNTING]
[RAY COUGHS]
[GRUNTS]
Oh, shit.
OFFICER: Our, uh, forensic
guy here picked this up.
Oh, I don't speak that language,
so I wouldn't know what that means.
Translator says it's Vietnamese.
Talks about the U.N. moving them
from some refugee camp in Hong Kong...
- ...looking for a new life in America.
- Hong Kong refugees. Ray.
Call Amnesty. See if they can trace these
to the ones that disappeared last month.
Yeah, sure, chief.
Thanks.
That's quite a statement, if that's
what they wanted to make. Guys.
Think it has something to do
with the big Chinese conference in town?
Yeah, 10-6.
...under U.N. supervision.
"The fact remains that although these
refugees were housed in Hong Kong...
they were under the supervision
of U.N. officers."
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[IN ENGLISH] Sweatshop.
TRANSLATOR: "You talk of human rights.
Three miles from here, sweatshops."
TRANSLATOR: "A mile from here,
homeless people living in doorways.
Yet you lecture my country...
on our human rights record.
- The only right that concerns me...
- Chinese Ambassador Jian Tze Wu.
TRANSLATOR: ...is the right
of 1.5 billion people to eat."
In two days, China signs
a U.N. trade agreement...
ending 50 years of isolation,
not only culturally, but commercially...
opening the door
to 1.5 billion new consumers.
And you think Ambassador Wu is connected
to the dead refugees from the boat?
I have my suspicions.
Before becoming U.N. ambassador,
he was responsible for refugee resettlement.
Here he is meeting with a group of
gentlemen tied to various triad concerns.
Human smugglers.
- Slave traders.
- Exactly.
My instinct tells me something
is lurking under the surface.
You always think something
Tonight David Chan is hosting a banquet
honoring Ambassador Wu.
You want me to put a wire on Wu.
If you're ready. How's the shoulder?
Technically? Fucked up.
THOMAS: There she is. Eleanor.
Here.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
I don't believe we've met.
We still haven't, sir.
Yes, of course.
Uh, would you excuse us, please?
We've been watching Security Council.
He was going nuts.
Yes, I saw.
Are you gonna do something about it?
Oh, he's been briefed.
We're moving forward.
SHAW:
I'm guessing that Thomas is not a fan.
On the contrary.
With the achievements of last year...
and the Chinese trade
agreement on the horizon.
Thanks to you.
One of the many reasons
I can't let you quit.
Look, Eleanor, I'm not one to complain,
but in the last two years I've been shot twice...
I got six broken bones,
and I don't even have a health plan.
You know we are owed billions
in dues payments.
Every U.N. staff member
has taken cutbacks.
Yes, so maybe I should make a move
before I get cut back. Permanently.
Find a career.
Career? Like what?
CIA, NSA? There's no guarantee.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
- McDonalds. Yeah, I'm gonna own one. Yeah.
- Shaw.
- Yeah. Maybe two.
- Ugh.
SHAW: Listen to me.
Governments, they come, they go...
but the McDonalds, they last forever.
All right, your point is taken,
but right now we have a situation...
that is rapidly deteriorating
into a political time bomb.
No parachutes, no submachine guns,
just a simple eavesdrop, right?
A walk in the park.
Heh. This is New York City, baby.
A simple walk in the park can get you killed.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
MAN 1: They want to sell us
the benefits of free trade!
Free trade? How can we make trade deals
when there is no accountability...
for Tibet, Tiananmen, and dead refugees
arrive on our shores like cattle?
Stop the U.N. deal!
Support human rights in China!
Take that. The U.N.
calls it free trade...
but this deal is about trade
at the expense of freedom. Free Tibet!
WOMAN 1: The magnificent hotel,
recently purchased...
by Chinese business mogul David Chan...
is alive with diplomats...
who are welcoming China
into the world trade arena.
- I didn't like it. Let's try another one.
- MAN 2: Sounds like a good idea to me.
- WOMAN 1: The magnificent hotel...
- MAN 3: Masi.
- Could you please look it up?
- WOMAN 2: Yes, sir. Yes. Yes, sir.
JULIA: Wait. Hold it. Hold it.
I'm sorry.
[CHATTERING]
Your microphone is poking into me.
- No, actually, it's not my...
- I'm just messing with you.
"Greg. U.N. reporter," huh?
Couldn't get a real job?
Smooth. Smooth.
[MAN 1 SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
REPORTER [IN ENGLISH]: Three, two, one.
We're moments away from the most historical
trade agreement announcements...
in Chinese and American relations.
- For tonight's gala features state...
- MAN 2: Okay. Yup.
MAN 3: Passes, please.
WOMAN 1: Get that over there. Stop.
MAN 4:
I need these cables checked immediately.
MAN 5: I'll get right on it.
Hey.
[IN CHINESE]
[IN ENGLISH] You're a free spirit.
I don't know how you do it.
Well, first move from a society
that discourages individualism...
then move to a city that embraces it
for three years.
It's easy.
- I'll take the first shift on the floor.
- Sure.
[CHATTERING]
MAN 1: A lot of American companies
would love unrestricted access to China.
Well, we see this as a major shift
in economic powers.
There are two sides to consider,
particularly when the Chinese are concerned.
That sounds very
prudent of you, actually.
WOMAN 1:
The ambassador's been here about a week.
What will he be wearing this evening?
[WU SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[WOMAN SPEAKS IN CHINESE]
[WU SPEAKING IN CHINESE OVER RADIO]
NOVAK: We are on the air.
Yes, yes, yes. Everything's okay.
[NOVAK COUGHS]
He's complaining about the menu.
Seems he's not a fan of Szechuan cuisine,
and somebody should have known that.
What? He doesn't like
the pickled pig knuckles? No.
[LAUGHS]
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for your warm welcome...
and your presence here this evening.
China and the West began their history
together not in war, but in trade.
It is trade that brings us all together
tonight, and it is trade that will bind us...
and unite us for years to come.
This agreement brings to fruition
years of hard work...
by leaders on both sides...
- ...driven by a belief that economic prosperity...
- Hey, man.
CHAN: ...will forge an era of peace
that the world has never enjoyed.
Marco Polo would be proud to know
that we go to the next level here.
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
CHAN: Open the door to the 21st century
and announce that, yes...
China wants to become a member
of the club...
that will guide this planet's destiny
into the next thousand years.
With the signing
of the U.N. Trade Agreement...
1.5 billion Chinese will have access
to the world markets that will...
There will be no future reforms of trade until
there's accountability for criminal aggression!
I'll check him out.
- I'm there already.
- MAN: Let's go. Right through here. Come on.
Well, you make that 1.4999 billion.
[ALL LAUGH]
And without any further delay, here he is,
the architect of China's future...
Ambassador Jian Tze Wu.
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
What's he saying to Chan?
The level is too low,
and he's blocking the bug.
Come on, I gotta know.
It's recording.
I'll keep the tape once we're done.
[IN CHINESE]
[IN ENGLISH] "Today I'm very happy
to participate in this party.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
I'm honored to open the
door of China to the world."
[TRANSLATOR GRUNTING]
[WU GRUNTS THEN ALL SCREAMING]
BLY [OVER RADIO]: I'm out of
the building. What's going on?
I got him. Black tracksuit. Bly?
- BLY: Novak, get out of there!
- Copy. I'm gone.
SHAW: Moving to the seventh floor.
JULIA: Anna!
[JULIA CRYING]
Help! Somebody help me!
- SHAW: Emergency exit. West side.
- BLY: Copy that. I'm mobile.
- Cut him off outside.
- BLY: I'm on it.
Parking structure.
Oh, no, you don't.
BLY: I'm at street level.
Moving to you. Box that fucker.
[GRUNTS]
MAN: Hey!
Oh, no. Stop!
[SHAW GRUNTS THEN WOMAN SCREAMS]
MAN: Halt! Halt!
- WOMAN: Aah!
- SHAW: Shh!
SHAW: Oh, shit.
[GRUNTING]
BLY: Check in. What's your situation?
Shaw!
SHAW: Head outside!
BLY: Shaw, talk to me.
- Shaw, what's your situation?
- Shots fired.
BLY: Talk to me, Shaw.
- I'm on the east side. Coming to you.
- BLY: Okay. East side. I'll be there.
He's heading for the street.
You should have visual.
BLY: Negative. No contact.
[TIRES SCREECHING
AND CAR HORN HONKING]
I got him, I got him. Oh!
- BLY: Where?
- Damn. 77th.
BLY: Copy, 77th Street.
We're coming to you.
- I'm almost there.
- Okay, mid-block. Construction site.
Location?
- Location?
- BLY: 76th.
You got him?
He should be right in front of you.
- BLY: Negative, negative.
- Bly.
- BLY: I got him. I got him, I got him.
- I can't hear you.
- BLY: I got the mark. I got him.
- Bly!
[GUNSHOT THEN BLY YELLS OVER PHONE]
BLY: Shaw, help me. I'm hit.
- Shaw, I'm hit.
- Bly!
Bly! Oh, God.
Bly, come in.
- Oh, shit.
- OFFICER: Freeze! Drop your weapon!
I said, drop your weapon!
Drop it! Drop it now!
Drop it now!
Put your hands behind your head.
Hands behind your head.
Get on your knees!
On your knees!
SHAW: Bly!
Bly!
BLY: Shaw, help me.
Oh, Shaw.
OFFICER: Okay, let's go.
- Come on.
- SHAW: Yeah.
- Oh. Heh-heh-heh.
- Ah! Oh, I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- Heh, heh.
- I'm so sorry.
- That's okay. You're Julia Fang, right?
- Mm-hm.
- Heh.
I'm Franklin Cappella,
Special Agent with the FBI.
You mind if we chat?
You're moved to a five-star
accommodation courtesy of the FBI.
You got the wrong man.
How many jokers you think we snatch sprinting
along 76th Street with a 9-millimeter?
Including me?
Maybe we should just hand you over
to the Chinese.
Let them kung fu your ass.
[SCOFFS]
It's not him.
Well, thank you very much, miss.
We... We'll find you if we need you.
Ceramic gun?
Clears metal detector nicely.
U.N. credentials, too difficult to fake.
High-tech communication gear,
almost government issue...
which means, ahem,
we shop at the same store...
but only you have a higher limit
on your credit card.
Which makes sense for a...
CIA officer?
Army intel?
Foreign government?
Just feel free to, uh, chime in at any point.
I'll just keep on talking.
The point is, Greg,
that we have dead Chinese refugees...
and we have a dead Chinese ambassador.
And I don't need a fortune cookie to tell
me that someone wants to put the kibosh...
on the... What do you call it?
The Chinese trade agreement type deal.
What's going on?
Go! Go, go!
FRANK: Son of a bitch!
Cock-sucking assholes!
[SIGHS]
I'm too fucking old for this.
[PANTING]
[GRUNTS]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[IN CHINESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES]
[SNIFFS]
[GRUNTING]
[HORN HONKING]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
Goddamn it! Shit!
[SIGHS]
Woo-hoo.
[SCREAMING]
REPORTER: Tensions flared with news
of the ambassador's assassination.
Meanwhile, in an unusual move...
the FBI's withholding the identity
of the assassin...
who fled captivity last night
in a daring escape.
You check your e-mail?
I'll have to call you back.
- Give me the phone.
- Is everything all right?
Listen.
Transfer the call.
We're both here now.
MAN [OVER PHONE]:
The U.N. is running a secret unit...
that assassinated China's ambassador
to the United Nations.
This will be the news
story of the week...
- ...and will damage the U.N. permanently.
- Unless?
MAN: Unless the Chinese trade
agreement dies on the table.
We don't have the power to kill it.
Others do. We don't.
MAN: Nevertheless, you have 24 hours.
THOMAS: Kill the treaty. Why?
Who stands to gain by that?
[BEEPING]
- HOOKS: It's the way we would've done it.
- What are you talking about?
The blackmail.
Our own techniques
being used against us.
Your techniques, Eleanor. I told you
this was gonna come back to haunt us.
There is no free lunch.
You have to pay the piper.
Now, I want everything
to stop immediately.
I don't want anything to happen without
my consultation and my permission.
Mr. Secretary, I must insist...
No, no, no, you listen to me, Eleanor.
Who is this man?
The assassination
of Chinese Ambassador Wu...
could not have come at a worse time
for U.S.-China relations.
U.N. representatives
expressed concern...
the incident could delay
the Chinese trade agreement.
But others fear more permanent damage
to relations between the two countries.
Businessman David Chan is recovering
at a downtown hospital.
His doctors made a brief statement
a few hours ago.
Mr. Chan is resting comfortably.
The bullet was removed from his arm
without complication.
[NEWS THEME SONG PLAYING ON TV]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[WU SPEAKING IN CHINESE
OVER RECORDING]
[KEYBOARD CLACKING]
[MEOWS]
Wagner?
Hey, baby.
Think you got something for me.
[OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[NOVAK SCREAMING]
MAN: Keep going. Yeah.
Same caliber that took
out Ambassador Wu.
Yeah, I'm sure
Greg Brogan's prints are on it.
So our boy gets rescued
by these triad assholes...
punctures one of them in the melon and
renders the others into Chinese salsa.
- Do you ever watch wrestling, Ray?
- Sure. I mean, you know, now and then.
- Because this is just like wrestling.
- How?
Well, it's reality mixed with illusion,
mixed with bullshit...
mixed with big scary guys
from parts unknown...
in dire need of psychiatric care.
[SIGHS]
[GLASS BREAKING THEN NOVAK GRUNTS]
[OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKER]
[NOVAK WHEEZING]
[GRUNTING]
[WHEEZING]
[GUNSHOT]
[GRUNTING]
Have it your way.
Thank you.
Now...
[WHIRRING]
The level is too low
and he's blocking the bug.
It's good to see you too.
[DEVICE BEEPING]
[WU SPEAKING IN CHINESE ON RECORDING]
[SIREN WAILING]
REPORTER: Why is it police believe the man
is the killer when you said he was not?
Would you comment on rumors linking
you with the suspect romantically?
Oh, Ms. Fang, may I
have a word with you?
No. Don't you have a certain
fugitive to apprehend?
No, no, no. I just wanna
talk to you for a second. I...
This is harassment.
- I'm just trying to protect you, ma'am.
- From who?
Um...
Our fugitive friend is
mixed up with the triads.
You know what that means?
My best friend is dying up there.
If you want to help, find the person
who tried to choke the life out of her.
Okay.
If you wanna call me, there's my card.
Fuck.
WOMAN: Dr. Phyllis.
OFFICER 1: Sarge says we need
to keep a 24-hour watch.
WOMAN 1: Dr. Judy Baker.
OFFICER 2:
I got Perez in front of her room now.
OFFICER 1: Be right back out.
MAN: I don't know how long she'll last.
WOMAN 2: Nurse Grant, 153 south.
JULIA: Help! Somebody help me!
[WHIMPERS]
[IN CHINESE]
WOMAN [ON PA]: Dr. Patterson to ER 7.
Dr. Keene, call your service.
Gurney assistant to Room 215.
MAN [ON PA]: Dr. Smith to Emergency.
WOMAN: Dr. Peter Mallory.
[IN CHINESE]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
[GASPS]
Go. Go.
[CHATTERING]
SHAW: Go. Come on. In the car.
Come on. Come on.
Move over.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[SIREN WAILING]
Not a word.
- MAN 1: Oh, man.
- OFFICER 1: What do we got here?
OFFICER 2: Hands behind your back.
- MAN 2: All right.
- OFFICER 3: All right, show's over.
- Move it back, move it back.
- OFFICER 4: We saw you buying.
- OFFICER 3: No drama.
- MAN 3: Yeah, all right.
OFFICER 3: There's nothing going on.
Mind your business.
Move along. Move along.
- Nothing's going on.
- Not a word.
MAN: Die!
WOMAN: Just get out of here now.
Come on, get moving.
Phew.
Who do you work for?
Are we just going to sit here?
[KNUCKLES CRACKING]
Please, stop that.
No.
No?
I've got you figured out.
Oh, you do, huh?
You think I don't see
that you're as scared as I am?
You won't tell me what's going on
because you don't know.
Okay, all right, that's enough.
Okay?
All right?
Mm.
So, what are you?
Some kind of government agent?
Translate this for me and you go free.
Free? Free to go where?
[WU SPEAKING IN CHINESE ON RECORDING]
All right. Play it again.
- This is Ambassador Wu.
- Yes.
[WU SPEAKING IN CHINESE ON RECORDING]
He's saying that the dead refugees
were a deliberate action...
to derail the trade agreement...
and he knows who is responsible.
Who was he talking to?
FRANK: He got here too late.
She was already dead.
So he took it out on a triad stiff.
"Jenna Novak."
Her passport is Czech.
[GLASS BREAKING]
Her file came up blank.
Same as our guy, same dead end.
- Weird same.
- Weird.
Um...
Phone records you asked for.
There's definitely a
pattern showing up here.
You mean other than
half a dozen dead bodies?
Well, yeah, look.
Phone numbers in sequence:
"555-3901, 555-3902, 555..."
Okay, fine. Sure, all right.
What you gotta do is you gotta
go all the way up to 99...
isolate the possibles...
stake out all the locations,
wait for our guy to show up.
Bob's your uncle.
That's a good plan, but who's Bob?
He's your uncle.
[LINE RINGING]
MAN [OVER PHONE]:
This better be a fucking emergency.
Hello? Who is this?
WOMAN [ON RECORDING]: We are
unable to complete your call as dialed.
Please check the number and dial again.
REPORTER: Protests like this one
at the U.S. Embassy in Beijing...
are causing many to believe that
the U.N. trade agreement...
will dissolve before it starts.
And all eyes are on
Secretary-General Douglas Thomas...
to find a peaceful solution to the
strained relations between the countries.
[ENGINE REVS]
CHAN: You have a monumental crisis
emerging, Mr. Secretary-General.
THOMAS: I'm convinced that there's only one
man in the whole world who can compel...
those fellows in Beijing
to stick with their agreement.
And that man is you, David.
I don't know if you're trying
to flatter me or frighten me, sir.
I think what the secretary-general
is suggesting...
is that you can remind
all parties involved...
that as history has shown...
economic prosperity does
wonders at keeping the peace.
Excuse me, Madam Hooks,
I missed CNN today.
Is there a war going on
that I'm unaware of?
There's always a war going on.
There's your side, there's their side...
and me stuck in the middle
trying to make it look like it's peace.
The secretary-general spoke to
the president this morning...
and if the situation does not improve...
he's prepared to fly in
from Washington tomorrow...
and attend the ceremony himself
as a show of support for the agreement.
THOMAS: It's a last resort.
I don't want it to happen. I want this
to be a United Nations initiative.
But more than anything else,
I want it to work.
And I'm afraid that,
as things stand now...
without the president's presence,
it can't work.
Don't bring in the president.
It'll only complicate things.
And in the meantime, we were hoping...
that you wouldn't mind
acting as interim diplomat.
An ambassador of good will, if you will.
I'd be honored to help.
And allow you to take the headlines.
"Secretary-General
Saves China Trade Agreement."
[PHONE RINGING]
Excuse me.
Eleanor Hooks.
You posted a missing cat?
Yes.
Yes, I did.
- You found him healthy?
- Yes.
You're going to need to keep him
for a few days. Is that a problem?
No problem.
I know where to reach you.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
- Asshole!
- Get a house, you jerk!
Internet chat rooms,
though, they're a free-for-all.
You just have to know where to go.
"Triads killed Wu. Framed me."
JULIA: "Possible mole in department.
Hold communications...
and expect cover to be compromised...
within 24 hours.
Stay under radar.
Good luck."
- Yeah, good luck.
- Mm.
You work for the U.N., don't you?
- Jesus, you do.
- Okay, I want you to go in there...
and I want you to buy some bottled water
and some food that will keep.
When you come out,
I want you to do one more thing.
One more thing? It must be nice
for you to assume...
that I will bend over
whenever you please.
- It's...
- Yes, "bend over backwards"...
is what I meant.
Thank you.
I'm trusting you.
Oops.
WOMAN: I really don't care nothing
about it that you're drunk.
But you better cook that food
like you're supposed to, though.
- They got...
- Excuse me.
[LINE RINGING]
- WOMAN [OVER PHONE]: Hello?
- Yeah, is Marie there?
- WOMAN: No Marie here.
- Oh, sorry. Sorry, wrong number.
Pay phone?
Over... I am not through with you.
[LINE RINGING]
WOMAN: I keep telling you
nobody wants this sorry food.
All you do is make excuses all the time.
[MAN SPEAKING IN CHINESE OVER PHONE]
[IN ENGLISH] Hi, Lo Kee Bakery.
SHAW: Bingo.
Oh, great.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Whoa!
[ALL SCREAMING]
WOMAN: Help! Help!
Move!
Down! Down! Everybody down!
[GASPS]
- Get undressed.
- Excuse me?
- Strip. All your clothes off now.
- You think I'm...
Now! Take your clothes off now.
- You think I'm gonna get undressed for you?
- You're bugged.
- There's a transmitter in your clothing.
- A transmitter? How?
I don't know how. How do you
think they tracked us to the diner?
Just think about it.
They went after you in there,
not me. Take them off.
[IN CHINESE]
What was that?
[IN ENGLISH] You said I was free to go.
Oh, you wanna go? Okay.
Here. Go.
See you.
Thought so.
Glasses, watch.
SHAW: Best I could do.
You're not used to this, are you?
Not having control of the situation,
being manipulated.
You're normally on the other side
of the equation.
What, are you just stating the obvious
for your own personal enjoyment...
or you moonlighting as a psychic friend?
If I help you,
it would follow that I help myself.
Okay. Well, then help yourself
by telling me about Ambassador Wu.
You said you worked
for him for a long time.
Ambassador Wu was an outsider.
He knew China's future lay
in economic growth.
But the party line was
to keep a separation with the West.
He believed that the
gulf could be crossed.
What gulf?
I'm talking about
appearances and meaning.
Frankly, I thought you'd be more
sensitive to this concept.
- JULIA: Who are you calling?
- SHAW: You tell me.
MAN [OVER PHONE]: Lo Kee Bakery.
SHAW: Okay, it's a front.
- For what?
- This is an athletic club.
[WOMAN SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
A private gentleman's club
for gambling and...
SHAW: And...?
And sex.
Heh. Ah.
Hey, what's going on? You are late.
MAN 1: Hey, where's one of the
moron brothers? Where are you guys?
- MAN 2: Frank, my clients are waiting.
- MAN 3: They're in the back.
Okay.
You'll be able to hear me with this.
And you'll be able to talk to me...
with this.
I need your help.
Help me find what I'm looking for, okay?
- What are you doing?
- I don't have time to worry about another thing.
- Where would I go?
- I don't know.
Someplace I obviously
haven't thought of.
[GRUNTS]
Can you tell me why helping you
is conditional on being a prisoner?
You're not a prisoner.
I'm protecting you from yourself.
[MEN SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[LAUGHING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[MEN LAUGHING]
One of these days, you're gonna have
to tell me how you know about this place.
Julia?
Julia.
Are you awake?
I'm awake.
I was just in a different place.
Can we stick to the present?
JULIA: You know, I read a book once
about these prisoners of war...
who construct the house of their dreams
in their head...
- JULIA: ...to keep their sanity.
- SHAW: Sanity?
Thought you'd lost that a long time ago.
JULIA: Right now I'm sitting at a café,
in a small village...
in the south of France.
SHAW: Now, there's a familiar face.
- Shaw, there's cops pulling up everywhere.
- MAN 1: Everybody out.
- MAN 2: Go, go, go!
- OFFICER 1: Police, stay down!
Did you hear what I said?
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
Yeah. Party's over.
- OFFICER 1: Police! Police, don't move!
- OFFICER 2: Police!
OFFICER 1: Police! Police! Don't move!
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
OFFICER 3:
Federal officers! Hold it right there.
OFFICER 4: Take it easy. Take it easy.
OFFICER 5: No!
MAN 1: I wanna go.
OFFICER 6:
Shut your mouth. Pipe it down, son.
- Okay, okay, one at a time here.
- OFFICER 7: Stay down.
[WOMEN MOANING ON TV]
[MOUTHS] Hi.
Did you, uh, need any help with those?
- We have a full license.
- Oh, you've got a fucking license?
Well, we'll just, uh,
be on our way then.
You're in way over your head, boy. You see,
we have an understanding with the police.
Well, now you have an understanding
with the FBI.
OFFICER 1:
I said, assume the fucking position.
MAN: You assume the position.
Kung fu motherfucker.
SHAW: Didn't you hear the officer?
What's wrong with you?
Get over here. Give me those.
Get up the stairs with your bitch ass.
[OFFICER 2 LAUGHS]
All right, let's get their names.
Get them out of here. Come on.
FRANK: Sometimes it's hard
to tell the difference...
between the good guys and the bad guys.
It's not always obvious.
Oh, excuse me, miss. Is this man
bothering you? Steel. Left hand.
- Nice and slow.
- All right.
Step back.
Not exactly FBI waist regulation, is it?
FRANK: I'm on probation.
Okay, Cappella, why don't you ask her?
Ask her who the bad guys are
and if she wants to walk away with you.
Look, uh, we're both after the same thing.
Why can't we work together on this?
Because your idea of
cooperation is me in a cell.
I don't particularly like that.
- MAN 1: Right here.
- MAN 2: Behind your back.
I'm just after the truth.
Well, why don't you check out the
Vietnamese refugees underneath the bakery?
My guess is that they're linked to the
dead ones you found in the container.
You can be a hero, huh?
There's no weight requirement
for attorney general.
- Probably not.
- SHAW: Probably not.
- Oh, Cappella.
- Yeah?
Oh.
[FRANK LAUGHS]
Thank you.
SHAW: That club stinks of David Chan.
He's in bed with the triads
and definitely linked to the refugees.
But I need proof that he took out Wu
to kill the trade agreement.
I'm not so sure about your theory. I mean,
David Chan was supporting the trade initiative.
SHAW:
Appeared to be. But ask yourself this:
Who benefits the most from Wu's death?
JULIA: Besides Mrs. Wu?
SHAW: If the trade agreement
is signed tomorrow...
Chan's business monopoly would be over.
He'd have to compete
with the Western companies.
Kill Wu and the U.N. trade agreement
with him, Chan keeps China to himself.
You make a lot of sense for a car thief.
Okay. Just relax.
[JULIA CLEARS THROAT]
- Okay. Ready.
- You're gonna log on to the main website...
then you're gonna follow
the instructions I gave you.
Wait, the access is denied.
Okay, simultaneously
press control-alternate-F8 twice.
Backslash. Enter.
"Password and log-in ID."
Don't worry about it. You don't need it.
Just follow the last lines of codes on the page.
"Department of Defense"?
- Julia, look...
- Don't tell me. I don't want to know.
A little trick I picked up
from friends I used to train with.
Did they train you
to be this vague, or is it a gift?
- And what's that supposed to mean?
- You know what I mean.
I mean your evasiveness.
Comes with the territory.
Well, the "strong silent type"
cliché thing is becoming tiresome.
Okay, we're in.
Okay.
- Whoa, whoa, wait a minute. Wait, stop.
- What?
Rewind.
Play it again.
All right, let's go frame by frame
and look very carefully.
JULIA: Chan's looking
before the shot was fired.
I don't believe it. He knew.
SHAW: He knew that it was coming?
More like he made it happen.
SHAW: All right, make a copy
and get back to the car.
Twenty-four hours are nearly up.
I'm putting the trade deal
in the president's hands.
I'm gonna let him run with it.
Bringing the president in, sir,
seriously undermines your authority.
Your strength is what
will keep the U.N. strong.
I'm using all my sources. If anything
should leak out, I can kill it.
I feel certain you can keep this
deal together and avoid a scandal.
Thank you, Eleanor.
Thank you, but no.
REPORTER: Reports are coming in that
Secretary-General Douglas Thomas...
has asked the president
of the United States to intervene...
and solidify the Chinese trade agreement
before it collapses.
The president and secretary-general will
address the general assembly tomorrow...
and attend the signing
ceremony at the U.N.
If Chan is serious about killing this deal,
that's where he'll make his next move.
All right, I want you to take the videotape
and Wu's recording to Eleanor Hooks.
She can get it to the right people
without bringing me into it.
Meanwhile I'll provide the final piece of
this puzzle, finish this once and for all.
- Where are you going?
- The last place I should.
MAN: Let's go. Let's get these papers.
Yes, I will.
I'm sorry, Ms. Hooks is quite busy.
I hope you don't mind waiting.
[CHATTERING]
[IN CHINESE]
[BEEPING]
Happy New Year.
[PHONE RINGS]
MAN: Yeah.
She's ready to see you now.
Do you always exhibit such flair
at entrances and exits...
or is it just when
visiting my hotels, Mr. Shaw?
Well, actually,
I find them rather inviting.
Kind of like a second home, you know?
As my most effective
asset in the field...
I'm almost embarrassed
that you're not on my payroll.
Then maybe you'd like
to make me an offer I can't refuse.
I would, but I'm afraid you would
never get to enjoy the rewards.
Well, guess this is my reward.
[GRUNTING]
Excellent, actually.
Assassinate the man
who's been tracking you...
and at the same time, blow apart the trade
agreement that could cost you billions.
Now, I know that nothing
is what it seems.
But I'm dying for you to explain this.
[GRUNTING]
If this information were to get out...
the scandal could seriously damage
China's credibility on the world stage.
Do more harm than good.
I never thought of that.
Appearances are everything, Ms. Fang.
Politics and deception are built on it.
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
SHAW: Heading for the street!
I got him, I got him!
Okay, mid-block, construction site.
Location?
[SAW BUZZING]
Bly!
OFFICER: Freeze! Drop your weapon!
I said, drop your weapon! Drop it!
[DEVICE BEEPING]
That should do it.
[GRUNTING]
- Come on!
- Hey, Neil.
You're gonna need some silk.
[GRUNTING]
Are you all right?
How does it feel to be a
puppet without the strings?
[HORN HONKING]
[PHONE BEEPING]
HOOKS: The Art of War teaches:
Win by destroying your
enemy from within.
Ironic, isn't it...
that a 2000-year-old strategy would be turned
against the very people who created it?
Better us doing it to them
than them doing it to us.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about 20 years
of China fucking America from within...
and nobody noticing.
Well, now they're going to notice.
You.
You're behind all this.
With just enough help from David Chan
to keep everyone guessing.
David Chan, most of all.
I don't understand.
Of course you don't, my dear.
Because you, like most people,
never stop to look at the big picture.
I've been looking at the big picture
every day for 20 years...
and I've tried to look forward.
And you know what I see?
I see China maintaining
a stranglehold on freedom...
influencing our political process
with illegal campaign contributions...
stealing our most secret military
technology and selling it to our enemies...
weakening us from
the inside like a virus.
This trade deal is an invitation
to finish the job.
We intend to cancel that invitation.
We intend to return
America to Americans.
"We"? Who do you think
you are representing?
The people who have steered this nation
for decades behind the scenes.
The people who protect democracy
from itself.
For a woman obsessed with
Chinese conspiracies...
you sound frighteningly similar to the
government you are trying to stop.
Thanks for stopping by.
And thanks for this
useful bit of evidence.
I'm sure you'll find your own way out.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
[PANTING]
Shit, shit, shit.
Just think, girl.
[DOOR RATTLES]
[GRUNTING]
[PHONE RINGS THEN JULIA GASPS]
Oh, fuck.
Julia.
- Shaw?
- SHAW: Julia.
- Hello? Can you hear me?
- You're breaking up. Shaw.
Move where you can get better reception.
- SHAW: If you can hear, move...
- Shaw.
SHAW:
...where you can get better reception.
I'm locked in the U.N. building.
Hooks is behind everything.
Julia. Julia. Ju... Shit.
[SPEAKS IN CHINESE]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
Hey, guys, you call this a perimeter?
Come on, wake up! Jesus Christ!
[PHONE RINGS]
- Cappella.
- America's most wanted.
Oh, the man of the hour.
Why are you calling? To explain Chan's
murder or to apologize for this afternoon?
SHAW: Both. You wanna meet, let's meet.
Okay. Are you in the area?
SHAW:
With rookie boy's head in my sights.
Really? I could live with that.
SHAW: Get back in your car.
Drive to the other side of the park...
- ...and pick me up.
- No, I've got a better idea. What the...?
[GUNSHOT]
Uh...
Okay, I get the message.
- Gotta go.
- What are we gonna do?
Fuck, I don't know, Ray.
Figure out something.
[DIAL TONE BEEPING]
Do not underestimate your friend.
There's a reason I chose him
as team leader...
and there's a reason I asked you
to deal with him.
You obviously do not appreciate
the schedule I'm working with.
I agreed to play Neil because I
wanted to, not because of the money...
and certainly not because
of your right-wing ideology.
You let me handle Neil my way.
This is not about male testosterone
between you and your idol.
[CHUCKLES]
You were just a cog
in the wheel of a larger machine.
It could've just as easily been you
out there chasing your own tail.
I understand.
What do you wanna do about the girl?
It's almost midnight.
Security will be doing a check
of the upper floors.
You have a 30-minute window.
What about the guards in the lobby?
I'll take care of them.
Yes, ma'am.
[LINE RINGING]
- What?
- SHAW: Drive.
Oh, okay.
Where's your first-aid kit?
[PHONE RINGS]
Security.
Yes, ma'am.
Attention.
Stand by for a motion sensor test.
GUARD [ON PA]: Protocol T-7.
All lobby personnel
report to Sublevel 1.
Repeat: Lobby personnel stand down
for a motion sensor diagnostic.
[GRUNTING]
The trail ends with Eleanor Hooks.
My guess is that she was using Chan
and then she double-crossed him.
It's a long story.
Just drive.
Jesus Christ.
This information has to come out
to clear your name.
I can't do that. Any connection between
Wu's murder, Chan, the triads and Hooks...
- ...would kill the trade agreement...
- Holy shit.
SHAW:
...and completely destabilize the U.N.
Damn it, that's it. That's it.
- All she has to do is come clean, tell the truth.
- Truth?
Yeah, the truth about me, about the U.N.
covert operations unit, everything.
She pins the assassination
on you to discredit the U.N.?
Taking out the one organization...
that could hold everything together.
Back to a cold war.
Give me your business card.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING
THEN JULIA GASPS]
[DOOR CREAKING]
Hello.
[BEEPING]
[IN CHINESE]
SHAW:
Roll your window down so I can see.
Jesus.
Security's not where
they're supposed to be.
Neither am I.
[PHONE RINGING]
Cappella.
[MOUTHS] It's for you.
Yes.
Well, I have a proposition for you.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
Come on, sweetheart.
[BEEPING]
All right, you wanna play?
Let's have some fun.
BLY: The Art of War.
Sun-tzu.
Chapter 13: "Doomed Spy."
Does any of this ring a bell?
"Sacrificing an agent without his knowledge
can turn the battle in your favor.
Befriending you, gaining your trust...
all the while setting
you up to take the fall."
You disappointed me, Shaw.
You were always one step behind.
I gotta tell you, my friend.
By the time we're done with you...
you're gonna make Lee Harvey Oswald
look like a fucking Boy Scout.
[GRUNTS]
But first we're gonna have a short class
on Pacific Rim social economics.
Specifically the effect of negative
Chinese population density...
and how it relates
to the African-American worldview.
In other words, you're gonna watch me
put a bullet in Little Miss Shanghai here.
Shit.
[ELEVATOR BELLS DINGING]
I was thinking neighborhood rules.
Sounds good to me.
[GRUNTING]
It's nice when an opponent
raises the level of play.
You're too kind.
No, I'm not.
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTING]
[CLICKING]
There's still one left
in the chamber, amigo.
Tell me, master.
What are you gonna do now, huh?
Move.
[GRUNTING]
[YELLS]
[SCREAMS THEN GRUNTS]
[BLY WHEEZING]
[GASPS]
You all right?
FRANK: Hello.
Get me out of here.
Oh, hello.
Here's your paper.
Have a nice day, Ms. Hooks.
[SIGHS]
Dramatic.
[PHONE RINGING]
I'm just reading about your handiwork.
Yeah, well, I was thinking of yours.
SHAW: You betrayed me, Eleanor.
Shaw.
I thought our Eastern associates would've,
uh, made arrangements for you by now.
SHAW: Well, staying alive
is what you pay me for.
But I'm curious.
What makes you think that what you
did to Chan won't happen to you?
I don't like to speak ill of the dead...
but between you and me,
and whoever is listening...
David Chan was a self-inflated,
pig-headed asshole...
who no doubt deserved
whatever came his way.
And as for you, Shaw,
well, you're still alive.
You just remember, Eleanor,
what goes around comes around.
Sore loser.
Max, you missed the entrance.
Ma...
THOMAS:
Eleanor Hooks was my right-hand man.
She was my mentor.
She taught me that
a successful road to peace...
THOMAS: ...is founded on a principle
of action, not reaction.
She said that if what I believed to be
the destiny of the United Nations...
is to be fulfilled, then we could
not afford to wait around...
and then react
to a member nation's call for help.
[TIRES SCREECHING AND SIRENS WAILING]
We had to anticipate to diffuse volatile
national and international conditions...
before they became explosive...
before they led us to catastrophe.
- So it is in the memory of Eleanor Hooks...
- Freeze!
THOMAS: ...that I pledge the
commitment of this organization...
to a policy of intervention,
a policy of leadership...
a policy of aggressive peacekeeping.
Down on your knees!
Call the coroner.
[CHATTERING]
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[MAN SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
[IN ENGLISH] Excuse me, do I know you?
No, I don't think so.
Do I know you?
Maybe it was in another
lifetime or something.
[LAUGHS]
So, uh, have you eaten?
I have not eaten.
There's food at my place.
But how are we gonna get there?
Maybe we should take a cab.
Why don't we just walk?
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
[English - US - SDH]