You hungry?
You know you've
got to come get it.
Don't play hard to get.
You will like it.
It's cat...
There you go.
Leave room
for breakfast.
¶¶ I can think of ¶¶
¶¶ younger days ¶¶
¶¶ when living for my life ¶¶
¶¶ Was everything a man ¶¶
¶¶ could want to do ¶¶
¶¶ I could never ¶¶
¶¶ see tomorrow ¶¶
¶¶ I was never told ¶¶
¶¶ about the sorrow ¶¶
¶¶ How can you mend ¶¶
¶¶ a broken heart?¶¶
¶¶ How can you ¶¶
¶¶ stop the rain ¶¶
¶¶ from falling down? ¶¶
¶¶ How can you stop ¶¶
¶¶ the sun from shining? ¶¶
¶¶ What makes the ¶¶
¶¶ world go round? ¶¶
Hello?
Please...
don't hurt me.
Here, take anything
you want.
You want some food?
Take it.
- I'm not going to hurt you.
- Yeah?
That's what the
last guy said.
Could you help me?
The wheel came off.
I can't fix it.
Maybe if I...
if I could...
but I can't.
The only good thing
about no soap ...
is that you can smell
hijackers a mile off.
I am impressed!
This man ...
smelled us...
from thirty feet away!
What does that say
about our hygiene?
What you got there
in that pack?
What pack?
He's got a gun.
Well shit, it
isn’t loaded.
They never are.
Isn’t that right,
old man?
Open the pack and
tip it out on the road.
Nice and slow.
Can't do that.
Take off the
fucking pack...
and put it on
the ground...
or die!
Are you listening to me?
- I am now.
- Good.
- Are you listening to me?
- Yeah.
Good.
Put that hand
on me again,
and you wont
get it back.
Can you believe
this fucking guy?
Alright, we will do
it the hard way.
Why did you do that?
You just cut my hand off!
What are you standing
around for?
Kiss him!
What did he say?
He's in shock.
I think he meant
"Kill him".
I told you, you weren't
going to get that back.
Yeah, you did.
Who are you?
Where's your water?
They don't have none.
They were going to take yours, ...
and then eat you.
It's true.
It's in the cart.
You're not taking it?
- Where are you going?
- West.
- Can I come with you?
- No.
No!
Woah, woah, woah...
Where are you going?
Stay on the path.
No!
It's not your concern.
Stay on the path.
- I don't know you.
I know.
I'm not from around here.
No shit, you're not from around
here. Who are you?
I don't want any trouble.
Okay.
- Just a customer, okay?
- Okay.
I'm sorry I got to
see the hands.
I'm not one of them.
Okay.
I'm going to take something
out of my pack.
Take your finger
off the trigger.
Yeah.
Oh, sweet. That's
a Fathom 900, man.
Is it?
I haven't seen one of
those since the 90's.
Yeah, I got it
back east.
- Does it still work?
- Yeah, just need a charge.
Can you do that
for me? Give me a charge.
I got cables.
I don't need the cables.
I can put a trickle charger on it.
Good.
I need to get the coin.
Yes I do.
- It's American.
- Oh yeah.
I got a whole
bunch of these.
How about Chopstick?
Got any Chopstick?
No Chopstick.
I got cat oil.
- Fresh cat oil.
- No, no.
It's good, it's good for...
Works the same way.
What about toys?
Got any toys?
No, I don't play.
Oh, I got...
Oh yeah.
Yeah yeah.
Okay, alright.
I'll have this,
with these.
Oh, absolutely,
those are yours.
Okay, give me a
couple of hours.
- I'll charge it up for you
- Thank you.
You can wait over there,
across the street at The Orphan
- No, I'm good.
- The bar is about ready to open.
I'll wait here.
You don’t trust
me, do you?
- I'll wait here.
- Alright.
Carnie, one of the road
crews just pulled into town.
They got something
for you.
- Books?
- A whole pack of them.
Tell them I want to
see them. Right now.
We did good.
The one you want.
It isn’t there?
No.
I just don’t understand.
That's a shitload of books.
You don't have
to understand.
I understand.
Leave that to me and
we can be friends.
I have faith in you.
You will find it.
Ah, wait!
I got this too.
Oh, now this is a treat.
It's shampoo.
Go get slammed.
Get some pussy.
Everything on me as much as
you and your boys can stand.
Then go back on the road.
Then we'll get you your book!
Of that I have no doubt.
You're sending guys out
that can't even read
to look for one book.
No wonder they
never find anything.
Yeah, I use the
tools I have at hand.
Unless you'd like
to go with them.
- What about these?
- Burn them.
The place across the street -
they got any water?
They have if you
can pay for it.
Here. Smell this.
One of the road crews found it.
Who knows...
It might be the last
shampoo on the planet.
And it's yours.
Did they find your book?
No.
Outlander?
Let me see.
- Alright, what will it be?
- Water.
That's the good stuff.
I got to eat into
my own rations to sell,
so it don't come cheap.
That will get you
maybe half way.
Solara!
Take this and get it filled.
Wait. You need this.
Can you please move?
Thank you.
That was my cat.
Fine specimen.
I saw you knock
him off the bar.
No, I kind of shoot it,
I didn’t really knock it.
You raised your
hand at him.
Won't happen again,
I promise you.
Hey Martz, how about
another drink?
That cat's been coming
in here for 2 years.
It's got more right
to be here than you.
I don't want any trouble.
That's too bad,
cause you...
I know who you are.
Murderer of innocent
travellers on the road.
You are going to be
held to account
for the things you've
done, do you know that?
It's okay.
I'm going to grab my things,
and walk out of here.
- Alright, brother?
- Yeah.
Cursed be the ground,
for our sake.
Of thorns and thistles, it
shall bring forth, for us.
For out of the ground
we were taken
for the dust we are.
And to the dust
we shall return.
Stop!
Please.
Redbridge!
Redbridge.
- And who are you?
- Nobody.
Oh, I doubt that.
The men you killed in my bar.
They were nobody.
- But you now...
- He isn’t got the shakes.
He isn’t one of them.
Good. This is a
civilized town.
We don't eat humans.
We don't see too many
people from before.
Not anymore.
- Do you read?
- Every day.
How good for you.
Me too.
You know what's funny?
As old as we are,
people like you and me,
we're the future.
What do you want with me?
Straight to the point.
I like that.
You're not just educated.
I never saw anyone handle
themselves the way you did
I don’t know
where you learned it,
but I sure as
hell could use it.
It's a little town,
is just the beginning.
I’m about to expand.
I need expert help.
I could use
someone like you.
Thank you. But I'm
really not interested.
People who work for
me live better than
any worker dreamed.
Ask Redbridge, here.
Ask the boys, anyone.
Real beds,
hot food, women.
Clean water.
You could do a lot
worse, my friend.
Thank you.
But I got
somewhere I need to be.
Where?
West.
There is nothing west.
I've been told different.
By who?
Tell you what.
Stay the night.
Try a little of
our hospitality,
See how you like it.
We'll talk again
in the morning.
Word of advice, Walker.
It's not a choice.
There's always a choice.
There'll be someone
outside your room all night.
- If you need anything.
- I don’t need anything.
You never know.
This is for you. It's
water for washing
and some food, some
special dessert too,
compliments of the house.
I need you to take
this or say something,
so I can find you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Can I get you
anything else?
No, I'm fine, thank you.
You get blinded in the war?
Or the sun after?
I was born this way.
I think probably I'm
lucky because I was
already used to being
like this by the time
it happened.
Well, thank you,
for the food.
You're welcome.
I like your perfume.
It's just shampoo.
But thank you.
Good night.
I don't think he's
going to change his mind
by the morning.
He's not going to stay.
He's different
than the others.
You're not going to be
able to make him do
what you want him to do.
Who said anything about me?
I'll send Solara.
You can't do that.
It's about time I got
better use out of her.
Don't do that... Please.
Please, don’t. Please.
Can I come in?
Give me a minute.
Somebody already came
with food and water.
I got everything
I need.
Are you sure
about that?
It's really bright in here.
- I'm Solara.
- Right
You filled my canteen
downstairs.
Yeah. You're that
walker, right?
Right.
If you're worried about
paying its on the house.
Paying for what?
Why don't you
take a seat?
No.
No, I can't go.
I can't.
If I do he'll hurt my mom.
- Who?
- Carnegie.
- He's your father?
- No
We belong to him
just the same.
I'll sleep on
the floor.
Tomorrow you can
tell him you had
a good time. I promise you,
I will be no trouble.
Please.
Knight to b4.
Your move.
- So... how old are you?
- Excuse me?
I haven’t really seen
too many people
your age come
through here before.
Well, it's been...
30 winters since
the flash.
I really don’t remember.
Do you remember
what it was like?
- In the world before.
- Yeah
What was it like?
People had more
than they needed.
We had no idea what was
precious and what wasn't.
We threw away things
that people would
kill each other for now.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You have a book.
Can I see it?
No, you cannot.
I just want to
look at it.
I can't even read, please
let me just see it.
What is with you?
It is just a book.
It's not just a book.
What do you mean
it's not just a book?
No more questions
about the book, okay?
No more questions.
I got a question for you,
since you're here.
Maybe I'll answer it.
Maybe I won't.
Where do you get
your water?
I can't tell you that.
You can't tell me
or you don’t know?
Oh, I know.
But if you're not
talking about the book,
I'm not talking
about the water.
You're something else.
Alright, I got another
question for you.
Great.
You hungry?
There's a lot of food there.
More than I can eat.
Tell you what. We
can share it,
like old people used to.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Wait a minute.
Sit.
Sit down.
Give me your hands.
What are you doing?
Trust me, give me
your hands.
Close your eyes.
Dear Lord, we thank
you for this meal.
We thank you for
a warm bed and
roof over our head
on cold nights,
such as this.
- It's been too long.
- Is this from the book?
Close your eyes.
We thank you for the
gift of companionship,
in hard times like these.
Amen.
Now we eat?
Now we eat.
Morning, Solara.
How was your night?
Did you sleep well?
- I did what you said.
- Of course you did.
but I said: Did it work?
- Is he staying?
- We didn't do much talking.
Solara, honey, eat something.
Mom, give me your hand.
Close your eyes.
Mom, trust me.
Dear Lord.
We thank you for our food.
Thank you for my mother.
Thank you for the
roof over our heads.
And...
Well I guess that’s
all for now.
Amen.
That's the word
you're looking for.
Amen.
That's how you stop.
You said you
didn't talk much.
But did he do any reading?
- I asked you a question.
- Bill, don't.
You shut your mouth.
Stop!
You're hurting your
mother, Solara.
He said he read
every day. Did he?
Your mother, would
like you to talk.
I don’t know!
I don’t know.
Yes, okay. Yes,
he was reading.
What kind of book
was he reading?
I don't know, an
old leather one.
And?
I don't know, it had
some thing on the front.
Tell me.
I need you to let her go.
Show me!
Redbridge!
Shit! I stayed
up all night.
Where is he?
I don’t...
I just want to
make sure...
...there's no
acid in there.
Doesn't matter, just
take these off.
- Take them off.
- Let me dry...
- Hey!
- Alright!
Thank you. You can tell
them I made you do it.
- Say it.
- You made me do it.
Is that thing loaded?
I don't think
it's loaded.
One way to find out.
Look, I need that book.
I mean I want
the book. And you.
If you make me choose,
I'll kill you,
I'll take the book.
Why? Why do you want it?
I grew up with it.
I know its power.
And if you read it,
then so do you.
That's why they burned
them all after the war.
Just staying alive
is an act of faith,
building this town
is an even bigger
act of faith. But they
don't understand that.
None of them do.
And I don’t have the
right words to help them,
but the book does.
And I admit...
I've had to do things,
many many things
I hate to build this,
I confess that.
But if we had that book,
I wouldn't have to.
Can you imagine how
different, how righteous
this little world
could be if we had
the right words for our faith.
The people would truly
understand why
they're here and what
they're doing,
they wouldn't need any
other uglier motivations.
It's not right to keep
that book hidden away,
it's meant to be
shared with others.
It's meant to be spread.
Isn't that what you want?
With all my heart and soul.
I always believed that
I'd find a place where
this book belongs,
where it was needed.
I haven't found it yet.
I love this guy.
Shoot him. Please.
What are you
standing around for?
Take him out, goddamnit!
Take him out!
I don't like being followed.
I want to come with you.
- No you don't.
- I hate it here.
Then change it.
My mother thinks I'll
be safer with you.
I'll take you to where
we get our water.
You can have all
that you can carry.
I mean all that
we can carry.
Carnegie knows about two
more springs up North.
He says he's going to
build more towns.
How did he know
about this one?
He's been here.
When he was young.
In the world before.
I guess everyone else
who knew about it died.
We really better hurry.
Shoot.
I think I left my
glasses inside.
Can you take a look for me?
I'll look out here.
What are you doing?
You are such a liar.
I'm not a liar.
You said I could
come with you,
if you got your water.
I didn't say that.
You said that.
Besides, the road's
no place for you.
Much worse than
you think.
Good bye, Solara.
Nice knowing you,
I mean that.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
Fuck you!
Have you washed your
filthy fucking hands?
Twice, Sir.
With your soap.
Put a crew together.
We're going after them.
- For a fucking book.
- It's not a fucking book!
It's a weapon!
A weapon that aims
right at the hearts
and minds of the
weak and desperate.
It will give us
control of them!
If we want to rule more
than one small fucking town,
we have to have it.
People will come from
all over and do exactly
what I tell them if the
words are from the book.
It's happened before,
and it will happen again.
All we need is that book.
Then I want Solara.
Are you
bargaining with me?
Is this a deal
we're making?
We lost a lot of men.
You need me
more than ever.
When you say that
book's worth the trouble.
Well I believe you.
But I want Solara for it.
Why not?
Let's get the
fuck out of here.
Which way are
we heading?
West.
Hello?
Can anyone help me?
Hello, is anybody there?
Are you okay?
Oh, yeah, I'm fine.
You go along,
I'll be okay.
- Let me just...
- No! Really, please!
I'm fine, really. I need
a man to help me...
You just go along.
It's okay, it will just
take a minute.
I'm fine. Please...
Help!
Get off me!
Hold them there.
- What's wrong?
- Did you hear that?
Don't move.
Take the wire off
of that. Spool it up.
- What is that?
- Dinner.
It's like he's
protected somehow.
Like there's nothing
that can touch him.
He's just a fucking man.
You put a bullet in him
he'll go down
like any other man.
Still warm.
No more than a
few hours dead.
He can't be far.
Son of a bitch.
Solara.
You sure you
still want her?
It's going to be
dark soon.
We can't track
them at night,
they'll see us coming.
We'll drive right past
them and never know it.
He's right.
They're on foot. Tired.
They'll have to sleep.
We'll make up the
ground tomorrow.
We'll have them
before morning, Sam.
That better be
a guarantee.
Do you really read the
same book every day?
Without fail.
Will you read some to me?
Please.
The Lord is my Sheppard.
I shall not want;
He makes me to lie down
in green pastures.
He leads me beside
still waters;
He restores my soul.
He leaded me in paths
of righteousness
for His name's sake.
Yea, though I walk
through the valley
of the shadow
of death,
I will fear no evil;
for Thou art with me
- That's beautiful.
- You like that?
- Did you write that?
- Yes I did.
- Really?
- No.
That was around
a long time before
you and I got here,
that’s for sure.
What did you mean
when you said it's
not just any book?
It's the only one.
Really?
After the war people
made it their business
to find and destroy any
that the fires didn't get already,
some people say this
was the reason
for the war in the first place.
Anyway, it's the only
one that survived.
How did you get it?
They said that the war,
tore a hole in the sky.
You probably
heard the stories.
Yeah.
Tore a hole in the sky,
sun came down,
and burned everything.
Everything and
everybody.
You were lucky, to
hole up and hide in
a place like this,
or underground.
Most people weren't lucky.
So, a year later we
started coming out.
People wandering around.
Not knowing what
I was going to do.
Trying to find a place to survive.
One day, I heard a voice.
It's hard to explain,
but it was like if it was
coming from inside of me.
But I could hear it as
clear as I can hear you
talking to me now.
What did this voice say?
It led me ... to a place
where I found the book ...
buried, under some rubble.
The voice told me to
carry the book out West.
It told me a path had
been laid out for me,
that I'd be led to a
place where the book
would be safe.
Told me that I'd
be protected,
against any one or anything
that stood in my path.
I've been walking ever since.
And you did all that
because a voice
in your head told
you to.
Yes, I did.
I know what I heard.
I know what I hear.
I know I'm not crazy.
And I know I would
have never made it,
without help.
- What's that?
- One question too many.
Go to bed, we've got an
early start in the morning.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry, I thought
you were sleeping.
I wasn't sleeping.
What are you doing?
I just wanted to
see the book.
Nobody touches it but
me, you understand me?
- Do you understand me?
- Yes, I understand.
Go to sleep.
You said you don't know
how to read anyway.
It's of no use to you.
Yeah.
So teach me.
Hold on. Hold up.
Stop!
You say you've been
walking for 30 years, right?
Right.
Have you ever thought
maybe you were lost?
No.
How do you know you're
walking in the right direction?
I walk by faith,
not by sight.
- What does that mean?
- It means you know something,
even if you don't
know something.
It doesn't make
any sense.
It doesn't have to
make sense. It's faith.
Its a flower of light,
in a field of darkness,
giving me the strength
to carry on, understand?
Is that from
your book?
No, it's Johnny Cash.
'Live from Folsom Prison'.
What?
Do you think anyone
lives there?
I don’t know.
Maybe there's water.
Stay behind me.
This is weird.
Who are you?
Travellers, that’s all.
Don't mean any harm.
No trespassing. Didn't
you read the sign?
We're very sorry,
I didn't see it.
- What's your business?
- We were just...
No business.
We're very sorry,
and if you let us,
we'll be on our way.
George, look at them.
One of them is
just a girl.
Old story. Heard it a
hundred times before.
We get so few
visitors these days,
George is suspicious
of everybody.
I'm Martha.
Would you care
for some tea?
How about some music?
It's so soothing.
George!
You can ring my bell,
ring my bell.
How do you like it?
You can ring my bell,
ring my bell.
- Is that good?
- Good, good.
Great.
It's amazing that you
two have survived
out here all by
yourselves.
Well, now. George is
something of a handyman.
He did a lot of
work on this place,
making it safe.
We may be old, but
we're resilient.
We've had more
than a few try to take
this place from us.
Haven't we George?
Yes we have.
I want to show you
something, come on.
George, no. Not now.
Come on!
- Are these...?
- Graves? Sure.
It'd be uncivilized
not to bury them.
Besides, it's good
for the soil.
Come on back inside.
I might be able to rustle
you up some sandwiches.
Well, thank you. Thank
you very much.
- We got to go now.
- They killed all these people.
They didn't just kill
them. They ate them.
- Their hands are shaking.
- Too much human meat.
Let's go.
I found some meat.
I hope you're hungry.
No. No, thank you.
- Well, we got to be going.
- So soon?
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
Are you sure you
won't stay?
I'm sure. Very sure.
Put the gun down.
Sorry. Take this. Open
the door for us, please.
- Thank you for the tea.
- Thank you so much.
Go back inside.
George, what's wrong?
A whole company of armed
degenerates, that’s what's wrong,
and they led them
straight to us.
I just set out the
good china.
Fuck the china.
Have you got any
more weapons?
Weapons? I'll show
you some weapons.
Come on.
We know you're
in there.
Come on out and nobody
needs to get hurt.
I'll make it easy.
Send out Solara
with the book.
What are we going to do?
I know what the
fuck I'm doing.
Wait, wait.
-- That's all I want
is the book!
And the girl.
They isn’t coming out.
Shit! Get down!
Everybody down!
Hey! You know that
voice you heard?
Did he say anything
about this?
We'll get out alive.
Both of us.
What about us?
Didn't mention you.
Cease fire!
Cease fire.
Motherfuckers!
Over on the side!
Fucking bastards!
Hold your fire!
- What are they doing?
- Nothing good.
Where is the book?
Check his pack.
It isn’t here.
This is your last chance.
You give it up, or
I swear I'll bury
you out here.
Son-of-a...
Let's try this again.
- Carnegie!
- What!?
Now. Where's the book?
Give him the book.
Please.
Don't tell him.
It's in the house.
Back of the TV.
- Go check the TV.
- The what?
You're fucking shitting me.
You go!
Go!
Ask and you
shall receive.
God is good,
is he not?
All the time.
Not all the time.
No!
You see?
What did I tell you?
He's just a man.
No! Leave him alone!
Where's your protection now?
Hmm?
Pray for me.
Okay?
I mean it.
Shit.
Go back!
Come on.
Come on!
We've barely got enough
fuel to make it back.
Do you want to
go after her?
No.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going West.
Got to go West.
Hey.
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
This. This is
all my fault.
- No, it's not.
- Yeah it is,
if I didn't come with
you, none of this
would have happened.
It's not your fault.
Did what I had to do.
Didn't think anything
could make you
give up that book.
You know, for years
I've been carrying and
reading it every day.
I got so caught up
with keeping it safe
I forgot to live by
what I learned from it.
Yeah? What's that?
Just to...
Do for others more than
you do for yourself.
It's what I got
from it anyway.
Do you smell that?
- What?
- In the air. Salt.
We're getting close
to the ocean.
That's it.
Get the Engineer!
That's far enough!
What's your
business here?
My name is Eli.
I have a King James
Bible in my possession.
Remain where you are.
Don't attempt to make
any sudden moves, or
you will be fired upon.
Be careful with it.
Thank you.
Careful with it.
Wait.
We've been doing this
for a long time now.
Feels like a museum.
Oh no.
It's much more than that.
This is where we're
going to start again.
We've got a printing
press that will be
operational quite soon.
We're going to teach
people about the
world they lost.
Help them start
to rebuild it.
And look, Shakespeare,
Britannica.
Missing only a
few volumes.
There's a whole series
of beautiful Mozart
and Wagner records. Still
in very pristine condition.
But never a Bible.
Well, not until now.
May I ask what
condition it's in?
It's beat up. But it
will do the job.
Do you think
I could see it?
Yes, you may.
- That's it. It's open.
- Good.
Do you have anything
to write on?
Could you get us some
writing paper, please?
A lot of it.
A whole lot of it.
It can't be.
It's impossible!
It can't be!
Pay close attention.
And write down
everything I say.
Exactly as I say it.
The first book of Moses.
Called Genesis.
Chapter one,
verse one:
"In the beginning God
created the heavens
and the earth. "
Verse two:
"And the earth was
without form and void;
and darkness was upon
the face of the deep.
And the Spirit of God
was hovering
over the face
of the waters. "
Verse three:
"And God said, Let
there be light:
and there was light. "
Where is Solara?
Out there. Her choice.
I tried to bring her
back. She refused.
What did you do
when she refused?
Read it.
What did you do
to my daughter?
Read it!
What did you do
to my daughter!?
You can start anytime.
Sorry.
It's been so long
I don’t remember.
- You have to.
- I have to? Really?
You have to. Please.
- Your leg.
- It doesn't hurt anymore.
I can smell it.
You worked so hard
for that book.
You sacrificed so
much, so many men.
More than you
could spare.
Now, all those people
who were too scared
to even say your name.
They're downstairs,
tearing up the bar right
now, did you know that?
And there's no one
there to stop them.
And you are feverish.
I can't imagine what
it must feel like to
have what you want
so close and it might
as well be a
million miles away.
Stop it!
Are you leaving me?
Claudia?
Claudia!?
Claudia!
Dear Lord. Thank you for
giving me the strength
and the conviction to
complete the task you
entrusted to me.
Thank you for guiding
me straight and true,
through the many
obstacles on my path.
And for keeping me
resolute when all around
seemed lost.
Thank you for your
protection and for your
many signs along
the way.
Thank you for any good
that I may have done,
I'm so sorry
about the bad.
You don't have to
leave, you know.
You're very welcome
to stay here.
You'll be perfectly safe.
Thank you.
But this is something
that I have to do.
Where will you go?
Home.
Thank you for the
friend I made.
Please watch over her,
as you watched over me.
Thank you for finally
allowing me to rest.
I'm so very tired.
But I go now to my
rest at peace.
Knowing that I've done
right with my time
on this earth.
I fought the good fight.
I finished the race.
I kept the faith.