[ Narrator] Legend has it,
in the mystic land of Prydain,
there was once a king
so cruel and so evil...
that even the gods
feared him.
Since no prison
could hold him,
he was thrown alive
into a crucible ofmolten iron.
There, his demonic spirit
was captured...
in the form
ofa great Black Cauldron.
For uncounted centuries,
the Black Cauldron
lay hidden, waiting,
while evil men
searched for it,
knowing whoever possessed it
would have the power...
to resurrect an army
ofdeathless warriors...
and, with them,
rule the world.
[ Man] There's something wrong.
I can feel it in my bones.
- [ Bones Cracking]
- The Fairfolk know it too.
- You don'tsee any ofthem around.
- [ Meows]
The Horned King,
that blackhearted devil.
- [Continues Meowing]
-What's he waiting for?
Yes,yes, cat.
I knowyou wantyour breakfast,
but,just now,
thinking is more important.
[Sighs, Gasping]
Taran,
the pot is boiling over!
-[ Pot Boiling]
-Oh, Dallben. I was justthinking.
What ifthe war's over,
and I never had a chance to fight?
Hmm, and a good thing too.
War isn'ta game.
People get hurt.
But I'm notafraid.
Ouch !
[Chuckling]
Yes,there you are.
Ifthe Horned King
ever returns,
you'll have a great deal more
to worry about...
than a burned finger.
No, no, no, cat. That is not foryou.
It's for Hen Wen.
Hen Wen, Hen Wen.
It's always Hen Wen !
And one day, my boy,
you may learn why.
Now, no more dreaming.
You have chores to do.
Yes, sir.
[Sighs]
He's so anxious...
and so blind
to the dangers ahead.
Look, cat. You're in luck.
Justenough left foryou.
Hmm.
- [ Quacking]
- Dallben doesn't understand.
I'm not a little boy
anymore.
[Squawking]
I should be doing heroic deeds
for Prydain, notwaiting
hand and footon a spoiled--
Hey!
[Chuckles]
Oh, all right, Hen.
I didn't mean it.
You'd bettereat it.
Dallben made it
especially foryou.
Is this to be my life ?
Pampering a pig ?
I'm a warrior
nota pig keeper.
Dallben thinks I'd be afraid,
but I wouldn't.
All I need is a chance,
and I could be
a famous warrior.
Look atme, Hen !
I can do it! Ha !
[Squealing]
[ Taran Laughing]
Even you're afraid.
-[ Quacking]
-Do you challenge me ? Run,you cowards.
[Squawking]
-There you are.
- [ Bleats]
His Majesty,
the Horned King.
So we meetat last.
Ha !
[ Laughing] Even the Horned King
shakes with fear.
See, Hen? Everybody runs
from the famous Taran of Caer Dallben !
[ Laughing]
[Groans, Coughing]
Prydain's finestwarrior...
draws his last... breath.
Dallben.
Hmm, notquite the blade
for a hero.
[Stammering] I was--
It's justthatwe were--
Hen Wen got dirty.
[ Dallben] Oh, I see.
Another dream,Taran ?
But, Dallben,won't I ever be anything
butan assistant pig keeper?
She's a special pig,Taran.
- [Snorting]
- [Chuckles]
Now, give her a nice bath.
Well, Hen,
it looks as though...
I'll still be an assistant pig keeper
when I'm as old as Dallben.
[ Laughs] You like that, don'tyou ?
[ Laughing] Nowforthe part
you like best.
Hey, come on, Hen.
I haven'tfinished scrubbing your ba--
- [Squealing]
- Hen,what's the matter?
Calm down, Hen.
- [Continues Squealing]
-Stop it, please ! What's the matter?
- Hen Wen--
-Taran,what's going on ?
I-I don't know.
There's something wrong
with Hen Wen.
What? Quickly, lad.
Bring her inside.
-[ Taran] What's that for?
- Put Hen Wen down.
I never use her powers
unless I have to,
but now I must.
- ''Powers'' ?
-Taran,whatyou are aboutto see,
you must never reveal to anyone.
Hen Wen,from you,
I do beseech...
knowledge that lies
beyond my reach,
troubled thoughts
beyond your heart.
Pray you now
those thoughts impart.
[ Dallben Sighs] The Horned King.
- [Gasps]
-Shh-shh-shh. Don't interfere.
He is searching.
The Black Cauldron !
-So that's it.
- ''The Black Cauldron'' ?
[ Dallben] An awesome weapon, Taran.
It's been hidden
forcenturies,
but ifthe Horned King
should find it...
and unleash its power,
nothing could stand
against him.
[ Taran] That's Hen Wen.
[ Dallben] He knows.
Stop ! Enough !
You must leave here atonce.
Take Hen Wen
to the hidden cottage...
atthe edge
ofthe forbidden forest.
Hide there and never bring her out
until I come foryou.
''Hide'' ? Butwhy?
Only I knewthe secret
of Hen Wen's power,
but nowthe Horned King
has discovered it.
We mustmake sure he never uses
itto find the Black Cauldron.
I'm notafraid
ofthe Horned King.
Then you are a very foolish lad.
Untried courage is no match
for his evil.
Just rememberthat.
Now, off you go,
my boy,
and take care
of yourself.
Good-bye, Dallben.
I won'tfailyou.
So much, so soon...
to rest
on his young shoulders.
[ Thunder Rumbling]
Oh,yes.
Yes, my soldiers.
Soon the Black Cauldron
will be mine.
Its evil powerwill course
through my veins,
and I shall make you...
Cauldron born.
Yes. Yes. Oh,yes.
Then you will worship me!
Me.
Oh, my soldiers.
How long
I have thirsted...
to be a god...
among mortal men.
[ Taran] Gosh, Hen Wen.
I never knew...
you could create visions
and things like that.
I thoughtyou were just
an ordinary pig.
I had no idea
you were so... special.
Dallben's going to be glad
that he put his trust in me.
Justyou waitand see.
Now, don't go
wandering about.
And don'tyou worry.
Keep close to me,
and no one
will do you any harm.
Notwhile I'm around.
- I won't letthe Horned King
getclose to you, Hen.
- [Sniffing]
- I'll protectyou.
-[ Crowd Cheering]
[ Cheering Continues]
[ Man] Taran ofCaer Dallben,
the greatestwarrior
in all Prydain,
a true hero!
[ Crowd Cheering]
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you all.
Butwithoutthe help of my pig,
Hen Wen, here, I--
Hen Wen,where are you ?
Hen Wen ?
Oh, no !
Hen ?
[ Echoing]
Hen Wen !
[ Twigs Cracking, Wings Flapping]
Is thatyou, Hen ?
Look what I've got.
-Come on out. Here's a lovely--
-[ Yelling]
[ Laughing, Kissing]
Ooh, great prince. Give poor, starving
Gurgi munchings and crunchings.
Nice apple.
Good prince. Good apple.
Oh, boy, what a juicy apple.
** [ Humming]
Hey. No,you don't!
I didn't give you thatapple.
You took it. Ow!
Hey, hold on,you hairy, little thief.
Come back with my apple !
If you don't give it back,
you'll be sorry. I mean it.
I'm warning you.
Give it back.
Come on. The apple--
Where is it?
Uh-uh. Gurgi not know
where the ap-- Uh-oh.
Give it back.
I warn you.
[Slurping]
Come on.
-Aha.
-Come on,the apple. Let's have it.
You horrible,
greedy thing.
You should be ashamed
of yourself!
Oh, poor,
miserable Gurgi deserves...
fierce smackings and whackings
on his poor,tender head.
[Sniffling] Always leftwith
no munchings and crunchings.
[Sobbing]
Forgive poor Gurgi.
Oh, stop thatsniveling.
I'm not going to hurtyou.
Now, look here.
Have you seen my pig ?
Piggy?
Round,fat piggy?
- Big snout? [Snorting]
- Yes,yes.
-Curly tail ?
-That's her. That's Hen Wen !
Uh-uh. Nope.
Gurgi notsee piggy. Nope.
Oh, nevermind.
No telling where
Hen Wen is by now.
Ooh, master, master.
Now Gurgi remembers ! Yes,yes !
Clever, sharp-eyed Gurgi saw
the piggy run. [ Imitates Hoofbeats]
Yes, rightthrough the forest!
Mm-hmm. I saw it! I saw it!
Come !
Gurgi will find the lost piggy.
Then we'll be friends
forever.
Munchings and crunchings
in here somewhere.
-[ Distressed Squealing]
- It's Hen Wen ! She's in trouble !
Good-bye.
Hen Wen !
Hen !
[ Squealing Continues]
-[ Flying Creatures Squawking]
- Hen Wen !
- [ Hen Wen Squealing]
- [ Roaring]
[ Taran] Hen Wen, look out!
[ Roars]
[ Hen Wen Squealing]
[ Taran] Look out!
[Continues Squealing]
Come on ! Hurry, Hen !
No ! Don't! Hen, hurry!
[ Panicked Squealing]
Don't! No !
No ! No !
[ Roars]
No ! Come back!
Please !
No ! No ! Come back!
[Grunts]
[ Thunderclap]
[ Hen Wen Squealing]
[ Panting]
Hen Wen.
I must get her
outofthere.
[ Gurgi] Oh, no, great lord.
Not go in there.
Forgetthe piggy.
-Whatare you doing here ?
-Gurgi come back to be yourfriend.
''Friend'' ?
You're no friend !
Why,you ran awaywhen I--
Oh, nevermind.
I promised Dallben
I would keep Hen safe.
I have to go.
- [Thunder Rumbling]
-Well, uh, are you coming ?
Me ? Go in there ?
Oh, no, no, no.
It's a terrible place.
Justas I thought.
You're no friend.
You're just
a miserable coward.
Here. This is all
you wanted.
[Sniffs]
If great lord go
into evil castle,
poor Gurgi will never see
his friend again.
Nope. Never.
[Thunderclap]
[ Snoring]
[ Snoring Continues]
[Continues Snoring]
[Snarling, Barking]
[ Snarling, Barking Continue]
[ Henchman] Shut up,
you thick-skulled dolt.
Always barking at nothing.
-All right,
mightas well make our rounds.
- [Growling]
[ Door Creaking]
[ Men Chattering]
[Chattering, Laughing]
Here's to everybody!
More wine and meat
formy men !
-And more women.
- [Screams]
Quiet. I'm trying to sleep.
[ Laughing]
- [ Henchmen Cheering, Hooting]
- How abouta kiss, princess ?
Gad,you're a lovely one !
-Come on!
- Here.
Keep your hands off,
you little creeper.
Going somewhere,
Creeper?
[ Henchmen Laughing]
Kiss me, love, and I'll die
with a smile on my face.
[ Eerie Howling]
[ Electrical Crackling]
[Gasps]
[ Laughing]
Welcome,Your Majesty.
We're justcelebrating
our success.
Oh, I mean your success.
We've made no mistakes,
this time.
[ Laughing, Panting]
Bring in the prisoner!
[ Taran Whispers] Oh, no.
[ Laughing]
There, sire.
This is the pig thatcreates visions.
[ Laughing]
All right,pig,
show His Majesty...
where the Black Cauldron
can be found !
Go on!
Show it!
[ Laughing]
Stubborn little thing, isn'tshe ?
[Gasping, Laughing]
Yes, sire. You're quite right.
I'll take care of itatonce.
The Black Cauldron.
Where is it?
-Show us, swine !
- [Gasps]
I warn you.
The King's patience is short.
No !
[ Banner Rips]
[ Henchmen Chattering]
Get him! The sneaking, no-good--
Get back, or I'll--
[ Mumbles, Grunts]
Oh.
- [Chuckling]
-[ Creeper] Release him.
What?
Well, here.
Hen Wen.
Oh, Hen Wen.
There,there.
I presume, my boy,
you are the keeper
ofthis oracular pig.
[Stammering]
Yes, sir.
Then instruct her
to showme...
the whereabouts...
ofthe Black Cauldron.
Oh, sir, I-I-I can't.
I promised.
Verywell.
In thatcase,
the pig is no use to me.
[ Creeper Laughing]
- [ Hen Wen Squealing]
-Whatare you going to do ?
No ! You can't!
-Don't!
- [Squeals]
[ Taran] No! Stop!
I'll make hertellyou.
That's better.
Now, geton
with the vision, pig.
Hen Wen,from you,
I do beseech...
knowledge that lies
beyond my reach.
[ Laughing] Look! Look, sire !
It's working !
[ Horned King Sighs]
The Black Cauldron.
So it does exist.
Go on.
Yes,yes.
Where is it?
Showme.
- [Screams]
- [ Horned King Screaming]
-Come on, Hen !
- [ Hissing]
Afterthem !
Getthem ! Afterthem !
- [ Henchmen Shouting]
- [Chains Clanking]
[Squawking, Gasping]
- [Creeper Laughing]
- [ Butcher Grunts]
- [Taran Gasps]
-Gotcha, pig boy!
[Screaming]
[ Henchmen Shouting]
The moat.
It's our only chance.
[Grunting]
Come on, Hen.
-[ Henchmen Shouting]
- [Taran Grunting]
- [Squeals]
-[ Taran] Swim, Hen! Swim!
- I'm coming ! [Gasps]
- [Creeper Laughing]
Gotcha, pig boy!
I caught him,Your Majesty!
I caughtthe boy.
Butyou letthe pig go,
didn'tyou ?
Itwasn'tmy fault.
[ Laughs]
[Gasping]
Throwthe boy into the dungeon !
[ Henchmen Chuckling]
[ DoorSlams]
[ Dallben's Voice] You must make sure
he never uses Hen Wen...
to find the Black Cauldron.
[ Taran's Voice] I won't
fail you, Dallben.
Look at me, Hen!
I can do it!
[ Echoing]
[Crying]
I can do it. I can do it.
[Continues Crying]
[ Stone Moving]
[ Taran Gasps]
Hmm, I thought
I heard a noise in here.
Oh ! Was thatyou ?
-Yeah. Yes.
- You're being held
a prisoner, aren'tyou?
-Yes.
-I'm being held against my will too.
[Gasps]
It lights up.
[ Girl Giggles] Ofcourse.
It's magic.
Oh, I hate this place.
I do hope
there aren'tany rats in here.
Notthat I really mind them,
you know,
butthey do jump out
atone so.
I'm Princess Eilonwy.
Are you a lord or a warrior?
No.
I'm an assistant pig keeper.
Oh,whata pity.
I was so hoping for someone
who could help me escape.
Oh,well, if you want
to come with me,you may.
-Can I ?
-Yes. I said you could.
Oh,thatwicked,
wicked king.
You know he stole me. He thought
my bauble could tell him...
where some
old cauldron was.
That's what
he wanted my pig for.
[ Eilonwy] Oh,yes. Your pig.
Butmy pig
can tell the future.
Ooh, how interesting.
[Giggles]
Well,you'd better stay close
to me, oryou'll get lost.
[ Rats Screeching]
[ Hissing]
-Your bauble.
- It's always chasing those rats.
[ Eilonwy Gasps] A burial chamber.
This could be the tomb ofthe great king
who built this castle...
before the Horned King
took it over.
[Gasping, Groaning]
[Coughing]
Are you all right?
[Sighs]
Well, come on,then.
Help me look around.
[ Taran] He must have been
a greatwarrior.
[ Gasps]
Asword.
[Gasps]
[ Cart Approaching]
[ CreeperChuckling]
This will please him.
It's a good lotthis time.
Hurry! In with it!
Finally,
he'll reward me forthis.
[Chuckling, Grunting]
- [ Panting]
- Don'tstop,you weakling !
Putsome muscle into it.
[ Panting, Grunting]
Let's getoutof here
before they come back.
[Gasps]
Where did you getthatsword ?
- Back there.
-You mean--
Well, he's not going to use it.
[Sighs]
[ Dog Barking]
[ Man] You're making a horrendous
mistake. I'm not a spy.
I'm a bard.
I-I-I sing.
-I-I-I entertain. I-I--
-[ Barking Continues]
Careful, sir.
These are the hands of an artist.
- [Groaning]
-This will hold you.
Look,you seem an intelligent
sort of chap to me. Eh ?
[ Chuckles] I assure you, I had
no idea who owned this castle.
- Ijust happened to be passing.
- [Growling]
He's nice, isn't he ?
What's his name ? [Whistles]
- [ Ferocious Barking]
- [Screams, Stammering]
Down, boy! Down !
- [ Barking, Growling]
-[ Henchman] Come on.
[ Bard] You don't realize who I am.
I shall sing
of your dastardly deed.
I'm Fflewddur Fflam,
minstrel of minstrels !
Balladeerto the grandestcourts
in all the land !
And I--
Well, have you forgotten ?
I have sung in some
ofthe finestcourts.
I'm onlywaiting
for an invitation.
- [ Bass String Snaps]
-Oh, shush.
Why do you have to judge
everyword I say? [Gasps]
Who's that?
Help !
Oh, hello. We'll have you
untied in a moment.
I'm Princess Eilonwy...
and you're in bad trouble,
aren'tyou ?
''Trouble'' ?
Don'tyou knowwhere you are ?
Haven'tyou seen him ?
[ Henchman] Pig boy has escaped.
Look in there.
-[ Taran Gasps] We've been discovered.
-That's you ?
Oh, great beelin.
Run ! Run !
Make haste !
''Make haste'' ?
I mustsave myself.
[Gasps]
[ Henchmen] I think he went
through the passage!
All right.
Let's try down here.
[ Henchmen Shouting]
Princess ?
Princess Eilonwy?
[ Roars]
Pig boy!
You little scut!
[Growls]
- [Grunting]
-[ Henchman Yells]
- [Gasping]
- [Continues Yelling]
Hey.
[ Drops Axe]
No, no, no.
[Chuckling]
[ Laughing]
Are you all right?
-Oh, good. You're safe.
-Why, of course. I--
-Come on. I'm going to getyou
outof here.
- [Screams]
-[ Henchman] There they are!
-Quick! Up here.
- [ Panting, Screams]
- [ Roars]
Taran,the sword.
[ Dog Barking, FflewddurShouting]
Help ! Murder!
[Gasping]
Don't!
Keep going, Princess.
[Sword Humming]
- [Taran Laughing]
-There he is ! There he is !
[Continues Laughing]
Overthere !
Stop him !
- [ Eilonwy] Taran !
- There they are!
-Come on ! Getthem !
-Oh, no ! Taran !
[ Creeper Laughing]
We've gotyou now,pig boy!
- [Growls]
- [Gasps]
Taran, do something !
- [Gasping]
- Use the sword !
[ Fflewddur] Make way! Make way!
Stand aside. I command you !
Getoutfrom undermy feet!
[Creeper Screams, Laughs]
[Whimpering]
Letme go,you brute !
[ Taran] Run, Princess! Run!
Stay up !
Please, stay up !
Why didn'tyou tell me
you had a magic sword ?
[Wheezing, Sighs]
I'll say itwasn'tmy fault.
That's it.
That's it. I always get blamed
forthese things.
[ Panting]
I'lljusttell him,
and if he gets mad...
[Groaning]
I'lljust
straighten him out.
That's it. I'm not going
to be kicked around forthis.
[ Knocking]
S-Sire ?
You bring news ofthe pig ?
No, notexactly, sire.
[Stammering]
Oh, it's the pig keeper.
He's-- Ooh, he's--
[ Stammering Continues]
He's... escaped.
[Gasps]
Oh. Oh. Oh, sire !
Allowme.
[Gasping]
[Continues Gasping]
Isn'tthatenough ?
Good.
He'll find his pig.
Send the gwythaints
to followthat boy.
Oh,yes, sire !
Oh,yes !
[ Laughing]
By all means, sire !
[ Creeper Laughing]
[Squawking]
[ FflewddurSinging]
* The world will applaud me *
* Its praise will reward me *
* And I, Fflewddur Fflam
will find fame **
[ Laughing]
They're almostfinished, Fflewddur.
Hmm, it's nottoo good,
but itwill hold for awhile.
Yes, I shall sing
of your deed.
Itwould be betterto sing
of our heroic escape.
Weren'tyou a bitfrightened,
Fflewddur?
A Fflam frightened ?
[ Laughs]
-The word is not in my vocabulary.
- [Strings Vibrating]
But in this case,
well-chosen, my dear.
- I wasn'tafraid.
-Ouch ! Notafraid ?
Why,we were running
for our lives.
Well, I got us out
ofthe castle, didn't I ?
You ? I'd say itwas
the sword's magic.
But ittakes a greatwarrior
to handle a sword like this.
Butstill,
it is a magic sword.
Ha ! What does a girl
know aboutswords anyway?
''Girl'' ? Girl ?
If itweren'tforthis girl,
you would still be
in the Horned King's dungeon.
Here now,
Princess Eilonwy,Taran.
At least I don't keep
talking about itforever.
Oh,you're so, so boring !
[Stammering]
Princess Eilonwy--
How dare you
take his side !
[Gasping]
I really didn't--
[Continues Stammering]
I didn'tmean to interfere,you know.
Silly girl.
Even if she is a princess.
[Gasps, Crying]
Butwe're going
to have to,to--
[Sighs, Mutters]
Dear, oh, dear.
- [Crying]
- Hello.
Hello.
Fflewddur is right,
you know.
We are going to have
to work together.
And we'll find your pig.
I'm sure it's important.
Thank you for getting me
outofthe dungeon.
Oh, butwe couldn't have
done itwithoutyou.
Well, at leastwe're all safe.
-[ FflewddurShouting] Great beelin!
- [Gasps] Fflewddur!
Help ! Murder!
[Gasping]
Hurry!
- [ Laughing] Gurgi's lucky day.
-Getthis thing off me.
-Wow.
-Yes, keep it! It's a gift!
-Wantthis. Gurgi wantthis.
-Go ahead.
- I'm sure you've murdered for less.
-[ Harp Twanging]
Want. Want.
Gurgi want!
-[ Gasping Continues]
-Gurgi.
- [Grunts]
- Master? Oh, old man fell down.
Get up. Get up.
[ FflewddurSighs]
Well, really.
Who is your pungent,
little friend ?
He's no friend of mine.
He's just a coward
and a thief.
[Scoffs]
Too big anyway.
[ Eilonwy Sighs]
[ Laughs]
You're charming.
-And pungenttoo.
- [ Laughing]
Well,whatare you
waiting for?
Yes,yes. That's it.
Toddle off. Toddle off.
[Scoffs]
Gurgi go !
Tracks ? Tracks !
Gurgi remember.
Saw piggy's tracks.
-You did ?
-Today!
-Today? Waita minute.
- He'll try anything.
Oh,you're both horrid.
He justmight know.
- Pretty lady come too ?
-Well, I--
-Yes,yes,yes !
Follow Gurgi ! Follow Gurgi !
- [ Laughing]
You better
be telling the truth.
Gurgi not lie,
notthis time.
See, master?
Piggy's footsteps.
No lie.
Oh, good.
They look fresh.
Oh, master. Master!
Gurgi, hold on !
[ Eilonwy] Oh, no! Taran!
-Give me your hand !
-We're doomed.
How did they
get in here ?
[ Laughing]
Old Doli's whirlpool broke again.
- [ Laughing]
- I bettheywake up soon.
We bettertell King Eidellig.
No, silly. You knowwe're not
supposed to be up here.
Uh-oh. We're all
going to be in trouble.
- Notme.
- Me either.
- Uh-oh.
- [Water Dripping]
Oh,yes. I see you fixed that.
Yep. When...
I getthis...
last peg in here,
I'll be finished.
Good. Hmm.
Yes. Thatshould work.
It's perfect.
Grab that pole !
[ Eidellig] Uh, I got it.
Oh, aren'tyou
all darling ?
[Stammering]
Uh, hello.
I'm King Eidellig
ofthe Fairfolk.
Howthe blazes did they--
[ King Eidellig] I thought I told you
to fix the whirlpool.
I fixed it. I did fix it!
Itwas perfect!
Evidently, notcompletely perfect.
It's supposed
to keep them out.
- Uh, can I be of any service ?
-Is everything that happens
around here my fault?
-Are you on a friendly visit?
-And I suppose it's my fault
the pig's here too !
- Hen Wen ?
-Oh, she's your pig ?
Oh, good.
One less thing
for old Doli to worry about.
-[ King Eidellig] Uh, Doli.
-[ Doli] What now?
- Would you hurry and fetch the pig?
-[ Doli Shouts]
- [ Muttering]
- [Giggling]
Hey,you kids.
Whatare you doing ?
Oh, Mr. Doli, Ijustwantto see
the pretty lady.
Well, now,you watch yourselves.
Hear?
I can't believe my eyes,
Your Majesty.
[ Laughing]
[ Doli] Watch it. Watch it!
[ Taran] Oh, Hen!
Thank goodness you're--
[ Laughing]
Tell me. Is the burning and killing
still going on up there ?
You refer
to that-that-that-that...
joke on humanity,
the Horned King.
Will no one
ever stand up to him ?
We've seen him, and if he finds
the Cauldron, he'll kill us all.
Oh, no, no.
He'll neverfind it.
No, no.
It's safely hid in Morva.
- ''Morva'' ?
-Well, at least I think it is.
Oh, Doli, is it?
-[ Clattering]
-[ Doli] Really?
Is that one ofmy new jobs,
remembering where
the Cauldron was lastseen?
[ Doli Laughing] Gee!
Oh, he'll know rightwhere it is.
You'll see.
Ifwe could get to the Cauldron
first and destroy it--
-Oh,this isn't right,Taran.
- But don'tyou see ?
Ifwe destroy the Cauldron,
itwill stop the Horned King.
Please, come with me.
Wait, I neverthought--
Morva.
-That's a hard place to getto.
-Yep.
-Why,you can take them.
-What?
Do you mean we're trusting
our lives to-to-to him?
-And what is wrong with me ?
- [Stammering] Oh, nothing.
-Splendid choice. [Chuckles]
- [Twanging, Snaps]
Shall we,then ?
[Groaning]
[ FflewddurSputtering]
Wait! Hen Wen !
Oh, don'tworry.
We'll get her home safely.
Oh,thank you, sir.
Be good, Hen.
[ Doli] Well, ifit's
the Marshes of Morva you wanted,
here you are.
Ooh !
Such a dreary place.
Let's see what it looks
like from up here.
I think we're lost.
[Sighs]
Are you sure this is
the right place, Doli ?
Yes, I'm sure !
Well, if you ask me--
[Sputtering]
[Yelling]
- Fflewddur! Doli !
-Are you all right?
[ Muffled ] Hey, look out,
you big, clumsy oaf!
Look where you--
Uh-oh.
Welcome to Morva.
Well, s-someone
must live here.
Gurgi not like this place.
Uh-uh. No.
Itseems empty.
Maybe we should
have a look.
If I can just
getthis door open.
Howwill we everfind the Black Cauldron
in a place like this ?
Itmust be here
somewhere.
[Gasps]
[ Door Creaking]
- [Croaking]
- [Screaming]
- [ Frog Croaks]
- They're only frogs, Eilonwy.
Those were people.
You mean theywere
turned into frogs ?
- [Grunts]
-Ooh, master, come quickly.
Gurgi found
the wicked Cauldron.
Quick, quick, quick!
Follow Gurgi !
- Behold, master.
-The whole room is full of cauldrons.
I don't understand.
Whywould,whywould
anyone wantso many--
[ Woman Screams]
Thieves! Thieves!
Someone stole
all ourfrogs!
You evil, nasty people.
You shall all be turned
into frogs and eaten !
Huh ?
[Cackling]
Nice and tender.
Stop that,you,you--
Oh. So nice to meetyou, ladies.
[ Nervous Chuckle]
-Good-bye. [Gasps]
- Wait.
My, aren'tyou
the handsome one ?
[Sputtering]
Wh-Who ? M-M-Me ?
Oh, honestly, now,
don'tyou find me
irresistible ?
Yes. Well, of course,
mostattractive.
- [Twanging]
-Shush ! Stop that.
You don'tmind if I...
pluck your harp,
- [Stammering]
-do you, handsome ?
Bah ! Enough ofthat
lovesick nonsense.
- [ Electricity Crackles]
-Great beelin' !
[Cackling]
Quick!
We're going to have
toad stew.
[ Blowing]
[Cackling]
You're not gonna eat
this one.
Come here, love.
-Can anyone here perform marriages ?
- Marriages ? [Sputtering]
You lovestruck witch !
Where is he ?
Where'd he go ?
Yoo-hoo !
Where are you ?
Don't go.
Now look whatyou've done.
- He's gone ! I'll never
forgive you forthis, Orgoch.
- [Sighs]
- Never!
- [ Panting]
Whoo ! There you are !
- [ Buzzing]
- [Slurps]
[ Witches Laughing]
Enough! We've come
forthe Black Cauldron.
Did you hearthat, sisters ?
Why, nobody's asked for
the Black Cauldron in over 2,000 years.
It's a trick. We're not going to let
them have it, are we ?
Don'tworry.
Leave itto me.
Perhaps I might interestyou
in something else:
a kettle, a cook pot,
a skillet, a teapot,
-a bucket, a jar, a platter?
- [Clattering]
See anything you like ?
I don't believe it.
[Clattering Continues]
I've never seen
a sword like that.
[Sighs]
I've gotto have
thatsword.
Listen carefully. We'll trade
the Cauldron forthe sword.
Butwhatcan they do
with the Cauldron, Orddu ?
Nothing ! That's the point.
Don'tyou see ?
We'll end up with both the sword
and the Cauldron. [Chuckles]
It's decided then.
You shall have the Black Cauldron.
You mean...
you'll give itto us ?
[ Laughs]
That's notwhat I said.
You weren't listening.
We never give anything away.
Whatwe do is bargain,
-trade.
-Well,you'll not have my sword !
May I ask you ladies to perhaps
considerthis magnificent harp ?
A harp ?
Oh,when we wantmusic,
we send forthe birds.
- [ Birds Chirping]
-Whatwould we do with a simple harp ?
Wait! Gurgi will trade
his crunchings and munchings.
-Who would want--
-Hold it, sister. Notso fast.
All right.
I knowwhatyou want.
Yes ?
No,Taran ! No !
It's our only chance.
Here is my sword.
Take it.
Is ityour own choice,
duckling ?
Remember:
With this sword,
you could be
the greatestofwarriors.
Yes. I offer
my dearest possession...
in exchange
forthe Black Cauldron.
Agreed. We have
made a bargain.
[ Laughter Echoing]
[ Pots Clattering]
-[ Taran] Look out!
- [Wind Whistling]
[ Doli] Help!
[ Creaking, Clattering]
[ Eilonwy] Taran, watch out!
- [Gasps] Great beelin' !
-[ Objects Crashing]
Duck!
[ Rumbling]
[Gasps]
Look!
- [ Roots Creaking]
-[ Rumbling Continues]
The Black Cauldron.
It's ours !
[ Witches Cackling]
[ Orddu] I say,
what funny little ducklings.
Don'tthey knowthe Black
Cauldron is indestructible ?
Now, listen carefully.
The Black Cauldron
can never be destroyed.
Only its evil powers
can be stopped.
Then there is a way.
But how?
A living being must
climb into it...
of his own free will.
Gurgi is bold and brave.
He will climb
into the evil Cauldron.
However, the poorduckling
will neverclimb out alive.
Yikes !
N-N-Now, look here, madam.
Don'tforgetwe had
an agreement.
Yes. You said we could
have the Cauldron.
Of course we said
you could have the Cauldron.
It's notourfaultyou can't
do anything with it.
[Cackling]
[Thunder Crashing]
[ Orgoch] Good-bye, goslings.
Remember, we always keep a bargain.
[ Laughing]
Whata bunch
of blundering misfits !
Things just neverwork outwhen
you're dealin'with people !
You can go back
to feeding pigs !
I've had it!
Good-bye !
Doli's right.
It's-It's my fault.
I letyou down.
Withoutmy sword,
I'm nothing...
just an assistant
pig keeper.
Look,you are somebody.
You must believe
in yourself.
- I believe in you.
-[ Taran] Y-You do?
And I think thatyou're--
Uh... I mean--
- That is--
-[ Eilonwy] Yes, Taran?
I mean, uh--
[ Both Laughing]
What I mean is
I'm grateful to all ofyou.
You've been true friends.
Now it's up to me--
-[ Screeching]
- Look!
- Uh-oh. Trouble. Good-bye.
-[ Screeching Continues]
Quick! We can't
letthem find us.
[ Henchman Grunts] Pig boy!
[Grumbling]
-[ Fierce Grunting]
- [Screams]
[ Henchmen Continue Grumbling]
Fightwhere you are,
pig boy.
Gotcha.
[ Henchmen Laughing]
[ Chains Rattling]
[ Creeper] Get a move on!
Careful, now.
You ! Pile them up
overthere !
And getthatcart
outof here !
Oh, oh! I'm sorry.
I've ignored you.
You did come forthe Black Cauldron,
didn'tyou?
Good. Then climb in !
[ Laughs]
Itwill only costyou your life.
[ Laughs] Oh.
Oh !
E-Everything
is-is ready, sire.
My, such a brave
and handsome group:
a pig boy,
a scullery maid...
and a broken-down minstrel.
Perhaps itmay interestyou to see
whatfate has in store foryou.
[Sinister Laughter]
Now I call on my army
ofthe dead,
the Cauldron born.
- [ Bones Rattling]
-Arise, my messengers of death.
Ourtime has arrived.
[ Rumbling, Bubbling]
[ Electricity Crackling]
[Thunderclap]
[ Rats Screeching]
[ Electricity Crackling]
[Gasps]
Oh, it's horrible.
[ Horned King] My beloved warriors
have come to life.
All the dead
ofcenturies past.
Never has anyone created
an army like this.
Go forth,
my deathless warriors !
Destroy all in your path!
[Crazy Laughter]
Come, sire. We can get
a betterviewfrom above.
Oh,Taran.
[Sighs]
I'm afraid it'll soon
be overfor us.
I-I hadn't planned it
to end like this, Eilonwy.
Oh, I wish I'd stayed a toad.
Only moments away
from victory.
My greatest triumph.
We did it, sire !
We did it!
I-I-I mean, I mean you.
Yes, of course,
you did it, sire.
Y-Y-Yikes !
[ Panting]
[ Taran] Gurgi? Gurgi?
Is thatyou?
- Master!
-Gurgi...
whatare you
doing here ?
Gurgi is sorry he always
runs awaywhen there's trouble.
He will untie everybody.
Then we will leave
this evil place.
Yeah, but, uh,
geton with it.
Good boy, Gurgi ! Eilonwy,
you and Fflewddur go with Gurgi.
I muststop the Cauldron.
Oh, but,Taran,that's impossible.
Why,you'd be--
- Taran!
- I'm sorry, Eilonwy.
Please,Taran.
No ! You can't!
My mind is made up.
Wait, master!
Gurgi not letyou jump into Cauldron.
-Gurgi, getoutof myway!
-Whoa !
- [Thunderclaps]
Please, master.
Not go into evil Cauldron.
If I don't,we're all lost.
Outof myway!
No, Gurgi not let
his friend die.
Taran has many friends.
Gurgi has no friends.
Gurgi, no !
Don't jump ! Wait!
No ! No !
[ Fire Crackling]
Oh, no.
- [Wind Whistling]
- [ Electricity Crackling]
Sire ?
Sire, look.
Something's wrong.
What is it, sire?
They're-They're dying!
Itcan't be.
-This had better not be yourfault.
- [Gasps]
[ Nervous Laughing]
Perhaps it needs another body, sire.
-Yes. Yours !
- [Gasping]
Get Eilonwy outof here.
Hurry!
- But,Taran, I-- Please, I--
-Go on ! Go with Fflewddur.
M-Maybe there's still
a chance for Gurgi.
-[ Crumbling]
- [Gasps]
[Wind Whistling]
[Grunts]
No, sire ! Please !
[Gasping]
Get up !
Come alive !
Maybe they're only resting, sire.
[ Nervous Chuckle]
Do something !
My life is atstake !
Get up,you fools ! Kill !
Look! Sire, look!
It's the pig boy.
It's his fault. Yes.
He's the cause of it!
You've interfered
forthe lasttime.
[Crazy Laughter]
Go for his throat, sire.
Now, pig keeper,
you shall die.
No ! Don't!
[Grunts]
[Yelling]
What? What's this ?
No,you'll not escape.
You shall satisfy
the Cauldron's hunger.
Oh, no.
No !
You'll not have me !
My power cannot die !
Curse you !
No ! No !
- [ Electricity Crackling]
- [ Horned King Screaming]
[Continues Screaming]
Oh, no.
How-How-How horrible.
Poor sire.
[Sniffs]
He-He's gone.
[Gasps, Chuckles]
He's gone.
[ Laughing]
He's gone !
[Continues Laughing]
[ Rumbling]
Fflewddur! Eilonwy!
[ Eilonwy] Over here! Hurry!
Thank goodness you're safe.
Come on, Fflewddur.
Hurry!
[ Roaring]
Run foryour lives !
[ Blubbering]
Come on. Jump.
[Yells]
Taran, look!
Quick. Get in.
Let's go.
Here. Push off, Fflewddur.
Eh ? Uh-oh.
Uh,trouble.
Oh,we can't
getthrough.
I-I'll try
to open the gate.
Taran, be careful,
please.
[Chains Rattling]
Hurry! Move on through.
Come on, Fflewddur.
Hurry!
Oh, good work, lad.
Letme give you--
Look out!
[Creeper Laughing]
[ Laughter Fades]
[ Rumbling]
Look.
[Whispers]
Gurgi.
-[ Witches Cackling]
-Gurgi ?
-[ Orgoch] Why is the duckling so sad?
-[Sobbing]
Yes. He's got
what he wanted,
and he's still
notsatisfied.
Justwhat do you think
you're up to, ladies ?
Oh,we have business
with your little hero.
Hero ? Gurgi was the hero.
The only thing thatmattered
to you was the Cauldron,
but now it's
no use to you.
-So we'lljusttake it
and be on ourway.
-[ FflewddurSputtering]
Stay your hand, ladies.
We never give anything away.
[Clears Throat]
We bargain. We trade. Remember?
Did-Did these old ears hear
the word ''bargain'' ? Hmm ?
Yes, madam,
those old ears heard right.
Ohh !
I adore forceful men.
Oh, pullyourselftogether, madam.
[Grunts]
Now, come on, outwith it.
What is your offer?
- No, notmy--
-Then I'll do it.
[ Electricity Crackling]
[ Orgoch]
A magnificentsword fora warrior.
I'm nota warrior.
I'm a pig boy.
Whatwould I do
with a sword ?
Absolutely nothing.
-But I would trade...
- [Together] Yes ?
the Cauldron for Gurgi.
- [Gasps] Dear!
- It's not possible.
Justas I thought, ladies.
You've got no real power!
-Admit it! Admit it!
- [Thunder Crashing]
[Wind Whistling]
[ Orddu] We have made a bargain.
[ Laughing]
[ Eilonwy] Oh, Taran.
Munchings and crunchings
in here somewhere.
Gurgi !
You're alive !
He's alive.
-[ Eilonwy Laughs]
-[ Fflewddur]
Great beelin', He is alive.
Oh, Fflewddur, Fflewddur.
He's alive !
I'm alive ! [ Laughing]
Gurgi's alive !
Look, look, look!
Touch me ! [ Laughing]
Gurgi,you clever
little thing.
[ Laughs]
- [ Laughing]
- [ Both Laughing]
Come on, Gurgi.
Let's go home.
[ Laughing]
Gurgi's happy day!
- [ Both Laughing]
-Come on.
Great beelin'.
[ Laughing]
Hmm.
You did well, my boy.
Yep.
[ Laughing]