What time is it?
Sorry. Didn't mean to wake you up.
I'm cold. Come back to bed.
I can't. It's half six.
Give us a kiss.
I can't. I told you.
So this is what it's going to be
like when you and me is married?
I won't work. Not after the war.
This bleedin' war,
can't end bloody soon enough.
You're a wonderful girl.
You know that, Grace.
Couldn't live without you.
You're my best girl.
Harry...
What?
We need to talk.
What about?
You know what about.
We've already talked about that.
I know, but...
Not now, Gracie.
You've got to get to work.
Go on. Hop it.
Oi!
What?
You forgetting something?
I'd forget my own head, if
it wasn't screwed onto my shoulders.
You heard what the quack said.
You've got to look after yourself.
I tell you what,
how about you and me meet for tea
at the Corner House after work?
Can you afford it?
You can pay.
Harry!
Don't let Mr Johnson see you
on your way out.
BICYCLE BELLS DING
Thanks, Stan.
Have a nice day.
Bye-bye.
WOMAN: I thought you'd taken them
again. I know you.
Down in the dumps?
Cheer up, love.
It's not as bad as all that
down in this dump, eh?
Don't tell me old Adolf's had
another go at you.
I haven't seen him, not yet.
Someone ought to tell him
he's on the wrong side.
I reckon he'd go down a treat
in Berlin.
The trouble with Eddie is
he was wearing the wrong jersey
when the whistle went.
You all right, dear?
You're looking a bit peaky.
I'm just tired I think.
Come on, Grace.
You're gonna make us late.
MACHINERY RUMBLES
Sir.
So what's this, then?
It looks like a hairpin.
It doesn't look like a hairpin.
It IS a hairpin.
What's it doing here?
I'm sorry, Mr Baker, I missed it.
All right?
No. It's not all right, Miss Law.
You want this to fall into a machine
and make a spark?
You want to blow yourself
and the rest of us to smithereens?
It's one hairpin.
I didn't see it.
I'm sorry.
The next time I find one of these,
I'm docking you five shillings.
Now, get in there.
Come on, Grace. Wakey, wakey.
All right?
Grace, I might as well
get that other one now.
SCREAMING
I was wondering...
We all go to my parents
in Haslemere.
My sisters'll be there
and Martin of course.
I was wondering
if you'd like to come.
Edie...
Well, you haven't got any family,
have you? No.
Well, you don't want to be
on your own at Christmas.
I've spoken to Mother
and she'd love to see you again.
You'd just be there
as a friend of the family.
I'd love to.
Would you?
Yes.
Then that's settled, then.
You can leave me here.
No. I'll wait.
You don't want to be late.
Did you say you're meeting Mr Foyle
for lunch? Not exactly.
You go on. I'll see you tonight.
Good morning.
I'm afraid we're not open yet, sir.
No, I do understand. I was hoping
to make a reservation for Christmas.
We're fully booked, I'm afraid.
Oh, dear.
Are you Mr Tremayne?
Yes, that's right.
Jack said I should mention his name.
Jack?
Jack Bentley.
Ah. Jack.
He recommended you.
Ah. So you know Jack?
I do know Jack.
Mainly socially, but we do
a bit of business now and again.
Is that so, Mr...?
Black.
And what is your business, Mr Black?
Well, a bit of this, a bit of that.
Got to stay on your feet.
You know how it is? True enough.
Where did you see him exactly?
Smithfield.
Smithfield's a big place.
The Hind.
Ah. Yes, he's always in there,
isn't he?
He's always in there, isn't he?
Suggested I should ask you
about your special menu.
Did he give you a price?
Well, five bob's
meant to be the limit, isn't it?
Not for what we're offering.
There's a 7/6 cover charge plus an
extra three bob for the cloakroom.
You'd be offering something
VERY special for that, then.
We've got something you won't find
anywhere else. Is that right?
Would you like to take a look?
I'd love to.
Frank,
bring that package.
Have I seen you in here before?
No, I used to come in,
but not since you've been here.
How long has that been?
I came down this year.
London...you don't wanna know!
Now, you take a look at this.
Well, that's very special, isn't it?
See what I mean?
I do.
Good old Jack.
So I take it you're interested,
then?
I certainly am.
So, do we have a deal?
We do, yup.
How many of you will there be?
Oh, there's half a dozen of us.
I'll introduce you.
Happy to clear up here?
Yes, sir.
And what about the evidence?
Bring it all back.
ENGINE STARTS
(HUMS CHRISTMAS CAROL)
# God rest ye merry gentlemen
# Let nothing ye dismay
# I think I'll have this chicken
here and carry it away!
(CHUCKLES)
# Tidings of comfort and joy... #
What are you doing?
It looks like Christmas
has come early this year.
What do you mean? Well,
Mr Tremayne won't be needing it now.
Put that back!
What?
You heard me. Put that back now!
Come on. We're closing this place
down. No-one's gonna want this.
That's not the point.
What you are doing is theft.
It's exactly the same reason
we arrested Tremayne.
We arrested him for racketeering.
We're just cleaning up.
Oh, is that what you call it?
What's the matter with you,
Mr Milner?
You was never like this
before they made you sergeant.
How dare you speak to me like that,
Constable!
You can consider yourself cautioned.
And if one more item of food
goes missing from this kitchen,
you'll be spending Christmas
behind bars.
Do you understand?
PHONE RINGS
Sir. There's a lady here to see you.
Are you in charge?
I'm never sure.
It's just that
I've been here an hour
and I've only got the afternoon off.
I want a word, if you don't mind.
All right.
Hilda Greenwood.
You're Mr Foyle?
I am.
You're the one I want to see.
Somewhere private.
It's important.
This way.
Brookie,
am I dreaming or is that a...?
It's a turkey, Miss Stewart.
It's an absolute whopper.
About 15lb, I should say.
I haven't seen a turkey like that
since before the war.
Where did they get it?
I've got a feeling
it came from Smithfield Market.
Your old stomping ground?
Mm.
You can't move up there now
for spivs.
They've even got tic-tac men out
to warn them if anyone's coming.
What will happen to it? I'm locking
it up until there's a trial.
Why? It hasn't done anything.
Evidence, Miss Stewart. I thought it
safest to put it behind bars.
We wouldn't want it flying away,
now, would we?
Peters! I want a word with you.
I bought it fair and square.
I've read the Poultry Order.
There's nothing to stop anybody
buying or selling turkeys.
For breeding.
I was going to breed, but it died.
What else was I meant to do?
Who did you buy it from?
I've told you.
At the market.
He's a registered breeder.
Really? This is the bill...
with a fake signature.
How was I meant to know that?
It's signed "W Churchill".
I didn't look at it.
Mr Tremayne,
men are dying
to bring food into this country.
You know what's happening.
You think they're doing it so people
like you can make a quick profit?
I was only thinking about
my customers.
Well, maybe you should be thinking
of 14 years. What?
But this is just between you and me
and these four walls. Right?
Yup.
I hadn't know Grace Phillips long.
But she was a nice girl.
Used to work in a hairdresser's
before she came over to us.
She'd only been with us
a couple of months
and she seemed so happy
at the start.
But then she changed. I could tell
she'd got something on her mind.
And then about a week ago,
I caught her on her own in the
ladies' room crying her eyes out.
I asked her,
"What on earth's the matter?"
But she wasn't very coherent.
It was all just tears, you know.
But she did say something to me.
"It's wrong to steal."
That's what she said.
Her exact words.
What do you think she meant by that?
Well, you tell me.
I've got no idea.
But a week later
there's this "accident",
and that's the end of it.
Now, I'm not saying anything,
Mr Foyle,
but you tell me.
A girl who's been perfectly happy
suddenly changes overnight.
She's scared.
She won't talk to anyone.
And then she makes a mistake,
and suddenly she's dead.
Now, they're all saying
it's an accident,
but I just think someone ought
to take a look. That's all.
For Grace.
COINS JINGLE
Thank you.
Ladies.
We've got ten more minutes,
Mr Baker.
All right, all right,
keep your hair on.
I'm just passing the hat round.
For Grace.
Grace?
Poor Grace. Not going to be
needing it now, is she?
No need to be like that.
She's got a mother.
Thank you. 70 years old.
All on her own.
I just thought some of us might like
to do something for her.
If you're not interested,
I won't force you.
I didn't mean it like that.
Here.
Very generous of you.
I take it
you're not going to the funeral.
You'll dock me half a day's wages
if I do. I don't make the rules.
You're all heart, Mr Baker (!)
You've got five minutes, not ten.
Enjoy your tea.
It's for Grace.
Morning.
How do?
Harry?
What is it?
I didn't expect to see you here.
Not after what happened.
I... I mean...you know.
Grace.
What else am I going to do?
Stay at home, I just think of her.
Does no good sitting on my own,
does it?
Might as well be here.
Of course, Harry. That's right.
I'm glad to see you.
So how's it going, then?
It's no bloody good.
These are all cracked.
And the ignition harness is useless.
Waste of bloody time, if you ask me.
Yeah.
Well, not for much longer.
You're still going ahead, then?
Not me. WE, Eric.
We're still going ahead, right?
I just thought
what with Grace and everything.
Grace doesn't make any difference.
Three days.
That's when we're going to do it.
Right.
You are still with me?
Of course I am.
Cos I wouldn't like to think
you've turned against me.
I'm with you, Harry, all the way.
All the way.
I like that!
Are you still working on that bike?
What do you mean, Mr Johnson?
You know what I mean.
That bike's been here since Monday,
and you've hardly started on it.
We've got a problem
with the ignition cables.
I know there's a problem
with the cables, Eric.
That's what it's here for.
Er...I'm not in tomorrow,
Mr Johnson.
I've got the funeral.
Yeah. Course.
I'm...
sorry about Grace, Harry.
What happened to her...
it was awful.
Well,
we've still got work to do.
Since you're here,
you'd best get on with it.
He never cared about Grace.
He doesn't care about anyone
except himself.
Old bastard.
"You might as well get on with it."
Get on with what?
This pile of junk's going nowhere.
Look what you've done.
That's really done it.
Just shut up, Eric.
Just shut up, all right?
Miss Stewart?
Brookie.
I was just looking at...
A real shame, isn't it?
It'll go off just sitting there.
In a couple of weeks, I suppose so.
When will the trial be?
The way things are at the moment,
not before the end of January.
Seems a terrible waste.
Yeah.
Sorry. Mr Foyle's ready to go home.
Oh, gosh. Right.
How did you get on?
Once he started,
he just wouldn't stop. Good.
Sir.
Ready? Yes, sir.
Good night.
Good night, sir. Good night, Sam.
Paul.
Jane!
They told me
you were still working here.
You've got a new desk sergeant.
What are you doing here?
In Hastings?
- No. Here.
I've come to see you.
Why?
I want to come home, Paul.
I want to come back to you.
Jane...
Stop.
It's been two and a half years.
I know. But we're still married.
I'm still your wife.
I know I was stupid.
I know I made mistakes.
But I want you to take me back.
Do you mind if I got myself
a cup of tea while I waited, sir?
Go ahead.
Just try to avoid getting recruited.
Don't worry, sir. Worker's Playtime
is definitely not for me.
Mr Foyle. Very good to meet you.
How do you do?
Come this way.
I'm Godfrey Watson,
Managing Director here.
Used to be an engineering firm,
didn't it?
In happier times, yes.
It was converted in 1940.
Now it's high-explosive shells,
20,000 of them a week.
Do come in.
This is Edward Baker,
my works manager.
Please take a seat.
Thank you.
Would you like some tea?
I won't, thank you very much.
A lot of women employed here.
Yes. About 40% of our workers here
are women.
Couldn't do without them.
Now we've trained up
a whole second army of women
on centre lathes, hand-millers,
routers, tapping machines.
And they're very good at it.
Some would say better than the men.
Cause problems?
Well, there's
a certain amount of rivalry. Yes.
What is it you're investigating,
Mr Foyle?
Well, I'm not investigating anything
as such.
Just want to know what you can tell
me about a woman who worked here.
Grace Phillips.
Ah, yes.
Her funeral's this afternoon.
It's... it's very sad.
Mm.
Many accidents?
One last year.
Two the year before.
It's dangerous work.
Everybody knows that.
The slightest vibration
can cause an explosion.
Friction. A spark. Anything.
Even so, we've had only
four fatalities in three years.
Well below the national average.
We certainly don't expect to be
at the receiving end
of a police enquiry.
Could I see where she worked?
Yes, of course.
Was she a reliable sort of girl?
I didn't really get to know her.
Mr Baker?
She was a good worker, although
she hadn't been here that long.
Two or three months, maybe.
She was a bit highly strung.
Poor health record.
Saw the MO a couple of times.
Why was that?
I couldn't tell you.
But we can easily find out, though.
A lot of the girls come down
with minor complaints.
Nervous debility is the main cause
of sickness here, as you'd imagine.
Erm...we get respiratory,
digestive disorders
and skin ailments too, of course.
Is that right?
Girls like Grace are handling
a lot of poisonous materials.
Tetryl. Cordite. Trinitrotoluene.
TNT.
They can get a yellow discolouration
of the skin.
Particularly the ones in the
pellet and powder sections. I see.
We could let you have her
personal file, if that would help.
It would, thank you.
We've had to close off
the entire area.
There were a lot of chemicals around
when the blast occurred.
It'll take us a few more days
to clean it up.
We may lose a whole week
of production.
Poor girl.
I have to say, Mr Foyle,
if there's anything
you know about Miss Phillips
that you're not telling us,
then perhaps you should.
I know absolutely nothing.
That's why I'm here.
She was a very ordinary girl.
One of hundreds.
Mind if I join you?
No. Go ahead.
Look at that. Penny halfpenny
for a little bit of Swiss roll.
Profiteering, I call it.
Is that your car outside?
My boss's. Yes.
Who's he, then?
He's a police officer.
You're with the police?
Mm. In a way.
I'm a police driver.
You're here about Grace?
I was there when it happened.
You work in the shell filling room?
The suicide squad.
I'm a fully paid-up member.
So what happened?
I don't know. I didn't see anything.
I expect she dropped a fuse.
Mind you, I wasn't surprised.
Grace wasn't at all well
that morning.
Half asleep on her feet.
If you ask me,
they should never have let her in.
But you weren't hurt?
No. I was lucky.
Just stepped out
to fetch some more fuses.
I wouldn't like to do your job.
I wouldn't mind doing yours.
Nice way to lady it through the war.
So what's it like here?
It's a man's job, isn't it?
But we do it just as well as them
and they resent us because of it.
They pay us half as much as the men
too.
Three pounds, three shillings
a week.
Aren't they glad to have you?
They're always picking holes
in what we do.
I can't tell you how often
I've thought about packing it in.
So why don't you?
Because I'm an idiot.
No. It's not that.
I've got my Billy out in Libya.
He's a gunner.
I like to think that what I'm making
here, he'll get to use out there.
Know what I mean?
It makes me feel part of it.
Is it long hours?
They've given us two hours off
this afternoon.
That's down to Grace.
The funeral.
Yeah.
The foreman doesn't like to give us
time off, normally.
He's organised a whip-round
for her mum
and a few of us thought
we ought to be there.
That tells you a bit about our work,
doesn't it?
Going to a funeral is
the high point of my week.
Is anything wrong, Mr Baker?
No, sir.
You seemed a little off-hand
with Mr Foyle.
Was I? I didn't mean to be.
Oh, I'm giving two of the girls
who knew her best
some time off to go to the funeral.
Are you sure that's a good idea,
sir?
Everyone's upset.
It'll be good for morale.
Production's been affected anyway.
Well, even so.
I'm going myself
and I think you should be there too.
Sir, there's something
I wanted to talk to you about.
What's that?
Well, actually, it's this turkey.
I know it's none of my business.
That's right.
But I wondered if you were going
to leave it in the evidence room
until it rots.
Where would you like me to put it?
What I mean is -
do you really need it for the court?
Yup, afraid so.
It's Christmas soon, sir.
And sardine pancakes are
all very well and good,
but they're not exactly festive,
are they? Well.
You don't think the judge would mind
if it was missing the drum-sticks?
You mean, eat the evidence?
Not all of it.
Just a leg or two.
What do you think the judge
will say about that?
No. Nothing we can do.
End of subject.
You know, sir, quite soon,
it will begin to smell.
Sir...
Sorry to ask, but could I have
some time off this afternoon?
It's a personal matter,
but it's important.
Of course.
Thank you.
Everything all right?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Sam.
Sir.
You could do something for me.
Yes, sir? This funeral
this afternoon, Grace Phillips's.
I wondered if you'd mind...
Not at all. I'd be glad to.
Well, find out what you can,
see who's there.
Have a word with the mother
if possible.
St Paul's Church and cemetery.
You don't mind going?
Not at all.
I'll see what I can dig up.
Jolly good.
Only way to get a couple of hours
off in this place, a funeral.
We should have more of 'em.
(I wouldn't mind going to his,
for a start.)
Mr Johnson.
Mr Johnson!
Not going, Mr Johnson?
Oh, no. I didn't think
it was right for me to be there.
Why's that?
I didn't really know her.
You rented a room to her.
She used to say that
you were like a father to her.
When did she say that?
She said it often.
But you please yourself.
I rented out a room. That's all.
Come on, Harry.
Get on with you.
And I'll see you back here
first thing tomorrow.
Pastries?
Yes, please. No, thank you.
When you came back from Norway,
I know I was beastly to you.
It wasn't just your injury.
Please believe that.
We'd had so many plans together,
and everything had suddenly changed.
YOU'D changed.
And I was wrong.
I see that now.
But I've learned so much
being away from you.
The one thing I know is that I still
love you and I want to be with you.
I've met somebody else.
What?
Who?
Does it matter?
Well, yes. I'd like to know.
It's Edith.
Edith Ashford?
She always did give you the glad eye
even when we were at school.
Is she living with you?
Is she in OUR house?
It's not our house, Jane. It's mine.
No, she isn't. Not yet.
But you've asked her to?
It's none of your business.
Aren't you forgetting something?
We're not actually divorced.
It's been over two years.
But it's THREE years, isn't it?
The Matrimonial Causes Act, 1937.
I can come back if I want to -
and I do.
My sister doesn't want me in Wales.
I've got nowhere else to go.
So you can tell Edith.
You stay away from me, Jane.
And you stay away from Edith.
I'm warning you.
What?
It's over between us.
You're not part of my life.
So just keep away. Or else!
VICAR: As we contemplate
this young life,
brought to so sudden and premature
an end,
we have to remember
that Grace Phillips
gave her life for her country
in exactly the same way
as so many of our young men
are doing overseas.
We must salute her courage
and the courage of all the men
and women who worked with her,
supporting our troops.
(Grace.)
You wanted to say a few words?
Yes, sir.
Grace was my best girl.
We was going to be married.
We was going to spend the rest
of our lives with each other.
I'm... I'm sorry.
But this is my fault.
Erm...
the thing about Grace was...
..she was happy where she was.
And then I had to go
and put my foot in it
and tell her
she could be doing her bit.
Doing something more.
And she believed me...
..because
that's the sort of girl she was.
I thought you'd look after her.
She was ill that last day.
You know that,
and you still made her do it.
Wait a minute.
Why didn't you just send her home?
My lovely girl blown to bits
and me left on my own.
What am I going to do?
We didn't know she was ill.
We did everything we could
to keep her safe.
Gentlemen, this is neither the time
nor the place.
Harry.
Come on.
Let's drown our sorrows, eh?
Yeah.
I don't want to be here.
Not with THEM.
Shall we say the Lord's Prayer
together?
Our father which art in heaven
Hallowed be thou name
Thy kingdom come
Thy will be done
On earth as it is in heaven
Give us this...
SHOP BELL
Jane, dear, if you're going up,
pop the kettle on.
I'm only going to be about ten...
Mollie, did you know about Grace?
Yes, it's terrible.
You didn't tell me.
I didn't know whether to or not.
You've got so much on your mind,
I didn't want to worry you.
Are you all right?
Yes...
Not really. No.
Did you see him?
Mollie, I have to go back out.
But you've only just..
Sorry. I have to see Paul.
What, again?
She used to be one of my best cutters
- Jane Milner.
I'm sorry, ma'am. He's not here.
Do you know where he is?
I imagine he's gone home.
Could you tell him I was here and I
want to see him? Certainly, ma'am.
Lovely, isn't it, sir.
Is it?
The smell.
Fresh turkey, sir.
Ah.
I haven't seen a bird like that
for two years.
Been talking to Sam?
Miss Stewart, sir?
Not recently.
Good night.
Good night, sir.
It's only been three months.
Three months, three weeks
and two days.
It's just sometimes you talk
as if...
As if we're going to be together
for ever?
Of course we are.
We're going to muddle on
until Hitler throws in the towel
and then we're going to get married
and have as much milk as we want
and oranges and bananas and sweets
and all the other things
we can't get,
and we'll have a proper life.
You really think that?
Paul. I've told you.
I'm not going to let you go.
JANE: Certainly do not.
What do you mean?
What are you trying to...?
Why are you following me?
What do you want?
What are you doing?
This is ridiculous.
Get off me!
What are you doing?
No!
How did you get on yesterday?
- The funeral, sir? - Yup.
Well, strange, really.
Was it?
Well, there weren't many people
there.
People she worked with
and some of her family,
but not her mother, though.
Why was that, do you think?
I don't know.
Perhaps she couldn't face it.
Anyway, they had a collection
for her at the factory. Mm-hm.
Boyfriend?
There was a young man.
Good-looking.
He made a speech at the grave.
He said Grace should never have been
at work when they knew she was ill.
I'm afraid it wasn't much fun.
It's a funeral.
No. I mean...
there was something about HIM.
It was as if...
This is a horrible thing to say,
but it was as if
he was putting the whole thing on.
Like a performance.
Well, thanks for going.
You know me, sir.
Always glad to be of service.
Funeral service included.
Sir.
Bad news, I'm afraid.
They found a young woman dead in
an alleyway just off the parade.
Killed some time last night.
Beaten around the head.
Do we know who it is?
Yes, sir.
I've tried to keep it quiet,
but word gets around.
It's Mrs Milner, sir.
What?
Jane Milner?
Yeah, his wife.
His ex-wife, I mean.
I understand they were divorced.
But that's not possible.
She's in Wales.
There's no doubt about it,
I'm afraid, Miss Stewart.
She was here yesterday evening,
as a matter of fact,
asking for Mr Milner.
I saw her myself.
What time was that?
6:30 exactly, sir.
I made an entry in the book.
Where's he?
He's not in yet, sir.
It's the first time I've ever known
him to be late for work.
Killed at around ten o'clock
last night, they think.
It appears that's the murder weapon.
You just missed the MO, sir.
He's been called to Hove.
He asked me to give you this.
Thank you.
Who found her?
A couple of young ladies, sir.
They work in Hardcastle's, the
drapery shop. On their way to work.
That's empty, sir.
Not a word about this to anybody
for the time being.
Don't you worry, sir.
You can count on me.
Sergeant Milner.
Where is everyone?
Er...
there's been an incident in town.
What sort of incident?
I couldn't tell you, sir.
What are you doing here, Miss Law?
I don't believe it's time
for your morning break.
They told me you were here,
Mr Baker.
If you want to see me,
you should come to my office.
I thought you might like to see me
more informally.
You see, the thing is,
what with Christmas coming up,
I was thinking of
taking some time off.
The factory doesn't close
for Christmas. You know that.
You'll get a day and a half off
like everybody else.
I'd like three days.
I'm sorry?
I think you heard me, Mr Baker.
Christmas Eve, Christmas Day
and Boxing Day.
Is that too much to ask.
Why are you asking me this now?
It's out of the question.
And you might like to think about
a Christmas bonus too. Miss Law.
Or...
I might start talking about
Grace Phillips.
What are you talking about?
I was at the funeral yesterday.
Remember?
I got chatting to someone.
Turns out he was her cousin.
He had a lot to say.
What are you talking about?
Well, he told me about Grace.
And about her poor old mum.
Is it true the police were here,
Mr Baker?
Asking questions, were they?
They were making routine enquiries.
Well, they might not be so routine
when I talk to them.
I can't do what you ask.
You're in charge of the roster,
and when it comes to pay,
they'll do what you recommend.
You're blackmailing me.
I'm not doing nothing of the sort.
I do a good job here.
I just want to get a bit more like
what I deserve.
I'll think about it.
You do that.
I'd be careful if I was you,
Miss Law.
A place like this.
And you with your husband away.
All on your own.
What are you saying?
I know all about you.
I know where you live.
You try put the finger on me.
You don't know me, Miss Law.
You don't know anything about me.
You don't know what I might do.
You're sure it's her?
Can I see her?
You know she was here?
Yes, sir.
I saw her yesterday.
How was she...?
She was erm...
attacked with a brick.
When?
Last night, about ten o'clock.
What can you tell me?
I had tea with her yesterday
afternoon at the Spread Eagle.
That was the last time I saw her.
What did she want?
It's difficult to explain.
Well, I hate to ask,
but in the circumstances...
Sir, I told you that
we were divorced,
but it wasn't true.
It would have been in a few months.
She was the one who left me.
But it turns out
that wasn't what she wanted.
She asked me to take her back.
Did she know about your erm...
current circumstances?
Edith.
I told her.
She was upset, angry.
She asked me if she could move back
into the house,
and I said that
that wasn't possible now.
Where was she staying?
There's a hairdresser's
on the High Street.
She used to work there
before we were married.
And...
Last night?
I was on my own.
I left Edith around nine.
Sir, I know how this must look.
You have every right
to treat me as a suspect.
Well, I mean, I have absolutely
no doubt whatsoever
that you had nothing to do with this,
but if we're not seen to be doing it
by the book. I understand.
Are you suspending me?
No, no, no, no, no. But obviously,
you can't be involved with
the investigation.
And we're going to have
to take a look
at your home and your office,
I'm afraid.
I do wonder why you felt it necessary
to lie about the divorce.
I suppose it was just easier.
After she left, I did write to her
suggesting we divorce,
but she never replied,
so...
I just pretended that we were.
The more I said it,
the more I believed it.
Tell Edith?
No, I lied to her.
I just...
I just wanted Jane out of my life.
She is now.
Sir, you can't think
for a single minute
that Mr Milner had anything to do
with the death of his wife.
What makes you think
I'll be answering this question?
Have I made it clear that
cases are not for discussion?
Yes, sir.
Do we discuss cases?
No, sir.
Will we be discussing this one?
I want everything put back exactly
where it was.
If you find anything that raises
an eyebrow, come straight to me.
Yes, Sergeant.
Sarge.
Oi. I don't want anyone
larking around
with Sergeant Milner's things.
You two back downstairs.
I know this is difficult,
but if you felt able to answer
a few questions I'd appreciate it.
Yes.
Just give me a minute.
I'll be all right in a minute.
Of course.
Jane...
Jane was staying with me.
I couldn't understand
why she didn't come back last night.
I was very worried about her.
You know where she went?
Yes. I do.
She went to see her husband.
But of course you knew that.
He works for you.
He did this, didn't he?
Have you arrested him?
Jane didn't have an enemy
in the world, apart from him.
He didn't treat her well.
Did she tell you that?
Why are you asking
all these questions?
She came back yesterday.
She'd seen him.
She was very upset.
She said she was going to go out
and see him again.
And that was the last time
I saw her.
I know he's your friend
and you're trying to protect him.
But he killed her.
He killed her!
Have you heard?
What's that, then, Eric?
The bogies are all over Hastings.
They found some bird's been murdered
down near the parade.
That's terrible.
I tell you,
nobody's safe these days.
So you don't know nothing about it?
Why should I know anything?
I just thought you might have heard.
That's all.
No. It's all news to me.
SHOP BELL
You want a cup of tea?
Yeah, if you're making a brew.
So who was that woman
who came here last night?
That was my wife.
What?
It's a joke, Eric. Who was that lady
I saw you with last night?
That was no lady. That was my wife!
Oh.
What's the matter with you today?
What's made you so jumpy?
I don't know.
You know, I was just thinking,
Harry...
What with all this business -
the police and everything -
maybe it's not the best time,
you know?
You getting cold feet?
No, no, no.
It's the right time, Eric.
Everything's set. I know.
And with the rozzers chasing after
whoever bashed in this poor woman,
they won't have any time for us,
will they? Right.
How did you know she was bashed in?
You told me.
Did I?
Well, I don't know.
I must have heard.
Come on. You really think
I had something to do with it?
I don't know her.
I don't even know who she is.
She's got nothing to do with me.
I'm so sorry about Jane.
Thank you, Sam.
I can't believe it's happened.
There always seems to be
someone dying somewhere,
but you never expect it
to be someone you know.
If there's anything I can do to
help, you will tell me, won't you?
Of course. Thank you, Sam.
Sit down.
Have you found anything, sir?
Well, I spoke to the woman
at the hairdresser's.
Mrs Summersgill.
Mm.
Was she helpful?
I wouldn't say so.
Er...we did find this.
This was with your wife
when we found her.
Wondered if you recognised
the handwriting.
No, sir.
It's postmarked Hastings.
Sent about a week ago.
Was there no letter with it?
There wasn't.
Could this be the reason
that she was killed?
Unfortunately, we erm...
We also found this.
This is my shirt.
Taken from your house.
Why?
Well, why do you think?
Is this where I'm supposed to say,
I cut myself shaving?
Well, I'm very glad you didn't
because it's not your blood.
It's your wife's.
It's ridiculous.
It must be a mistake.
There's no explanation.
Of course. That's not true.
There can be only one explanation,
can't there?
Also...er...went to the hotel where
you and your wife were last seen.
A few people there who...um...
Heard us arguing.
Well, arguing violently
is how it was described.
It was... It was heated,
but it wasn't violent.
Well, whatever it was,
did you threaten her?
No.
Not in so many words.
How many words do you need?
Sir,
I don't deny the argument.
But I can't explain the shirt.
What are you going to do?
Mr Foyle.
Yeah.
I know I shouldn't be here,
but I wonder if I might come in.
Yes.
I...
I understand you've suspended Paul.
Um...
have you seen him?
I spoke to him yesterday,
but only briefly.
You can't really suspect him
of killing his wife, can you?
You know that would be absurd.
I know. You're going to tell me
you can't discuss it with me.
But how can you be so cruel?
He's been with you
for more than two years.
He's totally loyal to you.
He'd do anything for you.
Listen, I'm very sorry,
but I do think you should leave.
No. Wait.
I'm sorry. I had no cause to speak
to you like that.
That wasn't why I came here.
The truth is...
I'm desperately worried about him.
You see, he...
he told me about the shirt.
You found blood on it.
Her blood.
That's what he said.
Yes.
They met, you know.
He never denied that.
Maybe it got there...
Somehow...
Did you know that
they had never divorced?
I didn't know.
Not until last night.
He told me then.
Come as a shock?
Paul lied to himself.
I don't think he lied to me.
He still lied.
You're right.
I shouldn't have come here.
You know that
in any other circumstances,
he'd have been arrested, suspended,
quite possibly put into jail.
I know.
You're doing what you can.
No, I'm doing
what I believe is right.
And I'm sorry I can't tell you
what you want to hear.
You really think he's guilty?
No, I don't.
I think YOU do.
Terrible, isn't it, miss?
What is? A waste of good food -
and at a time like this, you know.
It won't be long before it starts
to rot.
I wasn't even thinking about it.
No. I suppose not.
This whole place is rotten,
if you ask me.
What they're saying about
Sergeant Milner, it's tripe.
I'm sure Mr Foyle
will get to the bottom of it.
I hope so. We all do.
By the way, for what it's worth...
..I do have the key.
What for?
The evidence room.
Just thought you'd like to know.
Everything all right, Miss Stewart?
Yes, thank you, Brookie.
No. Not really.
It really is a bleak midwinter,
isn't it?
Well, we've just had some news
that might cheer you up.
There was a witness.
What?
When Mrs Milner was killed.
There was someone there,
and he's just been on the blower.
MAN: In a way, I'm quite grateful
to Herr Hitler.
Him and his war
have given me something to do.
Oh, yes, I saw her.
I was on my way home.
There are 12 of us fire guards
in this district.
Responsible job.
Yes.
Mind you,
we haven't had a raid for a while.
It's all reports, really.
Weekly meetings.
I've never actually seen a fire.
I drink a lot of tea.
Do you want some?
No, I won't, no thank you.
Would you be kind enough
to explain to me again
what exactly it was you saw?
I thought I already told you.
Well, you told me
that you saw a young woman
and somebody was following her.
Oh, yes.
He was definitely following her.
I heard her calling out to him.
"Why are you following me?"
That's what she said.
Did he say anything?
I can't really remember.
I don't think so.
If he did, I'd have heard his voice.
I didn't know
he was going to kill her.
I only read about that in the paper
this morning.
I thought it was one of those,
you know,
one of those husband and wife
arguments.
Did you see him?
Oh, yes, I saw him,
but of course it was dark.
Would you recognise him
if you saw him again?
I wouldn't want to see him again.
But if you did?
Yeah, I suppose so.
I'd have to see him again
to be sure.
Well, if we organised
an identity parade at the station,
would you be kind enough
to come down? I don't mind.
I don't mean now,
but I'll send a car to collect you.
Oh. Thank you.
Thank you.
Ready?
Ready, sir.
Sorry to interrupt.
Sorry, I just get a bit bored
standing around.
There's something in here
about Grace Phillips. Front page.
Is that her?
Yes.
Poor girl. She was only 20.
I've seen her before.
This is Grace, isn't it?
Yes.
That was taken before the war.
She changed her hair.
These days, it's all Victory cuts
from America.
It's easier to wash and curl.
All the girls want to look like
Veronica Lake.
You ever meet her boyfriend?
Well, not properly.
But I did see him a couple of times
going in and out of the bank
next door,
but he didn't come in here.
Jane and Grace were friends,
isn't that right?
Yes, well, they were more than that.
They were cutters together,
but Grace had been orphaned
when she was young
and she was all on her own.
She used to look upon Jane
as her big sister.
Jane ever mention her
when she was staying with you?
Yes. Well, she saw the story in the
newspapers about Grace being killed
and she was terribly upset.
Recognise this hand writing?
Well, yes. That's Grace's.
Mr Foyle, what has this got to do
with anything?
Grace was killed in an accident and
you said that Jane was murdered.
I mean,
two completely different things.
You've found something,
haven't you, sir?
Have I?
I can always tell.
You have a look.
A sort of "Cry havoc,
and let loose the dogs of war."
That's Julius Caesar.
It's "slip".
What?
It's, "Let slip the dogs of war."
Is it really?
Yes, it is.
Keep your eyes on the road.
Oh, hell!
Oh, my gosh.
Radiator?
Radiator.
Is this as far as we go, then?
Seems so, sir.
Can you get as far as a garage?
I hope so.
Well, do your best.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'll walk.
You'll forgive me for saying so,
Mr Foyle,
but this isn't a very good time.
We're just putting out
the Christmas payroll.
I'm sorry, Mr Watson, it's a little
difficult arranging a murder enquiry
around your wages schedule.
Murder? What you talking about?
Well, I'm afraid another woman
has been killed.
A woman called Jane Milner.
Does that mean anything to you? No.
A friend of Grace Phillips?
No.
It seems on the morning Grace died,
she hadn't been feeling
particularly well, is that right?
Who told you that?
It's true. Yes.
She did seem half asleep
that morning.
You never told me this, Mr Baker.
Well, no, sir. I didn't want
to trouble you with the details.
If she was so tired,
should she have been at work?
That was my decision, sir.
And I stand by it.
It's easy enough to make judgments
in hindsight.
Anaemic evidently.
Taking a supplement
for iron deficiency.
Yes, she was tired.
Yes, she was under
a great deal of stress.
But that's all there is to it.
She made a mistake.
It does happen, Mr Foyle.
There are munitions workers
all over the country
missing fingers and worse.
There's no way this
could be anything more
than a terrible accident.
She also mentioned something
about a theft.
What theft?
First it's murder.
Now it's theft.
There is no theft in this factory,
Mr Foyle.
All the girls are searched for
anything metallic -
hairpins, safety pins,
anything that might cause a spark.
Cigarettes, lighters, matches too.
On the way in and on the way out.
They're watched throughout the day.
We have passers,
over-lookers and inspectors.
So you have no idea what she meant?
Absolutely not.
Possible to speak to
a Hilda Greenwood?
Oh,
that was her handwriting.
What was inside it?
It was empty.
"Jane Milner."
She was the woman...
That's right.
Oh, Lord!
They were friends evidently and
she got this just before she died.
I don't understand
what you're saying, Mr Foyle.
I don't think I want to understand.
You thought Grace had been killed
deliberately. I never said that.
Isn't that why you came to see me?
She was frightened.
Isn't that what you said? Yes.
About some stealing going on here.
That's what she said.
But that's all she said.
Oh, I wish I'd spent more time
with her now,
but you know how it is.
You're either late for your shift
or you want to get out of here
as soon as you can.
I've told you everything I know.
Right.
Did you ever meet her boyfriend?
No.
Did she say anything about him?
She thought
he was going to marry her,
silly little minx.
There's one born every minute,
isn't there?
She used to say he was like
that actor in all those films.
You know. What's his name?
Jimmy someone.
Stewart? Cagney.
Oh.
Yes, he hero-worships him.
That's what she said.
She showed me his photo once.
A handsome enough devil.
He was the one who persuaded her
to come here, the war effort.
All right for him.
He wasn't the one who got blown up.
He was at the funeral, wasn't he?
Yes, that's the only time
I ever saw him, really.
I didn't like him.
There was something about him
that gave me the creeps.
Don't suppose you know
where I can find him?
No.
All she ever told me was his name.
And not even his full name.
Harry.
Hello!
I'm sorry to bother you
but it's my car.
I wonder if you can help.
It seems I have a split radiator.
Oh, sorry.
I can't do nothing for you.
This is a private garage
and we're full.
Well, if you could seal it,
even briefly.
You see this is a police vehicle,
so it sort of takes priority.
You the police?
Yes.
Do I know you from somewhere?
I do, don't I?
You were at the funeral.
You're Grace Phillips's friend.
What of it?
Well, you seemed so obviously upset.
You were going to be married.
Maybe.
I'm sorry.
Why was you there?
Well, it is difficult to explain.
But you was there.
And now you're here.
What's your game?
Nothing.
I told you. My car's broken.
Nice and convenient.
I was near here
and I saw your garage first.
But if you're too busy to mend it,
I'll take it elsewhere.
You're not going anywhere.
Now, wait a minute.
Harry? What's going on?
Trouble.
What?
She's a copper.
She's been following me.
No. I'm not, really.
I haven't, I promise you.
Asking questions.
I just wanted to get my car mended.
Harry, she's got nothing to do
with us. Just let her go.
We can't risk it.
What are you talking about?
Oh, just shut your face!
Get out! Get out! Go, go!
Out my way! Out! Get out!
Harry, what have you done?
You bloody fool, Harry.
You shouldn't have got in the way.
You've hurt me.
You know, I went to see Mr Foyle.
Why? Edie, you shouldn't have.
I thought, I can't see
why he's doing this. He knows you.
He can't possibly think...
He's only doing what he has to.
I'd do the same.
How do you think...?
I mean, do you have any idea
how that blood got onto your shirt?
I don't know.
It has to be a mistake.
Paul...
Only that if you HAD killed her,
I could try to understand.
I mean...
No, Edie.
You must never say that.
Why?
Because murder is murder.
I've met men like that,
and you must never believe,
even for a minute,
that I'm capable of that.
I'm sorry.
Sir?
Is Sam back? No, sir.
But Sergeant Milner's here,
and Mr Bradshawe's standing by.
Right.
Ready for this?
If you think it'll help.
I think it'll sort it out, don't you?
Unless you'd rather...
No, sir.
No, I want to do it.
Good.
Mr Bradshawe, hello.
You understand what you've got to do?
Yes. I understand.
Good. Take your time.
I understand what to do.
Good.
(This is the man.)
This is the man you saw in the alley?
He was there.
This is the man you saw
with the woman Jane Milner?
I'm sure it was him.
Well, thank you, Mr Bradshawe.
Would you be kind enough
to see Mr Bradshawe home?
He couldn't have seen me, sir.
I wasn't there.
Mr Foyle.
Yeah?
Pardon my saying it, sir,
but you must have it wrong.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I haven't known Sergeant
Milner all that long, but...
a man less likely to murder his wife
is hard to imagine.
Well, that's very helpful.
Anything else you want to say before
I get you transferred? No, sir.
Who did pick up Mr Bradshawe
from his home?
Constable Peters, sir. As you asked.
I want to see him.
Right away, sir.
Know why you're here?
No, sir.
Well, it looks like
I'm going to need a new sergeant.
Yes, sir. I suppose so.
I understand you and Milner
trained together at Brighton.
Joined the force about the same time.
He got promoted, you didn't.
That's about right, sir.
Well, it's never too late.
Interested?
To work with YOU, sir?
Anyone would jump
at the opportunity.
I get the impression that
you never liked Milner much, anyway.
Is that right?
You want the truth, sir?
Generally, I find it helps.
I thought he was a bit hoity-toity.
Yeah, he could be a bit unreasonable
sometimes, don't you think?
I mean that business
at the restaurant, for example.
I did think he came down on me
and the lads a bit much, sir.
You were only stealing food.
It was there for the taking.
And he disciplined you and...um...
..you thought you'd get
your own back?
What do you mean, sir?
Well, what I mean is...
you picked Mr Bradshawe up,
old, unreliable Mr Bradshawe,
had bags of opportunity to describe
Milner to him,
even perhaps help to point him out.
No, sir. And it seems to me,
there are only two ways
that Milner's wife's blood
could have finished up on his shirt.
A) if he'd murdered her.
Well, that's...
And B)
if somebody had put it there.
You brought the body in.
Not on my own, sir.
You...
searched his room.
Look...
I never meant it to go this far.
How far did you mean it to go?
The hanging?
No, no, no, no.
It started as a prank. That's all.
He got at me, so I thought
I'd have one back on him.
It was just a stupid joke.
I just wanted to see him
sweat a bit.
But once it'd begun,
I couldn't stop it.
I wasn't going to let him hang.
Of course I wasn't.
What are you going to do with me,
sir?
You'll be charged with obstruction
and perverting the course of justice.
For starters.
Would you be kind enough to leave
now, please?
Sergeant Brooke!
Mr Foyle, sir!
He's mad, quite mad.
Sir.
Oh, my God, oh, my God, oh, my God.
Who are you?
Well, I'm a policeman. Who are you?
This is my garage.
I'm Neville Johnson.
Was he like that when you found him?
That's a screwdriver.
Do you know him?
Of course I do.
That's Eric, Eric Clayton.
He worked for me.
This is...
Harry done this, didn't he?
He did this to him. Did he?
I should have known. I never should
have employed the little bastard.
Why's that?
I always knew there was something
wrong with him. Sick in the head.
A nasty piece of work.
Did that have anything to do with
why he hadn't been called up?
No, he said he was asthmatic.
That's what he told me.
I think... I think the forces
probably just took one look at him,
and decided
they could manage without him.
I don't believe this.
I just don't believe this.
Where is he now?
Harry? Well...
he gave me an address
on Helm Street,
but he was never there.
Spent most of his time
with his friend.
Friend?
That girl, Grace Philips.
Of course
they were more than just friends.
He thought I didn't know,
but I had a good idea
what was going on in there.
In where?
There was a flat at the back,
over the stables.
I mentioned to him and Eric
that I wanted to rent it out,
and the next thing I know
she appears out of nowhere.
A munitions worker. Nice girl -
that's what I thought.
It was only later on that I realised
that they were together.
Of course by then, it was too late.
But you let her stay?
She paid the rent.
On the dot every week.
There was nothing wrong with her,
except that she managed
to fall in with him.
Can I see the flat?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
This is more or less
how she left it.
I didn't quite know what to do
after she...
I thought a relation,
someone might come for her stuff.
What's that? Medicine?
I never knew she was ill.
It's a supplement
for an iron deficiency.
That's his clobber.
Disgusting, ain't it?
Young people nowadays,
they've got no sense of decency.
Well, I think she thought he was
going to marry her, didn't she?
Well, I suppose he could turn on
the charm when he wanted to.
After all, he fooled me.
When he first started work,
I thought he was just
a good looking boy.
What's that you've got there?
Ah, well,
that just goes to show you.
That's exactly
what I was talking about.
I don't think
they were going to be used
for what YOU think they were,
Mr Johnson.
I'm sorry. We're closed.
Yes, I-I-I know.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry to bother you.
I just wondered whether I could...
Well, the thing is...
(SCREAMS)
I've already told you, Mr Foyle,
the last time you were here.
All the workers are searched.
They're also scrutinised
every minute of the day.
Why do you need to ask again?
The last time I was here,
I wasn't aware she was involved
with a safebreaker.
Really?
They shared a room together.
We found wires, buttons,
tamping sticks, prophylactics.
Condoms?
Condoms are filled with explosives
and placed between
the back of the door plate
and the front of the lock cap.
What he was short of
were the explosives.
You think they came from here?
We do, through Grace. He might even
have been responsible for her death.
He killed her? He couldn't have
got through the gate.
He wouldn't have needed to.
What chemicals did she have access
to?
Mainly cordite and TNT. Brought
from the storeroom over there.
Everything measured and recorded.
Nothing else?
We store a very small amount of
nitro-glycerine.
Unstable. Horrible stuff.
And that's putting it mildly.
Assuming she could have got her
hands on it,
she couldn't have smuggled it out of
here without blowing herself up.
She could have used a stabiliser.
Still too dangerous.
Right, well, thank you.
Incidentally,
Grace Phillips's mother? Yes?
The mother you took a collection for.
What about her?
She's been dead 15 years.
Is that true?
How much did you collect?
Answer the question.
About 18.
And you kept it?
Well, thanks again.
I'll leave you with that one.
Sir, we got a call saying banging
had been heard coming from the bank.
I can't get hold of the manager.
Incidentally, this is the bank
that handles
the munitions factory payroll.
A call from whom?
The solicitors at the back.
Not the hairdresser?
No, sir.
Have you been in there?
No, sir, not yet.
Is it open?
I don't think so. There doesn't seem
to be anybody there.
Not even Mrs...?
Mrs Summersgill, no.
Do we know where Harry Osborne is?
No. sir, we don't.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Isn't this the place
where your wife used to work?
And Grace.
This is to do with the explosives,
isn't it, sir?
Possibly. We should take a look.
I don't mind going in, sir.
Neither do I.
Perhaps this isn't the best time
for you and Mrs... Summersgill.
True.
Sir, if he is in there, why don't
we wait until he's finished,
and arrest him when he comes out?
That'd be fine, if we knew for a fact
that she wasn't in there.
Who the hell are you?
I'm a policeman.
How'd you find me?
I came through that hole in the wall.
Has Eric bought it?
He has.
Then they'll hang me, won't they?
Perhaps.
You on your tod?
Well...
you like gangster films, don't you?
Isn't that right? Yeah.
You probably know the answer
to that question.
(AMERICAN ACCENT) You've got
the place surrounded. Yup.
You think I'm going to give myself
up? There's just you.
Are you going to make me or
do you think you can talk me out,
make me see reason?
Well, you're wrong.
Do you know what this is?
Tell me.
It's nitro-glycerine.
I smash this, we all die.
What do you say about that, copper?
Did Grace get that for you?
That's right.
How did she do that?
It was easy.
They thought they were so clever
at the factory with all their narks.
She said she'd never be able
to do it,
but in the end she just walked into
the storeroom in her lunch break.
No-one was there.
She'd have been searched,
wouldn't she?
She sewed a little pocket
in her dress. In the hem. Right.
Nobody looked there. It was easy!
(WHIMPERS)
Shut up!
They will hang me, won't they?
Yeah, they will.
This is faster.
We all go together. And it's fun!
I take a copper with me.
There is something
I'd quite like to know.
You'd like to know.
What would you like to know?
How you killed her.
Gracie?
Mm. You put something in
her medicine, didn't you?
Strychnine, wasn't it?
Who told you that?
Well, you left it in the glass.
Well, yeah.
That's right, Mr Policeman.
But it was rat poison.
Right.
So you got her to steal this stuff?
Yeah.
And she got frightened?
She got cold feet.
"Don't do it, Harry.
You mustn't do it.
We don't need the money."
But I wanted to do it,
so I made her get me the stuff.
I mean,
why do you think I was walking out
with her in the first place?
Right. What, so she...she stole it
and then had second thoughts?
Yeah, she asked me to give it back
or get rid of it.
I knew she was going to tell
someone.
I did it like you said.
I poisoned her.
I thought she'd have croaked it
before she even got to the factory,
but...
that wasn't how it happened, was it?
You must admit
it's the perfect murder. (LAUGHS)
She blew herself up.
I couldn't believe it when I heard.
All the evidence gone.
No dead body for you
to poke around with. Nothing.
But then that was Gracie for you.
She was always very considerate.
But she wrote the letter.
You like it all neat, don't you?
Dot the I-s and cross the T-s.
How long have you been a copper?
Yeah.
Some old friend of hers.
I didn't know that
until that interfering bitch
came to the garage.
She had a letter
and she knew all about me.
And then suddenly Grace is dead,
and she thinks I've got something
to do with it. She threatened me.
You know what?
I followed her into town
and then I hit her with a brick.
I killed her.
I took the letter
and that was that, you know.
Grace shouldn't have written to her,
you know?
It was stupid of her.
If it hadn't been for Grace,
then I wouldn't have had
to touch her.
Is there...er...
anything else you want to know?
No. I think that about covers it.
Yeah. I think you're right.
You know, it's funny, really.
When your friends come in,
they're not going to know
which is you and which is me
and which is her.
There's just going to be pieces,
and in the end,
they'll have to bury us together.
For ever
and ever.
Grace.
Oh, Grace.
You lying bitch.
Nice sense of humour, though.
Thank you. Thank you.
So it was just glycerine.
It was, coloured.
Nothing nitro about it.
Did you know that?
Well, she couldn't have got
the real stuff out of the factory.
A) The searches were too rigorous
and B) if she had,
she'd have blown herself up.
But she had to give him something
to keep him sweet.
As soon as she did
she knew she was in trouble,
and that's perhaps when
she wrote to your wife.
And he killed her.
I'm sorry.
This whole thing - trying to rob
a bank, all the killing.
He was completely off his rocker.
It seems so. Anyway, thank you.
For what?
For finding him.
Well, it was just an accident.
Well, your accidents
are very helpful.
Are they, sir? I'll have to arrange
some more, then.
And you also helped confirm
that Grace's mother was dead.
Did I?
Well, all I knew was
that she wasn't at the funeral.
Surviving mothers tend to turn up
to their daughters' funerals,
don't they?
Yes,
of course they do.
Is it true?
Is it over?
Thank God.
You know I would have stood by you.
Whatever.
I know.
Brookie!
The turkey!
I know, Miss Stewart.
What happened to it?
I wish I could tell you.
But Mr Foyle's gone up the wall,
and he was asking for YOU.
He doesn't think I took it, does he?
Well, I wouldn't like to say.
But I can tell you, he had steam
coming out of his ears.
And he's looking for me?
He said you were to see him
the moment you came in.
Sir.
Yeah.
I want you to know that
I had nothing whatsoever to do
with the disappearance
of the turkey.
I know.
I don't know who took it.
And I've no idea
why they left a photograph.
You know?
The photograph is the evidence.
I don't understand, sir.
In the circumstances I thought, much
as you did, what a waste of a turkey.
So I rang the local magistrate.
And he said we could eat it?
No, he didn't say that.
He did say he'd give us
special dispensation
to use the photograph as evidence.
So who is going to eat it?
Well, I thought we'd offer it to
the children, the local evacuees.
That's a terribly good idea, sir.
Well, I'm glad you think so.
The magistrate seemed to.
Would you mind driving it round?
Not at all.
KNOCK AT DOOR
Yup.
You manage that?
Absolutely.
Here we are, sir.
All plucked and ready for the oven.
My mum's old recipe.
Right.
It was a bit tricky
stuffing it without any onions.
They...erm...
also hoped
you'd be able to join them.
When?
Tomorrow, lunch?
Well, that would be wonderful, sir.
The evacuees.
I had them in mind, really.
All the time.
CHURCH BELL CHIMES
You hear that?
They're ringing the bells again.
It's all over for Hitler.
He's finished!
Happy Christmas!
And you.
From now on, you work for me.
Sabotage?
That's right.
What happened?
You've made a mistake.
It's you who's made a mistake.
We'll make this the last one.
transcript:chocolate
sync:innuit
www.tvsubtitles.net