[O.R. Chatter]
Suture. Clamp.
Suture.
- Sponge.
- [Scoffs]
Frank, as long as we
have to work together...
- I don't see why we can't be friends.
- Friends?
Don't you dare mention the word "friend"
to me, you... you nurse. Scissors.
- Ow!
- Hmm.
Hey, you two, these public displays
of affection have got to stop.
- [Both Chuckling]
- [B.J.] I've seen it happen before.
Married men go all to pieces
when their girlfriends get engaged.
- Cut.
- It's not losing a girlfriend.
- He's afraid of getting
his own wife back.
- [Chuckles]
Look at this foot...
kid's quite a marksman, isn't he?
Don't let Frank hear you say that.
If he finds out this kid shot himself...
he'll form a posse
and have him lynched.
Yeah. Suture. Wonder why
they always go for the foot.
Why didn't he try shooting
himself in the canteen?
Yeah, then they could win
the Purple Tush.
- Close for me.
- Blow it out your ear.
All right, where did you hide
the Band-Aids?
Band-Aids? You're working on
an abdominal wound the size
of the Grand Canyon.
It's for me, you simp.
She pinched my pinkie with her scissors.
She was getting even.
You pinched her plenty of times.
- Tit for tat.
- Yeah, what's that?
That? In medical parlance,
we call that a foot.
- See? It's a matched set.
- You know what I mean.
I happen to be an expert on foot wounds,
and that looks fishy to me.
- I think he has a fish fetish.
- This man shot himself.
- No, no, no, no.
That's not what happened.
- No?
See, this is Danny Fitzsimons,
the star placekicker from Fordham.
Now, what happened is,
an enemy soldier...
shot at him
from very close range.
And instinctively, Danny tried to kick
the bullet out of the way.
- It's true.
- You're kidding!
- No.
- Well, what about the enemy soldier?
- Ten-yard penalty.
- For roughing the kicker.
Twerps.
There's an incoming chopper, sirs.
Two wounded.
- Radar, get him into post-op.
- Then go find Father Mulcahy.
He oughta have a little talk
with our football hero.
Yes, sir.
- Corporal?
- Yes, sir.
Does Fordham
have a football team?
- I don't know, sir.
I've been in post-op all morning.
- Oh.
Take care of my pal first.
He's much worse.
- We're gonna take care of everybody.
- Please go check on him.
- He saved my life.
- Lift him out.
[B.J. Chattering]
- Notice anything unusual about this guy?
- He's out of uniform.
- He's wearing a fur coat.
- I'm glad he's conscious.
I'd hate to have to give him
mouth-to-mouth resuscitation.
- How is he?
- He's fine.
He just asked me how you bust out
of this chicken outfit.
[Knocking]
Come in.
Um, Father...
Oh, I'm sorry, Father.
No. Oh, what is it, Radar?
Oh, Father, Captain Pierce
wants you in the O.R. Right away.
- He says he has someone
he wants you to talk to.
- Well, certainly.
- It's not for the last rites, is it?
- Oh, no, sir.
- Thank heaven.
- Oh, uh, Father...
excuse me, would you happen to know
if Fordham has a football team?
A darn good one. They don't call them
the Rams for nothing.
I knew a priest
would know.
He tried to warn me about the mine,
but I wasn't paying attention.
So he tripped it...
saved my life.
I think he's gonna
be all right.
It's mostly the leg,
especially the paw.
Captain, I don't mean to seem
unsympathetic, but that dog
really shouldn't be in here.
- Think of the germs.
- You have more germs
than that dog, Nurse.
- I beg your pardon!
- I rise in defense of the lady.
- She showers frequently.
I know because I watch her.
- Pervert.
I just meant that dogs don't have
as many germs as humans.
- Forget it.
- Hawkeye? There's someone
you want me to talk to?
Yeah. I got kind of
an unusual case for you, Father.
Oh, my!
What denomination is he?
[Hawkeye] He's a German shepherd.
I guess that makes him a Lutheran.
Oh, gee.
What happened, fella?
It's not the dog, Father.
It's Private Fitzsimons in post-op.
- What's the trouble?
- Why don't you just go
have a talk with him, okay?
Certainly.
- Oh, Frank, um...
- Huh?
I got a case over here.
It's a little over my head.
It's another foot wound. Since you're
the expert, why don't you take it?
Of course. You understand that
it's not necessarily because
I'm a better surgeon than you.
- It's just that, uh, I know my feet.
- I know.
Uh, listen. L-I, um,
I think I oughta warn you...
that this definitely
is self-inflicted.
- You're sure?
- Positive.
He tripped a land mine on purpose.
We have a witness.
[Sighs]
Well, I'm here as a doctor.
I mean, first we'll get him healthy
again, then, uh, court-martial him.
And if all goes well,
put him in front of a firing squad.
- Where is he?
- Right over here.
- That's a dog!
- Very good, Frank.
- I knew he'd get it.
- I'm not operating on any damn dog.
Oh, come on, sir. You've got to.
After all, dogs are people too.
Well, I'm not going to do it. Especially
because that's a self-inflicted wound.
- He did it to save my life.
- Well, that's what he says now.
Look. He might be a dog, but he
also happens to be a corporal
in the United States Army.
See, these two were scheduled to be
rotated back to the States any day now.
And it wouldn't look very good, Frank,
if... if, uh... What's his name?
- Cupcake.
- Really?
If Corporal Cupcake
never made it back to the States...
because you wouldn't
operate on him.
- Don't forget. He's a hero.
- He's scheduled to be awarded
the Silver Fire Hydrant.
Well... I better scrub.
You're gonna be okay, boy.
An altar boy, my.
Where you from?
Philadelphia.
Saint Isadore's Parish.
Philadelphia!
I was in the seminary there.
- You must know Father Marty Gallagher.
- Sure do. He's my pastor.
Oh, I studied with him.
Oh, what a man.
- We used to call him
"Boom Boom" Gallagher.
- So did we.
- Father, do you know how
he got his name Boom Boom?
- No, I don't.
He was a chaplain
in World War II.
He was always
way up at the front.
He was so close to the artillery
that when he finished a sermon,
the enemy would say "Amen."
[Laughs] Yes, he used to tell us
stories about the war.
But I have to admit, I don't find war
quite as exciting as he did.
- Neither do I.
- You know, Father Gallagher...
would be proud of you
right now.
- I don't think so.
- Oh, why wouldn't he be?
Because I shot myself
in the foot to get outta here.
Oh, my goodness.
Danny, how old are you?
Eighteen... and a half.
Well, you're young. You're far
from home. You made a mistake.
But we all do foolish things.
It wasn't foolish.
I'd do it again in a minute.
You can't mean that.
Father, you sit around
with your butt in the mud for weeks...
watching snipers pick off your buddies
one by one.
They sneak up at night in canvas shoes,
so you can't hear them.
One night, I was in a foxhole
with four other guys.
I snuck out to go to the latrine,
and when I got back...
all four of them were dead.
I couldn't take it anymore.
Danny, I'm sure
it's rough out there.
L-I imagine
it's very difficult, but...
You imagine? Father,
haven't you ever been up there?
- No.
- Not even once?
You've never been up there?
Not even for a little while?
Well... I've wanted to go...
but... I'm not allowed.
[Sighs] Boy, if Boom Boom
could see us now.
He'd wonder
where he went wrong.
Well, let's not talk about Boom Boom.
Let's talk about you.
Tell me about it.
I know it's rough.
Father, with all due respect,
we don't have anything to talk about.
Let's face it. You have no idea
what it's like up there.
Whoops! Missed again.
I have the same trouble
myself, sir.
Well, at least my cheeks
won't be bloodshot.
If these drops of yours work,
I'll get you a field promotion.
Sir, I know we've talked
about this before...
but I want you to understand
how useless I feel here.
Why, the men don't need
my words of comfort...
when they're safe
and being taken care of.
They need comfort up there, where
they're wet and cold and facing bullets.
Father, you've got
the toughest job in camp...
and there's not much glory in it
like there is for the surgeons
and the nurses.
But you're the one
who really holds things together.
You should be proud.
Colonel, I had
a seminary teacher...
who was a chaplain
in World War II.
- Father Marty Gallagher.
- Boom Boom Gallagher?
- Oh, why, you knew him?
- No.
Heard about him.
He was famous for the poker games...
he used to organize whenever
the German artillery took a break.
Colonel, Boom Boom
used to excite us with his stories...
about being right up front with
the men, and that's where I wanna be.
Father, this is a different war.
Line officers don't want
chaplains up at the front.
It's just another unarmed man
they have to be responsible for.
Whoops!
Got the ear that time.
Yeah, right. We don't have any choppers,
and you don't have any ambulances.
Now if we could just run out
of wounded soldiers, we wouldn't
have to be in business at all.
All right. Look, I'll send a litter jeep
right up there, okay?
All right. Yeah, okay.
- [Sighs] Radar.
- Yeah.
They got a guy up at the aid station
who needs surgery.
Do you think you and Igor
could grab a jeep and go get him?
Go up to the aid station
where all the shooting is?
- A man's life depends on it.
- Well, I know.
But I got all this work here.
Colonel Potter expects me to...
- Okay. I'll do it.
- Okay. Thanks. I gotta go back to O.R.
[Sighs] Hey, how's the dog doing...
Corporal Cupcake?
Oh, he's gonna be fine. He's got
a pleasant little snarl on his face.
You don't belong up there.
You belong right here.
We need you.
Sir? Oh, pardon me.
- Uh, what is it, Radar?
- Uh, sir...
there's someone badly wounded
up at the aid station.
Your permission for Igor and me
to go get him?
All right, Radar, go ahead.
But be careful.
- Yes, sir. Sorry I interrupted
your service, Father.
- [Mulcahy] Hmm?
You're doing a fine job,
but try to understand.
You're a chaplain, not a soldier.
Well, I think I'm a soldier too, sir.
I certainly look like one.
I once saw a picture
of Calvin Coolidge in a war bonnet...
but that didn't
make him an Indian.
- Sorry, Father.
- Yes, sir.
[B.J.]
Father.
Father Mulcahy,
is anything wrong?
You have a very determined
look on your face.
Do I? Well,
I don't mean to.
- Is there something I can do for you?
- No. No.
I guess I'll have
to do for myself. Thank you.
Sure.
Come on, Igor.
We gotta get rolling.
Igor, you stay here.
I'll go with Radar.
Uh, Father, you gotta get permission.
I only got orders for Igor and me.
I'll be responsible, Radar. There's
a wounded man, and he needs a priest.
- Here. Take my helmet.
- Father, you're gonna get
both of us in trouble.
- Radar, you play poker, right?
- Not now, Father.
No, no, no, no. A very wise priest
once said...
"No matter how well you bluff,
eventually you have to
put your cards on the table."
- I can't argue with that...
- [Engine Starts]
'Cause I don't know
what you're talking about.
- Okay, take it away.
- [Explosions In Distance]
Easy now.
That's good. Okay.
- Yeah, just sign here.
- Yeah.
You guys are lifesavers. I don't know
how long he'd last without surgery.
That's a bad chest wound.
No use, Padre.
Every once in a while...
the Chinese let us know
that they invented gunpowder.
How in heaven's name
do you ever get used to it?
You get used to
never getting used to it.
I wish he were conscious.
I'd like to offer some comfort.
Being unconscious is as comfortable
as you can get up here, Padre.
Do you ever get
any wounded dogs up here?
Nah. They're too smart
to get wounded.
They just point out where the Chinese
are, and they step aside.
- They're kinda like generals.
- Radar, we'd better get underway.
- This man needs attention.
- Right.
- Well, wait a minute.
- What?
We had a goat up here once though.
Very serious shrapnel wounds.
Oh, wow. What'd you do?
We ate 'im.
[Engine Starts]
- How's he doing, Father?
- He seems okay.
Radar, I want to thank you
for bringing me along on this.
I really needed the experience.
That's okay, Father. Sometimes it's
more important to be nice to people...
than to worry
about the rules, you know.
Geez, I remember once in school,
we were having this test, you know...
and there was this boy,
Leonard Gerst.
- He wanted to, you know, copy off of me.
- Ah.
And I knew his mother would beat him up,
uh, if he flunked the test...
- so I let him copy.
- That was a very nice thing
to do, Radar.
- Also, he gave me three dollars.
- [Laughs]
I'll have a cafe espresso. And for
my friend here, a cappuccino deluxe.
- Help yourself.
- Ah.
We also have a special today on roast
crown of lamb with cranberry stuffing...
served with a side order
of fresh poached salmon and dill sauce.
No, thanks.
I had that for breakfast.
This is terrible,
even by my standards.
And this from a man who drinks lime
Kool-Aid with strips of bologna in it.
Klinger, have you seen
Father Mulcahy?
No, sir, I haven't seen him all day.
But if it's a spiritual problem...
give me a minute,
and I'll come back as a nun.
Careful, Klinger. Dressing as a nun
can be habit-forming.
It isn't a spiritual problem.
It's physical...
- a hole in a foot.
- Spare me.
Some guys shoot themselves in the foot
to get sent back home.
Not me. I'd ruin a perfectly
good pair of nylons.
Say, Pierce...
Butt out.
I checked on that
Fitzsimons kid...
and he couldn't have played football
for Fordham... he's only 18.
He entered when he was 16, Frank.
Got lucky.
- He went there on a bingo scholarship.
- Oh, those Catholics.
- How's Corporal Cupcake?
- [Frank] Who?
The pooch.
Woof! Woof!
Oh, him.
Resting comfortably.
He'll be back on his paws
in no time.
What a humiliating experience.
No surgeon with an ounce of self-respect
would operate on a dog.
Frank, some vets earn
more money than doctors.
- Oh?
- Sure.
Better get his address.
- Put him on my Christmas card list.
- Couldn't hurt.
Oh! You know, you really
don't get used to it.
- Radar! Radar, pull over!
- Huh?
Stop the jeep. He's choking. There's
something wrong! Oh, God, pull over!
I am.
Wait a minute!
- What's the matter?
- Help me.
- Help me to clear his throat.
- Ooh!
- [Soldier Gasping]
- It isn't working.
Well, maybe there's something
stuck down there, Father.
- [Soldier Choking]
- His tongue is swollen.
It's blocking the passage.
Oh, he's not breathing!
He's not breathing at all!
Radar, call the base.
Get one of the doctors.
Right.
Hi. This is the litter jeep,
MASH 407...
Litter jeep calling MASH 4077!
Come in! Come in, anybody!
I'm not just anybody, but I'll talk.
What is it, Radar?
Uh, Klinger, it's Radar.
Listen, we're in trouble here.
Get me a doctor, real quick.
Gotcha! Captain Pierce, Hunnicutt,
Colonel Potter, an emergency!
- What?
- The radio, sir. It's Radar.
- Put it on the speaker.
- What's the problem, Radar?
The guy we're bringing back
can't breathe. Father Mulcahy
says his tongue is swollen up.
- What's Mulcahy doing there?
- This is Father Mulcahy.
I know I'm not supposed to be here,
but we've got a man in bad trouble.
- He needs help!
- Father, where's the man wounded?
Well, in the chest, Hawkeye,
but I don't think that's the trouble.
His tongue is swollen,
and he can't breathe.
- Is he getting any air at all?
- No, sir. Not much.
- Hardly any at all.
- Tracheotomy.
- Right.
- Father, Radar, listen carefully.
You only have
a couple of minutes.
One of you is gonna have to cut a small
hole in the man's throat to let air in.
- You mean, cut like a doctor?
- We'll give you
step-by-step instructions.
I'm no good at step-by-step.
You do it.
- Hawkeye, do you think we can?
- If you don't, the man's dead!
- Oh, very well. We're ready.
- [Soldier Choking]
All right, Father,
here we go.
First you need something
to cut with... a sharp knife.
- Sharp knife.
- You have a first-aid kit.
See if there's anything
sharp in there you can use.
- [Soldier Groaning]
- Uh, let's see.
Geez, there's nothing in here
but these funny little scissors
they gave us in kindergarten.
Why can't they keep
these things complete?
- Don't you have anything else?
- I've got my Tom Mix pocketknife.
- Tom Mix pocketknife.
- Your what?
Tom Mix was an old radio show.
It's very sharp.
Okay, fine. That's fine. Look. You need
a small tube. When you make the hole...
you're gonna put the tube in,
and the man will breathe through that.
- A tube?
- Part of a syringe will do
if there's one in the kit.
You could use the top of a fountain pen.
Just snip off one end.
- Is a pencil okay?
- No, it has to be
something hollow. Think!
- Wait! Wait! My bottle of eyedrops.
- Eyedrops!
The dropper is plastic.
I'll just pull the cap off.
[Hawkeye] Okay, that's kinda small,
but that'll do.
Now, look, Father,
you're gonna have to work fast.
In the first-aid kit, get the alcohol.
Sterilize the knife and the man's neck.
Where's the alcohol?
Oh, okay, okay.
We're doing it.
Okay. Father,
if you're ready...
Iook for a notch
at the base of his throat.
It's right where the chest starts.
Right in the middle.
- Oh, boy!
- I got it!
Good. Now take the knife
and make an incision...
a vertical incision through the skin
about two inches long.
There's gonna be a little blood,
but that's okay.
- Oh! Oh, sure. Okay.
- [Incoming Shell]
Oh!
Oh, ick!
He did it! He did it!
Good, Father. Very good. Okay,
now open that skin with your fingers...
and keep cutting until you see a couple
of little horizontal rings of tissue.
- I got it.
- He got it.
Okay, now this is it, Father.
That tissue is fibrous.
It's not going to be easy to cut.
Make an incision between
the rings of tissue...
and then stick the tube
in the hole you made.
The man will be breathing
through that tube. Now work fast!
- I have to say a prayer first.
- He's gotta say a prayer first.
Make it a damn short one.
- I can't think of any.
- Oh, my God.
Bless us, oh Lord,
and these thy gifts...
which we are about to
receive from thy bounty...
- through Christ, our Lord. Amen.
- That's grace!
[Screams]
Don't pay any attention to the blood.
Just get the tube in there.
[Groans]
[Strained Breathing]
He's breathing!
You hear that?
He's breathing! He did it!
Tape the tube in place and pack some
cotton around it to stop the bleeding.
- You did it!
- Oh, the skin and the tissue...
seem to close right in
around the tube.
Father, that's exactly what's supposed
to happen! You did it!
You did it!
- Amen.
Good work, Padre. Get that man
back here as fast as you can.
We did it.
Oh, boy, we did it.
- Well, what do you think of that?
- I think I'm a fool.
- What do you mean?
- I came all the way over
to Korea to perform surgery.
I could have stayed at home
and phoned it in.
- Come on. I think I'd better drive.
- Okay.
- Radar, you all right?
- Oh, yeah. Sure.
I'm just a little carsick.
- What happened to the wheel?
- [Incoming Shell]
Oh!
Father, let's get outta here!
Very well, Radar.
If you insist.
[Engine Starts]
- ##[Jukebox. Mellow Jazz ]
- You know, Father,
I thought we had a deal.
We save the bodies.
You save the souls.
Oh, my. Well, I hope I didn't
violate any union regulations.
- Father.
- Hey, Father.
Thought you'd like to know
your patient is doing just fine.
We're all thinking of trading in
our scalpels for Tom Mix pocketknives.
Padre, I could swear I told you
not to go up to the front.
Yes, sir.
You did, sir.
And in spite of the fact
that I saved a man's life...
I now feel I was wrong
to disobey you.
Cleverly put. Boom Boom Gallagher
would be proud of you.
Oh... what a nice thought.
You know, Father, first time
I operated, I was scared stiff.
And there weren't any bombs
going off around me either.
I can imagine
what it was like for you.
- No, Hawkeye, you can't.
- Why not?
You had to be there.
- Hello, Danny.
- Hello, Father.
I understand you had
quite an afternoon.
Oh, you heard, did you?
Yeah. Everybody's
talking about it.
You actually cut a hole
in a guy's throat.
And under fire too.
Were you scared?
Terrified.
You know, l-I think it gave me a little
taste of what it was like for you.
Danny, maybe it almost gives me
the right to talk to you.
- What do you think?
- Let's talk, Father.
Yes. Why don't we?
Seoul is a very big city, and there are
certain females you gotta watch out for.
Sir, you don't have to warn me
about stuff like that.
I wasn't talking to you.
I was talking to him.
So long, Corporal Cupcake.
It's been a pleasure serving with you.
Well, taking off, huh?
Bye, pooch.
- [Growls, Barks]
- Oh, nice!
If it weren't for me,
you'd be in a wheelchair.
- Go ahead, Phil.
- [Engine Starts]
You know what's funny?
When Cupcake gets his promotion...
I'm gonna be outranked
by a dog.
I know how you feel. I'm only
a captain, and Frank is a major.