Subtitles by peritta
GUNSHOT
GUNFIRE
Not so keen to die
for Ireland now are you?
Gladly die for her, but I'm starting
to think I'm more use to her alive.
It would simply seem that I have
been able to give him what you have
not.
I'm not coming
home, I'm needed here.
You're going to be fine my
love, you're going to be fine.
From our spilt blood the
phoenix of freedom shall arise...
LOUD EXPLOSION
...know that we have won!
EXPLOSIONS IN THE BACKGROUND
Well?
What's left of the GPO is an
inferno, whole street's been
levelled.
GUNFIRE IN THE BACKGROUND
GUNFIRE IN THE DISTANCE
They know it's over, don't they?
In their hearts.
We need to fight with our
brains, as well as our heart.
Well then it's agreed.
We avoid any more casualties.
Talk to them please
Sean, on all our behalfs.
NO SOUND ONLY
SEAGULLS CRYING OVERHEAD
Liz, I'm...
No, I don't regret a thing.
And forward march.
Thank you, yes I'm
grateful to you for informing me.
Thank you Mrs. Magee.
You're welcome sir.
Surrender?
I've taken the liberty of
drawing up our resignation letters.
Were we not just doing
just as we were instructed?
We were the ones who were
doing or not doing none the less.
I repeatedly attempted to warn you,
Under Secretary, and Chief Secretary
Birrell to the dangers.
That will be for an inquiry to
establish the truth of or otherwise.
Since when were
inquiries interested in the truth?
Do the honourable thing Hammond.
Is it not more honourable Sir, in
light of your resignation that I see
to the continued
administration of the country?
I've only ever followed orders.
You may go now Hammond.
What are you looking at?
Nothing much.
Oh, we've got a smart alec here!
LOUD THUD
(Grunts and groans)
That's what real gun feels like.
SPITTING SOUND
Unconditional
surrender, get used to it.
Hurry up missy!
Move, move, quicker.
Move it, move!
CROWD SHOUTING ABUSE
Miss, Miss, Miss, will you tell me
ma you've seen me and that I'm all
right, will ya.
Move it!
Will ya, Miss, Miss.
Do you know him?
No.
Next.
Name.
Michael Collins.
Carry on.
Stephen!
Please accompany me.
I insist on my right as a
member of the Irish Citizen Army.
I'm the officer
Lizzy, you're the prisoner.
I do the insisting, just move.
So you had no
intention of marrying me?
Look, I know, I know things needed
to change Lizzy but they were going
to change anyway.
And you and your friends went and
did this, I mean, look at the place,
the city is in ruins.
Lizzy look at me,
I'm talking to you.
Don't you touch me!
Two years, I was gone for
two years and I come back to this.
This is bigger than us Stephen.
I've been ordered to round up the
women and send them home except the
ring leaders and dangerous.
Well, I'm not going home.
You are.
I'm not.
I'm not going home,
I'm not going home!
You are!
Have you not seen
the state of this country?
Yes!
No you haven't, you haven't!
You've got money, I've got money...
I came back to this.
No!
You're going.
I'm not.
You're going home.
No.
Get out!
The Mahons, ma'am.
Please.
Would you like some more?
You're a saint to feed people in your
lovely house when food was so scarce.
Was it my brother that sent you?
His church, Father
Mulcahy's at the GPO they said.
He promised to fetch me
son, but it's been three days.
In fact we should be
getting home in case there's word.
Come on.
Oh no, please, I
couldn't possibly accept anything.
Oh no, we're not charity.
Me husband's in the army.
Well, he's doing his
bit and we're doing ours.
LOUD CRASH
Sylvester!
I'm terrible sorry, ma'am.
Well done.
Doubled in price since yesterday.
Hope they remember all
this when all this is done.
One shouldn't let one's left hand
know what one's right hand is doing
or don't you have
that line in your bible?
Thank you very much.
We could do with
some full-time help.
We haven't any letters
of recommendation with us.
Minnie, is it?
Yes ma'am.
Why don't we try.
Sylvester will find you a uniform.
Thank you ma'am.
Sylvester?
Elizabeth, Elizabeth!
Thank you Patrick.
Mr. Hammond.
Gretta.
Is it over?
It is.
That's a relief.
Has everybody been all right?
Well, I expect it
was a bit worse in town.
Ms. Lizzy been comfortable?
Most uncomfortable if you
ask me, and she's been sick.
With what?
With what she shouldn't have been
doing without a ring on her finger.
Sorry sir, that's my garrulousness
as Mrs. Hammond calls it.
Mrs. Hammond?
Yes, sir.
I'll check on our guest first.
TINKLE OF PIANO FROM OTHER ROOM
Halt.
COUGHING
I'm sorry I
disobeyed you at City Hall.
Perhaps you chose right.
We've been locked in
this foul place all week.
Tell me, what's the news?
We held out the week.
Come, come join us.
Thank you.
(From other room) I am so sorry.
I had no idea it would last this
long, I was desperate to come back.
I tried calling but Vanessa
wouldn't come to the telephone.
At least you were safe.
I thought many times that being
obliterated by a shell would have
been preferable.
I know, I'm so sorry, she can be...
What, what can I be?
Vee!
What can I be Charles?
Come to see your
whore before your own wife.
Mrs. Hammond please.
Out!
Vanessa please.
I want her out of the house this
minute.
You seemed lost in your playing.
I don't wish to remain your guest
a moment longer than I have to.
Do you still have feelings for her?
No Vanessa, no of course not.
Well then, I want her gone.
Now then darling
don't be silly, look...
Don't!
I just think we should sit
down, just talk about this calmly.
Nor are we staying in this
Godforsaken country a minute longer
than we need to.
I'm now the most senior
member of this administration.
No you're not
Charles, you're resigning.
If this week wasn't
enough to destroy your career.
Without me this country would be
rudderless, Sir Matthew begged me
to stay on.
If you're the only helmsman
this country has, God help it!
I'm very grateful to you Mrs.
Hammond for the board and the
doctor.
I don't want your money,
what do you take me for?
Please leave my house!
I'm leaving.
May, May.
CHIME OF THE CLOCK
Aren't you coming to bed Charles?
What does, what does
she have that I don't?
Stupid me.
She has a child.
But it's me that's
failed you isn't it?
I haven't given you what you wanted.
Please don't leave me, I beg you.
I beg you Charles.
Vanessa, I won't leave you.
Vanessa, Vanessa, listen,
listen, listen to me, listen.
I think you should go back home to
England just while I fix things here,
hmm?
Yes of course, whatever you say.
Sir?
Mr. Sylvester
said evening brandy sir.
And you are?
New help sir, Minnie.
Wasn't aware we were hiring.
I take it you were
not involved in this?
I'm firing any of my staff who were.
No sir, I didn't go near it.
No.
Oh, put it there.
Thank you, now
would you pour it please?
Put it there.
Fine, thank you.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Mam, Mam?
Father.
I am sorry Mrs. Mahon.
I got there too late.
Peter was shot at the post office.
Yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
SOBBING
You can of course apply to the unit
commander for leave for the funeral.
My deepest condolences.
Come on in and have a cup of tea.
Hello Nelly.
May, May.
I'm so happy you're safe.
What are you going to do?
I can't go home.
My father will not have me.
I have to go across the
water, there's convents there.
To hell with that, you're not givin'
that child away to the nuns and to
hell with all them who
condemn you, the world is changing.
You still believe a few bullets and
bombs are going to change anything
for me?
For any woman?
Your mother had to give you up
Frances, it'll be the same for me.
It won't, I'll stand by you.
If they find out I took that
document for you, I'll be sent to
prison.
That's one solution I suppose.
I've taken care of the document.
What about your friends?
Pearse, the boys,
should you not stand with them?
What good would I be
doing to them in prison?
The battle is fought but the war is
just beginning and I'm seeing how
it's going to be fought.
On your feet.
Name?
Thomas Clarke.
Occupation?
Tobacconist and
President of the Irish Republic.
Strip him.
Now, what are you Clarke?
President...
...of the Irish Republic.
Look at him.
Look at him!
All of you bastards, look at him.
Your president, king
of the Fenians (laughs).
I'll fix that fucker some day.
If they don't fix us first.
LOUD SLAP
(Grunting and groaning)
LOUD THUDS
SOBBING
They killed him.
They killed Peter.
Put your clothes on!
Mr. Brophy, I...
The interest has doubled again.
I had to wait till
daylight for the banks...
It's Sunday, the banks are
closed, but your daddy owns one.
Any good was he?
I don't understand
sir, where are we going?
Richmond Barracks.
But I'm not in the reserves.
General Maxwell has instructed me
to prosecute the rebels, I need a
junior.
He wants to hold
the trials immediately.
Of course sir,
thank you, a great honour.
A heavy honour, Wilson.
Yes, sir.
Who's defending?
No one.
Maxwell's insisted on
trial by field court martial,
so it might be done as
swiftly and silently as possible.
What about due process?
Martial law, Wilson.
Military process.
Sylvester, Sylvester?
Where's Sylvester?
Is my father in?
No sir.
Bring me some sherry, dry, and
a plate of cold cuts, and a hard
boiled egg to his study.
Yes sir.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Enter.
Sorry sir, but Mr. Sylvester said
that's all we have left in the
larder.
While mater feeds half
of Dublin, her family starves.
I thought charity
was meant to begin at home!
Wait!
Come here.
Look at me.
It's you!
The little floozy.
I'm not a floozy
sir, you took advantage.
Please, I need the work.
Me father doesn't want me working
in the laundry, besides now they
wouldn't have me back anyway.
I'm desperate to
get out of that tenement.
All of us on top of each other,
there's no life for me there.
Please, I want to make
something of my life sir.
Don't worry Kitty, I'll be okay.
But having one's floozy
about the place is not really on,
it's better if you skidaddle, go on.
Hold on.
I wouldn't like to see you short.
You're a good little girl... here.
Ten pound?
Better than a cheap hat.
Thank you sir.
Mahon.
Sarge?
Your request for compassionate leave.
Sarge.
It's been refused and they want you
transferred immediately to the 1st
Regiment.
You're shipping out
for France straightaway.
Who's taking -- what
about me son's funeral?
Look Mahon, if you want to make a
run for it, I'll look the other way,
tell them I couldn't find you.
No, no I can't, it's not an option.
Me wife relies on
the separation money.
Ah, then good luck.
Papers please.
COUGHING AND SOFT MOANS
Can I help you sir?
Yes, what is all this?
It's a temporary field hospital, sir.
In the Castle?
Military trying to humiliate us.
That's Connolly
isn't it, the union leader?
It's a gangrenous wound, but the
doctor says if we operate we can save
the foot.
Why save the foot, when you
have no intention of saving me?
I'm sure we do intend saving you.
And I am sure you don't.
We're British Mr. Connolly, we
abide by the rule of law, we're not
savages.
Who are you?
Charles Hammond,
Assistant Under Secretary.
Well, the game has changed,
Mr. Assistant Under Secretary.
We you shall see
your true colours now.
How dare you reproach me.
We've done our best
to treat you people fairly.
Do you have any idea of the
problems that you've caused us?
All of us, me personally.
Like I said, Mr. Assistant
Under Secretary, true colours.
Half a crown for the water.
You thirsty?
Little rats.
You'll need to get your hands in
your pockets though because you're
not getting it for free.
Who's thirsty?
Nobody thirsty
here, no, you thirsty?
Half a crown mate and if you ain't
got half a crown your watch will do.
Thought not.
All very quiet now aren't we?
PING OF COIN
Him.
It's your lucky day.
Here you go, ah-ah-ah.
SPITTING SOUND
Drink it up now.
Every last bit.
You dirty little rats.
Eyes down, no heroics.
Don't be letting on you're
anything but a humble volunteer.
Name?
Thomas Clarke.
Is this man known to be signator,
plotter, commander, or otherwise
significant in the rebellion?
Yes, sir.
Step out!
Name?
James Mahon.
Is this man known as signator,
plotter, commander or otherwise
significant in the rebellion?
No, sir.
I recognise him, sir.
He's one of Connolly's commanders.
Thank you detective, stand out!
Name?
Michael Collins.
Is this man known as signator,
plotter, commander, or otherwise
significant in
the rebellion, detective?
He's a nobody, sir.
Stephen?
Stephen!
Ha, I heard you were here.
George.
I'm here for the trials.
We're going to see General Maxwell.
I should be there now in fact.
How are you Stephen after...
After what?
Elizabeth, have you seen her?
She's in prison.
Why?
It was her decision.
And close the gate.
Has Mr. Butler returned Sylvester?
Just, he asked for supper
to be brought to his study.
He'll be relieved to know the
shops will be re-opening tomorrow.
We'll be back to normal soon.
That is a relief, ma'am.
(Shouting) Dolly, come here.
Goodness sake
Edward, what's going on?
My money is gone.
Gone where?
From this desk, robbed, someone has
forced their way in and taken it.
You, with your poor people and
your charity, one of them did this.
Edward they were only ever
in the kitchen and the hall.
How could they possibly...
That girl, the maid, she saw me
doing my accounts, where is she?
She didn't show up today.
Why didn't you tell me?
I'm terribly sorry ma'am, I presumed
someone had given her the day off.
No I hadn't.
I'm calling the police.
Oh, Edward please.
What's her name, what's her address?
DOORBELL
Minnie, wasn't it Mama.
Minnie, Minnie what?
The door Sylvester please.
Brunswick Street
Police Station, please.
Please calm down.
Edward Butler, yes,
I wish to report a crime.
A robbery, Fitzwilliam Square.
Do not touch anything Harry, either
of you, this is a crime scene.
Ma'am.
Thank you.
Yes.
Hello, thank you.
As soon as possible please.
Thank you.
They're on their way.
Where are you going?
Our daughter is in prison, Edward.
You're going there?
Yes of course.
I forbid you to go.
She's our daughter no longer.
You speak for yourself Edward.
But she's still my daughter and if
she is in trouble I will do whatever
I can to help her.
Sylvester.
There's needs of
course we cannot cater for.
Mr. Hammond.
We raided Pearse's school and we
found this in one of the classrooms.
We've been through the employee
records and we have a lead on who
took it from the Castle.
Thank you detective.
I'll look into it,
as soon as time allows.
Maxwell, he's prejudged them.
I'm a barrister, George, but I'm
also a reservist, I must follow
orders.
Then why bother with this at all?
What can we do for them Mr. Wiley?
See that these men get as
fair a trial as possible under the
circumstances.
How?
There's no defence,
no proper judge, no witnesses.
For the charge of assisting the
enemy at time of war to stick, there
still has to be some evidence.
Yes, their own proclamation,
our gallant allies in Europe.
Hmm, could refer to the Belgians,
the Serbs or the Finns as much as
the Germans,
stronger evidence is needed.
There's something I
want you to do for me George.
George Wilson.
I expect you know who I am.
I was writing a letter to my mother.
I'm sorry if I interrupted.
I was finished.
Would you like a cigarette?
No thank you, why
are you here Mr. Wilson?
A courtesy Mr. Pearse.
The senior prosecutor, Mr. Wiley, has
asked me to inform you of the charges
you and your fellow leaders face.
The charge is of assisting His
Majesty's enemies in the time of war,
a capital offence.
That's very kind of him, but please
tell Mr. Wiley that I'm in no need
of a defence counsel.
In a field court martial
you will not be entitled to such.
No matter, I don't intend to
defend myself and even if I did,
I'm a qualified barrister.
Mr. Pearse, as prosecuting counsel
it's not Lieutenant Wiley's role,
nor mine to advise
you on your defence.
I'm grateful for that.
Just to go back, if for such a
charge to be upheld, you would need
evidence?
If no such evidence emerges then
you and your comrades will face the
lesser charges of rebellion and
incitement to cause disaffection.
These are not capital offences.
Well, I'm grateful to you,
Mr. Wilson and to your Mr. Wiley.
Would you like me to see that
your mother receives your letter?
I'm sure our friends will
want to read it when I'm done.
What was it you said to Pearse?
Exactly what you told me.
And he writes a postscript to
his mother, asking her to send his
thanks and warmest regards
to his good friend the Kaiser.
What's his game?
He must want to die.
Well Maxwell's only too
delighted to help him with that.
What about the other leaders?
He signed their death warrants too.
Patrick Henry Pearse is charged
that you did take part in an armed
rebellion and in the waging of
war against His Majesty the king.
CROWD SHOUT ABUSE
Cheer up girls.
Remember, don't
let them see your fear.
What are you doing here Charles?
I couldn't stop
thinking about you May.
Did you have something to say to me?
Sorry?
Well, yes, of course, I'm sorry May.
Vanessa treated you abominably.
What about how you treated me?
Well, I suppose I could
have treated you better, yes.
But I have decided I'm not going
to resign and return home to England
immediately like
Vanessa wants me to.
I'm going it stay here and put
things back the way they were.
I'll fix everything May.
All these little boxes you put the
different parts of your life in,
Charles they've collapsed.
You can't put them back
together again so easily.
I'm serious this time.
You and I will have this child
together, I have it all worked out.
Even if you could work it out, I'm
not prepared to live in one of your
boxes.
But why?
Because I don't love you Charles.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit of thy
womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the
hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of
God, pray for us sinners,
now and at the
hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus...
Here ma.
What's this?
It's for Peter, so he
can have a proper funeral.
He won't have to get
buried with the paupers.
Have a hearse.
Where did you get it Min?
Mrs. Butler gave
it to us when she heard.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of
God, pray for us sinners,
now and at the
hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners, now and at the
hour of our death, Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of
God, pray for us sinners,
now and at the
hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of
God, pray for us sinners,
now and at the
hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women, and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of
God, pray for us sinners,
now and at the
hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee...
Such act as calculated to be
prejudicial to the defence of the
realm and being done with the
intention and for the purpose of
assisting the enemy.
Sentenced to death by firing squad.
Squad-shun!
Ready...
Aim...
Fire!
GUNFIRE
METALLIC BANGING
37, Mahon, James.
112, Fitzgerald, Desmond.
104, Houston, John.
54, Cosgrave, William.
88...
Squad-shun.
Ready...
METALLIC BANGING
Aim...
Fire!
GUNFIRE
LOUD METALLIC BANGING
Ready...
BANGING
Aim...
Fire!
GUNFIRE
Subtitles by peritta