[Indistinct talking in Japanese]
Miller: Psst! Hey.
What?
They're packing up.
And they're taking everything...
fire pits, trash, fuel.
What does... What does that mean?
Are they moving us?
Means they're scared.
Means the James is close.
We got to let them know just how close.
Ma'am.
We'll only get one shot at this.
You're engineering. You're
the most qualified.
Heads up, Frenchie's coming this way!
On y va! Get up!
You.
Time for blood.
The rest of you, you work.
[Grunts]
I got you.
[Grunting]
Spider's a no go.
UAV footage shows extensive fire damage
and not a trace of anything manmade.
It looks like Hornet's much too sparse.
Takehaya couldn't hide
himself on that island,
let alone six prisoners and his boats.
Any updates?
Well, we've just ruled out
two of the islands we got from Peng.
UAV is finishing up
a sweep of the third.
Seeing scattered
vegetation, fresh water,
but no signs of human life.
Hang on. There.
What's that?
Wild birds.
There goes option number three.
I'll check in with the helo.
[Radio crackles]
Nomad, Nathan James. What's
the status of Dragonfly?
Jesse: Bad news, Nathan James.
It's almost completely under water.
How long till we reach Mantis?
At least an hour.
Let's check the footage again,
make sure we didn't miss anything.
Hey.
We'll find them.
Takehaya knows we're coming.
The longer we wait, the
more time he has to disappear.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
They just eliminated the fourth island.
That leaves just the one.
Well, that's assuming
we can trust the intel
that they got from Peng.
Move it!
Lots more to load onto the boats!
[Grunting and dog barking]
Hey, Toshiro, let me ask you something.
Man to man. Pre-plague, who were you?
I mean, before you became an asshole.
Always asshole.
I mean, come on. You
must have done something.
- Huh?
- I was a cook.
I prepare fancy food for fancy Americans
in a fancy hotel in Macao.
Everybody love my cooking.
[Panting] 40.
50.
60.
70.
They say to me, "Toshiro,
how you cook so well?"
[Chuckles] I laugh.
But I don't tell them the truth.
290.
[Panting]
300.
I never wash my
hands after I take a dump.
True story.
[Sighing]
Man: Oy.
[Conversing in Japanese]
[Conversing in Japanese continues]
[Electricity crackles]
[Radio crackles]
Sir! I'm picking up something on HF.
- Distress call?
- No, sir.
I think maybe someone's
putting out what sounds like
line voltage on a
radio broadcast antenna.
You like fried chicken?
Next time I make special
dinner just for you.
Can't wait.
Stop!
Oy.
[Man shouting in Japanese]
Please... I got lost.
They'll punish me.
- [Man shouts in Japanese]
- [Gasps]
What are you doing?
Helping your wife.
You're letting her
work? Pregnant and sick?
Get back to work.
My wife does not need your help.
Signal's emanating from
300 Relative 095 True.
That bearing intersects with
only one island, sir...
Kumonosu.
That's not one of the islands
from Peng's map.
In fact, it's at least 150
miles outside the search area.
Then Peng was wrong.
Redirect a UAV to the new coordinates.
It's a message from our people.
Or it's a trap.
There's a reason Takehaya's a legend.
Either way that's the place.
Bridge, CIC.
Make course for Kumonosu Island.
[Replaces receiver]
Kumonosu Island.
This is where Captain Chandler
believes the pirates are based.
They're certain? They
never checked the fifth island.
They're not certain, but confident.
Sir, the VBSS teams are geared
up and ready to go.
What are they waiting for?
The official orders from
the Commander in Chief.
I want updates every 30 minutes.
Send them in.
Yes, sir.
[Indistinct conversations and chuckling]
Copy that, Nathan James.
We'll expect a status
report in a half an hour.
Mark it.
Michener: I can confirm...
off the record, of course...
that Captain Chandler's
no longer in Hong Kong,
that he joined the crew
of the Nathan James
in the South China Sea,
and that he's searching for the hostages.
Are they making any progress?
They're engaged in diplomatic
initiatives in that regard, yes.
Diplomatic initiatives?
From a guided missile destroyer?
Jacob, who leaked that story to you?
About Captain Chandler
aboard the Nathan James.
[Sighs]
Came from one of the regional leaders.
You know I can't say which one.
You realize you're being used, Jacob?
Used and manipulated.
So they're gunning for you.
I thought you said it came
from only one of them.
It did.
They all seem to have the same concerns.
They have small
concerns, regional concerns.
I'm thinking about the whole country.
You say I'm being used.
I have to wonder by whom.
Everything off the record, no cameras...
It's not exactly
what Kara Green promised.
If you can't stick to
your end of the deal,
I can't be counted on to stick to mine.
We expect the crisis to be resolved
in a matter of a few hours.
If you keep your mouth shut till then,
you'll be the first member
of the press that I speak to.
If not, you'll never have
access to this office again.
Any updates on Vulture team?
They've advanced two klicks inland.
So far, no contacts.
T.A.O.?
Negative on surface and subsurface.
There's nothing in the water.
[Radio static, static stops]
Ma'am? The static, it's gone.
[Electricity crackling]
Hai! Wakarimashita!
Alisha: Vulture Team, Nathan James.
Be advised, the signal has stopped.
Proceed with caution.
Tom: Copy, Nathan James.
We've reached the camp perimeter.
Commencing target assault.
[Clatter]
Clear!
Vulture Team, we found another hut.
100 meters off the edge of the camp.
Clear.
All these supplies are fresh.
Man: Hey, there's six
boxes of rations over here.
[Muffled talking]
Man 2: Why would they
leave all this behind?
Yeah, they must have been in a hurry.
Maybe they're still close to camp.
- All clear.
- Let's check the perimeter.
Clear.
Nathan James, Vulture Team.
Target is secure.
This is definitely the place,
but the prisoners are gone.
What the hell is this?
[Door opens]
Our landing team has
safely reached the beach.
They found the camp, but
there's no sign of the hostages.
Two speeches.
One if we succeed, one if we don't.
First one was easy.
But what do I say if we
lose all those people?
- Jeffrey...
- There's riots in California.
Wilson and Price say they're
fending off protests
at their power plants,
but I'm not even sure they're
trying to stop it.
Or they might be inciting
the unrest themselves.
Stop. Stop.
They're gonna make it home.
We're gonna get through this.
Tom: Nathan James, this is Vulture Team
requesting updated intel from UAV.
You see anyone out there?
That's a negative, Vulture Team,
but we're still sweeping the island.
Tom.
It's fresh. I'd say
bank blade or machete.
Let's go!
This is the way to the
docks. Our plan backfired.
We're leaving even sooner.
No, no. No way he'd leave his wife.
[Grunts]
Master Chief, you need help?
I'm fine.
Takehaya, you just
took this man's blood.
He needs rest.
You did this to him.
You and your trick with the radio tower.
If he dies, it's your fault.
Keep moving!
[Groans]
They're gone.
[Water dripping]
Don't move!
I need to examine her. She's sick.
Then run a line.
I can't.
The wrong blood type might kill her.
Same blood as Kyoko.
That's the only
reason he's here... for her.
She doesn't need
blood. She needs medicine.
You fix her yesterday.
Does she look fixed?
With malaria, the fevers come in waves.
Without the proper
treatment, she might die.
The baby could die.
[Gun cocks]
[Slowly] Give her blood.
[Gunshot]
Man: Contact break!
Wallace down! Wallace down!
Damn it! He's dead.
Nathan James, Vulture Team.
Troops in contact 30
Mikes north of camp.
Request support from UAV.
Copy, Vulture Team.
Rerouting to get eyes on your location.
Make the heading 090
- and descend 1,000 feet.
- Aye, sir.
I've got eyes on Vulture Team.
There's no one else out there.
We got negative contact, Vulture Team.
UAV's detecting no heat signatures
within 500 yards of your location.
You're all alone.
How you doing, Diaz?
Almost there, sir.
Hang in there, Master Chief.
Captain, when the time comes,
get them to safety, no matter what.
If I can't make it...
You're gonna make it.
[Object slams]
No more talk.
Let them talk.
Doesn't matter now.
Soon it'll be over.
It's not over till we're dead.
Your friends will
die, but you will live,
and you'll be tied to me for
as long as your heart pumps blood.
Woman: Vulture Team, we've
increased the UAV search radius.
[Gunshot]
Butler's down!
Set perimeter!
What the hell? We
just cleared that area!
How the hell did they get so close?
They're picking us off one by one.
[Rustling]
Aah!
[Groans]
Son of a bitch.
That's how they're
getting the drop on us.
Be advised, the
pirates are using tunnels.
They're camouflaged by foliage.
Split up and take them out.
[Explosion]
[Man grunting]
Sounds like bad news.
And you're looking a little weak.
Get up!
Everyone, on your feet!
[Explosions in distance]
[Men conversing in Japanese]
[Panting]
Hayakushiro.
Free as a bird, sir.
Aah!
[Yells]
[Yelling in Japanese and grunting]
[Bones crack]
Danny: We got two tunnels
neutralized on the right flank.
Copy.
- Tom?
- Captain.
Diaz.
I got Diaz on the main trail.
Where you coming from, Ray? Who's alive?
This way.
[All yelling in Japanese]
Man: Hai, Kancho.
[Men conversing in Japanese]
Danny: Sir, we've reached
the northwest perimeter.
We are hearing hostiles and hostages.
Copy that. Approaching from the south.
Standby for smoke.
[Men arguing in Japanese]
Man: I'll go after them,
but first things first,
I want to kill the son of a bitch!
He killed one of ours.
What's right is right.
No. Don't. You son of a bitch! No!
Do it.
No!
[Groans]
[Shouting in Japanese]
[Machine-gun fire]
Aah!
[Groans]
[Shouting continues]
Man: Nothing's visible
through that smoke, sir.
Come left to 2-4-0.
Elevate to get an
overview of the island.
Aye, sir.
Aah!
[Machine-gun fire]
[Grunting]
[Both grunting]
[Groans]
[Yelling]
[Straining]
[Panting]
I've got five down.
Wolf: Four more over here.
Set perimeter.
Mike: That's all of them!
Mike!
Except the leader.
Takehaya? Yeah.
He's the last one.
Must have escaped through the woods.
Told you I was planning a visit.
Head count! Who's up?
Cooper... up!
Garnett, Jeter... up!
Man: Fiores, Swain... up!
- Green... up.
- Hume... up!
Diaz... up!
Who's got Cruz?!
He's down!
Cruz is down!
Hey.
Hey. You're all right. You're fine.
It's nothing. It's not that bad.
Okay?
You remember Gitmo? Huh?
We got you out of that, right?
[Chuckles] We got you out of that.
Just like Gitmo.
Badass.
Tell Manny and Christopher...
their uncle was a badass.
[Breathing stops]
A bunch of them had the virus.
For some reason our blood helps them.
They didn't get the cure?
No. Takehaya thinks it's poison.
America used it to wipe out Japan.
Makes no sense.
Tell me about it.
He left Miller and
Rios back at the camp.
The wife's blood bank.
We already cleared the
camp. There was no one there.
Unless they're underground.
What?
He's got tunnels. That's
how they ambushed us.
Maybe there's an entrance
back at the camp we didn't see.
[Radio chatter]
[Computer key clicks rapidly]
We've just lost
communication with the UAV.
- What happened?
- I don't know, sir.
Attempting to reestablish uplink.
Get everyone else to the
extract point, then back to the ship.
You'll come back for us.
Green, Taylor!
You're with me.
I'm not leaving without our boys.
We need that vest.
Danny: Fiores, you get him to
the RHIB as soon as you can.
We leave no man behind.
Fiores: I got it.
[Grunts]
Okay.
I rebooted it three
times. It doesn't make any sense.
Unless it's not the uplink.
Isolate and play back the
last 20 frames of the UAV footage.
That gray area.
Lieutenant Burk is
right... this is no uplink issue.
Could Takehaya have shot it down?
An RPG could do it if
fired from the right location,
but it'd have to be a
hell of a dead shot.
Whatever it was came
from bearing 050 relative.
Here.
On the other side of the island.
There's nothing there but beach.
The bogy didn't come from the island.
It came from the water.
Takehaya has a ship
strong enough to take out a UAV?
There's a storage shed a couple
hundred meters down this trail.
- [Machine-gun fire]
- Cover! Take cover!
[Shouting in foreign language]
Who are these guys?!
Chinese Secret Service!
What the hell are they doing here?
Watch out! Six o'clock!
Aah!
In the hooch! On me!
Ah!
[Shouting in Chinese]
Go! Go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
All teams, be advised,
MSS is on the ground.
The Chinese are on the island.
It's a damn Chinese ship!
Bridge, X.O. set Emcon
Condition Alpha. Radio silence.
Vulture Team, setting
Emcon Condition Alpha.
Keeping open channels bridge to bridge.
[Machine-gun fire, shouting in Chinese]
Nathan James, what's
the status of Cobra Team?
The exfil was successful,
and they're en route back to the ship.
Working on an extract plan for you.
We have to give Vulture
Team some backup,
get a QRF team out there.
The bird can be at the
camp in five minutes.
You just make sure Jesse
flies low enough
to stay out of that ship's radar.
Yes, ma'am.
They're only 10 minutes
late for their check-in.
Anything?
No, sir.
They're still not
responding to our hails.
[Machine-gun fire, shouting in Chinese]
I got eight approaching
from the left flank!
[Shouting continues]
You picked a hell of a vacation spot!
Rooms ain't much! Food's top notch!
Aah!
[Grunting]
[Machine-gun fire]
[Groans]
[Screams]
[Panting]
[Helicopter approaches]
[Shouting continues]
Nice timing, Nomad. How's
it look out there?
Trying to clear you a path to the north.
Check your nine o'clock!
I'm coming around.
Bad news, Vulture Team.
You got more hostiles approaching
your whiskey...
a lot of them!
[Shouting in Chinese]
They're using the trees for cover!
[Machine-gun fire]
I'm losing them in the brush!
This is as close as I can get you!
Then take us higher.
Vulture Team, focus your firepower
on the wave from the north.
We'll take care of the rest.
[Shouting continues]
If we take a position
that creates the right angle
for the five-inch, Nathan James
can take out the east flank.
Once they lock onto our coordinates,
we'll have plenty of time to scram.
Got it!
Nathan James, request
you target our location
and prepare to fire the five-inch.
Copy that, Nomad.
Guns, T.A.O..
Slew EOSS and get a
bearing and range on the helo.
Guns, aye.
[Whirring]
I'm out!
Nearly Winchester here, too.
And here I thought we were in trouble.
- [Chuckles]
- [More shouting]
Vulture Team, Nathan James.
Preparing to fire on your whiskey.
You need to clear south-southwest.
Do you copy?
That way. That way.
We copy, Nathan James,
but we're gonna need a minute.
Roger. Standing by.
[Banging]
Nishioka: I got the helo.
Calculating firing solution now.
If they can hold steady,
I can find a target
and they can get out of the way.
I can't lock on. The
shift is too strong.
Nomad, we can not lock target.
If you bank hard from a hover,
how far can you get in 6.4 seconds?
50, 60 yards, maybe.
Nathan James.
Take your visual on us.
We will hold position.
Give us a count.
You fire, we dive!
That's too dangerous.
Nomad, request approved.
Expect incoming on my mark.
T.A.O., request batteries
release on helo's position.
Vulture Team, are you clear?
It's now or never, sir!
Start the countdown. Go, go, go, go, go!
Five... four...
You bank hard, girl.
Two...
Batteries release, kill target with guns!
Shot over!
Shot out!
Hang on!
[Screaming]
[Helicopter blades whirring]
[Tom coughing]
You all right?
[Groans] Yeah.
Mike. Mike!
You okay?
- Never better.
- Come on.
[Grunting]
We're all good here, sir.
[Panting]
It's quiet.
Kilo is clear!
Target confirmed.
Enemy appears to be neutralized.
Nice shooting, Nathan James!
Green, Taylor... secure the camp,
find Miller and Rios.
We're going after Takehaya.
Yes, sir.
At the last point of contact,
Nathan James was here.
There are at least a dozen reasons
why we might not have heard from them.
Most likely, they went to Emcon.
Without telling us?
It's protocol, in the
case of imminent threat.
[Chatter]
[Groans]
[Speaking Japanese]
Aah! [Groans]
- [Gun cocks]
- Stop!
I don't care how
much she needs your blood.
I will kill you if you
make one more stupid move.
[Groaning]
[Groaning stops]
You okay, doc?
I'm fine.
Miller! Miller!
Miller!
Whoa! Hold!
Leave! Now!
Let him go
It's over, Takehaya.
What was it you said?
"It's not over till I'm dead."
That can be arranged.
Take him down! Don't worry about
me, just take the shot!
You don't want to die now.
You have too much to live for.
Lieutenant, where are we?
Based on the trajectory of
the missile before it hit the UAV,
we believe the Chinese
ship is loitering here...
on the northeast side of the island.
Probably one of their destroyers.
You pick up any signals on SLICK 32?
No, sir. So far, they've been quiet.
Should we call St. Louis?
We can't break Emcon.
Not until we're out
of their engagement zone.
Tell the bridge to head South
for open water at flank speed.
Aye, sir.
Good job today, Lieutenant.
Thank you, sir.
Master Chief...
Hi. I'm Sasha Cooper.
How you doing?
[Groaning]
How many we lose looking for us?
Kudelski in the minefield.
On the island...
Wallace, Butler, Cruz.
All my fault.
Never should have
gone in that nightclub.
There were coming for us,
Mike, no matter what we did.
Who?
The Chinese, Vietnamese, Takehaya?
What the hell's going on, Tom?
That's what we're going to find out.
Get some rest.
When you're ready, ship's yours.
[Sniffs]
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --