(theme music playing)
(distant explosions)
(man shouting orders)
(gunfire)
Man:
Hanging, fire!
Sledge, drop...
- (bullet zings)
- Ahh!
(indistinct shouting)
Thanks.
- Burgin.
- Hillbilly.
You used to
not smoke.
Guess I do now.
I need volunteers!
NCOs report to me
at 1050.
Corpsman,
do blister checks.
Draw ammo
and be resupplied
and ready to move
at 1100.
Room service awaits
and there's time to
savor every bite.
Go and get your chow.
1100? Ack Ack just
gave us the fucking morning off.
Man:
Let's go get some breakfast!
I can't even recognize
this place.
Judging from those planes,
I think it's the airfield we took a while back.
Oh, yeah,
now I remember.
We were over there and
the Japs were over there.
- The Japs were where we're sittin'.
- Right.
It's all coming
back to me now.
Why didn't I enlist
in the Seabees?
I could have come to Peleliu
in the seat of a bulldozer.
Any of you guys got
a Jap sword or flag?
I'll pay
good money for it.
Or a Jap bayonet?
Any kind of Jap weapon...
I'll take it.
Sure.
I keep them in my ass.
Reach up,
grab what you want.
Seriously.
I gotta get me
a Jap sword.
I can't go home from
the war empty-handed.
I can arrange for
a Purple Heart.
Ain't nobody going home.
Any of you guys
got a Jap sword?
Fuck off!
- Boys.
- Hello, sir.
- Hey, Skipper.
- Hey, Skip.
Skip.
Never run when
you can walk.
Never walk when
you can stand.
Never stand when
you can sit.
Never sit when
you can lay down.
Both: Never lay down
when you can sleep.
And never pass a supply
of clean water.
Amen.
(grunts)
You get enough to eat?
I did, sir.
You're a Southern man,
right?
Yes, sir.
Mobile, Alabama.
You realize our ancestors
probably shot at each other
at Gettysburg or Bull Run?
My great-grandfather
served with General Bragg.
Yeah?
What's your old man do?
He's a doctor,
internal medicine.
Treated vets from
the First World War.
Might have patched up
Gunny Haney.
My dad's a shop foreman
at a textile mill in Massachusetts.
He weaved wool fabric
for the military...
all our Marine greens,
our blankets.
It's nice to think my father
might have had something to do
with the blankets we
sleep in.
(flies buzzing)
(explosion)
- Man: Fuck!
- Man #2: Damn.
I got a detail for you.
Yes, sir.
No no, as you were.
As you were.
You got a watch?
Yes, sir.
You show 0950?
I do, sir.
Good. Wake me up
in 20 minutes.
Will do, sir.
- Look at that.
- Haney: Let's go!
Let's go!
You heard the skipper!
That's the way
to kill Japs...
buzz in, fry 'em,
buzz back.
Man:
Hey, look, it's Colonel Puller.
It's the 1st Marines.
- Man: Sir.
- Puller: You're up, boys.
Colonel.
Hello, sir.
Puller:
Go get 'em!
Good job.
Man:
Way to go, 1st.
- Here you go.
- Thanks, man.
Semper fi.
Hey.
How you doin'?
Man:
Let's go!
Man: What kind of man walks
into a field of fire
in defense of his country?
What kind of man has already
served his country
as a soldier in the Philippines
way before Pearl Harbor,
then volunteers to fight
the Japs as a Marine
in the islands
of the Pacific?
What kind of man
risked his life
throughout a night
of combat
running barefoot much-needed
ammunition back and forth
to his buddy on
the frontlines,
manning his machine gun
throughout the fight,
suffering horrible
wounds
while killing countless
savage Japs
in the key battle
that won us Guadalcanal?
I will tell you, brothers:
A fighting man
like no other,
winner of the Congressional
Medal of Honor,
America's own
Sergeant John Basilone!
Little R&R, Johnny?
Reporter:
How long's he been here for?
(golf club striking)
Reporter:
A whole lot of buckets.
John!
(distant explosions)
(twigs breaking)
(man shouts
in Japanese)
(men grunting,
shouting in Japanese)
Ooh!
What was that?
What happened?
- What the fuck is going on out there?
- I don't know.
Who the hell was that?
Two Japs, I think.
One ran down the road.
The otherjumped in Packer's foxhole.
All right, stay in
your foxholes.
- Man: Stay in your holes.
- Stay alert.
There might be more.
How long you people
been doing this!?
You don't get out of
your fucking hole at night
because this is
what happens!
One of us
gets tired.
gets lazy.
One of us doesn't
keep his edge on,
and this...
this is what happens.
What kind of guy gets out of his hole at
night without sounding off?
The kind with
two Japs up his ass.
Just one.
Leyden knows what it's like
to have a Jap up his ass.
- Fuck off!
- Can it, Bill.
Wh... what kind of asshole
shoots the guy?
An asshole like you.
- (gun fires)
- Ahh!
Move out! Down line!
Go for cover!
- Let's go!
- Man: Move down line! We're moving left!
Burgin! Plant your unit
behind that bunker!
- Move out!
- (explosions)
Man: Move down the line!
Let's go, let's go!
Ahh!
God damn it! Oh, God!
- Get the bunker cleared!
- We got it! It's been cleared.
(explosion)
(machine-gun fire)
(chattering)
(explosions continue)
(gunfire grows distant)
Burgie. Burgie.
Japs in the bunker.
First platoon cleared it
with grenades.
- They must have checked.
- No, listen.
Wake up, Sledge.
Burgie...
I'm sure.
They're in there.
(distant gunfire
continues)
(men whisper
in Japanese)
- Son of a bitch!
- (firing)
(men shout
in Japanese)
(gunfire continues)
Sledgehammer, check that side!
Ahhh!
Sledgehammer, Burgie,
up here!
Keep 'em bottled up
till I come back!
(machine-gun fire)
(firing)
Leyden.
Both:
Fire in the hole!
- (explodes)
- (Japanese soldiers scream)
- (speaks Japanese)
- To your right!
Grenade!
(grunts)
- Oh, fuck!
- Look at me, look at me. Look at me.
- I can't fucking see.
- You're all right.
Burgin:
Target 100yds to your right!
Look at me, look at me.
You're all right.
- You're all right.
- I can't fucking see.
- You're gonna be all right.
- Burgin: Get off the bunker, God damn it!
- Ahh!
- Come on.
Bill, come on.
You gotta help me.
We gotta move. Come on.
- No no.
- Hold on, Bill.
(Japanese soldiers
screaming)
(fires)
- (firing)
- (men screaming)
Look at me.
Gene!
Ahh!
- (shouts in Japanese)
- Gene!
Ahh!
Leyden:
Gene?
Gene!
- Gene?
- Burgin: Fry 'em, Womack!
Ahhhh!
Leyden:
Gene!
(Japanese men scream)
Let the bastards
burn!
Ahhh!
(men scream
in Japanese)
Die, you Jap fuck!
Fuckin' die!
You okay?
Why don't they
just surrender?
Because they're Japs.
We're gonna have to
root 'em out one by one.
Fucking rats.
Man:
Look at the gold teeth on this one.
What have you got there?
(plane passes overhead)
(shouts
in Japanese)
(Japanese soldier
gagging)
- Ahh!
- Christ! Put him out of his misery.
Fuck off.
(groaning)
Makes it easier.
(distant explosions
continue)
Snafu:
Bullshit.
The McCulloch boosted
my old man's Mercury V840%.
It only adds
four PSI, Snaf.
You get better torque.
You know that.
Yeah, well, you run that thing
for a while and it'll get noisy.
So?
- How you doin', boys?
- Skipper.
Gunny made some coffee
if anyone wants some.
It's actually
pretty good.
Burgie here says
superchargers are worthless.
What you think, Skipper?
Out here,
I'd have to agree with him.
Here, take this.
I'll get some more.
Go on, take it.
Any word on Leyden,
Skipper?
They already cleaned him up.
That New York Irish
hide of his
is tougher than any little
bit of Jap shrapnel.
He'll be back soon.
We're moving into the hills
come dawn.
Aye aye, sir.
Burgie, I'm gonna need some
of your mortar squad
to volunteer as
stretcher-bearers.
You can't dwell on it.
You can't dwell
on any of it.
Try and get some rest, boys.
(gunfire)
Gotta move!
Move it up there!
Russo, get up there
and find Hillbilly!
Pull him back!
Go!
(explosions)
Stretchers, go!
Go!
(shouts order)
Direct run!
Man:
Go go go!
Ahh!
(bombs whistling)
(indistinct shouting)
Man:
Don't stop! Keep moving!
Keep moving!
Here!
Pick him up!
Move!
Sledge, Snafu, up here!
Sledge, get your stretcher
up here now!
Come on, go!
Man: I need more ammo!
Give me more ammo!
Man:
Corpsman!
Over here!
Get that litter
opened up!
Man:
Let's get him back.
- Boys.
- I got the sulfur.
Corpsman: We're good to go.
Get him on the stretcher.
Man:
We're gonna need to move him fast!
(gunfire continues)
God damn it. Ah!
Get him up!
- Clear.
- Oh!
Ahhh!
- Oh, fuck!
- Man: Fall back!
- Get up here.
- Fall back!
Let's go!
Man:
(man shouting,
indistinct)
Eddie?
(panting)
Eddie.
(grunting)
Take him back.
(gunfire continues)
Let me help you.
Come on.
Let's get you out of here.
Jay:
Did you see Haney?
Sledge:
I saw him.
Haney is the old breed.
If a guy
like that breaks...
(distant
gunfire continues)
And Hillbilly's dead.
You can't dwell
on it, Jay.
on any of it.
We go into those hills again,
I'm gonna get hit.
I know it.
I don't care anymore...
just as long
as it's quick.
- (gunfire)
- (screaming)
- Man: Get that fucker!
- Man #2: Everywhere!
- (man shouts in Japanese)
- (Marine shouting)
- Fucking Japs!
- Japs are everywhere.
Japanese soldier:
Yankee... (speaks Japanese)
- (gunfire)
- (soldier screams)
(sobbing)
Hey hey.
Hey, you're okay.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're okay.
You'll be okay.
- (plane flying overhead)
- (distant gunfire)
How you holdin' up?
(grunts)
Oh, God.
- (man screams in Japanese)
- Oh, shit!
- (gun fires)
- Oh!
- (screaming)
- Jay: Somebody fucking shoot him.
Man:
Get him! Get the bastard!
Jay:
Shoot! Shoot!
Shoot him!
What the fuck is
the matter with you?
Why'd you take so long
to shoot him?
Damn, Jay, if it ain't coming out your
mouth, it's coming out your ass.
(men laugh)
Looks like you
in a sack race, Jay.
Aw, shit.
I shit myself.
- (all laughing)
- No kidding.
Fuck...
I fuckin' shit myself.
You guys are
fucking nuts.
Go back and get some
new dungarees, Jay.
It's all over
my hands.
You left a trail, boy.
They gonna
find us now.
(gunfire continues)
- Who's up ahead?
- Their platoon is on point, sir.
Right up there.
All right, Kelmar,
what do we got?
Men in the hill,
right up there,
covering from that ridge
all the way to the left.
That's good.
Go slow.
(distant gunfire continues)
Mortar!
Hold it up here!
(guns firing)
Man:
Corpsman!
Sniper got the skipper.
Captain Haldane?
Ack Ack's dead.
(sobbing)
Man:
Skipper's dead.
Burgin: All right,
let's get your shit together!
Man: Squad leaders, let's go!
Let's get it movin'!
- Burgin: We're going up!
- Man: Get your gear. We're goin'.
(distant gunfire
continues)
Man:
Let's go! Move up!
(flies buzzing)
(gunfire continues)
Mortars, hold it here!
Smarts with me, God damn it!
See what's up top!
Man:
Let's go!
(opening can)
(dripping)
(distant gunfire)
What you doin',
Sledgehammer?
I thought I'd bag me
some Jap gold.
You don't want to do that.
Why not?
I saw you do it.
Don't.
You shouldn't do it.
The germs.
Doc Caswell says all these
dead nips have germs.
- Germs.
- Bad germs.
Diseases that'll
make you sick.
Bad germs.
Well, is it all right with you
if I cut out his insignia then?
No danger in that I know of.
Yeah?
That pass muster with you?
Here, man.
(men chattering)
Keep it.
Thanks.
(men chattering)
- Nurse: Welcome back.
- Man: Thank you very much.
Welcome back.
You're a sight
for sore eyes.
- Welcome back.
- Very kind of you.
- Nurse: Here you go.
- What the hell are they doing here?
Nurse:
Hi.
- Hi.
Thank you, ma'am.
- Thank you very much.
- Here you are.
Thanks, ma'am.
Hi, welcome back.
It's good to see you.
- Thank you.
- Mac: Okay, Marine.
You've had your look-see.
Now move along.
(theme music playing)