(theme music playing)
- (waves lapping)
- (gulls cawing)
- (jeep approaches)
- (man shouts)
You've gotta take
more salt than this.
- (men grunt)
- You're just depleting yourself, all right?
(men chatting)
Are my eyes yellow?
Why would
your eyes be yellow?
Come on,
your old man's a doctor.
Look at my eyes.
Give it a rest, Snafu.
Seriously.
I'm getting
that yellow jaundice
that's been going around.
I know it.
The heebie-jeebies.
It's hepatitis
and you don't have it.
I'll catch a fever
then turn inside out
through my asshole
like Carson in Love Company.
Come on,
look at my eyes.
- I'm dying, Sledge.
- Hey.
Hey.
Check out my eyes, Jay.
They look yellow?
I just got transferred
out of King.
What?
Where?
Headquarters Company.
Snafu:
Lt'll be all right, Jay.
Shit. You're just
down the road.
Yeah, I'm just
Least I can do is buy you guys a drink
at the slop shoot.
- (car honks)
- Man on radio: This is NBC,
the National
Broadcasting Company.
(NBC theme plays)
Man #2: Carlo works
at a camouflage factory
and Angelo is
a fireman at an army depot
in their home
of Raritan, New Jersey.
Well, you brothers have
a lot to talk over.
What do you say, Carlo?
Well, for one thing, I'd like to be out there
fighting with Johnny,
instead of making
camouflage paint.
That's where
you're wrong, Carlo.
Some guys have
to fight, sure,
but some guys have
to give us the stuff to fight with.
I'll never forget that day
you left for overseas.
Johnny, remember?
All of us kids
at Mom's house,
and after putting away
all that grub.
Ha-ha, that's right.
You got up to go
and all you said was,
"Goodbye, folks.
Be seeing you
in the funnies."
- And that's just what happened.
- Yeah, sure sure.
Go ahead, Johnny. Tell us about the night
you killed all those Japs.
Remember? You were out in the jungle,
standing guard form 8:00 till midnight.
- It was raining.
- It had stopped raining.
My guns began throwing
a lot of stuff
and plenty of stuff
was coming back.
I was in charge of two sections
of heavy machine guns.
While the enemy was hammering out
our defensive positions,
we fought valiantly to check the savage
and determined assault.
- The fierce frontal attack...
- (people chatting)
- Oh, this is good.
- That's right.
- Can I have some more?
- (speaking Italian)
Angelo: Yeah, Dad,
I was so nervous.
I've never been more nervous.
Let me tell you.
Hey, sweetheart,
I was good though.
I sounded like
a movie star, right?
I don't know.
I was shaking like a leaf.
- (speaks Italian)
- Of course, Pa. Of course.
Moses said I sounded like a movie star.
That's me, right?
Carlo: I sound like that too, Pa...
the voice of an angel.
(speaks Italian)
Oh, Johnny,
we're so proud of you.
Ma, all I do is dress up
and say what they tell me.
Well, everyone in America
knows the family name
- because of you, Johnny.
- Carlo: That's right.
I don't want
everyone to know me.
But they do,
because you're so special.
Hey, I get free drinks
because of my hero brother.
- How about that, huh?
- That's right.
- I love that, Johnny.
- Yeah, me too.
(speaks Italian)
- (speaks Italian)
- (Salvatore speaks)
- This looks great, Ma.
- Dora: What's the matter?
- It smells good, Ma.
- Thanks, Ma.
- Dora: What did I say?
- Mom, he just needs some time.
That's all.
(typewriter clicking)
- (bucket thuds)
- (water sloshes)
What can
I do for you?
Sir, I joined
the corps
because I knew the marines
were gonna be the ones
who went in first
and the hardest,
and that's how
it worked out.
But I've been back
more than a year, sir.
I've done what the corps
asked me to do.
Well, that you have, John.
Well, I see your enlistment's
up in six months.
I'll tell you what...
I'll push through your discharge,
- let you go home now.
- No, sir, that's not what I mean.
My home is
the Corps.
I just can't push
pencils anymore.
Please, let me go back
and train the new kids,
let me help them
the way I know how.
Sergeant Basilone,
you make me proud
to be a marine.
Thank you, sir.
- (car honks)
- (marines chanting)
Sergeant Basilone.
Man: They brought you back
after Guadalcanal?
Yes, sir.
I was
at Tarawa.
No war bond drive
for me though.
I guess it's good to have another combat
veteran training.
Where's the rest
of the company?
I'm told they're coming
in three days... a week.
What would you like to to do
until then, Captain?
Take it easy.
Put your feet up.
Whatever you want.
(typewriter clicking)
(men chatting)
(grunting)
Company! Fall in
on your racks!
Shit.
- Names.
- Tatum, Charles! Private First Class!
Evanson, Steve!
Private First Class!
Well, Tatum, Evanson,
why do I find you in your racks
in the middle of the day?
We've had
no orders, Sergeant.
So you've been doing what you've
been told to do...
- nothing.
- Aye, Sergeant.
As of now you are
the first machine-gun squad
in B Company's
Weapons platoon.
Fall in for PT,
five-mile run.
- Three minutes.
- Aye, Sergeant!
(whispers)
That's John Basilone.
Who the hell is
John Basilone?
Jesus. Do you live
in a cave?
The guy killed like
1,000 Japs on the Canal.
The president gave
him a medal. He's a hero.
Let's go! Let's go!
Move! Move your ass!
You've got to go faster than that!
The Japs are killing your buddies!
Get up that net! Move!
1500 marines waiting
to follow you down that net!
The sea is pitching and rolling.
It's not steady like this.
Now we're doing
the range at 1400.
Go draw your weapons
and stand by to move.
Aye, Gunny.
The Jap banzai charge
is right there!
They're coming,
damn it! Hurry!
You drop that gun,
I'll make you carry it
- for one solid month.
- (grunts)
Teamwork is the key to the Marine Corps
machine-gun squad!
- Set that pin on the tripod.
- Shit.
Get that gun
out of the dirt!
Sorry, Gunny.
You drop your rifle in a firefight,
you die, Tatum!
Drop that machine gun,
fumble with a belt,
your buddies die!
Do you understand?
- Aye, Gunny.
- (both panting)
You cannot
fuck this up, ever.
Lives depend on it.
- Is that clear?
- Both: Aye, Gunny.
Break it down.
Do it again.
(chatting)
- Hey, Greg?
- How you doing, John?
How's the chow, boys?
- Sorry.
- Man: You stupid...
- Man #2: Good hands! Good hands!
- Woman: Lend him a hand.
- Go on, get yourself some more.
- Yes, Sergeant.
Come on, move it.
- VIP on deck.
- Who?
That gunny
with the ocean of hair.
It's John Basilone.
Oh, and he looks
even better in person.
Oh, and here he comes.
Can I give you
a hand?
We've got it
under control.
Are you sure
about that?
Do you see
these stripes?
I'm an NCO
just like you.
I have work to do.
- What's her name?
- Sergeant Lena Riggi.
I'm Lucy.
You know, every Friday
us girls catch
the 6:00 train to LA,
just in case
you're interested.
(swing music playing)
(train whistle toots)
(chatting)
- Sergeant Riggi.
- Yes.
I'm assuming
that's Italian, right?
(chuckles)
Here it comes.
"I'm Italian.
You're Italian.
Hey, we're both probably
related to Joe DiMaggio.
Oh. You know, I know where we can get
the best lasagna in the city."
I could go
for some good lasagna.
(chuckles) Look.
LA is full of girls for a guy like you.
You'll do fine.
Happy hunting,
Sergeant.
- (chatting)
- (pop music playing)
- Sergeant.
- Gunny.
- If that's all right with you.
- Sergeant Basilone.
(Lena laughs)
- Yeah.
- That's right.
That's... oh, really?
This is so nice.
I love it here.
Man:
To better days.
- Hey.
- (chuckles)
Boy, it's true what
they say about you.
You get shot down,
you keep coming back.
What? Everybody comes
to the Biltmore, don't they?
(chuckles)
There's another medal
in your future
- if you can get us a table.
- How long have you been waiting for?
We gave up waiting.
It's like this every liberty.
Well, I'll see
what I can do.
And what would
that be, exactly?
Making a table appear
out of thin air?
They know me.
Oh, hey.
Big shot here
thinks he can get us a table.
- I want to make him prove it.
- Lucy: No.
You go. I'm thinking
ofjoining the navy.
Looks like it'll
just be the two of us.
This place is bigger than
the house I grew up in.
Yeah, I never ask for it,
but they always put me up
in the Presidential Suite.
And I'm supposed
to be impressed?
That's why
you arranged all this?
To impress me before
we get down to business?
Business?
Exploring
the bedsheets together.
No.
Well, that's standard
operating procedure for you, isn't it?
No. Not anymore.
You know, I saw you once
at the Brown Derby.
Me and the girls were
waiting to get in
when you arrived with one of those
blonde starlets on your arm.
There you went, right to the front
of the line,
and everyone was
saying, "Ooh. Ah.
There goes John Basilone,
the hero of Guadalcanal."
The line to get in
was so long
I was still there
when out you came,
a brunette starlet
on your arm,
and back into
the same limousine.
And everyone said,
"Ooh. Ah.
There goes John Basilone,
the hero of Guadalcanal."
You ever make it inside?
I had a shrimp cocktail and a Coke
just before they closed the joint.
Gunnery Sergeant Basilone,
dinner was delicious.
- Thank you.
- You barely touched it.
Did I do
something wrong?
This is nothing
but steaks and conversation.
I am now going
to turn in.
- Turn in?
- We girls all share a room,
fight over the bathroom
in the morning.
Tell the chef the Caesar salad
was excellent.
The porterhouse is
a little tough.
Lena,
if I did something stupid,
I'm sorry.
You didn't do anything
a million other guys haven't done.
You just did it
in a nicer room.
(door opens, closes)
- Man: Left right left.
- Men: Left right left.
John:
Gunnery Sergeant Basilone, sir.
Stand at ease.
I'm Lieutenant Sohn.
I'll be replacing
Captain Le Francois,
who went AWOL
while on liberty.
How are the men
shaping up?
All two of them?
The rest of the company
comes in today from Mainside.
They'll be
pretty green, Gunny.
Don't worry sir.
I'll take care of that.
Well, you haven't
got much time.
Your enlistment
runs out in... July.
I've been
in eight years...
four with the doggies,
four in the Corps.
I understand.
(men grunting)
Get up that tower!
- Go!
- Get off my wall, marine! Get off!
John:
One more time!
Up that
cargo net! Now!
Man #2:
Keep moving, boy!
(panting)
What is this,
a mob?!
In formation,
two ranks behind me.
- Oh, come on.
- Man: Move it!
Move your ass!
Man #4:
Let's go. All right.
(all panting)
(chatting)
- Okay, that's the last of the butter.
- 26 Ibs.
Private Dowling, grab a hand truck
and get those sacks of rice.
- Got it?
- Grab those from the bottom.
All perishables go
in the reefer.
All right.
Sergeant Riggi.
Gunny Basilone.
This may not
be appropriate, but...
Hold on.
Just a couple more
and we'll have all this cleared out.
Uh, I would be happy
if you would allow me
to take you out for a proper dinner.
- When?
- Friday night,
a place I know
just off the base...
- a restaurant.
- Clancy's?
- So you know it too.
- Nice place, but no.
Friday's no good for me.
I have orders...
a big banquet
for the officers.
- Maybe some other time?
- How about breakfast?
Tomorrow morning.
The KP reports 0530.
I show 0500.
Show up a little earlier,
I'll make you French toast.
(door bangs)
Every marine out of those racks
and on my deck!
Man:
Get your ass up!
John:
You've got five seconds!
- Five seconds!
- Man: Up up!
- Let's go!
- Move your ass!
Get up! Move!
Don't you eyeball me!
You stand at attention!
And how come we're the only ones
running like this?
- Every damn morning.
- To make us the best.
Oh, shut up.
I'm so sick of this shit.
I just want to get
out there and slap a Jap.
What did you say?
- I said I want to slap a Jap, Gunny.
- (men chuckle)
"Slap a Jap"?
Well, how about it, boys?
I bet you all want
to do more than slap a Jap.
All:
Yes, Gunny!
"Slap a Jap."
That's what the enemy is
to you, huh?
A fucking bucktoothed
cartoon dreamed up
by some asshole
on Madison Avenue to sell soap.
Well, let me
tell you something.
The Jap I know,
the Japanese soldier,
he has been at war
He's a combat veteran,
an expert
with his weapon.
He can live off
of maggoty rice
and muddy water for weeks
and endure misery
you couldn't dream up
in your worst nightmare!
The Japanese soldier
doesn't care if he gets hurt or killed,
as long
as he kills you.
Now you can call them
whatever you want,
but never ever fail
to respect their desire to put you
and buddies into an early grave!
- Is that clear?!
- Yes, Gunny!
Why aren't you
in your full packs?
Gear up!
10-mile run
in formation
- in two minutes!
- (men shout)
You're gonna
enjoy this.
Almost ready.
Pretty fancy for 0500.
(Lena laughs)
You strike me as an Italian mama's boy,
worshipped and pampered
just like my brothers.
I wanted to make
you feel at home.
Well... I was told
at a very early age
I was the best thing
- since sliced capicola.
- (laughs)
And there's enough
for seconds.
- You'll want seconds.
- This is good.
(chuckles) When I first got here,
the coffee was dreadful.
How a marine mess can serve
bad coffee is beyond me.
I can't live
without it.
The best coffee I ever
had was on Guadalcanal
the morning
after the battle.
- I know the story.
- Not this part.
We stole some coffee from the doggies
when they came ashore.
Liberated some hooch
from their officers too.
Anyway, the morning
after the battle,
my guys cooked up the coffee
over a fire of green coconut logs.
There wasn't any part
of me that didn't hurt...
burns on my hands,
ears still ringing
from the shelling.
But when they handed me
that cup of coffee,
I never tasted
anything so good.
Not that I don't
appreciate this.
What was the best cup
of coffee you ever had?
My parents were
real traditional.
I was supposed to get married
and give them grandkids.
So when I announced
that I'd joined the marines,
there was a lot
of yelling and crying
and finally my father
just stopped talking to me,
cut me out
of the family.
A year later I got my stripes.
I went home to see my mom, my brothers.
I was sitting
in this diner
and my pop walked in,
sat down beside me.
He ordered two cups of coffee
and he put the milk
and one sugar in for me.
That was the best
I ever had.
It's incredible what can happen
over a cup of coffee.
My enlistment's up
in July.
I don't know
what I'm gonna do.
You're gonna take a discharge
and you're gonna go home.
I should be looking
forward to my freedom,
but I can't imagine it.
I love the marines.
You do too.
I love everything about it.
I can't imagine being anywhere
or doing anything else.
- Lena.
- Yeah?
You might hear this
all the time,
but you're the most beautiful woman
I've ever seen.
No.
I don't hear that
very often.
Must be the uniform.
- (girls laughing)
- I could use a coffee.
(chattering)
- Shh, she's with the movie star.
- Interesting.
- Woman: Yeah.
- Woman #2: Look at Gunny.
Woman:
A little early morning.
(gossiping, laughing)
- Clear!
- Clear.
Tatum, Evanson, set it up.
Two short bursts,
85 rounds.
Ready!
Gun set.
Fire!
That's good.
Nice.
John:
Listen up!
This is a bale.
It'll make it easier to carry the gun
with a hot barrel.
You won't burn
your hands.
Now it's not made for its
stability and accuracy
but if you're
in a pinch,
you can shoot
and move with this.
Let me show you.
I couldn't hit the side
of a barn with that thing.
You'd better
start practicing.
Yeah.
Lena:
It's gorgeous.
- John: Come on, let's go in the water.
- No.
- Come on, come on.
- No, I'm not going in that water.
- Come on.
- No way.
- No!
- John: I'll get you.
(squeals)
I'm not gonna have you drown.
No, put me down.
- Put me down.
- We're going in.
No!
Oh, my hat.
My hat.
My...
I'll get it.
John, you're crazy.
- Ah!
- (laughing)
(gasps)
I got it!
Oh no.
Oh no, you don't.
Don't you dare.
(soldier shouts)
(plane passes overhead)
Attention on deck!
Stand easy.
Gentlemen, the 5th Division
will ship out very soon
for action in the Pacific
theater of war.
We won't know our destination
until we're well underway.
But wherever we go,
we will see
the job through.
- Am I clear?
- Yes, sir!
I have some more
good news.
Gunnery Sergeant
John Basilone
has decided
that home can wait.
He will be joining us.
(silent)
Carry on, Gunny.
Atten-hut!
(door closes)
At ease.
- So is anybody scared?
- AIl: No, sir.
- I said is anybody scared?
- (shouts) No, Sergeant!
You lying sacks of shit.
(scattered laughter)
It's good to be scared.
It means you're awake,
you're ready.
Company dismissed.
(chatter)
Man:
You ready? You scared?
- Woman: It's not ready yet.
- Woman #2: Oh, okay.
Woman:
Can I have a bowl this time?
(chattering)
She's back there. Lena?
- Hey.
- Hey to you.
Out with it.
- Out with what?
- Whatever grim tidings
you men carry around
with you like rock sacks.
I've shipped over.
I've re-enlisted.
I see.
They can ship me out
whenever they want.
So if you're looking
for something else,
somebody in a different
line of work,
tell me now.
That sounds
like an ultimatum.
- I'm just saying...
- Look.
I'm in for the duration
plus six months.
I know how it goes,
Sergeant.
So?
Where do we go from here?
(laughter, cheering)
Congratulations!
Lucy: Stay there.
I'm gonna take a photo.
You look so beautiful.
Lucy, let me
get a shot.
No, you stay there.
I want to take it.
No, I want a shot of Lena
alone in that dress.
Look here, darling.
Try not to blush.
I feel like
a paratrooper.
- I don't know why I wore this dress.
- You look beautiful!
Be-au-ti-ful!
(camera clicks)
Okay, John, go pose with your wife.
Let's make it official.
Whoo!
(crowd cheering)
Now kiss her
like you mean it.
- I can do that!
- (laughter)
(hooting, cheering)
(gulls cawing)
(laughs, squeals)
Don't you touch me.
(panting)
Hold it.
Wait.
What?
Go stand
over there.
Take your clothes off.
What?
Do it.
John, what have we done?
We've gone respectable.
You know...
I woke up one day
and I was 30 years old.
Satisfied.
Then you walk
into my mess hall,
and look at me now.
Just wait
and see.
- We're gonna have six kids.
- That's a lot of kids.
You should have
come around 10 years ago.
Little boys
for you to pamper,
and little girls
for me to drive crazy.
I'd like that so much.
This is yours now.
I want you to wear it.
- You want some food?
- Dear God, yes.
Let me see
what I can rustle up.
What?
(explosions)
(grunts)
(screaming)
(whimpering)
Look at me!
I said look at me!
You want to live?
Get off the beach.
Move!
Soldier:
Help, help me.
(shrieks)
Help me!
Corpsman!
I need a corpsman!
Move it back.
Get off the beach!
Keep moving.
(screams)
Don't stop.
Keep moving!
Get off the beach.
Keep moving.
Off the beach!
Get up!
Move!
- Someone help me!
- (screaming)
Help him back.
Off the beach!
Off the beach, get off!
Evanson, Tatum,
let's go.
Get the fuck off the beach,
you sons-of-bitches!
(gunfire)
(soldier wails)
Set that fucker up here.
Move!
We gotta kill the bunker.
Get me a rabbit team.
Get your charges
ready to move.
Soldier:
Captain, up here!
Aim for the gunport.
Short bursts.
Go go!
(gun firing)
Keep firing!
It's jammed.
Pegg!
All right, Gunny!
Go, move forward!
Further up!
Here!
Let's go!
Go go go go go!
(shouting in Japanese)
(screaming)
Fire in the hole!
Let's go, let's go!
- Get in, get it.
- On me!
Flamethrower up!
(screams Japanese)
Move!
- Go go.
- Come on.
(screams)
Tatum!
Take out that machine gun
and set up position!
Tatum, clear
the back line!
Hold your fire.
Go go go!
Stay low, stay low!
- Those are ours!
- (plane roaring)
Tatum, set the gun
up there!
They're firing
for the ridge.
Go go!
Move move move!
Down low.
Steve, Steve, lower!
Do not leave this position
come hell or high water.
- Do you understand?
- Both: Aye, Gunny.
(tanks creaking)
You tell that tank
to follow me!
- Aye aye.
- Move!
Let's go!
The rest of you, grab as
much ammo as you can find
- and get off the beach!
- Aye, Gunny.
We're fucked.
What are we gonna do?
Get that gun over here!
- Move!
- Get down!
Go!
(gulls cawing)
(theme music playing)