(theme music playing)
(animals chittering,
screeching)
(distant screech)
You see Briggs?
His men?
No, sir.
- (machine-gun fire)
- Man: Hold that front.
Man #2:
Guard that front.
Cease fire!
Cease fire.
Break 'em down.
- Man: Give 'em the damn password.
- Man #2: Lorelei, Lorelei.
- Man #3: Cover the rear.
- Man #4: Make a hole, make a hole.
Morgan:
Jesus Christ.
Fuckers really are sneaky.
Hey.
Are you hit?
No.
Chesty wants your squad to hang back
with Able Company,
see if the Nips follow us.
Then we'll rejoin
the battalion further north.
Yeah.
- JP?
- Yeah?
- Set up on that trail.
- On it.
Manny, hand that piece
to Garland and dig in next to me and Mo.
Come on, let's go.
Deploy.
Man:
You heard him. Let's go, let's go.
- Evans, on me.
- Yes, Sergeant.
(thunder rumbling)
Supper's on.
Got anything good?
- What are those?
- Army rations from 1918.
Quartermaster
over in Dog Company
claims they're edible.
After you suck on them
for about an hour or two.
This is all
you could find?
You fuckin' forage
next time.
Hey, who you
writing to, Leckie?
Is it a broad?
Runner:
Aw, come on, Leckie.
Read it.
I'd do it for you.
- "Dear Vera..."
- I knew it. It's a broad.
"Dear Vera,
it's raining.
I'm entertaining Runner
by reading this letter.
Can't wait to see you
and ever so slowly
strip you of your..."
You don't need
to hear that part.
Oh, that's precisely
what I need to hear.
Tell her
how handsome I am.
I'm gonna tell her
the truth.
We've been swallowed
by the jungle
and 5,000 Japs
waiting to kill us.
(thunder rumbling)
Hey, thanks for
brightening the mood.
Oh, I do what I can.
(men talking on radio)
Man:
...unless it's somebody with BO.
That's really dismal.
Man #2:
Yes, and the most dismal thing
- about BO is...
- (flies buzzing)
Man:
Keep that line moving. Let's go.
...especially the ladies.
Woman:
Well, Mr. May, the ladies know
how easy my pancakes
are to make.
Turn that shit off.
I don't wanna hear
about BO and pancakes.
I don't answer
to you, Morgan.
- What?
- Shove it.
- Whoa whoa whoa.
- Man: Tear his head off.
- Get the fuck off me.
Relax relax.
Man: Yeah, rice.
Just what I was hoping for.
What do you got
against Aunt Jemima?
Jap navy sails up and down
this slot every night and plasters us.
That don't got nothing
to do with her.
The only radio reports
I wanna hear
is that a bunch of Jap ships
have been sunk somewhere
off some crappy island
called Guadalcanal.
But we'd need the Navy
for that, wouldn't we?
- So fat chance.
- Come on. Hey hey.
So the Japs
got us surrounded.
Is that
what's buggin' you?
John, I shit like 20 times a day.
My ass is killing me.
JP's in a bad mood,
Manny.
Next he'll be complaining
about the mosquitoes.
Come here.
Hot chow'll
cheer you up.
Think of it as meat.
- Fuck it.
- Next.
Puller: Boys, Division just translated
some Jap newspapers
that was found on the other side
of the Matanikau.
Would you care to know
what the Nips think of us?
Men:
Yes, sir.
"The Americans
on this island
are not ordinary troops,
but Marines,
a special force
recruited from jails
and insane asylums
for bloodlust."
(laughter, cheering)
- They got that right.
- (men laugh)
Puller:
I got some more good news.
Rumors that they would never get here
are to the contrary.
The Army just landed.
- (men grumbling)
- I know, I know.
I want every man
in my battalion shaved by 1600.
Men:
Yes, sir.
I guess there ain't nothing much we can do
about our dungarees.
I figure we're just
raggedy-ass Marines.
- We look this way for a reason.
- Yes, sir.
We can't do it
if they don't run.
Jesus Christ, Evans,
you sound like my fucking wife.
- Kinda looks like her too, huh?
- A little bit.
Basilone:
What's this? Hey.
- Hey, whoa. Hey hey hey!
- Whoa whoa whoa!
Hey, fuck you!
- Fuck you guys.
- Put your face right fuckin' here.
- Thanks for coming, guys.
- Fuckin' Army.
- Just fuckin' wait.
- (men chuckle)
- (voices overlapping)
- Man: Get in here.
(air-raid sirens blaring)
(bombs thudding)
- (men shouting)
- (machine-gun fire)
See, Evans?
The Army don't know
the Japs bomb the airfield,
but not the beach.
Stay low, get greedy.
Let's go.
Come on.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Over here, over here.
Basilone:
Grab it, just grab it.
- Hey, Manny. Over here, Manny.
- Come on, come on.
Man:
Give me some stuff.
Man #2:
Fill it up. Let's go.
Man #3:
Jackpot, boys!
Look at this!
Let's go, let's go,
let's go, let's go.
Come on, JP,
get it in the bag.
Get it in, get it in.
Come on, JP, come on.
JP, make sure
you get those cherries.
- Hurry.
- I got the cherries.
Man:
Hey, give me a hand.
- Man: Let's go.
- Man #2: Can't get it open.
- Man #3: Doesn't matter, any of it.
- Man #4: Hey, grab this.
Man #3:
Throw it in there.
- Man: Pop that locker.
- Man #5: I got it. I'm trying.
Man:
Get moving!
Army gets the new stuff
and we fight with shit
my grandfather used.
Hey, guys!
Look what I got.
Hah!
Crackers.
- Look at this. Give me a hand.
- I got it.
- Hey, you there, halt!
- Man: MP, MP!
- Let's go, come on!
- M. P: I said halt!
- Come on, JP.
- M. P: Halt!
Stop right there.
That's Army gear. Halt!
(laughing, whooping)
- Try and catch us.
- Thanks for the chow.
Here.
There you go.
- Private Leckie.
- Sir.
The Army captain
from the 164th's raising hell
about somebody
breaking into his trunk
and stealing a box of cigars
and shoes.
Not just any shoes.
Said they were his favorite pair
of moccasins.
Well, that's bad luck
for that captain.
Yeah, well, you might
wanna watch where you wear those
or smoke any cigars
you might not have.
Or drink any hooch
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Anything happen
while I was prospecting?
Betty Hutton stopped by
giving out blowjobs.
- What'd you get?
- (grunts)
Well, these...
are for me.
But if you're nice and mind your manners,
I might give you a puff.
These...
are for you miscreants.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, yeah.
Traded the crackers
with F Company.
- Hey, peaches.
- Peaches?
I got the goddamn runs
and you had to get peaches.
They were all
out of cheese, Runner.
Chuckler:
Oh, my God, these are amazing.
Ah, where have you been all my life,
you beautiful can?
Ah.
(laughs)
(groans)
(grunting)
Peaches.
Your new name is Peaches.
- Fuck you.
- You got it, Peaches.
(both laughing)
- You gotta write Vera about this.
- (laughing)
(gagging, coughing)
Runner,
your new nickname
is Old Faithful.
Fuck you, Peaches.
(distant rumbling,
booming)
Bud...
bud, we gotta go.
Come on, bud!
Come on! We gotta go!
- Ahh!
- Shit.
- Fuck!
Son of a bitch!
- (Hoosier yelling)
- (barks)
(dog whining)
Fuck!
You're okay.
We're gonna make it through.
- You're okay. You're okay.
- Shit.
Shit!
- I ain't going anywhere.
- God damn it!
Fuck you, fuck you!
Man:
Ahh!
(explosions booming)
(men coughing)
- Basilone: Sound off!
- LaPointe.
- Evans.
- Upton.
Garland.
- Come on, get up.
- (men shouting)
Help me out.
I got him.
(men coughing)
(Evans crying)
- Evans.
- (crying, whimpering)
- Start digging out.
- I can't, I can't.
- Miller.
- Garcia.
(men continuing
to sound off)
Man:
Let's go. Keep looking for bodies.
Man #2:
What about the Jeeps?
Rodriquez:
Direct hit.
Some little Jap lady,
weapons plant...
she puts in five more grams
of explosives.
Morgan:
Man, that could've been us.
Basilone, Manny, JP.
Briggs, what is it?
Basilone:
Briggs.
Chesty wants
Dog Company NCOs at his CP.
Puller:
Our battalion will join Hanneken's
in our old position
south of the airfield.
Now it's been
a quiet sector.
It's rough terrain.
Topside thinks
the Japs
are going to attack
up by the Matanikau,
hoping that they can
run their armor
up the coast road
right into the airfield.
If that happens,
they might pull Hanneken,
put him up north to reinforce the 5th
and the 1st Marines.
And that is gonna
leave us alone,
singled up on the line.
Now if the Japs
do break through
and they retake
the airfield,
our orders are
to take to the jungles
and fight as guerrillas.
This is not
going to happen.
Men:
Aye aye, sir.
Move your men
to the line at Sector 3.
- Get it done.
- Men: Aye aye, sir!
Basilone,
you and Rodriguez stay behind.
Listen, can you spare
this hombre?
I need another runner.
Hell, Colonel,
we're sick of him.
Get your shit.
Meet me back at the CP.
Aye aye, sir.
Good luck, man.
Hanneken's being pulled
up north to the Matanikau.
Japs will make
their push up there.
Where's Briggs
headed?
Rodriguez:
Setting up an outpost south of the line.
Fuck it.
We're on our own.
Let's go, Marines.
Move move move.
You'll be singled up.
Just like Chesty said.
Man: Okay, Marines, let's get
these supplies up the line.
- How did Chesty get all the phones?
- God knows.
He wants every gun-pit
on a party line
so we got a man
listening at all times.
(cranking phone)
Man:
Hey, you want some limit stakes
in there, Sergeant?
Yeah, go get it.
(gun clinking)
The Japs are on the move.
Hoosier and Runner,
I want you to set up an LP.
- 30 yards inside the tree line.
- Aye aye, Captain.
I want your MG
smack up on the wire,
but preset placements
so you can move back.
How thin are we
on the line, sir?
We're putting
the cooks on the line,
but don't have
enough cooks.
Best case, we hear the shit
going off on the other side of the ridge.
Why the other side
of the ridge?
The Japs decided to go around
us to hit the airfield.
We're too spread out,
same as Puller and the 7th.
Well, same old story
for the 1st Marines.
Two-hour watches tonight
all along the line.
What you guys smokin'?
Raleighs?
That's our allotment.
Only the officers
get the Lucky Strikes.
Well, I can't have
my platoon suffering.
Eyes open, ears up.
Aye aye, sir.
That was a gesture
of a gentleman.
- Hoosier: We must really be fucked.
- Runner: Yep.
(thunder rumbling,
crashing)
Thanks, Evans.
Here, Sergeant,
while it's still dry.
Thanks.
A buddy of mine's
up there with the 5th,
played the trumpet with me
in the Division band.
You any good
on the trumpet?
Nah, mostly because
I play the trombone.
That was a joke.
Look at you.
We'll make a Marine
out of you yet.
Man:
It's starting to come faster.
(thunder rumbling,
distant booming)
Sir, it's Briggs
at the outpost.
Puller.
Report, over.
(whispering)
I got the whole fucking Jap army
headed your way, over.
When they're past you,
pull out and hook up with Able Company.
1st Battalion,
hold your fire as long as possible.
Say again,
hold your fire.
Over.
We don't have enough men.
- Puller: Get Division on the line.
- Man: Aye aye, sir.
- Rodriguez.
- Sir.
Run as much ammo
down there as you can.
Aye aye, sir.
They're not just coming
across the Matanikau.
They're coming
right at us.
(gun clinking)
(flare gun fires)
Man:
Squad leaders, give me a head count!
- Man #2: First squad's up.
- Man #3: Second squad's up.
- Everyone okay?
- Yes, Sergeant.
Man:
Japs!
Japs left, crawling in!
(screaming)
On your right!
- Reload.
- Man: Changing the box.
Cover.
Reload.
- Man: Medic!
- Man #2: Reload.
- Man: Cease fire!
- Man #2: Cease fire!
(mortars whizzing)
Man:
Contact on the left.
Morgan:
No shit.
(laughs)
That's JP for you.
- How much ammo you got?
- Half a belt.
- That's it?
- Yeah.
This is our last box too,
Sergeant.
- (yelling)
- Fuck!
Fuck!
Reload!
(shouts in Japanese)
Fuck, my gun's jammed!
Basilone:
Evans, mend the gun.
(Japanese troops yelling)
Man:
Grenades out there!
You're up!
Sergeant!
Sergeant,
they broke through!
They overran us.
Both guns are out.
Man: Conserve your ammo.
We're running low.
Evans, we're going.
We gotta help JP.
Where the hell is my glove?
- LaPointe, the tripod.
- Aye aye, Sergeant.
- (sizzles)
- Ahh.
Cover cover!
Man:
To my right! To my right!
Get it on there.
Man:
Fill in that gap!
(grunts)
- (yells)
- (shouting in Japanese)
(shouting in Japanese)
(roaring, shouting
in Japanese)
(man shouts
(both grunting)
(whimpering)
(choking)
(speaks Japanese)
(yelling)
Let's go!
(men screaming)
Man:
Ammo ammo!
Reload!
(machine-gun fire,
bullets whizzing)
(men shouting in Japanese)
- How many got through?
- At least 50.
- Ahh! Shit!
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
- Here they come!
(Japanese troops yelling)
Jesus Christ.
(shouting)
God damn!
(gunfire stops)
Man:
I need a head and ammo count.
Man #2:
First squad: Two down,
80 rounds remaining.
Man #3:
Third squad: Three casualties.
- JP, cover me.
- John, wait. What are you doing?
John, what are you doing?
(yelling in Japanese)
(grunting, panting)
John, move,
left flank.
John,
get outta there!
Grenade!
- What the hell was that?
- Now you've got a clear field of fire.
- A clear field...
- LaPointe, Evans,
stay here,
hold this position.
- I'm gonna get more ammo.
- Morgan: Hurry back.
Ammo for the 30s!
Come on, come on,
come on!
That's all we got.
- Ahh!
Ugh!
(groaning)
- Ammo!
- Man: I need cover!
(Japanese troops yelling)
Just keep it still.
Man:
Damn this. Goddamn bugs.
Follow this barbed wire
and find out where
the bridge is.
(sighs)
Is he okay?
Yeah, he's okay.
He's sleeping.
- Manny all right?
- Haven't seen him.
Guess I need
a new one, huh?
You and me both.
- Has he had any morphine?
- No.
- (groaning)
- Thanks.
- Hold him down.
- (speaking Latin)
Hey, Sergeant,
hand me that pail.
(continues in Latin)
Those are
third-degree burns.
Have a seat over there
and we'll get to you when we can.
(gasping)
Sir, anybody bring in
Sergeant Rodriguez last night?
- Manny Rodriguez?
- I wish I could keep track.
(wincing)
Check the aid station?
Man: Doesn't take long
to get ripe in this heat.
Man #2:
They're real damn stupid
to keep running into
a machine gun like that.
- Man #3: Morning, sir.
- Puller: As you were.
Nice work.
(sighs)
I'm putting you in
for a medal, John.
We're gonna be moving
west toward Lunga, up on the ridge.
164th's gonna take
this position.
- Get yourselves some hot chow.
- Aye aye, sir.
Captain.
(bugle playing)
(birds twittering)
(breathing deeply)
It's gone, isn't it?
Doesn't matter.
I'm enlisting tomorrow.
I'd do it tonight
if they were open.
- Eugene...
- I don't need your permission, Father.
I haven't for some time.
The worst thing about treating those
combat boys from the Great War
wasn't that they had
had their flesh torn.
It was that they had
had their souls torn out.
I don't want to look
in your eyes someday
and see no spark,
no love, no... no life.
That would break my heart.
Give me some time
to break the news to your mother.
After supper
I'll take Deacon for a walk.
That would do it.
Thank you, Father.
Come on, Deacon.
Leckie's voice:
"The foe you gave was strong and brave
And unafraid to die.
Speak to the Lord
for our comrades,
Killed when the battle
seemed lost.
They went to meet
a bright defeat...
The hero's holocaust.
False is the vaunt
of the victor,
Empty our living pride.
For those who fell
there is no hell...
Not for the brave
who died."
Say hi for me.
- What?
- Vera.
Tell her Runner
says Howdy do.
It's not a letter,
it's a poem,
- an ode.
- Hmm.
An epitaph
in celebration of our...
glorious victory
at Guadalcanal.
Must be tough
to write that poem.
I mean what the hell rhymes
with "Guadalcanal"?
How fucked are we now
on Guadalcanal?
Corrigan:
Get your gear and stand by to stand by.
We're finally leaving
this shithole.
Man:
Clear the raft.
Man #2: Squad leaders, make sure
all your Marines
have all their gear
and all their equipment.
Jesus fucking Christ,
out with it.
Man:
First squad, pick up your gear.
As fast
as a bullet goes...
It's just a split second.
Manny steps to the left
instead of his right...
- He slows down...
- Yeah, but he didn't.
I mean he was
where he was and, you know...
he did what he did.
You don't ever
think about that?
You know me, John.
I try not to think.
If it happens,
it happens.
We should get moving.
Yeah.
No chow till 1400.
I'm sorry.
Hey, we heard
there was coffee.
Coffee?
Shit, I can get you guys
some coffee.
Milk and sugar?
Cook:
So how bad was it?
'Cause I heard
it was bad.
- From who?
- What do you mean?
I mean before
you got here,
had you ever even
heard of this place?
Guadalcanal?
Everybody's heard
of Guadalcanal
and the 1st
Marine Division.
You guys are
on the front page
of every newspaper
in America.
You're heroes back home.
(theme music playing)