IN 1979, CONGRESS AUTHORIZED
A FORMATION OF A CONTINGENT
OF ELITE SPECIAL FORCES
SOLDIERS WHO ANSWER ONLY
TO THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES.
THEIR MISSIONS AND
THEIR VERY EXISTENCE
ARE CLOSELY GUARDED SECRETS
PROTECTED BY
THE SOLDIERS THEMSELVES
AND THEIR WIVES WHO POSSES
SECRETS OF THEIR OWN.
YOU DO NOT TELL
YOUR MOTHER,
YOUR BEST FRIEND,
YOUR PRIEST,
WHAT YOUR HUSBAND DOES.
ARMY REGULATIONS STATE--
WE ARE NOT IN THE ARMY,
YOU'RE IN THE UNIT.
PREVIOUSLY ON  THE UNIT...
YOU RE-UPPED.
HONEY, I HAVE NOT RE-UPPED.
I'M LEAVING THE UNIT
TO KEEP MY PROMISE.
YOU MUST BE
MRS. COLONEL TOM RYAN.
WELL, I SUPPOSE
THAT'S RIGHT.
I WOULD LIKE
TO THANK YOU, MRS. RYAN,
FOR YOUR SPEECH.
THERE'S THAT TIME
AFTER HE MADE MASTER--
[GUNSHOTS]
AAH!
GET DOWN!
CHECK ON THE WOMEN!
www.1000fr.com present
sync:FRM@个人ID
[DOG BARKING IN BACKGROUND]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
AHH.
[DOG BARKING
IN BACKGROUND]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[SHEEP BLEATING
IN BACKGROUND]
COME ON.
CAN'T DO IT.
SAM?
WOULD YOU?
TOM?
[GURGLES]
FOR HIM.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
[BUGLE PLAYING]
BE CAREFUL NOW, MR. GREY.
[STATIC]
WELL, I'LL BE.
SHE'S GOT
ENOUGH C-4 ON HER
TO SINK THE BISMARCK.
WE'RE ABOUT TO HAVE COMPANY.
IMMINENT RURU.
DARLIN', YOU CAME
TO THE WRONG DOOR.
[CHANTING]
www.1000fr.com present
sync:FRM@个人ID
DON'T SHOOT ME.
DEAR, GOD.
I FORGOT
THE DAMN PASSWORD.
WHY ARE YOU WEARING
A COAT THAT COULD BLOW
US ALL TO BOMBAY? WHY?
I FORGOT THE DAMN--
E.R.S.
E.R.S.?
WHAT'S THAT?
EMERGENCY.
FIREFLY. FIREFLY.
ADD IT UP.
7 LETTERS.
SECOND AND FOURTH
ARE VOWELS. IT SCANS.
THEN WHO THE HELL
ARE YOU?
FIREFLY.
AGENCY?
NO. THEY AIN'T
GOT NO ONE THIS DEEP.
IS THAT SO?
[COUGHING]
LOOK, RAIN
OR SHINE, BOSS,
WE'VE GOT 5 MINUTES
TO GET OUR PACKAGE
TO THE RENDEZVOUS.
SHE'S SICK.
NO, SHE AIN'T SICK.
SHE'S DYING.
[BEEP]
CARD'S INVALID
AS OF 1700.
CHANGE OF STATION?
YEAH. I'M LOOKING
FOR THE COLONEL.
WILL YOU WAIT
OVER THERE PLEASE?
I NEED YOU
TO SURRENDER THE CARD.
WHEN YOU'RE IN,
YOU'RE A GUEST,
WHEN YOU'RE OUT,
YOU'RE A PEST.
[BEEPING]
ARE YOU SURE?
I SPELL FOXTROT-
INDIO-ROMEO--
FIREFLY? IS THAT THE RIGHT
CRASH CODE FOR TODAY?
FOR YESTERDAY.
TODAY'S CODE IS FORGER.
WHAT?
FORGER.
SNAKE DOC.
FIREFLY IS YESTERDAY'S CODE.
HOW MUCH TIME WE GOT
TILL THE EXFILL?
WHEN'S HER FLIGHT OUT?
PAST DUE. NOW.
THEY'VE GOT THE PACKAGE?
YES, SIR.
HOLD. HOLD. HOLD.
MATT?
SIR?
I'M WRAPPIN' OUT
TOMORROW MORNING.
TURN YOUR BACK.
GET HIM ON THE LINE.
WISH YOU THE BEST
FOR THE REST OF YOUR
CAREER, SOLDIER.
WHATEVER THAT MAY BE.
IS THE TEAM ALL RIGHT?
JONAS IS BACK, RIGHT?
LEAVE YOUR CREDS ON MY DESK.
GOT THE DIRECTOR OF COVERT
OPS OF THE CIA FOR YOU.
WE'VE GOT A WOMAN.
WE GOT A WOMAN THAT
SAYS SHE'S CIA.
DEEP, DEEP
UNDER OUT THERE.
SHE'S BEEN
THERE HOW LONG?
CRASH CO'S A DAY OFF,
SNAKE DOC.
YOUR CALL.
ROGER THAT.
WHAT DAY IS IT, FIREFLY?
TUESDAY?
TUESDAY IS YESTERDAY, FRIEND.
I'VE BEEN SICK.
THEY GAVE ME A SHOT.
WHY'D YOU COME HERE?
I KNEW YOU'D BE HERE.
I KNEW THIS SAFE HOUSE.
WHAT--WHAT CHANCE--
HOW LONG YOU BEEN UNDER?
20--28--30 MONTHS.
WHO'S YOUR STATION CHIEF?
WORK FOR LANGLEY.
6-5 AND PICK 'EM.
YOU'VE BEEN LIVING UNDERCOVER
FOR MORE THAN 2 YEARS?
WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE TODAY,
FIREFLY?
AND IF'N YOU'RE WRONG,
YOU KNOW YOU'RE THE ONE
TO GO FIRST.
SHE DON'T CARE IF SHE'S
THE FIRST TO GO, BOSS.
SHE CAME DRESSED
FOR THE PROM.
AND WHAT ARE YOU DOING
HERE WITH ALL THIS BOOM-BOOM
ON YOUR BODY?
HUH?
WHAT ARE THE EXPLOSIVES FOR?
IF THEY FOUND ME OUT--
WHAT, YOU'RE GOING
TO BLAST YOUR WAY
OUT OF AN ENTIRE COUNTRY?
NO, I...
I THOUGHT I'D TAKE
THEM WITH ME.
GIRL HATES TO TRAVEL
ALONE, YOU KNOW?
HEY, SAM, DO YOU REMEMBER THIS?
GEORGE WASHINGTON
AND THE IRAQIS.
WHAT'S THAT?
WHEN SAM WAS IN MY CLASS,
WHEN HE WAS THE STAR
OF MY CLASS--
DID GEORGE WASHINGTON
ACTUALLY FIGHT THE IRAQIS?
HOW'S JONAS DOING?
HE BACK TO FULL DUTY?
YOU CLEARED HIM.
DID I?
I SUPPOSE I DID.
WAS IT BEFORE HIS TIME?
NOT ACCORDING TO HIM.
MS. GERHARDT,
YOU STILL WITH US?
YEAH. SAM FELL OFF
THE SWING SET AT HOME.
HMM.
AND WHERE
ARE HIS PARENTS?
STILL TRYING
TO LOCATE 'EM.
BENTON, SAMUEL,
12/21/96.
DID THEY HAVE
IRAQIS IN GEORGE
WASHINGTON'S TIME?
IT WAS THE FRENCH
AND INDIAN WAR.
IT WAS ACTUALLY
THE IROQUOIS,
BUT THAT'S HOW SAM
WROTE IT DOWN: IRAQIS.
WHEN HE WAS MUCH YOUNGER.
WAS HE ACCIDENT PRONE
THEN, TOO?
4 TRIPS TO THE E.R.
IN THE LAST 6 MONTHS.
DOES THAT HURT, SON?
YES.
CAN YOU MOVE
YOUR HAND?
MMM.
WHAT BRINGS YOU IN, FIREFLY?
THAT'S THE MESSAGE.
THE MESSAGE I STOLE
FROM THEIR LEADER.
THAT--THAT'S WHERE
THEY'RE TAKING THEM.
THEY'RE TAKING THEM ON
A BUS TO THE AIRPORT.
MEN--MEN ON THE BUS,
THEY'RE--
[MUTTERING]
SEND--
[WHISPERING]
They're sending a bus.
A bus.
The bag.
Look at the bag.
BRING THE BAG OVER HERE.
WHATEVER IT IS, SHE RISKED
HER LIFE TO BRING IT IN.
ATTENTION TO ORDERS.
YOUR MOM'S
A LITTLE LATE.
IN THIS EVOLUTION,
WE SHALL HAVE 1--
PLAYING WITH THE NEW BABY,
AND 2--CHINESE FOOD.
WHERE'S LISSY?
IN HER ROOM WITH CJ.
IT'S NOT SO FAR AWAY.
NO, LISSY.
IT'S NOT.
AND I'M GOING TO CALL
YOU EVERYDAY.
EVERYDAY.
GIRLS.
DINNER.
CJ, YOU CAN STAY.
I TOLD MY MOM I'D BE HOME.
AND I WILL CALL YOU.
HOW YOU DOIN', DARLIN'?
IT'S HER FIRST
CHANGE OF STATION.
WELL, I'VE GOT
SOME BAD NEWS.
THERE ARE 2 THINGS YOU
WILL NOT BE ABLE TO DO,
MAKE YOUR BED AND
CLEAN UP YOUR ROOM.
I AM GOING
TO LET CORPORAL SMITH
FINISH THE FESTIVITIES,
AS HE HAS DONE
MANY MORE THAN I.
RADIUS AND ULNA,
GREEN STICK BREAK.
THE PARENTS?
NOT AT HOME, WE CALLED.
HE GET IT FALLING
OFF A SWING?
HOW WELL DO YOU KNOW
THE BOY, TIFFANY?
I HAD HIM
IN THIRD GRADE.
THIRD GRADE?
WHY'D HE COME TO YOU?
WELL, HE'S ALWAYS--
I WAS JUST ALWAYS
THE ONE HE SOUGHT OUT.
I WAS MORE THAN JUST
A TEACHER TO HIM.
HE'S A SPECIAL KID, BILL.
ALWAYS LOVED TIFFANY.
SPECIAL KID.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THE PARENTS?
BOTH IN. MOM'S AN E-4,
DAD'S AN E-5.
KID NEEDS SOMEONE
TO TALK TO.
SOMETHING HE CAN'T
TELL HIS PARENTS.
HOW DO WE KNOW?
HE CAME TO YOU.
HE WILL, I WOULD THINK,
COME BACK TO YOU.
CAN YOU--
SOMEONE NEEDS
TO TALK TO THE PARENTS.
HE VOTED FOR YOU
BECAUSE HE TRUSTS YOU.
GOOD.
NOW, YOU NEED TO KEEP AN EYE
ON HIM AND LET HIM KNOW.
BILL.
SURE, IF WE HAD COUNSELING,
BUT WE DON'T HAVE COUNSELING
FOR KIDS ON THE BASE.
AND SO, OF COURSE,
THE JOB FALLS TO YOU.
BILL.
TIFFY AND MAC ARE
LEAVING THE UNIT.
LEAVING THE BASE.
AH, YES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
[SIGHS]
I WAS AN ARMY BRAT
LIKE YOU, DARLIN',
BUT DIFFERENTLY FROM YOU.
WE LIVED ON 5 BASES
BY THE TIME I WAS 10,
AND I LEARNED,
AND YOU WILL LEARN
THE FOLLOWING,
WHICH WILL BOTH SURPRISE
AND DELIGHT YOU.
WHEN YOU REACH THE NEW BASE,
YOU WILL FIND YOU
ARE STILL AT HOME.
HOW ABOUT THAT?
AND HERE'S
THE REAL KICKER, NOW.
WHEN YOU GET MARRIED--
TIFFY? WHERE'S THE--
WHERE'S THE--
WHERE'S MOM?
SHE'S OUT WITH MOLLY.
YOU HUNGRY?
YOU WILL, I'M GOING
TO BET YOU $5.00 NOW,
MARRY AND/OR BOTH BE
A SOLDIER YOURSELF.
YES.
AND CONTINUE
MOVING BASE TO BASE,
AND CURIOUSLY,
ALWAYS BE AT HOME.
MAN WON'T SELL
YOU HIS LIFE,
BUT HE'LL TRADE IT
TO YOU FOR A LITTLE
PIECE OF RIBBON.
HOW DO YOU WALK WITH ALL
THAT TRASH ON YOUR CHEST?
I DON'T KNOW.
I AIN'T DONE IT
IN YEARS.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO GO?
'CAUSE YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND,
THE COLONEL WILL TEAR
UP YOUR TRANSFER AND KILL
THE FATTY CALF.
I'M SURE HE WOULD.
THEN, DON'T GO.
YOU ARE ASKING THE WRONG
MEMBER OF MY MARRIAGE.
WHAT YOU READIN'?
THE BIBLE.
LOOKING FOR A NAME
FOR OUR SON.
WELL, BIBLE'S
A GOOD PLACE TO LOOK.
HAIR CLIPPERS.
ANY REGRETS?
REGRETS ARE FOR
THE AIR FORCE, MA'AM.
I AM A RANGER.
[BUZZING]
WANT ME TO DO
THAT FOR YOU,
OR IS THAT TOO SAMSON
AND DELILAH?
NO, I AM NOT SHORTENING
MY LOCKS BECAUSE OF DELILAH,
AND I AM NOT SHORTENING THEM
BECAUSE OF MY WIFE, TIFFANY.
IT'S CALLED
CHANGE OF STATION.
AND WHEN IT'S TIME,
IT'S TIME.
BEST HUSBAND IN THE WORLD'S
A MILITARY MAN.
YOUR WIFE IS A LUCKY WOMAN.
IS THAT SO?
DIDN'T I JUST SAY IT?
WE'LL BE BY
IN THE MORNING
TO SEE YOU OFF.
[BUZZING]
[NO AUDIO]
[CHATTER]
PAKISTAN, ARABIC.
[NO AUDIO]
THE GUARDS GOT RECEIVED
RATION SHARE DOSAGE.
GUARDS RECEIVED EACH--
[NO AUDIO]
SYRIATAH.
LAST WORD IS SYRIATAH.
THERE'S SEVERAL WAYS
YOU CAN SPELL IT, COLONEL.
IT'S NOT AN ARABIC WORD.
IF IT'S
NOT ULU, IT'S--
SPELL IT.
[NO AUDIO]
IT'S A TRADE NAME.
IT'S A TRADE NAME
FOR A MEDICINE.
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GUARDS RECEIVED DOSAGE OF...
IT'S A MEDICAL
TRADE NAME FOR--
OH, HERE IT IS.
IT'S AN IMMUNIZATION.
WHAT'S THE IMMUNIZATION FOR?
I NEED DR.
MUHAMMAD SHIZEH,
EX-WORLD HEALTH, RETIRED.
BRUSSELS, PARIS,
CODE WORD RIVER FRONT.
COUNTERSIGN: FAIRFIELD.
yes madan.
YEAH.
THEY WANT THE BOOK BACK,
AND THE GIRL.
WE'RE TAKING HER
OUT OF HERE.
IT'S BIOLOGIC.
IT'S A BIOLOGIC ATTACK.
HEY, FIREFLY.
HOW ARE THEY GOING
TO SPREAD THE DISEASE?
20 MEN,
DRESSED AS TOURISTS.
IT'S A DISEASE. BUT HOW?
THE TOUR GROUP.
THAT'S HOW
THEY'RE SPREADING IT.
IT'S 20 HUMAN BOMBS.
IT'S THE CHIEF OF STAFF.
RYAN.
YES, SIR.
IT APPEARS TO BE
A BIOLOGICAL ATTACK.
TERRORIST SELF-INFLICTED
WITH SOME DISEASE
PRESUMABLY CONTAGIOUS.
THEY'RE PLANNING
TO SPREAD THE DISEASE
THROUGH HUMAN CONTACT.
WE BELIEVE THEY'VE
ALREADY INFECTED
10 TO 20 INDIVIDUALS.
NO, SIR, WE DO NOT
KNOW THE EXACT NATURE
OF THE DISEASE.
AS I HAVE THAT INFORMATION--
DR. MUHAMMAD SHIZEH,
HE'S HOME,
IN PARIS, 0900.
DR. SHIZEH?
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
IN FAIRFIELD,
CONNECTICUT.
YES, SIR.
I HAVE A TRADE NAME
FOR A MEDICATION,
AN IMMUNIZATION GOING
BACK 40, 50 YEARS.
ASYRIATHAM.
MY QUESTION--
WHAT DISEASE--
MERCI, DOCTOR.
YEAH, IT'S A CASE
FOR A TACTICAL ATTACK.
GO TO PINNACLE.
HAVE THEM SCRAMBLE
THE AIR FORCE.
PINNACLE?
DOG PATCH 6, REPEAT,
DOG PATCH 6.
WE REQUEST POTSHOT,
REPEAT, POTSHOT.
BRAVO, QUEBEC, 00242321.
ARE YOU CALLING
IN AN AIR STRIKE?
CIA HAS LOCATED
AHZMEH TOURS.
NSA FIND AIR CONNECTIONS
IN THE NAME OF AHZMEH TOURS.
THIS DATE, 1600, LIMA.
PARTY OF 19
TOURISTS CONNECTED
FROM LAHORE TO NEW DELI.
THE CLOSEST AIRFIELD
WHICH CAN ACCOMMODATE
A 20 PAX PLANE
IS KERIAPUR.
HERE.
20 MILES FROM OUR TEAM.
CIA REQUESTS WE EYEBALL
AND IDENTIFY THE TARGET
FOR AN AIR STRIKE.
SO, LET HIM GET
ON THE PLANE, AND
THEN TAKE IT OUT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
RYAN.
GO FOR PINNACLE.
YES, SIR.
THE MEN TO EYEBALL
THE BUS FOR AN AIR STRIKE.
NEGATIVE.
THE PACKAGE WILL BE AIRBORNE
BY THAT TIME.
YOUR EQUIPMENT IS DOWN?
HOW LONG IS YOUR HOLD?
NO, SIR. THAT IS OUTSIDE
THE WINDOW.
YOU WANT MY MEN TO WHAT?
PUT THE BUS ON THE GROUND.
DELAY THE BUS.
NO, SIR.
I WILL NEITHER INSTRUCT
NOR ADVISE MY MEN,
AND I WOULDN'T DO IT IF
I WAS STANDING AT HIS ELBOW.
YOU CAN BE THE PROUD PARENT
OF THIS OPERATION,
OR YOU CAN GET THE HELL
OFF MY PHONE.
SNAKE DOC?
SNAKE DOC.
MISSION SHIFT.
GET READY, EM.
AIR FORCE FAST
MOVER CAME UP BLANK?
FAST MOVER DIDN'T
COME UP BLANK.
IT'S POLITICAL.
MAN ON THE GROUND
IS DENIABLE.
F-16 IS NOT.
SNAKE DOC, THAT BUS HAS
GOT TO CEASE TO EXIST.
NEGATIVE, I DO NOT HAVE
THAT ORDINATES FOR YOU.
NEGATIVE.
THE AIR FORCE IS ON BREAK.
YOU'RE THE MAN ON THE GROUND.
I UNDERSTAND.
NO ORDINATES,
AIR SCOUT'S ON BREAK.
NO, SIR.
SUICIDE'S A SIN,
AND I ALREADY GOT TOO
MANY POINTS ON MY LICENSE.
SNAKE DOC OUT.
MR. GREY.
BOSS?
MISSION HAS SHIFTED.
YOU WILL EXFILL THE GIRL
AND THE PACKAGE
AS PER THE FALLBACK PLAN.
YOUR TEAM,
MR. GREY.
GOT A BUSLOAD
OF INFECTED TOURISTS
TO NEW DELHI.
FROM NEW DELHI
OUTBOUND TO LONDON,
CHICAGO, MADRID.
BUSLOAD OF TOURISTS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHAT ARE THEY
BRINGING WITH THEM?
THEY AIN'T BRINGING
NOTHING WITH THEM,
'CAUSE WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE A LITTLE TALK.
BUT WHAT ARE THEY
PLANNING ON BRINGING?
YOU'VE ALL HAD
YOUR SMALL POX SHOTS?
UH-HUH.
SHE HASN'T.
SHE'S BEEN UNDER
SINCE BEFORE THE '04
IMMUNIZATION MANDATE.
GOT TO GET HER
SOME HELP.
BOSS.
KERIAPUR.
LOOK, LET THEM FLY
IN TO LAHORE, BOSS.
LET THE AIR FORCE DEAL
WITH THEM ONCE THEY'RE THERE.
BY THEN, THEY WILL HAVE
SPREAD THE DISEASE.
WE'LL TURN THEM OVER
TO PAKISTANI SECURITY.
HALF OF THEM'S
AL QAEDA.
NO, WE'RE GOING
TO STOP THEM HERE.
SHOW ME.
ONE ROAD
TO KERIAPUR AIRSTRIP.
FLYING OUT IN--
THERE, THAT'S WHERE
THEY'RE GOING TO BE.
I'M GOING TO RUN
THEM OFF THE ROAD
AND GO FROM THERE.
MR. GREY.
MOVE YOUR TEAM OUT.
[MUMBLING]
PUT HER OUT.
YOU GOT A PLAN, JONAS?
I ALWAYS GOT PLAN.
YOU GOT A PLAN
TO MEET UP WITH THE TEAM
FOR EXFILL?
SEND THE KID AFTER ME.
"THE 1921 SMALLPOX
A-STRAND IS INDICATED
BY THE PRESCRIBED
IMMUNIZATION
HYPERPERDROXY TERADRINE,
TRADE NAME: ASYRIATHAM.
1921 SMALLPOX A-STRAND, YES.
WE ARE AWARE OF THAT.
I'VE GOT RELATIVES
IN CHICAGO.
MANY PEOPLE DO.
I SAY IT'S A DISGRACE.
AND I SAY IT WITH YOU.
WHAT ARE THE ARMY CHILDREN
SUPPOSED TO DO?
FOR HELP--FOR HELP
OUTSIDE THE FAMILY.
WHAT ARE THE CHILDREN
SUPPOSED TO DO?
WHO DO THEY GO TO?
WE'VE GOT MONEY FOR EVERY
HALF-BAKED, FOOLISH STUDY
ON THE EARTH AND NOTHING
FOR OUR CHILDREN.
WHO CAN THEY TURN TO?
THEIR TEACHERS.
MRS. GERHARDT?
HOW LONG ARE YOU
GOING AWAY FOR?
NOW, SAM.
THE ARMY, AS YOU
UNDERSTAND IT,
CONTROLS
AND MUST CONTROL
THE MOVEMENT OF TROOPS.
BUT HOW LONG ARE
YOU GOING AWAY FOR?
THIS ISN'T
YOUR FIRST BASE.
NO.
AND IT ISN'T
MINE EITHER,
AND WE'VE
BEEN REASSIGNED.
[KNOCKING]
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT.
NOW, THIS IS MY NUMBER
AND SHOULD YOU,
AT ANY TIME, NEED HELP--
EVERYBODY NEEDS HELP
OR SOMEONE TO TALK TO--
SOMEONE A LITTLE
BIT MORE SENIOR.
HE FELL OFF THE SWING
SET IN THE BACKYARD?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE ISN'T A SWING SET.
SOMEONE TO TALK TO
IN ADDITION, OF COURSE,
TO YOUR MOTHER
AND YOUR FATHER.
MY FATHER BEATS ME.
WHERE'S MOM?
SHE IS OUT
WITH AUNT MOLLY.
STRESSFUL
CIRCUMSTANCE MOMENT.
YOU WANT
SOMETHING TO EAT?
DAD?
NOBODY FORCED YOU
TO JOIN THE ARMY.
LOOK AT ALL THESE FORMS.
DRIVE ANYBODY INSANE,
BUT I DIDN'T JOIN THE ARMY
TO DO HOMEWORK, DID I?
I JOINED THE ARMY
BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE
THE BIG MONEY WAS.
TILL THEY TOOK AWAY
MY CLOTHING ALLOWANCE
AND MY COMBAT PAY.
NOW, I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I WONDER IF I'M GOING
TO LIKE THIS NEW BASE.
WHY ARE WE MOVING?
WE'RE GOING
TO BE NEAR THE BEACH.
NEAR YOUR GRANDPARENTS.
BUT WHY?
I'VE DONE THIS
A LONG TIME, BABY.
BUT YOU LOVE THIS JOB.
AND I PROMISED
YOUR MAMA A CHANGE.
NOW, YOU WOULDN'T
WANT ME TO BREAK
MY PROMISE, WOULD YA?
DADDY?
YEAH.
ARE YOU ALWAYS STRONG?
NOBODY'S ALWAYS STRONG.
MS. GERHARDT
WAS THE YOUNG BOY'S
TEACHER 3 YEARS AGO.
3 YEARS AGO?
HE CAME TO HER FIRST,
BUT THEY WERE ALWAYS CLOSE.
HIS PARENTS?
I DO NOT KNOW.
WE BROUGHT HIM HOME AND HE...
HE SAID THAT
HIS FATHER BEATS HIM.
HIS FATHER
BROKE HIS ARM?
HE SAID THAT HE FELL
FROM A SWING SET.
WHEN WE BROUGHT HIM HOME,
HE CHANGED HIS STORY
AND SAID THAT HIS FATHER--
HIS FATHER BEAT HIM.
HIS FATHER'S
NOT HERE NOW.
HE CAME TO
YOUR MS. GERHARDT--
THAT'S RIGHT.
BECAUSE...
YOU SIT HERE, BABY.
I'M GOING TO GO GET
YOU A FEW THINGS, OK?
I SHOULD HAVE
TRIED HERE FIRST.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
TRIED HERE FIRST?
SAM LIVES HERE.
NO, HE'S BEEN
LIVING WITH HIS AUNT
THE LAST 6 MONTHS.
YOU'RE SURE HE DOESN'T LIVE
WITH HIS FATHER AND MOTHER?
I DON'T SEE HOW HE COULD.
THE LAST 6 MONTHS
THEY'VE BOTH BEEN
ON DEPLOYMENT IN IRAQ.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
THE COMPLAINT
IS AGAINST HIS FATHER.
HIS FATHER IS IN IRAQ.
I'M DESIGNATED
LEGAL GUARDIAN
IN THEIR ABSENCE,
AND GOD FORBID,
IN THE EVENT
OF THEIR DEATH,
I AM HIS LEGAL GUARDIAN.
HIS FATHER DIDN'T
BREAK HIS ARM.
HOW DID
HE BREAK HIS ARM?
HE'S BEEN
IN THE EMERGENCY ROOM
4 TIMES
IN THE LAST 5 MONTHS.
HE'S A BOY. HE--
IS HE GETTING COUNSELING?
COUNSELING.
FROM THE ARMY?
COUNSELING FOR CHILDREN
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
HAD THIS JOB, SIR?
LOOK, HIS PARENTS
HAVE BEEN ON DEPLOYMENT
FOR THE LAST 6 MONTHS.
NOW, SINCE
THEIR DEPLOYMENT--
WHERE'S HIS DISCHARGE
FROM THE E.R., PLEASE?
SIR.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT ARMY
YOU THINK YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT, BUT...
...TRYING TO ESTABLISH
IS HOW THE BOY GOT HURT
AND ALL YOU'RE TELLING
US IS THE PARENTS...
SAM.
WE'RE LOW ON GAS.
LOW?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GUNFIRE]
NO DEPOSIT, NO RETURN.
HOW'S THE GIRL?
JUST HOLDING ON.
GOT HER?
SNAKE DOC, SNAKE DOC,
SNAKE DOC.
WE'RE KIND OF PERSONA
NON GRATA DOWN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
A PARTY COMING ON
AT RIKKI TIK.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
I SEE 'EM.
SNAKE DOC OUT.
[HELICOPTER]
GOT A REAL NAME, FIREFLY?
ASK ME AT STATESIDE.
[SIGHS]
LOSE THE BEARD IN 3 HOURS.
WE'RE STAYING.
YOU WANTED TO MOVE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE STAYING
BECAUSE OF ONE KID.
YOU TELL ME WHO
THEY'RE GOING TO TURN TO
WHEN THERE AIN'T
NOBODY THERE BUT ME.
NO.
I'M STAYING
FOR ALL OF US.
SO, WHAT WAS GEORGE WASHINGTON
DOING FIGHTING THE IRAQIS?
GUESS THEY WERE JUST
ON DIFFERENT SIDES.
SOMETIMES YOU JUST
GOT TO TAKE SIDES.
YEAH, GOOD IDEA.
YOU CAN GO TO WORK NOW.
[HISSING]
[BUZZING]
[AIRPLANE APPROACHING]
WELCOME HOME, SIR.
WHAT?
I SAID, WELCOME HOME!
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
20th CENTURY FOX AND CBS
welcome to www.1000fr.com