Ragnar:
Previously on "Vikings":
Aghhh! (Axe slices)
Ancient seer: The gods desire
you to have a great future.
Hail, Earl Ragnar!
All: Hail, Earl Ragnar!
How will we ever be equal now,
my brother?
I'm with child again.
I know you're a boy - my son.
Siggy: We have to leave here. They
will shun us like a bad smell.
No one will force you
to go anywhere.
They wouldn't dare.
Tostig: I have been a
warrior all my life.
I beg you, lord,
gift me the chance
to die with honor in battle.
Let's take him with us.
All: Aye!
Are these pagans
not men like we are?!
Do they not bleed
when they are cut?!
Let us prepare
to defend ourselves.
They're not welcome
in my kingdom.
♪
♪ more, give me more ♪
♪ give me more
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I...
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing out ♪
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
(rooster crows, sheep bleat)
(Birds sing)
(Water churns)
(Sheep bleat)
(Geese honk, sheep bleat)
(Water churns)
(Bell clangs)
Saxon warrior: (Shouting)
Make way there! Come on!
Make way! Make way!
(Panicked screaming
and shouting)
(Horse snorts)
(Bell clangs in the distance)
(Loud buzz of chatter)
Noble: (Shouts) Brother!
Brother! Where are you?
King Aelle: Aethelwulf?!
(Laughs)
Thank God you are come.
Lord Aethelwulf: What on earth
made you think I would not, sire?
King Aelle: No, I never doubted you.
But others...
Our own youngest brother,
fled to Mercia.
He was always the runt
of the litter.
Our parents should've
drowned him at birth.
(Laughs)
Where are the heathens now?
Only one, perhaps two days away
and your forces are ready
and armed?
Yes, if you are ready
to lead them.
I would regard it
a great honor, sire,
to defend thy kingdom
and our homeland.
Lord Edgar: And there's no
man better, lord Aethelwulf.
The poets sing
your battle praises
in the halls.
That's because I paid them.
(Everyone laughs)
If you paid them,
they'd sing your praises too.
That's poets for you!
(Everyone laughs)
My lady, pray,
have you no time for laughter?
No, my lord Aethelwulf,
only for fear.
(Banging and tapping)
(Scraping)
(Log thumps)
Rollo: (Tired exhale)
How soon will they come?
Ragnar: Soon enough.
Tostig: I hope so.
I can't wait for Valhalla.
(Men chatter as they work)
(Seabirds cry)
(Vendors shout in the market)
(Loud buzz of chatter)
Lagertha: Good day to you, folk.
What is the problem here?
Peasant man:
The problem is her!
What has she done?
Peasant man: She has had a
child - the boy in her arms.
What of it?
He's not my child.
(Crowd murmurs)
We tried for many years
to have children,
but without success.
And then, just over a year ago,
a young man came to the door.
I remember the day,
I was making a loom.
The young man
said his name was Rig.
He gave us some good advice
on our work
and stayed at our house.
After three days, he left...
And then nine months later,
she gave birth to a son.
(Crowd laughs, baby cries)
Whose child is it?
(Tearful)
I do not know, my lady.
We were all in the same bed.
I was too scared-you see?
She is not an honest woman.
She had sex with Rig,
and could not bring herself
to tell me the truth!
Do you know who this Rig was?
No. He was just a young man.
On the contrary.
We know from
our ancient stories
that Rig is another name
for Heimdal.
The God Heimdal?
Peasant man: My lady!
Yes, the God Heimdal!
You are fortunate
that he chose your household
to appear in.
That's just a story!
Our whole lives
are just stories.
You should be ashamed
you did not trust your wife,
despite the joy and comfort
she has brought you,
and the fact that a God
chose you
of all people to visit.
Do not punish her,
but rejoice with her.
Drink wine with her.
And sacrifice
one of your animals
to Heimdal the God.
But if I hear
you have harmed this woman,
or this child,
you will answer for it to me!
(Crowd murmurs quietly)
(Steady clopping of hooves)
(Water splashing)
(Thundering of hooves)
Lord Aethelwulf: It seems they
intend to stay here a while.
I had not expected that.
My lord, why don't we attack?
They have a strong position.
Perhaps if we can make them
leave their position
and attack us.
Saxon warrior 1: How can
we force them to do that?
They're scavengers,
little more than beasts.
We must be able
to out-think them.
Saxon warrior 2
if we leave it much longer,
they'll be even better dug-in.
My lord, if a wolf comes
into your sheep fold,
you don't try to out-think it.
You go in and drive it away,
- or kill it!
- How dare you argue with me?!
Saxon warrior 2: Lord Aethelwulf,
forgive us. We only meant...
lord Aethelwulf:
I know what you meant.
You meant that you're already
greater warriors than I am...
although only yesterday
you were still green
sucking on
your mother's breasts.
Go do your jobs. Set up camp.
(Banging and tapping)
Rollo: You see them up there?
Ragnar: Yes, I can see them.
What're we waiting for?
To see what they'll do.
So you want to hand them
the initiative.
We can't afford
to lose half our men
by being stupid and attacking.
We wait until the odds
are in our favor.
(Fire crackles, crickets chirp)
(Foliage crunches underfoot)
(Horse snorts nervously)
Floki: Shh... shh... shh...
Shh... shh... shh...
Shh...
(Men snore, crickets chirp)
(Light metallic clinking,
footsteps scuff quietly)
(Flames crackle)
(Hard kick,
Saxon warrior grunts)
(Flame whooshes and crackles)
Saxon warrior: Awake! Awake!
Under attack!
(Weapons slices) Agh!
Saxon warrior: Arm yourselves!
Saxon warrior 2: Rise! Rise!
(Weapons clank, men grunt)
Run! Run!
(Grunts of pain rend the air)
(Weapons and shields clank)
Tostig: Odin!
Saxon warrior: They're on us!
Weapons!
(Praying in Latin)
(Saxon warriors grunt
and scream in pain)
(Axe whips through air) Ungh!
Aethelwulf: (Praying in Latin)
Saxon warrior: My lord!
We're being attacked!
(Whispering quietly in Latin)
(War cries and screams
rend the air)
(Arrow whizzes through the air,
Saxon warrior grunts)
(Weapons clank,
men scream and grunt)
Amen.
Lord Aethelwulf:
(Roars in frustration)
(Floki giggles)
(Grunts of pain fill the air)
(Clattering and clanging)
(Ragnar blows his nose)
Ragnar: Who are you?
I'm lord Aethelwulf,
brother of king Aelle.
Ragnar: You are the
brother of the king,
yet you lead his army?
Hmm.
Does he send you to fight
all his battles?
In the bedroom too?
Floki: Ragnar!
Come and see!
Rollo: Their iron is stronger
and better than ours.
(Hard whack)
Leif: (Laughs) And we've captured
a dozen of their horses.
Floki: I'm hungry already!
Ragnar:
What ails you my friend?
The gods won't lift my curse.
I am fated to live forever
on this miserable earth.
(Men chatter quietly)
Rollo: Who is this?
Ragnar: This?
This is the king's brother.
What do you say?
Shall we go visit the king?
King Aelle: God help us!
My brother defeated. Dead.
God help Northumbria.
Lord Edgar: Sire, we do not
know if your brother is dead.
King Aelle: But we do know, my
lord, that he was defeated!
Who are these barbarians,
these savages?
Why have they come
to torment us?
Bishop Unwan:
Sire, some learned and wise men
say that these northmen
have been sent here by God
to punish our people
for their many sins
and transgressions.
That we have departed from
the path of righteousness
that our lord set out,
so now he is holding us
to terrible account.
(Nobles mutter in agreement)
Noble 3: Forgive me, sire,
but what if God has not
sent these northmen here
to plague us?
Then who has, pray?
Could it not, sire,
rather be the work
of the devil?
(Nobles mutter in agreement)
King Aelle: Go on then, my lord.
What is your advice?
Noble 3
my advice, sire, is that,
as we are facing
the forces of Satan,
we must resist them
at all costs.
Even at the cost of...
Of all our lives,
if necessary.
For evil cannot be accommodated
nor yet ever bargained with.
Several nobles:
Aye! (Murmuring)
Noble 4:
Sire, if I might speak?
I-I put it to you
that it might be that
these pagans have come here
by their own account,
and that they are neither
of God
nor the devil.
They are just savage men
more interested in robbery
and plunder
than in matters of the spirit.
King Aelle: Then what is your advice?
(Nobles yelling)
Noble 4: Sire, since
they have come for gain,
then let us offer them
enough money,
or whatever else they desire,
to go away
and leave us in peace!
(Nobles yell and shout)
Noble 2: Shame! Shame on you!
Shame on you!
Noble 5: He is right!
Why waste more blood?
Let's pay them off!
(Nobles yell and shout,
divided)
King Aelle: My lords,
let me think on it,
just a little while.
In the meantime,
let it be known
I have sent envoys out
to raise more men to arms,
for our use if need be.
Nobles: (Muttering quietly)
Long live the king!
(Hall buzzes with chatter)
King Aelle: (Sotto
voce) Contend, o lord,
against those
who contend with me;
Fight against those
who fight against me!
Draw the spear and javelin
against my pursuers;
Say to my soul,
"I am your salvation."
(Door creaks open)
Noble 2: Sire, they are here.
(Inhales slowly)
(Thundering of hooves
in the distance)
(Birds chirp)
(Horse whinnies and snorts)
(Gates creak open)
(Birds chirp)
(Horses snort)
Lord Eadric: Greetings.
King Aelle invites your leader
to meet him in his villa
to talk.
Who is your leader?
(Silence)
The king did not know that
his brother was still alive.
He would like to talk to you
about what he can give you,
to set his brother free.
Do you accept
the king's invitation?
Where are you going?
(Hooves thud loudly)
(Birds sing,
foliage crunches underfoot)
Rollo: We should attack,
while they are weak.
How long will it take them
to raise another army?
Ragnar: Attack, attack, attack!
That's all he ever says.
I want to talk to the king.
Rollo:
What is there to talk about?
Imagine the treasures
the king keeps
in his household?
I want them.
I want to see how he lives...
What manner of men they are,
and I'm hungry.
Rollo: Listen to me:
If we agree
to walk into his house
he can kill each
and every one of us.
Ragnar: You forget, we
hold his brother hostage.
Why should he care
about his brother?
Do I not care about mine?
(Hooves thud)
(Horses snort, horses pant)
Man: They're coming!
(Saxons murmur nervously)
(Horse whinnies)
(Saxons murmur)
(Spitting)
(Sheep bleat, cow moos)
(Saxons murmur nervously)
(Sheep bleat)
Men: My lord Eadric.
(Footsteps scuff in the dirt)
(Hushed murmuring)
(Distorted murmurs)
(Flame whooshes)
(Echoing murmurs)
Lord Eadric: Sire, this
man is Ragnar Lothbrok,
his brother rollo,
and their companions.
King Aelle:
Ah yes, Ragnar Lothbrok...
We've heard that name before.
We are pleased
you have decided to talk to us.
(Quiet, nervous whispers)
Perhaps, sire,
you should invite them
to eat first.
Forgive me.
Let us feast together...
And then talk.
_
(Floki giggles)
Noble: The king!
King Aelle: Ragnar Lothbrok,
may I present my wife Ealswith,
and my son, egbert.
Leif: (Speaking old norse)
Ragnar: Hello.
(Floki giggles)
(Chuckles)
Ealswith: Go on now.
(King Aelle claps twice)
Vikings:
(Grunting and eating noisily)
(Disgusted shudder)
Bishop Unwan: In the name of
the father, and of the son,
and of the holy spirit, amen.
King Aelle and Ealswith: Amen.
All: Amen.
(Priests begin to sing
a prayer)
(Conversing in old norse)
(Prayer ends)
(Vikings grunt and laugh)
(Musicians start to play
a piece)
(Sniffs)
(Floki shatters plate,
vikings laugh)
(Plate shatters, vikings laugh)
(Speaking old norse)
Shall we talk, king?
(Musicians stop playing)
King Aelle: Very well.
What do you want,
for the safe return
of my brother
and for leaving my kingdom?
Is he a priest?
He's a bishop of our church.
A man of God.
I too have a man of God
at home.
Two thousand pounds
in gold and silver.
Bishop Unwan: What did he say?
How much?
Two thousand pounds.
I do not think I heard you
properly, Ragnar Lothbrok.
Ragnar: (Lightly) Hmm...
(Bellows loudly)
Two thousand pounds in weight.
(Nobles laugh derisively)
That is the price.
(Viking belches)
(Hall goes quiet)
(Benches scrape back)
(Metallic rasp
of weapons being drawn)
I agree to the terms.
Ragnar: (Belches) Good.
(Laughing)
King Aelle: But first...
You must return my brother.
Ragnar: When we receive payment,
you shall have your brother.
You must give me time
to collect such a vast amount.
And in the meantime,
you and your men must remain
in your camp
and make no further attacks
on my people
or their property.
Agreed.
Lord Eadric: Sire! How can we
trust the word of a pagan?
Bishop Unwan: Let me
baptize one of them.
There is one further condition.
I desire that either you,
or one of your companions,
agrees to be baptized
into our faith.
And that way,
I can make peace with a friend
and fellow Christian...
And not an enemy.
Ragnar: You want one of
us to become Christian?
Yes.
(Speaking old norse)
(Vikings laugh)
Leif: Tostig!
(Laughing)
Rollo: (Speaking old norse)
I... will be Christian.
(Geese honk)
Athelstan: My lady Lagertha,
I hope you can find it
in your heart
to speak to the wife
of the late Earl.
Of course. Hello, Siggy.
Please sit down and join us.
Bjorn wait!
Earl Haraldson tried
to kill my father.
(Sighs heavily) I know.
And if he had succeeded,
I would be standing
where Siggy's standing now.
So what would you like me
to say to her?
I would ask her to sit down.
Siggy: Thank you.
What can I do for you?
Siggy: It is what
I can do for you.
I want to serve you.
That is not necessary.
I remember very well
how I served
the father of my church,
and it did me no harm.
In fact, I found in service
a great freedom and honor.
When I accepted that I should
forget about myself
and serve father Cuthbert...
Well... then I became happy.
If it's really what you want,
I accept your offer.
Thank you.
Lagertha: You and your daughter
are now under my protection,
but I will never treat you
as a servant.
(River babbles loudly)
Bishop Unwan: O lord, holy father,
almighty and eternal God,
expel the devil and his
kin from this person:
From the head, from the hair,
from the brain, from the brow,
from the ears,
from the nostrils,
from the mouth,
from beneath the tongue,
from the throat, from the neck,
from the chest, from the heart,
from the entire interior
of the body,
from the thoughts,
from the words,
and from the deeds,
in the name of Jesus
Christ our lord.
King Aelle and saxons: Amen.
Bishop Unwan: I anoint thee...
In the name of the father
and of the son
and of the holy spirit.
Amen.
Rollo: (Sputters)
Priests: Et spiritus sancti.
(Vikings laugh hysterically)
Bishop Unwan: I now pronounce
you baptized and born again,
with the new Christian
name of Rolf.
(Vikings laugh)
May the lord bless you
and keep you,
from this day hence,
and for ever.
Amen.
(Laughter dies down)
(Spits angrily)
King Aelle: We have
witnessed a true miracle.
Now I ask you to fulfill
your promises,
return to your ships,
and await your payment
in peace.
Agreed, Ragnar Lothbrok?
(Horses whinny)
(Water splashes, rollo laughs)
(Howling in the distance)
(Fire crackles nearby)
(Crackling)
What is it?
I can't sleep.
Come here, beside me, daughter.
What worries you?
I fear for father, so far away.
Our lives are fated, Gyda.
We all have to accept that.
Gyda: I can feel it moving
underneath my hand.
Mm-hmm. He has a strong kick.
He? Are you so sure it's a boy?
A long time ago,
the seer prophesized
that your father
would have many sons.
That's how I know it's a boy.
Now sleep.
(Men chatter and laugh)
Warriors: Oh!
(Dice rattles)
(All laugh)
Rollo: (Laughing) I won again!
(Under his breath)
Well done... Rolf!
What's wrong with you, Floki?
Oh, there's nothing wrong
with me.
I did not renounce the gods
in front of everyone.
It was a joke.
I didn't believe it.
I didn't even know
what the old fool was saying.
Floki: It doesn't matter.
Surely you've made them
very angry.
Rollo: Don't be stupid.
Floki:
No, you are the stupid one...
To risk the wrath of the gods.
How will you ever get odin
to forgive you now?
Arne: They're here!
Come and see!
(Viking warriors shout
and laugh excitedly)
(Warriors laugh and shout)
(Casket thumps)
(Vikings chatter excitedly)
(Viking chuckles,
metallic clank)
Agh!
Viking 1:
(Shouts) They're empty.
(Frustrated groans)
(Hooves thundering)
(Horse whinnies)
(Horn bellows)
Ungh!
(Distorted thundering
of hooves)
(Axe clangs)
♪
(Hooves thunder loudly)
(Horn bellows)
(War cries rend the air)
(Horses whinny shrilly)
Ungh!
(Whinnying shrilly)
Saxon warrior: Move back!
(Men screaming and grunting,
horses whinnying)
(Confused yelling
and screaming)
Saxon warriors: Fight back!
Regroup!
Stay together!
Pull up!
(Horse whinnies shrilly)
Aggghhhhh!
(Battle cries rend the air)
Ungh!
(Weapons clank and swipe,
men yell and scream)
(Weapons clanking,
slashing and slicing)
men grunting)
Lief: Ungh!
Aghhh! (Hard blow)
(Yelling and screaming,
weapons clash and clank)
Agghhh! Ungh!
(Shield clanks,
shield-maiden grunts)
Shield-maiden: Agghhhh!
Saxon warrior: Ungh!
(Men scream and grunt,
weapons striking hard)
(Battle cry rends the air,
Saxon warrior groans)
Aggghhhhhhh! Agh! Odin!
Saxon warrior: Aggghhhhhhh!
(Floki grunts, weapons clank)
Aggggghhhhhh!
(Growls triumphantly)
(Men yelling and shouting,
weapons clanking)
Aggggghhhhhh!
Ungh!
(Shields bang)
Aggggghhh!
(Saxon screams in pain)
(Swords clash,
tostig cries out)
Noooo!
(Warrior screams, sword rings)
(Hard blow,
Saxon warrior grunts)
(Swords clank)
Saxon warrior: Aggghhhhh!
(Panting)
(Labored sigh)
(Raven crows)
(Struggling grunts)
(Hard blow)
(Terrified whimpers)
(Saxon cries out, hard blow)
(Rollo grunts)
(Hard metallic clank,
Saxon grunts)
(Rollo grunts, almost crazed)
Agghhh!
(Grunting)
Rollo: Aggghhhh! Saxon: Ungh!
(Panting)
Rollo: Aghhh!
Ungh!
Ungh! (Panting)
Agghhh!
How many christians did I kill,
Floki?
(Bellowing angrily) How many?
Do you think odin
is still angry with me now?
(Panting)
(Men chatter)
Ragnar: (Breathing hard)
(Sighs) Whew!
(Exhales sharply)
It seems your brother
the king...
Does not care if you live
or die.
If you let me talk to him,
I will persuade him
to honor his pledge.
(Chuckles)
Why should I not...
Just kill you now?
Then you'll have nothing left
to bargain with.
I have this.
(Horse gallops,
litter dragging behind it)
Saxon warrior: Open!
Open the gate!
(Litter drags through the dirt)
(Seabird cries)
(Sobbing)
(Jewelry jingles lightly)
Lagertha: (Short, shaky
breathes, sniffling)
(Siggy gasps)
(Lagertha whimpers and sobs)
(Weeping and sniffling)
(Gates rattle open)
(Horses snort and grunt)
(Wagon rattles)
♪
(Water churns as they row)
(Coins clink)
King Aelle:
I swear before God almighty,
I declare war eternal
on the Northman
Ragnar Lothbrok.
I swear to our lord
Jesus Christ
and to the blessed virgin
one day I will avenge myself
on him,
and bring him to justice
and to death,
so help me God.
(Coins clink)
(Metallic ting, Floki giggles)
(Splash)
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com