Ragnar:
Previously on "vikings":
A large fleet of northmen
have come ashore in wessex.
King ecbert:
I hope I can negotiate
with ragnar.
King horik:
Where is torstein going?
I sent him to inform the king
of our return.
King horik:
But you will never ever
do anything again
Without consulting
with me first,
For you and I are not equals.
(axe strikes)
King ecbert:
Princess kwenthrith of mercia!
I would like to hire
some northmen as mercenaries
To help you succeed in gaining
the throne of mercia.
Aethelwulf:
Athelstan is waiting to see you
at my father's villa.
He hopes that you will be
prepared to talk to him.
King ecbert:
Ragnar lothbrok
is no longer alone
If you and I join together,
we should surely overcome him!
Aghhhhhhh! Oof!
♪
♪ more,
give me more ♪
♪ give me more
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I...
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪
Athelstan:
"caesar had sent his cavalry
a little in advance
And was following
with the rest of his forces.
The battlefront was not formed
According to rules
of military theory,
But as necessitated
by the emergency
And the sloping ground
of the hillside.
The legions were facing
different ways
And fighting different actions.
The 9th and 10th legions
were on the left,
And discharged a volley
of spears at the atrebates."
King ecbert:
Yes. He's always thinking,
always using the terrain.
Go on.
The roman cavalry
and light-armed troops,
Seeming to appear
from nowhere-"
King ecbert:
Ah! But he knew where.
They were in here.
And what of his person!
What of he himself?
Athelstan:
"as the situation was critical,
Caesar moved to the front
of the line,
Addressed each centurion
by name,
And shouted encouragement
to..."
King ecbert:
Hmm. But we can imagine
how it really ends.
We must do battle with
ragnar lothbrok and his allies.
I cannot believe that ragnar
does not want to negotiate.
I know him too well.
He's looking for land,
Farming land,
for his people.
King ecbert:
His men killed all of my envoys,
sparing only my son.
By which they sent me a simple
but clear message.
Athelstan:
Why not send me
to speak to him?
You are already too dear to me,
and too important.
Which is why, I think,
they would kill you.
Athelstan:
When? When will you attack?
King ecbert:
As soon as king aelle returns
with his warriors.
I'm sure you would prefer that
earl ragnar and I made peace.
Perhaps then you could be
at peace with yourself.
Ragnar:
King horik, your behaviour
has made it very difficult
To talk peace or to negotiate
with king ecbert.
King horik:
I never had any intention of
negotiating with king ecbert.
I thought you were aware
of that.
I only want revenge.
I want to kill king ecbert.
And then, perhaps,
I shall talk to him.
Lagertha:
If we defeat ecbert in battle,
He may be prepared
to offer us more
In terms not only of gold,
but of land.
Ragnar:
This was a gift
in good faith.
King horik:
What is good faith?
Why should there be good faith
between us and christians?
What do you say, floki?
Floki:
They worship a false god.
They're fleas and vermin.
Ragnar:
I will go myself
and talk to him.
King horik:
You will not divide our forces,
earl ragnar.
You seem to forget
I am king.
We will strike camp tomorrow,
And, armed and ready,
we will go to seek battle,
As our father odin
has taught us.
Erlendur.
Rollo:
(spits)
(metallic scraping)
(low hum of chatter)
(approaching footsteps,
warriors chatter nearby)
(crickets chirp,
owl hoots)
Bjorn:
I can't sleep.
I am thinking about
what it is like to die.
Only those who have died
would know.
The seer would know.
Ragnar:
He is not truly dead;
that is his curse.
He told me something about you.
That you would marry
the daughter of a king,
Or else sail round a sea
that has no tides.
Then I shall not die tomorrow?
Not according to the seer.
(fire crackles)
Bjorn reminds me
of odin's favourite son, balder.
You know the story.
Floki:
The gods made everyone swear
an oath that he would be safe.
Nothing could injure
odin's favourite son.
King horik:
The gods even tested the oaths.
They threw stones at him, darts,
struck him with axes,
And slashed at him with swords,
But it seems nothing
could harm balder.
Floki:
Everyone rejoiced
That it was impossible
to harm balder.
All except loki.
The sly one watched
with distaste and impatience.
And it sickened him to see
how balder was immune
From all sorts of attacks.
Yes. The sly one knew he had
to find a way to kill him.
Athelstan:
Help me, lord.
Who are these gods
who haunt my nights
And wreck my peace?
Odin, thor, freyr...
You have taught us
not to worship false gods,
But I have seen them.
I have seen thor in the sky!
I have seen the sparks
from his anvil.
I felt the sea heave
with his anger.
(sighs)
why is this false?
Things that I've seen
with my own eyes.
Things that ragnar believes.
Whatever happens,
do not let ragnar die...
Nor yet lord ecbert.
(foliage crunches underfoot)
(raven croaks)
(weapons and shields thump
and clank)
(weapons clank and thump)
(ravens crow)
Ragnar:
This is the place.
King horik:
How do you know?
Because they are already here.
Anglo-saxon captain:
Over here! Stay close!
Here.
Come!
King horik:
A large force,
but not large enough.
We will go down to them.
King horik:
I'm not waiting!
The enemy is there!
We have the advantage
of the hill.
Forward!
(foliage crunches underfoot,
warriors chatter quietly)
Rollo:
(sighs heavily)
(horses snort)
(weapons clank against shields,
warriors shout threateningly)
Warrior: Let's be having you!
Shield-maiden: Saxon heads!
(warriors shout threateningly,
weapons clank against shields)
(attack yells fill the air)
rollo: Ragnar!
Soldier:
Forward!
Ragnar:
Form!
Rollo:
Behind the wall!
Move!
(horn bellows)
King horik:
Why are you stopping?
The gods are with us!
Forward!
(unsheathes sword)
Charge!
(battle cries fill the air)
(anglo-saxon captain
yells a command)
Rollo:
Hold your position!
Lock shields!
(shields clatter)
torstein and rollo: Brace!
(warriors scream)
king horik: Together!
(attack screams fill the air)
(weapons clash and thud,
warriors and soldiers scream)
Anglo-saxon captain:
Attack!
Lagertha: Shield-wall!
Rollo: Forward brace!
Rollo:
Brace!
(hooves thunder,
charging cries)
Yah!
(axe strikes)
(charging cries)
Lagertha:
Hold!
Hold the wall!
(thundering crash)
(weapons clank and clatter)
King horik:
Stand! Stand your ground!
(fighting grunts,
weapons striking)
(swords clank)
ungh!
(axe clangs,
pained yell)
(sword slashes)
aghhh!
Warrior:
Agghhhh!
(thundering crash)
(fighting grunts,
weapons striking)
(trumpet bellows)
aelle's captain: Attack!
(fighting grunts,
weapons clank and strike)
(distorted whinny
and muted thundering hooves)
(thundering hooves,
battle cries)
(thundering crash,
weapons smash and clang)
(fighting grunts and screams,
(smash)
ungh!
Yahhhhhh!
Agghhhh!
Agh! Oof!
Warrior:
Aggghhh!
(axe strikes)
yah!
Soldier:
Aggghhh!
(repeated blows)
(fighting grunts,
weapons clashing)
Rollo:
Ungh! Argh!
(fighting grunts,
weapons clashing)
Ungh!
Rollo: Ungh!
Solider: Agghhhh!
(fighting grunts)
Soldier: Ungh!
(sword strikes)
(fighting grunts)
(horse whinnies)
rollo: Agghhh!
(horses crash)
(battle cries fill the air)
Warrior:
(grunts and screams in pain)
(sword strikes)
agghhh!
Rollo: Wah!
Aethelwulf: (charging cry)
Ungh!
(horse whinnies,
thunderous trampling)
♪
(slow motion distortion
of bodies and weapons crashing)
(heartbeat pulses loudly)
(pained grunts, warriors shout,
weapons clash)
(fighting grunts,
weapons clank)
(frustrated grunt)
Soldier:
Ungh!
Ragnar:
Yah! Hyah!
(dull roar of fighting grunts
and weapons striking)
Soldier: Hyah!
Warrior: (hard thud)
Warrior:
(screams in pain)
(fresh battle cries)
Run!
(screams)
run!
(horse whinnies)
Soldier: Ungh!
Lagertha: Agghhh!
(hard smash)
agghhhh!
King horik:
Unghhhh! Ungh!
Floki:
Horik! King horik!
(exertion grunts)
come.
(fighting grunts,
weapons clash)
Bjorn:
Father!
(swords strike)
(hard smash)
agghhhh!
♪
(ominous music)
(spear strikes,
dying warrior grunts)
(dying warrior groans,
spear strikes)
Soldier:
(grunt of effort)
Warrior:
Help!
(sword strikes)
soldier: Here, swine!
Soldier:
Friar! The cross! Please!
There's another!
Soldier 2:
Here, brother!
Come! Come!
Athelstan:
No! Wait! Stop!
(groans and cries of pain)
King ecbert:
Athelstan, who is it?
Do you know this man?
King aelle:
I know this man.
His name is rollo.
He's ragnar lothbrok's brother.
We baptized him,
but it made no difference.
King ecbert:
It is unfortunate
that he's dead.
Rollo: (gasps in pain)
athelstan: No! He's still alive!
King ecbert:
Father!
This is an important man.
See what you can do
to save him.
Priest:
Yes, sire.
Athelstan:
He's badly wounded.
There.
(ravens croak and caw)
(crowing)
(gurgled breaths)
Ragnar:
So...
Do you still think
That we should not have
talked to them first?
King horik:
You always think you can
second-guess the gods, ragnar!
What has happened today
was fated.
It had nothing to do
with you or I.
Bjorn: Agh!
(shield crashes)
(hard kick)
(tired exhale)
Ragnar:
You fought well today.
Bjorn:
I was fortunate,
that is all.
Ragnar:
You were favoured
by the gods.
Favoured?!
We were defeated.
We live to fight
another day.
We lived,
but my uncle died.
We do not know
if he is dead.
It would take a lot
to kill him.
Since no axe, spear, or blade
could touch my son today,
He will be known
as bjorn ironside.
Lagertha:
We must make some decisions,
and we must make them quickly.
Do we leave tomorrow
and abandon this raid?
Bjorn:
If my uncle is captured
and wounded,
I want to stay in this place...
As long as it takes
until he is free.
Ragnar:
(sniffs)
well, king,
What are we fated to do?
(rain pours down)
King aelle:
Victory over the northmen!
(loud cheering and laughter)
King aelle:
Now your father surprised them
with his tactics, hmm?
He surprised me too!
How does he know
these things?
Who knows, sire?
Maybe he read something
somewhere,
Which helped him.
Reading,
for monks mostly!
Very little use
otherwise.
(celebratory laughter)
(metallic hammering,
low buzz of chatter)
(water splashes)
(footsteps squelch in the mud)
Athelstan:
Rollo!
(laboured breaths)
priest?!
(gasping)
Look at you!
Horik was right.
(laboured breath)
you betrayed us.
(laboured breaths)
If I had enough strength
to kill you now,
I would.
(flames crackle)
♪
(footsteps squelch
in the mud)
(footsteps splash
in the water)
(flames roar)
(water laps gently
at the shore)
(retreating footsteps)
(flames roar)
King aelle:
Allies! Hmm!
(goblet splashes)
allies and friends, huh?
Mmmmuah!
(king aelle and men laugh)
When shall we attack again
our wounded foe, huh?
And wipe them out?
(men laughing)
King ecbert:
That might not be a good idea.
King aelle:
Of course it's a good idea!
We've won half a victory.
Now, with god's help,
We'll annihilate our enemies,
hmm?
King ecbert:
Forgive me, king aelle,
but I might suggest that
Even the complete destruction
of one northern army
Will not lead to the end
of their incursions.
Probably quite the opposite.
Motivated by greed
and by the need for revenge,
They're very likely to return
with renewed strength.
And not just once or twice,
but again and again,
Times without number.
The only way to bring an end
to these incursions
Is to negotiate an agreement
that is good for both sides.
But, in the meantime,
king aelle,
Buying the services
of these northmen,
As mercenaries,
Will certainly help us
to overcome mercia.
Aelle:
Mm. Very well.
As you say.
But someone has to take
this offer to the pagans.
That is, if they have not yet
already sailed away.
(spurting)
indeed.
Bishop edmund:
Considering their treatment
of our envoys so far,
You're not going to have
too many volunteers.
(men laugh)
Aethelwulf:
I have a suggestion.
I think we should send
athelstan.
King ecbert:
But they may kill him.
Aethelwulf:
(laughs) oh, I doubt that.
In any case,
would it matter?
King aelle:
(laughs)
(hooves thud)
(birds chirp)
(low hum of chatter)
Warrior:
Ragnar! There you are!
Warrior 2:
Look who's here!
Warrior 3:
Olaf, come here.
Look who it is.
(low hum of curious chatter)
(approaching footsteps)
(low hum of chatter)
Athelstan:
Hello, bjorn.
Do you remember me?
Bjorn:
Of course I remember you.
I wanted to kill you
when I was a child...
And then I loved you.
I know you were close
to your uncle.
I want you all to know
that rollo is alive -
Wounded but alive -
and being taken care of.
King horik.
Lagertha:
Why have you come,
athelstan?
Did you escape?
Athelstan:
I came here to talk to you.
King horik:
King ecbert sent you!
You do his bidding.
You are one of them.
Athelstan:
He offers you a chance
for peace.
He wants to talk of many things
with you.
Good things.
King horik:
Yes, and then kill us.
Athelstan:
No. He will not, I swear.
I know him.
Horik:
You are his dog.
You lick his fingers.
You lick his arsehole.
(men laugh)
Floki:
I really like your new clothes,
athelstan,
And your hair.
Very nice.
Lagertha:
Is he prepared to offer us
a hostage?
Athelstan:
Yes. He wants to reassure you,
in any way he can,
Of his honest intentions.
Then we will meet him.
Lagertha:
You do not need to come.
Ragnar and I will go,
And if ecbert means to kill us,
so be it.
Athelstan:
I will give him your answer.
Ragnar:
I will accompany you,
Part of the way.
(chatter resumes in the camp)
Shield-maiden:
Why does he go with him?
(foliage rustles underfoot)
(leather creaks with tension)
Ragnar:
(sighs)
It is good to see you;
I feared that you were dead.
Athelstan:
There were times
that I wish I had been.
I gave into despair.
Ragnar:
So have you returned
to your faith,
Renounced ours?
Athelstan:
I wish it was so simple.
In the gentle fall of rain
from heaven, I hear my god,
But in the thunder
I still hear thor.
That is my agony.
Ragnar:
I hope that someday our gods
can become friends.
I have something
to return to you.
(sighs)
You are safe to go now,
But I will see you
very soon.
Thank you, friend.
(foliage rustles,
hooves thud)
(birds chirp,
dogs bark in the distance)
(hooves thud)
guard: Gates!
(gates unlatch
and creak open)
(hooves clop)
King aelle:
So who have you chosen
for our hostage?
Your son again?
King ecbert:
No. It did not seem just
or right
To place him in danger
for a second time.
Who then?
Actually... You,
king aelle.
(chuckles)
me?!
That the northmen will place
a higher value on than you
And they are bound to know
the consequences
If they should harm you
in any way.
Of course, if you do not wish
to place yourself at risk...
No, no.
I will play the part.
Warrior:
Riders!
(horse whinnies,
hooves thunder)
Riders approaching!
Do you not think
you should prepare yourself,
King aelle?
(hooves clop)
Floki:
This is a mistake.
Ragnar:
What do you say?
Floki:
I say this will end
very badly.
Now you've had
your say.
All this
for your brother.
We're all put in danger
Why must we save
your brother?
He killed arne,
he nearly killed me.
He betrayed all of us.
Lagertha:
This is not just about rollo.
Floki:
No, it's also about
the priest...
Who lured us here.
How can you trust him?
You talk about trust -
you!
What are you saying?
I am a trustworthy
person!
(scoffs)
(horses snort)
Aethelwulf:
(speaking norse)
Ragnar:
(horse hooves clop)
(speaking norse)
(harnesses jingle,
hooves thud)
(horse hooves clop)
(footsteps crunch)
(approaching footsteps)
King ecbert:
(speaking norse)
(footsteps scuff
the stone floor)
(speaking in norse)
Athelstan:
King ecbert desires me
to set before you -
Outline - possible terms
of a treaty.
He is completely sincere
In his wish for peace
and cooperation
And believes that
ragnar lothbrok
Shares his wish.
The king will agree to pay you
monies and/or treasures
To prevent any further
depredations
Of his territories.
More importantly,
He is prepared to offer
5000 acres of good land,
For farming,
In peace.
Finally, may I present to you
princess kwenthrith
From the kingdom of mercia.
King ecbert and the princess
are willing to pay
Any of your warriors
a fat fee
For fighting for her.
Ragnar:
What about my brother?
Athelstan:
The king will agree
to release rollo
Upon your acceptance
of his offer,
And upon the safe return
of king aelle.
Ragnar:
I accept the offer.
Lagertha:
As do I.
(wagon creaks and rattles)
(rain patters)
(wagon rattles)
Floki:
It's all here.
(hooves thud)
(wagon rattles)
(floki hisses)
Ragnar:
Hello, brother.
Athelstan:
(calling out) whoever among you
wishes to act as mercenaries
For princess kwenthrith,
Come forward now!
(horse snorts and whinnies
impatiently)
(footsteps squelch
in the mud)
(rollo grunts in pain)
Ragnar:
I am taking my brother home.
Will you come back with us
Or will you stay here with...
Your people?
I want you to come back.
(fighting grunts,
swords clang)
Man:
Stand your ground!
Porunn:
(panting)
(swords clanking)
Man: Good! Strong grip!
Porunn: Yes!
Man:
Shield up.
(fighting grunts,
swords clang)
Man:
That's enough.
(wind blows fiercely)
(wind blows fiercely,
waves lap at the shore)
Aslaug:
Who told you to do that?
Porunn:
No one. I am doing it
for myself.
I want to fight
in a shield-wall.
I want to be like
lagertha!
Why does everyone
want to be like lagertha?
Don't worry,
I understand.
I know what you meant.
I have decided to make you
a free woman.
You are no longer my servant,
or bonded to me.
You will only serve me
and my household if you choose,
As a free person.
That is impossible.
And yet it has happened.
This is a gift.
(wind blows fiercely)
♪
(chain clinks)
(chain clanks heavily)
(footsteps crunch in the sand)
(waves lap at the shore)
♪
(footsteps splash)
(breathing heavily)
(preparatory breaths)
(exhales)
(happy exhale)
(clothing rustles)
(jingling sound)
♪
(gates creak open)
(townsfolk chatter)
(sheep bleat)
King ecbert:
So, these are the northmen
Who've agreed to fight
as your mercenaries
To help you gain the crown
of mercia.
Kwenthrith:
And ragnar lothrok is not here?
King ecbert:
Alas, no. But-
Kwenthrith:
Doesn't matter.
They're violent men, hmm?
King ecbert:
They are great warriors, yes.
All of them.
Kwenthrith:
Ah!
They are very... Strong.
King ecbert:
Well, they live hard lives.
They farm and they fight.
And they do not fear death.
(clothes rustle)
Warrior:
(gasps and pants)
Kwenthrith:
Ooh. (laughs)
Aethelwulf and king aelle:
(chuckle)
You know, I always knew
I would love these northmen.
Mm.
(clothing rustles)
I should like to breed
with them.
I think we would
produce giants!
Women:
(weeping)
(hurried footsteps thud)
(footsteps thud)
(wind blows fiercely)
(sighs with relief)
(excited chatter,
ivar coos)
Aslaug:
Welcome home, all of you,
and thank the gods.
Lagertha, you are most welcome;
please stay.
And you, you came back!
I did.
I came back because you,
and ragnar,
All of you,
are my family.
Torstein:
Heh! Drink, priest.
Bjorn: Princess.
Aslaug: Bjorn.
Bjorn:
Porunn?
I have made her
a free woman.
She is no longer
a slave.
Welcome back,
bjorn.
(rollo grunts in pain,
knife rings)
Elisef:
Thank you.
(rollo groans,
flesh sizzles)
(gasps in pain)
(grunts and gasps in pain)
Elisef:
Ragnar.
The leg, siggy.
Siggy: Lift.
Rollo: (groans in pain)
Elisef:
That's it.
(bone crunches,
muffled screams)
Elisef:
Splint.
Splint!
Rollo:
(grunts and passes out)
(fire crackles)
King horik:
Floki,
We can be honest
with each other,
Can we not, hm?
We know each other
well enough.
We know the things we like
and those we hate.
We share many things...
Many ideas,
feelings,
About the earth
and the gods.
Am I not right?
Yes.
I have a proposition
to put to you.
♪