[Man Narrating]
"What is past is prologue."
Yes, here at the National Archives
in Washington D. C...
past is prologue...
for this is the final resting place
of the histories and records...
of tens of thousands
of illustrious Americans.
World War II has come
to a victorious conclusion...
and now new names and new records
are being added to the list...
for the nation and the world are
for the first time learning...
of silent and significant deeds
performed in foreign lands...
by a legion of anonymous men and women...
the Army of Secret Intelligence.
When Washington, recovering from
the staggering blow of Pearl Harbor...
realized how effective had been
the long-established...
espionage machines
of Germany and Japan...
from the White House came orders
that the United States, too...
must have eyes and ears
within enemy countries.
Immediately, the nation commenced...
for the first time in its history...
to recruit a Secret
Intelligence Corps.
As the man best capable of organizing
the secret activities...
of the new United States
Intelligence Corps...
the president chose a Saint Louis
attorney, Charles Stevenson Gibson...
whose background in international
affairs had been gained...
from ten years'special service
in the American Embassy in Berlin.
As director of
Secret Intelligence...
Gibson reported only to the president
and theJoint Chiefs of Staff.
Among the top-level executives
of United States Secret Intelligence...
was a widely traveled scholar
and soldier of fortune...
Robert Emmet Sharkey
of Saint Paul, Minnesota.
Master of five languages and one
of America's foremost athletes...
Bob Sharkey was twice captured
by the Germans in World War I...
and both times escaped
with a brilliant record of
achievement behind enemy lines.
To Washington, in the weeks and months
that followed Pearl Harbor...
had come 76 carefully selected
groups of candidates...
for training and assignment
to secret operations overseas.
At the Union Station
one morning in 1944...
among thejostling thousands,
came the 77th group of candidates...
each unknown to the other.
The Washington headquarters of Secret
Intelligence was under tight security...
its address and telephone unlisted
in any governmental directory.
Few even knew of its existence.
The story of Operation 77
is typical of the activities...
of any of the 76 groups
which preceded it.
Each candidate's qualifications
and background...
had been checked and rechecked
before he was called to Washington.
Every member of O77 had volunteered
without reservation...
for hazardous duty
behind enemy lines.
Among those assigned to O77
were men like Pappy Simpson...
a British intelligence officer
in the First World War...
and, until early 1942,
a professor of English literature...
at Dartmouth College
at Hanover, New Hampshire.
Suzanne de Beaumont,
a French citizen...
had found herself stranded in the
United States when France fell in 1940.
Ofher husband, a captain
of artillery in the French army,
nothing had been heard.
Jeff Lassiter, son of a former
American consul at Bern, Switzerland...
was educated at Geneva
and Oxford.
Lassiter was recruited from the
Officers Training School at U.C.L. A...
partly because ofhis
superior knowledge of French.
Bill O'Connell,
a Rutgers graduate...
had been employed in the Foreign
Department of the Chase National Bank.
He spent two years in the bank's
European branches...
then Hitler went on the march...
and O'Connell returned
to New York.
- Say, do you remember the maiden
name of your grandmother?
- Sure.
She was quite a dame.
I wish mine had been.
[Narrator] Far away from the eyes of
inquisitive, gossipy Washington...
in secluded, country estates
requisitioned by the government...
O77 candidates entered
phase one of training.
Oh, is this bunk taken?
- Not yet.
- You bought a roommate.
I don't know. A guy that can't remember
the maiden name of his grandmother...
- She's got one now.
- [Knocking]
- [Both] Come in.
- Sorry for intruding, gentlemen.
I'm your conducting officer.
The name is Simpson.
- Bill O'Connell.
- Lassiter. Jeff Lassiter.
- Quarters all right?
- Great. Fine.
The library, the lounge, the pool...
all the facilities of the club
are for your convenience.
We'll be here two weeks.
I hope you'll be comfortable.
- Are we going to start training?
- No. This is assessment school.
You'll be given tests
to determine your mental...
and physical qualifications
for training.
To see if we can make the grade,
is that it?
Well, everyone isn't temperamentally
equipped for every job, you know.
We lose a few of you.
If you're thirsty, you'll find plenty
of beer in the icebox all the time.
Just help yourselves. Oh, uh,
supper in the main dining room, 6:30.
Dress optional.
Carry on.
Even a housemother.
Rugged duty.
- This is gonna go all right.
- [Chuckles]
- Play backgammon?
- Yeah.
- Let's have a game after dinner.
- With ya.
- Cigarette?
- Thanks.
- [Chattering]
- ¶¶[SlowJazz Piano]
This is your group, Bob.
You're in charge.
Three months of indoctrination school,
two weeks of practical exercises...
and they've got to be
in shape to go.
- Is that my assignment?
- That's one of them.
22 potential agents.
Most of them have a foreign background.
All can speak French.
- One of them can speak German.
- Mm-hmm.
You've got to find out
who that is.
All right.
That's not as easy
as it sounds.
- Why?
- Because one of the students in
that group is a German agent.
A German agent?
- You know?
- Yeah.
Man or woman?
When you find out,
let me know.
Mm-hmm. All right.
Ladies and gentlemen...
¶¶[Stops]
I've got a couple of things
to say to you before you begin
the next phase of your training.
Your instructors are all
experts in their jobs.
They're going to cram their years
of experience into your heads.
It shouldn't be necessary,
but I'm going to remind you of security.
Everything you learn,
everything you do, is secret.
Even your closest relatives can't know
you're an agent in O77.
Maybe nobody will ever know.
That's not important.
But keeping your mouth shut is.
Now, you're gonna have
a lot to remember...
and a couple of things
to forget.
Now, the average American is
a good sport. Plays by the rules.
But this war is no game, and no
secret agent is a hero or a good sport...
that is, no living agent.
You're going to be taught to kill,
to cheat, to rob, to lie.
Everything you learn is moving you
toward one objective...
just one, that's all...
the success of your mission.
Fair play? That's out.
Years of decency
and honest living?
Forget all about them,
or turn in your suits...
because the enemy can forget...
and has.
Well, work hard. I'll be with you
every inch of the way. All the way.
Working right with you.
Good luck.
Take over, Pappy.
The group will leave
for area "B" this afternoon.
Departure, 1500, front entrance.
That'll be all.
[Grunting]
Uh... you.
[Grunting, Punching Continue]
When searching a person for
concealed weapons, search thoroughly.
- Even below the knees.
- Hands up!
No, aim for the point
on the chin. The button.
Try it again.
Hands up!
That's better.
Start the fall from here. Follow it
right on over. Watch carefully.
I'm very relaxed,
you understand? And slap.
Here...
Slap hard. All right... you.
Don't forget the slap.
It'll break the force of your fall.
Good. All right.
Slap harder.
[Planes Crashing]
You have exactly one minute.
Time.!
What kind of planes
were involved?
How many motors
on the second plane?
Which plane was cut in half:
Top, bottom or the center?
How many planes crashed? If more
than one, which plane crashed first?
[Tapping]
[Narrator]
All O77 agents had to be able to send...
at least ten words a minute.
Those chosen for special jobs
as communicators...
received more thorough training.
[Tapping Continues]
- Now, listen.
- [Air Roaring]
[Roaring Continues]
- [Roaring Stops]
- Was that a freight train...
or a 155-millimeter shell
passing overhead?
Now, listen carefully.
[Metal Clicks]
A door latch or the cocking
of a.45 caliber pistol?
[Whistling Descending]
[Whistling Continues]
Ajungle bird or a falling bomb?
- [Dinging]
- Someone tapping on a champagne glass...
or Swiss bells?
Wind from the northeast.
Northeast.
Velocity: 15.
Wind from the northeast.
Attention, strip markers...
- [Engine Approaching]
- Arms in the air. Arms in the air.
Simulate your flashlights
and mark the strip.
Go.
Keep that bundle dry.! Go.
That room there.
That there.
Right. Left. That room right there.
Come on. Snap it up!
Mr. Jones is the president of a plant
which produces a secret war weapon.
You have been discovered
in his office going through papers
on his desk. What were you doing?
- Mr. Jones sent me there.
- That's a lie.
- No. That's why I have his key.
- Where did you get it?
- Mr. Jones gave it. At the restaurant.
- Key to his private office?
What were you after?
A very important telephone number.
He sent me for it.
- Mr. Jones sent you?
- When?
Oh, 20 minutes ago.
It, uh...
- It was a... lady's telephone number.
- Why didn't Mr. Jones come?
He was dining with someone. He...
- He didn't want her to come with him.
- Who?
- His wife.
- You're lying.
- No.
- You're a Nazi agent.
- No!
- What were you doing in that office?
[Sharkey] "How long does it take
to install this detonator?
"Nine... Find out the advantages offered
by this new detonator over the old one.
Ten... Get all secret data possible:
Blueprints, drawings, etc."
Now, there's your test.
Any questions?
"72 hours." Does that mean
back here in 72 hours?
- Correct. Very little time.
- The submarine base
in New London or Portsmouth?
You have your choice. They both
make and install the equipment.
And very well-guarded too.
But that shouldn't pose any
great difficulty for a couple
ofbright lads like you.
- He really dug down deep for that one.
- Interesting problem.
- That's about all. Wasting time.
- We're ready.
You're free to leave anytime.
Call the Special Equipment Department.
- A camera's a useful gadget.
- Thanks, Pappy.
Good hunting.
- Good old Pappy.
- Yeah.
The camera's a good idea.
Unless we can get our hands
on the blueprints.
- They don't leave blueprints
lying around to copy.
- Yeah.
Two problems:
How to get in, and...
We'll get jobs as laborers.
It'll take less faking.
- How can we get close enough
to photograph the parts?
- We won't find out here.
- Any luck?
- They assemble the detonators
in the exploder room.
- Yeah?
- But you can't get near it.
- We gotta be back tomorrow morning.
- Here's the angle.
- They take the detonators to the
torpedo shed where they install them.
- Is that restricted too?
When they change shifts,
they leave everything.
The whistle goes, they walk out.
Before the next shift gets in,
the detonators are left lying around.
- That's when to get the pictures.
- Right.
I'll head for the torpedo shed.
You tail me.
- But get the pictures. That's
the important thing. I'll cover you.
- Right.
[Metal Clanking, Motors Running]
[Horn Sounding]
[Horn Continues]
[Horn Stops]
- What are you doing in here?
- I work here.
You're not supposed
to be in here.
- I didn't know.
- Didn't know you're not
supposed to smoke here?
- I wasn't smoking.
- What are you doing with matches?
- Nothing. I was just...
- Gimme those matches.
- I wasn't smoking!
- Why don't you do like I told you...
- What's the matter?
- This fellow was gonna smoke.
This is a restricted section.
I'm his security officer.
My credentials.
Had my eye on this guy all day.
Your number is six, huh?
Let me call for ya.
I'm gonna take him
for questioning.
Gimme those matches.
[Indistinct]
- Hope I didn't hurt you.
- Hurt me? You saved me
from blowing the problem.
This is a... a badge of honor.
- Where did you get that card?
- In the special service section.
I didn't tell you.
- Bill, we made it.
- Hope so.
Have you found the German agent?
Yes. O'Connell.
He stands at the head ofhis class.
That was the lead.
And the report on
the final problem clinched it.
- Have you read it?
- Yes.
I checked the results
of the other groups on the problem.
- It was designed for them
to make mistakes.
- O'Connell didn't make any.
Thanks to quick thinking... too
quick for a beginner. O'Connell
has been through it all before.
This is a manual from the German
espionage school. Very good too.
"Es gibt keine Kameraden.
"Greift selbst den Kameraden an.
Verdachtigt ihn.
Vernichtet ihn wenn notig."
"There are no comrades.
Turn in a comrade, accuse him,
even destroy him if necessary."
Well, there it is.
That was the technique he used.
American kids would have slugged
the guard and fought together.
- Would you say he was good?
- Only one thing the matter...
he's on the wrong side.
- His name is Kuncel. Abwehr Five.
One of their best.
- K-U-N-Z-E-L?
- C-E-L.
- When do you want to pick him up?
- Kuncel's going with
the group to London.
He must never know
that he's suspected.
That's why no one has been told.
- It's going to be
more difficult for you.
- I'll be careful.
We've had him pegged,
but we've nursed him along.
He's after something big,
or it wouldn't be Kuncel.
- Information on our organization?
- It's bigger than that.
Second front.
That's what we think.
Where and when.
They'd love to have that.
Kuncel's a big shot.
The German High Command is
counting on what he brings in.
That's our hunch anyway.
Now, we've got to arrange for Kuncel
to get information...
the wrong information...
and take it to the German High Command.
The plan must have a logical way
for him to escape.
It's got to be cleverly staged.
We're dealing with a very smart man.
Mm-hmm.
When do we start?
As soon as we get to London.
- We're leaving tomorrow.
- Right.
Simpson will follow with the group.
We'll be ready.
[Narrator] Upon the arrival
of orders for overseas duty...
the Secret Intelligence
candidate becomes at last
a Secret Intelligence agent.
No more textbooks.
Less than 24 hours away
are the grim theaters of war.
[Engines Rewing]
London:
War-racked, battle-worn...
a grim reminder of the power of
destruction of a ruthless enemy.
Here were concentrated
the multiple activities
of Allied intelligence operations.
But top-secret groups like O77...
were billeted in remote,
country estates where they
were held in complete isolation...
while awaiting specific assignments.
[Engine Stops]
[Buzzer Rings]
- Your identification, sir?
- Sharkey, O77.
Yes, sir.
- O'Connell?
- He's in his quarters.
- I'll be glad to get him for you.
- No, I'd rather see him there.
- [Knocking]
- Come in.
- Bill...
- Hello, Mr. Sharkey.
You stay where you are.
I'll sit here.
Bill, uh, how well
do you know Holland?
- I've lived there many years.
- But how well do you know it?
I don't mean just Amsterdam.
The coast and inland.
- I know it very well.
- Good.
- Bill, things have changed.
- How do you mean?
You read the papers.
Full of talk about a second front.
- Everybody knows there's gonna be one.
- You think Holland?
Well, what I think doesn't count.
That's somebody else's job.
- We just obey orders.
- Yeah, sure.
Bill, I've been given a job, and
I need help... help of the right kind...
from people I know whose backgrounds
match the assignments...
and able to come through
in the clinches.
- Want a job?
- I didn't go through
all that training...
- to become an English country gentleman.
- Good.
Pack your gear. You're going to London
to work there in tight security.
- That security begins now. Clear?
- Clear.
No good-byes, nothing.
Not a word to anybody
about anything I've said to you.
You've got a job. That's all.
- I understand.
- I think you'll like it.
- I'm sure I will.
- We start early in the morning.
Good night.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Narrator]
This undistinguished building...
housed the undercover activities
of the Netherlands section
of Allied intelligence.
Here were coordinated thejoint efforts
of all agents operating in the Lowlands.
- Identification, please.
- O77.
Very good.
Show us, please.
All right.
You may go.
- Colonel Van Duyvil?
- Oh, yes, he's expecting you,
Mr. Sharkey.
Thank you.
- Hello, Sharkey.
- Colonel.
- Colonel Van Duyvil, chief of
Dutch Intelligence. Bill O'Connell.
- How do you do?
- O'Connell is my chief assistant
on the Dutch project.
- I understand.
It'll be his responsibility to
coordinate all of our circuits
in Holland.
- That is a tremendous job.
- He'll need every scrap
of information you can give him.
You will have
my complete cooperation.
- Thank you.
- We will begin immediately.
[Lock Rattling]
There are a great many details.
These maps cover only one
small phase of the project...
known to us as Plan B.
To invade and penetrate Germany
through the Lowlands.
Exactly.
These are messages from agents
already operating in Holland.
This one concerns bridges
and lines of communication.
Here you can see how we have tied this
information in with the operation.
You can find it here
in index number 15.
[Van Duyvil]
That's it.
[Paper Rustling]
[Narrator] Hidden away
in a remote corner of London...
was the headquarters of
combat operations of O77.
- My head's still swimming.
- There's a lot to absorb
in so short a time.
- How long do we have?
- Not long.
- It's a great plan.
- It had better be.
A great many lives depend on it.
- I've arranged six planes
at your disposal.
- Yes.
You'll be sending new agents in.
The teams already
there will be needing supplies,
so keep in touch with Van Duyvil.
Gonna be a great many problems.
Don't worry. I'll work them out.
I'm sure you will.
That's why you have the job.
A thankless one too.
No rewards, payoffs.
Just the satisfaction of doing
a job for your country.
- [Buzzes]
- We're depending on you.
- You won't be sorry.
- I know.
- Would you show Mr. O'Connell
to his office?
- Yes, sir.
All right.
[Narrator]
As plans for the impending invasion...
of Europe were speeded up...
agents of Operation 77
were broken up into combat teams...
and given their final briefing.
They are trying to help me
locate my husband.
Could I stop by the
communication section for a moment?
Later, Suzanne.
Mr. Sharkey said 0600, and Mr. Sharkey
is a singularly punctual gentleman.
[Knocking]
- Captain Ferraro, checking in.
- Captain Ferraro?
Threats of Hitler's secret weapon
are not idle. It's no longer a secret.
It's called V-2.
It's a self-propelled, pilotless bomb...
with a warhead said to contain
one ton of explosives.
Well-camouflaged launching platforms
such as these have been springing up...
along the French coast
for the past six months.
Our air force is
bombing them continuously,
but that's just expediency.
The enemy is building faster
than we can knock them out.
- We have to find them first.
- Why haven't they used them?
We think we know why.
The greatest concentration
is through here, and every
one of these launching platforms...
is pointed toward, and zeroed in to,
one specific target...
- [Simpson] London?
- No, not yet.
Southampton. The enemy knows
there's going to be an invasion.
He doesn't know where or when.
He does know that the invasion
base is in Southampton...
and he's building up
a tremendous supply of these rockets.
When he launches his attack, it's going
to be a sustained barrage on this area.
- When do you think it'll start?
- When Eisenhower makes his move.
The Germans know they can't win the war.
They're hoping for a stalemate.
They've got to prevent an invasion.
That's why we're here...
to help the Allied High Command
gain the preciously needed time...
to complete
the invasion buildup.
Lassiter, you've got a job.
- You're going to France.
- Right.
You, too, Suzanne,
as Lassiter's communicator.
Simpson, I want these agents briefed and
equipped to jump in one week's time.
- Righto.
- Their cover stories are now in work.
Follow through immediately on the forged
documents and proper wardrobe. Right?
Now the mission.
The most closely guarded area
in all of France is right here.
Every civilian in this area
is virtually a prisoner.
A main assembly and supply depot
feeds rockets to all these
launching platforms.
The depot's location
is about... here.
To destroy this target we have to know
every detail of its construction.
Even the French Resistance...
the Maquis... have been unable
to get this information.
All of the workmen...
forced labor, of course...
have been liquidated soon
as they finish their jobs.
Up to this point we've been stymied...
thoroughly stymied...
except for one vitally
important lead...
this face, this name, this man...
is still alive.
Monsieur Duclois.
A very important man to the Germans.
Burn that face, that picture,
into your memory...
because the success of your mission,
and subsequently...
the destruction of the target,
is linked to that man.
- Duclois.
- Well, what is his connection
with the bomb depot?
He... a Frenchman...
designed and built it.
This is only a draft
of your cover story.
Do not hesitate to comment
on any detail...
- which you may find
difficult to support.
- Right.
- Your name is Henri Masson.
- Henri Masson.
You were born, educated, and later
worked as a petty government official...
at the Ministere du Travail
in the small town of Carcassonne.
- That's in the south.
- Yes.
- Ah, about, uh, 50 miles north of
the Pyrenees. Département d'Eau.
- Oui.
[Narrator] Much of the success
of Secret Intelligence operations...
was due to foresight
and meticulous preparation.
No detail was permitted
to be overlooked.
Do you think maybe there's
too much crease in the pants here?
All right, sir,
I'll have it taken up.
Vous tes prt?
- [Clicks]
- Et voil. C'est fini.
This is your food ration book,
clothes ration, tobacco...
automobile license, bus tickets,
your travel permit...
and this is your certificate
of demobilization.
This is your identification card.
And this is a certificate to
prove that you're an inspector
of compulsory work service.
I'll need your thumbprint
right here.
[Machines Clattering]
These operators will receive
your transmissions.
- I want them to be familiar
with your touch.
- Is it enough?
- I'm sure we'll recognize it.
- Thank you.
- Good-bye and good luck.
- Mr. Mason...
- Mm-hmm?
I'm so sorry to keep on
bothering you, but...
have you had any word
about my husband?
Uh, not yet,
Madame de Beaumont.
But we've contacted
an agent in the Le Havre area.
You'll be informed as soon as we hear.
- Thank you very much.
- Not at all.
- Where you been?
- Where have you been?
- Walk off in the middle
of the night, huh?
- Had to leave in a hurry.
- How about a cup of coffee?
- With ya.
I don't know what's going
to happen with me.
- Haven't you a good assignment?
- Important, not much action.
Looks like I'm grounded. What are
you doing... prepping for a mission?
- I can't tell you what it is.
- I knew you were a bad investment.
- How much do I owe you, 13 million?
- I don't know.
- Fourteen.
- As much as that? I'll whittle it
down as soon as I get back.
- When are you leaving?
- I don't know.
I didn't think it would happen this way.
Wish I were going with you.
Me too. Well, I better meet Simpson,
get back to the holding area.
- Bring me back a souvenir.
- Sure thing.
[Knocking]
Come in, Jeff.
You know Mr. Gibson.
Jeff Lassiter.
- Hello, Lassiter.
- How do you do, sir?
- Sit down, Jeff.
- Yeah.
You, uh...
- Two days ago you saw
your friend O'Connell.
- Yeah, in the canteen.
- We had a cup of coffee.
- This is not, uh, an accusation.
- You didn't reveal the nature
of your mission?
- Of course not.
- You understand why I asked.
- No, I don't understand.
Your chum O'Connell...
is an agent of the Nazi government.
- What?
- His name is Kuncel.
He's a clever, thoroughly
trained German secret agent.
Oh... Oh, you're kidding.
- No, I'm not kidding.
- But that's silly.
I was with him all through school.
L... I lived in the same room
with the guy for months.
Jeff, this is a tough, realistic
business with a thousand twists.
- Don't feel badly. He fooled me too.
- I can't believe it.
It was hard. Harder to find him...
although I'd been told there
was a German agent in the school.
- German agent...
- Not just a German agent.
One of the best they have.
Planted there for a reason.
That's why he's still in the group.
That's where you with
your disarming naiveté came in...
to keep him from suspecting
we knew anything about him.
- You did a very much betterjob
not knowing who he was.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I did a good job.
Now you got a tougher one.
Ajob that you can't do
without knowing.
O'Connell has been assigned
a mission in Holland.
That's the clincher
to all the misinformation
we have allowed him to obtain.
- Holland?
- The invasion of Holland.
That's the lie we're trying to sell...
to the German High Command, and Kuncel...
O'Connell... is the salesman.
- That's where you come in.
- What could I do?
- O'Connell asked for you.
We're going to send you with him.
- What about Duclois?
Still your mission as planned.
You'll proceed to Le Havre.
- How?
- You'll be dropped near Rotterdam.
Contact a man
by the name Wolfert Bockman
at the Department of Public Works.
- Bockman will see that you and
Suzanne get through to France.
- S-Suzanne?
She'll be briefed for the Holland
mission with you and O'Connell.
The briefing will be short
and, of course, a phony.
You'll be on your way
within 48 hours.
Now comes the rugged part.
- Yes.
- We think O'Connell is sold.
If we're right, he'll make his break
and you'll never see him again.
Could he know anything
about Duclois?
- Not unless he gets it from you.
- He won't.
Never forget you're dealing
with an extremely clever man.
Drop your guard one minute,
we'll have failed, you may be dead.
Don't forget the time he slugged you.
He thinks fast...
he's ruthless,
lets nothing interfere.
- That's why we're gonna do it his way.
- His way? What's that?
If he isn't sold,
and should in any way suspect
that you're on a double mission...
if he doesn't make his break
and tries to follow you...
you're going to shoot him.
- Shoot him?
- And make sure it's for keeps.
- Tha... That's rough. Tha...
- That's war.
And that's your mission.
Yeah.
O'Connell can do it.
Can you?
Yeah, I can do it.
- That's all for now.
- Right.
- Jeff...
- Yes?
- I know how you feel.
- Right.
- Some more?
- No, thank you. I had too much.
Isn't it the most exciting evening
in our lives?
- The room is so beautiful,
and the food was so delicious.
- Yes, indeed, yes.
- Kind of like the Last Supper.
- Not the Last Supper.
There is noJudas.
Not the Last Supper, no.
To the success of your mission...
to your safe return, to the good things
in life for all of you.
To a better, happier world.
A message for you, sir,
and the car is ready.
- Oh, we'll be right there.
- Thank you.
- Luck, Jeff.
- Luck.
Well, let's get started.
Suzanne.
Oh, have they heard?
Yes, Suzanne, they have.
Oh.
Pappy, I'll...
I'll be back in a minute.
Sorry.
Bad news?
- Yes.
- Your... husband's... dead?
What a rotten break.
- Maybe it's just as well
you're not going back to France.
- [Simpson] We have to go now.
- Would you like some coffee?
- No, thank you.
- How about you fellows?
- No, thanks.
How are we doing?
Just past the coast of Holland.
Won't be long.
- Jeff?
- Yeah?
We used to talk about this one.
- Yeah.
- Feel like you thought you would?
Yeah.
You know something?
What?
I don't believe you.
Getting close.
Check your static line.
Check?
Check.
- Check?
- Check.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
There is. You're lookin' at me
like I was in a test tube.
- Sorry, I... guess I'm nervous.
- Yeah, I'm nervous too.
[No Audible Dialogue]
Comin' over the target.
Action stations.
Jeff...
- Yeah?
- You know that 14 million you owe me?
I'm wiping it off the books.
What's 14 million anyway?
Never have time to spend it.
We're even, Jeff.
We'll start from scratch.
- You don't owe me anything.
- Running in.
One... Go!
Two...
Go.!
Three...
"Lassiter killed in jump. Stop.
O'Connell fired at reception
committee. Stop.
"Disappeared. Stop. O'Connell
in possession of all Henri Masson
documents. Stop.
Proceeding mission area as planned.
Stop. Suzanne."
- Which one of you girls received
this message from de Beaumont?
- I did, sir.
- You sure it's her transmission?
- Positive.
Killed in the jump.
What a break.
Yes, it is.
Well, right now we're batting
zero-zero-zero.
- [Knocking]
- Come in.
This just came in, sir,
from the operator on the plane.
Lassiter's static cord
was deliberately cut.
- What!
- His chute never opened.
He was murdered.
What a way to die.
What did Kuncel know?
- Could he have known anything
about Lassiter's mission?
- No.
- He knew he had Vichy credentials.
- He knew more than that.
He also knew the Holland invasion
was a phony.
Yeah. Or else he wouldn't
have killed Lassiter.
Well, Sharkey, you've done a great job.
Where do you go now?
- Back to Minnesota
to sit on a draft board.
- What's that?
I've made the only mistake
you're allowed to make in this outfit.
Yeah, they might send you on
a rest cure for that one, except...
There are no "excepts,"
and they're right.
- It'd look good to me.
I might do it again.
- So might I.
The one thing we can hope
for is another chance, unless...
- Unless what?
- Unless you want to concede the victory.
- Ah, not from you, Gib.
Keep your punches up, eh?
- I said, "unless you want to."
I concede nothing... until
they throw dirt in my face.
- That's better. Now, who have you
got to send to France?
- Only one man to send.
Too short a time to get Duclois
and blast that target. Who?
- Me.
- No.
An agent who wasn't familiar
with the mission wouldn't have a chance.
We haven't time to bring one up to date.
We need the time on the other end.
- You know I can't send you.
- Why not? I'm familiar
with every detail. I planned it.
- You know I can't send you.
- Why not? I'm familiar
with every detail. I planned it.
I could leave immediately.
Give me one reason.
- You know the date and place
of the invasion.
- I've forgotten.
- Do you realize what would happen
to you if you were captured?
- Torture? Certainly.
Every agent carries an L-tablet.
And dead one minute after you bite one.
- And Kuncel's probably waiting for you.
- I'd like that.
- We're 100% failure
unless we get Duclois.
- Right.
There's a man loose who knows
every one of our 15 agents.
- We took that chance
when we left Kuncel in.
- I trained that group.
Every one of their lives is in
jeopardy while Kuncel's around.
- We're losing time.
I'll need these minutes.
- I don't want to send you.
I've been working hard.
I need the change.
You won't come back.
- I've just discovered
something about you.
- What?
You're a worrier.
Running in.
Go!
Giselle, show him the way.
You can go in now.
- Are you sure that's the right house?
- Oh, yes.
[Kisses]
I am very grateful
for your hospitality.
You are welcome to spend the night.
- Tomorrow I could not have taken you in.
- Oh?
Today two German officers arrived.
More Germans are moving into this area.
They need this house. They will be
back tomorrow. They take the best.
- I must leave tomorrow.
- That is well.
Has, um... Has anyone else arrived?
Not the Germans?
- Many people have arrived here.
- But I mean today, tonight.
I'm expecting to meet someone,
a young lady.
During the war,
I have been left alone. You arrive.
I do not ask whom you are
or where you come from.
I understand. But if someone should
arrive and ask for Gabriel Chavat...
- It's very important.
- Food... what we have... at least
it will be warm... is waiting.
- That's very nice, but...
- I will show you to the kitchen.
This way, please.
Now I will retire.
You are leaving early.
Good-bye.
- Was it difficult?
- Not too difficult.
- A fine woman.
- I know.
I was here when
the German officers arrived.
- When are we leaving?
- As soon as it's daylight.
- Where are we going?
- Pont-I'Eveque, near Le Havre.
Good. I know a safe place
for our transmission.
- Same mission?
- Duclois.
The unfortunate death of
my friend will force their hand.
- They may already have sent
an agent to take his place.
- Yes, it's possible.
And that's the man
we must find.
- That man will give us the answer
to your question. Karl...
- Yes?
Tighten every security check in
the costal area. Forget the name
"Masson." They'll change it.
I will be at Abwehr headquarters
in Le Havre.
- Report any discrepancies
in any civilian's behavior.
- Yes.
Hold for questioning any civilian
carrying Vichy credentials.
Yes.
They will send another man.
He'll need papers of authority
to allow him to perform his mission.
We will find that man,
and you shall know the mission.
- Good morning, monsieur.
- Good morning.
Merci, monsieur.
Fill in this form, please.
[Clerk]
How long do you wish to stay?
[Sharkey]
Long enough to accomplish my business.
- How long will that be, monsieur?
- Two or three days.
Very good, monsieur.
- Good morning.
- I must trouble you to see your papers.
- But why?
I'm sorry, but I must trouble you.
By what authority?
Oh, all this red tape,
all this interference holds up business.
There was an insurance adjustor
here a week ago.
- And two days later
you had another air raid.
- Not from German planes.
From British and American.
They bomb their friends.
[Chuckles]
Friends.
[Bell Dings]
Room 14.
Just a minute!
Where was your grandfather buried?
- Which one?
- Well, on your father's side?
- In the St. Maurice Cemetery at Toulon.
- Oh, I see.
Yes, Chavat.
C-H-A-V-A-T.
Chavat. Yeah.
St. Maurice Cemetery, Toulon.
Mm-hmm.
[Footsteps Approaching]
May I present my letter
of commission?
Department of Compulsory Labor.
- You represent the government at Vichy?
- Of course.
The nature of your business?
My government and yours is not satisfied
with this town's labor record.
I cannot understand that.
We have tried to cooperate.
That is precisely what you have
not done. You have not cooperated.
- This is a very small town.
- France is full of small towns...
only this happens to be
a very important one.
You know as well as I the kind
of work that's going on here...
a most important project.
And one that requires
the utmost secrecy.
I only know we have turned over
every available young man...
for German labor battalions.
You forget I have the facts.
The government has sent me to
investigate a serious protest.
Protest?
I don't understand.
From whom?
A cooperative Frenchman...
a man who realizes full well
where the future of France
lies... Monsieur Duclois.
Has your town been molested
by our protectors? No.
Haven't your people been allowed
to enjoy the peace they had
before the Germans came?
No. Things are not the same.
They can never be the same when
we must give over the young men.
You know what will happen, of course,
if you don't give them over.
Yes, I realize.
The Germans will take them.
Exactly. That's why I'm here...
to help your townspeople.
- You must cooperate.
- What can I do?
The size of the project
has been increased.
Monsieur Duclois
has asked for more men.
How many more can we give?
I will be able to give you
those figures as soon as I've
spoken to Monsieur Duclois.
Where does he live?
- I do not know.
- You must know.
I do not know
any Monsieur Duclois.
I appreciate your caution.
You have been advised
to remain absolutely silent
about this entire project.
You obeyed those orders.
That's good.
We will still observe the rules
of caution. You will take me
to Monsieur Duclois' house.
- I do not know any Monsieur Duclois.
- Very well.
I shall return to Vichy
with your stubborn refusal
and you will be removed from office.
I have no time to waste
on stupid people.
I am sorry.
You must understand my position.
I am mayor of a small town.
The Resistance movement
is strong and well organized.
- I do my best,
but I'm hated by my own people.
- The people do not understand!
You could be a member of the Resistance.
I must be sure.
I will have you taken
to Monsieur Duclois.
Emile.
This gentleman is from the Department
of Compulsory Labor at Vichy.
Take him to Monsieur Duclois.
- Good day.
[Engine Starts, Runs]
- Does he live outside of town?
- Yes.
How far away does he live?
Ten kilometers.
We've gone farther than that.
It won't be long.
- [Engine Stops]
- We get out here.
- Where's the house?
- They don't let this man
live in a house.
He's carefully protected
from, uh, air raids.
There's a shelter
on the side of the hill.
- There?
- On the other side. Follow me.
Who's in charge here?
I must talk to your leader.
Dig.
[Paper Rustling]
Monsieur Chavat,
he went to see the mayor.
- Take me up to his room.
- Yes, mon colonel.
This is the record
of his visit.
He had a letter of commission
in the Department of Compulsory Labor.
He said he was returning
to the hotel.
[Door Bangs Open]
You're the leader?
- I must talk with you.
- Why?
- We're on the same side.
- You're a traitor.
I'm an American agent from London.
Parachuted in here two days ago.
- And these?
- All forged.
Why did you come
to Pont-I'Eveque?
On a mission. And I'll need
your help to carry it out.
- Pierre!
- You must believe me.
German agents are parachuted here too.
Even from Allied planes.
I have a radio operator with me, a girl.
I can take you right to her.
The Germans have them too.
We can't take any chances.
But you can't take the chance
of killing a friend...
someone who would help your
cause, someone who was sent here
to help liberate your country.
I know, everything I have is French:
My suit, my shoes and all my papers.
But we're fighting a clever enemy.
We can't afford to take chances either.
You must give me proof,
or else l...
- You have a radio? You can hear London?
- Yes. Yes.
All right. Can you give me
a courier to take a message...
- to a safe house not far from town?
- Why?
My operator will contact London.
She will instruct them to repeat
a personal message to you...
on the news broadcast tonight.
You will select the message, anything
you want. I will write the message.
Joseph!
What is your message?
A lamb is ready
for the slaughter.
[Clicking]
Be patient.
We'll get them.
[Man On Radio] This is London. Our
news bulletin will follow in a moment.
But first, here are
a few personal messages.
The little dog laughed.
The play is over.
Jill wants Jack to come home.
The churchyards yawn.
This ends the personal messages.
And now for the news.
One of the largest daylight raids,
5,000 Allied planes...
battered 27 invasion area targets
in Holland, Belgium and France.
I must interrupt the news
for an important announcement.
Listen carefully, please.
A lamb is ready
for the slaughter.
[Turns Radio Off]
Why did you come here?
- To get Duclois.
- To destroy him?
No. To take him alive.
And I'll need your help. I know
he's somewhere near Pont-I'Eveque.
You are right. He lives
and works at the Hotel Moderne.
We have wanted
Monsieur Duclois alive too...
but there would be
bloody reprisals.
We can wait until there are
no longer German guards.
- He's kept under guard?
- Always.
Duclois is an important man
for the Germans.
Right now he's a more important man
for London and for France.
Now listen.
I've gotta get back to the village.
- An agent of the gestapo
is waiting there for you.
- Gestapo? You sure?
He came to my office this morning.
He is still in the village.
We will keep you in a safe place.
- I must get Duclois.
- Alive? That's impossible.
You have men and arms.
You can help me. You must help me.
We must keep hidden
until the right day arrives.
Once we come out in the open,
the Germans will know us
and destroy our small force.
We will do good work
when the time comes.
We must wait for the right time.
This is what you've been waiting for.
This is the right time.
No. Only when
the Allied armies come...
the English and the Americans.
We must wait.
Monsieur Gallimard,
this is the right time.
- The invasion?
- You've heard our broadcast,
you've seen our planes.
- More and more raids every day.
- You know when they are coming?
You've seen the care that London
has taken to get me to Pont-I'Eveque.
- Yes.
- So much depends on this mission.
You must help me, even if it costs
the lives of some of your countrymen.
This much I will tell you...
In a few days it'll be too late.
This is the time.
[Speaking French]
[Narrator]
In the seaport city of Le Havre...
gestapo headquarters for the
heavily-fortified channel coast area...
of enemy-occupied France...
was located at 13 Rue Madeleine.
[Man]
The high forehead. Clear.
Heavy eyebrows.
Deep set eyes.
Very straight thin lips.
Yes.
No, no, no, no.
The nose is a different shape.
Straighter.
Much straighter.
Mm-hmm.
Wait a minute.
That's the man.
Herr Kuncel. Herr Kuncel.
Can I see you a second?
Of course.
Of course!
[Man On Radio]
If the moon shines...
Maxine will not be lonely
tomorrow night.
If the moon shines...
That's it. We'll receive confirmation
on the next news broadcast.
- Good. Did you get them, Joseph?
- Yes.
- We will go ahead as planned.
Evening will be the best time.
- Good.
Here is the Hotel Moderne.
- This is the floor plan.
- Mm-hmm.
Here is the town hall.
Here is the Hotel Louis Quatorze.
At 6:30, I will be at my office.
- I will send for the gestapo agent.
- Uh-huh.
- You will get the men together
and assign them.
- Yes.
All day long
I have found these:
In my house, in my pocket,
in my mail...
under my door, in the car, in the
office, in the streets, everywhere I go.
They think it is I who have bled
this town for workmen.
Two days ago
another man from Vichy.
- The people know why he is here...
to get more Frenchmen.
- Where is he?
He has disappeared. The Resistance.
He will never be found.
I do my best. The people
do not understand. Now this.
- My life is in danger.
I must have protection.
- [Gunfire]
They are going to kill me.
[People Chattering, Yelling]
Call your men.
Call your men from the hotel!
I will talk to the people. Hurry...
or it will be too late.!
Hello? Hello?
Hotel Moderne, at once.!
My fellow townspeople...
you must go back to your houses.
This is breaking the law!
There will be reprisals.
You are a traitor
to France, Gallimard!
There will only be trouble.
French lives will be lost.
There will be reprisals.
You must go back to your houses.
He is a traitor...
Gallimard!
Return to your homes.
- Return to your homes!
- [Gunfire]
- We'll be right there.
- [Bell Rings]
Sergeant, Resistance at the mayor's
office. Riot. Get right over there.
Yes, sir.
[Engine Starting]
[Man]
Hello? Hello?
Gestapo headquarters,
Le Havre.
- Put that wood down and get out of here.
- Who's going to pay me the money?
- There's nobody else around here now.
Come back later.
- I need my money. I'm poor.
[Officer]
Put that wood down and get out ofhere.
I'm not going to until
you give me my money.
I told you to get...
[Groans]
- [Whispering]
Are there any others in the house?
- The night detail.
They are sleeping on the third floor.
Perhaps 12 of them.
- Duclois?
- He's on the second floor...
but I haven't been able
to find out what room yet.
- [Switchboard Buzzes]
- You go the back way.
See if you can find the room.
[Buzzing Stops]
Corporal?
Corporal.!
Corporal!
[Footsteps Approaching]
- Room 210, in the front.
- Get rid of him.
- Come on, Duclois.
- No. No.
If they get you, they'll kill you.
I want you alive. Come with me.
Resistance? Huh.
Hello? Hello?
The fastest way to Pont-I'Eveque.
Stop here.
That's an O77 landing operation. When
they land, they'll be there 30 seconds.
Wind: 90 degrees.
Velocity: 20. Velocity: 20.
Wind:90 degrees.
Velocity:20.
Coming in fine.
You're coming in fine.
To the plane.
Come on.
Look!
Cover. I'll stop the car!
[Engine Starts, Runs]
[Tires Screech]
Find the driver of this car.
He can't be far away.
[Plane Taking Off]
Look through every foot
of that brush.
Hurry up.!
- Look out!
- [Gunfire]
[Engines Starting]
[Vehicles Approaching]
[Tapping]
It's very close by.
We are moving to point "B" now.
[Tapping]
[Brakes Squeak]
- [Door Rattling]
- [Tapping]
[Door Bangs Open]
[Gunfire]
This area is a grain field.
Now, how far is it exactly
from the river to the depot?
From the river to the depot...
12 kilomtres point 27.
- Have you got all those details?
- [All Murmuring] Yes.
That's all we shall need from him.
- The French Intelligence
are not through with him.
- Take him along.
Will you come along too, Gallimard?
We know where the depot is,
every detail of its construction...
the size of the stuff
we shall need to wipe it out.
You can be very proud
of your organization, Gibson. I want
to thank you for your cooperation.
- Right.
- Now it's our job.
- Good night.
- Communications just sent word.
They've contacted Suzanne.
- I'll go right up.
From de Beaumont.
[Gibson Reading]
- It broke off there.
- Why? What's your guess?
It was an interrupted message.
The signal stopped, but
I could still hear the carrier.
He wasn't lucky.
No, he's still alive.
That's all.
Just three questions,
that's all, Sharkey:
What was your mission?
Where is the invasion coming?
When?
We'll make you tell,
you know that, Sharkey.
A man can take so much punishment,
remember? You taught me.
"Fair play, years of decency,
that's out."
You've done your job.
Now I'll do mine.
Where, Sharkey?
Where are they comin' in?
- Have you got a map?
- Right here.
Where?
Right...
Take a good look at this house.
This is your target.
Familiarize yourself with it:
The house, the grounds...
the ornate fence,
the street.
It's got some good landmarks too:
The chimney, the bay,
the surrounding hills...
this large building
on the right.
Take a good look at it
and remember.
This has got to be a job
of total destruction.
Not a wall left standing.
No one must escape in
that house alive. No one.
The nature of your mission
is unusual...
but I cannot emphasize too strongly
how very important.
Two squadrons dropping
high explosives...
followed by two squadrons
at minimum interval...
to smother the entire target area...
with rockets and machine gun fire.
You know it must be important.
You've been given
your route of approach.
Time over target, 0300.
Bombers will go in at zero feet.
- [Men Gasp, Chattering]
- I know.
I know, it's tough.
Any questions?
Well, Colonel, I think on a mission...
well, a mission like this...
we'd kind of like to know
who's in that house...
whether it's Fatso Goering
or Hitler or who?
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty
to answer that.
I know this is a tough assignment.
You'll be risking your lives.
You have a right to know.
That house is the headquarters
of the German gestapo in Le Havre.
That's an important reason
for destroying it.
But it's not the only reason.
There's an American agent
in that house.
And ifhe talks,
it may cost the lives...
of a great many American soldiers.
Right now he's suffering the cruelest
tortures the Germans can devise.
But he won't talk...
not as long as he can stand
that punishment.
And no human body
can stand it too long.
Not even this wonderful,
tough guy from Minnesota.
As soon as you can.
All right, men,
let's synchronize our watches.
[Whip Snapping]
[Snapping Continues]
[Snapping Stops]
[Snapping Resumes]
- What have you found out?
- Nothing.
[Air Raid Sirens Wailing]
[Softly]
They're over the target.
- [Bombs Exploding]
- The lamp!
[Plane Engines Droning]
[Bombs Continue Exploding]
[Chuckling]
Mission completed.