(narrator) In the early days
of the present war,
a neutrality act prohibited
American manufacturers
from delivering planes
to belligerents on foreign soil.
Sympathetic to Great Britain and her allies,
but legal to the last,
their pilots were ordered to fly the ships
as close as possible to the Canadian border.
Democratic ingenuity
and a stout rope did the rest.
(plane approaching overhead)
Where's he going?
That's another Harvard trainer, isn't it?
Yes.
- Hi. Baker's my name. Tim Baker.
- I'm Flight Lieutenant Redmond.
I was told to deliver
this ship here. Here she is.
- You were told to deliver it here?
- This is Trenton?
Yes. Trenton, Canada.
- Canada?
- Yes.
Well, what do you know about that?
I was looking for Trenton, New Jersey.
My compass must have gone haywire.
You got a cigarette?
How could I have ever mistaken
Canada for New Jersey?
- You'd better come along to the CO.
- OK with me.
Mr Baker, have you ever heard
of the Neutrality Act?
- Yes, sir. The newspapers are full of it.
- Then why did you deliberately violate it?
What difference does it make whether you
tow it across or whether I fly it across?
You get the same aeroplane.
Who does anybody think they're fooling?
We won't argue the point, Mr Baker.
Nor will we be a party to any action
likely to embarrass a friendly government.
I'm afraid you will not be permitted
to ferry any more aircraft. Good day.
OK. OK, if you want to keep the war in
low gear, there's nothing I can do about it.
Just a moment, Mr Baker.
If you know of any capable pilots,
you might mention that we're in need of men
to ferry bombers across to England.
- Pays rather well, you know.
- Just what do you call "rather well"?
A thousand dollars a flight and all expenses.
A thou...
Of course, we wouldn't want our aircraft
delivered by way of Berlin,
since they are to be employed
in that vicinity eventually anyhow.
A thousand bucks a flight
will keep me on my course.
Shall I drop a memo
to the flight superintendent?
Drop it by telephone.
I like to take ajob while I'm enthusiastic.
- Not a bad idea, Baker.
- Thank you, sir.
Oh, by the way, England's to the east, isn't it?
(both laugh)
Well, we're off.
We're on our way.
(thunderclap)
If I could fly back to Canada instead of
taking a boat, I could make a trip a week.
You better concentrate on this first time.
There's no beam out here.
That's four trips a month. 52 trips a year.
Taking two weeks out for vacation,
that's 50,000 bucks.
- What was that?
- 50,000 bucks.
Boy, what a war.
I've tried all the frequency bands.
I can't even get a whisper out of this set.
Why don't you try BBC?
When I was flying the mails in America,
I used to always ride in on Kate Smith.
Boy, there's a beam for you.
This was London in the early days of the war,
a city of homes and churches
and shops and pubs,
of roast beef and old school ties,
and Big Ben and the fog.
The very heart and core of England.
Extra special, sir. Standard, Sporting Times.
Paper. Morning leader, Daily Mail.
Paper? Thank you, sir.
Paper, sir?
- Wake up, sir. Wake up, sir, we're at the hotel.
- Go away, go away.
You really got to get out, sir.
It's against orders to loiter here.
(newspaper seller) Paper!
- Oh, I'm dead.
- Paper!
- Morning leader, Daily Mail.
- Any more baggage, sir?
Paper, sir?
I'm gonna sleep till that boat pulls out.
Daily Mail morning leader.
Paper, sir? Paper?
- What's up?
- Uh...
On second thought,
I can sleep on the boat home.
- Yes, but...
- I think I've found the beam again.
Extra special, sir. Standard, Sporting Times.
Paper! Daily Mail morning leader.
All about Hitler. Paper! Read about it.
Meow.
I beg your pardon, but have you seen
anything of a little grey-white cat?
Cat? Why, no.
She's a gorgeous creature. Been in the
family for years. You know, long, silky fur...
- Hello, darling!
- Hello, dear.
- Friend of yours?
- No, just a man who's lost his cat.
Poor fellow, he must be terribly cut up.
(alarm sounds)
Quickly, everybody inside. Downstairs.
In the underground.
Careful, don't tip that stretcher.
- What's happened?
- Don't get excited. It's air-raid practice.
Lie down. Be quiet, young man.
You know you're in a very serious condition.
(alarm sounds)
Hey!
Miss Brown? Hurry, girls. Miss Brown,
you drivers are responsible for the blankets.
When inspection closes,
return them to the ambulances.
Yes, Lady Fitzhugh.
Yes, very good, very good indeed.
Thank you both very much. Thank you.
Oh, yes, that's very good. Yes, goodbye.
This bandage is far too tight
and needs a splint.
Loosen it, and be sure you keep
your patient well covered.
Yes, very good indeed.
Yes, thank you, goodbye.
Miss Cross! I'm completely mystified.
This man's bandage?
And the nature of his injury? Really!
Thank you, gentlemen.
(Cockney accent)
I say, miss. Can't you help me?
(gasps)
- Tim!
- Hello, honey.
- You worm.
- How was that for a fractured jaw?
I didn't expect to see you here.
Or anywhere, if I could help it.
That kiss says differently. Besides,
nobody could hold a grudge for a year.
- I can.
- I'm the one who ought to be sore.
I come home to Dallas, find you gone,
and as for that nasty note...
I'd have rigged up a shotgun
pointing at the door, if I'd had any string.
How can you say that? Could I help it if I ran
into a snowstorm and had to make a detour?
I know all about that "detour".
Her name was Irene.
So that's what you thought. I knew I could
clear it up if I could see you and explain.
That's the best thing you do. Explain.
Don't bother. I'm not interested.
As far as you and I are concerned, it's over.
You understand? Finished, done. Now scat.
That's a fine way to treat a guy who just flew
all the way across the Atlantic to see you.
You flew the Atlantic?
I heard you were in England.
Nothing could keep me away.
- I don't believe you.
- But it's true, honey, so help me.
I've changed. You'll be surprised.
- You'll never surprise me again.
- Hey, wait a minute.
I'm not gonna take that for an answer
after flying 3,000 miles to be with you.
Oh, stop it. I've got work to do.
Oh, my, you make an awful cute soldier.
Great idea, enlisting the chorus.
Funny nobody thought of it before.
I'm not in the chorus. And it's not funny,
my trying to help out. At night, I dance at...
- Where?
- Never mind where. And keep away from me.
There you go again.
Still talking about the old Baker.
The new Baker's a pretty steady model. What
harm could there be in giving me a tryout?
I tell you what I'll do.
I'll stay in London. They need fliers.
They need fliers in the RAF.
But that's hardly in your line.
If I remember correctly, you black out
at less than a thousand a month.
Why don't you give me credit? I have ideals.
I have as many ideals as the next fellow.
You've got the wrong word. You're talking
about ideas, and yours isn't going to work.
- Aw, honey, don't be that way.
- (sighs)
- I haven't looked at another girl.
- Well, I've looked at other men.
Maybe, but not in the same way you looked
at me that first night in Kansas City.
Remember?
You were going east, I was going west. Then
we saw each other and I was going east too.
That old spark's still there.
Sure, we've been off-course a few times,
but we can get back on again. Why fight it?
Young man, what are you trying to do?
I'm trying to kiss her.
Apparently, the seriousness
of our work has escaped you.
I'm sorry, Lady Fitzhugh.
You really should be ashamed
of yourself, young man.
What time do you go off duty, m'lady?
I... Really!
(lively swing music)
I'm sorry, sir. This table is reserved.
- For whom?
- Lord Delby, sir.
Oh. His Lordship prefers
something less conspicuous.
You might give him the table
you were going to give me.
(d "Hiya, Love")
- Frightfully good, isn't she?
- Yeah. Frightfully.
Would you like me to introduce you?
Awfully decent of you, old chap,
but I already know her.
Oh.
Then would you mind introducing me?
- What are your intentions?
- Nothing good, I'm afraid.
Then you can see how impossible it is
for me to do anything for you.
Absolutely. Would you like a drink?
No, thank you, I'm on my way to call for her.
I envy you. If there's a lull
in the conversation,
you might put in a good word
for Flying Officer Roger Pillby.
If there's a lull in the conversation,
it'll be no time for recommendations.
Thank you.
- Darling.
- How are you?
- Carl, dear, I'd like you to meet Miss Jones.
- Oh, how do you do?
Miss Lynn, may I present Captain Dearing?
- Miss Jones, Captain Dearing.
- How do you do?
I, uh... I beg your pardon.
Has Miss Brown come out yet?
Well, uh, she must've left some time ago.
Oh.
Uh, just a minute.
- What are your plans?
- I had a tentative engagement, but...
- Something both of us could do?
- I don't mind.
(door opens)
OK. We'll do it in a fortnight.
(sighs)
- What are you doing here?
- Waiting to take you to supper.
I mean in that uniform.
Oh, I'm just breaking it in
for a friend. Come on.
Didn't I make it clear I don't want
anything more to do with you?
You don't have to have anything
to do with me in a restaurant.
We'll just eat, tip the waiter
and go our separate ways.
- How'd you find out where I was working?
- I've a friend in the Ministry of Information.
All right. Only cos I wanna know how you got
that uniform. We'll keep the table between us.
A splendid idea. We'll have the waiter
put food on it, too, huh?
An interesting supper. Every time I moved my
chair closer to yours, you moved yours away.
We must've looked like a merry-go-round.
You still haven't told me
what you're doing in that uniform.
Well, that ought to be perfectly clear.
I want to go where you go,
do what you do and be where you be.
Come on, warm up. We're in the same army.
That ought to make it official.
Driver, right here.
- Tim, you needn't bother to get out.
- I'll just see you to your door.
- That's all, cabby. Cheerio.
- Thank you, guv'nor.
- Good night.
- I said I'll see you to your door.
There's no harm in that, is there?
You said you wanted to say goodbye like a
gentleman. This is your chance. Goodbye.
Hadn't I better come in and open a window?
Or, if the windows are open, turn on the heat?
You've been turning it on all evening,
but it's not going to do you any good.
I give up. Here I am,
acting like a gentleman - the perfect escort.
Thoughtful, considerate...
Oh, gee, but you're beautiful.
Goodbye, honey.
Oh, Tim.
You worm.
(crash)
- What the...
- Why don't you look where you're...
l-I'm awfully sorry.
All right, go ahead.
- It was definitely our fault.
- Oh, no, no, I'm sure it was mine.
We shouldn't have backed out
without warning you.
- That's kind...
- I trust you're not shaken up.
Oh, no, not at all. I hope I haven't
done you any damage either.
- Of course not. We're perfectly all right.
- Oh, well, thank you.
We must be going.
All right, get in.
Run along without me.
I just remembered I must see Richardson.
- An excellent idea. Wish I'd remembered too.
- Give him our love. (laughs)
Well, this is a surprise.
Did I forget my dinner pail?
No, I'm here on official business
for Lady Fitzhugh.
Well? Which one's yours?
Oh, stop kidding. These are
Lockheed Hudsons. Bombers.
Where are all those cute little Spitfires?
That's what I've been trying to find out.
Can you imagine?
They put me in school. Me!
Operational training. Teaching me
to fly under wartime conditions.
I've forgotten more about an airplane
than they'll ever know.
Didn't you tell them about all the experience
you'd had testing and flying the mail?
- Sure, it's no secret.
- Well, what'd they say?
They were very polite about it.
They said that with all my experience,
I wouldn't have any difficulty catching on.
Meanwhile I suppose I won't see you at all.
Of course you will. I'll pick you up tonight
after the show, backstage.
Now I'm a schoolboy, I need somebody
to help with my homework.
I can't wait.
I better go. I don't want to be tardy.
I'm going to a lecture. Bye.
Goodbye. And don't be
too difficult with teacher.
This Messerschmitt 109 was shot down last
week. Before I show you its vulnerabilities,
I have here a report made by the pilot
of the Spitfire which brought it down.
It seems that he was at 30,000 feet...
Mr Baker. If I were you,
I'd listen rather carefully to this.
You might want some information
on a 109 in a hurry one day.
Yes, sir. That's all right, go ahead.
I'm listening.
(engine churns but does not start)
It'll start better with this in place.
- What's that?
- The rotor off your distributor.
- Oh, did it fall off?
- No, I took it off. You know the regulation?
I know there's one about taking something
off your car so parachutists can't drive it,
but I never knew what it was
you were supposed to take off.
This is it. You just lift it out. I did it for you
so the police wouldn't catch you.
- That's very nice of you.
- If anyone catches you, I want to be the one.
- Do you catch many this way?
- I never tried before.
- Really?
- In fact, I never thought about it before.
You couldn't have done better
if you'd spent hours working it out.
You suppose you could put it back as easily?
If you insist.
Maybe I'd better watch
so I can do it myself next time.
If you ever lose it, apply to
the nearest German parachutist.
They undoubtedly carry duplicates.
- They're quite thorough, you know.
- So I've heard.
- I'm afraid I've botched this.
- How far did you expect to get on one rotor?
- I hoped to learn your name.
- Why? I don't know yours.
- I'm John Morley.
- How do you do, Mr Morley? Goodbye.
Goodbye, licence BHX 528.
Friend of yours, Morley?
My cousin, sir, from Glasgow.
She's going to spend a few days in London.
When your cousin spends
a few days in London,
does she usually dance and sing with eight
beautiful girls at the Regency House?
You don't say, sir. I'm afraid
my aunt will be terribly upset.
(laughs)
Very sorry, sir, but they're all reserved.
I can give you something not too far back.
That won't do, Louis. I want to get
a close look at the chorus.
That's what everybody wants, sir,
There must be something you can do.
This is an important occasion.
There is a flying officer
at one of our best tables.
- And I'm a squadron leader.
- So you are, sir. This way, please.
Sir, there is a mistake in the reservations.
Would you let me find you another table?
Definitely not.
Excuse me, sir, but I'm sure the squadron
leader will consider it a personal favour.
It's rather important to me.
I'm afraid you can't use your rank to exert
pressure. I'm not ambitious in a military way.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- But if you share my table, I've no objection.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, sir. And thank you too, sir.
(d "Another Little Dream
Won"t Do Us Any Harm")
- Good, isn't she?
- Very good.
- The singer, I mean.
- So do I.
Really? Would you like me
to introduce you, sir?
- Thank you, but I already know her.
- You do?
How is it everybody knows her but me?
Would you like to introduce me?
No. Anyone who creates
competition for himself is an ass.
- I agree, but I thought I'd try.
- Thanks for the use of your table.
- You're going to meet her now?
- Yes.
If opportunity knocks, shove in
a good word for Roger Pillby.
If opportunity knocks, I'll be speechless.
Thank you.
(both whisper)
- Hello there.
- Hello.
I hate to seem persistent.
- Well, let's face facts. You are.
- Yes, so I am.
Now we've run into each other,
we can have supper.
Oh, I'd like to very much, but...
I'm afraid my husband wouldn't like it.
Your... Oh, really? You're married?
That's the way one usually gets a husband.
It's rather stupid of me. I suppose I should've
considered that possibility, but I didn't.
He wouldn't like me
dismantling your distributor.
No, I'm afraid he wouldn't.
There's nothing wrong with what I did.
That car's as good as ever.
Better, now I know its innermost secrets. Bye.
- May I see you home?
- Uh, no.
No, thank you,
my husband will be along directly.
I see I've made a botch of this all over again.
But I've enjoyed meeting
you once more. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- However,
on second thought, since your husband
isn't here yet, I may as well have a cigarette.
I wish you wouldn't.
He might misunderstand.
Oh, I don't see how he could. I'd rather
imagine he'd think the joke was on me.
- Will you have a cigarette?
- No, no, thank you.
- Do you mind if I do?
- Hm? Oh, no.
Perhaps I will have one.
He, uh... he might have fallen asleep.
Quite.
- He works days.
- Really?
- I'm afraid something's detained him.
- Possibly.
- Perhaps I had better run along.
- I'd be delighted to drive you.
- No, that won't be necessary.
- Not necessary, but very pleasant.
(siren)
(man) Air raid. Take cover,
everybody, the alert is sounded.
Take cover. Take cover, please. Air raid.
- The alert's sounded, sir. Take cover.
- Thank you.
Not at all, sir.
Air raid. Take cover.
The alert is sounded. Please take cover.
Shall we go in that church?
It looks quite unperturbed.
All right.
From what I read in the papers,
a church is the one thing they never miss.
A few others seem to have had the same idea.
There's lots of room in front,
among the sinners.
Shall we sit here? I knew that old boy.
He was quite a stickler.
Went to his grave convinced
the Lord made only two kinds of people -
his kind, and the rest of the world.
If he were here tonight,
he wouldn't approve of all this.
- I take it this is a fashionable church.
- Indisputably.
Some of our very best people
have been married here.
- By the way, were you married in a church?
- No.
- Judge's chambers?
Registry office?
Why all this sudden interest
in my vital statistics?
You may as well know, Miss Brown,
I'm vitally interested.
- You may as well know I'm not married.
- You don't say.
- I only told you that to discourage you.
- Well, it worked perfectly. I was discouraged.
Then you might as well also know
I think you're very attractive.
- Ah.
- But a little late.
I see. There's someone else.
But there must be some hope.
You say I'm attractive. You aren't married.
Unless your wedding's arranged within
the next half-hour, I have a sporting chance.
You must be terribly in love with him.
- Insane.
- I wonder if he knows how lucky he is.
- I... I think so.
- (siren)
- There's the all clear.
- Then I must go.
Of course, they... they may come back.
General feeling seems to be that they won't.
Dull fellows. No feeling
whatever for romance.
Good night.
Shall we say the Ivy,
about one on Thursday?
- What for?
- Lunch.
- There's no purpose in it.
- There's no harm in it either.
All right. The Ivy at one. Good night.
I hope you believe me when I tell you this is
the first air raid I've ever actually enjoyed.
No doubt the spiritual effect of the church.
Good night, Miss Brown.
Oh, hello.
- It's almost two. I'm due back at school.
- I hope I didn't upset your plans.
No, no, it was my fault.
I'm sorry I stood you up.
It's quite all right. How was kindergarten?
Jolly. Some jerk gave us
a lecture on fundamentals.
Over and over again, the same things.
I nearly went nuts.
So I came here to take a nap
rather than going to the Regency House.
- It really doesn't matter.
- Now, don't be like that.
- At least I wasn't out with anybody else.
- Really?
I was. He was very charming.
If I'd known you were here,
I'd have asked him in.
Oh, so that's it, hm?
Trying to make me burn.
Not at all. Just bringing you up to date.
I'm having lunch with him Thursday.
Say.
I believe you were out with somebody else.
I know, honey. I'm a worm.
Gentlemen, you've completed your training
and you're now ready for active service.
And you've got a pretty tough job
in front of you.
But I want to thank you all
for the keenness you've shown
that has helped make my job
such an easy one.
Your appointments will be posted on the
notice board. Congratulations and good luck.
Come in.
- Yes?
- Pilot Officer Baker, sir.
- Oh, the American.
- I've been assigned to your flight, sir.
That's right. I'm glad to have you, Baker.
Take a seat.
Thank you.
I've just been going over your record.
It's excellent.
If it's so good, why wasn't I
assigned to a fighter squadron?
Each man in the RAF is assigned to where
he's most needed and is best qualified to fit.
I think you'll find a bomber has its points.
Perhaps, for those who like
that sort of thing, sir.
But frankly, grousing along over the Ruhr
in a bomber isn't my idea of excitement.
Aren't you labouring under
a slight misapprehension, Baker?
Flying a fighter in a scramble is one thing.
You can go up and get it over with.
It's something else to be five hours
in a bomber, making a target of yourself.
Maybe, sir. But I'm not, as they say,
constitutionally suited to it.
I'm the nervous type. I don't like
to brood over anything for five hours.
We'll try to see you get enough action
in this squadron to keep you happy.
Oh, come in, Wales.
This is Pilot Officer Baker, just posted
to our squadron. Flying Officer Wales.
- How do you do?
- I'm sure you'll find itjolly here.
- Yeah. Jolly.
Come along. I want you to meet the others.
Gentlemen.
This is Pilot Officer Baker,
our new squadron member.
- Flight Officer Starling-Richardson.
- How are you, Baker?
- Flying Officer Graves.
- How do you do?
- Pilot Officer Thorndyke.
- Baker.
And Flying Officer Watson.
- (Tim) How do you do, Watson?
- Hello, Baker.
- And Flying Officer Pillby.
- Oh, hello.
- How do you do?
- I know you.
- You wouldn't introduce me to Carol Brown.
- Sure, I remember. How are you?
This is remarkable.
Morley wouldn't introduce me to her either.
All the men who wouldn't introduce me
in one room.
Seems we have more
in common that I thought, sir.
- Apparently.
- Have you known her long?
- Not very.
- I haven't seen much of her lately.
Been confined with that operational
training they hand you over here.
- How is she?
- Oh, splendid.
Perhaps you'd like to see the place?
This is the Blue Room.
And over here is the Hall of Mirrors,
where we hold all our soirees.
Let me see, Baker. B-A-K-E-R.
Yes, that'll fit in just nicely.
I do the carving myself.
Rather neat, don't you think?
(phone rings)
I'll take it.
Yes?
Yes, sir.
- We're wanted in the Operations Room.
- Let's go.
I haven't had a chance to add Wilson's name
yet. He's the lad you're replacing, you know.
And your objective tonight is Berlin.
Men, you've received your operations orders.
In addition, I want reconnaissance reports.
Observe particularly landmarks, lights,
and concentrations of troops and equipment
that are not indicated.
Each aircraft will carry 200,000 leaflets
to be scattered thoroughly over the city.
Leaflets?
Yes, Baker. Leaflets.
Any further questions, gentlemen?
Zero hour, 1800 hours.
Synchronise your watches, gentlemen.
It will be exactly 15.32... now.
- Good luck.
- Thank you, sir.
No.
I'm not in a war.
I'm back carrying the mail.
- Can I help you, sir?
- No, thank you.
But see if there's anything
you can do for Mr Baker.
- Mr Baker, sir?
- Yeah, that's me.
Bomb aimer, navigator,
second cook and bottle washer.
I'm like the friend who went along
on the honeymoon just for the ride.
This is a coincidence, you might say,
seeing as how my name is Baker too.
Harry Baker. I wonder if we could be related.
- Could be. Do you spell it with a B?
- Oh, yes, sir.
B-A-K-E-R. Baker.
- Take over for a while, Baker.
- Yes, sir.
We're nearing our objective. I'll take over.
Corporal?
Stand by.
- Those guys aren't kidding, even if we are.
- Go aft and give Corporal Baker a hand.
Yes, sir.
Oh, no, no, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
That's not the way to do it.
You do it like this.
Sir, we're supposed to open
them up so they can read 'em.
Well, I think they'll make
more of an impression this way.
You just pass them to me
and I'll make the deliveries.
D I been workin' on the railroad
d All the livelong day
d I been workin' on the railroad
d Just to pass the time away
d Can't you hear that whistle blowin'...
Whoo-whoo!
D So early in the morn?
D I been...
d I've been labouring on the railway
d All the bloody afternoon
- That's all right. That's all. Close it up.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, wait a minute.
No, no, no, sir.
That was only supposed
to be used in case of fire, sir.
- Close it up.
- Yes, sir.
(phone ringing)
All right, all right,
I'm hurrying as fast as I can.
(knocking on door)
Just a minute, Tim.
Hello?
Hello, Tim. Just a minute, just a minute.
Just a moment, please.
Hello?
Listen, honey, I'm afraid
I'm gonna be a little late.
We got held up by a traffic light in Berlin.
I had to have a few hours sleep
so I could look my best. Do you mind?
No, no, of course I don't mind.
How long will you be?
45 minutes on the dot. OK?
Of course it's OK.
Attagal.
But don't be late, Tim. Bye.
Oh! Oh, goodness.
- Hello. I hope I'm not interrupting anything.
- You caught me in the shower, that's all.
Well, give me a minute.
Count three, then come on in.
Righto.
One, two, three. Here I come.
I was only 30 streets away
so I decided to drop in.
- I'll be out in a minute.
- I knew you had no show today,
and as I have 48 hours' leave, I hoped you'd
drive to my father's place in Kent with me.
Sorry, I would have loved it,
but I already have a date.
Nothing you could ignore?
I'm afraid not.
Sometimes, being rude at the right moment
makes a social career.
- Or wrecks one.
- Well, there's something to that.
You've completely ruined my weekend.
- Can't you go anyway?
- No.
I hope you'll forgive the way I look,
but I was trying to hurry.
Beautiful.
There's nothing for it but to go to the club
and grumble about staying in London.
- I'll be getting along.
- Oh, you needn't hurry.
Why should I tantalise myself?
It's much better to make it
a quick, clean wound and go.
But I'll try again next week... earlier.
- Goodbye.
- You're sure you won't...
- Mm-mm.
You've no idea how lovely it can be
in Kent at this time of year.
Then I expect it is goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- (knock on door)
- Come in.
- Hello, old boy.
- Hello, Roger.
- Where are you bound for?
- London.
- To meet her?
- Rather.
I'm going to London too.
Is there any possibility...
Not the slightest, old boy.
Your esprit de corps
is practically nonexistent.
How does a fella get to London in a hurry?
Fellows who haven't got cars
walk to the village and get a train.
The journey takes approximately three hours.
That's just dandy.
I told her I'd be there in 45 minutes.
Then you'll be exactly two hours and
15 minutes late, if the train's on time.
- Well, come on, let's hurry.
- I'm not taking the train. I've a car. Cheerio.
Oh boy, a car!
That's what I call a break, you having a car.
No. It won't do you a bit of good
dropping all those hints around, old man.
If you won't share your female with me, then
I certainly won't share my Austin with you.
Oh... Now, look here.
There's nothing I'd rather do
than introduce you to Miss Brown.
Then I'd be delighted
to drive you to town. Get in.
Thank you. I'm in.
Hey, Al! Al Bennett!
Tim! Hey, Tim!
Stop, Roger. That's Al Bennett, a friend of
mine from America. I want you to meet him.
Come on, back up.
- Hello, Al.
- Tim! How are you?
- What are you doing in England?
- Ferry service.
- At the moment I'm looking for the beam.
- They've another name for it here.
- What are you doing?
- I inherited a dukedom.
A provision of the will was that I join the RAF.
Roger Pillby, Al Bennett.
- How do you do?
- Swell.
- We oughta preserve this reunion in alcohol.
- It's no coincidence you're outside a saloon.
- They call it "pub" over here.
- Oh. Come on, Roger.
I'd like to some other time,
but we've got an engagement in town.
It'll only take a minute.
We'll still beat that train.
- When did you get in, Al?
- Yesterday. Pushed up a new record.
- Eight hours and 12 minutes.
- Eight hours and... Say, that tops my time.
Look at that. That's a lot of hot air.
They'll never try that again.
- Hello, sister.
- Good evening, gentlemen.
- Three Bass beers.
- Yes, sir.
Bitter for me, miss.
When you ask for whisky, you get Scotch.
And when you ask for ice,
you get hot water.
- How's it going?
- Still flying them across. Three a month.
I'd be a wealthy man
if my wife wasn't attaching my salary.
- Yeah, that's good dough.
- How much do you get?
- Me? They pay me off in stamps.
- I don't savvy.
- One and elevenpence, please, sir.
- Righto.
- Shall we say to Miss Brown?
- Brown? Carol Brown? Is she over here?
- You know her too?
- Sure. I knew her when Tim knew her.
Everybody in the world knows her but me.
But this is my day. I mean night. Tonight,
at last, Miss Brown and I will find each other.
- Wait a minute. You're only meeting her.
- I know, but the war being what it is, old boy,
if there should be any sudden sadness,
she'll have me to cry on.
- She might even receive the Pillby ring.
- What's that, a telephone number?
It's a gold ring in frightful taste,
worth absolutely nothing,
but the family tradition is that
it must always go to the right woman.
- How do you know?
- I never carry it with me. I don't trust myself.
But it might be in the cards
that Miss Brown gets it.
That is, of course, if you cooperate
and don't get silly ideas about living forever.
- Three more.
- No, really.
He's ordered them.
We might as well drink them.
- What's happened to all the boys?
- Still ferrying. All but Heck Newman.
- He crack up?
- No, he got food poisoning at a picnic.
Did you hear Slip Mason's here? He married
a dame with a title and a lot of money.
- Slip?
- Yeah.
Gee, I'd like to see him. Slip flew
upside down from St Louis to New York.
- You know what the time is?
- I'm on my way there.
- You two can drop me.
- No, thanks. Really.
- I'd like to, but I've got to get to London.
- It's right on the way.
You can just run in and run out.
Slip would be glad to see you.
Well, OK, butjust for a minute.
We can still beat that train.
- That's what the hare said to the tortoise.
- Oh, is Hare over here too?
Here we are.
- You're sure this is it?
- I swear it.
- Will it be all right for me to come up?
- Sure.
Here it is, 4am and you said it would take
a minute and that he lived on the way.
Slip lives nearer Glasgow than London.
We couldn't refuse Slip
when he asked us to dinner.
It wasn't dinner. It was telling
the life story of every pilot in America.
I didn't know America had as many pilots.
I thought you were unprepared.
- Is this the...
- Shh.
Shh!
Yoo-hoo. Honey?
- Carol!
- Shh. She's gone to bed.
- But we had a date. Why should she?
- Perhaps she was sleepy.
- I'll wake her up.
- Tell her not to go to any trouble for me.
- She's not home.
- Well, she must be.
How do you like that?
Just because we're a little late.
All that hurry for nothing.
She couldn't have misunderstood me.
I talked to her on the phone.
She knew we had a date.
Perhaps she's on an errand.
Pardon me. Will you have a drink?
- You gonna have one?
- I am.
I wouldn't think of letting you
drink alone, old boy.
I can't believe that she'd just walk out.
There's usually a simple explanation
everyone laughs at once it's out.
But this isn't like her.
She's so dependable.
- Is she the coy type?
- What do you mean?
- Hiding under the bed.
- No. Nobody could get under her bed.
Everything's so lovely down here.
You'd never believe there's a war on.
I wouldn't be too sure. Dad and his home
guard might pop out of a bush any moment.
- Parachutists, you know.
- (car horn)
Shall we take the short cut back?
It's likely to prove the longest way.
By all means.
I wonder if you can possibly realise
what all this has meant to me -
staying in that house that looks as if
it's been there forever.
It has. The part you were in
last night's the new part. It was built in 1748.
The other wing dates back to the Norman
Conquest. But nobody's been in it for years.
- Maybe it's still full of Normans.
- That's always been one of my pet theories.
And to think, back home I lived in
the oldest house in town. It was 32 years old.
- I'll wager the plumbing was better.
- It didn't have plumbing. It was in Oklahoma.
- You must have been through a great deal.
- You don't know anything.
We moved to Kansas and had a lovely house
with hot and cold water and steam heat.
And along came a big wind
and blew the roof off.
And there you were, out in the cold again.
Of course, I'm giving you
a one-sided picture of my life.
I once had a house in New Rochelle
and nothing happened at all.
It must have been a very wonderful house.
Somehow I prefer this one.
It's yours if you want it to be.
I mean that, Carol.
What is it people say? "This is so sudden"?
It would have been suddener if I'd asked
when I wanted to, in that church.
Marry me, Carol.
- I can't.
- Why not?
Oh, lots of reasons.
Hold this, will you?
What about your father?
Does he know that we've seen
each other exactly six times?
That I'm a dancer at the Regency House?
Yes. And I must admit he was
a little difficult about that.
Kept asking "Is she a good dancer?"
And that my family came from Oklahoma?
Of course, it might be better
to break Oklahoma to him by degrees.
Does that clear up everything?
No.
No, it doesn't.
It wouldn't be Baker, would it?
- How did you know?
- The best possible source - the man himself.
Well, that's it.
- Are you going to marry him?
- Oh, let's drop it.
(sighs)
I don't love him.
I don't know that I ever have or ever will.
But when I'm with him
I can't seem to remember that.
Once I didn't see him for a whole year
and I thought that...
When I did it was...
just the same.
I see.
You're the one I ought to love.
You're everything that Tim isn't.
Then you should marry me
at once, by all means.
- You still want me to?
- Of course.
Baker happened before you knew me.
That's merely poor timing on fate's part.
I couldn't.
When I'm not even sure of myself.
Well, it's about time.
What are you doing here?
- We had a date, didn't we?
- Yes. We had a date yesterday.
I know, honey. I'm sorry
about standing you up, but...
It's all right.
Here. Let me.
I'll get it.
I don't have an excuse either.
I just ran into Al Bennett.
We did some hangar flying
and I just lost track of the time.
That might happen to anybody.
Here, let me. I'll get that.
- These are pretty. Where'd you find them?
- In the country.
- You been to the country, huh?
- Mm-hm.
- Alone?
- No.
- Did you have a good time?
- Wonderful.
- Who'd you go with?
- A friend of mine.
Listen.
I know I'm a heel and I'm sorry.
Will you forgive me?
But there's nothing to forgive.
I've had a lovely time.
I just don't want you to feel hurt.
But I'm not hurt.
I guess I'd better be getting back.
Yes, I think you had. It's rather late.
- Goodbye, Carol.
- Goodbye.
I said I was sorry, didn't I? I crawled.
I apologised. When do I get relief?
But what have I said or done?
I'm not mad, really I'm not.
Stop needling me. Why don't you
bawl me out and get it over with?
But why should I bawl you out?
- I'm glad you didn't show up.
- Look here. What's this all about?
Nothing, except we're through.
Notjust again, but through for keeps.
Well.
- That must have been some weekend.
- It was.
He couldn't have spent all his time
picking flowers.
He didn't. He did something
that would never occur to you.
Something you couldn't even understand.
He asked me to marry him.
So that's what's bothering you.
Why didn't you say so? If you really
wanna get married, I'll marry you.
You mean you'd make
that great sacrifice just for me?
Sure. I'll marry you tonight if you say so.
That's awfully sweet of you, Tim.
Your proposal was beautiful.
Romantic.
Everything a girl could want it to be.
But for your personal and private
information, I'd rather marry a...
I'm very grateful, but I can't accept.
Now please go.
Get out!
And get that tramp friend of yours
out of my bed!
Did, er...
- Did somebody come in?
- No. Somebody went out.
- Not her?
- Yes, her.
Oh, dash it all. I muffed it again.
... sources of large-scale German troop
concentrations along the Dutch frontier.
Advices filtering in from the lowlands
appear to confirm the suspicion
- that some sudden military action...
- Hello.
- Have you fellows heard the news?
- Sure. I could have told you that months ago.
- Really?
- American cunning. Positively a genius for it.
All leave is cancelled and the flight
commander has orders for us to stand by.
You had better let him know you're back.
Maybe they're gonna let us drop
welcome mats on the Low Countries.
You look a little faded. Strenuous weekend?
If you must know I spent my whole leave
in a certain flat. If you must know.
(knock on door)
Come in.
Wales said you were worried about me, so I
rushed over to say the problem child's home.
Then I suggest you do what I'm doing.
Get into uniform.
- That's funny.
- What's funny?
We both seem to go in for
the same kind of flowers.
Yes, it is, rather.
As a matter of fact, we seem to
go in for a lot of the same things.
We have more in common
than we've realised.
Yeah, that may be,
but Carol's not one of them!
Sir, the CO wishes to speak with you
on the phone right away.
Thank you, Roger.
There's a flap on. We're wanted at Operations.
Better get changed.
Your objective tonight is the
marshalling yard at Dortmund.
There are heavy concentrations
of mechanised units and material.
Undoubtedly, you will encounter
heavy anti-aircraft opposition,
and for some of you this will be
the first time under fire.
But I see by your faces that
you're not averse to the idea.
That's all. The intelligence officer will
give you the latest details from his reports.
- Good luck.
- Thank you, sir.
Gentlemen, the advance of the enemy
has been far greater than was anticipated.
It appears that the flank of the Peel Line
has already been turned.
Your mission, therefore,
is of extreme importance.
Yes?
Six minutes on this course
to reach our objective.
Right. Corporal?
Stand by.
I'll try to get below this muck.
We'll make our run-up at 2,000 feet.
- Bomb doors open.
- Right.
Right.
Steady.
Go on.
Nice shooting, Baker.
What's the matter?
Pull her up. Climb out of these searchlights.
Considering that we're on one engine,
this aircraft is performing exceptionally well.
That chap's in trouble down there.
He'll never get out of those lights.
I'd better go down
and see if I can't turn one of them off.
Old boy, you've been in the spotlight
long enough. I'm coming to give you a hand.
Stay out of this, Roger. Stay out!
Job's completed. Return to base.
Too late, sir. I'm on my way down.
How bloody considerate of them to keep
those lights on. Never did like the dark.
Even as a child, used to complain bitterly.
Regular tantrums.
Refused to be put in a room
with the lights out. Never got over it.
Probably explains my passion
for nightclub life.
Take that, you dirty!
(engine spluttering)
Well, at last we're out of that.
Yes, but Roger isn't.
Bale out, boys, we're in a dead duck.
(Morley) Pillby! Pillby!
Pillby!
- Do you see him?
- Yes, in flames.
I heard him tell the crew
to bale out, but there wasn't time.
(engine spluttering)
(engine runs normally again)
(spluttering)
Stand by to bale out.
Go up, Baker, with the others,
and get ready to bale out.
We're at 2,000 feet. Bale out.
After you.
- Cheerio.
- So long, matey.
- Baker, bale out. We're losing height fast.
- Not me. I'd rather ride than walk any day.
I won't take a chance there's any ceiling.
All right, you bale out. I don't call it a chance
when I can see a perfectly good beach.
- What?
- Blimey! There's the seaside, right under us!
Sit down, Corporal.
- Jolly good show, Baker. Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- Where are we?
- Holland. That's a bloody windmill.
There's a stroke of luck,
coming down in a neutral country
when I was all ready to be concentrated
in a German concentration camp.
- Get out, Corporal.
- Yes, sir.
Stand clear, both of you.
I'll join you in a moment.
Look, everything but the tulips.
This is real luck. Boat, sea, and perhaps some
genial Dutchman to steer us to England.
Blimey! Look! What's them?
(shouting in German)
- Jerries.
- Jerries?
- What are they doing here in Holland?
- Head for that house, and keep down.
- Hurry, Corporal.
- Yes, sir.
(shouting in German)
Corporal, throw that blasted parachute away.
Stay down. Into the house. Hurry!
- What's this?
- A wireless. Somebody's just been here...
Hnde hoch!
- What's he say?
- Better put your hands up.
Vorwrts.
Move forward, or you're liable to get
shot in the back. They're noted for that.
Hier.
He says "turn around".
Wie kommt ihr hierher?
- What's he say now?
- He asked how we got here.
I'll tell him.
It's a tough break, squarehead.
There's a couple of other British planes
down on this beach. General Gort's in one.
Just what I thought.
He doesn't understand a word of English.
If we can keep him from letting the others
know, we can get to that boat and beat it.
You two make a break for it.
Leave him to me.
Oh, so that's it, huh? A hero to the last.
Well, get this - we all go or we all stay.
I'm still in command here.
When I jump him, you go.
Very interesting debate, gentlemen.
Unfortunately, you are not going anywhere.
Go on, sir, run for the boat!
(shouting in German)
There's nothing more we can do for him.
Come on.
Stand back. They're coming.
We must get to that boat. Come on.
Get back.
Make a break for it.
(gunshot)
Cast her off, sir.
Aw, come on, roll over. Get going, Maggie.
(gunshot)
Can't you get it started?
They're too close for comfort.
Well, I'm trying bloody hard, sir.
(engine starts)
Do you mind moving over
on the other side, sir?
Feuer!
(wheels rolling and footsteps)
Hey, Miss, come here.
- Where is this?
- It was the maternity ward.
The maternity ward?
What's the matter with me?
Nothing to worry about. Exposure, mostly.
Lie down. Open your mouth.
Put this under your tongue.
- How long have I been here?
- You've been asleep almost 40 hours.
Keep it under your tongue, please.
Say, you're kind of cute.
Here are your clothes.
Listen. What happened to that officer
that was brought in with me?
- Squadron Leader Morley?
- That's him.
He's all right.
He was discharged about an hour ago.
Orderly, this bed is available, ready
to change. Hurry and dress, please.
What's all the rush?
I heard the head lady say how they're
expecting a lot of new ones. Evacuees.
My, this is a handy little garment, isn't it?
(knock on door)
Tim...
- Are you all right?
- Oh, sure, sure. It's nothing at all.
Of course, I won't do much elbow-bending
with this broken wing for a while.
- Won't you come in?
- Oh, thanks.
Have you seen Morley?
No, but he telephoned me.
I'm meeting him at the Savoy for tea.
Mind if I sit down?
I'm still kind of shaky, you know.
Oh, I'm sorry, Tim. Here, sit over here
in this chair by the window.
Here, I'll take it.
- Would you like something under your foot?
- Yes, it might relieve the pressure a bit.
- Is that better?
- Yes, that's much better, thanks.
Morley said you were still
in the hospital when he left.
Do you think you should be
up and around so soon?
Oh, just seeing you is doing me a lot
more good than any hospital ever could.
You know, it's funny. When I woke up,
the first thing the nurse said to me was:
"You've been raving about a Carol.
Who is she, your wife?"
I don't know why, but I said yes. Maybe that's
because it's what I want more than anything.
We're not going into that again.
Oh, I can't say that I blame you,
after the way I've acted,
but I can't hurt someone I love so much.
- Tim, I've got to go now.
- No, wait a minute.
Look, maybe this'll convince you. I had this
for you the other day when you threw me out.
That's why I was so late for our date.
Now, I may be dumb, but I'm not that dumb.
You said you were with Al Bennett.
Sure, but I was just covering up
so that I could surprise you.
When I got to the store, the jeweller
had closed up. I had to track him home.
It's true, honey. Come on, put it on and we'II...
Oop, I dropped it.
Here, wait a minute, I'll get it.
Of all the contemptible, dirty,
low-down things you've ever done!
- Listen to me!
- Get out. Get out!
I love you. I wouldn't
go to this bother if I didn't.
(phone ringing)
Yes?
Hello. I'm sorry, I was held up.
I'll be ready in a minute.
No, no, Carol, don't. I can't meet you.
There's a flap on. All leaves are cancelled.
I've reported for duty.
I understand.
I'll be waiting.
Good luck, darling. Goodbye.
I know you're only a shattered hulk of a man,
but you'd better report for duty.
All leave is cancelled, and your CO won't be
taken in by a broken wing as easily as I was.
All right, I'll go. But not until
you wish me good luck, too.
- Good luck and goodbye.
- Now, you listen to me.
That guy can phone you every day.
You can call him "darling" all you want.
But it won't do you any good.
You're mine and you'll stay mine.
Let go of me, you're hurting.
- If I've got to knock...
- No, I won't. (gasps)
There you are, my bride.
And when I come back, I'll make it official.
Come back here and take this thing with you!
Don't cry, darling. Don't worry about me.
I'll be back. Nothing ever happens to me.
He would get the wrong size!
Hello, Falcon Leader.
Message acknowledged. Rearm, refuel.
Emergency landing ground five two.
Further orders follow. Over.
The Falcon Leader calling.
The message understood.
The message understood. Over.
32 Squadron returning, sir.
Three aircraft missing.
54 Squadron, six aircraft missing.
87 Squadron, four missing. 93 Squadron...
- Order replacements from the reserve pool.
- Quite so, quite so.
There's no time to rest. There's never been
a situation in history comparable to this.
325,000 men, the heart and core
of our army, are at Dunkirk,
being bombed and strafed every moment
by the enemy, who outnumber us four to one.
The navy has every vessel afloat
waiting to bring the men off.
The air force must see that they do it.
We must put every available man into action
to wrest control of the air.
That's 32 Squadron coming in to land now.
Yes. Yes, yes, definitely...
We engaged the enemy just south
of Dunkirk, sir. About 12,000 feet.
One formation, 20 Heinkels,
18 Messerschmitts about 3,000 feet above.
We used number three attack. We got
five Heinkel and three Messerschmitt.
Good. We're holding them,
in spite of their numbers?
- I think so, sir.
- How did you get on, Walker?
I got a four-second burst at a Heinkel at 200
yards, sir. He went out of control in flames.
- Then I attacked two Messerschmitts.
- These might be our replacements now.
Johnson shot down two Heinkels then lost
control. I watched him land in the water.
There was a launch.
I expect he was picked up.
Get some coffee while you're being refuelled.
Pilot Officer Carson, sir,
from the reserve pool.
- Pilot Officer Baker, sir.
- Sergeant Johnson, sir.
Good. Report to 32 Squadron.
I expect you'll have just about time for a spot
of coffee with the others before getting away.
Yes, sir.
- What's it really like over there?
- Cloudy.
32 Squadron. 32 Squadron.
Report for takeoff at once.
If you get through, tell them
the enemy has our position.
Enemy aircraft are bombing and strafing our
embarkation point. We need aircraft help.
Look, sir, they're coming over the Channel!
Spitfires! Spitfires! Spitfires!
All right, chaps. All set?
Kern. All set, sir.
Benson. All set, sir.
McKay. All set, sir.
O'Brien. All set, sir.
Baker. All set, sir.
- Tally-ho!
- Tally-ho! I'm with you, Johnny.
That's for Roger.
That's for the corporal.
This one's just for me.
(band plays "Hiya, Love")
Yes?
Just a minute. Yes?
Call me back at this number
if you hear anything.
- Any word at all?
- He's still missing.
They just brought in one of his squadron,
O'Brien, who baled out south of Dunkirk.
He saw Tim shoot down two MEs
and then get a burst himself.
O'Brien thinks he might have baled out. I've
checked every place I can. You'll have to wait.
If Tim baled out, he'll get back.
I know it. I'm sure of it!
Why, he's had a hundred forced landings.
Once he was lost in a snowstorm
for a whole week.
Everybody said he couldn't be alive.
They gave up the search.
Then one day he was brought into town
on a sled by a couple of Indian squaws.
Another time, at the state fair,
he was skywriting.
All of a sudden, the motor fell out
of his plane. People screamed.
He made a perfect landing
right in front of the governor's grandstand.
Why, nothing ever happens to Tim.
He has luck.
He certainly has. And that isn't all he has.
From the first, I was afraid
I couldn't shake you free of him.
Hello? Yes, speaking.
Thank you. Goodbye.
In half an hour they'll be bringing in
another boatload. It'll be the last of them.
Wait for me outside.
I'll be dressed in a minute.
(man) Oh, Peter! Peter!
Dad! Dad!
- My boy! Are you all right?
- I'm all right.
Good.
- Did we miss him?
- They just started coming off.
- Then where could he be?
- Carol, there are 1,000 men on this boat.
- We could have missed him.
- But you said we saw the first of them.
It's easy to overlook someone
in a crowd like this.
Stay near this gangplank.
I'll go nearer the other one.
All right.
Tim!
Tim! Tim!
- Tim...
- (mouths)
Oh!
Darling, are you hurt?
This? Oh, this is just a new fad collar
I picked up on the other side of the Channel.
Oh, Tim, I knew nothing
would happen to you.
Sure you did. I told you, didn't I?
Oh, it's so good
to hold you in my arms again.
All the time I was floating in the Channel,
I was thinking of you.
Look. Look, Tim.
I couldn't get it off.
Congratulations, Baker.
Getting through and all that.
- Thank you, sir.
- Mr Baker?
Our car is ready.
I won't need it. Some friends have met me
unexpectedly. Thank you for all your trouble.
You won't forget Thursday?
Oh, no, no. I'll change the bandage.
And thank you for your blanket.
Goodbye.
- Tim?
- I know, honey.
I'm a worm.