- [Taps]
- [Morse Code Beeping]
## [Instrumental Fanfare]
[Chattering In Aboriginal Language]
[Boy Narrating]
My grandfather, King George-
he take'em me walkabout...
teach me blackfella way.
Grandfather teach'em me
most important lesson of all.
Tell'em story.
[Aboriginal Language Continues]
That day I down the billabong.
King George-he teach me how
to catch'em fish using magic song.
## [Sings]
See, I not blackfella.
I not white fella either.
Them white fellas call me mixed-blood...
- half-caste-
- Yea!
- creamy.
- [Men Shouting]
- Hyah!
- I belong no one.
- [Man Whistling]
- That day I see'em them white fellas.
They were pushing
them cheeky bulls across the river...
onto Carney land.
[Speaking Aboriginal Language]
King George angry at them white fellas.
King George say
them white fella bad spirit.
Must be taken from this land.
[Whinnies]
[Blowing]
Shh.
[Blowing Softly]
[Blusters]
[Whinnies]
[Horse Blusters]
Coppers.
[Boy Narrating]
Them coppers come take me away.
They want to put me
on that Mission Island.
[Whinnies]
- Make me into a white fella.
- [Aboriginal Language]
But they're not coppers.
- Whoa there. Whoa. Whoa.
- [Whinnies]
[Narrating]
And that first time I saw her-
that Mrs. Boss.
The strangest woman I ever seen.
She's not from this land.
This land my people
got many names for...
but white fellas call it...
Australia.
But this story not begin that day.
This story begin a little while ago
in a land far, far away.
That land called England.
My husband must sell Faraway Downs.
But the offer from
this "Cattle King,"Mr. Carney...
is only one-sixth
of what it was once worth.
We need the money, Ramsden.
But Maitland
is just about to muster the fats.
What?
Get the-the big cows ready for market.
Ramsden, you and I both know...
there is only one reason my husband
has spent so much time down under...
and it has absolutely nothing
to do with cows.
At least not of the animal variety.
Lady Ashley,
I-I do think that's a bit harsh.
- Oh, Ramsden, drink your tea.
- Lady Ashley!
What do you intend to do?
I intend to travel
to this cattle station...
sell it...
and bring Maitland home myself!
But, Lady Ashley, it's Australia.
[Maitland]
Darling Sarah, I implore you, do not travel.
Outbreak of war imminent. Stop.
[Sarah] Maitland, your concern
regarding war duly noted. Stop.
[Maitland]
Have plan concerning cattle.
Sale to King Carney not necessary.
- Need more time. Stop.
- [Sarah] Nonsense. Stop.
Expect contract for sale of station
to be drawn by time of my arrival. Stop.
[Maitland]
Cannot meet you. Stop. Am mustering. Stop.
Have sent trusted man. Stop.
The Drover. Stop.
The Drover?
[Laughs]
Drover, you boong lover.
Any of you other Carney boys
want to have a go?
Come on, fellas.
Don't let fear stand in your way.
I'll have ya.
- [Aboriginal Language]
- Hey! No boongs in here!
- He's not in the pub, Ivan.
- [Aboriginal Language]
- [Horse Whinnies]
- [Man] Go on.
Run after your boong friend, 'cause as far
as this town's concerned, you are a black.
You work with them,
you eat with them...
and you sleep with them.
[Laughs]
Oh, crikey.
When you see her, wave your hat.
What are you waiting for, an invitation?
I hate coming to town.
[Man]
Lady Sarah Ashley.
A genuine aristocrat
living right here in Darwin.
Administrator, we're at war.
Oh.
- [Squawks]
- As the officer...
in charge of livestock purchases
for the armed forces-
- She's quite a looker.
- I fail to see...
what Lady Sarah Ashley...
has to do with Carney's stranglehold
of the beef industry.
Her husband, Lord Ashley...
claims he's mustering fats
at Faraway Downs.
- Faraway Downs?
- Faraway Downs.
The only cattle station
in the whole of the north...
not owned by Leslie "King" Carney.
- Lord Maitland Ashley
is mustering on Faraway Downs?
[Man] Yeah, yeah.
- Isn't quite what we had in mind, is it, Neil?
- No. Yeah.
And now his missus has arrived
on the flying boat.
Doesn't look like they're gonna sell
Faraway Downs to me, Neil.
Ah, she won't last.
A delicate English rose withers
in the outback. Hmm.
You with me?
If you must know, I am to be met-
[Yelps] by my husband's trusted man,
a Mr. Drover.
The bloody Drover?
[Both Grunting]
Bring it. Yes.
Move it.
Look at my wife and daughter down there
giving her the royal welcome.
My fiancé, Neil Fletcher,
manages Faraway Downs.
Good day.
A bit pale.
Not a bad-looking sheila,
but what's the story on the luggage?
Wants to settle down
in the outback, does she?
If she stays and Lord Ashley manages to
get his cattle down onto that wharfthere...
then we've got a competitor
for the army contract, Neil.
Carney's control of every
cattle station in the north...
jeopardizes the supply of beef
to our troops.
But it's a poor war that doesn't make
a decent patriot rich, so...
I don't want a single beast
from Faraway Downs...
to set a hoof on that wharf.
- You with me, Neil?
- Yeah, yeah. Nature will take its course.
[Shouts]
[Carney]
What about the missus?
No, I've arranged for someone special
to give her the old scenic route.
[Both Shouting]
Give her a taste of the outback.
- [Both Grunting]
- No!
- [Carney] Who's taking her?
- The Drover.
[Both Shouting]
The Drover?
Enjoy the ride, sweetheart.
[Gasps]
I'm Sarah Ashley.
[Engines Revving]
- [Shouting]
- My husband, Lord Ashley...
has sent a trusted man to collect me.
A, uh-A Mr. Drover.
It seems as if he has been waylaid.
No women.
Ladies' lounge next door.
The hen parlor's thataway, my dear.
No wonder your establishment is empty.
Good day.
Oh! Oh!
[Man]
You can take him!
[Screams]
- [Crowd Cheers]
- [Laughing]
No!
[Gasps]
[Grunting]
[Screams]
[Exhales]
[Panting]
[Aboriginal Language]
Oh! No, no!
No, not my bags. Not my-
Oh, no, no!
[Yelps]
[Sobs]
Here.
Welcome to Australia.
[Boy Narrating]
Drover take Mrs. Boss to Faraway Downs...
in a great, big, fancy truck.
He even let her sit in his special seat.
She even drinks
Drover's own water bottle.
[Drover]
That's it.
They get along like a burnin' house.
Now, Magarri-he sit'em up top.
And Magarri's cousin Goolajbaloong-
he come along for the ride.
- Oh!
- They make'em friends right away.
Water.
Oh.
That's it. That's it. Stay, Jedda. Stay.
[Chuckles]
"Trusted man."
Typical of my husband.
Actually, your husband's
a pretty good bloke.
Yes, well, he certainly knows
how to choose his employees.
- Employee?
- Mmm. No wonder the place is bankrupt.
- Lady, I'm not an employee.
- [Scoffs] Really?
So you're just driving me
all the way out to Faraway Downs...
- as a personal favor to my husband, are you?
- No.
Him being
such a good bloke and all, hmm?
I'm driving you out there because he
promised me a drove of 1,500 head of cattle.
- What, to buy?
- No, you goose. To drove.
[Gasps]
I'm a drover, right? I move
the cattle from "A" to "B."
All right? I work on commission.
No man hires me, no man fires me.
- Oh-
- Everything I own...
I can fit in my saddlebag,
which is the way I like it.
Oh! Yes, well, it's all-
all very "outback adventure," isn't it?
- I'm not saying it's for everyone.
- No.
Definitely not for everyone.
Most people like to own things.
You know, land, luggage, other people.
Makes them feel secure.
But all that can be taken away.
And in the end, the only thing
you really own is, uh-
is your story.
Just tryin' to live a good one.
Yes, yes. An adventure story.
Mmm. You sound just like my husband.
[Chuckles]
[Gasps]
Oh!
Oh, they're kangaroos!
- Big reds.
- Oh! Lovely.
- Beautiful.
- Oh, yeah, yeah. Beautiful.
[Sarah] I've never seen a kangaroo.
Beautiful, jumping.
- [Drover] Yeah, they're jumping.
- Oh!
Oh, it's beautiful.
- Uh-
- Oh! Look at them jumping!
- [Gunshot]
- [Screams]
Ah!
[Chuckles]
[Gasps]
[Whispers]
Mr. Drover.
Hey, Miss Boss.
Tucker, Mrs. Boss?
- Mr. Drover.
- Yeah?
- There's only one tent.
- That's right.
For the four of us?
Well, you know, it gets
pretty chilly here at night.
We, uh-We like to bunk up together,
eh, Magarri? Goolaj, huh?
Nice and close, you know.
[All Shuddering]
[Chuckles]
Oh!
Oh, come on, Lady Ashley.
We're just having a laugh.
Never really slept in a tent in our life.
We just bunk around the fire, you see?
- See, we're not really used to, um-
- A woman?
I suppose you think I should be
back in Darwin at the church fete...
or the ladies'. uh, whatever you call it.
Well, I will have you know
that I am as capable as any man.
Guests. We're not used to guests.
That's what I was about to say.
But now you mention it, I happen to
quite like the women of the outback.
But they're mostly native women.
Aboriginal women.
They're very easy to, uh-
[Clears Throat]
to get along with, if you try.
# Whoa, babe
something is bothering me #
[Aboriginal Language]
Go!
- Ho!
- Him always punctual.
[Groans]
- [Laughs]
- Get out of here!
- [Sarah] What's that?
- Your accountant.
[Woman] Hey, Drover!
He's your bloody problem now!
- See you, Drover!
- [Snoring]
[Whimpers]
Kippelly Flymm.
- Kippelly Flynn.
- I'm sorry. What was your name again?
Lipelling Klymm, mi- mila- milady.
Kipling Flynn.
Thanks.
[Sarah]
How long till we reach Faraway Downs?
[Drover] Oh, we've been on it
for the last two days.
- Drover! Hey, Drover!
- Yeah, love. How you doing?
Good. Aren't you gonna stop
and have a rest for a while?
Nah, gotta make a delivery.
Put the kettle on.
- I'll be round in a couple days. Give us a kiss.
- Okay.
See you soon.
- She's easy to get on with.
- Ah, she's trouble, that one.
- See you later!
- Bye!
You and my husband
share an interest.
An interest? Really?
Come on. We all know the real reason
that my husband is out here.
Oh. Right.
You mean the breeding. Yeah.
- [Gasps] Breeding?
- Yeah.
No, we're both dead keen on breeding.
I have this idea,
which, uh-which he loves.
You might be quite excited
about it too, actually.
Now, I'm a brumby man,
but his fancy English filly, Capricornia...
has really caught my eye.
I got to admit.
She is gorgeous. Really gorgeous.
Gorgeous creature.
I've always wanted to mate an English
thoroughbred with a bush brumby.
I mean, it'd be magic, wouldn't it?
Magic.
- Imagine that combination.
- Don't. Don't you say another word.
- I know what you're implying.
- You've thought about it, too, haven't you?
Capricornia-You- Poppycock!
- What are you talking about?
- Poppycock!
[Whinnies]
Coppers.
- What are you talking about?
- You-You want-
- You want to have it on with me.
- What? What was that?
Oh, you know exactly what I'm saying.
Just like you have it on with
that poor girl you're exploiting...
and-and-and God knows how many others.
What are you talking about?
- You got a filthy mind, lady.
- You're an animal!
I wouldn't have it on with you
if you were the only tart left in Australia.
- Animal! You are a-
- Believe me, I wouldn't-
You-
[Whinnies]
[Coughs]
Oh!
[Whinnies]
What was that?
- Stay in the car.
- No, no.
Get your hands off me.
For once in your life,
do as you're bloody told.
- [Aboriginal Language]
- [Whinnies]
[Flynn]
There she is.
Faraway Downs.
[Boy Narrating]
And that first time I saw her-
- that Mrs. Boss.
- Oh! Oh!
[Muttering]
[Mutters]
Lady Ashley, wait! Don't go in there!
[Woman Sobbing]
- [Sarah Gasps]
- [Man Speaking Chinese]
[Chinese]
I'm so sorry.
My family has had the honor of serving...
the owners of Faraway Downs
for three generations.
We know how hard this land can be.
But Lord Maitland Ashley-he-
he never gave up.
The only thing that could stop this decent
and courageous man was a spear...
from a murderous black,
the so-called King George.
And he will be brought to justice.
Let us now pray for Maitland Ashley...
that his soul may enter peacefully
through the gates of heaven.
## [Harmonica]
[Neil] Lady Ashley, we can leave for Darwin
first thing in the morning.
[Sarah]
Yes, yes. Certainly, Mr. Fletcher.
Watch the, um-
I can't understand what my husband
would have seen out here.
Yeah, this land has a strange power.
## [King George Singing
In Aboriginal Language]
## [Continues]
[Boy Narrating]
That first night, when the sun go to sleep...
King George tell me
this land be healed.
He tell'em me that woman-
that far, far away woman-
she be like the rain.
I've been thinking
I'm gonna sing her to me.
[Aboriginal Language]
- [Boy Narrating] Make the land sing.
- [Aboriginal Language]
[Chirps]
## [Boy Singing In Aboriginal Language]
## [Continues]
[Chirps]
## [King George Singing]
## [Continues]
- [Gasps]
- I let you see me now.
Who are you?
I Nullah.
How did you get in here?
I make myself invisible...
with gulapa magic!
## [Singing In Aboriginal Language]
## [Ends]
What do you want?
That balanda Fletcher
been curse to this place.
But you like Rainbow Serpent.
You mien-muk.
You heal this land, so I sing you to me.
Like I sing a fish to me.
## [Sings]
## [Continues]
I sing, too...
when Mama and Fletcher...
make wrong-side business.
Wrong-sided business?
You know.
Laying down and tickling.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Me and you secret.
Oh, my goodness. Mr. Fletcher?
I got to sing to Mama to warn her...
that Lord Boss Ashley is coming down.
Maitland? I- I-
I mean, Lord Ashley?
Yeah. He plenty funny.
So that's why I took him down the billabong,
shown him all the big, fat, cheeky bulls.
Come here. Look'em. Look.
Get pushed across that river...
over to Carney land.
The bulls.
"Billabong"?
That's where Maitland was killed.
- [Nullah] But, Mrs. Boss, that spear was-
- [Door Opens]
Please don't.
Don't make'em that policeman
take away my boy.
Them coppers. That bad Fletcher.
He say you see me,
you send me to the Mission Island.
To that lock-lock.
Throw away bloody key.
Please, missus! Quick!
I make us invisible.
[Gasps]
[Footsteps Departing]
[Man Whistles In Distance]
- [Rooster Crows]
- [Man Shouting In Distance]
[Shouting Continues]
- Mrs. Boss.
- Oh! Oh. It's you.
- Last night, I show you-
- [Hoofbeats Approaching]
Hyah!
- where-
- [Whinnies]
Yeah.
She's a beautiful day, isn't she?
How was your sleep? Restful?
I wouldn't say so, no.
Yeah, now, the boys are-
the boys are just finishing up.
Gotta tell you, they're a pretty sorry mob
of cattle. Seems hardly worth the effort.
Ready to go, Lady Ashley?
[Whispers]
Billabong.
Mr. Fletcher...
tell me about the big,
fat cows that cross the river...
down at the "billabalong,"
or whatever you call it.
Near the billabong?
No, that's Carney property over there.
Our cattle don't cross the river.
- Apparently they do.
- Yeah?
Who-Who says they do?
That little boy there.
[Gate Creaks]
[Chuckles]
Oh, you mean the little half-caste fella?
Hey. Hey, little fella. Come here.
Come and tell Mr. Fletcher
what you told me last night.
Yeah, come on, Nullah.
- [Sarah] Yes.
- They're funny ones.
[Aboriginal Language]
Now...
did you see big, fat cattle
crossing Marmont River?
Or were they just Carney cattle on
the other side of the river having a drink?
[Aboriginal Language]
Them just Carney cattle, Mr. Fletcher.
- I been lookin' myself.
- Yeah?
Ah, you tell great, big,
tall stories, don't ya, eh?
[Sarah] It's all right, Mr. Fletcher.
I'm sure the boy just made a mistake.
[Neil] All right.
We best get going, Lady Ashley.
Sing Song. Take the little fella to the kitchen.
Give him a big feed of that tucker he likes.
- [Sarah] Forgive me, Mr. Fletcher.
- Look. I understand.
You barely slept.
- Wait, wait.
- Let me go.
[Chinese]
Yeah. Well, that old windmill
hasn't turned in years.
He's a sweet little boy.
I don't think he meant any harm.
Yeah, no, they're funny, little creamies.
They're all a bit soft in the head, yeah.
That's why the, uh, government
sends them to the mission.
They all tell bloody monstrous lies.
Yeah. And the next one, quick.
Come on. We haven't got all day.
[Nullah]
I no bloody liar!
He liar! He say this not work!
Fletcher liar!
- No! Leave him alone!
- Nullah!
- Fletcher!
- [Nullah] I curse you!
Leave him alone! Leave him alone!
- Please!
- Run! Run! Run, Nullah! Run!
I curse you!
Leave him alone!
[Sarah]
Mr. Fletcher!
- Leave him alone!
- Mr. Fletcher!
- [Nullah Sobbing]
- [Sarah] Get off my property.
You no longer work for me.
- [Sobbing]
- [Neil] If I go, my men go with me.
There won't be a single bloody beast in the
stockyard to start the drove in the morning.
You heard what I said.
Get off my property!
- Yeah?
- Go!
Now!
You're the boss.
Flynn, get in the car.
I'll give you a new job somewhere else.
Bunchemup, grab the gear.
Pack it up.
I'll see you in Desperation Creek
in a few days.
Bloody old fool.
- [Truck Door Closes]
- [Engine Starts]
Carney's gonna get this property.
Been a pleasure working for ya.
Real pleasure.
Yeah.
- [Men Whistling]
- [Horn Honking]
[Men Shouting]
[Whistling Continues]
[Nullah Narrating] That strange woman-
she fire'em that Fletcher.
He can't hurt Mama no more.
From that day on,
we call her... Mrs. Boss.
Why would Fletcher block the water pump?
I don't know. All crazy.
- White fella, blackfella- all crazy.
- Crazy.
- [Knocks]
- [Sarah] Mr. Flynn.
- Milady.
- Don't get up.
[Door Closes]
The truth, Mr. Flynn.
This, uh, ledger...
which, um, Fletcher had me keep
for the benefit of your husband...
is a tale of decline and ruin...
redolent of the great Gibbon.
There is, however, another...
kept for the benefit...
- ## [Piano]
- of Mr. Carney...
in which is recorded
all the unbranded...
fat cattle...
- siphoned off across the river and into his herd.
- ## [Woman Singing Aria]
And the boy.
He's Fletcher's son, isn't he?
As with all things Fletcher,
it's impossible to prove anything.
Still, if Carney's good Christian wife...
ever comes to the same conclusion
as yourself...
Fletcher's chances of marrying
their daughter would be dashed.
I'm going to the authorities,
and I will be telling them-
- Carney is the authority here.
- Are you suggesting...
I let him steal my cattle and buy my property
for a fraction of what it's worth?
I'm suggesting that you continue
to do what your husband set out to do.
Drove.
Drove the cattle to Darwin.
- ## [Continues]
- Would you mind?
- [Door Closes]
- I need a drink.
My lady, drove.
Drove the cattle to Darwin,
sell them to the army...
and you'll break Carney's monopoly.
Use the profits to put Faraway Downs
back on its feet.
You go back to London.
You're sitting pretty
for the rest of your life.
That's what Maitland
said he was doing.
And there's no reason
why you can't do the same.
## [Continues]
[Whimpers, Exhales]
There is just one small problem.
Having dismissed Fletcher,
there's no one to muster the cattle.
[Rumbling]
[Horse Whinnies]
Hyah! Hyah!
[Nullah]
Flynn! Mrs. Boss!
It's the Drover!
[Whinnies]
Drover! Drover!
- [Whinnies]
- Hyah!
Yeah, Drover! Yeah!
Teach me how to
break them brumbies!
- See any boys in there?
- No.
Goolaj, go see if they're
out in the top paddock.
- Mr. Drover!
- Just get the bloody brumbies in there.
- I'll find out what the hell's going on.
- Teach me to break them horses.
- Fill the water trough, son.
- I need to speak to you!
Where the hell are
all the bloody stockmen, eh?
- That's what I need to speak to you about.
- Where's Fletcher?
- We disagreed, and I dismissed him.
- Dismissed?
- Yes.
- Wa- Hang on. What about the cattle?
Well, it beggars belief,
but as he was leaving...
he deliberately let the cows out of
the, uh- I don't know-whatever you call it...
and they ran off!
Damn! Do you realize, woman,
what you've done?
Mr. Drover, do not take that tone with me.
Thank you very much!
- Don't take that tone with you, huh?
- No.
I'm asking you, woman,
do you know what you've done?
I won't get another drove this late in the season.
You've cost me my living.
- Can't you just round them up?
- Round them up, huh? Oh, round them up. Yeah!
- Yes. You just go get them.
- 1,500 head of cattle-
Oh!
Scattered over a million acres
with just me and my two men.
That's a great idea. Stupid cow.
Mr. Drover,
I was right to dismiss Mr. Fletcher...
on moral grounds.
Moral grounds?
You're at that again, are ya?
Let me guess.
He wanted to, uh, exploit you, did he?
- Fancy you, did he?
- What?
Stop it. I -
Is there any man in this
world who doesn't fancy you?
- Please.
- Huh?
Mr. Fletcher is working for Mr. Carney.
They were pushing the best
of the unbranded cattle...
across the river
onto Mr. Carney's property.
They were stealing!
- There's no surprises there.
- No, he's a bad man.
All right, all right.
But look. You can't prove it, right?
- Well-
- You can't.
And you can't win against Carney.
So just take my advice, lady.
Grab King Carney's offer and go the hell
back to England as quickly as possible.
That way you'd make everybody happy,
especially me.
[Speaks Aboriginal Language]
So you're just going to walk away?
I learned a long time ago
not to fight other people's wars.
Wait! Wait! Wait! Mr. Drover, wait!
Please, please, please!
Mr. Drover, please! Please! Wait!
- Please. I-
- [Horse Whinnies]
Listen. You said that your dream was
to breed a thoroughbred with a-
with a bush brumby.
If you agree to help me, I-
I will give you my Capricornia.
[Horse Whinnies]
[Whinnies]
And how we gonna do a drove
with just me and my two men, huh?
Oh, crikey.
[Nullah]
Mum was a drover's boy for Fletcher.
Bandy was a drover's boy
a long time ago.
Some white stockmen like to have
an Aboriginal woman on the drove...
to keep 'em company at night.
They shave their heads,
make 'em look like boys...
and work 'em like any other stockman
during the day.
That's, uh-What do you call it?
- Exploiting them.
- Exploiting, yes.
Anyway, we're still in trouble.
We gotta have seven good riders at least,
and the most I can count is five.
- What have we got? We've got me-
- You.
- Magarri.
- Yeah, Magarri!
- Goolaj-
- Great.
We got Daisy. Nice ride.
And, uh, Bandy. Good work.
Oh. What about Mr. Sing Song?
Mr. Sing Song, ride horse?
- Hey. Don't look at me.
- Sing Song, me real good cooker.
Cook's wagon at best.
We got five, right? It's not enough.
We need two more experienced riders.
I did that run once back in 1935...
with Magarri, Dingo Jones
and the Drongo brothers-
Drongo brothers.
- true knights of the outback.
- Mr. Flynn. Can you ride?
- I can.
- I won't carry a drunk.
But don't.
I ride'em real bloody good!
I drove those no-good cheeky bulls
into the big, bloody metal ship.
- All right. Five and a quarter.
- Six and a quarter.
What?
Lady, this ain't trotting
in Kensington Gardens.
[Scoffs] Mr. Drover, I could show you
a thing or two about horses.
Pretty sure, when it comes to horses,
there's nothing you can show me.
- Bring the horse.
- You can't be serious.
Bring the horse.
- Oh, this should be interesting.
- [Men Chuckle]
Move along! Move along!
Rah! Rah!
- Move along!
- [Lowing]
Rah! Rah!
- What are you doing?
- Shoo! Shoo!
Rah, rah! Rah. Rah! Move it!
- Lady Ashley-
- Move it! Move it! They're going the wrong way.
Rah! Rah!
Oh! It's easy.
Stubborn things. Silly cows.
- Hey, hey, hey. What the bloody hell you doing?
- Come on.
You're scattering them all over the place.
Get up the back there, up the tail.
Get up there. Go, go, go, go, go!
Don't let 'em break away.
[Aboriginal Language]
Go on.
- [Lowing]
- Run, you cows! Move, you cows!
We're trying to get the cows up there.
- Not too bad, Lady Ashley.
- I've got him! I've got him!
I think we're doing pretty well.
You crazy- take all this stuff.
Where you think you going?
Shanghai?
A lady never knows
what she might need.
[Vehicle Approaching]
[Gasps]
Run, Nullah! Run! Run!
- [Nullah] Coppers! Coppers!
- Tank! Run! Tank.
Tank, Nullah! Tank!
Bandy, coppers!
Hurry up!
[Grunts]
Turn 'em loose.
[Man] Go on. Get out.
You two, check the east side.
Move, move! Hurry up!
[Aboriginal Language]
[Bandy]
Daisy's in the tank.
- [Breathing Heavily]
- Shh!
Bandy, tea. Tea.
- [Man] Where's the creamy?
- [Sing Song Speaking Chinese]
[Nullah]
Trackers.
[Squeaks]
Nullah.
Lady Ashley, Sergeant Callahan
of the Northern Territory Police.
[Daisy]
Grab the float.
I can't begin to tell you,
Lady Ashley, how the...
tragedy which befell
your late husband has...
wrung sympathy from the hearts of every civilized
man and woman in the Northern Territory.
Let me assure you, Lady Ashley...
that the suspect, King George,
will be brought to justice.
But surely a witch doctor could conceal
his own tracks, Sergeant, could he not?
Makes no difference.
It's only a matter of time.
[Aboriginal Language]
[Muffled Shouting]
[Muffled Shouting Continues]
- [Muffled Shouting]
- Shh!
Oh, incidentally, I met up with
your former manager, Neil Fletcher.
He informed me that there's a half-blood
Aboriginal child out here somewhere.
I thought we might pick him up
and put him in the good hands of the church.
I will be sure to look out for him.
Till we meet again, Lady Ashley.
[Whistles]
- Get 'em in the back, Constable. Let's go.
- [Engine Starts]
[Sarah]
They're in the tank!
[Bandy]
Drover!
[Sarah]
Drover, help them! Quickly!
Mama!
[Panting]
[Drover]
Easy. That's it. I got you. I got you.
[Grunts]
Come on, Daisy. Come on.
[Bandy]
Daisy! Daisy!
[Wailing]
Daisy! [Sobbing] Daisy.
Daisy!
[Sobbing]
[King George Chanting
In Aboriginal Language]
[Chanting Continues]
[Shouts In Aboriginal Language]
[Aboriginal Language]
Daisy.
[Screams]
## [Singing In Aboriginal Language]
When someone dies
in the Aboriginal culture...
you're not supposed to
say their name again.
He needs motherin'.
Mothering?
Yep.
You're a woman,
so, go on, get down there.
I'm, uh- I'm not, uh, uh-
What?
Good with children.
Oh. Huh.
[Nullah Sobbing Softly]
Nullah.
I wanted to extend my condolences.
Go away.
Would you, uh-
Would you like to hear a story?
[Sniffles]
What story?
Uh, well, it's, uh- it's called-
- It's called The Wizard of Oz.
- What's a wizard?
Well, a wizard is a sort of...
magic man.
Gulapa.
## [King George Singing]
[Nullah]
Mama say I gulapa.
- I magic man.
- Really?
I wizard man.
We can't say
Mama's name no more.
No. Well-
Uh, anyway, there's a girl...
and there's a dog.
Ruff. Ruff, ruff, ruff!
And there's a tornado-
- Well, no. It's a- In the film, it's a twister.
- Who twister?
Oh, no, no. Twister's not a person.
It's like a big-Whoosh!
- Like a storm.
- Like the wet?
Like the wet.
Anyway,
the story takes place in a, um-
well, a faraway land...
called Oz.
- This good story.
- Oh, well-
- Got song?
- Yes, yes. Lots of songs.
I like song.
You sing'em me,
I learn'em song.
No, no, no. No.
No.
Well, I- Uh, some.
- I'll sing a little.
- Good.
# Somewhere over the, uh-
the rainbow #
- Rainbow Serpent?
- Yes.
That bloody good. Keep going.
You funny singer, but good song.
Oh.
# Somewhere #
## [Humming, Vocalizing]
#There's some birds and they-#
- Uh- Oh-
- Keep going. Come on.
# Someday I'll wish upon a- a star #
#And #
- Come on. Sing more.
- Uh-Yes.
#Wake up where the clouds
are far behind #
# Dreams really do come #
#True ##
## [Holds Higher Note]
Oh!
Dreaming song.
Mrs. Boss...
we gotta get those no-good, cheeky bulls
into the big, bloody metal ship.
That's right.
That's what dreaming songs
tell us, Mrs. Boss.
We've got to get those
no-good, big, bloody bulls...
into that metal ship.
[Cattle Lowing]
I'm sorry. I thought he could-
I thought he could do it.
Yeah, well, people don't change,
Miss Ashley.
Twister. Twister!
- No desert comes drier than Kipling Flynn, milady!
- Well done!
Well done, Kipling!
[Laughs]
Hey!
- Flynn Kipling! Yea!
- [Mutters]
- [Chuckles]
- [Chuckling] Hey, hey!
- Welcome! Welcome!
- Hey, Nullah!
- All right.
- [Laughs]
Well, Mr. Drover, I believe
we have the appropriate number.
- The appropriate number, huh?
- Yes. [Chuckles]
Well, listen up. [Clicks Tongue]
I'm only gonna say this once.
I run the show.
Everybody does exactly...
as she's told.
- Understood?
- Understood.
No matter your experience
or your age, you pull your weight.
Yes, boss.
And above all,
the Drover's law: no grog.
- [Horse Blusters]
- Now...
if there's a rush and the cattle
are stampeding towards you...
it's not much good prancing
and dancing about on your show pony.
There's only one thing cattle fear
more than a man on a horse...
and that's a man standing
on his own two feet...
staring 'em right between the eyes.
Now, you sure you mob
are still up for it?
Mm-hmm.
You can count on us.
Oh, crikey.
Well, we're what we are.
Gotta get to Darwin
before the ship sails.
Let's get cracking.
[Aboriginal Language]
The rest of you jokers follow me.
- Hyah!
[Drover] I'll get the gate.
Stay back. Don't let 'em scatter.
[Braying]
There, mate. Push 'em over.
Don't let 'em go down there.
- That's it.
- Get 'em up!
- Whoo!
- Hyah!
Get up there!
[Chanting In Aboriginal Language]
[Nullah Narrating]
So we start cracking them whips...
and driving them cheeky bulls
all the way across the land...
to that place they call'em Darwin.
All right.
We'll push 'em straight across here.
Ho!
Very good. Keep 'em movin'.
Nice and steady.
- [Lowing]
- [Drover] Go on!
- Go on!
- Hyah!
[Drover]
Keep 'em moving.
Giddyup! Giddap!
## [Film: Instrumental
Newsreel Theme]
[Man Announcing] While the war rages on
in Europe, the Japanese are on the march.
There are reports of an alliance
between the warmongers...
of Germany, Italy and Japan...
which threatens to expand World War II
to the shores of Australia.
This is a war of the air,
but on the ground...
the War Office will announce
who has won the army's contract...
to supply good Aussie beef to the troops.
[Carney] Couple of days
won't make any difference, Captain.
Might as well sign
the contract now, eh?
I wouldn't be too sure of that,
Mr. Carney.
Air force chaps just spotted a big mob of cattle,
1,500 head, crossing the Marmont River.
Marmont River?
That's Faraway Downs.
Are you, uh, running cattle
out of Faraway Downs, Mr. Fletcher?
Uh, no, no.
I don't work there anymore.
Well, I suppose Lady Ashley's droving
the cattle herself. [Chuckles]
- [Laughs]
- Someone must be helping her.
That's right, Neil.
Someone must be helping her.
[Cattle Lowing]
[Nullah Narrating]
When Mrs. Boss first come to this land...
she look but she not see.
Now she got her eyes open
for the first time.
Some places got spirits.
White fellas don't know.
Some places no good to go.
You gonna sing'em
them cattle tonight?
No, Nullah. Not me.
I'm the orchestra.
That's why I always carry this-
the famous J. Albert & Son
boomerang harmonica.
Can you play that rainbow song?
Well, I've got the latest 100 songs
of the hit parade here.
## [Harmonica: "Over The Rainbow"]
[Nullah]
I like that rainbow song.
It's all about the dreaming.
Gulapa not teach me that yet.
Who's gulapa?
[Whispers]
He's my grandfather, King George.
King George... is your grandfather?
He teach me sing a fish song.
He teach me sing down fear.
Fear, evil spirit, wild beast.
Gulapa teach me plenty songs.
[Whispers] Gulapa teach me
that day down the billabong.
- [Cattle Lowing]
- [Chanting In Aboriginal Language]
[Aboriginal Language]
- [Exhales]
- Mr. Drover, what is that chanting?
Goolaj and Magarri singing the cattle.
Just keeps them calm at night.
We do it in shifts. Those boys will
finish up in a couple hours. So, Bandy-
- Yeah?
- You show Mrs. Boss...
- how it's done, all right?
- Right.
Sing Song, you and me are gonna
serenade 'em till 3:00, and, uh...
the safest shift is predawn, so that's
the boy soprano and his orchestra.
- All right? You're on till the sun comes up.
- Yes, boss.
All right.
Everybody get some shut-eye.
Uh, Mr. Drover...
I really don't think it's appropriate
to work a child of Nullah's age like that.
Now, I am more than willing
to take his shift.
- But, Mrs. Boss, I plenty old enough.
- No.
- I'm talking now, hmm? Manners.
- [Drover] Oi, oi, oi. Steady on.
I'm talking.
Look. Just relax, will ya?
The boy's gotta pull his weight
like everyone else.
When I was his age,
I was manning outstations.
- Not everybody's you, Mr. Drover.
- That's right.
Not everyone's me. I'm the boss.
You're on the 3:00 shift. All right?
Yes, boss.
- Night, boss.
- 3:00 a. m?
- Relax, lady. He'll be fine. Good night.
- Night, Mrs. Boss.
Oh. Good night.
Good night, Sing Song.
You're on the 12:00 shift.
I suggest you get some sleep.
[Nullah] Night, Bandy.
- Night, Nullah.
- [Nullah] Good night, Flynn.
[Flynn]
Night, Nullah.
[Nullah]
Night-night, Jedda.
[Chanting]
## [Harmonica: Single Notes]
Lord Ashley was killed
by a glass-tipped spear.
Are you sure?
[Whispers]
You and me secret.
[Cattle Mooing]
- [Whinnies]
- [Mooing]
Rush! Rush!
They're heading towards the cliff face!
A stampede! Where's Nullah?
Get on your horse
and stay with Goolaj.
Come on. Split up and circle the herd
before they go over the edge!
Sing Song, pack the camp.
Get the hell out of there!
[Drover]
Head them off!
Don't let them split!
Get in the front!
Hyah! Hyah!
[Flynn] Good boy! Come on!
Pull them round! Pull them round!
[Mooing]
Nullah!
You're too close to the edge!
[Flynn]
Courage, my boy! Courage!
Well done, my boy!
[Mooing]
Nullah!
We have to turn the herd!
Hyah!
Hey, hey!
Never fear, Flynn is here!
[Laughing]
- Yeah, Flynn!
- Hyah!
[Whinnies]
Flynn!
Nullah, run!
- [Chanting]
- ## [Singing]
Nullah!
- ## [Singing Continues]
- [Chanting Continues]
- [Whimpers Softly]
- [Snorting]
[Cries Quietly]
Nullah!
[Drover]
Oh! Oh.
Oh.
It's all right. You're safe.
I've got you.
You're safe.
You're safe with me.
I'll stay with you.
Hey.
How's the little fella?
- Oh, he's fine. He's fine.
- Yeah.
I have a feeling I might not be able
to complete the next lesson.
Right, old mate.
I'm gonna get you some water, huh?
Water's the last thing I want
at this moment in my life.
Under the wagon-
a bottle of Poor Fella.
I'm sorry, Drover. Just in case.
Of course, mate. Of course.
If you'd all share a drop.
It would be a terrible shame
to waste it.
[Groans]
The spear- Nullah told me.
A glass-tipped spear.
Tell milady I'm sorry.
I was a coward.
We lost just about everything,
except for a few swags and tins of beef.
And this.
I can't believe I was so insistent
upon bringing these...
silly things.
It was Fletcher who did this,
wasn't it?
The last thing Flynn told me
before he died was that-
that your husband was killed by a-
by a glass-tipped spear...
like the ornamental ones
in the homestead.
Glass-tipped is a Kimberley spear.
King George is from Arnhem.
Fletcher was trying to make it
look like King George.
- Fletcher.
- It can't be proved.
Sorry.
Maitland-
## ["Over The Rainbow"]
We can't let them win.
We won't.
[Chattering]
[Drover Shouts]
Get 'em up!
- [Mooing]
- Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
They pushed on during the night.
Maybe that little creamy
has got the blackfella magic.
Shut up, Bull!
They're gonna need more than magic
to get 'em to Darwin.
[Drover]
Hey, Nullah.
Nullah, after you're done, I need you
to help hobble these horses. All right?
[Nullah]
Yes, boss.
I never thought I'd see this day.
- We're gonna break the Drover's law.
- I plenty old enough too!
Yes, you are, and that is why you
are gonna keep an eye on the rest of us.
All right?
- All right, everyone. Let's be upstanding.
- Good girl, Jedda. Here.
To the memory of the gentleman.
- To the gentleman.
- To Flynn!
- [Coughs]
- [Groans]
- [Exhales]
- [Coughing Continues]
I'd say one more before dinner.
## [Guitar]
## [Vocalizing]
[Chuckling]
- Let's dance.
- No.
- Come on!
- No. No.
Come on. Please?
- No. I don't know how.
- It's easy. I'll show you.
You put your hands on my shoulders.
[Giggling]
[Giggling Continues]
And you step back.
- Back. No, no.
- Oh, back. Sorry.
- I'm a bad teacher.
- Stop! [Chuckling]
- [Squeals]
- You don't drink much, do you?
No.
I'll give it a go. Come on.
I can do it. I can do it. All right?
[Nullah]
Now you do wrong-side business?
- ## [Continues]
- Uh-
No, mate. No.
We're just having a dance here.
- Ceremonial dance?
- Uh, yes. It's called the fox-trot.
Fox dance?
You gonna teach me that dance?
- Uh, you're a bit too young for her, mate.
- [Bandy] Nullah!
Get down from that tree now!
Got bad spirits up there.
[Whispers]
You're in big trouble.
[Chuckles]
[Bandy] Come on, Nullah.
Time to go to bed now.
You know better
than to go up in the tree.
Have you ever fallen
into wrong-side business?
Uh, yeah.
- Oh.
- Yeah. I was married once.
- Really?
- Mmm. To a lovely girl.
That was before I went off to war.
And what happened?
Well, I marched off
for Mother England...
and by the time I came back,
she was sick...
with T.B.
But back then, the hospitals
wouldn't treat, um, blacks.
Oh, right. I see. Yeah.
Do you have children?
- No.
- Well, that's a shame.
I think you would have
made a great father.
- You?
- No.
I can't.
Oh.
That's too bad.
You would have made a great mother.
Well, good night.
- Good night.
- Yeah.
[Hoofbeats Approaching]
[Aboriginal Language]
- Water no good, boss.
- No.
Might be Carney boys
already been here, eh?
There has to be water
some other place.
- Next bore is five days.
- There has to be water.
You can be sure Fletcher
will have been there as well.
- Hey, boss.
- What?
There's water three days' ride away.
We'd have to cross the Kuraman.
The Kuraman?
That's Never-Never Land. No.
- We've got to try.
- We can't.
- No one has drove the Never-Never.
There's nothing to guide you.
You don't know where you are.
You get caught out there,
you're gonna lose more than your cattle.
I'm sorry.
Boss!
Look!
He a wizard.
He gonna sing for us.
[Aboriginal Language]
Sing?
He can find his way anywhere.
[Drover Continues]
The ancestors created songs for everything.
For every rock and tree.
They're all linked,
so when gulapa, the magic man...
- sings them in order, he'll sing us to water.
- [Grunting]
Even across the Never-Never.
[Chanting]
[Nullah Narrating]
And we went on for three days.
Every day drier-hotter.
All that dead land.
Then come that big dust storm.
Keep driving into the wind!
[Chanting]
[Sarah]
Nullah, stay close to me!
[Nullah Narrating] Them cattle stop moving.
Magarri and Goolaj stop moving.
We all stop moving.
[Chanting]
- I'm gulapa.
- [Laughing]
I magic man. I wizard man.
[Woman] Dead. All of them.
That's what he said.
The pilot swooped down
to get a closer look.
Dead as doorposts they were.
- It's a real tragedy.
- How terrible!
And on the eve of the ball too.
What were they doing in the Kuraman?
[Carney]
Nothing personal, Captain...
but I got a business to run,
and you got an army to feed.
So let's not muck about.
I suppose it's not a real war
unless someone's making a profit.
[Phone Rings]
- You got 'em ready to load, Neil?
- Yeah, we're right to go.
'Cause I got a feeling the captain's
gonna put pen to paper.
All hail the king. Yeah.
[Cow Moos]
- [Moos]
- [Woman] Where'd he come from?
Oh, look.
- Hello, little sweetie.
- [Moos]
[Chuckles]
[Mooing]
What the bloody hell is that?
Gentlemen!
I'm Sarah Ashley,
owner of Faraway Downs.
We are making delivery of 1,500 head
of prime F.D. branded shorthorns.
We will require a holding yard.
- We're full.
- Says who?
- The owner.
- You must be Mr. Carney.
Too right, love.
Lady Ashley, I'm Emmett Dutton.
I'm the officer in charge
of livestock purchases.
We will accept 20% less than what
the Carney Cattle Company is asking.
No can do, love.
You're late. The contract's signed.
This contract is not binding
until the cattle are loaded.
Load the bloody cattle now!
We've got to load the cattle
on the ship before Carney.
- Get off your backsides!
- You drive 'em straight down the wharf.
I'll try and keep Carney's cattle
in the yard.
Load the bloody cattle now!
- Drover!
- Hyah!
Load!
You blokes, load!
Hyah!
Hey, Bull!
Open the bloody crush!
Come on!
Close that flamin' gate!
You missed the boat, sunshine.
Yeah. Good luck, Drover, you drongo!
Over here, Drover.
Hyah!
[Whinnying]
[Crowd Cheering]
Drover!
Push 'em straight down the wharf!
Hah!
- [Cattle Mooing]
- Hyah!