(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
PRIEST: Body Of Christ.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS RUMBLING)
Ah, Monsieur Wraysford,
we had almost given up on you.
- Your train was late?
- A little.
You're certainly not the last.
Let me introduce you to Monsieur
and Madame Bérard.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Isabelle, my wife.
He came all the way from England.
She, I suspect, only from one of the more
fashionable shopping parades in Amiens.
(GREETING IN FRENCH)
Gregoire. Don't tease the dog, please.
We have dinner?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SINGING IN FRENCH)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
RENE: Bravo.
Oh, Papa has such a beautiful voice.
An artist is nothing without his patron.
Do you sing, Mr Wraysford?
- Very badly.
- Pity.
I have a particular fondness
for the patriotic song.
You'll be staying with us
long, monsieur?
A month or more.
London is very keen to see
how these new machines work.
They can do in a single day
what 30 of my women manage in a week,
and for one third of the cost.
Monsieur, how old are you?
- ISABELLE: Grégoire.
- I'm 20. How old are you?
Ten.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Remember, Lisette,
we are speaking in English tonight
for the benefit of Mr Wraysford.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MONSIEUR BERARD: Madame?
Did I see you today walking along
the Rue Saint-Leu?
I might have walked that way.
I passed that, um...
...beautiful house near Les Jardins d'Eau.
There was someone playing the piano.
I couldn't recognise the melody.
I just stood in the garden
trying to stop myself
from walking right inside.
And did you?
Stop yourself?
MONSIEUR BERARD: it was one of those
sentimental folk songs, I'll bet.
I cannot bear them.
Musicians of today are now satisfied
with four notes they can sell on
a song sheet on a street corner.
Give me one of our great composers.
- Now Camille Saint-Saëns.
- Ah...
Now, there is a composer.
Rene, forgive me,
I cannot shake this headache.
Perhaps Monsieur Wraysford
can take my place at cards.
Of course.
And I had another little song
I was so looking forward to singing.
Another time?
Madame. Monsieur.
- Good night.
- ALL: Good night.
Oh, poor Madame Azaire,
I hope she is not unwell?
My wife is of a nervous disposition.
(STIFLED SOB)
(RENE SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
(ISABELLE SOBBING)
(ISABELLE SOBS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(ISABELLE SOBBING)
(SHUSHES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(PANTING)
Sir, Captain Weir has taken
two men underground.
- How long have they been down there?
- Six, seven hours, sir.
And who told Captain Weir
he could take two of my men?
Captain Gray, sir.
(SOFTLY) Turner's heard something.
(WHISPERING) Turner's heard something.
(WHISPERING) Just here.
Vibrations.
Could be Fritz laying a wire.
Too far down.
They'd blow their own boys up
at the same time if it was.
Close the air feed off.
(PANTING)
TIPPER: Tyson!
Tyson!
Cut off the air feed.
Turner's heard something.
(RUMBLING)
The air feed's off.
For God's sake, Firebrace,
we're expiring down here.
(GASPING)
I can't bloody breathe.
BRENNAN: So shut up
and save your breath, Tipper.
It's shell fire.
I heard wrong. It's just shell fire
(SIGHS)
(RUMBLING)
Get out!
- Get out! Get out!
- Get back!
(SHOUTS)
Jack!
I want my men out now.
We want everyone out, sir.
I'm going to get you out, Turner,
I'm going to get you out.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
TIPPER: Get out HOW!
BRENNAN: Keep going forward! Come on!
Look at me. Keep looking at me, all right?
Look at me. Look at me, Turner.
MAN: Help!
Damn it, Weir. I will not allow you to take
my soldiers and put them in danger.
They're fighting this war too.
Hurry UP...
STEPHEN: Tipper.
(TURNER SOBBING)
Breathe out sharp. It makes it quicker.
Go on. Go on.
Easy lad, easy.
STEPHEN: Tipper, Tipper!
STEPHEN: Tipper!
(COUGHING)
Tipper!
You all right?
Turner.
- Tipper!
(SCREAMS)
Tipper!
For God's sake!
Do you want to get us all bloody killed?
(PANTING)
Get up.
Don't you ever let me see you do that again.
Do you hear me?
(PANTING) Sir.
I will not have you endangering
the lives of the other men.
Get him to the MO.
WEIR: Tyson, Shaw, rest up,
then I want you back down
and start to pump out.
Yes, Captain Weir.
I'm on sentry duty in an hour, sir.
- Tunnellers don't do duty...
- TYSON: They're short of men.
Firebrace, take his watch.
Yes, Captain.
WEIR: The water table must be too high,
it's all the rain.
So how many men did you lose?
One. Turner.
You talk to Gray. It was his idea.
I will.
STEPHEN: Sir?
Did you order my men
down with Captain Weir, sir?
Weir? Captain Weir.
Yes. He's an engineer, isn't he?
Yes and we're infantry, sir.
We're not clay-kickers.
Those clay-kickers are doing their bit.
You'll find you like them when
they blow Fritz sky-high from underneath.
My men nearly drowned.
Yes, I know.
Water table's up.
There's nothing we can do, unfortunately.
Sir, we are infantry.
We do not go underground.
Wraysford, they are laying mines
under Fritz's trenches.
If the Boche hear them, they'll dig down
and break through. They need protecting.
You try telling that to my men
when they're on a shilling a day, sir.
Try leading by example
and go down with them.
Are you frightened, Lieutenant?
No, sir.
Refresh those sewer rats
in the basics of combat
and then maybe I'll reconsider.
They may have been taught
how to hold a rifle
but I'm not convinced
they'll be able to fire
it if the Boche break
through into our tunnels.
Yes, yes.
(EXPLOSIONS)
(OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- Thank you, Riley.
- Sir.
(DISTANT SHELLFIRE)
Rumour has it we'll get some rest tomorrow.
Then who'll keep the French company?
I don't know what's worse,
being underground
or coming up and being under this.
Oh, you better get used to it.
The big guns take at least a week to dig in.
They're not going anywhere now.
Aren't you going to open that?
It's been lying there all day.
Christ.
Mother has surpassed herself.
At least I get post.
If only from my wretched mother.
I've never even seen you
get so much as a bar of chocolate.
Even the Red Cross sends socks.
(RUMBLING)
(RATTLING)
You ought to get yourself
a sweetheart, Lieutenant.
Riley, bowl!
(RENE SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
(BELL TOLLING)
ISABELLE: Are you lost,
Monsieur Wraysford?
No, I'm...
Yes, I am.
I meant to turn left, but...
Yeah, there is a quicker route,
but then one would miss the roses.
Ah.
Are you settling in well?
Quite well. Thank you.
I am sorry that you are joining us
at such a difficult time.
I fear the situation at the factory
will grow worse before it is better.
Grégoire is a fine boy.
Yes.
And Lisette, she's...
They are my stepchildren.
René's first wife died eight years ago.
We married two years after.
Ah.
I saw you today.
Near the Rue de la Gare.
There is a very fine café there.
I know it well.
You were visiting a friend?
A friend? No, um...
I have very few of those.
PRICE: On the command, load,
safety catches off and open the bolt.
- I've forgotten how you hold it.
- Like you hold your sweetheart.
Quiet.
PRICE: Take the charger clip
of five rounds and place it in the breech.
Push the rounds firmly into the magazine.
Open the bolt.
Close the bolt.
Safety catches on.
Check the safety catches, boys.
Good.
The weapon is now loaded.
Fire!
Miles away.
Blast!
His finger's too fat for the trigger.
Hope you don't have that problem
anywhere else, Mr Shaw!
(CHUCKLING)
Don't hold it like you
were in a penny arcade.
Tuck it under your shoulder.
No, tuck it under.
Tuck it in.
Fire!
Hey, good man! Not bad.
It's all muscle
from that hard digging we do
while you boys are nancying
around upstairs that does it.
- Anytime you want to swap places, mate?
- No thanks.
At least we get some peace down there.
Unload.
Close the action,
safety catches on
and rest your rifles.
Douglas, check the targets.
That's not much cop if that's all we get to
practise shooting at Fritz in the tunnels.
Suits me.
I came here to dig, not hold a gun.
You'll do what I say if it's needed.
Sir.
- He's a cold bastard.
- He's a queer one, all right.
He's just trying to get through this war
like the rest of us.
I'd rather him than Florence back there.
Captain Weir's all right.
Jesus Christ.
Don't Fritz ever stop for tea?
Nor for breakfast, nor dinner.
WEIR: Move out! Move out!
Come on.
Douglas, look at me.
I'm here, Douglas.
Hold onto my arm.
Grip harder. Harder, Douglas.
There you are.
Do you have a sweetheart, Douglas?
Morphine! Morphine!
You do? What's her name?
Iris.
I want you to think of her
and I want you to think
of the last time that you saw her
and I want you to think of the first things
you will say to her when you see her again.
Think of her, Douglas...
For God's sake, morphine!
Keep thinking of her.
Keep thinking, keep gripping.
Keep gripping my arm.
(DOUGLAS GASPS)
Get him out of here.
(DISTANT SHELLFIRE)
(CUTLERY RATTLING)
Bad luck... today.
This war provides daily lessons
in the extraordinary simplicity
of the human anatomy.
See this muscle here?
I never knew that there was another one
here inside the sartorius.
Not until I saw it.
You're drunk.
Not nearly enough.
Who's she?
Someone I once knew.
Would you believe it if I said
I've never been with a woman?
Never?
How old are you, Weir?
Old enough.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, the next village.
We don't want you to die curious.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MADAME BERARD:
Your family are close, monsieur?
No. No, I have no family.
- No parents?
- No, no parents.
No. My, um...
My father before I was born
and my mother when I was four.
Then you must have
children, monsieur.
They are the greatest gift.
Yes, people say that.
STEPHEN: Grégoire, how many is that now?
Five, but only the fat one.
I've promised a centime
for each one that he caught.
Then you are more foolish than I thought.
LISETTE: It's too hot.
It's beautiful.
Maman?
Do we know her, Stephen?
You mean Monsieur
Wraysford, Lisette?
Lisette.
Grégoire, attention.
Grégoire, you'll bankrupt me.
(GREGOIRE CHUCKLES)
They are all asleep.
It is very beautiful here.
Yes.
Yet all around there is such decay.
I take bread to the workers.
That's where I was going
when you saw me in the Rue de la Place.
The children are starving.
My husband would not approve.
Madame, forgive me, but
I cannot stay silent.
At night, I hear you crying.
LISETTE: Maman!
(LISETTE SPEAKING FRENCH)
MONSIEUR BERARD: Everyone.
A souvenir, if you please.
Attention.
Un...
deux...
trois...
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Perfect!
(DUCKS QUACKING)
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
Were you asleep?
I don't know...
Yes, sir.
What's your name?
Firebrace.
Pick that up, Firebrace.
You know, some of my men think
that you tunnellers don't work fast enough.
You don't hear the noise of the enemy
so they're terrified of being
blown up from underneath.
And now they must escort you underground
as well as fight a war above it. And...
in return...
you fall asleep on your watch,
just 50 yards from the German front line.
You know the punishment for falling
asleep on sentry duty, Firebrace?
Court martial.
Sergeant Major Price
will bring you down in the morning.
- Eyes skinned, Brennan.
- Yes, sir.
Byrne, bail out some of this water
if you don't want your feet to rot.
Sir.
(WHIMPERS)
Smarten yourself up, lad.
Put your cap on straight.
Firebrace, is there something wrong?
Lieutenant Wraysford asked to see me, sir.
He was asleep on sentry duty,
it's punishable by firing squad.
For Christ's sake, Lieutenant,
you can't be serious?
He's the best tunneller I've got.
Sit down, Firebrace. Have a drink.
No. Thank you, Captain.
Sit down.
My son's not well.
My wife...
She says it's worse this week.
Diphtheria.
You turn it over in your mind.
Funny, you know, how your...
your head's here,
but your heart's always somewhere else.
Do you have children, sir?
No.
No, I don't.
- I've not been sleeping properly...
- I have two men on guard
in a shell hole in no-man's-land for three
days with their feet rotting in their boots.
What happens if one of them falls asleep?
Each one of them is someone's son.
Yes, sir. Sir.
Are you a gambling man, Firebrace?
No, sir. I don't believe in chance.
Tap that top card.
Tap it.
For Christ's sake, Lieutenant, you don't
have the authority to have this man shot.
Seems like the man upstairs
is on your side today, Firebrace.
The ace...
Power and stability.
No further charge.
WEIR: You may go, Firebrace.
Yes, Captain.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I should fire every one of them
and let them go hungry.
(CROWD CHANTING)
One cannot deny progress, monsieur,
when the world is demanding more
and we must supply them
with what they need.
(SIGHS)
But they do not understand commerce.
One must be fearless if one is to survive.
A big order. French military.
(PIANO PLAYING)
Oh.
Jeanne.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
- This is my darling sister, Jeanne.
- Jeanne, enchanté.
And this is Monsieur Wraysford,
our visitor from abroad.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SISTERS SPEAKING FRENCH)
(GASPS)
(WOMAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
My sister was just reminding me that
as children we used to say that, um,
I would open a shop in Paris and she...
Would live in the jungle
and be a missionary.
- But only after your lover
had rejected you. (LAUGHS)
LISETTE: Maman!
And what about you,Monsieur?
What did you imagine as a little boy?
Well, the usual, I suspect.
And what was that?
A life of sorts.
No adventures at all?
Every child should
wish for adventure, monsieur.
Lisette.
(LISETTE SPEAKING FRENCH)
ISABELLE: That's the way
all the young ladies are wearing it.
Do you not think it should be a
little higher, monsieur?
Uh...
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Maybe a little higher?
Lisette.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
Oh, Grégoire.
All right, you bat, I'll bowl.
- D'accord.
- (WOMEN LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MONSIEUR BERARD SINGING)
You must think we are
silly, monsieur,
but we see each other so little.
Then, when we are together...
Not at all. She seems very happy
now that you are here.
No. I don't think it is my visit,
Monsieur Wraysford.
At last, she has someone under 40
to keep her company. (LAUGHS)
- You never married, madame?
- No.
I resisted my father's choice for me.
And Isabelle did not?
Be careful, monsieur.
My sister is very dear, but I'm afraid
you will be the one who is hurt.
(APPLAUSE)
(PEOPLE SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
- Sir.
- Have you read it, Freud?
No, sir.
Pity.
Captain Weir said you wished to see me.
Yes. We are sure Fritz are going to
break through any day now,
but we need to keep laying charges.
I need you down with those tunnellers.
It's not natural to be buried alive,
I know, but, uh,
we need a regular rota
going down with them
- if we are ever to mobilize near Amiens in...
- Where, sir?
Amiens. In around six weeks, yes.
Do you know it?
I spent a summer there before the war, sir.
I will not...
I will not go down that tunnel, sir.
I did what you asked,
I went over their basic training with them.
For God's sake, is that not enough?
You're curious to me, Wraysford.
I've seen all that rubbish in your dugout,
your carved figures in bits of candlestick.
You're quite superstitious.
- Aren't we all?
- No. An officer can't afford
to be superstitious.
Our lives depend on strategy and tactics,
not matchsticks or card games.
It passes the time.
You'll go down with them.
All right, dismissed.
So, Armitage, Byrne and Tipper.
Here, give us that.
You do my watch tonight.
Cheers.
Oi! What about me?
Give over, will you?
- Cigarettes out.
- Wraysford, you joining us today?
It would seem so.
You keep that pump working.
Brennan, you go first.
BRENNAN: Yes, sir.
(BRENNAN GRUNTING)
BRENNAN: Here, I got your back
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
There better be no crawling.
Just shut up, Byrne.
(PANTING)
WEIR; (WHISPERING) Down here.
Fighting tunnel. Fighting.
Listening. We've heard Fritz just beyond,
so if they break free, you back us up.
We stick together and
we talk only when I do.
Firebrace.
You sure this will hold?
It's not up to London Underground
standards, sir,
but I reckon you could
run a train through it good enough.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Brennan, you first, then Byrne.
All right, go on.
BYRNE: (GASPS) I can't! I can't! I can't!
(BYRNE COUGHS)
BRENNAN: Byrne! Byrne!
(GASPS)
No, sir.
I'm infantry.
I'm not supposed to be down here.
I'll take my chance in the trench
but not in a bloody hole.
None of us signed up for this, Byrne.
But if the sewer rats can do it, then so can you.
Now, you will go down that tunnel
or I will send you on every patrol until
you've out the wire from here to Switzerland.
(BYRNE PANTING)
(BYRNE COUGHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOLDIERS SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
(SHUDDERING)
Back! Get back, get back, back!
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
FIREBRACE: Sir.
Sir.
(GRUNTING)
Tyson!
- You're leaving already, monsieur?
- Yes. I must go on business.
I will not be back until tomorrow.
I leave you in charge of the factory, monsieur.
- Jeanne, are you ready?
- Oui.
Tell her, Rene. Tell her to stay.
I will not let you leave today.
Don't be silly,
your sister cannot visit forever.
You are shaking. Have you a chill?
No.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
- I am so sleepy.
- ISABELLE: Mmm.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
A walk in the garden
and then a little nap, I think.
ISABELLE: A walk is a good idea.
Do you want to go into town?
LISETTE: No, I think just a nap.
Oh, and wake me
if I am not up by 5:00, please.
Excuse me.
(MAN GRUNTING)
- We got you.
- Move him out!
All right.
(EXPLOSION)
- PRICE: Get him out!
Get him out! Get him out! Move!
(EXPLOSION)
(MEN SHOUTING)
MAN: Morphine, please! Morphine!
(RENE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I can't look at you.
I'm going to give myself away.
ISABELLE: René...
- All's well?
- Bonjour.
Bonjour.
(MEN CHANTING IN FRENCH)
This malevolence has spread
to the other workers.
(READING IN FRENCH)
"We must stand together in this matter
or we will all fall."
Did she seem preoccupied to you?
My Wife?
I'm...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
No, no. Not at all. I... She doesn't.
I'm sorry. You're right, you're right.
You are very good for us, monsieur.
MILITARY MEDIC: Morphine. Morphine.
No. He's gone.
Name, tag him and lay him out.
(MOANS)
No, no, a moment longer.
- René will be home really soon.
- Isabelle...
Do you feel guilty?
No.
Is that terrible?
I don't know why, but no.
No, I don't believe it is.
Perhaps I should...
You must want more.
- Than what?
- Than...
Picnics...
And endless dinners,
the numbing hours with him.
Let us not talk of this...
- I could take care of you.
- Stephen, please!
I could take care of you.
So that he won't hurt you any more.
- He doesn't mean to hurt me.
- Well, then why does he do it?
Hey.
He grows frustrated.
He can't...
For some reason, with me...
He is unable to...
My boy...
So serious.
Now that you are here,
he can't hurt me at all.
How does this fasten?
(CHUCKLES)
- How does...
(LAUGHS)
Mademoiselle.
The trees are too close together.
Or, perhaps, you are trying
to sketch Maman?
Isabelle.
- What do you mean?
- I have seen you.
You think we're all asleep?
Do you not want me?
Do you not want to do those things to me?
She is not even my mother.
(WHISPERING) She need only say a word.
She won't.
Leave him.
This is madness.
Did you want her?
She's a child.
Did you?
I want you.
(HORSES APPROACH)
(DOOR OPENS)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
- Morning, beautiful.
- Fancy a bit of that, Jack?
- Too early for me.
- Oi, I'm starving.
Ah, put 'em away.
You're putting me off me eggs.
Who's the new brass?
- Must be Wraysford's replacement.
- Do you know where they put him?
Over with the rest of them. Might be brass,
but makes no difference.
We're all the same when we're dead.
Sir.
- Lieutenant Cartwright. He'll be...
(CLEARS THROAT)
...taking over from Lieutenant Wraysford.
Yes, sir.
Sir, has Lieutenant Wraysford got family?
I don't know...
I really don't know.
Someone should write to his family, sir.
Send his badge.
Yes.
Would you like me to go, sir?
Say a prayer?
Yes, Firebrace.
That would be very...
Kind. Yes...
If you wouldn't mind.
Captain.
- Get me a souvenir.
- Get it yourself.
You're going soft, Jack.
You'll miss breakfast.
Save us some.
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Another order in today.
Two thousand more coats for the military.
The promise of five francs extra in
their pay and they just look at me.
(CHUCKLES)
Where's their sense of national duty?
We'll break the strikers yet.
The strangest thing I've heard today.
Someone has been taking
parcels of food to their families.
Well, they...
They do have some supporters, sir.
One or two sympathetic men.
No. This is the oddest part.
It was a woman. Apparently, of some rank.
Now, isn't that the strangest thing?
Their children were hungry.
I saw them going through
the dustbins in Saint-Leu.
Don't ask me to stop,
because I'll do it again.
- Isabelle...
- Punish the men, not their families.
Leave the room.
Lisette, I said leave the room.
- It is all your fault.
- ISABELLE: Lisette.
We were happy before you came.
Your father is right. Leave the room.
I discounted these rumours, even though
it was your name attached to them.
- René...
- Be quiet.
Monsieur, if you please,
I would like to be alone with my wife.
- Sir...
- No.
Let him stay.
I want him to stay.
There was another piece of idle talk.
I chose to ignore it.
I'm so sorry.
I meant you no harm.
This boy...
This English boy!
In which room?
In my own house! Which room?
I pursued your wife, sir. I seduced her.
You have never taken
the trouble to know me, René.
- Forgive me!
- Yes, I forgive you.
I forgive you for all the wrong
you have done me
and I ask you to forgive me
for all the wrong I have done to you.
You will leave my house now.
Then I'll go with him.
You think you will be able to keep her?
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(RENE SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
Isabelle, we must leave now. Come.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Wraysford.
(PANTING)
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
LISETTE: Maman! Maman!
GREGOIRE: Maman!
Isabelle!
If you go with him, you go to hell.
(MUMBLING)
(SOFTLY) Help me. Help.
Help.
Get me up.
(GRUNTING)
Isabelle.
(CHUCKLES)