[man shouting orders]
[typewriter clacking]
[man continues shouting]
[men marching]
I'll let you have
some more information
as soon as I know
myself. All right?
Thank you, Mokrane.
11:00 tonight.
Don't forget.
[speaking Arabic]
The General will see you
now, Maj. Brand.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
[man continues shouting]
[grunts]
(Barton)
You're late, Wilkins.
Where've you been?
Talking to the Major.
I don't understand it, sir.
He doesn't seem to like me.
Well, hurry up
and try and get used
to this Arab costume.
We taking a little trip,
are we?
What do I do
with this lot?
Michael, you tell him.
There's a commando operation
tomorrow at 1830 hours.
It's to go
behind the lines.
Surprise the Germans
at Benghazi.
Plan all worked out?
Not quite.
We only received final
instructions an hour ago.
You can call on me
at any time, sir.
That's good.
I know you've
always wanted action.
Well, you may be the man
to command this operation.
(Paterson)
It is paper work, after all.
D-Do you speak Arabic,
by the way?
I'm afraid I'm not
very good at languages.
I left South Africa, but I
never got rid of my accent.
(Paterson)
Oh, well, your knowledge
of German will help, anyway.
It's a great opportunity
to show what you can do
and a chance of
quick promotion, too.
We'll let you know
later tonight, say, 10:00.
Thank you, sir.
[typewriter clacking]
(Brand)
Hello, Leith.
I thought the fan
should cool the colonel's head
and not the flies
on the ceiling.
Yes of course.
[door opens]
(Callander)
Would you like
to come in now, Jimmy?
Yes, thank you, Mike.
[typewriter clacking]
Maj. Brand, sir.
Yes?
Uh, it's your wife, sir.
What's happened?
Well, nothing's happened, sir.
She's here.
Here?
Yes, sir.
She landed in Heliopolis
an hour ago.
Where is she now?
She's waiting
at your hotel, sir.
Thank you.
Will you have a cigarette?
Uh, no.
No, thank you, sir.
Well?
It's a very
difficult operation.
But you think
it's got a chance?
One in a million.
Does that mean
you're against it?
Of course not.
You do know
Benghazi well, don't you?
Yes, I spent two years
in Libya before the war.
But you were on archaeological
work then, weren't you?
Andover's expedition?
No, that was in India, sir.
It was more fashionable
in those days.
(Paterson)
Indeed.
Do you speak Arabic?
Yes, sir.
(Paterson)
German?
No, sir.
Are you considering me
for this operation, sir?
We'll let you know
that in good time.
Very well, sir.
I'm not a regular officer
like Maj. Brand.
I'm a volunteer.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
Good night, Michael.
Good night, Jimmy.
I want it.
[typewriter clacking]
Did you tell him about Brand?
No, sir. He saw him outside.
I told you, he's no fool.
He caught on right away.
No... no fool.
You didn't tell me
he was hardly civilized.
He knows the desert, sir.
He's lived with the people,
he speaks their language.
Brand's got
over 15 years' service.
And he'll know
all about those documents.
You don't think
he's been behind a desk
for too long, sir?
He's commando-trained.
So is Leith.
Leith hasn't been
in the battle.
Neither has Brand.
I can't be expected to find
the right man for this
at 20 minutes' notice.
(Paterson)
Anyway, Brand will have
more authority over the men.
Leith's... he...
he's an intellectual.
And besides, he's Welsh.
It's M.I.5's idea, sir.
##[music playing]
They're going to surprise
Benghazi with 200 men,
let the prisoners
out of the cage,
we've got 10,000 there.
Then bring the navy
over from Malta and...
[imitating explosion]
[imitating door
creaking open]
[imitating footsteps]
[imitating brakes screeching]
[imitating gun firing]
[imitating machine gun firing]
M.I.5 says there aren't
any POW cages in Benghazi.
They're all 200 miles
to the south.
[Jerry imitating
incoming missile]
[imitating machine gun firing]
[whistling]
Hello, Leith. Come on,
I want you to
meet my wife.
Jane,
this is Capt. Leith.
Hello.
Won't you sit down,
please?
Thank you.
You've been top-secret,
Mrs. Brand.
Your husband hasn't
spoken a word about you.
How long?
It's almost as old
as the war.
That's quite old.
We all have short
memories nowadays.
Maybe it's for the best.
What'll it be?
Whiskey, please.
Two.
Mixing drinks, Jane?
Three whiskies.
I wonder why people
have short memories.
Do they forget
what they want to forget,
or don't they care?
What do you think?
They don't care.
Haven't you ever cared
deeply about anything?
Yes.
(Jane)
What was it?
Jane!
Careless talk costs lives.
So does careless silence.
Well, this isn't top-secret.
I cared once.
It happened before the war.
Yes?
(Leith)
The first time
I went to Libya,
helping to excavate
a Roman city.
I've never cared
about anything much since.
What about the war?
Well, that's something
you have to survive, like, uh,
like love.
Is that what you told
Gen. Paterson tonight?
Oh, yes,
but he didn't agree.
Apparently he has
some elaborate plan
to prevent my survival.
They're considering you, too?
What are you two
talking about?
This is top-secret.
So we'd better have
a little careful silence.
To us, Jane.
To us.
Oh, good lord,
I forgot.
I'll take you back
to the hotel.
I won't be long.
Well, then I can
wait for you here.
I'll look after her, Brand.
All right.
An officer can't keep
G.H.Q. waiting
to know how many camels
were born this week.
See you later, dear.
You don't understand. Here.
To your marriage, Jane.
Thank you, Jimmy.
[imitating gun firing]
Friday, August 25th, 1939,
3:00, in front
of the British Museum.
Like every Friday.
You never came.
I waited an hour,
and then I telephoned.
No answer.
I've never had an answer.
I had to go back to Libya.
You knew I had to go.
But why did you have to do it
that way, Jimmy?
Why did you have to run away?
Because I was afraid of you.
If I'd stayed...
If you stayed?
Jimmy, why didn't you stay?
So you married a Major.
So I married a Major.
Why?
I loved him.
David didn't run away.
He isn't a coward.
All men are cowards
in some things.
Let's dance.
Yes, it looks like it may be
just what we want.
When do they expect
to have it in service?
October, sir.
Fine.
Excuse me, will you?
Certainly, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
May I have a moment?
Of course. What is it?
I just wanted
to explain, sir,
in case you thought
I wasn't eager for action.
[chuckling]
Dear fellow,
I never had
the slightest doubt about it.
Go on, fall out.
I'll probably see you later.
Thank you, sir.
[imitating airplane]
##[music playing]
Did you cure
the General's insomnia?
I beg your pardon?
By setting him right
on the birth rate of camels.
No time for jokes, Leith.
Oh.
Your permission to leave, sir.
Good night, sir.
Good night, Mrs. Brand.
Good night.
Anything the matter?
Mmm-mmm.
Want to go home?
Mmm-hmm.
Sorry about...
[airplane whirring]
Sorry about what?
Leith.
No manners at all.
Famous for it.
But I suppose one
must make allowances.
Yes.
Always.
Did you object to the way he
invited himself over tonight?
Did you mind?
But you invited him.
No, next corner here.
Oh.
So you didn't mind?
I thought so.
You didn't dance with me.
But David,
you didn't ask me to.
You never gave me a chance.
The moment he sat down,
you ignored me.
But aren't you being
a little silly, David?
I thought he was your friend.
I was only being polite.
Polite?
You call that polite?
You never took
your eyes off him.
The way he held you
when you danced.
I saw you.
Oh, but Jimmy...
Jimmy! You call him Jimmy?
Please, David.
You're hurting me.
How do you know
he's called Jimmy?
I heard you call him that.
That's not true.
I've never called him
anything but Leith.
If you knew
just how much
I needed you.
And now,
the first night
you are here...
Stop it, David!
You're hurting me!
Not bad, eh?
I can't take me eyes
off her.
Hey, Frenchie.
Eh?
How do you say
"chick" in francais?
Hey, boys,
look... look at that.
That's a smasher.
[men continue chattering]
[men laughing]
I'm sorry, Jane.
If I didn't care so much,
I wouldn't...
I can't help
being jealous.
Try, David.
Let's go home.
You want something?
The General
wants to see you.
Oh, really?
Sorry, darling. I'll be back
as soon as possible.
What is it, David?
Can't tell you now.
A little walk
in the desert.
You shouldn't joke
about it, Leith.
Especially when
you're staying behind.
I'm not so sure that I am.
Goodbye.
Good night.
Mokrane!
[speaking Arabic]
I am very happy
to see you, sir.
It has been
long time.
It will be very good
to work with you again.
Thank you, sir.
[speaking Arabic]
Very good, Mokrane.
Very lucky
to have him with us.
You seem to know him
pretty well.
Oh, yes, I met him first
about five years ago.
First time I went to Libya.
We worked together.
Loyal?
A friend.
Oh, Michael?
Sir.
Start the briefing
right away, will you?
Very good, sir.
I want to see you two
for a moment.
Well, gentlemen,
I've decided
you're both indispensable.
So you're both going.
(Paterson)
Maj. Brand will be
in command, of course.
John Barton,
who, in my opinion,
is the best young
commando officer we've got,
will also be with you.
These are your orders.
I need not remind you
that you'll be
entirely responsible
for the lives of 30 men.
They're all expendable.
All of us.
We don't expect you to do
anything inhuman, of course.
But we need those documents
from Benghazi.
We need them here,
right away.
I understand, sir.
All right, then.
Thank you, sir.
(Callander)
Two planes will drop you
in the desert,
three hours' march from
German HQ Benghazi.
Sgt. Evans of the Camel Corps
will meet you with your gear,
and you'll proceed
to rendezvous.
At 2305 hours,
Maj. Brand will
lead his attack.
At the same time,
Mr. Barton
will put in
his diversionary attack
from the north.
Barton, will you show me
on the model
the point from which
you'll make your attack?
From this direction, sir.
Good. Now remember:
if Maj. Brand is to succeed,
you must hold out
for 20 minutes.
Yes, sir.
Now carry on.
(Callander)
After the two groups have
accomplished their missions,
they will rendezvous
24 hours later at El Sidi.
They will then proceed
to Crown City,
where Sgt. Evans will be
waiting with the camels
to bring you back.
It will be a four days' ride.
Ok, tomorrow night
at 2300 hours, where
exactly will you be?
Right here, sir.
(Callander)
Good.
Any questions?
What happens, sir,
if the camels don't arrive?
We walk it.
What, with my feet?
You'll have to carry me
on your back, sir.
Anything else?
All right, fall out.
And get some rest.
It may be a long journey.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
[speaking Arabic]
Good night, David.
Good night, sir.
(Callander)
Good night.
(guard)
Sorry, fellows,
you can't go out tonight.
[men clamoring]
(guard)
These are my orders.
(soldier)
I've got a date tonight.
Let's get out of here
I'm sorry, fellows.
[all shouting]
(Wilkins)
Well, whose orders
are they, then?
Orders of Maj. Brand, Wilkins.
Oh, it seems our Maj. Brand
doesn't like me, personally.
He likes
discipline, though.
Yeah.
The only thing
he ever slept with
is the book of rules.
Maj. Brand, please.
Who are you, please, ma'am?
I'm the book of rules.
Jimmy!
Is it true you're going?
Yes.
When?
In a few hours.
How long will it last?
Well, the survivors
should be back in a week.
Survivors?
Your husband's still here.
[door opening]
I don't want
to see him yet.
[door closing]
All right.
It's all so mixed up.
A year ago, I joined up
to be with David.
What if he doesn't come back?
Then he and I and you
will become a part of history.
Of its futility.
Don't talk to me
in riddles, Jimmy.
It's a long time
since I was in Libya.
The Romans built wonderful
cities in Libya, you know.
Dead bones
sticking out of the sand.
War rolled over them.
Be good
to see them again.
But you always seem
to prefer stones
to people.
You learn things
from stones.
What?
All that people have forgotten
in the centuries, and...
I seem to remember
that I was less than
a stone to you.
I loved you, Jimmy.
Better go in.
There isn't much time.
What can I say to him?
[door closes]
Tell him all the things
women have always said
to their men
before they go to the wars.
Tell him he's a hero.
Tell him he's a good man.
Tell him you'll be
waiting for him
when he comes back.
Tell him he'll
be making history.
[airplane whirring]
(Evans)
Sgt. Evans, sir.
Mr. Barton's plane
arrived an hour ago.
(Brand)
Very well.
Camels all right?
Oh, pretty healthy, sir.
We're relying on you,
Sgt. Evans.
They can't
pick us up by plane.
If you're not at Crown City
with those camels...
Don't worry sir.
We'll get you back all right.
Well, here's
your Arab clothing.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Your gear and provisions
you will find
at map reference 278225.
That's at the head
of the wadi,
the river bed,
27 km due east
of Benghazi.
All right.
I'll have a man
watching for you, sir.
Thank you.
Synchronise watches.
##[Arabic music playing]
[hooves clomping]
[people chattering]
##[music playing]
[speaking Arabic]
[woman ululating]
[children chattering]
[speaking German]
[speaking Arabic]
[engine starts]
[speaking German]
[people chattering]
[dog barking]
[whispering]
What are you waiting for?
[footsteps approaching]
[screams]
[gasps loudly]
[explosion]
Barton!
He's early.
No, sir.
We're late.
[gasping]
[door slamming open]
[machine gun firing]
[machine gun fire continues]
[explosion]
[gunfire continues]
[machine gun firing]
[gun firing]
[breathing heavily]
Hey, Wilkie! Your baby!
[exclaiming]
[glass shattering]
[lock clicking]
Give us a touch, lovely.
Hurry it up, Wilkins.
Can't rush it, sir.
Skilled labor.
Lucky I'm not
charging you overtime.
(Wilkins)
Here she comes.
Wilkie's won the war.
So crime doesn't pay, eh?
All right. Start loading.
Assemble the others, Leith.
I've got them.
(Leith)
All right, everybody out.
I'll wear your hat
for you, mate.
[dogs barking]
[whistle blowing]
[motorcycle approaching]
[tyres screeching]
[engine revving]
[speaking German]
Wonder what has happened?
[Lutze speaking German]
Just look at this.
The papers have been stolen!
[speaking German]
We must take off right away!
[Lutze speaking German]
You come with me.
[speaking German]
Fidel and Abel,
you go in the second car.
[all yelling in German]
[speaking German]
Lutze, you come with me.
Hurry up.
[speaking German]
Yes, sir.
[barking orders in German]
[dogs barking]
Glad to see you,
sir.
Mr. Barton left
a few minutes ago.
He's just ahead
at rendezvous.
(Brand)
Was he all right?
(soldier)
He seems to be
all right, sir.
[car engine approaching]
With your permission, sir,
I'll rejoin my group.
Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
I wanted to ask you
something, Leith.
Go ahead.
Why did you take over
with the sentry?
I've been wondering
when you'd ask me that.
Oh, you have?
What was the matter?
Couldn't you stand
the tension?
Couldn't you?
Is that what you're
going to tell them
back at headquarters?
What?
That I failed?
What happened tonight
has nothing to do with me.
That's between you...
And you.
[vehicle approaching]
[gun cocking]
Are you insinuating
that I was afraid?
Well, I wasn't.
Stout fellow.
I was.
All right,
let's move on.
Yes, ok, sir.
Please yourself.
There's Barton.
[explosion]
Leave the documents.
[guns firing]
[explosion]
[machine gun firing]
[gunfire continues]
[gunfire stops]
Good work, Barton.
Oh!
We got here
a few minutes before you did.
Jerries didn't see us.
We saw them,
so we opened up
on them.
You know what
the instructions were.
We'll have all the patrols
in the desert on our tails.
We could have
taken care
of ourselves.
I'm sure
you could have, sir,
but we got the half-truck
with our first grenades...
I think
you lost your head.
Who's that?
[wind howling]
You hang on there,
Browning.
You'll be all right.
Just my horrible luck.
[groaning]
[speaking German]
Lutze.
Oberst Hans Lutze?
Jawohl.
The man in charge
of the documents.
Good work, Barton.
Just the man
to help you
sort them out, sir?
Our patrols
will sort you out.
(Barton)
Seems a bit sulky,
doesn't he, sir?
And he's probably right
about the patrols.
Colonel, you come with me.
Capt. Leith,
we have to go on.
You stay behind
with the wounded.
Casualty report, sir.
We lost Perkins
and Hunter.
Roberts very
badly wounded, sir.
Browning got a small chunk
taken out of his leg.
And the Germans?
They're all dead, sir,
except the colonel here,
and one badly wounded.
Thank you,
Sergeant.
Sir.
Yes.
Yes, what?
I'll stay.
Then take the men
you need.
Wilkins.
Sgt. Dunnigan,
you'll stay
with Capt. Leith.
Sir.
With your knowledge
of the desert,
you should be able
to overtake us
before tomorrow night.
Barton,
fall in the men.
Yes, sir.
[gasping]
What are we going to do
about the two wounded men,
sir?
Maybe we could
rig up a stretcher
of some sort.
No.
They'd bleed to death
in an hour.
Anything
I can do for you?
Would you like
a cigarette?
[soldier groaning]
[mumbling]
Easy, easy, easy.
Try to take it easy.
What are you
going to do, guv?
Knock 'em off?
I'm the one
for that job,
you know.
They're no good to you.
Stand in your way.
There's no
profit in it.
Why don't you let me
do it for you?
Follow the others.
Ah.
I'd like to stay here
with you, sir, if I may.
Follow the others!
Sir.
All right, Jackie,
I'll take that.
I can manage.
Come on,
give it to me.
Thanks, Sergeant.
Aw, get along with you.
I still
don't get it.
What?
Not waiting
for Leith.
Maybe he's trying
to lose him.
Maybe not.
Training
for the postwar Olympics.
I wonder
when that'll be.
[groaning]
[groans]
[metal clanging]
[groaning]
[coughs]
[soldier whispering]
Nein.
[gasps]
[groans]
[exhales]
Meine frau,
mein kind.
We were so happy
before the war.
Help.
Help me.
No.
No more war.
Nein, nein!
Nein!
[gun firing]
Hurry up.
Any family?
Don't drag things out.
Do what you've got to do.
[groans]
But be quick about it.
You're a brave man.
[trigger clicking]
[sobbing]
[groans]
Damn you!
[sobbing]
[groaning]
Let me down, damn it!
You're hurting me!
You coward!
[sobbing]
Leave me alone!
We have been watching you,
my friend.
He's dead.
[wind howling]
Yes.
[chuckling]
I kill the living,
and I save the dead.
It's written
for everyone to die.
It makes no difference.
Yes.
Except for that little matter
of when, and for what.
[airplane approaching]
German.
All right, Browning
let's have a look at it.
Doesn't hurt much.
This is not a break.
We have to reach the camels
as soon as possible.
If we don't
make an effort...
This little piggy
went to Benghazi,
and this little piggy
stayed home.
You sensible fella.
And this little piggy
had roast jerry.
Wilkins, don't you want
to reach the camels?
It's not me, sir, it's him.
[all laughing]
Get up.
I don't think
we can go on, sir.
The men
are worn out.
It's none of your
business, Bob.
Get up!
Ask me nicely, Major.
Death for death,
I'll take this one.
It's quicker.
[gun cocking]
[gibbering]
He's right off
his rocker.
He's gone farmy.
Nutty as a fruitcake.
Who is?
Wilkins or the Major?
Jimmy and Jane.
Jane and Jimmy.
Who's Jane and Jimmy?
(Wilkins)
Jane and Jimmy.
Jimmy and Jane.
[laughing maniacally]
[muttering]
Jane and Jimmy.
Jimmy...
Take a break.
All right, let's take a look
at that leg now.
Hadn't we better make sure
that Wilkins is all right?
He'll come out of it.
More than we will.
He always does.
All right, come on.
[gasping]
Yes, sir.
Fall in the men.
Come on, men.
Let's get moving.
[wind blowing]
Sergeant.
Yes?
Why do they call it
Crown City?
It looks
like a crown.
Does it?
Yes. Why, it goes in and out.
Tents and things.
Can't you see that?
No.
No. It looks like
Piccadilly Circus.
Yeah.
If the camels
are there.
Hmm.
Tired, Sergeant?
I'll be all right
for another five days, sir.
Soon as I get
my tablespoonful
of water.
[chuckles]
[wind howling]
[whistles]
I'm glad
someone isn't thirsty.
Evans.
It's Evans, sir.
Where are the camels?
[footsteps approaching]
Mokrane.
Capt. Leith.
(Barton)
It's Mokrane
and Capt. Leith, sir.
What happened to you?
I had to hide
from a German plane
after you left.
When that had gone,
you'd gone.
Mokrane knows
the desert.
Without him,
I'd probably
be dead, too.
Too?
The wounded
you left me to kill.
I left you
to save them.
(Leith)
One man to save three?
(Brand)
You should have waited.
Barton.
Sir?
Detail a party
to bury those men.
Sir.
Sergeant.
Yes, sir?
Get up a burial party,
will you?
Yes, sir.
Spicer, Anderson,
over here.
You broke the rules.
I know.
It's inhuman.
War's inhuman.
No good trying to shift
the responsibility.
What else have you been
doing all this week?
I have my orders.
What were your orders
about attacking
the sentry at Benghazi?
I've been in the army
for 13 years.
I still find it very difficult
to kill a man in cold blood.
But not to arrange for him
to die by himself.
You said the wounded
hadn't a chance.
Without Mokrane,
I didn't have a chance.
You're imagining things.
That's exactly what I mean.
What?
You're running away again.
(Brand)
And you are running
into a court martial.
Capt. Leith, if you've
any complaints against me,
we'll take them up in Cairo.
I suppose there was
nothing else to do.
About the wounded,
I mean.
I broke the rules.
What would you
have done?
I don't know.
I don't know enough
to break the rules.
Mmm.
You're lucky.
How many others?
The entire party.
Evans, too,
I suppose.
Yes, sir.
Camels?
No sign of them.
I see.
Any trouble with Lutze?
Not so far, sir.
This must've been
quite a city.
I can't make it out.
Berber, I think.
10th century.
Built, I suppose,
to protect themselves
from Arab invasions.
I'm not very good
in this period.
Ah, it's too modern for me.
Without camels...
how long do you think
it will take us
to reach headquarters?
I hadn't thought about it.
[camel grunting]
Blimey, the camels are here.
What about that bloke
Mokrane, then?
Come on!
# The camels are coming,
hooray! Hooray! ##
(soldiers)
Hooray! Let's go!
(soldier)
This is it.
[soldiers chattering]
[camel grunting]
Find any more?
[all chattering]
[soldiers yelling]
(Brand)
Load the documents on him.
Yes, sir.
Come on. Come on.
Leith, as soon
as the burial detail
is completed,
will you fall in the men?
We'll move out.
All right.
[bucket grating]
Here we go.
It's coming up.
[men chatting excitedly]
(soldier)
He got some!
[soldiers chattering]
It may be poisoned.
Cheerful Charlie.
I don't mind a bit
of arsenic in mine.
(Leith)
Get back, Wilkins.
Mokrane knows his desert.
Get back!
Yes, he knows
his jerries, too.
It's an old German trick,
poisoning wells.
How about letting him
take the first drink, sir?
We do not poison wells.
Then it will be all right
to drink this, won't it?
You'll take a Crown City
cocktail with us, won't you?
With or without
a cherry, jerry?
I tell you, we do not
poison wells.
Who is poisoning wells?
(Barton)
Mokrane's afraid the Germans
may have poisoned the well.
So, suddenly,
nobody's thirsty anymore.
[sloshing]
[coughs]
This water is not poisoned.
It's too soon
to tell yet.
Mmm-hmm.
Come and get it.
[speaking German]
Are you disappointed, Jimmy?
Would you be happier
if the poison were
burning out my guts?
Why did you drink
the water, Brand?
Was it to make yourself a hero
in front of the German?
We may be missing
an officer.
Drink, sir?
Thank you, no.
Well, I could fall in.
What's so funny?
Hmm?
Courage.
What about it?
It's odd
that you had the courage
to drink that water,
but you didn't have
the courage to
kill the sentry,
and you don't have
the courage to kill me.
Why should I
want to kill you?
Because I...
I saw the truth of you.
I wasn't afraid.
Yes, you were.
You were afraid to go in
and kill with your bare hands.
That's what makes a soldier
and destroys you as a man.
War is not murder.
[laughing]
Brand, you're wonderful.
You have the Christian decency
that forbids killing
a dying man,
but approves the work
of the sharpshooter.
Well, war is killing.
[laughing]
Better and better!
So the fine line
between war and murder
is distance.
Anybody can kill
at a distance,
with the same sort of courage
that a man shoots rabbits.
But when it comes
to the dirty work, you have
to call in the civilian.
What are you
trying to say?
That I despise you
for the professional
coward that you are.
You left me in the desert
so there wouldn't be
any witnesses left
to the real Maj. Brand,
didn't you?
Therefore, my death
becomes essential to you.
I'm a kind of mirror
of your own weakness.
And it's unbearable,
isn't it?
Are you trying
to goad me
into killing you?
[sighs]
Perhaps.
Why?
Perhaps, because...
I haven't the courage
to do it myself.
Nice work, eh, Brand?
Approved killing
from an approved distance.
They were the Arabs
you saw
at the water hole
with the jerry.
Weren't they, sir?
Of course, they were.
You sure?
What's the matter, sir?
Scorpion! Kill it! Kill it!
Look at his leg.
It's all right.
Where's the kit?
Yes, sir right here.
[men chattering]
Of course, he won't die.
Here, drink.
Huh!
Here.
Ah!
[groans]
(soldier #1)
Blimey! A gent with guts.
(soldier #2)
Knock it off.
[groans]
[panting]
There's nothing
in the kit for this?
(Brand)
It wasn't foreseen
in regulations.
It may help you.
If it gets worse,
we can always
put you on a camel.
(Wilkins)
Then who'll carry the water
and the documents? Eh?
(Barney)
Exactly.
[groaning]
[camel grunting]
Mokrane!
You want to kill me, too?
Ammonia. I should have
thought of that.
Finest medicine chest
in the desert is a camel.
It could save him, sir.
You call it saving?
[groaning]
Pity about the camel.
Might have saved one of us,
mightn't it, Major?
Now we have to go on.
Divide the water
and the documents
among yourselves.
Yes sir.
Come on.
Ah!
[coughing]
Barton, fall in the men.
Yes, sir.
Come on, men. Fall in.
(Barton)
All right, sir?
I'll give you a hand.
(Barton)
Here you are, Barney.
That's fine.
(Barton)
Come on, then.
All right, sir.
I've got him.
(Barton)
Wilkins and I'll
look after him, sir.
All right.
Captain doesn't look
too good, does he?
No, he doesn't, poor devil.
Everything all right?
Yeah.
Don't see anything?
No.
Keep your eyes open.
Yeah.
I could do with some sleep.
Aye. So could I.
Maj. Brand.
Mokrane?
What's the matter?
I'm going to kill you.
I know you saw the...
[groaning]
[gun firing]
He tried to kill me.
Is it that easy to kill?
I'm afraid Capt. Leith
is pretty bad, sir.
Can he walk?
I don't think so.
Barney's afraid
it's gangrene.
(Brand)
If we left him
half our water...
And he has a gun.
To shoot himself with
when he runs out of water?
This is from my orders:
"You must not be captured
by the enemy.
"If it endangers your mission,
you are not obliged
to save the wounded."
But that's...
That's not war, sir.
Isn't it?
I'll stay
with Capt. Leith, sir.
No.
I can't spare you.
I'm sorry, James.
But I hoped you would feel
more fit today.
Prepare to move, Sergeant.
Yes, sir.
Is there anything
I can do for you, sir?
Take over, Mr. Barton.
Get the men started.
I have to talk
to Capt. Leith.
But, sir l... I...
Take over, Mr. Barton.
We're all murderers now,
aren't we?
Welcome to the club.
Don't be a fool, Leith.
I want to get you
out of this if I can.
So I see.
I wonder
if you have the courage
to finish me off now.
You said you wanted to die.
Did I?
(Brand)
Whatever I did,
you drove me to it,
with your
insinuations
about Jane.
Your insinuations.
Not mine.
You're not the sort of man,
Brand, who'd...
who'd kill for his woman.
But you'd...
murder...
to stop her from finding out
that you're a coward,
wouldn't you?
Brand, the returning hero.
The stuffed dummy...
with the medal on his chest.
And all the witnesses dead.
Mokrane dead.
Leith.
My veins full of poison.
You're...
You... you're not a man, Brand.
You're an empty uniform,
starched by authority,
so that it can stand up
by itself.
But I'm standing.
Yes. Yes.
You're right.
You know, Brand,
for the first time,
I almost have
some respect for you.
You'd better go now.
You'll miss the column.
Is there anyone to notify?
Mrs. Brand.
Any message?
Tell her she was right
and I was wrong.
And ask her to
to forgive me.
[wind howling]
Now,
if you haven't got
the courage to kill me,
don't try to save me.
Huh!
[wind howling]
(Leith)
Stop! You'll walk
to your death!
(Brand)
Don't you try to save me.
I contradict myself.
I always contradict myself.
Dig in!
Can we hold out?
How much longer will it last?
Ghibli can blow 24 hours, sir.
Or minutes.
Leith and Brand,
we've got to get back to them.
We can't, sir.
Unless this lifts.
[wind howling]
The ghibli must've killed him.
Wilkins.
Here, take this.
There they are.
...my lucky man!
[all yelling]
[all cheering]
Barton, Barney, come on.
Sir.
(soldier)
What happened?
(Barney)
Oh, no.
[soldiers chattering]
[door opening]
Sir.
Ah, Mrs. Brand.
I'm glad you're here.
I've just had some news.
Eight men and two officers
are on their way back.
Which officers?
I beg your pardon?
We don't know yet,
I'm afraid.
(Paterson)
Michael.
Coming, sir.
Excuse me. The General's
waiting for me.
(Paterson)
Any news?
(Callander)
I'm afraid not.
Still the same numbers.
Eight men and two officers.
I wish I knew
who they were.
(Paterson)
You send an operation
out like that,
you expect casualties.
I'm prepared to accept that.
[inaudible conversation]
(soldier)
Hey! The group from Benghazi!
[soldiers cheering]
Hello, Brand.
I'm glad to see you got back.
Will you bring your stuff
into the office, right away?
The General's waiting
for your report.
David! I'm glad
to see you back.
Well done. Splendid,
splendid show.
Start on these
right away, will you?
Yes, sir.
I hope what we've brought back
is of some help, sir.
So do I.
May I ask your permission
to leave for a few minutes?
What?
Oh, yes.
Yes, of course.
Don't go away, though.
I want to see the men
with you.
Thank you, sir.
It's good to have
you home, dear.
I'm proud of you.
[men chattering]
I suppose you'd like to know
what happened to Leith.
Yes.
[chattering]
The men think I killed him.
Did you?
I wanted to save him,
but it was too late.
Anything else?
Just before the ghibli
struck us, he was saying:
"Tell Jane..."
And then the wind
drowned him out.
I suppose he
would have said:
"Tell Jane I love her."
Those would have been
my last words, too.
(Paterson)
Where is the hero of Benghazi?
[soldiers muttering]
(Wilkins)
Here he comes.
Here he comes, the old man.
(soldier)
Attention.
First, may I
congratulate you.
All of you.
From what I've seen
of the stuff
you brought back,
I think I can assure you
that Gen. Rommel
is shortly going
to find himself
in a very delicate situation.
And I have the authority
and pleasure
to award to the man
who led you,
Maj. David Brand,
the Distinguished
Service Order.
Those who did not come back,
when I write
to their families,
I will do my best
to tell them
exactly what happened.
May I say how proud I am
to have had you all
under my command
for this operation.
That's all, I think.
Fall out. Get some rest.
[soldiers muttering]