ADULT ANTONIO: Why is
there evil in the world?
Let me start
from the beginning,
when I was innocent of the
ways of God, and men.
It was the summer
when I was seven.
The summer Ultima came to us.
Papa! Mama! Mama!
Mama, they're coming!
Deborah! Theresa!
They're here.
Is Ultima really a witch?
No. And you will call
her La Grande.
I'm afraid.
Mind your manners!
We are honored that she
comes to live with us.
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BOTH CHUCKLE) Come, come.
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
What beautiful daughters
you have raised. (LAUGHS)
Toño.
Antonio.
Antonio?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Antonio, Grande.
ULTIMA: Let it be.
This was the last child
I pulled from your womb.
I knew there would be
something between us.
I've come to spend the last
days of my life here, Antonio.
You will never die.
I'll take care of you.
(CHUCKLING)
(GABRIEL SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CONTINUES IN SPANISH)
It's too hot to be standing out
here and chatting all day.
THERESA: She's a bruja!
They sometimes
become owls at night.
DEBORAH: Mama says she's not a witch.
She's a curandera.
She won't hurt you.
THERESA: Why does
she have to live with us?
DEBORAH: Mama says she has no family.
Now, go to sleep.
(OWL HOOTING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
MAN: Marez!
(BANGING CONTINUES)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Mi hermano! He killed my brother!
(ENQUIRING IN SPANISH)
Lupito! Lupito shot him!
Lupito? No, no.
No, I don't believe it!
Go get your rifle.
The other ones
are at the bridge.
The bridge?
He took to the river.
(WHISPERS) Qué pasó, Antonio?
(SHUSHING)
My brother was just at that
bus depot having coffee,
when that guy went up to where he was
and shot him in the back of the head.
Oh, Dios, be careful, Gabriel.
(GABRIEL AGREEING IN SPANISH)
I'm sorry.
Maria, lock the door.
Ese Lupito,
the war's made him crazy.
(LOCKING DOOR)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Antonio, what are you doing?
I'm gonna tell.
(MARIA PRAYING)
(OWL HOOTING)
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Could be on the other side.
Hey. Yeah.
MAN 1: What about
the tall brush over there?
MAN 2: You gonna make
up the clearance?
(TWIGS SNAPPING)
Ssh! Did you hear that?
He's there!
There! There!
Run! Japanese soldiers!
Japanese soldiers!
NARCISO: Put
those rifles away!
No! He's down there!
He's an animal.
He's gotta be shot!
No! We need
to talk to him!
Marez is right.
Marez is right!
Por Dios, hombres!
Let us act like men!
That's Lupito out there!
You all know Lupito.
You know the war made him sick!
Go back to your drinking,
Narciso.
Leave this job to men.
That animal crawled behind my
brother, and took his life.
He's gotta be destroyed!
Wait!
(GRUNTING)
I will talk to him!
Lupito!
It's me, Narciso!
Listen, my friend.
A very bad business
has happened tonight.
Let me come down
and talk to you.
Let me help you.
Remember before
you went to the war.
When you first came into the
Eight Ball to gamble a little?
Remember how I taught you
how Juan Botas marked the aces
with a little tobacco juice,
and how you beat him?
Those were good times, Lupito!
Those were good times!
(SCREAMING)
That's your answer!
(WHIMPERING)
(GUNS COCKING)
(GASPING)
Bless me.
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
I'm heartily sorry
for having offended Thee,
and I detest all my sins because
of Thy just punishments.
Oh, my God, I'm heartily sorry
for having offended Thee.
(OWL HOOTING)
You knew.
Yes.
They killed Lupito.
Will he go to Hell?
That's not for us to say.
And the men on the bridge?
Papa?
Men will do as they must.
MARIA: Gabriel, get up!
(SPANISH SONG PLAYING)
Go, go. We go.
(WOMAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BOY SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
La bruja.
(CONTINUES IN SPANISH)
Hey. Hombre!
(APOLOGIZING IN SPANISH)
I don't believe you.
(BOYS EXCLAIMING)
(CUSSING IN SPANISH)
Hey, there's that kid again.
Hey, kid, come here.
What, you scared or something?
Come on!
(GRUNTING)
Darn, did you see that?
BOY: Whoa!
The kid threw me!
They call me Horse.
Shake hands.
No, thanks.
Smart kid.
Shut up!
Listen, kid, don't think you
could do it again, understand?
(GIRL SPEAKING SPANISH)
Mass is starting!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
We are very
lucky today. Mira.
Gordolobo.
Good for throat and lung,
fever, infections.
No, no, no!
Speak to it.
It is alive, like all things,
like the trees,
the rocks, the river...
You must speak to it before you
take it from its home. Mira.
To all you who dwell
here by the river.
You that dwell here
by the river.
ULTIMA: We lift you
to make good medicine.
ANTONIO: We lift you
ADULT ANTONIO: There is a
beauty in the time of day,
and the time of night,
and there is peace in the
river and in the hills.
Ultima taught me to listen to the
mystery of the living earth,
and to feel complete in the
fulfillment of its time.
(CHUCKLING)
What's that?
It's the spirit of the river.
Can it speak?
Yes, listen.
What's it saying?
(CHUCKLING) Ay, my child,
you want to know so much.
Toño.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GRUNTING)
Pedro!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
And La Grande, you know,
has come to live with us.
(PEDRO GREETING IN SPANISH)
Papa sends
his blessings to you.
(THANKS IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
How is Papa?
He's well.
He sends his love.
And our brothers?
Um, Lucas, he's...
He's very bad.
Even the great doctor
in Santa Fe cannot help him.
A few of our cows
wandered away, so...
So Lucas crossed the river
to look for them.
(SIGHS) He walked toward
a grove of cottonwood trees.
An evil place.
He'd been warned before
not to go there,
but, Lucas, he...
He doesn't listen.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
He came up on the three daughters
of Tenorio Trementina.
(CHANTING IN SPANISH)
He saw them pour the blood of a
beheaded rooster into a pot.
(CHANTING IN SPANISH)
(SIGHS) Within the week
he got sick.
And now so many weeks later,
he lies in bed wasting away.
(MARIA GASPS)
He's dying.
MARIA: Did you go
to the priest?
PEDRO: The priest came
and blessed the house.
You know, the priest
in El Puerto, he...
He washes his hands
of the whole matter.
(SNIFFLING)
Ay, Pedro Luna,
you're like an old lady who sits and
talks, and wastes valuable time!
You will go?
Yes, I will go.
But you must understand, that when
one tampers with the fate of a man,
a chain of events is set in
motion that no one can control.
Can you accept
that responsibility?
Sí. On behalf of my brothers.
Good.
Antonio will have
to go with me.
What? What for? Why?
ULTIMA: It must be so, if you
want your brother cured.
It will be good for
Antonio to see his uncle.
He's not going to visit.
Antonio?
Antonio, you wanna
help your uncle?
(AGREES IN SPANISH)
And if someone says that
you walk with a curandera,
will you be ashamed?
No, Ultima.
I will be proud.
Good! Let's go.
We waste precious time.
ULTIMA: It's a good sign.
They call this valley
El Puerto de la Luna.
Because it is the door
through which the moon
passes on its journey
from the east to the west.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hola, Grandpa.
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
Médica, my son is dying.
Abuelo, I have the cure
for your son.
Like old times.
I will pay you in silver
if you save my son's life.
$40 to cheat la muerte.
It's been many years since a
curandera has come to cure.
There are women who are already
mourning your son's death.
Ah, neighbors.
Get rid of them.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Is Tenorio in his dog hole
that he calls a saloon?
Wait!
I'll have Pedro and Juan
go with you.
I don't need them
to deal with Tenorio.
My grandson!
Antonio goes with me.
Venga, mijo.
Are you afraid, Antonio?
No.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
TENORIO: Show me
what you have.
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
Tenorio Trementina!
Are you afraid
to face an old woman?
What do you want, bruja?
(LAUGHS)
Ay, Tenorio.
You're as ugly
as the devil will allow.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I am a curandera.
It's your daughters
who are witches.
(SCOFFS) You lie, vieja!
Tenorio, I know
about the curse.
And I know when
and where it was laid.
And you're a fool if you
don't tell them to lift it.
Bruja! You shame my daughters and
my good name in front of these men.
I will see you dead.
Don't threaten me, Tenorio.
You well know the power
of my medicine.
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
I tried to reason with you.
Do not harm
my daughters, bruja!
ULTIMA: They chose
to tamper with fate.
Pity the consequences.
(WIND HOWLING)
I grew worried.
La curandera!
ULTIMA:
Is everything ready?
(GRANDFATHER AGREEING
IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WISHING LUCK IN SPANISH)
(DOOR OPENS)
Lucas.
He has been like that
for the last two weeks.
Beyond hope.
ULTIMA: Life is never
beyond hope.
Go. Go now.
Antonio, make the fire.
It'll be difficult.
They made him wait too long.
Why did they wait?
The priest would not allow your
grandfather to send for me.
He's afraid of Tenorio.
Drink, Lucas.
(GROANING)
Drink. Un poquito.
Un poquito, Lucas.
(CONTINUES GROANING)
Drink. Lucas.
Lucas, drink this.
Un poquito.
I believe they had his fresh
cut hair to work with.
The curse is very strong,
and his strength is gone.
Will he die?
ULTIMA:
They stole his soul.
We must get it back.
At the cantina, you weren't
afraid of Tenorio.
No, mijito.
Good is always
stronger than evil.
Always remember that, Antonio.
The smallest bit of good
can stand against all the
powers of evil in the world.
(DISTANT HOWLING)
(LAUGHS) Oh, those,
Trementina girls
will be all cut and
bruised in the morning.
(WIND BLOWING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
Ultima. Ultima.
(OWL HOOTING)
(OWL SCREECHES)
(GASPS)
(DOOR OPENS)
There is no fever.
The blood of the Lunas
is strong in you.
We have beaten
the death spirit.
Now, all that remains is for
him to vomit the curse.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You have done evil.
But good is stronger than evil,
and the evil you did
will fly in your faces.
(SHIVERING)
(MOANING)
(GROANING)
Lucas. Lucas.
Drink this.
There we go, just a
little, just a little.
(LUCAS GROANS)
(YELLING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
Let it out. Let it out.
Let it out! Let it out!
Ah.
(SOBBING)
We will burn this by the tree
where the witches dance.
Your son lives, old man.
Papa.
Lucas!
(THANKING GOD IN SPANISH)
Do not tire him
too much at first.
(THANKING IN SPANISH)
Médica, I can never repay you
for saving my son's life.
Perhaps someday
the men of El Puerto
will save my life.
Antonio, vámonos.
(THANKING IN SPANISH)
We must burn this.
ADULT ANTONIO: The doctors and
their medicines had failed.
The priests had failed.
ULTIMA: Take us to the river where
Lucas saw the witches dance.
(AGREEING SPANISH)
ADULT ANTONIO: Was Ultima's
magic stronger than the saints?
And the Holy Mother Church?
It was Mauricio's oldest boy.
He was crushed
beneath a tractor.
That's right.
He... He worked the potato
fields in Colorado.
VAQUERO: Now, his other boy,
he runs whiskey in Texas.
You know, to the cotton
fields in the dry counties.
Mauricio? Does he
run whiskey too?
Mauricio? He just runs
from his wife.
(ALL LAUGHING)
ADULT ANTONIO: When my father's
friends, the vaqueros came to town,
they always found
their way to our table.
I liked to watch my father
reminisce about the old times,
because for a while
he was happy.
Other times he'd curse the war
that had taken my brothers
so far away from home,
and from his dream of moving
us all to California.
When do you plan to go?
When my boys come back
from the war.
Then we'll all go together.
You know, there's... There's
lots of work out there,
and now with the war and all.
As I said, there's work
in Texas too!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(TOASTING IN SPANISH)
GABRIEL: Oh!
MARIA:
My man of learning.
The last one to leave me.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ Tony's going to school! ♪
Theresa, stop!
He should be a scholar.
Perhaps a priest,
a man of the people.
Remember you are a Luna.
And a Marez.
Deborah, take him
to Miss Maestas.
She knows my family.
Sí, Mama.
My scholar.
Ooh! A scholar already,
and only on your first day
of school, mijo? (CHUCKLES)
You know, in my day only the
rich got to go to school.
My father, he gave me a saddle
blanket and a wild pony,
and he said, "There, the
llano, there's your life."
Ves, mijito?
That's why we live here,
on this dry piece of dirt
where nothing grows,
so your father can be close
to his old Marez ways.
Mijo, why don't you
ask your mom,
what was it that made her
fall in love with me, huh?
Was the sweat of the horse
in my clothes,
or its smell on my hands that
made her fall so in love with me?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
DEBORAH:
Time to go, Mama.
Yes, it's time to go.
Yeah, so it is.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Theresa?
Mis hijos! All right. Remember,
be respectful to your teachers.
And Antonio, suerte.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Give Miss Maestas
my blessings, hmm?
(SCREECHING)
(BOY SCREAMING)
Vitamin Kid!
Who?
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
(EXHALES)
Your classroom's over there!
Good morning!
Como te llamas?
Antonio Marez.
My mother said
to send you her blessings.
Hmm.
"Antonio Marez."
You wanna learn to write?
(AGREES IN SPANISH)
Good, come in. Let's put
you next to Melissa.
Melissa, this is Antonio.
(CLEARING THROAT) Up!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Attention, class,
it's lunchtime.
You'll obey Marisol
until I return.
(GIGGLING)
(GIRL LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
This is cardo lechero,
good for cleansing the liver.
We have some in the house.
Ah, mira, this...
This is marrubio
for when you have a cold.
You can make candy with that.
ULTIMA: Antonio!
Antonio!
Andrew! Leon! Eugene!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHING)
Mama!
Hola! Hola, Papa!
(CHUCKLING)
So, tell me
all about California.
Well, we were only there
a few months, Papa.
Tell us about the war!
It was all right.
Like heck, it was!
Eugene, shame!
In front of La Grande!
Did you see
all the vineyards, huh?
Ay, Dios mio. It was
so hard without you.
It'll be all right now, Mama.
Híjole! You know,
I would give anything to move
to California right now!
Gabriel...
They've just returned.
Ay, mi amor,
I don't mean tonight.
Mis hijos.
Do you get to punch
the buttons on the, um...
ANDREW: Cash register?
Yeah.
That'll come later.
For now I work
mostly in the back.
Gotten any faster?
Think you could beat me?
Race you across!
(CHUCKLES)
It's him, the Vitamin Kid!
Let's go!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(ALL PANTING)
Ah, who the heck was that?
The Vitamin Kid.
Nobody could beat him.
Some day you'll beat him,
Tony. Some day.
(SIGHS) See you after work.
What is sin, anyway?
It's not doing the will of God.
Is it a sin to do this? Yes.
Why?
It's a bad sign.
But nothing happens
when I do it.
You will be punished.
When?
When you die.
What if I go to confession?
Then your sins are forgiven,
your soul is clean
and you're saved.
You mean I can go out and sin,
throw the finger,
say bad words,
steal, do a million bad things,
and when I'm about to die,
just go to confession
and I go to heaven?
Yes, if you're
sorry you sinned.
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Hey, Tony, you missed a fight.
That was a real
good tackle, Horse.
Now let me up.
Did you see the fight?
It was funny when Willie
peed on Roque's shoes.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, how come Willie
and those farmer kids
don't have to go to catechism?
'Cause they'd miss
the bus, stupid!
Protestants don't
have to go either.
They go to Hell!
No, they don't!
You're going to
Hell too, Florence.
You don't believe in God.
If you don't believe in God,
there's no Hell to go to.
Hey, let's go tease the girls.
Why don't you believe in God?
I don't know. My mother
died when I was three.
My father drinks
himself to death,
and my sisters are
floozies working at Rosie's.
The old man hasn't been
very good to me.
You mean God?
So why do you
go to catechism then?
I wanna be with you guys.
You know, I don't
want to be left out.
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
We're gonna be late.
I would not have
expected you to be late.
I'll excuse you this time,
but take care of your company.
The devil has many ways
to mislead you.
You think this kind of
disrespect can be tolerated?
You think this is play time?
Let us pray.
(SAYING THE LORD'S PRAYER
IN SPANISH)
FATHER BYRNE:
Who made you?
CHILDREN: God made me.
And where is God?
CHILDREN:
God is everywhere.
(WHISPERS) At Rosie's.
How many persons
are there in God?
ALL: Three!
The Father, the Son
and the Holy Ghost.
They have to squeeze in tight.
If you die with a mortal
sin on your head,
where do you go?
Hell!
And is there
any escape from Hell?
ALL: No!
FATHER BYRNE: No.
You burn in Hell forever.
For eternity.
How long is eternity?
Without end.
Twenty years.
(SMIRKING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
FATHER BYRNE:
That is enough.
ADULT ANTONIO: The dark buds of
spring were on the branches.
And I understood why they
called the raging sap
that brought forth life,
the bad blood.
Now it ran through my brothers.
There were whispers in town
that they were wasting their
service money at the bars,
pool halls,
and even at Rosie's.
(GOAT BLEATING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(GABRIEL SHOUTING) EUGENE: When
are we supposed to come to you?
When are we supposed
to come to you?
GABRIEL: That's not
what I'm talking about!
I said, I'm working
days and nights.
EUGENE: And we're not working?
GABRIEL: No, you're not!
We're not working, huh?
What's this about?
GABRIEL: Now I'm trying to keep
you guys in line. I have work!
EUGENE: What kind of work
can you have for us here?
GABRIEL: I have
jobs lined up!
You are going to work
with me on the highway!
We don't wanna work with
you on the darn highway!
Eugenio!
Watch your language!
Do not defy your father.
I'm not defying my father, Mama.
That's enough!
EUGENE: Perdoname, Mama.
MARIA: Perdoname, Mama.
(EUGENE SPEAKING SPANISH)
What is it you want? Eh?
You've been gone so long,
and now that you've returned
you want to leave again?
What about California? EUGENE:
What about California?
We don't wanna
go to California.
We wanna be on our own
and make our own way.
Go to Santa Fe and work.
You are forsaking me.
We're not forsaking you, Mama.
EUGENE: Mama! We're men.
We have seen the world.
MARIA: Ay, Marez men.
The Marez blood draws
them away from their home
and their parents, Gabriel.
You still have Tony.
Thanks be to God.
You're not going with them?
I got a job here.
Figure I could do as well here
as they do in Santa Fe
or Albuquerque.
Will you miss them?
Sure.
Me too.
Will you become a
farmer like Mama wants?
No.
Will you become a priest?
(SCOFFS)
Thank you.
Okay, everyone,
class is dismissed.
Have a great summer.
Hold... Hold on,
Antonio, hold on.
Bye, Miss Maestas. Bye-bye.
Thank you so much.
Goodbye, boys.
Thank you.
Antonio, you're a little older
than most of the other kids.
And your progress
has been very good.
So, instead of passing you
to the second grade,
we're passing you to the third.
Gracias. I mean, thank
you, Miss Maestas.
(LAUGHS) Have a good summer, Antonio.
Y, suerte.
I'll see you next year,
Miss Maestas!
Yes, you will.
Hey, Tony!
Pass?
Yeah.
Come on, let's go!
One of them
has started melting.
(ULTIMA ASKING IN SPANISH)
The doll.
Don't touch it.
(PANTING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(SPEAKING SPANISH) Tenorio.
(ENQUIRING IN SPANISH) Tenorio.
He's drunk! NARCISO:
No, I'm not drunk!
Grande, you must hide!
Hombre! Hombre,
make sense!
Maria, put the children
in the other room.
Why do I have to hide?
NARCISO:
Have you not heard?
GABRIEL:
Heard what, hombre?
Ay, Dios mio, living on this
cursed hill away from town.
Today Tenorio's daughter,
his witch, died.
He blames La Grande for it.
(MARIA EXCLAIMS IN SPANISH)
Who told you this story?
Jesus Silva
came from El Puerto.
He said that Tenorio filled
some men with whiskey
and had them
spread his vengeance.
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
Oh, my God!
(MEN CLAMORING)
Wait here.
Papa!
Antonio! Antonio!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Antonio, you stay there!
Stay!
MAN: Gabriel Marez!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
We don't wanna
quarrel with you, Marez!
We only want the witch.
Who speaks?
Come, come.
You call me by my name!
You walk on my land!
I wanna know who speaks!
TENORIO: Our business here
tonight is not with you, Marez.
GABRIEL: You walk
upon my land!
That is my business!
TENORIO: We do not want
to quarrel with you.
MAN: We only want the witch!
Just give her to us.
We'll take her away
and there'll be no trouble.
Who accuses her?
I, Tenorio Trementina!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
And, you are idiota
with nothing but...
(ALL CLAMORING)
Wait! Wait, Marez!
We're not here to fight you.
There's not a man here, not one,
that doesn't hold you in respect.
You know that.
Pero, esta brujería,
this witchcraft,
it's serious business, hombre,
and the charges
must be answered!
Give us the witch!
There's no witch here.
ALL: (CHANTING) Give us the witch!
Give us the witch!
(CLAMORING)
Get away!
(NARCISO ENQUIRING IN SPANISH)
Why are farmers out playing
vigilantes when they should be home
sitting by a warm fire,
playing cards?
I know you're not men who need the
cover of darkness to hide behind.
You shame your good names by
following este idiota de Tenorio!
He has lost his daughter today,
and for that El Puerto
can sleep easier,
now that her evil doing
has gone to heck with her!
(CUSSING IN SPANISH)
I may be a beast,
but I am not a fool.
He calls you fools.
Enough of this talking!
We came here for the witch!
Give us the witch!
Give us the bruja!
Wait!
You know the simple test
for a witch.
Are these needles holy?
Sí. Blessed by the priest.
Take the holy needles
and pin them to the door.
No, no, no, no, no.
MAN: Just give us the witch!
Put them in
so they are crossed.
In the name of God, you'll know
that a witch cannot
walk through a door
so marked by the sign
of the Christ!
CRUZ: It's true!
It's legal in our customs!
NARCISO: But we all must
abide by the trial!
I'll abide by that test!
I'll abide.
But if she crosses it,
then she can never again
be accused for witchcraft!
We call God as our witness!
Who is it accuses me?
I accuse you of being a witch!
(OWL SCREECHES)
(MEN YELLING)
(MEN YELLING IN SPANISH)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
It's proven!
It's proven.
Her evil bird has blinded me!
I curse you, bruja!
Grande, come inside. TENORIO: Don't you see?
She's a bruja!
Narciso, I swear,
you'll pay for this!
I will see you dead!
Híjole.
What a night, huh?
Come on, my old friend.
I could use a drink.
(BIDDING FAREWELL) Bye.
Send my love to Grandpa,
and tell Mateo
he's still a lousy pitcher.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(AGREES IN SPANISH)
(WOMAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
Do you believe that God
will burn all the sinners
forever and ever when they die?
(AGREES IN SPANISH)
Do you think if God was a
woman, she would forgive them?
Like the Virgin Mary, she forgave
the people who killed her son.
I don't know, Antonio.
Why didn't you come
to warn us last night?
Well, your grandfather
wouldn't let us mix
in what took place yesterday.
But, Ultima cured Uncle Lucas.
Isn't he grateful for that?
Of course he is.
(SIGHING) You just
don't understand.
What?
El Puerto,
it's a small village.
We've lived there
for a long time.
We've never passed
judgment on anyone.
But you let Tenorio
pass judgment on Ultima.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
ADULT ANTONIO: The end of summer
was the time of the harvest.
My mother's family
had always been farmers
who took their only truth
from the earth.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
The chilis, corn and fruit that
would carry us through the winter,
they saw as sacred gifts from
the ground beneath our feet.
The harvest of my grandfather's
was my favorite time of year.
(MEN LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Okay, Papa.
Good night, Papa.
So, Porfirio Baca
told me about Tenorio.
He came back
from the hospital today.
He said he lost an eye.
JUAN: He told me that the
two remaining sisters
spent their day
making a coffin.
MATEO: No, no, no, porque they
were gathering cottonwood branches
and weaving them into a coffin.
God, that... That... That
proves that she was a bruja!
Because a bruja cannot be
buried in a regular coffin.
And they will burn sulfur
instead of holy incense.
And they will slay a rooster and
sprinkle its blood on the body,
so the devil himself
can come at night...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I love you.
I'm sorry.
Okay. Sorry.
It is true, man.
Mark my words.
Tomorrow when they bring
that bruja to the church,
it will be in a coffin
made of cottonwood branches.
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
HORSE: Hey, Tony!
BOYS: Tony! Tony!
Tony! Tony! Tony! Tony!
Who's your teacher, Tony?
Miss Harris or Miss Violet?
We all got Miss Violet.
All the dumb kids
got Miss Violet.
Is it true your brother's
been spending time
with the girls at Rosie's?
Knock it off. Everyone
in town goes to Rosie's!
Including Ernie's old man!
(CUSSING IN SPANISH)
Very funny!
But at least I don't have
a witch around the house!
RED: There ain't no such
thing as witches.
There are if you're a Catholic.
Bull!
Red don't know nothin'.
He's going to Hell
'cause he ain't Catholic!
ABEL: It's true. Protestants can't
go to heaven, only Catholics!
Come on, Tony, she's
a witch, ain't she?
I heard they were
gonna burn her.
She's not a witch.
You callin' me a liar?
Yeah!
BOY: Fight!
(BOYS YELLING)
Get off of him! Get off!
Come here. Come.
Come.
ADULT ANTONIO:
Winds swept across the llano,
and locked the earth
in an icy grip.
Our river no longer
sang the songs of summer.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Spring storms freed the land,
but still,
there was evil in the air.
(MEN ARGUING)
TENORIO: Let me go!
(NARCISO YELLING IN SPANISH)
(BOTH YELLING)
(BARTENDER YELLING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
I'm gonna kill that guy!
You don't have the agallas!
I'll show you agallas!
That means you seek
to do harm to La Grande!
I will cut your heart out!
I'll find a way
to get to that witch!
You get in the way,
I'll kill you!
(TENORIO CUSSING IN SPANISH)
Déjalo! Déjalo, vamos!
Nothing! It's only words!
It's only words!
Come in before you catch
your death in this cold!
Come on!
I'll buy you a drink.
No! BARTENDER: No. Come on!
No. I have to go
to warn La Grande.
Narciso!
You can't go to Marez
in the storm!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SONG PLAYING)
NARCISO: Let me in!
Let me in!
Narciso!
What's happened?
Let me in!
You're too drunk!
And I only allow gentlemen
to visit my girls.
I didn't come
for pleasure, Rosie!
I came to see Marez!
Which Marez? Don't
play games with me.
Call Marez!
Quién? Who?
Oh, Narciso, come in.
Come in.
No! No!
There's trouble.
You have to go to your home
and warn your parents!
What?
Tenorio!
He's making threats
against La Grande.
Is that all?
Come on!
NARCISO: Is that all?
He's made threats!
Where's Tenorio?
He drove off in his truck!
Just now we fought
in the saloon!
In the saloon, right!
You've been drinking
and quarreling,
and now you're gonna make
a big story out of it!
(NARCISO EXCLAIMING)
For the sake of your
mother, please come!
Come where?
You have to leave now.
You're making trouble!
(CUSSING IN SPANISH)
These girls
have turned your mind!
Just go!
(CONTINUES CUSSING)
Ah!
(BOTTLE BREAKING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(PANTING)
(GUN FIRES)
May your soul be
damned and go to Hell!
(SPITS)
No!
You child of that witch!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I'll go get my father!
No!
I'm dying.
I need confession.
I'm not a priest.
But you're pure of heart.
Confess me.
Come. Come.
ADULT ANTONIO: My father
went to the sheriff,
but he only had the word
of a small boy
as a witness against a man
of means and family name.
I wondered how God
could take such a man,
how he could let him sink
so quietly into the ground,
like the rain.
I wondered.
And in time,
no one remembered
anything good about Narciso.
Not long after, Andrew quit
his job at the grocery store.
And he dropped his plans
to finish high school,
to join Leon and Eugene
in Albuquerque.
(CHUCKLES) Thanks, Mom.
No one knew that
he had forsaken Narciso.
No one knew that he
couldn't face his shame.
GABRIEL: They've forsaken
their father.
My boys have left me.
It's my fault...
My fault.
I should have known that the Marez blood
in them would make them restless.
The same blood that set me
wandering when I was young.
Papa!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SIGHING) Oh!
It's time for supper, eh?
You know,
we're all just wanderers,
adrift at sea.
It's in the name, Marez.
Perhaps the Luna blood
should win in the end.
It's more quiet, like the moon.
(WHISPERING) Go inside.
ANTONIO: (READING)
"I believe in the Holy Ghost,
"the Communion of Saints,
"the forgiveness of sins,
"the resurrection of the body,
"life everlasting...
Amen."
Mmm...
I'm so proud of you, Antonio.
Just think, when you take
your First Communion,
all your sins will be forgiven,
and you will be
at one with God.
Really?
I'll be one with God?
Yes.
He asked me how many people
is there in one God.
What'd you say?
Three, four...
I don't know!
What about you, Tony?
I had to recite
the Apostles' Creed
and tell what each part meant.
(BOYS EXCLAIMING)
Bull!
Tony could do it
if he wanted to.
Tony's gonna be a priest!
I have an idea.
Why don't we all practice
going to confession
and make Tony the priest?
No, no.
Tony's the priest.
Yeah.
BOYS: (CHANTING) Tony's the priest!
Tony's the priest!
Okay! Okay.
I'm the priest.
Do it right. Yeah,
do it for reals!
Me first.
Bless me father...
Uh...
You have sinned.
Yeah.
What are your sins? Tell
him your worst one.
I know! I know how to do it!
Yeah!
One day, when Miss Violet
let me go to the bathroom,
I made a hole in the wall
with a nail.
ALL: Oh!
Then I could see
into the girls' bathroom.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Oh-ho-ho!
AGNES: You're dirty!
Give him a penance!
Okay, for your penance,
say a rosary to the Virgin.
Florence next!
Nah, that's enough practice.
Florence needs the practice.
Yes. Why doesn't
he believe?
Stop it!
ERNIE: Confess him!
HORSE: Confess him!
What are your sins?
I don't have any.
Yes, you do, you jerk!
Everybody has sins!
Just tell me one.
I don't have any!
Confess your sins or you'll go to Hell!
Yeah! Confess!
I haven't sinned!
God sinned against me.
Florence, don't say that.
Why?
It's the truth.
Why did he take
my parents from me?
Why did he take Narciso?
What harm did Narciso ever do?
We shouldn't
even listen to him.
He shouldn't even be here.
Give him a penance.
Make his penance hard!
No! There'll be
no punishment!
His sins are forgiven!
BOY: What?
AGNES: Punish him,
you have to!
I'm the priest. I've
absolved him of his sins.
AGNES: You're
a bad priest, Tony!
We don't want
you for our priest!
Punish the priest.
ALL: (CHANTING) Punish the priest!
Punish the priest!
Come inside.
Everyone!
Are you going to confession?
Yeah.
You?
No.
I can't.
I have to.
ANTONIO: Dear God...
I'm trying to remember
all the sins
I've ever committed.
Please forgive me for them.
Please forgive me.
Did he harm you in any way?
No.
Did he leave anything
by the tree, hmm?
Anything you might have
touched, or picked up?
No, but...
(SIGHING) The day
he killed Narciso,
he swore he would kill you.
Don't worry about Tenorio.
He's just an old wolf
who drags around the ground
where he made his kill.
His conscience
will not let him sleep.
But where there is no penance,
there can be no forgiveness.
(DOOR OPENS)
The door's opening!
It's a big day, Antonito.
Florence said the blood is wine
because the priest is a wino.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, my God,
I'm sorry for all my sins...
(SHUSHING) All good
and deserving...
FATHER BYRNE: Corpus Christi.
Amen.
BOY: Amen.
Corpus Christi.
(GAGGING)
Amen.
(CONTINUES GAGGING)
Tony! Tony! Go on,
you're holding up the line.
Dummy! You got us
all mixed up!
Darn!
I almost choked.
Do you feel anything?
I feel hungry.
(SIGHING)
ADULT ANTONIO: Now that
I was one with God,
I would ask him why Tenorio
was alive instead of Narciso?
Why he had allowed evil
to happen?
Why it went unpunished?
I called out to him
that now was a part of me.
Go in peace with Christ.
CONGREGATION:
Thanks be to God.
ADULT ANTONIO:
But there was no answer.
In time,
everyone got up to leave.
It was over.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(FARMER SPEAKING SPANISH)
ADULT ANTONIO: After Communion, I
spent more and more time with Ultima
whose wisdom gave me comfort.
I learned that the ways of healing
attended more than just the body.
And no road was too long for her
to travel to ease someone's pain,
or to lift a curse,
or cool a fever.
But often when
their miseries passed,
they shunned her just the same.
What'll you do this summer?
I don't know.
Play.
Fish.
Take care of my animals.
Go to El Puerto to learn about
farming from my uncles.
Do you wanna be a farmer?
I don't know.
Ultima says a man's destiny must
unfold itself like a flower.
With only the sun, earth,
and water making it blossom,
and no one else meddling in it.
She sounds like
a very wise woman.
Yes.
Goodbye, Miss Violet.
I'll come by
to see you next year.
Goodbye, Antonio.
(YELLING) Race!
You know that there are
hidden lakes in those hills?
You know, with mermaids
in them, right?
And they call you,
and you go to them,
but no one ever sees you again.
BOY 1: (YELLING)
I can't see him!
BOY 2: He's been down there
way too long!
They're not supposed to be there!
Something is wrong.
Hurry!
MAN: Where is he?
ABEL: He's under!
Hurry up!
What happened? It's
Florence, he's down there!
Bones dared him to go in!
He didn't come up.
Look!
MAN: I told you kids
not to swim here.
(SOBBING)
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
ADULT ANTONIO: Florence
died without confession,
without the grace of God.
Alone in death
as he had been in life.
Was he wandering in purgatory?
Would he burn forever in Hell?
I wondered if God was angry
with him for not believing.
But mostly I wondered,
if he even cared at all.
Tony!
Antonio.
(GASPING)
It's all right.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
MARIA: He feels
everything too much.
Maybe he's seen too much.
He needs to rest.
A visit to El Puerto
will do him good.
Women will take an hour saying
goodbye if you let 'em.
Papa?
Why is there evil in the world?
Ay, mijo, you have
so many questions.
Didn't the priest
talk about it in church?
But I'd like
to know your answer.
Oh... Oh, okay, well...
In that case, I'll
tell you how I see it.
I think most of the things we
call evil, aren't evil at all.
It's just that we don't
understand what they are,
so we call 'em evil.
Like, when Lucas, he...
He got sick,
and we were all afraid.
But Ultima, she wasn't afraid,
she understood what was wrong.
But, I took the Holy Communion
because I wanted to understand.
Understanding doesn't
come that easy, Tony.
Doesn't God give understanding?
(SIGHING)
Understanding comes with life.
As a man grows,
he sees life and death.
He's happy, he's sad, he works,
he plays, he meets people.
Sometimes it takes a whole
lifetime to acquire understanding.
But, mijo, in the end,
understanding simply means to have
sympathy, sympathy for people, yeah?
And Ultima...
Ultima has sympathy for people.
But with her, mijo,
with her it's so complete that she
can touch their souls and cure them.
That's her magic?
(AGREES IN SPANISH)
And in all this world
no greater magic can exist.
(CHUCKLES)
ADULT ANTONIO: All summer
I worked alongside my uncles.
I watched the care and the respect
they showed the earth and the plants.
Only Ultima showed such reverence
for the land and its offerings.
I learned that the phases of the
moon not only ruled the planting,
but almost every part
of their lives.
That's why they were Lunas.
They would not gather plants or save next
year's seeds until the moon said so.
I thought of my father too.
His wild and restless spirit,
that forever
reached out somewhere.
I didn't know if his or my mother's
blood would claim me in the end.
But the bad dreams that had
plagued me, did not come.
Antonio! A letter
from your mother!
They'll come for you
in a few days.
School starts early this year.
It comes early every year.
Your mother says
you do well in school.
You like school?
Yes, I like it.
Well, that's good.
A man of learning can go
far in this world, Antonio.
It makes us all very proud.
It's been a long time since
there was an educated Luna.
I'm Marez.
(CHUCKLING) That's right.
You're a Marez first,
and then Luna.
But I just wanted
to say that, ah,
that we're very pleased
with your work.
We know that you must choose
what you'll do as a man,
but if you ever decide
to become a farmer,
you'll be welcome here.
This earth that was your
mother's will be yours.
MAN: Pedro, can I
see you a minute?
There's trouble in town.
(INDISTINCT)
PEDRO: Antonio!
Something's come up, so we'll drive
you home today after supper!
There's only a few hours
of work left to do,
so, go to your grandfather's
house and pack your clothes.
Hey, if anyone asks
why you're back early,
tell 'em you got time off for
being such a good worker.
Okay, tío.
(CURSING IN SPANISH)
(GRUNTS)
I hope you've broken
your neck, you little jerk!
Eso vieja bruja has killed
another of my daughters!
I'll avenge her death tonight!
Do you hear me?
Don't you crawl about!
The coyotes will have sport
when they devour you tonight!
You, hijo de la bruja!
ADULT ANTONIO: My uncles
had betrayed Ultima before,
so I ran to save her myself.
I ran to save the spirit
that protected us from the evil
that men brought to our hills.
That had been there when the
heavens looked on in silence.
I ran from the river
and took to the llano.
(PANTING)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
PEDRO: Antonio!
GABRIEL: Pedro? Qué? Qué pasa?
PEDRO: Is Antonio here?
Qué pasa?
Aquí! Tenorio's here!
(GUN CLICKING)
(OWL SCREECHING)
Toño!
Antonio!
MARIA: Antonio!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GUNSHOT)
(PANTING)
Oh, my God!
Ultima?
Where's Ultima?
Antonio!
May God help me.
The owl!
It's dead.
Not dead.
Winging its way to a new place,
a new time.
When I was a child,
a wise old man gave me the owl
as a... As a bond
to the time
and harmony of the universe.
Evil men create disharmony
that reaches out
and destroys life.
But it passes away,
it passes away.
Gather my medicines,
and burn them
somewhere on the river.
Everything.
But take the owl now
into the hills,
and bury it at a...
At a forked juniper tree.
Go...
Go quickly.
Bless me, Ultima.
In the name of all that's good
and strong and beautiful
I bless you.
Go.
Go, quickly.
Grande...
(SNIFFLES)
ADULT ANTONIO: My father
built a fine pine coffin,
and people came from miles
around to mourn La Grande,
her cures and her magic.
But, I knew to look
beyond their sadness.
Ultima taught us how to make
strength from our experiences.
To hold wonder in our lives.
She taught us that the eternal
soul expands by embracing life,
and all that happens,
both good and evil.
No, I did not cry.
Her voice is everywhere.