[Orchestral music]
[Music continues]
[Bell tolling]
It's alright, doctor.
You can tell me, I'm not afraid.
Go on, I told you
I'm not afraid.
But you are afraid.
Afraid I'll tell you there's
nothing wrong with you.
However,
I'm not going to say that.
Because there is
a great deal wrong with you.
It's my heart, isn't it?
I know.
It-it pounds so that I can't
breathe sometimes.
There's nothing wrong
with your heart, organically.
You're sick,
but not in the way you think.
Don't try to soften it,
you see, I know.
I know that I'm going to die.
You know it because
you want to die.
You're willing yourself to die.
The physical examination
I made of you indicates
You are free from
bodily illness.
But you don't want to
accept that, do you?
You'd rather have me tell you
that your heart was feeling bad
That you were doomed
Than to tell you the truth.
- The truth?
- It's quite simple.
Something is making you
so desperately unhappy
That you'd die
rather than face it.
Then you don't believe
that I feel pain?
Of course I believe it, that
pain is pretty real, to you.
Oh, yes, the pain is there.
But it's there only because
something has happened
In your life that you
are not able to bear.
You've tried to forget it
and you've failed.
The pain you feel is proof
of that failure.
And so it becomes a pain
to hide behind.
And you want a doctor to tell
you that you are sick in body.
Because you can't face
the sickness of your soul.
But don't you see,
you'll get no release?
A bottle of medicine, a box
of pills or surgeon's knife
You'll find no answer there.
- Where then?
- Within yourself.
'Meet this inner conflict.'
'Understand it
and then set it right.'
It'll not be easy.
But I think it's the only
possible help for you
And for the man who loves you.
The only way I can help him
is by letting him forget me.
Our life together...
Has no meaning.
No meaning?
For you or for him?
Not for either of us.
Because of me, I've tried
to be the way I was before.
I've tried to go on,
but I can't.
I can't let him touch me,
doctor.
He's so good, he's so kind.
It's not-it's not fair.
But you shut him out.
The way you shut him out of
your heart and your mind.
He's suffered enough.
I'm not gonna let him
suffer anymore.
I'm not going back to him.
'He's waiting for you.'
But it's no use.
I have nothing left for him... or
for anyone.
Marise, I knew your father and
mother when they were alive.
I watched you grow up.
You were a child
well worth watching.
You always had courage.
- Have you changed?
- Yes.
That's not possible.
The girl I remember
faced life without fear.
She went to work to care for
her widowed mother.
Met the young fisherman
from Brittany one day
Married him the next.
No, that girl will
always have courage.
You are right about one thing.
When I first met Paul,
in those days I wasn't afraid.
From the moment he looked at me,
I knew.
I think he did too.
We talked and he told me
about his country.
The people and his fishing fleet
and his boat house in the sea.
All at once, it was
my country too.
Oh, we were happy, doctor,
so happy.
But it lasted such
a little while.
Why, Marise?
Why? Well, the war.
Paul was one of the first to go.
Then, few letters.
After that, silence.
Go on, Marise.
He was in a reprisal camp.
It was one of the worst.
[Instrumental music]
The place where the Germans
'Sent the most
dangerous prisoners of war.'
'Men who'd tried
many times to escape.'
'And he would try again.'
'Paul met a man there.'
'His name was Jean Renaud.'
[Music continues]
[Men humming]
Why did you start
that song again?
I won't get it out of
my head all night.
The first day
I met her in Paris.
They played it over
and over that day.
Let me see her picture again,
Aubert.
Wait for the light.
Be careful, Renaud.
It's her hair,
a man notices...
And her skin.
- White skin, red hair.
- I know.
"Carrot top," that's what
I used to call her.
Marise.
Marise. I like to say her name.
Then say all of it,
Marise Aubert, that's her name.
- Marise Aubert.
- Alright.
You've told me that before,
I know she's your wife.
My girl from Paris.
Born and brought up there.
You wouldn't think
she'd fit in
As a fisherman's wife,
would you?
'But she did.'
'She was so happy.'
- 'You know, that she was?'
- 'I'd stake my life on it.'
'She loved my people.
They loved her too.'
'As soon as they got used
to her funny little ways.'
There was one thing they didn't
understand for a while.
She had no use for keys,
always forgot to lock the doors.
"If they are friends, we don't
want them out," she said.
"If they are enemies,
let them come in."
"We'll make friends of them."
She trusted people... everyone.
You trust her,
don't you, Aubert?
Five years away?
You're still sure of her?
As I am of God.
Yes, I'm sure of Marise.
As sure as I am that someday,
someday I'll be going back home.
(Paul narrating)
Home, under my own flag.
To my own country, Brittany.
Where I was born and my father
and his father before him.
I'll go along the road
I know so well.
Yes, so well.
And all at once, there will be
that wonderful sea coast.
The place where you
turn off the road.
Our way to the house.
I'll be on
my own ground once more.
I'll look down at the
whirlpool, always changing
Yet always the same,
since I was a boy.
From there I can see
the path.
I'll start down.
A little way
and I'll come to the shrine.
It's been there forever
I guess.
As long as I remember, anyhow.
Marise never passed it
without touching it.
For luck.
(Jean)
Then?
(Paul)
When I get to the beach,
I'll look up.
And there will be our house.
Now, think,
as I always do
When I've been away
for a while
It looks lonely.
It never was though.
Not for me.
Not after
I brought her there.
Not that we had
many visitors.
The village priest sometimes.
Postman almost every day.
He was an old friend
named Alex.
Knew everybody.
And everybody's business too.
Oh, Alex.
Hello! How are ya?
Hello.
Who are you?
[Instrumental music]
(Paul)
She'd always forget
to lock the door.
"If they're friends, we don't
want to keep them out"
She said.
"If they're enemies,
why then... let them in."
"We'll make friends of them."
She trusted people.
Everyone.
Marise?
The cottage was very old
and simple.
Full of pleasant things.
Some mine, some hers.
She promised
there'd be nothing changed.
Don't matter how long
the war lasted.
We were proud of the piano.
It'd been my mothers.
She used to teach
the children of Kergat on it
In the old days.
My chair stood by the fire.
She sent to Paris for it.
It was comfortable.
Big enough for both of us.
[Instrumental music]
[Sighing]
Ah.
Ah, ha ha ha.
The kitchen
was always scrubbed
And full of good smells.
Only one thing wrong.
There was a gas jet
that whistled.
She was going to do something
about that but...
She never did.
[Gas jet whistling]
[Music continues]
[Piano music]
Paul!
I knew you weren't dead.
Oh, no.
I thought you were Paul.
I thought you were my husband.
Why did you think that?
That song...
How did you come to
know that song?
I've heard it often enough.
Your song, Marise.
My name, you know that too.
Why shouldn't I?
I've said it often enough,
over and over.
[Whispering]
Marise.
Yes, I know your names,
I know this house.
The chair by the fire,
the piano.
The gas jet in the kitchen.
'Glad you didn't fix that,
Marise.'
[Thunder rumbling]
The weather this time of year,
that's an old friend too.
Rain at night,
bright sky in the morning.
Even that dress your wearing.
One you bought in Morley.
"Expensive," you said,
"but good quality."
[Instrumental music]
Who are you?
Does my name matter?
Why did you come here?
How do you know these things?
Paul told you.
You know Paul?
I knew him.
Knew him?
Don't say it...
As if...
As if he were...
I wont believe that.
No, it's not true.
They sent me papers and...
And documents and...
I tell you,
I wont believe it.
I saw him die, Marise.
[Thunder rumbling]
I'm sorry.
They...
They said he was killed
Trying to escape
from the reprisal camp.
Go on.
Tell me exactly how it happened.
It won't be easy
for you.
Paul lived for one thing.
To get away,
to get back to you.
He worked out a plan
for an escape.
It was a long chance
but he was ready for it.
So were some of the rest of us.
And when the time came...
I found myself next to Paul.
Crawling towards
the barbed wire.
Just the two of us.
Cut off from the rest.
At first, luck was with us.
We thought we'd made it.
And then...
[Men speaking foreign language]
[Dramatic music]
[Grunting]
[Speaking foreign language]
[Gunshot]
[Whistle blaring]
[Thunder rumbling]
If only he hadn't tried
to come back to me.
Do you hate me, Marise,
because I had all the luck?
Why should I hate you?
You have a right to your luck.
To your life.
[Instrumental music]
[Sobbing]
Don't cry.
[Crying]
Paul.
[Sobbing]
Marise...
[Music continues]
[Sobbing]
Thank you for coming here...
And telling me.
I didn't come here for that.
I came here because I fell in
love with a woman I'd never met.
With you, Marise.
In the camps, a man has to find
something to hold on to
Something to keep him sane.
With Paul, it was you.
Talking about you.
And he talked to me, Marise.
And it kept me sane too.
Don't, soldier.
This is Paul's house.
And Paul's wife?
But Paul is dead, Marise.
And life belongs
to the ones who are left.
When Paul talked,
he shared you with me.
He didn't know that,
but he did.
If could have guessed
what he was doing maybe
He would have stopped,
but he didn't guess.
So you became mine too.
Oh, yes, you were there with me
as well as with him
And I kept myself alive
as he did
To get back to you.
Don't talk that way.
It's wrong.
- I won't listen
- Why?
Are you afraid to listen?
Has the waiting been long
for you too?
Or have you waited, Marise?
I've waited...
For Paul.
That first night you came here.
The curtains were open then too.
The beam from the lighthouse
touched you, and then...
No, no, don't!
[Instrumental music]
I'm remembering, Marise.
Help me to remember.
You have no right
to remember these things.
Please go, now, soldier.
Please.
[Music continues]
[Thunder rumbling]
Paul said this door
was never locked.
Against anyone.
"If they're friends,
we don't want to keep them out"
You said.
"If they're enemies... well,
then let them in.
We'll make friends of them."
Wait.
You know I can't
let you go out there.
I hoped you couldn't
send me away, Marise.
You can sleep here tonight.
But in the morning you must go.
Goodnight, Marise.
Goodnight.
[Instrumental music]
(Paul narrating)
She said she'd hide the tin
of English tobacco away.
And when I came back,
she'd have it ready for me.
There in the jar,
on the fireplace.
[Instrumental music]
[Crying]
Jean!
'Jean, help me!'
Jean! Help me!
'Jean! Help me!'
'Jean!'
[Marise sobbing]
[Instrumental music]
Paul.
[Sighing]
[Music continues]
[Train whistle blaring]
Paul.
[Window creaking]
[Birds chirping]
[Instrumental music]
[Music continues]
- Good morning.
That dress you have on
is the one I like best.
It was Paul's favorite too.
Marise...
I heard you crying
in the night, I...
I'm afraid I didn't tell you
the way I should have.
Well, it's alright.
It's morning now.
Yes, it's morning.
You said I was to go,
didn't you?
If I frightened you,
I'm sorry about that too.
But you must understand
how it was with me.
I didn't want to share
another man's life anymore, I...
I wanted to live it myself.
I wanted to know what it was...
What it was like
to come home to my own house.
My own wife.
Can you understand that, Marise?
Yes, I think I can...
When one is lonely.
Where are you from, soldier?
Where's your home?
Paris. Mormant.
And you, you're
from Montparnasse.
You know that too.
I know you very well, Marise.
Better than
anyone alive knows you.
You say that about me and...
Yet I don't even know
your name.
Jean.
Jean Renaud.
Well, you've no place to go,
Jean?
Is there no one...
No woman waiting for you?
No, no one.
I'm alone, like you, Marise.
But your old life?
Nothing to go back to.
I'm glad you came here.
You were Paul's friend.
His friend?
I don't know, Marise.
Can you call a man friend, or...
One minute your comrades
and the next
You're at each other's throat.
It was like that with all of us
in that place.
He must have trusted you.
He couldn't have talked to you...
Well, he did,
'cause he trusted you.
So I trust you too.
You'll want to rest
and-and, uh
Few days to get on your feet,
make some plans.
Paul would want me
to help you too.
Oh, it's not quite
all like that.
I'm being little selfish too.
'Cause you're right
about one thing.
I am alone.
You're never so alone
as when you're waiting.
Well, the waiting's over now
and it's time
I was of some little use
in the world again.
I think Paul
would want that too.
So you're welcome to stay here
a little while, Jean.
As Paul's friend,
you're welcome in Paul's home.
[Instrumental music]
Hello, Emile.
Beginning to look
like old times, eh?
[Speaking foreign language]
- A whole loaf?
- Yes, please.
It's a pleasure to see you
looking yourself again, madam.
Thank you.
A whole loaf.
- Instead of the usual half.
- Now, now.
Who's going to eat the other
half do you think?
That's not my business
or yours.
[Music continues]
Hello, Alex.
- Good morning, mademoiselle.
- Good morning, Monsieur Martin.
- Could you give me a moment?
- Why, yes, of course.
I think I found a buyer
for your husbands business.
(Marise)
'Oh, so soon?'
I hope you haven't
changed your mind.
Now that the fishermen
are out again
There's no one
to manage for them
Or to take care of their catch.
Thank you for your trouble.
- May I let you know later?
- Go ahead.
Uh, I'm glad to see
you're looking so well today.
Thank you.
No wonder she's looking so fine.
[Inaudible]
Alex,
you shouldn't spread gossip.
I? I only know
what the good ladies tell me.
You know how it is
when a fancy new hen
Is put in with
the old brown ones.
Cackle, cackle, cackle.
- Good morning, Father Donnard.
- Good morning, Alex.
[Instrumental music]
Jean?
Oh, Jean.
[Music continues]
Jean!
Where did you learn
how to catch shrimp?
I'm just learning now.
Come on down.
Come on!
'You're afraid of getting wet?'
[Music continues]
I have something special
to show you, Jean.
'Look, this is my own
private pool.'
I found it the first summer
I was here.
But the-there's something
about it that I haven't
Told anyone before.
Not-not even Paul?
Not even Paul.
Why not?
I was afraid he might laugh.
At what?
Why?
I don't know whether
I should tell you or not.
I won't laugh.
Well, then...
It's a singing pool.
- Singing pool?
- Yes, and when it sings it...
It tells you things.
Wait and see.
You'll hear it.
If you listen long enough.
There, do you hear anything?
I hear the ocean and the wind.
Nothing more?
There.
There's a kind of music.
Yes.
That's what I mean.
Stronger now.
Shh.
It must be the play
of the wind
And the sound of the sea
through these rocks.
Yes, I expected
something like that.
Makes a kind of... hum.
Sometimes you hear it better
over there
And sometimes better here.
Now I know something
Paul didn't know.
Carrot top.
- Marise.
- Yes, Jean?
It's been a good day,
hasn't it?
We've had a good day together.
A fine day.
- I've been almost...
- Happy?
It's been... easier.
Has it, Marise?
Is that wrong?
Tell me.
Is it wrong?
Do you feel that it is?
I don't know, Jean.
I don't know.
[Instrumental music]
There.
Now just try
and tell that those aren't
The best shrimps
you ever tasted.
Ah. It brings Mormant
right back to me.
Mormant or Montparnasse?
All of Paris.
You know, Jean?
It's no fun to cook when...
When you're alone?
Mm-hmm.
I'll tell you another thing.
You don't care much about eating
either when you're worried, so...
You don't cook,
you don't eat...
You don't live.
- Well...
- That was what you meant.
You're not eating.
Here.
Look at me, Marise.
Now, uh, smile again.
With your eyes too.
You're eyes show
what's in your heart.
There, that's better.
Not good enough,
but better.
[Instrumental music]
[Piano music]
[Laughing]
Why don't you play this,
Marise?
[Piano music]
No, Jean.
Not that one.
You'll play it for me someday,
Marise.
No, Jean.
[Piano music]
[Instrumental music]
Let go!
Oh, Jean... oh, put me down.
Okay, fine.
Oh, put me down...
I had a wonderful day.
(Father Donnard)
'Good morning, Marise.'
Good morning.
Good morning, father.
This is Jean Renaud, father.
He was with Paul in prison camp.
Ah, so you've come because
you are Paul's friend.
Hardly, father.
So you knew Paul Aubert.
You were privileged, my son.
He was that rare a thing,
a man liked by everyone.
Rich and poor, wicked and pious.
He was also the best fisherman
in Kergat.
The good women of the town
were quite put out
When he brought Marise back
from Paris with him.
Hey, my child?
I see.
For once,
the fisherman was the catch.
Father, may we offer you
a glass of wine?
Please, will you sit down,
father?
Only for a moment.
This is a busy day for me.
And early tomorrow morning
I go to the neighboring villages
'In Giles
for the pardons.'
The "pardons?"
That's what we call
these festivals here.
The people from all over
the countryside journey
Someone-for some by boat
to one of the shrines
To obtain the
intersession of a saint
And bring the blessing of God
into their households.
Oh, yes,
I've heard about the pardons.
And afterwards,
they drink a lot of wine
Dance all day
and make love all night.
I don't like
your implication, my son.
The church doesn't expect to
change human nature by ritual.
And what's more natural
than friends meeting
And enjoying themselves
after the services.
And making love?
Many couples
are honorably betrothed
At our religious festivals.
And that too
is natural and fitting.
I don't know your plans, but
if you're staying in Kergat
Can I help you
find a place to live?
I'm used to taking care of
myself, thank you, father.
Goodbye, my child.
I'll go a little way
with you, father.
Thank you, Marise.
Goodbye, father.
'Marise, wouldn't it be
more sensible'
'To change your wet clothes?'
[Instrumental music]
I know why you're crying
even if you don't.
- It's because I'm so ashamed.
- Oh, no.
That's not it.
It's because he spoiled
something by coming here.
What did you mean
by acting as if I were...
Your wife,
as if this were your house?
You're trying to make him think
you had the right?
You would have been in my arms
if it hadn't been for him.
Don't say that,
don't think it or I'll...
Or you'll do what?
Tell me to go?
- I'm sorry, but...
- Of course you're sorry!
Women love to pity.
Especially men who'll fetch
and carry for them
And be tamed as a dog
about the house
But I don't want your pity,
thank you!
- You'll get no more of it.
- That's good!
- But before you go...
- Oh, I am to go, eh?
Of course.
Don't you think
you'll miss me, Marise?
Look at yourself. That's the
face of a woman who's alive.
You didn't look like that
the first night I saw you.
Even those tears in your eyes
Are happier
than the one I saw then.
What's made the change?
Ah, you've been
alone long enough
With your thoughts of Paul?
But he's dead now and I'm not
gonna let you die with him.
You were his friend. Something...
Something overflowed
from him to you.
If there's been any change
at all, it's because of that.
If you seemed to belong in
my life these last few days
And I belonged in yours
It's because of that.
You're only here
because of Paul.
Only because of Paul?
I suppose I've... needed
someone to talk with and...
To be with...
I've liked you being here.
But it was wrong.
I was wrong.
[Instrumental music]
Marise, wait.
If you knew the way I feel,
you wouldn't be angry.
Once when the police
were chasing me
And some other kids through
the streets in Paris
I came to a church.
I ran in to hide.
I even pretended to be praying.
Then suddenly I was praying.
Me!
I didn't want to go back
to thieving in the alleys
I wanted to stay.
And that's the way I feel now.
You're the chance I want.
The chance I need
to be different. Better!
Oh, don't send me away.
I'd miss staying near you.
For a little while.
Just a little while longer.
[Music continues]
[Sighing]
Oh, Jean...
Yes.
Stay.
Let's go to the pardons
tomorrow, Marise.
Why?
Why does anyone go to the
pardons except to ask pardon.
[Music continues]
Yes.
I should go.
Why do you want to go?
Perhaps to... pray.
Perhaps to dance with you
afterwards.
[Music continues]
[People singing
in foreign language]
[Singing continues]
Marise.
Marise, it's like a holiday
When-when all Paris is...
[Dramatic music]
[Singing continues]
It is a holiday, but different
from any you've seen in Paris.
Oh, postman did come today.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Oh, look.
'That should please you.'
[All cheering]
[Dog barking]
Look at the sheep. They're
on their way to be blessed.
I have been
blessed already today.
I'm going to the pardons
with you.
This is the first pardon
since the war.
Seems as if the day
were blessed too.
[Singing continues]
Marise, let's go buy a boat too.
- Buy a boat?
- Why not?
There must be something
in the boathouse we can use.
Oh, Jean.
I haven't been inside
Paul's boathouse for so long.
Somehow I-I find it hard
to unlock the door.
Well, then, it's time
someone made you do it.
Remember, it's wrong
to be unhappy.
Here's the key.
[Singing continues]
It doesn't look the way
it used to.
Well, here's a row boat that
looks easy enough to handle.
[Door creaking]
Jean!
What's the matter?
How odd that his door
opened by itself.
No door opens by itself.
This one did. It did.
Then there must be a window open
somewhere making a draft.
I'll see.
[Dramatic music]
Jean?
Jean, what was it?
Just an open window, Marise.
Nothing to be worried about.
No, no. It's more than that.
Paul's here.
What?
He's... he's everywhere here.
Nonsense.
You're-you're just
imagining things.
Y-yes, I suppose I am.
It-it's true in a sense,
Paul is here.
No, I... I can't sell
this place, Jean.
Paul wouldn't want
strangers in here
Running his business for him.
He'd sooner have you.
What about that, Jean?
This could be
a good life for you.
Good future.
I can't walk
in Paul's shoes any longer.
I don't want to stay
where Paul's been
Where everything
reminds you of him.
But yesterday
you begged to stay.
What's changed you?
Nothing.
Something has.
Let's go away from here.
To Paris.
Oh, don't look as if
I had said something crazy.
You told me
you planned to go back
To Paris yourself,
didn't you?
You know you don't belong here
anymore than I do.
There're jobs there.
I'll get one and keep it.
This place is haunted.
You'll never be happy here.
Come with me Marise.
Someday I suppose
I... I'll be leaving here.
It's not my country anymore.
But-but not now.
No, Jean, I can't come with you.
Then stay here
with your ghost!
Live in the past if you like!
I'm going to Paris.
- You mean you're leaving?
- Now.
- Today?
- The sooner the better.
Then-then we're not
going to the pardons?
No, I'm not.
Here's your key back.
Oh, Jean, you know
how to be cruel, don't you?
Maybe, but not so cruel as you.
Goodbye, Marise.
[People singing
in foreign language]
[Singing continues]
[Bell tolling]
[Man singing
in foreign language]
[All singing
[Speaking in foreign language]
[Instrumental music]
[Singing in foreign language]
Thought you were gone for good.
I thought so too.
Found I couldn't.
[Instrumental music]
[All cheering]
[Music continues]
Here you are, ladies and
gentlemen, here you are!
Spinning Tantalizing
Wheel Of Chance!
Watch a few francs
grow into a fortune.
Fill your pockets
with this magic gold!
That's right, young fellow.
Let your pretty sweetheart
try her luck.
'Fortune smiles on red heads.'
Let's try our luck.
We're taking all sorts
of chances tonight.
You can win a lot
taking chances.
[Dramatic music]
(Marise)
'What is it?'
I thought I saw someone I knew,
but it wasn't.
Now let's try the wheel.
I feel luck's with me.
Here you are! The Spinning
Tantalizing Wheel Of Chance!
- Uh, thank you.
- Goodnight, sir.
- Now here's...
- How much is this?
- Well, 45 francs, sir.
- Alright, I'll give you 35.
No, no, no. I couldn't
possibly sell it for that.
- Well, we'll make it 40.
- Alright, thank you.
Forty francs, sir.
Alas! You have me
fight the devil!
[Screaming]
[Instrumental music]
Oh, Jean, what's this?
Real pearls as pink
as your cheeks.
Oh, as cool as the sea.
- Thank you, Jean.
- Thank the Wheel Of Chance.
Now let's dance.
[Instrumental music]
The latest from Paris.
- Pretty lady?
- From Paris?
From Paris.
Oh, you should see yourself.
Look.
Soldier, five Francs, please.
Oh.
Thanks.
[Indistinct chatter]
[Dramatic music]
- Where were you?
- I dropped something.
Important?
Oh, secrets, eh?
Well, I thought
we were gonna dance.
[Instrumental music]
[Marise singing
in foreign language]
(Marise)
'I thought I'd forgotten
how to dance.'
Do you know why I
came back today?
No, Jean.
[Instrumental music]
Now do you know?
Did that tell you why?
- Please.
- It told me something too.
You wanted me to come back.
- No, Jean.
- Yes, Marise.
You wanted me back
and when I leave again
You'll go with me.
[Music continues]
[Train whistle blaring]
[Instrumental music]
This is where my part
of the coast begins.
Smell that air. Did you ever
breathe anything like it?
Sounds like a man going home.
You're right. After five years.
Three days ago,
I was in a hospital.
And now, breathing my own air
I can lift up
one of my boats with one hand.
[Laughing]
There's the lighthouse.
Kergat Lights.
Oh, it's guided me home safely
past these rocks many times.
[Instrumental music]
Well, there they are.
One day,
she won't sell anything.
The next, it's all on the market
And she's leaving
on the first train.
I hear it's the soldier
that's changed her mind.
You're going to bid
on Aubert's business?
Hm, yes. I'm-I'm
due there now.
- Gossips will miss her.
- So shall we all.
[Chuckling]
Well, I hope
you won't let sentiment
Keep you from driving
a good bargain.
No doubt.
Or from finishing my coffee.
[Instrumental music]
All the records are here.
Just as he left them.
What's this doing here?
Oh, that's a keepsake.
Belonged to Paul's father.
Probably useless.
Sea air is not good for guns.
Somehow, I never thought I'd
find myself selling this place.
But what would we do
with boats and paddles?
[Music continues]
And I'm sorry we're going.
And I'm sorry
you belong with me now.
Do I belong with you, Jean?
For the rest of your life.
It means so much to you then?
So much? Listen to me, Marise.
I'll never let you
get away from me.
Remember that.
No matter what happens.
[Sighing]
What could happen?
Well, you know...
You could talk some more
about hating to sell this place.
You could go on
keeping ghosts alive.
But, Jean, my memories of Paul
take nothing away from you.
Well, I won't share you.
[Music continues]
We'll make our own memories.
We'll start
by getting rid of this.
Oh, no, no, Jean. No.
I didn't know that Paul
had kept it.
Ah, don't be angry.
[Sighing]
It's no good
to hold on to the past.
Jean, when we finish here
Would you come over
to Father Donnard with me?
Why?
His blessing would mean
a great deal to me.
Why not, then?
There's no reason
why the good priest
Shouldn't give us his blessing
And why we shouldn't take it.
You're not a religious man,
are you?
Only frightened people
are religious.
That's not true.
Don't say it.
Alright, it's not true.
I won't say it.
[Music continues]
[Instrumental music]
Hello?
Hello, there!
Come on up.
I'm late.
I confess I didn't miss you.
Hector Martin, Jean Renaud.
Oh, yes. I've heard of you.
The sharpest businessman
in Kergat, they say.
I've heard of you.
Well, I've come prepared
to set a price.
I'm sure it'll be a fair one,
Hector.
I'm glad that you're the buyer.
You knew Paul and-and you'll
run the business the way that...
Hector, would you mind settling
all this with Jean Renaud
Instead of with me?
I've been over
everything with him.
An-and, Jean, if you'll forgive
me, I'll meet you over
At Father Donnard's.
Of course, Marise.
Thank you.
- Good morning, Hector.
- Mademoiselle.
[Instrumental music]
It's all here.
Just what we have to offer.
A good business for someone.
Yes, it took Paul Aubert
a long time to make it there.
A very long time.
And much work.
Well...
You'll expect to pay well
for that effort, eh?
Thank you.
- Good morning, father.
- Oh.
Good morning, my child.
Well, sit down.
Thank you.
Father, I've been going through
some of Paul's belongings
And I found this.
And I want you to have it.
Oh.
I think Paul would
want that too.
Oh, thank you, Marise.
[Dog barking]
I shall cherish it.
You're sure of yourself, Marise?
And you're sure of this soldier?
You know my plans then?
Kergat is a small town, my dear.
I repeat, are you sure?
Father...
No man could ever
take Paul's place with me.
[Instrumental music]
But I've been so lonely.
I need someone to need me.
Jean does.
And I need him, father.
Someone to...
'Someone to do for
and care about...
'Once more.'
[Music continues]
'And to care about me.'
'A new life, father.'
'Not as good as the old one,
I know that.'
'But at least... a life
of some kind.'
[Music continues]
Paul.
Paul Aubert?
That's right.
[Instrumental music]
Paul.
Under all this,
you'll find Paul Aubert.
You, is it possible?
The report came.
It was official.
"Killed trying to escape,"
it said.
No, we forged.
The wall was full of reports.
All I know is I woke up in
a hospital instead of a coffin.
- Welcome home.
- Thanks.
You tell the men I'm back.
Tell 'em to get their boats
in shape right away.
First, I've gotta get home.
[Music continues]
Home. You know what that word
can mean to a man, Martin?
[Music continues]
And I was afraid
I'd never pass this way again.
Marise?
Marise!
[Instrumental music]
Marise?
[Music continues]
No, my child, it isn't wrong for
you to reach for happiness.
But are you happy, Marise?
Your face doesn't tell me
that you are.
[Knocking on door]
Come.
Your pardon, father.
Madame Aubert,
there's something you must know.
This is very difficult
for me and I...
- Yes, Hector.
- He's here. I saw him.
As I live, I saw him
walking down the street
As if he'd never been away.
Just the same,
except for the uniform
He spoke of the men, the boats.
Who, Hector, who was it?
Your husband, Paul.
- Paul!
- He's on his way home now.
I left him a moment ago.
Paul alive?
I should never have
stop believing!
[Foghorn blaring]
Good morning.
Where's Marise? She was
to wait here for me.
Come in, my son.
I want to talk to you.
If Marise has been here
There's nothing for us
to say to each other.
'I think there is.'
'Sit down.'
- You don't trust me, do you?
- I don't know you.
I wish I did.
Well, if it's the story
of my life you're after
It's not very interesting
from your standpoint.
I'm only a small sailor.
Nothing worth your while.
At the moment, I'd rather
hear of your virtues.
Oh, that's an even shorter list.
I was born in Paris,
that's a virtue.
I live there,
another virtue.
I worked a little, oh,
great virtue that.
I went to war,
I fought...
That is I fought
when they let me
I was in a prison camp
for almost five years.
I escaped, I met Marise,
I want to marry her.
- Virtues, all.
- Go on.
I love Marise. That's a word
I used to laugh at.
[Foghorn blaring]
Do you believe that
I love her, father?
I believe that you believe it.
Then, what else is important?
There are many kinds of love.
Some good, some bad.
- What kind is your's, my son?
- What do you mean?
If it's a good love, you go away
at once, you leave Kergat.
I intend to go tonight
with Marise.
No, my son, without her.
Where I go, from now on,
she goes too?
Paul Aubert is alive.
I have a feeling you knew that.
You did? What makes
you think so?
Alright, I won't deny it.
I did know it.
Paul Aubert is here.
In Kergat.
He's home and his wife
has gone to him.
'Be grateful,
that he came back in time.'
Grateful?
Yes, I am grateful.
Why not? I'd rather face
a man than a ghost.
'My son...
[Foghorn blaring]
[Dramatic music]
- Paul!
- Marise!
Marise.
Carrot top.
Hold me,
just for a little.
Kiss me,
just once more.
Once more?
A hundred times more,
without stopping.
- What's wrong, Marise?
- I shouldn't have listened.
- Listened?
- To anyone.
Why? What is it?
I should've known
you were still alive.
I should've kept
on believing.
Does it make so much
difference then?
It makes all
the difference, Paul.
I don't know
how to say it.
how to tell you.
It's not a new story,
these days.
No, it isn't.
But it's a story I thought
I'd never hear.
Not from you, Marise.
Go on, go on.
Paul, it was someone
who knew you.
- Who could tell me about you.
- Go on.
He knew you
in the camp.
He told me how... how you
were shot down trying to escape.
I never believed you
were dead until then.
Nor all that time without word,
not even when the report came
That you were killed.
Our life together here,
went on in this house.
That's how I was able to stay
on here, waiting for you.
Waiting for you.
Until he came.
And told me
that he saw you die.
I had to believe it then.
There was no way of knowing
that it wasn't true.
But you are still alive.
Yes, I'm alive.
Doesn't seem to matter much
now that I am, does it?
Why didn't you
let me know, Paul?
Why didn't you write?
Write? I did write as soon as
I could, from the hospital.
- When?
- Two weeks ago.
I had no letter.
No word. Nothing.
Are you in love
with this man, Marise?
Love?
With what was left of me,
I-I felt sorry for him.
He seemed so lost,
and I was lonely.
And me? What did
you feel for me?
Paul, I love you.
But with you gone,
what did anything matter?
I stopped believing
you were alive
And I promised to marry
another man.
I'll go away from here now, it's
the only thing for me to do.
No, you're my wife,
this is your home.
No, not any longer.
Not mine.
I haven't the right.
Paul, Paul,
what'll I do?
'What'll I do?'
I used to wonder what I'd do
if a thing like this happened.
I thought I'd want
to kill you.
I don't.
Not you, Marise.
I'd rather be dead,
than hurt you.
Who is he, Marise?
Tell me, who is it?
No, Paul,
names don't matter.
I think they do,
who is he?
Renaud,
Jean Renaud.
- How long has he been here?
- A week.
Perhaps, a little longer.
Maybe my letter did come.
Maybe Renaud stole it.
You think Jean
would steal?
He was a thief
and coward in camp
Why shouldn't he be a thief
and coward here?
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Don't lie to me,
Marise.
He's in Kergat,
isn't he?
You wouldn't be so frightened
if he were out of my reach.
Well, there aren't many
places he can hide.
Wait, Paul, let me go and see,
and let me send him away.
Why don't you want
me to find him?
Are you afraid for him?
No, for you, Paul,
of what you might do.
I'll ask him one
question, Marise.
Just one. Did he know
that I was alive.
Most people aren't strong like
you, Paul. Most of us are weak.
I told you I couldn't send him
away, but you didn't ask me why.
And that's important.
He didn't seem
like a stranger.
He seemed to belong here.
He knew about us, Paul.
Things that only you
could've told him.
If I told him
too much about you
It was only the way a man
might talk about his religion
To another who had none.
You shared our life
with him, Paul.
You shared me.
He was only coming
back to something
That he believed
was his own.
You can't kill a man
for believing what's wrong
When you yourself
taught him to believe it.
Give him a chance.
He is in Kergat.
He'll come here.
Give him a chance.
Alright, when he comes,
I'll ask him one question.
Just one.
You're tired.
I'll get you some coffee.
[Wind howling]
[Foghorn blaring]
(Marise)
'I won't be a minute,
Paul'
[Foghorn blaring]
[Wind howling]
[Branches cracking]
Who's there?
It's your friend Renaud.
You came back a little
too soon, old bear.
'In another hour,
we'd have been gone.'
[Foghorn blaring]
[Gunshot]
Paul!
[Foghorn blaring]
(Paul)
I did have one question
to ask you, Renaud.
I don't have
to ask it now.
[Gunshot]
You never were a good shot.
[Foghorn blaring]
(Marise)
'Paul!'
[Gunshot]
When all the bullets are gone,
what will you do then?
[Foghorn blaring]
Are you waiting
for me, Renaud?
'You gone as far
as you can?'
[Gunshot]
[Man screaming]
Aaah!
[Sobbing]
[Foghorn blaring]
[Bell tolling]
(Dr. Leclair)
The only cure for this sickness
Lies within you, Marise,
within you.
You can either learn and grow
from what has happened to you
Or you can be destroyed.
The choice is yours.
Yours, Marise.
(Marise)
A man died, because of me.
(Dr. Leclair)
No, Marise. Not because
of you.
That man was so formed,
so deformed by life.
That what he did was part
of his pattern.
The pattern he was forced
into by a society
Which, which sends its children
out into the streets
To lie and thieve
in order to live.
Remember this, the only
happiness Jean ever had
He had through you.
He came closest to redemption
through you.
Go back to him, Marise.
Go back to man you love
And who loves you.
Go into his arms,
naturally, gladly
Freely as you
did once.
Help him to build
his life again.
Go on together, Marise.
Together.
[Instrumental music]
[Music continues]