[Captioning sponsored by
Artisan Entertainment]
Radio newscaster:
This is the Australian
Broadcasting Commission.
And now the news.
Japanese forces continue
their heavy attack
on the Philippines
and Dutch East Indies.
Occupation of Manila
is now complete
with American
and Philippine forces
(explosion)
under the command
of General MacArthur
withdrawing
to the Bataan Peninsula.
His Majesty's forces
are carrying out
an orderly evacuation
of the New Guinea coast
in preparation for defense of
Port Moresby and the southern...
ah.
Yeah, yeah, ye
?? I got me ten fine toe
s to wiggle in the sand ??
?
?? Lots of idle fing
ers snap to my command ?
?
?? A lovely pair of heels
that kick to beat the band ?
)
(explosion
?
?? Contemplating nat
ure can be fascinating ?
??
?? And, you'd reason
, knows that I can bum
??
?? Hand 'em out, by gum, have I
?? To tell the whole damn world
t ??
?? If you don't happen
to like it, deal me ou
??
?? Thank you kindly
y ??
?? Pass me b
?? Pass me by ??
?? If you don't happen
to like it, pass me by. ??
Hey, hey, hey.
(explosion)
(harmonica solo)
(humming)
(explosions continue)
(whistling "Pass Me By")
Here, just a minute.
Where do you think you're
going with those, hmm?
am?
Do you know who I
Um, not exactly, no.
Well, we'll let
it go this time.
nd.
Yes, sir.
I understa
Salamaua will be
cleared by noon
the latest.
Nothing left that
the Japanese will
be able to use, sir.
Sir, there's a chap
outside who...
May I respectfully
remind the admiral
that I was harbor master here
for nearly 20 years.
I helped put the docks together
so I should certainly be able
to blow them apart.
Sir, there's
a chap outside
who's pinching our petrol...
l
Yes, sir,
all our coasta
watching stati
ons are assigned,
except, uh...
Matalava, sir.
ir.
Except Matalava, s
I haven't been able
to find a replacement
for Anderson.
I don't believe
there's a civilian left
on the entire
north coast.
d
We could h
ave transferre
ior
George Dickens
from the inter
.
if he hadn't
got himself
eaten that way
You needn't make him sound
such a shirker, Stebbings.
What's that, sir?
For want of a nail,
the war was...
Yes, I'm well aware
of that, sir.
Hello, hello, hello.
r.
I think I ma
y have found
our nail, si
A rusty one,
I grant you, sir
er.
but they don't
come any sharp
.
Excuse me, sir
Sir, that's the chap
I was telling you about.
He was...
Later, Stebbings.
Who is he, sir?
Is he someone
I should know?
His name's Walter Eckland,
an American.
He knows these islands
like the back of his hand.
Oh.
Oh, well, now that
America's in the war
.
he's probably
on his way
back to enlist
Eckland's not on his way
anywhere, Stebbings.
Hasn't been for years.
(humming)
Hello, Walter.
(stops humming)
Frank!
That you inside
there, Frank?
What have you
done to yourself?
There's a war on, Walter.
Everybody's saying that.
At the moment,
we're losing it.
Guess you must be.
Cheek of the man.
)
(whistling
That's quite
a boat you hav
e there, Walter.
Doesn't it belong
to old Vanderhoeven?
No.
en?
Whose is it th
Mine.
?
How did you get it
I bought it
from old Vanderhoeven.
h?
What wit
American dollars.
You've never had
more than $200
at one time
since I've known
you, Walter.
u
You can't tell me th
at Vanderhoeven sold yo
an $18,000 lau
nch for $200.
No. It cost me $400.
?!
$400
You know, that's exactly
the way he said it.
Only I pointed out to him
he might as well sell it to me
than let the Japanese
have it for free.
.
What impresses me,
Walter, is the fact
that you even had $400
Well, I didn't.
I only had $200,
just as you said.
I owe him the rest.
Well, come along.
Lend a hand.
Come on.
Empty hands
make idle minds.
Here, pick those up.
No, no, no, no.
Two. Come on.
?? Contemplating nature
can be fascinating... ??
?
You know what
the coast watching
service is, Walter
I beg your pardon?
ce?
The coast
watching servi
It's a chance
to become a hero.
Why would I
want to do that?
It's a cushy
assignment
for anyone who knows
these waters intimately.
With never a dull
moment, I can tell you.
Working behind
the enemy lines
No, no. Stebbings.
not knowing from
one moment to the next...
Please.
me.
Walter,
listen to
There's nothin
g to it, really.
Each man is assigned
an island, often
uninhabited.
He stays there alone
and he radios to headquarters
any movement of Japanese
ps.
planes
or shi
?
You're not listening
to me, are you, Walter
Hold it, hold it.
Hey, hey! Hey, hey!
Come on. Beat it!
Scram! Come on!
Get off!
Did you hear
what I was saying?
No. What were
you saying?
About the coast watchers.
Matalava will be
in the center of things
when the Japanese start
moving towards New Guinea.
It's important work,
Walter.
Damned important.
I'd like you to volunteer.
Oh, I'd love to, Frank
but I've only
just volunteered
for another important
watching service--
The Watch Out
For Walter Eckland service.
A great many liv
es are at stake,
Mr. Eckland.
Now, listen to me,
both of you.
Several years ago,
I made peace with the world.
Now, if the world
isn't bright enough
to make peace with itself
it'll have to settle things
without me.
It isn't anything
permanent, Walter.
It's just until I find
a replacement for you.
The other man
went down with fever
and we had
to take him off.
Well, now, Frank,
you've known me a long time.
Do you really think
you're going to talk me into it?
No, I suppose not.
Stebbings, confiscate
all the small craft
on this pier.
But this is
the only one
there is, sir.
Confiscate it.
Frank, you won't
get away with that.
Proceed with your orders,
Stebbings.
ir.
Aye-aye, s
Frank, you can't
do this to me!
I'll go over your head.
Who's in charge here?
He is.
Frank, you can't
do this to me.
That boat's all I have.
You said we've
been friends
for a long time,
Walter.
Do you really think
you can talk me
out of it?
If I go to Matalava,
I can keep the
boat, right?
Mmm.
Well, there's
no use fighting it.
ff?
What time do I shove o
An hour be all right?
Anything you say, Frank.
.
You're the skipper
Hey, buddy, lend me a hand
with those cans.
I'll get on board.
m
Uh, sir, you don
't really expect hi
to go to Matalav
a, do you, sir?
bor
As soon as
he clears har
n.
we'll never
see him agai
Where's your faith
in human nature, Stebbings?
(humming)
Oh, yeah.
(explosion)
Good heavens!
What is it?
He...
he made a gesture, sir.
(shouting):
You set a fine course,
there, Walter.
My compliments.
Yeah.
I should have led you
up on the reef.
It's a sorry day when a man's
friends don't trust him.
What about all those provisions?
You don't suppose that boat
of yours could carry them?
Frank, I want you to take all
those provisions
and I want you to...
Hey! Be careful
with that.
We'll be at King's Point
in Australia.
When you call us,
we want you to use
the following code:
King's Point is "Briar Patch."
I'm "Big Bad Wolf."
Stebbings here
is "Bo-Peep."
And you're...
"Mother Goose," sir.
That's it--
you're "Mother Goose!"
Now, try to remember
all that, Walter.
It's bloody
important.
Yeah-- bloody.
All right, then.
Good-bye, Mother Goose.
"Mother Goose."
(chuckling)
Let's get underway,
Stebbings.
Sir, it has occurred to me
that as soon as we've gone
Mr. Eckland might...
Proceed, Stebbings.
Hard to port.
All right, sir.
Coxswain, hard...
Excuse me, sir, but,
uh, did you say...?
Hard to port, son.
Aye, aye, sir.
Coxswain, hard
to port.
Hey, hold it, hold it!
Are you crazy?!
Look out! Look out, Frank!
Did you hear me?
Hard to starboard,
Frank!
Hold it now! Watch out!
Oh, you've gone nuts!
Look out.
Frank, can you hear me?
Hold it!
Starboard, you English,
silly son of a...
(crash)
Oh, great!
Have you lost your minds?
Look at my boat!
Terribly sorry, Walter.
Our steering must have jammed.
I'm sorry.
If you didn't know how
to work one of those things
why didn't you say so?!
I'm sorry.
Oh, stop saying that!
Look at my boat!
What am I going to do now?!
Become a coastwatcher,
I expect.
Lucky we put all those
supplies ashore.
Oh, Walter?
We'll stand by
until you get safely in.
Frank, I'll sue you!
I'll sue!
I'll sue the entire war!
Quite right, Walter!
I'll be your witness.
Oh, and Walter?
Thanks for volunteering.
(bird squawking)
Oh, come on. Buzz off.
(engines droning)
(squawking)
(loud, shrill squawking)
(sighing)
Houghton:
Mother Goose?
Frank!
I knew you wouldn't
leave me here!
Mother Goose,
this is Big Bad Wolf.
Go away.
I know you're saying something,
Mother Goose
but I can't hear you.
You've got to flip the key.
I said go away.
You're still not coming through,
Mother Goose.
There's a button
on the microphone.
You have to press it down
while you're speaking.
(belching)
Can you hear me now?
That's better.
You'll find some
charts there, Walter
identifying enemy ships
and aircraft.
Study them, will you?
Oh, sure.
Have you seen anything yet?
Any planes or ships?
Yes, a plane.
Ours or theirs?
Kind of depends which side
you're on, doesn't it?
Walter,
news has just come through
that the Japanese
took Singapore this morning.
Frank...
(clearing throat)
What keeps them
from taking Walter Eckland?
We've 32 spotters
spread over 3,000 islands.
So, you see, the odds
are in our favor
that you'll never be found.
Ourfavor?
You're not stuck out here
in the middle of nowhere-- I am!
Now, when do I get off?
I've told you--
as soon as we can find
a replacement for you.
Meantime, be good enough
to keep in touch, Walter.
Oh, and I am sorry
about your boat.
I really am.
Is Big Bad Wolf really sorry?
Because if he is,
Big Bad Wolf and Little Bo Peep
can do something
for Mother Goose.
They can go...
(chuckling)
I don't really
blame him, do you?
I can't see that
we've accomplished
anything, sir.
I don't think
he'll report in.
I mean, you can lead
a horse to water
but can you
make it drink?
When he gets thirsty enough,
he'll drink, Stebbings.
He'll drink.
Frank, can you hear me?
Frank?
Loud and clear,
Mother Goose.
What is it?
Where'd those men of yours
put the whiskey?
I've been looking
all over this dump.
You don't suppose they kept it
for themselves, do you?
Seamen of His Majesty's Navy?
You must be joking.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Where is it?
Well, I can imagine
how dull it must get
for someone left all alone
on a small island
so I decided...
All right. All right.
Get to the bad news.
Well, I decided
to liven things up a bit
by making a sort of
fun and game thing out of it.
What sort of fun and games?
I had my men hide all the
bottles around the island.
In very unlikely places.
You'd never find them
by yourself.
The ground rules are simple.
You report an enemy ship
or plane movement
and I tell you where
the bottles are.
One report, one bottle.
Um, um, hold it a minute, Frank.
I hear a flight going over
right now.
Yeah, isn't that odd?
Now just a minute while I get
the binoculars.
Oh, yes, there's six, seven,
eight of them
heading south.
They're, uh, uh, Nakajima 97s.
But just a minute
while I verify that
on one of these
little old charts.
Walter, there is another rule
attached to this.
It has to be a confirmed report.
"Confirmed"? Confirmed how?
By other spotters
along the line.
(chuckles)
Now just tell me
what all those planes were
that you saw, hmm?
(aircraft approaching)
(whistles)
(whistling)
(humming)
Frank!
Frank! Frank!
Frank, wake up, Frank!
Frank?!
Briar Patch here, Mother Goose.
Bo Peep speaking.
"Briar Patch"? What's that?
That's a new one, isn't it?
We've moved.
Oh, you're at King's Point
already?
Listen, Mother Goose,
you must use the code names.
If you don't like it, fire me.
Now get Houghton.
The regulations say...
Frank here, Walter.
Mother Goose, sir.
What's new?
Five Mitsubishi light bombers
at around 10,000,
headed southwest.
Southwest at ten thou.
Got it, sport.
Thanks.
Now, wait a minute. Whoa!
It's fun and game time now.
I played the game,
how about the fun?
Confirmed, Walter, remember?
But Frank, I swear.
Well, in that case
you have nothing to worry about,
have you?
Sit tight, Mother Goose.
"Sit tight. Sit tight."
(Morse code beeping)
Briar Patch here.
Are you there, Mother Goose?
I'm here, Frank! I'm here!
I'm here!
We've just received news
that your report has been
confirmed.
Congratulations.
Never mind the congratulations.
Where is it?
(chuckles)
Proceed 50 yards east
northeast to a large rock
then 20 yards due east
to a coconut palm."
No, no.
Not so fast. Not so fast.
Wait a minute. "Large rock..."
20 yards due east
to a coconut palm.
(squawks)
Sir.
Sorry to disturb you
at this hour, sir
but we've heard
from Humpty-Dumpty.
Oh, come on, Stebbings.
You can tell me.
Who's Humpty Dumpty?
(quietly):
Perry on Bundy Island.
He reports enemy landings
here on Desfare
here and here on Greater
and Lesser Tomango
and here on Prince Concert.
They've ringed him in
pretty well, haven't they?
He says they don't know
that he's there yet
but he expects somebody
along at any time now
and requests
to be withdrawn.
Well, combat can't spare
a thing, Stebbings.
All our planes and
ships are committed.
Who's our nearest man?
I'm afraidheis, sir.
Stebbings:
Briar Patch calling
Mother Goose.
Come in, Mother Goose.
Briar Patch calling
Mother Goose.
Come in, Mother Goose.
Do you read me, Mother Goose?
This is Briar Patch.
Yes, yes, I read you.
What's even worse,
I can hear you.
Now what do you want?
Walter, I haven't been sleeping
too well
because I've treated
you so badly
so I'm going
to make it up to you.
Whatever it is, Frank,
the answer is no.
I don't blame you, sport.
I don't blame you at all.
I'm not listening, Frank.
But supposing I got someone
to repair your boat for you?
I'm listening, Frank.
And after it's repaired
to stay on there
as your replacement?
Who is he?
Malcolm Perry.
He's one of our regulars.
When can he be here?
Tonight too soon?
No, Frank. Tonight's just fine.
Just fine.
There's just one small thing.
Uh-oh.
He's not able to get to you, so
you'll have to go and fetch him.
From where, Frank?
Bundy Island.
Bundy?!
How do you suggest
I get there, Frank?
Well, that launch of yours
has a dinghy, hasn't it?
All those miles of open sea
and back again
in a seven-foot dink?!
You're nuts!
(chuckles)
Shall I call him
back, sir?
No, no.
Frank?!
Yes, Walter?
Suppose I could make it
to Bundy.
Where would I put in,
the south jetty?
That's right.
Only be careful.
There's a pretty fair moon
tonight.
You got some special reason
for telling me that, Frank?
No. Only it's a bit better
without a moon.
Why, Frank?
Well, Bundy's liable
to be occupied.
With what, Frank?
I didn't say it would be.
Frank?
Yes, Walter?
Kiss my foot, Frank.
(chuckles)
If he leaves
within the hour
he should make Bundy
just after dark.
But, sir, you heard
what he said.
He won't go to Bundy.
Frank?!
Yes, Walter.
All those miles of open sea
a man would need something
to keep warm, wouldn't he?
Two bottles.
All of them, Frank.
Three.
Five.
All of them, Frank.
Got a pencil?
Number four is ten yards west
of the shack under a mango.
Five is 30 paces from there,
due north in a stunted palm.
Just a second. Slow it down.
Number six is...
Perry?
(glass clatters)
(clicking button)
(silence)
(yelps)
Who are you?
I...
I asked you first.
Where's Perry?
Who's Perry?
Perry, the man who lives here.
I buried him.
He was dead!
I found him here.
A Japanese plane
must have attacked the house.
How did you get here?
I...
Duck!
They've passed
by before.
I think they're landing
on the other side
of the island.
What makes you
think that?
Well, I saw them.
If you want to look,
there's a place over there.
Why would I do a silly thing
like that?
Come on. Let's get out of here.
Do you have a boat?
No, I walked.
Come on.
We're leaving now.
Huh?
Look out.
Come on, look out.
Just a...
Just...
What...
what are all those?
As you can see,
they're young ladies.
Now, listen, Miss...
Whatever your name is.
Oh. Freneau.
Catherine Freneau.
Charmed.
Now, suppose you tell me...
What is your name?
Uh, Eckland.
How do you do?
Now, Miss, I don't know
what this is
all about, but...
Please, Miss...
Miss?
Shh.
Where is your boat?
I can't see it.
Lady, it's right
where we're standing.
If you spit, you'd sink it.
Oh, dear.
Oh, well.
I suppose we'll just
have to manage.
Come on, girls,
into the boat.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait a minute.
Hold it.
Everybody settle down.
You don't think they're all
going to fit in that?
All right, Mr. Eckland
which ones do you
suggest we leave behind?
You decide.
I'll leave it to you.
It's suicide.
Would you stand a better
chance without me?
Naturally.
Very well.
Well, I suggest you
leave immediately.
Well, that's really
very decent of you.
You're a very good sport.
Thank you.
Now, the rest of you
snap it up.
All right.
Jenny, you're
the smallest.
Sit in the back.
You'll be out of the way.
Do you mind, lady?
This is my boat,
such as it is.
If anyone's going
to sink her, it'll be me.
Now, I'll seat them.
You sit in the back.
Give it to me.
Let it go.
Mr. Eckland.
This is not theQueen Mary.
There's no room for baggage.
Come on, you.
My glasses.
I don't want to go.
Oh, that's tough.
Come here.
Please take your hand off that.
All right.
My scent.
Huh?
Scent.
It's called Anticipation.
Two pounds ten the ounce.
You don't say.
All right.
Now sit there.
That's right.
Take you hands off that.
(yells)
What is that thing?
A cricket bat.
Isn't it a smasher?
Yeah, a smasher.
I only hope you all can swim.
Take your hand off that.
Now, you two, get in
the bottom of the boat.
Get in the bottom
of the boat.
They don't
understand English.
Sure they do.
See?
(yells)
Please.
All right.
Now, I guess
that's about all.
Don't forget Gretchen.
What?
Oh, that's her friend.
I'll help her in, dear.
Would you mind?
Oh...
Now, then, Mr. Eckland, I
suggest you leave immediately.
Oh, lady, lady,
do you mind?
Just get in the boat.
Well, you said it would...
I don't care what I said.
If, by some miracle,
we do make it
I'd be stuck with them.
Now, get in the boat.
All right.
Come on.
That's right.
No, no, no, no!
Not that.
We'd have had
a use for that.
Come on. Come on.
(girls squealing)
Now, don't be afraid.
Quiet, quiet.
Mr. Eckland, please
keep the boat quiet.
The girls are extremely
frightened.
Will you shut up, lady?
Now, here,
get off my paddle.
Well, I'm terribly sorry
but you put it there in
the first place, you know.
Now, that's all right,
children, don't be scared.
There we go.
Mr. Eckland...
Must you?
What are you, some kind
of religious fanatic?
I couldn't care less
what you do to yourself
but must you do it
in front of the children?
No.
Well, then.
Well, then, tell them
to turn around.
That is not exactly
what I had in mind,
Mr. Eckland.
Now, lady...
The name is Freneau.
Catherine Freneau.
I don't know what
you had in mind.
I don't even know
who you are
or what you were doing
on that island.
Well, if you must know
an American plane
left us there.
We were on our way
from New Britain...
I want to go home.
Oh, Anne, it's rude
to interrupt.
We were on our way from
New Britain to Port Moresby
when the pilot was ordered
to pick up eight survivors
of a Australian bomber that
had crashed in the water.
Unfortunately...
Hey, you, take that bat
or whatever it is
out of the water.
It's acting like a rudder.
Harriet, really.
The name's Harry.
All right, Harry.
He said he'd try and come
and pick us later
but that was five
hours ago, and he...
Quiet.
You don't have
to be so rude.
Quiet, I think I hear something.
(rumbling)
Duck.
What? What's
the matter?
Put your heads down.
Do as I tell you.
Keep your faces covered.
Harry, keep
your face down.
Are they Japanese?
I don't know.
Do you want me to ask?
Hold on.
We've got to ride out
the wake.
Girl:
We're sinking.
Well, don't just sit
there, damn it, bail.
Mr. Eckland, your
language. Really.
Just bail.
Do as I say.
Come on,
you can move
faster than that.
Come on, all of you,
Use your hands... anything.
Come on, keep bailing.
Faster.
Bail!
Why aren't you?
Come on now, get to work.
Go on.
That's better.
Hold on to the boat,
Harry.
Hold on.
Hang on to the boat.
Well, really.
Come on, girls.
All right, come on.
Come on, Anne.
King's Point, get Houghton.
Is that you, Mother Goose?
Walter, I can't tell you
how delighted I am.
Oh, you've Mother Goosed me
for the last time.
What are you talking about?
Now don't play stupid with me.
You'd sell out your own father
if you knew who he was.
(clattering)
(girls speaking French)
Walter, what happened? Walter?
Frank, get them off of here.
Get who off?
You know who.
Get them off.
No one could have known
we were there, Mr. Eckland.
The radio was destroyed.
Will you please stay out
of this, lady?
Freneau:
I'm only trying to...
Eckland:
I'm quite capable of handling
this myself, thank you.
Girl 1:
I'm hungry.
Girl 2:
So am I.
Walter, what's...?
(girls shouting)
Walter, who's...?
Walter!
Thank you.
Now, suppose you tell me
who's there?
Well...
I am Miss Catherine Freneau.
Who is this, please?
Commander Frank Houghton
of His Majesty's Navy.
Who are you, Miss Freneau
and what
are you doing there?
I'd like to hear
that myself. Go ahead.
I am the daughter
of Charles Freneau
the French Consul at Rabaul.
I heard children's voices.
Yes.
I am in charge of seven students
from the consulate school.
Four English, two French,
one Australian
all of them daughters
of diplomatic personnel.
When the bombing started
it was decided to evacuate
them to Australia.
Unfortunately, the plane
our group was on
put us down at Bundy
and now Mr. Eckland has been
kind enough to bring us here.
What about Malcolm Perry?
Well, I'm sorry, Commander.
The house apparently had been
attacked from the air
and when we found him...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Commander, how soon
do you think
you'll be able to...
arrange for our
transportation?
I'd like to hear
that as well, yeah.
That's a difficult question
to answer, Miss Freneau.
If you'll just be
a little patient...
Oh, never mind
their patience, Frank.
It's my patience.
Get them off of here.
All right, Walter,
I'll take it to the top.
Stand by.
If you're waiting for
the big finale, I'm sorry.
This is all I do.
Oh, son of a...!
Mr. Eckland.
(girls laughing)
I'm bleeding.
Mr. Eckland, we could all
do with some food.
Elizabeth, you and Harry
open some tins.
And Christine and Jenny, find
the knives, forks and napkins.
That'll be
a good trick-- napkins.
(speaking French)
Both:
Oui, Mademoiselle.
Hey, what are...
Be careful.
What are you doing with those?
(speaking French)
Mr. Eckland, where
are your tea things?
My what?
Your tea things.
Last time I looked
they were next
to the finger bowls.
Hey, hey, be
careful with that!
Didn't I tell
you that...?
Oh, it's an empty.
Houghton:
Are you standing by, Walter?
All set to go, Frank.
What did you work out?
A parachute drop.
A what?
They've got to be
picked up, Frank
not put down.
We thought you could do
with more provisions
what with all
those extra mouths.
I want their mouths out of here.
When are you
coming for them?
Well, that's rather
difficult to say.
Well, try saying today.
I don't think
it'll be today, Walter.
Well, what's making that
parachute drop, a seagull?
We can only manage a night drop.
There's no way to land.
Frank, you still haven't said
when you're going
to get them off.
No, I haven't, have I?
Two or three weeks.
Two or three...
Four.
Four?
With luck.
We'll have to stay
here a month?
I don't want
to stay here.
Well, Frank, you've slipped it
to me again, haven't you?
I'm sorry, Walter,
there's a war on.
Oh, stop saying that.
Commander, would
you be so kind
as to contact
my father in Rabaul
and have him inform
the parents of the girls
that they're quite safe?
All civilian personnel
are being evacuated
from New Britain, Miss Freneau.
But I'll see to it
that they're informed.
Signing off.
Three or four weeks.
I heard it.
I heard that.
Mr. Eckland, may I
speak with you
outside for a moment?
Some other time.
I've been up all night.
I'm going to bed.
Girls, go outside and play.
But stay close
to the house.
Yeah, tell them
to stay off the beach
or out
in the open.
Mr. Eckland.
Yes, sir.
It now appears likely
we'll remain here together
for some time to come.
Mm-hmm.
This being the case
I think it would be
wise of us
to arrive at
an understanding.
It must be
quite clear to you
that the children must be
our first consideration.
Your first
consideration.
I'm my first
They are young...
Look out.
...sensitive
and impressionable.
So am I.
They've been through
a most trying experience
and they will need a normal,
orderly routine established
and I would expect you
to do your share.
Oh, sure, sure.
It was quite one thing
for you to live
as you did when you were
alone on this island
but you are no longer alone
and your behavior is
totally unsuitable.
Your language is common
your eating habits
revolting.
Oh, yes?
Your appearance disgraceful
and as for your drinking,
that must stop immediately.
I will not have the children
subjected to it.
You are, after all
the only man with whom
they'll come in contact.
That makes you
the father figure.
Are you finished?
Yes.
Good.
Let me tell you something.
I am not a father figure.
I am not an uncle figure
or a brother figure
or a cousin figure.
In fact, that only figure
I intend being
is a total stranger figure.
So now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm going to bed.
I'm now supposed
to cover my eyes
and run screaming
from the room?
You'll be disappointed.
Isn't she a pip?
I doubt very much anything
you could do would shock me.
Let me repeat: My only concern
is for the children.
Well, why
don't you
go and concern
yourself with them
and let me get some sleep.
Gladly, as soon as you've
told me where we will stay.
Stay anywhere you like.
Well, as this hovel
seems to be
the only shelter
on the island
it's obvious we will
have to stay here.
You know what
fat chance means?
This is my hovel
so why don't you back out
and let me get some sleep.
Very well.
(sighing)
(grunts)
Oh, for...
(loud pounding and clattering)
What... what... what...
(screaming in French)
Lady, you are making
a powerful enemy.
Girls, let's get in.
(engines droning)
(humming jaunty tune)
(whistling)
(girls screaming)
You ought to be ashamed
of yourselves.
A gentleman simply
does not enter a room
where ladies
are not decent.
Well, you learn
something every day.
I have to use the radio! It...
Freneau:
All right,
Mr. Eckland.
You may come in now.
Oh.
Didn't you want
to use the radio?
Uh...
Yes, radio.
Yes... what's it doing
over here?
King's point,
this is Eckland.
Six Mitsu 104s heading east
at 10,000.
Message received, Mother Goose.
Message received.
Are you looking for something,
Mr. Eckland?
I asked you
to stop drinking
but you wouldn't.
Oh, no.
Where is it?
Somewhere where you won't
find it.
Gone again.
Of all
the meddlesome... Oh!
Come on, now,
where is it?
You got it up here?
(groaning)
Wait!
Oh, you wait!
You just wait!
King's point, this
is Eckland again.
Hello, Mother Goose.
This is Briar Patch.
Get Houghton,
on the double.
Big Bad Wolf
is engaged.
I don't care if he's married.
You get him!
You know, lady
you missed
your calling.
You ought to carry
a tambourine
and put fig leaves
on statues.
Houghton:
What is it, Walter?
Frank, now, this
is a military zone
and you're in command.
You tell Miss Goody Two-Shoes
here to get off my back.
Goody Two-Shoes?
Yes, you tell her!
Tell her she's a pain in the...
Uh, please, Walter, be civil.
Civil?
Who pushed who out
of whose home?
Who stole whose liquor?
Who bit whose hand? Twice.
She bit you?
Yes.
Miss Freneau?
No! Now, you tell her...
you tell her to give me
back my booze.
You tell her to butt out!
You tell her...
All right, Walter,
I'll speak to her.
Yeah, here.
Yes?
Miss Freneau, I'm sure
you've noticed
that Mr. Eckland is not
the most sociable sportsman...
Mr. Eckland is a rude,
foul-mouthed
drunken, filthy beast.
Well, be that as it may...
This is the filthy
beast speaking.
Now, listen, Frank
when you send
those supplies
send plenty of whiskey.
Plenty...
I insist you do nothing
of the kind, Commander.
Now be quiet,
both of you.
We've arranged
for the parachute drop
to take place
tomorrow night at 2200.
I suggest, therefore,
if you want anything at all
you better give me a list
of your needs.
Whiskey!
Yes, we know about you.
What about Miss Freneau
and the girls?
Girl 1:
Formal clothes!
Magazines!
Peppermint drops.
Glass of chocolate!
(speaking French)
Tennis clothes!
Bow and arrow!
Girls, please!
I have prepared
a list.
Now, hold it.
You've taken over
everything else
but the radio is still
my responsibility.
Eight nighties.
Would you repeat that, Walter?
Mr. Eckland
isn't here anymore, Commander.
I'll give you the list.
Eight nighties.
Nighties?
That is correct,
in various sizes
starting
with children's size six.
And would you please make
that one a bunny suit?
A what?
A bunny suit.
I'm sure you've seen them,
Commander.
You know, with the hands
and feet.
With... the hands and feet.
Mother Goose!
Monsieur Eckland?
Big Bad Wolf is calling you
on the wireless.
Oh.
Don't touch anything.
In fact, you better get off
the boat.
Get a shirt
and his pants.
Oh, look at this!
Oh, look.
Good morning.
Uh, I'm wanted
on the radio.
Uh...
Oh... oh...
Hey, King's Point,
this is Eckland.
Come in, Mother Goose.
This is Briar Patch.
Well, you had
something to tell me.
Big Bad Wolf had a message
for you
concerning the parachute drop.
Gave it to Goody Two-Shoes.
Oh, the...
Um, Commander Houghton
couldn't wait.
He asked me
to give you the message.
Well?
Well, what?
The message.
What message?
The message message.
Oh, oh-- that message.
Oh, I wrote it down
for you.
That's in French.
Oh, is it?
Oh, so it is.
Read it, please.
(speaking French)
No, no, no, no.
You're reading it
in French.
Well, it's written
Oh... translate it.
Oh, you want it
in English.
Um, Commander Houghton says
there's too much enemy activity
in the area to chance a...
How do you say,
in English, "parachute"?
Parachute.
Oh, really? Oh.
There's too much enemy activity
in the area to chance
a parachute drop
and he asks us to make do
with the supplies we have.
Oh, no.
Mr. Eckland?
What?
I don't suppose there's any use
my asking your permission
to share certain of your
personal belongings with us?
Well, so far, you've "shared" me
out of my home, my bed, my food
and my shirt.
Now, how about
sharing some of
my things with me?
Would you like some tea?
Tea?
Lemon or milk?
Milk?
Oh, sorry.
We're out of milk.
Oh...
But we could use
some additional
place settings
some rope...
some, uh, tools
and above all,
a change of clothing.
Above all, I could use
some whiskey.
Now, how about making
a trade?
Sorry. That I can't do.
Then, Madam, I wish you
a good day.
Mr. Eckland,
wait!
Hello,
Mr. Eckland.
The answer is "no."
Bonjour, Monsieur.
(speaking French)
I wouldn't think of it.
Oh!
You stepped
on my foot!
You put it under mine!
Look out!
All a bunch of nuts.
Oh, now hold it.
And what have
you got there?
(screams)
Oh, no!
Oh, no. Ow!
Come back here,
you pirate.
Mr. Eckland,
stop chasing the girls.
I'm not chasing...
They're all crooks!
And you're the crookiest.
And a good day to you,
Mr. Eckland.
Rumplestiltzkin,
Rumplestiltzkin.
Can anyone hear me?
Houghton:
I can hear you, Rumplestiltzkin.
I can hear you, too.
Where's Mr. Eckland?
He's not here.
Nobody's here
except my friend Gretchen.
We're not well today.
Say "hello," Gretchen.
Did you hear Gretchen?
She said, "hello."
Hello, Gretchen.
I'm sorry you're not well today.
Go and get Mr. Eckland, please.
The filthy beast?
Oh, we don't speak
to him.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Come on!
Get away from there.
Come along, Gretchen.
That you, Walter?
No, it's Gretchen.
Keep them away from that radio,
will you?
You keep them away
from the radio.
Beat it.
Miss Freneau told us to stay
in the house.
Ah.
(chuckles softly)
?
After breakfast, may w
e go out with the others
Nope. Not until
you're feeling better.
It's Gretchen
that's not well.
e.
I'm tired of staying her
Oh, you stop complaining.
You sound like Anne.
Is anything wrong?
The whole Japanese navy's
anchored offshore.
They're sending a boat in.
Where are
the other children?
Uh, they're...
Come on,
let's round them up.
Let's get them
in the shack.
Oh, Mr. Eckland...
shouldn't we report the Japanese
to Commander Houghton?
In five minutes he can
talk to them personally.
You and Gretchen
stay in the house.
Come on, hurry it up.
Get in the house.
(speaking French)
Oui, mademoiselle.
Quickly.
Where are the other two?
They're down
on the beach
collecting coconuts.
I told you to keep them
off the beach.
No, you didn't.
Yes, I did
but you weren't listening,
as usual.
Come and show me.
Come on, let's go.
Show me where.
Anne's up in one
of those trees.
Uh-huh. Get down.
Stay here. Don't move.
Hey, stay. Shh.
(speaking Japanese)
If she opens her
mouth, we've had it.
Jenny hasn't said a word
since she left her parents
seven days ago.
I thought you
might have noticed.
She can still scre
am, can't she?
Here.
(grunting quietly)
Shh, shh, shh.
(crying quietly)
Baby, shh, baby,
shh, don't cry.
Shh, don't cry,
don't cry.
(crying softly)
(speaking Japanese)
(continue speaking Japanese)
I wish I knew what
they were saying.
Shh.
The one with the glasses
is the cook.
Their captain
adores turtle soup.
Hmm?
He sent them ashore
for turtles.
There doesn't seem
to be any.
Oh, it's all right--
they're going to leave now.
(men speaking Japanese)
Oh, dear.
What?
One of them suggested they
bring back coconuts instead.
It's a bad dream.
(speaking Japanese)
The cook said the
captain wants turtle
soup or nothing.
s.
He's sick of coconut
Good for him.
Oh...
What?
g.
He just called the
captain a dirty na
me, and they're leavin
Anne (whispering):
Help...
I'm slipping.
(Eckland grunts)
Quick, let's go.
Oh, go on, beat it.
Come on. Buzz off.
You're not supposed
to be on the boat.
Get off the boat.
(clears throat)
Thank you.
Hey, what's your name?
You've got a name,
haven't you?
Oh.
See this whistle?
Would you like
to have it?
Okay.
Now, all you have to do
is repeat three simple words
after me.
Is that a deal?
Just repeat three words.
All right.
Elephant.
Rhinoceros.
Wrong.
Why?
No, not "why"-- "wrong."
"Wrong" is the third word.
You lose.
No! Give me that back.
Oh, I didn't think
you'd be a sore loser. Here.
All right.
(whistle blowing)
I'm sorry. We're
all out of whistles.
I told Harry she
could help us.
Help us do what?
Fix your boat.
Harry knows everythi
ng about boats.
Uh-huh. Well, how'd you like
to swab down the deck?
Smashing! I'd love to!
Good. You'll find a mop
down below.
Go ahead.
lo.
Oh, hello, hel
(both speaking French)
Oh, uh-huh. Well, you do that.
Yeah. Do that. Mm-hmm.
But do it quietly.
Mr. Eckland?
Quiet, quiet.
Do you want me
to mess this up?
Mr. Eckland?
Now, I know you've
saved up a lot to say
but would you mind
spreading it out a little?
g.
You're doing it wron
.
It's backwards
No, it isn't.
See the boat's upside down.
You do it this way so when
you turn it over you...
Well... how can I
get anything done
when you're chattering
all the time?
Besides, you should be
working. Come on.
It can't be.
(quietly):
Red light!
So this is where you are.
?
What are you
all doing here
s.
Look at their clothe
They'remyclothes.
But they're filthy.
No. They're dirty.I'mfilthy.
e.
All of you, get
back to the hous
ns.
It's nearly ti
me for your lesso
Mr. Eckland asked us
to help fix his boat.
Well, I'm sure he
will excuse you now.
re.
But we wan
t to stay he
I don't...
What did you say, Jenny?
We want to stay here.
Mr. Eckland
got her to speak.
I created a monster--
a talking person.
(chuckles softly)
Well, better do as she said.
Get goin
g.
Thank you, Mr. Eckland.
Next time I want them
to talk or doanything
I'll call you.
t
Well, it's not my faul
that boats are mor
e fun than lessons.
I did it on purpose.
Nothingis ever your
fault, Mr. Eckland...
and if I return
seven wild Indians
to their families
who trusted me
well, then that won't
be your fault, either.
h.
Shh, shh, sh
Huh?
(whispering):
Well, you don't have to be
a schoolteacher all the time.
(whispering):
I am not a schoolteacher...
but some form of discipline
has to be maintained.
Shh...
Why don't you teach them
something useful?
What do you suggest,
drinking and swearing?
(loudly):
Why are we whispering?
Oh!
?
I don't know. Why
are we whispering? Hmm
Is it edible?
ly.
No. I get lone
--
Now, why don't you teach
them something like that
something practical,
like catching fish?
Oh, well, that doesn't
seem too difficult.
I mean, if you can do it,
I'm sure anyone can.
et.
Try it. I haven't
had my morning laugh y
All right.
Oh, that was good. Good.
Whoa!
(spluttering)
I didn't quite understand
the reason
for that last movement.
Would you mind
demonstrating
it again?
I have an infuriating lack of
talent for doing simple things.
You probably don't
do them right. That's why.
All right, all right,
just stay there.
I like fish,
but fish don't like me.
...
All right, now
Now, be quiet.
Just keep still.
Now, give me your hand.
Cup them, cup them.
That's right.
Oh.
See?
Mm-hmm.
Now, watch
what you're doing.
Hey, here she comes again.
?
How do you know it's a she
Her mouth is open.
Now, be quiet.
Okay, now... now, slowly...
Slowly now...
Slowly... s... s...
w?
Mr. Eckland, aren't
we moving too slowly no
Hmm? Hmm?
Shouldn't we...
Shouldn't we what?
What?
You said "shouldn't we."
Shouldn't we what?
Well, you've got
the hang of it now.
Oh... we-we didn
't catch a fish.
I know, I know.
That's right, that's right.
W-we didn't.
But you got the hang of it.
t.
You already said tha
Oh, I did, huh.
Mr. Eckland, are you
going to show me
how to catch a fis
h or aren't you?
I aren't.
I want to go back now.
Mmm, just as soon as I pick
some of those berries.
What if they're dangerous?
Oh, we can always
ask Mr. Eckland.
Yeah, if he says, "Eat them,"
we'llknowthey're poisonous.
Oh.
Oh!
Oh, something bit me.
A snake--
there,
next to your leg.
Oh!
It bit you!
Oh, l-let's go
back quickly.
(speaking French
excitedly)
Mm-hmm.
(continuing French)
What happened?
I don't know
what she's saying.
A snake...
It was a long snake.
I saw it.
It bit mademoiselle
on the leg.
Okay, everyone out.
Freneau:
Girls, do as Mr. Eckland says.
I'll be all right.
Harriet:
I want to watch.
Oh, Harriet, please.
Go on.
(gasps)
Is it painful?
Your hand is wet.
Yeah.
Now, this is going
to hurt a little.
You should enjoy that.
Quiet.
Go ahead, you can yell
if you feel like it.
I don't feel like it.
Okay, it's all done.
Do you really think
it was poisonous?
Well, no sense
taking any chances.
Lie back.
It isn't going to hurt.
(spits)
Mr. Eckland...
I want you to know
I really appreciate
what you're doing.
Save it.
(spits)
Come in, Kings Point.
This is Eckland.
Stebbins:
Briar Patch
Mother Goose.
Bo Peep here.
Get Houghton, will you?
We got trouble here.
What's wrong, Walter?
What kind of snakes they got
around here, Frank?
Is that a rhetorical
question, I hope?
No, Miss Freneau went
and found one.
Houghton:
Good grief.
Is she...?
She seems all right
at the moment.
Find out if they're poisonous,
will you, Frank
and if so,
what we can do about it?
Right away.
Oh, and Walter...
until we get a
positive identification
don't try and
be a movie hero
and suck out
the venom.
(gargling)
Houghton:
Walter?
Are you there, Walter?
Yeah, I'm here, Frank.
Shoot.
Plug in the phones, will you?
Yeah.
(sniffs)
(clears throat)
Go ahead.
It's not good.
I've got Dr. Bigrave here.
He's checked
with Tropical Medicine.
I'll put him on.
Mr. Eckland...
(clears throat)
there are three varieties
of serpent
indigenous
to those islands
and I'm afraid all of them
are extremely poisonous.
Mmm, well, I opened the wound,
doctor.
I think I got all the venom out.
Well, taken orally,
it can't hurtyou,Mr. Eckland
but if she were bitten,
it's entered her bloodstream.
There's nothing we can do.
I'm afraid she's bought it.
Well, there must be some...
The venom is neurological
and attacks the nervous system.
The end will come suddenly
preceded by a general
numbing sensation
and dizziness.
Oh, oh, I see, Doctor.
I suggest you do everything
to make her as comfortable
as possible
including the liberal use
of any strong analgesic sedative
you happen to have.
Well, I don't have anything
like that.
Nonsense, Wally.
You've been using
one for years.
No, I haven't.
Oh, yes, I have, yeah.
Call me, Walter...
when it's over.
Good-bye.
Yeah.
It's bad, isn't it?
Where's the whisky?
Oh, I knew it.
I'm going to die
and you're afraid
I'll take the secret
to my grave.
Whisky is still the best thing
for snakebite.
Where is it, lady?
Stop calling me "lady."
It sounds so awful.
It's in the oven.
It can't be in the oven.
I looked there.
I know you did.
Gretchen told me.
I put it thereafteryou looked.
Hey, I thought
it was for me.
Just want to make sure
it hadn't gone bad.
Oh, here.
Now, come on,
drink that.
That won't hurt you.
Go on.
Hey-hey, be careful.
You'll ruin
your amateur standing.
(sighing contentedly)
I'm French, Mr. Eckland.
My parents started me
on wine mixed with water
when I was six...
but I don't believe in
excessive drinking...
Uh-uh.
Especially in
front of children.
Oh.
No, the truth is...
when my mother died
I became the
mistress of...
the consulate.
Oh, oh.
Oh, well...
I presided over all
the diplomatic dinners.
We had, uh, martinis
before dinner
white wine
with the fish
red wine with
the main course
champagne with
the dessert
cognac with
the coffee
and port
after dinner.
Sounds great.
Freneau:
Isn't it getting hot in here?
Whoo, is it getting hot
in here?
Isn't it getting hot
Darling, you mustn't
move around now.
Oh...
Now, come on,
just-just...
That's right.
Just lie quietly.
I bet you think
I'm an iceberg.
Do you know
how old I am?
No.
The truth is... we've
lived in 11 countries.
I can speak
seven languages.
I'm excellent at bridge.
I play the cello
very well.
I'm double-jointed
and I know how
to ride a camel.
(laughing)
I was engaged once.
Oh? Oh?
His name was Cesare
and he worked
in the Italian
consulate at Fiume.
Do you know
where Fiume is?
Uh, Yugoslavia,
isn't it?
No, it's in Yugoslavia.
He called me,
"Carissima"
and gave me handkerchiefs
with my initials on them.
Oh.
Every time he
wanted to kiss me
he'd say, "Permesso?"
and, then, afterwards,
he'd say, "Grazie."
You've had enough.
(laughing wildly)
(continuing laughing)
Oh, Cesare would
never have done to
my leg what you did.
No, probably couldn't reach it.
I liked what you
did to my leg--
the last part,
I mean.
Oh, that.
Tell me...
I'd like to know
what did my blood
taste like, hmm?
Delicious.
Now, come on.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
I'm being serious.
What did it taste like?
Well, how would I know?
I'm not a vampire.
Oh, oh, oh,
was it salty?
A little salty, yes.
Too salty?
No, it was just right.
Oh, no, you thought
it was too salty.
I can tell.
You didn't like it.
No, no,
I-I liked it, mmm.
Oh, really?
Yeah, I liked it.
You're not just
saying that?
No, great blood.
Uh, uh, please,
now-now-now
buzz off, will you?
Uh, Miss Freneau isn't
feeling very well.
Now, come on.
I'm going to kill
that rotten snake.
Anne!
Your opinion of me's correct,
you know?
I'm a... a picture-straightener.
You're a what?
A picture-straightener.
Oh.
When I see a
picture on a wall
that doesn't hang...
straightly...
I straighten it.
Oh, you do that? Oh.
And I brush my teeth every
morning and every night...
Hmm.
and if I don't have
a toothbrush...
I use my finger.
Mmm.
Oh...
I feel so numb.
"Numb"?
Where?
Everywhere.
What does it mean?
Oh...
Oh, you'd better lie down.
And I'm so cold.
Oh, why am I so cold?
Well, I...
here we go.
Oh, I'm dizzy.
Yes.
I'm very dizzy.
You lie down.
Just rest.
(moans)
That's right.
Oh, come closer, so I
can tell you something.
My coconut is empty.
Y...
Oh.
Have a belt yourself.
Uh... no, no, thanks.
Uh, th-there'll be
plenty of time later.
Uh, I mean,
y-you go ahead.
What was she like?
"She" who?
The lady who drove
you to this.
"Drove me to" what?
Drink.
Oh, there was no lady.
That was your wife.
(laughing)
No, uh,
there was no wife.
Then from what are you
running away from... hmm?
Oh, I'm not running away.
Oh, there must've
been some... some...
Well, well, therewas.
It was a necktie.
A what?
A necktie.
I was late for class
one morning.
I forgot my tie.
They wouldn't let me in.
Um, how long ago
was that?
About eight years ago.
Weren't you a little old
to be going to school?
Oh, I wasn't going.
Well...
(clears throat)
I was teaching.
Oh...
I was a professor
of history.
Ah.
A-A-And what about
the necktie?
Well, now, this is no time
to talk about me.
Why not?
(sighs)
Yeah, why not?
Well... see, I thought
they'd be more interested
in what was inside
a man's head
not around his neck.
Mmm.
Then I noticed
theyallwore ties.
They all looked alike
and they all behaved alike
and they all talked alike
but they were all going
the same way
no matter which way
they said they were going.
So, what was the use
of teaching them history
or anything?
They weren't learning
by it...
still creating
the same old problems.
So, I packed, got on a boat
and got away from them.
Mmm.
Mmm, now look what
they've got me doing.
Mmm.
(chuckles)
(laughing)
Uh-huh.
What's so funny?
(laughing)
You're the schoolteacher.
(laughing continuing)
(gasps)
Oh, dear.
No...
Oh...
(clicks tongue sadly)
What's that?
The snake.
But that's not a snake.
It looks like a snake.
You ninny.
You'd better tell Mr. Eckland.
I want to go home.
He'll be furious.
Why?
Because Miss Freneau's
not dead.
Oh, la.
(clears throat)
This is Eckland.
Is Houghton there?
(Morse code tapping)
I'm here, Walter.
Frank...
it's all over, Frank.
She's, uh...
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
What do I do about the kids,
Frank?
They don't know yet.
They'll have to be told, Walter.
Yeah.
Well, stick around, will you?
I may need you later.
Sure, sure.
I'll stand by.
(sighs)
Mr. Eckland...
Oh, oh, oh.
Uh, just a minute.
I...
Uh, will you all come
over here, please?
Mr. Eckland...
Ju-Just let me finish.
There's something
I want to tell you.
There's something we want
to tellyou.
Yeah, uh,
just a minute, now.
This isn't going
to be easy.
Now...
Those of you who
are old enough
to understand what
I'm going to say
will be able to help the
ones who, uh... well...
Mr. Eckland...
Uh, please,
there's a good girl.
Now, Miss Freneau,
who I guess we all gave
a very difficult
time to when she...
Well...
Miss Freneau has...
has gone away.
No, she hasn't.
You tell him, Anne.
Why me?
Because it was
all your fault.
Uh, just a minute.
Tell me what?
I-It wasn't a snake.
It was this.
But that's not a snake.
Itlookslike a snake.
Well, that's not a snake.
Here.
Watch out
for the thorns.
(gasps)
Thank you.
Not a snake.
Itlookslike a snake.
No, that doesn't.
This looks
like a snake.
Is it morning already?
Walter?
Are you there, Walter?
I have the chaplain.
I thought it might be a comfort
if he said a few words.
Never mind the chaplain, Frank.
She's alive.
Thesnake'sdead.
Walter...
explain yourself.
Walter!
Were you really
a schoolteacher?
All of you, raise
your right hands.
Come on, raise your right hands.
All right.
Now, none of you heard
anything I said in there.
You got that?
Okay, now, spit.
Go ahead. Spit.
The first one
who breaks the pledge
will get warts.
Qu'est-ce quewarts?
Uh... Mr. Eckland...
may I speak
with you, please?
No.
Oh! Oh! You don't
have to shout.
I don't even
have to talk.
Um... Mr. Eckland
do I owe you
an apology
or an explanation
or anything
like that?
Probably.
Some other time.
I seem to remember
someone saying
that a drop
or two helps...
No, not that!
Ooh!
I went through enough nonsense
with you
just to get this much.
Mr. Eckland,
what, exactly
did I do
yesterday?
Oh, nothing.
You just put a flower
between your teeth
and danced around
the room naked.
I couldn't have!
I did?
You mean
you don't remember?
No.
Oh. Oh, well, then
you don't remember
anything I said, do you?
Why? What
didyou say?
Nothing.
Well, there
doesn't seem to be
much to remember,
then, does there?
No, no, no, no, no.
Well, unless you
mean what you said
about running away
from civilization
because
of a necktie.
I thought you said
you didn't remember anything!
Oh, oh, oh...
nothing after that.
There wasn't anything
after that!
Then when did
I dance around naked
with a flower
between my teeth?
I only told you
those things about me
in strictest confidence.
Why, I haven't
told anyone.
You just told me,
didn't you?
You are the one
who told me.
Well, I don't care!
I only told you because
I thought you were dying.
Sorry
I disappointed you.
Oh...
I... I don't mind
that you were
a schoolteacher.
There you go again!
Now, it's none
of your business.
I-I... I thought
you were running away
from something
muchworse than that.
I wasn't running away.
I was escaping
from hypocrites like you
who have to get drunk
before they can let go.
There.
Well, then, you're a happy man.
That's right.
And that's why
youdrink so much--
because you are so happy.
Yes.
Is this boat tilted?
No.
Now, you listen to me.
Before you mess around
with other people's lives
you'd better take
a look at your own.
And what's
wrong with it?
Well, maybe, if you'd
stop straightening pictures
and let men
wear their own pants
maybe they'd
be able to touch you
without askingpermesso.
Dear Lord...
Oh, Harriet,
Dominique's going to say grace.
Mon Dieu, benicez-nous
articles de nourriture
que nous allons prendre.
Et donnez du pain
a sur a mon faim.
All:
Amen.
Oh, Mr. Eckland.
Oh, uh, um... I thought,
if you had enough food, I...
Well, certainly.
Look, he's combed his hair.
And he's actually
wearing socks.
Well, you see,
my feet were chilly.
Uh... I'm...
We're delighted
you could come.
Um... Anne, move over
next to Elizabeth
so Mr. Eckland can sit down.
I don't want to sit there.
She never wants
to do anything.
That's not true.
I want to go home.
All right, Anne.
Uh... change places
with Harriet.
My name's Harry.
Oh, sorry.
Harry, on the other side
of Mr. Eckland.
Thank you, Harry.
We fellas should
stick together.
Passez a Monsieur Eckland.
That'smydinner.
Well, then take it.
I'm sick and tired
of tinned beef.
Then give it back.
I want to go home.
Why can't we have fish
once in a while?
Professor Eckland
was giving me lessons
but he never finishes
what he starts.
(choking)
Raise your arms.
Lower your head.
Bebez de l'eau.
Drink something.
Give him something
to drink, quick.
Drink.
Hold it.
Jenny!
Well, how strange...
Why?
that you should
bring me this.
I've done it before.
No, you haven't.
Yes, I have.
Shut up.
Well, since it's here,
I'll, uh...
Uh-uh-uh... there's
already a beverage
on the table,
Mr. Eckland.
Yes? What?
Coconut milk.
You're kidding.
Well, it happens
to be very tasty
and quite healthful.
Well, I'm sure it is.
Uh-uh-uh-uh...
Mr. Eckland...
Delicious.
Coconut milk.
Young coconuts must love it.
(all laughing)
(airplane engine roaring)
Get back!
Come on.
Let's get back in the shack.
Uh... I-I...
I hurt my ankle when you...
when I fell.
Now, get up.
Now, let's see.
Put your
weight on it.
That's not too bad.
All right.
That's fine.
This is Eckland. Get Houghton.
Man:
Stand by, Mother Goose.
Houghton:
Yes, Walter, what is it?
A plane, Frank.
He dove at us.
Go on.
Well, go on where?
He spotted us.
And now you'd like me to take
you off the island, is that it?
Naturally.
Really, Walter?
You never give up, do you?
All right,
tell me what happened.
I've already told you.
A Japanese plane flew over.
What kind?
I don't know what kind.
Well, that's what
you're there for, isn't it?
Really, Walter,
planes are supposed to fly over.
We wouldn't need you
where planesdidn'tfly over,
would we?
Now, just because
one gets a little close...
Alittleclose!
Now, you listen to me, Frank.
You get us out of here
by tonight.
I really don't think
it will be tonight, Walter.
Thanks a lot.
I won't need you
when I get the launch ready.
Walter, I'd forget
about the launch if I were you.
You're completely
ringed in there
which means you could
only travel by night--
in a boat which
you can't be too sure of.
And, even if you could break
through-- which I doubt--
Port Moresby
is the only place open
and that's over 200 miles away.
Then do something.
Walter, I have 32 men
in precisely the same position
you're in.
How is it that I spend most
of my time listening to you?
Now, be a good chap and relax.
Signing off.
The fathead.
I'll be down at the launch.
Mr. Eckland?
Hmm?
Oh, I thought
your ankle was
bothering you.
Oh, well, it feels
much better now, thank you.
Fine.
I wanted
to thank you.
For saving my life,
I mean.
I behaved
quite stupidly.
Can you forgive me?
Sure.
I wouldn't want you
to think badly of me.
No.
Doyou think
badly of me?
I don't think badly
of you either.
Good for you.
Mr. Eckland?
You can kiss me if you want.
I may?
Oh, my darling.
I have thought
of nothing else
since that moment we met.
This first burning kiss
is but the beginning.
Tonight, you will
leave those children
and come live with me
on my boat.
What... what
are you doing?
But of course.
How thoughtless of me.
We must be careful.
What time can I
expect you tonight?
But Mademoiselle
doesn't let us out at night.
Oh, well.
(engine grinding)
(grinding)
Mr. Eckland, have you
been listening to me?
How can I help it
with you screaming
in my ear?
Because you've been talking
total nonsense, as usual.
It's quite clear
you know nothing
whatsoever about children.
Uh-huh, and you're
an expert, of course.
I know one thing--
Elizabeth is at that...
Wait, wait, wait.
Hand me those
pliers, will you?
Which one?
The small one.
This?
Thank you. Now,
what were you saying?
Elizabeth
is at that difficult age
and you frightened her.
Yeah, well,
I'm at a difficult age myself.
She nearly scared me to death.
How about teaching those kids
the facts of life?
Or don't you
feel you're up
on the subject?
I wouldn't exactly
call them backwards.
Not the way they were
watching during lunch.
Watching what?
(engine starts)
(engine running)
It worked!
Of course it worked.
Now, what were they
watching during lunch?
They were watching us.
Watching us what?
Watching us
watch each other.
So we watched each other.
So what?
They're not
blind, you know.
What do they
think watching is--
a proposal of marriage?
Whoever said
anything about...
Just because
a man puts on socks
and comes to lunch...
If you think I'd want
to get involved with
an undisciplined, self-indulgent
escapist like you...
Well, that's better than being
a frustrated spinster
who can't
find a husband.
Spoke to Oliver, Sir.
Mother Goose is
requesting a chaplain.
A chaplain?
Good heavens, he's killed her.
No, sir.
They want to get married.
Married?
Goody Two-shoes
and the Filthy Beast?
What's taking
him so long?
He's had enough
time to get
the Archbishop
of Canterbury.
Oh, Mr. Eckland,
really.
Oh, stop calling me
Mr. Eckland.
It sounds ridiculous.
Houghton:
Walter? Are you ready, Walter?
Just a minute, Frank.
Here, use my tie.
Oh, thank you, Harriet
but ties don't
suit Mr. Eckland.
Oh.
Have you got
the chaplain, Frank?
Yes, he's here.
There's a little
paperwork, Walter.
Bride's full name.
Catherine Louise Marie
Ernestine Freneau.
Groom's full name.
Walter Christopher Eckland.
Mm.
Witnesses.
Who's the maid of honor?
Um, Elizabeth Anderson.
And the best man?
Oh.
Harry McGregor.
Harry?
Just believe me.
Proceed, padre.
Thank you.
Now, is everyone ready?
Yes, padre.
(playing "The Wedding March")
Dearly beloved
we are gathered here
and... there, in the presence
of these witnesses
to join together
this man and this woman
in the bonds of holy matrimony
which is an honorable estate
instituted of God...
(airplane approaching)
into this holy estate.
These two persons
come now to be joined.
Duck! Down, quickly!
Get undercover!
If there be any present...
Up!
Everyone out!
Come on, all of you!
Quickly.
Come on, come on, get going!
...why they may not lawfully
be joined in marriage
I require him now to make it
known or ever after
to hold his peace.
Any-anything there?
Good.
Now, then.
Do you,
Walter Christopher Eckland
take this woman to be
your lawful wedded wife
to love and to cherish
to have and to hold
so long as you both shall live?
Uh, Mr. Eckland?
Do you,
Walter Christopher Eckland...
Walter!
Stay there!
...to be your lawful
wedded wife?
Hold it, padre. Hold it.
Mr. Eckland, do you...?
I do, I do. Get Houghton, quick.
What is it, Walter?
They came back, Frank.
I told you they would.
Who came back?
You know who. Now listen!
(airplane approaching)
Did you hear that?!
Yes, I'll get onto it
right away. Stand by.
I want the name
and exact position
of every
Allied submarine
within 12 hours'
running distance
between here
and Matalava
and get onto it
right away.
Aye, aye, Sir.
Walter.
I told you to stay
where you were.
The plane's gone.
I was afraid
I was a widow
before we were
even married.
Uh, er, Mr. Eckland.
What should we do now?
Well, all right, we'll take
another whack at it
if you will, padre.
So take your time,
but hurry it up.
Oh, eh, yes, yes, of course.
I understand. Uh...
Let me see now.
Do you Walter
Christopher Eckland
take this woman...?
Oh, we-we did
that part, padre.
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
I-I'm a little rattled.
Uh, let me see here.
All right, then.
Do you Catherine Louise
Marie Ernestine Freneau.
take this man to be
your lawful wedded husband
to love and to cherish,
to have and to hold
for as long
as you both shall live?
I do.
Forasmuch as you have consented
together in holy wedlock
and have given and received
a ring in token of your troth...
Wait a minute.
What ring?
Didn't we do the ring?
No, we didn't
do the ring.
Oh, I'm afraid
we'll have to do the ring.
Well, here.
Hold it, padre.
All right, padre.
We did the ring.
Oh, good.
Forasmuch as you have consented
together in holy wedlock
and have given and received
a ring in token of your troth
I now declare you
husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride,
Mr. Eckland.
Mr. and Mrs. Eckland,
if you're finished now
I suggest you
get the hell out of there.
Yeah, that's a good
suggestion, padre.
Thank you.
Hold on, Walter, hold on.
What, Frank?
One of your American submarines,
theSailfin,is in your area.
She's running submerged
so we'll not be able
to make radio contact
with her until
she surfaces tonight
but she ought to be able
to get through to you
by dawn tomorrow.
She'll have to lie off the reef
to await your signal
so I suggest
you stay on the beach.
Have you got that?
I've got it.
Oh, and incidentally,
Walter
congratulations
to you and Mrs. Eckland.
and the best of luck
to all of you.
Mmm.
And they're
going to need it.
Walter, are
you awake?
Uh-huh.
I was thinking
about yesterday.
Somehow, the word "wedding"
has always called to mind
a different picture.
Mm-hmm. Somehow the words
"wedding night"
have always called to mind
a different picture, too.
Well, we couldn't
very well have left
the girls by
themselves.
They're our
responsibility.
They're not
ourchildren.
No, if theywere
our children
they'd have never gotten
tobeour children, would they?
You won't be coming
with us, will you?
How did you know?
Oh, when a woman
has been married
as long as I have
she knows what her
husband's thinking.
Oh, well.
I'll shove off
right after the rest of you
and get through
to Port Moresby in no time.
Well, you know
what Commander
Houghton said.
I can't leave my boat.
Must be a good one.
Good or bad, it's all
the dowry you're going to get.
I'm thinking of starting
a charter service
right after the war.
Somewhere around the Solomons
and New Hebrides.
Good money there for anyone
who knows the islands.
All right. I'm not
leaving without you.
Oh, yes, you are.
Someone's got
to get those children
back to their parents.
Lord, you're stubborn.
That's right.
Come on.
Yeah, come on.
That's it. Go to sleep.
(engine humming)
They're here.
Hold it.
Girls.
That's a Japanese
patrol boat.
Oh, my God.
They picked
a fine time
to check us out.
What about the submarine?
She won't surface
while that
thing's there.
Get off the beach.
Come on.
Come on, girls.
Wake up!
Quickly as you can,
wake up! Come on!
Take your gear.
Got it?
Thank you.
They're sending
two boats ashore.
Now, these fellows
aren't looking for turtles.
They're looking for us.
Well, what if the
submarine leaves
without us?
Can't you
radio them?
No, I can't
make contact
while they're
submerged.
Now, take the kids
to the launch
and for God's sake
keep them quiet.
Here. Here...
Oh. Walter.
Hmm?
I look awful in black.
(growls)
(air hissing)
Over here.
The house is on fire.
I know, I started it.
Oh. When did
you do that?
Oh... Last night,
when you were asleep.
What else
was there to do?
Hey, hide
all that stuff.
We're getting off
this island.
Is the submarine there?
It had better be.
Are we going
home now?
That's right.
I don't want
to go home.
Oh, come on.
Get in the dinghy
and hurry it up.
Commander Houghton said
there'd be a signal.
He wasn't joking.
They're coming out
to meet us in the launch.
Dead slow.
Dead slow, sir.
Answers dead slow.
Holy cow.
An enemy patrol boat
giving chase.
Ready the bow torpedo tubes.
Tubes forward, con.
Make ready forward tubes.
Submerged reef
300 yards from shore.
No torpedo clearance.
The launch is heading out
beyond the reef.
They're following.
That's what he's up to.
He's bringing them out to us.
They're plastering him.
He's cleared the reef.
They're right behind him.
Bearing?
Mark.
Zero two five.
Range.
Mark.
Six five oh.
Tubes one and two,
open outer doors.
Check fire. Check fire.
The launch is veering
into target path.
(explosion)
Get going, get going.
Final bearing.
Mark.
Fire one.
Fire two.
On the nose.
Not that it'll do those
poor devils any good
let's take her up and
look for survivors.
Freneau:
Walter!
Mr. Eckland!
Oh, zig!
What's the matter
with this thing?
Mr. Eckland!
There's his hat.
Jenny, move over.
I want to catch it.
Mrs. Eckland,
I presume?
Mr. Eckland!
Walter!
Took me forever
to tie the wheel off.
I thought I'd have
to stay with her.
Our boat, theCatherine.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, well, in a war
everybody loses something.
I'm just glad
it wasthatCatherine.
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Hold on. You want
to invite me in first?
Oh, uh...
Oh, Walter,
you'll tip us in.
(kids screaming)
Not if you do it right.
Now, just shift
your weight.
Get over there.
You, too.
Oh, uh, Walter,
I-I really don't think
it's such a good idea.
Now, p-please,
just this once
will you do it my way?
All right.
Shut up.
I didn't say anything.
It looks like we'll be
taking on passengers
after all,
Mr. Cartwright.
Break out a raft.
Aye, aye, Sir.
Oh, I wonder if they serve
coconut milk on submarines.
[Captioning sponsored by
Artisan Entertainment
Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]