NARRATOR: 1942,
most of Western Europe
has fallen under the onslaught
of German troops.
But in the East
the Soviet Union
withstands the invasion
of Nazi forces.
Desperate fighting
for every inch of land
goes on along
the entire Eastern Front.
Both sides suffer heavy losses.
And neither party will settle
for anything but victory,
victory at any cost!
FIRST SQUAD
Attack!
(WHINNYING)
(GASPS)
(WHISPERING) That girl is
obviously not in her right mind.
MAN: (SIGHS) Come on.
She's just an orphan,
a victim of war.
(ACCORDION PLAYING)
(SINGING UPBEAT FOLK SONG)
Smile!
It's for the frontline paper.
And now, your next performer
is, without a doubt,
a girl wonder.
Let's give her a hand!
She will answer any question.
Ask her anything,
even your innermost secrets.
Come on, ask her. Don't be shy.
What's my name?
Dmitry Sonin.
That's right, fellas!
Damn good!
And you are Private
Panteleyev, from Tula.
Your nickname in
school was Mozart.
That's true, he told me so.
Hey, let's find out
when the offensive will start.
SOLDIER 1: And what's my name?
SOLDIER 2: When am I gonna get
a letter from home?
SOLDIER 3: Who stole my knife?
SOLDIER 4: Will Lyuba marry me?
(ALL CLAMOURING)
(SILENCE)
I just wanted to ask
how long do I
have left to live?
(GASPS)
(GASPING IN HORROR)
Nadya, time to wrap up.
ALL: Aerial attack!
(EXCLAIMS)
(GASPS)
(FILM PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
THE MINISTRY OF SPACE AND TIME
presents
Happy birthday, little Nadya.
(BLOWING)
(BOTH GASP)
It's wrong to steal apples.
Yes, sorry
I'm Leo, what's your name?
Nadya.
(EXCLAIMS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(CLEARING THROAT)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING
DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(AUDIENCE MURMURING)
(AUDIENCE GASPING)
(LAUGHING)
ZENA: This is the Friendship
of Nations fountain.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BB GUN SHOOTING)
(RINGING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Nadya, this is for you.
Wow, cute!
Thanks!
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(HAMMERING)
(LAUGHING)
Marat, let's race.
I can't go any faster
with this bike.
(MIMICS GUNFIRE)
(GASPS)
Did I scare you?
Don't forget, "Always be prepared."
(ALL LAUGHING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
Don't worry,
you'll learn it, too.
Everybody at our boarding
school can do this.
(GUNSHOTS)
Explosive substances
can also be mixed using...
INSTRUCTOR: It is your duty
to be fearless,
determined,
keep calm in any situation,
stay in the mental link
and, most importantly,
abide by the principles
of the 6th Division.
(AEROPLANES APPROACHING)
(GASPS)
(GUNFIRE)
(GROANS)
Quick, hide in there
and don't come out
until I get back!
I'll get the rest
and come back.
Don't worry,
and don't leave,
whatever happens!
(BARKING)
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING)
(GASPS)
SOLDIER: We got them. Let's go.
(SOBBING)
Run for the exit,
it's too soon for you to die!
(GASPS)
Leo, I don't understand.
You are caught between life and
death, but you must survive.
Run!
(PANTING)
At last, we meet again.
OBERGRUPPENFÜHRER: Gentlemen,
leaders of the Reich are worried
about the state of affairs
on the Eastern Front.
During the winter campaign
our offensive failed.
The army proved unable to
break the Russian resistance.
To win this war, we need to
resort to most radical measures!
What do you suggest?
It is time to begin
Operation Sword of Vengeance!
Astrologers confirm that the
Moment of Truth is approaching.
ELDER: But, Chairman, for such a
ritual we would need an artifact
with very high energy.
And at last, we have one!
Gentlemen,
behold Grandmaster Baron Von
Wolff's legendary sword.
Using it we shall conjure the
Baron's ghost to join our ranks!
Isa.
Ihwaz.
Haaglaz.
Gebo.
Mannaz.
Dagaz.
BARON VON WOLFF: That is my sword!
Give it back!
Grandmaster,
we Elders of the Ahnenerbe,
call on you and
your fallen brothers.
Rise from the dead,
and with this sword,
take revenge on your sworn
enemies: the Russians.
BARON VON WOLFF: I have been waiting
for 700 years, dreaming of revenge!
At last my sword
is back in my hands.
I accept your offer!
(RUMBLING)
Come here, Nadya.
(GASPS)
That knight,
I have dreamed of him.
In a recurring nightmare.
That dream is
the last thing I remember.
He was a legendary warrior and
magician, Baron Von Wolff.
The Baron and
the knights of his order
were excommunicated
for practicing black magic.
In 1242, he led his order
to attack Russia.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
Von Wolff's Crusaders
torched towns
and slaughtered
their inhabitants.
Many believed that he was served
by demons of the underworld.
Finally, though, the people of many towns
united in their resistance to the Order.
They defeated Von Wolff in a battle
called the Battle on the Ice.
The knights of the Order perished
at the bottom of the lake.
This book says that 700 years
after the Baron's death,
his grudging ghost will
be called back to life.
This year, 1942,
will mark 700 years
since the prophecy.
But why have I been
dreaming about this?
Nadya, these are not merely
dreams, they are visions.
You have the gift of
seeing into the future.
And you must use your gift
to avert disaster.
But I don't even know who
I am, or where I am.
Eat, now,
you have a long journey
ahead of you.
I have nowhere to go.
I don't remember where I live.
Together we will go to Moscow,
to the Kremlin.
I'll take you
where your help is needed most.
(GASPS)
Nadya, go to Moscow.
The horse will find the way.
Find General Below in the Kremlin,
he will explain everything to you.
And you...
- Don't worry about me. Just go!
(WHINNYING)
Go away!
Please let me through.
I really need to get in.
NADYA: Where is General Below?
Please, I must see
General Below right away.
You know what, girly?
If you behave violently again,
we'll have to sedate you.
I can't let you see General Below
because no such person exists.
He is a product of your imagination,
a side effect of the contusion.
Oh, contusion?
I see, but then...
Lies! You don't know anything!
Let me out now!
(GRUNTING)
DOCTOR: Why do they admit
these loonies here?
We're busy enough
with the wounded.
(SCREAMS)
Who are you?
You don't know who I am?
I'm your commander,
General Below.
We have been searching for you all over.
What happened to you?
Sorry, but I don't remember.
Right, I talked to the doctors.
A blow to your head
has damaged your memory.
Do you remember
anything at all?
Circus, friends,
summer, the boarding school.
Then the war began.
My friends were killed.
Mmm. That was more
than half a year ago.
Many things happened since.
We don't have much time.
I'll tell you everything
you need to know.
World War II is underway.
Nazi Germany has
attacked our country.
Parallel to regular
military operations
two occult secret services are
engaged in a covert struggle:
The German Ahnenerbe
within the SS,
and the 6th Division of the Soviet
Military Intelligence. That's us.
We're not your regular
intelligence corps though.
We use tools of
occultism and magic:
Astrology,
clairvoyance and hypnosis.
I'm the head of the 6th Division.
And you, you are my best agent.
Since the beginning of the war,
you have completed numerous
important missions.
A week ago we sent you, as a
member of a propaganda team,
to the frontline
on an assignment,
where you completely vanished.
Your parents both had
extrasensory abilities.
Ever since they died,
the 6th Division
has been your family.
Died? Why? When?
Before the war,
in the line of duty.
BELOW: We have an enormous workload right
now, and I need you like never before!
So much depends on the current
counter-operation we are planning.
(PURRING)
The astro-radar shows enormous
activity in the beyond.
We have intelligence that the Ahnenerbe
have obtained a strong ally.
If it's Baron Von Wolff
and his knights,
we have a real problem!
Does this look familiar?
I saw him in my dreams.
He will come.
Yes, very soon.
The old prophecy is coming true.
(MEOWING)
That means that within hours
the spirits of Von Wolff
and his warriors
will fall upon our positions.
Obviously, ghosts and demons
are not afraid of our weapons.
The living
cannot even see them.
But how can I help?
You are the only one who can.
I'll explain.
For years, the 6th Division
has been developing a special task
force of teen agents: First Squad.
At the beginning of the war, it
was terminated by Ahnenerbe.
Leo,
Zena,
Marat,
Valya.
They were all killed.
You're the only survivor
of the First Squad.
Training at our school
was aimed at building
a mental link
between the Squad members.
That's why only you can call upon
the spirits of your fallen friends,
and with them,
stop Von Wolff's assault.
The time has come
for you to meet them again!
But how? You said
the Pioneers were killed.
Exactly. I want you to go
to the other side.
The 6th Division has designed a
special machine for this purpose,
Sputnik 01.
This is our last chance.
Can you handle it?
I'll try.
Your locker is marked
with the letter "N".
In it you'll find everything
you'll need for the assignment.
(GASPS)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
The machine travels
to the beyond
through the pilot's subconscious,
so you'll land someplace you know.
Your sword is a rare and powerful
weapon against ghosts and demons.
Don't hesitate to use it.
You're good with it, too.
You have very little time,
so act fast.
Most importantly, don't
miss the red return signal!
If you miss it you'll
be stuck there forever.
Let's go!
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(INAUDIBLE)
Hello? Anybody here?
(CAWING)
(HIGH-PITCHED SOUND)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
Seventy-seventh,
seventy-seventh,
cease fire, over.
(GROANING)
Brothers! When the enemy stole
our victory through deceit,
and the ice on the lake
cracked under our feet,
they thought we
were defeated forever.
They were wrong!
We haven't spent 700 years
in this gorge in vain!
The new Moment of Truth
is approaching,
and this time,
we will be victorious!
We shall sway
the destinies of the living!
(ALL GRUNT IN AGREEMENT)
What?
She is alive!
There's no place
for the living here.
All right,
take her to the butcher!
Time waits for no man!
We're moving out!
The evil spirits
came out of the man
and went into the pigs,
and the herd went rushing down
a steep slope into the water
and met their destruction.
The Gospel of Luke.
(RUMBLING)
What is this?
(GASPS)
Ready to roll?
(LAUGHS)
Not a moment too soon,
as usual.
How'd you get here?
So you actually died?
Didn't I warn you?
NADYA: No, I'm alive.
General Below sent me.
They have a machine that
can send people over here.
Are they crazy there
at the 6th Division?
No one comes back
from here alive!
Now they do!
How did you find me?
We all sensed you.
Remember mental frequency
synchronization exercises at school?
We may be dead, but we still know
everything we learned while alive.
(EXCLAIMS)
Get down!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
NADYA: So scary.
And so beautiful.
What a strange place.
Yeah, not the best place
for a class reunion.
This is the Gloomy Valley,
where the spirits of fallen
warriors go after death.
They say there are other lands beyond those
mountains, but no one knows for sure.
There is no way out
of the Gloomy Valley.
So, why are you here?
After 700 years of death
Von Wolff is about to
break through the boundary
between the worlds.
He reached an agreement
with the Ahnenerbe
and will fight on their side.
ZENA: Unbelievable!
The divide has not been
broken in centuries!
LEO: The dead versus the living.
The living don't have much of a chance!
Von Wolff has become an extremely
powerful demon over the centuries.
His hate has enormous
destructive power.
Once the Nazis learn
to use that power,
they'll rule
the world of the living.
I've come for you.
We must stop Von Wolff.
I can't do it on my own!
Nadya, don't you get it?
We were killed,
we're out of the game.
We can't go back. It's taboo!
But if you don't intervene,
millions of people will die!
The world of the living and the
world of the dead will become one!
It'll be doomsday!
You were killed,
and I kept living.
But I'm asking you to
help us, the living,
to win this ruthless war.
Let everyone
decide for themselves.
I, for one, am ready.
It's my war, too.
I can't just sit and watch things
get so screwed up back there.
Guys, maybe we
weren't killed for nothing.
Let's kick those
Teutons' butts!
Well, Nadya, typical,
you just love the limelight!
(SIGHS)
All right, I'm in. I don't want to miss
an opportunity to kick some Nazi butt.
As for me, I'm in, too!
(ALL LAUGHING)
You know, I knew you'd agree.
The First Squad is back together,
just like the old days!
Comrade General,
Sputnik is overheating.
Let's bring her back!
(GASPING)
What's this?
- What's going on, Nadya?
The signal!
We need to hurry to the Ferris wheel!
What's taking her so long?
(ALARM BLARING)
WOMAN: We're going to lose her!
BELOW: Come on, girl!
Come back here when the
amusement park starts up again.
That will be our signal
to break through!
We'll be there.
See you on the other side.
(ALARM BLARING)
(GASPS)
Thank God you're back!
(PANTING)
You had me worried sick.
Congratulations! You're the first human
ever to return from the world of the dead.
Now, tell me,
what's going on over there?
Did you see them?
Von Wolff is ready
for the break-through.
But First Squad will fight!
BELOW: I've got a surprise
for you.
Oh, hello!
You see, I'm safe and sound,
just as I said.
It was a close call,
but those two were after you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Let's get back to business.
700 years after his death
Von Wolff will break into this
world at the Moment of Truth,
but we don't know precisely
when or where it'll happen.
The Moment of Truth!
That's what Von Wolff said to his knights.
What does it mean?
Moments of Truth are the most
critical and decisive of moments,
when the actions of one man
determine the outcome
of a battle or an entire war.
Moments of Truth are instants,
imperceptible to mortals,
when creatures
from the other world
may enter our world and interfere
with the natural course of history.
Moments of Truth have always
existed and will always exist,
but only those with a rare gift
can foresee and endure them.
And you, Nadya, have this gift.
BOTH: Herr Obergruppenführer.
And here are our beauties!
What's the good news?
The girl was identified
at the Eastern Front,
a clairvoyant, working for
Russian intelligence.
Despite our efforts,
we failed to eliminate her.
(SIGHING HEAVILY)
Can you, please, get rid of that
clairvoyant from the 6th Division?
It must be done
before the Moment of Truth.
Tomorrow morning you will be in Moscow.
Dismissed.
BOTH: Yes, sir!
Here is what we know: a large
number of troops on both sides
are concentrated
along the lake shore.
Both sides have been trying to attack,
but every attempt has failed.
It's around here that the
Moment of Truth will occur.
The Commander in your dream
is the only one
who will dare to rise
from the trench, under fire,
and lead soldiers
in the attack.
At the Moment of Truth, Von
Wolff will try to behead him.
Should our attack
not take place,
the Germans will launch a
counter-offensive and break the front.
Give it another try,
maybe you'll see his face,
or maybe his unit.
I'm trying.
No, I can't see.
- It's okay. Next time.
You just need to rest.
A driver will take you
to the army quarters.
Go have a good sleep
and recover. It will work.
DRIVER: I know you.
You were a circus performer.
I drove you before the war.
I also remember your mom and dad.
They were wonderful people.
May they rest in peace.
Please, tell me
about my parents.
I hardly remember them.
You don't remember?
But it's only been a year since they...
(GUNSHOT)
(EXCLAIMING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(METRO BELL RINGING)
(GASPS)
NADYA: "Captain Alexandr Nemov,"
"the subdivision's
sole survivor."
”After a massive
enemy air raid,
"Alexandr was treated
in hospital
”and now wishes to return to the
front to fight the enemy."
The only survivor!
That's the object of the Moment of Truth!
I found him!
NADYA: it's me, I found him.
Captain Alexandr Nemov_.
Yes, I need the exact
location of his regiment.
No, I'm fine, but
the driver has been killed.
I'm being followed. Got you.
I'll call you from the station.
(CHATTERING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Can I get over there
before the fork?
(GRUNTS)
(INAUDIBLE)
(TRAIN BRAKING)
Soldiers retreating from their positions
without an order are traitors.
Scaremongers and cowards
will be executed on the spot.
The enemy shall be defeated!
We shall prevail!
Here we go. I hope he's there.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
HUNCHBACK: Go away!
We're closed!
What do you want?
Can't you read?
CLOSED
What are you doing?
Everybody wants something
from the Hunchback.
I told you,
I have nothing to sell!
Listen, Hunchback,
we don't have time.
How about a swap?
Hmm. 6th Division,
Russian Military Intelligence.
Very rare.
All right.
(GASPS)
ZENA: Man!
VALYA: Wow!
Holy cow!
(GASPS)
That's more like it!
HUNCHBACK: Newest models
on the market.
Russian, German, Japanese.
All guns have
augmented firepower,
and are in perfect
working condition.
(COCKS GUN)
Let me check.
(GUNFIRE)
HUNCH BACK: Was that
really necessary?
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
I just hope it works.
ZENA: Really? Here?
LEO: This is the only pavilion
with lights on.
This will be the entrance
to Nadya's subconscious.
Come on!
Get in. She's calling us.
This tunnel should take us
to the world of the living.
(GASPS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
NADYA: It's wrong
to steal apples.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
VALYA: It's speeding up!
NADYA: Hurry up, faster.
(ALL COUGHING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL SHOUT)
(ALL GASP)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
They didn't come.
BARON VON WOLFF: Knights, you are
taking part in the greatest of battles.
Your names will remain unknown,
but your deeds
will live in eternity!
(CHUCKLING EVILLY)
Here we go.
It's starting.
(GASPS)
(WHINNYING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
Some like it hot, huh?
Not a moment too soon.
(GASPS)
Leo!
(GRUNTING)
(WHINNYING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
Nadya!
Welcome to the Gloomy Valley.
ZENA: What happened?
Did Nadya take out Von Wolff?
Have a nice trip home, freaks!
Attack!
(ALL YELLING)
SOLDIER: Fire!
Speaking!
Good. Roger that.
(ALL CHEERING)
BELOW: Prepare an aeroplane.
I will pick up Nadya
from the front personally!
(GASPS)
It's not him!
He escaped.