## [Instruments Join In]
## [Chinese Chorus Singing]
## [Instruments, Chorus
Fade, End]
The Chinese have crossed the river
in six locations around Chamdo.
- Has anyone died?
- [Sighs]
The radio operator said
one man had been killed.
Then he said,
"The Chinese soldiers, they're coming."
And then the radio
went silent.
## [Militaristic Drumbeat
Resumes]
[Chinese Radio Announcer]
This week began the peaceful
liberation of Tibet.
Members of the People's
Liberation Army have entered
this western region of China...
at the urging
of the Tibetan minority.
Long a stronghold
of imperialists, the Tibetan people
have found themselves living...
in a feudal kingdom
under the tyranny of the Dalai Lama.
As the People's Army moves
toward the capital of Lhasa,
the local peasants gratefully
welcome their liberators...
and happily join
the crusade.
What do the people say, Norbu?
They think it's time
for you to rule them now.
I'm too young.
I have no experience.
Of course you have experience,
Kundun. Who else would be here?
- Norbu?
- Yes, Holiness?
Do you ever wonder
if Reting found the right boy?
No.
I want to be 18
when I'm enthroned.
All the Dalai Lamas
were given until 18.
## [Percussion, Horns]
[Hissing]
[Monks Muttering]
- [Grunts]
- "His time has come."
[Monks Chanting]
Holiness, November 17, 1950...
has been selected as the most
auspicious day for your enthronement.
- Yes.
- We ask that...
you be prepared to leave Lhasa
immediately afterwards as a precaution.
As you say.
[Sniffling]
## [Horns Blaring]
## [Horns Fade, Stop]
## [Cymbals Crash,
Horns Resume]
[Low Chanting]
[Chanting Stops]
[Dalai Lama] Tibet will
call on the West for help.
I am sending delegations to America
and Great Britain, as well as India,
in hope that these countries
will recognize our independence.
Lukhangwa and Lobsang Tashi,
I am making you
my prime ministers.
Send a delegation to China.
We will begin to make plans
for reforms and modernization.
Today, I declare
a general amnesty.
Free the prisoners.
It's time to take this down.
- You still won't come?
- No, Holiness.
You must continue
to study very hard,
and don't let them
tangle you in politics.
Remember, you're a monk.
I will miss you.
- We have had fun, you and I.
- Yes, we have.
- And you have grown up very good.
- And you...
have grown older and more stubborn,
but you've stayed good.
Tonight, Kundun,
you see the world.
"The gods will win.
The devils will lose."
[Ratcheting Noise]
[Horse Neighs]
I'll send it back to you.
It'll work.
Good-bye, Kundun.
## [Militaristic Drumbeat
Resumes]
## [Fades, Ends]
[Taktra Rinpoche] We will move
the government to Dungkhar Monastery,
near the Indian border.
We will wait there for
the world's response to our crisis.
[Men Shouting
In Distance]
[Monks Speak Urgently
In Tibetan]
He goes for a short time. He will
not leave Tibet. He will return.
Please don't let him go.
Don't let him go.
[Pleading In Tibetan]
[Pleading Together]
[Ling Rinpoche] The Precious One
will not abandon you. Please.
The Precious One will not
abandon you. He will return.
He will not leave Tibet.
Please, get up.
Please, let him go. Please, he will
return. He will not leave Tibet.
Please, please, he will not leave Tibet.
The Precious One will not abandon you.
Please. Please,
venerable monks, please. Please.
[Monk Chanting]
It's quiet.
Yes, Holiness.
- Where are you from?
- Kham, Holiness.
Warriors.
We are that, Holiness.
My army and the Khambas,
they fight with almost nothing.
No airplanes. No trucks.
No weapons. Nothing.
No one can stop them.
Not even me.
They fight for you, Holiness.
Are they wrong?
Violence is never good.
Every result, be it good or bad...
It had a cause.
Why have they come, Holiness?
What did we do that is bad?
Nonviolence takes a long time.
Do we have the time, Holiness?
I have never known.
[Monk Chanting, Faint]
Holiness?
This has come for you.
"Then, at the time of midnight,
the Bodhisattva
saw a clear light.
Then he saw in a single instant
the three states of existence:
The past, the present
and the future,
purified by the clear light.
Then, sitting at the Tree
of Enlightenment, he conquered...
all the devils."
## [Horn Blowing,
Growing Louder]
No, no, wait.
[Continues In Tibetan]
Wait, wait, please. Let's do away
with some of these formalities.
It's enough now.
Stop, stop. Please.
Holiness,
your Nepalese visitors...
- It appears they've
brought you an elephant.
- An elephant?
- Yes, Kundun, an elephant.
- Is it here now?
- They have it with them.
- How fortunate.
He's a modern man,
just like he was the last time.
[Chinese Radio Announcer]
Today, the surrender of Tibet
is complete.
In Peking, representatives from
Tibet and the People's Republic...
signed a Seventeen Point Agreement
returning Tibet to the motherland.
The Dalai Lama's representatives
have signed the agreement in his name...
and with his best wishes
for Tibet's speedy reunification
with the motherland.
- [Plates Crashing]
- Point One: The Tibetan people
shall unite and drive out...
imperialist aggressors
from Tibet.
[Announcer Fades Out]
Your Holiness, may I present
General Chang Chin-Wu.
Chairman Mao asks me
to convey his respect.
I have been instructed
to provide you...
with this copy of the Seventeen Point
Agreement for your signature.
I am empowered to accept
your ratification.
I'm certain you wish
to return to Lhasa.
Do you have plans
to return soon?
[Clears Throat]
We are discussing our plans.
And we can discuss our plans
with you in Lhasa, when you return.
Thank you. Let me know if we can be
of any help on your return journey.
[Men Chattering]
I thought he would be
some kind of monster,
even with horns growing
out of his head.
But he is only a man, just an ordinary
human being, like myself.
They are the worst
of the worst.
They're worse than ghosts.
[Chanting]
[General Chang Chin-Wu]
We were like you.
We were an isolated country.
Then trade began.
For our spices, silks, tea.
But there was nothing that we,
the Chinese, wanted from the West.
So they gave us something
to want: Opium. We craved opium.
They tried to use it
to destroy us, the imperialists.
We are here to rescue you
from imperialists,
or they'll do the same to you.
[Monk Chanting]
You cannot imagine,
sitting here,
where I came from.
The floods,
the famines,
were so bad.
China was fragmented.
Society was crumbling.
There was a day
before the war...
when I came upon a man
with a dead baby.
He was gonna cook it.
He shouted, "It died.
I did not kill it. It died."
That is what it was like
in China before Chairman Mao.
[Gasping]
We believe that the time has come
for you to go to India.
India is our friend.
You'll be safe there.
The Americans will help us, Holiness.
You've read their letter.
That letter's unsigned.
It is not a real promise.
China is close.
America is far away.
Many Tibetans could die,
and China would still be close.
[Clears Throat]
If you stay in Tibet,
we cannot guarantee
your safety, Holiness.
If you flee, Holiness,
you might never be able to return.
We've managed the Chinese
for many years.
These are not the Chinese we know,
Holiness. These are Communists.
The Fifth Dalai Lama joined
an alliance with the Chinese.
And a great spiritual revolution
began in the East.
A spiritual revolution?
Does it begin like this?
Friends, who is
the Fifth Dalai Lama now?
- [Snaps]
- Things change.
Our own short lifetimes
are not the only consideration.
My first and foremost duty
is to protect my people.
I'm going back.
[Conversing In Tibetan]
[Dalai Lama's Eldest Brother]
At first, things were good.
The People's Liberation Army
were kind and helpful.
But that was a long time ago.
They were with me all the time,
never left me alone.
Prodding and insulting and...
Mother, no women
in the monastery after dark.
Go on.
They have burned homes,
bullied people, like they did me.
They think l...
They let me come...
They let me go because...
Tell me.
The Chinese believe
I've agreed to kill you.
Kill me?
I am to convince the Dalai Lama
to agree to their rule,
and if I cannot convince you,
they believe I will kill you.
They think my own brother
will kill me?
They believe that?
[Engines Rumbling]
I hate meeting up here.
This place is a tribute to the past!
And another thing.
I want the songs stopped.
Songs? What songs?
Street songs
about General Tan.
They are singing
about his gold watch.
He's right.
They are quite insulting.
- [Snorting]
- We have no authority
to ban singing in our country.
Then ban the public meetings.
And we want 2,000 more tons
of barley.
This is impossible. You will bring
famine down on the people of Tibet.
More food. The best land
for your soldiers to camp.
The People's Liberation Army
pays for all food and lodging.
So far, they do.
But the quantity does not exist.
You'll have
to reevaluate your needs.
How much tea do you drink,
Prime Minister?
It depends on the quality,
and that it be Indian.
I am instructed to tell you today
that plans for the Tibetan Army...
to be absorbed into the People's
Liberation Army have been finalized...
- I will not approve it.
- Then, we will begin by replacing...
the Tibetan flag
with the flag of the motherland.
And we will begin
with tearing it down.
[Announcer Over P.A.,
In Chinese]
## [Chinese Choir Singing]
## [Continues, Faint]
- I am so sorry.
- [Lukhangwa] It must be done.
We can no longer meet
with the Chinese. They refuse us.
I accept your resignations.
Have you chosen
your new prime ministers, Holiness?
There will be
no new prime ministers.
## [Continues]
They have taken away
our silence.
## [Ends]
[Lord Chamberlain]
Britain, Nepal, America, India...
All of those governments have refused
to meet with our representatives.
[Dalai Lama]
And the United Nations?
The United Nations
voted not to hear our appeal.
So, we must face China
and her might all alone?
I'm afraid so. We have
no choice but to negotiate.
The Chinese must come to Lhasa.
Times are desperate, Phala.
We can go to Peking.
## [Chinese Choir Singing]
[Plane Engine Revving]
## [Fades, Ends]
## [Children's Choir
Singing In Chinese]
## [Continues]
- [Window Shutting]
- ## [Muted]
[Bicycle Bells Ringing]
## [Continues]
[Man] The news of the People's
Liberation Army's march into Tibet...
was enthusiastically supported
by all sections of the population.
In particular, Tibetans
in all parts of China...
jubilantly celebrated
the news...
and demanded their return
to the motherland.
The mission of China
is to bring progress to Tibet.
We welcome you, Tibet,
back to the motherland.
It is too early
to implement all the clauses
of the Seventeen Point Agreement.
[Coughing]
The pace of reform
must meet...
with the desires
of the Tibetan people.
Changes must be made slowly,
as you, yourself,
judge necessary.
Tibet is a great land,
a wonderful history.
Long ago, you even conquered
a part of China.
But now, you have fallen behind,
and we want to help you.
In 20 years time,
you could be ahead of us.
And then, it will be your turn
to help China.
You know, my mother
was a Buddhist.
I have a great respect
for your Lord Buddha.
He was anti-caste,
anti-corruption, anti-exploitation.
For some,
politics and religion...
can mix.
Please, have some sweet.
Made in my home province.
The kind my mother used to make.
[Dalai Lama] I have great hopes
for a mutual cooperation.
He has made important promises.
You know, his family were Buddhist.
They were farming people.
I think socialism and Buddhism
have some things in common.
She will be fine,
Your Holiness.
The climate does not
agree with her.
He has made
important promises.
As you say.
I hope you will not feel badly about all
the things of childhood you missed.
You lost so much.
I am sorry.
Good-bye, Kundun.
No, Norbu. Don't die.
No, none of you. Don't die.
[Man] In passing, a few words
about our nation's minorities.
The people of the whole country
are pleased that the minority
nationalities...
and the Han people are united.
But, we must combat
Han chauvinism.
Don't get the idea that it is
the Han nationality that...
has been primarily helping
the minority nationality.
The minority have given
the Han people great help.
Their every participation
in the community of the Chi...
- [Water Running]
- [Man Continues, Indistinct]
Dalai Lama, excuse me.
Chairman Mao Tse-tung
has sent for you.
Dalai Lama.
Thank you for coming so late.
I leave tomorrow.
Yes, I know.
How has your stay been?
Very interesting.
Your factories are very impressive.
- And I enjoyed the agri...
- You have a lot to learn.
How to draw out people's opinions
and make decisions.
Instruct your young Tibetans,
when I make contact with you,
I want to reach you through
a Tibetan, not a Chinese.
Very good. I agree
with some of your ideas.
For years, we have been reforming
our monasteries and reorganizing...
Your attitude is good, you know.
I understand you well.
But you need to learn this:
Religion is poison.
Poison.
Like a poison,
it weakens the race.
Like a drug,
it retards the mind...
of people and society.
"The opiate of the people."
Tibet has been poisoned
by religion,
and your people
are poisoned and inferior.
Let me walk you
to your car.
[Coughing]
We cannot persuade you
to stay in Peking?
I must return.
Take care of your health.
Write me often.
Welcome to your old home,
Your Holiness.
[Bird Crowing]
[Sniffling]
Are you happy?
I am very happy
and prosperous...
under the Chinese
Communist Party...
and Chairman Mao Tse-tung.
[Crying, Sniffling]
[Plane Engine Buzzing]
[Indistinct Shouting]
- [Gunshots]
- [People Screaming]
I admire them so.
They face a modern, equipped army,
and still they fight.
I have always asked
for just plain information.
The Chinese have bombed
the monastery of Lithang.
It has been destroyed.
They throw rocks from airplanes.
Nuns and monks are made
to fornicate in the streets.
They put their guns in the hands
of our Khamba children...
and force the child
to kill the parent.
- [Crying]
- [Soldier] Die!
- [Gunshots]
- [Screams]
[Gasping]
[Sniffling]
I'll write to Mao again.
He doesn't answer
your letters, Kundun.
Nonviolence means cooperation
when it is possible...
and resistance
when it is not.
You have tried cooperation.
Your resistance must come
from outside Tibet, Kundun.
[Sniffling]
[Gasping]
We will be moving Chinese families
into Tibet territory.
Farmers... 40,000.
A revolt has broken out
in the East.
We have decided that
the Tibetan army must be used
against the Khamba guerrillas.
General Tan,
our people would never...
You do not understand
our people.
I will not approve that.
You have bombed
on peaceful people.
- It is my job to deal
with reactionaries.
- No, we are peace-loving people.
We are here to heal
the people of Tibet.
You need reform.
We are here to liberate you.
No, Buddha is our physician,
General Tan. He will heal us.
Wisdom and compassion
will set us free.
You cannot liberate me,
General Tan.
I can only liberate myself.
[Swords Crashing]
[Crowd Cheering]
You are in grave danger. The Dalai Lama
cannot fall into Chinese hands.
- Our only hope is to fight.
- We cannot.
If they kill you,
they kill Tibet.
You must flee.
[Shouting]
[Crowd Shouting]
"General Tan Kuan San wishes to invite
the Dalai Lama to a dance recital...
at the newly erected Great Hall
of the Liberation Army."
- A dance?
- Yes.
"And because of the climate
in Lhasa, General Tan requests...
that the Dalai Lama come
without his bodyguards."
"One attendant is fine," it says.
They would like to provide him.
Yes, I'm sure they would.
It's no time to anger
the Chinese, Phala.
There are tanks in the streets.
Airplanes wait outside Lhasa.
I think we can safely say the Chinese
are already angry, Holiness.
What would you do,
my friend?
- [Sighs] I am only a bug, Holiness.
- [Chuckles]
Holiness,
I would think of what survival
for Tibet really means...
in the years to come.
I would consider my duty
to protect my people.
And so,
I would leave now...
for India.
But I won't do that.
So, write them. Say I am sorry
to miss their dance.
Another time, maybe.
Tell them to write me often.
I know it's a lie.
But times are bad.
As you say.
You know, Kundun,
I would never have
let you go alone.
Don't ask me
to leave Tibet, Phala.
I won't ask you today, Holiness.
[Creaking]
[All Chanting]
[Chanting Continues]
[Chanting Stops]
[Woman]
You must go. You must go.
[Man #1] Please don't go.
Please don't go. Please.
- [Man #2] I beg you to leave, please.
- [All Pleading]
Your Holiness...
[Crying]
[Pleading,
Mumbling In Tibetan]
[Crying]
[Pleading In Tibetan]
[Hissing]
[Grunting,
Hissing]
[Gasping]
[Hissing Continues]
[Whimpering]
"Where there is no crossing
a big river, no fords, no shallows,
[Mumbling In Tibetan]
Where the only hope is a boat,
and there is no boat,
[Continues]
I will put a boat, Kundun.
The Wish-fulfilling Jewel
will shine from the West."
- [All Shouting, Indistinct]
- [Man] Long live His Holiness!
- Long live His Holiness!
- We have a letter. May I?
- [Dalai Lama] Please.
"If the Dalai Lama
and a few trusted officers...
can stay within the inner wall
and inform General Tan...
exactly which building
you will occupy,
we certainly intend that
this building not be damaged."
They're going to bomb us.
- Apparently.
- Well, we want no mistakes.
He adds as a postscript:
"The Chinese have taken the strictest
measure to prevent your escape."
Tell them I will be here
with my people. Right here.
[Shouting Continues]
[Men, Women Chanting]
[Lord Chamberlain,
Speaking Tibetan]
How is it outside today?
- [Counselor]
It's a sea of frightened faces.
- Hmm.
- There is a rumor
that His Holiness is gone.
- Hmm.
The supply trucks coming
from the Potala...
- Could we fill them with guns?
- Yes, we could.
Khesan, I want you
to call the tailor in.
Have him make you
a soldier's uniform.
Make it look old and worn,
and do it quickly, please.
[Bells Ringing]
[Hissing]
[Grunts]
"Go. Tonight.
Go."
Holiness, the Oracle's route takes us
right past the Chinese encampment.
- We cannot possibly...
- Shh.
- [Explosion]
- [Yelling, Indistinct]
- I'll fight them.
I'll get a gun and fight them.
- I am so confused.
I'm told we have to make a journey,
but no one tells me when or where.
I will go if you are going.
Just go ahead.
The saddest thing is,
we were about to change.
We were going
to do it alone.
We were just about
- I'll go to war.
- The Dalai Lama
does not believe in war.
## [Horns, Percussion,
Faint]
[Monks Chanting]
Dim the lights.
We have a long journey
to make, Pompo.
We do not know how it will end,
and it is very sad.
But I would not consider
going without you.
Holiness, the Chinese
have moved their camp.
The Oracle's route is safe
for us now. We must go.
- Yes.
- Sanctuary has been arranged in India.
- They're expecting you.
- Thank you.
I see a safe journey.
I see a safe return.
Now I am ready.
[Dalai Lama] "I rejoice
in the Awakening of the Buddhas.
And also, in the spiritual levels
of their Sons.
With folded hands, I beseech
the Buddhas of all directions...
to shine the lamp of Dharma for all
bewildered in the gloom of misery."
[People Chattering, Shouting]
- Move aside. Let us through.
- Tour of inspection. Move aside.
Move aside.
Move aside. Move aside.
Tour of inspection.
- Move aside. Move aside.
- Move aside.
Let us through. Move aside.
Let us through.
We have time.
We have time. Move aside.
Let us through.
Move aside.
- [Men Chanting]
- Move aside.
Move aside!
[Chanting Continues]
[Bumping Noise]
## [Choir Vocalizing]
[Dalai Lama] With folded hands,
I beseech all the Buddhas...
who wish to pass away,
to please remain for countless aeons...
and not to leave
the world in darkness.
[Men Murmuring, Indistinct]
My foes will become nothing.
My friends will become nothing.
I, too, will become nothing.
Likewise, all will become...
nothing.
"Right will win.
Wrong will lose."
[Dalai Lama]
Just like a dream experience,
whatever things I enjoy
will become a memory.
Whatever is past
will not be seen again.
[No Audible Dialogue]
I will liberate
those not liberated.
I will release
those not released.
I will relieve
those unrelieved.
And set living beings
in nirvana.
## [Percussion, Horns]
[Counselor] We repudiate
the Seventeen Point Agreement.
We constitute
a temporary government of Tibet,
the only legal authority
in the land.
[All Cheering]
[Dalai Lama] The Buddhas neither wash
ill deeds away with water,
nor remove beings' sufferings
with their hands,
nor transfer their realizations
to others.
Beings are released
through the teachings of the truth.
The final reality.
[Sneezing]
[Dog Barking]
- [Whispering]
- [Laughs]
Shh.
[Lord Chamberlain]
Hurry, Holiness. The Chinese are close.
Hurry, Kundun.
They are close.
[Monks Chanting]
[Ringing]
[Men Chattering]
Kundun, you must walk
to India.
We have won.
Come on.
[Dalai Lama] Thus, by the virtue
that has collected...
through all
that I have done,
may the pain of every living creature
be completely cleared away.
With all respect, sir,
may I ask,
who are you?
What you see before you
is a man, a simple monk.
Are you the Lord Buddha?
I think I am a reflection,
like the moon on water.
When you see me,
and I try to be a good man,
you see yourself.
[Clicks]
[Latches Clicking]
## [Monks Chanting, Low]
## [Ends]