[ Drums ]
[ Band Joins In ]
[ Man Shouting Orders ]
[ Man's Voice ] As I was leaving
my hotel this morning...
the doorman asked me...
''Where are you
bound for, sir?''
When I replied, ''West Point... ''
he remarked,
''It's a beautiful place.
Have you ever
been there before?''
[ Students Laughing ]
Duty, Honour, Country.
Those three hallowed words
reverently dictate...
what you ought to be...
what you can be...
and what you will be.
They are your rallying points.
They give you
a temper of the will...
a quality of the imagination...
a vigor of the emotions...
a freshness of
the deep springs of life...
a temperamental predominance
of courage over timidity...
an appetite for adventure...
over love of ease.
In this way, they will teach you
to be an officer...
and a gentleman.
From your ranks come the great
captains who will hold...
the nation's destiny
in their hands...
the moment
the war tocsin sounds.
The Long Grey Line...
has never failed us.
Were you to do so...
a million ghosts in olive drab...
and brown khaki,
in blue and grey...
would rise from
their white crosses...
thundering those magic words:
Duty, Honour, Country!
This does not mean
that you are warmongers.
On the contrary, the soldier,
above all other people...
prays for peace...
for he must suffer and bear...
the deepest wounds
and scars of war.
But always in our minds
ring the ominous words of Plato.
''Only the dead...
have seen the end of war. ''
[ Explosion ]
[ Man Groaning ]
[ Engines Revving ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Male Dispatcher On Radio.
Indistinct ]
Heads up, soldiers!
[ Air Raid Siren Blaring ]
[ Clamouring ]
[ Panicked Shouting ]
[ Bombs Whistling ]
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
[ Air Raid Siren ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
- Heads up!
[ Explosion ]
- Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir?
Major Huff's got himself wounded.
Would you look after him, please?
Right away, sir.
Corporal, would you take this?
[ Muttering, Groaning ]
[ Distant Explosion ]
Major.
So, one of the Battling
Bastards of Bataan, eh?
Yes, sir. No Mama,
no Papa, no Uncle Sam.
Well, help is on the way.
I have Washington's
solemn promise on that.
[ Man ]
General Marshall, Admiral King...
will you go right in, please?
Thank you.
You said you wanted to talk over
the Corregidor problem.
I certainly do. I've gone
out on a limb with the Filipinos.
We should be getting more
than inspirational radio messages...
through the Japanese blockade.
Have any of our ships made it?
One ship has reached Mindanao,
two more made it to Cebu.
- The rest were either sunk or captured.
- Thank you.
So far we've lost better
than 80,000 tons.
In other words, MacArthur
has received practically nothing.
That's about it, Mr President.
- How long can they hold out?
- Matter of weeks.
We're still dispatching submarines
to Bataan and Corregidor.
We managed to land
some munitions and drugs...
and evacuate a few of the wounded,
but that's all we can do.
Unless you wanna start stripping
the defences of the West Coast,
the Panama Canal--
One bombing of the canal
and it's out of action for two years.
It's a more vulnerable target, more
important target than Pearl Harbor.
And Hitler will have the whole
North American continent for a target...
- if we don't stop him in Europe.
- Exactly.
But you know
what's going to happen.
Like everything else, Douglas is going
to take our strategy personally.
He thinks the blockade
is a figment of my imagination...
and that I'm somehow deliberately
robbing him of glory.
[ Sighs ]
I wish you people would send Douglas
a globe of the world...
to remind him we have
obligations all around it.
We have to support Stalin...
while he fights the bulk
of the Nazi army.
We have to assist Churchill
to keep England functioning.
We have to protect our flanks,
the Panama Canal...
and General Douglas MacArthur.
I need him.
The country needs him.
We can't leave him
to the Japanese.
He won't leave the Philippines
unless you order him off, Mr President.
Cut an order.
Put my name to it.
[ Man #1 ]
L-O-5-O-6-7-3-D. L-9-2-6--
[ Man #2 ]
So long, baby.
That's 1 40 million bucks
theJaps won't get.
[ Man #1 ]
L-4-9-4--
I'm army to the marrow
of my bones, Dick.
I've never disobeyed
an order in my life.
Now, for the first time,
I feel bound to disobey.
Sir, you couldn't.
You'd be court-martialled.
Then I'll resign my commission
and fight on here as a private.
I want you to direct a statement
for the president to that effect.
General, pardon me,
but you don't mean that.
I will not leave!
I'll stay here with my boys.
Sir, you are the only man alive
that can save the Philippines.
[ Distant Explosions ]
They would never have issued
an order to this effect...
unless they intended you to mount
an immediate counteroffensive.
Damn it, those convoys
they diverted...
the troops and supplies
that never got here--
they're waiting for you
in Australia.
And if you leave now, you can be
back before the food runs out.
[ Male Dispatcher On Radio.
Indistinct ]
Sir, you cannot disobey
a presidential order.
[ Male Dispatcher On Radio.
Indistinct ]
The president.
Strange ways
destiny pulls men's lives.
We have to believe that,
don't we,Jack?
[ Aeroplane Engines Droning ]
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
[ Typewriters Clacking ]
[ Distant Explosions ]
I can't even find these supplies.
File that goddam requisition.
Yes, sir!
- Major.
- Is the general busy? The general busy?
You come and see.
He lead a big parade.
[ Music Playing,
MacArthur Singing ]
Excuse me, General.
The submarine has arrived
to evacuate President Quezon
and his family, as you ordered.
- He still wants you to join them.
- No, Sid.
[ Boy ]
Boom-boom-boom
Boompity-boompity
Boompity-boom
Much more on the drums! Let's hear
those drums. Louder on the drums.
Sir, President Quezon is concerned
about your safety. He advises--
If a commander sneaks out, how
are the men supposed to feel?
I'll not skulk out of here
on a submarine.
I'll go in one of
Johnny Bulkeley's PT boats.
Sir, I know those boats.
Their engines are shot.
They'll only make half-speed.
They're made of plywood. They've
got gasoline drums all over the deck.
They're like floating coffins.
They'll go up like a bomb.
At least put your family
on a submarine.
They'd be safer there.
No, Sid, no. I will stay
with the general.
- Jean, you don't understand.
- Come here.
We don't even know how many
Japanese are out there.
A submarine might be the only
safe place for you and Arthur.
We are staying with you.
- Don't forget those
other soiled clothes.
- Yes, ma'am.
[ Explosion ]
Jeannie, Sid is right. It's gonna
be a very dangerous journey.
I'd rather have
you and Arthur--
Now, sir, as you are
so fond of saying...
''We three are one.
We drink of the same cup.''
Jeannie.
You're my finest soldier.
How did Shakespeare put it?
''The general's wife
is the general's general.''
Colonel Wainwright, sir?
General MacArthur's arriving.
Thank you, son.
There goes Dugout Doug and
his whole goddam gypsy caravan.
Goodbye, General, sir.
Castro, keep up
the good fight.
A guerrilla force is forming.
- I'm joining them.
- Very good.
I've got my rifle.
- Ammunition?
- Enough.
All right, then.
Cross over to Bataan.
There are good men in
the hills there.Join them.
- Fight with them.
- Yes, sir.
Good luck, Castro.
We'll meet again.
Well,Jim, I have no choice.
I know.
If we get through to Australia...
I'll be back as soon as I can...
with as much as I can.
- I suppose I can't convince you
to go by submarine.
- No, no, no.
If we can break through,
it will demonstrate to Washington...
that this blockade
can be pierced...
if you have the daring for it.
In the meantime...
you've got to hold on here.
Yes, sir.
Cigars, shaving cream.
Thank you.
Jim...
let the men know
that I'm obeying...
a direct order
from the president.
[Jim ]
I will. I will.
- [ Boat Engine Rewing ]
- When I return, I'll make you
a lieutenant general.
I'll be here, or I'll be dead.
- Goodbye,Jim.
- Goodbye.
- Welcome aboard, sir.
- Thank you, Lieutenant.
[ Tokyo Rose ] I'm saying hello
again to you boys on Corregidor.
Especially you,
General MacArthur.
On behalf of theJapanese nation,
allow me to invite you to a party...
to celebrate
our forthcoming victory.
A surprise party.
In fact, a necktie party,
here in Tokyo.
- Sorry, General.
- [ Radio Clicks Off ]
Let's skip that
little party, shall we?
Aye, aye, sir.
[ Boat Engine Droning ]
What is it?
Mines.
I think that's the last of them, sir.
There's a pot of hot coffee
up forward, sir.
- Would you like some?
- No coffee!
How do you feel, sir?
I'm not exactly a navy man, Sid.
Well, when we get to Australia,
the commissioner of railways...
has ordered his own personal car
for your trip to Melbourne.
Anything I can do, sir?
Can't sleep.
We're safe.
They're doomed!
I know what they're saying.
''Dugout Doug MacArthur
lies a-shakin' on the Rock...
safe from any danger
and any sudden shock.''
I've heard that song.
Well, I'm sure that the men
who thought that one up...
were just blowin'
off steam, sir.
I'm only thankful my father
isn't alive to hear it.
Sir!
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Woman Counting In Foreign
Language, Little Arthur Responding ]
[ Counting Continues ]
I knew the train
would be the best.
This is the first time he's really
slept since Pearl Harbor.
Hmm.
[ Counting Continues ]
[ Fanfare ]
[ Cheering ]
Good crowd, and it looks like all the
Australian brass you want to talk to...
are out there
waiting for you, sir.
All I see is people.
Where are the kangaroos?
I'm sure we'll see
some soon, dear.
[ Man ]
What I'd like to have is a public
address system by the back railing.
[ Crowd Cheering,
Band Playing ]
Hello, Dick.
Do you have a report for me?
Ah, yes, I do, but-- but there's
a crowd waiting.
Why don't you go out,
and I'll brief you in the hotel.
Well, good news can wait,
bad news can't.
Let's have it.
Well, sir...
I, uh--
Nobody knows anything about
a Philippine relief expedition.
I'm sorry.
In the whole of Australia,
there is a grand total
of some 30,000 U.S. personnel...
mostly artillery
and engineers...
scattered all over
the continent.
At present,
there's no American infantry.
Air units?
There are about 250 planes
of all types...
more or less in commission.
Sixty-five of them
are undergoing repairs...
a hundred and twenty-two
of them are being assembled.
There's almost
no navy at all.
[ MacArthur ]
And no infantry. God help us.
Well, there are approximately
300,000 Australian troops...
but they've been described as
undertrained and underequipped.
You know what that means.
Not only is the Bataan rescue mission
so much blue sky over the horizon...
it is even open to question
if we can defend Australia.
[ Crowd ]
MacArthur! MacArthur!
- Ready to go, Daddy?
- Shh.
However, there is
one more thing, sir.
Headquarters here
at Melbourne has received...
a message for you from
President Roosevelt.
He has awarded you
the Medal of Honour.
Congratulations, sir.
[ Crowd ] MacArthur! MacArthur!
MacArthur! MacArthur!
MacArthur!
Congressional Medal of Honour.
MacArthur! MacArthur!
MacArthur!
You know, my father...
was awarded the same decoration
when he was only 1 9.
MacArthur! MacArthur!
I had to wait
just a little bit longer.
MacArthur! MacArthur!
[ Microphone Feedback ]
But at this moment...
I would swap it
for just one trained division.
[ Band Playing,
Crowd Cheering ]
[ Applause, Cheering ]
Excuse me, gentlemen. Would you
please shoot from a low angle?
The general likes
that effect very much.
The president
of the United States--
The president--
[ Band Stops Playing ]
[ Cheering Continues ]
The president of the
United States ordered me...
to break through
the Japanese lines...
and proceed from Corregidor
to Australia...
for the purpose of organizing...
the American offensive
against Japan...
a primary object of which...
is the retaking of the Philippines.
I came through...
and I shall return.
[ Over Radio ]
This is General Wainwright speaking.
Subject.Surrender.
To put a stop to further
useless sacrifice of human life...
I've decided to accept...
in the name of humanity,
the formal surrender...
of all American and Philippine
army troops...
in the Philippine Islands.
It became apparent that the garrisons
would be eventually destroyed.
This dissension
was forced upon me...
by means entirely
beyond my control.
Let me emphasize there
must be no thought whatever...
of disregarding
these instructions.
My assistant chief of staff
will repeat the complete text...
of this letter by radio
to General MacArthur.
[ MacArthur ]
It's a trick! It's a Japanese deception!
No, sir. Everyone recognized
the general's voice.
He struck Old Glory
and ran up a bedsheet!
By what authority does he issue
such an unlawful order?
He's the acting commander.
The only possible explanation
is that he's temporarily deranged.
For that reason alone,
his orders have no validity.
I place no credence
on this alleged broadcast.
Everybody up there believed him,
the Japanese included! The conditions--
If it's true, then we
should get back at once.
It's not too late to join
the guerrillas on Luzon.
General,
you-you can't be serious.
They-They won't be
organized for months.
Now, we both know that Wainwright
could not hold on indefinitely.
He was not asked
to hold on indefinitely!
His job was to defend the island
until help arrived!
- That was his assignment.
- He had no supplies, no food left!
The malaria was
totally out of hand.
If he had tried to
hold out one more day...
we would've had
a dreadful massacre.
General, would--
[ Aeroplanes Fly By ]
Yes, yes, yes.
I suppose it was
just a matter of time.
[ Buzzer ]
- [ Man On Phone ]
General Blamey on line two, sir.
- I can't speak to him now.
He'll call back later.
There's some talk
in Washington about...
a Medal of Honour
for Wainwright.
They want you
to recommend it.
Medal of Honour?
If Wainwright received it...
it would constitute an injustice
to others who have done far more.
Send the following radio
to General Marshall.
''I believe that Wainwright has
become temporarily unbalanced...
and that his condition renders
him susceptible of enemy use.''
Unquote.
[ Shouting ]
[ Man ] General, this training is well
and good, but it's not enough.
These troops are green corn!
They won't be ready for weeks!
All soldiers are green
until their first battle.
Shit, sir-- excuse me--
I don't even have the transport...
to supply a single division
for 24 hours.
Hell, I can't even
land 'em on the beach.
Harding, I want action
from you, not complaints.
If I don't get going,
the navy's gonna win this war.
Look what Nimitz did up
at Coral Sea and Midway.
I know you don't have
everything you need.
Sir, if I could just have
a little more time--
That's because our
friends in Washington...
are sending it all to George Patton
in North Africa...
so he can run around in the desert,
fighting a seesaw tank battle.
- If I could just have--
- Sid, I want to see
my new air commander.
Where's General Kenney?
- General Kenney?
- Good morning.
[ MacArthur ]
Where'd you get the B-1 7?
It flew in from the States
this morning.
We're puttin' together several
squadrons up in Brisbane.
Good! How soon can you
get 'em in the air?
Soon enough to get
the enemy off our back...
and maybe go kick his butt
for a change.
Good, good!
My boys say you can't do it.
Well, your boys aren't fliers.
Give me five days to prepare...
and I'll ship the whole goddam
United States Army to New Guinea by air.
[ Chuckles ]
Really?
- My staff hear about this?
- I doubt it.
Don't tell 'em.
You'll scare 'em half to death!
Attack!
[ Man ]
And you ram it right down his throat!
The recent bombings of our
northern airfields give us
every reason to believe...
that the nips' next move
will be a massive invasion
of the Australian continent.
The garrison at Darwin,
up here...
doesn't have enough troops
to hold for more than 48 hours.
So our best plan, therefore,
is to show token resistance...
and fall back rapidly to this,
the Brisbane Line.
To the north, the enemy
will find only burnt offerings.
Meanwhile in the southeast,
we will throw everything...
into the fight for the cities
and the farmlands around them.
This is the living heart
of Australia...
and we shall defend it
with our lives.
- General.
- Thank you.
Gentlemen...
I've been deeply moved...
and deeply stirred...
by the Allied efforts...
and by the courage and
determination of the Australians...
as expressed by
General Blamey, but...
as supreme commander of
the southwest Pacific area...
I will not be the leader
of another lost cause.
We are attacking, gentlemen.
I am going to make
the fight for Australia...
up here in New Guinea.
[ Murmuring ]
[ Tokyo Rose ]
Hey, Joe, whatcha doing out here?
You should be home on the farm
walking with your girl...
getting your chores done
and sitting down to supper.
Or maybe you should
be taking in a show...
walking down Broadway,
sipping Coke.
Thejungle's where we live.
It's where you die.
[ MacArthur ]
Bob, I sent for you...
because I don't think you like
a stalemate any better than I do...
and that's what we've got
here in New Guinea.
They tell me that American boys
are actually throwing away
their rifles and turning tail.
That hasn't happened since
the first Battle of Bull Run.
I want you
to relieve Harding.
This isn't the Civil War, General.
Harding's a good man,
he's a good officer.
- It's just that he's up against--
- I'm sending you in, Bob.
I want you to remove
all officers who won't fight.
If necessary, put sergeants
in charge of battalions...
and corporals in charge
of companies.
Anyone who will fight.
I want you to take Buna
or don't come back alive...
and that goes for
your chief of staff too.
[ Birds Twittering ]
Yes, sir.
Bob.
If you come through this
all right...
I'll give you
the Distinguished Service Cross...
I'll recommend you
for a high British decoration...
and I'll release your name
for newspaper publication.
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much, General.
I don't care how deep
the goddam mud is!
I want you to kick ass,
or I'm gonna ream yours!
Good news, General.
This battle is over.
It says so right here
in Stars and Stripes.
General MacArthur
won it yesterday.
Well, the great Sarah Bernhardt.
Another dramatic moment.
God, he tells
the newspapers...
but I wish he'd told the Japanese.
Son of a bitch.
''Mopping-up operation''!
Now, what kind of a phrase
is that to ask men to die for?
I'm surprised he didn't say
we're just policing the area.
- I wonder who really
writes that propaganda.
- I don't know.
I don't trust any of those ass-kissers
up there at D.H.Q...
surroundin' MacArthur.
Hell, he doesn't have a staff,
he's got a court!
You ever see any of'em?
They remind me of
a bunch of barracuda...
I used to play poker with
in Shanghai years ago.
We had to put the goddam
cuspidor in the centre of the table...
because no one dared look away
long enough to spit!
- Where you off to?
- Gotta go to the latrine, sir.
But I shall return.
[ Explosions ]
[ Man #1 ]
8-5-9-9-7-0-0.
U.S. 7-6-9-9-7-2-6.
Australian. No tags.
No tags?
Take care of him later.
U.S. 7-7-2-5-9-6-2.
Jewish.
[ Man #2 ] Oh, my God,
here comes General MacArthur!
[ Man #1 ] Yeah, yeah, and I bet he's
got Eleanor Roosevelt with him too.
No, I'm serious. Look.
General, sir!
Excuse me, sir, but we just--
We just killed a Jap sniper here
not five minutes ago.
Fine, son. That's the best thing
to do with them.
Thought you said there were 1 ,500 Japs
here. We ran into more like 6,000.
[ Man #1 ]
U.S.
5-8-1-3-8-6-4.
[ Man #2 ] You mind repeating
the last four again?
[ Man #2 ]
3-8-6-4.
Not my idea
of how to win a war.
[ Man #1 ]
Australian. 0-0-8-0-2.
Protestant.
Jensen, Steve.
2-4-4-0-7-8-6.
[ Minister Blessing The Dead ]
[ MacArthur ] I'm thinking
about Hansa Bay still up ahead.
Yes, and Hansa Bay is not
some little outpost...
- that we can overrun with
galoshes and determination.
- [ Distant Explosion ]
We need men, supplies.
Plenty of both.
Well, bombing Hansa Bay is one thing.
Taking it's another.
You can say that again.
Well, let's just say
we won't take Hansa Bay.
- We won't what?
- [ Aeroplanes Fly By ]
That's it.
We don't want it.
- General, the farther up
the New Guinea coast we go...
- [ Machine Gun Fire ]
the more trouble
we're gonna run into.
And I hope you don't think
it's gonna be any easier at Wewak.
There's 60,000 of them holed up there,
sharpening their samurai swords.
Good. I hope there's more.
We don't want Wewak either.
We'll bypass their strong points...
cut their supply lines and leave 'em
to wither and die on the vine.
- But what about my men?
- Starve Hansa Bay. Starve Wewak.
Starvation is my ally.
[ Man On Film ]
Okay, soldier, welcome to the fight.
So the cut of the cards
has dealt you a tour of the Pacific.
What's it going to be like
fighting the nips...
and who is this man, Douglas
MacArthur, your new commander?
Let's take a look at the general
who in a few short months...
has turned the tide
toward victory.
Colonel Whitney! Yes.
We've been expecting you.
- Welcome to New Guinea.
Come in out of the light.
- I'm so sorry.
That's all right.
Please, have a seat right over here.
Excuse me just a moment.
I have to watch this one section.
Okay, that's more like it.
I understand you're here to organize
Philippine guerrilla activity?
Yes, yes, that's right. But you know,
I've just come from Washington.
I must tell you straight off...
you've done an absolutely
topnotch job on the general's press.
He's America's hero now, and no
small amount of credit belongs to you.
Well, we don't want the home folks
to forget about us out here.
Oh! I don't think you realize
the dimensions of the excitement.
Here. Letters
from congressmen, senators...
corporation executives,
even two governors.
And thousands of
just plain folks.
''You are big, B-I-G...
''enough to do a complete
housecleaning...
''of parasitic bureaucrats
in Washington.
''As long as the war is on,
only a military figure like yourself...
can unseat the man
in the White House.''
There's one from a lady
in New Jersey I want you to read.
- Excuse me a minute. I just
want to look at this closing.
- Oh, sure.
Just remember, America's
greatest combat general
will be leading you into battle.
''Hit 'em where they ain't.''
That's his motto.
This is the MacArthur touch...
combining sea and air power
as never before...
he's leapfrogging right over the enemy's
strongholds to cut their chow lines...
all the way to the Philippines.
Now you get your chance to
fulfil the immortal pledge.
I came through,
and I shall return.
[ Film Ends With Fanfare ]
Good! Good!
- Some exciting stuff there.
- Thank you.
Okay on this one
to Washington.
Wow! President MacArthur.
I like the sound of that.
Only question is,
how does it sound to MacArthur?
[ MacArthur ] You know that I have
no political ambitions whatsoever.
General-- General, this country's
always had a hero.
Washington, Lincoln, Lindbergh.
Now you.
It's in all the papers.
- The Republican ones.
- No, sir. Democratic ones too.
Listen to this woman
in New Jersey.
She says, ''I have never wanted to
sin with any other man in my life...
but I would with you.''
How about it, General?
Uh-oh. Here's a little boy
in Moline, Illinois.
Wants to know,
''Why do you carry a cane?
Are you feeble?''
[ Men Laughing ]
General, what we want to do is
to print ''I shall return''...
on candy bars, matchbooks, chewing
gum, sewing kits and pencils...
and drop them on the Philippines
to boost morale.
- First-rate idea.
- Yes, sir.
But back in Washington, the Office
of War Information wants to know if...
before things get going...
you'd be amenable to
a small revision of the wording.
What sort of a revision?
Well, sir, they feel that
''We shall return'' is more to the point.
- ''We shall return''?
- Yes, sir.
I fail to see what purpose
that would serve.
[ MacArthur ] Why does Roosevelt
want me at Pearl Harbor?
What's he up to?
Why haven't I been told
what this is all about?
I'm perfectly willing to discuss
strategy with Admiral Nimitz,
if that's what they want.
I suspect Roosevelt has been pulling
some strings to keep me in the dark.
You know, he's always
favored the navy.
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Whistling Stops ]
[ Cheering ]
That's our general.
And you should see the fire-engine
red car he just drove up in.
Douglas MacArthur
starring Douglas MacArthur.
He keeps me waiting
half an hour, and then he gets
a bigger reception than I did.
Now I see what
Eisenhower meant.
He said he spent nine
long years with MacArthur--
studying dramatics!
Excuse me, sir.
Would you look this way?
Keep talking and act natural.
You're looking well, Douglas.
Tell me about your family.
Just fine, thank you,
Mr President.
Sorry that I couldn't entertain
Eleanor when she was in Australia.
She enjoyed visiting
with Mrs MacArthur.
You, as I recall,
were out of town fighting a war.
Oh, and, Douglas, before
we get down to business...
I'd like to take this opportunity
to present you with a decoration.
The Order of Merit for
Conspicuous Inspiration...
of the American People.
[ Roosevelt Laughing ]
General MacArthur,
we have asked you here because
the joint chiefs of staff...
have been considering for about
a year, without a decision...
the next step to be taken
in the Pacific war.
The president has decided he
would like to hear firsthand...
the views of his commanders
in chief in the field.
Admiral Nimitz, would you
please present the plan prepared
by you and Admiral King.
Yes, sir.
In our westward drive
across the Pacific...
the navy's consistent goal...
has been to cut Japan's
line of communication.
Now, as you know, the central
Pacific offensives...
have taken under control
the Gilbert, the Marshall,
and the Marianan island groups.
In our view, the sound strategy
for early victory...
is to occupy the western Pacific
and seize Formosa...
both to control
the Formosa Strait...
and as a jumping-off point
against Japan.
Now, this means bypassing...
the main Philippine island
of Luzon...
until Formosa is secured.
After General MacArthur's troops...
have seized
the southern Philippines...
the access of advance
that should get the highest priority...
is the central Pacific offensive
toward Formosa.
General MacArthur
could then move into Luzon...
and recapture Manila after
my forces have taken Formosa.
In fact, with the fall of Japan...
the liberation
of the northern Philippines...
including Manila...
will follow de facto, without
any need for force of arms.
We therefore propose
to invade Formosa...
at the earliest opportunity.
And my planners are convinced...
that a target date
of March 1 , '45...
is not unreasonable.
Well, Douglas,
how does it sound to you?
I'm a soldier, and I'll
hold the horse if so ordered.
To bypass isolated islands
is one thing...
but to leave in your rear...
250,000 Japanese troops...
drawing their sustenance
from the Philippines...
involves serious
and unnecessary risks.
From Luzon,
I can clamp a blockade...
on all supplies
from the south to Japan...
thus forcing her
to an early capitulation.
Therefore, I propose...
that we land
at Leyte Beach on Luzon...
and then carry
the fight to Manila.
Given a successful landing,
aren't you afraid of a long
and bloody campaign?
With the kind of
performance and support...
provided thus far by the navy...
I can be in Manila
in five weeks...
from the day my troops
step ashore on the beaches...
and well before next March.
General, how can you say that?
Because for two years, Filipino
guerrillas have been working...
behind the Japanese lines to
set the stage for our landings.
It's your position to know,
but I can't conscientiously
agree with this estimate.
To take Luzon would demand
heavier losses than we can stand.
It seems to me
we should bypass it.
In my two years of fighting
in the southwest Pacific area...
and they have been
long, hard years...
fewer Americans have been killed
than in the single battle of Anzio.
The days of the frontal
attack are over.
Only your mediocre
commanders use it.
Your good commanders
do not turn in heavy losses.
[ Roosevelt]
Douglas, Admiral Nimitz's victories
have been no less than your own.
Franklin, all the years
we've known each other...
I don't believe I told you how
my father won his Medal of Honour.
No, you never did. But you're
about to do it now, aren't you?
It was during the Battle
of Missionary Ridge.
At the height of the fighting,
he saw the flag go down.
As others around him faltered,
he seized up the colours...
and rallied
the troops to victory.
Admiral Nimitz is one
of our greatest admirals.
But just now,
as I listened to the plan...
I thought I saw our flag
going down.
Oh, did you?
Mr President,
had we the will to do so...
we could have saved Bataan and
Corregidor in the first place!
To sacrifice Luzon a second time
cannot be condoned or forgiven.
My dear General...
bypassing Luzon is not
synonymous with sacrificing--
But bypassing Luzon has implications
which stain American honour.
Do you realize what
theJapanese propagandists are
telling the Filipino people?
That Americans will never
shed their blood...
to save the coloured peoples
of the earth!
Your zeal is understandable.
I admire it.
But we can't let it interfere...
with a workable Pacific strategy.
''I give to the Philippines
my solemn pledge...
''that their freedom
will be redeemed.
''Entire resources of men
and material of the United States...
stand behind that pledge.''
Your words, sir.
Mr President...
General MacArthur's points
are well taken...
and I'm sure that the joint chiefs will
wish to consider them very carefully.
I shall return.
I am going back there next fall
if I have to paddle a canoe.
If your decision be to bypass
Luzon with its millions of people...
thousands of American
prisoners of war...
to continue to languish there
in agony and despair...
I daresay that the American
public would be so aroused...
that they would register
complete resentment
against you at the polls next fall.
Arthur! Arthur Prettyman!
[ Roosevelt ] Get me an aspirin tablet.
No, no, make it two.
Nobody can talk me into a headache
the way General MacArthur can.
Gentlemen, I think
it's time to call a recess.
- It's been a fatiguing day.
- Indeed it has, sir.
Recess was my favourite time
in school.
It's getting
to be that way in war.
[ Roosevelt Coughing ]
- Douglas.
- Yes, Mr President?
Why haven't you come home
all these years?
Well, I've had
my hands full out here.
The country has evolved...
grown mature.
Change is inevitable, you know.
The things I value never change.
My only regret is that my son
has never seen his country.
He's never been home.
Where is that for you?
Well, in a sense,
the army is home.
Even my swaddling clothes
were khaki.
Mainly I--
I think of West Point as home.
The lecture halls...
the football fields
where I became a man.
And I--
I also see a terrace
overlooking Manila Bay.
Yes, the Philippines
were also home.
I appreciate and understand
your feelings, Douglas.
Now, I shall inform
the joint chiefs of staff...
upon my return home, that
I have had two excellent briefings.
I'm sure they'll be
both pleased and delighted.
And I shall ask them to make
their decision promptly.
Thank you.
I'd like to return to my command
as soon as possible.
For 40 years,
I've held a firm conviction...
that a commander's place
is at the scene of the battle.
I agree with you entirely, Douglas.
That is why I am here.
[ Man ]
''Southwest Pacific forces...
''to invade Leyte.
Target date
advanced to 20 October. ''
Hot damn, we got it!
This'll make the old man happy.
He'll be returning to the Philippines
two months earlier than he expected.
Sergeant, I want you to get this
out immediately, if not sooner...
to all top command
headquarters.
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning, General.
- Earplugs, sir.
- Thank you.
- Good morning, Mr President.
- Good morning, General.
- President Osmea,
earplugs for your ears.
- Thank you.
I hope to hell they do as well
on the beaches as they did in training.
I don't think you have to worry
about that, General.
I know the 5th Cavalry.
When I was a little boy, my father
was a captain at Fort Selden...
in the New Mexico Territory.
Geronimo, the Apache scourge,
was on the loose...
and it was a troop from this same 5th
Cavalry that rode through to help us.
They fought then.
They'll fight now.
And they'll win.
Look at that, Mr President.
The second wave
is going in upright.
Our intelligence reports said the
Japanese wouldn't let us on the beaches.
But just look at those boys!
Nothing will stop them!
Where's my landing craft?
I'm going ashore.
I had it delayed, sir. Heavy enemy
mortar fire on the beach.
I felt it was unsafe for
the commander in chief--
- The landing craft, Captain.
- Aye, aye, sir.
President Osmea,
you're home at last.
Follow me.
Correspondents, please
stay in the rear until after
the general makes his statement.
No questions--Jerry, where
are you going with that?
I'm gonna get a better shot
down the beach, sir.
I want that camera where it was.
I wanna see that wreckage
in the background.
The general will think
this smoke is marvellous!
Get back.
Correspondents, back.
Low angle, remember.
Right over there. Stay.
You see, General...
my people are going to laugh
if I fell in deep water.
- I cannot swim!
- That's not so bad, Mr President.
Everyone's about to see
that I can't walk on water.
People of the Philippines...
I have returned.
By the grace of Almighty God...
our forces stand again...
on Philippine soil.
The hour of your
redemption is here.
Rally to me.
Let the indomitable spirit...
of Bataan and Corregidor lead on.
As the lines of battle
roll forward...
rise and strike.
For your homes and hearths...
strike!
For future generations...
of your sons and daughters, strike!
In the name of your sacred dead...
strike!
Let no heart be faint.
Let every arm be steeled!
The divine guidance of God
points the way.
Follow in his name to the Holy Grail
of righteous victory!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hold it! Hold it!
General, sir, you've
arrived at the front lines.
Well, I see our boys fully
1 00 yards up ahead.
Sir, that's only a forward patrol.
The men are under enemy fire.
You'd be in extreme hazard
if you go on up past this point.
There's Japs right up there.
You can't fight 'em
if you can't see 'em, son.
Let's go.
[ Soldier ]
I don't believe it.
That's the first time I've ever seen
a commander in chief take the point.
Yeah, he's the greatest general
since Sergeant York.
[ Gunfire ]
[ Explosion ]
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Come on.
Will you look at him?
Does he really think
that he can't get hurt?
God damn it,
of course he does!
I've got a little surprise
for the general.
- Morning, gentlemen.
- Good morning, sir.
Sir...
pursuant to an act of Congress...
you have been promoted
to the rank of General of the Army.
Such promotion to take effect
1 8 December, 1 944...
by order of the president.
Sir, we thought that you should
get these on as soon as you can.
[ Explosion ]
[ Man ]
You got your fifth star, General.
Well, I have no objections.
I like the look of'em.
- Congratulations, sir.
- Thank you, Court.
[ MacArthur ]
I think it would be a good idea...
to take that mortar out
before someone gets hurt.