[man on television]
I can't hear you.
It's them bells!
I've had them in my
ears for ten hours.
Ding, dong, ding, dong.
[man 2] Hey, sergeant.
Where's Major Lance?
[man 3] We moved the CP back to
that stone building. The major's there.
[man 2] Get him,
the colonel's here.
Hold it!
[guns firing in distance]
[man] Colonel! Am I glad to see you!
[man 2] Those bodies...
Get those bodies down!
- What are you doing? Get 'em down!
- Of course. Yes, sir.
- We've been under fire...
- I know you have, but I don't care!
Get 'em down! Down!
Don't want those boys left up there.
We're gonna hold this town till
the linkup does come, whenever it is.
Today, tomorrow,
till hell freezes over.
For their sake,
if for no other reason.
- [man] Private?
- [man 2] Yes, sir.
- [man] It's a hell of a war.
- [man 2] A privilege to serve with you.
Well, God willing, we'll do
what we came here to do.
- Ready, sir.
- Move out!
Pilgrim, we fought
for this country, too.
Five postcard stamps, please.
- Thank you. Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas.
Thank you so much.
Have a Merry Christmas.
Airmail to Kingston, Jamaica.
Stamps only?
[speaks Jamaican]
Twenty-cent stamp, please.
Excuse me, sir?
- Rodolfo.
- You.
[gun fires]
[screaming]
- Hey, buddy.
- Um, press.
OK.
- Are you Detective Ricci?
- That's my story.
I heard about you.
[grunts] Yeah, well,
you oughta change friends then.
I'm Tim Boyle. Daily News.
- What happened?
- Read about it in the New York Post.
They left here two hours ago along with
The Times, Newsday and every channel
you can get on TV with a wire hanger.
Ain't you ever heard of the early bird?
- Christ.
- Go find a wailing wall.
- I got lost.
- Comin' here?
Find another way
for a dollar to change pockets.
- It's my first day as a reporter.
- It's probably your last.
Welcome to New York.
Be like Governor Rockefeller:
- Come and go at the same time.
- Give me some angle.
All I can give you
is an empty feeling, kid.
The perp's over at Bellevue,
eighth floor peanut gallery.
The victim's deader
than yesterday's beer.
Heard he wasn't special
when he was breathing.
My next job's gonna be stuffin'
ballot boxes on Staten Island.
Remind me to vote. I live there.
Most cops do. Go home, kid.
- Don't stop for bread.
- Come on.
Gotta be something I can work.
Can I give you a tip on a hot horse?
I'll play Santa at the PA
on Christmas Day. Or I'll...
I'll pay Hong Kong Sue over on Forty
Deuce to blow your noodle like Satchmo.
How about I put a story
in your hip pocket?
"Good Cop Helps Poor Kids."
Honest to Jesus, you get three months
of Saturdays out of it. Come on.
I can't go back to scratching out obits.
See those guys?
Don't turn around.
They're rolling up to Harlem
to sniff around the perp's apartment.
Only case that dynamic duo has cracked
has Schaefer written on the side,
but maybe you'll see something.
Don't quote those gumflappers.
- You need a quote, you call me.
- OK.
- Haggerty, Dillard!
- Yeah, what's up?
- Take this guy uptown with you.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Come on.
- All right.
We'll start in the living room
and work our way back.
Close the door behind you, kid.
This perp is very, very religious.
Nothing wrong with being
in good standing with the Lord.
And a war hero, too.
Look at this, a Purple Heart.
Hey, Keith, the Brown Bomber.
[Keith] Muhammad Ali would've knocked
him out. Way too fast for Joe Louis.
He can run, but he can't hide.
Hey, Dan, what the hell is this?
- [Dan] What you got there?
- I don't know. It's heavy.
Whatever this is, it ain't junior-grade.
This thing looks expensive.
My wife claws around flea markets
looking for this crap every weekend.
I'm telling you, this ain't normal.
This definitely ain't normal.
- Back up, buddy.
- Sorry.
[Keith] No problem.
- Professor Brooks?
- Yes.
I get a lot of these things.
Old rocks. Antique specials.
It seems like every
schmuck in the world
who finds a backyard arrowhead
mistakes me for Iris.
Put it here.
From Greek mythology.
She is the faithful voice of Zeus.
She flies from place to place
and commands respect
from mortals and from im...
...immortals.
- Where the hell'd you get this?
- From a perp's apartment.
- It's got this mark...
- Don't touch it.
This is over 450 years old.
It's the missing Primavera
from the Santa Trinita.
Is that the Niña, the Pinta
or the Santa Maria?
Oh, for God sakes, detective.
It's the oldest elliptic
arch bridge in the world.
It's in Florence, Italy.
Built by Ammanati.
This was one of four statues on it.
The Primavera, meaning "spring."
This head has been missing
since the Nazis blew up
the bridge in 1944.
My God! This is a gold mine!
A gold mine!
Yo!
[elevator dings]
Merry Christmas. From Tim Boyle.
Oh, wise guy.
[Tim] Mr. Hector Negron?
[children shouting]
[in Italian]
Darling, come back to bed.
Please. Enough.
I need a little break, OK, baby?
[Tim] They say you haven't
spoken or eaten in two days.
They'll try to force-feed you.
Make you rise, like Jesus.
Come on. I've hiked all over
New York asking about you.
I talked to everybody.
Cops, your sister.
Spoke to your cousin in San Juan.
You're clean as a board of health.
You got no kids, no debts, no enemies.
Four years in the service. Purple Heart.
Twenty-five years
of a great marriage,
till your wife's heart gave out.
So why you stick a German Luger
in a guy's chest
three months short of your retirement?
Five million dollars.
That's how much that head would
draw on the black market.
What's it doin' buried there
on the bottom of your closet?
You're looking at 25 to life, pal.
Unless you can afford a lawyer,
you're gonna swallow happy pills
in this nuthouse the rest of your life.
But my story could help you.
And you need help, mac.
[woman, in Italian] Enrico, what kind
of art dealer specializes in Nazi art?
Because it's a lucrative business.
[in Italian] You Americans love work
more than you love 'love.'
[groans]
[in Italian] My love,
are you ignoring me?
[Keith] Pina, no.
Don't come over here.
[in Italian] Enrico, you said
you only needed ten minutes.
I gotta catch up. World might've
ended, I wouldn't know
'cause we've been going at it
two days. For crying out loud.
[in Italian] The world is still here.
You and I are still here.
Baby, not right now.
There you go. Excuse me.
OK?
Oh, God. Oh, that feels good.
[Pina giggling]
You're killing me, baby.
[in Italian] Yes, I love you to death.
[sighs]
I...
Hmm? What is it, Mr. Negron?
I... I know.
You know what?
I know who the sleeping man is!
- [Tim] You know what?
- I know who the sleeping man is.
[bells tolling]
[child yelling in Italian]
[man whimpering]
Mama. I want mama.
Kill me now! Kill me now,
I wanna go home to my mama!
I don't wanna be here.
I wanna go home!
Kill me now! Kill me now!
Oh, Jesus, I want my mama!
I don't wanna die! I don't wanna die!
Shh!
- Hector, shut him the fuck up.
- Yes, sir.
- I don't wanna die!
- Shut the fuck up!
[whispering] You wanna get us all
killed? That's your mama right now.
- This far enough?
- Keep movin'.
- You doin' fine, big fella.
- Help me, Lord. Help me, Lord.
Help me, Lord,
I'm prepared for Thee.
- Get off of me, sniper bait!
- Bishop, Train, switch flanks.
Bishop, take outer.
Train, take the inner.
- What's that?
- Take inner flank.
- Come on. Switch places, dummy.
Gimme some room.
Hey, Bishop.
Why we got to cross this river?
They sellin' hoecakes
and beer on the other side.
[laughs]
- My good luck charm gives me strength.
- Piece of shit you found
in the gutter in Florence?
Couldn't draw a bowl of turtle soup
from Uncle Amos with that.
Worth more than a bowl of soup!
Shh!
Train.
Hector, you speak Italian.
Cut-off head worth somethin'?
- Yo speaky Puerto Rican, man.
- Hey, muzzle that.
Keep moving.
[man speaks German]
[man on radio] Germany calling,
Germany calling.
Guten morgen, 92nd Division.
Buffalo soldiers, welcome to the war.
[woman on loudspeaker]
We've been waiting for you.
Do you know our German Wehrmacht
has been here digging bunkers
for six months on the Gothic Line?
Waiting.
Your white commanders
won't tell you that, of course.
Why? Because they
don't care if you die.
[whimpering]
But the German people have
nothing against the Negro.
That's why I'm warning you now,
with all my heart and soul.
Save yourself, Negro brothers.
Why die for a nation
that doesn't want you?
A nation that treats you like a slave.
Did I say slave?
Yes, I did.
[speaking German]
Why don't they shut her up?
What is she saying?
Berlin can afford to pipe
that garbage all the way here
but can't give us potato soup.
Individual guns only, on my command.
We have enough ammo
for an hour, maybe two.
[woman] Look around you.
Do you see any white soldiers
in the river next to you?
Are they sending any white
soldiers to die with you today?
- Of course not!
- [man] Steady, ya'll. Adolf Hitler.
Spreadin' that nonsense.
Don't believe a word of that!
Lyin' bastard thinks we monkeys,
apes, baboons, subhuman.
Show him who we are.
[woman] Think of your poor children,
your families suffering at home.
The American white man
is raping your wives and daughters.
Jody is busy right now in your
bedroom, with your wife,
your daughters, even your sons.
And who will stop him if you die today?
Do you think the profitmongers
in Washington, D.C.
care about your children?
They're not thinking of your children!
They're home right now.
Asleep, in a nice warm bed.
Think about the sacrifice
you're making,
just for the privilege of being
second-class citizens back home.
Where can you vote?
Come to the winning side
and, please, teach me those dances.
That Lindy Hop and the Black Bottom.
War is folly, boys.
Better to drop your guns,
give up and dance!
Come out of that cold water, cats!
[speaking German]
You got any more biscuits?
No.
- Or anything else?
- Not for you.
I'll give you money
for a vitamin biscuit.
Go over and beg the Blacks.
What about you?
You a replacement?
65th Army Corps.
I thought they were freezing
their asses off in Russia.
- So?
- You got any biscuits?
No.
They must have given you something.
If I die, you can have all my rations,
but for now,
SHUT THE FUCK UP!!!
I got a hole in my stomach.
[woman] Come on over.
Feel the warmth of the German people.
[speaking German] I can't hear a thing
over that damn whore's prattling.
[woman] We have hot food,
fried chicken,
greens, candied yams
and even delicious biscuits
straight from the oven,
just like your mama cooks.
Hey, boys.
I have two big white biscuits
right here for you.
Buffalo soldiers. Hey, cool cats.
Do I have something
special for you.
And you can have all you want.
That goddamned bitch
is gonna start a race riot.
Is that a white woman, officer?
What's your name, soldier?
- Lieutenant Birdsong, sir.
- Who is that?
- You heard of Tokyo Rose, sir?
- Yeah.
This is the Kraut version. Axis Sally.
She visits us from time to time.
- Is she American?
- Don't know, sir.
[Axis Sally] Have you ever wondered
how it felt to be free?
To be your own man?
To stand tall?
Need a sniper to splat that nag's
brains all over the Serchio.
I can't see a thing outta these.
Roust me up a better set of cans.
Right now, and a drink of water,
on the double.
Yes, sir.
[man] Negative, Abel Six. Stay firm
and await further commands. Over.
What's he gonna do,
give her a smack on the lips?
He sets himself up a mile away with fire
control, then complains he can't see.
Oughta be with his men
like a real captain.
He ain't been here
long enough to learn.
Yeah, and you won't be here
long neither, listenin' to him.
[speaks German]
Stupid white man.
Right now!
Let's go, goddamn it.
New cans, fresh H2O, sir.
[Axis Sally] Buffalo soldiers,
take the first step, fellas.
We have warm fires. Pretty...
- Hold that.
- Yes, sir.
Next time I want you
to take the caps off.
Yes, sir.
German Frauleins like big strong bucks
more than lollipops.
And we love lollipops.
She the one selling
hoecakes and beer?
Your brain's had a rough shuffle.
For the last time, muzzle that shit!
- [machine gun fire]
- Coming down!
- Let's go!
- Suppressing fire!
[screaming]
[yelling]
Withdraw! Withdraw!
[man] Withdraw! Withdraw!
[grunts]
Come on, Train! Come on, move!
Go, go, go, go, go!
[man screaming]
Fire!
George Company. Request artillery
to grids four, seven, nine and 1-6!
- Send the mail!
- Where the hell are you?
- We've crossed!
- You what?
We're with Uncle Jerry!
Put smoke, H.A. to grids four,
seven, nine and 1-6!
It's impossible to be
on the other side of that river.
- Is that Huggs calling out a grid?
- Huggs! What is your position?
Sir! Huggs is down!
Stamps here! Send the mail!
- Send the mail now!
- Write this name down. Stamps.
Stamps. He's across?
He's lying.
Now, set fire to grids two-three,
two-four and two-five.
- That's Rudden, Fox Company.
- George Company? They've crossed?
I'm new to this outfit
doesn't mean I gotta argue
with goddamn second lieutenants acting
like uppity Negroes. You follow me?
Do you follow me, soldier?
Yes, sir.
Smoke and fire to grids
two-three, two-four, two-five.
- Sir.
- Smoke and fire to grids two-three,
- two-four, two five. Over!
- two-four and two-five!
- [grunts]
Adolf Hitler, this is for you.
What the hell!
Radio!
- Withdraw!
- Withdrawing!
[Stamps] Cease fire! Cease...
Adjust fire! Adjust fire!
I repeat, adjust fire!
Request artillery to grids four,
seven, nine and 1-6! Send the mail!
[speaks German]
Fire!
[screaming]
Incoming!
[screams]
[screaming]
Get off me!
Help!
Help! Help!
Cover me!
[screaming]
[both panting]
[distant artillery firing]
Come on. Come on.
OK. You and me gotta
get to that tree. OK?
- All right.
- Go!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Get down, get down, get down!
[artillery whistling]
[grunting]
[yelling] Oh! Oh, Lord!
Oh, I'm coming up yonder!
Meet me, Jesus!
- Shut up.
- Oh, Bishop, they got you, too.
- No. Listen!
- Is we dead, Bishop? We dead?
No, listen to me. You was dead.
OK? But I brung ya back.
You ain't dyin' till I get my
money. You owe me $1,400.
Look here. Go check out that
haystack. That shit is moving.
What in the world?
[in Italian] Arturo!
Arturo, where are you?
Arturo!
Arturo.
[in Italian] Beautiful.
Where did you find it?
Watch me throw it.
[singing] # Little black face
# Beautiful Abyssinian
# Wait and hope,
The hour is already near
# When we will be
# Close to you
# And there to give you
a different law and a different King #
Arturo! Now, I am nine years old.
Move, sniper bait, go!
[boy speaking Italian] Okay,
maybe I'm eight. I'm really only eight.
[boy groaning]
Good God!
[in Italian] A Chocolate Giant.
- [grunting]
- [in Italian] Help me.
I'll give you a banana,
Chocolate Giant.
[both grunting]
Sorry, boy. I done gived it
every muscle I got.
[in Italian] Use your tail,
Chocolate Giant.
Jesus is waitin' on you, child.
This world ain't worth
a pinch of snuff nohow.
[in Italian] No, please don't leave.
Oh, my God, it hurts.
Come on. Come on.
[straining]
[straining, yelling]
[gasping]
Boy! Hey, boy! Hey!
Boy. You breathin'?
[in Italian] Giant,
you don't taste like chocolate.
[in German]
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
You can't kill me.
I'm invisible!
Come on, boy. Come on.
Let's go.
[artillery shrieking]
[Bishop] Train! Train!
[whispering] Oh, no.
Where's Train?
He ain't...
He ain't make it.
That nigger's dumber than a dime.
You sent him over the hill?
- I ain't tell him to risk his life.
- It's nobody's fault.
That boy was born over the hill.
[Bishop] Follow me.
- [man grunts]
- Special delivery for the Führer.
[in Italian] Holy Mother of God.
Train!
Train, you damn fool!
I thought you was dead!
[Hector] Told you
he was going over the hill.
[whispering] Oh, no.
The fuck is he...
We wait here till dark,
and then we cross back.
Good.
[speaks Spanish]
This shit is heavy as hell.
Bishop!
- Where you going?
- Y'all go on back across that river.
The only person with any luck
around here is him.
Plus, he owe me $1,400.
That's the kind of money
that can set me up
for the rest of my life.
Even if the rest of my life is today.
[grunts, in Spanish]
To hell with this.
I'm up shit's creek.
- Jesse Owens!
- [Train] Jack Johnson.
You go talk to your wife up there.
I never felt so lonesome
in my whole life, Bishop.
- I been dreaming a lot.
- Yeah.
Nigga, I ain't really interested in your
dreams. I want my motherfucking money.
I got something's
worth more than $1,400.
Better than black cat's bones.
Make you invisible.
Gives the strength of five people!
I think your cheese
done slid off your biscuit.
You never see me chalk the line
for no white kid like you done.
- You told me to!
- I didn't tell you to get us killed.
This uniform don't change nothing for
us. This is a white man's war, Train.
Negroes ain't got nothing to do with
this. This boy ain't got no life nohow.
Why he don't? Hmm?
A life of goodness is not what these
white folk has chosen for they children.
Look at me.
Good book says it, Proverbs 22:16.
"Raise up a child the way you want him
to go, and he will not depart from it."
Now, he's trained to hate.
Shit, his life ain't worth
a dollar of Chinese money.
Listen here, Bishop.
This boy ain't done nothing to you.
Mm-hm.
You didn't want him before, did you?
- Where you goin', Sam Train?
- Hey, Stamps, we movin' or not?
We hold here till night.
Me and Bishop'll take first watch.
Hector, you and Train take second.
Give the boy whatever first aid you got.
What'd you get us into now, Diesel?
It's always something with you,
big fella. Here, you gonna need these.
Come on, kid.
[speaks Italian] Eat.
Eat.
Come on.
He won't take the medicine.
Go on, give it here.
You want some chocolate, boy?
I wouldn't get attached.
He'll be dead in a week.
I ain't never been this close
to a white person before, Hec.
Never even touched one.
Not even a dead one.
If this one dies, I'll give you
a whistle as a consolation prize.
- You really think he'll die?
- Why worry about it?
We could all be dead
in an hour anyway.
Why you always kissing that thing, Hec?
- Reminds me who my father is.
- I don't need help remembering my pa.
His name's Chester.
Chester Train.
Let's give this kid some water.
[in Italian] Water.
Arturo?
Can I ask you something?
What you want, boy?
[in Italian] Can you tell me who I am?
Hector, you speak that Italian?
What's he saying?
He said, "Who am I?"
But who's he talking to?
Lord, I knew it!
I could see it in his face!
Look at him, Hec.
Shh! Quiet down.
Good God!
- He got the power!
- What power?
God knows it. In the olden days,
everything could speak.
- The trees, the birds.
- Shh!
If you could hear them things,
then that mean you had it.
This boy's standing
in the shadow of God, Hector.
Thank you, Jesus! Thank you for standing
on Your holy righteous word, Lord!
Hallelujah! Thank you, Jesus!
As you were.
- General Almond.
- Colonel.
I have a photo you should see, sir.
Forget that a minute. How bad
are the numbers from yesterday?
- Bad, sir.
- And Ike gets mad when he gives me
waiters and shoeshine boys
to fight the Krauts with.
Germans are dug in.
And that gun at La Spezia's killing us.
Fifteen thousand colored soldiers.
One in four is a casualty.
And all I'm hearing about
is one goddamned gun?
We have guns, too, here.
Look, see, colonel? I got one.
This colored division...
This is an experiment, Jack.
An experiment. These are the first lady
Eleanor Roosevelt's niggers. Not ours.
- Sir, I respectfully disagree.
- That's why they sent you here, Jack.
To lead me into the New World.
A gift from the Brits.
Taken at 11,000 feet. See?
That's a German buildup at
Lama Di Sotto. Two or three regiments.
- Surprise attack you worried about?
- I hope not.
I got corroboration from a partisan.
Anybody crush grapes
with feet can't be trusted.
Get some Krauts to confirm.
Already working on it, sir.
Captain Rudden!
- Good evening, general.
- Come.
Germans may be planning counter-
offensive down the Serchio Valley.
We need a POW to confirm.
You running patrols there?
George Company has a squad
sitting right in that area.
- How?
- They pushed across the Serchio
beyond Hill Maine at the weak point.
I heard them call for artillery.
Might've broken Jerry's hold
on the river. Captain Nokes didn't fire.
- Why not?
- He couldn't see 'em, sir.
Didn't believe they crossed,
they got hung up.
I had Fox Company positioned
down the river from George Company.
Got pretty hot over there.
Four of 'em right up a mountain.
Got weapons and a radio
if they're alive.
- Who are the four men?
- Shouldn't be hard to find out.
One of them's the biggest Negro
you've ever seen in your life.
Mmm.
Very well then. Dismissed.
[door shuts]
[speaking German]
My God, I've had it.
Come on, it's enough.
Yeah, let's go.
I need something to eat.
[speaking Italian]
The Germans are leaving!
[bell tolling]
[speaking German] Push it up
or I'll kill it right now.
I'm pushing as hard
as I can.
Pull, pull, pull.
My goodness I'm hungry.
Finally something to chew on,
rather than the slime they feed us.
[in Italian] Goodbye meat.
Now there'll be nothing left.
They won't get fat on it.
Let's hope they choke on it.
Shut up, the two of you!
Now, let's see if your husband
will come back from Russia.
Mary, Joseph, Jesus,
tell us if we'll see him
or never see him again.
Is he still alive?
My eyes aren't
what they used to be.
- [rattling table]
- Come on!
So, so, so?
We can't even joke? Come on.
That thing is just a stupid kid's game.
You're the usual scoundrel!
Just because he carries
the Fascist Party card,
he thinks he can do what he wants.
Oh yes?
Then who was it who took butter
from the Germans the other day?
The Pope?
Maybe, because it wasn't us.
And the light?
How did your electricity come back on?
Papa.
Come with me.
How did the light come back on?
The truth will never
come out of his mouth.
You would think that
after all these years,
you would treat your friends better.
What is wrong with you, Papa?
Would you tell me?
It's Natalina.
What did she do?
She put the evil eye on me, that Witch.
You still going on about the same story?
The Germans stole your rabbits, not her.
There's strange things going on.
My electricity returned...
from God knows where
after two and a half years.
I was going to ask you about that.
Now I'm lit up like a carnival...
for every bandit and German to see.
It's Natalina's fault. She wants to see
me dead and buried behind the Church.
What are you talking about?
She prays for you every day.
Know what I say?
You go back in there
and apologize to your friends.
Tell everyone that
Mussolini disgusts you,
and that you are not a Fascist anymore.
Il Duce made us a world power again.
His only mistake was to get in bed
with that imbecile Hitler.
Papa, II Duce betrayed Italy.
And now you'll see
how this is going to end.
You are still so young, my child.
You don't know the ways of the world.
But you will learn.
And from whom?
From a Fascist like you?
You're just like your mother.
And she used to tell you
that Blackshirts
are only good for hiding dirt.
Okay, let's go.
[knocking on door]
Germans!!!
It's your house.
Holy Mother of God.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
Hector, ask who's in charge.
Tell them we're Americans.
[in Italian] Americans?
[in English] Me, too. Half.
[in Italian] Half.
[in English] Me sister Ida, half.
[in Italian] We called her little Ida,
because she was the baby.
Put us together,
we make one American.
[in Italian] Okay, wait. Wait.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
Thank you.
Who's in charge here?
Anybody here speak English?
[in Italian]
Where are the Germans?
Everywhere. Boom, boom.
My name is Renata.
- Where'd you learn English?
- I was nanny for a British family.
And a jolly good tuck-in-the-bed
tinkerer you must be.
- You can nanny me. Want a Camel?
- Cool it, Bishop.
I'm Staff Sergeant Aubrey Stamps.
We got a boy that needs help.
[in Italian]
A boy? He has a boy.
Oh, my God.
Is he alive? Put him here.
Slow. Slowly.
Where did you find him?
[Hector] On the Mountain.
Do you know him?
[Natalina]
No, I don't know him.
But he can stay here
until he gets better.
Tell them we're taking the boy
to a hospital. They can come.
They need to evacuate.
We'll escort them down the mountain.
[in Italian] We're going to a hospital.
You can come with us.
The hospital around the corner?
The Germans are everywhere.
Torrite, Rontano, Mezzana.
All the way to Barga
and down to the Serchio.
I don't know how you
got past Vergemoli.
The only way to Pietrasanta...
where the Americans might be...
is over that way,
over the Mountain of the Sleeping Man.
Says we're surrounded.
Doesn't know how we got
past German lines,
but the only way we might find
some Americans is up there.
- The Mountain of the Sleeping Man.
- Sleeping Man?
- [in Italian] What is that?
- It's a legend.
A shepherd fell in love with a girl
who would not love him back.
So he lays across the Mountain...
to protect her from the wind and rain.
He still lies there today,
to protect us all.
Legend has it that
one day he will awaken.
A legend about a shepherd
that fell in love...
Whatever she's saying,
we gotta rest until sunup.
- OK.
- Stay here? No, no.
Stay here. Si, si.
If they sing to the Krauts,
we will pull a trigger on this
and tell the hammer to hurry. Won't be
nothing but powder and steel here.
We are not Germans.
We are Italians.
- Full blood.
- And what are we? Half blood?
[in Italian]
We should take him...
and put him to bed.
The boy stays here. He's sick.
Heil Hitler!
[in German]
Catching up on your reading?
Yes, Colonel, I'm informing myself
about the enemy.
The Partisans often take their names
from banned poetry and literature.
This helps us identify them.
Who is the poet?
Giovanni Pascoli.
Do you think it's appropriate
to waste your time reading poetry?
In the past nine months we've seen
a sharp rise in Partisan activity.
What are you planning to do about it?
Colonel, we are down
to shovels and mule shit.
My men are exhausted.
We need ammo and food.
Food? You want food?
You can suck icicles
in Russia...
like you did before your so-called
neck wound brought you back here.
You think you're the first
to command hungry troops?
I mean no disrespect, Colonel.
Good. Listen closely.
I have come too far to repeat myself.
First, there is a peasant, a terrorist.
Named The Great Butterfly.
He's causing many problems.
He's hiding in these mountains.
Find him.
When he is found,
issue Directive Bandenbefehl...
to him and his criminal friends.
Bandenbefehl?
Is there an echo out here?
General Kesselring's standing
field order for the Italian Republic.
At a commander's sole discretion,
for every one German soldier killed,
we execute ten Italian civilians.
You should have been capable to execute
that order at least once in nine months.
Colonel, with all due respect,
if I execute this order...
my men would kill innocent civilians.
It would be a violation
of the Geneva Convention.
Partisans are not civilians;
they are terrorists.
They are not protected
under the Geneva Convention.
Bandenbefehl!
Bandenbefehl.
Secondly, the surprise
counterattack is still planned.
I will tighten supply lines
with food and ammunition.
And three:
A delicate intelligence matter
of the utmost priority.
We are missing a Corporal...
from the 35th Regiment,
2nd Battalion, 5th Company.
Name: Hans Brandt,
gone AWOL three weeks ago.
[Eichholz] We have some every day.
What's so special about him?
You and I are not here...
to question the Führer's orders.
You are to send out a search party.
Find him.
Don't let him escape.
And when you have him...
get word to me immediately.
Let's go!
[in Italian] If I am no longer
that lamp...
which flickers in front
of a sweet Maria.
[in German] What does that mean?
God help this poor bastard Brandt.
Whatever he's done,
it's no worse than what anyone else
has done in this war.
Mount a search party.
We have to find him first,
hold him and give him a few days...
before Pflueger pulls out
his teeth, one by one.
Yes.
I'll be relieved when this war is over.
I want to return to my family.
[in Italian]
I've watched you grow up.
But you haven't become much.
And he can't do much.
- You're laughing at me?
- Of course.
Where did you get that?
So many things you want to know.
Here. Take it and eat.
Give me some, too.
Are you afraid you're
not going to get any?
Here. Grow.
Give me a chestnut, too.
My goodness, you stink like a sheep.
Hey, leave me alone.
Aren't you the dandy?
Ah, he's offended.
What the fuck are you doing, Peppi?
You have to be on the lookout.
If I had been a German,
you would all be dead... 1, 2, 3.
I almost choked.
You wait here.
My friend.
The Americans are getting closer.
We have to warn them about
the Germans' counterattack.
They know it already, for sure.
You? How are you?
Me? I'm okay.
You?
I always have Marco's
face in front of my eyes.
Don't worry about that.
My brother is dead.
Nobody cares about him any more.
I care.
In your opinion...
when we will be in front of God,
if we ever get there,
is he going to ask us
for our political card?
Is he going to say,
"Marco, no... Ludovico, no.
You're not allowed in
because you're Fascists."
What's the difference between
us and them in the eyes of God?
You're asking yourself
too many questions.
If you think too much,
it will drive you crazy.
And then who will kill the Germans?
Hey.
Anyway, what's done is done.
George Company to 370,
George Company to 3-7, over.
George Company to 370, over.
[in Italian] Someone tell that
big beast to get out of my room.
Shh! The Boy has a fever.
He needs to eat and get some rest.
Try thinking of others
every once in awhile.
Arturo.
The Chocolate Giant's Castle...
if you could only see it.
It's enormous.
No, even bigger.
Of course I saw it.
It's all made of chocolate.
You break a piece off,
and it grows back.
Yes, I did save a piece for you.
Good heavens.
Something's not right.
Someone put the evil eye on him.
Bewitched or not, he's got to go.
- To where?
- With the Americans.
I think he brings good luck.
The Boy stays.
This is my house.
I have a house too.
Natalina.
What do you think?
I say this Boy is talking to the Devil.
We need a Priest here.
He doesn't need a Priest.
He needs a Doctor.
A Priest can take
the Devil out of him.
Train, get up. We gotta book.
[Train] Excuse me.
Hey, boy. Hey.
Time for you
to take your medicine again.
Here it comes. Ready?
[humming]
There. Thank you.
Get you some of that soup, boy.
Mmm.
- Yes.
- He would not eat before.
Here you go, boy.
It's all over your shirt.
- Come on, boy. Let's go.
- [in Italian] My Chocolate Giant.
- OK, sarge. We ready.
- Oh, hold on, hold on, hold on.
We? Boy, where the hell "we" goin'?
You wasn't chiseling him,
we wouldn't be here.
- You think Nokes is lookin' for us?
- What?
Hector been tryin' to fix that radio
since we got here.
- Shh!
- What?
Arrive- damn-derci.
Hector. We gotta bail. Ask the old man
if he'll show us another way outta here.
- Maybe we can reach the 366.
- We can't get five feet outta here
without being flavor of the week
for the Guten Tags.
These people survived for years
without mortars. Stay with the paisans.
You wanna stay here and play house,
go ahead, but I'm bookin'.
Ask the old man if he'll show us
another way outta these mountains.
Tell him we'll pay him. We got plenty of
that funny money they use around here.
[speaks Italian]
Can you show us a safe path?
There is no safe way.
Germans. Boom! Boom!