[Chorus]
#Sea wife #
[Man Singing]
#I'll find you #
#And birds will sing again #
# Till I do #
# There'll be no spring again #
#I miss you like the flowers #
# Would miss the morning dew #
# The seconds seem like hours #
# When they're not
shared with you #
#I'll find you
You haunt my heart and mind #
#In each breeze
I seem to hear you sigh #
# You tell me to forget you #
# You wouldn't if you knew #
#I'll find no peace of mind #
# Till I find you ##
[Man]
Attention, please. Calling all passengers.
Passengers wishing
to send radio messages...
may now do so at
the radio office on "B" Deck.
The ship will berth at Dover
in 30 minutes. Thank you.
I, uh, want to put an advertisement
in the newspapers.
Would that be possible by radio?
- You mean send a radio telegram
to the newspapers, sir?
- Yes.
- Well, I don't see why not, if it's urgent.
- Very urgent.
It's been urgent for many years.
If you'd care to give me
the name of the paper and the message.
Right.
To all the big national papers.
Here's the message.
Please insert following advertisement
in personal column earliest.
Stop.
Uh, message begins,
"To Sea Wife.
Home at last.
Please get in touch."
- And the signature is Biscuit.
- Biscuit?
B-l-S-C-U-l-T.
[Man]
Paper.! Paper.!
[Phone Ringing]
- That'll be 27 shillings, madam.
- Twenty-seven shillings?
That's very expensive, isn't it?
- Costs a shilling a word, madam.
- How many words are there?
- Twenty-seven.
- I see. That'll be 27 shillings then.
- That's right.
- Never mind. As long as I can find my Topsy.
Thank you.
I want to put this advertisement
in the personal column.
- Sea- Sea-
- Wife. Sea Wife.
"Sea Wife,
have returned with fatted calf...
and the cherry trees are in bloom."
- Biscuit?
- Biscuit.
- Afternoon, Henry.
- Afternoon, sir.
- Whiskey, please.
- Certainly.
- Put some soda in it, would you?
- Yes.
Very quiet this afternoon.
Always is
on Tuesday, sir.
Thank you.
- Hello, Teddy. Still looking for the winner?
- That's right, old boy.
As a matter of fact,
I've got a red-hot tip for the big race.
Well, you might share it.
Well, as a matter of fact, I'm not
quite sure which horse it is, old boy.
That's not much of a tip.
Well, it's all this stuff that's been appearing
in the papers in the last fortnight.
This Sea Wife and Biscuit business.
Have you seen it?
Yes. What's that got to do
with the big race?
Well, obviously a tip, isn't it?
I mean, bound to be!
- Well, I suppose it might be.
- What do you mean it might be?
- What else could it be?
- I know this will come as
a great shock to you, Teddy...
but there are other things
in life than horse-racing.
No, no. Now, listen.
Here are the lists of runners.
There's nothing about sea,
unless you count Permanent Wave.
And there's nothing about wife,
unless you count Little Pest.
Absolutely nothing about Biscuit.
Well, it may be something
subtler than that.
Yeah.
Yes. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
- Of course! Crusted Port.
- Crusted Port?
Yeah. Don't you see? Port.
Sailors have sea wives
in every port.
Crusted. Biscuit.
[Sighs] Well, it's certainly very ingenious,
Teddy, but do you think-
100-to-1!
Let me get that telephone!
[Laughs]
- The other half, sir?
- Oh, no, thank you.
- I'll go to my room.
- Very good, sir.
[Knocking]
Come in.
Good morning, sir.
This has just been delivered for you.
- Thank you.
- The chauffeur is waiting for a reply.
- I'll be down in a minute.
- Very good, sir.
Mr. Cannon
to see you.
- Bulldog.
- Hello there.
Will you forgive me for not getting up?
My leg's playing me up.
Of course.
I'm sorry you're not well.
Oh, I'm well enough,
everything considered.
Sit down.
Thank you.
- You just got back?
- Yes.
Been a long time.
I was in hospital
a long time.
[Sighs] After that, I got mixed up
in the war again and went to Burma.
Yes, yes, yes.
That isn't important.
This business.
These advertisements of yours-Absurd.
There can be no question
of publication.
After all, Biscuit,
we're gentlemen.
I'm going to find
Sea Wife.
Biscuit...
let me give you
a word of advice, my boy.
Forget the whole thing.
After all,
it's over and done with.
Isn't it?
Forget it while you can.
Otherwise, there'll come a time
when you can't forget it.
Every night,
sometimes during the day...
but certainly at night...
you'll have it with you,
bobbing there in the sea...
its filthy, evil hand coming over
the side of your bed...
and screaming at you!
- Relax.
- [Grunts]
[Shouting]
As senior man, I was responsible, wasn't I?
Yes. Yes, of course.
What was all the muttering
and conferring about?
A girl, a Negro
and a knife...
on that crazy raft.
What else could I do?
Let him come.
I'm not afraid ofhim.
Did my duty.
Do the same again. Do the same again.
[Bomb Whistles, Explodes]
[Bombs Continue]
- [Whistle Blows]
- [Man On P.A.] Get on board quick as you can.
[Chattering]
Identification, sir?
Thank you.
[Bells Ringing]
I'll see to it, sir.
Straight ahead, sir.
You chaps are up forward.
Oh, sorry.
Hey, steady on,
old man!
There you are, sir.
I always feel
there's a type of person...
who'll arrive at the gates of hell
with somebody carrying his luggage.
Yes, and pushing people
out of the way to get there.
- In a great hurry to get home, isn't he?
- We all are.
I'm sorry, madam.
All cabins have been acquired.
- But if you take this slip to
the forward saloon on "C" Deck-
- You must have something!
Yes, madam. A thousand passengers,
and five cabins to contain them.
- So if you'll take this slip-
- Uh, pardon me.
With a slip, you obtain floor space
in forward saloon on "C" Deck.
- Thank you.
- That's it, madam. Two deck's descent.
Purser, is there a stewardess aboard?
Sorry, we have
no stewardess, madam.
- But if you take this slip to, um, "B" Deck.
- Thank you.
Now, about my cabin.
- All cabin accommodation
has been acquired, sir.
- Yes, never mind about that.
- We are a party of five ladies,
and we have only two bunks.
- Will you excuse me?
All cabins have been taken, sir.
- It'll mean somebody moving out.
- Up to you.
The only individuals in cabins are old,
or with children, or with sickness.
Oh, that's not my business.
Very well, sir.
If you
will come with me.
[Chattering]
Do you wish me to
tell them to move out, sir?
[Bomb Whistles, Explodes]
[Coughing]
[Speaking Japanese]
##[Humming]
## [Humming Continues]
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
- [Ship Horn Blows]
- Mama!
[Crying]
- Torpedo hit amidships. Stop the engines.
- Coming full stop, sir.
Hello, Engine Room. Captain
to Engine Room. Hello, Engine Room.
[Child Crying]
Off you go. This way.
There, now. This way. Come along.
[Child Sobs]
Where's your life belt?
Oh, you'll have to
have mine. Here.
[On P.A.]
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the captain.
- There is no reason for panic.
- [Screaming in Distance]
Please proceed to the boat deck,
where you will be allocated to your lifeboat.
The officers and crew
will be there to assist you.
Will you please walk?
And do not panic.
[Repeats In German]
Lower away!
Steady! Steady!
Sister Therese! Sister Therese!
Don't leave us! Don't leave us!
Sister Therese, don't leave us!
[Sobbing]
[Man]
Any more women and children?
It's the last boat.
Women and children only.
Come on, you ladies.
Any more women and children?
It's the last boat.!
[Shouting In Foreign Language]
Keep back, I say!
Women and children only!
Come on, you ladies.
Get back! Don't your kind
ever know their place?
- I have as much right here as anyone.
- Right? What right have you got?
You should stay in the jungle
where you belong.
Please, please.
Let's have a little Christian charity.
- We need it at a time like this.
- You keep out of this, Padre.
It's preachers like you who put the wrong
ideas into the heads of these savages.
If you really believe
all that religious tosh...
why didn't you stay in Singapore
and convert theJapanese?
Lower away.
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Screams]
[Man]
Stand by to abandon ship.!
[Man #2]
[Screaming Continues
In Distance]
[Man] Sail, water, biscuits.
Right. Over she goes.
Next one!
[Man]
Sail, water, biscuits.
[Exhales]
[Biscuit]
You all right?
- You English?
- Yes.
Good.
- Ah, we're in luck.
- [Bulldog] Help.!
Help.!
Help!
[Gasping]
Oh. Well done, old man.
You hung on like a bulldog.
Very much obliged.
Thanks.
Pleasure. Welcome aboard, Mr. -
Mr. Bulldog.
[Explosion]
Shark!
[Screaming]
Shark! Shark!
Ladies and gentlemen,
is there room for one more?
Course there's room for a fourth.
Come on in.
No more after this.
[Explosion]
Here you are, Number Four.
One mouthful.
Bulldog.
- [Groans]
- Is that arm bad?
Only for the moment.
There you are.
Now, do we paddle all night
or do we lay up?
Oh, lay up. Let's get some sleep
while it's reasonably cool.
But better leave someone on watch.
Fair enough. We'll split it.
- Now, say nine hours between three of us-
- Between four of us.
It will be better if you sleep.
Tomorrow will be very hot.
I think it'll be better if you rested.
Then, in that case,
I can't have the water or the biscuits.
People share or do not share.
Did you never hear of
the equality of women?
Thank you, Mr. Biscuit.
It's all right. Just your turn
to keep watch. That's all.
- What time do I call Number Four?
- 2:15.
What? Are you saying your prayers?
- Yes.
- Very touching, my dear.
But you'll learn that in this life,
it's every man for himself.
When I'm in trouble,
I call on God to help me.
Don't you?
Just straightforwardly asking someone
up there to send a ship along, huh?
- Why not?
- But you can't believe because
of that, one will come?
I believe that we are all
in the hands of God.
And if it is his will,
we shall be rescued.
Hmm. And if it isn't?
We're still
in the hands of God.
[Groans]
These are the hands that I believe in.
I'm the captain of my ship.
I'm the master of my soul.
Oh, you keep your faith,
my dear.
I think I also have hope...
and trust...
and that's what we need
more than anything just now.
Trust in each other.
You, Biscuit and Number Four.
There are some sorts of people in whom
lfind it very difficult to place trust.
- I've seen too much of'em.
- Oh, no.
It isn't that you've seen too much.
You've seen too little.
That makes about as much sense
as your ship from heaven. [Scoffs]
Ahh. Well, how is it?
- Not too good.
- Pity you can't come in. It does make a difference.
Yes.
Not too far!
There are sharks about,
you know.
That's funny.
I never noticed her on the ship.
- Nor I.
- You would not have recognized her then.
Now she looks like a sea wife.
- Huh?
- A sea wife.
- What's that?
- When one refers to a sea wife,
one implies a mermaiden.
Sea wife. I like that.
- Sea Wife!
- What did you say?
Come on in.
Breakfast.
[Sighs]
Thank you.
- What was that you called me?
- We christened you Sea Wife.
According to our sea-going professor here,
it's a kind of mermaiden.
Sea Wife.
Thank you, Number Four.
It's a lovely name.
Is there any reason to suppose that
we are going in the right direction?
How much water is there?
Enough for two more days.
Two days? Ha!
What a pity it isn't gin.
It would have made dying
more amusing.
Now, let's see.
When the water's gone...
we kill someone
and drink their blood, don't we?
Put a sock in it, will you?
But we must remember to drink it
while the patient's still alive...
otherwise it won't flow.
Shut up.
No doubt this sounds very revolting
to you now, but we'll see.
When the food and the water's gone-
When your throats are
really parched and burning-
When your tongue's swollen to the point
of struggling for breath and your bellies-
Shut up!
I said shut up, didn't I?
[Scoffs]
You don't like facing facts.
Well, I do like facing facts.
Facts, facts.
Lovely things.
Shh! Please.
I think I hear something.
You hear something?
Yes. Listen.
Put your ear
to the float.
- Sounds like heavy breathing.
- A sea monster.
[Groans]
Superstitious nonsense!
Natural sounds
have natural causes.
[Splashing]
It's over there.
There!
Put that light out!
You're blinding us!
[Speaking Japanese]
[Bulldog]
We don't understand you. We're English!
- Put that blasted light out!
- [Japanese]
[Japanese]
[Man]
Who are you? English? American?
- English!
- What are you doing?
- We're on a pleasure cruise.
- What did you say?
Ship. Sunk.
Night before last.
- [Japanese]
- What did you say about pleasure?
My friend is ill.
We are short of food and water.
- May we come onboard?
- Wait.
[Speaking Japanese]
- What was your ship?
- The San Felix.
- [Japanese]
- From what port?
- Speak up, please.
- Singapore!
What other ships
left Singapore?
I've no idea.
What British and American warships
are in the Indian Ocean?
- You refuse to tell?
- I don't know!
[Leader Speaking Japanese]
If you do not give information,
you are useless.
My honorable commander
say good-bye.
But we need
food and water!
We have nothing to spare.
Well, if you will not supply us, we will be
compelled to give ourselves up as your prisoners.
[Speaking Japanese]
My commander regrets that
he has no space for prisoners.
If you are not prepared to
die honorably by your own hand...
he is prepared, as a humane man,
to slit your boat with his sword.
- That's murder!
- It's against every code of any civilized nation.
On the contrary, my commander is behaving
strictly according to international law.
He will leave you unmolested.
You say your commander
is a humane man...
and I'm sure he is...
but he cannot turn away from us
and leave us... to die.
That would be a stain
he must not place upon his conscience.
[Speaking Japanese]
[Number Four
Speaking Japanese]
[Number Four Continues
No! No!
[Speaking Japanese]
What's going on?
What the devil are you up to?
- The commander will give me food and water.
- Why? What did you say to him?
- I told him that-
- I know what he said.
It was something rather personal
and nothing to do with anyone else.
For you. Wear it.
[Speaking Japanese]
Hey, wait a minute! What's our position?
Where's the nearest land?
There is land all around.
How long to reach it?
Empty your minds.
You must learn to eat time.
You must learn
to eat time.
Number Four,
I'm very grateful to you...
for not having told the others
what you told theJapanese.
That you are a nun?
That beggar's up to something.
Better watch him.
Bulldog is a man
of very deep prejudices.
I don't want to make it
more difficult for him.
I wish she wouldn't
encourage him.
It's asking for trouble.
I tried to warn her the other night, but-
Oh, I don't think there's anything
to worry about. He's all right.
You chaps who served overseas
are all the same.
You get stationed out here for a while-
Oh, you know all about the East.
I tell you, you don't
understand these beggars. I do.
He got us the food, didn't he?
That's better than you or I could do.
[Biscuit]
Now more than ever seems it rich to die.
To cease upon the midnight
with no pain.
See that star up there?
The light from that star has taken
billions of years to get to us.
If I wasn't so tired,
I'd tell you how many billions of years.
Very comforting, isn't it?
That we are small compared with it?
So small that we don't matter.
Oh, no.
The comfort is that,
though we are small...
there is someone
who thinks that we do matter.
- You're better, aren't you?
- Mmm. Miles better.
You know, Sea Wife,
I met an old man on the ship.
He had white hair.
He was going home to England,
first time for 30 years.
He wanted to see
the cherry orchards in bloom.
Sea Wife, the old man will never see
the cherry orchard in bloom now, will he?
Do you think we will?
Oh, yes.
Sea Wife,
promise me one thing.
Lf, by some miracle,
we ever get out of this alive...
you'll come with me
to see the cherry in bloom.
- I can't promise you that.
- No?
I would've thought that's a nice,
simple thing to ask a girl.
No, I can't come with you
to see the cherry trees...
but I shall remember
that you asked me.
You're a rum girl.
Madam, have I a rival?
- Yes, sir, you have.
- Oh.
Is he handsome?
You're certainly better. Men always
talk that way when they're better.
[Grunts]
You blasted idiot! You were lookout!
Why'd you let her go?
- They nearly ran us down!
You could have signaled them!
- I didn't see them.
There wasn't time!
It was on top of us before I saw it.
Why didn't you call us?
You let her go.
You wanted to kill us.
That's why you let her go!
I tell you.
I didn't see it!
The ship has gone.
Let us accept that.
- Quarreling won't help us.
- [Number Four] There's a paddle missing.
And the food and water
were swept overboard!
To your right, you fool!
To your right!
A bit further!
A bit further.!
To your right.
Shadows.
Only shadows.
It's too dark.
The current's too strong to find the rest.
No food, no water.
No doubt... that was your ship
from heaven, madam.
[Scoffs]
[Bulldog Mumbling]
Yes. Yes.
Sails. Sails.
[Bird Squawking]
Aah.! Got it.! Got it.!
Release the sails.! Paddle.! Paddle.!
[Bird Squawking]
[Quietly]
Stop it. Stop it.
You're behaving like savages.
[Whispering]
You're all insane.
- Stop. Listen to me.
- [Bird Squawks]
Don't you see?
That bird means land.
- Only a little longer.
- Not right to have done that, not to a sea bird.
Bad luck to kill a sea bird.
[Tapping]
[Wind Howling]
[Thunderclap]
I see trees.
Get in the current.
Back paddle.
What day do you make it,
according to your reckoning?
I'm not sure.
Maybe Monday, maybe Tuesday.
I don't know.
Why? Does it make any difference?
Well, I got a funny feeling...
when we were out there
on the raft...
somehow I... lost a day.
Tell me. Was I delirious?
A bit.
- How long?
- About a day.
We were all a bit shaky.
So, I did lose a day.
What happened on that day?
- Oh, nothing much.
- No.
No, I want to know.
All right.
- You remember the seabird?
- Seabird? No.
I remember the storm,
or bits of it.
I'm wondering
why I wasn't washed overboard.
The answer to that is that, uh...
Number Four hung on to you
for several hours.
- Oh?
- If it were not for him,
you would have been a goner.
Just lay across you
and hang on, that's all.
I see.
Well, I'm very much obliged
to you, Purser.
You are very welcome. I'm sure you
would have done the same thing for me.
But I'm afraid
I'm not a purser any longer.
You see, I've lost my situation.
You know, even I am able
to grasp that fact.
And what do you suppose
you are now?
Just one of the party.
Well, Bulldog, I feel fit enough now
for a very short...
very gentle exploratory potter.
- What about you?
- I'm game.
- Where's Sea Wife?
- Collecting shellfish.
- Number Four, if you'll get some coconuts-
- Yes, I'll do that.
Okay. We won't be long.
- [Groans]
- I'm very disappointed in this place.
In every respectable desert island
that I've read about...
they have everything
except electricity and main drainage.
Here, we have
coconuts and water, period.
With all that bamboo around...
we could make a raft.
If only we had something
to cut it with.
Well, it's no use
worrying about that.
Better get on with this hut for Sea Wife.
Pity she didn't see it before it collapsed.
Sea Wife...
what's your name?
My name is Sea Wife.
I mean your real name.
I'm not a real person here.
None of us are.
I think it's better
if we keep the names we have.
I don't agree.
My name is Michael Cannon.
You'll find me any time propping up the bar
at the St. George's Club, London.
I'll remember that, Biscuit.
- Michael.
- Biscuit.
Sea Wife,
what's your Christian name?
Why?
So that I have something to call you by
that- that others haven't.
I don't understand you.
So calm, so removed.
Don't you have any feelings,
any emotions?
Of course I do.
But don't ask me to explain...
because I can't.
All right. I won't ask you.
But I promise you one thing-
If ever we get out of this place,
I will ask you.
And if necessary,
I'll wait till doomsday for an answer.
Never mind about
what will happen after.
The main thing is to get out.
- I suppose we could hang on
here for a while longer-
- No, not for much longer.
Why not?
We've got coconuts, water, fish.
Yes, but there's no faith anymore...
and we can't live without that.
It's as though the springs
have dried up.
You mean Bulldog and Number Four?
- It's not only them.
- You mean us, Sea Wife?
I mean-
We must go
before it's too late.
You can't escape me, you know.
There's no way off this island.
A way will come.
[Snoring]
[Snoring Continues]
- Hello.
Sea Wife thinks we ought to be
leaving pretty soon.
What time's the next train?
Where does it go to anyway?
You know,
if this is one of the Nicobars...
there ought to be land
pretty near through the north.
As a matter of fact, I thought I saw some
the other day when the haze lifted.
How far?
About 1 0 or 15 miles,
if it was land.
The currents are all dead north
and pretty strong.
[Rustling]
Hey, what have you
got there?
A useful discovery, huh?
- What is it?
- A machete.
Where the devil did you get it?
Along the shore, buried in the sand.
Let's have a look at it.
I said,
let's have a look at it!
I should prefer
to clean, sharpen...
and entirely renovate it first,
Mr. Bulldog.
What price your raft now,
now that we have something to cut with?
Should be a piece of cake.
You don't really believe he's thinking of
using that for peaceful purposes, do you?
Are you happy with your knife?
- Yes, it's like silver.
- Let me look at it.
No.
Give me the knife, Number Four.
No, I'm sorry, Sea Wife.
I need it.
The knife belongs to all of us.
We all need it.
- What for?
- If we have the knife, then we can build a raft.
Then we can leave the island.
- Leave?
- There are some islands not far from here.
Please, give me the knife.
Pardon me. I cannot.
The knife is now sharp.
I wouldn't want anyone
to... cut themselves.
Then will you show me
how to make a fire?
- Will you?
- Certainly.
With steel it is easy.
But I keep the knife.
What's wrong, Number Four?
What's happened to you?
No, Sea Wife.
L- I don't know
what you mean.
Why don't you tell him
that you are a nun?
I've already told you
the reason.
Perhaps there is
another reason.
What other reason?
Biscuit.
No, no. That is all wrong!
Kindly leave it to me.
Shall I go and cut
some more bamboo?
No, thank you.
I will both cut and build.
Then perhaps when the raft is ready,
you'll select me captain.
Captain? Rapid promotion.
You think that's a good idea?
I think it's a very good idea.
After all, he's the only sailor
amongst us.
He's making the thing.
Of course
he should be captain.
- Thank you, Mr. Bulldog.
- You certainly earned it.
Uh, when do you think the raft
will be ready to leave the shipyard?
If we work very hard, I shall
have it ready by the next full moon.
You worked like a demon
this morning, Number Four.
How much longer
before the raft's ready?
Only two more days.
It must be ready by full moon.
The tide is best then.
I think the weather's going to play.
The main thing is to catch
that big northward current.
I reckon it runs at five or six knots.
Are you ready? One, two, three!
Heave.! And again.
Heave.!
Once more.! Heave.!
- Well done, Captain.
- [Number Four] Do you like it?
Well done.
May God bless this raft
and all who sail on her.
Father, Son, the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
[Biscuit]
Hello.
Would you like to hear
another lecture on the nebulas?
I'm afraid the last one
was a little disjointed.
No, I don't want to
hear about them.
I just want to
look at them.
Sea Wife...
listen to me.
I know I promised
I wouldn't ask you this again...
but why are you running
away from things?
- Tell me that.
- I'm not running away.
Yes, you are. You're running away
from life, from yourself.
There are voices talking to you,
aren't there, Sea Wife?
- You can hear them, can't you?
- No.
Listen to them, Sea Wife.
Listen to them.
Oh, don't touch me.
Please, don't touch me.
Sea Wife.
[Sighs]
Oh, don't.
Listen to those voices,
Sea Wife.
They're the only real voices-
the voices of life.
I love you, Sea Wife.
Oh, no, don't.
You mustn't say that.
Why not? It's true.
And why shouldn't I love you?
You're young and brave
and beautiful and good.
When I was sick, you nursed me.
If ever we get out of this island alive,
it's because you've held us together.
All this time,
I've been so near you.
All this time...
so near you.
Why shouldn't I love you?
Because-
Because l-
I've given my word...
to someone else.
But when you gave your word, you weren't
to know that this would happen.
Neither was he.
No.
Not this case.
You see, I didn't make
any conditions...
when I promised.
I can't start
making them now.
What time is it?
8:00. High tide in two hours.
Half an hour after that,
we'll be all aboard.
Are you sorry to be leaving,
Sea Wife?
Oh, I don't know.
Why? Are you?
If Bulldog and Number Four sailed away
and left us here together, would you be sorry?
I begged you last night
not to ask questions like that.
If you think I'm sorry about last night,
you're mistaken.
When we get back-
if we get back-
I shall ask you again.
And I shall keep on asking
until I get an answer...
and a truthful one.
- Have you looked on the raft?
- No, it's not on the raft.
- I have looked.
- I thought I saw you drop it.
- Over!
- What's the trouble?
His knife- He's lost it.
Do you need it so badly?
It's served its purpose now.
I need it more than ever.
I must have it.
It's not on the raft!
Look back there,
where you were cutting the bamboos.
No, I don't like
the look of this trim.
I think it's all right.
Yes, but how's it going to be
when we all come on board, huh?
Come on. Come on board.
Let's try it.
All right.
It'll be all right
with Number Four up front.
Yes, but what's going to happen
when the wind catches the sail?
- Steady on, old man.
- What?
Have us all in the current.
Be impossible to get back.
How far out do you reckon
we have to go...
before we catch
the current?
I don't know.
About 30 yards.
Right.
- [Grunts] Here we go.
- Steady, old man.
- Can't you see what he's doing?
He's leaving behind Number Four!
- Hey, Bulldog.
- Stop him!
- Oh, shut up!
Cut it out!
Are you crazy?
You've killed him.
Killed him?
I've saved his life and yours.
Number Four! Number Four!
Too late, Captain.
The boat's sailed.
But, Sea Wife,
I am one of the party!
Wait!
- Bulldog, please.
- I'm sorry, but somebody's got to be sane.
- Sane?
- Yes, sane.
And it's not sane to sail on a raft...
with you, a Negro and a knife.
Any two together,
but not all three.
If you don't turn back, I'll go-
We can't! We're in the current.
Sea Wife!
- Don't be so damned sentimental.
- Let go!
Sea Wife, I am one of the party.!
It is my raft!
Go back! We'll send you help!
Go back, you fool!
- Sea Wife, tell him to go back!
- Go back, Number Four!
- He'll be shark meat!
- Go back, Number Four! Sharks!
Go back!
Look out on the right, you fool!
Splash! Splash!
Watch out on the right!
Splash, you fool!
Splash.!
[Screams]
The fool.
It was his own fault.
It was his own fault, I tell you.
He was the best one of us all.
A knife, a Negro and a girl.
No, no, no.
Any two, but not all three.
No alternative.
Into thy hands, O Lord...
I commend my spirit.
Lord, grant us a quiet night...
and a peaceful end.
- My God, I love thee.
- Who-
Who are you talking to?
It's not the end.
I love thee.
Whom do you love?
- It's a quiet night.
- Face facts.
You know what he would
have done to you, my pretty?
Because I do. Oh, yes.
I know them.
Don't worry.
I'll look after you.
Now shut up, all of you,
while l-
while I think.
Now, if- if the current's moving...
southwest...
we must be-
[Murmurs]
L-
I'm sorry to be so indecisive...
but it's not easy- it's not easy-
[Quiet Praying]
Should have stayed on the island.
Stayed on the island...
with Sea Wife.
Biscuit?
Poor Bulldog.
He didn't understand.
Did he, Biscuit?
He didn't understand
about love.
All those questions.
I couldn't answer them.
I'm sorry, Biscuit.
I didn't want to deceive you...
but I didn't know
the answers myself.
There was a time...
I almost listened
to those voices.
It's over now...
so you'll never come
and look for me.
You'll never know.
God forgive us all.
God be merciful to me...
a sinner.
[Squawking Sound]
[Squawking]
Biscuit!
Biscuit.
[Seagull Squawking]
[Biscuit] It was several months before
I discovered that we'd been saved by a boat...
and I'd been taken ashore
at the nearest port.
I would like your assurance...
that you'll forget
the whole matter.
I'm afraid I can't promise you that.
Ah, that's the trouble
with you, Biscuit.
You're conceited.
You don't know what you're up against.
You think every woman
must be in love with you.
I love her.
Do you understand?
I love Sea Wife.
I must find her.
Please help me to find her.
She's alive, isn't she?
Tell me where she is.
Uh-Yes, we're all alive
in a way.
- She and I and the other-
- [Sighs]
And all dead.
For practical purposes, Biscuit,
you should consider yourself...
the only survivor.
What do you mean?
She's dead.
Sea Wife is dead.
She died on the ship.
Her last thoughts
were of you.
She said...
"Tell Biscuit that I loved him."
She said that you were always
to think of her...
as she was on the island.
What's wrong, Sister Therese?
Just someone I once knew.
He didn't seem to recognize you.
No one ever looks at the face of a nun.