(STONES SCRAPING)
(EXHALING)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(NEIGHING)
(GUN FIRING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(GRUNTING)
(BULLET RICOCHETING)
Well, we definitely got him.
It's a gut shot,
but we got him pretty good.
He didn't even take his rifle.
His horse run off, though.
Cleared up some.
We ought to get a move on.
Let him bleed.
If he keeps going down, he's going
to get some distance on us.
He ain't going nowhere.
We let him bleed.
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(GASPING)
(SPLUTTERING)
(YELLING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(MUTTERING EXCITEDLY)
Well, let's just get paid
up and be done with it.
He went in.
Yep.
There's no tracks
on the other side.
He done gone over them falls.
Ain't no body.
Well, he went in
that there water...
There ain't no body.
There ain't gonna be no body.
There's always a body.
You expect us just
to conjure him?
I expect you to find him.
That's what I'm paying you for.
(GASPING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(SHIVERING)
(GROANING)
Stay, stay.
Stay.
(EXCLAIMS)
(EXHALING)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
(WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(WHIMPERING)
Oh, God.
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Y'all smell that?
(GRUNTING)
Oh, fuck.
(PANTING)
Don't touch it.
He's doubled back
on his tracks.
Hayes, you and the kid
follow those two.
Pope, you take that one.
Mr. Parsons,
you wait here.
I'll take this one.
He's not far.
So watch yourselves.
I got his gun.
He ain't bleeding no more.
Yes, he is.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(WHISTLES)
Where's Pope?
The intervals are 10 feet.
Be ready. He's here.
Remember, if you kill this son of
a bitch, you will not be paid.
Extremities only.
(GUN COCKING)
God damn it.
Oh, hell.
Lord almighty.
What did he do to Pope?
Mister, who the hell
is this man?
Get the horses.
We have him now.
He must be part Indian or wolf.
Eat a man like that.
He didn't eat him. Go.
Hey!
(HORSE NICKERING)
Go.
(GUN COCKING)
CHARLOTTE: Just what in the
hell do you think you're doing?
I guess it makes sense.
Finished off by a young'un.
I ain't no young'un.
And I don't care to hear you
say another goddamn thing.
Now, come on out of there and put
your hands out in front of you.
Come on.
You been shot.
Trying to steal somebody
else's horse, I reckon.
I'd say you need a new
line of work, mister.
(GRUNTING)
Nathaniel!
Nathaniel! Come on.
Come on, now.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you.
Who is he?
Horse thief.
But he's hurt.
I'll pay for the horse.
You best rest yourself.
Pa'll be home after a while, and
he'll decide what to do with you.
No more tracks, Carver.
The trail's gone cold up there.
Your sister...
She don't take
kindly to thieving.
Hmm?
There's plenty of time for
that when you grow up.
See that.
Yeah, he's still bleeding.
There's something
else down here.
Take a look.
Yeah.
What'd you see?
Charlotte.
We caught him
trying to steal Red.
He's hurt. Shot.
Who are you, mister?
I do some trapping
a bit north of here.
Must be quite
Quite a bit.
I don't expect
you shot yourself.
No. No.
Somebody after your hides?
Hmm?
Fringing on your territory?
I couldn't say.
You come down out of that
pass without a horse?
Up here, a man without a horse
is generally a dead man.
That I can solve.
So I don't take kindly to a
man trying to steal mine.
Like I told your girl,
I'll pay for the horse.
It's only about six days'
walk from here to town,
as I recall.
I'll pay you twice
what you paid for her.
If you can pay,
why don't you just
walk yourself down there?
I'd rather not.
Nothing there.
Not a goddamn thing.
I'll go down there
and take a look.
No.
We're done here.
We'll follow the ridge.
That's 16 days.
Seventeen out Mount Olive,
at $1 a day.
You'll get your money
when we find him.
Not before.
What do you mean?
You saw.
That trail ends down
at the end of that ravine.
'Cause he never went
down the ravine.
We follow the ridge.
(MAKE SHOOTING NOISE)
Oh!
(MAKES SHOOTING NOISE) Oh!
Come here.
I'm Gideon.
You don't talk much,
do you, boy?
You know, it's not
considered polite
to shoot a man who's
sleeping in your house.
Well,
get on back to bed.
Where is he?
Who the hell...
I'm doing the asking here.
Coffee and biscuits, woman.
Now, lie to me
and I will fire this place
with you and yourn in it.
Now where is he?
Must have left at first light.
We done got here at
first light. Damn fool.
Were he able-bodied
when he come here?
No.
Did you give him
supplies or a rifle?
No.
He had a pistol.
Took that off of Pope
after he killed him.
You give him a horse?
No.
Ain't no horse for that one.
Mister, I don't know
where you come from,
but we helped a shot
mongrel of a man,
and he's gone away
in the night,
and that's all we know.
You lying son of a bitch.
(GRUNTS)
What did you sell him?
What did the devil
get for his money?
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
Hayes.
I ain't paying you
to play with womenfolk.
(GRUNTING)
Tell me about the man
who came here.
If I think you're lying,
I'll kill your brother and
hand you over to Mr. Hayes.
He was here,
and he left in the night.
Stole a mare, looks like.
What about that gold?
I don't know.
I took it.
He was sleeping.
I took it from his bag.
I only wanted a gun
to protect us.
Son, nobody can protect
nobody in this world.
The sooner you realize that,
the better.
Hey.
Pope's horse stays.
You son of a bitch.
No wonder you don't talk much.
Too busy thieving.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
How do you write "wife"?
Kid, that's W...
H-O-R-E.
Don't much matter
how you spell it,
a woman ain't gonna be yours unless
you're paying her for the night.
You pay her to be sweet
to you, kid, that's all.
Don't never mix up
money and love.
Toss the pistol.
(THUDDING)
What do you want?
I'd have thought
that it was obvious,
seeing as how I've
been shooting at you.
Keep them hands out.
Turn around.
Why are you doing this?
Seraphim Falls.
Colonel Carver.
Turn around.
I wanna see your face.
(WHISTLES)
What?
Double watches
the rest of the night.
You'll be on him before long.
He was here today.
Watch the sides.
Make sure he didn't
break off and cover.
(GRUNTING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(COUGHING)
Jesus Christ.
He's still breathing.
We got to get
this thing off him.
(GUN FIRES)
Parsons, see about that horse.
Well, now we got some
discussing to do.
Right here and now.
We ain't negotiating based on
tracking no killer like this.
You're being
well-paid.
We're 18 days on
a 30-day commission,
and two of us is already dead.
Can't say I'm surprised.
The man we're after preys
on the weak and unprepared.
I'd advise you to take
this as a warning.
Well, what if we just decided to
take that as our walking papers?
You are, of course,
free to do that, Mr. Hayes.
You will, however, do it
without the assistance
of my horse on which you sit.
Am I clear, gentlemen?
We'll keep on.
But we want to split the pay
that's due them, instead.
Done. Now we've got
distance to cover.
If our man makes it
to the low country,
we'll likely never
see him again.
Wouldn't catch me
complaining about that.
(CHATTERING)
(LAUGHING)
Morning, stranger.
I didn't figure any
transients this far up.
I'm just passing through,
is all.
You need some whiskey?
We got some whiskey.
Shut up, Horace.
No, I can't say as
I'm looking for whiskey,
but I sure could use some food.
Looks like you boys have got
other things on your mind.
Would have been helpful
if you hadn't seen those.
Well, if you ain't planning on
eating, I'll just be getting on.
I'm afraid I can't
let you do that.
You see, we is fugitives
from the law.
They catch us,
they're gonna string us up.
Horace, if you don't get quiet,
I'm gonna hang you myself.
It don't much matter to me.
I'm just looking
to be left alone.
Same as you.
So, I'll be on my way.
You look powerful familiar,
mister.
I know you?
I doubt it.
I'll be damned.
That's one of McClellan's
boys up at Antietam.
Ain't you gonna kill him, huh?
Waste of a bullet.
He's so banged up and hungry, he
won't make it to town anyway.
Lost both his sons
in one day at that
goddamn bridge.
I seen it myself.
Yeah?
But nothing touched him.
Not a scratch.
Not a splinter.
(LAUGHING)
They say he killed over
100 men that day alone.
Him? Nah.
Hey, you use some of that money
to get yourself
some spectacles.
(LAUGHS)
Still, Virgil, the way
you shot that teller,
I thought you'd be
itching to do it again.
I'm itching to get out
of here. Get going.
Goddamn right. Let's go.
Don't ever go chasing
after that man.
If you don't shoot him,
I swear to Christ I will.
We can't be letting
no stranger,
whoever the hell
you think he is,
just walk into town and tell
them authorities where we gone.
Let's go. Come on.
Take care of it myself.
Horace!
Horace, come on!
Afraid I'm gonna have to
ask you to stop walking.
Let me be, boy.
Best just go on
back up to your kin.
Mister, I never shot nobody
in the back before.
So it's best you
just turn around,
and you get what's
coming to you.
Boy,
now you put that
gun up and go on.
Turn around.
(CLICKS)
(HORSE NEIGHS)
You're a fool, boy.
I told you to let me pass on.
Hey!
There was three of 'em.
Two of 'em went on up,
one went down that way.
Look familiar, gentlemen?
Figure it's him that done it?
'Course it's him.
Who else would be
dropping folks
like owl pellets
out on these hills?
If he's got himself
another horse,
we won't catch him
before sundown.
I reckon we ought to
move down valley, then.
He won't be heading
toward Carson City.
Come on. Let's get
off these cursed hills.
You two can go on without me.
What?
Those boys have been
wanted for six months.
He's worth 250 in Carson.
That's a damned sight better
than what he's offering.
And this boy don't
require no chasing.
You can't just leave.
The hell I can't.
You would, too, if you knew
what was good for you.
The posse's take is all
yours when the ride's done.
No less than 120 and
you don't have to ride
with a stinking corpse,
neither.
All right.
You sure?
You go on and get yourself killed.
I'm done.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Okay.
(NEIGHING)
Let him earn that
250 the hard way.
He ain't never going to make
it to town without a horse.
I told you boys.
Them horses are mine.
We can water your mare.
She looks hard-ridden.
Mercy to the beast is blessed
in the eyes of the Lord.
He sees your sin.
(HORSE GALLOPING)
That's all you got.
I don't know you.
Well, well, well.
Looky here.
Boys,
we've caught ourselves a real,
live, notorious criminal.
$250 for that
horse-thieving varmint.
You ought to have known better
than to steal from the Bar H.
Old man McCleeny
don't take kindly
to losing horse
flesh like this.
Want another one?
Yeah, fuck you.
(ALL GRUNTING)
You the foreman?
Who's looking?
Might have been a man
rode through here.
Tall. Don't talk much.
Is that so?
I'd like to find him.
There's nothing for you here.
What do you want
with this fella?
I just want him.
Is the horse yours?
Ain't about horses.
'Cause there's been some horse
thieves around these parts.
A lot of men like to see
them caught, you know.
Well, they won't trouble us.
I reckon so.
I'd be obliged if we
could take water here,
and then we'll leave you
to your work.
Yeah.
Lewis here will show you where.
(HORSES APPROACHING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
Help yourself, Paddy boy.
Shut up.
Gotta piss.
I'll find you.
You gonna hold it for me?
Paddy boy.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
I said, shut your
goddamn mouth.
(GRUNTING)
(SCRAPING)
He's gone.
Gone? How in the hell...
All right, you two!
MAN: Yes, sir.
Down by the bridge.
Jesus, Mary, Joseph.
All right.
Down that way, idiots.
Open the gate.
Go check on them other two.
I want them out of here.
I thought you weren't
interested in horses, mister.
I'm not.
I think it's time you told me what
it is you are interested in here.
Nothing.
I like that.
Like I said, I'd be obliged for some
water, and we'll be on our way.
Suppose you just be
on your way then, huh?
(COUGHING)
Get up, you big baby.
Get your gun!
Fuck you.
Let's move.
Pilgrims, you arrived
just in time.
May we offer you
shelter and fellowship?
We can pay if you have
some food to spare.
The Lord is bountiful.
Our venison stew
is a week in the pot
and fire every day.
Come.
Reckon we ought to
camp somewheres else?
Afraid the word of God
will spoil your digestion?
I never was much for scripture.
Nothing to fear,
Mr. Hayes.
Them's just words.
Ain't no God out here.
(SNORTS)
Say, how'd you come by
that scar on your neck?
Indians? Them savages?
No, it was worse.
Mormons.
Praise be to God
and a good rifle,
he answered my prayers
and not his.
You ought to have a talk
with your God about that.
Figure he ought
to be more careful.
You being the
chosen folk and all.
Could be he was careful,
or I'd be dead.
So, you figure God
were on your side then?
He's always on the side
of the righteous, son.
If you don't mind,
I'll take his share.
It'll help me digest
that fine stew of yourn.
Play something for our guests,
children. No hymns.
(VIOLINS PLAYING)
You ready?
No damn hymns.
(MANDOLIN PLAYING)
(PEOPLE WHOOPING)
(NEIGHING)
(MUTTERING)
Goddamn preacher.
Did that to yourself.
Why don't you mind
how you talk to me?
It's just you and me
out here now.
You go for me,
you don't get paid.
Anyway, the noise would make that
head of yours split clean through.
Much obliged.
Don't you ever
threaten me again, boy.
Understand?
Check your weapon.
(CLICKING)
Oh, shit.
Goddamn missionaries.
Thieving bastards
emptied our guns.
I told you we ought to
camp someplace else.
As long as I've still
got the one for him,
I guess it don't much matter.
What the hell were
they doing out here?
Certain kind of decision.
Once a man makes it, he can't
end up nowhere but here.
(GROANING SOFTLY)
(MURMURING)
(GRUNTS)
You go.
You go, now.
Go now.
What the hell kind of
animal has done that?
Shit.
Hell, there ain't no animal...
(YELLING)
Get off the horse.
Easy now. Easy now.
Yeah.
Get off the horse.
Toss the gun over here.
Just do what he says, Carver.
You do it.
Easy.
(GRUNTS)
On your knees. Now.
Ain't you gonna ask me
to spare you, Captain?
Ain't that what cowards
are supposed to say?
Just as well.
'Cause I ain't planning on it.
Toss that knife over here.
I ain't gonna let you try
anything before I send you down.
Finish it then, huh?
Not so fast.
I've been hunting you for...
I don't know how long.
No sense in rushing it now.
The war is over, sir.
It has been three years.
Won't never be over.
It was war.
War.
War is men fighting,
you son of a bitch.
That weren't war what you did.
It was orders.
Orders you gave, Captain.
Yeah. There we go.
All right, Danny, your turn.
Hit it round the edges,
nice and hard.
Watch your fingers.
Get your balance.
Put that leg over.
Nice and hard now.
Now you're getting it.
Now you got it.
(CHOPPING)
It's not gonna bite you.
Danny, come here.
Get off this land.
Ma'am, we have it
on good information
that this is the home
of Colonel Morsman Carver.
He's my husband.
Is he here, ma'am?
No. He's not here.
Search the house, Lieutenant.
Yes, sir. House, march.
Show them the hard hand, boys.
Check upstairs.
The cellar's clear.
Where's the Colonel, ma'am?
(SPITS)
Mind yourself, Lieutenant.
Where is he, ma'am?
Fire the barns.
Leave the house.
No! Stop!
Rose!
No.
ROSE: No!
Colonel!
Where are your men, Colonel?
The war is over.
You know the war is over.
(EXCLAIMING)
Where are your men?
I released them.
Months ago, I released them.
And the cannon?
Shattered all to hell.
Abandoned outside Atlanta.
Get your hands off me,
you Yankee scum.
No! My baby, please!
ROSE: Let go! Let go!
No!
(SCREAMING)
Rose! Let go of me!
Danny, no!
Danny! Danny, come back...
Danny! Danny, come back!
Oh, God.
Somebody, help me.
You said the house was empty.
You...
You son of a bitch.
God damn you to hell.
You said the house was empty!
They're Rebs, Captain.
You burned that house.
And them in it.
Your turn now.
"For they that take the sword
"shall perish
with the sword."
(GRUNTS)
Enough! Enough!
It's done.
(CHOKING)
Forty miles to Red Rock City.
You head over that ridge,
you'll be all right.
You keep coming after me,
you ain't going to find
nothing but torment.
You will pay for that life,
or you will pay with yours.
I'm going to fill my skin
and water the horses,
and then I'll be leaving.
That there's life.
Nothing 'round here is free.
Ain't got no gold.
You can look for yourself.
How to value a man's life?
How 'bout
one for another?
The black one is good.
Leave him.
You may go.
"Blessed be the Lord,
my strength.
"He teaches my fingers to
fight and my hands to war."
Amen.
Come on.
Leave me be, old man.
(CHUCKLES)
That your horse?
No.
(CLICKS)
It's yours.
Go as you wish.
That which is yours
will always return to you.
That which you take
will always be taken from you.
That's for the water,
not the horse.
A man could die out here
if he's not careful.
I didn't see you come up.
That's 'cause you keep
looking behind you.
Perhaps you'd be interested in a little
ration of Madame Louise's Cure All.
'Course, some say it's the
demon rum in a fancy bottle,
but it'll cure what ails you.
Thank you kindly.
But I'm afraid
ain't no bottle going to
sort out my troubles.
You men,
you always choosing
a gun over a remedy.
It don't really much
matter what I choose.
Got no money either way.
Oh, hell.
I never let that stand in
the way of making a deal.
What's wrong
with that .44?
Nothing.
How old's the animal?
I don't really know.
Steal her, did you?
Not exactly.
Spoken like a true sinner.
Well, hell, don't
matter much out here.
Man's got to do what a
man's got to do, right?
Yeah.
I suppose we best fix you up.
Cost you the horse.
I reckon I ain't getting
out of here, anyway.
Hell, I'll even throw in
a bottle of the curative.
Hey,
don't forget your curative.
Look at that sun long
enough, you go blind,
or worse,
mad.
What the hell do you want?
I'm just a humble peddler offering
a cure to an ailing world.
I ain't looking for no cure.
Why, that's just
what your friend said.
That what he's calling himself?
What would you call him?
Somebody who could use a
taste of that Colt of yourn.
Tell you what, stranger.
I got three thirsty
animals over there.
I'll trade you this here steel
for that water you got.
What do you say?
Got us a deal?
Yeah.
Just the one shell?
You looking for more?
I reckon not.
Time was,
you said your war was over.
Only the dead can only
end a war, Captain.
Go on,
finish it.
I believe it's up to you, sir.
Rose.
Forgive me.
♪ Oh, down in rollin' green
Such a sight was never seen
♪ The earth all
stood in a quiver
♪ Well, they run them nine miles
♪ And we stacked
them up in piles
♪ Besides what we
drowned in the river
♪ All day
♪ Falter all the day
♪ Black horse is coming
♪ Well, you needn't
mind the weather
♪ We'll all get down together
♪ And scurry round the
happy land of Canaan ♪