(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC)
(UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC)
NEWSREEL: 1,500 lucky diggers
are poised to show
Australian might in action
and dispel any fears
of a Japanese invasion.
They're headed for the capital
of New Britain - Rabaul.
As soon as they've unpacked,
they're off to the nearest beach.
Is the surf as good as Bondi, fellas?
And what better way to spend the day
than dancing on a tropical beach
with some of our prettiest flowers?
Pick one for me, mate.
(EXPLOSIONS)
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
WOMAN: So it's not far.
WOMAN 2: Hang on, OK? You right?
(PEOPLE CHATTER INDISTINCTLY)
WOMAN 3: Don't worry, mate.
We'll be at the mission soon.
You enjoying the war, Sister?
(SCOFFS) I'd enjoy it much more
on a bitumen road.
So what happens
when we reach this mission?
Well, you and I will find
a nice quiet beach somewhere
and continue where
we left off last week.
Len!
So where will we be evacuated to -
Moresby or Darwin?
(GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE SPEAK LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Won't be long. We'll be there soon.
Our ships will be
picking us up, won't they?
Sure, once they've driven
the Japanese back to Tokyo.
Then we're stuck here?
Anyone would think
you're scared of the Japs.
It's not them I'm worried about.
It's fighting you off
till the end of the war.
You could always surrender,
couldn't you?
(GOAT BLEATS)
WOMAN: Boris!
Boris!
If we put that goat in handcuffs,
he'd still get away.
He's Houdini with horns.
Boris!
(AEROPLANE ENGINE
DRONES IN DISTANCE)
(AEROPLANE APPROACHES)
(TENSE MUSIC)
WOMAN: Sister,
I need your help over here.
(PEOPLE SPEAK INDISTINCTLY)
There's some nurses staying here
from a Baptist mission station.
They've agreed to help us out.
And the nuns have some medicine
and bandages in their dispensary.
Is there anything else
that we, uh, urgently need?
Coffins.
(WOMEN ISSUE INSTRUCTIONS)
MAN: You're right, mate.
You're right, mate.
They'll look after you, mate.
Arggh!
They'll look after you.
MAN 2: You're right, Dave.
WOMAN: Sister, can you help me?
(MAN YELLS)
WOMAN: Cal, I need some iodine.
WOMAN 2: Can't get it
for you right now.
Got my hands full.
I'll be with you in a tick.
Sister. Quickly.
(NURSES ISSUE INSTRUCTIONS,
MEN GROAN)
Now.
Arggh!
Sorry, Dave. We're nearly done.
For Christ's sake, get a move on.
I... I don't want to hurt him.
Unless you pull your finger out,
that wound's gonna get infected.
Kay, give us a hand here, will ya?
Can you hold onto this, please?
He didn't survive the Japanese
to get himself killed by a nun.
I've got it, Sister.
Won't be long now.
What's your name, mate?
MAN: It's Dave.
When did you start
sending boys to war?
When we ran out of men.
Either we fight the Japs up here
or we hand them Australia.
Which would you prefer, Sister?
Have these patients
had their medication yet?
No, Major.
Well, don't just stand there gawking.
Do it!
Thanks a lot.
You don't criticise army doctors.
It's like telling the Pope
his sermons are boring.
Now he's got the shits,
he'll take it out on us.
We've been told to keep fighting.
With what?!
That piece of rust
won't kill any Japs
unless they pick it up
and die from tetanus.
Orders are orders.
Disobey them.
Lorna...
The army could've got us out.
But they dumped us. They left us here.
They don't have the right
to ask us to die.
Would you leave your patients?
I can't leave my men.
MAN: Come on, Len. We've gotta go.
So how about a smile
to remember you by?
MAN 2: Keep moving. Let's go.
Why weren't we all evacuated?
There were ships in the harbour
sailing out empty.
'Retreat's a dirty word in the army.
Some general would have
lost face at his club.
What will the Japanese do to us?
Treat us like prisoners of war,
of course.
One of the boys here heard a whisper
they've been raping nurses
in Hong Kong,
so I'm keeping this handy
just in case.
Morphine?
I'll kill myself before
I let those buggers touch me.
Oh, Tootie, come on.
The most infectious disease
in this world is panic
and I won't allow it here.
So get back to work, all of you.
Have we been given any orders?
Keep our uniforms clean...
...and act confident.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
I've been praying
for that young soldier.
Save your breath. He's got gangrene.
Will he survive?
Maybe. If we operate.
But we're out of anaesthetics.
Do you know anyone who can
turn water into chloroform?
The Americans will be here soon.
I'm sure they'll have
plenty of supplies.
They lost all their ships
at Pearl Harbor,
so unless they're damn good swimmers,
we'll be stuck here with the Japs
for the next few months.
And what would they do with us?
That's anyone's guess, Sister.
Please.
Call me Berenice.
Lorna Whyte.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
Relax. They're miles away.
I'm not scared.
I'm sure that our god
will protect us.
Your god isn't white,
he doesn't play cricket
and he won't give a hoot
what happens to you.
Sorry, Berenice,
but it's hard to believe in anything
when you haven't slept
for three days.
We have our own little cure
for insomnia.
Here.
Gonna need more than holy water
to make me nod off.
(CHUCKLES) No, it's brandy.
It's medicinal, of course.
Oh, yeah?
I'm sorry that I wasn't
much help at the hospital.
It doesn't matter now.
We'll probably both be raped and shot
before the week is out.
You want a smoke to go with that?
(BIRDSONG)
Sisters.
Sisters!
(WOMEN CHATTER EXCITEDLY)
What is it? What do you see?
Oh, yes. I knew they'd come.
Oh, what a wonderful day!
WOMAN: Have our boys landed?
What is it?
The Americans have come.
Our prayers are answered!
I told you God wouldn't abandon us.
We're saved. God bless America.
(RINGS BELL)
WOMAN: That's not our flag.
MAN: Grab the bags.
WOMAN: Boys, get inside.
Get off the veranda. Come on.
Everyone, back in your beds.
The Japanese are on the beach.
Should we evacuate the patients?
Where to? The jungle?
It's every man
for himself now, Lorna.
If you smart,
you'll get the hell out of here.
Wait.
No. Come back!
You can't just leave us! Wait!
You can't leave the patients.
You can't leave them!
We'd better fetch the doctors.
You're too late.
They've hightailed it out of here.
Well, did... did they
give us any orders?
Yes. They said,
"Every man for himself."
They left us? I don't believe it.
What's happening?
Shh. Lie down.
(MAN YELLS IN DISTANCE)
(MAN WHISPERS) Who's that?
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(GUNSHOTS NEARBY)
(MAN YELLS IN JAPANESE)
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
Hurry. Hurry. Please.
WOMAN: Lock the doors.
Lock all the doors.
Quickly, Sister.
WOMAN 2: Cover the door.
Lock the doors and windows.
WOMAN: I can see them.
They're coming.
WOMEN: Give us this day
our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
(WOMEN CONTINUE PRAYING)
(MAN YELLS IN JAPANESE)
Get down!
We surrender!
Get down! Get down!
Don't shoot! Please!
(ALL YELL FRANTICALLY)
We are Red Cross nurses!
These are our emblems.
No talk. Outside.
(THUDDING)
(SOLDIERS YELL)
(MEN YELL IN JAPANESE)
(SOLDIERS YELL AND SMASH ITEMS
IN NEARBY ROOMS)
(YELLS IN JAPANESE)
(SISTERS WHIMPER)
(PEOPLE YELL AND WHIMPER
FRANTICALLY)
(CAR HORN TOOTS)
WOMAN: No.
MAN: Halt! Sofort!
Heil Hitler!
(SPEAKS JAPANESE QUIETLY)
Bishop Leo Scharmach,
personal envoy to Adolf Hitler.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
This mission is German territory
under the protection
of the Führer himself.
He has decreed that our natives
are honorary Nazis.
(SOLDIER TRANSLATES
INTO JAPANESE)
Go ahead. Order him to shoot.
Then explain to your superiors
why you have declared war
on the Third Reich.
(SOLDIER SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(SPEAKS JAPANESE QUIETLY)
(RELAYS ORDER)
And I'll be sending you a bill
for the damage you have caused.
Heil Hitler!
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Let me help.
(WOMAN SPEAKS GERMAN)
They're from our Berlin convent.
Great - Japs out there,
Third Reich nuns here.
All I need is some Italians
and I'll feel really relaxed.
You're in luck, then.
Five of our sisters are from Rome.
(MAN BREATHES SHALLOWLY)
(QUIETLY) It has to come off.
That's a job for surgeons.
We've assisted them often enough.
They brag about their skills,
but we can do it if we have to.
Kay?
Have we got enough equipment?
We can amputate and cauterize.
But there's no ether.
What about your morphine?
He had the last of it this morning.
Then we'll do what they did
in Lord Nelson's day.
We'll get him drunk
on the convent's brandy.
There's none left, I'm afraid.
Two Japanese soldiers
found the bottle last night.
Well, that's it, then.
No, not by a long shot.
WOMAN: Where are you going?
To the pub.
Captain says, "No medicine,
no anaesthetic."
Please explain to the captain
that I only ask for alcohol - sake.
Why does a woman need sake?
To get a young soldier drunk
so that we can cut off his leg.
And he would allow
a female to do this?
He must or he'll die.
Captain says you stay. Drink.
No.
(REPEATS JAPANESE)
I only drink milk.
No!
Ohh!
19's too young for a boy to die.
He might have made it to 20
if our doctors hadn't run off.
Let me take over here.
It's alright.
Kay.
I should have saved him.
LORNA: If you'd given in
to that captain,
the Japs would have come
for the rest of us.
You think they won't anyway?
(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC)
This was under his pillow.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
DAVE'S VOICE: Love Rabaul.
Sheilas everywhere.
Maybe I won't
die a virgin after all.
Discovered my rifle
is from World War One.
No wonder it won't shoot straight.
Arrive - Vunapope.
Only females in sight
are nuns and nurses.
Some not too bad
if you like older women.
LORNA'S VOICE: Been a prisoner
since January 1942.
Coping alright.
Miss fights with Len
and his silly jokes.
(MAN SPEAKS JAPANESE)
Just put your head down a minute.
LORNA: The worst part
of being captured
is you don't know
how long you're in for.
Some wars are over
in a couple of weeks,
but I'm sure there was one in Europe
that went on for a hundred years.
Imagine going a hundred years
without a bath, a bloke or a beer.
I've gone without them
for three weeks now
and I'm going nuts already.
The nuns never complain.
They share everything they have
with our wounded patients.
Bishop Scharmach runs the place
as though the Japs weren't here.
He reminds me of an army doctor,
full of confidence, giving orders,
but all the nuns adore him.
(RECITES PRAYER IN LATIN) Amen.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(RECITES PRAYER)
(MAN YELLS ORDER IN JAPANESE)
WOMEN: Ichi. Ni. San.
Shi. Go. Roku. Shichi.
(MAN YELLS ORDERS IN JAPANESE)
(CONTINUES YELLING ORDERS)
Banzai.
SOLDIERS: Banzai!
LORNA: Sometimes, if we're lucky,
the natives set up meetings
between us and the soldiers
who are fighting in the jungle
and we gladly risk our lives
for a few minutes with them.
I'm sure it's a sin to be doing this
without the bishop's permission.
It's never a sin to save lives.
You're a sight for sore eyes.
Len.
God, you look terrible.
I just lost my beer gut. That's all.
Here's quinine and I managed
to scrounge a few extra treats -
socks, some tobacco, our Bible.
"Our Bible"? You're not
turning into a holy roller?
(CHUCKLES) We don't have
any cigarette papers,
so we're using that instead.
Don't let Bishop Scharmach
find out that I've been here.
We think he's a collaborator.
The natives are telling him
what we're up to
and he's passing it along
to the Japanese.
Can't you stop him?
How?
We're in the jungle
and he's in there.
I knew you wouldn't let me down.
Sometimes at night...
...I think about us
in a house, with kids.
That's the most ridiculous thing
I ever heard.
Yeah. I must have been delirious.
Toss it over. Quickly.
Oh, bugger it.
Leave it, Len. Go.
If the Japs find this
they'll shoot ya.
(SPEAKS IN JAPANESE)
Guards!
Get the hell out of here.
(PEOPLE CHATTER CALMLY)
What's going on over there?
The bishop is hearing
his confession.
There are no priests left outside.
(CRYING)
Suzuki, this is Lorna.
What did he want?
Just a few kind words.
The poor kid's homesick.
And he's Japanese,
in case you haven't noticed.
Suzuki's not like the others.
(SCOFFS) Give him a gun
and he will be.
You've seen how they behave.
They don't have feelings.
Well, he showed me
his mother's photo and cried.
He's the enemy.
He's barely 15.
So what are you gonna do?
Cheer him up?
Make him stronger so he'll be able
to shoot a digger one day?
(YELLING)
No.
Len? Len!
Lorna, if the Japs find out you know him
they'll torture you too.
Just pray Len's strong enough
not to say who helped him.
(MAN YELLS IN JAPANESE)
(LEN SCREAMS)
JAPANESE SOLDIER:
Who gave you food and medicine?
(LEN GASPS AND MOANS)
Leonard James Parkinson.
5-1-8-0-5.
(SOLDIER YELLS)
(LEN SCREAMS)
Who gave you food and medicine?
Leonard James Parkinson.
8... 0...
(MAN SPEAKS IN JAPANESE)
This Australian
is an enemy of the emperor.
Now you will see
how we treat our enemies.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
All people must watch.
Watch or you join him.
Look at him, Lorna.
LORNA: I can't.
Make yourself do it
or you'll be next.
Come on, you bastards!
Get it over with!
You don't bloody well
scare me!
(SWORD STRIKES)
Lorna.
Go away.
I'm so sorry.
I suppose you've come to tell me
how Len's in heaven now
downing schooners with the angels.
Try and eat. It's horse.
When we were at the fence with Len,
you said it was a sin.
Did you confess
that sin to Scharmach?
I don't understand.
Scharmach's a collaborator.
Len told me so.
No.
No, Lorna. This was not
the bishop's doing.
Did you confess
your sin to Scharmach?
Did he know that I'd helped Len?
Bishop Scharmach is not a traitor.
(SCOFFS)
If anyone's to blame for Len's death
it's the generals of your army.
They were the ones
who left you here.
If the bishop hadn't rescued you,
you'd all be dead now.
(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC)
LORNA: I can't believe
that our routine continues
as if nothing has happened.
The one thing that keeps me going
is that I must find a way
to get at Scharmach
so no more of Len's men are betrayed.
MAN: Look.
Just what we need - more Japanese.
They're not Japanese.
They're American.
Sister, the Yanks are miles away.
(AIR-RAID SIREN BLARES)
What do you know?
They've finally come to save us.
Over here!
(WOMEN CONTINUE CALLING OUT)
What's all this?
We're saved!
Oh, God bless America.
Oh, we're saved! Finally!
Take cover, everyone!
(SCREAMING)
MAN: Sisters, get inside now!
They're attacking,
they're attacking!
All of you boys under the bed now!
Get down now!
WOMAN: Run!
Berenice, run!
Run!
(PEOPLE YELL AND SCREAM)
Get down!
No, Cordula!
(WOMAN SINGS MOURNFUL SONG
IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(CONTINUES SINGING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
Go see to the others. I am fine.
Keep still.
It's a tiny cut.
It will heal itself.
Put a bandage on and let me go.
I don't believe you, Bishop.
I'm not one of your nuns.
Did you talk like that
to your army doctors?
All the time.
No wonder they left.
Ouch!
Take care of them.
I'll do this by myself.
Lorna, when you're ready.
We need more dressings.
WOMAN: And some water
over here, please.
Bishop.
Get one of your priests
to give you the last rites.
How dare you joke like that!
A piece of shrapnel has landed
in that tiny cut of yours
and it's lodged against
your carotid artery.
I don't understand.
Any time soon, it'll pierce it
and you'll bleed to death in seconds.
I could remove that shrapnel now,
but I know you're a busy man.
Thank you for saving our bishop.
I didn't save him. I just did
what I've been trained for.
It's not like you
to be humble, Lorna.
Sometimes I think you have
the makings of a nun.
A nun?
If you think that's even
remotely amusing...
I'm not joking. Think about it.
Nuns take three vows -
poverty, chastity and obedience.
You're poor, obviously.
You're chaste,
through no fault of your own.
You're obedient to the Japanese.
And you already wear a veil.
Welcome to the convent,
Sister Lorna.
What's all this?
We're building an air-raid shelter.
The bishop says
there's no time to waste.
Surely the Yanks must know
they made a mistake.
They wouldn't bomb nuns,
not deliberately.
They would murder half of heaven
to destroy a Japanese base.
I will not allow my mission
to be turned into a slaughter yard.
(PEOPLE CHATTER HAPPILY)
PEOPLE: Ooh!
MAN: Nice.
MAN 2: Hey!
MAN 3: Here we go. Pressure's on.
MAN: Bodyline!
ALL: Ohh!
Isn't it time they were
getting back in bed?
You won't be tucking us in
for much longer, Sister.
The Japs are shutting
the hospital down.
They're moving these boys
to Rabaul... for their safety.
MAN: Let's go, Bird.
WOMAN: Get a wicket!
ALL: Hey!
KAY: Alright, I'm in now.
MAN: Nice run.
Be gentle, Bird.
Everyone in close, everyone in close.
Come on, Matron.
MAN: Come on, beautiful.
ALL: Whoa!
MAN 2: Don Bradman in a veil!
KAY: Oh, is that the best
you can do, Bird?
(MAN YELLS IN JAPANESE)
LORNA: The last of Len's men
have been rounded up from the jungle.
There are so few of them left
and they look like hell.
Please let them be safe.
(PEOPLE CHATTER QUIETLY)
Your favourite.
Thank you.
There you go, soldier.
Thanks.
You sure you don't
want to join us, Sister?
We could hide you down the back.
Sorry, fellas. I get car sick.
They'll need bandages for the trip.
Can you scrounge some?
Alright.
Can you pass that round?
There you go.
(GASPS SOFTLY)
You right?
(MAN HUMS)
(BOTTLE DROPS)
(CRIES)
Oh, you beauty! Free cigarettes.
What? Suzuki?
Where are they?
You just missed them.
They said to tell you goodbye.
One of the young blokes
wants to marry you.
He's a bit too shy to ask.
Wait!
Please!
MAN: See ya, sister!
No, it's a trap!
(SOLDIER YELLS IN JAPANESE)
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
No, you're wrong. Suzuki couldn't.
This was all over him -
Australian blood.
(MAN LAUGHS, SPEAKS JAPANESE)
Konichiwa.
Auf Wiedersehen.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Konichiwa.
It is not decent
for women to be in my house.
Japanese troops have been
murdering Australians.
They've taken
all our patients away in a truck.
It's not too late to save them.
KAY: You must contact
the Red Cross at once.
Oh, forget it, Kay. He's useless.
They were butchered...
...at a place called Tol.
More than 100 Australian soldiers.
How do you know?
A native brought news to me
before their blood had dried.
Then why aren't you
trying to save our men?
What in God's name
do you think I have been doing?
Our captain has performed
a special act of kindness.
Kindness?
He has agreed to place all of your
patients under his protection.
Do you know how much sake
it took to do this?
Enough to get a whale drunk,
but he gave me his word
they will not be harmed.
KAY: Can he be trusted?
Drunk or not,
his honour is at stake.
Now, I need to lie down.
If only I could have used prayer
to persuade him.
I've never had a hangover
from a rosary.
Can we trust him?
Well, we have to.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Lorna, I have a message for you.
For me?
A boy from my village brought it.
He says Australian soldiers
got onto a boat,
a big boat in the harbour,
and one of them asked him
to tell Lorna Whyte,
"Everyone is safe
and you play lousy cricket."
(METAL CLANGS)
Aren't they exquisite?
They must be Japanese nurses.
Most nurses don't charge
by the hour, Sister.
They've been brought in
as a gift for the troops.
They'll perform
at the emperor's birthday.
Lorna.
I have an idea for the party.
(CHEERFUL PIANO MUSIC)
(SINGS) # Three little maids
from school are we
(BOTH SING) # Pert as a schoolgirl
well can be
(ALL SING) # Filled to the brim
with girlish glee
# Three little maids from school
# Everything is a source of fun
# Nobody's safe for we care for none
# Life is a joke that's just begun
# Three little maids from school
# Three little maids who,
all unwary... #
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(BERENICE PLAYS 'BEHOLD
THE LORD HIGH EXECUTIONER'
FROM 'THE MIKADO')
(SINGS) # Behold
the Lord High Executioner
(BOTH SING) # A personage
of noble rank and title
# A dignified and potent officer
# Whose functions
are particularly vital
ALL: # Defer, defer
to the Lord High Executioner
# Defer, defer
# To the noble Lord,
to the noble Lord
# To the Lord High Executioner... #
(WHISPERS) Sugai's here.
(SINGS) # Taken from
the county jail... #
(YELLS IN JAPANESE)
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(TENSE MUSIC)
(BERENICE PRAYS QUIETLY)
I guess it must be treason
to make fun of the emperor
and somehow I don't think
we'll be let off with a warning.
(CONTINUES PRAYING)
On our last night alive,
I would like some companionship.
I haven't got time.
I'm too busy praying for you.
I don't want your rosaries.
I want a schooner of beer,
a Clark Gable movie
and to hear you say
you detest the Japs.
Did you ever stop to think
that this is where
all wars are born?
Yes, part of me wants
to give in to it, Lorna,
but I'm fighting to resist that.
I will not leave this life
with hate in my heart.
I didn't know you liked Clark Gable.
If you weren't a nun,
we'd have a great conversation.
What's it like to be kissed?
(LAUGHS) Berenice!
Well, I want to know before I die.
When Clark Gable does it,
he makes it look easy.
Len was a wonderful kisser.
If only we'd had more time.
Now I'll never know what it's like
to be with a man.
Sometimes I really want a child.
My whole body aches for one.
Really?
Nuns call it 'pram ache'.
I often dream
I have a baby in my arms.
Who's the father?
Guess.
Clark Gable?
(LAUGHS)
You little tart!
He's not even Catholic.
Maybe I should be praying for you.
I should never have picked
that song from 'The Mikado'.
I am a truly wicked person.
Why didn't you stop me?
Because it was funny.
Do you reckon they'll behead us?
Swords and honour they save for men.
Lowly females just get shot.
It won't be so bad.
We'll hold each other's hand
and there'll be a loud bang
and the next thing you know,
you'll be in heaven.
And where will you be, Lorna?
(SOLEMN MUSIC)
(SOLDIERS YELL ORDER
IN JAPANESE)
(YELLS ORDER)
The captain has bad news,
I'm afraid.
She had nothing to do with this.
What?
'The Mikado'. It was all my idea.
And a poor one too,
but there are worse things
in this world than impudence.
(READS) "I regret to report
that a Japanese ship
"was last night torpedoed
by an American submarine.
"The 'Montevideo Maru'
"was transporting 1,100
Australian soldiers and civilians
"from Rabaul to China.
"There are no survivors."
They can't mean our boys.
Not our patients.
(SOLEMN MUSIC CONTINUES)
(METAL CLANGS)
WOMAN: It's stuffy, hey?
Suzuki.
I go war. Tough guy.
I'm so sorry.
Bow!
Of course.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
(MAN SPEAKS JAPANESE)
Lorna, did you hear that?
It's just thunder.
But the sky is clear.
It must be one hell of a battle.
(YELLING IN JAPANESE)
WOMAN: What's happening?
What are they doing?
(SOLDIERS YELL)
Don't touch that!
(YELLS IN JAPANESE)
(GRUNTS)
(WOMEN SHRIEK AND PROTEST)
Friend. Friend.
Suzuki friend.
Ohh!
(YELLS)
This is all your doing.
What have I got to do with it?
Don't treat me like a fool.
Half the Japanese fleet
has been wiped out
because the Americans
knew they were coming.
Someone tipped them off.
Oh, how would I do that?
He thinks you have a wireless.
Well, that's ridiculous.
Ask your nuns if we have a wireless.
Ask them if they've seen us at night
sitting up chatting to Canberra.
MAN: All nurses, all nuns, pack.
Leaving in one hour.
I forbid this. You understand?
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
You cannot do this to my nuns
without permission.
(MAN SPEAKS JAPANESE)
When the Führer learns of this outrage,
you will be sorry.
(TRANSLATES)
All nurses, go inside and pack.
You will be leaving this camp.
All nuns must stay.
Lorna, here's some curtains in case
you need clothes where you're going.
I got the idea from
'Gone with the Wind'.
Keep them. I don't want
to look pretty for the Japs.
All of you, one minute!
I'll pray for you. We all will.
Who's the patron saint of brothels?
That's probably where we're heading
thanks to your bishop.
Scharmach could have fought for us.
He could've kept the nurses here.
No. He tried. I know he did.
He's booting us out 'cause
he thinks we have a wireless.
That's not true.
Your beloved bishop
is a Japanese collaborator
and when all this is over
I'll make sure
he hangs for war crimes.
(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC)
NUN: Goodbye, Lorna.
We will never forget you.
'Bye!
Thank you!
Goodbye!
BERENICE'S VOICE:
The priest nearly fainted
when I told him that I'd slapped you.
He says I've been contaminated
by the violence of this war...
... and he's ordered me
to apologise, Lorna.
But since you're gone,
I can only do it in writing
and hope that by some miracle
my letters might reach you one day.
I've actually started to miss you.
Whole months go by when I don't
play poker or smell tobacco
or hear you tell a risqué joke.
I still don't understand what
the actress said to the bishop.
But nothing kills hunger pains
like a good laugh.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
Injured Japanese soldiers keep arriving.
Most have lost limbs
or are shell-shocked.
They remind me of children
who are trying not to cry.
(GUNSHOT)
BERENICE'S VOICE: Last night, some
of the wounded were taken outside.
Then the Japanese doctors
went around and medicated each
with a bullet.
I didn't pray for any of them.
To be honest, prayers wouldn't come.
(GUNSHOT)
And soon the thought occurred to me -
if the Japanese
would kill their own men,
what must they have done to you,
to you and all the nurses?
LORNA'S VOICE: We arrived
at our new camp yesterday, Berenice.
We don't even know where we are,
but there's a harbour outside
and we think our guard
calls it Yokohama.
So now we're a million miles from home.
Our new Japanese
have got us quite worried.
They bow all the time
and shower us with food.
I haven't a clue what's going on.
Kay says they want to fatten us up
like Christmas turkeys
for their brothels,
so we have to stay
as skinny as possible.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(YELLS IN JAPANESE)
BERENICE'S VOICE:
Our second Easter in captivity
and all of us
are prisoners of this war-
Japanese and missionaries.
(AEROPLANE ENGINE
DRONES IN DISTANCE)
What are they?
Americans.
Everyone, hurry to the shelter!
(PEOPLE YELL FRANTICALLY)
(YELLING AND SCREAMING)
One at a time!
There's room for everyone.
Don't panic!
(PLANES DRONE OVERHEAD)
(WOMEN PRAY)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHISTLING)
(PEOPLE SCREAM AND WHIMPER)
(ALL YELL AND SCREAM)
(SOMBRE MUSIC)
I built this mission
as a place of peace.
Look at it now.
Where was God
when this was happening?
Where was he, Sister?
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(SOBS)
(LORNA WHISTLES
'WALTZING MATILDA')
(PERSON JOINS IN WHISTLING)
(LORNA STOPS)
MAN: Gee, it's great
to see an Aussie.
I'm Geoff.
Lorna Whyte. 2/10th Ambulance Corps.
Yes, I heard you lot were up here.
(DOOR OPENS, FOOTSTEPS PASS)
They were trying to make me
do propaganda broadcasts
and some of them
were about you nurses.
Us?
Haven't they told you?
They're conducting
prisoner exchanges with the Allies.
That's why you're here.
They're sending you home.
No, no, it must be
some sort of trick.
Eight American nurses
left last month
and you lot are next.
When your ship docks in Fremantle,
have a beer for me, Lorna.
(WOMEN SING) # Should
old acquaintance be forgot
# And never brought to mind... #
LORNA'S VOICE: I deserved
that slap you gave me, Berenice.
Your bishop has sent us
up here to freedom.
That wonderful man
has delivered us from evil.
It isn't New Year's Eve,
but we're singing 'Auld Lang Syne'
because the Japanese have told us
we're leaving Yokohama.
Australia, here we come.
'Home'. Is there a lovelier word
in the whole English language?
(DOOR OPENS)
(YELLS IN JAPANESE)
BERENICE'S VOICE:
Month after month
the Americans return
and pound Vunapope into dust.
We have nothing left,
no food, shelter,
no water to wash in.
By now I must smell like
a chook house in a heatwave.
So we weren't surprised
when the Japanese announced
that we too are being moved,
miles away to a valley called Ramale.
There are no raids there,
so we shall have some
peace and quiet at last.
Timber and prayers
are no match for bombs,
but we carry our faith inside
and nothing can destroy that.
We left our mission
and all our dreams
on 6 June 1944 -
a date no-one will remember but us.
We are now in the hands of God.
(TENSE MUSIC)
BERENICE'S VOICE:
After three days, we have arrived
and now our work begins.
We will find the biggest hut
and turn it into a church -
Our Lady of Ramale.
(WOMEN GRUNT AND GROAN)
LORNA'S VOICE: The Japanese
have moved us inland
to a village called Totsuka.
They say the Australian Government
cancelled the prisoner exchange
and left us to rot here till we die,
but not even Canberra
could be so cruel.
(YELLS IN JAPANESE)
Ohh! Bloody hell!
(YELLS ORDER)
No speak!
(GROWLS)
(SNORING)
LORNA'S VOICE: Thank God for death.
It's what keeps us alive.
When Japanese people
drop off the twig,
their family don't bother with flowers.
Instead, they leave rice balls.
(DOG GROWLS AND BARKS)
Not on your life, mate.
I was here first.
LORNA'S VOICE: Yeah, I'll admit it -
we have to fight for everything.
But we win.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(MAN YELLS IN JAPANESE)
Arggh!
(SCREAMS)
Stop this! At once!
(WOMAN SCREAMS AND CRIES)
She stole a soldier's food.
I didn't!
Release her!
Or what? You'll tell your Führer?
Hitler is dead!
You have no friends left!
Sister Marie
will not live much longer.
She was the first nun I ordained.
Does she blame me?
For what?
For not sending all of you down
to Brisbane when I had the chance.
A wiser man, a better man would not
have brought his flock to this.
We chose to stay...
...and you respected that.
You are a good man.
Am I?
The captain gave it to me
as a punishment.
You see, I told him he could
take the Australian nurses
if my nuns could
remain at the mission.
I thought they would be
part of a prisoner exchange.
And the nurses?
Trapped in Yokohama.
And I am responsible.
I have hurt too many people.
I cannot face Sister Marie.
Marie needs you, My Lord.
We all do.
I am dried up inside.
Marie cannot...
She must not leave this life
without your comfort.
You come with me now to her bedside.
Please.
Through this holy anointing,
in his most tender mercy
may the Lord forgive you
for whatever sins you have committed
through your sense of sight.
Amen.
(EXHALES)
Through this holy anointing,
in his most tender mercy
may the Lord forgive you
for whatever sins you have committed
through your sense of taste
and through your ability to speak.
Amen.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
LORNA'S VOICE:
Our guards have just told us
that thousands of bombs
have sent Tokyo up in flames.
Since its houses
are made of paper and wood,
everything is burning.
The wireless says people
are running through the streets,
their clothes on fire
as they try to reach the river.
I know I should be happy that
the enemy is destroyed, Berenice,
but all I feel is shame.
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
The captain's wife... and child...
...died last night.
Please tell the captain
how sorry we are.
He says that this
will be your grave.
You will die here, buried here,
never leave Japan.
(WOMEN WHIMPER)
I wish I could speak your language.
I wish I could say that I understood
why you want to end your life.
We've all seen
more than we can bear.
(SOBS)
LORNA: It's a glorious sunny day.
And we've forgotten
how blue Sydney Harbour is.
Will anyone be meeting us?
Our mothers.
Did they bring food?
Roast chicken,
mashed pumpkin, meringues.
We can smell them
as we race down the gangplank.
(LAUGHS, COUGHS)
They know us at once.
We've hardly changed.
So they bury us in their hugs
and say, "Welcome home.
We've missed you."
BERENICE'S VOICE:
We've been ordered to dig a tunnel.
They say it's for air raids,
but one of the remaining guards
has confessed there is
a death squad on the way.
I've been told
you've died already, Lorna.
I hope with all my heart
it's not true.
But if it is,
please, please forgive me.
Whoever finds these, pray for me
and for all of us who are forgotten.
Sister Berenice Twohill,
July 1945.
PEOPLE: Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour of our death.
(PEOPLE CONTINUE PRAYING)
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
VOICE: Cooee!
Cooee!
(TENSE MUSIC)
WOMAN: Gone?
LORNA: Every last one.
So Kay and the others
have gone out scrounging for food.
(MAN SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(CAR ENGINES RUMBLE)
Come on.
Leave me, Lorna. No.
Lorna, go.
(MAN YELLS IN JAPANESE)
(THUDDING ON DOOR)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(MAN SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(FOOTSTEPS RESOUND)
(DOORS OPEN IN DISTANCE)
(DOOR OPENS)
(COUGHS)
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
We are nursing sisters of
the Australian Army General Hospital.
(AMERICAN ACCENT)
If that don't beat it all.
You gals white?
(GENTLE, SOLEMN MUSIC)
(MUSIC ASCENDS)
(UPLIFTING MUSIC)
(ALL SPEAK INAUDIBLY)
Don't you ever get up off your knees?
Well, say something.
You're dead.
(CHUCKLES) Really?
Ever seen a ghost smoke Craven A?
How did you know I was here?
I wrote to Bishop Scharmach.
I told you we'd both make it back.
You never said that.
You must have been
too busy praying to hear.
Lorna.
You're so pretty.
You still look like a holy roller.
How can you live without lipstick?
I felt naked for the entire war.
Anyway, I happened to be in Sydney
and I thought we might catch up,
maybe go to the pictures sometime.
I hear 'A Streetcar
Named Desire's terrific.
But your mother superior
wouldn't approve.
No, I guess not.
Of course, I could buy the tickets,
sneak you in when
the lights went down.
Then no-one would ever know.
I'm really glad that you came.
Whoever thought
I'd miss a Protestant.
Or that I'd have a nun for a mate.
(WOMEN CHATTER CHEERFULLY)
(UPLIFTING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(BOTH CONVERSE INAUDIBLY)
(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC)