(MAN SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
MAN: It's a choir.
(CHOIR SINGING)
(WAVES CRASHING)
(CHOIR CONTINUES)
(WOMAN ARGUING INDISTINCTLY)
HART: "A land of leaning ice"
"Hugged by plaster-grey
arches of sky"
"Flings itself silently
Into eternity"
"Has no one come
here to win you"
"Or left you with
the faintest blush
Upon your glittering breasts?"
"Have you no memories,
O Darkly Bright?"
"Cold-hushed, there is only
the shifting moments"
"That journey..."
(CATTLE LOWING)
"That journey toward no Spring"
"No birth, no death,"
"No time nor sun"
"In answer."
(COW MOOING)
Harold!
(RAGTIME MUSIC PLAYING)
HART: You know he is seeing
other women in Cleveland.
MOTHER: Your father
is nothing to me.
He is a tiny man
with nothing but his
chocolate and his numbers.
HART: Then why don't we
bleed him for all he's worth?
If he is so heartless,
then why shouldn't we be?
Dance with me, Harold.
I don't want to go
back to Cleveland.
I want to stay here
in New York.
Dance with me, Harold.
I don't want you to call me
Harold anymore. Call me Hart.
"Hart"?
Yeah.
(LAUGHING)
That is my new name.
MOTHER: Okay, Hart.
HART: "And so it was
I entered the broken world"
"To trace the visionary
company of love..."
(CHOIR SINGING)
(WAVES ROLLING)
(CHOIR CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
(PANTING)
HART: Here it is.
Diffututa mentula.
"Fucked flat."
That's how I feel.
My fuckin' father.
Why does he make
you work here?
Punishment. He doesn't want
a goddamned poet for a son.
He wants a calculator.
Then why don't you kill him?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm going to go to New York,
go to Columbia University,
Learn French.
Well, I know French.
I love you.
I know.
HART: Sometimes
I love you so much I cry.
Why?
Because you have
the eyes of Pierrot.
Who's that?
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, just this
guy from Italy.
(MOANING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(YELLING)
(BELL RINGS)
Yes!
Isadora Duncan
was incredible.
Magnificent.
But the crowd, what a bunch
of conservative bores.
So after, she comes back,
breast exposed.
She tells 'em all to go home
and read the Calamus section
from Whitman.
I'm sure most
don't even know Whitman.
It was... It was incredible,
Breast hanging out,
nipple exposed,
Telling them that
the truth isn't beautiful,
That in fact,
it's quite indecent.
But the important thing,
is how do we
get that into poetry?
All of it. Jazz,
Woolworth's, typewriters,
Buildings,
freeways, everything.
It's... It's popping up from
bridges and... And tunnels,
You know, from... From
here to... To San Francisco.
How do we... How do we
get that into poetry?
Eliot did it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
But Rabbi Crane,
(CHUCKLING) Rabbi Crane
will do it with
a positive affirmation.
It's not enough to join
a bunch of Apeneck Sweeneys
saying life is shit.
We all know life is a dance
of death, but you can still
make something out of it.
You can do something with it.
Munsey, Munsey, Munsey.
There's something...
There's something
beneath this...
This hell of our modernized,
mechanized world.
There's something true,
Some essential
Antique beauty
that we can get at,
We can get at using the very
Elizabethans that Eliot, that
master of death, utilized.
We can use Shakespeare,
Johnson, Marlowe, Webster,
We can use them for a
resurrection, for an
affirmation.
Hart, forgive me for saying
this, but you want to speak
for America.
Yeah.
Does it matter
that you're queer?
Whitman was queer.
That's why he could
love all of America.
The roustabouts, the slaves,
The... The... The soldiers
he nursed in the Civil War.
So you will expose yourself?
That's funny, considering
my truck driver left me.
No, people can know everything
about us when we're dead,
But for now,
it's better
to keep quiet,
For Father's sake.
Right.
You wouldn't want to lose that
tremendous job for the sake
of some queer affirmation.
(GROANS)
That job is killing me.
You know, I might be
the last Romantic alive,
But if I don't...
If I don't get out of there,
I'm not gonna be able
to write anymore.
MAN: Fuck!
HART: You okay?
Does it hurt?
Stop the bleeding.
FATHER: Harold, come here.
HART: I'm eating.
You're living with your
mother, go eat with her.
Why don't you eat
with her, you pig?
I will not be spoken to like
that in front of these people.
HART: What, in front of
the workers? Your slaves?
Is that what you mean?
You will apologize to me
and to everyone here.
Oh, yeah? Yeah?
That's what I am, right?
One of your slaves? Huh?
Why don't you go to hell?
Take your money and
shove it up your ass!
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
HART: Hey. Munsey, wait.
You all right?
(RETCHING)
MUNSON: Ugh.
You okay? You okay?
You all right?
Yeah.
I'm all right.
You okay?
Yeah, come on.
(HART WHOOPING)
(MUNSON GROANS AND SPITS)
(LAUGHING)
HART: Shh! Stop!
Shh! Go, go, go, go! Go.
Come on. Hurry. Go!
No more drinking
in this house!
Fuck you! Fuck all of you!
I'm astounded by your picture.
Apples and Gable?
Yeah. I'd... I'd love to
write a... I'd be honored to
write a... An essay about it,
In a comprehensive essay
about your work.
Okay, Hart, fine, fine.
Really? Great. Uh, would you
uh... Would you like to go to
the the cinema with me?
Right now?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Hart.
There is so much work to do.
Okay. Well...
I'll see you soon then.
Yes.
Okay. See ya.
(WHIMSICAL PIANO
MUSIC PLAYING)
Tough.
Don't hide from Naugahyde.
Naugahyde.
Just messing around.
Naugahyde,
Naugahyde, Naugahyde.
Naugahyde. Tough.
(IN GRUFF VOICE)
Tough. Tough. Tough.
Naugahyde.
(GROWLING)
(IN SCRATCHY VOICE)
Naugahyde.
(GURGLING)
"What is that?"
(GROWLING)
Naugahyde.
I've got some
Naugahyde for you.
(LAUGHING AND WHEEZING)
(GROWLING)
I've got some
Naugahyde for you.
(GROWLING)
I've got some
Naugahyde for you.
(GROWLING)
I don't go anywhere
without my Naugahyde.
(GROWLING)
I don't go anywhere
without my Naugahyde.
HART: My Grandmother's
Love Letters.
"There's..."
"There are no stars tonight
But those of memory"
"Yet how much room
for memory there is"
"In the loose girdle
of soft rain."
"There is even room enough
For the letters of
my mother's mother"
"Elizabeth"
"That have been
pressed so long
Into a corner of the roof"
"That they are brown and soft
And liable to melt as snow"
"Over the greatness
of such space
Steps must be gentle"
"It is all hung by
an invisible white hair"
"It trembles as birch
limbs webbing the air"
"And I ask myself"
"'Are your fingers
long enough to play
Old keys that are but echoes"
"'Is the silence strong enough
To carry back the music
to its source"
"'And back to you again
As though to her?'"
"Yet I would lead my
grandmother by the hand"
"Through much of what
she would not understand"
"And so I stumble."
"And the rain
continues on the roof"
"With such a sound
of gently pitying laughter."
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDS)
(HART CLEARS THROAT)
The Marriage
of Faustus and Helen.
"The mind has shown
itself at times"
"Too much the baked
and labeled dough"
"Divided by
accepted multitudes."
"Across the stacked
partitions of the day"
"Across the memoranda,
baseball scores"
"The stenographic smiles
and stock quotations"
"Smutty wings
flash out equivocations"
"The mind is brushed
by sparrow wings"
"Numbers,
rebuffed by asphalt, crowd"
"The margins of the day,
accent the curbs"
"Convoying divers dawns
on every corner"
"To druggist,
barber and tobacconist"
"Until the graduate
opacities of evening"
"Take them away
as suddenly to somewhere"
"Virginal perhaps,
less fragmentary, cool"
"There is the world
dimensional"
"For those untwisted
by the love of things
irreconcilable..."
"And yet, suppose some evening"
"I forgot
The fare and transfer,"
"Yet got by that way
Without recall"
"Lost yet poised in traffic"
"Then I might find
your eyes across an aisle"
"Still flickering with
those prefigurations"
"Prodigal, yet uncontested now"
"Half-riant before
the jerky window frame"
"There is some way,
I think, to touch
Those hands of yours"
"That count the nights"
"Stippled with pink
and green advertisements."
"And now,
before its arteries turn dark"
"I would have you meet
this bartered blood"
"Imminent in his dream,
none better knows
The white wafer cheek of love,"
"Or offers words
Lightly as moonlight
on the eaves meets snow."
"Reflective conversion
of all things
At your deep blush,"
"When ecstasies thread
The limbs and belly,"
"When rainbows spread
Impinging on
the throat and sides..."
"Inevitable,
the body of the world"
"Weeps in inventive dust
for the hiatus
That winks above it,"
"Bluet in your breasts."
"The earth may glide
diaphanous to death"
"But if I lift my arms
it is to bend
To you who turned away once,"
Helen,
"Knowing
The press of troubled hands,
too alternate"
"With steel and soil to hold
you endlessly"
"I meet you, therefore,
in that eventual flame"
"You found in final chains,"
"No captive then
Beyond their million brittle,
bloodshot eyes"
"White, through
white cities passed"
"On to assume
That world which comes
to each of us alone."
"Accept a lone eye
riveted to your plane"
"Bent axle of devotion
along companion ways"
"That beat, continuous,
to hourless days"
"One inconspicuous,"
"Glowing orb of praise."
Two.
"Brazen hypnotics glitter here"
"Glee shifts
from foot to foot,
Magnetic to their tremulo."
"This crashing opera bouffe
Blest excursion!"
"This ricochet
From roof to roof."
"Know, Olympians,
we are breathless"
"While nigger cupids
scour the stars!"
"A thousand light
shrugs balance us"
"Through snarling
hails of melody."
"White shadows slip
across the floor"
"Splayed like cards
from a loose hand"
"Rhythmic ellipses
leap into canters"
"Until somewhere
a rooster banters."
"Greet naively, yet intrepidly
New soothings, new amazements"
"That cornets
introduce at every turn"
"And you may fall
downstairs with me"
"With perfect grace
and equanimity"
"Or, plaintively
scud past shores"
"Where, by strange
harmonic laws"
"All relatives,
serene and cool"
"Sit rocked
in patent armchairs."
"O, I have known
metallic paradises"
"Where cuckoos
clucked to finches"
"Above the deft
catastrophes of drums"
"While titters hailed
the groans of death"
"Beneath gyrating
awnings I have seen"
"The incunabula
of the divine grotesque."
"This music
has a reassuring way."
"The siren of the springs
of guilty song"
"Let us take her
on the incandescent wax"
"Striated with nuances,
nervosities"
"That we are heir to
she is still so young"
"We cannot frown upon her
as she smiles"
"Dipping here
in this cultivated storm"
"Among slim skaters of the
gardened skies."
Three.
"Capped arbiter of beauty
in this street"
"That narrows darkly
into motor dawn"
"You, here beside me,
delicate ambassador"
"Of intricate slain
numbers that arise"
"In whispers, naked of steel"
"Religious gunman!"
"Who faithfully, yourself,
will fall too soon"
"And in other ways than
as the wind settles"
"On the sixteen thrifty
bridges of the city"
"Let us unbind our throats
of fear and pity."
"We even,
Who drove speediest
destruction"
"In corymbulous
formations of mechanics,"
"Who hurried the hill breezes,
spouting malice"
"Plangent over meadows,
and looked down"
"On rifts of torn
and empty houses"
"Like old women
with teeth unjubilant"
"That waited faintly,
briefly and in vain"
"We know, eternal gunman,
our flesh remembers"
"The tensile boughs,
the nimble blue plateaus,"
"The mounted,
yielding cities of the air!"
"That saddled sky that shook
down vertical
Repeated play of fire"
"No hypogeum
Of wave or rock was good
against that hour"
"We did not ask for that,
but have survived"
"And will persist
to speak again before"
"All stubble streets
that have not curved"
"To memory, or known
the ominous lifted arm"
"That lowers down
the arc of Helen's brow"
"To saturate
with blessing
and dismay."
"A goose, tobacco and cologne"
"Three winged and gold-shod
prophecies of heaven,"
"The lavish heart shall always
have to leaven"
"And spread with bells
and voices, and atone"
The abating shadows
of our conscript dust
"Anchises' navel,
dripping of the sea"
"The hands Erasmus dipped
in the gleaming tides"
"Gathered the voltage
of blown blood and vine"
"Delve upward for the new
and scattered wine"
"O brother-thief of time,
that we recall"
"Laugh out the meager
penance of their days"
"Who dare not share with us
the breath released"
"The substance drilled
and spent beyond repair"
"For golden,
or the shadow of gold hair"
"Distinctly praise the years,
whose volatile"
"Blamed bleeding hands
extend and thresh"
"The imagination spans
beyond despair"
"Outpacing bargain,"
"Vocable and prayer."
(CHOIR SINGING)
(CHOIR STOPS ABRUPTLY)
(RAGTIME MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
HART: "Dear Mr. Kahn",
"My first collected poems,
White Buildings, are
to be published next spring"
"With a forward
by Eugene O'Neill."
"Although my poems have
appeared from time to time
in various magazines,"
"Such as The Dial and
The Little Review,"
"I'm not yet well enough
known to reap
any substantial benefits"
"From what I've written."
"I'm 26 years of age,
and for the last seven years,"
"Have been entirely
dependent on my efforts"
"As an advertising
copywriter for my living."
"What real writing I've
done has had
to be accomplished"
"After office hours
and sometimes at the risk
of losing my position."
"Last June, as a result of ill
health and nervous exhaustion,"
"I had to resign my position
at Sweets catalogue,"
"Regardless of my dependence
on my salary there,"
"And live in the country until
my health recovered."
"But as I find myself
now completely without funds,"
"My circumstances seem
to be rather acute."
"One of my friends
has suggested"
"That you might be
sufficiently interested
in the creation"
"Of an indigenous American
poetry to possibly
assist me at this time."
"Besides the poems collected
I White Buildings,"
"I have partially
written a long poem,"
"The conception of which
has been in my mind
for some years."
"I've had to work at it very
intermittently between night
and morning,"
"And while shorter efforts can
be more successfully completed
under crippling circumstances,"
"A larger conception such
as this poem, The Bridge,"
"Aiming as it does
to enunciate a new
cultural synthesis"
"Of values in terms of our
America, requires a more
steady application"
"And less interruption than my
circumstances have yet granted
me to give it."
"With $1,000,
I could live in
retirement and cheaply"
"In the country for at
least a year's time and
complete this poem."
"My references, Waldo Frank,
Allen Tate, Gorham Munson,"
"Eugene O'Neill, James Light,
Marion Moore, Jane Heap,
and Paul Rosenfield."
HART: "My dear mother",
"For almost six weeks now,
I've not heard
from you or Grandma."
"I've put off writing you
under these conditions,"
"There was enough reason
to do so simply on the basis
of your own indifference,"
"Or possibly disgust with me."
"I don't know where
you may be at this time,
but in case you may,"
"For any reason,
wish to write me,"
"I'm writing to say that
I shall probably,
for the next year,"
"Be at the following address."
"Mrs. Addy Turner in
Patterson, New York."
"I'm unusually well provided
for, and shall leave for the
country next Saturday."
"Yesterday afternoon,
I had the pleasure of being
rewarded in some measure"
"For some of the work
I've been doing."
"After an interview
with Otto Kahn at his home
at 1100 Fifth Avenue,"
"I was given the sum
of $2,000 to spend
on my living expenses"
"During the next year,"
"Which time is to be
opened and writing"
"In the most creative
message I have to give,"
"Regardless of whether
it is profitable in
dollars or cents or not."
"I'm very tired now.
With all the strain and effort
of the last two months,"
"I shall probably pick up
as never before"
"When I get into
the quiet of the country"
"And have the first real
opportunity in my life to use
my talents unhampered by fear"
"And worry for the morrow."
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Rich!
RICH: What?
Get in here! Get in here!
Hey! (LAUGHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(TYPEWRITER CLACKING)
(CAT MEOWING)
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
HART: "Dear Waldo",
"For many days now,
I have gone about quite
dumb with something"
"For which 'happiness'
must be too mild a term."
"At any rate,
my aptitude for communication,
such as it ever is,"
"Has been limited to one
person alone"
"And perhaps
for the first time in my life,"
"And I can only think
it is for the last,"
"So far is my imagination"
"From the conception of
anything more profound
and lovely than this love."
"I have wanted to write you
more than once,"
"But it will take many
letters to let you know
what I mean,"
"For myself at least,"
"When I say that I have
seen the Word made Flesh."
"I mean nothing less, and
I know now that there is such
a thing as indestructibility."
"In the deepest sense,
where flesh became
transformed"
"Through intensity of response
to counterresponse,"
"Where sex was beaten out,
where a purity of joy was
reached that included tears."
(MOANING)
(MOANING LOUDLY)
(PANTING)
HART: " How many dawns,
chill from his rippling rest"
"The seagull's wings shall dip
and pivot him"
"Shedding white rings
of tumult,
building high"
"Over the chained
bay waters
Liberty"
"Then, with inviolate curve,
forsake our eyes"
"As apparitional as
sails that cross"
"Some page of figures
to be filed away"
"Till elevators
drop us from our day..."
"I think of cinemas,
panoramic sleights"
"With multitudes bent toward
some flashing scene"
"Never disclosed,
but hastened to again"
"Foretold to other eyes
on the same screen"
"And Thee,"
"Across the harbor,
silverpaced"
"As though the sun
took step of thee, yet left"
"Some motion ever
unspent in thy stride"
"Implicitly thy freedom
staying thee!"
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
"Out of some
subway scuttle,
cell or loft"
"A bedlamite speeds
to thy parapets"
"Tilting there momentarily,
shrill shirt ballooning"
"A jest falls from the
speechless caravan"
"Down Wall, from girder
into street noon leaks"
"A rip-tooth
of the sky's acetylene"
"All afternoon
the cloud flown
derricks turn..."
"Thy cables breathe the
North Atlantic still"
"And obscure as that
heaven of the Jews,
Thy guerdon..."
"Accolade thou dost bestow
Of anonymity
time cannot raise"
"Vibrant reprieve and pardon
thou dost show"
"O harp and altar,
of the fury fused,"
"How could mere toil
align thy choiring strings!"
"Terrific threshold of the
prophet's pledge"
"Prayer of pariah,
and the lover's cry"
"Again the traffic lights
that skim thy swift"
"Unfractioned idiom,
immaculate sigh of stars,"
"Beading thy path
condense eternity"
"And we have seen night lifted
in thine arms."
There's nothing like
this in the world.
Shh.
HART: " Under thy shadow
by the piers I waited"
"Only in darkness
is thy shadow clear"
"The City's
fiery parcels all undone"
"Already snow submerges
an iron year"
"O Sleepless as
the river under thee"
"Vaulting the sea,
the prairies' dreaming sod"
"Unto us lowliest
sometime sweep, descend"
"And of the curveship
lend a myth to God."
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
(YELLING)
Wellwood Toothpaste!
Don't suffer from tooth decay!
It's all right!
Everything's okay!
You're not gonna suffer!
You won't suffer
from decay with Wellwood!
Everything's all right!
You got Wellwood Toothpaste!
And then, it's over!
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(HUMMING)
(MUTTERING)
"Under the shadow
by the... By the pier..."
(CONTINUES MUTTERING)
Allen? Allen, hey. It's Hart.
How are you?
Yeah, I know,
I know it's late.
It's, uh, um,
I'm, uh, I'm in the cabin.
Um, did... Did you get my...
Did you get, um,
the package I sent you?
Yeah, well, yeah, well,
you could've told me.
I know, it's just,
uh, it's just nice
to hear, you know?
It would've
been nice to hear...
Well, what'd you think?
Uh-huh.
Mmm-hmm.
Look, look, look, I,
uh, I have more. Here, let me,
uh, let me read it to you.
No, uh, uh, just let me read
you what I got.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Um, um, um...
"Under thy shadow
by the piers I waited"
"Only in darkness
is thy shadow clear"
"The City's fiery
parcels all undone"
"Already snow submerges
an iron year"
"O Sleepless..."
No, it's, uh, um, "To...
To Brooklyn Bridge."
Mmm-hmm.
Well, that's the end of it.
Yeah, uh, it's like a,
you know, a prologue, I think.
You know, to the whole thing.
Mmm-hmm.
No, I know, uh, I know
it's late, I just, you know,
I just wanted to...
All right.
All right, I'll call you
tomorrow. Okay, all right.
(HUMMING)
(EXHALES LOUDLY)
Waldo.
Hey.
It's Hart.
Harold,
There's no doubt
you can write.
You've shown me that.
But what good does it do you
If you can't
make your own way?
I can't do anything else.
I can see that, Harold.
But I'm not sure what
I'm supposed to do about it.
I can't make
you work with me.
Not if you make me a stock boy
and put me at the bottom
of the ladder.
Harold, I can't give you any
position. You can't hold
down a regular job.
You have proven that.
How am I supposed to write or
find time to write
If I spend my...
My soul's life
trying to sell toothpaste?
Listen. Every man makes his
way in the world,
And a man who can't
isn't worth a damn.
Listen, Harold.
Your grandmother's
about to pass.
I know you've spent that
inheritance a thousand times
already in your mind
But I urge you to be prudent
with that money.
(SOFT RAGTIME MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
HART: What are you reading?
MAN: I just saw this one and
I thought it was nice.
(CHOIR SINGING)
(MAN AND WOMAN
CHATTING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR OPENING)
Monsieur?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I don't have any money.
I left my...
I left my wallet
at the hotel
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I can come back.
I'll come back and pay
for the wine. Okay?
MAN: Ma'am, we can,
we'll pay for it.
(OWNER SPEAKING FRENCH)
(WOMAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
I'll go and get
the money, okay?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I'll go to the hotel and...
Get off of me!
WOMAN: Richard!
What are you doing, Richard?
HART: Get off me!
WOMAN: What are you doing?
MAN: Guys, guys...
HART: Fucking...
WOMAN: Richard!
WOMAN: No!
Fuck! Get the fuck off me!
MAN: Guys, guys...
HART: Get off me!
WOMAN: Richard!
HART: Get the fuck off me!
MAN: Guys, guys...
HART: Get off me!
WOMAN: Richard! Step away. No!
It's all over.
What do you mean?
Hart, stop.
Hart, please! Stop!
What is it, Hart?
Hart!
No! Son of a bitch!
Don't you ever
fucking do that again!
(PANTING)
What?
I can't do
it anymore.
HART: "Dear Lotte and Ricardo,
I'm sailing to Mexico."
"Damn the gendarmes."
"Dear Lotte and Ricardo,
I'm sailing to Mexico
next Saturday."
"Damn the gendarmes."
"The change from going back
to France was made"
"Without any trouble
by the Guggenheim people."
"I'm happy at the change."
"Truly, for me,
a pretty locality,"
"And everything and pregnant."
"First a week in Mexico City
with my old and wonderful
friend Katherine Anne Porter,"
"And possibly
Peggy Cowley,
Malcolm's ex,"
"And then on
to some country location."
(SIGHS)
(BOSSA NOVA MUSIC PLAYING)
(BELL TOLLING)
(PLAYING MARIACHI MUSIC)
(SINGING AND PLAYING)
(BAND FINISHES SONG)
(BAND PLAYING NEW SONG)
Hey!
HART: The Broken Tower.
"The bell-rope that
gathers God at dawn"
"Dispatches me as though
I dropped down the knell
Of a spent day"
"To wander the
cathedral lawn
From pit to crucifix,"
"Feet chill
on steps from hell."
KATHERINE: Hart.
Hart.
Mmm?
Wake up.
Hart.
You can't get arrested again.
They'll take away your
fellowship.
I can't write anymore.
I'm washed up.
Hart. Come on.
We'll put you to bed.
HART: "Have you not heard,
have you not
seen that corps..."
"Have you not heard,
Have you not seen that corps
Of shadows in the tower,"
"Whose shoulders sway
Antiphonal carillons
launched before"
"The stars are caught
and hived in the sun's ray?"
(BELL TOLLING)
"The bells, I say, the bells
break down their tower"
"And swing I know not where."
"Their tongues engrave
Membrane through marrow,"
"My longscattered score
Of broken intervals..."
"And I, their sexton slave!"
"Oval encyclicals
in canyons heaping"
"The impasse high with choir."
"Banked voices slain!"
"Pagodas, campaniles
with reveilles"
"Out leaping
O terraced echoes
prostrate on the plain!"
"And so it was I entered
the broken world"
"To trace the visionary
company of love, its voice"
"An instant in the wind
I know not whither hurled"
"And not for long to hold
each desperate choice."
"My word I poured."
"But was it cognate, scored
Of that tribunal monarch
of the air"
"Whose thigh embronzes..."
"Whose thigh embronzes earth,
strikes crystal Word"
"In wounds pledged once
to hope cleft to despair?"
"The steep encroachments
of my blood left me
No answer"
"Could blood hold such
a lofty tower
As flings the question true?"
"Or is it she
Whose sweet mortality
stirs latent power?"
"And through whose
pulse I hear,
counting the strokes"
"My veins recall
and add, rev..."
"And through whose pulse..."
"The steep encroachments
of my blood left me
No answer"
"Could blood hold such
a lofty tower
As flings the question true?"
"Or is it she
Whose sweet mortality
stirs latent power?"
"And through whose
pulse I hear,
counting the strokes"
"My veins recall and add,
revived and sure"
"The angelus of wars
my chest evokes"
"What I hold healed,
original now, and pure..."
"And builds, within,
a tower that is not stone"
"Not stone can jacket heaven"
"But slip
Of pebbles, visible wings
of silence sown"
"In azure circles,
widening as they dip"
"The matrix of the heart,
lift down the eye"
"That shrines the quiet lake
and swells a tower..."
"The commodious,
tall decorum of that sky"
"Unseals her earth,
and lifts love in its shower."
(BELL TOLLING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANING)
HART: I'm done.
Hart, have you slept?
Not for a long time.
Hart, please go to bed.
HART: "Above the fresh
ruffles of the surf"
"Bright striped urchins flay
each other with sand"
"They have contrived
a conquest for shell shucks"
"And their fingers crumble
fragments of baked weed
Gaily digging and scattering"
"And in answer
to their treble interjections"
"The sun beats lightning
on the waves"
"The waves fold thunder
on the sand"
"And could they hear me
I would tell them"
"O brilliant kids,
frisk with your dog"
"Fondle your shells
and sticks, bleached
By time and the elements"
"But there is a line
You must not cross
nor ever trust beyond it"
"Spry cordage
of your bodies to caresses"
"Too lichen-faithful
from too wide a breast."
"The bottom of the sea
is cruel."
(MILD APPLAUSE)
HART: Okay. Thank you.