[Horn Honking]
- How are you, Bill?
- Hi, Tommy.
What's with you and Betsy?
Couldn't be better.
Uh, look. Did you say something to me
the other day about wanting to make a change?
Oh, well, not exactly.
What I said was that I like it
at the Foundation okay...
but I'm having a little trouble
making both ends meet.
The reason I ask-
I hear there's a spot opening up...
in Public Relations where I work-
United Broadcasting.
What would it pay?
Oh, I don't know. Eight, 10,000, I guess.
Something like that.
Well, I could certainly do
with eight or 10,000...
but I don't know anything
about public relations.
Who does?
You got a clean shirt.
You bathe every day.
That's all there is to it.
Oh, I guess not.
Thanks just the same.
You're probably right.
I don't think you'd be very happy
in that chromium jungle anyway.
[Bell Ringing]
Tommy!
[Chattering]
Well, how was your day?
- Not too good, I'm afraid.
- No?
For one thing, the washing machine
finally conked out.
Well, can't you
have it fixed?
Not anymore.
It's really gone this time.
How much
does a new one cost?
- About 250.
- Wow.
And Barbara's
got the chicken pox.
Oh, my. Better stop
at the drugstore.
I'll pick up a present for her.
How's she feeling?
Happiest little polka-dotted girl
in the State of Connecticut.
Hey, Daddy.
- Hi, Pete.
- You know what, Daddy?
- What?
- Barbara's got the chicken pox,
and we're all gonna get it.
- Oh, maybe not.
- But Mama promised! Didn't you, Mama?
- That's what the doctor says.
- Here we go.
We're all gonna get it
and stay in bed all day.
Huh. I can just see you
staying in bed all day.
Janey says she's gonna take her
rock collection to bed with her.
You come with me and help
Mommy fix Daddy's dinner.
I'm gonna take Millie
to bed with me.
- Well.
- I've got the smallpox.
Chicken pox, honey.
Don't make it worse than it is.
Are you sure you didn't
paint those on there yourself?
Honest I didn't, Daddy.
Look. I've got 'em all over.
- Well, if you say you didn't-
- Thank you, Daddy.
- How are you, sweetheart?
- Is she going to die?
Of course not. People
don't die from chicken pox.
Did you ever have
chicken pox?
- I've had everything. How about you?
- I've been trying to remember.
- You won't have to try long.
You'll know in a day or two.
- That's what's worrying me.
You can go on down.
I'll be down in a minute.
- I think she's going to die.
- Will you stop talking like that!
And you can mix one
for me too...
because I can certainly
use it tonight.
I think she's dying now.
What do you think
you're gonna do with him?
- I'm gonna take him in bed with me.
- But he's filthy, Petey.
I'm gonna wash him
in the bathtub first.
Oh, Janey gets everything.!
You never let me have one little thing.!
All you do is take things
away from me.!
I'm gonna run away from here,
and you're never gonna see me again.!
I'm gonna run
a million miles away.!
And I don't care if you die.!
I don't care if you die
a hundred million times.! I don't care.!
- Now listen, Petey.
- I don't care if you die too.
I'm gonna run away
from here this very minute.!
Petey boy, have you forgotten
that you and I are buddies?
I am not your buddy.!
I want you to die too.
- I want everybody to die.!
- Shut up!
What have we got around here-
a bunch of necrophiles?
Oh, they're all right.
Just a little fretful.
Skoal.
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
Hello. Oh, hello, Alfred.
I tried to get you on the phone
at the office, but you had just left.
It's about the estate.
I've just heard
from the auditors...
and the news is
a little disappointing.
I'll look it over again of course.
- Is that final?
- That's all there is to it.
- I see.
- Nothing left but that old house.
Well, thanks
very much anyway.
Good night, Alfred.
You're gonna have to brace yourself
for this one, honey.
Okay, let's have it.
That was Alfred.
He says there's nothing left
in Grandma's estate.
- Nothing?
- Nothing but that old barn of a house.
And there's a $ 10,000
mortgage on it.
What about the money
Grandpa left?
- Apparently she lost it.
- [Sighs]
Well, that's certainly
one on the button.
What about the house?
What do you think we can get for it?
- I've already had one offer: 20,000.
- Twenty thousand?
That house must have cost
150,000 to build.
That was 50 years ago. Nobody wants
an old rookery like that today.
Get the butter, will you?
It's one of the few houses in Connecticut
that hasn't grown old gracefully.
- You're gonna let them have it for that?
- What do you think we oughta do?
Well, if that's the best
offer we can get-
- Good-bye.
- Good-bye, dear.
Send us a card
when you get there.
[Cat Mews, Screeches]
I forgot my mittens.
I think we ought to hang on
to it for a year or two anyway.
Till we can figure out
something better than that.
Do you know what it would cost
to keep up a place like that?
Something like 6,000 a year.
On a $7,000 salary.
But you're not going to
always be making 7,000.
That's what I mean.
I could be making less.
But you can't look
at things like that, Tommy.
You've got to believe that
things are gonna get better.
Promotions, opportunities,
some good breaks.
That's what life is-
hope and- and the breaks.
You can't just accept
the way things are now.
I think we ought to sell it, put the money
in the bank for some insurance.
- [Groans]
- Did you ever stop to think
what might happen to you...
if I should drop dead
some morning?
- I'll drop dead right there by you.
- What about the children?
I don't even want
to think about that.
What I want to know is, you don't expect
to be with the Foundation forever, do you?
Well, of course not. But you've got
to admit it's an absolutely safe spot.
All right then.
What about this?
We sell Grandma's house
and this house too...
and we get us a nice house
in a nice neighborhood.
- So here we go on that again.
- But why not?
If we can make maybe 15,000 on this one
and with what we clear on Grandma's-
- Look, honey, don't you understand?
- I'm sorry, Tommy.
You know how I hate this house,
but you don't know how much I hate it!
Its ugliness, its depression,
but most of all its defeat.
- Don't you feel that at all?
- Well, it's not exactly a palace.
It's a graveyard, Tommy. A graveyard
of everything we used to talk about-
happiness, fun, ambition-
and I want to get out of it.
But if we put it all
in the bank-
- And go on living here for the rest of our lives?
- Maybe you don't know it...
but there are a lot of people
who are doing a lot worse than we are.
Oh, no, they're not. They may
look like it, but they're not.
There are things about this house.
It's not a happy house, Tommy.
- I don't think that's true.
- Ever since the war.
Will you stop harping on the war.
It's been over for 10 years.
It's gone and forgotten.
I don't believe it. Not for you anyway.
Whether you know it or not-
All I know is that I don't think
this is any time to be taking chances.
Then if it wasn't the war,
what has happened to you?
What do you mean,
what's happened to me?
I don't know.
Except that you've lost your guts,
and all of a sudden I'm ashamed of you.
Do you want another?
No, thank you.
- How's that, pal?
- Thanks, old Pop.
- Good night, pal.
- Good night, old Pop.
Is she dead?
Go to sleep.
Say, about that spot
at U.B.C.
If you're interested, I can
set up an appointment for you.
- You wouldn't mind?
- No, not in the least.
- Just let me know when.
- I'll call you.
Anytime you say.
[Speaking German]
Do you see those coats?
We'd better get back in the woods
and cross the road further south.
We gotta get
those coats, Hank.
Are you nuts? They got people all over
this place. Come on. Let's go.
I'm freezing to death.
- Danke schön, Fräulein.
- Danke schön.
How many do you see?
Two.
Well, if I don't get
that coat, I'm dead anyway.
Okay, let's get 'em.
[Speaking German]
[Metal Scraping]
Ahh.
Fritz?
- [Yells]
- [Grunts]
[Hank]
Where is your gun?
[Tom]
Behind the wall.
[Hank]
I'll get it.
[Chattering In German]
Come on. There's
more of them coming.
He's not dead. He made
some kind of a noise.
Finish him off then. Use your knife.
We gotta get out of here.
[Chattering In German]
Come on, Tom.
We gotta get out ofhere.
- [Hank] All right. Get out of the way.
- [Yells]
It's no use trying.
I just can't get used to it.
Used to what?
The idea of the Brooklyn Dodgers
as world champions.
My guys'll kill me.
I wonder how
we could not tell 'em.
When do we take off,
Captain?
It's all yours, el Capitán.
We take off any day,
starting one week from today.
We're all packed, Captain.
But it's not for home.
Are you kidding, sir?
It seems we got another
little war out in the Pacific...
and that's where
we're goin' next.
Pacific? So what's the navy
been doin' all this time?
They can't do that!
Look, I don't know anything
more about it than you do.
You know what us soldiers need
at a time like this, Captain?
A tiny little blast of vino.
[Driver Speaking Italian]
Un momento.
Wait a minute, honey.
Now you come right back here.
You understand?
We don't want to have to start
tearing this whole thing apart.
I will come back
to you, baby.
Is this the post
already?
Oh, now look, Captain. You don't want to
go back to the post feeling like that.
I got a little somethin' comin' down
here's gonna take your mind off all that.
- I, uh- I hope, anyway.
- I wanna go back to the post.
Look, Captain, we came out here
to have a celebration. You remember?
Now, we don't wanna go back to the post
feelin' worse off than when we came out, do we?
[Speaking Italian]
Hey, Captain.
Not bad, huh?
Shake hands
with Maria, Captain.
I wonder if I could interest you
in a proposition to be my widow?
Would you do something
very nice for me?
You have only
to name it, my dear.
Will you not talk like that
anymore tonight?
You're unwilling
to face facts.
After such a good dinner,
with wine and music...
and we are riding together
in the moonlight...
is that what we should
be talking about- death?
You would prefer, perhaps,
the subject of love?
Anything but death.
Very well then.
I love you.
You mean you
like me very much?
No, I said I loved you.
No, not love.
Not so quickly.
Why not? Is there some sort
of timetable on love in Italy?
No, but I only want something
I can believe tonight.
Like if you said
you liked me very much...
or that you thought
I was pretty...
something I can believe
for tonight anyway.
But not love.
Not in just one dinner.
I like you
very much, Maria.
You're more than pretty.
You're beautiful.
That's what's
so wonderful about night.
The later it gets,
the more beautiful I become.
[Driver Speaking Italian]
- Cuanto costa?
- Mille lire.
Mille lire?
[Arguing In Italian]
[Maria] Wait a minute.
[Shouting In Italian]
- Arrivederci.
- [Murmuring In Italian]
- Take off, Mac.
- Yeah, take off-a, Mac.
[Italian]
It's not a very pretty place,
I'm afraid.
And nothing works anymore.
I have a candle here.
Are you feeling all right?
Just thinking.
I may instruct my attorneys
to draw up a new will...
and leave my entire
estate to you.
That's no good.
It's too far away.
- Oh, no.
- Please. Please. You promised.
I'm sorry.
What I would like-
What?
Something to eat.
Again?
No, not tonight.
But if you could, perhaps,
give me some Spam.
- Spam?
- If you could.
You mean you want Spam?
I would like something
to eat tomorrow.
Who do you live with
here in this place?
Gina and Gina's mother.
- No men?
- They're all dead.
- What about your family?
- They're dead too.
Just you three women?
And Gina's little brother.
And they all like Spam?
Any kind of food
in tins or boxes.
Okay, let's go
get some right now.
Oh, no, not now.
But in the morning,
if you will.
How was it, Captain?
- He said the party is over, gentlemen.
- When?
Well, the plane's in already.
We're pulling out of here tomorrow.
- For home?
- You know where for.
Well, I guess we got
no beef coming, Captain.
I never heard of nobody else gettin'
six weeks of freedom, especially in Rome.
- You gonna tell Maria, sir?
- Of course. But alone, if you don't mind.
Captain, please! You think
I got no delicacy at all?
No offense intended.
It's just that Miss Montagne and I wish
to spend our last day together by ourselves.
Well, where do you think I was gonna tell
Gina good-bye? In the Coliseum?
Sir!
Come on. Get out of there.
I've finally got that jeep.
Ajeep? But it's
going to rain, isn't it?
Who cares? There's no law
against a picnic in the rain.
- Where's my sweater?
- Look behind the screen.
Oh, Tommy!
All right, boys.
Put it right down here.
But you brought so much
only last week.
Hurry back down
and get the rest.
Will you get in there
and get your clothes on?
You oughta see what
Gardella got for Gina.
I don't want
to sound stuffy...
but I think it's wrong
to liberate that much.
Where are we going?
Well, I can't tell you
because I don't know myself.
Let's make it a mystery
picnic, shall we?
We'll let the jeep decide
where we're gonna wind up.
Now, really, who could ask
for anything better than this?
Rain on the roof and a beautiful girl
to keep me warm.
Does this bother you?
It probably will,
but I don't object to that.
Nor that either.
- Can you sing?
- No, I'm sorry.
- You can drive, can't you?
- Yes, I can drive.
All right. You drive,
and I'll sing.
[Speaks Italian]
- Whoop.
- All right?
[Squeals, Laughs]
Did I step on your toe?
There's nothing like
a little singing in the rain.
Now, which would you prefer-
"Boola Boola"-
- "Boola Boola"?
- Or "I'm a Ramblin' Wreck From Georgia Tech"?
[Laughing]
I'm a ramblin' wreck
from Georgia Tech
And a hell of an engineer
A hell of a, hell of a hell of a, hell of a
hell of an engineer
Like all
jolly good fellows
I drink my whiskey clear
I'm a ramblin'wreck from Georgia Tech
and a hell of an engineer
This the last day, yes?
[Sighs]
Yes. We're leaving tomorrow.
I knew it.
Everybody I know
dies or leaves me.
I was going to tell you tonight.
The last night.
And then I'll never
see you again.
And you won't
remember for long.
- You know better than that.
- How long?
If you're asking that seriously, you still
don't know how much you mean to me.
But say it. How long?
As long as I live.
Even when you're
back with your wife?
I wish I could forget you.
It would be better.
But I know
I'll never be able to.
You don't still believe that...
when you get out to the Pacific-
- About being killed?
- You don't believe that anymore, do you?
No. I don't think
like that anymore.
I don't think anything
at all about the future.
Or the past either.
Just what's now, this minute.
And this minute, what?
It's a minute I wouldn't take
anything in the world for.
A warm fire, the wind
and the rain outside...
a good bottle of wine,
and I'm with you.
I don't think I could stand it if you went away
and I thought you hadn't loved me really.
It would be like taking
the light out of the room.
I wouldn't be able
to see anything anymore.
What will you
remember really?
This minute first.
- What else?
- You.
No, I mean
what other minutes?
The first minute
I ever saw you.
Not too clearly...
but enough.
Then the night...
when all of a sudden
I knew you meant it too.
And every minute
with you since then.
I was so Ionely then.
You have no idea.
You couldn't know what it was
to be as Ionely as I was.
But now I think I'll never
be Ionely again.
I think I'm going to have
someone of my own.
My child.
You're going to have a child?
Yes, I think so.
Do you want it?
I pray for it
morning and night.
- Even though-
- There is no "even though" about it.
I want my baby.
I want my baby
to hold and love...
and love me, I hope,
until I die.
[Train Door Opens]
Want me to set up
that appointment today?
- Why not?
- What time?
Well, noon would be
best for me.
Okay. I'll call Gordon Walker.
He's head of Public Relations.
I'll let you know
as soon as I find out.
Thanks very much.
I'll be in my office all morning.
[Horn Honking]
U.B.C. Legal
department, please.
- Express to 25.
- Thank you.
- U.B.C. Public Relations.
- Express to 36.
Thank you.
- How are you, Mr. Rath?
- Very well. Thank you.
- Sit here.
- Thank you.
Your friend Bill Hawthorne
gave you quite a buildup.
I remember when Bill first came with us,
about 10 years ago.
Bill started in
the radio department.
Then he moved up
to the 19th floor.
Then he went in to Copy.
Crazy, isn't it?
Looks very comfortable.
My doctor tells me
I need plenty of rest...
and this is one of the ways
I have of doing it.
Why do you want
to work for U.B.C.?
Well, for one thing,
I'd like to make more money.
Well, that's a wholesome,
refreshing approach.
Also I'd like to work
in a place...
where there's more opportunity for
advancement than there is at the Foundation.
- Can you write?
- Well, I do most of the writing at the Foundation-
reports to the trustees,
things of that sort.
Well, I tell you what
I want you to do then.
I want you to go
in that room there...
shut the door after you...
and write me your
autobiography in one hour-
everything you can think
about yourself in one hour.
Along any particular line?
Explain yourself for us.
Examine your life and tell us
just what kind of person you are...
and why we should hire you.
I'll try.
And at the end, I want you
to finish this sentence for me:
The most significant thing
about me is-
That's right.
It's now five minutes
of 12:00.
Try to have it finished
by 1:00.
The results, of course,
will be entirely confidential.
[Yawns]
[Airplane Droning]
All right, men...
we go on the green light.
Remember your assembly area-
northwest corner of the drop zone.
Your objective is the pass.
You take it and hold it till the ground
troops come up from the beach.
The light's on, sir.
Get ready!
Stand up!
Hook up.!
Let's go!
[Ordnance Exploding]
Come on, you guys!
Let's go, men! Let's go!
Hurry up! Let's go!
[Shells Incoming]
If we don't get those mortar positions,
we're dead ducks.
All right. Let's go.
All right, you guys!
Spread out!
[Tom] Right up there
on the left. Pillbox.
Dive behind that tree
and let go.
Now!
Two of you,
take that pillbox and hold it!
Those guys
are First Platoon men.
I wonder where Hank is.
Give me some smoke.
All right, cover us!
Could be among those
rocks somewhere.
Cover me.
- Look out, Hank!
- Huh?
In front of you!
Go get him.
I'll cover you.
Hank!
- Medic!
It's all right, boy.
I'll get you some help.
We'll be there soon, boy.
Somebody get a medic.!
How do ya like that?
Medic.
I want you to take a look
at this man. Quick!
Put him over there.
This man's dead, Captain.
He's not dead!
Take another look at him!
I'll put him
over there, Captain.
Don't you touch him!
I'll find a real doctor!
Hey, fellas,
come here a minute.
You'd better take a rest, Captain.
That man is dead.
Not till the doctor says so. I'm gonna
have a real doctor take a look at him.
You better let him go, Doc. Try to stop him,
and somebody's gonna get hurt.
Can I help you, Captain?
I want a medic.
Well, there's a hospital
boat coming in now.
Maybe you better let me carry him a little piece.
You look kind of beat to me.
Oh, that's all right.
I'll take him.
No, you better let me,
Captain.
Say, this man's dead,
He's not dead!
You're right, Captain. We ain't gonna
take nobody's word for it...
till the doctor says so.
We're not gonna put him
with the dead.
No, sirree, we ain't. We're gonna lay him
right down here by your side...
so you can look after him
your own self...
till we can find out what's
the best thing to do about it.
Will you watch over him
while I go get somebody?
Will you do that for me, Captain?
That's a good captain.
Now, you sit right here and look after
your friend like he'd want you to...
and I'll go get us the best
doctor they got down there...
just so as we'll be
good and sure.
Thank you, Sergeant.
And, uh, get yourself a little
rest too, all right, Captain?
[Airplane Droning]
[Droning Fades]
Okay, Bill.
I'll send you a memo on it.
Already?
- Is this all?
- That's all.
But you've still
got 12 minutes.
I've written all
I think is necessary.
"The most significant
thing about me...
"so far as the United Broadcasting
Corporation is concerned...
"is that I am applying for a position
in its public relations department...
"and after a reasonable
period of learning...
"I believe I could do
a good job.
"I will be glad to answer
any other questions...
"relevant to this
application for employment...
"but after giving it
serious thought...
"I am unable
to convince myself...
"that any further speculation
on my importance...
"could be of any legitimate
interest or value...
to the United
Broadcasting Corporation."
Anything else?
No. We'll call you
when we decide anything.
Good-bye.
Thank you.
- Good-bye.
- [Door Closes]
[Train Brakes Hiss]
Bill Hawthorne told me about
an opening at U.B.C. Yesterday.
I went over to see them
about it this afternoon.
I'm awfully sorry
about last night, darling.
Maybe I had it
coming to me.
What's the matter
with us, Tommy? Is it me?
There's nothing
the matter with us.
We don't want to make too much
out of a little blow-off do we?
We ought to be
pretty happy really.
Your job's
plenty good enough.
We've got three nice kids,
and we love each other.
- Must be the house.
- Yeah. [Chuckles]
How much will
that new job pay?
I don't know.
Maybe eight or 10,000.
- You know what I think would be nice?
- Now, just a minute there...
- I haven't got this job yet.
- I know, but when you get it.
A trip somewhere together.
Wouldn't you like that?
If it works out that way. Maybe that
little shack in Vermont I was telling you about.
I think I'll call the agency tomorrow
about that day woman to take care of the kids.
Now look, honey.
Let's not pack our bags yet.
Not until it's a little more than
a possibility anyway.
But forgetting the money
for the moment...
you know what
I'd like really?
- What?
- All I'd like really...
is to do something-
I don't care what-
that would
make you, well...
a little proud
of me, that's all.
Well, I don't know what U.B.C. Wanted,
but that's significant enough for me.
- If you told them that-
- [TV: Gunshots]
Can you beat that?
All right, upstairs. Oh, Petey,
you know better than this.
- Turn that thing off, will you?
- [Man On TV] Fire!
Didn't you hear what
your mother said?
They ever have
but that one picture?
[Betsy]
Tommy.
Just a minute.
What I don't understand is why he doesn't
let you handle the job as usual.
Or why he insists on going
outside the organization for somebody.
- Is it possible he doesn't trust us anymore?
- [Intercom Buzzes]
- Yeah?
- [Woman] Mr. Thomas Rath.
Send him in.
- How are you, Tom?
- Good morning.
Bill Ogden,
Mr. Hopkins's assistant.
- How do you do, Mr. Ogden.
- Very well, thanks.
Mr. Hopkins was quite impressed by
the tone of your application.
- Ralph Hopkins?
- That's right. Ever meet him?
No. I never have, but I've heard
a lot about him, of course.
To put you in the picture here,
I'll let Ralph fill it in for you...
this is a personal project of his.
Something he's giving his own personal
attention to: Mental health.
Yes?
Some kind of a national campaign,
but he'll tell you about it himself.
- Hmm. Ralph?
- Good morning, Gordon.
We have Thomas Rath here
with us, Ralph...
and we were wondering when
it would be convenient for you to see us.
Come on up, now. I'll be through
with this in just a minute or two.
It's up a little. Not much. Nothing to worry about.
And your heart sounds pretty good.
I'm certainly glad
to hear that.
But you've had a warning,
and, if only to satisfy my own conscience...
I've got to tell you again,
you've got to slow down.
I've been getting
plenty of rest.
You oughta cut way down on your schedule.
Sleep a little later.
Come into the office around 10:30,
11:00 in the morning.
Get away around 3:00 or 4:00.
And cut out these outside activities of yours.
Not, of course, that I expect you to pay
the slightest attention to what I say.
But I will. I promise you. Thanks so much
for coming right in the middle of your day.
- Not at all, sir. Good-bye.
- Good-bye, Doctor.
[Woman]
Yes, sir.
Will you ask Mr. Rath, Mr. Walker
and Mr. Ogden to come in, please?
Yes, sir.
- Good morning, fellas.
- Ralph.
- Mr. Rath.
- Mr. Hopkins.
This is awfully good of you.
I know how busy you must be.
- How are you, Gordon?
- Fine. Thank you, Ralph.
- How about that cold, Bill?
- It's better now, thanks.
Oh, that's good. I was worried about you.
Really sounded quite bad.
- Could you have lunch with us, Mr. Rath?
- I'd be happy to.
That's wonderful. I have so many
engagements this afternoon.
- Haysey?
- Yes, sir.
- We're going in for lunch.
- Can you take a call from Mrs. Hopkins first?
- Hold it for just a moment will you?
- Yes, sir.
- Will you fellas go on in?
I'll join you in five minutes.
- Of course, sir.
I'm terribly sorry, Mr. Rath.
It's just one of those things, you know?
It's quite all right, sir.
I'm sorry, dear.
How are you?
Can you come out today? I've got to talk
to you right away about Susan.
- What about her?
- Many things really.
But she's just informed me that she has
no intention of going to college...
and l-I just don't know
what to do about her anymore.
I'll be there this evening,
if that'll be convenient for you.
- Don't fail me, Ralph. Please.
- I won't, dear.
Don't worry too much.
I'm sure we can straighten it out.
- I'll be looking for you.
- [Line Disconnects]
Did you know that more hospital beds
are occupied by the mentally ill...
than all the cancer, heart and polio
cases put together?
No. I didn't know
it was that bad.
I never dreamed it was that bad
until I talked to those doctors.
That's a very good idea about
the research endowment. What else?
Well, what about backing
legislation...
to get more state and federal funds
for mental hospitals?
- Yes, that could be done too.
- And then on the local level...
you might look into the organization
of community clinics...
psychiatric clinics,
sort of preventive measures.
- How?
- "How" what?
How could we organize
community clinics?
I can't answer that
this minute.
You've got to remember I just
heard about this thing an hour ago.
But I'd certainly look into
the possibility of local clinics.
- I think we should too.
- Very good idea.
It's a little too early, actually,
to spell out any of these ideas in detail.
Oh, dear. I'm afraid I'm going to have to
ask you gentlemen to excuse me.
I have a very important
engagement.
Mr. Rath, I can't tell you how much
I appreciate your coming.
It's been a genuine pleasure,
as well as very useful indeed.
I hope we'll be able to see each other
again soon. Good-bye.
- Good-bye, sir.
- Wait here, please.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Clears Throat]
This wouldn't be a very high-paying job,
you understand?
Well, what kind
would it be?
The figure we had in mind
was something around 7,000.
Well, that's no good.
That's what I'm getting now.
I know.
What did you have in mind?
The job, as I see it,
should be worth at least $10,000.
I'm afraid that's
out of the question.
So is 7,000,
as far as I'm concerned.
We don't like to quibble
over things like this.
We feel that if a man
really wants to work for U.B. C...
it shouldn't
be necessary.
Well, that's strictly
up to you, of course...
but you can hardly expect me to switch jobs
purely for the pleasure of working for U.B.C.
Well, not that anything
can be decided now anyhow.
We just wanted to get a line
on the way you were thinking.
That's all right.
I'm in no hurry.
We'll call you then.
Thank you very much.
I wouldn't count too heavily
on anything, you understand?
There's nothing very definite
about any part of this idea.
I understand.
Thanks for the lunch.
[Door Opens, Closes]
What do you figure, eight?
Nine, I imagine.
Strictly a split-the-difference man.
[Engine Off]
- Yes?
- I'm Mr. Hopkins.
Oh. Excuse me, sir.
- How long have you been here?
- About two months, sir.
- Will you tell Mrs. Hopkins I'm here?
- Yes, sir.
[Clears Throat]
Hello, dear.
You are really
a wonder.
I'm terribly worried.
- Will you have a drink?
- No, thank you.
When did you
last see Susan?
About a month ago.
She's becoming
a real beauty, isn't she?
Have you any idea of the kind of life
that she's leading these days at 18?
- No. But I'm sure-
- She lives in nightclubs.
Well, at 18, don't all rather
well-to-do girls go through that stage?
She's not rather well-to-do,
she's very rich.
And she's your daughter
with your name.
She's a celebrity
in that filthy crowd.
I can't tell you how-
how unattractive it is in her.
- A celebrity.
- And the men she goes with.
Never a boy of her own age
or of-of what should be her crowd.
The man she spends most of her time
with now, he's-he's older than I am.
- Who is he?
- Byron Holgate his name is.
He's an old leftover
from the Scott Fitzgerald era...
still marrying
and divorcing women.
- A pure horror.
- He's notorious. He's a public fool.
Even the gossip columnists
know that.
What can she be thinking of,
running around with a clown like that?
I hate to say this...
but I think that what she's thinking of
with him is marriage.
I couldn't believe that for one second.
It's just unthinkable.
The other one is a writer...
45 years old, three children
and a wife he doesn't live with.
He took her to the opening of
one of his plays on Broadway last week...
and an all-night party afterwards,
waiting for the reviews to come out.
- At 18.
- What's his name?
- Patterson. Michael Patterson.
- I know him too.
That can't have been a very merry party
when they read those reviews.
- Why do you let her go out with such people?
- How can I stop her?
- I can't lock her in her room.
- Have you had a really serious talk with her?
Well, of course. "Mother," she says,
"don't be medieval."
- And that- [Sighs]
- "And that" what?
And that who am I to offer advice when
my own marriage has been a failure.
- Well, that's hardly the whole truth.
- That's not the point now.
The point is that I can't do anything
with her anymore.
Apparently, we'll have to get
a little tough with her.
I'll have a talk with
her right away.
Not just a little talk, Ralph,
and then forget the whole thing.
You've got to do something.
This is the time for you to make up
for all the things you've never done before.
She was such
a darling little girl.
Both she and Bobby
were so good, so sweet.
They were
wonderful kids.
You never really knew Bobby,
not really.
He had genuine character.
Always held high grades in college.
Never got himself into trouble.
He could've had a commission,
but he turned it down...
enlisted, because he thought
that was the right thing to do.
- Did you ever know that?
- Well, of course, darling.
He wasn't
a complete stranger to me.
I just had lunch with a young man who
reminded me of him.
Same eyes and mouth.
Same kind of smile.
Oh, but Susan has me licked,
and I'm asking you to help me.
I haven't done that in...
many years.