[dramatic music plays]
>> That's gonna be pretty
upsetting for him.
No one's ever dared
to go in there.
You think that's gonna
cause a ruckus?
[dramatic sounds]
[baby crying]
[speaking foreign language]
>> Careful.
>> Get over here!
Mike Boettcher: What is that?
>> R.P.G.
Camera Man: R.P.G.?
>> Oh my god.
>> That thing is straight out
of China, like, yesterday.
>> Yeah.
Mike: How could they
get out of China?
>> Yeah. That thing's
brand spanking new.
>> I'm down here, on
Objective Richmond,
and, uh, first platoon can't
get to the first
series of building.
They keep finding
more ammunition.
They keep finding more
mortar fuses.
They keep finding more stuff.
>> I don't know what it is.
It's a rifle. Bolt
action of some sort.
Mike: What does that look like?
>> Six to seven R.P.G.'s,
probably eight mortars,
a couple box of fuses...
>> Definitely an indicator that
we caught them by surprise.
Break.
[suspenseful sounds]
>> Hey, Zee?
>> What's up?
>> Give me eyes on that
bridge at your eleven.
[explosions]
[rapid gunfire]
>> Get down around here now!
Get something in front of you!
>> Fuck!
[gunfire continues]
>> Roger. We're shooting.
We've got contact up on the
hill for our fucking --
[explosion]
[voice over radio]
>> Break, break, break, break.
Holding six, moving three six.
>> Yeah. Roger. Where are you
getting fire from?
What target?
[indistinct radio chatter]
[explosions continue]
>> I got shot...
>> Bostic's shot!
[muted voices]
[dramatic sounds]
[airport announcement]
Mike: My name is
Mike Boettcher.
For the past thirty-four years,
my job has given me a front
row seat to history.
As a war correspondent,
it's taken me to some of the
worst places on the planet.
[dramatic music plays]
Everything that I have achieved
in my career has come at a high
price. It cost me my
relationship with my
family and my son. I've
missed Christmases,
birthdays, graduations...
[chuckles]
You name it. So
when it was time
for me to re-embed with U.S.
Troops in
Afghanistan, my son, Carlos,
decided he was coming, with
or without my permission. He
said, "I need to know why you
chose your work over us." As
much as I wanted to
say no, I realized this could
be my last chance
to reconnect with my son. So
off we went... together,
father and son. The
only trick was...
we had to come out of
there alive.
[dramatic sounds]
[rock music plays]
[helicopter whirs]
[helicopter passing]
>> Looks like they attached two
different wires to try
and make an I.D., maybe
stretch out the wire
so they could get further away
from us, when they
detonate, gives themself a
better chance to get away.
>> For power? Where
does it go to?
>> Right into the house.
>> Well, I know, uh, I know in
his house. I can see that.
I meant, when it goes in here.
Where is it
getting the power from?
[inaudible response]
>> Hey, Gould, Gould!
[indistinct radio chatter]
[natives chattering]
Camera Man: What were
you saying again?
[radio chatter]
>> He's next to the vehicle.
Why?
>> So you're a good luck charm?
>> Whoa!
>> Whoa! Son of a bitch!
>> Yeah, still warm,
still warm.
>> Yeah, we got a bunch of
these that we were just shot
at by the enemy from that
hillside. This is
a Dishka round, uh,
little over twelve
millimeter diameter, round,
very deadly when it hits you.
[dramatic music plays]
[gunfire]
Chris Fields: And
then watch me.
Hey, I'll either go up, left,
right, or back.
[gunfire]
>> He's still too low!
>> Oh, nice. Good shot.
>> One person injured.
>> They are reporting
everything's okay right now.
>> Good.
>> It's not gonna be okay.
They don't, they don't know
what's about to hit 'em.
[radio chatter]
>> Roger that. I need to go
tothe left of that.
There's a rat drill on the
left side of that.
Give me, uh, three shots
rightthere for right now,
so we're gonna you
right on her.
[gunfire]
[jet passes overhead]
>> Yeah! Good hit!
[dramatic music plays]
[explosion]
>> Whoa, baby!
>> Two-zero-seven, dark
knightfour-two.
It's good bombs, good bombs.
>> There's a false
bravado involved.
They see us. They've been
watching us for awhile.
They're moving in position.
They don't think we
can harm them.
Uh, they just haven't
fought us yet.
[dramatic music plays]
>> How close were those
bullets coming to you?
You were close enough to hear
the bzzzz go by, huh?
>> Gunfire buzzes when it's
close enough to you.
It sounds like a bee passing
over your shoulder,
and that's when we knew that
things were serious.
[country song plays]
[helicopter whirs]
>> Steve Lutsky,
Colonel Lutsky.
Lutsky was this character who
was larger than life.
He lived to be out front.
[soldiers chanting]
Colonel Steve Lutsky: I expect
these guys to risk their
lives to get the mission done.
I mean, mission comes first.
I can't ask them to do
something that I
wouldn't do myself.
Now, that's not saying that
I'mlooking for a fight,
but I can't sit in a
truck and say,
"Hey, I want you to go
risk your life."
>> It was a fight to stay alive
when you were with
Steve Lutsky,
because he was going to be at
that pointy end of the spear.
And sure enough, we were.
>> Tag two, tag one, over.
They saw three,
uh, possible insurgents.
They went us to head
southwest along the ridge.
Over.
[voice over radio]
>> They were regressing
straight south from
that location.
Staying in that low land ridge,
they're probably
hiding somewhere out there,
behind the rock
the rock line, break.
>> The problem was, the Taliban
found us before we found them.
[clattering]
[soldiers yelling]
[heartbeat sounds]
>> I'm up here
[unintelligible]!
[dramatic sounds]
>> The problem is, he had no
idea where they were
firing from. The Soviets call
them "Ghosts," and they
were. I mean, you couldn't...
They were there. They were
somewhere, and they were
shooting at us.
You couldn't see them.
[soldiers yelling indistinctly]
[heavy breathing]
[gunfire]
>> Yeah.
Snipers firing from us,
in the tree line
over there. Snipers
firing at us from the
tree line just over there,
behind some
cover, but not much.
[dramatic sounds]
>> They want us to go up.
>> Okay, okay.
[indistinct yelling]
>> Okay, I'm going.
Here we go.
[dramatic music plays]
[rocks sliding]
Shit.
[breathing heavily]
[gunfire]
>> Carlos!
Carlos!
[grunts]
Carlos!!
>> I had no idea if he
was alive or not.
I wasn't a reporter then. I
was being a pop.
[solemn music plays]
And the one thing I could not
let happen was...
was to let my son die.
Mike: Carlos!
Carlos!
[breathing heavily]
[gunfire]
Carlos!
Mike: What the hell
were you thinking?
I told you, don't
leave my side.
This is a damn war zone,
Carlos.
You okay? Well, you were
covering me, as well, right?
>> Roger. Yes.
To the best of my ability,
I was.
>> I thought you did pretty
goodat covering me.
[chuckles]
>> Thanks.
>> Hey, by the way,
their aim sucks.
>> Okay, ambushes along the
road are one of many
reasons construction's
taken so long,
with mountainside... Fuck.
I fucked up.
[background chatter]
Ambushes along the road are one
of many reasons construction's
taken so long, with the
mountainside providing
no cover, and insurgents
offering no quarter.
>> All right. That was good.
>> Any suggestions?
>> We're getting ready to
clearthat ridge line.
Uh, at least one of
them got hit.
Uh, we saw him go down, so
we're gonna check
for bullet trails and, uh, see
if we can find him.
A.W.T. has nothing on
him right now.
[dramatic percussion]
>> You all right?
>> These are the first houses
that they would bring him to.
Mike: The guy who's wounded?
>> Yeah.
[background chatter]
>> Hear any of the shooting?
[speaking arabic]
Translator: Yeah, we
heard the fighting.
>> One of them was wounded,
so you may
have them come down and cometo
your house for help.
I understand, Polesh and Wally,
that you're going to help them.
Did they come to your house?
[speaking arabic]
Translator: He says you can
search, uh, the houses.
>> Oh, they already are.
They're up there
searching right now.
[speaking arabic]
[dramatic sounds]
>> Watch your head.
>> What the hell is this?
>> I, I don't think you're
Taliban, but I think you
turn the other way when
Taliban come through.
>> We had to arrest the
insurgents and tell them
they're not welcome here.
'Cause I want your
children to be safe. I want
you to be safe too.
[speaking arabic]
[voice over radio]
>> I need a roger.
>> Yeah, we're in route at this
time. A, uh, actually
developed this situation for
what we need, we
need to know when you think we
should come in from the
south, and do it right past,
past the way, north. Over.
>> Six four, roger.
>> That'll be six-four-six.
[radio chatter continues]
[explosions]
[screaming]
>> Go, go, go, go!
[baby crying]
>> The American convey was
traveling this direction.
The other way,
civilian vehicles.
They slowed down when the
convey passed.
So did a suicide bomber,
and inside his car,
he has six hundred pounds of
high explosives.
[dramatic music plays]
Rhyss Heeter: After we
realized what happened,
we pushed out of
the blast zone.
I got out of the truck. We
realized it was a "vee-bid."
[explosions]
There was a lady off to the
side, next to a, uh, kalat,
and uh, she was screaming that
her kids were dead.
I started calling for the
medic over the radio,
and we just started treating
them, did everything we could.
Mike: Private Richter, how long
you been in the Army?
Paxton Richter: Uh, exactly a
year, sir. That was the first
actual, uh, trauma casualty
I'd... in my care, sir.
[solemn music plays]
>> And, uh, it didn't
need to happen.
[helicopters overhead]
[music continues]
[muted voices]
[engine whirring]
>> One-oh-one over sixty,
pulse seventy-two.
One two saturation was one
hundred percent.
>> I looked at the eyes of the
medics, and you could see it.
They weren't gonna let him die.
[melancholy music continues]
>> The name of the child?
We were more
concerned about
saving his leg than
getting his name.
>> The family has a
patient over here.
>> How's he doing?
>> Doing okay. He's
supposed to be going,
hopefully, to the O.R. today.
>> Going back to the O.R.
today?
>> I'm very happy that
he kept his leg.
We go out of our way
to make sure
people like Sadich
don't get hurt.
Mike: In the end, does it
change Afghanistan?
Probably not, but it saved
that kid's life,
and maybe that kid will change
Afghanistan someday.
>> Get well. We'll see you.
I got a son, Jake, who's
ten years old.
Mike: Can you imagine?
>> No.
Mike: Did it sink into you that
you had saved a child's life?
>> It did, but uh, that's,
that's what I'm here.
That's why all these guys that
are out here do what they do.
It's 'cause they
just wanna help.
>> Afterwards, ground
unit came up by and
thanked us, and that was
probably the biggest
reward, uh, that I've ever had,
is having the
ground unit come by and
say thank you.
>> This all-woman crew who put
any men I've known to shame.
I call it, you know, the band
of sisters and a
little brother.
>> We just consider ourselves
just soldiers, like, like
everyone else, and to us, it's
really not a big deal.
>> The countdown to hugs and
kisses, and this is Chloe.
She's so cute!
I'm a mom. I understand how
every other mom feels,
and if I was in her shoes, that
I'd want those people
to help my son or daughter out
as much as possible.
[dramatic sounds]
[speaking arabic]
>> Kids are the ones that
usually give all
the good information.
Taliban do the same
thing, from what
we've experienced.
They'll usually go tell the
kids where they
put in an I.E.D. The kids
seem to be the, uh,
the best guys to utilize
for references.
[speaking arabic]
>> I talked to some kids
here on scene.
They confirm Taliban had
placed an I.E.D.
here about, uh,
forty-eight hours ago.
>> The villages are the ones
that actually came to us,
and, and A.U.P. and
reportedthis I.E.D.
In my mind, I mean, that's
a very positive
step. Seems like they're
starting to kind of, you
know, support the government
a little bit more.
[dramatic percussion]
[indistinct background chatter]
>> Naw, I love doing this.
Mike: Really?
>> Yep.
>> Why?
>> 'Cause right now, my job
is to help protect
these guys, make sure they
don't get hurt.
[ominous sounds]
>> Yep, got the pressure plate.
>> Hey, they found the
pressure plate.
>> Pressure plates on
both sides and
a power source for each
pressure plate.
>> Yep.
>> Wire running off to the
side. There's a little hole
dug right there, with the wires
running down into it.
>> It's about twelve to
fourteen inches in diameter.
>> In this area, we haven't
seen charges that big.
It would have done
some damage too.
>> Yeah, it's pretty, it's a
pretty large charge.
But uh, we've definitely
located, uh, one
pressure plate at this time.
Uh, exploiting
with the robot.
Front line traced to the
pressure plate, Victor
Bravo seven-eight- one-niner,
plate.
[dramatic sounds]
[sirens wailing]
>> Holy hell.
Mike: How much you
think was in there?
>> Forty to fifty pounds. I'd
say probably closer
to the fifty pound range.
>> Tell all the kids
that they need to
stay away from that area,
'cause
there still could be some
stuff out there.
They're doing a lot more
patrolling around this area,
and they'll continue to focus
specifically around this area,
now that we know that bad guys
are putting I.E.D.s.
[dramatic sounds]
Mike: My intent is for us to
get in there, and
then get out of there
in one piece.
>> Yeah.
[sighs]
Well, my, my intent is always,
is also to
get out of there in one piece,
so.
>> But let's not do anything
fucking stupid, huh?
We have a mission tonight,
from here,
past those mountains,
into the always
dangerous river valley.
>> I believe in each and
every one of you,
and I love each and
every one of you.
You're the most precious
resource that America has.
Trust in your brothers,
dedicate yourself to
American battalion
and our mission.
Your measure is not
found in how
much time you have
on this earth.
It's what you do with the
time that you've had.
These people have
suffered for too
long. Change the
course of history
in Afghanistan.
[wind howling]
[dramatic music plays]
Mike: We had marched
for days with the
Marines. It was summer,
and it was hot.
One hundred thirty degrees.
Unbelievable.
And we did it all carrying more
than eighty pounds
of gear on our back. We ran
out of everything.
We ran out of food. We
ran out of water.
Mike: And then, we got,
finally, to the location that
we're supposed to capture.
This could be Gulf Company's
new home. They're
looking for headquarters to
establish their
presence down here, and we're
going in to check.
It's been eerily quiet. We
haven't had a bullet
fired at us in over
twelve hours.
[indistinct yelling]
[middle eastern music plays]
>> This is it!
>> Okay, let's get a
team up there.
>> Next team, coming up!
[indistinct radio chatter]
>> Roger. Fox One is clearing
the area right now.
[dramatic music plays]
>> Go! Go!
Hot, hot!
[explosions]
>> Go! Let's go, go, go, go!
[explosions continue]
[indistinct radio chatter]
Go, go, go, go!
>> Oh my god.
Mike: What is this here?
>> This is, uh, nitrate to, uh,
make I.E.D.s.
>> And this is pure heroine
down here, you said?
Mike: So what do we have here?
>> Walled compounds like this
one fill Helmand Province,
providing valuable cover for
Taliban, and for Marines.
>> Marines say the objective of
this mission was met -
to plant their presence here
and to make a statement to
the Taliban that the Marines
are not leaving.
Mike: We knew that we'd
accomplished our mission,
and I was up all night
feeding stories back to
ABC. I was exhausted.
Everyone was.
And the Marine commander said,
"We gotta go
another ten miles."
[dramatic music plays]
There is a squad that's
surrounded. Someone
else has to go, and Carlos
came to me, as I was
suiting up, and said, "Pop,
if you do
this, you're gonna die." I
was just too tired.
He said, "I'll go. Not you."
[chuckles]
That's my son... saying he'll
go in place of me.
And he went, and I stayed.
>> Hey, do I got any
friendlies over there?
>> Right or left?
>> Uh, go left of the compound.
Keep going
all the way over. You
got the dude in
the white turban that
keeps looking at us?
>> Yeah.
>> Naw, it's
definitely not them.
>> All right.
>> Set south, southwest.
Carlos: While movement
through the fields
and canals is slow, every step
the Marines take is
one closer to securing peace
in Helmand Province.
>> Here at Camp Koshtay,
the work
continues. The Marines are
now in the position
of setting up this base, in the
heart of this town
called Koshtay, which was a
Taliban stronghold.
Mike: There's a copper wire.
Where is it?
Oh, yes. And it's running up to
that compound there.
A patrol this morning
found an I.E.D.
We're walking towards it. They
cut the command wire,
which is a wire that runs to a
device that would trigger
the bomb. Hopefully, that is
the only command wire.
Voice over radio: Command,
three two.
Mike: When you enlisted,
you didn't
ask for this job, did you?
>> Negative.
[engines humming]
Mike: The villagers did not
come. The Taliban
did not attack. But the
question now is - where
is the Taliban?
[dramatic percussion]
>> Stand by!
>> Hey, we got two people, six
hundred meters away
from us, moving southeast.
[indistinct chatter]
[distant gunfire]
>> Hey!
>> Yeah?
[indistinct yelling]
>> Fuck!
[gunfire continues]
>> Huh?
>> Hey, what is he
talking about?
Send your traffic, O.P. Rock.
>> I got pan left.
>> Shoot him, dammit!
[gun fires]
[dramatic percussion]
>> I shot that motherfucker
that walked by the compound
down there. I don't know if I
fucking hit him or not.
Saw him running with a fucking
A.K. in his hand.
I don't know if I fucking hit
that son of a bitch.
>> Shoot him!
[gunfire continues]
>> Hey, guns and
[unintelligible]! Let's go, go!
>> I hit that son of a bitch.
>> Go!
[clattering]
>> Did you see those fuckers?
[indistinct chatter]
[dramatic music plays]
Mike: Just last night, the
platoons of Gulf Company
Two-Eight Marines were
attacked by small arms
fire eleven times, uh,
resulting in two concussions.
It was very lucky that, uh,
there were no major
casualties, or no deaths on
this march south here.
Mike Boettcher for Nightline,
Camp Koshtay, Afghanistan.
[dramatic percussion]
>> Stand by!
>> What's up?
>> We got smoke.
>> Look straight down the road
here is where everyone is.
[indistinct chatter]
>> Hey, one, twos, move in!
[music swells]
[gunfire]
>> Open it up!
>> Okay, let's go.
>> Let's go, let's go!
[breathing heavily]
[gunfire continues]
>> Hey, let's go!
[voice over radio]
>> We're taking fire!
We're taking fire!
Mike: All I heard on the radio
was that they were in trouble,
and he was surrounded, and
there were Taliban all around,
and they were taking
fire constantly.
[breathing heavily]
[gunfire continues]
[indistinct yelling]
>> Start suppressing! Let's use
suppress across the way.
>> Good luck!
>> Let's go, let's go!
[gunfire continues]
>> Over there! [inaudible]
[indistinct yelling]
[screaming]
>> Gill!
[ominous music plays]
>> I had no idea what
was happening.
I felt completely helpless. I
didn't know what to do.
I thought I'd never see
my son again.
[gunfire]
[inaudible yelling]
[canon fires]
>> Yeah!
[cheers]
>> Go, go! Hey, let's go!
>> Let's go, dudes!
>> Yeah, more smoke, bro!
>> Fuck yeah, brother!
>> Hell, yeah.
[cheers]
>> Hey, let's go. We're up,
bro.
Mike: Being reunited with
Carlos after that... to see
him alive... was the best damn
thing I've ever seen. The best.
[dramatic music plays]
>> Initially, I was scared
going into it. We heard
that there was gonna be
gunfire directed at us,
all the way down, and so
there was, but after
the first few explosions, after
the initial contact, after
the initial rat-tat-tat of the
A.K.-47s coming at
us, uh, the adrenaline almost
fades and you being to
grow, if not numb,
then used to it.
Mike: Carlos grew up real fast,
and I was so proud of him.
My time is almost over, and
now it's Carlos's
turn, and I believe my son is
going to be a better
storyteller than I ever was.
It's his turn.
Diane Sawyer: We want you
to meet two people
who are unlike any other, the
only team of journalists
to embed for one solid year, on
the front lines, with
the troops here, and not only
that - they're father and son.
They are Mike and
Carlos Boettcher.
>> And about twelve
minutes into it, I was
just dying. I was just, my
whole, it was like
the thing where your whole
body overheats,
and I started to feel like
asthmatic, which, probably
'cause I smoke too much, but it
was just way too much.
>> Yeah, yeah, you gotta...
See, my joints
have a limited shelf life,
so that's why
you don't see me
hitting the gym.
>> Yeah, true.
[chuckling]
[dramatic music plays]
Mike: Carlos's time was up,
and after everything
we'd experienced here, it
was going to be
tough to watch him go back to
the States without me.
You wake up every morning,
facing death,
and you cherish every
moment you're with
the people you're with, and
here I was, with
my son, and ironically, in a
war zone, we reconnected.
It was worth the risk to be
a father again.
[helicopter whirs]
But, I think, deep down,
as afather,
I was relieved that Carlos
was headed home,
because I knew where we
weregoing next
was one of the worst places
you could go in
Afghanistan. It was the
heart of darkness.
[dramatic sounds]
Tye Reedy: Q.Z.R.
controls the entire
northern part of our
area of operation.
He controls, uh, the fighters,
the
equipment, uh, the training,
everything.
He's our number one target.
It's an
extremely important mission.
>> Now, you're gonna have a lot
of young, inexperienced
fighters, who want to go to toe
to toe with an American,
and they'll get their ass
handed to them, because
they don't know what
they're doing.
They just graduated that
[unintelligible],
so they've been instilled
with that bullshit
extremist philosophy. They
don't know any better.
Let 'em come to you. Let
'em come to you.
>> We can't just air strike
them. It would do no good
to kill him or our enemy, along
with civilians, so
we have to go in, put
boots on the ground,
and root these guys out.
Matthew Mendez: As a leader,
you have to, as my
son calls it, manning up, so...
that's what, that's what I did.
>> This is gonna be the final
nail in the coffin against
this asshole. He's going down.
His abilities to
fight in the future are gonna
be extremely degraded. We're
gonna create a lot of good
things for the people
that don't have the reach of
security forces or
governments as a result of
this. That's all I got.
[all respond unintelligibly]
Kevin Mott: I don't
think anybody was
necessarily prepared for
exactly what it
was gonna be like,
but some of us
had the worst in mind,
mentally prepared
that way, so we wouldn't have
any surprises.
[dramatic sounds]
Mike: After almost dying,
why would you
wanna come back to
this hellhole?
[sighs]
>> I think it was... a personal
thing, on a level that,
you know, I wasn't gonna let
these guys beat me.
[dramatic music plays]
I've been through quite a
few fire fights.
I'm not different than
anybody else.
I wanted to get back, get
back in the fight,
whether it be sitting in this
three shop, you know,
doing paperwork or whatever, I
wanted to come back.
[music swells]
[helicopter whirring]
[ominous sounds]
Mike: We landed at three
in the morning,
and all of us were tense.
>> Now, based off the map, it
looked like there was a,
a trail that we could
have taken to head.
Pretty sure it does not
exist at all.
It just some trickery the
imagery showed.
>> I'm glad we waited til
daybreak to actually move,
because somebody would
have actually
broke their leg or, or worse.
[dramatic music plays]
[speaking arabic]
>> Hey, Ramone, take
the low trail!
>> Going through the kalats,
uh, you can tell,
men, men did live there. They
just weren't there,
and the, uh, excuse they gave
of that they were,
um, day workers in Jalalabad,
you know,
is completely ridiculous.
[dramatic sounds]
[speaking arabic]
>> Hey, Zee?
>> What's up?
>> Give me eyes on that
bridge at your eleven.
[explosions]
[gunfire]
>> That shit sounds like it's
right in front of us.
>> Yeah, it does.
[gun firing repeatedly]
>> We have landed in the
hornet's nest.
>> Stay down. Stay
behind Jim Coper.
>> This was command and
controls for the Taliban,
right there in that valley.
[gunfire continues]
[indistinct yelling]
And they were gonna
make us pay.
[speaking arabic]
[middle eastern music plays]
[gunfire continues]
>> Hey, we gotta start getting
them in this fucking kalat.
Can we get the fucking sixties
up on this fucking hilltop?
>> Yeah, they're working
on it right now.
>> All right, this is, this
is them right here,
above phase line white,
this is us
down here, the grid
liner section.
>> Okay.
>> They're righthere.
They got packs
moving up and down
this ridge line,
generally east of them.
[indistinct chatter]
[gunfire continues]
>> They're there! I
saw 'em moving!
>> Fizzo?
>> Yeah?
>> Make shit start blowing up!
[aircraft overhead]
>> R.P.G. seven!
>> Oh, shit!
[explosion]
[muted sounds]
Mike: In this muddy, friggin'
hillside, we were surrounded,
and I thought, "What's it
gonna feel like when
the bullet comes through me?"
[dramatic sounds]
[gunfire continues]
[indistinct voice over radio]
>> Go ahead, one-six Romeo.
[voice over radio]
>> Six-three-six, stand by.
[bullets whizzing by]
>> Three pads, two urgent,
one priority.
>> Break, break, break, break!
>> Yankee, Delta, zero, four,
niner, three, eight,
six, five, four, one, three,
zero.
Mike: I was sitting
there on this
mountainside, hearing their
radio calls come in.
[indistinct radio chatter]
"We need choppers now. These
guys are gonna die."
>> Roger.
[indistinct radio chatter]
>> Dammit. I need
that Medevac now.
>> And you knew... choppers
weren't coming.
>> Tell them, "Hey, the bird's
coming, the bird's coming,
just hang in there. The
bird's coming."
After awhile, you...
the person saying
it is getting tired and
under-sure, and the
person hearing it is getting
tired and under-sure.
>> Star cluster?
[sighs]
[dramatic sounds]
>> There he is!
[helicopter approaching]
>> Medevac's inbound?
>> Yeah. They're in the valley.
>> Hell, yeah!
[cheering]
>> You pull in, turn sideways,
and...
ding, ding, ding, ding, ding.
You just get lit up.
[gunfire]
>> Made multiple attempts,
until the
bird was, you know, it
was damaged so
bad, it actually had
to go and land
for immediate maintenance.
[dramatic music plays]
>> Fuck! Dammit!
>> A kick in the balls,
more than anything.
As soon as we got 'em here,
we just lost 'em
again. Um... So we had
to wait again.
>> It was a very low moment,
because you knew...
nothing could get there to you.
You were on your own.
>> It went through everybody's
mind that, you know...
this might be the day. This,
this might be the day.
Mike: You don't know who you
are, how far you will
go, until that moment,
when you know
someone is dying, and if you
don't get there,
they're going to die, and you
may die trying to save them.
And that's what these
soldiers did.
>> Hey, tell 'em, tell 'em I
want a gun run from
fucking west to east, running
up this spur here.
>> Arrechaga and the lead
section had already started
moving, roughly twenty
minutes before.
It probably took a couple
minutes before,
uh, they got ambushed. The
insurgents that
were attacking certain
Arrechaga realized
that they had caught 'em
in a bad spot.
[explosion]
[gunfire]
[missile whizzes]
[dramatic percussion]
>> In the draw. Hey, they're
in the draw, Meyers.
>> Roger, sir. Nine-five-nine-
th hr re ee e, hey,
we got eyes on 'em in the
draw now. Over.
>> Hey! We'll provide coverage
fire. You guys come to me!
[gunfire]
>> Cease fire!
[indistinct radio chatter]
>> What's that?
>> What I heard was, uh,
A.C.'s down. My
men need help. It
just clicked into
my head. It was like
muscle memory.
You just run, you
just run to them.
>> Hey, Wade, get ready!
>> Ready, sir!
>> All right, let's get moving.
>> Let's go, let's go!
[gunfire]
[dramatic music plays]
Mike: In the middle of this
battle, Specialist Lindskog,
this timid young man
who you wouldn't
expect would do
anything heroic,
runs through a hail of gunfire,
to try to save
his fellow soldiers and
another Afghan soldier.
>> Let's go, let's go!
[gunfire]
>> Move!
>> Go!
>> Move, move, move, move,
move!
[explosion]
[dramatic music plays]
Kellis Richardson: As soon
as I said, "Let's
go," he grabbed his bag and
took off running.
He didn't ask a
single question.
He just grabbed his bag and
stayed right behind me.
>> I looked back and I saw
him grab his, his,
his, uh, his side. He
was our medic.
>> Lindskog was
coherent enough to
talk to Sizemore and tell
him,"Hey do this
for thay guy, do this
for that guy."
>> He wanted to do
everything he could
to give us medical advice,
while he
was hit, on how to treat him.
>> He treated three people in,
like,
a matter of ten minutes.
>> Oh, he was fully alert.
He talked,
up until the point he passed,
uh, actually
apologized for not being
able to hang on.
>> When he was sitting there
bleeding out, he
apologized... for dying.
>> Go ahead, three-six.
[gunfire in background]
>> Roger.
[sighs]
>> How do you process that?
As a reporter with a camera...
[dramatic music plays]
You don't.
[gunfire]
>> Fucker!
[voice over radio]
>> Roger, we don't know...
>> Give me this radio. Get
it on battalion.
>> When we gun it, a
three hundred and
sixty degree fire fight,
coming down on our
current position. You
should have it, right?
>> Fuck, dude!
>> I tried to let you know as,
soon as I saw it.
>> Okay, listen up. Prepare
to copy, all right?
I got two urgent surgicals.
They're
at building one-three-zero.
[gunfire]
[muted sounds]
>> I could tell by A.C.'s tone
of voice that, uh... I'm, I'm
pretty sure he didn't think he
was gonna make it out of there.
[dramatic music plays]
>> Looked to A.C. like, "A.C.,
this is gonna hurt."
At that point, he was like,
"I don't care. I'll
take the pain. I just wanna
get out of here."
[helicopter whirring]
>> He actually, you know, did
us the big A.C. smile.
>> Couldn't explain, in words,
how I felt...
After helping them out, having
to run down there,
all that effort... and
you know, the only
thing that I could
question myself,
which I try not to do,
is I could
have ran faster, you know.
>> Watch it!
[indistinct yelling]
[gunfire]
>> Go, go, go, go!
Go, man!
>> Shit.
>> You okay?
>> It's definitely exposed.
>> Get back.
>> Come on. Get
farther in there.
>> Hey, go in the
fucking doors.
>> Hey, Kent!
>> Loaded, sir.
>> He's right here.
>> All right, breathe.
Who else was with us?
>> Albright.
>> Albright, right here.
>> Albright?
So...
>> Two, three, four, five...
>> Hey, where's,
where's Meyers?
>> He, he, he
didn't make it up.
>> Hey, Meyers! Meyers!
[middle eastern music plays]
Brit Jacobs: This is
Strong Eagle Three.
Got up to our over watch
position. Uh, wasn't...
wasn't that easy,
uh, this time, as,
as it has been
in other operations.
>> He actually had to fix his
boot. His shoelace
was busted, so we were just
joking around a little bit.
>> Let's talk about the
seven layers of hell.
>> Yeah. Right here
in Afghanistan.
>> Well, I think we're at about
layer four or five now.
[chuckles]
>> I heard, like, a couple
Afghanis talking, like,
really quiet, just a
couple whispers,
and they were right in
the trees above
us, and I asked
Sergeant Burgess,
like, we don't have no A and A
right next to us, right?
And he said, "No," and soon as,
soon as he said no...
I heard, I heard 'em flip
their, flip their weapon
to fire, and started
opening up on us.
[gunfire]
[dramatic sounds]
>> I'm looking at the trees,
just, you know...
They're literally in
the trees firing
down at us. What is,
what kind of
crazy crap is that?
>> I started shooting up in
the trees, 'cause
they were directly above us,
and
it was all pretty much
chaos from there.
[bullet whizzes]
Eric Matheson: We made
a plan to get
the hell out of there, and,
and make sure
we radioed it forward
to the rest of
the element, which we did,
and we
all got up out of there,
and unbeknownst to
us, the gun team stayed behind,
including
Smith, Mark Gonzalez, uh,
Jeremy Faulkner...
[gunfire]
[indistinct yelling]
>> Go, man!
>> That's when Jeremy was, uh,
shot and killed.
>> We can't fucking move,
and we're
waiting on this stuff -- Hey!
[indistinct yelling
Bryan Smith: I heard my
buddies saying
that they were hit.
>> I heard the radio go on,
and I heard
someone kind of whimpering.
No one
told me that there
were casualties.
I knew, because of
that whimpering.
>> Dusty Feldhaus, he
was hit at least
five times.
>> ...and he was apologizing as
if, you know, he had
something to, to apologize for.
I mean, naw, don't...
you know, "I'm sorry." What
are you sorry for?
So... you're a freaking hero.
We love you.
>> Yep. Yeah.
>> We miss you.
Bryan Burgess: My
daughter is Makayah.
She turns four next month. My,
my son
is Xander. He turns
three in January.
>> Cool. You miss 'em?
>> I do.
>> How much?
>> A lot.
[dramatic music plays]
[singing indistinctly]
>> All right, Feldhaus, show
us how to fight.
[indistinct chatter
and laughter]
>> They're dying.
And they're fighting, not for
some war on terror.
They're fighting for
their buddies.
Mike: What kept you going?
>> The rest of these guys.
>> We all kind of saw it in us
to, to, to try to
be strong, if, if not for us,
for, at
least, you know, the
guy beside us.
>> I stayed there, even though,
I should...
my, my instinct was to get the
hell out of there,
but I stayed there for all my
guys, my squad, my,
my platoon, stayed there
for the bastards.
>> They're sacrifices are not
going to be forgotten.
>> Got, um, hoisted out,
and that was,
that was good, all
three of them.
Continue getting
[unintelligible] to traffic.
We found a bunch of enemy
weapons, enemy I.D.s, so...
found the radio station.
[aircraft overhead]
>> John, what, what are you
cooking there, dude?
[sizzling]
>> Um, I'm cooking up, uh,
paratha.
[speaking arabic in background]
>> What? Paratha?
>> Yeah. Paratha.
>> Paratha.
[laughter]
>> Yeah. Paratha.
>> Paratha.
Looks good.
>> Inshallah.
[laughter]
>> You want some, Jim?
>> Yeah.
>> Yo!
>> Don't listen to Hoosa.
>> Hoosa had one whole bread,
man.
>> Hoosa had, he
already had his own.
[indistinct chatter]
Kellis Richardson: As a leader,
you gotta put it
out of your mind
and keep going,
and keep moving on
for the guys,
so they don't, uh, they
don't get all
tripped out and stuff, so...
just keep going.
>> Sure was.
[goat bleets]
>> So what is the goat
saying there?
>> The goat's named Roman.
>> Roman?
>> Yeah, Roman.
[laughter]
And, uh, this is a gift
for Captain Maud.
[indistinct chatter]
[chicks chirping]
Mike: Is that your new friend?
>> It is my new friend.
>> What are you gonna --
>> I'm gonna name him... Pep.
You okay, Pep? How are you?
Go back to your mama. Go
back to your mother.
>> Ooh!
>> First fly! You got it
on camera! Good.
>> Yay!
[laughter]
[exclaims]
[birds squawking]
[laughter]
You have a problem with a
fucking chicken.
[laughter]
>> The chicken flew
up here and he
just made him, like, reject it.
>> Damn.
[laughter]
>> Like, I've never seen
someone just up that
fast in my life.
[all laughing]
[indistinct chatter]
>> It was a rough day.
>> Sure was.
>> How do you think
today's gonna go?
>> Hopefully, better than
it was yesterday.
[dramatic music plays]
[indistinct yelling]
[canons firing]
[cheers]
>> This went on for nine days.
[gunfire]
[indistinct yelling]
>> Hey, we got forty-five
seconds til a bomb drop.
[unintelligible chatter]
[yelling in arabic]
>> Motherfuckers.
[helicopter whirs]
>> Six-four, roger.
[gunfire]
[yelling in arabic]
[crashing]
>> Take that! Yeah!
[soldiers cheering]
Yes!
>> I don't think they
liked our bombs.
>> I don't think
they did either.
Mike: Do you know
why you've done
this for twenty-two years?
>> Sir, I do not know why
I've done it for
twenty-two years. I've just,
I've enjoyed it, and I've
just kept doing it and... As
long as I can stay
healthy and keep doing it, I'm
gonna keep doing it.
>> I can't see myself
doing anything else.
>> Yeah.
>> Even after a
mission like this.
[helicopter whirring]
>> I think that we made a
huge difference here,
that we reduced the
insurgent credibility
here. We went right in
their back yard,
right in their home town, and,
and succeeded.
>> It's hard to tell
families that their
sacrifice quantifiably
made a difference,
'cause they're ten
thousand miles away,
and you're trying to
explain that to 'em,
and their husband,
their father, their
son is, is, is, uh, is
not coming home.
[dramatic sounds]
[helicopter whirring]
[announcement over speaker]
>> Attention!
[soldiers respond indistinctly]
>> Staff Sergeant Sizemore is
also receiving a second
bronze star Medal of Valor for
Operation Strong Eagle Three.
["The Star Spangled Banner"
plays]
>> To those fought beside us,
this is the
time to reflect on how we can
best carry their memory
forward, and ensure their
sacrifice is for a greater
good, and that we'll never let
their memory fade.
>> It was hard. I knew all
of them, and as
a task force commander, it's
very difficult to, to
know that the orders you gave
for combat cost us.
>> They gave their life for
what they believed in and
for their buddies. It's our
responsibility to
remember their courage, their
commitment, and their heroism.
>> Every soldier in No
Slack knows that
if that time comes,
that the honor and
respect is bestowed on them,
for their
ultimate sacrifice will
always be met.
>> Sound off for roll call!
Sergeant Mendez?
>> Here, Sir Major.
>> Sergeant Trickendaus?
>> Specialist Lindskog?
Specialist Jameson L. Lindskog?
[dramatic music plays]
>> Lindskog was a young guy.
You know,
who knows what he could have
brought to the world.
>> Cary Fruthers, as he,
himself, needed
urgent care. This is
heroism defined.
>> Sergeant First
Class Arrechaga?
Sergeant First Class
Ofren Arrechaga.
>> He was the rock for the
platoon. He was the,
uh, humor. He was always the,
the happy
guy. He always had a
smile on his face.
>> These bonds are so
close that...
you're not gonna leave
somebody out there to
get shot or die by themselves.
You're
gonna run out there
and help them,
no matter what.
>> Staff Sergeant
Frank Adamski.
Staff Sergeant Frank E.
Adamski.
>> Sergeant Adamski was a
husband, father,
a squad leader, and
my best friend.
>> Staff Sergeant
Bryan Burgess.
Staff Sergeant Bryan A.
Burgess.
>> The last thing Sergeant
Burgess said to
me was, uh, "Where's my
chariot?" He was
talking about the Medevac bird.
About the sixty that was
hovering above us.
"Where's my chariot?"
And I said, "It's right here."
>> Specialist Dustin Feldhaus.
Specialist Dustin J. Feldhaus.
>> We went through thick
and thin together,
and though I am sad that
he's gone, I'll
always cherish the memories
that I have shared with him.
I love you, Mouse. Rest in
peace, brother.
>> P.F.C, Jeremy Faulkner.
P.F.C. Jeremy P. Faulkner.
>> With such a famous last
name, I told him he should
live up to it. He
gave back to me,
and no kidding, he told me,
quote,
"I'm gonna make history, sir,
not write about it."
>> You'll always be remembered,
and
you'll always be loved by
all the bastards.
Rest in peace, Remy.
[yells command]
[guns firing]
>> It becomes, uh, to a point,
that it gets to be enough.
[yells command]
>> All these men, his men,
dead.
He didn't know the
camera was rolling.
He hung back the whole time.
When
no one else was around, he
walked up, and he
let the tears of this entire
war come out, right there.
And I could do nothing...
but cry, myself.
[solemn music plays]
You sit down and you
come to grips with
your life. But you have
to realize that
what you've done is
something important.
And you hope you've left
something behind.
We only do this to make
a difference.
That's why you constantly
keep going back,
keep fighting, keep trying to
tell these stories.
Otherwise, my whole life's
been for nothing.
You know something? It's
been for something.
It has.
[uplifting music plays]
>> I think I have an I.E.D.
on you.
We'll have to dig and find out.
>>Dude.
[children chattering]
[laughter]
>> Is she still following me?
>> Yep.
[speaking arabic]
Good luck with that tractor.
>> Hey, buddy. How you doing?
High, high five. There you go!
Fist bump! No fist bump?
>> No.
>> Oh. I'm hurt.
[speaks arabic]
[makes whooshing sound]
>> Mott, hold the tea cup up
and said, "America."
>> "America."
[laughter]
[rock music plays]
>> Yeah! Whoo!
[children chattering]
Mike: What do you miss most
about home on Fourth of July?
>> Spending time
with my family.
But I have my new family here,
so I'll spend quality
time with my new family.
To everybody
back home, I miss you
and I love you.
>> What kind of message
would you wanna give
Americans about what you've
been doing here,
and on this Fourth of July?
>> I'd say, uh, to support the
troops. It's, uh, it's
pretty tough, being out here.
>> We're so blessed with what
we have back in the States,
and I just hope everyone
remembers that back home.
>> Puts a different perspective
on what it means to
be American.
["Chariots" plays]