I hope you enjoy
the hat, Mr. Stovall.
- And a pleasant voyage home to you.
- Well, thank you.
I'd like to thank you
for something else too.
Back home, I'd buy
a hat in five minutes.
- Thank you for a most enjoyable
hour and 40 minutes.
- It was a pleasure.
- Come back soon, Mr. Stovall.
- Good-bye, sir.
[No Audible Dialog]
- Where did you get this?
- An auction at Archbury, sir.
- I'll take it.
- That one's been
knocked around a bit, sir.
- I have a fine Staffordshire here...
- No, no, no. I'll take this one.
- How much?
- Only ten shillings, sir.
- I'm afraid it's not much value...
- Value? I want you
to pack it carefully.
Very carefully.
As you say, sir.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
[Men Singing]
Anyone else but me
No, no, no don't sit
under the apple tree
With anyone else but me
Till I come marching home
Bless them all
Bless the long
and the short and the tall
Bless all the blondies
and all the brunettes
For each lad is happy
to take what he gets
[Continues, Indistinct]
The long the short
and the tall
We're poor little lambs
Who have lost our way
Baa, baa, baa
We're little black sheep
Who have gone astray
Baa, baa, baa
[Engine Sputters]
[Engine Starting]
[Coughing]
We can't go back.
We mustn't go back.
- Easy with his right leg. It's broken.
- I got it. I got it.
Easy now, easy now.
You have to hold him.
I've been
sitting on him.
We can't. We just can't.
I wouldn't believe it if I wasn't
looking at it. You can see his brain.
It was a 20 millimeter
that hit him.
Step on it, Doc.
- What do I do with an arm, sir?
- An arm? Whose arm?
- Campbell's, the turret gunner's.
- What happened to the rest of him?
He's in a French hospital... I hope.
He couldn't have made it home.
It was blown off too close to put on
a tourniquet so I bailed him out.
I put the ring in his good hand.
The chute opened.
That's all right.
I'll take care of it.
- Sergeant, get me a blanket
out of that ambulance.
- Yes, sir.
Come on.
I'll give you boys a lift.
- Hospital, Mac.
- Yes, sir.
Mac's had it.
Did you get the coordinates on a Fort
and a Spitfire down in the Channel?
I've already passed them
to Air Sea Rescue, sir.
That's it, gentlemen.
Thanks a lot.
Next crew.
- Take this one.
- Next crew.
Come on, Jesse.
- McKesson's crew.
- Right.
- McKesson coming?
- McKesson's dead.
Oh, I didn't know. I'm sorry.
Well, we might as well
get this out of the way.
Sit down.
Where did you first
encounter enemy action?
- Bishop.
- Leave him alone.
He's had enough today.
Leave him alone,
can't you?
What is it, Willie?
I don't know, sir.
Not all of it.
We got hit pretty bad
the first pass the F.W. S made.
That was when Mac got it.
It took the back
of his head right off.
Only he didn't pass out.
It just made a crazy man out of him.
He was still shouting orders...
and trying to get the controls
away from Jesse when I got
up there two hours later.
The kid had been
flying with one hand...
and trying to get the controls
away from Mac with the other.
Wiping frozen blood
off the windshield so he could see.
For two hours, sir.
He made a good bombing run too.
We unloaded on the target.
Didn't you know he was in trouble?
Why didn't somebody
get Mac out of there?
The intercom was shot out
and I thought it was
violent evasive action.
For two hours?
Mac's foot was jammed
in the controls and...
that's how we broke his leg
trying to get it out of there.
That seemed
to hurtJesse worst of all.
He started shaking and I...
I sat on Mac and held him...
whileJesse brought us in.
Give me a copy of that, Fred,
just the way he told it.
I'm sending it in with
a recommendation for a Medal of Honor.
- Jesse will be okay.
I'll drop by later and see him.
- Thank you, sir.
- That's enough for this crew.
- That's all, gentlemen. Thank you.
Next crew. Next crew.
[Men's Chorus On Radio]
Is he in there, Harvey?
No, he hasn't been in since
right after interrogation.
He looked like the devil.
Well, who wouldn't with today?
That's for you, Ben.
They're flying down
three replacement aircraft.
Hmm. That's very,
very nice of them.
Lose five, get three.
That's a nice gain, not
counting battle damage.
[Man On Radio]
This is Germany calling.
Lord Haw-Haw,
talking from Berlin.
Today I want to bring a special
greeting from the fiighter
pilots of the Luftwaffe...
to the first American pilots
in England, the Eighth Air Force.
That's all we need. Our submarines
checked you very carefully...
when you flew across from America...
four groups in place so far.
Too bad about the ones
who you lost on the way.
But we wanted to let you know...
that a U-boat picked up the crew
and they're quite safe here.
We found them quite
agreeably talkative too.
But what we want to know...
Whoever persuaded you to try this
incredible idea of daylight bombing?
It must have been
your friends, the English.
They know better
than to try it themselves.
Losses are a little
heavy, aren't they?
- Let's take the 918th group
at Archbury, for instance.
- That's us.
The hard-luck group. You lost
fiive bombers today, didn't you?
Five out of the one group.
Let's see, 21 in a group?
At that rate, it won't
take very long, will it?
Something pleasant to think about
before your mission tomorrow.
Yes, Colonel Keith Davenport.
You'll have another one tomorrow.
Pleasant dreams,
my misguided friends.
I don't know why
we listen to him.
It's always the same pitch...
we've already lost the war.
On a day like this, I could
find myself believing him.
What was today's
count on crews?
Five crews didn't make it back.
Three killed, 11 wounded
out of those who did.
A lot of letters to write.
I'm glad I don't have that one.
- Did you hear about Lord Haw-Haw?
- Twice on the way over here.
That kind of news moves fast.
Don't let a Kraut newshound
throw you too much.
He was right about one thing.
We're alerted for tomorrow.
The warning just came down.
- Again tomorrow? You're kidding, Ben.
- I wish I were, sir.
Fine, fine.
Four days in a row.
Well, we'd better start
getting things together.
- Alert the crews and I'll
see you in the ops room.
- Yes, sir.
- This will make you happy.
Flak City again.
- St. Nazaire?
It's either a feast or a famine.
Chew your nails off for three
weeks waiting on the weather...
and then cram a month's
bombing into four days.
Must be an easier way
to run a war.
Field order's snafued too.
It says here 9,000 feet.
That's a mistake. I'm sure they mean
19,000. I'll check with Savage.
Another maximum effort.
What have you got
in the way of weather?
Give us some fog, can't you?
I wish I could, but the target area
ought to be C.A.V.U.
About three tenths cloud cover
over the Channel. Ideal almost.
- You're no good to me. Let me
know if there's any change.
- Yes, sir.
How many airplanes
have we got left?
With the three new ones and
working the crews all night,
Nero thinks we can have 18.
- How many are the other
groups putting up?
- Twenty-one a piece, sir.
We'd better camp
on Nero's tail.
No, if he says 18, he's giving us
everything with wings on it.
What did the other
groups lose today?
Two in the 916th,
zero in the others.
Our stinking luck. Those flak
gunners had the range good
by the time we made our run.
- What about crews, Doc?
- I could give you a couple
of different answers, sir.
I'd better get started
on routes and timings.
- No coffee, Ben?
- Oh, not now, thanks.
That's getting to be your diet,
isn't it? That and cigarettes?
How long since you've
had your clothes off?
Never mind my pants,
what about crews?
You're crew, when it comes to my
certifying you for a mission.
There's the crew availability.
Colonel, about the route and timing
of tomorrow's mission?
Start on the routes. But I wouldn't
figure on that 9,000-foot altitude...
- until Colonel Davenport
checks with Pinetree.
- Yes, sir.
Thanks for worrying
about me, Doc, only don't.
What about the rest of them?
That brings us
to the two answers.
On that list are 28 men
asking to be excused
from tomorrow's mission,
three times more
than normal.
They give a lot of reasons,
colds mostly, and most of them
haven't got colds.
And that doesn't mean that
they've suddenly gone yellow.
It just means that they're
getting their bellies full.
Now, do I okay them physically
and mark them "duty"?
How much can a man take?
What's physical and what isn't?
The rules say a man ought
to go right up to the point
where he may endanger his crew.
I wish I knew what that meant.
If I did, I'd tell you.
Well, can you tell me this...
do I okay Bishop for tomorrow?
He had a tough deal.
Jesse's a tough boy.
How tough? What happened today
must have done something to him inside.
It had to have
cost him something.
Somebody's got to give me
a policy, some kind of yardstick.
I wish you'd tell me
what a "maximum effort" means.
Doc, I wish I knew.
I wish I could answer that one.
[Phone Rings]
Hello. Yes.
Hello, Pinetree. All right.
Frank, Keith Davenport.
Yeah. Yeah, I heard it.
Look, Frank, I didn't call up
to talk about Lord Haw-Haw.
What about that cockeyed field order
that came down that said 9,000?
What? Oh, you're kidding.
Yeah, but the strike photos don't show
what the flak is like in there.
Listen, are you gonna
be there a little while?
All right. I'll be right up.
They meant 9,000. Maybe when I get back
I can give you an answer, Doc.
No, no mistake.
It's 9,000.
Well, we've got to try it.
We're not getting hits
on those sub-pens.
Yeah, I know. Then twist it.
Had the same request all day.
So long, Curt.
The Wailing Wall is just
around the corner, Keith.
Oh, I don't know.
I guess this is it. Sit down.
If you're on the level
about this 9,000 foot stuff,
the boys will drop their bombs
here tomorrow instead of St. Nazaire.
- Look, Frank...
- It won't work. It was tough at
19,000 it'll be suicide at nine.
The guy who dreamed this one up
ought to have his brain
in a glass jar at Harvard.
- Anything else?
- You're kidding?
You've been a group commander.
You didn't lead the first
ten missions for nothing.
- Why couldn't you tell them
what it'll be like? You...
- Keith.
I signed the field order.
Why? That's what
I want to know.
All right, I'll
spell it for you.
We haven't been penetrating
the concrete in those sub-pens, Keith.
We can't get concentration
and accuracy from 19,000.
We've got to go in once
down low to see if we can
get the job done in one trip...
instead of fighting our way
to the target five times
and back for nothing.
Nine thousand feet.
Let's allow from here in that
when the old man cuts a field
order, he's thought about it.
There isn't time to take every one
of them apart to see what makes it tick.
If I were you, when I got one,
I'd just go ahead and fly it.
I was gonna bring these
down to you tomorrow.
I had to steal them
from the RAF.
Hope they're
the kind you wanted.
Yeah.
Yeah, thanks, Frank.
I won't need them at 9,000
though. It'll be plenty hot.
Well, I better get on back
and get the chores done.
Stay put a minute
now you're here.
Thought I might run
down tomorrow to see you.
How many you expect to put out?
Eighteen.
- Pretty bad luck today?
- Not good.
We had one break through
the runway at takeoff.
That threw us late.
We never made it up.
It cost us plenty.
I don't know how anybody
outguesses that one.
No.
I'd like to help you locate
where the trouble does lie, if I could.
What about your formation?
I can tell you where the real trouble
is, Frank. And it isn't formation.
- Shoot.
- It isn't down in the groups either.
It's up here, where a bunch of boys
get to be nothing but a set of numbers.
That's what's the trouble.
Do they know up here what my boys have
been taking for three days in a row?
That they'll be up all night
to get 18 in the air for tomorrow?
How much do you think they can take?
You know they're falling
asleep at briefing?
- Are you gonna drive them
till they crack?
- Take it easy, Keith.
Take it easy?
Bomber Command can take it easy.
Those boys are flesh and blood.
They'll die for you, but they've
got to have a chance and they
know they haven't got one.
Frank, they can add. They know
a man's chances run out in 15 missions.
Somebody's gotta give them a limit,
a goal, some hope of living.
What do you think
they're made of?
- Look, Keith.
- [Buzzes]
- Yes, sir?
- I just got the reports from
the groups. Come on up, Frank.
I'll be there in a minute, sir.
Those things are coming, Keith.
Replacements, combat limits.
But right now
the deal is to hang on.
And look, Keith, you've got to find
a way to save yourself a little.
You can't carry
all the load. It's too big.
Don't worry about me.
If you want something to worry
about, worry about the crews.
You and the old man.
You better go on up and see him.
- Give him my love.
- If I do, he'll send you his.
He rates you pretty high.
Not according to Lord Haw-Haw.
Good night, Frank.
Never mind the reasons.
There it is and you can't
make anything else out of it.
Five missing today and they'll
only put up 18 tomorrow.
- It's getting worse instead of better.
- Yes, sir.
I've just been talking to Keith.
He's low enough about it.
What really happened today?
Did he tell you?
No, I didn't dig into it.
He had tomorrow ahead of him.
What do you make of it?
Hard luck, I guess. There's always
some outfit that picks up a jinx.
You don't believe that.
Fill yourself a drink.
Thanks.
It might scare off
that bug of yours.
I don't believe in hard luck.
There's always a reason.
What have you got on your mind,
Frank? Spill it.
I'd rather not.
Let's have it
with the bark on.
You won't like it. I don't.
It's the group commander.
Keith?
It's always the group commander.
It's his job, isn't it?
A little funny, coming from you.
He's your friend.
I didn't ask you
to ask me.
- I didn't mean it
to sound like that, Frank.
- It's okay.
I don't believe it though.
I don't think I do.
On paper, Keith looked to me like
the best group commander we've had.
He's flown every mission. He gets more
loyalty out of his men than anybody.
Courage, he works hard.
I don't know where to fault him.
If a man like that can't
cut it, we're in trouble.
- What happened downstairs
to change the picture for you?
- Nothing.
Added this to it though.
He's gonna bust wide open.
And he's gonna do it to himself too.
Why? Because he's
a first-rate guy.
Because those are his boys and he's
thinking about them instead of missions.
Over-identification
with his men.
I think that's
what they call it.
And you aren't going
to change it either.
I can't buy it, Frank.
Not yet anyway.
Is Keith still here?
No, he had tomorrow
to get ready for.
I'll give you that much,
we'd better find out.
If it's true, we're in trouble.
Why should the other groups hold
together if the 918th can't?
Call my car, will you, Frank,
while I get my pants on.
You mean you want me
to go down there with you?
You bet I do.
It's your idea.
We were three minutes late
on the target and got most of it
here on our bombing run.
That was a deadly
three minutes, Keith.
The idea was to get all the groups
over the target simultaneously...
so that enemy flak couldn't
concentrate on any one group.
We sure were sitting ducks
out there alone. Maybe I
shouldn't have tried the target.
But we were there and
I figured the boys wouldn't want
to bring their loads back home.
No man makes a perfect plan.
You couldn't foresee a plane
breaking through the runway.
Maybe the mistake lay in not
going on to the secondary
target once you were late.
But I figured we could make up the time,
catch up with the other groups.
- We could have too if it hadn't
been for our stinking luck.
- Luck? What luck was that?
- It wasn't luck, sir. It was my fault.
- It wasn't anybody's fault.
- I'd like to hear
the lieutenant's version.
- Yes, sir.
We had to alter
the navigation in flight, sir,
to cross the enemy coast here.
We picked up an error...
wind change.
And I missed a checkpoint
here at St. Lo.
By the time I had caught it,
here at Rennes,
it had cost us three minutes
and we never made it up.
If there's any fault, it's mine.
I was in command. I ordered
the change in flight plan.
- The weather was thick enough.
Could have happened to anyone.
- Well, I think that covers it.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Thank you, gentlemen.
- Zimmy.
- Yes, sir.
It's okay.
Don't worry about a thing.
Keith, I know you're tired,
but let's talk a little.
Sit down.
Let's talk about luck.
A pretty critical
three minutes, Keith.
- Five crews, 50 men.
- Do you think I don't know?
- I know you do.
Whose fault was it, Keith?
- Primarily it was mine.
- Were you flying?
- Yes, sir.
- Do you fly and navigate or
do you rely on your navigator?
- You have to, but...
- It was the lieutenant's fault.
- He missed the check point, but
it could've happened to anyone.
I know and I'll allow
he feels as rotten about it
as any of us do, more so maybe.
But what happens now, Keith?
I don't understand you, sir.
We're talking about luck.
I don't believe in it.
I believe that to some degree
a man makes his own luck.
Yours has been pretty bad down here
and it's getting worse, not better.
Maybe the navigator's in point.
He blew it. What are you going
to do about it?
General, I don't believe in chopping off
heads because of one mistake.
Well, I just don't think
that's any way to run a group.
I feel sorry
for the boy, Keith.
But what are the men in your
group going to be thinking about
the next mission he navigates?
That he messed up
the St. Nazaire mission.
It's just that much more load
on them. And one day, if they
fall apart, that won't be luck.
There isn't a man in the outfit
who wouldn't stake his life on Zimmy.
General, if it was anyone
but him. He's got two strikes
against him to begin with.
You don't realize. That boy's
got a persecution complex.
He wants to fly every mission
trying to live down the fact...
that his parents were mixed up
in the German-American Bund.
They screened Zimmy plenty
before he ever got overseas.
That's what's riding him now.
Keith, good navigators
is the one thing we're not short of.
If you decide that you ought
to relieve this boy, I'll
give you a good replacement.
You might as well ask me
to stand him up against the wall
and shoot him in the back.
No, I won't do it, sir. I just
can't do it to him. I won't.
Keith, I want you
to get to bed.
Have the flight surgeon give you a shot
that will make you sleep 24 hours.
I guess a man only has so much to give
and I guess you've given it.
Effective now, you are
relieved of this command...
and you will report to me
for duty at Bomber Command.
I'll send someone down
to take over here.
- Good night, Keith.
- Good night, sir.
Major, the 918th will stand down
until a new commanding officer arrives.
Yes, sir.
[Door Shuts]
- Want me to take it, sir?
- No.
I want to talk, Frank.
There's a hole in the dike, Frank.
I'm scared stiff.
Maybe you know how deep
all this goes, and maybe you don't.
I've got to spill it anyhow.
We're fighting
all over the world.
Every theater commander
is screaming for crews and equipment.
Fifty thousand airplanes, that's
what they say they're building.
I wish we had 500.
Our problem right now
narrows down to one group.
If the 918th folds, it can spread
to the other three groups.
It can fold the whole deal.
There's only one hope
of shortening this war...
daylight precision bombing.
If we fold, daylight
bombing is done with.
I don't know. Maybe
it means the whole show.
We could lose the war
if we don't knock out German industry.
You can smell
what's coming, Frank.
I'm promising you nothing except
a job no man should have to do
who's had his share of combat.
I've gotta ask you
to take nice kids and fly them
until they can't take anymore.
And then put them back in
and fly them some more.
We've got to find out
what a maximum effort is.
How much a man can take
and get it all.
[Sighs] I don't even know
if any man can do it.
That's what cracked Keith.
What time do you think you can
get down there tomorrow?
Early, I guess.
No squawks?
Pretty hard to have one,
the way you put it.
Thanks, Frank.
- Smoke, Ernie?
- Thank you, sir.
- All right, Sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
- Do you know me, soldier?
- No, sir.
- Then why are you
admitting me to this station?
- I saw it was a staff car, sir.
Goering could have been in it.
- Here's my A.G.O. Card.
- The general may proceed, sir.
Soldier, this is
a military post, not a zoo.
From now on, you'll check everyone
who enters and without exception.
Take a good look at me.
If you or any man on this post
passes me up without saluting
even if I'm a block away,
you'll wonder what fell on you.
- You might pass that word around.
- Yes, sir.
- Locate my quarters
and drop my bags off.
- Yes, sir.
- Good luck, sir.
- Thanks, Ernie.
[Man Humming, Typing]
- [Whistling]
- How do I address you?
I don't think
I quite understand the general, sir.
What's your rank?
How am I supposed to know?
Sergeant McIllhenny, sir,
U.S. Army Air Forces.
It's Private McIllhenny now.
Where's the air exec?
I... I don't think he's
on the station, sir.
He left right after
Lieutenant Zimmerman's funeral.
- Zimmerman?
- Yes, sir. Navigator, sir.
- And what happened to him?
- Suicide, sir.
- Where's the ground exec?
- In the hospital, sir, mumps.
- And the adjutant?
- I think maybe Major Stovall's
at the officer's club, sir.
When you get your clothes on, find him
and ask him to report to me here.
Yes, sir.
[Knock On Door]
Major Stovall, sir,
Group Adjutant.
- Yes, I remember you, Major.
You the only one around?
- Probably, sir.
- I presume you've come down
to take over the group.
- That's right.
- Have you been drinking, Major?
- I have.
It's the first time
I've been drunk in 20 years,
but it may not be the last.
- Where's the air exec?
- I don't know, sir.
It's only an opinion, but I think
it's possible he may be drunk too, sir.
- I'll take straight answers,
Major. Is he off the station?
- Yes, sir.
- Where?
- I don't know that, sir.
Send the M.P. S out and find him
and bring him to me under arrest.
- Does the general mean
under actual arrest?
- Exactly.
Two... cancel all
leaves and passes...
and make sure that all squadron
commanders are back here by tonight.
Three... bring me
the personnel files,
the 66-1 's on Gately
and the key staff...
- including yours.
- Yes, sir.
Four... set up a meeting
for all combat crews...
in the briefing room
tomorrow morning at 0800.
- Is that all, sir? Yes, sir.
- That's all.
- Colonel Gately is here, sir.
- Send him in.
Yes, sir.
That's all, men.
- May I ask the general why
I've been placed under arrest?
- No.
Stand at attention.
You're the son of Lieutenant
General Tom Gately, aren't you?
I believe that's
my standard identification, sir.
- What do you think
of him as an officer?
- None better, sir.
That's right.
You're the son of one fine officer
and the grandson of another.
You're a graduate of West Point
with nine years service.
You're form five shows that
you have more four engine time
than any man in the group.
For those reasons, you could've
done more than anybody to take
the load off Colonel Davenport.
The record shows that you've
flown only three missions
since you've been here.
- Is that right?
- If you don't count twice
I turned back, sir.
I take it that you don't even
care about the part you had...
in breaking one of the best
men you'll ever know.
Add to it as air exec you were
automatically in command here...
the moment
Colonel Davenport left.
And you met that responsibility
exactly as you met his need.
You ran out on it.
You left the station to get drunk.
And Gately, as far as I'm
concerned, you're yellow.
A traitor to yourself, to this group,
to the uniform you wear.
It would be the easiest course
for me to transfer you out,
to saddle some unsuspecting guy
with a deadbeat.
Maybe you think that's what
you're gonna get out of this,
a free ride in some combat unit.
But I'm not gonna pass the buck.
I'm gonna keep you right here.
I hate a man like you so much
that I'm gonna get your head
down in the mud and tramp on it.
I'm gonna make you wish
you'd never been born.
- If that's all, sir...
- I'm just getting started.
You're gonna stay right here
and get a bellyful of flying.
You're going to make
every mission.
You're not air exec anymore.
You're just an airplane commander.
And I want you to paint this
name on the nose of your ship...
Leper Colony.
Because in it you're gonna get
every deadbeat in the outfit.
Every man with a penchant
for head colds.
If there's a bombardier who can't hit
his plate with his fork, you get him.
If there's a navigator who can't find
the men's room, you get him.
Because you rate him.
- Is that clear?
- General Savage, I have a right
to file charges against you...
for personal abuse and exceeding
your lawful authority...
Hello, get me Pinetree.
I want General Pritchard.
- The line's busy, sir. Will you wait?
- Yeah, I'll wait.
Rights, Gately?
You've got a right to explain
to General Pritchard cowardice,
desertion of your post,
a yellow streak a mile wide.
And maybe he can explain it to your
father so they'll both be proud of you.
- Hello. Hello?
- You can tell him right now.
Hello, I have your line, sir.
- General Savage,
I withdraw my statement.
- Hello? Hello?
- Hello, I have your line, sir.
- Never mind.
That's all then.
- Cut an order relieving
Colonel Gately as air exec.
- Yes, sir.
Anybody else, sir?
I'll let you know, Major.
There's one file there,
Cobb, Squadron Commander,
shows a good record in the air.
What are his personal
qualifications?
I'm sure the general will be
pleased with any selection
he makes in the group.
Thanks for the help, Major.
- I'll be around the station.
- Yes, sir.
Sir.
- I've been assigned
as the general's driver.
- Fine.
- Aren't you the clerk that I saw...
- Yes, sir. Private McIllhenny.
Well, general officers
rate sergeants as drivers.
- Better put those stripes back on.
- Yes, sir.
With anyone else but me
Anyone else but me
- No, no, no don't sit
under the apple tree
- Beer.
- Yes, sir.
- With anyone else but me
Till I come marching home
Don't go walking down lovers'
lane with anyone else but me
Anyone else but me
No, no, no don't go
walking down lovers'lane
Remove your cap
in the club, Major.
- That's regulations, huh?
- It is.
Have another,
Major Cobb.
Scotch.
- I've got it.
- No regulation against
buying my own, is there?
That's right.
- Corporal.
- Yes, sir.
- This bar is closed for tonight
and until further notice.
- [Officers Murmuring]
[Men Chattering, Indistinct]
I'll probably see you
tomorrow morning.
- Good night, Ben.
- Good night. I'll keep a light
in the doghouse window for you.
Come in.
Major Stovall, cut an order
assigning Major Cobb as air exec.
Yes, sir.
- Good night.
- Good night, sir.
[Chattering]
- [Footsteps Approaching]
- Attention.
Rest.
There will be a briefing for a practice
mission at 1100 this morning.
That's right, practice.
I've been sent here to take over
what has come to be known
as a hard luck group.
Well, I don't believe in hard luck.
So we're going to find out
what the trouble is.
Maybe part of it's your flying,
so we're going back to fundamentals.
But I can tell you now one reason
I think you've been having hard luck.
I saw it in your faces last night.
I can see it there now.
You've been looking
at a lot of air lately...
and you think
you ought to have a rest.
In short,
you're sorry for yourselves.
I don't have a lot of patience with this
what are we fighting for stuff.
We're in a war, a shooting war.
We've got to fight.
And some of us have got to die.
I'm not trying to tell you
not to be afraid. Fear is normal.
But stop worrying about it
and about yourselves.
Stop making plans.
Forget about going home.
Consider yourselves
already dead.
Once you accept that idea,
it won't be so tough.
Now if any man here
can't buy that,
if he rates himself as something
special, with a special kind
of hide to be saved,
he'd better make up his mind
about it right now.
Because I don't
want him in this group.
I'll be in my office in five minutes.
You can see me there.
Attention!
- [Man #1] I'll take
Colonel Davenport any day.
- [Man #2] Me too.
I'd better get over to the office 'cause
the traffic is gonna be pretty heavy.
[Door Closes]
The air exec and the group
flight surgeon are here, sir.
- Tell them to come in.
- Yes, sir.
They beat you to it, Major.
I thought you'd be the first one
in line to ask for a transfer.
- No, sir.
- Well, it wouldn't
have done you any good.
- Doesn't go for staff.
You're stuck with me.
- Yes, sir.
- You might tell them.
- They thought you'd want to see
them about the practice mission.
- Good.
- Yes, sir.
For the general's information, I think
you'll find Major Kaiser a top man.
Thorough,
knows his job, honest.
I think Cobb's an excellent man too.
It's just he's a little too frank.
- Thanks, Major.
- Yes, sir.
- General, this is Major Kaiser.
- I'm glad to see you, Doc.
- And I think you met Major Cobb.
- Indeed I have.
General, I don't know if you still
want me here after last night.
No need to tell you,
I was stiff.
Well, stiff or not,
you laid it on the line.
You got the job after I saw you
at the club, not before.
You were in the briefing room.
You still want it?
I think I can
cut it for you, sir.
See you at takeoff.
Now, what about the crew
availability, Major?
We have a very critical
morale problem, General.
You gave them the shock treatment
this morning, a bucket of cold water.
I take it that's the key in which
you want me to approach the problem...
as to how much
stress they can take.
If a man is physically capable
of handling his airplane, he goes.
Well, that's definite enough.
But some things can't be
accomplished just by issuing an order.
- Have you seen the sick reports?
- Yeah, I've seen them.
Our sick reports indicate
something else to me.
Besides the normal stress
of a lot of flying,
these men have had the breaking up
of a strong personal attachment.
They were devoted
to Colonel Davenport.
- He was the main thing
they had to hold on to.
- You suggest a treatment?
Yes.
Ease up.
Give them a chance
to get used to you.
No, Major.
For two reasons.
First, there isn't time.
Second, I can't enter a popularity
contest with Keith Davenport.
I'd lose that one.
And one more thing, I think
they're better than that.
All right, sir.
That's it.
Lieutenant Bishop
to see you, sir.
- Bishop? Who's he?
- A pilot, sir.
Yesterday a recommendation
for the Medal of Honor was
forwarded to you at Pinetree.
- Oh, yes. I'll see him
in just a minute.
- Yes, sir.
I think I know how deep
the problem is here, Major.
And I'm convinced that the one thing
that will solve it is pride,
pride in this group.
The kind of pride that will
make it the last thing a man
wants to be left on the ground.
And that's my job, not yours.
- Paint it with iodine and
mark them "duty," Doc.
- Yes, sir.
- Send Bishop in.
Yes, sir.
I better practice saluting you,
Lieutenant. That goes with the medal.
- It was a privilege to add
my name to that recommendation.
- Thank you, sir.
- Sit down, Bishop.
- Thank you, sir, but...
- Well, first, I better
tell you why I'm here.
- Go ahead.
The pilots asked me
to be their spokesman, sir.
They want to transfer out.
- How many of them?
- All of them, sir.
Well, I can see why
they sent you, Bishop.
You make quite a spokesman.
Have you thought this out?
You're sure that's
the way you feel?
I... I think so, sir.
All right, that's it. Tell them
to put their requests through channels.
Meanwhile, they fly.
- That's all then?
- Yes, sir.
[Intercom Buzzes]
- Yes?
- I just made some coffee.
I thought you might like some.
- Shall I bring it in?
- Thanks, Major.
I'll come out there and get it.
What are you doing?
Personal effects of boys who got it
to be sent to next of kin.
I'm a little behind.
I always write a letter.
It always takes time
to screen the stuff pretty well.
It might save somebody back home
getting hurt unnecessarily.
That's a tough chore.
I don't envy you.
How did you happen
to get into paperwork?
They didn't give me any choice.
See, I'm... I'm a retread.
I had my shot at combat
in the first war.
Of course I kind of wanted
to get into this one,
but I guess they figured
I was too old for anything but a desk.
Maybe they were right.
You, uh...
You liked Keith Davenport,
didn't you? A lot, I mean.
Yes, sir.
I thought he was one
of the finest men I ever knew.
The same way
the boys felt, I'm sure.
Loyalty is a fine thing.
Well.
- Thanks for the coffee, Major.
- General Savage.
I'd like to tell you
something else, I think.
[Clears Throat]
I'm a lawyer by trade.
I think I'm a good one.
And when a good lawyer takes on
a client, he does it because...
he believes in the client's case,
and that's all that matters.
When I came over to England
I took on my biggest client.
That client
is the 918th Bomb Group.
I want to see my client
win its case.
Does that answer what
you had in mind?
- On the button.
- What did you have in mind exactly?
I need time before
those transfers go through.
- Mm-hmm. How much time?
- As much as we can get.
Ten days, anyway.
Well, it'll take those
squadron adjutants...
at least two days
to draw up all those requests.
And, let's see...
I believe in thorough, methodical work,
everything in order.
I've got a good deal
of stuff on my desk here.
So, it might be three days
before I could get around to them.
- That's five.
- Take a couple of days to check them.
That's seven.
And those squadron adjutants
are pretty sloppy sometimes,
and I certainly don't want this group
criticized for sloppy paperwork.
- Do you, General?
- Couldn't permit it.
So my guess is
every one of those requests...
may have to go back to the squadron
adjutants to be done over.
By the time I recheck them,
it'll be ten days anyway before
they can be ready for signature.
What a way
to run an outfit.
- You red-tape adjutants are all alike.
- That's right, sir.
But Harvey,
there can be trouble in this.
I don't think so, sir. I never heard
of a jury convicting the lawyer.
Let me have
your attention.
Now, in case any of you aren't clear
as to what this is all about,
I'm supposed
to be a deadbeat.
And so are you.
That's why you were assigned to me...
"The Leper Colony."
How do you like it?
Well, you'll like it a lot less
the first mistake you make.
We've got a blowtorch turned our way,
and nobody's gonna shove me into it.
- Is that clear?
- [Vehicle Approaching]
- Everything set?
- Yes, sir.
You fly. I'll ride
in the top turret where I can see.
- Radio, rig an extension
to the top turret...
- Yes, sir.
- So the general can talk
on the command set.
- Yes, sir.
All right.
Let's go.
"Close it up.
Close it up. Closer.
Shove that there wingtip
right in his lap."
Sweet Savannah!
That wingtip of Baxter's
been tickling me...
right in the ribs
for three days now, man.
- I'm gettin' mighty tired of it.
- That's a-tellin' 'em, Birdy.
Yeah, and another thing
I noticed.
For folks that talks about
other people's ability as a pilot,
that there general seems mighty willin'
not to do any of it hisself.
Hmph. Looks like we just
got ourselves a talking general.
"Stack it in there, now."
[Continues, Indistinct]
- [Water Splashing]
- We're alerted, sir!
Field orders
coming in now.
Tell Cobb to wheel and deal.
I'll be right over.
Operator. Operator.
Keep this line clear.
I've got 24 fast calls for you.
Get me the bomb dump and hurry.
[Men] Bless them all
Bless them all
Oh, the long and the short
and the tall
Let's bless all the blondies
and all the brunettes
For each lad is happy
to take what he gets
'Cause we're...
Two missions.
Only one aircraft lost.
Very little battle damage.
That's because most of the time
we flew good, tight formation.
Those enemy fighters
took one look...
and didn't want
any part of the 918th.
The bad side...
the bombing.
Fair. Particularly,
the Low Squadron.
That means we start dropping
practice bombs every day that
we haven't got a mission.
- Cobb?
- Yes, sir.
- That's your baby.
- Roger.
Anybody got
any comment?
Well, I've got some more.
Hanley!
- Here, sir.
- Those strike photos show...
that you've been toggling late
with your bombs the last two missions.
- What's your reason?
- No excuse, sir.
Well, I'll say this for you, Hanley,
you're honest.
But nine men risked their lives
to ride with you...
in order to put
bombs on a target!
Gately, here's
a new bombardier for you.
- Pettinghill!
- Yes, sir.
We're plenty lucky to have
only one loss on this strike.
Why did you break formation?
Well, sir,
Ackerman was in trouble...
Two engines on fire,
and we were getting enemy fighters. I...
I figured I'd better stay back
and try to cover him...
going into the target,
but he couldn't make it.
Ackerman a pretty good
friend of yours?
My roommate, sir.
So for the sake of your roommate
you violated group integrity.
Every gun on a B-17
is designed...
to give the group
maximum defensive firepower.
That's what I mean
by group integrity.
When you pull a B-17
out of a formation,
you reduce the defensive power
of the group by ten guns.
A crippled airplane
has to be expendable.
The one thing which is never expendable
is your obligation to this group!
This group.
That has to be your loyalty,
your only reason for being.
- Stovall.
- Yes, sir.
Have the billeting officer work out
a reassignment of quarters...
- so that every man
has a new roommate.
- Very well, sir.
- Gately!
- Yes, sir.
Baxter is promoted
out of the Leper Colony.
Pettinghill's
your new copilot.
Well,
that's all I've got.
Anybody got anything else
they want to bring up?
What about
our transfers, sir?
- Okay, if that's all, dismissed.
- Attention!
- [Knocking]
- [Savage] Come in.
Keith! Come on in.
Glad to see you.
How are you, Frank?
How's the adjutant
business, Harvey?
Just went out of that line of work, sir.
Ground exec now.
- Well, glad to hear it.
You had it coming.
- Thank you.
- Good to see you, sir.
- Good to see you, Harvey.
- Piece of cake?
- Thanks.
Uh, birthday.
It's a little old.
Oh, many happy returns.
Well, seems to me
I've seen this joint before.
It looks better
with you in it, Keith.
Have a drink.
Say, you're in time for chow.
- The boys'll be glad to see you.
- I'm not so sure of that.
I saw Sergeant Keller
at the gate.
- Had to show
my A.G.O. Card to get in.
- [Chuckles]
And I'll pass up the supper, I guess.
I just dropped down for a minute.
I had something I wanted
to talk to you about, Frank.
Well, I'll get on about
my ground exec-ing.
- I'll see you before you go, Keith.
- All right.
- Nice guy, Harvey.
- First-rate.
Sit down.
Aah, tastes good.
Gets the chill out of your bones.
- What a stinkin' climate.
- It's pretty bad.
Only I guess you didn't come down
to talk about the weather.
No...
Or maybe I did at that.
- There's a storm coming, Frank.
- The old man?
No. I don't know
if he even knows about it.
There's been a lot of talk
about requests for transfer,
only none have come through.
- Have you been sittin' on 'em?
- I have.
You've got what amounts
to a mutiny on your hands.
There's a rumor that
the inspector general's got hold of it.
If he investigates you,
you're cooked.
Can you slow him down?
You know the Old Man
can't interfere with the I.G.
I know what you're after...
a little time, get a few
good missions under your belt,
maybe the boys'll
change their minds.
- But it won't work that way.
- You got any ideas?
Well, to be perfectly frank
about it, when you took command,
I was hoping you'd fail,
fall flat on your face.
I'm that human.
So now, me,
the guy who blew it...
- wants to tell you
how to run this group.
- Shoot.
All right.
You're blowing it too.
You can't drive those boys.
I told you once before...
they can't just be
a set of numbers, and it still goes.
The fact that I blew it
doesn't mean that idea was wrong.
I figured it was me.
I wasn't good enough.
You've got
to help them, Frank.
You've got to take the time
to win something from them,
or they will walk out on you.
And that'll be a worse failure
than mine ever was.
Give them something
to lean on, you mean.
Call it
anything you like.
Well, Keith,
I don't believe it.
Here's where
you and I part company.
I don't think they're boys,
they're men.
Too bad they have
to find out so young.
How old is Bishop?
Twenty-one, maybe.
It's pretty tough to have
to grow all the way up at 21.
But that's the only way
we're gonna get the job done.
And I think
they can do it too.
Lean on somebody?
I think they're better than that.
And if that's not true
then we're a dead duck,
and we'd better find out
about it right now,
once and for all.
Well, that's that.
You called the turn
for me once,
and I couldn't
see it.
Now we're even.
- Good night, Frank.
- Good night, Keith.
[Men] The stars at night
are big and bright
- [Hand Claps]
- Deep in the heart of Texas
- The prairie skies...
- [Man] Not again.
[Teletypes Clattering]
No good, sir. Acknowledgement
from the other groups,
they've already turned back.
- But nothing from the 918th.
- Forget code.
- Try to reach him in the clear.
- Yes, sir.
Pinetree
to Flashlight leader.
This is a recall.
Do you read me?
Pinetree to Flashlight leader.
This is a recall.
Do you read me? Over.
- Nothing, sir.
- I don't get it.
Weren't all commanders told
to guard channel "B" because
of possible weather change?
- It was in the field order, sir.
- Well... something's happened.
They've gone on
to the target alone.
I'm going down there, Keith.
I can't just stand here and take it.
That's 21, sir.
They're all back.
Well, that's something.
I'm glad we still have miracles.
Well, we had
a little weather, sir,
but the target area had
cleared off just long enough...
- for the 918th
to clobber it good.
- That's fine, Frank.
- What about the recall?
- Recall, sir? What recall?
Never heard it.
- Must have had radio malfunction.
- I see.
- Let's get up to your office, Frank.
- Yes, sir.
- The bar's open, Harvey.
The boy's really earned it.
- Yes, sir.
[Pritchard] And you think I'm going
to buy a quick Persian rug...
about a radio malfunction?
And I suppose you'll tell me next
the weather was just bad enough...