They're here.
They're coming, sir.
Hand me those files on the death
of young Williams, will you, please?
Colonel Waldron, you know Herr Rinder.
Herr Doktor from the Swiss Red Cross.
Oberleutnant Strauss.
Major Von Steiner.
Colonel Waldron is
the senior British officer.
Major Rose,
head of the lntelligence Committee.
Wing Commander Shurlock,
head of their Escape Committee.
Nicht wahr?
I think you've come to investigate
the killing of my officer.
An accident.
I would like the Red Cross
to see the whole camp.
Your sleeping quarters, mess, toilets.
And see that you are being treated well...
...according to the spirit
of the Geneva Convention.
Come on.
Please, sir, can I have my ball back?
You are the Sportfuhrer?
I'm Colby.
Colby?
That's very familiar.
It's a common name.
They're very enthusiastic.
No bloody good, but very enthusiastic.
Do you play matches?
Oh, yeah, we have a league.
Four divisions.
We even play internationals.
Internationals?
Yeah.
England, lreland, Scotland, Wales.
You call that international?
It would be international
if you played against Germany.
We'd murder you.
Colby! John Colby.
Yes. Westham United and England.
That's right.
It's a shame the war
has ended your career.
Interrupted.
Let's hope so.
The colonel's protest will be
a waste of breath, I'm afraid.
Two hearts.
If we don't kick up a stink, we give
the blighters permission to do it again.
No bid.
Pass.
Colby, what were you talking
to Jerry about?
None of your business.
Two spades.
It is our business.
You were seen in conversation
with the enemy, a Major Von Steiner.
What did he want?
He recognized me.
As what? Pass.
Pass.
So the major's a football fan, huh?
Elementary, my dear Shurlock.
Karl von Steiner played
for Germany in 1938.
What did he say to you?
Buzz off.
-In German?
-Yeah.
I think I'm getting something.
...working to extremes
to divert world attention...
...from their losses in North Africa...
...and the reported inhumane treatment of
the prisoners from East European nations.
Over here, over here.
What's the verdict on Williams?
Regrettable mistake.
The whole bloody war's
a regrettable mistake.
I agree.
Do you?
You can believe me or not,
it's nothing to me.
If nations could settle their differences
on the football pitch...
...wouldn't that be a challenge?
How would you like...
...to play a game against a team
from the Wehrmacht?
A team from the army base nearby?
What for? To settle the war?
Unfortunately not.
Let's say, for morale.
Yours or ours?
For both.
Life in this place must be very boring.
What sort of team? They any good?
I haven't chosen a team. It's just an idea.
It's not an order. You can't make us play.
No, it's a challenge.
No.
It'd be a washout. A complete washout.
Why?
Look at them.
Look at them. They're bloody useless.
I mean, look at those clothes,
and those bloody great boots.
They're charging about there
like a herd of elephants.
Play football? They can hardly stand up.
Boots can be supplied.
You mean, proper gear?
Shirts and shorts?
No.
They couldn't run about for 90 minutes.
They'd be chuckin' their guts out.
All right, I'm sorry.
Major....
I'd want...
...special conditions, special rations.
The team would have to live together,
eat together....
I'd want meat...
...fresh vegetables, eggs...
...beer.
You talk to your colonel?
No matter what he says,
if you could supply us with all that stuff...
...you'll have a game of football.
Which reminds me...
...if it's confined to officers...
...I'm not bloody playing.
I want a decent team. I want the lads...
...from over there.
Okay?
We shall see.
All right.
Just a minute.
Right. Escapes.
We've had all the usual requests...
...but here's a new one you might like.
Peter Bailey has a plan to pole-vault
the south fence.
God, what will they think of next?
Oh, Christ, refused.
Anything else?
No. Let's have Hatch in.
Hatch.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You're an American?
Enlisted Canadian Army '38,
transferred commandos.
How long have you been with us?
Since Dieppe.
How many attempts?
Two on the way, three since then.
Time before last, I got as far as Stuttgart.
How's this one going?
Well, sir, the whole thing
depends on the fact that...
...some of the goons don't patrol
when we're havin' a shower.
Some of them?
Yes. Like Hans and Anton.
At least one of them should be outside
walking back and forth...
...but they know we're inside
havin' a shower.
They come inside, lean against the door,
have a smoke if they can bum one.
I think if somebody went missing,
they wouldn't report it.
-Why not?
-They wouldn't be sure.
They'd think they'd miscounted
and leave it until roll call.
And if you could cover for me at roll call,
I could be gone for days.
Wait a minute.
You're going too fast for me. How are you
gonna get out of the wash house?
There is a vent in the shower room.
It leads into a storeroom or something.
Yes, I know.
It must have been built as a lavatory
to match the one on the German side.
If I can get in there,
with something to pick the lock--
And you'd be back in the enclosure
where you started.
But I'd be all alone. There's no one there.
And I could get onto the roof...
...go underneath the barbed wire
and drop into the German compound.
Naked?
How are you planning to get out
of the German compound naked?
I've got five or six ideas.
Shall we discuss them?
Yes.
Colby insisted on playing the other ranks
against the best of the officers.
What's the idea behind that?
I suppose he wants to pick
the best team possible.
I don't think he's quite got the point,
has he?
Tell him to come and see me, will you?
Cover him, Tony. Let's go.
Good goal. Well done, sir.
-What's your name?
-Sid Harmer.
How'd you like double rations
for a month or so, Sid?
Whose mother
do you want me to strangle?
Welcome aboard.
Okay, I'm ready to sign up.
Sign off, Hatch.
Give 'em the ball. Stop it.
Come on.
Tackle it.
Nice try.
Thanks, Colby.
It's not quite like playing for Manchester...
...but it's better than not playing at all.
Welcome aboard.
What about me?
Get out there.
Get out there and play.
The map of Marburg is from an old
guidebook, but it's reliable, I should hope.
There's a fast train to Cologne
at 5:33 every Saturday.
Now, under the map you'll see
they've done a sketch of the stadium...
...the exits, perspectives,
and changing rooms.
Colonel...
...what are you talking about?
I'm talking about your escape, Colby.
My escape?
Yes, of course.
The whole team if possible.
What about the lorry
that's taking you to the match?
You could loosen the floorboards
on the way in and...
...drop out on the way back.
You stick to scrounging, Pyrie,
and I'll stick to football.
It's your duty, Colby, as an officer.
It could be an excellent opportunity.
It's certainly worth considering, old boy.
I am not interested in getting them killed.
Are you afraid to try?
Your escaping is
just some bloody upper-crust game.
They've done their job
and want to be left alone till it's over.
Now, that will be all, Colby.
Thank you.
Come on, Hatch.
-Good tackle, Terry.
-Come on, Terry.
Go.
Did you see that?
Am I good, or am I good?
-What's your name?
-You know my name.
-Terry. Terry Brady.
How'd you like to come and live
with the officers?
Only if you've got a chaperone, mate.
Welcome aboard, Terry.
Where'd you learn to do that?
When I was a boy...
...in Trinidad...
...on the streets, with the oranges.
How'd you like to play football
against the Germans?
Why not?
Unload him, Tony.
Hey, foul there.
Stupid, bloody Yank!
What the hell do you think this is?
-Bloody hell!
-Well, what'd I do?
You know bloody well.
No, you tell me. What'd I do?
You can't tackle like that in soccer.
I've told you that for a year!
I was just goin' for the ball.
You use that bloody American style
again here, and you'll be barred.
You play English, I play American.
We don't play the bloody American game.
Get off.
Hey, what kind of game is this?
For old ladies and fairies?
I quit.
Okay.
One, two, three...
...four, five, six, seven...
...eight, nine, turn.
One, two...
...three, four, five--
Hatch, the committee
has considered your plan.
You may see the tailor and the forger.
And the locksmith.
I've got to see the locksmith.
Yes, but see the tailor first.
That takes time.
...seven, eight, nine, turn.
Thanks.
Hey, Colby.
Colby, I've been looking for you.
You know that football team of yours?
Know what you can do with that team?
Know where you can put it?
'Cause I don't want to be on that team.
As a matter of fact, you couldn't pay me
to be on that football team, Colby.
You got it, Colby?
I don't need you
or your football team anymore.
You got it?
I don't need this aggravation, Colby.
Captain Colby. How are you?
Sit down, please.
Why don't you tell me
what this is all about?
Our football match has been taken
a little out of our hands.
It has been decided...
...that a German national team will play...
...a combined team from the prisoners
of war of the occupied territories...
...August 15th,
at Colombes Stadium in Paris.
Paris?
That's crazy.
Come in, Muller.
This is Hauptmann Rainer Muller.
Coach for our national team.
Captain John Colby.
We've met.
A long time ago.
Yeah. In London.
You were center-half.
Hauptmann Muller will assist me
and manage our team.
Make sure you have everything you need.
Paris.
What if I refuse?
I think you will recognize
some of those names.
No, thank you.
Yeah.
There are some good players on here.
British, French.
Dutch.
Even a Norwegian.
What about the Poles and the Czechs?
I mean, off the top of my head
I could think of...
...half a dozen East European players
who would have to be on that squad.
Isn't that so, Muller?
I'm sorry. I cannot let you have
any Eastern Europeans.
Why not?
It's impossible.
Officially, they do not exist.
Germany does not recognize them
as prisoners of war.
They're in labor camps.
Well, maybe not officially,
but they do exist as players...
...don't they?
I don't know whether these
East European players are alive or dead...
...but you can find that out.
As an officer and a gentleman...
...you are obliged to give me
a marginal chance of winning.
Make your list, Captain.
I'll see what I can do.
Collaboration pays.
I don't consider it collaboration.
And you are to be exhibited in Paris
like performing fleas?
I don't think London is going
to take very kindly to this, you know.
You've informed London?
There's no need.
The German propaganda machine
will take care of that.
Get that, Hatch.
Oh, a customer, good.
-Captain Lawry, how are you?
-I'm very well, very well.
If you'll just get dressed.
That's it. Over there.
Will you be so kind as to stand guard
while I deal with our American friend?
Okay.
Stay where you are, Billy. Just listen.
Here we are.
Have you shaved?
Good enough?
Very good.
You know, it's really very gratifying.
I'm surprised at
the relatively good conditions here.
Compared to other camps, that is.
Everyone still wants to escape.
Getting dressed? Good.
Don't want to dilly-dally.
Now, I can't promise you
a studio portrait, but it'll do.
You didn't make the lens as well,
did you?
No. I'm a genius, not a magician.
Sit down.
All right, now, don't smile.
We want that criminal look
associated with passport photographs.
Solemn, depressed--
The jacket's up. That's lovely.
Now, hold that.
Wait. One more for luck?
No. Film's too valuable. Sorry.
This'll do.
Now, here we are.
Now, Dupin's the name you want, is it?
Yeah. Marcel Dupin, electrician.
I need an address in Lyon and papers
to show I'm a conscripted worker.
Yes. Why does Monsieur Dupin
want to go home?
Compassionate leave, death in the family.
-Can you do it?
-Yes, it's quite simple.
Quite simple. Might even manage
a letter on your bereavement.
Let's see.
What have we got?
French police...
...enter Germany, health officer,
military district....
They keep changing.
That's very inconsiderate of them.
Very.
How long will it take?
Well, you must realize, it's my busy time.
Everybody wants to escape
in the good weather.
Just be patient.
All right?
Be patient. Yeah. Thanks.
What the hell's that?
Who the hell are those guys?
I've had it. Look.
They've switched the guards on me.
Those goons are patrolling
like they're supposed to.
-Yes, I know.
-What do you mean, you know?
I know.
Hans and Anton have been switched
to watch over the football team.
Colby's football team?
They're my guards. I needed them.
A couple weeks, I was out of here.
That's bad luck.
Just between ourselves, Hatch...
...l never thought it was
a very good plan, anyway.
Here we are.
Luis, this is Arthur.
-Hello, Arthur.
-Sid and Terry.
Luis Fernandez.
Terry.
Here's your beds over here.
I'll have the top one.
Help yourself. First come, first served.
I'll take the bottom one.
Okay, just leave me one.
-Not bad, is it?
-It's like the Savoy Hotel.
How would you know?
There are no bleeding chambermaids.
This one?
Hi, guys.
-What do you think you're doing?
-I decided to join the team.
Tell me everything.
Being on this team
is a one-way ticket out of here, right?
You're not on this team.
Oh, yeah, sure I am.
-I'm the trainer.
-The what?
The trainer.
Colby, you forgot to put in for a trainer.
Maybe I can't play your kind of football...
...but in my kind, you know everything
there is to know about bruises, sprains....
So if you'll just get on
to your Von Steiner...
...to get me some bandages,
some lineaments, some oils, some tapes...
...we're in business.
I don't want a trainer.
Colby, I'm a ballplayer.
I don't want to be left out
of somethin' like this.
Pull the other one.
I just want to be around the guys.
Bullshit!
Don't do this to me.
-I don't need a con man.
-Easy, Colby.
-You and your team wrecked my escape.
-How?
I was ready. I was waiting for my papers.
I was going through the wash house,
but only if those two goons were on duty.
Now those two goons
have been transferred to you.
So the only way out of here
is by bein' on that team.
No.
Why not?
I won't be responsible for your death.
You'll get yourself shot.
That's my choice, isn't it?
So what is it, "yes" or "no"?
Okay.
Tony.
-Nice to see you.
-Great to see you. How are you?
-Hello. Hatch, the trainer.
-Hi.
-Doug Clure?
-Yeah.
-What's going on?
-I'll tell you in a minute.
-Hatch, the trainer, hi.
-Remy, Jean-Paul.
Colby's mine.
Michel Filieu.
Hatch, the trainer.
Welcome to my holiday camp.
Hello. How are you? Hello.
-Erik Borg, right?
-Yes.
Colby.
-Hatch, the trainer.
-Hello.
-Hello. How are you?
-I am Pieter Van Beck.
Come inside.
Hatch, the trainer.
We'll have something to eat,
and I'll explain.
The extra food is part of the deal.
We still respond to roll call
three times a day...
...but apart from that,
we make our own rules.
There is no rank here.
This is a football team.
I am the captain and the manager.
Any questions?
I don't know how you did it...
...but cheers anyway.
It's been a long time...
...and none of us feels like or...
...looks like world-class players.
It'll be tough getting into shape
with those boots...
...so let's hope the German major
gives us the proper gear.
We gotta start somewhere,
so let's start with basics, shall we?
Slow, easy, stretching it fully. Okay?
We won't be needing that for a while.
Come on, put 'em down.
Let's go. Pick 'em up.
Left, left.
Left, right. Left, right.
Pick 'em up. Pick 'em up.
Put 'em down. Good.
Good. Good. Good.
Good, Colby. Come on, guys.
Pick 'em up, put 'em down.
Good.
They're all different sizes,
so make sure everything fits.
Everything fits.
And I want you all to know
that if you're havin' any trouble with, say...
...appendicitis, heart attacks....
That's okay. There's no problem.
I can handle that. But listen...
...l don't want any blisters.
No blisters allowed.
So if there's anything wrong
with any of you guys, tell me now...
...not later, okay.
Minor inconveniences,
say like anal bleeding, tuberculosis...
...growing tumors, little inconveniences
like that. All right?
Shut up, Hatch.
I'm just trying to get some team spirit
going here. Right guys?
Yeah, right.
Make sure everything fits.
Yeah, everything fits. Everything fits.
I'll keep this myself.
Take no notice, lads. They're only jealous.
Up your's.
If you can get up here,
don't try and run through.
Don't try and be a hero
and get a goal yourself.
That center...l want up there,
and I want you to pass. Always pass.
Let the ball do the running for you.
Don't try and run with it.
You're in no condition to run
for 90 minutes, I tell you.
This especially applies to wingers.
If you can't cross, don't run it through.
Try and get a corner.
A set piece works in our favor.
Which means that, as they--
Give me this.
Colby, after givin' me ball here,
I do this...
...this, this, goal.
Easy.
That's the right spirit, Luis.
Keep it up. Before you know it,
you'll have me thinking it's easy.
Colby, old chap,
Waldron would like a word.
I'll be right back, lads.
How did they get here?
I insisted on having them.
You insisted?
They're all great players.
They were.
You are a naive fool, Colby.
Insisting on great players.
Von Steiner has sent you five skeletons,
guarantees that you'll turn up in Paris...
...for his propaganda victory.
The Germans are doing their job very well.
London knows.
We heard it on the news.
It's in all the papers.
They're calling it another German lie.
London is saying that no British officer
would ever be involved in such a game.
London is saying, Colonel?
What about those poor bastards there?
Do we send them back
to the labor camps?
That's a very good question, Colby.
They can't go in there like that.
Full of lice.
Should take 'em around back, scrub 'em...
...take off what they're wearin' and burn it.
You guys want to get some water?
Anybody got any soap?
Yeah, I have. I've got DDT, as well.
All right.
Come on, guys. Get some water.
I'm responsible for them being here.
And I'm responsible for them
being sent back, if we don't play.
I can't do that.
But I can't tell any of you
to disobey his high command.
So each of you will have to make
his own decision.
We play.
What else can we do?
Yes, we play.
Yeah?
-Everybody?
-Yeah, come on, let's play.
Of course, we'll play.
Come on. Looking good.
You got a good bunch out there.
These guys are comin' along real fine.
I think the Germans are gonna have to
go some to beat them.
-You're an optimist.
-Well, what are you?
That's not bad, Hatch.
What's not bad?
Using your hands.
You've got feet, I've got hands.
Gimme that.
-Get in there.
-Sure thing, General.
Luis.
Luis....
Fire a few at him.
You've got to do better than that.
Come on, you guys. Let's fire 'em in here.
There we go. Here we go. Come on.
Yeah, here we go. Put it in here.
Give me some balls, Charley.
You're gonna get serious now, huh?
Okay, guys, come on, fire 'em in here.
Fire 'em in here. Let's go. All right?
Let's go. Come on. Don't be afraid of me.
Yeah. What, what's that?
Right down the middle.
Can you do it with your mouth shut?
The mouth and the hands
work together as a team.
Come on, come on.
Get your body behind it.
Not like that, like that.
Hands behind it, pull it into the chest.
I'm aware of that.
Come on, Hatch. I want to see it now.
Come on, right there in the middle.
I thought you were my friend.
I am your friend.
You know, Hatch, to be honest with you...
...you don't kick well...
...you don't dribble well...
...but you could be a good goalkeeper.
-Keep trying.
-Thanks a lot.
He's right. You're not bad.
Ca va, Monsieur Dupin ?
I'm good. Do you have my papers?
I kept my word. It was ready,
but the colonel took it.
-He wants to see you.
-The colonel?
-The colonel took my passport?
-Yes, he did.
Thanks.
How's the French coming along?
-Comme ci comme ca.
-You don't need much.
I am going to a funeral. Fine.
Je vais a un enterrement,
something like that.
That's good.
Remember to take your identity tag
when you go.
-We don't want you shot as a spy, do we?
-No.
I don't want to be shot as anything.
Au revoir.
He's on his way, sir.
Good.
Enter.
Hatch.
-Hello.
-Sit down.
-Cup of tea?
-Yes, please.
Tea?
Beautiful.
God knows what the fellow will do
in civilian life.
Make his own pound notes
and share certificates, I shouldn't think.
Are you ready?
Pretty near.
Anything else we can do for you?
No. I just want to thank you all
for helping out.
Don't thank us, old boy. It's a team effort.
What Pyrie means is that nowadays
the Germans are up to all the tricks.
It's almost impossible
to escape without help.
Helping one another is the most
important part of the whole thing.
How would you like to do something
to help us, Hatch?
Provided, of course, that you get out.
Which way were you planning to go?
To Lyon then to the Swiss border.
Switzerland?
I suppose you hadn't thought of
going via Paris, had you?
No. Paris? No, sir.
I think you'd find it easier.
They wouldn't expect you to go that way.
But I'm still in occupied territory.
Where do I go from there?
We could supply you with contacts,
names, safe houses....
You'd be well looked after.
No, thanks.
I thank you all for your concern, but
I'm really not planning on seein' Paris...
...until after the war.
Why, Colonel?
We want you to contact
the Resistance for us.
What?
And arrange the escape
of the football team.
Colby's escape?
All of them.
The whole team.
This match is a propaganda stunt
for the Germans.
It's a wonderful opportunity for us.
But why send me?
The French may have thought
of all this themselves.
Indeed they may, and then again,
they may not.
We have to get word to them somehow.
What do you want me to do?
Find out if an escape is feasible.
Ask them to try it.
If they won't?
They won't.
But they'd help you
to get to Spain or Switzerland.
I suppose I could do that.
Wonderful.
-Thank you.
-I'll go over the details with you tonight.
-Not a word to Colby.
-He'll have to know something.
He'll have to know you're going,
but not why.
I really don't believe this.
What?
This frigging game is wrecking my life.
Good luck.
Red Cross.
-Good?
-Good.
All the best, Hatch.
I hope he makes it.
Stay close to it. Easy.
Easy.
Achtung. Achtung.
Lights out.
That was a wonderful evening, darling.
See you tomorrow. Sleep well.
Open the gate.
For Paris, please.
You must change in Strasbourg.
Come on! We must go. Hurry up!
All aboard, please.
What is the purpose of your trip?
Do you speak French?
-Don't you speak German?
-No.
I'm going to a funeral in Paris.
I'm going to a funeral.
My dear, wait.
Quetsche, s'il vous plait.
Merci.
Alors, salut.
Un autre.
Oui.
We don't even know
when or how they'll do the transfer.
'Cause the Germans
could take them one by one.
It all seems risky to me.
Well, I don't know. It seems too soon
to make a decision like that. Tell him.
Mister...
...the answer is "no."
That's what I figured.
We do not know
where they would stay in Paris...
...and I do not want a battle in the streets.
The Germans will have a whole battalion
at least at the Colombes Stadium.
The Colombes Stadium?
Why didn't you say so before?
My friends, the Paris sewer system
branches off just below...
...the foundations of the stadium.
-Are you sure?
-I'm sure.
Did I not work in the sewers 20 years ago?
What'd he say?
There were sewers there,
sewers going into the Seine.
It's covered over now.
Who knows.
We will have a look. Okay? Bonsoir.
What am I supposed to do?
You will stay with Renee, please.
The house is safe. Okay? Goodbye.
Salut.
-Bye, Renee.
-Good night.
Thanks. No. Merci.
Look, lady, I just said thanks.
No offense.
We are both on the same side, aren't we?
Please.
I just wanted to talk.
It's been a long time
since I talked to a woman.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Parlez-vous English?
I understand you very well.
Good. Then why don't you sit down
and we'll talk.
Hatch. My friends call me Hatch.
No.
You don't want to be my friend?
I didn't want to hear your name.
And now that I do, I don't want to hear
anything else about you.
The less I know, the better it is for you.
And for you?
And for me, too.
My bein' here has put you
and your friends in a tough spot.
Is that why you're mad?
I'm not mad.
But being in a tough spot,
as you call it, is where I choose to be.
How do you feel about me being here?
How do I feel?
I feel responsible, hopeful.
When I get word that someone
I sheltered is safe, then I'm happy.
I can forget them.
But when I hear
that they've been caught or killed...
...then I remember everything.
I remember their faces, their voices.
What they said about their parents,
their child, their pets.
And I mourn for them.
I don't want to mourn for you.
Well, you're safe with me, Renee.
How?
Well, I'm an orphan. A bastard.
I have no parents.
No money. I'm not married.
No children. I don't even have a pet.
And anything I might say in my sleep
to the contrary can't be held against me.
Do you live here alone?
No.
Are you married?
He got killed, the first week of the war.
Sorry.
Who do you live with?
With Francois.
Is that your boyfriend?
It's late. I'll have him move out
of his room so you can sleep there.
Wait.
You don't have to get Francois up.
I don't want to cause any trouble.
I can sleep here on the couch.
My son, Francois.
Herr Kommandant.
The American's escape
has put me in a very bad position...
...with the Kommandant
and the high command.
Hatch's escape had nothing to do
with my team.
That was his own idea.
Your men covered for him.
What would you expect them to do?
What would you do?
I want your word that there'll be
no attempt to escape from the team.
Scouts' honor.
The idea of the match was friendly.
That was the idea.
I want your word.
I can't give it to you.
You will all be very closely guarded.
All right.
And down the sewer here we discovered
a foundation pipe of the stadium.
Sounds good to me.
But...
...we must make sure which one it is.
We have to find the original plans.
We think the best chance to escape...
...will be from the visitors' dressing room.
Maybe they'll be left alone at halftime.
Maybe.
But we can run into a concrete wall.
Anything can happen.
You will have to go back.
What?
To the camp.
To tell them.
The team.
They must know that we'll be there.
It took me a year to get out of there.
We need a contact.
Colby must know, and also your colonel.
That's not my problem.
You believe that?
I don't know what to believe.
I don't. I mean....
What am I supposed to do?
Break back into the camp?
No. You get captured.
Get captured.
All right, suppose I get captured?
Then they send me to the wrong
prisoner camp. What about that?
-No, no.
-Now, what about that?
The Germans will take you
to the same place...
...to show the other prisoners
that you are not a success.
You got all the answers, don't you?
Yes.
Mister, you will leave tomorrow.
-Tomorrow?
-Yes, tomorrow.
This friggin' soccer game.
I'll leave you my papers.
They're pretty good.
I'm sure somebody will be able to use 'em.
All right?
He's back.
Schnell.
Thank you.
March, march.
So, our Hatch knows his mythology.
What does it mean?
Mercury.
Messenger of the gods.
No flies on Rosey.
News, eh?
How do we find out what it is?
Good question.
We sent him to Paris on your behalf.
Yours and the team's.
Colonel...
...l don't know what you're talking about.
We sent him to Paris
to arrange your escape.
-Hatch did that for you?
-No.
-For you.
-We could argue about that.
Why didn't you tell me?
No point, really,
unless he managed to arrange something.
He appears to have been successful.
The snag is he can't tell us.
He'll be in the cooler until after the match.
Then you'll just have to get him
out of there, won't you?
Excuse me.
I have a training session.
Just a minute. Colby....
I know you wanted to play for the sake
of those Eastern Europeans.
I admire you for it.
But you and I both know that you risk
a court martial for this after the war.
What have you accomplished?
Give them a couple of weeks of life?
And what is going to happen to them
after your match is over?
For the same reason
that you wanted to play you must escape.
If you can.
What can I do?
I can't get him out of there.
Now, Hatch is officially your trainer,
isn't he?
Von Steiner and the camp Kommandant
won't buy that one.
You'll have to think of something else.
Crazy Yank.
You, Colonel Waldron and Major Rose...
...will travel to Paris along with
other senior officers from various camps...
...to represent your countries.
I won't do it.
You have no choice.
Then I'll travel...
...but I won't represent anything.
You will be seen.
The team...
...will be ready to travel at midday
on Thursday.
Further arrangements
will be announced later.
One of my men is
in the punishment block.
In solitary.
I can give you a trainer.
You don't need him.
Hatch is my goalkeeper.
The American? No.
Tony Lewis is your goalkeeper.
He's broken his arm.
When did this happen?
This morning.
Put someone else in goal.
Hatch is my best man.
I thought the idea was
to give us a chance.
This is the idea.
If the camp doctor verifies
this broken arm...
...you may have the American.
Thank you.
Well, Tony?
Try and make it a clean break, will ya?
I'll try.
I won't even get to see the game, will l?
Sit on the bed.
Put your arm between those two.
Okay.
-Are you going to put those up?
-Yes, sir.
Which is the team for home?
Then the prisoners shall have it.
We'll have the other.
-The other is the same?
-Yes, sir.
Good.
Colby, I don't know
how to play this game, so...
...where do I stand for the corner kick?
What?
I said, I'm not very good at the game.
Where do I stand for the corner kick?
Go to sleep, Hatch.
Excuse me.
Colby?
What?
Where do I stand for a corner kick?
The far post, facing the ball.
Thanks. For a while there,
I thought you were keeping it a secret.
Mesdames et messieurs.
So, a hearty welcome
to all our listeners in England.
There are just a few minutes to go
before the kickoff of this historic match.
This great crowd of about 50,000
really has something to look forward to...
...during the next 90 minutes.
To insure fair play
and good sportsmanship...
...the German organizers have picked
a neutral to referee the match.
And he is now ready...
...for the toss of the coin.
Heads.
The winner will have his choice
of kicking off or defending.
But will most probably choose to play
towards the east goal...
...with the wind in his favor.
And the Allies will kick off
this great event.
Well, I tell you, years from now
men will say of this game:
"Did it happen?"
Well, I tell you in the listening audience:
Today, it is happening.
We're all witness to an occasion
long to be remembered.
Not just propaganda, as some would say...
...but as a magnificent sporting spectacle.
Hatch.
Hatch. Halftime.
All right. Thanks.
What'd he say?
That it's on for halftime.
Here's to victory.
Let's go. Let's play ball.
Play hard, eh?
Let's play hard.
Harmer kicks off for the Allies...
...and the game has begun.
You'd have a job getting...
...twenty-two better players than are
out there on the pitch right now.
The Allies are playing it very cool.
And Pauls of Denmark
makes it deep and shoots.
Very close.
The ball is back in play by Schmidt,
Germany's legendary goalkeeper.
Reinhart, Reinhart to Becker...
...to Baumann, Number 4...
...forward now to Brandt...
...back to Albrecht, Number 11 .
Albrecht out to the left.
He beats Number 4.
-Watch him.
-Watch my back, watch my back.
Watch out, Hatch.
There's your corner kick, Hatch.
-The guy drove me out.
-To the right, to the right.
Watch him back there. Watch him.
Watch him, watch him there.
Come on, lads, eye on the ball. Come on.
-Now, pick him up.
-Come on, guys.
I got it.
It's a goal.
Germany one, the Allies nil.
And listen to that applause.
The crowd is going wild.
Take it easy. You're as tight as a drum.
-Just give it to halftime, Colby.
-Don't let them pull you off your line.
That's a foul.
Watch him.
Come on. Stick with it. That's it.
That's it. Come on.
Referee, look at this.
Get it out.
Watch him back there. Watch him.
Play the ball.
Germany two, Allies nil.
Come out, Hatch.
Don't lose your temper. It's okay.
Everybody, out. Out! Out!
Take it.
Bravo.
Come on, Luis.
In the penalty area.
The referee will probably call a penalty.
And he does.
This is the fella here. This is the one.
I'll calm my team, but you calm them.
The referee trying to settle them down,
and the call will remain.
It will be a penalty kick, one on one.
Hatch, the goalkeeper...
...he'll have to be on his line,
that's 12 yards away.
He's not allowed to move
until the ball has been struck.
Yes, indeed. Germany's great Baumann
will take the kick.
Goal. He sends the ball past Hatch.
And it's three to nothing
in favor of Germany.
The Allies kick off again. It's Ray.
Ray to Fernandez. Fernandez back to Ray.
And we have seen
some very good football.
Very fortunate for us, indeed,
considering that...
...there are no international games
being played now.
Baumann makes a beautiful tackle.
Dispossesses him, and the Germans
are again on the attack.
Watch your back, watch your back.
I'll get it.
It's good.
Goal for the Germans.
Four, nil.
Stay on the bloody line, I told you.
I missed.
Stay on the line
and narrow the angle down.
When they come in, narrow the angle.
We'll play ten men.
I'll go forward, you cover that back.
This isn't going to be easy.
We've taken enough, mates.
Let's get 'em.
The Allies are playing with ten men.
Interesting, because Colby has chosen
to give this advantage to the Germans.
Good. On you go, come on.
Get it out.
Referee, look at--
Keep playing it, lads.
Four to one, and less than a minute
to go to the halftime.
This kind of action takes me back
to the World Cup of '38...
...played right here
in Colombes Stadium in Paris.
We did it. We made it.
The end of 45 minutes of play.
And it's been a brilliant first half.
I don't know about you,
but I can say for myself....
Well done, lads.
Hatch, we got you to halftime.
Let's see.
Fantastic, Terry. At least we put up a--
-We scored a goal.
-Oh, yeah?
-Who scored?
-Terry scored a goal.
Fantastic. What's the score?
Four to one. But at least
we scored a goal, one time.
We're doin' good. It's gonna be all right.
Way to go, guys.
What's happening?
All right, we're getting out of here.
How?
Our escape has been arranged
all the way to the Seine River.
Once we get on the other side,
we're gonna blow the tunnel.
There's a boat waiting for us
and in one hour we'll be in the country.
All right?
Salut.
Vite. Vite.
Vite. Vite. Vite.
Colby, you take the lead off,
I'll bring up the rear.
Okay. Get Luis and Pieter.
-I don't want to go.
-Just shut up and get in there.
We can beat them.
Bring Pieter over.
We've still got a chance.
Chance, my ass.
Hatch, don't you see?
You nuts or somethin'?
You have no chance.
Don't you understand? No chance.
Get Pieter ready next.
Hey.
Come on, let's go.
Don't worry. Come on. Hurry.
I don't want to go.
Let's go back. We can win this.
-Who said that?
-I did.
It's not as though
we're being slaughtered, Skipper.
What do you mean, we can win?
-Wait a minute.
-Colby, we're losin' time.
You mean you'd go back
and play the second half?
Move. We've only got a few minutes.
Yes, but we could win this.
You could never, with me as the goal.
Of course, we can.
He's not a bad goalie, is he?
What's the matter with you?
You want to go back to prison?
-Come back, we need you.
-That's right.
You guys do what you want,
but I'm leavin'.
-You're quitting.
-I ain't goin' back to prison.
You've got to come back. If you don't--
-I waited too long to get out.
-If you don't come back, we can't go.
Hatch, if you go,
we've all got to go with you.
We can't go back without the goalie.
-Hatch, come on.
-Hatch.
Please, Hatch.
That game means a lot to us.
You know that.
You must go back.
-Hatch, let's go.
-Please.
We can win.
Come on.
If we run now, we lose more than a game.
Please, Hatch.
Good luck, Hatch. Good luck.
Come on, lads, let's get 'em.
The Allies are playing above themselves.
Throwing everything into
a desperate attack.
Very quickly the Allies have come back
with a goal.
And it's four to two.
Come on, run with it.
Right tackle, Roy.
Fifteen minutes remaining
of this incredible game...
...and you won't see many
better than this.
A marvelous game.
We anticipated it, and so far, it's a sizzler.
The Germans are in top form.
Get lost.
Get me in there. Break fast.
The goal has been disallowed. No goal.
The goal has been disallowed.
What do you mean, no goal?
That's a bloody lie.
All right lads, we've been had.
This game has had all the drama.
An equalizing goal not allowed...
...so the Allies are still behind
three goals to four.
I want to play.
-You can't play like that.
-I feel good. I feel better.
-I must play.
-Ref, he's coming back on.
I'm okay.
...into the football festival
and only four minutes remaining.
-All right, lads, let's go.
-They're all very crucial.
The Germans are powerful,
and very strong.
Stick with him, boy.
Victory. Victory.
And so we're ready to pick up
where we left off in the action.
Very good, keep going.
And Schmidt, one of the best goalkeepers
in the world...
...showing us again
that he's not lost any of his skills.
About a minute remaining.
Schmidt left foots it down the field.
The Germans have a lovely ball.
It's Baumann. Baumann is...
...brought down in the penalty area.
The referee responds and rightfully so.
A deliberate foul by Ray
as the clock runs out.
And the penalty collects.
And at the very end of the game
they've resorted to fouling.
What a sad way to end this game.
This is not fair.
Come on, Hatch. Come on.