Please, you have to tell him.
I would never steal from him.
Please.
You can tell him yourself.
Please, Mr. Rabbit.
- Please.
- Shh. Shh, shh, shh.
Did you steal from me, Yuri?
No. Please. Let me explain.
Did you steal from me?
Yes.
Thank you.
Why?
For being honest with me.
Now we can talk like men again.
- Budmo.
- Hey!
- Budmo!
Mmm.
And I toast the two of you.
The truck job
was brilliantly executed.
Tell me, how did you get
your false credentials for that job?
The background check
should have taken six months.
Yeah, I know a guy.
It sounds like
we should all know this guy.
- Yeah.
- He doesn't like crowds.
Leave him, Olek.
Where would we be
without our secrets?
- Budmo.
- Hey.
So, you've had a very good year.
One last job next week
and then we go
quiet for a while, yes?
What? What?
That's what someone
always says in the movies
- right before they get caught.
- Stop it.
- I'm just saying.
- Well, don't say.
- Well, you know.
- You watch too many movies.
Why don't you
watch some with me?
Learn some English.
Get rid of some of that accent.
- It's part of my charm.
- Is that what you call it?
Daddy, what's this last job?
Capital Diamond.
- Seriously?
- We've been down this road.
I know, but I have
some new information.
One package,
10 million in loose stones.
Listen, that place is a fortress.
- The electronics alone...
- Yes, but luckily, you know a guy.
Right?
Well, I am wiped.
I'm gonna go home.
Olek will drive you.
- Good night, Daddy.
- Good night, Anastasia.
Night.
- Thanks.
- So?
- What?
- I know when you're troubled.
Look, Capital Diamond,
it's high risk.
Yes. Are you worried?
I don't know yet.
Just let me do some recon.
You listen to me.
Every time you and Ana
go out on a job,
I'm trusting you
with my daughter's life.
I could never do that
if I didn't see you as a son.
Do you understand?
You do your research.
You consider the risk.
You decide.
Have a good night.
You look very beautiful tonight.
Thank you.
Why don't I come in
for one more drink?
It's been such a long night.
I can barely keep my eyes open.
Another time.
Sure.
Thanks for the lift.
Good night.
I need to get a better lock.
I'd just come through the window.
What?
You know what.
We said it had to be the big one.
10 million in loose stones,
that's pretty big.
No one's ever stolen
from Rabbit before and lived.
We could do this.
- He'll kill you.
- No, he won't.
He won't. By the time Rabbit
realizes what's going on,
we'll be long gone.
- He'll find us.
- No, he won't.
I have it handled.
You have it handled?
Yeah.
You have to be a little
more specific than that.
You know what? You're right.
- I think you're ready.
- Ready for what?
Not what, who.
Who?
Whoo! Go, girl.
You take me to
the nicest places.
Nice shoes.
Did your daddy buy those for you
before or after he sodomized you?
What did he say?
That was nasty.
I'm sorry,
I couldn't hear you over the music.
What was that you were saying?
I said your daddy ass raped you.
No, no, no.
This here's a place
where we all can come
to express ourselves freely.
Lord knows I do.
These gentlemen here
have every bit as much right
to express themselves as any of us.
I applaud you gentlemen.
Coming here was an act
of great courage.
At this stage in your lives
when you're struggling
with your homosexuality.
Still buying each other rounds,
hoping one of you gets drunk enough
to suck the other one's dick
and then pretend to
forget about it in the morning.
Let's hear it
for our new gay friends,
ladies and gentlemen.
Let's give them a hand.
I am gonna fuck you up!
Baby, you ain't my type.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
I'll be here all week.
Let's go.
Hey, Job. How you doing?
Another night,
another drunk bigot to emasculate.
You almost made it
through the whole song.
You're getting better.
- Fuck you.
- You, too.
So this is her?
Job, Ana.
Ana, Job.
Hello.
Honey, you're much too hot
to be shopping retail.
That dress means well,
but it's cut all wrong.
Thanks, but I don't know
if we're going for the same look.
Style is style, honey.
You either got it
or you just think you do.
Come on,
I'll give you the nickel tour.
Place looks great.
The place is an abortion.
Sometimes I think I'm just
gonna gut the whole thing
and open a hair salon.
You cut hair?
Baby, I've hacked the CIA,
the FBI, and the World Bank.
I think I can probably cut some hair.
How we doing on the diamond job?
- It'll be ready when you are.
- And the other thing?
You'll be Carrie and Tom Palmer.
Licenses, credit cards,
checking accounts.
I've already leased you
matching Hondas.
You're both boring as shit.
Carrie.
That'll take some getting used to.
Well, then you'd best get started.
'Cause, girl,
I am not doing it again.
Can I help you, Agent?
Now how can you tell?
If you weren't a fed,
Viktor over there would have already
made you pay for your disrespect.
I'm Agent Jim Racine.
I'm taking over
for Agent Daniels.
What happened to Paul?
Paul was dirty.
But then I don't
have to tell you that.
I've been playing the game.
All the usual stuff...
wiretaps, surveillance, shakedowns.
And today I thought:
"I'm spending all this time
looking at this guy,"
"I ought to just come down
and meet him face-to-face."
I hope you're not disappointed.
On the contrary.
It's a real thrill.
It's a shame about Paul.
I quite liked him.
Of course you did.
He was weak and stupid.
You're very sure of yourself,
Agent Racine.
Is that gonna be a problem for you?
Not at all.
It will make it
all the more pleasurable
when I break you.
Don't be a stranger.
So we're looking for a
Chinese gangster named Fat Au?
- He's not Chinese.
- The Triads are backing him?
It's kind of hard to explain.
He's someone I knew
from the old days. Before your time.
Rabbit's not gonna
be alone in that church.
We need more firepower.
- Oh, so he's a gun dealer?
- Among other things.
- Are you sure he's gonna help you?
- No.
We had a complicated relationship,
but I did him a favor once.
- I hope he remembers.
- Me, too.
Hey, hey.
Yeah, I'm looking for Fat Au.
There's no Fat Au here.
Yeah, I'm not a cop, okay?
I'm an old friend of his.
He's gonna be very upset
if he hears you turned me away.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
This is a private club.
- Get lost.
- I came a long way to see him.
That's too bad.
Now get the fuck out of here.
We better go.
Hang tight. Just do what I do.
- What are you gonna do?
- This.
- You're welcome.
- Shit!
Don't fucking move.
Well, the good news is
we're going to see Fat Au.
Now who the fuck are you?
- Are you kidding me?
- I look like a fucking comedian?
You look like two fucking comedians.
I heard you died, man.
Yeah, I heard the same thing.
Y'all get the fuck out of here.
So you're running things now, huh?
Somebody's got to keep the peace.
Who is this you brought with you?
- This is Ana.
- Hello, beautiful.
What can I get you? Anything.
Name it, it's yours.
Eight Springfield automatics
with silencers,
preferably the AAC
Prodigy suppressors,
a few dozen ammo packages,
and something to carry it all in.
Ooh, I hope like hell
you're sleeping with this woman.
Listen, I don't have the money on me.
Your money is no good here.
You risked your life to save mine.
I think about it every day.
A few pieces of hardware
doesn't begin to make us even.
Thank you.
Now, with that being said,
I've got to ask,
what are you gonna do with the guns?
Target practice.
Not below Canal Street, you hear me?
You got it.
All right, then.
Package will be waiting
for you downstairs.
- Just like that?
- Oh, honey.
If I weren't so smitten,
I'd be insulted.
Now, let's celebrate, huh?
Soldier boy.
Back from the dead.
Today is a blessed day.
Why did he call you "soldier boy"?
- It's just a nickname.
- Yeah, I know, but why?
I guess when we first met,
I was a soldier.
You never told me
you were in the Army.
Not in the Army. Not exactly.
Anyway, it was a long time ago.
How many lives have you lived?
None, really.
You ready for the diamond job?
Will be.
It's a big score. Big risk.
You got something on your mind?
So much money. So much risk.
Some men would think
to take the money and run.
Where would I go?
I don't know.
But I would find you.
You want to talk shit
or you want to box, huh?
I want to fight.
What the fuck, Olek?
Whoo, that was a good shot.
I see stars.
You crazy motherfucker.
That's why
they pay me the big dollars.
You're quiet today.
I'm just thinking.
Are you worried about this job?
We could still walk away.
No. No, I think
we have that covered.
So, what, then?
It's nothing, Daddy. I'm fine.
You wouldn't keep something from me,
would you?
Of course not.
He knows.
He doesn't know.
You didn't hear him
this morning.
There's no way
he could possibly know.
You're reading into things.
I think we should wait.
Hey, listen to me.
He doesn't know.
Okay?
Look, every time we steal for him,
we risk our lives.
Why not risk our lives for us?
- I just have a bad feeling about it.
- Hey, hey, hey.
He doesn't know.
It's two miles from the highway
surrounded by forest.
At least we got that going for us.
The package is in a safe
on the top floor.
How do you know all this?
You know a guy, I know a guy.
Hey, you just worry about getting in.
There are two guard dogs
on free patrol.
The entrance has a fingerprint scan.
The lobby has video
surveillance and infrared.
This will get you through
the fingerprint scanner.
As soon as you go in,
I'll kill the infrareds,
but they're on an automatic reset.
You got 12 minutes to get in,
crack the safe, and get out.
The safe is a Xerxes XO series.
That's no problem.
It's not gonna be easy.
Nothing worthwhile ever is.
And then what?
And then you don't call me.
You don't e-mail me. Nothing.
Y'all are gonna have the cops,
the feds,
and the Ukrainian mafia after you.
I don't know you anymore.
You're having second thoughts?
No. No second thoughts.
We'll get it done.
These are your new documents.
You're married, by the way.
Mazel tov.
- Thanks for everything, Job.
- Don't mention it.
- No, I'm serious.
- I'm serious, too.
Don't you fucking mention it.
I don't care if they're
blowtorching your balls off.
You hear me?
I'll miss you.
Good.
Get the fuck out of here.
A direct assault is exactly
the wrong way to go here.
- Take it from someone who's tried.
- What do you suggest?
Blow the fucking place
to smithereens.
Nuh-uh. Too messy.
We got to be sure.
This is fucking suicide.
I'm coming.
Hey, you won't make it
to the lobby... Job.
Get back in bed.
Hey.
How am I gonna know
if you're dead?
You wake up tomorrow
and we're not here, we're dead.
Like I'm really gonna sleep tonight.
How we looking, Job?
Police bands are quiet.
I'm already into
the security system.
Copy.
Ana, come on.
- Hey.
- We don't have to do this.
- We can't back out now.
- Yes, we can.
I'll talk to my father.
I'll tell him about us.
He is never going to
let us be together.
You know this.
This is the only way.
Baby, I have a very bad
feeling about this.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Listen to me. It's gonna be okay.
I want to report
a robbery in progress
at the Capital Diamond warehouse.
211 Saw Mill River Road.
It's gonna be okay,
I promise you.
Tomorrow we're gonna be
Tom and Carrie Palmer.
We're gonna have
our entire lives ahead of us.
- Promise?
- Promise.
But right here, right now,
we have to do this, okay?
We have to.
You ready?
Yes.
Okay.
- Hello, Ana.
- Don't move!
I am unarmed.
- Layla.
- What?
You have her face.
- Almost exactly.
- Stay there.
I'd hoped to meet you
in friendlier circumstances.
Not likely with our family.
Where is he?
He is safe.
Whereas you, on the other hand,
are not.
When a family goes to war,
there can be no victory.
Him or us, right?
Damn straight.
Now!
- You okay?
- I'm out.
Me, too.
Hey, stick to the trees for at least
two miles. You'll be fine.
When I get up,
you run like hell
for the back of the church.
- No, I'm not leaving you.
- Listen to me! You do it!
What are you talking about?
Where are you going?
I'm gonna throw them off.
No.
You do it and you get
back to your family.
You hear me?
Don't do this.
- We can make it.
- Hey! Hey!
When I get up,
you run to the back.
Understand?
I'll catch up to you.
I'll be right behind you.
I love you.
No!
Whoo.
Seven guys with machine guns
and you're gonna stab them?
You really are
fucked in the head.
I almost didn't shoot 'em just so I
could see you try and pull that off.
Welcome to my life.
Hi, guys.
- I had it handled.
- The fuck you did.
So when did
you two hook up again?
Job tracked me down.
Motherfucker walked right into my
office with his gun out.
Looked like he was gonna pass out
right there on the floor.
You try getting a fucking
appointment with you.
How about we all go downtown,
get some breakfast?
You can tell me what
the fuck happened here.
I have a feeling it's gonna be a hell
of a story.
You have no idea.
This is one
fucked-up church.
He's not who we came for.
I'll make sure the cops
stay away for the time being.
- Buy you guys some time.
- Thanks.
Hey, soldier boy.
Still want to hear that story.
You will.
This time, make sure
he stay dead.
Come on, you crazy bald fuck.
I'll buy you some breakfast.
This could be the start
of a beautiful,
fucked-up friendship.
Morning.
The relentless Agent Racine.
I just figured I'd stop by.
See what you've been up to.
What's the expression?
"Same shit,
different day."
That's it, yeah.
I spent the night
at the 13th Precinct downtown.
They arrested some kid
who managed to break into
the Capital Diamond building.
It's not an easy
place to get into.
Kid would have gotten
away with it, too,
except someone
tipped off the cops.
I want to report a robbery
in progress
at the Capital Diamond
warehouse.
211 Saw Mill River Road.
I'm no expert,
but that sounds a lot
like a Ukrainian accent.
Doesn't it?
Yeah.
So I asked myself
how many Ukrainians do I know
who could report
a robbery in progress
before that robbery
was actually in progress?
And then I thought
Rabbit is Ukrainian.
Maybe he could point me
in the right direction.
So what do you say?
Can you...
point me in the right direction?
Go... now.
Yeah.
I had a feeling.
Well...
it was worth a try.
Agent Racine.
Someday I will lose my patience
and this wall between us...
the one you count on
to keep you safe...
it will come down.
That's what I'm hoping for.
Yulish?
- Is he dead?
- Yes.
- And now me?
There's a part of you that always
knows it will end like this.
Bullets and tears.
Yet you keep telling yourself
you will find a way out.
But there is no way out
because of who you are.
Sit with me.
Just for a minute.
Eternity can wait a bit longer.
I got married in this courtyard.
The band was over there.
Your mother...
she was so beautiful.
I couldn't stop shaking.
I thought I might pass out.
Just breathe.
Something in me broke
when she died.
Budmo.
I'm sorry, Anastasia.
I hope in death I can give you
some of the peace
I stole from you in life.
Time will tell.
Goodbye, Daddy.
You look at me and remember.
Somewhere in the future,
there is a bench just like this
waiting for you.
Go to hell.
Okay.
- Hello?
- You fucking bastard.
Anastasia.
I've been waiting for your call.
- You turned us in.
- You lied to me.
So what are you gonna do, huh?
Are you gonna kill
your own daughter?
No, you I forgive.
Well, I don't forgive you.
And I will tell your grandchild,
his child, who you
will never know,
what a sick fuck you were.
You're pregnant?
Fuck you.
Anastasia!
Look at that.
We made it.
Banshee.
It's kind of a strange name
for a town, don't you think?
No, it's just a town
like any other.
I think we're gonna be
very happy here.
Rabbit?
He's dead.
You sure?
Yes.
Well, then, good riddance.
What about Job?
He stayed in New York.
He's gonna look up
some old friends.
Figure out his next move.
It's gonna be strange
without him here.
Then again,
it's strange when he is here.
What about you?
What about me?
What happens now?
I've got to go see someone.
The deputy?
You sure about that?
Well, where would
we be without women to fuck us up?
Hmm?
I guess you came
back after all, huh?
I guess so.
How are things here?
Emmett left today.
Otherwise, all quiet.
Good.
That's good.
I just wanted you
to know that I'm back.
- See you at work tomorrow.
- Hey!
Why did you come here?
I needed to see you.
So say that.
Well, now you've seen me.
Yeah.
Well, what are you gonna do now?
It's okay.
- How did you get in here?
- I have my ways.
Do you have a message for me?
No.
So what can I do
for you, Amish girl?
I don't know.
What can you do for me?
There can be no question
of your loyalty.
There won't be.
Is that a knife or are you just
happy to see me?
You stupid bitch.
You really think
you can come in here and kill me?
Huh?
Are you really
that fucking crazy?
You can't kill me,
you stupid cunt.
I'm the Thunder Man!
I didn't realize
we'd crossed the state line.
Yeah, about 10 miles ago.
It already feels better,
you know? Safer.
I think this is gonna
turn out to be the best decision
we've ever made.
Go! Go! Go!
I've got all the thunder I need.
I was expecting Burton
to come pick me up.
What happened?
He's tying up some
loose ends for us.
What loose ends?
Who did this?
I did.
For you.
Till next time.
Hey, Deva.
Hello, Dad.
One, two, three, four!
Hell, yeah, bitch!
One, two, three!
Yeah!
This is Chayton.
What is it?
Alex Longshadow is dead.
Pack up.
Where we going?
Home.