Mayor Bader, what do you
have to say about all the recent violence?
We have men in the field, boys.
Sheriff's Department is on it.
When will some arrests be made?
- Any day now.
- Have you lost control of the city?
There's no need for wild accusations.
- But the bodies are piling up.
- Eleven murders and counting.
- That's a statement, not a question.
- Have you lost control of the city?
Sheriff Keck and his men are taking
every possible measure
- to ensure public safety.
- Have you lost control?
- We absolutely have not.
Is that what you want the tourists to believe?
The everyday visitor has nothing to fear.
Nothing to fear except gunfire.
These attacks are
gangsters versus gangsters
and ordinary citizens have
no cause for undue concern.
So you admit this town you claim to control
is in the hands of criminals?
- Where they from?
- New York? Philly?
- New York? Philly? Chicago?
- They Italians?
- One at a time, please. One at a time.
Are they the ones behind
the shootings at The Ritz?
Now, once again, that is the kind
of irresponsible exaggeration...
- What about the North Side killings?
- Are the Negroes involved?
- If you let me get a word in...
- Where's Nucky Thompson?
- Mr. Thompson...
- Is he pulling the strings?
- Is he alive or dead?
Let's get something straight.
Nucky Thompson doesn't run this city. I do.
Right!
REPORTER 23 That's a riot.
I left you nine messages at The Ritz.
I'm completely in the dark out here.
- They don't have papers in Pennsylvania?
- Did I miss something?
- I'm fighting a war from a fucking lumberyard.
- Now see? This is all new information.
- Are you at Overholt?
- I've been here for five days.
And?
- Don't you know what you got here'?
- I've never been near the place.
Then you need to come see it.
I can't make it down the block
without getting shot at.
That's too bad.
'Cause it's worth the trip.
What the fuck are you trying to tell me?
Well, I'm no expert,
but this place gets cooking,
you're the biggest bootlegger in the country.
- Did you hear me?
- I'll call you back.
What the fuck is going on?
Break it up. I said break it up!
- Hey, get off! Get off!
- You bastard!
- You promised to keep a lid on this.
- Got to blow off steam some kind of ways.
He gave his word they'd
stay on their own side.
How they supposed to get to the head?
Dig a hole. Why's it my problem?
How about I give you the shovel
and you do the digging?
Chalky, enough.
Okay?
Let's get something straight.
I need him and I need those men.
Maybe I ought to take my boys and go home.
Fine, call Torrio. Tell him the deal's off.
No, the deal's with me.
Then what's a handshake
with you supposed to be worth?
We'll head to the Boardwalk,
down by Margate.
See if we can get Rosetti
to stick his head out.
You need to watch out for civilians.
No, we need to watch out for ourselves.
The rest is for you to clean up.
Get your bingo-bongos to help.
Come on, we're going hunting.
You were all told to lay off the supply.
The whores are gone. The fuck we supposed
to do if we can't have a drink?
Keep sober so you don't
get taken out next time.
If I'm gonna catch it, I'd rather be tight.
- You want the boss to hear you say that?
- What the fuck do I care anymore?
No wine.
Forget about it.
I no come all this way to have a drink.
Keep everyone away from here.
Let's go.
How many men I give you?
- Exactly?
- Exactly.
- Forty-three.
- Huh.
And how many of my men you have left?
Exactly?
Thirty-one. Plus nine of my own.
So 12 of my men you lose. And for what?
I got the hotel.
I got the casino.
I got his warehouse.
You no have Nucky Thompson.
Huh? And Arnold Rothstein,
he's still eating dinner in Times Square.
All these words you say, what do they mean?
I'm leaving bodies on the ground, Joe.
We're winning.
And half of Thompson's crew, they're shines.
You can't count them as a whole person.
Kid...
They are from here.
So?
This is their home.
That's why they fight.
And the other ones, who are they?
What does it matter once they're dead?
Everyone dies.
Not everyone keeps their promises.
I'm gonna keep mine.
Hmm.
Ah.
Perfect.
Now you know what time it is.
Let's go, boys.
I'd like to go in, please.
Such a gentleman.
Not always.
Dear. I have your lunch.
It's your favorite.
Ham on white bread. A dill pickle.
And Oreos if you finish everything.
Aren't you hungry?
Why don't you come out
and we'll eat together?
Would you like that?
Then I'll come in and sit with you.
That way, it won't be so lonely.
Yes.
All right, darling.
I understand.
Harry, come on, we gotta go!
I'll get my jacket.
Hey, who's gonna do the cookin' today?
Hey, Jimmy,
you hear the game last night?
Here. It's good for another scrape.
- I'm in the middle of this.
- What happened?
Slug straight through the radiator.
- And the hose is shot.
- I'll do that after.
- You're gonna get all dirty.
- Who kept that old Willys of yours running?
- Who sold it to me in the first place?
- Wasn't anything wrong with it.
Except for the brakes,
rear axle, cylinder heads.
Worked well enough to get you
and June lost in the woods.
Yeah, those were nice rides.
You got them someplace safe?
With her sister up in Brigantine.
- You?
- How's that?
Margaret and the kids.
OW! Shit!
Fuck.
What are you laughing about?
Who said I'm laughing?
Look at us.
Two Pineys and a broke-down car.
- Maybe that's why.
- Why what?
We didn't stop while the going was good.
Always trying to pinch for a little bit more.
Just in case.
I never told them to pass
the 18th Amendment.
Did you?
Where's it gotten us?
Worry about that later.
After Rosetti's in the ground.
- Then what?
- Get the town running again.
Keep everybody in line this time.
Leave that part to me.
- Stop kidding yourself, Eli.
- You'll never be Sheriff again.
You got to rub my face in it? Hmm?
After all this?
That's not what I meant.
It's over here however this plays out.
No one's gonna come within 100 yards of me.
Not in Atlantic City. Not in New York.
- Not anywhere.
- Sure they will.
You just got to offer
them something they want.
How do I do that?
I don't know.
You're the man with all the angles.
- Mr. Doyle.
- Am I disturbing you?
Yes.
Oh, all right.
I know you didn't want to talk to me again.
It's just... I'm all at sea over here.
And, uh, where is it you've gone adrift?
I'm saying three words.
Overholt. Distillery. Pennsylvania.
I know about Overholt, Mr. Doyle.
What I don't is why you
wish to discuss it with me.
Because I'm sitting in it
right now.
It's
very large.
And a certain person that we both know
made an arrangement
with another person to run it.
But that first person, his back is to the wall.
I bet he'd give up anything
just to keep from going under for a third time.
I'm listening.
How'd you get that scar?
Mulberry Bend. You know where that is?
- Sure.
- Bandit's Alley.
Little shit came up behind me
one night with a shank,
carved me another smile.
It's a park now. Push your baby in a stroller.
Pricks like you, they come and go.
Nobody remembers them.
All that stays is the law.
Then I guess I'd better reform my ways.
- Who's your partner?
- Nobody.
Who do you buy from?
- Some chink.
- Which one?
Fuck do I know?
Name sounds like a toothache.
Who put up the money?
My sister.
She lifted it from your wallet
while she was yanking your ghianda.
There's something you don't understand.
You think you get some shyster,
walk out of here, beat the rap?
You could disappear.
You said there was the law.
We are the law.
What if...
What if I tell you where you
could find 50 pounds of white?
Yours?
- Why would I give up my own stash?
- To save your ass.
- Is that what you're offering?
- Nobody is offering anything.
Then what's in it for me?
You like to gamble, don't you?
Only when I got a chance of winning.
Best you could do here is not lose.
I got the broad here.
Please show her in.
That's all right. Thank you.
May I sit?
It's your house.
You don't have to ask permission.
Must be hard to be away from your girls.
Huh?
Your two daughters.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
At that age,
you take off for a few days, you miss so much.
- How old are they?
- Sixteen and 14, I think.
- Tommy's only six.
- Six.
Got his whole life ahead of him.
I've tried to shelter him from harsh realities.
It hasn't been easy.
Hey.
Don't get so down on yourself.
You're doing a swell job.
There's always company around here.
Kids love that.
Maybe...
Maybe it's best we let you
conduct your business
without distractions.
Don't see what you're getting at.
That Tommy and I go someplace else.
Just for a bit.
Yeah.
I don't think I want that.
Why not?
I like having you around.
If I didn't know where you were,
I might get anxious.
You don't have to worry about me.
Jeez, Red, I hope not.
This is gonna work out. You'll see.
Get everything settled,
then you and me,
we'll show this town how it's done.
You and me?
Set you up fine.
Best of everything.
All this grief running whores,
you won't need to bother.
I'm gonna treat you like a queen.
Would you?
Up there on a pedestal.
And where are you?
I'm way down below.
Like a little bug crawling around on your toe.
I could crush you.
Just squash me flat
till I'm begging for more.
Is that what you'd like?
I'm just having some fun.
People have fun in different ways.
There's no need
to be ashamed of any of them.
That's what this club is all about.
You're a pistol, Red.
Then why don't you pull my trigger
and see what shoots out?
I don't know about you, Gyp,
but sometimes,
I wish someone
would give me exactly
what I deserve.
- Hello?
- This is Arnold Rothstein.
To whom am I speaking?
Eli Thompson.
I was hoping to speak to your brother.
It's him.
Arnold.
- I'm calling with an offer.
- How did you get this number?
Is that important?
No.
Your distillery in Pennsylvania.
- Overholt.
- For a percentage of ownership,
I can arrange for Joe Masseria
to back away from Gyp Rosetti.
"Back away" meaning what?
That he completely pulls his support,
removes all of his men.
How much of a percentage?
Ninety-nine,
Mr. Thompson.
I will require 99%.
I'm offering you a way out.
If I can deliver Masseria,
do we have a deal?
Yes.
You'll be hearing from me later.
Big bait catches big rat.
- Have you lived here long, Mrs. Hollis?
- I'd say it's 16 years.
Spring of '07. So, yes, just 16.
Harold wanted to be somewhere he felt
he could be of the most use.
I can't say I didn't have
other ambitions in mind.
But we stayed, and I think
that turned out to be the right decision.
You live...
Over on Scholes Street. By Graham.
You've got everything you need there.
It's not far from the rest of my family.
Harold has a sister in Bushwick.
Well, dear?
- Why don't you show Mrs...
- Rohan.
Mrs. Rohan the room
and she can make her decision.
I'll just tend to a few things.
Would you like to?
- I would, yes.
- All right.
This is where my husband sees people.
Coughs, cuts, fevers,
indigestion, everything.
I need to bring my monthly on.
When was your last?
- Six weeks.
- He can help you then.
He does that for many women.
He's very careful. Very thorough.
You can take a little time.
Come back if that's what you'd like.
I'm lost.
I'm completely lost.
I never tell anyone what to do.
Do I leave my dress on?
I'll get you a clean gown.
You're looking at this the wrong way.
The bulls collared me, all right?
But I worked out an angle.
I'm not doing time. And no one's the wiser.
We just pick up where we left off.
And I'll cover the hit.
I will, Meyer. I guarantee it.
Out of my pocket.
- You're not gonna say nothing?
-50 pounds.
One hundred thousand
fucking dollars.
- Gentlemen.
- Let's get this over with.
What the fuck?
Salvatore...
I'm glad to see you're alright.
And you.
I sorry. I never know your name.
Meyer.
"Maya."
Is that ours?
Not anymore.
Charlie, Meyer, thank you for coming.
I won't keep you very long
since you have such full
portions on your plates.
What's that doing here?
I had it delivered
so that Mr. Masseria could see
that I'm as good as my word.
The two of you?
Have agreed to new terms of peace
given the change in circumstances.
What change?
That this heroin
that I paid for with my fucking money,
now belongs to him.
A.R., if I may inquire,
how did you obtain that?
Charlie gave it to my associates.
Sam, Gaetano, if you would.
How you doing, kid?
We treat you too rough?
You can always
file a complaint with the department.
He set me up, Joe.
You fucking set me up.
Who the fuck do you think you are?
- Charlie. Charlie.
- I worked for that.
I busted my ass for that.
It was my idea! My deal!
- Charlie.
- You wouldn't lift a finger.
Sit behind your desk, making phone calls.
I'm out there in the fucking world.
Charlie, if you don't shut up,
we're both dead. Yes?
A.R., Mr. Masseria,
you know how he gets.
All this time
I thought I'd had some civilizing effect.
But there's only so much
you can teach a person
until you reach the limits of his capabilities.
- You understand, though, don't you, Meyer?
- Yes, I do.
Then it's your job then if you want it.
Seeing as how I'm flush with product,
I'd like to offer a proposition.
How would you like to join me
in the heroin business?
In exchange for what?
- Son of a bitch.
- Dirty fucking shines.
Hey, what the fuck do you think you're doing?
Can't be too hard to figure out.
Give you a better view.
Just back it up, pal. Okay?
I don't know about you, once I let loose,
there ain't no stopping.
Yeah, get you some of that.
I can help you with that.
And me with both hands full.
Ain't that just like a dinge?
Going out with his dick swinging.
Come on, Joe.
Sure do like to reach for that pistol.
What you so scared about?
Nothing I'm looking at now.
Let's see what you're made of.
MANI Chalky!
Let him go. Come on.
I just hung up with Arnold Rothstein.
Gyp Rosetti's at the Artemis Club.
Joe Masseria is withdrawing his support.
I know that, Rosetti doesn't.
- How'd that happen?
- I paid for it.
I need to talk to you and you in private.
You can kill each other later.
In the meantime, let's plan this out.
Talk about this later.
Do YOU approve?
- You're class all the way, Red.
- I'm here to please you.
All you have to do is say the word.
Only I do that.
Little kink of mine.
I like a man who's careful
about his appearance.
Well? What is it you're intending to do to me?
- You really want to know?
- I can't wait.
I'm gonna break you in half.
Split you right down the middle
till you beg me to stop. But I won't stop.
Beg and beg, but there's nothing you can do.
And when I'm done,
there won't be nothing left but a wet spot
and a hunk of hair.
You know why?
Tell me.
You're a worthless piece of shit.
- Am I?
- You know you are.
You look in the mirror
and you know you deserve
everything you're gonna get.
I'm ugly, aren't I?
Just an ugly little animal.
- Say it again.
- Ugly...
little...
ape.
You laughing at me?
Why wouldn't I?
Everybody else does.
Go ahead if that's what you want.
Would you like me to whip you?
That's not tight enough, is it?
- No.
- Not for an ape like you.
No.
You need to be held down.
So you don't run off into the jungle.
What do you say?
- Hurt me.
- Hurt me what?
Hurt me, please.
Oh, Red, here I just thought
we were having some fun.
All I have is this house and that boy.
I don't blame you, Red. I really don't.
But the thing of it is,
somebody's always got to lose.
That car ready?
What the fuck?
Where they going?
What the fuck is going on?
Hey!
Hey, where the fuck is everybody?
- They're gone.
- Gone where?
New York. Masseria's orders.
Get down!
No,no,no!
Go!
- Where's Tonino?
- Fuck him, let's go.
Put the gun down.
Do you think I give a fuck?
Put it down.
Put it down!
Tommy, close your eyes.
Here comes Masseria's boys.
And here they go.
Die, you fucking cowards!
That's for you, sons of bitches!
Well, I got that out of my system.
You and me both.
Come on. Back to Chicago.
Jesus Christ.
God.
Jesus.
Who did this?
You came.
Where's Rosetti?
I was good. I did what...
I went upstairs like you said to.
- What?
- And the man...
The man, he...
Nucky. He did something very bad to me.
Who is it?
- Who's there?
- Me.
Don't turn on the light.
Why? What happened?
- Richard, are you all right?
- Neither of us are hurt.
What does that mean?
It's not our blood.
Then whose is it?
Take the boy. Go on.
Upstairs. Fred's room.
- I need to know what's going on.
- Just take him up.
Julia, please.
And turn off that lamp.
Did anyone see you pull up?
You don't come home like this.
Whatever battle you're fighting.
That's not what a soldier does.
You need to clean yourself up.
- I'll talk to her, and in the light of day...
- No.
He's safe. That's all that matters.
Randolph. Hello?
- This is Andrew Mellon.
- Is it really?
Why would I claim otherwise?
Are you in a location
where your conversation might be overheard?
- No one can hear me, sir.
- Then I have a request.
It has come to my attention
that a certain business enterprise of mine,
in the absence of my full attention,
has been illicitly commandeered
by a criminal organization.
What enterprise, sir?
The Overholt Distillery
in western Pennsylvania.
I don't understand what you want me to do.
Shutter the premises.
Apprehend and indict anyone
associated with its illegal operation.
You want me to arrest Enoch Thompson?
It was Mr. Thompson
who brought this illegality to my attention.
Then who are we talking about?
- Arnold...
- Rothstein.
- Made it out.
- Hiding in the closet.
Whatever you had to do.
That guy with the mask,
what the fuck was that?
Can't go to New York.
Not gonna be too welcome there.
So, just a suggestion,
we lay low in the woods.
The, what do you call, the Poconos.
Get our bearings, fresh air,
figure out our next move.
Relax, it's a party.
Huh?
I'm making a big decision.
From now on,
I'm only selling hooch every other Thursday.
Because I have important friends.
I'm an important person.
I have important
garters holding up my very important socks.
Do you have any idea who the fuck I am?
Do you?
- You're Nucky Thompson.
- I'm Barney Google.
With the goo-goo-googly eyes.
And I never, ever take anything personal.
Fuck 'em all, huh?
I came here with nothing.
How do you lose what you never had?
Start over.
What this country's all about, right?
So we head west.
Find some hick burg.
Blow 'em right over. How hard could that be?
Couple of speaks, truck in some girls,
keep the whole operation nice and tight.
And maybe I don't tell the wife, huh?
Yeah. Maybe I just do that.
Barney Google
with the goo-goo-googly eyes
bet his horse would win the prize
When the horses ran that day
Spark Plug ran the other way
Barney Google
I'm sorry. I gotta.
It's done.
Take him back to Masseria.
Let him know this
could be the end of the problems between us.
Or the beginning.
I'll oblige him either way.
Is that clear?
Tonino, I see you in Atlantic City again,
I'll kill you myself.
I don't want anyone knowing who I am.
I don't want anyone looking into my business.
I don't want anyone coming near us
we don't already trust.
Okay, brother.
I just want to talk.
That's all.
Can we do that?
I'm not going to... I would never hurt you.
I'm your husband.
I'm the only father Teddy and Emily have.
I'm willing to forgive you
for whatever happened in the past.
For whatever you felt a need to do.
I forgive you. And it's time to come home.
To submit yourself to this?
Out of what, spite?
It doesn't make sense.
Your life is with me.
You're spoiled for anything else.
You need to ask yourself
how much you're willing to sacrifice
just to prove some point
that doesn't matter to anyone.
Nobody's watching now. Nobody's judging.
Take this for the children.
Or take it for yourself.
You don't have to pretend with me.
Take it and decide later.
This is only money. It doesn't mean anything.
Yes, it does.
Say.
Say, you're Nucky Thompson, aren't you?