I'll make it up to you.
I've got a hook up with a guy
who'll get us a table at Mozza.
I'll call you tonight, baby.
Please, baby. I know a guy.
Remember to get us a gas card,
or you too busy making plans
to get your ashes
hauled when you get back?
See, Harry, if you wasn't
such a fuckin' monk,
you'd know what it's like out there.
It takes a lot of maintenance.
Yes, I got the gas card.
Then let's get goin' or we're
crossin' the desert at high noon.
Hold up. Bosch.
When?
Send him back.
- Nash.
- Wants to tell us he solved the case?
Hm.
Carl.
Wish you'd called.
Gettin' ready to hit the road for Vegas.
- Picking up your guy?
- The extradition hearing's
first thing tomorrow morning.
Yeah, that's sort of why I came in
- if you've got a minute.
- A minute, sure.
Yeah. Someplace private?
Grab a seat.
Yeah, the other day...
when you were asking
me about Tony Allen...
Yeah.
What's on your mind?
What'd you leave out?
Okay. About six months
ago I'm doing my rounds.
It's a nice evening, windows down,
I roll past the Allen's house,
I hear voices.
An argument. Two men, sounds
like it could get out of hand.
So you thought you'd check it out.
Yeah. So I park. I walk down
the side of the Allen's house,
Allen and this other guy are in...
looks like a home office, goin' at it.
What about? Could you tell?
Money.
The other guy's like,
"Where's my money, Tone?"
over and over, and Allen's like,
"Oh, I wouldn't do that to ya, I swear."
Other guy, he sign in at the gate?
I checked the log. There were no
visitors for the Allens that night.
So he must have come in with Tony.
So why are you tellin' me this now?
You said there'd been
an arrest in Vegas.
I was... started thinkin', yeah,
we talked about made guys, mob guys.
I just remembered this guy
Allen had the fight with.
I mean, he had that
vibe, the, you know...
- Vegas wise guy.
- Absolutely, definitely.
Mobster all the way.
Think you could pick
him out of a six pack?
Yeah, I think I could.
Follow me.
Nah. It's none of these guys.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
That's the guy. That's the guy!
You sure about that?
No doubt.
Okay, we'll check it out.
- Really appreciate it, Carl.
- Thanks.
Am I... Am I right? He's a made guy?
We talk to him, we'll
ask him about that.
Okay. I... I should shove off.
- Uh, good luck in Vegas.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
- Thanks for coming in.
Yeah, safe travel.
Joey Marks.
We got time for this?
Check In's not 'til 3:00.
Is it worth it? We got Rykoff.
On a platter.
Your Christmas pig. Courtesy of the FBI.
Feds got it all worked out.
Rykoff will give them Marks,
and Marks will give them
something on the Russians.
And that will give them something
on their counter terrorism thing.
- Exactly.
- Still want to find this Layla,
ask her what she knows.
Yeah, this is all residential.
Yeah, and Tony wrote it off
on his taxes as an office.
I dig this. What is this?
Sonny Rollins and Miles Davis
on Miles' album "Bag's Groove."
Sweet. What's it called?
"Doxy." Sonny wrote it.
- You know a lot about this stuff.
- A little.
Ever listen to anything
written in this century?
Still catching up on the last one.
Pull over, this is it.
Some office.
This is the life, huh, Harry.
Where did we go wrong? I mean,
we could be out here poolside
hangin' with these fine ladies.
You sure you guys don't need a warrant?
We're checking on her well-being, sir.
She was romantically involved
with a man who was murdered recently.
Murdered? That's awful.
Just making sure she's okay.
Of course. Hope to God she's all right.
Last time you saw here?
Ten days, two weeks.
Something like that.
How'd she pay the rent?
Direct deposit, first of the month.
I wouldn't be expecting
a deposit next month.
Yeah, it doesn't look
like she's comin' back.
Did she fill out an
application before she moved in?
Credit check, rental history.
We're gonna want to take a look at that.
I have it in the office.
We'll stop on the way out. Thanks.
When are we gonna interview
the girls at the pool, Harry?
Left dirty dishes.
Cell phone.
No wonder we couldn't
locate it. She killed it.
Smart.
What are those?
They're in Armenian. Religious, maybe.
Little girl, Layla? Grandma, maybe?
That's not L.A. for sure.
That's the old country.
Remember me?
Ah, you're one of the
assholes who busted Lucky.
We're looking for Layla.
- Knock on her door?
- Cut the shit.
- You know she's gone.
- Where'd she go?
No idea.
Soon as she heard Tony was dead,
- outta here.
- You see her go?
- Nope.
- So how'd you know?
Her car was gone. Poof.
Where would she go from here?
Now that her guardian angel's gone,
who the fuck knows.
Why would you call him that?
She worked in this
shit hole in North Vegas
with some other foreign girls.
Not a nice place. Tony
pulled her out of there.
A brothel.
I'd call it a cat house, but hey.
Yeah, still waiting on details.
- What time?
- Uh, tonight.
They said they'd let me know.
And this woman, Mo.
Yeah, I've been workin' on that.
Matched her face to a name.
Maureen O'Grady.
Vice cop. Mission Division.
Good work.
Yeah, well, it's a start.
We'll see who shows up
to the party tonight.
When do you see Lyle next?
Day after tomorrow.
You doin' okay with all of this?
No, I'm good.
I, um... I know it's been hard for you.
To make your own way in the department,
find yourself, get out
from under my shadow.
Uh, well, you know, I think I've got
a really good shot of
doing that with this gig.
You know, if I could just
get to the head of that snake.
I'm confident you will.
Well, thanks.
This look like a North
Vegas shit hole to you?
Yeah, the previous
address on her rental App.
Bet there's no pool.
Everybody sit tight.
We're looking for this girl, Layla.
She used to work here, live here?
_
Anybody know where she
is? We need to talk to her.
_
You work for Joey
Marks. This is his place.
This is my place.
Hey, get the fuck outta here. Go. Now.
Look, you want to tell me fairytales,
I got nothin' better to do.
We can stay here all day,
and you can explain to Joey Marks
where all his business went.
The girl you look for, Layla,
she not been here a long time.
- Couple years.
- Where'd she go?
She's dancer. Probably strip club.
- Dolly's?
- She meet customer.
_
Customer?
Customer fall in love with Lilliat.
Lilliat? Is that her real name?
Lilliat Saroyan.
Lilliat Saroyan. You know where she is?
I do not know. Please, leave now.
_
That was fucking depressing.
What do you think, they traffic?
Someone should talk to those women,
find out if they're free to leave,
and who's got their passports.
Joey Marks?
It's his place, I'll
reach out to Felton,
let them handle it.
How do people live out here?
It's a fuckin' desert.
L.A.'s a desert.
- With an ocean.
- It's still a desert.
I thought you loved L.A.
I do, but I know what it is.
Hmm.
Hey, how about some new shades?
Ray Bans?
Retro girl. Take after your dad.
I hope so.
Look, there's Monocle Optical.
Let's take the stairs.
It's on the third floor.
We can use the exercise.
I get lots of exercise.
Yeah, your thumbs look really
strong from all that texting.
Ha, ha. Very funny.
- Thumb war?
- No way.
Hey.
Oh.
Anything else?
Oh, I got my Krispy
Kremes, coffee, good to go.
- Have a good day, officer.
- All right.
Asshole.
Hey, you've reached George.
Leave a message. Call you back.
Hey, uh, call me when you
get a chance, will you?
Your mother wants to know what
your plans are for tonight.
Did you happen to check
out your groovy little case?
I know. It has a little
cleaner in there, too.
Always important.
Do we want to get coffee?
- Yeah.
- On the way out?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Okay.
Good.
Hey, I thought this new contract
was supposed to guarantee
us separate accommodations?
It does. Somebody fucked up.
Could be worse. Could be
bunking with Crate or Barrel.
Yeah.
Hey, Jerry, what color
is your toothbrush?
Blue. Why?
No reason.
Seeing the family tonight?
Yeah. Come with.
No, I thought I'd hit the Spearmint.
Hearing's at 9:00.
I'll be there.
Hey, honey.
Maddie?
- Daddy.
- Maddie, what's wrong?
Maddie, what's going on?
I'm supposed to... I'm
supposed to tell you
that Mom and I are both okay,
- and that...
- Maddie. Maddie!
Don't make this difficult.
- Who is this?
- Harry.
- What do you want?
- Don't call the police.
If you harm them, I will tear
your teeth out, you son of a bitch.
- And you...
- Harry, what's wrong?
What the fuck's going on?
Harry, what's going on?
Maddie and Eleanor have been kidnapped.
Who? Why?
I don't know. Marks.
Shit. We gotta call Vegas Metro.
No! No. No fuckin' police.
- They said no police.
- They always say that.
Look, until I know
what I'm dealing with,
I'm not taking any chances.
Fuck this.
This isn't our town. We don't
even know where to begin.
I do.
Where you going?
Eleanor's.
She's got an App. Tracks Maddie's phone.
Just don't kill us before we get there.
Clear upstairs. Laptop.
Kitchen.
Clear!
Harry, got it.
It's password protected.
Try AKQJ10.
Zero-1-1-0-0-1.
- Got it. What was that?
- Maddie's birthday.
Scroll up.
Right there. Open.
It's a home security system. Rewind.
Fast forward.
Play.
Oh. You motherfuckers,
I'm gonna kill you both.
The tracking App. The pin will
tell us where her phone's at.
They would have turned
it off after she called.
Shit.
History log can pinpoint
where she was when she called.
- There.
- Kyle Canyon Road off 157.
It's 20 miles from here at least.
It's getting dark.
Nice ride.
It's a loaner.
Jerry!
It's Maddie's phone.
There's a duffel back there.
Hmm.
Da-dosh.
What the fuck is this?
That? That's a can opener.
Saddle up, cowboy.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, where these from?
- What the fuck do you care?
- I want to know.
They're clean, all right?
There were used in a multitude
of felonies, but not by us.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, where we goin', anyway?
Drop house on Fig.
Pick up's once a week.
That's tomorrow.
And tonight is gonna be fatter
than a super gordo burrito.
You're crowd control, Junior.
Anybody comes near you, lay
that fire down. You feel me?
Yeah, I feel ya, Mo.
I feel you.
- Bosch.
- Detective.
- Who is this?
- Doesn't matter.
You tell Marks anyone
lays a hand on my family,
a single scratch, and I'll kill you all.
Burn you to the fucking ground.
Keep your cool, detective,
and nothing will happen to anybody.
I'm listening.
Tomorrow morning after the hearing,
Rykoff will be in your custody.
You're going to deliver him to us.
And if I do that,
how are you gonna deliver
my family back to me?
Do exactly as we say.
There is a truck stop just
before the California border.
Off 15 in Primm.
Pull in for gas.
Thank the Nevada State
Patrol for their escort,
and send them on their way.
Tell your partner to
go inside for coffee.
While you fill the tank,
certain things will happen.
Rykoff will come with us.
The ladies will go free.
Good.
Marks wants to trade Rykoff
for Maddie and Eleanor.
He's afraid Rykoff's gonna flip.
Must be to pull this shit.
Rykoff must have something heavy.
We gotta call Vegas Metro.
No. No cops.
You don't want to call the
local, let's call the Feds.
Fuck the Feds.
This is my family.
Watch the street.
Oh, shit!
Down on the floor!
What? Let's hit it. Go!
Whoa. Go!
- Go, go, go.
- Go on. Go!
Shit!
Oh!
Go! Go!
Goddammit.
Marks.
His people kidnapped
my ex wife and daughter.
Now he says he won't hurt
them if I turn you over to him.
Bullshit, you wouldn't do that.
You got one play here.
You give me something,
anything that gets my family back,
or I swear to God, I'll hand you
over to Joey Marks in a heartbeat.
Who are these mutts?
Brothers.
Samoans, Tom, Jerry.
Call 'em that 'cause nobody can
pronounce their fuckin' names.
Where do I find them?
Safe house in the
desert. Tooley Springs.
Sometimes use it for shit like this.
You tell me how to get there.
- Hello.
- Lieutenant Lyle, Deputy Chief Irving.
- Chief.
- I'm tracking my son's phone.
Has he checked in with you yet?
He's following protocol, sir.
I left him a message earlier today,
he never got back to me.
No cause for concern, chief.
I expect to hear from him
first thing in the morning.
We're tracking him, too.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
I can't see shit.
They're in there.
On the couch, front room.
- Samoans?
- Yeah.
Watchin' TV.
One's strapped. The
other one I can't tell.
I got an idea.
Ah, what is this shit now?
Like that's gonna help.
I can't see through your stomach, bra.
Maybe it's the wind again.
Go check the dish.
And take your fuckin' gun.
Tom or Jerry?
- Tom.
- Who's in the house?
- My brother.
- Anyone else?
What's he carrying?
A .44.
You move, you die.
Get on the fucking floor nice and slow.
Clear!
We're okay. We're okay.
We're okay.
- Daddy.
- It's okay, baby, it's okay.
It's okay.
Whatcha doin', Harry?
I'm calling Felton, have
him come take out the trash.
Okay, wait. Before you do that,
- can I speak to you?
- Okay.
Okay, I'll be right
back. I'll be right back.
Okay?
- You got this, Jerry?
- I got this.
All right.
It's just... I just...
I can't stop shaking.
It's okay. It's okay.
Shh, shh. It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
I don't... I don't want
you to call the cops, okay?
Eleanor, you can't let these pigs walk
after what they did to
you and our daughter.
Our daughter cannot be a witness.
- Not against Joey Marks.
- We can protect her.
No. You're gonna have to
find another way, okay?
'Cause I'm not gonna testify,
and I'm not gonna let her testify.
Okay, but you and Maddie have to
get out of Vegas by tomorrow morning.
- And go where?
- L.A. My place.
Until this blows over.
Okay.
Jerry.
Take Eleanor and Maddie to the car.
Gotta stop off at their
place and get some stuff
before we go back to the hotel.
Harry.
Go on. I won't be long.
You put a gun to my daughter's head.
Top lock sticks a little.
I'll figure it out.
Extradition hearing is this morning.
We're on the road by noon back to L.A.
I'm home by dinner.
Great. I hope nothing
happens before then.
Eleanor.
Nothing's gonna happen.
Billets is gonna send some cops
to pick you up at the airport,
and take you to my place.
They'll look in on you later.
Okay. Okay.
Dad, please come with us, Dad.
- Honey, I can't.
- No, Dad, please.
Honey, I can't.
There are some things I have to do.
I promise you,
none of those people will
ever bother you again.
Do you believe me?
Okay.
Now, look, your mother's very upset,
and she has every right to be,
but I would never knowingly
put you in harm's way.
I hope you know that.
I know that.
Just like I knew you'd come back for us.
I'll be home tonight.
We need to get through security.
Eleanor, there's a Glock
in the record cabinet,
and a 12 Gauge on the top
shelf in my bedroom closet.
I just want you to know where they are.
Okay?
Okay.
Detective Bosch.
I'm Dave Warren representing Mr. Rykoff.
Before we waive extradition...
What? You're not fighting it?
Well, what would be the point?
You got the murder weapon
and you tied it to my client.
How it got there and who put it there
is a matter for another day.
I need some assurances about the
security of his transport to L.A.
We'll drive straight through, no stops.
That's what I wanted to hear.
Docket 6-2-0-5, State
versus Lucas Rykoff.
Thank you, Tess.
This matter is an extradition hearing.
- Is the State ready?
- The State is ready, Judge.
David Warren representing the defendant.
Your Honor, if I may,
at this time the defendant
wishes to waive his right
to contest extradition to
the state of California.
So noted. Tess, what's next.
Be right with you.
Harry.
Yes, sir.
Uh, yes sir, this afternoon,
as soon as he's processed...
Hey.
Marks.
You ever come near my family again,
I'll cut your strings and
leave you drooling in a chair.
I don't suppose you're gonna tell me
what happened last night, huh?
You're right, I'm not. Let's go.
Bosch.
We ran that vehicle search
on Lilliat Saroyan, got a hit.
2012 Altima registered to this address.
Tony Allen's Vegas office.
You lookin' for the car?
We found it. Been in
our impound for a week.
She left it at the Greyhound station.
Shit. She could be anywhere.
Oh, we'll process it for
prints in case she surfaces.
- Thanks.
- All right, detective, remember our deal.
Partners on Rykoff.
He starts giving up secrets on Marks,
I'm your first phone call.
Right.
Nevada trooper will give
you a courtesy escort
- to the state line.
- Appreciate it.
What are you so happy about?
Why shouldn't I be?
First degree murder
indictment doesn't worry you?
Man, I got an alibi.
We heard different.
I got no motive to kill Tony Allen.
Joey Marks told you to.
That was your motive.
My lawyer's gonna shred
that search warrant,
and he's gonna shred you, Bosch,
for planting that fucking gun.
That gun gets kicked, I'm home free.
If that happens, which
it won't, then what?
As far as Joey Marks is
concerned, you're dead,
wherever you are, the
streets or in the joint.
- Unless you cooperate.
- Fuck you.
Rykoff, Luke.
Extradition out of Vegas on a 1-87.
Kiko, I want him put on keep-away
status, 100 percent isolation.
All right, when the
sheriff's come to pick him up,
make sure they know to put
him in protective custody
on a John Doe lodging.
Harry.
Not now, Mank, I gotta get home.
Billets wants to see you immediately,
as soon as his feet
hit the premises, APB.
- Pretend you didn't see me.
- I can't do it, buddy.
Bring me the head of Hieronymus Bosch.
Her exact fuckin' words.
Ah, shit.
Lieutenant.
You were just gonna leave
without giving me a full report.
I need to get home. My
family's waiting for me.
How are they?
Well, they were pretty shaky
when I took them to the
airport this morning.
Well, I can understand.
I can also understand why certain
decisions were made in haste last night.
- I appreciate that.
- But...
- Okay.
- You need to talk to Eleanor.
Get her to file on these thugs.
Letting them walk is a mistake,
and I am compromised
because you told me about it.
She isn't gonna change her mind.
They belong in prison.
Look, no way Joey Marks is
gonna let those guys skate
after screwing this up.
They will get what is coming to them.
Do you really want the full report?
No, I do not.
I just hope this doesn't come
back to bite us all in the ass.
It won't.
Go be with your family.
Thanks, Grace.
- Dad. - Whoa, what are you
people doing in my house?
Hey, how you guys settling in?
- In the spare room.
- Good.
- Find the towels?
- Same place they always were.
Brought some food.
- What are we having?
- Mexican.
Poquito Mas. Best
Mexican take out in L.A.
And I got you a new phone.
Thanks, Dad.
Why don't you go set it up.
Your mom and I'll put food on the table.
Okay.
I'll grab some plates.
How's she doing?
I don't know.
She seems fine but it
could all be a front.
I got a friend in behavioral,
shrink they sent me to last year.
You want I should reach out,
see if she'll talk to her?
Oh, give it a couple of
days, see how she does.
How'd the extradition go?
Routine. Rykoff waived, we
brought him back, booked him.
Does that mean we can go home?
Not just yet.
Where'd you find this?
Back of the linen closet.
Our trip to Catalina.
Midwestern girl. You didn't
even believe flying fish existed.
I still don't.
I see you redid the kitchen.
Yep.
Looks good.
So fuckin' weird being back here.
Ain't it the truth.
He's runnin' out of the house
with his, like, mask askew
lookin' out of one eye,
runnin' into a wall.
His mask askew.
Robbie, you are so full of shit.
- Hey, you know last night.
- Yeah.
Did y'all fuckin'
bump somebody in there?
No, bro, just the ceiling.
Gets their attention.
Well, is sure as shit
got mine, I tell ya that.
All that fuckin' drywall
dusk up in my nose.
That shit is fuckin' carcinogenic.
Now, what's that?
It's your end.
Mm-hm. Thank you.
Uh-huh. Oh.
Cap.
- Cap.
- How's it goin'?
It's goin' fine, just fine.
How are you all doin'?
Can't complain.
Irving.
I'm told you did real good last night.
Yes, you should have seen him.
He took out this big beaner
like he was fuckin' Ronda Rousey.
Uh-huh. Yeah, thank you.
I, uh... I think.
- Mm.
- And, uh...
Thanks for the dinero.
De Nada.
There's good times ahead.
Good times.
You're the key that's gonna unlock
a lot of new doors for us.
Just glad to be a part of it.
Oh, no, sorry.
You're not a part of it yet.
I'm not?
There's one more thing
you gotta do first.
We have a little...
initiation ritual.
We like to call it the Iron Rodeo.
Rodeo? What you, uh...
What you mean, like
riding horses and shit?
Yeah, it's somethin' like that.
All right. Yeah, but
I don't ride horses.
You'll ride this one.
Come on, man. Down to your skivvies.
Anything you don't want covered
in oil for the next 20 years.
You guys all did this?
- For real?
- All of us.
Even O'Grady.
Now that I would have liked to see.
Get up there, you little bitch!
- Yeah!
- Whoo, whoo!
Ride that thing!
Woo!
Woooo!
Yeah! Yeah!
Fuck's this?
I think it's a wire.
Shit.
Can you wipe it?
Keep him busy.
You got it.
Yeah!
www.addic7ed.com