Previously on Broadchurch...
You have to change all of this.
I can't.
If you don't, you'll end up dead.
If you or your family need to speak,
you call me.
He was put in a boat.
Mark, do you own a boat?
Yeah.
Do you know what it would do that
family, to this town if it was Mark?
What are you looking for?
Blood.
Don't look for the person who killed
him because it won't help.
Cos it will only make you upset.
Because you know the person
who killed him well.
Did you kill Danny?
You think I could kill my own son?
What if Danny found out about
Mark and Becca Fisher?
Father kills his own son to keep him
quiet? You think that's impossible?
I don't know.
One of the night-boats radioed in.
No sign of anyone on it.
Who do we call? Harbour master?
Coastguard?
I need people out there collecting
every piece.
The tide's coming in.
It will wash up soon enough.
No! Get it done!
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Hello?
You had Mark in most of the day.
Just routine.
Is he a suspect?
Oh, Beth, it's 4:30 in the morning.
No, I have to know. Have you ruled
him out for definite? At least tell
me that.
Beth, please, it's not as simple as
that. Of course it is.
Do you think he killed Danny?
There were gaps in his movements and
we really needed him to explain them
and he wasn't willing to do that.
Where was he?
You need to ask him.
Just tell me.
Beth...
I saw him tonight with Becca Fisher.
Does he know you saw him?
You need to tell him. You need to
talk to him.
I can't do it, Ell.
Oh, sweetheart, I'm sorry.
Really I am.
Who's that?
Is that Paul?
How long's he been standing there?
Morning.
Morning, Oliver. Don't normally see
you this early. Been in all night?
Yeah, almost. Sort of.
You all right?
No. Look, I've been doing some
digging on someone and I found
something.
Well, show me.
Do the police know about this?
It can't be Mark Latimer's boat.
That's still with our forensics.
Is this it?
On earth we say,
'Good morning, how you doing?'
I've told him. Makes no difference.
Connected to the Latimer death?
Traces of accelerant suggest the
boat was doused in petrol.
I'm finding flecks of glass and
fibres of cloth within the wood.
If I had to guess I'd say a lit rag
inside a bottle was used to ignite
it.
If someone took the boat out that far
at, what, 4am, to burn it, how did
they get back?
The rear section had marks where
an outboard motor might have gone.
They used that to get back on another
boat.
Or there was more than one of them.
Why burn this boat?
This piece might hold the key.
We sent a sample back for match and
analysis. Look in the grain.
Strands of hair.
Outstanding. Out-bloody-standing!
Oh, Miller, we've got them. Keep
going.
I want to know
as soon as you have confirmation.
Come on, Miller, no hanging around.
That's cheered you up.
100 quid says that's the boat they
used and those hairs belonged to
Danny.
They're panicking, Miller.
Fantastic. That is exactly what we
want.
Starting to show themselves.
And they're an amateur.
Haven't done this before.
That's clumsy - burning the boat
like that and so soon.
That's a big mistake they've made.
That's like oxygen to us. Breathe it
in, Miller, we're getting somewhere.
Hello?
27 unanswered calls and finally she
picks up.
Come on, explain why I shouldn't
sack you.
I've taken leave, that's all. I'm
owed loads and I've got a good story.
I specifically told you not to go.
We're gonna use an agency.
The police are struggling. I don't
think this is gonna be done in a day
or two.
Why do I care? Why will our readers
care?
Model family, two kids. Dad's a
plumber.
Quiet estate, idyllic market town -
definition of normal.
The mum - how photogenic?
Very photogenic. English rose.
Get me an exclusive with her, nice
photo, and I'll look at it.
OK.
Where the hell have you been?
Running. Am I not allowed to run?
I didn't know you were coming.
Just bringing you up to date.
I was just saying we've asked
forensics to examine Danny's
clothing in greater detail.
We're following up on leads
from the house-to-house.
Yeah, now you've stopped messing
around with me.
Don't be a wanker, Mark.
We're holding a public meeting
at the school later today.
Just to keep the town up to date,
answer questions.
You don't have to be there. I'm gonna
go. On behalf of all of us.
You don't have to, Mum.
I want to. Keep busy.
Why is there nothing more in the
paper about Danny?
It's like page 12, couple of
paragraphs.
Don't judge this investigation
by what's in the press.
No, we were saying if there's more in
the papers it might jog people's
memories.
What if there's somebody out there?
They might have seen something.
If we had more in the papers...
Please, let us handle the media.
We have the experience in this.
We're all asking, no offence,
but why's it taking so long?
Trevor, how many...
Multiple complex crime scenes,
particularly at the beach.
Lack of CCTV in key areas.
Er... absence of witnesses seeing
Danny on the night he sneaked out.
We've a lot of information still to
process. We'll get there.
Susan Wright. How many people
do you even have working on it?
I heard you were short staffed.
We have the right resources
for an investigation of this size.
Next question.
I've just come from the pier and
there's...
What did she say her name was?
Susan Wright.
New information came to light
overnight.
And we have to examine it
without contamination.
Is that the boat that was on fire?
My brother saw it when he was out
with his pots.
Erm... It's too early to talk about
specific types of evidence.
You said the tents on the beach
would come down at any moment and
they're still there,
and now you're adding bloody great
vans.
You have to understand
the work going on there.
Every grain of sand has to be gone
through.
Every cigarette butt or stray hair,
shard of plastic,
fingernail, toenail, piece of skin
has to be tested.
We will do everything we can to limit
the effect on your livelihoods,
but my priority is to a thorough
and efficient investigation.
But low-key.
We don't want the name Broadchurch
to be a byword for murder like
Sandbrook.
I told you there was a boat.
God, you're just what I need.
Great. A boat. There's hundreds
round here. You got lucky.
Lucky. Yeah, well, did you look for
it, eh?
Does Beth know you didn't follow that
up?
How about you heed my very strong
advice?
Stay away from her. Do not get
involved.
Right?
Oh! Hey! There he is!
You're Liz, right? Danny's grandma.
You must really miss him.
Oh, he shone, that boy.
I promised myself I wouldn't do this.
I'm the strong one in all this.
I just want them to catch the sod who
did it.
I'm Karen. I work for the Herald.
We're not talking to the press.
No, I know.
But can I just say one thing?
Just be sure you're getting the best
advice. I'd hate for Danny to be
ignored.
Hi.
All right?
You said Mark Latimer didn't fix a
burst pipe at the hut on the cliff.
Yeah.
He did. We checked his paperwork.
He said he got the keys off you and
you even arranged the cheque for him.
Must have got it wrong. Now if you
don't mind, I gotta be somewhere.
The longer this goes on the more
everyone wants to get involved,
stick their oar in.
Develop their pet theory.
People getting restless, too many
opinions. I don't like it.
Here we go again.
Will you pass on to Beth and Mark,
whenever they feel able to talk,
come to us, to me.
They know we do things properly.
I'll make sure they know.
And Oliver has got something else to
tell you.
Well, we always love hearing from
Oliver.
I found this on Jack Marshall,
who runs the newsagent's here.
He was in prison before he came
here. He's got a previous conviction
for underage sex.
Don't try and avoid me.
I know where you live.
I know what your van looks like.
I told you, I don't want to see you.
It's not that simple, though, is it?
It is.
Cos I'm telling you it is.
We're connected now, you and me.
- You can't just turn your back.
- I can.
I don't want you near me.
You may not like it...
but it can't be undone.
So, you and me need to work out
what we're gonna do.
I ain't talking to you.
Do you understand?
You stay away!
A few days ago I told the police
about evidence they should look for.
They took no notice.
Now they've got that evidence, but it
was burned before they got to it.
It makes it harder to analyse it.
Why are you telling me this?
Because I can help. I can help.
But I need to be taken seriously, and
that's...
It's not happening right now.
What if you're wrong? Beth, I've got
no reason to lie to you.
I wish... I wish we'd never had cause
to meet.
But what I have told you is genuine.
And you need to convince the police.
Is this about the postman?
The one who was arguing with Danny?
No, though we did talk to him. He
said he never had an argument with
Danny that day.
Load of rubbish. I know what I saw.
Tell us about your conviction
for sex with a minor, Jack.
So... we're into the muck-raking,
are we?
Just wanna establish the facts.
You didn't mention it when we spoke.
It's nothing to do with anyone.
Nothing to do with Danny.
You help with the Sea Brigade.
That requires CRB checks
cross-referenced
with the Sex Offenders' Register.
I am not a sex offender.
That conviction was a farce.
I'm not on any register.
Only because it happened
before the Register came into being.
Why didn't you tell us about it?
You've got the file, haven't you?
I've served my time.
You should have declared it.
Put up a little sign, should I?
'Ex-convict here'.
I came here to get away from that.
I am not what you're insinuating.
When did you last see Danny Latimer?
I told you, the day before he was
found. He came in, did his paper
round.
What about the night of Danny's
death? Where were you then?
In, on my own, reading a book.
Anyone vouch for that?
Only the book.
Which book?
Jude The Obscure.
You might not like it. Not many
pictures.
We've been told you're a keen
amateur photographer, Jack.
Took a lot of pictures of the boys
in Sea Brigade.
I really do pity you.
Seeing depravity in perfectly normal
behaviour.
I'd hate to be in your mind.
Now, if you've an accusation or
evidence to put to me, let's hear it.
Otherwise, let me go back to work.
Why are we relying on journalists
to do our work for us?
He wasn't a suspect. We haven't
prioritised him.
Well, make him a priority now.
She's here.
Summoned to the inner sanctum.
Should I be worried?
Did you set him off looking into Jack
Marshall?
No, it had nothing to do... Yeah, I
did. I had a run-in with Jack.
Welcome to the club. Still want a
desk?
Definitely. Why would you do that?
Better to have you inside the tent
pissing out, than outside the tent
pissing in, I suppose.
Mine's white. No sugar.
Huh.
Try now.
Yeah. Brilliant.
Thanks, mate. Don't know why I didn't
spot it.
Did you block the sink, Nige?
Why would I do that?
I don't know.
Keep me busy, take my mind off
things.
It's gonna be all right.
I know it'll never be the same,
but... I'll keep the business going.
Whenever you're ready to come back
you just say.
No pressure. Just step back in.
Thanks, mate.
Can I cook for you? This weekend.
Sunday lunch, all of you.
Nah, I don't think so, Nige.
Still got to eat, mate.
You've done it for the rest of us
often enough.
I'm good with beef. You all like
beef?
Yeah, all right.
Come on.
You asked us here for this?
Tell them.
Danny wants people to know
he was killed by someone he knew.
This is offensive. I'm calling a halt
right now. I told you about the boat.
You didn't listen and now you've
found a boat.
I want you to hear him out, please.
Just hear him out.
Tell her.
Beth, we checked Steve's record.
He's bankrupt with previous
convictions for vehicle theft,
petty theft and conspiracy to
defraud.
No.
What?
Right. Out.
No. No, Beth...
Beth, Beth...
Come on!
And you're a bloody idiot for
letting him in.
It's got nothing to do with this.
Beth!
Look, I don't know if you are
mentally ill,
a liar, or somebody who believes
they're telling the truth,
but I have to find this killer
and prove my case in court.
I deal in facts. All you're giving
her is fantasy.
Pete is now gonna escort you to your
vehicle and you are gonna stay away
from this house.
Final warning. I see you again,
I will have you in prison.
Why would he do that?
I haven't given him any money.
In two weeks he'll speak to the
press, in six months he'll write a
book:
How I Solved The Broadchurch Murder.
All those books are in the bookshop
in town.
Oh, my God.
I'm so alone.
Beth, have you spoken to Mark?
I can't.
You've got to.
No, no, no, no!
There you go, love.
Thanks.
Thrill ride round the bay.
Best 15 quid she'll ever spend.
Kids go half-price.
Perfectly safe.
Looks good.
Er... Maggie. I edit the Echo.
Yeah, I know. I saw you at the
meeting.
You're Susan.
Yeah.
Or is it Elaine?
Only I've got a picture of you with
the Sea Brigade boys under a
different name.
Your people must have wrote it down
wrong.
RIB rides! Broadchurch Blaster!
Thrill ride round the bay.
You still coming to dinner?
Joe's going shopping today, so you
can't back out now.
I said, didn't I? What we asking
this vicar?
Er, he was flagged up in the
house-to-house
as one of the few without an alibi on
the night Danny was killed.
Do you know him well? Not really.
Only been here a couple of years.
We're not really churchgoers.
Midnight mass, Easter, if we
remember.
If you remember Easter? We're
normally doing Easter egg hunts.
And so did Christianity fall.
What about you, then? You religious?
Yeah.
I pray nightly you'll stop asking me
questions.
Liz, his grandmother,
she's one of our sidesmen,
and I used to teach the IT club
at Danny's school.
Oh, yeah, Tom did that too.
Yeah.
So you knew Danny quite well.
I wouldn't say really well.
Erm... he was a quick learner. Same as
Tom.
They were good kids, both of them.
Why are you taking the IT club?
I try to connect with the community
whatever way I can.
Plus I got asked to.
I think the last teacher who really
understood computers had a nervous
breakdown.
Mr Broughton. He'd sit there
and laugh to himself. They got him
to
leave.
I'm one up from the man
who sits there giggling to himself.
Where were you on the night of
Danny's death?
I did talk to your uniformed officers
about this.
I know.
I was at home. On my own.
I live in the house at the bottom of
the hill. I was up late trying to
write a sermon.
Trying being the operative word.
Are you often up late?
I was on the verge-side about 4:30
the other night, saw you standing
outside the church.
Was that you?
OK, er...
Yeah... I have terrible insomnia.
I have had for about six or seven
years.
Can't find anything to cure it,
so... I'm often up late, wandering.
That's my best attempt to deal with
it.
Anything specific that triggered it?
Not really. No.
You weren't out wandering that
Thursday night?
No, I don't remember it.
How was Danny with computers?
Great. They just instinctively get
it.
Like I say, with Danny and Tom,
you only have to tell them once and
they got it.
Line of sight. You can see the field
that backs onto the Latimer house.
And my house too.
I hate what I'm becoming.
A good detective?
Hardened.
I'm not here to hassle.
I've been here since day one and I've
left you alone.
It's true. I left one of Danny's
toys at the beach.
She brought it back to me, save it
getting nicked.
But I bumped into Liz at the school
and...
I think this should be getting more
coverage. Yeah, so what shall we do?
OK, you're not gonna like this.
The reason Danny's death isn't
getting proper attention is it's not
the right profile.
Had Danny been a girl with blonde
hair and a few years younger
then this place would be crawling
with reporters by now.
I hope you're kidding.
I'm sorry. It's the way it works.
11-year-old boys
go missing from home all the time.
So we're just gonna get ignored, are
we?
If you want more focus on this case,
then it's gonna have to come from
you, Beth.
Me? Why me?
You tell us your side of things,
how it's been for you, every mum will
respond.
I don't know. Do we want this?
Shouldn't we clear it with the
police?
It's the Herald. I read the Herald.
What if she shows us what she's
written before she sends it in?
Good idea. Would you do that?
Not normally.
Maybe this time if I can get a photo
with Beth and Danny to go with the
article.
What do we think?
OK.
Yeah?
That's it. I want to see this area
covered. Keep going.
Hi, Mr Marshall.
Oliver. Come to help?
Well, could we maybe just talk
inside?
No, we can talk here, can't we? Can't
you see I'm busy? What do you want?
OK, erm... I've come across
some information and...
being as we know each other I
thought I should come to you before
it gets out.
Before what gets out?
I'm sorry, there's no easy way of
asking this.
Do you have a conviction for
underage sex?
Why, you little bastard.
I'm not trying to stitch you up.
Who told you? The police? I can help
you put your story across.
You're all as bad as each other -
gossiping and accusing.
OK, I think you should let go of me.
You've known me how long?
When did I ever do anything improper?
OK, if we could go inside and
talk...
So you can trick me into
incriminating myself?
Is that what that bitch your boss
wants? That's a bit...
How can I incriminate you if you're
innocent?
They've trained you to be a clever
weasel, haven't they?
Go on. Get away. Go!
Weasel! Go! Go!
Oh, you're in a suit.
Is that bad?
No, I didn't expect it. We didn't
get poshed up. Neither did I.
Well, there we are, then. Come in.
I bought wine.
That's very kind of you.
And flowers.
Oh, you didn't need to...
And chocolates.
Wow.
Wasn't sure which to choose so I got
them all.
Bless. Come in.
Thanks.
Alec bought wine and flowers and
chocolates.
Full house - you can come again.
I can call you Alec tonight, not
Hardy or sir?
'Here's your dinner, sir.'
I don't like Alec. I've never liked
Alec.
'Alec.'
You can always choose another one.
Why does everyone use first names so
much, like they all work in
marketing?
Why do people insist on doing that?
I mean, if you look at a person I
look at you...
You know I'm talking to you. I don't
need to say your name three times
to congratulate myself on remembering
it, to create some...
sort of false intimacy or...
Shall I show you to the dining room?
How did you two meet?
Er, through work.
Joe used to be a paramedic.
Not any more?
Gave it up when Fred came along.
I was getting a bit jaded anyway.
Jaded, how?
More red tape.
Stuff that stopped us from being
able to help, masquerading as health
and safety.
Where are you from originally?
Cardiff.
Moved down here 13 years ago for
work.
Met Ellie. The rest is history.
You married? This is great food.
You make this yourself?
Mm. Self-taught. Mexican's my
speciality.
We should really be having
margaritas, shouldn't we?
No.
Not married. Not any more.
Sorry to hear that. What was it?
The pressures of work?
Sort of. This job does it to you.
Not to us.
No, I didn't mean...
Any erm... any kids?
Daughter. 15. Lives with her mother.
Oh, that must be hard.
Do you think you'll solve this case?
Joe.
Certain.
Good.
Right, I'm gonna have a wee.
No more talking about work.
Well, that's us told.
No, no, not for me.
Shut up and drink!
Does she like me?
Sorry?
Does she like...
working with me?
You're here for dinner, aren't you?
I think I irritate her.
She hasn't mentioned it.
You bloody liar.
I've said nothing.
And yet...
What are you laughing about?
Nothing.
Sure you don't want a taxi?
No, no. Walk will be good.
See you in the morning.
That was nice. Thanks, Miller.
A whole evening and it's still
Miller. Unbelievable.
I love you, Miller.
Oh, don't you start.
You and your new bloody little mate.
Lord... give me the strength
to deal with tomorrow.
You are my strength and my shield.
I ask for wisdom and courage
in this darkest of moments.
In the name of Christ the king.
Amen.
Why are you so bothered about me?
What's my life got to do with you?
I think you should leave.
You're gonna stop asking questions
about me.
Why would I do that?
I know men who would rape you.
Night.
It's OK. We're getting you to
hospital. No, you can't.
It's gonna be OK. You don't need to
worry.
Good morning, sunshine. Took quite a
crack. What am I doing here?
How you feeling?
What are you doing here?
You passed out.
Found you on the bathroom floor.
What were you doing in my bathroom?
The person in the room underneath you
complained about the banging,
luckily.
Is this your daughter?
What you doing with that?
I was looking for your next of kin
in the ambulance. I told them I was
your wife.
What? Is that bad? I think they
caught on pretty quick.
Anyway, look, I am glad you are OK
and awake. I have to get back.
Left Neil in charge, he's not exactly
competent.
Listen. You mustn't tell anyone
about this.
If they find out I'm sick they'll
take me off the case.
I don't want to come off this case.
I need to finish this case.
Becca.
It's my career.
This is my life.
You get some proper medical help.
Cos next time someone might not find
you.
I'm coming with you.
Ah, no, they want to keep you in.
I don't care. What's this?
It's a great piece. You captured Beth
just right. But Maggie's gonna be
miffed.
I'll talk to her. Mark and Beth were
desperate for people to know about
the case.
Think about the witnesses
that might come forward.
So you're the golden girl
on your news desk now?
Well, the boss is officially happy
and the rest of the papers are now
scrambling to catch up.
Half a dozen...
Hang on, I've gotta go.
You've gotta be joking.
Nothing to do with me.
Mum?
Oh, what are you doing with that?
Don't be brave, son.
For God's sake. I thought you said
you'd fixed it.
It's a mix-up. They got it wrong.
Why don't you understand the trouble
we're in?
Why has she done this?
It reads all right to me.
I told 'em not to. I'm gonna have to
go.
See you later.
I was thinking of taking the kids to
church this morning.
Church?
Yeah.
Why?
Don't know.
Just... felt... the thing...
Yeah. OK.
Bye-bye.
Ta-ra, love.
Bye, Mummy.
Bye. Good boy.
Jesus, what happened to you?
I slipped in the shower.
You've been glued up. You look
terrible, sir, if you don't mind me
saying.
Have you seen the Herald? Yeah, I
didn't know they'd done that.
It's opened the floodgates. Media
officer's been deluged with calls.
So I'm calling a conference for this
evening.
A family statement - try and keep as
much control as we can.
Meantime, I want full backgrounds on
Jack Marshall, Steve Connelly and
Paul Coates.
Anyone without an alibi goes top of
our list.
I'll get Frank and Nish on it.
Sir, can I ask a favour?
I was thinking of going to church.
That's a good idea. Everyone all
together, check who's behaving
normally.
No, that wasn't the... Never mind.
What time's the service?
In an hour.
All right.
Hey. I've got to tell you before we
go in.
I saw Olly Stevens and Jack Marshall
yesterday.
From what I can make out Olly was
saying... Jack's got a history with
kids.
Bad stuff.
You're kidding?
Beth! Beth!
All right, lads? Just let them go
through.
Away now, or I'll have you all
arrested!
We're not breaking the law.
Have a bit of bloody decency.
Lenses down or I will kick you all in
the balls.
You didn't hear me say that. I
promise you I will.
Your mum is awesome.
I know.
Come for lunch today.
What?
Nige is cooking.
Like we always do.
Jack.
Didn't know he was religious.
Didn't know we were.
Fair point.
Hello, husband. How's the head?
We are pressed on every side by
troubles.
But we are not crushed.
We are perplexed but not driven to
despair.
We are hunted down,
but never abandoned by God.
We are knocked down...
but we are not destroyed.
As a community, the hardest thing for
us is to remember,
we have not been abandoned by God.
We are not destroyed.
Nor will we be.
No? All right, I'll have it.
I want it.
Quite a spread, Nige. You've got
hidden talents.
You'll make someone a lovely husband
one day.
They'll have to catch me first, Liz.
I think one of those photographers
got in while we were out. I'll get a
lock first thing.
You all right? You've been quiet.
What do you expect?
Yeah.
We should go in, get something to
eat. Get ready for this press
conference.
Wahey!
He's a beauty.
Thanks.
All right?
Yeah.
Nige, there's a hair in it.
You all right, sweetheart?
Yeah.
You OK?
Can I ask you something? You can say
no.
Can I have a hug?
OK.
I miss his hugs.
I'd best get that.
You gonna have a cup of coffee?
Jack's here.
Everything all right?
I... found this.
Heard the beeping from the delivery
bags. It was in the bag at the
bottom.
He must have left it on his last
round.
Yeah, that's Danny's phone, isn't it?
Mark, I'll take it. Give it here.
What were you doing with this, Jack?
Mark.
Mark, Beth...
They're going to say things about me.
What sort of things?
Those things aren't true.
Jack. Come on, love.
Things happened before I was here,
and they'll be saying I did it.
I'm looking you in the eye,
because he was your boy,
and I'm telling you I'm not that kind
of man.
Please. Believe me.
You have to believe me.
The bastards!
I'm with you, mate.
Jack, I don't know what you're doing.
Come on, Jack.
Piss off! Go on! Get away, go on!
Public property this!
Is it? Is it?
Out the way, Mark.
Bad doggy! Bad doggy!
Terrible weather!
We're going, all right?! Stop it!
What have we done to ourselves, eh?
Why do they need all of us?
So people can understand
how much losing Danny meant to us.
How strong a family we are.
Right, are you ready for this?
Chloe, you go at the far end
and then Beth and then Mark.
I know about you and Becca Fisher.
Mark, now, please.
Sir. SOCO have confirmed the hairs
found on the boat - they match
Danny's.
I knew it. Also, something from North
Yorkshire Police,
about a killing on the cliffs in
Whitby 15 years back.
They've seen the details and think
it's got similarities to our case.
OK, later. Sir, Jack Marshall used to
live in North Yorkshire, five miles
from Whitby.
We miss Danny a lot and erm...
we just want whoever's done this
just to come forward because we're...
we're having a horrible time not
knowing why this has happened to us.
He was just a normal lad.
Never did anyone any harm.
He was everything to us.
We just want to know
what happened to our boy.
If anybody out there knows, might
know, think they saw something...
then you owe it to yourself
to come forward and tell the police.
Cos whoever did this needs to be
caught.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.