You gotta be kidding me.
I can't take you.
Well, how many times
have I taken you to the airport?
Matt has a soccer game tomorrow.
I have a report I have to finish.
It'll only take an hour.
Fine. I'll call a cab.
Oh, come on, Kyle.
[Text message tone]
[Sent tone]
Kyle, I'm running out!
[Car lock beep]
Uhh!
[Tires squealing]
Come on, Rossi.
I don't want to use them.
I don't even understand you.
It's a vacation, Rossi.
Everyone likes vacation.
Vacations are overrated.
Didn't you take a vacation
two years ago?
Luckily, two days in
I was called back.
Garcia: Yeah, and now
he's got 31 days.
A month?
You know, sunshine is an essential
source of vitamin D.
You should go to Florida
and get some sunshine.
That's for old guys.
What about a safari
in Africa?
Too hot.
Reid: How about Italy?
Too many relatives.
You sound hermetic.
No, Rossi just likes
his wine and stogies.
And I go crazy
if I have nothing to do.
You know, Rossi, if you don't
use 'em, you lose 'em.
Thank you. This is what
I've been telling him.
See this? This is my
"I don't care" face.
That's your normal face.
If I were you, I'd give your vacation
days away to a colleague in need.
[Snaps fingers]
Garcia, see how many people
in the Bureau
have spouses in the military
serving overseas.
I am on it.
Altruism is sexy.
Yes, it is.
Yes, sir.
Let's get started.
All right, crime-fighters,
last night, two victims,
Brenda Wipley
and Mark Coleman
were found murdered
hours apart,
one in San Diego,
one in Los Angeles.
They were blitz-attacked
and they were chained to a car
where they were dragged alive
to their deaths.
And the local P.D. does not believe
the victims knew each other.
And both received similar
text messages last night
from prepaid phones
asking them to meet.
So our unsub's a friend
or at least pretends to be one.
Based on how they were killed,
he wanted to see them suffer.
Morgan: He's sadistic.
Mm-hmm. And mission oriented.
Dragging's usually
associated with hate crimes,
but neither victim
was a minority nor gay.
Actually, dragging is steeped
in English history.
Back in the 11th Century,
drawing and quartering
was a common form
of punishment, and in fact,
they would also disembowel
and behead the victims when
they were done with them.
But that didn't happen here.
Maybe this is just
a serial killer who crosses city lines.
I don't know. Two victims in 3 hours?
That's a spree.
Our unsub may claim
another victim soon.
Which is why we're headed west.
We'll land in Orange County,
half of us will go to San Diego,
the other half L.A.
Wheels up in 30.
Uhh!
Wait. Wait. Come back!
What did I do to you?!
Please don't do this!
No!
Oh, no, no!
♪ Criminal Minds 8x02 ♪
The Pact
Original Air Date on October 10, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
Rossi: Ralph Steadman wrote,
"evil is always devising
more corrosive misery
through man's restless need
to exact revenge out of his hate."
All right, let's go
to victimology.
Neither of the victims was
sexually assaulted or robbed.
Well, Brenda was a teacher
and a mother of two.
She went to meet a friend
that night.
Mm-hmm. And her husband
backs the story.
And the other victim,
Mark Coleman, was an addict.
He was killed in the
parking lot of a drugstore
around the corner from
the sober living house.
A woman with no apparent addiction
and a tweaker in a sober living house?
They probably don't know
each other.
Garcia, did the unsub
call the victims
on the disposable cells
prior to that night?
Let's see. In the last
few weeks,
he called each of the victims
over two times a day.
That's not random.
It's hunting.
Without phone transcripts,
it's going to be hard
to understand what
the unsub's ruse was.
Well, it ended pretty bad.
Tying someone to the back
of a car is horrific
and uncharacteristically
high-risk behavior.
It was pure torture. Skin was
scraped off, bones were broken.
That's about desecrating
the body.
Well, our unsub is comfortable
using chains and hitching
equipment.
You know, the crimes could have
been committed to promote fear.
All right, just--
can we rewind for a second?
Is it possible to kill
someone in San Diego
and then drive 2 1/2 hours
up to L.A.
And then do it again?
If you drove a V8 engine
with a single plane crankshaft
80 miles per hour
in good traffic,
you took the I-5 to the 405
to the 10 east,
got off on La Cienega, went right
on Washington, north on Vermont,
and then snuck up Selma
using the back alley,
you could do it
in an hour, 42 minutes,
and still have time
for tacos.
Wow.
Yeah.
JJ, you and Morgan go to
the latest crime scene.
Dave, you and Blake to San Diego
to the medical examiner's,
and Reid and I
will go to the LAPD.
[Indistinct chatter
and police radio]
Officer: You gotta keep
the barricades back.
JJ.
The blood trail ends
about 3 blocks away
where the body
was found.
This is where he was
tied to the car.
What's up
with the drugstore?
It was closed Friday. They're
in the middle of a remodel.
That's convenient.
Yes. So is the fact
that the camera's not working.
So the unsub
drags Mark over here,
then blitz attacks him
from behind.
Ok, if the killer knew
the drugstore was closed
and the cameras
weren't working,
he wasn't expecting
anyone here.
And he scoped out
the nearby streets.
He knew there'd be
low traffic,
so he could drag
the victims without being caught.
What if Mark
was falling off the wagon
and he was meeting
his dealer?
Right? Like the first victim
also met the unsub
in a parking lot.
Maybe she had
a drug habit, too.
It's possible.
But either way,
our unsub is highly
organized.
[Cell phone rings]
Hello?
Oh, hi.
I can't do it today.
I know.
I'm really sorry.
Next week.
Promise.
[Text message tone]
Me, too.
Name the place.
Officer: The desk sergeant.
[Indistinct chatter]
Hi, I'm Detective Pratt.
You must be SSA Hotchner.
I am. This is
Dr. Spencer Reid.
Pleasure.
Well, I talked to San Diego PD.
They sent over everything on
the first victim Brenda Wipley's case.
And Mr. Coleman's updated
file's on the conference room table.
I'll start looking them over.
Now, should we notify
the press
that we're looking
for a spree killer?
Not until we know exactly
what we're looking for.
Ok. You guys can set up
right in here.
[Text message tone]
Thank you.
Morgan and JJ think
that maybe our second victim Mark
went to meet a drug dealer.
Have you gotten the tox screens back?
Neither of the victims
had drugs in their system.
It doesn't mean they didn't
go meet a dealer.
But a drug dealer doesn't call you
twice a day for two weeks.
Usually you call him.
[Cell phone rings]
Go ahead, Garcia.
The path of my cyber sleuthing
has had majestic results.
Digging into victim number
two's past,
it turns out meth isn't the only thing
Mark Coleman had done.
He also changed his last name.
From what?
Logan. And that's where
the plot thickens
like a bad pudding.
So when Mark was a junior
in college,
he gets picked up by police
on a drug charge.
They find some articles
of clothing
of a missing 8-year-old girl
named Kelly Taylor in his car.
They are covered
with Mark's DNA.
After a lengthy interrogation,
he confesses to sexually
assaulting her,
but denies killing her, and
because her body was never found,
they couldn't link him
to the disappearance.
What's he been doing
since he got out?
Eating hamburgers.
He got released a month ago.
Since then he's worked at 3
different fast food joints.
Send me everything
you've got on the case.
I'll have Reid
go talk to the family.
Yeah.
Outside.
I was having my soup.
Now.
Thanks. Garcia was only
able to give away
25 of my vacation days
to employees with loved ones
in Afghanistan.
Well, great. Now you just
have to figure out
what to do with
the remaining 6.
Hey. I'm Dr. Mathis.
I heard it took
the L.A. M.E. 4 hours
to find the second
victim's entire body.
Yeah, he was spread
all over the place.
Well, victim one had it
easy by comparison.
She was dragged postmortem.
We thought she was alive
at first.
No. She died from
a series of blows to the head.
So the unsub was scared
on his first kill,
then two hours later
when he got his second victim,
his confidence suddenly
evolved.
That's a pretty quick
evolution.
And therein lies the problem.
So I talked to victim
number two's father.
He said as far as he knew,
no one was trying
to get back at Mark
for the rape.
He got out of jail
last month.
He was getting out more, exercising,
trying to get on with his life.
Well, I just compared photos
from the first and second crime scenes.
The cars used to drag
were different.
Maybe the killer
switched cars?
Or we're looking
at two unsubs.
What did you
and Morgan find?
Well, at both crime scenes,
the nearby stores were either closed
or being remodeled,
so the killer would have
had to scope the area,
lure and drag the victim
without being caught.
This guy has a lot to do.
So the question remains,
how can you do that
twice in one night
in cities over
100 miles apart?
Two unsubs would explain
the evolution in M.O.
What did Rossi and Blake say?
The first victim Brenda
was dragged postmortem.
The second victim
was alive.
So we're most likely looking
at one unsub who's hesitant
and another one
who actually enjoys it.
What do you mean,
you killed her first?
I just couldn't do it
while she was still alive.
But that's the whole point.
Come on,
you know what she did.
I know. But she was
begging for her life
and I just couldn't hear it
anymore.
Oh, you should have
called me.
You had your own thing
to do.
Ok, we've been planning this thing
for 6 months.
If you thought you were
gonna chicken out,
you should have told me
at last week's meeting.
Ok, we're done now,
so let's just go home
and pretend
this never happened.
No. We're not going
anywhere.
When I killed Mark,
he told me there were
two other guys that helped.
What?
He didn't do this alone?
So what are we
gonna do now?
We're gonna kill them.
That is what we're gonna do.
I can't do this again!
Yes. Yes.
Yes, Darlene, you can.
I don't know...
Darlene, if we don't do this,
who else will?
We know most teams work
together, two unsubs versus one victim.
Here we have a team
that's 120 miles apart
using similar M.O.s
on radically different victims.
JJ: Ok, so how
do we think they met?
Blake: Something in the
victimology should tell us.
Morgan: Well, we know that victim
number two, Mark Coleman,
has a sketchy background.
What if victim number one
was hiding something
as well?
Let's start digging.
Who the hell are you?
You thought you could
rape and kill an 8-year-old
and get away with it?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Yeah. That's not
what Mark said!
Ok. Ok. I was there,
but I didn't do anything.
Shut up!
I thought if I tried
to stop them, they'd hurt me.
Imagine how Kelly felt.
What are you doing?
Let's just kill him now.
No, that's too easy.
Now get in the car.
You don't need to do this!
Karma's a bitch, isn't it?
I didn't do anything.
I didn't do anything!
No!
Help!
Come on!
No, no, I didn't do anything!
Help! Please help!
I didn't do anything! Help!
What did you find?
Paul Montgomery was alive
when he was dragged.
And it turns out Paul worked
the late shift nearby.
My officers found blood
around his vehicle.
He was probably blitz
attacked when he left work.
Did we find his cell?
Yeah, it was on the ground.
But he had no text messages
or prior calls.
That's a change in M.O.
Usually they lure
their victims out.
[Cell phone rings] What happened
to their organization?
[Ring]
Garcia, what did you find
out about Paul Montgomery?
So guess who were BFFs
in college.
Hmm. Mark Coleman
and Paul?
10 points to Blakendore.
Turns out Paul
was a character witness
in Mark Coleman's
rape trial.
He waxed poet about his boy.
The jury didn't care.
So we have two scumbags
and an innocent mom as victims.
Anything
in Brenda Wipley's past?
No, not that I've found yet.
She went to college at UCLA,
she went to high school
in Orange County.
Does she have a sealed
juvie record?
Why didn't I think of that?
See, this is why
you're the boss man
and I'm the minion
who types things.
Uh, it turns out Brenda
was not as coifed as her bob.
When she was 17,
she was involved in a DUI
that resulted in the death
of a 2-year-old boy, Sam Dolan.
Did she serve time?
Yeah, she was sentenced
to a year in juvie.
It was reduced to two months
after her father gave
hefty chunks of change
to some political
organizations.
So, we're definitely
looking at a vigilante team
avenging the death
of these two kids.
We should talk to the parents
of the original victims.
I'll bet they're the connection
to these unsubs. Thanks, Garcia.
Thank you for coming in,
Mr. Dolan.
That was taken
at his second birthday.
His mom sent one
to everyone.
I know this is hard,
but I need to ask you
some questions
about the death of the woman
who killed your son.
Like I told the cops,
I was returning home
from London
the night Brenda
was murdered.
I have my boarding pass.
Ok. Now, what about your wife?
Where was she?
She killed herself
a few years ago.
Uh...
I am so sorry
to hear that.
She said she was
getting better, and--
but ever since
Sam's death,
she was a mess.
Do you think
the lenient sentence
was a contributing factor
in her death?
Absolutely.
She thought the system
failed us.
She wouldn't leave
the house after that.
She even did therapy
over the phone.
Did she have friends over?
No.
She spent all her time
on the Internet.
Really?
Did she join any online
support groups?
How'd you know?
She said it was
making her better.
But I--I thought
it was making her worse.
Why?
Because it allowed her
to obsess about it.
And look where that got her.
Oh, no.
[Vomiting]
Not again.
I can't do this.
I thought it was gonna help,
but it isn't.
That's because
you're not letting it.
But it's wrong.
An eye for an eye?
It's biblical.
When I wake up
in the morning,
I see Kelly's face.
When I close my eyes,
she's still there.
I don't know how much longer
I can go on like this.
Don't. Don't you say that.
But that's how I feel.
You should feel
rejuvenated.
Come here. Come on.
Come on.
Look.
Look at you.
They did this.
They did this to you.
So don't tell me they don't deserve
what's coming to them.
Order's up.
Thanks.
Just finished my interview.
Sam Dolan's father
checks out.
His mother committed
suicide a few years ago.
What about Kelly's parents?
We've left them
messages, but...
You might send an officer
to their house
and places of employment.
We should also check
at the support group
Sam's mother belonged to.
Morgan:
Well, we got something.
The calls the unsub made to the victims--
twice a day at night.
That shows incredible
persistence.
The first victim, Brenda,
was a happily married teacher,
so why would she take calls
from a random man late at night?
If she was cheating,
she wouldn't meet someone
at a restaurant near her house.
I think she was meeting a woman.
The roommate said the second victim,
Mark, in a sober living house
said that he was talking
to someone online a lot lately.
The night he got killed,
he got dressed up like
he was going out on a date.
And he's straight, which further
confirms it was a female.
That would explain
the blitz attacks.
They weren't because our
unsubs were insecure men,
they were because our unsubs
are women,
who needed to subdue
their victims first.
We need to give the profile.
We believe that these unsubs
are two women
who are killing people
convicted of heinous crimes.
You son of a bitch!
He'll be out
in 10 years.
Unlike solo vigilantes,
they're working in concert
and they're planning
and executing coordinated attacks.
Their mentality
is like a lynch mob.
They believe the justice system
has gone wrong
and it's up to them
to set it right.
Due to the pre-planning
and level of commitment,
we believe our unsubs
are over 30.
And they probably learned
about the crimes they're
avenging through the media.
It's possible
they were involved
in these losses
personally
and now feel
they need to act.
No! I don't accept it!
My baby's life was worth
more than 10 years!
This latest attack felt
more improvised and personal.
They didn't lure
their victim.
Rather, they blitz
attacked him outside of his job.
Now, during a spree,
the threat is that an unsub
will either strike again
or disappear.
Now, if they've completed their vendetta,
then the latter is more likely.
Our unsubs may not have
prior criminal histories,
as they see themselves
as do-gooders.
Based on the fact that
one victim was dragged postmortem
and the other
were dragged alive,
we believe that one woman
is not as confident in the mission
while the other
is more domineering.
We're looking for mothers,
relatives, friends who have lost children.
We also need to look
at the collateral damage
of the crimes our current
victims committed years ago.
Since this is the only thing
our unsubs have in common,
it tell us
that as time goes on,
their friendship will become strained
and ultimately fall apart.
Hotch: So how do these
unsubs meet?
Maybe they're involved
in the trials.
In two different cities?
I don't know.
If Sam Dolan's mom was in
an online support group,
maybe after
she killed herself,
someone else became
obsessed with her grief.
Yeah, but who'd have
that same level of interest?
Let me call Garcia.
[Ring, beep]
- Hey, Garcia.
- At your service.
Were you able to find out
anything
about that online support
group Mrs. Dolan was in?
Uh, let me see.
Uh, uh, uh, it had 200 members.
It was an anonymous group.
Did any of them start
talking about Sam Dolan
about two months ago,
after his mother's suicide?
Ok, uh, I've got
a screen name, Ellen R.
From San Diego. She talked about
Sam in a private chat room.
Did Sam Dolan's mom have any friends
or relatives with that name?
Yeah, she's got a sister
Ellen Russel.
She works in a boat shop.
And that'd give her access
to hitching equipment.
Who was she interacting
with in the support group?
She talked
to a lot of people.
In the last year,
she was mainly
talking to a Darlene B.
Kelly Taylor's mom's
name is Darlene.
What's her maiden name?
Beckett. In the last
6 months,
most of their discussions
have been around the pending release
of Mark Coleman from prison.
And they probably
hatched a plan.
We need to get search warrants
for Ellen's and Darlene's houses.
Oh, my gosh! This just in.
So when Mark was released a month ago,
her and Ellen started calling him,
posing as a friend.
That would explain
the disposable cell phones.
That's the trigger.
Mark's release set them off.
Yeah, right, great.
So Ellen was still mad
because there was no justice
served for her nephew's death,
and...her and Darlene must
have agreed to swap revenge killings.
And they'd avoid
getting caught.
It's like
"Strangers on a Train."
Yeah, but this ain't
Hitchcock, folks.
Why kill Paul? He was just
a character witness for Mark.
A character witness who
traveled 300 miles once a week
to see his friend
in prison.
Friends usually
distance themselves
from rapists and murderers.
Unless you're involved.
Garcia, you and JJ look
into Kelly's disappearance.
We need to find out
how these unsubs got to Paul
and anybody else who might
have been involved in the case.
All right, I'll let him know.
Ok. Got it.
My officers just interviewed
Darlene's ex-husband.
He says she hasn't been the same
since Kelly disappeared.
She's been suffering
from chronic depression.
The loss of a child either brings
you together or breaks you apart.
The day she disappeared,
Kelly left school early
because she and her mother
were going on vacation,
but she never made it home.
They found her underwear
in Mark's car,
which led to his confession.
I got the lab results
back from Kelly's rape.
It turns out there was a second
DNA sample on her underwear,
but it's too degraded
to make a match.
Maybe the women suspected
it was Paul's.
San Diego PD just searched
Ellen's house.
She's not there, but they put an officer
out front just in case she comes back.
So we need to figure out
who Paul was to Mark in college.
They ran cross-country, sometimes
participating in a relay together.
It means
they were close.
Don't 4 people do relays?
[Beep]
Hey, baby girl.
Hey.
Listen, we need to figure out
who ran in the cross-country relay
with Paul Montgomery and Mark Coleman.
Bryce Phillips
and Jason Nelson.
They look inseparable.
And where are they now?
Bryce lives in Amsterdam,
Jason in the Los Feliz area
of Los Angeles.
And what was Jason's
relationship with Mark like
when he went to jail?
Jason was at the hearing and he
visited Mark once a week in prison,
so, close?
He probably participated
in the crime.
And our killing duo
found out about it.
That would explain
the change in M.O.
Maybe Mark gave a dying declaration
and gave up his boys.
Maybe our ladies
are improvising,
which explains killing
Paul outside his job.
We need to get to Jason's
house before they do.
[TV plays]
[Glass breaking]
[Turns TV off]
Today's your lucky day, Jason.
Who are you?
Kelly's mom.
You remember Kelly,
don't you?
Oh--I can explain.
I can explain.
Too late.
I'll do anything
you want. Ok?
I could take you
to her body.
Her body?
You know where
my baby is?
Yeah, yeah.
I can take you there.
If I do that,
you'll let me go, right?
[Sirens]
Clear.
Guys, there's broken glass
over here.
And blood on the floor.
Morgan! JJ!
Search the bedrooms.
Blake, check outside,
see if Jason was dragged.
I am serious. I am not--
I'm not the same guy
that I used to be.
Shut up!
I think about
what I did to her every day.
Which way?
I--right.
I--I--I have
a girlfriend now,
and I have a good job.
I've changed.
Change is crap.
Ok? People just become
more of who they are.
You don't know me.
Tell me what you did
to my daughter that day.
Darlene...
Where did you take her?
Don't answer that.
I have the right to know.
It's complicated.
She was 8 years old.
You tell me what
you did to her!
He was into improving himself.
"Let's do healthy
relationships."
Go figure.
Guy seems in love.
Ok.
Um...
Uh...it was, uh...
It was hot that day.
We were all just sitting around
getting high,
and then out of the blue,
Mark asked if, uh,
if any one of us
had ever been with a...
with a little girl.
I mean, of course
we said--we said no,
but then someone said...
that we should
go and get one.
And the next thing we know,
we were out on the corner.
We're waiting and...
I--I--
we were just about to leave...
When your daughter walked by.
And so you thought, we'll just
snatch this little black girl.
Hey. It had nothing
to do with race.
My best friend is black.
It's just...
Oh...
Oh, Kelly, she was
just--she was so pretty. Oh--
That's enough!
Oh, we just lit up. Oh....
Mommy should have been
on time.
[Sobbing]
Son of a bitch!
Aah!
Come on.
What are you doing?
Oh, you think this is funny?
Ohh!
I have been dying to tell
that story for so long.
Aah!
Stop it! Stop it!
- Are you serious?
- I need to find her.
I need to bring her
back home.
She is dead!
And we are killing
this guy.
No, I can't! I have got to
bring her back home.
[Groans] Ellen,
closure is important
to a mom.
And, uh...
[Coughs, groans]
Whoo! Ahh.
Besides, to protect myself,
I told a neighbor
to write down
the license plate
of any strange car
that came by.
So...
you were expecting us?
Well, I knew you found
the first two.
I assumed I'd be next.
Ucch. Why are men so messy?
I don't get down like this.
I'm a clean freak.
Why does that
not surprise me?
Something's just...
off about this guy.
Gut feeling?
Deep gut.
Jennifer Jareau, your gut
knows what it's talking about.
So nothing about Jason Nelson
seems out of the ordinary?
He seems as all-American
as apple pie.
No reports of any bodies found.
Maybe they haven't
killed him yet.
We'll keep you posted.
This guy might give these ladies
a run for their money.
Morgan: Trophies.
Kelly wasn't the only girl.
This is all a facade.
Jason's a psychopath.
A psychopath versus
two vigilantes.
I have a feeling this
is not going to end well.
Is this it?
Is this where
you put Kelly?
Uh...hmm...
No.
What do you mean?
You said
this was where she is.
Well, I will take you there
if you do something for me.
No! This is not
a negotiation.
No. It's a bribe.
What do you want?
Kill someone.
Anyone.
And then I'll tell you
where it is.
You want us to just kill
some random person?
That's what I said.
I want you to know
how good I felt.
That's disgusting!
We're not murderers.
Oh, really?
That's not what it looks like
from here.
And besides,
if you don't do it,
my neighbor will drop
a dime on you, remember?
You didn't tell
your neighbor.
You'll never know.
Darlene, do you want to
find your daughter or not?
Not like this.
You don't have a choice,
ladies.
Yeah, we do!
Darlene, just do it.
I can't!
Damn it!
Ohh!
Pow! Boom!
Noo!
Awesome!
Oh, no, no, no!
Now you take us
to her daughter.
Or you're next.
Ohh.
The victim says he was shot
by a white woman.
She was with a black woman
and a white guy.
These women have been
so specific about their victims
up until this point,
why shoot a random person?
Jason's a psychopath.
Maybe he made them do it.
He could be
holding them hostage.
Or he's got something
that's keeping him alive.
A bargaining chip?
Maybe he knows
where Kelly's body's buried.
But Ellen did the shooting,
not Darlene.
Ellen tortured
the second victim.
And she's helping Darlene
kill the rest of Kelly's assailants,
when she could have
just walked away.
So this woman
is a psychopath, too.
Then Jason's made
a love connection.
And he'll probably try
to manipulate Ellen
to do something worse.
We lost these women
a long time ago.
Blake, turn Jason's place
upside down.
We need to find where
they may have put Kelly's body.
Ellen, why?!
Now, why did you
go and do that?!
We have come too far.
Bull. She liked it.
No, she didn't.
Tell him
you didn't like that.
Oh, oh, you know,
if we were smart, Ellen,
we'd partner up.
Shut up!
We could drive
across the country
just killing people.
I'd get my little girls,
and you can get,
you know, whoever you wanted.
That's enough!
Wouldn't it be great...
To live in a world
where no one judged you?
I wouldn't judge you, baby.
I would have your back.
Come on.
Come on,
what do you say?
If we are not at that body
in the next 20 minutes,
I'm gonna take that gun and
shove it so far down your throat,
you're gonna wish
you were dead.
Yeah, yeah...
just make a left.
This is getting exciting.
Hmm...
Hmm hmm hmm,
let's see.
I think it was over here
to the right.
You think or you know?
I know. I just moved it.
Why would you do that?
When Mark died,
I needed to cover my tracks.
Uh...oh. Oh. Oh.
It's right here.
I remember.
Right...here.
Start digging.
The landlord says this is
Jason's storage closet.
It looks like
my storage unit.
My husband has so much crap,
it's not funny.
Is it hard being in a relationship
with someone overseas?
We make it work.
Working for Doctors Without Borders
is a very noble cause.
I would imagine you guys have
an epistolary novel by now, though.
We stick to Skype.
It's modern.
When we're together,
it's like we're dating,
and when we're not,
I get stuff done.
Look at this.
Fresh loam soil.
Usually found near
plains and streams.
Either he was
just camping...
Or used it
to move the body.
Jason finds out
his friends are killed,
he might take precautions.
What is taking so long?
I'm almost there.
Hurry up!
[Thud]
Oh...
Oh. Oh...
There it is.
That's just a skull.
Where's the rest
of my daughter?
We have a few more
holes to dig.
You cut up my baby?
That was my idea, too.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
[Laughing]
Oh, my God!
[Screaming]
There's loam soil surrounding
some Southern California beaches
and also loam soil around
some parks in the area.
What areas are near
running trails?
Uh, there is a trail
in the Hollywood Hills area
that is lousy with loam soil.
And I'm sending Morgan
and Rossi to the location now.
Over here.
They got him.
We've got officers at Ellen
and Darlene's homes
just in case
they come back.
And have them check the airports,
bus stations, train stations, everything.
I'll also put an APB out
along the coast.
Garcia cross-checked
the trophies we found at Jason's,
and they match articles
from 3 different missing children.
And have officers
excavate the area
around where
Jason's body was found.
There may be
more bodies there.
I'm on it.
Blake:
At least we got Jason.
He could have kept
killing forever.
And the women
just get away.
Hmm. For now.
You ok?
Yeah.
[Chatter, laughter]
So now what?
Well,
um, we're gonna split up.
I might keep heading south.
You'd do good here.
Yeah. You're right.
I think it's better
if we don't stay together.
You know what I don't get?
How this was so easy for you.
How so?
We had to kill 5 people.
Our deal was just for two.
That's not what
I'm talking about.
Does it bother you that none
of this took the hurt away?
I never thought it would.
Then why did we do it?
Because somebody
has to pay, ok?
I don't care
what anybody says.
Actions have consequences.
Maybe not at trial.
Maybe not in jail.
Come on.
Admit it, Darlene,
this gave you
a reason to live.
That's what I was hoping.
But it just made me
feel more...
more nothing.
Then you're a wuss.
I'm gonna go get us
something cold to drink.
Wait. I diss you and you care
if I'm thirsty?
Huh. You gotta start
thinking about yourself, honey.
That's the game.
Dollars ok?
Gracias.
Ellen Russel?
How'd you find me?
Darlene never unpacked
her daughter's bags from this trip.
And I took a wild guess.
So what happens now?
What happens now
is you go back to the U.S.
I take 6 days off
that I don't even want.
Where's Darlene?
She's long gone.
Personally, I have
mixed feelings about that one.
But we'll get her, too.
Levantese.
[Speaking spanish]
...a Los Estados Unidos.
Rossi: Thanks for your help.
Rossi: Paul Brown once said,
"If you win, say nothing.
If you lose, say less."
== sync, corrected by elderman ==