May your neighbors respect you...
trouble neglect you...
the angels protect you...
and heaven accept you. Mmm?
To better days.
- Cheers.
- Hey! Hey, hey, hey.
- Hey, who is that guy?
- Easy, lads.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Finn.
Caught the first flight soon as I heard.
Yeah...
Terrible circumstances.
But it sure is good to see you.
Be a good lad.
Go fetch our friend Finn a drink.
It's Rory...
isn't it?
This is him, then?
I didn't want him
to follow my footsteps...
but he insisted.
He came over to make his fortune
and now, look.
Two cents to his name.
He was a good kid, Finn.
And now he's dead.
You know, maybe you've been
out of the game too long to remember.
Death... is part of the deal.
Leave it, leave it.
Holy shit.
Jesus...
Cheers.
Yous all all right, yeah?
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
Now, this bloody shooter,
he stole $1.2 million of my money.
Man takes my son.
I lose a boy.
He takes my money.
I'm getting it back.
We will beat every mother's son
in this city
till I have my money in my hands,
and this shooter's on his knees, alive.
Or there'll be more of you
shining the inside of a box!
Do you hear me?
Get out!
Get out! Move! Let's go!
That bastard shooter
that massacred our brothers.
- Where is he?
- I don't know!
New faces.
Military training.
- Think fast!
- I don't know! Wait, wait!
Wait! I might have seen one guy!
Hey, excuse me! Yeah, you.
How's it going, huh?
- Oh, Jesus.
- You having a good day?
We're looking for a customer.
- What?
- Wears a jacket...
even in the middle of summer,
or so they say.
I... I mean...
Now, I count two ankles,
two knees, one elbow.
And guess what?
I got five more rounds.
I don't...
I think I know.
Has a dog, right?
Came in here.
I even saw him walk it once.
Elaborate.
Aw.
Sit.
Search the closets.
Dog's one of ours.
This is the place.
- Nah, it's empty.
- Find my goddamn money.
You heard him.
Let's go!
He's not one for fancy living, is he?
Pull that up.
Shut that damn dog up!
Hey! Knock it off!
Uh, nothing...
but it ain't money.
The money's not here.
That's who you are.
Move it.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard
www.addic7ed.com
- Hi.
- Hey.
- I'm just about ready.
- Okay.
- Uh, here, let me help with that.
- Oh, thanks.
- It's okay.
- Oh.
Sorry.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I'm just, uh...
recovering.
From what?
I don't really know the name for it.
But... you're feeling better?
Yeah.
Now.
With you.
Not that I can verify,
but you seem good at this.
Uh, well, my brother wasn't,
so that's where I came in.
You never said you had a brother.
Uh... you never asked.
- Uh, thank you.
- Mmm.
Come on. It's about time.
"Precious in the eyes
of the Lord...
is the death of his saints."
Well...
Elliot Grote was no saint.
He was human...
deeply flawed.
Every Sunday,
for as far as I remember...
Elliot would come here...
friendless and alone...
to sit.
Right there in that pew.
Often, I would see him take...
whatever money he had...
crumpled one hundreds, loose change...
a Rolex watch one time...
and put it in the collection plate...
hoping for redemption.
Which would never come.
Praying for the light...
but Elliot died still in the dark...
with no one to mourn his loss...
except the three of you.
And so, we might say...
one life gone...
one sinful life...
but one person is not just one person.
In each of us,
there is a world...
webbing out, reaching others.
Creating reactions.
Sometimes equal...
sometimes opposite.
We rush to say, one life gone...
but each of us is a world.
And today,
a world has been lost.
We didn't know him well, but I...
never loved the idea of letting
anyone die alone.
He... He wasn't alone?
They found him surrounded by
knocked out Dogs of Hell, right?
I get all the bad guys
confused these days.
Didn't think it could get much worse
out there, the violence, but...
What if I meet you back at the office?
I'm just gonna take a minute here.
Yeah, sure.
- It was a nice sermon.
- Thank you.
Most priests would have found something
kind to say about the man himself, but...
I said he came to church.
Nothing shines up a halo
faster than a death, Matthew.
But funerals are for the living...
and revising history...
only dilutes the lessons
we should learn from it.
It wasn't my fault.
- What wasn't?
- Grotto's death.
- No one said it was.
- Yeah.
There's a new man in town, he's, uh...
killing people in cold blood.
Yeah, I read about
what happened with the Irish.
Must have been a...
busy couple nights.
Yeah, I did everything I could to...
uh, protect my client.
- That work is done, Matthew.
- Because I failed.
At least you tried.
Well, like you said,
his life had value.
A whole world's been lost
and others are dying one after the other...
Matthew, what are you looking for?
- Forgiveness.
- For what?
Uh... not doing more?
You just said
you did everything you could.
If you're the man I understand you to be,
I'm sure that's true.
Then why do I still feel guilty?
Guilt can be a good thing.
It's the soul's call to action.
The indication that...
something is wrong.
The only way...
to rid your heart of it...
is to correct your mistakes
and keep going...
until amends are made.
I don't know what you didn't do
or what you should have done...
but the guilt...
the guilt...
means your work is not yet finished.
Thank you.
He's lucky to be alive.
This is all of the stuff
that the DA's collecting for her case.
And most of it's about
the Punisher's victims.
The Dogs of Hell, the cartel...
But this was in the middle of it.
Not someone he shot, him.
He's insane.
Maybe he shot himself.
I thought about that,
but at that close of a range...
Yeah, he'd be dead already.
Okay, not to go all tin-foil hat here,
but Tower obviously
slipped this to me for a reason.
What if the Punisher
isn't the worst of it?
What if Reyes is trying
to cover something up?
You think that murderous
psychopath isn't the worst of it?
No. And I think our best shot
at protecting Nelson and Murdock
is to find him.
It's our best shot
at career suicide...
or just getting shot.
- Am I insane?
- Nelson and Murdock.
- Matt?
- Sorry, what?
Nothing, just...
Father Lantom's eulogy
really got to me, I guess.
Yeah, he does that.
Mmm, Punisher's a lunatic.
But you care, anyway?
I wouldn't say that, it's more like...
curious.
In between these files and...
and Reyes' obsession
and the fact that humans are a pretty
complicated species to begin with,
I just...
I feel like there's gotta be
more to the story.
I think you are...
Oh, my God, you think I'm insane.
I'm kidding.
Compassionate.
- Hmm.
- It's a good quality, Karen.
Stuff of saints.
Yeah, well, I'm no saint.
I can't tell you
how glad I am to hear that.
Matt!
We have real, live,
non-criminal clients who need our help.
- Excuse me for a second.
- Yeah.
Tell me.
Mr. DiPesta defaced the elevator
in his building.
Which, technically,
makes him a criminal.
That's what his slumlord, excuse me,
landlord says, but look.
He's got no AC,
no hot water.
This has Nelson and Murdock
written all over it.
But we gotta file today.
Karen!
- Maybe she stepped out.
- Did she take the files?
- Huh?
- From Reyes.
The... the Punisher files.
Oh, shit.
I have to find her.
Find him first.
You're early.
You know
I don't like being rushed.
- I need the suit, Melvin.
- Yeah, I figured.
You know, you getting popped in the noggin
gave me a chance to try some new stuff
and I'm pretty excited about it.
Fortified, carbon tube helmet.
I mean, it's pretty damn close
to indestructible.
- How close?
- I'll leave the testing to you.
I threw in some reinforced alloy gloves.
You know, what the hell.
Gotta be careful.
Some new people
spilling a lot of blood out there.
Who?
Don't know.
But all my old contacts are showing up
again begging me to outfit 'em.
Did you?
No, I don't do that anymore.
I turned them all away.
- Oh, you look better.
- Yeah, I feel better.
Glad you're on the mend.
So am I.
Well, stay safe out there,
will you?
Thanks, Melvin. You too.
Oh, I'm not taking any chances.
Check this out.
Huh?
Gotta stay strong for Betsy.
You wanna take a look?
I mean, it's pretty wicked.
I'm gonna take your word for it.
Uh, George Buck?
Hi, the hospital told me
I might find you here.
Hi, uh... are you one of them?
Sorry, one of who?
Please, just leave me alone.
I'm not gonna
do anything to you.
If anything, I'd like to help
you get your job back.
Look, I need to understand why you were
fired from Metro-General
in the first place.
Could I buy you a cup of coffee?
You were with him when this was taken?
Yeah. That bullet tore through his head.
Not many people survive that.
Well, I'd like to know
what you remember.
John Doe.
Guy was a total vegetable.
I guess that's why they decided
he only needed one nurse.
Any family or visitors?
No.
I mean...
aside from the suits.
- Suits?
- Yeah.
Uh, sometimes men,
sometimes women.
You can tell 'em 'cause
they all wear the same ear pieces.
That and the... black suits.
Kind of like... uh...
Got any idea who these suits were?
No.
Uh, but they had their run of the place
and they were the ones
that pushed for the, uh, the DNR.
- A "do not resuscitate"?
- Yeah.
They had the paperwork.
And I was there when the doctor
pulled the plug.
I... I'm confused.
You're saying this guy died?
Yeah, for about a minute.
It's crazy, but they say
it happens sometimes.
You know, one minute,
flatline, then boom.
His heart starts back up again.
On its own.
He just didn't wanna die.
Within ten minutes of being awake...
he reaches up
and grabs my scrubs,
yanks me down,
and says, real close...
"Take me home."
I shouldn't have done it.
I should've known it'd get me fired.
His home.
Do you have an address?
Nice night.
I'm not alone.
You wanna come with us?
Or you wanna make a mess?
Don't shoot!
We want him alive!
Who, who needs me alive?
- Drop it! Drop it!
- Drop it!
Calm down! Everyone, calm down!
No one shoot!
Well, thanks
for thinning out the herd.
You're surrounded, son.
Now be a good lad and drop the iron.
Come on.
You seem like a smart one.
- Tell Carter we're about done here.
- Got it.
We're finishing up the murder scene
at Stanley's bar. Over.
Copy.
I need to know
what happened here.
I'm not telling you shit.
You helped us catch Fisk,
that don't make us friends.
Was this the Punisher?
Jesus.
The Irish, okay?
To find the Punisher.
They put a bounty on his head.
Now people all over the Kitchen
are getting hurt.
It's the goddamn Wild West out there.
Have the Irish found him?
As long as we keep getting
calls like this, I guess not.
Hey, stay out of it.
You hear me?
- I just wanna help, Sergeant.
- No, you can't help.
You're the problem!
'Cause of you, the uniform means dick.
Cops are no longer preventing crime,
we're just chasing it.
Mopping up the mess
that you people leave in your wake.
We're on the same side,
you and I.
You're on your own side.
2-Adam, shots fired.
65th Street transverse, by the carousel.
All units to back.
Fifteen Sergeant responding, Central.
Who did this?
People you don't mess with.
You're bleeding out.
And I got all night.
Go to hell!
Who did it?
The one they call Punisher.
Where is he?
It doesn't matter
'cause when we're done with him,
he's as good as dead.
That's helpful.
But it's not what I asked.
You're quite an artist
with the AK, aren't ya?
Nesbitt.
Kelly...
my oldest boy.
Every one gone to the angels
because of you.
You're dying tonight.
The hole's been dug.
But I'm giving you one chance
to meet your maker
with arms and legs attached.
Generosity's my defining trait.
You care for a nibble?
No?
Ah, suit yourself.
Helps calm me nerves.
I look nervous to you?
Boys.
Give us a moment.
I want my money back.
Your kid's in a box,
but you want your money. Huh?
The Irish may not have invented revenge,
but we sure as hell
took some time perfecting it.
Don't think you're showing me something
I haven't seen before,
'cause your killing spree
has all the signs
of a man seeking retribution.
Am I right?
Okay.
I'll tell you...
I'll tell you where your money is.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I promise you, it'll be over soon.
In a jiffy.
Come on, yeah?
How'd that feel?
Boys, hold him down!
Hey...
Come on! Come on!
Oh, I was hoping
it would come to this.
Yeah?
You gonna do it
or you gonna talk about it?
I'm here!
I'll kill every one of you bastards!
Come on, I'll kill you!
Where would you like it?
Here, huh? Here?
Not such a big man now,
are ya?
What was that?
Murph?
- Take that side.
- All right.
- Keep eyes on.
All right.
New plan.
Bring him in.
Hey...
It seems like you've taken
a liking to this mutt.
Good boy, good boy.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey, if I don't get my money...
everything I've done to you,
I'm doing double to poor Fido here, huh?
Huh...
Good boy, good boy, huh.
Wait, wait, wait.
Hey, let him go,
just let him go, you asshole.
I'll tell you where your money is, okay?
I'll tell you.
Your money's in a van, okay?
It's in a van.
It's on 48th and 10th.
Just let him...
Just let him go,
you asshole, let him go.
He's an animal lover.
That's sweet.
Take him out.
Come on, let's go.
Now, if you don't mind...
I'll keep you alive
until the cash is safe at hand.
Yeah?
48th and 10th.
Yeah, make it quick.
And watch your backside.
Get him.
Yeah,
I think it went well.
- Yeah, it's the same old story.
- I know, I know. I hear ya.
- What are you gonna do about it, right?
- Ah, nothing.
Yeah.
Yeah, I got the case.
Hold on.
Yeah, the money's all here, Mr. Finn.
Wait, wait, there's something else.
Son of a bitch.
He's loose.
Get down here.
Jimmy! Shaun!
Jimmy!
You wanted this.
No, I counted on it.
Now I can ask you face to face.
Who was there that day?
Who killed my family?
- Your family?
- Yeah.
- Who cares?
- Move!
Move! Go, go, go!
Shoot that son of a bitch!
- We got him! Come on!
- Yeah!
- Get down here!
- One batch, two batch.
Penny and dime.
They're gonna pay.
Every single goddamn one of 'em.
They will.
But not tonight. Move.
There! That room there.
- No killing.
- Altar boy.
All right,
let's get out of here.
Come on.
Hey.
Not bad.
Thanks.
I guess I, uh...
I guess I was wrong.
About?
About you being a pussy.
Don't get all sweet on me now, Frank.
- Help's on the way.
- Nah.
You should go.
I'm past saving.
At least I'd have company, right?
I think I might cash out.
You'd have made a hell of a Marine, Red.
That rhyme.
- What's it mean?
- What'd you say?
- Huh?
- Thing you say.
Right before you pull the trigger.
What do you...
You heard that?
Yeah, I heard it.
What the...
I gotta say, sometimes...
Sometimes I think
you really just might be the devil.
Sometimes I think I might be, too.
It's, uh...
One batch, two batch.
Penny and dime, you know.
It was her favorite book.
You know, you...
You gotta cross the ocean... and go fight.
You see...
whole time you're thinking
you're gonna be scared, right?
But then, you're not.
See, that part of it was
always easy for me.
Killing.
Even watching my buddies die,
it just...
it didn't mean nothing.
The first time I got scared...
was on a plane on the way home.
I kept thinking God was gonna pull the rug
out from under us, you know?
Shit, that's his kind of funny, you know.
But the plane landed safe
and we were home.
Driving through traffic.
Yeah, you pass fast food
and donut shops and all that...
that greasy shit.
It's the shit you fought to protect
and then the car stops.
We were outside her school.
I get to her classroom, right?
She's in there...
but she's got no idea.
She's got no idea that Daddy's home.
I walk in, these kids,
they're not even studying, they're...
doing some kind of yoga. Yeah.
You know?
She's there.
She's doing her poses,
you know.
She's bending and,
you know, she's moving.
She looks like a flower.
Yeah.
And, you know,
you can't even understand it,
you know, how does
something like that have...
How does something that beautiful...
How does that...
does that come from me, you know?
And she looks up and she sees me.
I see her.
By God, that's real.
That's real, Red.
Boom.
In an instant,
she's across that classroom floor,
she's in my arms.
She's squeezing me so tight,
I swear I was gonna bust a rib, you know?
We just stayed there like that,
we're holding each other.
Teacher, she's filming the whole thing
on her phone, you know,
she's gonna put it on
YouTube or some shit.
She can't hold the thing steady,
because, you know, she's...
she's bawling so hard,
and the kids are all wailing,
you know, they're screaming.
And me?
Shit, I'm the worst of all.
I'm a...
I'm a rubber-face clown,
you know.
I cried so hard.
But not my baby.
Not my girl.
You know,
she's my girl. She's...
She's not crying,
she's holding me up.
My girl,
she's keeping me on my feet.
She says,
"I knew it, Daddy. I knew it."
And then we go home.
Wife, the boy.
Place is the exact same.
It's like it was just holding its breath
waiting for me to get back, you know?
Then it hit me.
All of it, you know.
The first time I felt how tired I was,
you know, I was just...
tired, you know?
You...
You ever been tired, Red?
Yeah.
So, you know.
It's just, I couldn't do nothing,
you know?
All the things...
I couldn't take my wife to bed.
Ball with the boy. Shit...
I was too tired, I couldn't even drink
a goddamn beer, you know.
But not her.
My girl was up.
See, she wanted me to, uh...
she wanted me to tuck her in.
She...
She outgrew it, she knew it,
but she didn't care.
She wanted it.
She had that book.
Her favorite book was out on the pillows.
One Batch, Two Batch...
Penny and Dime.
Yeah.
I read her that book every night
before this shit.
I read it every single night,
but, see, that was over now
because Daddy's home now.
She looked at me and she begged me, Red.
She begged.
I said, "No.
Daddy's too tired, see.
But I'll...
I'll read to you tomorrow night.
I'll read to you
tomorrow night, I promise." Yeah.
Never think that...
for her there was not gonna be
any tomorrow, see.
The last time I'd see her,
I'd be holding her lifeless body
in my arms.
Meat was spilling out of her, Red.
The place where her face used to be.
Yeah.
I think I'm done... Red.
I think I'm done.
Police. Don't move.
Hands where I can see 'em.
Shots fired.
Bodies, mayhem and shit.
How come I just knew it had to be you?
I have something for you, Sergeant.
That's him?
- Cover him and get EMS.
- Yep.
And you,
you incredible pain in my ass.
You're under arrest.
Get him help.
Shut up.
- Take the collar.
- What?
You heard me.
You caught him, not me.
It can't be me,
it has to be you.
Why?
To protect the Kitchen.
For law, for order.
You're telling me
how to file a report now?
Yeah. Take the collar.
Take the credit.
Get a promotion, if you can.
- You've earned it.
- Bullshit.
No, people have to know the system works.
Not his justice and not mine.
Vigilante days are done in this town.
The police are in charge.
That's not how it happened.
Then make it how it happened.
Shit.
EMT and backup on the way.
Two minutes out.
Go.
Go!
I don't know what you are...
but I know you ain't him.
Frank Castle,
the gunman wanted in connection
with the Metro-General shooting
and linked to dozens
of recent gangland-related killings
throughout Hell's Kitchen
was apprehended just hours ago
outside Saint Michael's Cemetery.
An NYPD spokesman says, "Tonight,
New York has Sergeant Brett Mahoney
of the 15th Precinct to thank."
Gotta hand it to Brett.
I'm glad people like him
are looking out for Hell's Kitchen.
Yeah.
And I'm glad someone
was looking out for him.
Press are calling Castle
"a cold-blooded psychopath."
The DA's gonna have a hell of a time
using his prosecution
to turn herself into a hero.
It's all working out perfectly.
- Wow, way to bring us down.
- I'm...
Hey, Josie,
would you mind turning the TV off?
It's upsetting some of the regulars.
I think we've had enough Punisher
for one evening.
- Hmm. Okay. I'll drink to that.
- All right?
To Brett and... a safe Hell's Kitchen.
- Hear, hear.
- Mmm-hmm.
Oh.
- I'm gonna get us another round.
- Good.
I hope you two saved room for shots.
- Same again.
- Oh, no, no.
Oh, shots.
Thanks, Fog.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
Okay, that wasn't convincing, was it?
Um...
I don't know, I just, uh...
days like today...
remind me how precious life can be,
you know?
What's your brother like?
Um...
Uh, he's sweet. He's...
a good brother.
Careful, Matt.
What's that?
Keep going like this,
you just might end up happy.
And for a Catholic boy,
that's a pretty dangerous thing.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Godspeed, Matt Murdock.
Hey, where next?
Home.
I'm gonna sleep for a week.
Someone had the awful idea of doing shots.
I think I've had enough excitement
for one evening.
- See you two in the morning.
- Okay. Yeah.
- See ya, Fog.
- Bye.
Do you mind the rain?
No.
Then I'll walk you home.
- Can I take you to dinner?
- Yes.
- Tomorrow?
Good night, Karen.
Good night, Matt.
Hello, Matthew.
Elektra.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
Resync by GoldenBeard
www.addic7ed.com