Previously on Dexter...
No blood. What a gorgeous idea.
Refrigerated truck. He wants a cold
environment to slow the flow of blood.
I suppose I should be upset, but I'm not.
In fact, I think this is a friendly message, kind
of like, "Hey, wanna play?"
Kara, it's me. It's James.
You just opened a dangerous door.
No, man. You did...
when you murdered a cop
and an innocent lady.
Was Kara sleeping with someone
other than Ricky?
Was it you?
What the fuck were you thinking?
Going out tonight with the guys,
blow off steam. You in?
Hey, man. Sounds good.
I thought you said you wanted
to go get shit-faced.
I am shit-faced.
I showed my face to Guerrero, his whole
church. They're gonna think I'm behind this.
You fucked my sister.
You fucked a cop's wife.
Now you're just fucked, buddy.
He's escalating the thrill,
posing his victim in the middle of
a 20,000-seat arena
for all Miami to see,
to show us what he's capable of doing.
- What did I miss?
- Fingertips.
Fuckin'-A, that's my girl. This body belongs to
the frozen fingertips found in the truck.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you Tony Tucci, the ice-truck killer.
Bullshit.
Of course I agree with my sister,
but unlike her, I'm not upset.
He's still out there and I'm waiting...
breathless.
I find people around me
are all making some kind of connection,
like friendship or romance.
But human bonds always
lead to messy complications,
commitment, sharing,
driving people to the airport.
Besides, if I let someone get that close, they'd
see who I really am...
and I can't let that happen.
So, time to put on my mask.
- I need your expertise.
- I live to serve.
Excuse us, fellas.
Interesting hand job.
That's funny.
It is?
How long you think it's been there?
This feels familiar.
OK.
So, how long's it been there?
Blood stopped pooling, still wet,
couple hours at the most.
What time was it found?
A jogger called it in
this morning about 7:30.
No prints. Wiped clean.
Real creep show.
- Any sign of the rest of the body?
- Just Mr. Hand.
- Do you think this is our guy's work?
- The ice-truck killer?
It's hard to say.
There's blood. That's different.
Plus, it's a male victim,
haven't seen that before.
The cut appears to be almost delicate.
You see between the first and second row
of carpals... Very surgical.
Check out what else he left behind.
A postcard to remember him by.
How far is Rand Beach from here?
This is Rand Beach.
It was renamed Petrie Beach
a few years ago.
No, no, come on.
OK, everybody.
Everybody say...
"stinky feet."
Wait. Nobody move.
Dexter, were you smiling?
No.
We'll do another one.
This time everybody smile. You too, Dex.
- Yeah, pretend you're burning ants.
- Shut your damn face, Deb.
Language, please.
- What? She always talks like that.
- Enough, you two. Dexter, come here.
What's your problem?
I hate the beach. It's sandy and gross
and nasty, and I want to go home.
Too bad. You're part of a family.
And being part of a family
means smiling for photos.
Why should I pretend I'm happy?
Because it'll make your mom happy.
And because it's how you fit in.
- Remember we talked about that?
- Yeah.
This is how you do it. When somebody takes
your picture, you smile.
It doesn't matter if you're happy or not.
You just do it to fit in. OK?
- OK.
- All right.
Come here, handsome.
OK. Everybody ready?
One more time.
Stinky feet!
Yeah, I just need to stop by my
apartment to pick up a few labs.
Straight to the station after, yeah.
Thanks, Lieutenant.
Dexter Morgan...
this is your life.
It is my new friend,
the ice-truck killer.
When he broke into my apartment,
he took some time to get to know me,
my life.
My secrets.
..have brought in manpower from other
counties in an effort to expedite the search.
Officially, Mr. Tucci has not
been charged with any crime...
Then tell the fucking governor
to free up funds for overtime.
The more guys I got out there,
the sooner we find Tucci.
Kelly, I'll get back to you.
..is still the department's top priority.
What's wrong?
Fingerprint ID came back
on that hand from the beach.
It belongs to Tony Tucci,
your ice-truck killer suspect.
What?
Wait a minute.
No. No, no, no. No way.
No way.
I mean, this... This has to be a mistake.
The mistake was unleashing a high-profile
manhunt before you had all the facts.
Fuck.
OK. This doesn't mean
that Tucci is not the killer.
Don't.
Just.. Just don't.
You wanted to be on TV, well, get ready, cos
the press will annihilate us for this.
We'll be lucky if Tucci's mother
doesn't file a lawsuit.
All right.
You go talk to that woman.
Do your mea culpas.
If we handle this right...
maybe we can mitigate the fallout.
I'm the last person she wants to see.
I called her son a killer.
And now's your chance to make it right.
- LaGuerta screwed the pooch on this one.
- I'm taking point.
You can get all non-essentials off the beach.
- Secure and separate any witnesses.
- Will do.
What did the captain say?
Did he make her cry?
Just control the fucking beach, Angel.
I knew Tucci wasn't the killer. I knew it.
LaGuerta whipped up a manhunt
for a rent-a-cop.
I wish I could have been there
to see the captain rip her a new one.
Morgan, calm down.
LaGuerta insulted the killer's intelligence,
now he's getting back at us
for chasing after the wrong guy.
- You see all these people over here?
- Yeah.
- What are they?
- Potential witnesses.
And what do we do with
potential witnesses?
We...
We interview them.
Got it.
Where is he?
The rest of him?
We're... We're still looking.
The entire force is looking.
We're making every effort.
Are you sure it's Tony? Because...
Yes.
I'm afraid so.
Mrs. Tucci.
I said some very harsh things
about your son.
Thank you.
"Thank you"? For what?
For coming to tell me in person.
For God's sake, please.
- There's nothing more important than this.
- Can you find my son's body?
If it's the last thing I do.
- I made a grave...
- Bring him home, please.
I just want to bury my son.
- I do love Halloween.
- What's inside of a pumpkin?
See for yourself.
What? You don't like this stuff? I do.
Come on. Get in there.
I'll finish cleaning this out.
You can carve it tomorrow.
There he is again, Mom.
My God. It's every night now.
That dog? Where's it coming from?
Next door. My neighbor's.
Leaves the poor thing
in the yard all day and night.
It's been getting worse. I would talk to her,
but I don't want to start something.
Listen to him, Mom. He's so sad.
I just wish he would shut up
so I could sleep.
Do you want me to talk to her?
No, you don't have to do that.
I insist.
- Hello. I don't think we've met.
- Boyfriend of the blonde next door.
I've seen you around.
I'm just getting in. I'm tired.
That's precisely why I'm here.
We can't help but notice your dog cries...
- A lot.
- I know.
My ex moved out and left his dog.
I wish there was something I could do.
You could...
take him inside.
Walter's an outside dog.
- Put Walter inside, Walter's an inside dog.
- He doesn't like being inside.
Did he tell you that?
We'd appreciate it if you could find a way
to keep him quiet. The kids are upset.
Maybe that's cos they think
their crackhead father
is gonna come back
and beat their asses again.
You know what works for me?
Earplugs.
I could make things
so much easier for Rita...
but that would be wrong.
I love Halloween.
The one time of year
when everyone wears a mask, not just me.
People think it's fun
to pretend you're a monster.
Me, I spend my life pretending I'm not.
Brother, friend, boyfriend,
all part of my costume collection.
Some people might call me a fraud.
Let's see if it will fit.
Boo!
You stabbed me in the back!
I prefer to think of myself
as a master of disguise.
They're so excited.
Sure they are. They get to binge on sugar for
an entire day.
Who wouldn't love that?
What about a costume for you?
Maybe this one?
No. I think I'll be Snow White again.
It's kind of tradition.
Dexter, look. I'm a princess, too.
Just like your Mom,
two perfect princesses.
- Let me guess. You're gonna be a dwarf.
- No. I want to be Joe from Blue's Clues.
I keep telling him that a rugby shirt
is not a costume.
Another photo from my family album.
He's recreating my past
with Tony Tucci's body parts.
He's forcing me to see this.
Nobody paying you to stand around
and goddamn stare.
I thought Angel was working this case,
Sergeant.
Sergeant?
Friends of yours?
Don't worry about it. Worry about this.
The foot was severed between
the tarsus and the metatarsus.
The wound is circular,
again, almost surgical.
And there's blood.
Guy gives us body after body with no blood.
Why he's making a switch now?
He's trying to send a message,
one that's more important than his ritual need
to drain the blood and wrap the parts.
OK, so what's the message?
I'm not sure.
Well, who's he sending it to?
I can't tell you that, either.
What fucking good are you?
No fucking good at all, apparently.
- You OK?
- He's mocking me.
Don't take it personally.
Doakes hates all you lab geeks.
Who?
- Relax, bro.
- Sorry.
I need to bag this photo.
It's under the ball. Do you mind?
He knows.
He's not corrupting the happy
hallmark images of my youth.
He's revealing the ugly truth behind them.
Come on, Simon.
You want it? It's right there.
Over there. Oh, yeah.
- Guys, give it back!
- Pass it over here.
You guys, give it back.
Come on, Simon.
What you gonna do?
All right. Enough.
Get out of here.
- What the hell is going on?
- We're just having fun.
It didn't look like Simon
was having too much fun to me.
You're always telling me to fit in,
I'm just trying to be part of the team.
You can't be a bully, Dexter.
First of all, it's wrong.
Secondly, people remember bullies.
People like me, cops.
A bully is a felony waiting to happen.
So?
Blend in.
Go on.
Officer Morgan,
I have an assignment for you.
I heard we found a foot this morning.
You want me to head to the crime scene?
No.
Look, we pulled these
from security cameras
around the beach, stores, hotels, ATMs.
- I want you to check every frame.
- You are shitting me.
If we're lucky, we can see the killer
coming and going.
We have techs who can do this.
Not all techs have the skill
to spot suspicious activity.
I'm taking a huge leap of faith that you do.
Keep your eye out for another box
of surveillance tapes.
It's on its way from the new crime scene.
Hey, Doakesy, what's up?
Fuck anyone's wife lately?
Thanks to your little stunt, Guerrero's guys are
tailing me everywhere I go.
That's not good, James.
You should alert the police.
Unless, of course, for some reason
the officers of Miami wouldn't help you,
like, you know,
you fucked one of their wives.
You think this is a joke. I'm gonna
end up dead. It's just a matter of when.
You should have thought of that
before you stuck your dick in my sister.
You're right. I should have waited
until the divorce came through.
Bullshit.
What? She didn't tell you?
She filed the papers, jackass.
Ask the captain. He tried to pull Ricky
out of his assignment,
- but Ricky didn't want to come out.
- Of course not.
- His job was to bring down Guerrero.
- It was his job to protect his wife.
Ricky's the motherfucker who got her killed.
You backed the wrong cop, asshole.
Let's go, guys. Time for school.
Guys? Come on. You don't want to be
in the Halloween parade?
Shut up!
Shut up! Just...
- I need to talk to you about your dog.
- I talked to your boyfriend.
My kids are exhausted.
When it comes to my kids,
I stop being nice.
So I need you to bring him in at night,
feed him on a schedule
and take him for some exercise...
I'm sorry. Is this funny?
No, no, no. It's... It's sad.
But you're funny. Look at you, all tough.
- I'm gonna call the police. I can do that.
- There's nothing you can do.
The cops will tell me to keep him quiet,
I'll say I will, and then they'll leave,
and he'll go back to doing what he does.
But you're funny.
Unlike Harry, my new friend
doesn't place much value in blending in.
He wants me to see who he is
and what he does.
Everything about him is brazen, authentic.
What does that make me?
Crap.
- You OK, man?
- No.
Don't let this bastard get to you.
You're the best blood expert in the state.
And we need you to stay with this.
I'll be all right.
Wait. Before you get back to work,
check this out.
What is that, a butterfly?
No, socio,
it's a diamond-studded four-leaf clover.
I'm...
I'm giving it to Nina for our anniversary
tomorrow night.
Oh, congratulations.
How many years?
Ten years she's been
my lucky charm now.
Tin is the traditional gift,
but I didn't think she'd want a tin clover.
No. It's probably a good plan.
Are you sure that's not a butterfly?
Well, it does kind of look like a bug.
This can't be right.
- What's up?
- You see that?
- You see it?
- I don't know. What do I see?
The blood in the hand suggested the heart was
still pumping when it was severed.
Mean son of a bitch, no doubt.
But look at the foot, it's the same blood flow,
plus the lividity.
Look, it's the same bruising,
same ashen color,
the same level of decomposition
as the hand the day we found it.
But...
- We found them a day apart.
- I know.
Here's a picture. Hollywood.
LT, you got to listen to him.
It's the guard, Tucci, I think he's alive.
What are you talking about?
The ice-truck killer is keeping him alive
to perform amputations.
Tucci's alive?
Both limbs were taken from a live body,
and we found them 24 hours apart.
That's not all. Tell them, Dexter.
If the hand came off yesterday at seven am,
and the foot this morning at seven...
- We get another body part tomorrow.
- But he's alive.
Put together a task force.
I want all available personnel on this.
And put a priority status on all forensics related
to this case.
Captain Matthews, please.
Have him call me back immediately.
Mrs. Tucci?
Maria LaGuerta.
I have some amazing news for you.
We believe your son is alive.
No. No. We haven't,
but I promise we will.
No, thank you.
Yes. Yes.
OK, we'll be in touch. Bye.
We've got a live body now, people.
We want to find Tucci
while he's still breathing.
That means figuring out where tomorrow's drop
is so we catch our man in the act.
Any ideas?
Don't forget the photos. They're new.
Thank you, Officer Morgan.
We're doing just fine out here.
Why do we think he's taking photos?
He wants to be remembered.
You use photos to record memories.
I almost feel sorry for them,
trying to put together a puzzle
when they don't know pieces are missing from
the box, pieces he gave me.
He wants me to play the game his way.
OK, what else could it be?
Change.
- You got something to say, speak.
- The beach changed names.
The office park used to be a soccer field.
He's dumping the body parts in places
that used to be something else.
OK. Places that have changed.
Let's make a list, assign surveillance
to each location for the morning.
South Beach used to be
a mangrove swamp.
Homestead Park was originally
an air force base, right?
They turned Versace's mansion into a hotel.
Thank you, Officer Morgan.
The whole city reinvents itself
every five years.
Then we'll stay up all night
until our list is complete.
Lieutenant.
Anything?
Well, I am so glad you could make it.
Well, I just came by to show my support.
It's been a long time
since I've been to church.
Excuse me, everyone.
Excuse me.
I would like to introduce you
- to someone very special.
- No.
This is Maria LaGuerta.
She's the policewoman looking for Tony.
Not just me.
Actually, a lot of us.
There's a lot of us looking.
You brought us all here together
by giving us hope.
May the Lord bless you
and guide you, Maria.
This is Saint Anthony, patron saint of...
The lost.
Find him.
OK.
I tried to apologize,
but I couldn't get a word in edgewise.
And you wanted to apologize why?
You don't think I should,
the way I went after her son?
Yeah, you did fuck that up.
Yeah. I crucified him
without having all the facts.
I need to tell her that I'm sorry.
I need to let her know that I'm sorry.
I need to tell her.
Who is that gonna make
feel better, you or her?
Leave that woman alone
with her candles and Kumbaya.
So, where we at?
I added additional patrols
at Dolphin Stadium,
Bayside marketplace,
and Casa Casuarina.
That's everybody we have out in the field.
Homicide, robbery, off-duty patrol.
So what's next?
What's next is you should go home.
You've had the shit kicked out of you all day.
I like it here with you. You're the only person
people hate more than me.
Fuck you.
Come on. Let's both get out of here.
Nothing left but the waiting now, anyway.
Officer Morgan.
Call me on my cellphone
if you find anything.
Son of a bitch.
Fuck this.
What? Want a piece of me?
Fucking asshole!
I will pay you $1 million
if you help me figure out where
the next piece of Tucci's gonna show up.
I'm afraid I'm lost on this one, Deb.
It's like it's staring me right in the face, but...
- $1 million.
- You don't have $1 million.
I'll steal it from Evidence.
I've been stuck
in a goddamn fishbowl all day.
I want to be part of the hunt.
I'm almost off duty.
Sorry, sister.
$2 million.
I know you made a list of locations.
Just pick your favorite spot.
We'll stake it out together.
My favorite spot. Of course.
Come on. I want to play.
Deb, I got to go.
We'll compare notes tomorrow, OK?
I used to love this place, the bulldozers
pressing garbage, layer after layer,
right into the earth itself, burying it, hiding it.
I found it soothing.
But it wasn't condos back then.
This has to be the right place.
So what am I missing?
Sorry about that.
Go back to sleep.
- Hello.
- Mr. Morgan. Dispatch.
You've been called to the McCaffrey pumpkin
patch. Need the address?
No, I know exactly where it is.
Are you OK?
Are you kidding? That was awesome.
You've got some hay in your hair.
- Where?
- Right there!
OK, OK, OK, OK.
Enough. Enough, you two. Come on.
Let me take a picture of you and the kids.
You'll miss these moments
when they're older.
Thanks.
- It's great to see you having a good time.
- Are you kidding?
This hay's giving me an allergy attack, and
we're going in circles on a pumpkin patch.
Ready?
Smile!
What do we have?
Ankle to knee. He's moving up the leg.
You think Tucci's still alive?
If he is, he won't be for long.
Unless you're toting a portable DVD player,
you better be finished
watching that security footage.
I am on a break. I'm on my own time.
So you are, but your shift
starts in two hours.
So if I were you,
I'd head back to the station.
Traffic at this hour's a bitch.
Speaking of bitch...
Didn't Dad bring us here once
when we were kids?
I don't remember.
Hey, Dexter, come here.
Take a look at this.
Excuse us.
She's right, you know, about the traffic.
There's no sign of infection
where the foot was cut off,
like he gave Tucci prophylactic antibiotics
before amputating.
At least he's looking after his patient.
Hey, check this out.
Is this appropriate?
It's our anniversary.
And it's the big one.
Nina deserves the best.
"Ox"?
No.
Fuck!
What's the matter with you?
It's Xs and Os.
Like tic-tac-toe?
No, like hugs and kisses.
Diamond-filled hugs and kisses
in a white-gold setting.
That's good. You wouldn't want it to look like
someone's playing tic-tac-toe on her head.
Goddamn it.
- Where's Mom?
- She had to run a few errands
before she takes you two trick-or-treating.
But I'm too tired to go trick-or-treating.
I heard you two were up a lot last night.
It was that damn dog.
Hey, Code, grown-up language
is for grown-ups.
I don't think that dog will bother you anymore.
How do you know?
My mystic powers told me.
I heard Lindsay Lohan say damn.
All right, tell you what,
I'll make you a deal.
When you become a rock star,
you can swear, too.
Walter! Walter!
You're right. He's gone.
Where's my dog? What did you do with it?
All right. Here he is.
Just remember to walk him,
feed him, and love him,
OK?
My nieces are shy sometimes.
Girls, say thank you to Rita.
- Thank you.
They already made a doggy bed,
sweaters, towels.
It actually looks more comfortable
than my bed.
I knew this would be a perfect fit.
You did a good thing, Rita. Thank you.
Harry was the only one who saw me,
really saw me,
so he taught me to hide.
And that's what's kept me safe.
But sometimes, I'm not sure
where Harry's vision of me ends
and the real me starts.
If I'm just a collection
of learned behaviors,
bits and pieces of Harry,
maybe my new friend is right,
maybe I am a fraud.
Hi.
Hey.
Where's Astor and Cody?
They're passed out
in a sugar coma at Colleen's.
Can I come in?
Oh, yeah, sure. Sorry.
I should warn you,
I haven't really been myself lately.
Well, maybe I can cheer you up.
Trick or treat.
You look great.
Who are you?
Lara Croft.
Tomb Raider.
You raid tombs dressed like that?
That's impressive.
- What happened to Snow White?
- Well, I'm...
I'm sick of her.
You know, I never did
get to thank you
for picking the kids up for me.
You took care of your "errand"?
Yes.
The beagle has landed happily
in the arms of two loving girls.
You are a superhero.
It was such an incredible feeling
rescuing that dog.
You upset your neighbor.
Fuck her.
Well, I guess you're used to dealing with
people like her, right?
Considerably worse.
Is that why you haven't been yourself lately?
There's a case
I just can't seem to get out of my mind.
Well...
Maybe I can help.
No. I'm afraid
there's nothing you can do.
Oh, I don't know.
I'm a dognapper now...
And a tomb raider.
There's all sorts of things I can do.
What... What are you doing?
Whatever I want.
I've come to appreciate
the comfortable moments with Rita,
the easy, quiet moments.
This...
might be better.
Look, there's Mr. Tub-of-Lardy
bringing Mrs. Tub-of-Lardy
another bucket of fried chicken.
- Where's your brother?
- I'm not his keeper.
What do you think of this?
It's an anniversary present for Nina.
See, it's a diamond key to my heart.
It's a key, but, you see,
it's shaped like a heart.
You can't tell me it looks like anything else, cos
that's what it is. That's what I like.
And I'm not gonna take it back.
It's perfect, Angel. She'll love it.
Really?
I would.
How do I look?
Like the tie?
Angel.
Happy anniversary, baby.
You know you can't just walk in here
anymore.
I just thought...
Our anniversary...
Maybe tonight we could put all that
behind us.
It doesn't matter what night it is.
I told you I need time.
It's been three months, baby.
How much time do you need?
Don't turn this around on me, Angel,
not after what you did.
I need as much time as I need.
As long as you're here,
you want to see Aury?
Thank you.
That was...
unexpected.
Yeah. For me, too.
I have no problem with...
unexpected.
No, you certainly don't.
I have to get back to the kids.
Hey, what are these?
I've been reorganizing my photos a little.
Look how cute you are.
And your dad, such a nice face,
just like you.
I was adopted.
I know.
But you're both good men.
I can tell.
Very poetic.
Poetic? It's a water fountain.
Yeah, but look at the way
your dad took the photo.
His shadow's on the wall right next to you.
It's like he's always with you.
I'd frame this one.
All this time the answer was right here.
Harry, photographer
and foster father extraordinaire.
He is always with me,
and he's the common denominator.
You're a genius.
All those years of smiling for the camera,
it was empty and fake,
the pictures meaningless.
Until now.
Pictures of Harry.
So...
This is it.
It's cool.
Cool.
Dexter, this is the place
where my father,
your grandfather,
worked for 30 years.
He started out as a janitor,
worked his way up
to chief of maintenance.
This place put food on our table.
- In two weeks, it'll all be shut down.
- I know.
Excuse me, miss! Miss?
Would you mind?
Oh, come on, Dad. I don't want to...
Hey, you all right?
It's nothing. Bad medianoches for lunch.
I'm OK.
I'm sorry, miss. It's OK. Thanks.
We're not gonna be needing a picture, after all.
Yeah, we are.
- I really don't feel like doing this now.
- Don't be a baby.
Being part of a family
means smiling for family photos, right?
My friend left this.
He's showing me where to go.
Am I going because it's what he wants
or because that's what Harry would want?
And what do I want?
Hospital's shut down now,
abandoned for years,
but tonight it's visiting hours again.
Well, James...
Why did you have to be
such a pain in the ass?
- Fuck!
- I didn't tell you you could get up.
Please, please.
Now you get up.
You traumatize my little girl in church.
Break the knees of my best turner.
You're a wild dog, Sergeant.
The only thing to do with a wild dog...
Police! Hands in the air!
Thought you could use backup.
You could have filled me in, man. Shit.
Got you going after a goddamn cop,
motherfucker.
We own your ass now.
So this was the plan all along,
to use me as bait to bring down Guerrero?
Yeah, and now my sister
can rest in peace.
We're done now, Doakes. We're even.
- Fuck!
- I'll call this in, bring the paramedics.
Get this piece of shit out of here.
Please.
Just do it.
Kill me.
I'm ready.
Just don't cut me anymore.
Please don't cut me anymore.
Gift-wrapped and begging for death.
Tools at the ready.
Just kill me. It's OK.
He was left here so I would kill him,
but my new friend doesn't see me
as clearly as he thinks.
I can't kill this man.
Harry wouldn't want it.
And neither would I.
- Are you Morgan?
- Message came through dispatch for you.
Who left this?
Who left it?
Oh, Jesus, stop that. I'm getting bruises.
I'm sorry. I'm so excited.
Try a hug once in a while.
I don't know who your contacts are, Morgan,
but you are my up-and-comer.
You saved a man's life tonight.
- I'm just the one who got the call, sir.
- But you followed it up.
- Right place at the right time, sir.
- Where we at?
Morgan's tip was good.
They're taking Tucci over to County.
Alive?
Alive.
So, I suppose this gets Deb off
of surveillance-tape duty.
Really? Is that what you suppose?
I got your page, Lieutenant.
Doakes is caught up
in the Guerrero bust.
- You're taking point.
- You got it.
I'm tired of chasing this guy's shadow.
I want forensic evidence.
I don't care if you have to tear apart
this building brick by brick.
Use Morgan here.
How did your wife like that necklace, Angel?
You were right. She loved it.
You nailed that one.
Everyone hides who they are
at least some of the time.
Sometimes you bury
that part of yourself so deeply
that you have to be reminded
it's there at all.
Good work, man.
I told you we'd get that son of a bitch...
And sometimes you just want to forget
who you are altogether.
And what about me?
Maybe I'll never be the human
Harry wanted me to be...
but I couldn't kill Tony Tucci.
That's not me, either.
My new friend thought I wouldn't be able
to resist the kill he left for me,
but I did.
I'm not the monster he wants me to be.
So I'm neither man nor beast.
I'm something new entirely,
with my own set of rules.
I'm Dexter.
Boo.