- I can't take this case.
- You found her.
We've been through this.
Our things are in Sweden.
Mark and Bengt are waiting
and Mark starts school on Monday.
She was alive
when she went in the water.
It takes 20 minutes
for a car to fill with water.
She was raped several times,
vaginally and anally.
- How much do you know?
- It's too early to say.
- You'll find him'?
- We'll do our utmost.
- You'll find him.
- Now we'll have to...
think of the boys, we...
must be strong now.
We must tell them.
Look what I made, Mum.
She was found
in one of your cars.
I'd like to know
who drove it last.
We want to go public
so We're not hiding anything.
- You can't publish now.
- We're running a campaign.
- We can't wait
- You'll have to
The driver is John Lynge.
And We're going to get him.
In '96 he was caught
flashing in a playground.
He raped a 14-year-old girl.
- We're very close.
- How close?
- Today?
- I hope so.
You're welcome.
What?
A journo from an agency.
They know about the car.
They'll think
We're covering up a murder.
The alliance with the Centre Party
will be ruined.
He had three visitors
while he was incarcerated.
One is dead, one has moved
and one isn't answering.
Sarah Lund, CID.
- Do you have visitors?
- No, it's just my cat.
Lund here. I need backup.
The suspect may be
at this address.
We go in now. Get your gun.
I don't use one.
- We're staying here.
- Like hell we are.
Meyer!
THE KILLING
- What are you doing'?
- Not taking a pee.
- I told you to wait
- Relax, damn it.
Now.
You go left, I'll go right.
- Bloody hell.
- You weigh 7.682 kilos.
Mrs Heglberg'?
Mrs Heglberg, where is he'?
What's she saying?
Stay here and don't move.
- Don't go.
- I'll be back soon.
- Lean back like this.
I want my cane.
- Where's your cane.
- In the hallway.
Fine. I'll find it for you.
Stay here.
Get back! I'm a police officer.
Move back. All the way.
Take it easy.
I won't hurt you.
I'm alone.
- I didn't do anything.
- I'm not saying you did.
- You don't believe me.
- First put the knife down.
Right'?
- No more prison...
- I just want to talk.
Okay? Now, We're talking.
I fell ill at the school.
I took a cab to Nordvang.
When I got back
the car was gone.
I lost the keys when I threw up.
Someone took them.
- What keys'?
- The car keys. I was ill!
Fine. Okay.
You fell ill.
I'm hearing you.
Put the knife down and we'll talk.
- You won't.
- John!
- Drop the knife.
- Put your gun away!
He fell five meters.
Fractured skull, left side.
When can I talk to him'?
We must stop
his internal bleeding.
But he'll survive'?
Will he survive'?
Prints, hair and blood
have gone to forensics.
- They'll check his boots.
- He went to the psych center.
He lost the car keys
at the school when he got sick.
The car was gone
when he got back.
- He would say that.
- We didn't find out.
- He Would've out you again.
- Just check it out.
- Check if he has an alibi.
- Fine. I'll do it.
- Shouldn't you get that seen to'?
- Yes, I'd better.
- What about the old woman?
- She's with her family.
Good.
Get some sleep.
Report to me
when you know how he is.
It's arrogant to think
the voters wouldn't know.
We need housing in the city
that people can afford.
We have a plan.
It's pork barreling.
We both know that.
- The voters can count on...
- Let's see it first.
- Let's...
- That's all...
Thanks for coming.
Thank you, both of you.
Good luck with the election.
We continue with other news.
To the EU summit in Brussels.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Thanks for tonight.
- Yes, of course.
Only one journalist knows.
That's right.
What about the police?
I haven't heard from them
so I don't know.
We'll go ahead.
Tell the journalist
he'll get a scoop.
A crisis meeting, eh?
Lozenge'?
Why not?
If you don't mind me saying,
you were a bit rusty tonight.
- You think so?
- Yes.
Luckily the election
is a long way off.
Saving your ammunition?
That's sensible.
I've heard you'll need it.
We've got a problem.
- What?
- It's on the Internet.
Answer their questions
with consideration and authority.
Don't let them upset you.
I can't get hold of Lund.
What's your connection
to Nanna Birk Larsen?
A young girl has been found murdered
in a car leased by my campaign office.
That's all.
We're assisting the police.
They asked us not to comment.
- When did you know?
- I'd like to say...
that no one in our party
or organization is involved.
Do you deny withholding
information due to the campaign?
- I deny that categorically.
- Troels...
- It has nothing to do with politics.
We're assisting the police.
We're doing all we can
to solve this meaningless tragedy.
A young girl is dead.
I'd like to express my sympathy
to her family and friends.
What effect will the murder
have on your campaign?
Call the press
after I've talked to the police.
Half the council has called.
The Centre Party rang.
Call Eller back personally.
Give me only the important calls.
And no journalists.
- Call the parliament first.
- No, they can damn well wait
- Did we send flowers?
- Yes, that's done.
Coffee's on its way.
You went too far.
Don't let them get to you.
I know.
- That's howl am.
- I spoke with the journalist.
He was briefed anonymously.
- He may be protecting his source.
- He heard it from the police or from us.
- Why would he hear it from us'?
- Who else would know?
- Your calendar and the schools...
- It could be the police.
If I can access the server's log
I can check all outgoing mail.
- Personal mail?
- Not to read it.
- We can't.
- Just to check the traffic.
We can't.
We're all under suspicion...
No.
Find another way.
Okay?
Troels here.
Murdered girl
found in Hartmann's car.
Driver Wanted.
The car belongs to that politician.
They're looking for a driver.
- They say nothing.
- We'll know when they know.
They know more than they say.
- Don't you want to know?
- Stop it now.
It won't bring Nanna back, will it'?
- How did she know the driver?
- I don't know!
Darling...
Let's get away for a few days.
We could rent the summer house
we had before.
The police come around constantly.
The kids see Nanna
in the papers all the time.
Or on TV.
What about the funeral?
We'll talk to the pastor
and make the arrangements.
Okay?
Do you know what time it is'?
Hi.
Try not to throw your clothes
everywhere like that.
No wonder Mark's a messy boy.
You could use a plate.
What happened?
- Nothing.
- You're bleeding.
A cat scratched me.
No cat could have done that.
A wild one
Why do you have to continue
with that job?
You have a chance
for a decent life.
I'm only here till Friday.
We could move to a hotel.
Of course not.
Sorry, Mum. I'm very tired.
This is nice.
Bengt wants you to come
to our housewarming on Saturday.
He told me. He wants me
to design the guest room, too.
He called this afternoon,
Wondering where you Were.
Damn it.
Did you tell him
I was Working till Friday?
- You said you'd left...
- It's only till Friday.
Sorry I didn't call.
Come down here.
- And live with your mum'?
- Yes.
That would be cost.
The workmen and removalists
are here, so it's not possible.
How's the sauna?
Polar pine is really good for saunas.
Yes, that should be fine.
- I have to go now.
- I miss you.
Well, I miss you too.
- Say it as if you mean it.
- You know I mean it.
But I've got wood glue on me
that I can't get off.
Okay.
- We'll talk tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Good night.
- You too.
- I'd like to say...
- When did you know?
No one in our party is involved.
You deny withholding
information due to the campaign?
- I love you.
- Oh'? I'm happy to hear it.
Yes'?
It's true. Lynge was admitted
to Nordvang on Friday.
- For how long'?
- He had problems with his medicine.
He was in hospital all day.
- Could he have slipped out?
- Not unless he can fly.
- Lay off the chips, eh?
- Sorry, but I haven't eaten.
- Have you found her bicycle?
- No.
- Her mobile?
- The techs are Working on it.
The last call was on Friday.
It seems to have come from the school.
We'll go there in the morning.
- Don't count on going.
- Why not?
Buchard said
Hartman wants a meeting.
Get some sleep
and don't forget your report.
Sleep well, Mum
We 're assisting the police.
We're doing all we can
to solve this meaningless tragedy.
A young girl is dead.
I 'd like to express my sympathy
to her family and friends.
What effect will. ..
This is exactly
what we didn't want.
- We held back because of you.
- I guarantee we didn't leak it.
No one knew the registration
Only the core group did.
- Has the driver confessed?
- No, because he didn't do it.
- Didn't you say'?
- I know.
We thought he was the one
but he isn't.
Someone else used his car.
It's possible it was stolen.
- When will you go public'?
- We want to wait.
For What?
The driver's hurt but we hope
to question him today.
If our car was stolen
we want the press to know soon.
We may want the culprit
to think we have a suspect.
So you are pleased
someone leaked it'?
- We didn't know he was innocent.
- We want it out now.
- If you won't do it, we will
- We want you to wait.
It's not negotiable. Bye.
- I'll keep you informed.
- That would be nice.
Hartman!
It's unfortunate, but listen.
I've been hung out as a suspect.
- You promised to co-operate.
- We've Waited and waited.
- I'm begging you.
- We have to leave.
Lund! You've got guests.
Just a moment.
We're late. We have to leave.
Were they...
- Waiting Will make a difference?
- Yes. It Will.
You've got till tomorrow.
We've got an interim report
but forensics wants to keep Nanna.
We'll be leaving today...
for the summer house.
We just want to be sure
that the funeral's arranged.
Sure.
What are they doing to her?
Some further examinations.
You'll be contacted
as soon as you can collect her.
Where will they send her?
Normally to an undertaker.
- Do you have one'?
- We're seeing a priest.
- What exactly happened to her?
- I can't tell you yet.
But I understand
why you want to know.
No.
- Here's my mobile number.
- Excuse me.
Call if there is anything.
Close that door!
I deeply regret this.
I'm so sorry.
I think we'd better leave
Call me if I can do anything.
No matter what the time.
We still need some answers.
I'm addressing the students
at a memorial service.
She was last seen at the party.
I need to know about that party.
- Right now I need to...
- Your needs are irrelevant.
I want answers. Now.
You don't seriously think
any of us are involved?
The sooner I can do my Work
the sooner I can tell you.
Lynge got here at noon
and went to the office.
- Why?
- No idea.
Laziness? Or he felt ill.
- He could've lost the keys there.
- Or anywhere.
- Who had gym afterwards'?
- No one till Monday.
No one has seen lost keys
or anything like that.
What have we got on the girl'?
Top marks. Well-liked.
Not a negative word about her.
Lots of boys tried to score her.
- Did she let them?
- No, except for one.
The ex-boyfriend,
Oliver Schandorff.
- Any drugs?
- Nothing.
Drank occasionally.
Look at this picture.
She was seen dancing that night
but no one saw her after 9.30.
Why leave early
after having worked so hard?
You're right, but maybe
there's a good reason here.
Why didn't you tell me
she'd argued with her ex,
Oliver, on the dance floor'?
- It Wasn't important.
- Others noticed it.
Well, we were dancing and he
started arguing. It was nothing.
He threw a chair.
- Was Nanna drunk?
- No.
- But you Were?
- A bit, perhaps.
- What's Wrong with that?
- Why did they break up?
She thought he was
an overgrown boy.
Why did you say
she was with him on the Weekend?
I hoped she was
when I couldn't find her.
What did they fight about?
- He wanted to talk, she didn't.
- And she left shortly after'?
- Did you see Oliver then?
- It was his turn in the bar.
- You're sure'?
- I saw him there.
According to the bar roster
he Wasn't there at that time.
No one else saw him there.
Let me get this straight.
She hugged you and said bye'?
Yes.
She walked this way, downstairs,
and out the door'? Right?
- Yes.
- What was she wearing?
A witch's hat with a buckle.
And a purple wig.
And a rather tattered dress
with short sleeves.
Wasn't it odd
she was dressed so lightly?
I presume she had a coat.
You said she had bare arms.
I don't remember.
And her change of clothes?
I think we left them
in the classroom.
Why go downstairs and not up?
- Down and out the door'?
- She must have gone up.
People everywhere...
You don't know when or where
or if Oliver followed her.
We know you're lying.
Did he find the keys
and get into the car to show off?
- What?
- Listen.
It's important that you tell us
all you know. Right?
- I know nothing.
- You have to help us.
- Listen to me.
- I don't...
Come.
- Now.
- Are you okay?
- Where was it'?
- We found it in the garbage bin.
- What about her bicycle?
- We haven't found it yet.
Got a pen'?
Thanks.
Cordon off the area
and call forensics.
Better call them now.
Give me a call
as soon as you know.
Yes, bye.
- Did you see the latest poll'?
- I did.
That Egyptian foot ointment
is very good.
Reception in 20.
Then you hand out brochures.
I talked to the Centre Party.
The alliance isn't in danger.
- Did Bremer comment?
- No need to.
TV wants an interview
about straying politicians.
Okay. Let me have it.
- You think I'm handling it wrong.
- No, the voters do.
- Morten Weber.
- Say the car was stolen.
- No. We're helping the police.
- They have their own agenda.
- I'm not that kind of politician.
- You may not be one for long.
I want a clear conscience.
Eller's office called.
- She wants to talk.
- Wasn't that solved?
I thought so too.
- Coffee? Tea'?
- No, thanks.
I've met with my group.
I underestimated the case.
How?
This story has fanned
an internal discussion.
They smell blood
and want to go with Bremer.
The car was stolen.
He's innocent.
- Why hasn't that come out'?
- The police have asked us to wait
It won't matter now.
Relax, you and Bremer
don't want the same things.
He's just proposed
10,000 low-rent flats.
Has he?
He won't follow through.
I am sorry. It seems
there won't be an alliance.
Don't you see
that he wants you
to hesitate
and miss the deadline.
The group has decided.
It's out of my hands.
What?
You could top his offer.
Right, but let it pass
and see if it becomes necessary.
You're ruthless.
Just a moment.
- Not now.
- I want an explanation. Now.
Thanks.
Just a moment.
First you steal our proposal
and end up with
an unrealistic number of units.
- Oh, Kirsten!
- You exploit a girl's death.
And time it to create a crisis
when it's about helping people.
Wait just two seconds.
- This has nothing to do with politics.
- How dare you'?
I don't work in the chaotic way
you choose.
Choose?
You had nothing to do
with that car.
If you don't come clean
that's your problem.
And in regard to an alliance
with the Centre Party
I haven't lost all my teeth yet.
Yes, I'm back.
Yes, but it's no good.
I'm going on the TV news.
Those are the funeral hymns.
There are no right or Wrong choices.
It's important to find those hymns
that mean something to you.
Take a hymn book home.
To look at.
I'd like "I Saw a Rose Blossom
That's number 117.
It's a lovely hymn.
It must be beautiful for her
with lots of flowers.
- That's up to you.
- She loved flowers.
Blue irises.
And rushes.
- Anything else we need?
- No.
The eulogy...
I'd suggest you write
something down for me.
When you're at peace at home.
Don't talk about the crime.
I'll talk about Nanna
as you remember her.
Blessed are those who hunger and thirst
for righteousness, for they will be filled.
- She was always happy.
- That's important to mention.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You're always Welcome
if you need to talk.
She's happy now.
She's with God.
What good is that to me'?
I want to know.
Life is sometimes meaningless.
It's unbelievably hard
to lose one's daughter.
Faith helps to maintain hope...
and the belief that life after all
isn't meaningless.
What a load of crap!
I don't give a damn
if she's with God.
Do you understand?
She has to be...
with me.
Oliver Schandorff'?
You left early yesterday?
I didn't feel well. I was sad.
- And no school on Monday?
- No.
- I had a day off.
- You've had a few. 17%.
I know you think I'm involved
because we fought at the party.
I'm not.
I'd never do anything.
- Why did she break up with you'?
- We grew apart.
You use dope, don't you'?
Is that why she left you'?
You took speed at a concert
and again two months later.
I got a bit carried away.
But that's finished now.
- What did Nanna say'?
- First she thought it was a laugh.
But she got tired of it.
Tell me about the argument.
- I was drunk and stupid.
- What did you do?
I laid it on her.
She was so sweet.
And all the time
I could tell that she was... serene.
- She was happy.
- So you threw a chair?
Yes, regretfully.
- Where were you after 9.30 p.m.?
- In the bar.
- You're not on the roster.
- We overlapped a bit.
Who Would've seen you
in the bar?
- Heaps of people.
- Name one.
- Lisa'?
- She saw me for sure.
No, she's not sure.
No one else saw you.
I collected glasses...
Listen, mate.
No one saw you after 9.30 p.m.
- What did you do?
- Surely someone saw me.
Did you follow her'?
Or wait in the basement'?
No, I didn't.
You were jealous. Right?
You could tell
she had someone else.
- I said...
- You found the car keys'?
- Keys'?
- You knew the oar was outside
- What?
- You tried to score.
She didn't want you
so you raped her.
What? I loved her.
Yes. But she didn't love you.
You're nothing but a loser.
You couldn't measure up.
You raped her.
You tied her up and drove her
somewhere out of earshot.
That's what you did.
Oliver, if you've got something to say
now is the time.
May I have a word?
How dare you'?
- We're interviewing your son.
- I know, he's distraught.
- Maybe you should stop.
- He may be hiding something.
I don't give a damn.
Has he been charged?
No.
Fine. No more interview.
Thanks, Dad.
I'm sorry if I've interrupted
one of your meetings.
Are you involved in this'?
- No.
- I damned well hope not.
Get your things.
You thought I was too hard
on him, right'?
What do you want'?
Is it my fault that idiot turned up'?
I didn't say it was.
You did well, Meyer
- Call him in.
- We need some evidence.
He found the keys.
It was clear he was lying.
Nothing in the basement'?
It's impossible,
tracks like in a public toilet.
Press forensics.
If he drove the car
he must have left traces.
And time the route
from here to the woods.
So you're off
to the Canary Islands, then?
All we need is you two.
Is that necessary?
Yes, I need them for comparison.
Two pairs of pants each?
Yes, that's fine. Thanks.
You'd better be off
so you can get some peace.
Promise to call me
if there's anything.
Look after each other.
Come on. Wash your hands
so we can get going.
I'll just help Vagn empty the car.
Come when you're ready.
- Can we take the kite'?
- Yes, you can.
But don't take any more
or there won't be enough room.
Be sweet and take that one...
What, Mum'?
Run down to Dad.
I'll just be a moment.
- We'll leave you in peace soon.
- What happened in the Woods?
Sorry, I'm not the one to ask.
I'll have to ask you to leave.
I must...
I must know what happened.
What happened to my daughter'?
I'm not allowed...
I saw the photos.
You can't tell me anything
that's Worse than my imagination.
I'm begging you.
Great. Watch it, boys.
Have you heard anything?
- Vagn, how about some money'?
- What?
Do I look like a piggy bank?
Bloody hell.
Here. Buy a chocolate egg.
And one for you.
Emil, not beer.
A Kinder egg, okay?
Theis...
It was the driver, Wasn't it'?
They're sure it's him, eh?
I don't know anything.
He'll end up in prison.
Tell me if I can fix it.
- What are you on about?
- He'll get a ridiculous sentence.
- I want to help
- How'?
I thought...
That we should use pipes
and smash his kneecaps'?
Yes.
She's dead, Vagn.
Don't you understand?
Where is she'?
Pernille'?
- We're not leaving.
- Why not? I just told them...
She was alive when the car
hit the water.
What?
She Wasn't dead, Theis.
She was lying alone in...
the trunk, waiting all alone...
We'll have to stay here.
I want them to find him.
I want...
He must be found now, Theis.
We must top Bremer
or Eller goes to him.
We can't. Bremer's flung
an astronomical figure...
Troels...
They have other key issues.
She might compromise
if she can save face.
Find something we can live with.
Nothing too big.
And in a hurry...
so Bremer doesn't get wind of it first
- Does he sit in on our meetings?
- That's just it.
I got a copy
of the server's log files.
What?
- I decided for you.
- I didn't want this.
Never mind, I know
who mailed the journalist.
Never mind'?
- You went behind my back.
- It was Morten.
It was sent from Morten's mail.
There's no doubt it's him.
I think I've got it.
Okay, Morten.
- We can find a compromise.
- Let's look at it.
A perforated lung, blood pressure
70 over 40 and he's saturated.
- I can't justify it.
- Five minutes.
- We've doubled his morphine.
- I'm here because it's important.
- He's in room four.
- Thank you.
John?
I'm sorry about what happened.
Do you understand me'?
I know you didn't harm the girl.
I need your help.
What happened at the school
on Friday?
Who did you meet
and Where did you lose the keys'?
You parked and went inside.
Then you went to the gym
and felt sick there?
Yes.
What?
John?
The basement.
You went to the basement first?
To deliver the posters.
That's where you lost the keys'?
He got upset.
- I was not allowed there.
- Who got upset and said that?
John?
Was it in the bicycle basement'?
- No.
- Any bicycles there?
Not the bicycle basement.
The one next to it.
The boiler room.
Who did you meet
in the boiler room?
Was it him'? Oliver Schandorff'?
Was it him'?
Are you sure'?
- It Wasn't him.
- Look carefully at the photo.
- Please go now.
- One minute. I'm almost ready.
- Did you hear me'?
- Almost there.
Was he the one you met
in the basement'?
- It's ready.
- Thanks.
- Have a nice evening.
- You too.
Are you still at the school?
Yes, We're finished
and I'm starving.
- Go back to the basement.
- Bloody hell. Why'?
- Forensics are packing up
- Ask them to wait.
- Is there a boiler room?
- I have no idea.
- Are you there?
- Relax, damn you.
- I'm on my way.
- Find a door to a boiler room.
- Here's a door.
- I must know What's inside.
Okay, damn it.
Hey, you. We need help
to get this door open. Now!
- We're in a hurry.
- Is it open?
We're Working on it.
- What do you see'?
- A boiler.
A lot of old junk.
Chairs, tables, books and stuff.
- There's nothing here.
- Are you sure'?
Wait.
There's a door here.
No handle.
Here's another door. Wait.
What is it'?
Meyer?
You'd better come out here.
Right now.
Subtitles: Zanne Mallett
Brenden Dannaher
Subtitles SBS Australia 2009