You need to leave us alone!
You need to go away!
- She's drinking, isn't she?
- That's why I rang you.
I don't know why
she's started again.
I knew Vicky Fleming.
- Don't you think you should
tell the police?
- You don't know what that does to me.
I'm arresting you on suspicion
of the murder of Ana Vasalescu,
Aurelija Petrovic...
♪ Happy birthday to you! ♪
- Who's it from?
- It's from your dad.
He wants you and me shouting!
He wants you to hate me!
When has doing anything legally
got anybody like me anywhere?
You're going to have to do what
I've asked you to do.
That's wonderful!
Every day was a misogynistic delight
from start to finish.
The best thing when I joined up -
this is like 300 years ago,
in the 1980s -
you didn't get a truncheon
if you were a woman,
you got a handbag!
- Thanks(!)
- No, you did get a
truncheon. You got one of them,
you know, little doodah things.
That's right, yeah!
Like a vibrator. A handbag
and a vibrator. Great!
What you gonna do with that
when someone's coming at you with
an Uzi and a machete?
They were big enough to keep
a brick in, them handbags.
- Just!
- So, you were a police officer?
I was, yeah. 30 years and
then I come back as a civvy.
God knows why.
Well...
God does know why.
And skirts. There were no trousers.
You don't know you're born, you lot.
We used to freeze our knackers
off on a night shift.
Ooh, and do you remember,
"Stockings or tights?"
You'd run the gauntlet every time
you walked through t'CID office.
They'd have their hands up
your skirts,
twanging your suspenders to see
if you were sharp or flat.
And you just took it!
You had to.
Although. Although. Leonard Stott.
Inspector up at Brighouse.
He used to come up to me,
every time he saw me,
he used to come up to me like this.
"Oooh, Cathy!" He used to call me
Cathy. "It's Catherine, you twat."
"Oooh, Cathy," and I was like,
"Whatever," for long enough
and then one day, I just thought,
"Bollocks to this,"
and the next time he did it...
Right in his face
and I floored him. I decked him
and I'd only been out of
training school four weeks,
but he never did it again.
- In fact, he used to avoid me
after that.
- No shit.
We're doing tequilas, us lot.
You joining us?
- Yes!
- Yeah! Yeah!
You go home if you're knackered.
Nah, I promised Nev
I'd look out for her.
Has she said owt?
She's bereaved!
It's been what, four weeks?
It's the sort of thing you can
appear to be coping and then...
Best thing we can do is show her
we care and keep an eye on her.
Where is she?
- Not here!
- Why?
Are you sure about this?
Yeah. Honestly.
You can have my bed. I'm still
camped out in the conservatory.
- You're such a fantastic human being,
Catherine.
- I know.
I know I'm pissed, but do you know
what I think God is?
I think... God... is like this...
this collective goodness
that's in all of us.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
And someone like you...
it's like you have so much of this
goodness, this...
bigness.
It's like you embody what... God is.
OK. Now then.
- Ann.
- Hm.
Did you...
shag... that bloke?
Yeah.
Did I?
Did he use... a condom?
- Mm.
- Are you on the pill
or anything?
I can see two of you.
Omnipotent and ubiquitous.
God, I'm good.
♪ There's a tower block overhead
♪ All you've got's your benefits
♪ And you're barely scrapping by
♪ In this troubled town
♪ Troubles are found
♪ Stuck in Speed Bump City
♪ Where the only thing that's pretty
is the thought of getting out. ♪
- Morning, ma'am.
- Morning, John.
Right, Sean. Last time we saw you...
Last time we met,
we had a conversation...
Before we start...
there's something I want to say.
That's absolutely fine, Sean.
What would you like to say?
There's two questions you've asked
me that I've said no comment to
and I want to comment now.
And then there's something else
I want to say.
OK.
You asked me...
what I'd say if you told me
you'd found some...
somebody's DNA in my van.
Ana Vasalescu.
Well, I don't know her, but...
...if she's a prostitute...
I do... pick 'em up now and again,
and she could've been one of them...
'..and that's the only reason
- 'I can think of as to why it'd be
there.
- Good. Well, '
- thank you for that, Sean.
That's helpful.
- And then...
And then there's th-that other
one's number in my phone.
- Lynn, er...
- Lynn Dewhurst.
I don't know her.
As such.
I think...
I think I helped shift some
furniture for her
a couple of years ago as a favour.
She was a friend of a friend
and I had a van, so...
I didn't know her!
But...
I don't remember doing, but maybe
I just took her number in case
there were any problems, I couldn't
find the house or whatever, and then
- I never deleted it, cos I never
delete numbers, do you?
- No.
So who's this friend you were
doing the favour for?
I ain't seen him lately.
He was called Eggy.
Has he got an address?
He won't be there now,
it's all derelict.
- What's his proper name?
- I only ever knew him as Eggy.
Right.
And where were you shifting
this furniture to and from?
Somewhere up... Pellon,
from a flat in Halifax.
Can you remember a street name,
where she lived?
I don't know round there.
- What type of property was it?
- A terrace.
Describe it to me.
It was just ordinary.
It's been three years since.
So you don't remember
a house number?
It was just a settee
and an armchair!
It were only ten minutes of a job,
about three f...
About three years ago.
So what's this other thing you
wanted to say to me, then, Sean?
I'm worried that...
because I drink a lot,
I don't always remember stuff
what's happened...
...and I-I don't believe that
I did kill those women...
but perhaps I've got...
perhaps I've got so drunk that
I've done stuff and...
and I-I don't remember doing it.
- 'Look, I'm just trying to be
as honest with you as I can be.
'I'm pretty sure something like that
you would remember,
however off your head you was.'
But if it... if it was me...
...I honestly have no memory of it.
You do realise that isn't a defence
though, don't you, Sean?
Yeah.
Yeah, the problem is, Sod's Law,
the night I decide not to
sleep in the conservatory,
- something will happen.
- If them
Knezevics were going to do owt,
- wouldn't they have done it by now?
- Probably. Possibly.
That Goran bloke must've known
stuff Ilinka didn't know.
That must be why
they went after him.
Or else, they genuinely have
no idea where she is.
How did you work that out?
Because - duh! -
that's what you said.
Oh, OK. Well, yeah. Yeah.
I think you just like sleeping
in t'conservatory.
Yeah, but, you see, now I'm
thinking, never mind the Knezevics,
now I'm thinking that whoever left
that Scalextric is going to do
something else,
something even more weird.
Like what?
I don't know. A brick through
a window.
You see, I don't think a brick
through the window is as weird
as leaving a present on your
doorstep, actually.
And I don't think somebody
who'd leave a present
on your doorstep would put a brick
through your window anyway, so...
Yeah. No. Why?
It wasn't an act of aggression.
Oh, it was psychologically
aggressive.
- Yeah, but not violent,
just weird.
- Yeah.
Right!
I'm gonna grab some clothes
and get dressed, and then...
Morning, Mother!
Late night, was it?
Hiya. Then I'm going to... Yes, it
was. And then I'm going to go
and spend 150 quid that I haven't
got on the famous bloody toy
that Ryan never asked for
in the first place.
I must need my head examined.
We've been saying this for years
behind your back. Haven't we, Clare?
Ann Gallagher's upstairs,
just to warn you.
Why, is she dangerous?
Funny(!) You're so funny, Daniel(!)
That solicitor wasn't happy,
was he? Did you see him?
He stuck by him, though.
Did you believe him?
What he said about Lynn?
Well, it fits. Her number's there on
his phone,
but it's not like there's
ever been any calls between them.
Doesn't prove anything
though, does it?
I still think that last one's
different.
Vicky Fleming.
OK.
CPS says go for it. Charge him.
- All four?
- We've got significant
circumstantial, he's on
the sex offenders' register, he was
practically caught red-handed with
Leonie Farrell, and now he's talking
to us he's telling us
he's got no memory of anything
and no alibis.
And they're saying that's good
enough for them to go to court with,
so...
looks like we might get
a bit of a weekend after all.
So all four,
including Vicky Fleming?
All four.
Well done... team.
I've got to caution you again now,
Sean, and tell you that you do not
have to say anything, but it may
harm your defence if you do not
mention now something which you
later rely on in court.
Anything you do say may be
given in evidence.
You are charged that, on or between
27th of April and 29th of April 2015
- at Elland, murdered Ana Vasalescu
contrary to common law.
- I didn't...
On or between 29th of May and
2nd of June 2015 at Brighouse,
murdered Aurelija Petrovic
contrary to common law.
On or between 23rd of July and
6th of August 2015 at Halifax,
murdered Lynn Dewhurst
contrary to common law.
On or between 11th of September
and 15th of September 2015
at Brighouse, murdered Victoria
Fleming contrary to common law.
Is there anything you want
to say, Sean?
I didn't do it.
149.99, please.
Do you sell many of these?
We have met before. It was me
mother's birthday, year before last.
Do you remember?
I got a bit pissed
and went off in a strop.
Yeah, yeah.
So you...? You and your wife,
you've... split?
Yeah. It's all a bit mad.
Life is a bit mad though, isn't it?
Older you get.
I think...
looking back, I only married Lucy
to get away from here.
I liked her. Y'know.
I do like her.
But everything has to be so neat and
tidy and nothing out of place.
It's like living in a little
dolly house.
Is that cos of what
happened with Becky?
Wanting to get away from here?
It was an odd time.
After she died. Becky.
Me mum did go a bit mental.
Me dad couldn't stand it either.
He left.
How old were you?
20. She said some really stupid
things.
But, you know, she was ill.
I think she's fantast...
Oh, God.
What?
I just remembered something
I said last night, to her.
Moving on...
How was last night?
Did it do the trick?
What trick?
Cheer you up.
Cheer ME up?
Yeah.
Have I put me foot in it?
The bastards!
You OK?
It was silly what upset me. I
haven't told anyone. It was at work.
This... bloke asked me out for a
drink. A detective.
Nothing special,
old enough to be me dad,
and I knew he was married and been
having an affair with someone else.
But I quite liked him.
It was the first time I'd thought
about... the possibility of...
you know.
Being close to someone.
Since what happened to me.
So it was a big deal.
Not that he knew that.
Then...
...he didn't turn up.
So...
Tosser.
Yeah.
Space Oddity
by David Bowie
- '..losing 20 pounds and having
great sex for the rest of your life,
tied with just 22%...'
Don't Stop Me Now
by Queen
♪ Like Lady Godiva
♪ I'm gonna go, go, go
There's no stopping me... ♪
Jack!
'Hiya.'
It's me, Dad.
'You all right?'
Listen... Erm... I'm coming home.
Are you going to let me in?
'Yeah. Yeah, yeah.'
Cheers, mate.
Cheers, pal.
So! Hello. Good morning!
How are we all?
Good(!)
So I've got a little proposal
I'd like to put to you.
Contrary to what you think,
I'm not the one who's been having
some sort of sordid little fling
with some sad sod from Mirfield who
drives a Skoda - no, that'll be you.
So what I'm proposing is,
YOU move out,
you gather your bits and pieces,
you move in with loverboy,
you feel free
to do whatever you have to do.
I - me - the one who hasn't been
mucking about -
will stay here, in our house, with
our children. How about that?
I'm not leaving the children.
Yeah. Well, newsflash.
Neither am I.
And you're a liar. I know damn
well you've been up to something.
OK, then. Who is this mysterious
whoever who I've been having this
relationship with, then? Eh?
Where is she? Eh? She doesn't exist,
Amanda. She's in your head!
And you really should get your facts
straight before you start
accusing people of things.
Now go and pack your stuff and ring
Casanova. He'll be thrilled!
You can set up home together.
That's the plan, isn't it?
I assume that's the plan.
Does Graham know that's the plan?
Shut up!
Oh! Does he not?
Oh, does he not?
Can we talk about this sensibly,
properly,
not in front of the children?
Perhaps I should go
and tell him, then.
Perhaps I should keep him informed.
Perhaps I should knock his
teeth down his throat.
Where you going?
Mirfield.
You don't know where he lives.
I'm a detective, love.
I know bloody well where he lives.
Feel free to ring ahead and warn him
that I'm on my way.
If he's not in when I get there,
I'll ask his wife to pass on a
message. How about that?
No. Don't do that! John! Don't!
What, does she not know either?
So it's just you that thinks the
two of you's slinking off into the
sunset together, is it?
I shan't be long, kids.
Dad!
Shan't be long, tiddler!
Why did you let him in?
It's his house too, he lives here
as well!
Shit!
How many seconds?
I didn't even bother to count.
You're supposed to count!
- Two and a half?
- It was nearly a minute!
And the rest!
I'll have to do it again now.
Good morning!
Granny!
Hi!
Count how long I can balance!
Did you sleep all right?
- Granny!
- Yeah, yeah. Thanks. Sorry.
I'll drive you home in a bit.
Have you had some breakfast?
Just had some coffee.
Well, I got it. 149.99.
I don't want it.
What are you talking about?
I'll have it!
What d'you mean, you don't want it?
- I mean, I don't want it.
- Why?
- Because it's not the same.
It's exactly the same. Only
we know where this one's come from.
I wanted that other one.
Well, you couldn't have that other
one, and I promised I'd replace it.
I wanted the one me dad sent.
He's not your dad.
I've explained this.
Yeah. But he is.
Why don't I go and set it up?
And you go ring Cesco to come round
and have a race.
We'll have a championship.
No.
I'll set it up.
No, if he's not going to play with
it, I'll get my money back.
- He'll play with it.
- I shan't.
Sorry.
It's fine.
Oh, it's ridiculous.
It's impossible.
You need to find out who
put it there.
I will, I'm going to.
Bastard.
Don't get me started.
I'm sorry
if I was talking shite last night.
No, you weren't. You were happy.
Oh, I got you this.
From the chemist.
What is it?
Morning after pill.
Oh, Jesus.
I mean, I don't know that you need
it, I don't know what you did,
but I just thought...
Thanks.
- You know.
- Yeah.
- Just in case.
- How much do I owe you?
It's fine, it's nothing, it's a
present. Except you do know,
just for future reference,
if anyone'd seen you, it would've
been a Public Order offence
at the very least,
and you'd have lost your job.
Shit, can you answer that?
Hello, Catherine's phone? She's
driving, she's just dropping me
home.
Yeah, all right, bye.
She says, can you pop up to the
allotment after you've
dropped me off?
Deep joy(!)
So what's up?
Well, I've been expecting Neil all
morning but he's not shown up.
I knocked on his door on my way
down, no answer,
I've phoned him,
I've texted him, nothing.
And it's odd cos
we were reckoning to spend
the day on the allotment together.
He'll have forgotten.
It's not like him.
- I wouldn't know.
- Why don't you like him?
It's only lunchtime.
He's a really nice man.
So what wants doing?
I've got all these planks to shift.
Jerry at far end said
he'd have 'em.
Well, can't Jerry at far end come
and fetch 'em?
He's in hospital.
Hey. They've charged that fella.
Sean Balmforth. This morning.
It's been on t'radio.
They've charged him wi' them
murders.
Wow.
I know.
You all right?
I bought our Ryan that Scalextric
and he reckoned he didn't want it.
"I wanted that one me dad sent me."
I've said it till I'm blue
in the face, "He's not your dad."
And he goes, "Yeah, but he is."
It'll never go away, will it?
When I find out which sad, twisted
sod left that on our doorstep...
I'll make
'em wish they'd never been born.
- Nice weekend?
- Yourself?
Have you heard owt from Gravesend?
Yes! I did. Late on Friday night,
they sent a list.
Visitors, phone calls,
people he writes to.
I can't let you see it.
You being funny?
No. I can't have you taking
the law into your own hands.
- What, Friday night and you didn't
let me know?
- I've forwarded the list
to an analyst in the DIU.
He'll gather intel on all of 'em,
and as soon as we know anything
significant, I'll get back to you.
You know that's the right way
forward, Catherine,
don't start pulling faces.
Woman in the toy shop in Hebden
last week buying a Scalextric.
Exactly the same model.
I went in and asked the fella
behind the counter on Saturday
and he showed me his CCTV.
Looks like a lad.
Yeah, well, it's a woman,
the fella said.
- Either way, it doesn't mean it's
whoever it was left it on your
doorstep.
- No, I know that,
but was there anyone on the list
from round here?
No.
Not?
No. Not from round here.
Are you briefing t'troops?
Yes, I am. Are you saying,
"Well done, Catherine"?
What for this time?
Sean Balmforth. Charged.
That was me got him arrested.
Oh! Yes, but...
They're playing it down
till it's confirmed,
but there's another body
turned up in Rastrick.
When?
Early hours this morning.
And depending on when she died...
it could mean they've charged
the wrong fella.
- Sorry!
- Mornin'.
Oh, congratulations! He's been
charged, you'll have heard.
That fella you tipped us off about.
Oh, have you not heard?
Apparently another body's turned up.
Did you not know?
It's what I've just been told.
Good morning, you lucky people...
(Bollocks.)
Really?
(Shit.)
She thinks she's not been dead
more than 48 hours.
She'll be more specific
at the postmortem,
but it's looking like she died after
we had Sean in custody.
- Oh, f...
- I know.
Could it be a copycat?
Well, again, we'll know more
after the PM, but...
So, we'll be getting
the review team in.
And to restore public confidence
in the investigation,
I'll be getting my arse kicked
down the stairs in the traditional
manner, no doubt, by your dad.
I can only apologise.
Who is she?
White. Between 20 and 30.
Poor teeth, poor clothes.
You know, the only thing I'd have
done differently from you
on Saturday...
I'm sorry, do you want to hear this?
You wouldn't have charged him
with Vicky Fleming.
"'I'm sure that dog's getting
bigger by the minute, ' said Dad.
"Ben and Albert laughed.
"'If only Dad knew.'"
You're doing so well.
Ben and Albert!
They remind me of you and Cesco.
How?
Just, you're best friends.
Oh, yeah.
Do you and Cesco do sleepovers?
I used to love sleepovers!
That's the best thing
about a best friend.
- Sometimes we do.
- Yeah? Have you got one planned?
No.
Why?
How're things at home?
You know, if you ever want to
talk to me,
about anything, Ryan,
you know you can.
Other day...
at teatime...
...I said I wondered if we should
forgive him - me dad.
But they wouldn't talk about it.
They just get cross.
Who does?
Me granny. And me Auntie Clare.
And I've been worried, because...
you know when you said they don't
get much money in prison...?
Yeah...
Ryan?
Do you think... he gets
enough food to eat?
Do you think he's warm enough
at night when it's cold?
Oh, yes, yes, yes! I'm sure he is.
You mustn't worry about that, Ryan!
Oh, you're so sweet and kind
to think about that.
I know he hurt me granny
and everything,
but he's still me dad.
Yeah. I think the worst thing
about prison probably is,
he might get lonely sometimes.
And bored.
Have you ever thought
about visiting him?
I'm not allowed. There's no
contact cos of what he did.
I bet he'd love to see you.
I wonder if that's another reason
why he sent you that lovely present?
I wondered...
about writing to him.
You should.
I don't know his address.
Oh, I think you could just
put his name, and then...
Um... Oh, um...
Where is he? What prison is he in?
Do you know?
Oh... I think I heard
that he's in, um...
...Gravesend Prison.
- Gravesend?
- Yeah.
Where's that?
It's near London.
'Bravo November 4-5. Could you
look at log 271 of today -
'down in Sowerby Bridge?
'There's a fella kicking off
outside The Moorings.'
I can look at it, Mr Metcalfe,
but I've got no-one to deploy.
They're all off on the
house-to-house with this body
that's turned up in Rastrick.
'It's all started with
a plate of chips,
'and it's escalated from there.
'I don't suppose I could persuade
you to turn out yourself, 4-5?'
Well, I was just about to make
myself a cup of tea
and put my feet up for the
afternoon, but seeing as it's you...
'So he's been ejected from
the premises, we've got
'CCTV monitoring him now, he's
in the street with his top off,
'banging on the doors,
trying to get back in.'
Oh, lovely - a semi-naked man
at lunchtime in Sowerby Bridge,
how could I stay away?
Get out here, you little runt!
Come on, get out here!
You TWAT!
Come on, you short-arsed bastard!
Open this door!
Hey!
Neil?
Where've you been?
What you doing here?
Bravo November 4-5.
I'm code six, I don't need any
backup, I know this fella.
Oh, you won't need any backup?
Is that what you think?
Well, you're not going to cause me
any problems, are you, Neil?
I was just explaining
to this tosser...
Open the fucking door!
Can you calm down?
Make 'im open the door.
You're causing a disturbance
and you're upsetting people.
- Where's your top?
- No, I'm not!
Rat-face! Open this door!
If you don't calm down, I'm warning
you, you'll get locked up.
Do you understand?
I've warned you now, Neil.
Can you get your jumper back on
for me, please?
They've got me telephone.
Who's got your telephone?
THEM! In there!
Is that your telephone
on the pavement, over there?
Eh?
Down there.
- Oh.
- Can you pick it up for me?
Is that your telephone?
- Is that your telephone, Neil?
- YES!
He's been in here stealing food
off people's plates.
You bloody liar.
Why would I do that?
People don't want your dirty great
fingers in their chips!
It was a bit o' fun!
It was her birthday!
I've asked him to leave,
I've made it clear
he wasn't gonna be served any more,
and he just won't clear off.
- I'm dealing with it.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah...
- And you can tell him he's barred.
- Yes, I will, I'm dealing with it,
thank you.
BARRED? It's a shit-hole anyway!
You're barred, all right?
You're barred.
Oh, yeah - rock hard, stood behind
a little police lady.
If you could go back inside for me,
please.
Yeah, piss off back inside,
you little sod.
I don't want to hear any more
language, Neil - I've warned you.
I want to know he's understood.
It would help me enormously, sir,
- if you would go back inside
the premises.
- You...
You're not welcome in these
premises at any point in the future.
Oh, go and fuck yourself
up the arse.
You fuck yourself up the arse!
Hands behind your back, Neil.
I'm arresting you, do you
understand?
You're hurting me!
- You're being arrested...
- You're HURTING me!
- ..for Section 5 Public Order.
- You do not have to say anything...
- You hate me!
- That's not true, Neil.
- Any excuse!
- You do not have to say
anything...
First time you saw me,
you talked to me like shit.
Well that's fine and dandy,
cos I'm not right fond o' you.
- You've had too much to drink,
and you need to be listening not talking.
- You're loving this!
...but it may harm your defence -
believe me, I'm not -
if you do not mention
- when questioned...
- AAAAAAARGHHH!
...something you later rely on in court.
- AAAARGHH!
Anything you do say may be given
in evidence. Do you understand?
- Do you understand that, Neil?
- Piss off!
Right, come on, get up.
Dozy sod.
I've asked you to go back inside
three times, now go inside.
Come on, Neil. Get up.
Come on.
That pavement's gonna get very
chilly if you stay there
much longer, and you do know it's
where the doggies do their wee-wees.
How drunk?
'I would say...'
three days' worth.
He was pretty whiffy.
'Oh, good grief...'
I'm sorry to be the one
to tell you, love.
He were upset about something.
Last few times I saw him, and...
Damn.
He'll just get a fixed penalty
notice.
There's no reason why he'll lose
his job if he can pull himself
back together and stay that way.
'Custody Sergeant's going to
phone me when he's sober
'and we can pick him up.
'It'll be a good few hours though,
it'll be later this evening.
'What was he upset about?'
Oh...
Just summat to do with
when his marriage broke down.
'OK.'
Well, I'll see you in a bit.
Yeah, OK, I'll, um...
Yeah, I'll see you in a bit.
'Ta-ta.'
When you're ready!
Thanks. Um...
Most of you will know
Superintendent Gillespie.
He's heading up the review team.
Before we go through
everything with Mr Gillespie,
there's a few bits and pieces
from this afternoon.
We've got an ident on the victim.
She's Elise May Hughes.
20 years of age.
Address - 27 Conway Crescent,
Dewsbury.
Last seen three days ago.
After we arrested Sean Balmforth.
Yep, so... Shush!
The pathologist is telling me
she's confident it's the same
killer as... Well, certainly
the first three victims.
And Vicky Fleming, if we accept
that he was disturbed before
he'd finished doing what he wanted
to do to her.
Although I think now more than ever,
we'd be wise to keep an open mind.
The good news - for once! -
is we might have a bit of a lead.
The night Elise May Hughes' body
was left at the site in Rastrick,
200 yards away, just further along
the road that same night,
a parked vehicle was hit by
another vehicle. Hit and run.
I've got forensics onto it, it won't
be long before we can identify the
make and the model based on
fragments left on the vehicle
that was hit.
I want to know who was
driving that vehicle.
At the very least,
they may have seen something.
Daryl?
I made you some tea.
Thanks.
They let that fella go.
The one they arrested.
It's been on t'news.
Except I think he's in custody
for something else, now.
They're looking for the driver
of a red vehicle.
They know it was red, cos it hit
another one... Left marks.
Near where it happened.
They think he might have
witnessed something.
The driver.
They say it's only a matter of time
before they work out
the make and model,
if he doesn't come forward.
I think cos of the marks.
So?
So you better get your tale
straight.
About how you damaged your car.
If they come asking.
Why would they?
Well, them two coppers were up here
before, weren't they?
It's not me asking, it's not
something I'M interested in.
I'm just thinking ahead.
You don't want them to think
YOU did it, do you?
Why would they think it's me?
Well, apart from the car,
no reason at all, love.
Except they arrested the wrong fella
once, they could do it again.
And as I say,
they think this person might have
witnessed something, so...
Where did it happen?
What?
Your bump. This was up Rastrick.
I don't even know where Rastrick is.
Tell me about me mum.
What about her?
When she went out with me dad.
I don't think they ever went out,
as such.
I think she just used to hang out.
In the town.
With this group of...
...people, and...
But they had me.
Well, your MUM had you.
He was long gone.
To prison?
Did she love him?
She was... infatuated with him.
What's that mean?
She thought she was in love
with him,
but she didn't know what
he was really like.
And he took advantage of her.
What does that mean?
Had her on.
How?
I don't think she...
She was just a bit young.
To get pregnant.
She was 18.
17. When she got pregnant.
And it doesn't matter how old you
are - if you're not ready for it,
you're not ready for it.
- Shall we have a cup of tea?
- Yes, please.
Is that why she died?
Cos she wasn't ready?
What's Granny said?
She said that she died
when I was born,
but it wasn't my fault.
No. No.
Well...
Sometimes it just happens.
Yeah.
How're you feeling?
Clare's outside.
Public aren't allowed in here.
Well, not unless they've...
You can speak to me, you know, Neil.
I know what alcohol does to people,
I see it every day.
I know you're not like that.
I mean, I know you don't want
to be like that.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
Have you fallen off the wagon
before, since you've been dry?
Twice.
OK, well...
...you tell me what I can do
to support you.
You know yourself best, you know
your habits. What do you need?
What can I do?
Catherine, I just want to go home,
want to get a shower,
get rid of this headache,
get back to normal,
put it behind me.
Did you ring in sick at work?
You didn't just go AWOL?
I took three days off.
You see, when I know the way
things are going - up here...
...I plan ahead.
(Right.)
Well, just... I don't know what
triggers you, and I'm sorry
if you've got something upsetting
you at the minute
that's sparked it off.
But Clare's vulnerable too,
and she's my priority,
and I won't watch her get
dragged down. Not by anyone.
I'm sorry if you think
I've not been very friendly.
I am sorry. She's very fond of you
and I want to respect that,
all right?
But please don't mess her about.
I won't.
Three days?
What, and then he can just stop?
I don't know.
D'you think it's good for her?
Being with someone who's the same?
What can I do? She's grown up.
You think they'll be all right
together on their own in his flat?
I mean, it isn't five minutes since
she... fell off the wagon, is it?
No, they're coming here.
He's gone to tidy himself up,
then they're going to an AA meeting
in Halifax, then they're coming
here.
That WOULD worry me. If ever they
did decide to move in together.
It wouldn't have till today, but,
my God, you should have seen him.
Is this mental?
What?
Three days, he's been pissed.
Disappeared, God knows where.
And then another one of these women
has been murdered.
Why would you think that about him?
- He's really uncomfortable
around you.
- Yeah, I know,
but that could just...
...be my effortless
overwhelming charisma.
Yeah, and that, obviously.
It IS mental.
I know it's mental.
When the Ripper was around,
everybody was thinking it was
their husband and their son
and their dad and their uncle.
Yeah, but... It's someone.
And the other thing.
Ryan was asking about Becky.
After you went out.
About her relationship with...
...him.
I didn't say owt. I just said
she was infatuated
and she didn't really know what
he was like, but it struck me -
it's when he gets home from school.
That's when he's got a new thing,
a new question,
like someone's put ideas
in his head.
At school?
Yeah.
Mum?
Mum.
Mum, I need to talk to you, Mum.
What's the matter?
I don't feel so well.
What is it?
Headache?
I don't want to go and tell
the police about me car.
OK.
Is that OK?
Why?
Why don't you want to?
Because...
...I've done things.
What things?
Things.
I think you'll be cross.
No, don't turn the light on.
Do you mind?
What is it you've done, love?
You know you can tell me anything.
I've always said that. Haven't I?
If you tell me the truth,
I won't be cross. About anything.
Yeah.
Well, then...
I...
Have you hurt someone?
Yeah.
With your car?
No.
Is it...?
Is it to do with those women?
Why you saying that?
- Is it?
- Why you saying that?!
Because...
- I wondered.
- Had you? When?
A while back.
Why didn't you tell me?
If it was...
would you tell the police?
Well, would you want me to?
No.
I just...
I don't know what I'd do
if they came looking for me.
The thing is,
they've got my DNA now,
cos of that fight the other day.
And I'd not get far if I set off.
Why?!
Why did you?
Why, though?
I don't know.
We've had a funny life,
haven't we, lad?
What you thinking?
I don't know.
I'm wondering
if there's a way forward.
If we could get rid of the car.
But then, there's 1,001
other things to think about.
Are you sure it was you?
Did someone tell you to do it?
No.
Voices?
Sometimes people hear voices
telling 'em to do stuff.
No.
OK.
You'll visit me, won't you,
in prison?
I don't think you'd like prison.
No, but if you can't think of
anything, then it's what'll happen.
How's Neil?
He's gone to work.
- Oh, good.
- Half six this morning.
That's good.
Hey, have you run that theory
past Clare, Mum?
- What theory?
- Which?
That woman on your phone.
Oh, yeah! You know a couple of
weeks ago,
that new Miss Wealand, Whelan -
whatever her name is.
Asking Ryan questions
about his dad.
Yeah.
Daniel reckons it's always
when he comes home from school
that he starts asking
questions about him.
- Is it?
- Yeah.
- Have you met her?
Yeah, I told you I had.
Where's your glasses?
Isn't that a lad?
No, it's a woman.
The man in the shop said.
What you thinking?
I'm thinking...
What?
It's her.
This is nice.
I've got a plan.
Have you?
You've always wanted to go
to America, haven't you?
How we going to afford that?
I've got some money put by.
Quite a bit.
How much?
Couple of thousand.
We've got our passports.
We'll call a taxi.
Get on a train to Manchester.
Then we'll get on an aeroplane.
And they might catch up with us
eventually - I think they very
probably would -
but at least you'll have done
something.
At least we'd have seen something
of the world, had an adventure,
wouldn't we?
Las Vegas?
Is that what you'd like?
Nevada. The desert.
Duke and Gonzo, we could hire a car.
OK.
Seriously?
What else would you like to do?
To see?
- Florida.
- Yeah.
- California.
- San Francisco.
Who'll feed the sheep?
I'll ask me sister.
We could cycle across
the Golden Gate Bridge.
You can hire bicycles.
I saw it on a travel programme.
Will she do that?
Yeah. I'll pay her.
Then you can get the ferry back.
Go past Alcatraz.
Won't go there, though.
Can we go to Disneyland?
Course we can, love.