NARRATOR:
In the criminal justice system
the people are represented by two
separate yet equally important groups,
the police
who investigate crime
and the district attorneys
who prosecute the offenders.
These are their stories.
Nice trip, Mr. Grobman?
Too short, Rudy.
Is there any mail?
Oh, yes, sir. And a
package from the court.
Well, make sure my wife gets that
when she comes up from the garage.
Oh, sure thing.
(GUNSHOTS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
GROBMAN:
Oh, my God! God!
Call 911. Call!
Denise! Denise!
All I saw, Judge
Grobman was wounded,
and that car was
fishtailing out of here.
Brand new Jaguar XJR.
And did you see anybody hangin'
around here before it happened?
Nobody who didn't belong.
She's a nice lady.
She gonna be okay?
I hope so.
Thanks for your help.
Which hospital?
St. Marks.
Husband went with her in the ambulance.
Any witnesses?
Not that we know of. We got the
car info from the doorman,
APB went out maybe seven minutes
after shots were fired.
Okay, thanks. Canvass the tenants and see
if there's anybody we need to talk to.
Victim's Denise Grobman,
civil court judge.
She and her husband have lived
here for nine years and change.
Polite but not chatty.
Husband's an architect.
What do you got?
Victim went down, here. .38's hers.
Two rounds fired.
ED: Civil court judge
needs a gun?
Maybe she hands
out too much alimony.
You find the slugs?
No. Blood over here
can't be hers.
She might've hit him two
out of two, good shooting.
Fair. Good would be
him layin' here dead.
And over here, we have
three cigarette butts.
ED: So, guy waited here
for the first opportunity.
Fuse box is open. Maybe it
was an electrician working.
Maybe. Dust it anyway.
Yeah. No problem.
APB went out quick, if the
car-jacker's got two gunshot wounds,
how far can he get?
I'm feelin' lucky.
Last time I got lucky was 1986.
It's all in the
attitude, Lennie.
All I saw was Denise lying there
bleeding, nothing else registered.
Where were you and
your wife coming from?
We have a cottage
in Sag Harbor.
We'd been there a few days.
Notice anybody followin' you?
No.
Mr. Grobman?
She came through surgery.
We won't have a prognosis
until she stabilizes.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
DANA: Daddy?
What are her injuries?
She took two hits, one
severed her lumbar spine,
the other damaged her kidneys,
we had to remove one of them.
Will we be able to talk to her?
If she lives.
Give me your card.
Thanks.
Uniforms turned up a witness.
He was smokin' a cigarette.
The fuse box was open,
I figure he workin' on it.
What did he look like?
Like a guy who'd be
workin' on a fuse box.
And I don't think this is who
shot the lady and stole her car.
ED: Why not?
Well, if he wanted a car,
he would have taken my
Mercedes, wouldn't he?
I leave the keys
in the ignition.
Why?
Well, I got tired of
spending half my time
trying to remember
where I put them.
Thanks.
If he'd wanted just any car,
he'd have taken
the old man's Mercedes.
So you think Judge Grobman's
Jag was stolen to order.
LaMotte's checking the MO.
Well, hospitals don't have any
unaccounted for gunshot wounds
that match our needs.
Did you get a description?
Witness is in with
the sketch artist.
Here's your possibles.
They specialize in high-end
European cars to order.
So, in other words,
if I wanted an XJR,
and I didn't
want to pay retail...
Call one of these guys.
Check with the
auto theft squad.
These guys have all got DMV
clerks on the payroll.
Hard to catch them.
So the clerk puts the stolen car in the
system under a different VIN number?
Yeah. Well, how do you figure
out which ones are stolen?
By wearin' out
your shoe leather.
Okay.
I'm showin' 14 '99 XJRs
registered since last Thursday.
Two private party sales, which is almost
always how the stolen ones show up.
Well, who sold them?
Seller's gonna be a phony
if the car's hot.
Okay, then, who bought them?
Got a Susan Robbinson,
and a Matthew Carton, MD.
Six, two, four, one.
That's it.
It's the Judge's cars.
Hey.
And we have incoming.
What are you doing?
Dr. Carton?
Who wants to know?
I didn't know it was stolen.
Is this the guy
you bought it from.
No. He was older.
One of these?
You got no record, why do you
wanna do this the hard way?
Nice leather upholstery. Cleans up
pretty good, but not good enough.
What's that mean?
Blood in the seams.
Do you read the papers?
A New York state judge
was shot over this car.
You can probably figure out
what that means for you.
(SIGHS)
I got a hundred thousand
dollar med school debt.
I couldn't afford a
decent car any other way.
How much did you pay for it?
20k.
You could've gotten a perfectly
good, legal car for half that much.
What, a Ford Escort?
I'm a doctor for God's sake.
Which one?
(EXHALES)
Him. Krasner.
I don't know a damn
thing about any judge.
I sell used cars.
Yeah, the trouble is the people who were
using 'em aren't finished with 'em yet.
Attempted murder,
A1 felony, 15-to-life,
or peddling stolen cars, a whole lot less.
Your choice.
Bobby Ward.
He came by middle of last week,
said he had a line on
an XJR, did I want it?
He wanted 5k, I told him three.
Ha. The doctor paid twenty.
Nice profit margin.
How'd Bobby Ward look?
Five-ten, wiry...
No, I mean, was he in
pain, limping, bleeding.
Looked fine to me.
Where can we find him?
Robert Ward.
Police. Open up.
There's nobody home.
Get back. Him and his
girlfriend left this morning.
Get her back.
COP: Police.
Search Warrant.
COP 2: I got him, I got him.
BRISCOE: Ed. In here.
COP 3: Clear!
He's alive, get the paramedics.
One in the arm.
One in the belly.
Looks like the judge
did hit him twice. No gun.
Daniel K. Ward.
Visa receipt in the
name of Arlene Pulaski.
I love it when they're stupid.
What the hell is this, man?
One,
two.
Hey, that's mine.
Must be six,
seven hundred here.
Three grand goes
pretty fast, huh?
Well, well, well, what's this?
Blood. Wow. Probably
10, 15 grand here.
Where'd you get it, Bobby?
Bite me.
Go ahead, bite him.
I didn't steal the car.
I didn't shoot no judge.
Look, I wasn't even there.
You sold the car to Krasner.
He thought it was
his cousin's car!
Hey, the gun we took off
of you's at the lab.
If it turns out it's the
one that shot the judge,
it's bye-bye, Bobby.
I told you,
it's my cousin's gun.
The cousin you left to die.
Hey, I was gonna call that in,
you know, when
I got out of state.
Not that you asked,
but he's in surgery.
Your story better match the one
he tells when he comes to.
Where'd the bloody
14 grand come from?
Possession and sale
of stolen property.
No charges on the shooting
or the car theft.
That's up to the D.A., you can
take your chances if you want.
All right.
Danny said he has
a line on an XJR,
I told him I got experience,
he should let me rip it.
He said, no,
it's a piece of cake,
he just wanted me
to help him turn it over.
So you talked to Krasner.
Yeah, Krasner tops
out at 3 grand.
Danny said that's okay 'cause
he got something in the works
that's worth like,
10 times that.
ED: What was in the works?
He wouldn't tell me.
Ten times three is 30,000.
We took almost 15 off of you,
where's the rest of it?
That's all he had on him.
What? You ripped
a guy off for 15 grand
and you didn't even ask
him where rest of it was?
Yeah. He said
he didn't have it yet.
Look, you want more than that,
you're gonna have
to talk to Danny.
We got a situation.
Looks like that big wad of money
was some kind of down payment.
Half up front, half later.
Murder for hire?
Well that's what it looks like.
We won't know for sure until
we lean on Cousin Danny.
Well, you're gonna
have to lean pretty far.
He just died on
the operating table.
So we do it the hard way.
Who wanted Judge Grobman dead?
Well, she sat on the criminal
court bench for ten years
before she moved over to civil.
And she'd just accepted a position
at the Justice Department,
Assistant Attorney
General for Civil Rights,
due to move DC next month.
What's the connection
to Danny Ward?
Well, what we've got, Danny Ward
had 14 jobs since high school.
Pizza delivery, air conditioner
repair, pretzel vendor...
I get the idea.
Arrested four times,
penny-ante stuff,
one conviction for disorderly
conduct, probation.
Big step up from there to
carjacking and attempted murder.
The gun we took from Cousin
Bobby shot the judge.
Her gun shot
the late Danny Ward.
It's Danny's blood
on the money.
Okay, that's settled.
Let's move on to who hired him.
Had to be somebody who knew when they
were comin' back from Long Island.
Well, assuming she
didn't hire him herself,
we know one other
person who knew.
Start with him.
I don't know this man.
The name "Danny Ward"
mean anything to you?
No.
Do you really think that somebody
hired him to shoot my wife?
Yeah. Somebody who knew when you
and your wife were comin' back.
But nobody knew
except Denise and me.
Oh, you don't think
that I hired him?
Who else knew when
you'd be coming home?
Well, we came back early, we were
supposed to stay till Sunday.
But Denise's clerk
called Thursday morning.
Something about a meeting
she had to go to on Friday.
So you and the clerk
knew, who else?
Well, nobody that I know of.
You and your wife
get along okay?
Hey, it's our job to ask.
Yeah, well, you're
way off base there.
We've been married
twenty-seven years.
I've given her a painkiller.
You've got two minutes.
We'd like to talk to her alone.
I'm goin' in with you.
No, sir, you're not.
That's him.
You returned fire?
Yes.
I don't remember anything else.
Forgive me, you and your husband
have a good relationship?
Why?
It looks like someone hired
this guy to shoot you.
Not my husband, not possible.
Anybody besides
him and your clerk
who knew you were
comin' back to the city early?
I can't remember.
BRISCOE:
You did the driving?
Walter wanted a nap.
At noon?
Up late.
Why'd he get out before you
drove into the garage?
Not Walter.
Ridiculous.
Please, I need to rest.
ED: Your boss ever
get any threats?
All judges get threats.
The D.A.'s office
checks them out.
They never found
anything serious.
We'd like to check
'em out ourselves.
I'll get you the file.
What time did you
call the judge?
Around 9:30
that morning.
Were there ever any problems
between the judge and her husband?
Uh, he probably wishes
she wouldn't work so hard.
Career comes first, huh?
A tie for first.
They're a devoted couple.
Uh, did you tell anybody else
that she was coming back early?
I called her doorman
to tell him
I was messengering
a packet to her.
Documents she needed for
the conference on Friday.
The judge was a plaintiff
in a civil action?
Judge Grobman's president
of a co-op board,
they sued their management
company a couple of years ago,
Marleton Realty.
ED: What for?
They were extorting kickbacks from
subcontractors and service companies.
They get ugly?
Extremely. The head of
Marleton is not a nice man.
Greg Torino?
Yes.
Torino even found a way to put the
bite on other companies' delivery men.
This avenue look promising?
Torino's a real piece of work.
Judge Grobman ripped him to shreds
and almost put him out of business.
Where's that list
of Danny Ward's jobs?
He worked briefly for
All-Kool Heating and Air.
Guess who did maintenance and repairs
for Judge Grobman's building.
All-Kool.
There's the dot that connects
Torino to Danny Ward.
It doesn't explain how
Torino could've known
the Grobmans were
coming home early.
The doorman.
The judge's clerk
told the doorman.
And he probably knows
people at Marleton.
I didn't have a damn
thing to with it.
I didn't tell anybody the
Grobmans were coming back early.
It's a straight line from you,
to Torino, to the shooter.
I got nothing to do
with Torino!
I'm the one who blew the
whistle on him to the board.
Who got All-Kool
this contract. Torino?
They were already here when
Torino took over management.
They don't owe him anything.
And Torino put the bite on
everybody except All-Kool?
That's what I'm saying.
We're gonna leave Officer Johnson
here to keep you company
while we check on some things.
You can't leave a cop here.
It'll tone up the place.
Danny Ward didn't do any residential
work, strictly commercial.
Here.
Here's his job list.
There's no Torino
on any of these jobs?
No.
I'd like to help you
nail that son of a bitch
but I don't see how he and Danny
could have crossed paths.
How'd you get the maintenance
contract to Judge Grobman's building?
No idea.
I was a crew foreman then.
The owner back
then must've known,
but he's dead.
Would it be in those files?
Maybe.
Yeah, we got recommended off a job
we did at a Queens mini-mall.
Can you look up that job?
Ha. Here you go.
Well, well. Look who
designed the mini-mall.
Walter Grobman.
Did Danny Ward work
on this project?
Yeah. I remember.
The design firm had a bad experience
with another cooling company
and they were all over Danny
to make sure this
job got done right.
Thanks for coming in,
Mr. Grobman,
we know things
are tough right now.
Anything I can do.
Well, obviously we're
tryin' to tie the shooter
to someone who had a
grudge against your wife.
Well, I don't see
how I can help you there.
Well, we just wanted
to make sure, now,
you said you'd never seen
this man, Danny Ward, before.
Is that right?
Yes.
You sure about that?
Yes, why?
Because two years ago,
you worked closely with him
during the construction of
the Crosstown mini-mall.
He installed the
heat and the air.
No, no. Not this guy.
That guy was heavier.
Well, this picture was
taken two years ago.
His cousin says
it's a good likeness.
Nah, I'm sorry,
I don't recognize him.
Why don't you
recognize the name?
Well, I never knew
his last name.
BRISCOE: (SIGHS)
The owner of All-Kool
says you left instructions
for Danny almost every day,
in envelopes with "Danny
Ward" written on them.
Well, you know,
it was two years ago.
Why was your wife
drivin' on Thursday?
Because she wanted to.
She said you asked her to drive
so you could take a nap.
Oh. Maybe I did.
I don't remember.
Do you remember why you got
out at the front entrance
instead of going into
the garage with her?
Look, I didn't hire anybody.
Mr. Grobman,
we talked to your doorman.
You and your wife went to your
cottage 10, 12 times a year,
this was the first time you ever
got out in front of the building.
Yeah. We went to the market.
We had grocery bags
plus suitcases,
why not let the doorman help?
That your idea or your wife's?
Keep in mind
we're gonna ask her, too.
Look, My wife is lying in the
hospital in excruciating pain,
and you're accusing
me of puttin' her there.
I don't have to listen
to any more of this.
ED: We were thinking that
this was just a coincidence,
but you're doing
a lousy job explaining it.
I don't have to explain anything.
Now get out of my way!
Ed, Ed.
Mr. Grobman, you sure you
don't want to clear this up?
Excuse me, but I am on my way to
visit my wife in the hospital!
You're not going near her. You're
under arrest for attempted murder.
(SCOFFS)
The People ask the
defendant be remanded.
My client's wife is in the hospital
unable to care for herself,
Mr. Grobman needs
to be with her.
She's there because the defendant
tried to have her killed.
He shouldn't be
allowed near her.
This is an affidavit from
Judge Denise Grobman,
the victim in the case.
She gives him an alibi,
Your Honor.
"Walter was with me when I learned
we had to return to the city early"
"and he was with me
continuously thereafter."
"He had no opportunity
to arrange the incident."
In other words,
the D.A. has no case.
We ask that the
defendant be ROR'd.
Ms. Carmichael?
One million dollars.
That's ridiculous.
My client can't raise that.
He's a successful
architect, Your Honor.
He's not Frank Gehry.
Most of the Grobman money
is tied up in trusts
from Mrs. Grobman's family.
What is accessible is earmarked
for his wife's care.
Bail is set at $25000 dollars.
Did you read my affidavit,
Ms. Carmichael?
Yes.
Do you grasp the meaning
of the word continuously?
He was never out of your
sight, your hearing?
No. Now, I'd like
to be with my family.
You understand your husband
knew the man who shot you.
He lied about why you
were behind the wheel.
You call that evidence?
My God.
Whoever arranged this shooting
was someone who knew you were
coming back to the city early.
I realize that you are doing your
job, but please, it's absurd
and if you insist on
prosecuting my husband,
I will testify on his behalf!
I want you to leave
my parents alone.
Your father knew Danny Ward
and lied about it.
He made a mistake.
Look, you have no idea what these
past two weeks have been like.
My parents have a good marriage
and my father did not do this.
Hey. You guys. Hey.
Hi, Dad. Okay, now remember,
we have to be quiet.
Grandma wants to see you,
but she doesn't feel good.
Why didn't you ask Judge
Grobman about the alibi
before you arrested
her husband?
VAN BUREN: My detectives
didn't want him loose.
You want it on your head if
he kills her in the hospital?
The Grobmans left Sag Harbor
shortly after the judge
heard from her clerk.
How did Mr. Grobman
get it arranged so fast?
Well, he probably already had
it arranged for Sunday night,
that's when they were originally
scheduled to come home.
One phone call to
rearrange the hit.
You have phone records
from their cottage?
We're on it.
JACK: Now the judge has set low bail you're
right back where you didn't want to be.
I doubt that. He'd have to
be an idiot to kill her now.
So the arrest was pre-emptive?
Come on, Lieutenant.
What's the problem?
This man hired someone
to blast his wife.
And I'll be glad to nail
his hide to the wall.
If he did it.
If you bring me
a case. Fast.
We pulled the IUDs from the phone at the
cottage and both their cell phones.
Nothin' that day on the cells and
only one call from the cottage.
Who to?
Listed under a D. Van Horn,
11:17 a.m., Sag Harbor.
An hour and a half after the
clerk left the message.
Well, maybe Grobman
called D. Van Horn,
and D. Van Horn
called Danny Ward.
Yeah, we should be so lucky.
VAN HORN: It was
just after 11:15.
I just got back from the market
but Walter didn't
call Denise did.
What did she want?
Oh, to apologize for
last minute regrets.
They were supposed to stop by
for drinks that afternoon.
Denise said it was an office thing.
She just found out.
Just then, at 11:15?
Yes she had a message
from her clerk.
I can't believe Walter had
anything to do with this.
Why is that?
Ah. It just doesn't track.
I've known Denise
her whole life
and Walter for
damn near 30 years.
Ever since he came back
from California with her.
I mean they're the golden
couple that everybody envies.
There are no problems
between them?
Well, they're not saints
and they both have stressful
careers, but nothing major.
What does "they're
not saints" mean?
Walter wasn't thrilled about the
Justice Department appointment.
He didn't want to move
to DC, but who would?
Couldn't he design buildings
from pretty much anywhere?
I guess, but I think lately he's
been tired of playing tag-along.
How so?
We had a little reception
about a month ago
to celebrate
Denise's appointment
and Walter was introducing himself
as Mr. Judge Denise Grobman.
You said you went to
the market in Sag Harbor.
Yes.
Did you see
Mr. Grobman in town?
No. But I drove past their
house on the way back
and Walter was in the side yard running
water from the hose over his head.
I guess he'd been jogging.
Why do you say that?
He had his jogging clothes on.
He runs every day.
Took it up a couple
of months ago.
CARMICHAEL: Judge Grobman
swore in her affidavit
he never left the house
at all that morning.
If he heard the message
come through earlier...
You think he went jogging and
called Danny Ward along the way.
Briscoe and Green are pulling IUDs
on pay phones he would've passed.
You run across anything
that smells like a motive?
As far as the cops can tell Grobman
didn't gamble, he didn't play the field.
The insurance money and her
estate go to the grandkids.
Still looking.
No, I don't think
he tried to kill her.
But yes, I am breaking
off our partnership.
You mind if I ask why?
Walter's a really
good architect
but you have to consider
the client's needs,
and he's just not willing
to do that anymore.
Well, isn't that
part of the job?
Thank you.
Client wants Colonial, Walter gives him
50 reasons why it should be Bauhaus.
Won't take no for an answer,
client goes someplace else.
So do I, finally.
That's the Prager Prize, the
Nobel Prize of architecture.
Walter won it as part of a team
when he was starting out in LA.
That was 25 years ago.
Walter was a prodigy.
He never lived up
to expectations?
It's hard when you won't
listen to the client.
He's a great guy
in a lot of ways,
it's just that he,
I don't know,
he needs to be right
all the time.
Is that part of his
relationship with his wife?
It's part of who he is.
She never had a problem
with it that I could see.
He had free rein on their
new country house.
What new country house?
They bought 20 acres
in Dutchess County.
Walter was going to design
their dream house.
How many country houses
do they need?
The one in Sag Harbor's
Denise's, from her father.
This one was gonna be theirs.
Was?
He gave it up.
Denise's job at the Justice Department?
Eight days a week.
Walter said, what good's a
dream house with nobody in it?
Twenty-five years ago, he was an
award-winning young architect,
she was scrambling
to pay her student loans.
Now the shoe's
on the other foot.
He suddenly just had enough?
The co-op's in her name,
the cottage is in her name,
his net income last year
was half what she made.
Where'd he get the money
to pay Danny Ward?
He put a $20,000 deposit
on the land upstate
and got it back when
they changed their minds.
(PHONE RINGING)
And it was
never re-deposited?
Not in any of their accounts.
Carmichael.
You're sure?
Thanks, Lennie.
Bingo.
Your clerk left
a message at 9:30.
Mr. McCoy, this is
all the same nonsense.
At 10:14, a call was made from
a pay phone in Sag Harbor.
A call to Daniel Ward,
the man who shot you.
Are you sure?
CARMICHAEL: Yes.
At 11:00, your neighbor saw
your father in the yard
in his jogging clothes, cooling
himself off with the hose.
Tell the nurse I need Demerol.
Now, Dana.
You have a witness who
saw him use the phone?
Not yet.
His prints on the keypad?
We're running them now.
Isn't it obvious what happened?
Someone was watching us, that
person called Daniel Ward.
How did that person know you were
going back to the city early?
I don't want
to hear this. I can't.
Walter did not do this.
It's not possible.
Briscoe and Green have talked to
practically everyone in Sag Harbor,
no one saw Grobman
use the pay phone.
Anybody see him jogging?
About a dozen, but no one can
remember what time or which day.
And there's nothing
in Forensics?
No smoking gun.
As long as his wife's giving him an
alibi, this isn't going anywhere.
(PHONE RINGING)
Carmichael.
Yes.
(SIGHING) Thank you.
Judge Grobman filed an application
to terminate her treatment.
Her dialysis?
She wants to die.
Bad time for
an irrevocable decision.
Anytime's bad.
It's her life, only she can
decide if it's worth living.
I'm not sure
it should be up to her.
ADAM: Up to the proper court
to consider her application.
Even then.
You have a moral objection?
Yeah, I do.
CARMICHAEL: Have you forgotten
your professional obligation?
If for whatever reason she's not around
to testify on her husband's behalf...
That's pretty damn callous.
It's a civil matter,
anyway we have no standing.
We do now.
Mr. Grobman's
filed for a TRO
to block his wife's application
to terminate treatment.
Quick work.
JUDGE PONGRACIC:
You want me to grant a TRO
to stop Judge Grobman
from terminating dialysis?
In effect, her life.
Yeah, so she can
testify for your client.
Isn't this a civil
matter, Counselor?
She's a witness, Judge.
You can preclude her from taking
any action until after the trial.
That could take months.
In the meantime, my clients
spends every minute of every day
in unendurable pain.
I saw Mrs. Grobman on
Wednesday, Your Honor,
she's coping with her pain.
What, you're siding
with the defense on this?
Your Honor, this should be decided
based on what is best for my client.
Somebody else's
jurisdiction, Mr. Brizard.
Mine is protecting the integrity
of the trial process.
Her testimony is absolutely
crucial to my client's defense.
In that case,
I'm gonna grant the TRO.
My client has asked me
to propose an alternative.
Her testimony
could be taken now,
preserved on videotape
for the jury.
Any objection?
If we can tape her testimony
we'll withdraw the
application for the TRO.
You don't give a damn about
anything but her testimony.
Your Honor, this is giving
him exactly what he wants.
His wife dies and
he gets away it.
That's enough, Ms. Carmichael.
Mr. McCoy?
Your Honor, the D.A.'s
office has concluded that
Judge Grobman was mistaken
in her affidavit.
I'd welcome the chance
to cross examine her.
Are you saying she perjured herself?
Denise Grobman?
The word I used was mistaken.
This is an
inconceivable situation.
Denise is a friend
and a colleague.
But if her testimony is exculpatory,
I don't have much choice.
Application for TRO is moot.
Witness to be examined at the
earliest possible moment.
My husband never left
the cottage that morning.
He didn't go for a run.
CLAYMORE: Where was he?
Part of the time he was
in the yard with me,
and he spent an hour so
going over blueprints.
Where?
In the garage,
there's a studio.
Would you have
known if he had left?
Yes.
Is the telephone answering
machine in the garage?
No, in the house.
Thank you.
No further questions.
Can you explain why your husband
was in the yard at 11:00,
in jogging clothes, running
water over his head?
It was a hot day,
and he lives in his jogging clothes
when we're at the cottage.
He worked up a sweat
going over blueprints?
DENISE: I guess so.
And he was so exhausted from
looking at these blueprints,
that he needed to take a nap
in the car while you drove?
He was tired, yes.
At noon?
Yes.
I want to remind you,
Judge Grobman
that you not only took an
oath today to tell the truth,
you also took an oath 12 years ago
when you were sworn in as a judge...
Your Honor!
...to uphold the
laws of this state...
Walter did not do this.
...and the rules
of the court.
I'm tired, I'm in pain.
No matter how many different
ways he approaches the question,
the answer is the same.
My husband did not
arrange the shooting.
He had no motive,
he had no opportunity.
Why are you protecting him,
Judge Grobman? You know he...
JUDGE PONGRACIC:
That's enough, Mr. McCoy.
Your cross-examination
is over.
The witness is excused.
So I expect you'll
dismiss the charges now.
Not a chance.
You're gonna drag this out?
You don't give a damn
about this family, do you?
My motion to dismiss will be
on your desk in the morning.
Now what?
If she dies before we can shake
her loose from her lies...
Why is she doing this?
Why is she covering for the man who
turned her life into a living hell?
Of course she
knows, Mr. McCoy.
We both know that
my dad tried to kill her.
Did she tell you that she knew?
No.
She won't even admit it
to herself but I can tell.
If she knows,
why's she covering for him?
Guilt.
Guilt?
She can't take back who she is.
I'm sorry,
I'm not following you.
My mom's career
always came first.
And I don't mean that she neglected
being a wife and a mother,
she just never realized
how my dad felt.
See, she was more
successful then he was,
she kept moving up
and he just treads water.
They argued about it?
He would shout that he gave up his
dreams to move east with her,
that she had it all
and he had nothing.
JACK: What was your
mother's reaction?
Well, she thought that they
supposed to be partners,
that what was good for one,
was good for both.
She didn't see a problem.
Do you want your father
to be held accountable?
You think your mother might
change her mind about facing it?
Isn't it obvious that she would
rather die than face it?
If she dies, it's over.
I've tried so hard to talk
her out of wanting to die.
She still has her mind, and
she has people who love her.
She's so depressed that
she can't think straight.
Would you be willing to sign
an affidavit about that?
Yes.
You're challenging Judge Grobman's
competency as a witness on what grounds?
I have an affidavit from the Grobman's
daughter stating that her mother
is too depressed
to think rationally.
Is she qualified to diagnose
her mother's emotional state?
Our psychiatrist,
Dr. Skoda, is.
Your Honor, if you rule that my
client isn't competent to testify,
you collaterally damage her
application to terminate her life.
Not necessarily.
Already the State
Attorney General
and the hospital are contesting
my client's application.
Any ruling that puts her competency
in question weakens our position.
My only concern can be this
criminal case, I'm sorry.
You have my permission
for Dr. Skoda to examine her.
DR. SKODA: It's not
irrational to want to die?
Not if you're
in this condition.
Your condition is new.
How do know you won't
change your mind?
I'm not interested in
any more questions.
If you don't convince me
your decision is rational,
you may lose control
over your situation.
Look at me.
I'm not even in control
of my bowels.
Can't you people leave
me alone, let me die?
I'm in pain every
minute of every day.
I've spoken with your doctors,
they say the pain is treatable.
It's all treatable.
A catheter,
a colostomy bag,
a dialysis machine,
a wheelchair,
a physical therapist,
a lifetime supply of Demerol.
Would you want that?
Will your husband
take care of you?
Yes.
I know people who are
paraplegic, even quadriplegic,
who lead vital,
productive lives.
Would you like to meet them?
I'm tired.
Can't you people
just leave me alone?
Can't you let me die?
Is it her physical condition
or her mental state
that's driving her?
I can't give
a clean answer to that.
They're feeding off each other.
Is she competent?
She's overwhelmed,
depressed, confused.
Is that a no?
My opinion,
she's not capable of making a
rational decision right now.
So we make it for her.
Riding this into the ground.
At first, I thought the cops
were wrong, they weren't.
Walter Grobman hired
someone to kill his wife,
because he felt eclipsed.
He's destroyed her life
for no good reason.
Why she's shielding him,
I will never understand.
But I know my job, I'm gonna convict
this narcissistic son of a bitch.
What about her?
Her life is over
whether she dies or not.
His conviction is the only thing
we can salvage out of this mess.
If you have her declared
incompetent to testify,
no civil judge will let
her pull the plug.
Then she'll be alive, not dead.
For a life she doesn't want.
Is this a thing that
you decide for someone else?
She's clinically depressed
and in massive denial.
Her judgment is
impaired by depression,
pain, denial and drugs.
She's suicidal.
Thank you, Dr. Skoda.
If somebody came to you and told you they
were thinking of committing suicide,
you would treat
them wouldn't, you?
Yes. If that's
what they wanted.
Because your
profession considers
suicidal thoughts to be
symptomatic of neurosis?
DR. SKODA: Yes.
Can you foresee
any circumstances
in which a person could make a
rational decision to end their life?
Such decisions are
always made under duress.
Aren't rational decisions
often made under duress?
Yes.
I suppose so.
As a medical doctor, do you
support a patient's right to die?
My personal beliefs...
As a medical doctor.
Then, no. I don't.
Thank you.
No more questions.
Judge Grobman,
are you depressed?
Of course I am,
who wouldn't be?
Can you articulate your reasons for
wanting to terminate your life?
I'm in constant pain,
I'm told it will
never get better.
There's nothing the doctors can
do to give me back my life.
I don't want to live like this.
Does your desire to die spring
from your physical condition,
or from the possibility it was
your husband that did this to you?
From my physical condition.
My husband did nothing.
Thanks.
You do understand that we're not here
to decide your right to die, don't you?
Of course I do, Mr. McCoy.
You want to prove
I'm irrational
so you can preclude my testimony
on behalf of my husband.
You left the hospital three
days ago, is that right?
Yes.
Where are you staying?
With my daughter
and her family.
Why not with your husband?
Because my daughter
lost the coin toss.
Could you be
responsive, please?
My husband has a business to run.
My daughter doesn't.
Do you get nursing care
at your daughter's?
Yes.
Around the clock?
Why couldn't they do that
just as well at your house?
My daughter insisted
I stay with her.
Did she say why?
Judge Grobman?
You've convinced her
her father tried to kill me.
Do you understand that your husband
knew the man who shot you?
You say.
Do you understand that your husband
was one of a very few people
who knew that you were coming
back to the city early?
So what?
Do you understand that your
husband made the phone call
that set up the shooting?
I don't know that,
and neither do you.
But you do understand
that your husband
resented for 25 years
your accomplishments,
your success.
We had a good marriage.
Did he say to you,
more than once,
that if he hadn't knuckled
under to what you wanted
he'd have gotten the
recognition that he deserved?
He didn't mean it
the way it sounds.
How did he mean it?
Why do you hammer
and hammer at this?
Can't you see it's my fault?
(CRYING) Please, please
leave Walter alone.
I've loved him for
more than half my life.
Everything is my fault.
When is this over?
Lisa, please make them stop.
Let me die.
(DENISE CRYING)
All right, Mr. McCoy,
I think that's enough.
(DENISE SOBBING)
JUDGE PONGRACIC: This has been
a difficult decision to make.
I was asked to render an opinion
that affects, however indirectly,
Denise Grobman's control
over her own destiny.
I know my ruling here may well affect
the outcome of her application
for termination
of life support.
I am devastated by
that responsibility.
That being said,
it is the determination
of the court
that Denise Grobman is not
competent to give testimony
in the matter of
the People v. Walter Grobman.
(GAVEL BANGS)
Notice of intent to appeal, application
to Judge Pongracic to reconsider.
What goes on inside you
when you look at your wife?
Knowing that
you did it for nothing.
Knowing she'd rather die
than acknowledge it was you.
We're not pleading, Mr. McCoy.
Why the hell didn't
you just divorce her?
Was the wound to your ego
so big that she had to die?
I want it over.
Walter...
I want it over!
I did it! I did it!
I killed her. I did it!
Walter, shut up!
I did it! I can't take it
anymore. I want it over!
Attempted murder one,
25-to-life.
We'll take our
chances at trial.
No, what about my wife?
You have fixed it so that she
can't win her application,
she'll be like...
she'll be like that...
She'll...
Civil court won't get word of Judge
Pongracic's decision for weeks.
It can all be over before then.
We won't oppose
her application.
Knock it down to
attempted murder two.
No.
For God sake, McCoy,
toss us a bone.
In 25 years, when Mr. Grobman
comes up for parole,
the D.A.'s office
won't oppose it.
(EXHALING)
Denise Grobman passed
away an hour ago.
Was her husband with her?
Yes.
I hope he takes that image
with him to prison.