Oh! Just letting you know,
if we die, I blame you.
I know.
None of this would have happened
if you'd just gone to the movies
like I told you.
Yeah, if I'd gone to the movies,
you'd be in jail right now.
Jail is a big improvement
on my current prospect
of soon to be murdered.
5x10
The Frame-Up Job
sub by lala123, corrections & re-sync by me
for www.Addic7ed.Com
Oh, hey.
I just heard from the others.
They're gonna stay in D.C.
I know. Parker texted me.
I mean, for the next two days,
leverage consulting is closed.
No work, no cases.
How will we pass that time?
With murder.
Portland film noir festival?
I know how you love
a murder mystery.
There are five of them.
"Mystery street," 1950?
Nobody shows "mystery street."
I mean, it's incredible.
It's the first mainstream movie
that shows forensic science
in murder investigations.
The entire plot hinges on this,
uh, forensic anthropology
slide show.
Unh-unh! Spoilers.
What? One ticket?
It's one ticket.
Well, darling, I'm sorry.
I can't join you.
My theater is a wreck.
I've got to sort out
the rehearsal schedule,
I've got a guy coming over
to look at the lighting...
Wait, so you're not gonna...
I know.
I'm gonna be slaving away
in a dusty, old theater
while you sit back and relax
and watch alcoholic,
repressed insurance cops
harassing tragically
misunderstood femme fatales.
Mwah.
You're not supposed to root
for the criminals.
Always root
for the home team. Mwah!
Thank you.
I'm afraid most of the artwork
has already been sold.
I'm sorry, Miss, um...
Collins. From the London museum of art.
No, no, no. You misunderstand.
We're not looking to acquire
any work.
I just want to view
these incredible paintings.
Oh. I know.
I've been curating Mr. Gault's
collection here at the house
since I was in grad school.
Jonas made my career.
Seeing this collection
broken up
just weeks
after his death is...
I know.
Why would the family do that?
Liar!
Jonas wanted me to live
in the guest house!
He's gone,
and I want you gone, as well.
Come on. I want you out...
His daughter can't cash
the checks fast enough.
Bit of a lush, I see.
Actually,
that's his fourth ex-wife.
His daughter's the one
in the suit.
Could you, um, pardon me,
please?
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
I know this sounds cheesy,
but have I met you before?
Oh, no, I don't think so.
Um, lady Covington-Smythe.
Charmed.
Woodman Gault.
Oh, Jonas' son. Oh, I'm...
I'm sorry to hear of your loss.
He was sick for a long time,
but at least we got close
over the last year.
Well, a father and son should
leave nothing unsaid at the end.
Ah. Thank you.
Ah, you're very kind.
With the mister
tragically passed,
I have little else to do,
madam.
I prefer to serve.
That's Paolo, my dad's
manservant for 20 years.
Manservant?  Yeah.
Do you know I am sure
I've met you somewhere.
Mnh-mnh. Mnh-mnh. I doubt that.
Um...
Her ladyship dealt with
your father's overseas division.
Huh. Well, I better be, uh...
Of course.
You think you're so clever.
I deduced your location
at a random event
within 100-mile radius
in under 20 minutes.
I've had worse mornings.
Is this a, um, German Riesling?
New Zealand.
- How did you find me, exactly?
- Why did you lie to me?
Oh, it's just like old times,
isn't it?
Me in the dress
and up to my neck
in easy marks and valuable art,
and you show up, all serious.
There is a distinct lack
in you telling me
why you lied to me
in that last speech.
- Now, why is a grifter and art thief...
- Ex-art thief.
At a high-end art auction?
Asks the insurance cop.
Ex-insurance investigator.
Still stalling.
It's a personal thing.
I... I'm a fan of his work.
Jonas Gault, the tycoon?
The artist, Jean Mettier,
the greatest artist
of the French retro school,
his brief career tragically cut
short with his death in 1989.
Since that tragedy,
Jonas Gault
painstakingly assembled
the single greatest collection
of Mettier in the world.
Thanks to his daughter,
Fiona, the new C.E.O.
of Gault instruments,
and the hard work
of the Gault family lawyer,
Mr. Reinhold Shecter,
we can now share this collection
with other
discerning art aficionados.
There. I'm just a big fan
of Mettier.
Where else could I have seen
so much of his work?
That's all.
But the auction's over.
And they're just gonna announce
who bought what, so we should...
Huh?
That's all? That's all.
Of course, that's not all.
What's left is ma mystère.
Would those of you who have
purchased a special pass,
please join us
in the vault anteroom.
Oh, God.
Honey, where's your ticket?
I had it. It was in my pocket.
Tickets? Here you are.
So, ma mystère.
Jean Mettier's legendary
first painting,
and there are no pictures of it,
no reproductions.
It's never been sold
or exhibited.
He... he described it once
as his inspiration.
He wrote that it belonged
to no one but him.
Hmm. And you're here
to steal it?
No, I just... it's personal.
You won't give up any
of your secrets still, huh?
How did you find me?
My father acquired
the painting
after Mettier's death
and honored the artist's wishes.
Frankly, I would have put
in a ticket booth
and charged admission.
But for over 20 years,
my father kept ma mystère
locked in this vault,
where he and only he would come
down and look at it every day.
And now, our family lawyer,
Mr. Shecter,
will open the vault,
and you will be the first
to see what inspired a genius.
Oh, my God.
Ma mystère's been stolen.
Well, I'll be buggered.
A world-famous painting
goes missing.
And, oh, look,
there's a world-famous art thief
happens to be on the premises.
Ex-art thief.
And I didn't do anything.
I was standing
right next to you,
and I barely believe that.
- But if somebody like...
Hello, Nate.
Sterling.
Give us back the painting and
save yourself a lot of bother, Ms...
Still going by Developer?
Still a pompous ass?
Charming.
Sterling... what?
You're Interpol.
You don't have the authority
to do any of this.
Art theft, as you know,
is an $8 billion-a-year business
used to fund racketeering
and terrorism.
My new department at interpol,
which I created...
Congratulations.
We should have sent a card.
We should have.
Intends to choke off
the money at the source.
The Gault collection is
a high-profile target.
And here we have
the most valuable piece
in that collection gone missing
and my favorite art thief
on the premises.
Ex-art thief.
Ex-art thief! Why does nobody
take that seriously?
Well, I mean, because...
You know, sometimes
a coincidence
is just a coincidence.
Not where Annie Kroy
A.K.A. Felicity Shaw
A.K.A. Indira McCallister A.K.A.
Sophie Devereaux is concerned.
Oh, wait. Hold on. Excuse me.
- Indira McCallister? Seriously?
- Hmm? What?
How come I don't know that...
I know all of the aliases.
Darling, nobody knows
all of them, not even me.
Excuse me.
Huh? Yeah. Huh?
Can we get back on point?
Oh. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sure.
The painting, ma mystère, valued
at 5 million euro, missing.
Oh.
Well, look, I couldn't hide
a cocktail napkin in this dress,
let alone a painting, so...
Which, by the way,
looks just amazing on you.
Thank you. I got it in Paris
when we went on that little...
Obviously,
you don't have it on you
and you didn't have time
to get it off the grounds.
So, where is it?
Sterling,
the thing about it is,
is that you don't have evidence
on either one of us about this.
I mean, I know that must be
very annoying... you're right.
I don't have the proof... yet.
But I can keep you here...
Right here...
Until I do get the proof.
Oh, hands. Grabby.
They're very grabby.
Sterling, you owe me.
Yes, I do.
That's why I'm bothering
to gather evidence
before I send you
to our secret prison.
Huh? Huh? What?
Agents. What'd he say?
I hate that man.
I don't know how you were
ever partners with him.
Well, he's funny
in his own kind of way.
Oh, yeah. Hilarious.
That crack about secret prison.
Oh, no, he was serious
about that.
This is all your fault, Nate.
You couldn't just leave
well enough alone.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
"I'm Nate Ford.
"Something going on
that doesn't involve me.
I can't have that!"
"Going on"?
What's going on?
If you're gonna use
your sexy voice,
you can take these.
You're on his side.
You think I stole it.
A snatch from a vault
with no exit, no prep?
I'd never be such an amateur.
Oh, and stealing
would be wrong.
Now, the only way we're gonna
get Sterling off your back
is to give him the painting.
Which, because I did not
steal it, I do not have.
Well, then we find out who does,
and we hand him over.
I know that gentleman upstairs
questioning everyone
is interpol.
But you're undercover interpol?
Well, of course we are.
Who else would we be?
I mean, if we were the thieves,
do you really think
we'd be hanging around here?
Of course.
Tell us about the security
on the painting.
The keypad
opens the vault door.
Here's also an rfid tag
on ma mystère itself.
Moving the painting
should have triggered the alarm.
And is there a way
to deactivate the system?
Jonas gave me the code.
I was the only one he trusted.
But I only used it
moments before bringing people
down to the vault.
Oh, so we would have
seen someone
- trying to steal the painting then.
- Yes.
Now, with the painting gone,
who gets
the insurance settlement?
Woodman was disowned years ago,
so Fiona and Eleanor
would split it.
I already told
the interpol man upstairs that.
Yes, of course.
Thank you so much.
We'll take it from here.
Yeah. Thank you
for your cooperation.
Thank you so much.
Could you just drop that off?
Thank you. Thank you.
You do know
that he's going straight up
to talk to Sterling, don't you?
This is a two-tiered Glen-Reeder
2700 museum-quality alarm.
It would take two days
to crack.
Some of the keys are worn.
Ah, combination.
Same keys used over and over.
Listen, you do know
that this isn't about you taking
Sterling's side, don't you?
I'm not taking anyone's sides,
especially not Sterling's.
Now, listen, he... Shecter...
spilled a drink upstairs,
and his hand
when he just shook it, sticky.
Give me the...
give me the works.
Okay.
You think I'm lying.
Well, you did lie to me.
About the auction.
I just thought you'd find
the whole thing rather boring.
Yeah, and it turned out to be
a quiet event, didn't it?
Hmm. What do you see?
Someone who can't
turn their brain off.
Stop thinking just for a second
and feel. Trust me.
No, no. Come here. Look.
On the keys, what do you see?
Oh. Um... fingerprints.
Yeah. -But not on
the keys that are worn.
Yeah, now, you know,
Shecter entered the combination.
It was a different combination
than Jonas Gault had been using
for the last 20 years.
Someone changed the code.
Now, Jonas Gault
is the only one
who had access
to the combination,
so, clearly, he changed
the combination before he died.
And...
I would so much love
to trust you,
but you make it so hard because
you're still hiding something.
And I know you're just
trying to charm me into,
uh, telling you
how I found you.
Mnh-mnh. No.
That's not how it...
Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Wait. How did you find me?
How did you find me?
Nothing's been touched
since Mr. Gault... you know.
I'll always remember the time
he sent me 500 red roses
and a troupe of balladeers
for my sweet 16.
That was the mister.
Romantic heart,
but weak in the end.
Thank you so much for allowing
us this time to commune
with whatever bits of his spirit
may still be lingering.
Of course.
Manservant?
Right?
What are we looking for?
Glasses are
on the wrong side of the bed.
Huh. Right.
Reading lamp there, books there.
What was he reading
on this side?
Uh, last job
would be in the buffer.
Hit "print."
Hmm.
Alarm-company printout
of the times
that the vault was accessed.
Yeah.
The first ones
are at regular intervals.
Gault's daily visits. Right.
But on the day that he died,
there are six entries and exits
all clustered together.
Okay, well, that wasn't him,
not with that Walker.
Something makes
Jonas Gault suspicious.
He calls up the vault entries
and sees that someone's
been going in and out.
So he changes the alarm code.
And then conveniently dies.
This isn't just an art theft.
- It's murder.
Oh. Sterling. Good, come on.
Is this an escape? 'Cause if
it is, you're very bad at it.
Gault was murdered
by the same person
who stole that painting.
Sophie murdered Jonas Gault?
Gault was on a fistful
of medications.
Nazaprine, Achnofoline
for his heart
and Miridium
for blood thinners.
Look at the prescription,
the date he died,
and count the pills.
There are a dozen missing.
Anyone could have stolen those.
Yeah, or somebody
could cut open the gel caps,
take the medicine out,
dumped it into the glass that
Gault kept by his bedside, hmm?
Now, an old man dies,
nobody cares, right?
Now, if it were me...
I wouldn't just throw away
the empty gel caps.
- I'd flush them down the sink.
- Yeah.
Designed to dissolve
in the stomach.
Takes two weeks
to dissolve in water.
Also, Jonas Gault was sure
that someone had gained access
to the vault.
Assuming this is true,
the killer would need
constant access
to get into the vault
this number of times.
It's a member of the household.
Okay, so we've got Shecter,
the family lawyer.
The estate sale
has gone to hell.
Then you've got Katrina Hardt,
the art curator.
Collections kept in the house.
I-I-I've never been
in the vault.
Next you have Fiona Gault,
the daughter.
There is Eleanor,
the last ex-wife.
I could tie a knot in this
for you, if you want.
That's really nice. Thank you.
And woodman, the son.
Whoever was in the vault
the day Gault died,
that's your killer.
You have one hour.
If I don't have a suspect
in an hour,
you're both
going down for this.
Well, I don't need an hour.
I got a Sophie.
Darling, just mute the phone.
I can hear everything.
Do you really have to be here?
You're not innocent yet.
Sign here, ma'am.
Miss Hardt.
Oh, Miss Collins. Thank you.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
I just... I... the shipping crew
is here to take
all the Mettier paintings
these people purchased,
and it's just, um...
You poor thing,
you're in charge
of every single Mettier
in the house.
Yes. Jonas had me
here every day.
Really? That's awful.
That means you were here
the day he died.
Yes, I arrived that afternoon,
and I had no idea that he had
already slipped into a coma.
It makes me so sad that...
I was out here arguing
with Fiona
while he was
just slipping away.
Six years I have put
into this job!
Your job is over,
as far as I'm concerned.
I've decided we no longer need
a full-time curator.
That is not up to you.
That is up to your father.
How dare you try and tell me
what my father does...
Well, I mean,
I wasn't the C.E.O. At the time,
but now that father is gone,
I've accepted
that responsibility
as majority shareholder.
And I must see, on behalf
of the U.K. Shareholders,
we couldn't be happier
with the way that turned out.
Agreed, clive?
Yes. Of course.
I have to admit,
I was in a foul mood
after dealing with Eleanor.
That woman is a...
Drunk parasite
leeching off his pit!
Your father still loves me
and he trusts me a lot more
than he trusts you.
Hovering over him
like a vulture.
When he dies,
you will not get a penny.
He's not going to die.
When he gets better,
we'll prove our love to you.
I mean, what better proof
is there than getting remarried?
Sure, our first marriage
broke up,
but we'd grown
so much since then.
Thank you. God bless you.
I just hope me and my chauncey
are as happy
as you and your Jonas were.
I'm sure that's why he chose you
as our wedding planner.
Now, when exactly
did he propose?
He didn't,
but I know he intended to
because the lawyer explained...
That's why I'm here, Eleanor.
I have to get the documents
to file the marriage certificate
and change the will.
I knew it!
It's his wish to pass
his last days with you.
Oh! Let's celebrate
with a drink!
I have so much work, Eleanor.
But please, don't tell anyone
I told you.
Oh, I won't. I promise.
Because I knew he was never
going to remarry that woman.
Jonas was just getting
sentimental in his last days,
and the havoc that would wreak
on the estate, agent...?
Agent Tennant.
Are you getting this, agent Smith?
Yeah.
Inheritance issues?
Well, there were about to be.
Jonas had made
a very radical decision.
He's adding you
back into the will,
your full share
of the inheritance.
I don't want it.
Woody, we're talking millions,
plus your share of the stock.
I don't want the money.
None of it.
Can you believe that?
Pardon me.
- Hello? Yes?
- I admit, I do find that hard to believe.
What?
I finally understand
what he sees in you.
We need to find woodman.
Don't worry about it.
I'll handle it.
Weird, cold nights,
you get a little frost buckle,
it ruins everything.
The British lady's friend,
right?
Nate Ford.
What's a, uh... what's
a millionaire's son doing,
uh, working on a pool?
I screwed things up
first go-around, you know?
He gave me everything...
Private tutors, apartment
in Tokyo, art school in Paris.
I drank it all away.
He kicked me loose.
After a couple hard years,
I started a contracting company.
After dad got real sick, well,
I volunteered to fix the pool
just so I could be near him.
Sometimes money
just gets in the way.
Ain't that the truth.
The, uh, art girl, Katrina.
Cute, huh?
Was she here
the day your dad died?
She was up there as soon as the
maid that found him screamed.
Why?
Not quite sure who wants Gault
dead out of that lot.
All of them but one.
Katrina was
about to lose her job,
but if Gault died first,
she'd get a commission
for selling the collection.
Now, Fiona needed Gault to die
before he remarried Eleanor
so that she'd inherit
her shares.
Eleanor suspected
that those shares
were soon to be split
with woodman,
who, by the way, is
the only person without motive.
Shecter didn't have a motive.
Oh, but Shecter knew that Gault
wasn't gonna marry Eleanor,
so why is Shecter
in that office
pulling financial statements
for Gault instruments?
Shecter's embezzling.
I'd forgotten
how attractive that is,
the relentless tick-tick-tick
of you pulling apart
someone's well-laid plans.
Oh, including yours.
Oh, you've never
pulled apart my plans.
We are back at square one.
On the murder, yes,
but who cares about that?
We're here about an art theft.
Okay, they all alibi each other
for the times someone was going
in and out of the vault.
So, if the same person who
killed Jonas stole the painting,
then none of them did it.
Who's left?
Nobody.
Ooh!
I'm sorry.
What are you doing in my room?
So, the Butler did it.
Miss Hardt.
It's just beautiful.
Ma mystère... can you be sure?
It's never been photographed
or exhibited.
But thanks to Jonas,
I am the world's leading expert
in precisely one artist.
Mettier.
Hmm.
Brush strokes are right.
Texture on the oils.
Color palette is consistent
with his early works.
He stretched his own canvas.
Those are his nails.
I would have to do more tests,
but honestly, this is Mettier.
And the only one
I've never seen before.
It's ma mystère.
Miss Hardt, you can release
the rest of the collection
to the buyers.
I'll tag this for evidence
and return it to the estate
as soon as possible.
Of course. Thank you.
Thank you.
It's always nice
to bring a thief to justice,
even if it's not you.
Or you.
Only one problem. Hmm?
That is not ma mystère.
What do you mean
"it's not ma mystère."
It's complicated. Look.
What?
Gault's own curator
thinks it's legit.
I'm telling you
that is not ma mystère.
But how could you know that?
Uh... um...
Did you try to steal it once?
No.
Hmm. Did you actually steal it once?
Look, it could be a Mettier,
but it is not ma mystère.
How do you even know
what ma mystère is?
I mean,
there's no photographs...
I just...
I need you to trust me.
Ah. You.
You have actually seen
ma mystère, haven't you?
Not exactly.
Look, what if I can prove it
to you?
Look,
if it's not ma mystère,
how do we even know
that it's a real Mettier?
Well, the way to prove
that it's not a Mettier
would be to compare it
to another Mettier.
That's true,
and they've all been sold
to all these other rich people,
and that...
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no.
Sophie, no, no, no.
You are not gonna go in there
and steal a real Mettier.
No, no, no.
It wouldn't be stealing.
I'd just borrow it
just for a little while
just to compare it to ma mystère
and prove its a fact.
Which means we have to also
steal ma mystère.
I just got you off the hook
from stealing that painting.
Now you want to go and steal
that and another painting
just to prove it isn't real?
I don't want to.
What I want is
for you to take me at my word.
We've been working together
for five years,
sleeping together for two.
I mean, what is it gonna take?
Sterling is sitting
right on top of ma mystère.
Are you telling me
you can't outsmart Sterling?
I can't.
But he can't outsmart me,
either.
Okay, you go get Mettier.
I'll deal with Sterling
and get ma mystère.
Hmm?
Crate that up,
put an evidence sticker on it.
We'll take it with us
when we finish the interviews.
We'll handle the...
Jurisdictional issues.
What do you want?
Ah, nothing.
That's... that's
the whole case? Yeah?
Just...
If by which you mean the means,
the motive, the opportunity,
the fact
that I found the stolen item
in the possession
of the suspect...
Yes, that's my whole case.
I'll put that
in front of a jury.
Yeah? Hmm.
You think
I've missed something?
Hmm.
That's it.
Oh, you'd like to see
my whole case fall apart
just on some little...
Go back to the beginning!
Take that...
To the billiard room.
Um, all the shipping labels
are already on.
Once you get them
to the shipping house,
they will unload them and send
them to their destination.
Okay.
Oh, goodie.
Ooh, that's my painting.
Ma'am?
My painting.
I'd like it, please.
Oh, no offense.
You and your company, I've
lost art in shipping before,
you see, and I prefer to have
my possessions in my possession.
Well, you know I can't just
give you the painting.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You don't know who I am?
I'm the duchess
of Islington-barrow.
That is my property,
and I would like it.
I need to see some I.D.
Do I look as if I came out
carrying out I.D. On me?
Miss Hardt?
Oh, uh, yes, Miss Collins.
Oh, Miss Hardt,
I've got to say,
I'm really impressed
with your security.
I was thinking I'd like
to hire them the next time
the London art museum
loans something out.
The thing is, I was asking him
for his contact info
and he wouldn't give it to me.
What? No.
Which, you know, he said
it's protocol. I get it.
You know,
it's good for security,
but it's rubbish for business.
Do you think you could just...
Frank, Frank, don't be paranoid.
Just give it to her.
Thank you.
Frank, let's be friends. Don't pout.
Cold.
Cold, cold.
Warm.
Ish.
Get out.
Hmm?
Very warm.
Follow him.
Yes, sir.
I-I just left my phone in here.
You guys, cake's on fire!
Oh, God! Oh!
Excuse me. Let me through here.
Watch out, people. Move back.
Darn phone.
I just can't find it.
I can't find the darn phone.
Mettier mixed his own paint.
He used copal resin and clay
earth found near his home.
There's no way
a forger could match
the exact chemical composition
of his paint.
Okay.
A little, uh, silver Polish.
Right.
That.
Bleach.
And top it off...
With some fine vodka.
I think I drank this
in college.
This from this painting.
And a little of that
from that painting.
Okay. If you will.
Well, that is a match.
They can't match.
It's as close
as we're gonna get
without stealing
a chemistry lab,
and we're not gonna go, you
know, steal a-a chemistry I...
I was just... I was so sure
it was gonna be...
Something else.
I was wrong, I guess.
It ma mystère.
What did you think
it was gonna be?
There is one other possibility,
of course.
The paintings match.
So either that is
the real ma mystère or...
It's a fake Mettier.
That doesn't make sense.
It came straight out
of Gault's collection.
Even if there was
a fake in there,
what are the chances that I just
happened to steal that one?
Slim.
Unless all the paintings
are fake.
Or Gault's entire collection
is fake.
So let me get this straight.
You stole not one,
let but two paintings, ht.
One of which
you spent the entire day
trying to convince me
you did not steal,
all because
your girlfriend here,
an unrepentant,
inveterate, professional liar...
That's uncalled for.
Told you
with no evidence whatsoever
that ma mystère was fake.
Now you're so sure
that she's right,
that you not only think
that this painting is a fake,
but every other Mettier
that was in the house,
the entire collection,
is also fake?
That's right.
Arrest them both.
On what charge?
Theft.
We've brought you back
the paintings.
Obstructing an investigation.
We're helping you
with your investigation.
Being annoying and crazy.
That's not a crime.
Since when was that a crime?
No, it's not.
I don't care!
All right,
all right, all right.
Say, just say,
that you're right.
Do you have any idea
what it would take
to replace every one of these
paintings with a forgery?
Yeah, well, for starters,
I mean,
you would probably need
an elderly victim
whose eyesight was shot
so much to the point
where he wouldn't notice
the switches.
He'd have to repaint
every single painting.
Yes. Yes, so you'd need time.
Months. Months.
You'd need
a detailed knowledge of Mettier,
plus access
to all the paintings.
Yes, and most important,
of course,
you would need the ability
to establish provenance.
You would need to declare,
without question,
that every one
of these paintings
is absolutely
and undeniably legitimate.
The curator.
Hey!
I don't suppose anyone here
spent the last few years
secretly replacing every Mettier
in the house with forgeries
while no one was looking.
Very slick interrogation.
I didn't think that would work.
She's getting away.
I didn't think that would work!
All right, uh, you go that way
and I'll go this...
Fleeing the scene of the crime,
she slipped
on the edge of the pool,
hit her head, fell in.
Accidental death.
Nothing like bringing a thief
to justice again.
Hey, you know what?
Look at the bright side.
You solved a theft, a murder.
And once you go through
that woman's records,
you'll find all the people that
bought those stolen paintings.
I mean, it was
a pretty big forgery ring.
And despite your efforts
to drop off the map,
I now know
your new base of operations.
Everything is
sunshine and rainbows.
Be seeing you.
Ugh. He thinks he's so
intimidating, but he's not.
Let's get the hell out of here
before he changes his mind.
Yeah.
I was right.
It was like old times.
It was.
Art theft, chases,
dresses, and tuxedos.
I just...
I wish I had gotten to see
the real ma mystère.
Eh.
Sterling might find it once he
goes through Katrina's files.
Mm.
I'm sorry I couldn't tell you
how I knew it was a fake.
It's just, it's personal.
But I really appreciate
your faith.
I-I treasure it.
You made a good point.
I should trust you.
I mean, I do trust you.
I do. And...
Look, you and me, we're...
Me and you, we're...
Oh, it's just that...
We are, uh...
Shoes.
Huh?
That's how I found you.
Your shoes.
When you left that day,
you know,
you were wearing your
fancy shoes, uh, the high heels.
They're high enough for fashion,
low enough to run in.
You never looked at my feet.
Didn't have to. They sound
different on a wooden floor.
You're so clever.
What about the party?
Well, I mean, if you were
wearing those shoes,
it meant one thing... an event,
which meant catering.
So I called
all the high-end caterers
and I found that, uh,
there was one party.
An art auction.
That brain of yours is very,
very sexy.
Oh, thank you very much.
How about the rest of me?
It's a little beat-up, but...
It has its charm.
I have a change of clothes
for the morning.
I'm such an idiot.
Nate?
It didn't matter how many times
she came in and out.
She still couldn't crack
the second alarm.
But you knew that already,
didn't you?
They'll hear a gunshot.
Place is empty.
Too much death.
Everybody's freaked out.
Art school in Paris?
Wasn't talented enough
to sell my stuff.
But after dad cut me off, well,
talented enough
to fake other people's art.
Good coin for a while, too.
Then he got sick and I came home
to scam some money,
and there it was.
A whole house
full of valuable paintings.
Hmm. With its own curator.
Lonely curator.
The interpol agent found out
about the forgeries.
Woody, they know.
They know about the paintings.
Aah!
You'd, um, switch out one
painting every couple of months.
Nice.
When did you decide
to go after ma mystère?
When I saw the keypad,
and I knew the numbers.
You painted the duplicate
in advance.
Of course, you'd, um, have to
guess what it looked like.
No one else had seen it.
Ah.
But tried to keep it
close at hand, didn't you?
Do you think
that's what tipped him?
When he saw someone was
going in and out of the vault,
he called the alarm company
and took precautions.
Although you'd gone in and out
a bunch of times,
he changed the code
on that last trip.
Why did you go in and out
so many times?
Think you got it
all figured out.
But you're not as smart
as you think you are.
I'm smarter than you.
I'm smart enough
not to kill my partner.
You are a compulsive,
obsessive, selfish...
Really should run!
Right.
Oh! Just letting you know,
if we die, I blame you.
I know.
None of this would have happened
if you'd just gone to the movies
like I told you.
Yeah, if I'd gone to the movies,
you'd be in jail right now.
Jail is a big improvement
on my current prospect
of soon to be murdered.
Sophie, run. Run.
You kept the cuffs. Naughty.
That the shallow end, right?
Oops.
Anyone else in the vicinity
you'd like me to arrest
for the same crime?
Or is three our lucky number?
This is it.
He got ma mystère out,
but Gault changed the code
before he could get
the fake into place.
Yes.
Couldn't let a perfectly good
fake go to waste,
so he framed Paolo with it.
And the real ma mystère?
Eh, we'll get it out of him.
Again...
Be seeing you.
Turns out, you're still
the second-best detective
I've ever known.
Ah. So are you.
You ever want to do this again,
call me.
I'm hiring.
And you can bring
the art thief.
Ex-art thief.
I would really have liked to
have seen it, just to know.
How does a forger defeat
a two-tiered security system
in less than an afternoon?
I mean, when they don't have
those skills,
the skill he does have...
Is in construction.
See, all he had to do was just
wait until after the auction.
Shecter turned off the alarm
on the painting.
Then they could come back
anytime.
They just had to
keep the painting hidden.
So he built a false wall
and hid the painting there.
I bared my soul to him.
You bared more than your soul.
He vowed it would never be seen
by the world
till after my death.
So we're gonna steal it.
Of course we are, darling.
To honor his wishes.
Of course.
ma mystère.
He never even showed it to me
after he painted it,
and then I wasn't really tempted
when I knew it was locked up.
That's...
Yes.
You are...
Very young.
And...
Very naked. Yes.
I think you look better now.
Oh.
Mr. Ford,
you are quite the charmer.
sub by lala123, corrections & re-sync by me
for www.Addic7ed.Com