[theme music playing]
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
[Pop] They lose 65 games only to end
up with the fourth pick in the draft.
Did they tank that shit on purpose?
Read the words, Pop. Right
there on the wall.
Brother's got a point, Henry,
much as I hate to admit that.
That's right. Pay up.
You're right, you're
right. I shouldn't have cursed.
- My bad, Lonnie.
- It's okay, Pop.
[Pop chuckles] All right.
What's their record this
year, anyway, like?
[Pop] 17 and 65.
You know that Russian kid they
drafted? He better be good.
He's Latvian.
What they need to do
is fire Phil Jackson.
[Pop] Wait a minute, Phil Jackson
ain't out there playing no more.
Phil Jackson overrated, B.
Anybody can win with Jordan and Kobe.
Phil ain't no Pat Riley.
- [all groaning]
- Aw, Riley, again?
- [Pop] Yeah.
- Here we go.
[Chico] I mean, Pacino...
Now, I get why that white
boy makes your free haircut list.
The Godfather and Scarface guaranteed
that man an eternal ghetto pass.
- Carlito's Way, too.
- [Shameek] Mmm-hmm.
- [Chico] But Pat Riley?
- [Pop] Yeah.
[Chico] Why does Pat Riley get
so much love in this shop?
Right. Even punk-ass Derek
Fisher got more rings than Pat Riley.
Uh-uh.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
'Cause the Knicks played like
men when Pat Riley was head coach.
Oakley and Ewing went hard in the paint.
Plus Anthony Mason and John Starks?
Drive the lane, you might
go home in a body bag.
All right, now I heard that.
Later with all that Instagramming,
"let's all max contract on the
same team together" bullcrap
- passing as competition nowadays.
- [all laughing]
[Pop laughs] Mmm. Yeah.
[scoffs] Didn't Pat Riley sign those
Instagram dudes down in Miami
when he became the GM?
[scoffs] Maybe.
But King James is the
truth. LeBron can ball.
[Pop chuckles] Yeah.
Now pay up, Luke. You said "bullcrap."
"Bullcrap" ain't a
curse, man. I don't curse.
- [imitating Luke] "I don't curse."
- [laughs]
You don't cut hair either, negro.
Like, really, what do
you do up in here, bruh?
I sweep hair, Shameek.
I also mop, I wash the towels,
and I make sure that plate
glass window stays spotless.
It's called work. Something
you would never understand.
[scoffs]
Slam Magazine... Hmm?
Coaches used to live
up in this piece, son.
Kevin Ollie got a
shape-up right there from Pop's.
Pitino, too.
Stylin' and profilin', that's my work.
- See what I'm sayin'? Yeah?
- Yeah. Tell him.
For real?
Doc Rivers, uh, call you yet, Shameek?
[chuckling] Whoa, all right. Play nice.
- You can't even afford a haircut.
- [Shameek] Hey, you know what?
- I'm about sick and tired of...
- [Luke] What?
Hmm?
You sick and tired of what?
About sick and tired of the
Knicks losin' all the time, man!
- [Shameek sighs]
- [chuckles]
[chuckling]
You got some hair, too, right there.
- I'm not finished.
- Yes, you are.
[door opens and bell dings]
- Hey, Counselor.
- Aw, don't jinx me, Pop.
I haven't even passed the bar yet.
- Oh, you will.
- [chuckles]
Lonnie, you got Kumon tonight. Let's go.
Come on, boy, you heard your mama.
Let's get moving.
Don't make me repeat myself.
[chuckles]
Hey, Luke.
What time you get off?
I got another job I go to
right after I leave this one.
[sighs] Black man working. Ain't
nothing wrong with that.
[inhales] Well, we should at least
try to get some coffee some time.
Maybe you'll need a lawyer one day.
Hopefully, you'll have
some cards by then.
[chuckles]
[Pop chuckles] Hey.
Be sure and tell Bessie I said hey.
- I will.
- Mmm-hmm.
How's a woman that fine with a briefcase
gonna throw it at a
brother with a broom?
That's what you don't get, youngin.
Either you have it or you don't.
- [chuckling]
- Oh, I know I got it.
Shit. [indistinct muttering]
[Pop] Whoa, whoa. See the
words... right there on the wall.
- [scoffs]
- Hmm?
- [Pop] Pay up.
- Come on, Pop.
[dryer whirring]
[Pop] Huh, there you go again.
I shook everything else after I got out.
Cigarettes, paranoia...
But the pacing?
I do it, too. [grunts softly]
Reva again?
Reva always.
Look, it's been long enough.
Give Patty a call. She's a good woman.
[scoffs]
I don't drink coffee much.
I don't think she does either.
[chuckles] Like she said, "Ain't
nothing wrong with that."
When I'm ready, I'm ready.
But you'll want a cup of something
hot and dark sooner or later...
Mr. Bulletproof.
- [chuckling]
- There you go with the nicknames, Pop.
You said your rebound chick took
a shotgun at point-blank range...
pointed it under your chin,
and pulled the trigger.
I still get the occasional headache.
Not a problem for you, Power Man.
[chuckling]
[Luke grunts]
Mmm-mmm. [chuckles]
I love it when you do
stuff like that. [chuckling]
You should be out there helping
people, that's all,
like them other fellas downtown.
Reva used to say the same thing.
Yeah, well, she was right.
You don't ever think about all
the people you could help?
You should be more ambitious.
What if my ambition is to sweep hair...
wash dishes...
and be left the hell alone?
Well, that would be a waste.
You think I asked for any of this?
I was framed, beaten...
and put in some tank
like an exotic fish.
Came out with...
abilities.
Saved your life.
More like ruined it.
Reva's dead. [exhales]
I'm a fugitive.
So?
Take my advice, brother.
The past is the past.
And the only direction in
life that matters is forward.
Never backwards.
I'm just living my life...
day to day.
[hip-hop music playing over speakers]
Why don't you watch
where you going, man?
What's the gun for, Chico?
[scoffs] Is your name Wilfredo Diaz?
'Cause he walked out on me
and moms when I was nine.
I ain't need a daddy
then and I don't need one now.
[car engine starts]
- Let's get this money.
- Yeah.
Tsk.
Hey, Pop, I gotta go. I'm runnin' late.
Hey. Look, if I wasn't paying you
in cash, I could be paying you more.
You wouldn't have to
be workin' two jobs.
I gotta do what I gotta do.
Always forward.
Forward. Always.
[sighs]
[indistinct chatter]
[vendor] Hey, yo, my man, my man.
All HD. Got it right here. Blu-ray,
too, 'cause I'm nice like that.
Tony Stark, the big blonde
dude with the hammer,
the old dude with the shield,
the green monster, and I
don't mean Fenway.
You can't get better raw
footage of the incident
anywhere else than right here.
- Hey, Luke.
- [Luke chuckles]
Every time.
It's the bleach. I can smell
it from around the corner.
Pop has got you washing
towels again, huh?
Yeah, I took a New
Yorker off the top for you.
Can't tell you what's
on the cover, though.
Hey, I hope you got Connie's rent money.
She's on the warpath.
- [chuckles]
- Thanks, Ollie.
[Ollie] Mmm-hmm.
Ten days late, Mr.
Cage. I need my rent money.
[sighs]
Here.
I count $300. Not enough.
Let me go to work and get the rest.
Tonight.
[audience applauding and cheering]
[R&B music playing]
[woman singing]
- [music continues playing]
- [indistinct chatter]
I need a favor. Short one
bartender. Dante's sick.
You got the cash you promised me?
- End of the week.
- Come on, Nate.
You can keep all your
tips out there, okay?
When was the last time you made drinks?
I know the drill.
Okay, okay. Clean up.
Put a shirt and jacket
on. Mr. Stokes has standards.
Though you can't tell by what he pays.
Excuse me?
Raphael Saadiq.
- He's as good live as you said he was.
- Even better.
So you're not impressed by all this?
I've always been proud of you.
[Stokes] This place was a roach
trap by the time Mama Mabel died.
Now look at it.
Harlem's Paradise. May as
well be the new Cotton Club.
Then I shouldn't be up in here tonight.
Well...
Madam Councilwoman...
Colon's Gym is ready to make a
sizable donation to my pocket...
and your real estate project.
Sometimes you need a face-to-face.
"Colon's Gym"?
Is that what that two-bit drug
dealer is puttin' on his tax returns?
[laughs]
Why do you even waste time with him?
Politics is where the power is, Cornell.
Forget about all this other noise.
My noise keeps you flush.
All that "keep Harlem black" rack-a-bully-ack
might get you re-elected.
- Damn skippy.
- But when the smoke clears...
it's niggas like me that let
you hold on to what you got.
You know I despise that word.
I know.
It's easy to underestimate a nigga.
They never see you coming.
- What's that?
- It's a cosmo.
[chuckles] Your jacket's a little small.
So is your dress.
Touché.
- Cornell, my man.
- Champagne.
- [Stokes] All right.
- Councilwoman.
- What are you two celebrating?
- Success.
Partnership that should have
happened a long time ago, had...
my uncle and your brother had their way.
Uncle Pete was good people.
Salvador really liked Pete.
Anytime.
- [Luke] Lookin' for somethin'?
- No.
Saadiq's still got it. [chuckles]
Stone Rollin' was a dope album.
[chuckling] "Album"? Now
I know you're an old head.
You ain't no spring
chicken neither, sucker.
Touché.
[chuckling]
[man] All right. So let
me get this straight.
I give your cousin a contribution
and it's like a get out of
jail free card for me, right?
That's something to celebrate.
No, I don't do that.
[chuckles]
[inhales] See, me...
I celebrate when things are
finished. Not when it's just starting.
[woman] Listen to him.
This is nothing to celebrate.
You saw what happened to Fisk.
You two shouldn't even
be seen together...
let alone having me all
up in the Kool-Aid.
But you're here anyway. Something
must be right about it.
Otherwise, you wouldn't have
fronted me if you didn't agree.
I have no illusions about
our family's legacy.
But you are now turning legitimate
money illegal all over again.
[chuckles] What's illegal about it?
Our product is protected
by the Constitution.
But you came to me because
you trust me, Domingo.
[R&B music playing]
In your business, people need my
product like a fish needs water.
- He can buy his water anywhere.
- Nah.
What I sell is pure.
This the kind of shit that
could blow a hole in a battleship.
But it's light enough
to hold in your hand.
Trust me, Domingo.
You can brighten someone's
day permanently with this shit.
Top of the line.
The crème de la crème.
This that grade A, military,
Justin Hammer-level shit.
A hundred large per
case. Ten cases, a cool mil.
Wholesale. Brand spanking new.
No serial numbers... because
my connect is nice like that.
[Domingo] Who's your connect?
[Stokes] He's real and
his inventory runs deep.
- So that's it.
- That's it.
- Easy-peasy.
- Nothing's ever that easy.
So what happens after
they call to confirm?
Everyone walks away happy.
UPS ain't the only brown that delivers.
My man.
[gunfire]
[audience applauding and cheering]
[Shameek] Yeah, kid. That's
what I'm talkin' about.
Yeah.
Yo, you see this? Damn!
[man] Yo! You wasn't
supposed to kill nobody, man!
I had to make a move,
Dante. Shit went left. My bad.
[gasping] Oh, my God. Oh, fuck. God.
Shut up, Chico, before I
gag you with your panties.
[coughing and vomiting]
[Shameek] Yo, y'all see this money, B?
Yo, this shit is like
some Hollywood shit for real.
[Dante] Shameek, what am I gonna
do? They're gonna know it was me.
B, there's, like, a
million dollars right here.
Cottonmouth always lookin'
down at me at the bar.
He's gonna know I'm gone. They
gonna know it was a inside job.
- You right.
- [gunshot]
What'd you do?
- [breathing heavily]
- Yo, shit works.
Yo, this shit works, Chico.
Dante would have snitched.
You see... you see how shook he was?
Come on, man. I ain't...
Ain't no way I'm splitting that
shit three ways no how, man.
Dante was crew, B. That's Dante!
Yo, I made a
decision. I'm gonna be rich.
- [Chico breathing heavily]
- Let's go.
[Shameek] Let's go! Come on!
[R&B music playing]
So you're a bench-warmer?
Or did you miss the cut?
Excuse me?
I just figured you were... one of his.
One of Cottonmouth's?
[chuckles] I hear he hates that name.
- Mr. Stokes'...
- Cottonmouth's...
Models.
What makes you assume that?
You're beautiful. But...
But what?
You're a little older than
he usually likes them.
[chuckles]
Yeah, you're definitely not
getting a tip tonight.
But I'm not finished.
Mmm.
Dumb men like little girls.
Me?
I ponder a woman.
Why don't you...
ponder me another cosmo?
[both chuckle]
[Candace] Luke.
Hey, Candace.
You got promoted?
Dante's out sick.
You okay?
Table seven wants six
bottles of Ace of Spades.
I need you to help me carry them up.
I don't like being up there by myself.
I'm right behind you. Give me a second.
Why don't you... ponder
that 'til I get back.
You're a big one, eh?
He's wearing a little jacket.
[Stokes laughs]
Haven't seen you behind the bar.
Where's Dante?
Called in sick, I guess.
You want a job?
I can find something more
suitable for a man your size.
Better paying, too.
You ever carried a gun?
No.
I'm good. Thanks.
[Dante groaning]
[cell phone ringing]
Yeah?
Shit. Fuck.
[speaking indistinctly]
[typing]
You got to walk over
to Adam Clayton Powell
if you wanna catch the bus.
Uber?
- That's what you were gonna press, right?
- What are you?
- A cop?
- [chuckles] No.
You just look cold.
If you're looking for
Mr. Stokes, he just left.
Who?
Black Escalade.
Tinted windows.
Don't you have... somewhere
you need to be?
Yeah.
Home.
Just got off.
Congratulations.
You wanna go grab a coffee?
I don't like coffee.
Neither do I.
[keys clatter]
[Luke exhales]
[moans]
[both breathing heavily]
[Luke grunts]
[Luke exhales]
[men grunting]
[cell phone ringing]
- [gasps]
- [woman] When?
I'm on my way in.
[sighs]
You talk in your sleep.
What was I saying?
Shades? Comanche?
[Luke sighs]
The job is calling me in.
Can I call you later?
[sighs] You'd need my
phone number for that.
I know where you work.
I'll find you.
What is it you do again?
[zipping]
I'm an auditor.
What's that?
Basically, I look at
the financial books.
Make sure everything's on the up and up.
And you need a short dress for that?
Sometimes you got to blend in.
Impossible.
You stand out in any room you're in.
[machinery whirring]
[camera shutters clicking]
Dominicans? Cubans?
Puerto Ricans.
[Scarfe] Thought that
parade was last week.
- Who can keep track?
- [both chuckling]
Who do you think this
guy was trying to call?
- Ghostbusters.
- [chuckles]
He can laugh. You can't.
Hey, Bailey. How you doing?
It's another beautiful day at
the office. What's not to love?
Don't you start
singing show tunes on me.
Oh, shit.
Dante Chapman.
You know him?
I know his mama.
[Stokes] Of course it
wasn't a inside job.
We had people die, too.
Look... I don't have the stuff.
Hmm. We need to talk
about this in person.
My word is still my bond.
Hello?
That's Domingo?
Yo, what's up?
[sighs]
It's above your pay grade.
What?
[man] Tell your man what's
going on, Cornell.
Nice digs.
Even nicer than when Mama Mabel ran it.
Shades.
When'd you come home?
[takes deep breath] Ooh, a while ago.
Seagate wasn't shit.
Hmm.
[clears throat]
So... what can I do for you?
It's the other way around.
Y'all got hit last night.
That expensive, exclusive,
hard-to-get hardware that
Diamondback gave you
is in a police evidence lockup.
And the money... that Domingo and
his crew were supposed to give you...
is gone.
I'm with Diamondback now.
You knew that, right?
Well, tell
Diamondback, it's about time...
Uh-uh... Diamondback tells you.
[laughs]
I'm his number one seller.
I ain't here to spank you.
But I do need to look
you in your eyes...
Was it an inside job?
No.
Hell no.
I needed that money, too.
[sighs]
It took forever to build
up that kind of trust.
We're here to get you back on your feet.
Whatever you need.
Who is "we," you fake-ass Ray Charles?
[chuckles]
I got your back, B.
Just like back in the day.
Forget about back in the day.
Why is this feeling like a takeover?
[chuckling softly] It's not.
If it was...
you would never even
see Diamondback comin'.
He wants you to win.
How can I help?
[indistinct chatter]
[Pop] Dante was one of
my kids. So was Chico.
And Shameek, too.
Just like those kids playing over there.
[scoffs] You know, that's
how you get 'em on your side.
Sweepin' up hair. Runnin'
errands. [chuckling]
Lettin' 'em hang out, play video games.
Anything is better than what's waiting
for them out there on the street.
They want a way out...
but they have too much
pride to ask for help.
So you gotta Jedi mind-trick
them into something. [chuckles]
Everyone has a gun.
[sighs] No one has a father.
Ain't that the truth.
You sure they did it?
People started callin' me half
an hour after it happened.
Shameek has always been the spark plug.
And Chico... a follower.
I just can't believe that
either one of them...
would just turn around...
and kill... Dante.
You didn't see anything going
on with either one of 'em, did you?
No.
You live and die by your choices.
This is Harlem's garden. That's
what's happening here.
You are the ones that are
gonna keep this community...
[chuckles and gasps]
Where have... Oh, God.
This is Marisol. Baby...
Oh, my God, known her
since she was first born.
And here you are
upturnin' Harlem around.
I'm so proud of you.
Ah! I saw you running
for the bus this mornin'.
All right, darling.
I'm happy you made it, darling.
Uh-uh, uh-uh, cut him off at three.
I know this young brother.
He'll eat five hamburgers.
I've seen you do it.
Now, Harlem is a community that
welcomes everyone. All people.
But at the same time,
since the days of Langston Hughes,
Malcolm X, Zora Neale
Hurston, Duke Ellington,
Harlem has been the
jewel of black America.
It's a perpetual symbol of... of
hope and prosperity and excellence.
For black lives to matter,
black history and black
ownership must also matter.
Now, my multifaceted plan for
the Crispus Attucks Complex
is just yet another way to
bring hope to a new generation,
to incubate the kind of
innovation and creativity
and progress that Harlem's famous for.
Thank you again for your
time, Madam Councilwoman.
Oh, Megan, you're
always welcome in Harlem.
- All right.
- All right, darling.
Y'all need to fall the hell back.
Zip, give her some space.
I don't like the thugs.
- You need them for security.
- Mmm, they scare people.
They pass out flyers, get
contributions, tributes.
[in Jamaican accent] Just
like in Jamaica, you know?
- Yeah, well, we ain't Jamaican, Cornell.
- [chuckling]
You shouldn't be here. We don't
need to be photographed together.
Why?
You ashamed of me?
That hurts, Mariah.
- Tony.
- Hmm?
Will you give us a moment?
I need the money you promised me ASAP.
Now you want the money?
I used federal grant and
tax-deductible donation money
to complete construction on your club
and to facilitate that meticulous
deal that just fell apart.
I don't get the money,
I'm facing an audit.
We all go to jail.
It'll be there.
What happened at the
junkyard last night?
And who's the dude in
the sunglasses behind you?
Is he after the money, too?
Either you want the
details, cuz, or you don't.
That's what I thought.
What's the word?
Confirmation of what Dante
told us while he was dying.
His friends, the one that
play on your summer league team
at the Rucker, jacked your shit.
Shameek and Chico.
Any bites yet?
No.
Double down.
Twenty large to find those fools.
[hip-hop music playing]
Tone, Passion is
twerking for him right now.
He ain't going nowhere soon. Not
with all that ass in his face.
You want me to keep him
here, you need to pay me.
Hey, yo, my man. You
know what time it is?
8:15.
[men laughing]
Stay Harlem.
Stay black.
[playing jazz music]
[cutlery clattering]
- Hey, man.
- Watch your hands.
You need to pay me.
I'm paying you under the table,
which means I'll pay you whenever
I goddamn feel like it.
What you worried about?
[Shameek] I'm not worried.
I just never met Cottonmouth
before, that's all.
[Tone] Mr. Stokes.
Mr. Stokes. That's
important. Never Cottonmouth.
All right, okay, my bad.
After what happened with
Dante, we circling the wagons.
They after us, B.
Who?
Nigga, it don't matter who.
Mr. Stokes wanted me to
check on you... personally.
[Tone] Yo, what you doin'? Come on.
Shades.
You like my Biggie photo?
Me, too.
You know what draws your
eye when you look at that?
The crown.
Wanna know why?
Huh?
'Cause everybody wants to be the king.
- [grunts and sighs heavily]
- [Shameek groans]
[chuckles]
I slapped you like a little bitch.
[breathes deeply]
I'm not the kind of man to
use a closed fist on a woman.
Where's my money?
[Shameek] I... I didn't...
Uh-uh.
Only thing worse than
a thief is a damn liar.
[grunting] Where's... my...
- money?
- [Shameek groans]
[Stokes breathing heavily] Hmm?
[coughs]
You left Dante alive. He called Tone.
And with his dying words, gave
up you and your homeboy.
We got your money.
[breathing heavily]
Now you're gonna tell us where
Chico is so we can get the rest.
[spits]
[laughing]
Yeah. Thank you.
Now I can hit you like a man.
[mumbles] No...
[grunting]
[groans]
[grunting and breathing heavily]
[rapid punches landing]
[punching continues]
[bones crunching]
[breathing heavily]
[panting]
Get his ass out of here.
[breathing heavily]
And go fetch my money.
He didn't recognize you.
[breathing heavily]
[chain rattling faintly]
[cell door buzzing faintly]
Loneliness never goes away,
especially in places like Seagate.
If you don't make
attempts to befriend someone...
loneliness is guaranteed
to... eat you alive.
- [cell door buzzing faintly]
- [men shouting indistinctly]
[sighs]
[exhales]
I'm clear. [sighs]
I'm focused.
I promise, baby...
I'm ready.
[siren wails]
- [female detective sighing]
- Shameek Smith...
based on what they found in his pockets.
We'll need dental to confirm ID.
[chuckles] His face is jacked.
Mmm. They definitely dumped him
here. They got him somewhere else.
Mmm. Looks like he got hit by a truck.
Yeah.
- A truck with two fists.
- [Scarfe chuckles]
You know, Benjamin Franklin said,
"The only way that three people can
keep a secret is if two of 'em are dead."
First Dante, now Shameek. Chico's
the last man standing.
Benjamin Franklin...
Didn't he electrocute
himself flying a kite in a rainstorm?
I wouldn't base any
theories on that fool.
Benjamin Franklin is on
the $100 bill, Scarfe.
[scoffs] So? He wasn't a president.
That's even more impressive. Come
on, give the man some credit.
Well... So you think
Chico did this to Shameek?
Chico is what? A buck 50 soaking wet?
But we won't know for
sure until we find him.
You said Dante wasn't bartendin'
the night you were at the club.
No.
Well, did you talk to the
guy that replaced him that night?
[scoffs] I barely talked to the guy.
I mean... [inhales] all
I did was order drinks.
Well, maybe there's some
pattern, somethin' we're missin'.
We need to go talk to that guy.
That sounds like a
complete waste of time.
That's entirely possible.
But it's worth a shot.
[scoffs] All right.
You've been in this
country for how long?
And you still... can't speak English?
My English is just fine.
Show Mariah Dillard some love.
Contribute and we'll go away.
It's a family thing.
I own this restaurant.
My father owned this building.
Tell Mariah Dillard I am
not contributing to her complex.
We voted for her and
gave her money before.
And I respect Mr. Stokes.
But no. No more.
- I can't.
- [bat strikes]
Give us... the money.
Yo... I don't like your tone.
Excuse me?
You're being
disrespectful. It's unnecessary.
[men laughing]
[Koko] You need to step off, Mayweather.
I mean, what you think
you gonna do, man?
[Zip laughing]
I think he think he gonna bring it.
- [chuckles]
- [Luke] I can.
Not the way I want to. I'd kill you.
[mockingly] Ooh.
[chuckles]
I like this cat.
[clicks tongue] Yo, Amos.
What up?
Show the man what you famous for.
[laughing]
[bones crunching]
[screaming]
[Zip grunting]
- [gunshot]
- [Luke grunts]
[bullet clattering]
You want some?
I don't even like these niggas, man.
I'm sorry about your window.
[cash register opening]
Here.
- For what?
- For you.
Ma'am, I'm the one who owes you money.
You made things worse.
They'll come back again.
We want to hire you.
I'm not for hire.
But you have my word, ma'am.
I've got you.
[funk music playing]
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --