Fixed & Synced By MoUsTaFa ZaKi
SHAYLA: Did you have something
to do with Vera getting busted?
Who told you to put your business
anywhere near social media?
My aspirational
little brother.
Someone's gonna
get hurt for this.
ELLIOT: What
happened to Angela?
She's not gonna
work out for us.
Not on this level.
You didn't have to stick
up for me in there.
Don't do it again!
Evil Corp tapped you
for CTO, yes?
You're ruining your life.
I also ruined yours.
Terry Colby was involved
in the cover-up
of the Washington Township
toxic waste scandal.
Sharon, how do you not blow
your brains out married to him?
I'm in here.
Do you mind sleeping
here tonight?
That girl in there is mine.
If you're around tonight come
over and tell me about it.
(DOG YAP-PING)
(CELL PHONE RINGs)
Shayla?
VERA: (OVER PHONE) Sometimes
the universe aligns perfectly.
Here I am locked away, and still
it brings you right to me.
ELLIOT: I feel the
sensation, fight-or-flight.
It's constant.
I should just pick one.
I, ElliotAIderson,
am flight. I am fear.
I am anxiety, terror, panic.
(SONG ON RADIO) Some velvet mornin'
when I'm straight
I'm gonna open up your gate...
(CONTINUES PLAYING OVER RADIO)
Doesn't feel real.
You should eat.
Not hungry.
I don't even know
what I ordered.
I'm sorry.
You don't like
the guisada?
Uh, no, it's.._
It's good. Thank you.
What are you thinking about?
The first time we met.
Doesn't feel
that long ago.
And now look at us.
Who woulda thought?
If I could go back
and undo this...
You can't.
You promised me.
I'm gonna get you
out of this, okay?
Time's up.
Let's go.
Wait.
(MUFFLED WHIMPERING)
Sit down.
Come with me.
Let's go.
Hello? VERA: (OVER PHONE)
The origin of your name,
I looked it up for you, bro.
Where are you taking her?
VE RAI Elliot...
"Brave and true."
Did you know the origin of
"brave" evolved from "savage"?
I don't know what you
think this is about.
But you need to let her go.
Yeah, well, funny thing. My
name means something similar.
"Brave traveler, adventurer."
A savage traveler
becomes a brave traveler.
Are we savages,
or are we brave?
Don't know, bro.
Listen to me, man.
When I found out you did
this, I didn't get angry.
I got impressed.
Your power.
I want it, Elliot.
And I want it so bad
it makes my dick hard.
And I want it today.
Yo, I don't know what
you think I can do,
I can't just hack
you out of prison.
Not all prisons are networked
and even if yours is,
it would take weeks
to find security holes.
Has to be tonight. I got
crosshairs on my heart.
I don't make it out, I'm dead.
And that ain't meant
to be just yet.
You do your thing, bro.
You're asking
the impossible.
When we cross paths tonight,
Elliot, l'ma hug you.
Please listen, man.
Yo, Shayla.
This is on me,
okay? You gotta let her go.
Oh, that? She cool, bro.
Trust me, she cool.
She'll be there tonight, too.
it'll be one big happy-happy!
(LAUGHING)
Hey, Elliot
I love you, bro.
(DIAL TONE)
(TIREs SQUEAUNG)
Where's Shayla?
IVlan, I'm not gonna tell you again.
Stop askin' so
many questions.
Come on.
ELLIOT: Vera may be
out of his mind.
But, yes, it is possible to
hack into a prison's network.
Most of them use regular
industrial control systems.
(SCOFFS) I'm a blind man to
what Vera sees in this dude.
Amen. Techie computer hacker
genius, my thick Dominican dick.
(CHUCKLES)
ELLIOT: When you
have control of that,
you basically have control
of the cell doors.
(DOG YAP-PING)
But what these morons
don't know is,
it's almost impossible
without any research.
Time to shine your
cojones and get to work.
Our only rule,
"Do what we say."
You violate that dictate,
we kill your sweetheart.
Yo, yo, Isaac, uh,
how my dic-tate? Mmm?
(LAUGHS)
Shut up, bitch.
"Dic-tate."
ELLIOT: Vera's bro, Isaac.
Something about him bugs me.
And you know what I like
to do when that happens?
Hi, I'm trying to
reach Mister Beckett.
When would Mister
Lattimer be available?
I can come in today.
I already told you what
it's in reference to.
I'm trying again
for IVlrs. Nayar.
Regarding the Washington
Township scandal.
I may have found
some information.
Please don't put
me on hold again!
Happy Monday, Angela.
How fun.
Thanks.
IVlmm-hmm.
(CELLPHONE VIBRATES)
I'm Emily Moss' daughter...
Angela Moss. I called...
Six times.
Yes. I'm here to discuss the
Washington Township case.
I'm listening.
You represented the
victims' families.
Twenty-six families.
IVline included.
I thought, with the latest
news in the data dumps,
the Terry Colby scandal,
his covering up the
chemical waste spill...
Alleged.
Well, and documents.
Superficial.
But if we bring this
stronger, more concrete case.
You'll see that I have the
evidence from the data dumps,
along with
further research...
Stickies. Oh, you've
highlighted and underlined.
This is serious.
So, you wanna take Internet
gossip to federal court
and throw it at the
strongest conglomerate
in the history
of civilization?
Guy in the suit.
Twice convicted
of sexual assault,
charged again
this past weekend.
Raped his pregnant girlfriend,
bashed her head in with an Xbox.
Claims she cheated
during Halo.
Yet I have a better
chance of defending him.
You called back.
I called every lawyer
from this case.
And you're the only one
that called me back.
(LAUGHTER)
Shit, Shit, Shit...
ELLIOT: "Connection
closed by remote host"?
But we had a fish.
I was in.
The exploit started
to run and then...
Was it the code?
Bro, what's the deal?
(DOG WHINES AND BARKS)
I gotta take her for a walk.
Why?
'Cause she'll piss on
the floor if I don't.
You think I give a shit
about your goddamn floor?
(LAUGHING)
I'm just playin', brother.
Yeah, you can take her.
You hear what I said?
I said you can take her.
Come on.
It's out.
Okay, gotcha_
UNHALES)
Did she like
my little toy?
Did you write that
exploit yourself?
I had an hour.
So, what, you just pulled code
from Rapid9 or some shit?
Since when did you
become a script kiddie?
I repeat,
I had an hour.
Malware detection must've caught it.
You fucked me.
Hey, don't put this on me.
Okay, this is a shit show and you
gave me no time to do it right.
I can run circles around an ICS given
the proper Whitepapers and time.
Where the hell are you going?
I have no problem telling
these two douche tools
they're gonna have to sit on their pricks
till we can find a better solution.
You don't understand.
These guys are...
Assholes? Yeah, I'm gonna
tell them what's up.
That's what's up, girl.
Hmm? Now, let's go.
So, none of those guys called
you back? Not even Lattimer?
Pussies. I bet they didn't even
bother to read the data dumps.
But you read them.
You know it took me eight
years to rebuild my career
after our case was dismissed?
So,
as much as I think this
company is evil incarnate,
and trust me, they are...
You know, it's not worth it.
What would it take?
Hypothetically,
what do we need
to prove our case?
Hypothetically, a
reliable eye witness.
You know, if you miraculously find
someone on the inside to flip,
someone who was there
when the decision was made
to falsify chemical
waste intel...
(SCOFFING) So, unless
you're Facebook friends
with one of those assholes...
This hypothetical
is just that.
Let's move on.
Where're you
working these days?
You have a boyfriend?
How's your dad?
I work for a company
that doesn't respect me,
my boyfriend recently
cheated on me,
and my father is
drowning in debt.
I'll see you next time.
Okay.
(slGHs)
Fluorescent lights
are hell, no?
Was there a change
in schedule?
I thought I had Spencer next.
These interviews, they're
just a waste of your time.
I mean, you know our regulatory
and IP issues inside out.
I was thinking we play nooky the
rest of the day, hit the back nine.
Is that a Vacheron?
Patek Philippe Tourbillon.
A gift from the
Prince of, uh...
Oh, does it even matter?
(LAUGHING) NO.
But I'm not blowing off
my remaining interviews.
Look,
I know you think you
were a shoo-in for CTO,
and you're pissed...
Probably wishing I'd fall
into the subway tracks.
So, how 'bout you
cut the bullshit.
I'm afraid your paranoia
has gotten the best of you,
but, nevertheless,
please excuse me.
I'll leave you to review your
notes before Spencer arrives.
On, and thank you for dinner.
The entire evening
was enchanting,
the food, the wine...
Your lovely Sharon.
Please tell her
I say hello.
Did you enjoy the view?
What?
Did you think she
wouldn't tell me?
I'm not sure what
you're trying...
You wanna watch me piss, too?
I've had several
glasses of water.
Scott, a misunderstanding.
Happy to pull my dick out for
you, if that's your thing,
watching the Knowles
family urinate.
Hell,
I could fly my brother
in from IVliami.
He has a bladder
of a small child.
You'd probably bust a nut
watching him take a leak.
I'm not sure what she told
you, but if I were you,
I would tell her to find
more appropriate ways
of managing her imagination.
Tyrell,
I want you to accept a hard truth,
right here, right now, in front of me.
You are not going to be CTO.
I want to see that look
wash over your face.
It's the only way I know
you'll stop playing these
silly, silly games.
Oh, I'm fully aware
you're CTO, Scott.
I'm not sure what
more I can offer you.
Wait.
HSFS.
I feel bad. After all, you
got a child on the way,
you need all the
help you can get.
In fact,
this would probably pay off
the rest of your mortgage.
Aren't you still in that neat
little two-bedroom in Chelsea?
There.
That's the look
I was looking for.
(DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS)
ELLIOT: I keep brute-force
thinking, but it's not working.
I need help.
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
ANGELA: Elliot, you in there?
ELLIOT: Shit. Why is she here?
ANGELA: Elliot!
Lemme in!
Elliot, you in there?
Little blonde bitty_
ANGELA: Elliot,
hit the buzzer!
I know you're in there!
Go. Shut her up and get
her the hell outta here.
ANGELA: Elliot. Buzzer. Now.
What about Darlene?
She stays with us. And
we'll be watching you,
so don't bother trying any
dumb shit, you dumb shit.
(DOORBELL l3uzzlNG)
TYRELLZ Fuck!
Do you understand
why you're angry?
Because you know I'm right.
(SPEAKING SWEDISH)
Hey.
I tried looking for you after
Gideon's the other night,
where were you?
I had to think about
things, you know?
We always knew
what Evil Corp did.
We didn't have the proof,
but we knew.
We were right
about it all along.
In fact, that news report,
it wasn't a confirmation,
it was a reminder...
Of how angry I am.
You remember Nayar?
The lawyer on the case.
I went to her, Elliot.
Listen, Angela, now's not a...
I have an idea that
will change the world.
I know it sounds
really stupid.
But,
I know how to do it.
I think it could
actually work.
I can't tell you
what it is, because...
ELLIOT: Evil Corp, Angela,
Vera, his brother,
Darlene, Shayla,
this is too much.
But I feel passionate about it, Elliot.
I should just tell her
what she wants to hear.
Angela,
trust yourself.
You'll do what's right.
(slGHs)
That's all I needed.
How's Shayla,
by the way?
She's, uh...
You know...
Tell her I Say, "Hi."
You have no time to pull off whatever
it is you think you're doing.
What are you doing here?
How did you know?
Dadene.
These guys aren't playing around,
they will fucking kill you.
Now, wise up and let's go.
Darlene's in there.
We can't leave.
(GASPS)
Okay. Then we
call the cops.
I mean there's no
other choice here.
It's the only way
out of this.
I can't call the cops.
Shayla will die.
Oh, come on, she knew exactly what
she was getting herself into.
You think his employees have
a long life expectancy?
She was dead the minute she
started working with that maniac.
Forget it, it's not happening.
This is a zero-sum game.
Calculate all the outcomes.
If you don't pull off
this ridiculous miracle,
and odds are you won't,
you die and so does Shayla
That much we know.
But assume for a second
that you do pull this off,
bust Vera out of prison.
Who's to say he doesn't
kill you, Shayla, Darlene?
It would be in his own
best interest to do that.
Either way, you
all end up dead.
It's the only way Vera wins.
Zero-sum, Elliot.
You're playing a game
you already lost.
You know I'm right.
No, there's gotta be a way.
I can think of a way.
I get it, kiddo. You want to
help people, watch over 'em_
Best thing you can do for Shayla,
allow her to become a memory.
No.
True courage is about being
honest with yourself,
especially when
it's difficult.
There's no plan where both
you and Shayla survive.
I can think of a way.
This new world that we are so
close to creating will never be.
And that new world, that is
success, f society is success.
Look at what you accomplished
at Steel Mountain.
That got us nowhere.
You took them down.
You won that battle.
This... This is failure.
This is the old Elliot.
The one who turns to morphine,
to drugs when he feels weak.
A coward, who can't
face the truth,
even though it's staring
him right in the face.
ELLIOT: There's
that sensation again.
Fight-or-flight.
Three lives at stake,
including my own.
I, ElliotAIderson, am...
What?
Tom Petty, Pink
Floyd, Van Halen...
What's up, man? You ain't
got no Drake, no Pitbull,
no nothing?
Like, what's up?
What the...
What's up, Rain Man?
I'm ready to bust Vera out.
I can get into the network.
We need to go
to the jail, now.
She stays here.
No, I'm not leaving you.
Don't worry, he's in no position
to be giving out orders.
Let's go, girl.
ELLIOT: Remember when the panic
would set in and we had a solution?
To be honest, I miss that.
Life is so much easier
when you're numb.
What's the plan,
bitch boy?
First Shayla,
now Darlene.
Yo, what the f...
Elliot, what are you doing?
ELLIOT: Like a hard drive blasted by
excessive voltage, my mind is frayed,
close to fried.
I can feel the static
running through my brain.
Serotonin receptors
working overtime.
(DOOR BUZZING)
I need more time.
Tonight, tonight, tonight.
More time, right now.
I'm working on our
project as we speak,
so it's in your best interest
to keep talking with me.
At the security desk,
my cell phone's running
an undetectable,
activated signal sniffer
that will locate any kind of
wireless signal in sight.
By the time I
leave this building,
I 'll own its network.
Good on you. Brave.
But stupid.
You showed your face,
and then I skip
out tonight...
Who do you think
they're gonna finger?
I'm opening every cell.
That way, they can't
trace it back to you or me.
(LAUGHING) Yeah, bro,
that's what I'm talking about!
Woo!
I told you, didn't I?
The universe got big
plans for us, bro.
Sit back down.
When you get out, I realize
you're gonna have to split.
You won't be able to
stay in the tri-state area.
Oh, I love this. Go on.
Wherever you go, you're gonna
need funding to keep surviving.
Which means, your whole operation
still needs to be making you money.
Come on, Elliot,
give it to me!
I hacked Isaac's phone.
He had everything, your crew,
shipments, the entire operation.
I took it all. I own
your whole world.
I need your word,
when this goes down,
Shayla and I go free.
You leave us alone. Forever.
If anyone tries to hurt us, if I even
see one of your guys following me,
I leak everything.
You're saying this knowin'___
You can kill me anytime? Yes.
Yes. That's why I coded the leak
to auto-send every 24 hours
unless I continuously
disable it.
No one else has access.
If anything happens
to me, or Shayla,
your money gets deleted.
GUARD: Time's up,
Vera. Let's go.
Remember,
l'ma hug you.
(DOOR BuzzlNG)
(DOORBELL RINGs)
So what's your deal?
I'm here to see Terry Colby.
TERRY: Who is that?
Another damn reporter?
No comment.
Do you understand?
Do I know you?
Get the hell away from my
home, get away from my home!
ELLIOTZ WPA2 WiFi. Shit.
Borderline unhackable.
Getting that handshake could take days.
The noose is tightening.
(RADIO SQuAvvl<lNG)
The mobile feed
on the cameras.
I don't need to hack WPA2
when there's dedicated 4G_
We're good,
I can pull this off.
Get in.
Let's go, girl.
Nah, just him.
Yo, Isaac. What you doin'?
Nah, bro. It's, it's fine.
I just wanna have a
private chat with him.
Come on, it's cool.
We don't have any time, man.
I gotta get to work.
Get the fuck in the car!
Hey, man. Where you goin'?
Don't be stupid.
All good, all good. We're
just gonna have a talk.
Elliot, are you...
Why are you doing this?
I can free your brother.
I figured it out.
It just wasn't
your day, bruh_
I hacked your whole operation.
If you kill me, you...
You don't get it. Like I said,
it just wasn't your day.
Stop.
ELLIOT: I suppose a bullet through the
brain is peaceful in its own right.
You don't want
me to free Vera.
That's why you don't care
about the operation.
I'd pick better
last words.
You're trying to kill him.
That's why Vera wants
to leave tonight.
That's what's been
bugging me about you.
You never wanted me
to break him out.
Your best option for survival
is to kill him in prison,
because if you don't,
you're dead.
You're the reason Vera's
locked up right now,
and he knows it.
Doesn't matter anyway.
Vera was just gloating about how
he got in with the right crew,
how he got the
jump on some men.
Uh, he's not worried, man,
he's protected now.
Bullshit.
That leaves you with
a zero-sum game.
If you don't get him out of jail,
he'll have you killed for failing.
Only way this works in your favor
is for you to kill him first.
And you can't do that
with him inside anymore.
Shut up, motherfucker.
Shut the fuck up!
Let me free him.
When I break Vera
out tonight,
you do with your
brother what you want.
That's the only outcome
where you got the
possibility of living.
It's your best move.
What makes you think I still
won't kill you afterwards?
I don't.
I'm just playin' my best move.
(slGHs)
ELLIOT: I need
30 to 40 seconds
with the patrol car's
Bluetooth connection
to run the exploit on the PLC.
ISAAC: And then?
ELLIOT: The plan
executes at 9:49.
All the cell doors
should open.
Hey. I wanted to ask
you about something.
OFFICER: Oh, yeah, what's that?
You.
(KEYBOARD CLAC KING)
DARLENE: Why don't you just admit you think about...
(RADIO SQUAWKING)
DARLENE: Yeah, gimme a
call, we'll grab a drink.
DARLENEZ Talk. Whatever.
OFFICER: All right.
Do you know a
good spot nearby?
ELLIOT: The exploit's
on his laptop.
Now I need to force feed it
into the jail's network.
DARLENE: Well,
I like what I hear.
I paused the exploit. Drive.
Darlene's no longer
part of the plan.
INTERCOM: We got an
alarm going on right now.
What in the hell?
Tell you what, we go
out, we drink, we dance,
see where the night takes us.
You sure you wanna make
that choice right now?
I only need to press one
key to run the exploit,
or I can press another and
disable the entire plan.
I made my move.
You make yours.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Shit. Please move back, miss.
I gotta get back ASAP.
Whatever.
Look, I...
I gotta come back down now.
My computer's on the fritz_
Let's go to the meet, DJ.
ELLIOT: lfl mis-typed one
command, hit one wrong key,
the cell doors won't open.
And we both know
what that means.
Did I make a mistake?
No.
I don't make mistakes.
One minute till Vera.
For all his insane,
inhumane ideas,
he does understand the world,
the wild savagery
of the world.
What you need your
piece for, bro?
Boy Wonder says he's
opening all the cells.
If some fool
tries to rush us,
I wanna be ready.
(ALARM BLARING)
(PovvEl=zlNG SURGING)
DJ: Hey-o, what the shit?
Power surge. Caused by all cell
doors opening at the same time.
What, what about
security, sirens?
The jail's network will show
all cells locked and closed.
Alarms are silent
for two minutes.
(l=>ovvERING UP)
(GLASS sHATTERING)
(MEN sHouTING)
(DOG l3ARKING)
(CHEERING)
(WHOOPING)
MAN: Run, run, run!
(ALL cLAlvloRING)
Yes! Yes.
This shit right here!
This shit tastes better
than any pussy I ever had!
Whoo! (LAUGHING)
DJ, shoot the cocksucker.
My own brother.
That's what the
universe asked of me.
(GASPS)
To be my brother's keeper.
Like Cain after Abel,
I'll be a fugitive and
wander on the earth.
A brave fugitive,
a brave wanderer.
Look how you helped me.
That's the kind of bravery
I been talking about.
But, but now...
Now, I want you
to look at Isaac.
<GRoANs)
Look!
Dead proof.
My operation is over.
So go on, crash it,
burn it to the ground.
Doesn't matter.
I'm gone.
A spirit.
One with all the
heavens, all existence.
Shaylal
Where is she?
Keys, yo.
Told you you'd get
her back, bro.
You just didn't realize...
She was with you
the whole time.
(ALARM BLARING)
(OFFICER SHOUTING OVER INTERCOM)
(SHUDDERS)
(sNIFFLEs)
<soBs)
(SIREN APPROACHING)