Hey, you guys, check this out!
What is that, man?
That's straight Five-O.
Let me see that.
All right, you ready?
Byzantines fighting side by side
with cowboys and Indians?
It was an
imaginative
childhood.
You know, actually,
this garage was once a garage.
So check it out.
We're deriving
a set of coupled
differential equations
using a fourth order
Runge-Kutta Method.
You're kidding. Huh.
He's trying
to see how far
he can fling
a ball of fire.
Ooh. You know, I think
I liked it better when you,
uh, lit dead bugs
with a magnifying glass.
Don did that.
Oh.
Right, yeah.
All right!
Bingo!
Good shot!
What? Come in.
Alan Eppes?
Yeah?
Have a nice day.
What was
all that about?
Oh, oh. It's a project
that I consulted on.
Which project?
Kim's Day Night
Golf Center.
Yeah, that's the
driving range
in Koreatown, right?
Yeah. The neighbors
in the surrounding apartments
have been complaining
that the, uh,
floodlights are on 24/7.
Apparently, it's daytime
all night long.
I'm being sued.
What do you see, David?
Badge traces back
to an LAPD officer
went missing
in 1990.
Hmm. Missing how?
Uh, we don't know.
Found the badge
right there.
Officer's name
was John Everett.
23 years old.
Bureau initially
handled the case
as an unexplained disappearance.
Yeah, well,
this should give it
a new perspective, huh?
Reports indicate he went missing
wearing his uniform.
It's looking like
a cop killing with
the guy out there
still walking around.
That's Gary Walker
coming up the hill.
LAPD's gonna work
with us on this one.
So, Lieutenant,
how you doing?
Seen me on better
Sinclair.
Is this it?
This is it.
Man who wore this
was the finest young
cop I ever knew.
You were close
with John Everett?
Yeah.
Everett was on my
street crime team.
We hit hard and often.
Couple of weeks
before he disappeared,
he killed a real hard-ass
gang banger
named Stephon Bradley.
You think him
gone missing
was an act of revenge maybe?
I don't need to think,
I know, Sinclair.
His brother vowed
revenge at the time,
and Everett's
car was found
in his
neighborhood.
What, you couldn't make a case?
Not without a body.
What happened to Bradley?
Did ten years for armed robbery.
Paroled in '02.
Got a college degree while
he was on the inside, too.
I hear he even writes
a little poetry now.
But all that's about to change.
We got this cop
that disappeared
but, uh, the thing is, it
happened 17 years ago.
What can I do?
High rise was supposed
to be built,
but a lawsuit
shut it down.
And the lot's been
vacant ever since?
Yeah.
This area right here--
that's where the kids found
Officer Everett's badge.
Okay. A construction site
would be a pretty good place
to hide a body.
Yeah. Crew could bury
over the body without
ever knowing
about it.
Mm-hmm. Of course,
on the flip side,
doesn't even mean that
there's a body there.
Oh, there's a body.
Trust me, Agent Reeves.
Of course.
I'm-I'm sorry.
I just mean,
it's a lot of ground
to cover there.
Charlie?
Um...
laser swath mapping.
Well, take me back
to school, Professor.
It's a lot like radar.
Instead of sending out
radio waves,
we're shooting laser pulses,
which will allow me
to create a
highly accurate,
3-D, uh, topographical map
of the area.
And then we look
for abnormal erosion
in the Earth's surface.
See, ground earth is compact
until it's disturbed.
It's like when
you dig a grave.
Right, when
a person's body
is buried, uh, erosion
and decomposition create
a depression in the earth.
Um, here,
let me take this, um...
this bowl of...
this bowl of popcorn,
for example, and imagine
that this is the earth
under which a body is buried.
And this water
represents
erosion, time...
And there goes my lunch.
See that depression?
That is what our lasers
are looking for.
Well, that sounds
real good
as long as we
locate my man.
See, this isn't just
an unsolved homicide
for me. I knew John.
I was responsible for hi
as I am for all of my men.
17 years ago,
John's wife had to bury
an empty coffin,
and we didn't have the evidence
to take down his killer,
Calvin Bradley.
It's time
to bring Everett home...
...get this cop killer
off the streets.
So, there's Walker's
team back in 1990,
and he was married
for three years.
Had a little boy
who is now 19 years old.
According to Walker,
he and the team stay close
to the family.
Yeah, survivor's
guilt probably.
Hey, Liz,
thanks for helping us out.
Oh, yeah, no problem.
I was getting tired
of driving around Compton
breaking down
doors anyway.
Ooh, gang detail.
Mm-hmm.
War on drugs knows no end.
Anyway, these are the files
you asked for.
Okay, and Calvin Bradley?
He ran with a black gang
known as BSF:
Bixel Street Family.
I asked around.
He's actually a bit of a legend.
Yeah? How so?
I mean, guy clearly
is no angel, but word now,
he's a changed
man, and, uh,
runs a program helping kids.
And he's been clean
since his brother's death?
You mean since Everett's.
Uh-huh.
Hard to believe
we may finally find Everett
after all these years.
To think he's been
rotting out there all this time.
While Calvin Bradley's
been walking around
a free man.
No thanks
to the FBI.
Hey, what? Excuse me?
Let's just
say the Feds didn't put
much manpower on it
at the time.
Look, I wasn't there
at the time, okay?
Hey, listen, this has been
a very tough day
for all of us, but, uh,
we're on the
same page now,
and, uh, Eppes
has just come here
to find out what happened the
day that Everett disappeared.
I mean, if there's anything
you remember, you know,
that's come back to you,
you know what I'm after.
Night before,
a ten-year-old girl
was killed in a drive-by.
Word was a BSF crew had raided
a rival gang's stash house.
What's BSF?
Bixel Street
Family.
That was Bradley's gang
at the time.
Anyway, team had
the day off.
Commanders wanted
everyone on it.
Kid gets killed,
politicians want action.
Well, you know
how it is.
So I called everybody in.
Everett had some
appointments,
didn't get the
word till late.
By the time he rolle
we were all out on the street.
That was the last
we heard of him.
What's going on?
I got your call.
Did you find him?
No, no, no,
not yet.
Not yet,
I don't understand.
Well, some kids...
some kids found his badge.
Oh, my God.
What am I gonna
tell Kevin?
You just let us talk
to him, all right?
Thanks.
Just, uh...
What's that all about?
That's Everett's wife.
She's worried
about their son Kevin.
Uh-huh.
We tried to be
like a dad to him.
You can see why
we want Calvin Bradley
brought to justice.
Charlie, have you seen the...?
Laser Swath Mapping?
Yeah. Are you
familiar with it?
I am.
I consulted once with
the Army Corps of Engineers.
Oh, my.
They were checking
for coastal erosion
along the Gulf, but this...
This looks local.
Well...
I'm helping
the FBI
locate a missing police officer.
A missing police officer?
I didn't hear anything
about that
on the news.
Well, it was
back in 1990.
Bunch of kids
just recently
found his badge
in an empty lot.
So, you're looking for...?
His body.
Oh, God.
That-That's an awful thing
to happen.
Yeah.
So, um, have you seen Amita?
She was in her office earlier.
She's probably hiding from me.
Why would she be hiding
from you?
Oh, well, because she resigned
as the Chair
of the Curriculum Committee.
She resigned?
Mm-hmm.
In an e-mail.
Chairing that committee
is an incredible opportunity
for her...
Hey, Charlie, um,
I left your dad
a couple of messages,
and I haven't heard back
from him yet,
and I was
wondering if
you knew if there's a reason
he's not calling me?
Well, he's being sued.
He's being sued?!
Yeah.
Apparently, a golf driving range
he's been working on has become
an eyesore, literally.
Yeah, that's him.
That's Calvin Bradley.
I thought associating
with gang members
was a violation
of his parole?
Oh, he applied to a judge
for an exception.
Claimed he was
rehabilitating them.
You guys seem pretty sure
he's the one who
killed Officer Everett.
In 1990,
Bradley's bragging to
anybody who will listen,
he's gonna get revenge
on Everett
for killing his brother.
Words don't always
mean action.
Out there, you
learned real quick
there was no such thing
as an idle threat.
I grew up in this
neighborhood, all right?
Half the gang
bangers I busted,
I knew, and if they said it,
they did it.
We find John Everett's body,
this scumbag's going down.
So these are all the spots
I have.
How far down
do they have to dig?
Oh, just about...
just about four feet or so.
You worked that
gang case last year,
developed those, uh...
What are they called?
Shooting chains?
Yeah, a, uh, murder leads
to a retaliation,
and another and another,
and, yeah, it's a...
it's a domino effect, sure.
Any chance you could
do that here?
See if any other slayings
connect this cop's death
to Calvin Bradley?
Yeah, it's quite possible.
Where's your brother?
Hmm?
Oh, he's off
with the LAPD.
Does he know that
you're on this case?
No. I haven't had a
chance to tell him.
Oh, well, that'll be
a nice surprise for him.
You think?
I mean, has he said something
to you?
'Cause, you know, I...
he's just been a little...
No, he's...
He's been going through
some stuff.
Stuff?
Yeah.
I think you should talk
to him about it.
Sure.
Agent Warner,
we got something.
C1, just as
I had suspected.
It's him. It's Everett.
The Preliminary Coroner's
investigation here
indicates Everett had a single
gunshot wound to the head.
Fracturing indicates it was
probably at close range.
So this was
an execution.
Never been any
doubt about that.
Somehow Bradley got his
hands on Everett...
walked him to the
construction site,
planted one in his dome.
Then he dumped
him in a ditch,
and waited for a
construction crew
to seal his tomb.
Maybe. But can you prove it?
Well, I'm gonna let
Bradley to do that for me.
What makes you think
he's gonna talk to you now?
1990, I didn't
have a body.
Bradley knew that.
Now I do.
Calvin Bradley, FBI, open up!
LAPD. What the
hell's going on?
Get off him! Back off!
We're done here!
You see me here with no lawyer
because I have nothing to hide.
Yeah, why is it you look like
you got something to hide, huh?
17 years, nothing changes.
And you people wonder why we
don't want to help the cops.
We found him, Calvin.
You know who that is, right?
LAPD officer,
John Everett.
Same cop that killed your
little brother 17 years ago.
And disappeared two weeks later.
I have nothing to do with this.
Several witnesses say
you threatened
Officer Everett's life.
I was young.
I was a hothead.
Said some things
I didn't mean.
Hey, his car was found
a couple hundred feet
from your house.
Calvin, man, you've spent
more time in a law library
than we have.
You know that car
gives you opportunity
and your brother's death,
that gives you motive.
My little brother
was shot down like a dog.
Police didn't investigate.
You guys didn't care.
Your little brother
was a drug dealer who ran
with one of the most
violent gangs in the city.
You make it sound like
Stephon had a choice.
Like any of us did.
Got one choice out there, man:
Live or die.
Is that what you told
Officer Everett
when you put a bullet
through his skull?
I've already been to prison
for crimes I committed.
I'm not going back
for one I didn't do.
Life without parole.
Okay? That's the
only time you're going
to hear that offer.
You people think my brother
got what he deserved.
Well...
I think same might
be said for this cop.
What was that you said?
All right.
Say that again.
Listen, Gary, come on.
Hey, Gary.
Gary, Gary! Hey Gary!
All right, all right. Listen.
Down.
Could I talk to
you for a second?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yep.
You can't do that
around here, you know?
You gotta calm down.
Whew. Okay.
He wants to desecrate the
memory of one of my men.
You just let me have a piece
of him, I'll get a confession.
No, I can't do that.
Come on, Eppes,
just take a walk,
go have dinner
or whatever.
I understand how you feel.
It's not gonna happen,
all right?
Okay, listen.
Before Everett disappeared,
he was worried about
retribution.
He'd heard things on the street.
And we're running that down.
Yeah, well, I've been running
it down for 17 years.
And now,
you have the man.
You have him sitting right here.
The man who killed him.
Now, if you two don't
have the stomach for it--
That's not the case.
All right? We tried.
We don't have enough
to hold the guy. Period.
Are you setting him free?
Yeah, you bet I'm
setting him loose.
Excuse me.
Someone's not happy.
Bradley called
our bluff.
Well, it's about to get
more interesting.
The ballistics are in.
The bullet that killed
Everett came from a .38.
What? A revolver?
Or a revolver
that was issued
to Everett.
It's his duty weapon.
Same gun that killed
Stephon Bradley.
That means Everett was killed
with his own gun.
yeah.
Kevin wouldn't
even remember his dad
if it weren't
for those guys.
They took him to ball
games, camping trips...
How's he holding up?
It's been tough...
watching me get through this.
But he's lucky.
He's got four great
surrogate dads.
When Lieutenant Walker said
that your husband
had some concerns
after shooting
Stephon Bradley.
Uh, that's his way
of saying he was upset.
Case you haven't noticed,
Lieutenant Walker
doesn't exactly
express himself well.
Emotionally, I mean.
Truth is, the shooting
changed my husband.
He wasn't prepared for the way
he felt after killing that kid.
Was he depressed?
Depressed?
Did he have
trouble eating?
Or sleeping?
What are you asking me?
Well, our forensics indicate
that your husband
was killed with his own gun.
You think he killed himself?
No... No, he wouldn't do that.
Well, I'm sorry to put you
through this. We just, uh...
we just wanted to be sure.
Walker's got Bradley
tried and convicted.
Yeah, I know, I know.
Want some coffee?
No, I'm good.
What's going on?
Is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah, it's
just some stuff.
You know, I really don't
want to talk about.
Talking's not exactly
what I had in mind.
Uh, isn't this
sexual harassment?
Uh, I'll show you
sexual harassment.
All right. Hey.
I want your
input on that, Eppes.
Yeah.
Roger that.
That's amazing.
And in 1977,
there were fewer than...
500 murders in Los Angeles.
And by 1985,
the number doubled.
Well, there must be
some sort of causal
explanation for those
statistics.
Yeah, I mean, it was
the introduction of mass
drug sales by the gangs,
you know?
Fights over street corners--
territories shifting
led to more killings.
What?
You quit.
What are you talking about?
Chair of the Curriculum
Committee.
You know how
huge that is.
I can't believe she told you.
You know, neither Larry nor I
were ever asked
to chair that committee.
There's some pretty
heavy hitters, you know.
It can be intimidating.
I mean, maybe not for you...
Well, I've seen you
with the faculty,
you're very good.
Some of the professors talk.
About us.
What?!
Well, it doesn't matter.
No, just tell me...
What,
so that you can protect me?
Look, you can't and you
shouldn't have to.
I'm just not ready for this.
Agent Reeves,
did you mention
something about suicide?
Did you mention to Everett's
wife that he killed himself?
No, I never said that.
I know you
didn't say that.
But did you say something about,
"Well, was he depressed...?"
Eh, he was depressed,
Lieutenant.
Now, you shouldn't...
You really had no
right to do that.
Hold on. Don't come in here
telling us what rights
we do or don't have, Gary.
Now, I understand
how you feel...
No, I don't think you
do understand, Eppes.
I don't think understand
how I feel.
I don't think you know what
it's like to living it
in the streets,
the way we do.
And back then, it was a war.
Cops were dying every day,
trying to take back this city.
And Everett was one of them.
Did you know Everett was
killed with his own gun?
What?
Yeah, ballistics matched
the bullet to the .38
that killed Bradley,
all right? Take a look.
I don't need to see that.
What are you talking about?
That means that Bradley
got a hold of Everett's gun
and he shot him with it.
So what? The body
was buried, remember?
How did that happen?
I said before, the
construction crew could have
buried his body and
not ever knew about it.
What are you doing?
Are you writing
Calvin Bradley's
closing argument now?
I knew Everett. He wouldn't
have killed himself.
I got something.
The gang case
I worked on last year,
my guiding principle was
their territorial nature.
And it turned out some of
these gang members spent
their whole lives living
within a 10-block radius.
Their turf.
Right, I remember.
They live a mile from
the ocean; some of them
have never even
seen it...
Right, so here is a map
of all known gang territories
back in 1990 and using the
theory of collective behavior,
I...
Lieutenant Walker,
imagine a colony of ants
searching for food.
They send out a scout
and that scout wanders
around randomly.
If that scout finds food,
well, then the colony
marks that path as good.
If he doesn't find food, then
that path is marked as neutral.
And if that scout
never returns,
you better believe that
path is marked as bad.
Same thing
works with gangs.
Calvin Bradley was a member
of the Bixel Street Family.
This was their territory
back in 1990.
Everett's body
was found here
in an area controlled
by a gang called
the 18 Street Mexicali.
18 Street Mexicali and Bixel
Steet Family were rivals.
Factoring in for
territorial gang shifts...
I cannot find
a single safe passage.
For Bradley to
travel from his turf
to a rival's turf to even
have killed Everett.
It would be like a
Sunni going for a ride
in a Shi'ite neighborhood.
???
So Calvin Bradley
would've had trouble getting to
the crime scene.
Which doesn't make him
innocent...
Yeah, Charlie's math is all
about probabilities.
So, if he says it's unlikely,
it probably is...
Which takes us back
to what?
Suicide?
Well, what if we just keep
following the probabilities.
Meaning what?
Well, if the math says
it's doubtful anyone
from a rival gang
would have access
tohe 18 Street
Mexicali territories,
that narrows
our suspect list down.
To someone in the 18 Street
Mexicali crew.
Right.
I'll talk to Charlie
about running some names.
Hey!
What's going on?
Whoa!
Oh, hi.
Hi, the door was open.
I hope you don't mind.
Oh, no, no.
Not at all. Come in.
Good.
Thanks. Wow.
What's going on?
I love what you've done
with the room, huh.
You do?
Very, uh,
early American
interrogation room,
it's nice.
I can see your pores.
You notice, eh?
So, so what?
Charlie told me about
this whole lawsuit thing.
Yeah.
I just wanted to come
give you some moral support.
Well, uh, thank you,
I appreciate that,
but what I really
need are answers.
Yeah, to what?
I've been going
over my original calculations.
They're absolutely right.
I just don't understand
what the problem is
with the lighting.
I tried to
simulate it here.
Angles of incidence, good.
You got reflection,
absorption,
saturation coefficients.
Very impressive,
very impressive, Mr. Eppes.
Now I see where Charlie gets
hiinterest
in numbers.
Yeah, well,
I'm afraid there's only
one genius in this family.
Oh, I don't know.
Hey, I know, I know Charlie's
busy helping out Don,
and if you're interested
I'm available.
To go over your figures.
My figures?
Yes.
I got it.
Put your head down.
What do you say,
Lieutenant?
It's happy hour
somewhere, right?
Let me get a
club soda.
Club soda.
You know that
I've been trying
to pin this on Calvin
Bradley for 17 years.
It's a little hard
for me to believe
that after all this time
I might have been looking
at the wrong guy.
Hey, look, it's
not over yet.
Thanks.
Well, you'd think that I would
know after all this time
that things are never
what they seem.
You followed
your gut.
There's nothing else you can do.
It's a whole different world
out there now, Eppes.
It's a whole different way
of policing, a whole new way.
Down is up, up is down.
Everett wouldn't have
killed himself.
That's not the man I knew.
So, tell me
about 18 Street guy?
Well, they're not around
anymore, that's one thing.
And they used to be one
of the biggest drug suppliers
on the west coast.
All right.
So, if Everett was shot
in their territory,
then somebody knows something.
something, right?
Yeah.
Hey.
How you doing?
Tell me where Jimmy Lopez is?
The other side of this cab.
Jimmy Lopez?
FBI. I'd like
to talk to you
for a minute.
FBI?
Yeah.
Get your hands up.
How you doing,
Jimmy?
Officer Walker.
You got a good memory.
What's, uh...
what's going on
here, guys?
We thought
we would take a trip
down memory lane.
Yeah, maybe you didn't hear,
but...
I don't snitch no more.
right?
Well, they found Officer
Everett's body.
Who?
Officer John Everett.
Nah, that name don't ring
a bell.
Well, he was
found buried
in 18 Street
Mexicali territory,
so his name better start ringing
some bells
or I'm gonna ring
your bell.
I never had nothing
to do with killing no cop.
There's no way
he gets shot
in your territory
and it's not the news
of the decade.
No statute of limitations
on murder, Jimmy.
You know that, right?
I heard what everyone else
heard, okay?
What's that?
The cop was whacked courtesy
of the BSF.
Payback for some shooting.
So, what's he doing
in the 18 Street's territory?
No offense,
but when it came
to killing cops,
gang bangers can find
some pretty common ground.
Oh, hey.
There you are.
I went by your office
looking for you.
You did?
Yeah, I just wanted to talk.
About what?
Mm...
You know, thought about
walking away myself once.
You did.
Was first time I orally defended
a dissertation.
Charlie Eppes,
not confident about math?
I was more scared
of quitting
than I was of going
through with it,
so...
I couldn't walk away.
I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna chair
that committee.
You are?
I may make some mistakes...
No, you're gonna be great.
You're gonna be great.
I'll help you.
You know, if you
want my help.
I'm not saying that
you need my help.
If you want it.
I will take all the help
I can get.
See that?
We're a lot alike.
'Cause I'm always
asking you
for help.
Yes.
Speaking of help...
I see you're still
after that cop killer.
Yeah.
Liz Warner says that
he might be a member
of a street gang
called 18 Street Mexicali.
But none of the shooting
chains are tracking back
to a common shooter.
That's right.
What are you thinking?
You used collective
behavior theory
to define the path the
killer could have taken.
But that's not the
whole the story.
You're missing
a variable.
The victim.
I need to know the path
that Everett was taking as well.
All right, so according to this
18 Street had two
triggers
at the time
of Everett's death.
It could still be
anyone in the gang.
I hoping your brother's
got an answer.
All right,
Charlie, hey,
tell me you got a name
for us.
No, no.
Something else.
Charlie looked at
the timeline of events
for Everett on the day
he was killed.
And I applied
critical path analysis,
which is a mathematical
way of looking
at the most efficient manner
to complete tasks.
Imagine you're cooking
a holiday dinner,
and you cook it all
at the same time.
Well, some of your food's
gonna end up burnt.
Some of your food's
gonna end up cold.
What you need to do,
is prepare and cook
each part of the meal
in an effective order
and monitor them simultaneously
so that you serve all hot food
at all the same time.
The same concept applies
for Everett.
And he changed two appointments
he made that day.
All right, I mean,
so why's this significant?
Because people tend
to schedule meetings
as close to one another
as they can.
Schedule them
in a progressive order,
if they can.
Kind of like a...
math of convenience.
But his body and his car were
found a few miles apart.
Meaning that either
Everett was killed
where he was found and his car
was moved afterwards or...
Or else he drove
to the Bixel Street turf
and was transported
to where we found him
some other way.
Thus making one of those
two pieces of data skewed.
So...
I ran two different analyses.
I gave probability scores
to the areas
that Everett was most likely
headed to.
Now, this first map,
assumes that he was headed
to where his body was found,
to the 18 Street
Mexicali territory,
making this his most likely
next destination.
All right, and if he drove
to the Bixel turf?
Then Everett was most likely
headed here,
by a more
efficient path.
Do you see something?
Well, back in 1990,
Internal Affairs had their
headquarters right here.
Internal Affairs?
???
Charlie is righting.
Everett was on his way
to Internal Affairs
and he was killed
before he got there.
Yeah, that ain't
a coincidence-- no way.
Okay, so why was he
on his way to IA?
Well, Everett shot
Stephon Bradley.
Right?
Yeah.
But a shooting board ruled
it as a good kill.
Yeah, they did, only IA
was taking another look.
Yeah, why's that?
Well, three days
before Everett shot him,
Stephon Bradley
was picked up
by Homicide.
He was wanted
for a series of murders.
He was taking down rival
gangs' stash houses
and killing everyone inside.
And he offered
to trade information
against dirty cops.
Was he dirty, Gary?
No.
I don't believe that.
What were the circumstances
of the killing?
We got a tip that Bradley had
committed a double murder.
We found him
at his girlfriend's house.
Everett covered the back,
Bradley tried to bolt for it.
Everett shot him.
Starting to smell
like a bad kill.
All right, so...
Everett was headed
to Internal Affairs to confess,
and he stopped in the BSF
territory on the way.
Why?
Well, a cop with a
guilty conscience
might wanna come
clean to the, uh...
the brother of the guy that
he killed before he went to IA.
You saying that Everett went
to see Calvin Bradley?
Walked into the arms of the one
man who wanted to see him dead.
Calvin.
How many times
we gonna go through this,
fellas?
You're wasting our time.
We know you saw Everett
the day he disappeared.
Okay, you wanna prove
you're a changed man, Calvin?
How 'bout owning up
to what you did, finally, huh?
I did ten years taking
responsibility, Lieutenant.
What about you?
I hadn't committed
any crimes.
No, you had other
people do it for you.
Wait, hold on, say what?
What's that?
You really want to know?
Yeah, I really wanna know.
All right, Everett did
come to see me that day.
To apologize.
All right, he wanted
me to understand
what had gone down
with Stephon.
Only he left
my house alive.
You're a liar.
And you don't
know any better.
All right,
careful, hey.
What did Everett
say to you?
16 years I been the suspect
and you want my help.
The cops were giving
Stephon tips
on the location of
Mexican dope houses.
What?
Stephon ripped them off
while the cops
looked the other way.
Then they killed him when he
wanted to tell the truth.
Whatever my
brother was...
you were the ones
that made him that way.
Can I go now?
What do you think, Gary?
Yeah, get out of here.
Get out of here.
Yeah, well, you can ask but
I'm not giving you a deposition.
No, not until I know more facts.
Yeah, come in.
All right, if
that's your position
you can talk to my lawyer.
You got it.
You know a good lawyer?
I do. I know several.
Good.
Alan.
Geez...
Come here.
Huh?
Come here. Come.
Relax. Here. Sit.
No, it's all right, breathe.
Relax.
All right,
it's gonna be fine.
we are gonna tackle
each problem, one at a time.
Albert Einstein said that?
No, I read it on the back
of an iced tea bottle.
Oh.
It still applies.
You know what I did?
I simulated your design
on the CAD program at CalSci.
Well, I thought things like this
were, uh, frowned upon
by certain administrators.
Yeah, so I'm busted.
But who's gonna tell on me?
Me?
Well, if that
million-dollar computer
of yours is, uh, correct...
There's no way that that
driving range can be as bright
as the plaintiffs claim it is.
I know, but the measure
of foot-candles
is just off the charts.
So, I, it, it...
it doesn't...
Oh, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
I know what this means.
The hue of the
polypropylene is wrong.
They didn't use the synthetic
grass that I specified.
The contractor uses
a cheaper material
which reflects...
Which reflects more light!
See?!
Well, I'm off the hook.
Yeah.
Except for you electric bill's
gonna go through the roof.
Oh, that's all right.
Charlie owns the place now.
So the police were
using Stephon Bradley
to take down Mexican drug gangs?
No way Everett was
a part of that.
Then why did Everett
go see Bradley's brother
to apologize?
Easy.
Just saying, how long
we gonna live in denial here?
Okay, well,
let's look at
what Bradley's saying.
If what he's saying is true,
then someone had to be
telling the cops
where the locations
for these houses were
to begin with, right?
Well, if we find that source...
Maybe he can point us in the
direction of Everett's killer.
Okay, so let's take a look.
These are
the gang territories
where Calvin Bradley's
brother ripped off
those drug houses,
and they're spread
all through Mexican
gang territory,
except for one.
18 Street Mexicali.
Which is
the same territory
where Everett's body
was found.
Okay, so why'd these guys
get a free ride?
What it means
is that whoever
was feeding them
information was
18 Street Mexicali.
And he didn't want
to snitch on his...
on his own gang.
Jimmy Lopez.
Where's Jimmy Lopez?
I wish you
could tell me.
Took off. Haven't seen him.
Where's his rig?
Around the corner.
That's it.
That's wierd.
Jimmy Lopez.
Been keeping a secret
from me for 17 years.
Just doesn't add up.
Lopez was clean for years.
You think the pressure
of being questioned by you guys
pushed him over the edge?
Or someone else did.
The tip of the needle is
broken off in his arm.
Really?
Like he fought back?
Toxicology report shows
a mixture of heroin, strychnine
and powdered milk.
Nice little cocktail.
What are you thinking?
Most drug dealers,
they're very consistent
in the way they cut their drugs.
That's true--
signature,
brand-- helps them
sell it on the street.
Maybe we get
a tox report
from Lopez's OD
over to Charlie.
He can compare
the drugs
in Lopez's system
to the other ODs
in the coroner's database?
Sure, go for it.
It's worth a shot, right?
Statistical
identification?
Right.
Just looking at toxicology
records of recent ODs.
I'm trying to match
a specific drug
combo to a dealer.
Strychnine-- that's poison.
It's a trace dose.
It's not enough to kill.
You know, dealers put it
in their heroin mixes.
Poison plus heroin.
Yeah. A witness who identified
our cop killer OD'd,
so I'm just trying to
trace the drug supply.
What's happening
with the committee?
Some of the faculty
are demanding, but...
I think I'm up for the job.
I never doubted it.
What are you working on?
Uh, Millie has me
working on
some cluster analysis using
autocorrelation techniques
to analyze the most effective
undergrad classes
in the past two years.
Even going through
the past two semesters
would be a ton of work.
Yeah.
Millie thinks there's
as much to be learned
from the old curriculum
as the current.
What is it?
You know what?
Can we talk later?
I got to go.
Okay.
We got LAPD looking up
all his known associates.
against all the recent ODs
in the coroner's office, right?
Yeah, and?
There were no matches
to any current dealers,
which is why I re-ran
every overdose
in the Coroner's
database,
including old overdoses,
and I got a hit--
several hits,
actually.
Three overdoses going back
over a year,
all tracing back
to a drug dealer
named Hector Osorio.
Uh, Osorio was busted
by Lieutenant Davidson's
narco team.
A large quantity
of drugs were seized.
Which would be
in the evidence room.
And who would have
access to those drugs?
The lead detective of the team.
My guy Davidson.
Hey, Walker, what's up?
You guys got any news?
What the hell's wrong with you?
All right, all right!
You're under arrest for
the murder of
John Everett.
What are you
talking about?
They traced the drugs
in Lopez's system to a bust
that your team made, huh?
So what?
Yeah, that means that you
poisoned Lopez with those drugs.
Tell me the truth.
You got nothing.
You don't got jack on me.
How could you do that?!
All right, get off!
You ate at
Everett's table!
Hey!
You helped raise
his son!
Gary, cut it out!
Back off!
This isn't helping! Turn around!
Get your hands
behind your back!
We never took a dime.
I made the
streets safer.
Every drug dealer that
Bradley whacked...
I don't believe you!
No!
Not one drug dealer
Bradley whacked
ever killed another kid
with junk!
You got that?!
I made the streets safer!
So when Everett
was about to rat you out,
you killed him.
Because he had it coming!
You set him up
All right, all right.
to take the shot.
Let me just see him
for one second.
He was gonna go to IA!
Let me just...
Give me that.
Get this piece of
crap away from me.
He wouldn't listen
to reason! Hey, Walker!
Walker, I had no choice!
Hey, Dad.
Hey, Charlie.
What?
No plans with Amita tonight?
She's busy
chairing a new committee.
I guess...
Millie found
the magic bullet, huh?
Yeah, they dropped me
from the lawsuit.
Contractor's
on the hot seat now.
Oh, good. Well, I'm glad
she could help.
You know, if you would've
needed my help,
I certainly would've
been there for you.
Oh, yeah, I
know, I know.
Oh, by the way, Charlie,
when I hooked up
all these lights, I may have
blown a circuit or two.
A circuit or two?
Where?
Yeah.
I hope you had
the system
backed up with
that laptop of yours
in the garage.
Ah-ah-ah!
I was just kidding.
Hey.
So...
what's going on?
I'm worried
about you.
Ah, I'm all right.
I mean, you know,
did I do something to...
No, no, no.
Liz, it's not about you.
I mean...
Okay.
You can't just get me going
and disappear.
Yeah, I know.
I just...
I feel like
I keep second-guessing
so many moves.
Mid-life crisis, huh?
Ha, ha.
Anyone see you come in here?
Listen to you.
Hey.
I got plenty
in the bottle here.
I can see that.
300 bucks.
Thought he'd
appreciate it.
Gary, there was nothing
you could have done.
I mean, look, I know that
and you know that.
We'd both be lying to ourselves
if we said that, Eppes.
17 years.
It was right there
under my nose.
I just couldn't see it.
He was a funny kid.
He always walked around with
this goofy grin.
I remember he had
this little red radio
that he used to play,
and there was one song that
he really liked to listen to,
and I...
I just haven't been able
to remember that song.
I wish I could
remember that song.
Wasn't it you that said,
"At the end of the day,
you go home safe,
that's all you can ask"?
That's right, Eppes.
You...
You walk away...
it all works out.
welcome to www.1000fr.com