Factory break-in, that's what you said.
We should never have got into this, Tom.
On the night of June 21st, a
general strike will be called
across the city.
How do we know this foolish man
will hand over the diamonds
- when we're done?
- We don't, but that's another business.
When this business is done,
it will all be over...
And afterwards you and Arthur
can begin your new life.
So there's three cellars
underneath the house.
There's a tunnel here that
runs from the house underneath
the river to an underground strong room.
We need our tunnel to run from here
and hit the strong room direct.
I need to speak to you about the priest.
I will shoot him myself, Tommy.
I swear to God if my
son pulls the trigger...
I will bring this whole
organisation down around your ears.
Welcome to the opening of
the Grace Shelby Institute
for non-insured children of the poor.
I would very much like you
to join me in thanking the man
that made the founding of this
establishment actually possible.
Ladies and Gentlemen...
Mr Thomas Shelby.
SPEECH!
Come on! Speech!
Say it, Tom!
I didn't come here today to make
a speech, but I will say this,
these children are now safe.
In our care, they will be safe
because we are from the same
cold streets as they are.
And, in our care, they won't
be shipped away to the colonies,
or separated from kin,
or made to work for men
in their various ways.
They will grow up here, at home,
loved.
In Birmingham.
Because this is our city.
By order of the Peaky Blinders!
Now let us sing Immortal Invisible.
You hear that, Grace?
The absence of my
invitation for this event
was obviously an oversight
on your part, Mr Shelby.
But look, I have the keys.
I have allocated myself an office.
Just there, two doors in from the street.
It's the one that already has the stove
and the crucifixion on the window.
Mr Shelby?
It is the one that has the
crucifixion on the window
in orange and red. That will be my office.
And I will take them to St
Aloysius for confession.
You do understand that these keys
are part of our broader arrangement?
In the next 24 hours you will do
exactly as you have been instructed.
You'll not deviate. You'll not fail.
Come on, little fellas!
Slow down.
The, er...
The Lord Mayor would like
you to come and eat cake
and drink some tea.
Tommy says mingle and smile.
- It must be the trains.
- No Ruben?
Do you know any other guests
from London not turned up?
Some, I think, yeah.
Pol, I'm paid by the company now
so I have to talk to other people.
So you have moved from horses to
automobiles in just four years!
When you ship to New York,
you paying a higher dock duty.
You should consider coming
with us through Boston.
I just spoke to Johnny Dogs. He
said the tunnel's hit heavy clay.
- It's slowing him down.
- How long?
Two days before they hit the wall.
Tell him to dig a sink
hole to drain the clay.
He asked if you could go down
and have a look yourself, Tom.
- I told him wild horses
wouldn't get you down. - Mm.
Mr Shelby, I would just like to say
that I wish I'd met your dear wife
before she was taken from us and I
would like to allocate an hour a day
of each of my lady's time to make
winter clothes for the little ones.
Speak to my secretary, Miss
Stark, in the grey hat.
She knows my diary.
Fuck me, Tom, I don't know
how you do it. Incoming!
- Mr Shelby?
- Yes!
Oh! Your little boy
looks so much like you.
Yes. He's a little rascal, isn't he?!
Mr Shelby, would it be too
inconvenient to steal you for a moment?
No. No. No inconvenience at all.
Tommy, I'm sorry. He wants you.
Aw! Come here, Charlie. Oh, little boy!
So lovely to see a man willing
to hold his child in public.
From the members of Moseley
War Widows' Institute...
made by Mr Winslow himself
of Winslow Castings.
Look at that!
From a photograph of your
horse that ran at the Derby.
Oh, that is very kind.
Thank you very much.
- Grace's Secret.
- Thank you very much.
Would you mind holding it for us
so we can have a
photograph for the gazette?
Thank you very much.
- Thank you, Mr Shelby.
- Not at all. - Thank you.
Thank you for your time, ladies.
Thank you. Thank you for your time.
Thank you.
Where's Charles, Ada?
- I gave him to you. - Where
is he? - I don't know.
Boys!
Have you seen Charlie?
Ain't seen him.
Hold on, he's playing, ain't he?!
Pol, where's Charles?
- Lizzie, where's Charlie?
- I don't know.
Where is he?
Back door. Kitchen.
Get to Blake Street where the cars are.
Tommy, someone said they saw a nurse
take him through the back door.
- Fuck! - Which? - I don't know. Go!
- Arthur!
- What?
Somebody saw a woman and
a kid getting into a car.
Ah, fuck!
CHARLIE!
Charlie!
John!
- Where is he?
- John!
- Arthur! - Go find Moss!
- Arthur, where is he?
- Junctions, block them all off.
- WHERE IS HE?
- Tell me.
- Someone took him.
All right...
Listen to me. They put him in a car.
They put him in a car. They drove south.
We've got road blocks and spotters.
- I'll set up shop. I'll
put every man... - Yeah.
.. on the junctions
between here and Maypole.
- Yeah. - Right? - You do that.
You've got to go to the office.
- You've got to sit by the phone.
- Do that.
Whoever took him's going to call.
Polly!
Let's go, Pol. Stay by that phone.
Me and John will cover the roads.
I need Michael at the Maypole junction.
We need Moss to block all the roads south.
Get me Moss.
Gone where?
- Tommy.
- It's them.
- Who?
- It's fucking them.
Look, it might just be some random
woman. Sometimes women go mad...
No, it's them.
Did you break the phone?
You broke the phone.
It's all right, we've got another phone.
- Tommy?
- Ada?
There's someone outside. A priest.
Stay here, Pol. Stay
here. Don't do anything.
We have your son.
Get in the car.
First...
Is he safe?
Of course he's safe.
All children are dear to me.
You have all the cards.
Tell me what you want me to
do and I will certainly do it.
You ever drive one of these beasts?
I am asking you to conduct business.
I borrowed it.
Lent it by a Lord...
for the duration of this business.
I will certainly do what you
need me to do with no complaint.
We were forced into
doing this awful thing.
We did warn you that your
son would be in danger
if you deviated from the plan.
- It was you who made a mistake,
you understand that? - Yes.
What mistake did you
make? Do you even know?
Tell me what you want me to do.
- You made a deal with our enemies.
- I will do what needs to be done.
You went behind our backs
to stop the Soviets from
blowing up the train.
But it's all right. It's all right.
We've rectified your mistake.
You ask me, "What do I need to do?"
Well, here is what you need to
do you fucking mongrel, ya...
Since the Bolsheviks will
not be blowing up the train,
you'll blow up the train yourself.
It has always been about the explosion.
From the beginning.
The bang. The outrage.
Understand?
Those are notes and fragments for
you to scatter in the wreckage
implicating named officials
from the Soviet embassy.
- I will scatter them.
It will be done. - Good.
Our friends at the Times and
the Daily Mail will do the rest.
And once the British Government
cuts diplomatic relations
with the Soviet Union, that
will be our mission accomplished.
You'll have been part of a fine adventure.
To help with the outrage we need
people to die in the explosion.
How many?
Let's say... six.
Rail workers perhaps
or men from the factory.
Then I want my son returned to me
within an hour of the explosion.
Oh, it's conditions now, is it?
We need to fix the hand over in advance.
I haven't finished with
you yet, Mr Shelby.
We also hear you're digging a tunnel.
Mining for precious stones
under Wilderness House.
I'm told they have a
Faberge in the strong room.
The Lilies of the Valley egg made in 1898.
One of the Odd Fellows has a wife
who is obsessed with Faberge.
- He wants to give her the egg for her birthday.
- Then he will have it.
And the Economic League will take
all of the jewels that you steal
to cover our considerable expenses.
The fight against Communism
is not cheap, you know.
- So if you want to see your...
- I will give you all the jewels.
A bang first.
Then bring everything you have
stolen to your office at dawn.
No.
No, I'll not be able to get
the jewels to you by dawn.
The tunnel has hit clay.
If the St Andrew's clock strikes
5am on the night of the robbery
and we don't have everything we ask for,
the bell will be tolling for your boy.
Now get out of my fucking car.
- Where's Linda?
- With Esme.
Esme's waters broke. I was just with her.
- Running around fucking broke
her waters. - Where's Finn?
Out with the young 'uns
looking for the Riley.
We couldn't reach him.
I need to know who spoke.
Our enemies know everything. Everything.
I need to know who spoke about
business outside the family.
I need to know who spoke
and who they spoke to. Now.
Tommy, listen.
Your wife, Arthur?
I am going to tell
myself that you're, er...
you're not thinking straight.
Your mind is not clear.
Or Esme getting cash
for cocaine, eh, John?
Fuck!
All of a sudden, back
in the family, Ada. Eh?
That's a surprise. Out of
the blue. On whose orders?
Tommy, this is not helping find him.
And you and your painter.
He said he knows you.
Things developed.
You talked.
If anyone has talked about
the tunnel to anyone else,
I need to know, and I
need to know this second.
- What about your clay kickers?
- Hmm.
Drunk in a pub.
- I trust those men with my life...
- More than you trust us.
Yeah. As of an hour ago, yes.
Where is Michael in this
fucking line-up anyway?
- You leave Michael out of this...
- Yeah? - No, he should be here.
I don't even fucking know him.
How long have you fucking
known him? Fucking three years.
- He's not your whipping boy.
- I don't even fucking know the boy.
I never told Michael about
the Lilies of the Valley.
The only people I told about the
Faberge eggs are in this room.
Tommy, I want you to know
I came back for love...
.. and common sense.
And Esme's got no need for extra cash.
You bring my wife into this.
Means we speak when this business is done.
John, Arthur,
I need 50 sticks of BSA dynamite,
300 yards of cable
and six detonators by midday tomorrow.
This is evidence, I
need you to scatter it.
We're blowing up a train,
people are going to die.
Ruben and I talked about many things.
But not that. Not ever.
Tommy. I'm sorry I'm late.
We looked everywhere.
All the way to Hay Mills. So, nothing.
Put four cans of petrol in the
boot of my car and bring it round.
Put cigarettes and a lamp in the box.
And fetch Michael. I need him.
Ada told me he gave you red wine.
I imagine you can't remember
half what you talked about.
He was never interested in business.
He came to you at my wedding.
He pursued you, sought you out.
Why would an educated man of his
standing do something like that?
You mean, to a woman like me?
Yes.
I've done the odds on all
of you. Evens it's him.
There's another possibility.
But evens, it's him.
Bloody hell.
I asked you to come alone and unarmed.
Yeah, well, alone I ain't
never going to do, am I?
As for the cane, don't worry about it.
That's just me sciatica.
It always plays up around the
winter and the summer solstice.
What have you got for me, Alfie?
What you bring me out here for?
It's on the way to somewhere
I need to be in a hurry.
What have you got for me?
Well, seeing as you was prepared
to pay such an exorbitant amount
for this information, I decided
to give you value for money.
So, here are the names
of all the men in England
whom I would approach, right,
if I had a Faberge egg for sale.
Here you go.
And then, here is all the
men on that list, you know,
who would buy the old Faberge egg
even if they knew that
that item was stolen.
Yeah?
Then came your curious
fucking gyppo question.
I won't ask, but, um...
Here's a list of the men
who would buy a Faberge
because of their wives' obsession.
Oh, yes. Thank you, Mr Shelby.
Lovely doing business with you.
- You left a name off the
list, Alfie. - Did I? - Yeah.
I've already spoken to my
people in the jewellery quarter,
experienced dealers.
They tell me there are
only three men in Britain
whose wives are obsessed with Faberge --
makes them good customers.
- But you missed the richest one
off the list. - Yeah, well...
If you knew already,
how come you dragged me
- all the way out in the fucking
oggin, mate? - Two reasons.
Reason one.
By withholding a name that
you most certainly know...
you have proven to me that you have
done a deal with the Odd Fellows.
It was you who told them about the tunnel.
You who told them about the
fucking deal with the Soviets.
Reason two.
The name of the man you're
withholding must be my enemy
otherwise you wouldn't be protecting him.
He's now a man I can use.
Listen, sweetie, you can't take a man...
You gave information
in exchange for a share...
Tommy, there were things in that treasury
that God himself, he
spoke to me, and he said,
"Alfie, you were meant
to have these things."
- You crossed the line, Alfie.
- You fucking what?
- You crossed the line.
- "The line"?
They're using my boy!
Did you fucking know?
Yeah, I knew, you know?
But damned as I am, it made no
fucking difference to me, mate.
Fucking hell, Tommy!
Oh, for crying out loud...!
What the fuck is going on?
What is the matter with you, Tommy, eh?
- Eh? You gone fucking angry, ain't you.
- I got fucking angry...!
It's in your fucking head, mate!
This bastard deserves it!
I know this bastard deserves it!
I fucking know.
But if you kill him now, the
truce with the London outfits
- will be blown to fucking pieces, all right?
- Michael... Michael...
Don't worry about that truce,
kid, right, because it fell apart.
You've got nothing to worry about
when it comes to the
old, scary London boys.
Which fucking side are you on, Alfie?!
I don't give a fuck right now, kid! Right?
I do not want him to "spare" me
because of some fucking peace pact!
I want him to acknowledge that
his anger is un-fucking-justified!
I want him to acknowledge
that he who fights by the sword,
he fucking dies by it, Tommy.
So, what, they took
your boy, did they, yeah?
They've got your boy?
And what fucking line am I
supposed to have crossed?!
How many fathers, right?
How many sons, yeah, have
you cut, killed, murdered?
Fucking butchered -- innocent and guilty.
Just sent them straight to fucking
hell, ain't ya?! Just like me!
You fucking stand there...
You judging me?!
Stand there and talk to me about
crossing some FUCKING LINE?!
If you pull that trigger, right,
you pull that trigger for a
fucking honourable reason.
Like an honourable man, not
like some fucking civilian
that does not understand
the wicked way of our world, mate.
Look, Tommy,
the killing of Alfie Solomons
is not going to help.
It'll be very bad for business.
Michael...
Go and call Inspector Moss.
Tell him it's Palmer.
Well said, Alfie.
Well said.
- I did not know about
your boy, though. - I know.
I saw.
Hello?
Good Lord...
Polly...
Why didn't you come?
I was going to get on the
train last night, but then I...
I realised I simply wasn't
ready to enter your world.
- Good God, I'm shaking...
- Good.
But now, I am ready. I have
been searching all night for you.
Polly, whatever you've
been told, it's not true.
The painting was wrong.
She was too sure of herself.
And I'm not.
Not any more...
I can paint another.
Oh, Polly...
(Oh, Polly...)
What the fuck am I doing?
I want a dull life.
I want you. I want you.
I want you.
I want you to paint me in a
dress that I bought in a shop.
We have a life?
I think so.
Hello?
I demand to see my solicitor! I
have a right to have him here!
Gilbert Palmer, I want to talk
to you about a missing kid.
We are Peaky Blinders.
Where is he?
Deep breath.
- Johnny!
- Tommy?
What the fuck are you doing here, Tommy?
They've taken my boy, Johnny.
Everything's fucking changed.
I have to get the hole dug
before midnight or he's gone.
Do you hear me?
Are you not going after Charles yourself?
Tommy?!
I was, um...
This morning, I was on
the road with Tommy.
I killed a man.
He needed cover. I was all he had.
So, what did he give you?
He said it was good for close range.
You're better with my Smith & Wesson.
No, no. This is mine now.
Feels part of me hand.
Where'd you hit him?
I hit him in the side of the head.
How was you when he went down?
Tommy said I did all right.
This is where we think
Charles is being held.
They're not expecting nobody,
so... he should be alone.
There's two good men there.
You do what they say.
But I fire the bullet, all right?
Yes, you can be there.
But it's better if they do it.
See, these are experienced men, Michael.
When you're sure the kid's safe...
.. you call Finn.
All right.
Come on, boys.
Ah, hello there.
There you go. How's that?
You'd like a spoon, a shiny spoon?
Do you want to hold the spoon, there?
All out, boys!
Wildcat strike!
This locomotive...
.. couples in 15 minutes.
If we do not hear word by ten o'clock...
.. we blow it up.
There's men on board, Arthur.
Yeah.
Six men on board, Charlie.
Driver,
stoker...
Four men I hand-picked meself.
Me and John picked those men.
So, it's me and John who pull the switch.
The rest of you men can go home.
Tommy! Tommy!
He's got the shakes, help me with him.
Get him out. Get him out!
OK. Bringing him through.
We need to move! Now!
You wait here.
I'll do the killing.
That's a fucking order.
You move too fast, Thomas!
We need more timber!
Make it safe. I'll go on.
Thomas, it's too fucking wet! It's sludge!
Make it fucking safe and I'll go on!
OK.
What do you think you're doing, boy?
Please, don't...
Please don't shoot...
Please, don't shoot.
Please, don't. Please...
You rat!
What do you think you're doing, eh?
Do you know who you're
fucking messing with?!
We don't have much time.
I'll take the fucking
life from ya, will I?
Let's go!
You're a gypsy bastard.
Who wants to be in heaven, eh?
Who want to be in heaven when you
can be sending men to fucking hell?
Hey...
I'll do it, Arthur.
Eh?
I'll do it.
No!
- I will take him.
- NO!
This bastard's mine!
Go call Finn!
I told Tommy I'll do it.
So, I'll do it.
Arthur, wait!
Charlie's safe!
It's all right.
Let me speak to him.
Hello, Charlie?
Hello, Charlie.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
Yeah, you go to bed.
Good boy.
Where the hell have you been?
I've been out in Maypole.
There's been some trouble.
I can't stay.
You can't stay?
Tommy needs my help.
Family business.
- No, no... Please...
- I'm sorry.
Please...
- Where is he?
- He's upstairs.
Mr Shelby, this is Monsieur Silk.
He's here on behalf of
the Parisian buyers.
He needs to verify the value.
It was a pleasure doing business
with you these past few months.
You would never steal from
your family, would you?
The collection was
mostly my mother's anyway.
It is more mine than theirs.
And they would never have sold it.
- They would have wasted it on a lost cause.
- You needed a tunnel.
I need your signature
to make this sale legal.
Confirmed.
The original Duke Alexander
Petrovich's collection.
To raise a legal bill of sale
and get this across the border,
I need authorisation signed by yourself
in the family name in my presence.
As we agreed. Half for the tunnel.
Half for the signature.
Where will you go?
Vienna.
There's a man waiting for me.
Poor man(!).
You?
Birmingham.
I'm going to buy a racehorse.
Have it trained.
Also...£5,000 for the sex.
And five for helping you through
the grief of losing your wife.
You didn't even come close.
The... papers are in order.
Now I just need your
signature for the provenance.
Of course. I have a pen...
At home, these jewels saw way worse.
That's why they are all cursed.
As are we...
Mr Shelby.
If you're ever in Vienna, look me up.
Yes, yes!
Before I begin...
.. I want you to let you
know I made a mistake.
I made a mistake...
.. and I want to apologise to all of you.
Arthur,
you warned me against getting
involved in Russian business...
.. and you were right.
Hm.
I doubted your wife.
For that, I'm sorry.
Linda, I've added 3,000 here
in the hope you will forgive me.
Apology accepted.
Esme, I doubted you, as well.
Now, John's got innocent
lives on his conscience.
- Ordinary working men...
- Yeah, all right, Esme. Got it...
No, she's right.
And you and Arthur are going
to have to share that burden.
But, I hope the house that
you could buy with this
can become a place of...
.. contemplation.
Perhaps redemption.
Charlie, for lost tools dangerous goods
and Curly's wise words.
Johnny, for board and lodgings.
Lizzie...
Michael.
For the killings.
Five for cutting and five for shooting.
- No, Tommy, no...
- What?!
Tell me, eh?
This is who I am!
And this is all I can give
you for what you give me.
For your hearts and your souls.
Yesterday, I nearly lost my son.
You should fucking understand that.
For what?
For what? For this?
For this...?!
And I know that you all want
me to say that I'll change,
that this fucking business will change.
But I've learnt something
in the last few days.
Those bastards. Those BASTARDS...
.. are worse than us.
Politicians, fucking judges,
lords and ladies. They're WORSE than us,
and they will never admit
us to their palaces,
no matter how legitimate we become...
.. because of who we are.
Because of who we fucking are,
because of where we're fucking from.
Isn't that right, Ada?
Our Ada knows.
She got smart about revolution.
And she knows you have to get
what you want your own way.
Lizzie, I want it known, that money
was for you because, some
nights, it was you...
.. who stopped my heart
from breaking. No-one else.
And the rest of you, you
took the King's shilling.
You took the King's fucking shilling.
When you take the King's shilling,
the King expects you to kill.
Right, Arthur?
Yeah.
That's how it works, right, John?
That's right.
That's right, Pol.
That's fucking right.
Tommy...
You've had a bad time.
We understand.
So, at an alternative time...
.. when we have all recovered...
.. I would like
to put before the family
an alternative view...
.. of the future of the
Shelby Company Limited.
A more hopeful view.
Which I, for one, would
quite like to hear.
As would I.
Come on, Arthur.
The train for the dock
leaves in one hour...
.. then we'll get the boat to New York
and it'll all be in the past.
I'll be off, then, Tom.
I'll see you, eh?
I'll see you, brother.
Bye, Curly.
You can go, but you won't get far, Arthur.
Ah...
All right, Tom.
I spoke to Moss last night.
He told me that the Chief
Constable of Birmingham
has issued a warrant for your arrest.
Murder,
sedition,
conspiracy to cause explosion.
John, they're coming for you, as well.
Murder.
Conspiracy to cause explosion.
- Michael...
- What the fuck?
.. the murder of Hughes.
Polly...
Wait a minute, what the
fuck are you talking ab...?
.. the murder of Chief
Inspector Chester Campbell.
- Why didn't you fucking tell us? - The people
we betrayed last night want to bring us down...
They control the police,
they control the judges,
they control the juries,
they control the jails.
But they do not control
the elected Government.
- Listen to me!
- Why didn't you tell us before?!
- You're my brother!
- Listen to me...
So, I've made a deal...
- They'll hang us! - .. in return
for giving evidence against them.
- We'll fucking hang!
- It's all taken care of.
Lizzie, collect up the money
and bring it to the cellar.
You will all get your money in due course.
When the police get in, do not resist.
- You go with them, you do
not say anything... - Arthur!
Arthur, I've made a deal
- with people even more powerful
than our enemies. - Arthur!
Trust me, Brother.
Eh?
Trust me?
- Linda! Linda...
- You did this deliberately!
You made this happen to keep us!
Come here. Come here.
All I know, we run.
We have to run.
FUCK YOU!
♪ Once again
♪ I'm in trouble with my only friend
♪ She is papering the window panes
♪ She is putting on a smile
♪ Living in a glass house
♪ Well, of course, I'd
like to sit around and chat
♪ Well, of course, I'd like
to stay and chew the fat
♪ Well, of course, I'd
like to sit around and chat
♪ But someone's listening in. ♪
♪ On a gathering storm
comes a tall, handsome man
♪ In a dusty, black coat
with a red right hand. ♪