You're dead,Spencer.
What you doing, Shawn?
Nothing.
Looks like something to me.
Okay. I was running away
from Ryan Brickhouse.
That him?
Is he the same kid
who's been hassling you all week?
Yeah.
And why is he chasing you today?
I might have thrown a rock at him.
Did you hit him?
Almost.
Get back out there.
What?
Can't run away
from the bad guys forever,Shawn
Eventually, you've got to
come up with a new approach.
So...
so... find one.
You're flunking math?
Proudly.
Here's the deal...
leave me alone,
I'll make sure
you ace the test tomorrow.
How?
Every third answer is "c".
There's a pattern to all her tests.
Mrs. Bodansky does it every time.
I memorized it.
I'll show you.
You better not be lying.
Not bad. You faced your fears.
You got a new result.
You came out ahead.
Did you really
memorize those test answers?
Yeah.
Who are you calling?
Your math teacher.
No. No. No. No. Yes.
Yes...
nickel...
that's a nickel.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
Who was that?
Who was who?
The girl sitting at our front desk.
You're talking
about the lovely Dagmar.
Dagmar?
She's our new receptionist.
How did she get the job?
The agency sent her over.
You contacted a temp agency
without consulting me?
Gus, anyone can get a secretary
from a temp agency.
It takes real foresight
and creativity to get
one from a modeling agency.
A modeling agency?
Now, why would a
beautiful lady like that
want to be our secretary?
Oh, that's a bit
of a story, you see.
Apparently,
she got it in her head
that this was a runway gig.
I blame the agent.
I was very clear on the phone.
But she's cool with sticking around
for the rest of the
day,seeing how it goes.
You know how slow it gets
when it's not modeling season.
Does she answer the phone?
Yes, but only her cell phone.
She's expecting a call from milan.
Does she file?
Mostly her nails.
Coffee?
Yeah, she wants some.
Can I make you anything?
No.
Dude, I thought you weren't
coming in till, like, noon?
Big drama at the office today.
A doctor we supply
product to got killed.
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You didn't call me immediately?
You don't know him.
Gus,This is what we do, remember?
We can solve the case.
The police are already there.
This means nothing to me.
They're going to need help.
Guidance. Psychic vibrations.
Dagmar!
She doesn't speak english?
Does she need to?
Where  in the name
of all that is holy
is my forensics team?
All right,
what can you tell
me about this doctor
that I can pretend to ascertain
from the spirit world?
Dr. Blinn wasn't on my route.
I did cover him a few times.
All I remember is he
always made you wait,
and he had an picture
of Pete Rose on his wall.
Look how cute she
is in the fuchsia.
I have been sent by
the spirit of Pete Rose.
Pete  Rose isn't dead.
There was a photo of
Pete Rose on the wall.
Okay, why have I been drawn here?
Was there a murder?
Do I need the little
booties for the crime scene?
Thanks, but we're doing just fine.
Don't go in the back room.
My grandpa loved Pete Rose.
I want you guys ringing doorbells.
If anybody saw anything,
I want to know
about it. Patient files?
Cabinet's locked. We
haven't found the key.
Get ahold of the D. A. 'S office.
Tell them I need
access to those files.
If they say we
need a warrant, get it.
Also, get me a copy
of his desk calendar.
I thought I told you no.
But your eyes said yes.
Hey, who's that Cincinnati red
with the bowl cut?
Let me be perfectly clear.
This is my crime scene.
I don't need your help.
I don't want your help.
If you don't leave right now,
I will have you
arrested for interfering
with a police
investigation. Am I clear?
Like butter.
I've given this a
great deal of thought.
I think we should take
the rest of the day off.
What say you?
All we've done is eat a box
of animal cookies
and crash a crime scene.
The  case with the doctor...
they're coming back to us
eventually. You know this.
So let's go to the beach.
It's too nice a day
for murder and mayhem.
I have to see them
right now... nein! Nein!
It's important.
I'm sorry. I don't
mean to barge in, but...
I need help.
Mr. Dunn... Robert...
how can we help?
And can I call you "Bob"?
This is difficult.
Take your time. We're here.
I'm just going to
come out and say it.
I'm being haunted.
Haunted?
Yes.
There's a haunting...
Gus, can I talk to you outside?
Not now. We're in
the middle of something.
Gus.
Stop talking. Sit down.
Now, what exactly do you mean
when you say "haunted"?
Well...
my home...
sometimes I smell perfume
when no one else is around.
Things get broken or moved.
I think you have a test message.
I'll get it later.
I think you should get it now.
Sorry.
Work business.
Okay...
can I ask you a question?
Yeah.
Do these spirits ever
speak to you?
No. No. Whatever...
whoever it is,
it hasn't spoken to me.
Oh.
Have you contacted the police?
Yeah,but they said
there was nothing they could do.
So here I am.
Robert,
we deal with this
kind of phenomenon
all the time,
and what you need to realize
is that evicting a spirit
is a very time-consuming
and absurdly expensive process.
I don't care, okay?
I just can't go on living this way.
Excuse me.
Oh, really?
Yes!
Yes, Shawn.
All I'm saying is that
it might be
easier to try moving into
a different
house. One that's less...
haunted.
I tried that.
Whatever this
thing is,it followed me
all the way from san francisco.
Maybe it likes you.
No. I don't think so.
What makes you say that?
I think it tried to kill me.
Gus, what is all this?
Gear we might need.
If we're going to
be hunting for spirits,
we might as well do it right.
Methodically,systematically,
scientifically. Who knows,
we might be surprised what we find.
Video camera, nice.
Audio recorder. Motion detectors.
Gus, I am very impressed.
You only forgot one thing.
Really? What?
There's no such thing as ghosts.
Yes, there is.
Oh, Gus, no.
Okay.
Stop.
Please. Let's just...
let's just stop.
Come here, sit down. Please. Sit.
All right.
This is me talking. This is Shawn.
What's going on?
I usually have to drag you
to these cases
kicking and screaming,
and those are real police cases.
Now, all of a sudden,
we have some client
who is either bonkers,
or, judging by the size of the bags
under his
eyes,suffering from nothing
more than waking dreams
or hallucinations,and you,
you're ready to go ghost-hunting.
Talk to me.
All right.
I've never told
this to anyone before,
but...
I was 12.
Gus, it's me.
It  was late.
I was in my room
with the lights off.
I heard a voice.
Gus, I'm sure
there's a perfectly
logical explanation...
no, no, no, Shawn.
It wasn't on TV
and it wasn't a radio.
It was coming from the walls,
and the voice...
the voice told me
that our house was built
on an old indian burial ground.
Shut up.
She said...
she said she was sad
because she had died many moons ago
and was trapped between worlds.
When I asked her her name, Shawn...
she said...
"my name... "
My name is Wilting Flower.
I died without knowing love.
Will you be my friend?
How... How did you know that?
I never told it to anyone before!
I was Wilting Flower.
Gus!
I can't believe
that you fell for that!
I put an old walkie-talkie
in  the wall when your dad...
When your dad put
in the new insulation.
The old indian burial
ground? You bought that?
I got that from "Poltergeist"...
or "Poltergeist II".
"Gremlins"?
No, it wasn't "Gremlins".
That's not funny,Shawn.
Okay, you know what?
Let's add a "Trixie" to that...
now, she is the
companion to "scrappy," right?
Okay, great, let's add that to
"girl with flowers"
and "merry musicians. "
Okay, now, listen,
I need the card to read,
"happy birthday.
'Ex' is the loneliest
letter in the alphabet. "
But I need you to
spell it e-x,as in...
oh, you got it?
Okay, well, listen,it continues...
"from your
not-yet-'ex'"... "e-x"...
"husband, Carlton. "
Perfect. These'll
go out today, right?
All righty-dighty.
Thank you very much.
I didn't know you
collected figurines.
You know, I have
a grandmother who...
do you not knock?
There's no door.
And?
Sorry.
The  D. A. 'S office called.
They said that we can have access
to dr. Blinn's patients' files.
About time.
Let's get in
there,get those addresses,
and bring these
nutjobs in for questioning.
Here's where I found
all my paintings last weekend...
Upside down.
I've got a cold spot.
Right here.
Feel it?
Yes.
Yes, I do. Robert, we've definitely
got something here.
You're standing under a vent.
So all these are yours, huh?
Yeah.
I'm trying to get ready for a show.
No kidding.
Has anything strange
ever happened in here?
Sometimes I get the feeling
that the furniture has been moved.
Did you actually see it happen?
No, I just come into a room
and everything's
not where I left it.
Robert, do you have a photo album?
Yeah.
That's a nice shot, huh?
Oh. Oh, oh, oh!
I feel it.
I feel it! Oh, Gus! Gus!
Oh!
Oh, she is angry!
She is angry!
She is soaring with rage and...
She wants to go into the bedroom!
Where's the bedroom?
It's here. Here.
Take me!
I've lost her.
You don't believe me,do you?
No, of course we do.
You saw it, too, didn't you?
Guys.
Please.
Stay the night.
Then you'll see.
I mean, you don't
know what it's been like.
I can't work. I can't concentrate.
I wake up in the morning
more tired than when I went to bed.
Days pass and I can't remember
what I've done.
This pulls out into a
bed,but that's all I got.
Ah, no worries.
What's a little spooning
between old pals, huh, Gus?
Well, good night.
Good night, rob.
You got the floor.
We'll make it work.
You don't mind if I
nude up for the sleepover, right?
Seriously, Shawn.
Only one of us is
sleeping at a time.
The other one is on watch.
Oh, no, we'll both sleep.
I'll put on some socks,
make you feel more comfortable.
Stop playing, Shawn.
We're here to solve a case.
I already solved it.
When?
When you were
flapping the book like a bird?
Gus, if you must know,
it was a bald eagle... and yes.
You found the ghost?
There's no such thing as ghosts.
Yes, there is, Shawn.
No, there isn't,but
there is such a thing as
a pissed-off ex-girlfriend.
What ex-girlfriend?
No one mentioned
anything about an ex.
You didn't look at the photo album?
Redhead.
She's cute.
What makes you think she's an ex?
Oh, come on.
There's dirty dishes everywhere.
His bedroom is a mess.
His nails are filthy.
His hair is horrible.
No girlfriend's
going to put up with that.
And exhibit "a"...
who else would "x" through his face
in all of these pictures?
Okay, okay.
Say she's the ex.
We still don't know
she's actually been here.
There are strands of red hair
all over the studio.
Should we tell Robert?
How psychic would that be?
No. We'll spend
the night. It's fine.
Catch up with the ex tomorrow,
talk to her,see what's going on.
Meanwhile, I'm
going to do some sit-ups.
Come hold my feet.
I'm going to do a thousand!
Shawn! Get up!
What?
Fire!
Aah! Aah!
Ah! Get... Get Robert!
I could've died.
If you guys weren't here, I...
why is it doing this to me?
Why is it trying to kill me?
Okay. Okay.
Robert, hey, hey, hey.
Hey. Bobby. Look at me.
Now, who here
has communicated with more
dispossessed souls? You or me?
You?
That's correct.
Now I am telling you
that this, this fire,
was not an attempt on your life.
It wasn't?... No.
This was a sad and
desperate cry for help
from a very
frightened,very lonely apparition.
Are you sure about this?
Absolutely.
Of course,it's also possible
that someone simply
left a candle burning.
I don't burn candles.
Gus, did you burn a candle?
Why would I do that?
Cry for help it is.
No one came in
while we were sleeping.
I checked the
doors and the windows.
They were all locked...
from the inside.
Why are you
looking at me like that?
That's all you did?
Check the doors and the windows?
Yeah. Why?
Where did that come from?
Don't look at me.
I'm not wearing lipstick.
This is the only post office box
listed for Regina Kane.
According to dr. Blinn's calendar,
she was his last appointment.
She might have seen something.
I want to find her.
Well, if this is
where she picks up her mail,
she probably lives close by.
Canvass the neighborhood.
See if anyone knows her.
That's a really smart approach.
What? That... that shocks you?
I meant that as a compliment.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, thanks a lot.
Was that sarcastic?
No.
Oh.
Okay.
You're welcome.
You still think
it's the ex-girlfriend?
A woman scorned
is a woman with motive.
We need to talk to this woman.
You're on your own.
I'm tied up with work
for the rest of the week.
Gus, that's so lame.
Ooh! Pull over.
Good morning, detectives!
Collecting donations
for the policeman's ball?
We don't have balls.
I honestly have
no response to that.
Need I remind you, mr. Spencer,
what happens when you interfere
with a police investigation?
Uh... the case gets solved?
Wait a minute!
You guys are working on
that murder thingy,right?
I completely forgot about that.
How's that going?
Silly question.
We'll let you get
back to your investigating.
Bye, Juliet.
Okay, where to next?
Listen, we change our clothes,
we get some lunch,
and I have to get back to work.
Gus, the plot is thickening.
Shawn, I've already
missed two days this week.
Oh, fine, fine, fine.
I respect your wishes.
Thank you... jerk chicken?
You know that's right.
Oh, boy.
There he is!
What time is it?
Daytime.
What happened?
I might have
dropped six allergy pills
in your frosty
while you were peeing.
You did what?
Where are we?
Palo Alto.
San Francisco?
No, but close.
Robert's
ex-girlfriend lives up here, Gus,
and we really need to talk to her.
I will kill you,Shawn...
and then you're going to
buy me some new tires.
Oh, come on, this is fun.
Road trip.
Kidnapping.
That's exactly what this is.
That's it,we're not talking.
What, seriously?
So, we're really not talking now?
Come on,how mature is this?
The silent
treatment is not how conflict
gets resolved, Gus.
We need to work through this.
We need to share our feelings...
maybe a smoothie.
Yes?
Never mind.
It's not her.
Pardon me.
What do I mean,it's not her?
Lips.
Lips don't match.
Lips that kissed your forehead
do not belong to Amy Kessler,
therefore she's not our ghost.
You didn't drive
all the way out here
so you could
say,"it's not her,"and leave?
"We're talking to hep. "
"Her. "
"Carlton...
separation means apart. "
Whatcha got there?
Nothing.
Are you okay?
Of course I'm okay.
You look sad.
I am sad.
Why are you sad?
I'm sad because I don't have my
forensics report on my dead doctor,
or a lead on my
possible witness, Regina Kane.
What about that psychic guy?
Isn't Shawn great
at this sort of thing?
Finding people?
Maybe we should bring him in...
maybe you should just
keep your ideas to yourself.
That's a joke, right?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Okay.
Very nice.
Exquisite brush strokes.
It's a print.
I'm referring, of
course, to the original.
I'm sorry...
what's the name of
your gallery again?
That's been a bit
of a problem, actually.
We wanted to call it...
"Le Petit Louvre"...
But apparently,
the art snobs in France think
they have a monopoly
on all things "Louvre".
We also tried "Louvre II"...
"Louvre Junior"...
night gallery.
Nothing cleared.
The important thing is,
we want to show the amazing work
of Robert Dunn,
and he listed you as a character
reference.
We are very select with the clients
that we take on.
Isn't that right, François?
I have to admit,
I'm surprised Robert would list me
as a character reference.
We dated for a period,
and it didn't end well.
Can I ask why?
Not to pry,
but he did list you as a reference.
The usual.
Forgetting dates.
Standing me up.
Sometimes he'd get so wrapped up
in his work
he'd disappear for days at a time.
The worst was when he cheated
on me and lied about it.
You must have been
burning with furious anger.
It was just so stupid.
A girlfriend of mine saw him
in a club with another woman.
He was drunk and pretended that
she had him
confused with someone else.
He said his name was...
get this...
Martin Brody.
Martin Brody?
Roy Scheider's character from "Jaws"?
Yes.
How'd you know?
Well, I've seen "Jaws".
It's his favorite movie.
Anyway, when I asked him about it,
he pretended he'd never
even heard of the club.
That's, uh...
Horrible.
You must have wanted to kill him.
But...
probably not so much anymore.
You're pretty
happily engaged, aren't you?
Yes.
Isn't the ring great?
Okay, so she's not our ghost.
Even the longest journeys can
start with a tiny misstep.
Overall, it was
still a very good day.
How was it a good day?
Oh, come on, Gus.
First of all, road trip.
Always fun.
We got some fresh-baked sourdough.
Very nice.
And the agency's sending us
a new secretary tomorrow.
And yes,
she speaks english, fluently.
Shawn, we talked about this.
We can't afford a receptionist.
I don't think we can
afford not to have one.
- Gus?
- What?
I think maybe we should move.
Come on, Gus!
Get in gear!
Go, go, go!
The guy's like a whippet.
Tell me about it.
What's the supersmeller say?
Somebody had too much to drink.
What are you so happy for?
We almost got killed.
This was not an accident.
Whoever that is was waiting for us,
and we have a new
suspect for Robert's ghost.
He didn't answer his phone.
Maybe he's not home.
Robert?
Or maybe...
whoever tried to kill us last night
also paid Robert a visit...
and left the door unlocked.
Anybody home?
Robert?
Bob?
Shawn, you might want to see this.
"Save me. I'm trapped. "
I don't want to
jump to conclusions here,
but this very well
may be a cry for help.
Maybe someone died here...
or was buried alive.
This could be the
cry of a tortured soul.
So this guy just
happens to move into
two haunted houses in a row?
Don't touch that.
It's blood.
It's not blood.
Enjoy your hepatitis.
And this tortured soul might be
less tortured with a latex enamel.
He wouldn't get these messy drips.
Now what?
I've got it. I've got it.
I've got it.
Hallelujah!
What?
You've got to see this.
Not what I was expecting.
Okay,
I know what I'm looking at, but...
what does it mean?
Is it a ghost?
No, buddy,
it's not a ghost.
Is there a woman living up here?
That would certainly explain
the perfume Robert's been smelling
and all the red
hair laying everywhere,
but no, no dice.
Then what is it?
Come on, Gus.
Look.
What?
Robert is a woman.
No, he's not.
Not all the time,
but sometimes.
No,
doesn't seem like the type.
He's not the type.
Then how?
Unless he has
that personality thing.
What personality thing?
Oh, you know what
I'm talking about...
the multiple personality disease.
You know, that...
what's-her-name had.
The flying nun,
in the other thing, the tv movie.
"Smokey and the Bandit"?
Yeah, dude.
"Smokey and the Bandit".
Yes.
What does that have to do with
multiple personalities?
You asked.
I asked a real question.
Give me a real
answer, not a random guess.
Okay, fine.
Hooper.
Hooper?
Hooper was a stunt man.
I don't think Sally
Field was even in "Hooper".
Who are you thinking of?
You know.
Terry Bradshaw.
Yes.
Is it Norma Rae?
No,
but that would have
made that movie a lot cooler.
The thing you're
asking about, Shawn,
is referred to as
dissociative identity disorder.
That's it!
That's what Robert has, Gus.
It all makes sense.
Do you know how rare that is?
I'm not saying all of
Santa Barbara has it.
Just Robert, one guy.
I think that
qualifies as pretty rare.
I don't know, Shawn.
These are huge.
Look.
Think about it.
Two separate but
distinct personalities, one body.
One's a man,
the other's a woman.
The female
personality cooks dinner.
Robert thinks the meals
are the work of a ghost.
The female
rearranges the furniture.
Robert thinks,
the ghost is moving
things when he's not around.
His old girlfriend did say that he
would disappear for
stretches at a time,
which would explain.
When the female
personality was in control,
Robert would disappear.
And he would have no
clue about any of it.
Now, all we need to figure out is
how to bring out the woman
so that we can talk to her.
Okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Triggers.
Shoot him?
Then what?
No, no.
Sights, sounds, smells.
Something that would trigger
the personality to come out.
Triggers it is.
Gus, this is...
this is going to be kind of cool.
Or weird.
Where did all this stuff come from?
Is this where she lives?
The... the...
the angry female
spirit that you sensed?
Yes.
I feel her very
strongly here, Robert.
Do you?
Do you feel...
pretty?
What?
Do you feel pretty?
He...
he means, do you
feel a female presence?
No,
but I'm not psychic.
Do you think that you can,
Communicate with her?
I'm trying.
I am.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
You guys are
starting to creep me out,
so if I'm not needed,
I think I'll go back downstairs.
Okay.
Let me just put this away.
We'll all go down together.
You coming, Shawn?
Yes.
Robert.
These are some terrific clothes.
I bet they look
absolutely beautiful on you...
Regina.
Regina? Who...
who are you talking to?
Yes.
Yes, Gus.
Why don't you tell...
Regina...
how much you like her nice clothes?
Yeah, Regina.
Regina.
You look beautiful.
Regina...
Thank you, Gus.
I can't tell you how glad
I am that you got my message.
So...
do you think that you can help me?
Please?
Dude.
This isn't right.
I must look horrible.
No, not at all.
You are too kind, but,
then again, I already knew that.
The way you comforted Robert...
you were so sweet...
unlike most men.
Afraid to show their emotions.
I've been hurt a lot.
Now, if you two don't mind,
I really must put on my face.
So, Regina,
this message on the wall,
this was your way of trying
to get Robert's attention?
He doesn't even know I'm alive.
Why not write him a letter,
or an e-mail,
or even a post-it, even?
I tried.
I really did try.
But every time,
something or someone stopped you.
What are you talking about?
I think there's
another personality.
Regina,
there's another
personality, isn't there?
I mean, you don't smash
pictures or start fires.
You would never strangle Robert.
No, I wouldn't.
Regina, the police
would like to speak with you.
They're
investigating dr. Blinn's murder.
They think you
might have seen something.
You could be in danger.
I didn't see anything.
I didn't even go to my appointment.
Why would anyone
want to hurt dr. Blinn?
He was such a nice man,
and he was doing
so much to help me.
With what?
You ought to know
better than to ask that.
That's between a
woman and her doctor.
Okay.
Unless you're going to ask her out,
I think we're done here.
How do we get Robert back?
I have no idea.
You're her very special friend.
Regina?
We would like to speak with Robert.
Can you let
Robert come out and play?
For you?
Of course I can.
Thank you.
And I do hope that we meet again.
Robert?
Try "Bob. "
Easy, easy, easy, easy, easy.
We know it seems weird...
and... And...
and actually, it is.
It's really weird.
But we have good news.
We figured out who your ghost is.
Who?
You.
You're haunting yourself.
Life is good.
Life is great.
Robert gets the help
he so desperately needs,
and we get to
marinate in the delicious
satisfaction of
another job well done.
Leading Lassiter to Regina,
even though she saw nothing?
That's professional courtesy.
Plus, it helps
raise our stock, Gus.
Crime scene photos!
Love crime scene photos.
May I help you?
Detective O'Hara.
What a truly pleasant surprise.
I just dropped by to tell
detective Lassiter that I have...
we...
Have information regarding the
whereabouts of a one Regina Kane.
How did you know about...
never mind.
Stay right here.
Don't move.
I'll go find him.
Shawn?
Shawn, don't do this.
Gus, look at this!
Look, look, look!
- What?
- Here,
on the floor,
where poor dr. Blinn's
body was laying.
A toothpick.
A chewed toothpick.
So?
Don't you remember?
The car that tried to rammed us?
On the seat?
Chewed toothpick.
That means...
the person that killed dr. Blinn is
the same person
that tried to kill us.
It's a chewed toothpick, Shawn.
Lots of people chew toothpicks.
Yes, but we were
working for Robert.
Robert is also Regina.
Regina is a patient of...
dr. Blinn.
Yes! Take the baton!
So whoever the killer is
knew both Robert and Regina.
He said his name was...
get this...
Martin Brody.
How dumb is that?
Of course.
That's Robert's
other personality...
the violent one.
But why would he kill dr. Blinn?
That depends entirely on what
Regina was seeing him for.
You've got to be kidding me.
What?
Dr. Blinn's patient files.
All we have to do is find Regina's.
What are you doing?
Shooting.
It relaxes me.
Shawn Spencer says he
has information for you.
Where is he?
At your desk.
Is anyone watching him?
Found it.
No.
What?
Gender reassignment?
Regina's tired of feeling like
a woman trapped in a man's body,
so she wants to have her parts...
my g...
wait a second.
That means, if
Regina was successful,
both Robert and
the Martin personality
would also lose their parts.
But Martin can't do
anything to hurt Regina,
because he'd only
be hurting himself.
So,
dressed as Regina,
he goes after dr. Blinn.
That would explain how Robert
got the marks on his neck,
and with dr. Blinn dead,
Robert figured that
Regina would change
her mind about the
gender reassignment.
Right!
We got that!
Only she hasn't.
Gus.
No, no.
She found another doctor.
She's seeing him.
Today.
When?
Right now.
Right now, Shawn?
Like in 10 minutes.
Okay.
There had better be a really
good explanation for this.
He was in some sort of trance.
I couldn't control him.
He says this is the killer.
Kill...
he's going to kill again.
This is ridiculous.
Who?
Who's he going to kill?
What is it, Shawn?
Watch out,
watch out!
Watch out!
Dr. Drake?
Gender reassignment?
That's a big step, Regina.
Why don't you tell me
why it's important to you.
It's okay.
The machine can get that.
This is your time.
Thank you, dr. Drake.
No answer.
It's just the machine.
We have to go now.
It could already be too late.
Let's go.
I know this can be
a difficult process,
but it really is necessary to
ensure that
you're ready psychologically
for a change like this.
You do seem like an excellent
candidate for surgery.
Our time is up.
Why don't we pick up here again
next week, okay, Regina?
Okey-dokey.
Only...
my name is not Regina.
Hold it!
Get up!
What's going on?
Robert?
Bob?
You back there, buddy?
What am I doing here?
Great.
Thanks.
Good news.
They're going to admit Robert into
the H. T. Windsor
facility in Chicago,
and his doctor thinks
his prognosis is good.
Don't you understand, Shawn?
That's the premier mental health
hospital in the country.
Yeah, that's good. That's awesome.
Who is that?
Leslie.
No.
No, no, no, no.
Leslie is supposed
to be a swimsuit model.
Unfortunately,
he is,
although he says he's getting
completely sick of the grind.
I have to call the agency.
They're completely misrepresenting
their clientele.
Leslie's a guy's name, too.
Okay.
We have to fire him.
Fire him?
On what grounds?
What grounds?
On the grounds that he's a dude.
That's discrimination.
We can't do that.
Okay, listen to me.
No woman is going
to look at us twice
if we're sharing our office with
that ridiculous adonis.
He's better-looking than both of
us put together.
Yeah.
I'm not doing it.
Gus.
You know I can't fire people.
They look too sad.
This was your idea.
Figure it out.