My name is Bridget,
I witnessed a murder.
Just get up on the stand and
tell the judge what you saw.
- We'll protect you.
- You don't get it.
If Bodaway wants me dead, I'm dead.
I ran to my sister Siobhan for help.
Siobhan? Siobhan?
Siobhan killed herself,
and I assumed her identity.
It was so easy.
I saw a way out, and I took it.
They all think that I'm her.
Her husband.
- Her lover.
- Make a choice...
him or me.
Her best friend.
I think Henry's having an affair.
I believe Siobhan Martin
is harboring a fugitive,
and the more I find out about her,
the closer I get to Bridget.
Siobhan, we have a problem.
Bridget's still alive.
♪ Hold me darling, hold me tight ♪
♪ I will let you lead with me
tonight ♪
♪ hold me, darling... ♪
You're here.
Um, have you given
any thought to dinner?
I was thinking about
that Chinese place.
You know, the one around the corner.
Siobhan hates that Chinese place
on the corner, Bridget.
What did you just say?
Bridget Kelly.
That's your name, isn't it?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
They found your bag
at the bus station.
They thought it belonged to Siobhan.
It was full of clothes
that she would never wear.
It didn't make sense.
But then I found
this driver's license...
...With Siobhan's picture
and Bridget Kelly's name.
It's not what you think.
What have you done with Siobhan?
I didn't do anything.
We... we were on the boat,
and she died.
You let her drown.
I didn't. I swear.
I-I wanted to save her. I tried.
You've lied to us all.
Me, Henry, Gemma.
Andrew, I'm so sorry.
I never meant to hurt any of you.
Don't apologize to me.
Apologize to her.
Shiv?
You okay?
Yeah.
You haven't slept well in weeks.
This can't be good for the baby.
You know, maybe I should just
get out of the city.
That might be good for me.
I could go to the Hamptons.
By yourself?
Just for the weekend.
You know, um, I could use
some time on my own.
You want to be alone
on your birthday?
Oh, my God, I...
Everything going on, I...
I lost all track of time.
You, forget your birthday?
Look...
I know you're upset
about what happened last year,
but I had hoped you'd give me
a chance to make it up to you.
I thought we were supposed
to be making a fresh start.
No, I-I want that, too.
I... I like how things
have been between us lately.
Well, if you want to get away
to the Hamptons, let's go.
We can celebrate your birthday
on the beach like we used to.
I'd like that.
I'm sure I could
finish up work early.
We could drive out this afternoon.
There's no reason for you to rush.
I... I'll just take
the jitney this morning.
The jitney?
Yeah.
Really, shiv?
I mean, whatever next?
A new found appreciation
for the subway?
Just trying to keep you on your toes.
I'll send the car service for you.
In fact, I'll take care
of all the planning.
We'll do the usual, huh?
Yeah.
You know, I've really missed
these weekends.
♪ ♪
Yeah, he's the one who came over.
We have cameras all over.
Hold on a second.
Let me call you back.
When did this come in?
Hamptons PD just e-mailed it over.
Smart move putting the duffel bag
back where you found it.
Looks like she's still in New York.
Only way she could know
about that bag
is if her sister told her.
Siobhan knows where her sister is.
We're going to find Bridget Kelly.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Hey, Malcolm, it's me.
Uh, sorry to keep calling you.
Just haven't heard from you.
I hope you're not mad at me.
I know you don't want me
staying here,
but I'm doing okay.
Really.
I just hope everything's
okay with you.
Will you call me, please?
I miss you.
Siobhan?
You're here early.
I pawned off my work on Olivia.
Who wants to be in the city
when you can be on the beach?
Water's
so calm today.
Can't wait to get the boat out there.
I'll pass on that.
It just... the thought
of it makes me nauseous.
Of course... the baby.
Work?
It's just one text, shiv.
I promise, what happened last year
is not going to happen again.
I should never have left you
at dinner,
no matter what
was going on at the office.
We were in such a bad place.
I had no idea
if you even wanted me around.
I...
Look.
I am done with work for the weekend.
This year,
I'm going to make your birthday
the best birthday ever.
It's been a long time
since anyone's done that for me.
Okay, what you're
talking about is not football.
It's soccer, okay?
And you have to admit
it's kind of boring.
So you're telling me all those games
you sat through
cheering and screaming,
you were faking that?
Getting worried.
What else were you faking?
Stay here.
I thought you guys were calling
when you got close.
Sorry. We... we didn't
hear you come in.
We were just having a discussion,
and then he wasn't looking,
and the vase broke.
No, you threw it at me.
Is everything okay?
It's fine.
It's just a misunderstanding.
We'll pay for the vase.
Anyway...
Happy Birthday.
Thank you. I...
I didn't realize
you guys were coming.
Andrew said we were doing the Siobhan
birthday getaway, like old times.
Assumed you were expecting us.
We were.
Didn't think you'd be
letting yourselves in.
We can leave.
We should leave.
I was really looking
forward to a weekend away.
No work, no kids.
Look, if you guys want
to stay, we'd love
to have you, wouldn't we?
Please, stay.
It'll... it'll be a great weekend.
I, um...
I'll go get the bags.
Sorry.
Ah, think nothing of it.
Bridget Kelly fled from police
in Wyoming on September 6,
the night before she was
scheduled to testify.
Now, thanks to the bag
you recovered at the bus station,
we know that Kelly was here
in the Hamptons
on or before September 9.
Then she disappeared.
Siobhan sent Bridget that letter
long before Bridget was on the run.
And the woman can talk
her way out of anything,
so confronting her about the bag
will more likely than not
get me nowhere.
Unless I have hard evidence...
something that proves
that Martin and Kelly
have been in contact.
If I can find that,
then I have probable cause
for search warrants and phone taps.
And hell, I can even charge Siobhan
with obstruction of justice.
Oh. Those eyes you asked me
to put on Siobhan Martin...
came up with an unidentified car
at the Martin house.
We ran the plates.
Henry and Gemma Butler.
That's very interesting.
Why is that?
Takes a brave woman to share a house
with her husband and her lover.
What was that back there?
When Andrew called, I was so excited.
And then Henry and I
fought all the way here.
By the time we arrived,
I was so fed up, I lost it.
I'm trying to believe him when
he says he's not cheating.
Every bone in my body tells
me he's up to something.
I thought coming out here
would be good for us.
We used to love the Hamptons.
Now we can't even make it
through a two-hour car ride.
If you love him,
you have to fight for him.
You'd tell me if there
was anything I could do, right?
Thanks.
God, I'm sick of hearing me talk
about this.
I am going to check out
that adorable little
store around the corner,
pick up something for the twins.
Okay. Think I'm going to finish up,
and see you back at the house.
I want you to know how
much it means to me
that I can talk to you
about all this stuff.
You're an amazing friend.
Like a sister.
Hey, Bridget over here!
Oh Siobhan, it's beautiful.
One day I'm gonna have one of those.
We should buy something
for our birthday.
Mom gave us money.
20 bucks?
We'll find something.
Like...
...Those! They're pretty and cheap.
Not cheap enough.
But it's our birthday.
I know. We're supposed
to have tons of presents
and a crazy party.
I hate being poor.
When I get older, I'm going
to have everything I want.
I just really want that.
We could always buy one and share.
I don't want to share.
We won't know whose turn it is.
We'll make it simple.
It'll be your turn for a year.
And then on our next birthday,
it'll be my turn.
And then yours.
Like, forever?
That's kinda cool.
Gemma Butler?
Can I help you?
I hope so.
I have a few questions.
About Siobhan Martin?
No, about Bridget Kelly.
Siobhan Martin's twin sister.
You were gone a while.
The boys went golfing.
And I found a backlog of
six-months of trash magazines.
Did you know that Angelina Jolie used
to let her kids eat crickets?
Why didn't you tell me about Bridget?
What?
Your twin?
An FBI Agent just told me about her,
how she's on the run from the police.
You spoke to the FBI?
Agent Machado?
What did you tell him?
Nothing because I don't know
anything.
I've known you for five years, shiv.
I had no idea
you had a sister. A twin?
How do you keep that hidden?
We're not a part
of each other's lives.
My sister...
Did something unforgivable.
What?
She ruined her life.
Just... one bad choice after another,
till I didn't even
recognize her anymore.
I'm ashamed of what she did.
Do you have any idea where she is?
No.
I should have been able
to help her... save her.
Just when I thought I had her back,
she was gone.
Sweetie, I'm so sorry.
I haven't told Andrew.
Really? Why?
I met Andrew after the fallout.
I didn't know how to bring it up.
I mean, I know I need to tell him,
I just... I'm not ready.
Well, he won't hear it from me.
God, Siobhan, all these years,
I never would have guessed.
You're always so excited
about your birthday.
But it must have been eating you up
not being able to share it
with your sister.
It was our special day.
I miss her.
I thought I was clear.
I don't want to see you.
It's our birthday.
Red velvet... your favorite.
You're moving?
Yeah... to New York.
I met someone.
Siobhan, you can't just run away.
Don't you dare lecture me on what
I can and can't do.
Andrew loves me.
I can start over.
I never want it back.
Bonjour.
Excuse me.
Tyler, I've been trying to reach you.
I was busy with work.
You're not working right now.
May I borrow you just for a minute?
Sure.
I'm really sorry about how
things ended the other night.
I was really sick.
Yeah, it's no big deal.
Besides, I met Simone.
She doesn't speak
a lot of English, but then again,
she doesn't have to.
Tyler, I like you... a lot.
We had a connection.
Is that how you connect with people...
shove them out of your hotel
room without a second thought?
Look, I got to get back.
It was, uh, great meeting you.
Have a lovely stay in Paris.
Hello.
I hit a snag.
Look who's here.
It's just like old times.
All day, all I could think
about was this moment...
wondering if you were going
to show up,
whether... if we were going
to sneak off
or just, you know, do it right here.
What the hell are you doing?
How many times do I have
to tell you it's over?
Are you kidding me?
I was ready to leave.
You were the one
that asked me to stay.
With your wife, to
celebrate my birthday.
This is how we celebrate.
This is our place.
With them sleeping upstairs?
What is wrong with you?
It's like you've forgotten
the last year existed.
Don't you remember
how happy we used to be?
♪ Spend with you ♪
♪ fell through my hands and went by ♪
♪ without me understanding you ♪
♪ you ♪
♪ I beg you, let me inside ♪
♪ don't think of me as unkind ♪
♪ I was discarded by my own mind... ♪
I'm so happy you changed your mind.
I always wanted to be here with you.
I just had to keep up
appearances, or so I thought.
I take it you didn't have
trouble getting away?
Uh-uh.
Emergency work meeting.
Olivia actually showed
up at the restaurant.
You should have seen
the look in her eyes
when he left me there
all alone.
Wow.
So Happy Birthday to you.
Happy Birthday to me.
Hurry up and finish your book.
I don't want to be apart
from you another day.
I'm trying; Work is going slow.
The muses are not cooperating.
Excuse me, I thought I was your muse.
You are my muse.
Did you bring it with you?
I want you to read to me.
Uh-uh, it's terrible.
No, it's brilliant.
Come on, it's my birthday.
All right, I'll read it.
Hey, what's this?
Oh, I went
and picked up the mail.
I was hoping it was a present.
There's no return address on it.
I'm not picky.
I'll take presents from anyone.
Not exactly your style.
Who's it from?
An old friend.
We used to pass it
back and forth on our birthdays.
Hmm, that sounds sweet.
Why'd you stop?
You really don't want to
talk about this, do you?
I want you to read to me.
All right, but it's a first draft,
so please just be gentle.
Never.
Okay.
City burns by Henry Butler.
"The traffic
"in the city was worse
than usual that day.
"The smog rose hot off the grates,
"into the streets.
The mist parted
as the door to the taxi opened."
I haven't forgotten.
I'm ashamed.
And you know what?
You should be, too.
I-I don't want to hurt
Andrew or Gemma.
You don't give a crap
about Gemma or Andrew.
Maybe I didn't, but I do now.
What about me?
We were in love, Siobhan.
We had plans.
Somehow, overnight,
that all changed for you,
but where the hell
does that leave me?
I'm sorry.
I really am.
No, I don't want sorry.
I want you.
♪ Shall I speak the truth
or shall I bite my tongue? ♪
♪ this fighting talk is tiresome ♪
♪ I'm tired, I'm tired,
I need to close my eyes ♪
♪ but I know that home
is like a million Miles ♪
♪ no one sees us when we're
making waves, waves, waves ♪
♪ waves, waves, waves ♪
♪ and all I want to do
is walk away. ♪
Ms. Farrell.
Excusez-moi.
I need to speak with you.
In my office, s'il vous plaît.
Now's not really a good time.
It's important.
Neither of us wants to cause a scene.
But if you wish to
extend your stay here,
we must discuss payment
immediately.
My office is this way.
Hey, there you are.
If we leave now, we'll
just make the meeting.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
- Is everything okay?
- Very nice to see you again, monsieur Barrett.
I wasn't aware
that you knew Ms. Farrell.
She works for my company.
And we are about to
be late for the boss.
You know how he gets.
Please give my very best regards.
Will do.
Sorry to delay you.
Just please come see me
at your earliest convenience.
Thank you.
What's going on with you?
Just having a lousy week.
I've always dreamed
of coming to Paris.
I'd taken lessons for years.
This is my first trip.
My husband kept
promising to bring me.
When I left him,
I decided to come on my own.
Does he know you're here?
Guess you could say I ran away.
I had a plan.
I had money to live on.
But it's all just falling apart.
Somebody drained my savings account.
Can't afford my hotel.
And I can't ask anyone
back home for help,
because then he would know
I was here.
You think your husband
took your money?
I don't know.
I can't even really think about it.
I just know I'm not ready to go back.
And the most pathetic part of all:
Today is my birthday.
Wait.
Let me get this straight.
So you always wanted to come
to Paris, and now you're here,
on your birthday, miserable?
Pretty pathetic, huh?
Well, that is, at is not acceptable.
Come on.
We're going to go celebrate.
What about the brunette?
She's fun, but, uh...
I've always had a thing blondes.
Agent Machado.
Found a citation
from the local marina.
Somebody took the Martins'
boat out September 9,
and then returned it
to the wrong slip.
What's this have to do
with Bridget Kelly?
The timing fits.
We know Bridget was here that day.
I followed up by interviewing
everybody at the marina.
Nobody saw Siobhan or Bridget.
So then I checked local water cams,
radio traffic, coast guard
activity for that day.
That's when things got interesting.
Figured you'd want
to hear this for yourself.
Distress call, U.S. coast...
To Siobhan.
Happy Birthday, darling.
Thank you.
Sparkling cider.
Really?
Well, it is Siobhan's birthday,
and if she can't drink,
it hardly seems fair
for the rest of us to indulge.
Since when is life fair?
I can't believe all these presents.
It's too much.
You can never get enough presents.
And the personal chef?
I don't deserve all this.
We're just getting started.
You are happy with Giancarlo?
'Cause the last time
we were at Del Cavalieri,
you thought the branzino
was overcooked.
Oh, it's great.
I'm sure it's delicious.
Mmm.
Did you just eat meat?
Mm-hmm.
But you haven't touched meat for...
Three years.
I guess I just,
I've been really craving it
since I'm pregnant, and thought
today was as good a day as any.
Happy Birthday.
But it's our birthday.
We can always buy one and share.
Like, forever?
Hey, Siobhan.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm sure it's just the food.
Um, excuse me for one second.
"Dear Bridget,
"thanks for sending back
the necklace.
"Seeing it made me realize
how much I've missed you.
"I know it's not our birthday,
but I wanted to return it.
I hope you'll wear it
when you come visit me."
Happy Birthday, sis.
You're wearing it.
What?
The necklace.
I told you about this?
You don't remember?
You were, uh, pretty upset.
I guess... it's hard...
Thinking about her.
Your old friend.
You didn't, you didn't
tell me her name,
and you wouldn't put the necklace on,
but you couldn't stop staring at it.
Does this mean that you guys made up?
Wait. Last night, I was,
I was drunk and angry,
and I had no right
to talk to you that way.
No, you didn't.
Listen, I have watched you
with Andrew for years.
And you are so good at pretending,
that no one would ever guess
there is nothing there,
unlike, unlike me and Gemma.
Henry, don't do this.
But when you were with me,
it was like something else.
And you had this look, like...
Like I was the only person in
the world that mattered to you.
I lived for that look.
Tonight...
With Andrew...
You were looking at him that way.
I don't know what to say.
I just don't understand it, shiv.
But I do love you.
And if walking away
is what you want to be happy, then...
It's gonna kill me, but I'll do it.
It's what I want.
Okay.
That's not everything though.
You, um, you're pregnant.
And we both know...
We don't know.
That baby is ours.
Henry, can you just trust me?
Have the patience to know
that we'll figure this out?
Please?
Coming?
Hey.
Come on.
You okay?
Fine.
So, did I finally
get a birthday right?
It's stunning.
I... I don't know what to say.
♪ I'm staying ♪
♪ and if cupid's got a gun ♪
♪ then he's shooting ♪
This all looks incredible.
Thank you so much.
My pleasure.
Your favorite.
Gemma, can I interest you
in a little glass of vino?
You're finally letting us drink.
Sweet relief.
I can't believe you did all this.
It's amazing.
Oh, my goodness.
You gonna eat all these?
No, you're welcome to it.
Mmm.
Thank you, Andrew.
Thank you all for coming.
Bon appétit.
Cheers.
♪ So we're bound to linger on ♪
♪ We drink the fatal drop ♪
Oh, my goodness!
No singing. No singing.
Oh, come on.
No singing.
It's a piece of art.
We can't cut that.
Great looking cake, Andrew.
I-I can't.
I can't. I'm sorry.
♪ Then fall apart in parts. ♪
Gemma?
What's going on?
Did you say something to her?
No, no, I'll go... I'll..
No, no.
You stay. I'll go.
She'll-she'll talk to me.
Your breakfast, madame.
One night with me and you're
already speaking French?
Uh, one word a night.
This is gonna take a long, long time.
Thank God.
Maybe we should double up
on the lessons.
Mmm... mm... mm...
There is nothing that
I would like more.
Unfortunately, I have to go to work.
But first...
We never had cake last night,
and, we are in Paris, so...
Thank you. I love it.
Oh, uh, I ran into the manager
while I was downstairs.
I actually know him pretty well.
My company does a lot
of overseas business.
Clients travel here from all over,
so we have an account with the hotel.
It seems that he was
unaware that we have
a very valued client in town now...
Cora Farrell... who will be
staying here indefinitely.
Tyler, you can't do that. You
could get in serious trouble.
We have clients in and out
of town constantly.
No one even blinks at the charges.
I can't believe you did that for me.
You have no idea what it means to me.
It means that you can go
out with me again tonight.
Mmm. Have you seen
my tie, by any chance?
Um, check the bathroom.
Will do.
Ah...
For you.
Thank you.
I will pick you up at 7:00.
Okay.
The plan is back on.
Tyler Barrett just extended my
hotel stay, on the company dime.
This is gonna be easier
than we thought.
Gemma?
Gemma!
Please pick up your phone
or call me back, just...
Let me know you're okay.
I'm worried about you.
You really shouldn't leave your door open.
You can't be here.
This is private property.
This is a courtesy visit.
One last chance for
you to come clean.
I know you're lying to me.
Bridget was in the
Hamptons, with you.
This has to stop.
No more talking to my friends, my...
Hello? Hello? It's my sister!
Can anyone hear me?
Hello? It's my sister!
I bet you didn't know
the, uh, the coast guard
records all the distress calls
that it receives.
They have a dedicated channel.
Most radios are tuned to it
by default, so chances are,
you pick up your boat radio,
you're talking to the coast guard.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Cut the crap.
You were with your
sister on the boat.
Something happened that
made you make this call.
What happened?
Okay, you're right.
I was with my sister that day.
She showed up. I...
Because you invited her.
We found her duffel bag.
It was nice, at first.
We connected.
And then, Bridget told me
what she was mixed up in.
She was just trying to fix things.
I-I understand that now,
but at the time, I...
I was shocked, and...
We fought. I...
I was afraid that she might hurt me.
That's why I made the call.
I told her that was it.
I-I never wanted to see her again.
That was the last time I saw her.
How'd you know where to find
Bridget's duffel bag?
I found the key, after she had gone.
I thought it might be hers.
I went to get the bag to look,
to see if there was anything
that might lead me to where she was.
I'm just trying to do
the same thing that you are,
Agent Machado.
I'm just trying to keep Bridget safe.
Why'd you withdraw all
that money last week?
Because I needed it.
There's no law against spending
your own money, is there?
I don't know what you
want from me, Agent Machado.
I'm only trying to protect my sister.
You can search my house,
my apartments if you want.
You can follow me around
for the rest of my life,
but I promise you,
you won't find Bridget.
I think you know the way out.
Bridget's sponsor.
You never stop lying, do you?
Gemma, I've been looking
all over for you.
That's for sleeping with
my husband, you whore.
How could you? I thought you
were my friend, my best friend.
I opened up to you about
everything. God, you were
the one trying to convince me
Henry wasn't having an affair.
I'm so stupid!
- It's not what you think.
- I heard you, Siobhan. You and Henry.
How much he loves you.
How you're pregnant with his baby.
I'm so sorry that you heard
that, okay? I feel horrible...
Oh, I'm sorry.
You feel horrible?
I'm sorry, I don't
want you to feel bad.
Why don't you sleep with my husband
and see if that makes you feel better?
I didn't mean it like that, okay?
It's just, it's more
complicated than you know...
Hell yeah, it is.
Think of what this is
gonna do to Andrew.
Though I am going to enjoy the look
on your face when I tell him.
I hope you look exactly the way
I do now.
- Please don't do this. You don't understand.
- Get out of my way, you bitch.
Please, just look at me.
What, Siobhan? What?
Because there is nothing
you could possibly say
to me to make this okay.
I'm not who you think I am.
I'm not Siobhan.
I'm Bridget.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com