Welcome. I'm a Rhodium.
I'm just Iridium.
That's fine. I'm not a snob.
Sit down.
- You know what to do?
- I've been instructed, yes.
I'm very used to this. Don't be afraid.
I'm not.
Oh, my god! Are you okay?
A joy of controlling
how the hot water rises
before a torrent of pressure
penetrates the tamped beans.
Okay, I'm done watching
coffee porn.
How did instant get in my cupboard?
You are so impatient!
Maura, I just want a cup of coffee,
not a roman orgy.
- Morning. Morning.
- Oh!
Where are you going ...
a garden party?
- Going to work.
- Like that?
I think she looks beautiful.
And I love your shoes.
I haven't worn
high heels in a while.
30 years is more than "a while."
You know, there's a trick
to wearing high heels.
Yeah, I know ...
don't wear them.
Just slip these into your shoes.
- I can wear heels all day long with them.
- Yeah, she runs in hers.
Nice. Oh.
- Other one.
- See? It's easy.
How's that?
Nice.
And gushy.
Thanks.
- Bye, Mom.
- Bye.
I think my mom has
a gentleman caller.
- Your mother is a beautiful woman.
- My mother flosses in bed.
Oh. It's Hope.
- Answer it.
- What do I say?
"Hello, biological Mom Hope.
- My name is Maura. I didn't die at birth."
- Shut up.
No, you shouldn't say, "shut up."
Dr. Isles.
Oh, hello, Dr. Martin.
What a surprise.
Oh, yes, I-I would love
to have dinner with you.
Tonight would be great.
Uh, would you like to
come over to my house?
Sure, you ...
you can bring your daughter.
Okay, I ...
I will text you my address.
I-I look forward to it.
Okay, bye-bye.
Oh, my gosh.
Why did I invite them here?
The place is a wreck.
Oh, I'd be so embarrassed
- to invite anyone but me here.
- And what will I serve?
I mean, she probably has a more refined
palate than me.
Oh, saved by murder. Come on.
No, no, I-I can't go.
I have way too much to do.
Okay, I think I can
do an autopsy by now.
Well, I to take have a shower.
Maura.
Hot water gets shut off
in three minutes.
Bathroom's that way.
Running.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
3x06 - Money Maker
Wow. 3 million bucks?
Wow.
I didn't even ask her if she's a vegan.
What if she's allergic to shellfish?
- You just said she's a vegan.
- No, I did not.
You know, I can't pull
together a formal dinner
in ... what ... 10 hours.
Yeah, considering it takes you
4 hours to make a cup of coffee.
No. No, no, no, not
with the heavy breathing.
- No, stop, and I'll help you.
- I'm trying.
Okay, you call my mother.
All right? You flatter her.
You tell her what a great cook she is.
She eats that up.
She'll cook for you.
- Oh, it's such an imposition.
- Not if you invite her to dinner.
Somebody's Mercedes
got a parking ticket.
You run the plates?
What do we got?
A couple looking at
the house called police.
The real-estate agent is a handful.
Yay.
Is this your listing?
It's a beautiful property.
Georgette Wilkins. I have
many other properties.
It's all the exclusive
neighborhoods. Give me a call.
What makes you think I can't
afford a $3 million dollar home?
Well, cops' salaries...
never mind.
This house went into foreclosure
a year ago, while it was being renovated.
I almost had a sale.
Is all this really necessary?
Pretty necessary when there's a murder.
It wasn't a murder.
I'd say it's at least
a piece of a murder.
Division Detectives didn't
know what to make of it.
It's the entire
right fossa triangularis and the scapha.
You hear that, Korsak?
It's a whole fossil
triangle and a scaffold.
It's the right ear.
- Why is it 3 feet off the ground?
- It's listening through the keyhole?
Well, the minimum of blood
suggests that this ear
was detached postmortem.
Got a drop of blood out here.
It's not much, but I got
another drop over here.
- Hey, Jane.
- Yeah?
Mercedes is registered to Neal Murray.
And what's his car doing here
if he lives in Beacon Hill?
Do you know this man ...
Neal Murray?
No. Never seen him before.
Look, I have another listing.
You have my card.
- Run her.
- Got it.
You think there's a body
in the trunk of that car?
Georgette's clean.
Wait! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Stop, stop, stop! Put it down.
Okay. There you go.
He appears to be
wearing a cloak and a mask.
I think we found the body
that goes to that ear.
I'm not prepared to say conclusively
until I've tested tissue samples.
- Maura, he's got one ear.
- Looks like Neal Murray.
Something bad went down in that house.
Turns out our victim co-owns
an investment company.
What's a millionaire hedge-fund manager
doing in a garbage can
in a mask and a cloak?
Hiding?
Thank you, Sherlock Holmes.
What's this on his cloak?
It looks like jelly.
I'll have the crime lab test it.
Ooh, you got a treasure trove over here.
Where'd you find the blond hair?
- It was caught in this pin.
- Which is stamped "Rhodium."
Rhodium is a rare metal ...
the most valuable, in fact.
Hmm, the plot thickens.
My preliminary examination indicates
that he experienced a cardiac event.
It was quite an event.
Yeah, well, you haven't
heard the best part.
Let's talk about his penis.
If we must.
Not seeing much to talk about.
- You see the needle marks?
- No! I didn't look that close.
Consistent with treatment
for erectile dysfunction.
It's too bad he didn't
hear about viagra.
His heart condition prohibited it.
18 million american men suffer
from erectile dysfunction.
Injection therapy is very popular.
Oh, sure, yeah. Who doesn't
want to shoot up their privates?
The victim was left-handed.
I found seven injection sites
high on the left side of the shaft.
But the last injection site
was low on the right side.
So, a right-handed person injected him.
And the needle gauge
was much bigger, too.
Find out what was in that final
syringe.
Until we know, we can't
call this a murder.
Okay, I'm gonna go interview
his business partner.
Call me if you find something new.
Excuse me.
Hi, I'm Detective Jane Rizzoli.
This is Detective Barry Frost.
We'd like to talk to
you about Neal Murray.
What happened? We don't
know. We're investigating.
I'm his partner, Dale Bowman.
This is Doug and Lori Gatz.
Doug and I went to high
school right here with Neal.
Well, then, Neal was
supposed to be here today?
Yes, he was gonna give us a check
for a new athletic
complex and football field.
Hey, Doug, you'll get that check.
I can't believe he's gone.
- Could you give us a minute?
- Sure.
Uh, where were you last night?
- Home. Why?
- Any idea why your partner
would have been dressed
in a cloak and a mask?
No. What are you talking about?
Were you having any problems with Neal?
I loved the guy.
Plus, don't know if our company
will survive without him.
- Why not?
- He was a real people person.
He brought in all our big investors.
- We'd like a list of your clients.
- Oh, I'm happy to cooperate.
We have very high-end clients,
all the way down to Doug and Lori.
He's a coach.
She's the school nurse.
But they both have
pensions, thanks to us.
Maybe there was a
disgruntled investor ...
someone who lost money with the firm?
We don't lose money.
Somebody wasn't too happy with Neal.
It wasn't one of our investors.
That much I know.
I'll get that list for you.
Thank you.
We'll be in touch.
Take the gnocchi out of the
hot water, or it'll get sticky.
Jane, stir the wild-boar ragout.
Jane, can you open the Montepulciano?
Stirring boar.
Opening "montipoopanano."
Oh, my god. They're a minute early.
Oh, my god.
What if she saw this?
Just a minute!
Hide it in the bathroom.
Okay. Okay, okay.
Maura.
- Hi.
- Come in, please.
Dr. Isles.
This is my daughter, Cailin.
- Hi, Cailin.
- Hey.
And I think that we really are
settling into a ... a new city.
- Right, Cailin?
- Yeah. We are.
- How do you like Boston?
- I ... I miss London.
Honey, would you stop texting?
Sorry.
I'm just saying goodbye.
Are you in school?
- I was.
- Cailin was at Oxford.
- Oh.
- And you're not anymore?
- Well ...
- We had to move here.
Well, she needs to take a semester off.
Excuse me.
May I use your bathroom?
Of course. It's ...
it's right over there.
It's a complicated relationship ...
mothers and daughters.
Yes, it is.
- It's a phase.
- I hope so.
Cailin just misses her friends.
She doesn't know anyone here in Boston.
Tell me, did your mother
teach you how to cook?
- Actually, Angela made dinner.
- Well, it is delicious.
- Thank you.
- Mm.
My mother ... uh, she didn't
spend much time in the kitchen.
Uh, Maura's mother is an artist
and an art-history professor,
so she traveled a lot.
I traveled a lot when
Cailin was young, too.
Her father's my ex-husband....
he ... he had financial issues,
so I always had to work.
- That's hard.
- Look, Cailin's back.
I think I'll use your ladies' room, too.
Ah, good idea.
Cailin hates me.
She's 18.
She hates everybody over 18...
and under 18.
She's my sister, Jane.
Even when they know
they're related to you,
families are still complicated.
- Hey. This is pretty good.
- Oh, no, thank you.
Really? Not even one bite?
What are you listening to?
Oh. Music.
What kind of bands do you like?
It was nice of you to bring
the cake over. But it's okay.
You don't have to try to engage with me.
Are we that awful?
Will you tell my Mom
that I decided to walk home?
Wait, what?
It's not personal.
I just would like to be alone.
- Was that Cailin?
- She said she wanted to be alone.
Did Cailin leave?
Are you leaving?
She's very fragile right now.
Thank you for dinner. I'm so sorry.
What the hell just happened?
I don't think Cailin should have
been forced to have dinner with us.
Why weren't you this
evolved when I was 18?
Smells so good.
I'm so sorry about last night.
Why? It wasn't your fault.
What is that?
A chilled lavender towel.
Put it on your neck.
- No.
- It's very soothing.
It's used for treating amenorrhea,
athlete's foot, vaginitis.
I'm eating.
I don't need to be soothed.
Our victim's tox report came back.
No sign of his
erectile-dysfunction medication.
Still eating.
He was injected with something.
What was it?
I'm still testing.
I dissected his heart tissue.
And whatever drug was injected
did cause a heart attack.
There you are.
Hello, Dr. Martin. Hi.
Have a fabulous day. Call me later.
Hi.
- I feel the need to apologize for Cailin.
- No, please don't.
You know, I was 18 once,
and her life has been disrupted.
It's all right. I ...
I just feel bad for you.
Cailin is actually very ill, which
is why I brought her back to Boston.
Have a seat.
With what?
Can you say?
She contracted a bacterial infection
while I was doing relief work in Africa.
You can't blame yourself.
She's in desperate need
of a kidney transplant.
And of course, I would give her
one of my own in a heartbeat,
but... we're not a match.
And neither is her father.
It is so ironic.
I've helped so many patients,
and I cannot help my own child.
There must be something that I can do.
No, there isn't, but I
so appreciate the thought.
Got something.
Our victim was treated for chest pains
last week at the E.R. in Dedham.
Neal's next of kin is "heavy drizzle"?
- Who's that?
- Whoever took him to the hospital, I guess.
"Heavy drizzle"? The Drizz?
The famous crunk rapper?
Okay, check the list of
investors from Murray & Bowman.
See if "the Drizz" is on it.
I think his real name is Lamar Jones.
He once renegotiated
a recording contract
by hanging an executive from
his ankles off a balcony.
The Drizz!
"Crunk in the trunk" ... I love that song.
Okay, stop, stop.
What? Okay, Frankie.
- Stop, stop. Just...
- What?
- That's not how it goes, man.
- Aw.
If you're gonna do it, let
me show you how it's done.
All right.
All right, okay, so, it's, like,
side to side. Start side to side.
- Like this?
- Yeah.
- And then you just start to walk.
- I'm walking.
Okay, and then get ready.
Get ready. And then "aah!"
And then you bring this.
Yeah, there you go. Yes!
- You start smacking that.
- Smack it.
I'll show you thunk!
How's that? Would you
like some more thunk?
Keep doing that with your behinds.
I expect this
behavior from you, Francesco.
But not you, Barold.
- Why does she expect it from me?
- She likes Barold.
No idea why.
Let's get Mr. Drizzle
in here for questioning.
- Where you going, Jane?
- I got to go check on Maura.
Is that last night's dessert,
and am I about to get sick?
- I think we're a match.
- You're not really my type.
Me and Cailin.
I think we're having
different conversations.
Cailin needs a kidney.
So, you going to make
it out of that cake?
Of course not. I needed
a sample of her DNA.
Y-you can't give her a kidney.
It's my kidney.
I can give it to whomever I please.
Oh, so, you told Hope?
I'm going to donate anonymously.
You need any help getting it out, or
are you gonna do that by yourself, too?
What ... no, Maura.
What are you thinking? No!
Cailin's dying, Jane.
And Hope is overwhelmed.
The last thing she needs is to relive
the worst event of her life ...
my birth ... and death.
I guess I just don't get it.
If I ...
if I tell her who I am ...
I'll be a reminder of her tragic past.
I'll never be anything else to her.
- What? You only need one kidney.
- You're incredible.
You'd do the same for
one of your brothers.
Maybe.
They'd have to be really, really nice.
I'd definitely do it for you, though.
Your wretched lyrics
with tail shaking and behind flapping,
violent metaphors and images.
And you know something, mister?
Children are dying because of you.
- Shaking booty never killed nobody.
- "Anybody."
Who the hell is that?
That's a family-assistance counselor.
What kind of assistance
that sister offering?
Come on, Drizz.
Uh, posse waits downstairs.
- Frost?
- Hold on.
Uh, can I come?
Please?
All right, stand there
and don't open your mouth.
Nah, I ain't never met that dude.
That dude is your investment
adviser ... Neal Murray.
I got a lot of advisers.
Who advises you in murder?
Damn. Who did that man like that?
Maybe you.
Did he lose your money?
You're not a gangster anymore, Drizz.
You're a businessman
with a multimillion-dollar empire.
This kind of publicity
wouldn't be good for your brand.
Uh...
okay, Neal was my money man.
He brought me into his firm.
A diversified portfolio provides a buffer
against the vicissitudes
of the music industry,
So we were ...
What?
A homeboy can't know finance?
Let's talk about your visit
with Neal to the E.R., yo.
Look, Neal was a good dude.
He knew how to have crazy-ass fun,
but I needed my liquid capital back.
Neal said Dale wouldn't let
me have my own damn money back.
I'm still not hearing
anything about the E.R.
All right, I took Neal for
a spin on I-90 in my donk... yo.
Actually, it's my screen saver.
Nice. 28-inch chrome rims.
Officer... this is an interview.
How fast were you going in your... donk?
Oh, 55.
All right, all right.
Maybe a ... above 55.
Neal said it was giving him chest pains.
That's what you were
hoping for, wasn't it?
You told him you'd
take him to the hospital
if he'd give you your money back?
Eh, yeah...
something like that.
Neal told me not to tell Dale.
Neal gave me the money
out of his own pocket.
I feel like talking to old Dale again.
I'm ... I'm sorry
about playing that rap.
I've taught children for 55 years.
Some of the poorest
neighborhoods in the city.
It must have been challenging.
It was that, but it was also rewarding.
It was my life's work.
That's Dontrell.
He was in the last class I taught.
He was the loveliest,
sweetest little boy.
"Was"?
He died...
in a drive-by shooting.
Excuse me. I'm fighting a cold.
- I understand.
- Oh, yeah?
You understand the virus that's baffled
scientists for hundreds of years?
We're both trying to save the world.
Well, I couldn't save Dontrell.
- Stand back.
- What?
Take care of yourself, sister.
We'd like to talk to
you about Lamar Jones.
Who?
You might know him as Heavy Drizzle.
He's one of your investors.
Oh, yeah. Drizz.
Sure, I know him.
Why'd you make it so hard for him
to get his money out of your firm?
I run a hedge fund, Detectives.
I make a lot of money for
my clients if, and only if,
I lock in their money for a set period.
Did you know Neal gave
Drizz his money back?
I think it's time to tell
you to talk to my lawyer.
Have a nice day.
You see his key chain?
Just like the one we found on Neal.
Murray & Bowman's financial
statements are bogus.
There's no way they're
getting these returns.
This looks like a Ponzi scheme.
Explains why Dale
didn't want investors like
Drizz pulling their money out.
I know why Dale and our victim
carried the same key fob.
It's a flash drive.
Hmm.
It's taking me to a website.
10preciousmetals.com.
I'm in.
Neal was running an
underground sex club.
Drizz said old Neal knew
how to have "crazy-ass fun."
"To upgrade your investment,
contact your investment adviser."
10 different levels of call girls.
For 10 different levels of investors.
The more you invest, the hotter the girl.
Frost, click the link
that says, "calendar."
It's got party
dates and street addresses.
Look, two nights ago,
there was a secret sex party
at the vacant mansion
where we found Neal's ear.
- A "secret sex party"?
- What would you call it?
Entertainment.
Check some of the other parties.
See if they're at vacant homes.
They were. Good call, Jane.
Listing agent on all of
them was Georgette Wilkins.
I thought you ran her name.
I did. Nothing came up.
Maybe her name isn't
Georgette. Let's run her prints.
We don't have her prints.
Yes, we do. Georgette
gave me her business card.
Old-school has always wanted to try
new school's laser print scanner.
"Candy Smith."
Ooh, Georgette is a prostitute.
In fairness, she's a former prostitute.
Georgette sold Neal his house.
Neal and Dale were
desperate for investors.
So Georgette supplies the girls
in the houses she couldn't sell.
Neal throws the parties,
the rich whales swim in.
- Everybody's happy.
- So, why is Neal dead?
Thank you.
- Dr. Martin. Please come in.
- I'm sorry to barge in yet again.
There really was no one
else that I could talk to.
Well, you can talk to me.
Please.
Why is it so much
easier to tell a stranger
the most intimate details of your life?
Because a stranger doesn't judge.
Hmm.
My daughter.
I fell like I barely know her.
She's just so angry.
And she has the right.
I took her to a place
that made her sick,
and I've made her live my life.
I don't have children, but I ...
I think I understand.
Well, no one makes you know you've
failed the way your child does.
I think all daughters feel
that way about their mothers.
We fear that...
we won't measure up.
But it's a mother's job
to protect her child.
I've failed twice.
You said that you...
that your first baby died.
I mean, how ...
how can that be your fault?
And Cailin ... she's ...
she's a teenager.
You know, it's
her job to push you away.
It says that she's strong...
because of you.
Maybe.
Mass General called today.
They found a kidney donor for her.
It's an anonymous donor.
A complete stranger.
Maura, I'm afraid I've
already lost my daughter.
- Not to this illness, but...
- You haven't.
I know you haven't.
You have been so very kind.
The kindest of strangers.
We know you lied about your
relationship with Neal Murray.
I'm so sorry, officer. I have no
idea what you're talking about.
I'm late for a lunch appointment.
Drop the act, Candy.
Yeah, I knew Neal.
That isn't a crime.
Obstruction of
a murder investigation is.
I don't know how he died
or what he was doing in that house.
Maybe he was at a party for big,
fat investor whales,
and maybe you supplied the
high-class call girls for it.
- Maybe you were even there, Candy.
- Or maybe you don't have jack.
Excuse me.
I have a lunch appointment.
How does he know we're not members?
- Who you calling?
- The only member I know.
All right, well, where is she?
She couldn't have eaten
that fast.
Neal's latest tox panel came back
positive for potassium chloride.
Well, is that what stopped his heart?
Well, that's what was
injected into his penis.
Maura. You're gonna get us
kicked out of this place.
Why? Because I said
"potassium chloride"?
What are you having for lunch?
- What are "baby jewels and gems"?
- Lettuce.
We don't call those
"solid, vertical room separators."
- You mean the walls?
- Exactly.
Let-tuce.
Pre-ten-tious.
Ooh.
She's going to the bathroom.
- I'm coming.
- What? No.
I have to pee.
- You better be telling the truth.
- All mammals have to pee.
We got all day.
We know about the parties,
the super-secret precious-metal
code for the girls.
I'm homicide, Georgette, not vice.
Unless you killed Neal,
all I want to do is talk.
He was a nice guy.
Not much in the looks
department, but nice.
I didn't kill him.
Hi. It's safe to talk in front of me.
I'm working the case, too.
- Oh, are you?
- Yes, I am. I'm Dr. Maura ...
Save it. Who cares? Let's get
to the chase? What do you want?
Who was with Neal the night he died?
I don't know. It was busy.
Well, I know you supply the
girls, so give me their names.
Uh, let's see.
Caress, Delight, Peaches.
- I don't suppose you do
any background checks?  - No.
Well, you should at least
check for venereal diseases.
What are you, the health department?
We use the same girls every time.
The clients sign a release.
Informed consent. That's wise.
Look, you're gonna provide
these same girls again,
because one of them injected Neal
with potassium chloride and killed him.
And we're gonna find
her at tonight's party.
And if I don't?
Well, then you can say
buh-bye to all your fancy clubs
and say hello to
Framingham state prison.
Before we do anything, may
I have one of your hairs,
with the root ball attached, please?
What? Ew.
The hair we found on the victim
does not belong to Georgette.
Okay, so we go forward with plan "A".
Another undercover operation, Rizzoli?
Uh, we're just collecting hair samples.
Frost and Korsak will be there.
- I should be there, too.
- No, no, that's okay.
Uh, with, uh,
my comparison microscope.
- No, I don't think so.
- Dr. Isles is right.
She can go look at all the
samples and log them in.
- Preserve chain of custody.
- Okay, sure.
- Yes!
- What is your problem?
Oh. What are we going to wear?
I have never been a high-class
hooker before.
What?
I hate this outfit.
Stop complaining
about the outfits, already.
Why couldn't we dress up like
call girls? They look so cute.
They have to take their
outfits off, Maura.
Oh.
Let's find a place for your science kit.
Oh. Check out
the legs on that one.
That is the hottest part of a woman.
But I also like that little
"S" curve along the hip.
You know, like, when they ...
when they ... when they ...
When they lean back
like that and you just...
You guys know we can hear you, right?
Sorry. My bad.
One down.
17 to go.
That's the coach from Campbell high.
What the heck is he doing there?
Hitting on Georgette, it looks like.
His wife, Lori, is gorgeous.
Bill maher says, "show
me a beautiful woman,
I'll show you a husband who's
sick of sleeping with her."
How did he get the
money to hang out here?
- Wow. How you get in?
- What do you mean?
You're like, not even a ...
a Indium.
"An" Indium.
And, no, I am not.
So, what are you ...
like, Tin or something?
We're, like, aluminum foil.
Don't get all upset about it.
It's not my fault.
Ow!
Everyone here is a perv.
This cuticle thickness is close.
Aw. But the pigment
granules don't match.
Okay, last ones.
I'm gonna go track them
down in the leather room.
Leather certainly bears further study.
It's a historical fetish.
Think about it ...
corsets, dog collars ...
...whips, belts...
Is that Georgette?
Particles of type "N"
mortar from the pool coping
are embedded in the wound.
She hit the side
and lost consciousness in the pool.
- So, she was pushed in?
- Yes.
I'm ruling it a homicide.
And take a look... at this.
- Cubic zirconia?
- Hardly. Four carats, light yellow.
It looks like "fl/if."
Oh, no, that's a blemish.
What kind of hooker gets paid in carats?
- The girlfriend kind.
- Oh.
So, Georgette must
have hung up her mask?
Yeah. And no match on any of the
blond hairs from any of our call girls.
Thank you.
These are the results on the
jellylike substance on Neal's cloak.
- It's calcium acetate.
- Otherwise known as?
Canned butane gel.
It's used in food
service to keep food warm.
The caterers.
That's why we couldn't match
the hair to a call girl.
It's got to be from a caterer waiter.
- There's a print here.
- Could be the victim's.
I think a second person tried this
ring on. It's a different print.
So, as financial chair, I want to assure you
your investments are healthy.
I recommend that we stay the
course with Murray & Bowman.
We recommend you get
a new financial chair.
Excuse me?
You're under arrest for embezzling
your fellow teachers' pension money.
What?
What did you do, Doug?
Spent a bunch of money
on this diamond ring.
Mm. Lucky you, Mrs. Gatz.
Oh, wait.
That was for Georgette, wasn't it?
I don't know what you're talking about.
We found your prints on the ring.
We found Georgette's, too.
You tried it on before you killed her.
- Oh, god.
- We're thinking there was some pillow talk.
You told Lori about
Neal's heart condition,
his trouble getting it
up without an injection.
Handy that you're a nurse, Lori.
Pretty, too.
You snuck in with the catering,
and then you injected potassium chloride
into the man who ruined your life.
Did you know
Doug was having an affair?
Or did you figure it out
after you killed Neal?
This is insane.
Yeah, that's what we
thought when we saw you push
Georgette into the pool
on this surveillance tape.
This is your fault.
- We don't have a surveillance tape.
- She doesn't know that.
You couldn't let go of
your high-school buddies.
We were happy.
But you let Neal drag you in,
show you this life you
thought you were missing.
You fell in love with a whore.
- Let's go, Lori.
- Hands behind your back.
Cailin. Hi.
Come in.
Do you know at the name "Cailin" means?
- No.
- It means "uncertain."
That's the name that
my mother picked for me.
- "Maura" means "great."
- Yes, I know.
- That's the name she picked for you.
- Cailin, please let me explain.
Hmm.
Can you explain why you called
my mother out of the blue
with some bullshit story?
This is very complicated.
She's trying to bond with
me now, since I'm dying.
You know, make up for all
those years she wasn't there.
You're not going to die.
"Don't ... don't do what I did, Cailin."
Right.
Like I'm gonna have time to...
fall in love...
get pregnant...
have a baby...
...hold that baby once
before she dies.
You, um...
you put it back up.
I went snooping.
I found it in the bathroom.
I mean, it is my mother, isn't it?
And that's ...
that's your gravestone...
which is weird because...
you look okay to me.
Please just let me explain.
I didn't mean for any of this to ...
Do you have any idea what it's like
to grow up in the
shadow of a dead baby?!
I was never enough!
You are more than enough.
She loves you.
I know you think
I should have told her ...
- I should have told the both of you, but I ...
- Yeah. Yeah.
- I want to help you.
- I don't want your help!
And I don't want your kidney, either.
Yeah.
Yeah, I...
I thought that was you.
You just... you don't get
a match like that from a stranger.
Cailin, please, don't throw your life away
because of what you think of me.
I don't want any part of you
living in me.
Cailin!
What is going on?
- You followed me?
- Well, you took our car.
- So you called the police?
- Well...
Hope... there's something
I need to tell you.
I'm Paddy Doyle's daughter.
What?
I'm your daughter.
I know that must be strange to hear.
Don't say that.
This is my daughter.
Paddy told you that I died at birth.
I am not looking
to be your daughter.
I ...
I have a mother and a father.
- I just wanted you to know...
- Just stop!
I don't know who you
are or what you want,
but I've had just about
as much as I can bear.
Cailin. Honey.
Let's just go.
I don't know what to say.
Out of all the scenarios I thought of...
that wasn't one of them.
She's in denial.
She's in shock.
Imagine, how would you react
if a grown woman walked
up to you and said...
"How you doing?
I'm your... dead baby."
And what about Cailin?
If she doesn't let me
help her, she'll die.
Maura, you can't force your kidney on her.
I wish I could.
I don't know. I never, ever
meant to cause them any pain.
It's just so awful.
Well, I tried to warn you.
Family sucks.
Blow.
No.
I'm all cried out. Okay?
I'm done.
And, actually, I'm a little insulted.
- What'd I do?
- That girl rejected my kidney.
The nerve.
I know.
Right? It's a very nice kidney.
I'm sure it is.
You should keep it...
in your body.
I'm just saying.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~