Sherlock.1x03.The_Great_Game.HDTV_XviD-FoV
English SRT Subtitles - UF (v1.00)
BALALAIKA MUSIC PLAYS
MAN OUTSIDE SHOUTS COMMANDS
Just tell me what happened
from the beginning.
We had been to a bar,
nice place, and, er, I got chatting
with one of the waitresses,
and Karen weren't happy with that,
so...when we get back to the hotel,
we end up having
a bit of a ding-dong.
HE SIGHS
She's always getting at me,
saying I weren't a real man.
Wasn't a real man.
What?
It's not "weren't", it's "wasn't".
Oh.
Go on.
Well...then I don't know
how it happened,
but suddenly
there's a knife in my hands...
..and me old man was a butcher,
so I know how to handle knives.
He learned us how to cut up a beast.
Taught.
What?
Taught you how to cut up a beast.
Yeah, well, then I done it.
Did it.
Did it! Stabbed her,
over and over and over, and I looked
down, and she weren't...
..wasn't...
..moving no more.
Any more.
God help me, I dunno how it happened,
but it was an accident, I swear.
You've got to help me, Mr Holmes!
Everyone says you're the best.
Without you...
I'll get hung for this.
No, no, Mr Bewick, not at all.
Hanged, yes.
TWO GUNSHOTS
DOOR OPENS
HE INHALES DEEPLY
DOOR SHUTS, HE SIGHS
GUNSHOTS
What the hell are you doing?!
Bored.
What?!
Bored!
No...
GUNSHOT Bored!
Don't know what's got into
the criminal classes.
Good job I'm not one of them.
So you take it out on the wall?
The wall had it coming.
What about that Russian case? Belarus?
Open and shut domestic murder. Not worth my time.
Oh, shame(!)
Anything in? I'm starving.
Oh, f...
There's a head.
A severed head!
Just tea for me, thanks.
No, there's a head in the fridge.
Yes? A bloody head! Well, where else
could I put it?
You don't mind, do you?
Well...
Got it from Barts morgue.
I'm measuring the coagulation
of saliva after death.
I see you've written up
the taxi driver case.
Er...yes.
A Study In Pink.
Nice.
Well, you know. Pink lady, pink case,
pink phone. There was a lot of pink.
Did you like it?
Um...no. Why not?
I thought you'd be flattered.
Flattered?! "Sherlock sees through
everything and everyone in seconds.
"What's incredible, though,
is how spectacularly ignorant he is
"about some things." Hang on,
I didn't mean that...
Oh, you meant "spectacularly
ignorant" in a nice way(!)
Look, it doesn't matter to me who's Prime Minister or...
I know. ..who's sleeping with who...
Whether the Earth goes round the sun.
That again! It's not important!
Not impor...?!
It's primary school stuff. How can you not know that?
Well, if I ever did, I've deleted it.
Deleted it?
Listen. This is my hard drive,
and it only makes sense
to put things in there
that are useful. REALLY useful.
Ordinary people fill their heads
with all kinds of rubbish.
That makes it hard to get at
the stuff that matters. Do you see?
But it's the solar system!
Oh, hell! What does that matter?!
So we go round the sun. If we went round the moon,
or round and round the garden like a teddy
bear, it wouldn't make any difference!
All that matters to me is the work!
Without that, my brain rots!
Put that in your blog! Or, better still,
stop inflicting your opinions on the world!
DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS
Where are you going?
Out! I need some air.
Oh, sorry, love! Sorry.
Ooh-ooh!
Have you two had a little domestic?
Ooh, it's a bit nippy out there.
He should have wrapped himself up
a bit more.
Look at that, Mrs Hudson.
Quiet.
Calm. Peaceful.
Isn't it hateful?
Oh, I'm sure something
will turn up, Sherlock.
A nice murder. That'll cheer you up.
Mmm. Can't come too soon.
Hey, what have you done
to my bloody wall?!
I'm putting this on your rent,
young man!
EXPLOSION BOOMS
CAR ALARM BEEPS
GROANING
Morning. Oh...m-morning. See?
Told you you should have gone with the Lilo.
No, no, no, it's fine, I slept fine.
It's very kind of you.
Well, maybe next time I'll let you
kip at the end of my bed, you know.
NEWSREADER: '..which was discovered mouldering...
' What about the time after that? '..18 months ago.
'Experts are hailing it as
the artistic find of the century...'
Do you want some breakfast? Love some.
Well, make it yourself. I'm going to have a shower.
'..It fetched over £20 million.
'This one is anticipated to do even
better. Back now to our main story.
'There's been a massive explosion
in central London.
'As yet, there are no reports of any
casualties, and the police are unable to say
'if there's any suspicion
of terrorist involvement.'
Sarah!
'Police have issued an emergency number...' Sarah! '..f
or friends and relatives.' Sorry! I've got to run!
Excuse me, can I get through?
Excuse me. Can I get through?
I live over there.
DOOR BANGS Sherlock!
Sherlock!
PIZZICATO NOTE John.
I saw it on the telly. Are you OK?
Me? What? Oh, yeah, fine.
Gas leak, apparently.
PIZZICATO NOTE
I can't.
Can't?
Stuff I've got on is just too big.
I can't spare the time.
Never mind your usual trivia.
This is of national importance.
PIZZICATO NOTE How's the diet?
Fine.
Perhaps you can get
through to him, John.
What? I'm afraid my brother
can be very intransigent.
If you're so keen,
why don't you investigate it?
No. I can't possibly be away from the office for any
length of time. Not with the Korean elections so...
Well, you don't need to know
about that, do you?
Besides, a case like this,
it requires...legwork.
FALSE NOTE
How's Sarah, John?
How was the Lilo?
Sofa, Sherlock. It was the sofa.
Oh, yes, of course.
How...? Oh, never mind.
Sherlock's business seems to be
booming since you and he became...
pals. What's he like to live with?
Hellish, I imagine.
I'm never bored.
Good. That's good, isn't it?
Andrew West, known as Westie
to his friends. Civil servant.
Found dead on the tracks
at Battersea station this morning
with his head smashed in.
Jumped in front of a train?
Seems the logical assumption.
But?
Well, you wouldn't be here
if it was just an accident.
Hah!
The MoD is working on a new missile defence
system, the Bruce-Partington Program it's called.
The plans for it
were on a memory stick.
That wasn't very clever.
It's not the only copy. Oh.
But it is secret.
And missing.
Top secret?
Very. We think West
must have taken the memory stick.
We can't risk it falling
into the wrong hands.
You've got to find those plans,
Sherlock.
Don't make me order you.
I'd like to see you try.
Think it over.
Goodbye, John.
Mm.
See you very soon.
REPEATS RAPID PHRASE
FOOTSTEPS FADE
Why did you lie?
DOOR SHUTS
You've got nothing on.
Not a single case.
That's why the wall took a pounding.
Why did you tell your brother
you were busy? Why shouldn't I?
Oh.
Nice.
Sibling rivalry.
Now we're getting somewhere.
MOBILE PHONE RINGS
Sherlock Holmes.
Of course. How could I refuse?
Lestrade - I've been summoned.
Coming?
If you want me to. Of course.
I'd be lost without my blogger.
'You like the funny cases,
don't you?'
The surprising ones.
Obviously.
You'll love this. That explosion.
Gas leak, yes? No.
No? No. Made to look like one.
What?
Hardly anything left of the place,
except a strongbox.
A VERY strong box,
and inside it was this.
You haven't opened it?
It's addressed to you, isn't it?
We've X-rayed it. It's not
booby-trapped. How reassuring.
Nice stationery.
Bohemian.
What?
From the Czech Republic.
No fingerprints?
No.
She used a fountain pen.
Parker Duofold, iridium nib.
She?
Obviously.
But that... That's the phone.
The pink phone.
What, from The Study In Pink? Obviously, it's not
the same phone, but it's supposed to look like...
"Study In Pink"? You read his blog?
Of course. We all do.
Do you REALLY not know that
the Earth goes round the sun?
SHE SNIGGERS
It isn't the same phone.
This one's brand-new.
Someone's taken trouble to make it look the same,
which means your blog has a far wider readership.
'You have one new message.'
FIVE GREENWICH TIME SIGNAL PIPS
Was that it?
No, that's not it.
PHONE BEEPS
What the hell
are we supposed to make of that?
An estate agent's photo
and the bloody Greenwich pips.
It's a warning.
A warning?
Some secret societies
used to send dried melon seeds,
orange pips, things like that -
five pips.
They're warning us
it's going to happen again.
I've seen this place before.
Hang on.
What's going to happen again?
Boom!
Mrs Hudson!
You had a look, didn't you, when you
first came to see about your flat?
The door's been opened, recently.
No, can't be. That's the only key.
I can't get anyone interested
in this flat.
It's the damp, I expect -
that's the curse of basements.
I'd a place once when I was first
married. Mould all up the wall...
Oh. Dear me.
Shoes.
He's a bomber, remember.
MOBILE PHONE RINGS
SOFTLY: Hello.
RAGGED BREATHING OVER PHONE
WOMAN: 'H-Hello...sexy.'
Who's this?
WOMAN SOBS
'I've...sent you...a little puzzle,
'just to say hi.'
Who's talking? Why are you crying?
WOMAN CRIES
'I...I'm not crying.
'I'm typing.'
And this...stupid bitch
is reading it out.
The curtain rises.
What?
Nothing. No, what did you mean?
I've been expecting this
for some time.
SOBBING: '12 hours to solve...'
..my puzzle, Sherlock...
or I'm going to be...
..so...naughty.
So, who do you suppose it was?
Hmm?
Woman on the phone -
the crying woman.
Oh, she doesn't matter,
she's just a hostage. No lead there.
I wasn't thinking about leads. You're
not going to be much use to her.
Are they trying to trace it -
trace the call?
Bomber's too smart for that.
MOBILE BEEPS Pass my phone.
Where is it? Jacket.
Careful!
Text from your brother.
Delete it. Delete it? Plans are out
of the country. Nothing we can do.
Well, Mycroft thinks there is.
He's texted you eight times.
Must be important. Then why didn't
he cancel his dental appointment?
His what?
Mycroft never texts if he can talk.
Andrew West stole the missile plans, tried
to sell them, got his head smashed in,
end of story.
The only mystery is why my brother is so determined
to bore me when somebody is being so interesting.
Try and remember
there's a woman who might die.
What for? There's hospitals
full of people dying, Doctor.
Why don't you go and cry by their
bedside and see what good it does them?
COMPUTER BEEPS Ah!
Any luck?
Oh, yes!
Oh, sorry. I didn't...
Jim, hi! Come in! Come in!
Jim, this is Sherlock Holmes.
Ah.
And, er... Sorry.
John Watson. Hi.
Hi. So you're Sherlock Holmes.
Molly's told me all about you.
You on one of your cases?
Jim works in IT, upstairs.
That's how we met. Office romance.
JIM CHUCKLES
Gay.
Sorry, what?
Nothing. Um, hey.
Hi.
CLATTERING
Sorry. Sorry!
Well, I'd better be off.
I'll see you at the Fox.
About sixish?
Yeah.
Bye.
It was nice to meet you.
You too.
DOOR OPENS
What do you mean, gay?
We're together.
Domestic bliss must suit you, Molly.
You've put on 3lb since I last saw you.
Two-and-a-half. No, three.
Sherlock.
He's not gay!
Why do you have to spoil...? He's
not! With that level of grooming?
Because he puts product in his
hair? I put product in my hair.
You wash your hair,
there's a difference.
Tinted eyelashes, signs of taurine
cream around the frown lines,
those tired, clubber's eyes.
Then there's his underwear.
His underwear?
Visible above the waistline.
Very particular brand.
Plus the suggestive fact that he
left his number under this dish.
I'd say you'd better break it off
now and save yourself the pain.
DOOR OPENS
Charming, well done(!)
Just saving her time.
Isn't that kinder?
Kinder? No, no, Sherlock,
that wasn't kind.
Go on, then.
Hm?
You know what I do. Off you go.
Oh... No.
Go on.
I'm not going to let you humiliate me
while I... An outside eye,
a second opinion - it's very useful
to me. Yeah, right(!) Really!
Fine.
CLEARS THROAT
Oh, they're just a pair of sh...
trainers. Good.
Um...
They're in good nick.
I'd say they were pretty new,
except the sole has been well worn, so the
owner must have had them for a while.
Er, very '80s.
Probably one of those retro designs.
You're on sparkling form.
What else?
They're quite big. A man's.
But...
But there's traces of a name
inside in felt-tip.
Adults don't write their names inside
their shoes, so these belong to a kid.
Excellent. What else?
Er...
That's it.
How did I do?
Well, John.
Really well.
I mean, you missed almost everything
of importance, but, you know...
The owner loved these.
Scrubbed them clean.
Whitened them. Changed the laces
three...no, four times.
There are traces of flaky skin where his fingers
have come into contact with them, so he had eczema.
The shoes are more worn on the
inner side, so he had weak arches.
British-made, 20 years old.
20 years? They're not retro,
they're original.
Limited edition -
two blue stripes, 1989.
There's still mud on them.
They look new.
Someone's kept them that way.
Quite a bit of mud caked
on the soles.
Analysis shows it's from Sussex
with London mud overlaying it.
How do you know? Pollen. Clear as a
map reference. South of the river.
This kid came to London from Sussex 20 years ago and
left the trainers behind. What happened to him?
Something bad.
He loved those shoes, remember.
He'd never leave them filthy.
Wouldn't let them go
unless he had to.
So, a child with big feet gets...
Oh!
What?
Carl Powers.
Sorry, who?
Carl Powers, John.
What is it?
It's where I began.
1989, kid, champion swimmer, came from Brighton for
a school sports tournament, drowned in the pool.
Tragic accident. You wouldn't
remember it. But you remember.
Yes. Something fishy about it?
Nobody thought so.
Nobody except me. I was only a kid myself.
I read about it in the papers.
You started young, didn't you?
The boy, Carl Powers,
had some kind of fit in the water,
but by the time they got him out,
it was too late.
There was something wrong somewhere.
I couldn't get it out of my head.
What? His shoes. What about them?
They weren't there. I made a fuss.
I tried to get the police interested, but
nobody seemed to think it was important.
He'd left all the rest of his clothes in his
locker, but there was no sign of his shoes.
Until now.
CLOCK TICKS
SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE
Can I help?
I want to help. There's only
five hours left. MOBILE BEEPS
It's your brother.
He's texting me now.
How does he know my number?
Must be a root canal.
Look, he did say...national
importance. Hmm!
How quaint!
What is?
You are. Queen and country.
You can't just ignore it.
I'm not ignoring it.
Putting my best man onto it
right now.
Right, good!
CLEARS THROAT
Who's that?
John, how nice! I was hoping it wouldn't be long.
How can I help you?
Thank you.
Um, I was wanting to...
Your brother sent me to collect
more facts
about the stolen plans -
the missile plans.
Did he?
Yes. He's investigating now.
He's, er...investigating away.
I just wondered what else
you could tell me about the dead man.
Er, 27. Clerk at Vauxhall Cross.
MI6.
He was involved in the Bruce-Partington
Program in a minor capacity.
Security checks A-OK.
No known terrorist affiliations or sympathies.
Last seen by his fiancee
10.30 yesterday evening.
Lucy, love, I've got to go out.
I've got to see someone.
Westie!
He was found at Battersea, yes.
So he got on the train?
No.
What?
He had an Oyster card...
..but it hadn't been used.
He must have bought a ticket.
Hm. There was no ticket on the body.
Then... How did he end up with a bashed-in
brain on the tracks at Battersea?
That is the question -
the one I was rather hoping Sherlock
would provide an answer to.
How's he getting on?
He's fine.
And it is going...very well.
He's, um...
He's completely focused on it.
CLOCK TICKS
Poison!
What are you going on about?
Clostridium botulinum.
It's one of the deadliest poisons
on the planet.
Carl Powers.
Are you saying he was murdered?
Remember the shoelaces?
Mmm.
He suffered from eczema. It would be easy to
introduce the poison into his medication.
Two hours later he comes to London, the
poison paralyses the muscles and he drowns.
How come the autopsy didn't pick that up?
It's virtually undetectable. Nobody was looking for it.
There are still tiny traces of it
in the trainers
from where he put the cream
on his feet.
That's why they had to go. So how do we let the bomber know?
Get his attention, stop the clock.
The killer kept the shoes
all these years. Yes.
Meaning...
He's our bomber.
PHONE RINGS
SOBS
"Well done, you.
"Come and get me."
Where are you?
Tell us where you are.
SIRENS WAIL
LESTRADE: She lives in Cornwall.
Two men broke in wearing masks,
forced her to drive to the car park
and decked her out in enough
explosives to take down a house.
Told her to phone you.
Check the read-out from this -
pager.
If she deviated by one word,
the sniper would set her off.
Or if you hadn't solved the case.
Oh...elegant!
Elegant?
What was the point?
Why would anyone do this?
Oh...I can't be the only person
in the world that gets bored.
MOBILE PHONE BEEPS
'You have one new message.'
FOUR GREENWICH TIME SIGNAL PIPS
Four pips.
First test passed, it would seem.
Here's the second.
PHONE RINGS
It's abandoned, wouldn't you say?
I'll see if it's been reported.
Freak, it's for you.
Hello.
MAN, SHAKILY: 'It's OK
that you've gone to the police.'
Who is this?
Is this you again?
'But don't rely on them.
'Clever you,
'guessing about Carl Powers.
'I never liked him.'
TRAFFIC ROARS
Carl laughed at me,
so I stopped him laughing.
You've stolen another voice,
I presume.
This is about you and me.
Who are you? What's that noise?
It's the sounds of life, Sherlock.
But don't worry.
I can soon fix that.
You solved my last puzzle
in nine hours.
This time you have eight.
CLOCK TICKS
Great!
We've found it.
The car was hired yesterday morning by
an Ian Monkford. Banker of some kind.
City boy. Paid in cash.
Told his wife he was going away
on a business trip, never arrived.
You're still hanging round him.
Yeah, well...
Opposites attract, I s'pose.
We're not...
You should get yourself a hobby. Stamps, maybe.
Model trains. Safer. Before you ask,
yes, it's Monkford's blood.
DNA checks out.
No body.
Not yet.
Get a sample sent to the lab.
Oh...!
Mrs Monkford...
Yes. Sorry, but I've already spoken
with two policemen.
We're not from the police, we're...
TEARFULLY: Sherlock Holmes.
Very old friend of your husband's.
We, um...
we grew up together.
I'm sorry. Who? I don't think
he ever mentioned you.
Oh, he must have done. This is...
This is horrible.
I mean, I just can't believe it.
I only saw him the other day.
Same old Ian.
Not a care in the world.
Sorry... My husband has been
depressed for months. Who are you?
Really strange that he hired a car. Why would he do that?
It's a bit suspicious, isn't it?
No, it isn't. He forgot to renew
the tax on the car, that's all.
Ah, well! That was Ian.
That was Ian all over.
No, it wasn't.
NORMAL VOICE: Wasn't it? Interesting.
Who was that?
Why did you lie to her?
People don't like telling you things but they love
to contradict you. Past tense, did you notice?
What? I referred to her husband
in the past tense.
She joined in. Bit premature. They've only just found the car.
You think she murdered her husband?
That's not a mistake
a murderer would make. I see...
No, I don't. What am I seeing?
SALLY: Fishing.
Try fishing.
Where now?
Janus Cars.
Just found this
in the glove compartment.
CLOCK TICKS
Can't see how I can help you
gentlemen. Mr Monkford hired the car
from you yesterday.
Yeah, lovely motor.
Mazda RX8.
Wouldn't mind one of them myself.
Is that one?
No, they're all Jags.
I can see you're not a car man, eh?
But surely you can afford one -
a Mazda, I mean. Yeah, fair point.
It's like working in a sweet shop. Once you start
eating the Liquorice Allsorts, where does it stop?
You didn't know Mr Monkford.
No, he was just a client.
He came in here
and hired one of my cars.
I've no idea what happened to him.
Poor sod!
Nice holiday, Mr Ewart? Eh? You've
been away, haven't you? Oh, the...
No, it's sun beds, I'm afraid.
Too busy to get away. My wife
would love it, though - bit of sun.
Have you got any change for the cigarette machine?
What? I noticed one on the way in and I'm gasping.
Um... Oh!
No, sorry.
Oh, well! Thank you very much
for your time, Mr Ewart.
You've been very helpful.
Come on, John!
I've got change, if you still want to...
Nicotine patches, remember? I'm doing well.
So, what was all that about?
I needed to look inside his wallet.
Why?
Mr Ewart's a liar.
FIZZING
PHONE RINGS
Hello.
The clue's in the name - Janus Cars.
Why would you be giving me a clue?
Why does anyone do anything?
Because I'm bored.
We were made for each other,
Sherlock.
Then talk to me in your own voice.
Patience.
CLOCK TICKS
How much blood was on that seat,
would you say?
How much? About a pint.
Not about. Exactly a pint.
That was their first mistake.
The blood's Ian Monkford's,
but it's been frozen.
Frozen?
There are clear signs.
I think Ian Monkford gave
a pint of his blood some time ago
and that's what they spread on the seat.
Who did? Janus Cars. The clue's in the name.
The god with two faces?
Exactly.
They provide a very special service.
If you've got any kind of a problem - money troubles,
bad marriage, whatever -
Janus Cars will help you disappear.
Ian Monkford was in trouble - financial at a
guess, he's a banker - couldn't see a way out.
But if he were to vanish,
if the car he hired was found with
his blood on the driver's seat...
So where is he?
Colombia. Colombia?!
Mr Ewart, of Janus Cars,
had a 20,000 Colombian peso note
in his wallet.
Quite a bit of change, too.
He told us he hadn't been abroad
recently,
but when I asked him about the cars,
I could see his tan line clearly.
No-one wears a shirt on a sun bed.
That, plus his arm. His arm?
He kept scratching it. Obviously
irritating him, and bleeding.
He'd recently had a booster jab. Hep-B, probably.
Hard to tell at that distance.
He's just back from settling Ian
Monkford into his new life in Colombia.
Mrs Monkford cashes in the life insurance,
and she splits it with Janus Cars.
Mrs Monkford?
Oh, yes. She's in on it too.
Go and arrest them, Inspector,
that's what you do best.
We need to let our bomber know
the case is solved.
I am on fire!
MOBILE RINGS
MAN: 'He says...
'you can come and fetch me.'
Help!
Help me, please!
Feeling better? Mmm.
We've hardly stopped for breath
since this thing started.
Has it occurred to you...?
Probably.
No, has it occurred to you that
the bomber's playing a game with you?
The envelope,
breaking into the other flat,
the dead kid's shoes -
it's all meant for you. Yes, I know.
Is it him, then? Moriarty?
Perhaps.
MOBILE PHONE BEEPS
THREE PIPS That could be anybody.
It could be, yeah.
Lucky for you, I've been
more than a little unemployed.
How d'you mean? Lucky for you, Mrs
Hudson and I watch far too much telly.
'..Thank you, Tyra! Doesn't she
look lovely, everybody, now?'
MOBILE PHONE RINGS
'Anyway...speaking
of silk purses...'
Hello?
WOMAN, HALTINGLY: 'This one...
'is a bit...'
..defective.
'Sorry.'
She's blind.
'This is...'
..a funny one.
I'll give you...
..12 hours.
CLOCK TICKS
Why are you doing this?
I like...
..to watch you...
dance.
SHE GASPS
TV: '..And I see you're back
to your bad habits.'
REPORTER: '..Continuing into the sudden death
of the popular TV personality Connie Prince.
'Miss Prince, famous
for her makeover programmes,
'was found dead two days ago by her
brother in the house they shared...'
Connie Prince, 54. She had one of
those makeover shows on the telly.
Did you see it?
No.
Very popular. She was going places.
Not any more.
Dead two days. According to one
of her staff, Raoul de Santos,
she cut her hand on a rusty nail
in the garden. Nasty wound.
Tetanus bacteria enters the
bloodstream, good night, Vienna.
I s'pose.
Something's wrong with this picture.
Eh?
Can't be that simple, otherwise the bomber wouldn't
be directing us towards it. Something's wrong.
John?
Mm.
Cut on her hand, it's deep.
Would have bled a lot, right?
Yeah.
But the wound's clean.
Very clean, and fresh.
How long would the bacteria
have been incubating inside her?
Oh, eight, ten days.
The cut was made later.
After she was dead?
Must have been.
The only question is, how did the
tetanus enter the dead woman's system?
You want to help, right?
Of course.
Connie Prince's background - family
history, everything, get me data. Right.
There's something else that
we haven't thought of. Is there?
Yes. Why is he doing this -
the bomber?
If this woman's death was
suspicious, why point it up?
Good Samaritan.
Who press-gangs suicide bombers?
Bad Samaritan.
I'm...I'm serious, Sherlock.
Listen, I'm cutting you slack here,
I'm trusting you,
but out there somewhere, some
poor bastard's covered in Semtex
and he's just waiting for you to solve the puzzle,
so just tell me, what are we dealing with?
Something new.
CLOCK TICKS
Connection, connection, connection.
There must be a connection.
Carl Powers, killed 20 years ago.
The bomber knew him,
admitted that he knew him.
The bomber's iPhone was in the
stationery from the Czech Republic.
The first hostage from Cornwall,
the second from London,
the third from Yorkshire,
judging by her accent.
What's he doing? Working his way round the
world, showing off? MOBILE PHONE RINGS
You're enjoying this, aren't you?
'Joining the...dots.'
Three hours.
CLOCK TICKS
Boom...boom.
SOBS
PHONE RINGS OFF
CLICKS PHONE OFF
CAT MIAOWS
We're devastated, of course we are.
Can I get you anything, sir?
Er, no. No, thanks.
Raoul is my rock.
I don't think I could have managed.
We didn't always see eye to eye...
but my sister was very dear to me.
CAT MIAOWS
And to the, er, public, Mr Prince.
Oh, she was adored.
I've seen her take girls who looked
like the back end of Routemasters
and turn them into princesses.
Still, it's a relief, in a way, to know
that she's beyond this vale of tears.
CAT PURRS Absolutely.
Great.
Thank you. Thanks again.
It's a real shame. I liked her.
She taught you
how to do your colours.
Colours?
You know, what goes best with what.
I should never wear cerise,
apparently.
Drains me.
Who's that?
Home Office. Home Office? Well, Home Secretary, actually.
Owes me a favour. A pretty girl,
but she messed about
with herself too much.
They all do these days. People can hardly
move their faces. It's silly, isn't it?
Did you ever see her show?
Not until now.
CONNIE PRINCE: 'You look pasty, love.
'Ah, rained every day but one...'
That's the brother.
No love lost there,
if you can believe the papers.
So I gather.
I've just had a fruitful chat with
people who love this show.
The fan site's indispensable
for gossip.
'..Don't you think, girls?
Off, off, off, off, off, off, off!'
AUDIENCE JOINS IN CHANTING
It's more common
than people think.
The tetanus is in the soil, people cut
themselves on rose bushes, garden forks,
that sort of thing,
and if left un...treated...
I don't know
what I'm going to do now. Right.
I mean, she's left me this place...
which is lovely...
..but it's not the same without her.
That's why...
my paper wanted to get the, um...
the full story straight from the horse's mouth.
Are you sure it's not too soon?
No. Right.
You fire away.
CAT MIAOWS
MOBILE PHONE RINGS
John. 'Hi. Look, get over here
quickly. I think I'm onto something.
'You'll need to pick up
some stuff first. Got a pen?'
I'll remember.
DOOR CLOSES
That'll be him. What?
Ah, Mr Prince, isn't it?
Yes.
Very good to meet you.
Yes, thank you.
So sorry to hear about...
Yes, yes, very kind.
Shall we, er...?
CLEARS THROAT
You were right, the bacteria
got into her another way.
Oh, yes? Yes.
Right, are we all set?
Er, yes. Shall we, um...?
Not too close. I'm raw from crying.
CAT MIAOWS
Oh, who's this?
Sekhmet. Named after
the Egyptian goddess.
How nice. Was she Connie's?
Yes, a little present
from yours truly.
Sherlock, light reading?
Oh, er...
2.8. Bloody hell!
What are you playing at? Sorry!
You're like Laurel and bloody Hardy,
you two! What's going on?
I think we've got what we came for.
Excuse us. What? Sherlock. What?
We've got deadlines.
But you've not taken anything!
WATSON LAUGHS
Yes! Ooh, yes!
You think it was the cat.
It wasn't the cat.
What? Yes. Yeah, it is. It must be.
It's how he got the tetanus into her system.
Its paws stink of disinfectant.
Lovely idea.
No, he coated it
onto the claws of her cat.
It's a new pet,
bound to be a bit jumpy around her.
A scratch is almost inevitable.
I thought of it when I saw the scratches on her arm,
but it's too random and clever for the brother.
He murdered his sister for her
money. Did he? Didn't he?
Nope. It was revenge.
Rev...? Who wanted revenge?
Raoul, the houseboy.
Kenny Prince was the butt
of his sister's jokes.
Virtual bullying campaign. Finally, he had enough,
fell out with her badly. It's all on the website.
She threatened to disinherit Kenny, Raoul had grown
accustomed to a certain lifestyle... Wait. Wait!
Wait a second. What about the
disinfectant on the cat's claws?
Raoul keeps a very clean house.
You came through the kitchen door,
saw the state of that floor -
scrubbed within an inch of its life.
You smell of disinfectant.
No, the cat doesn't come into it.
Raoul's internet records do, though.
I hope we can get a cab from here.
CLOCK TICKS
Raoul de Santos is your killer.
Kenny Prince's houseboy.
Second autopsy shows it wasn't
tetanus that poisoned Connie Prince,
it was botulinum toxin.
We've been here before.
Carl Powers. Tut-tut.
Our bomber's repeated himself.
So how'd he do it?
Botox injection. Botox?
Botox is a diluted form
of botulinum. Among other things,
Raoul de Santos was employed to give
Connie her regular facial injections.
My contact at the Home Office gave me the
complete records of Raoul's internet purchases.
He's been bulk-ordering Botox
for months.
Bided his time, then upped
the strength to a fatal dose.
Are you sure about this? I'm sure.
All right, my office.
Hey, Sherlock, how long? What?
How long have you known?
Well, this one was quite simple.
And the bomber repeated himself.
That was a mistake.
No, but Sherlock, the hostage, the old
woman, she's been there all this time!
I knew I could save her.
I also knew that the bomber had given us 12 hours.
I solved the case quickly, that gave
me time to get on with other things.
Don't you see? We're one up on him.
PHONE RINGS
Hello?
Help me!
Tell us where you are.
Address? 'He was so...'
His voice...
No, no, no, no!
Tell me nothing about him, nothing.
He sounded so soft.
DIALLING TONE
Hello?
Sherlock?
What's happened?
REPORTER: 'The explosion,
'which ripped through several
floors, killing 12 people...'
Old block of flats.
'..caused by a faulty gas main.
'A spokesman
from the utility company...'
He certainly gets about.
Well, obviously I lost that round.
Although technically,
I did solve the case.
He killed the old lady
because she started to describe him.
Just once,
he put himself in the firing line.
What d'you mean?
Well, usually, he...
must stay above it all.
He organises these things,
but no-one ever has direct contact.
What, like the Connie Prince murder,
he arranged that?
So, people come to him wanting their
crimes fixed up, like booking a holiday?
Novel.
Huh!
CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICK
Taking his time this time.
WATSON CLEARS HIS THROAT
Anything on the Carl Powers case?
Nothing.
All the living classmates
check out spotless, no connection.
Maybe the killer was older than Carl?
The thought had occurred.
So why is he doing this, then?
Playing this game with you.
Do you think he wants to be caught?
I think he wants to be distracted.
Oh...
I hope you'll be
very happy together.
Sorry, what?
There are lives at stake, Sherlock.
Actual human lives! Just so I know,
do you care about that at all?
Will caring about them
help save them? Nope.
Then I'll continue not to make that mistake.
And you find that easy, do you? Yes, very.
Is that news to you? No, no.
I've disappointed you.
That's good,
that's a good deduction, yeah.
Don't make people into heroes, John.
Heroes don't exist, and if they did,
I wouldn't be one of them.
MOBILE PHONE BEEPS Excellent.
A view of the Thames.
South Bank, somewhere between
Southwark Bridge and Waterloo.
You check the papers,
I'll look online.
Oh, you're angry with me,
so you won't help.
Not much cop, this caring lark.
SIREN WAILS
Archway suicide... Ten-a-penny.
Two kids stabbed in Stoke Newington.
Ah, man found on the train line,
Andrew West.
Nothing!
RINGING TONE
It's me. Have you found anything on the South Bank
between Waterloo Bridge and Southwark Bridge?
BIRDSONG
Do you reckon this is connected,
then, the bomber?
Must be. Odd, though,
he hasn't been in touch.
Then we must assume that some poor
bugger's primed to explode, yeah?
Yes.
Any ideas? Seven, so far.
Seven?
He's dead about 24 hours.
Maybe a bit longer. Did he drown?
Apparently not. Not enough of the
Thames in his lungs. Asphyxiated.
Yes, I'd agree.
There's quite a bit of bruising
around the nose and mouth.
More bruises...
here and here.
Fingertips.
He's late 30s, I'd say,
not in the best condition.
He's been in the river a long while, the
water's destroyed most of the data.
But I'll tell you one thing,
that lost Vermeer painting's a fake.
What?
We need to identify the corpse,
find out about his friends and...
Wait, wait, wait, wait. What
painting? What are you on about?
It's all over the place,
haven't you seen the posters?
Dutch old master, supposed to
have been destroyed centuries ago.
Now it's turned up,
worth £30 million.
OK, so what has that
got to do with the stiff?
Everything.
Have you ever heard of the Golem?
Golem?
It's a horror story, isn't it?
What are you saying?
Jewish folk story, a gigantic man made of
clay - it's also the name of an assassin.
Real name - Oskar Dzundza.
One of the deadliest assassins in the world.
That is his trademark style.
So this is a hit? Definitely.
The Golem squeezes the life out of
his victims with his bare hands.
But what has this got to do
with that painting? I don't see...
You do see, you just don't observe!
Yes, all right, all right, girls!
Calm down.
Sherlock, do you want to
take us through it?
What do we know about this corpse?
The killer's not left us with much,
just the shirt and the trousers.
They're pretty formal, maybe
he was going out for the night.
The trousers are heavy duty.
Polyester, nasty, same as the shirt, cheap.
They're both too big for him. So
some kind of standard-issue uniform.
Dressed for work, then.
What kind of work?
There's a hook on his belt...
for a walkie-talkie.
Tube driver?
Security guard? More likely.
That'll be borne out
by his backside. Backside?!
Flabby, you'd think he'd led
a sedentary life.
Yet the soles of his feet and the nascent
varicose veins in his legs show otherwise.
So, a lot of walking
and a lot of sitting around.
Security guard's looking good.
The watch helps too.
The alarm shows
he did regular night shifts.
Maybe he just set his alarm
like that the night before he died.
No, no, no. The buttons are stiff,
hardly touched.
He set his alarm like that a long
time ago, his routine never varied.
But there's something else. The
killer must have been interrupted,
otherwise he would have
stripped the corpse completely.
There was some kind of badge
or insignia on the shirt front
that he tore off, suggesting the dead
man works somewhere recognisable,
some kind of institution.
I found this
inside his trouser pockets.
Sodden by the river,
but still recognisably...
Tickets? Ticket stubs. He worked in a
museum or gallery. Did a quick check.
The Hickman Gallery has reported one of its
attendants as missing - Alex Woodbridge.
Tonight, they unveil
the rediscovered masterpiece.
Now, why would anyone
want to pay the Golem
to suffocate a perfectly ordinary
gallery attendant?
Inference, the dead man
knew something about it,
something that would stop the owner
getting paid £30 million.
The pictures are fake. Fantastic.
Meretricious. And a Happy New Year.
Poor sod.
I'd better get my feelers out
for this Golem character.
Pointless, you'll never find him,
but I know a man who can.
Who? Me.
Why hasn't he phoned?
He's broken his pattern. Why?
Waterloo Bridge.
Where now, the gallery?
In a bit.
The Hickman's contemporary art,
isn't it?
Why have they got hold
of an old master? Don't know.
Dangerous to jump to conclusions.
Need data...
Stop!
Can you wait here?
I won't be a moment.
Sherlock?
Change? Any change?
What for? Cup of tea, of course.
Here you go, 50.
Thanks.
What are you doing? Investing.
Now we go to the gallery.
Have you got any cash?
No, I need you to find out all
you can about the gallery attendant.
Lestrade will give you the address.
OK.
We'd been sharing about a year.
Just sharing. Mmm.
May I? Yeah.
Sorry.
Stargazer, was he?
God, yeah. Mad about it.
It's all he ever did
in his spare time.
He was a nice guy, Alex.
I liked him.
He was, er...
never much of a one for hoovering.
What about art?
Did he know anything about that?
It was just a job, you know?
Mmm.
Has anyone else been round
asking about Alex?
No.
We had a break-in, though.
When? Last night.
There was nothing taken.
Oh, there was a message
left for Alex on the land line.
Who was it from? I can play it for you, if you like.
I'll get the phone. Please.
PHONE BEEPS
WOMAN: 'Oh, should I speak now? Alex?
'Love, it's Professor Cairns.
'Listen, you were right.
You were bloody right.
'Give us a call when...'
DIALLING TONE
Professor Cairns?
No idea, sorry. Mmm.
Can I try and ring back?
No good. I've had other calls since.
Sympathy ones, you know.
PHONE RINGS
Don't you have something to do?
Just admiring the view.
Yes.
Lovely. Now get back to work -
we open tonight.
Doesn't it bother you? What?
That the painting's a fake.
What? It's a fake. It has to be.
It's the only possible explanation.
You are in charge, aren't you,
Miss Wenceslas? Who are you?
Alex Woodbridge
knew that the painting was a fake,
so somebody sent the Golem
to take care of him. Was it you?
Golem? What the hell
are you talking about?
Are you working for someone else?
Did you fake it for them?
It's not a fake.
It is a fake. I don't know why.
But there's something wrong with it,
there has to be.
What the hell are you on about? You know I could
have you sacked on the spot. Not a problem.
No? No, I don't work here, you see.
Just popped in to give you
a bit of friendly advice.
How did you get in?
Please! I want to know.
The art of disguise is knowing
how to hide in plain sight.
Who are you? Sherlock Holmes.
Am I supposed to be impressed?
You should be.
Have a nice day.
DOOR CREAKS THEN SHUTS
WOMAN: He wouldn't.
He just wouldn't.
Stranger things have happened.
Westie wasn't a traitor.
That's a horrible thing to say!
I'm sorry.
But you must understand...
That's what they think, isn't it,
his bosses?
He was young man, about to
get married, he had debts.
Everyone's got debts,
and Westie wouldn't want to clear
them by selling out his country.
Can you, er...? Can you tell me
exactly what happened that night?
We were having a night in.
Just...watching a DVD.
He normally falls asleep, you know,
but he sat through this one.
He was quiet.
Out of the blue he said
he just had to go and see someone.
And you've no idea who?
Hi, Liz. You OK, love?
Yeah. Who's this?
John Watson, hi.
This is my brother, Joe.
John's trying to find out
what happened to Westie, Joe.
You with the police?
Sort of, yeah.
Tell them to get off their arses,
will you? It's bloody ridiculous.
I'll do my best.
CLEARS THROAT Well, er,
thanks very much for your help.
Again, I'm very, very sorry.
He didn't steal those things,
Mr Watson.
I knew Westie, he was a good man.
He was MY good man.
Spare change? No.
Any spare change?
Alex Woodbridge didn't know
anything special about art.
And? And...
Is that it?
No habits, hobbies, personality?
Give us a chance.
He was an amateur astronomer.
Hold that cab. Spare change,
sir? Don't mind if I do.
WATSON: Can you wait here?
Fortunately, I haven't been idle.
Come on.
Beautiful, isn't it?
I thought you didn't care about...
Doesn't mean I can't appreciate it.
Listen, Alex Woodbridge had a message
on the answerphone at his flat.
A Professor Cairns. This way.
Nice. Nice part of town.
Any time you want to explain?
Homeless network.
Really is indispensable.
Homeless network?
My eyes and ears, all over the city.
Ah, that's...clever.
So you scratch their backs, and...?
Yes, then disinfect myself.
Sherlock! Come on!
What's he doing sleeping rough?
Well, he has a very distinctive look.
He has to hide somewhere where tongues won't wag...much.
Oh sh... What?
I wish I... Don't mention it.
No! No! No! No!
TYRES SQUEAL
It'll take us weeks
to find him again.
Or not. I have an idea where
he might be going.
What? I told you, someone left
Alex Woodbridge a message.
There can't be that many Professor
Cairns in the book. Come on.
'Jupiter, the fifth planet in our
solar system, and the largest.
'Jupiter is a gas giant. Planet
Earth would fit into it 11 times.'
Yes, we know that.
FILM SPOOLS
'Titan is the largest moon...'
Come on, Neptune.
THUMP
'Many are actually long dead...'
Tom, is that you?
'..exploded into supernovas.'
'Discovered by Urbain Le Verrier
in 1846...'
FILM SPOOLS
'..composed mainly of hydrogen.'
SHE STRUGGLES
'Their light takes so long
to reach us...' Golem!
'..many are actually long dead,
exploded into...'
FILM SPOOLS
I can't see him. I'll go round.
Who are you working for this time,
Dzundza?
'A star begins as a collapsing ball
of material composed mainly of...'
Golem!
COCKS GUN
Let him go...
or I will kill you.
FILM SPOOLS
'The fourth planet of the solar system,
named after the Roman god of war.'
'..it is a gas giant...'
FILM SPOOLS
'..takes so long to reach us...
'..into supernovas...'
GUNSHOT
'..exploded into supernovas...'
It's a fake. It has to be.
That painting has been subjected to
every test known to science.
It's a very good fake, then.
You know about this, don't you?
This is you, isn't it?
Inspector, my time is being wasted.
Would you mind showing yourself
and your friends out?
PHONE RINGS
The painting is a fake.
It's a fake, that's why Woodbridge
and Cairns were killed.
Oh, come on, proving it's just
a detail. The painting is a fake.
I've solved it, I've figured it out.
It's a fake, that's the answer,
that's why they were killed.
OK, I'll prove it. Give me time.
Will you give me time?
CLOCK STARTS TICKING
'Ten...' It's a kid.
Oh God, it's a kid.
What did he say? "Ten."
'Nine...' It's a countdown.
He's giving me time.
Jesus... It's a fake,
but how can I prove it? How?! How?!
'Eight...'
This kid will die. Tell me
why the painting is a fake. Tell me!
'Seven...' No, shut up.
Don't say anything.
It only works if I figure it out.
It must be possible.
It must be staring me in the face.
'Six...' How?
Woodbridge knew, but how?!
'Five...'
It's speeding up! Sherlock!
'Four... ' Oh! In the Planetarium,
you heard it too.
Oh, that is brilliant,
that is gorgeous!
'Three...'
What's brilliant? What is?!
This is beautiful. Love this!
'Two...' Sherlock!
The Van Buren Supernova.
TICKING STOPS
'Please, is somebody there?
Somebody help me.'
There you go. Go and find out
where he is and pick him up.
Van Buren Supernova, so-called.
Exploding star.
Only appeared in the sky in 1858.
So how could it have been...
painted in the 1640s?
PHONE BEEPS Oh...
Oh.
Oh, Sherl...
You know, it's interesting.
Bohemian stationery,
an assassin named after a Prague
legend, and you, Miss Wenceslas.
This whole case has a distinctly
Czech feeling about it.
Is that where this leads?
What are we looking at, Inspector?
Well, criminal conspiracy, fraud,
accessory after the fact,
at the very least.
The murder of the old woman,
all the people in the flat...
I didn't know anything about that.
All those things, please,
believe me.
I just wanted my share.
The 30 million.
SHE SIGHS
I found a little old man in
Argentina.
A genius - I mean, really.
Brushwork, immaculate.
Could fool anyone. Mmm.
Well, nearly anyone.
But I didn't know how to go about convincing
the world the picture was genuine.
It was just an idea.
A spark which he blew into a flame.
Who?
I don't know.
LESTRADE LAUGHS It's true!
It took a long time,
but eventually I was...
put in touch with people.
His people...
Well, there was never any real
contact.
Just messages...
..whispers.
And did those whispers have a name?
Moriarty.
WATSON: So this is where West was
found? Yeah.
Are you going to be long?
I might be.
Are you the police, then?
Sort of.
I hate 'em. The police?
No, jumpers.
People who chuck 'emselves in
front of trains. Selfish bastards.
Well, that's one way of looking
at it.
I mean it. It's all right for them.
It's over in a split second, strawberry jam all
over the lines. What about the drivers, eh?
They've got to live with it,
haven't they?
Yeah, speaking of strawberry jam,
there's no blood on the line.
Has it been cleaned off?
No, there wasn't that much.
You said his head was smashed in.
It was, but there wasn't much blood.
OK.
Well, I'll leave you to it, then.
Just give us a shout when
you're off. Right.
Right, so, Andrew West...got on
the train somewhere. Or did he?
There was no ticket on the body.
How did he end up here?
CLANKING
The points. Yes!
I knew you'd get there eventually.
West wasn't killed here, that's
why there was so little blood.
How long have you been following
me? Since the start.
You don't think
I'd give up on a case like this
just to spite my brother, do you?
Come on,
we've got a bit of burglary to do.
Missile defence plans
haven't left the country,
otherwise Mycroft's people
would have heard about it.
Despite what people think,
we do still have a secret service.
Yeah, I know, I've met them.
Which means whoever stole
the memory stick can't sell it
or doesn't know what to do with it.
My money's on the latter.
We're here.
Where?
Sherlock! What if there's
someone in?
There isn't.
WATSON: Jesus...
Where are we? Oh, sorry, didn't
I say? Joe Harrison's flat.
Joe...?
Brother of West's fiancee.
He stole the memory stick,
killed his prospective
brother-in-law.
Then why did he do it?
KEYS RATTLING
Let's ask him.
Don't! Don't.
He wasn't meant to...
What's Lucy gonna say? Jesus.
Why did you kill him?
It was an accident. I swear it was.
But stealing the plans for the missile
defence program wasn't an accident, was it?
I started dealing drugs.
I mean, the bike thing's
a great cover, right?
I don't know how it started.
I just got out of my depth.
I owed people thousands.
Serious people.
Then at Westie's engagement do,
he starts talking about his job.
I mean, usually, he's so careful.
'But that night, after a few pints,
he really opened up.
'He told me about these
missile plans.
'Beyond top secret.
'He showed me the memory stick,
he waved it in front of me.'
You hear about these things
getting lost,
ending up on rubbish tips
and whatnot.
But there it was. And I thought...
'Well, I thought
it could be worth a fortune.
'It was pretty easy to get the thing
off him, he was so plastered.'
Next time I saw him,
'I could tell by the look on his
face that he knew.'
What are you doing here?
What have you done with the plans?
What happened?
'I was going to call an ambulance,
but it was too late.
'I just didn't have a clue what
to do. So I dragged him in 'ere.'
I just sat in the dark, thinking.
When a neat little idea
popped into your head.
Carrying Andrew West way away from here.
His body would have gone on for ages
if the train hadn't hit
a stretch of track that curved.
And points. Exactly.
Do you still have it, then -
the memory stick?
Fetch it for me,
if you wouldn't mind.
Distraction over -
the game continues.
Maybe that's over, too.
We've heard nothing from the bomber.
Five pips, remember, John.
It's a countdown.
We've only had four.
SHOUTING ON TELEVISION
No, no, no!
Course he's not the boy's father.
Look at the turn-ups on his jeans!
I knew it was dangerous. Hm?
Getting you into crap telly.
Not a patch on Connie Prince.
Have you given Mycroft the memory
stick yet? Yep. He was over the moon.
Threatened me with a
knighthood...again.
You know, I'm still waiting. Hm?
For you to admit that a little
knowledge of the solar system
and you'd have cleared up
the fake painting a lot quicker.
It didn't do you any good, did it?
No, but I'm not the world's
only consulting detective.
True. I won't be in for tea.
I'm going to Sarah's. There's still some
of that risotto left in the fridge.
Milk, we need milk. I'll get some.
Really? Really.
And some beans, then? Mm.
DOOR CLOSES
FOOTSTEPS
Bought you a little
getting-to-know-you present.
That's what it's all been for,
isn't it?
All your little puzzles,
making me dance.
All to distract me from this.
Evening.
This is a turn-up, isn't it,
Sherlock?
John! What the hell...?
Bet you never saw this coming.
What...would you like me
to make him say...next?
Gottle o' gear, gottle o' gear,
gottle o' gear. Stop it.
Nice touch, this. The pool,
where little Carl died.
I stopped him.
I can stop John Watson, too.
Stop his heart. Who are you?
DOOR OPENS
I gave you my number.
I thought you might call.
Is that a British Army Browning
L9A1 in your pocket,
or are you just pleased to see me?
Both.
Jim Moriarty. Hi.
Jim?
Jim from the hospital?
Oh, did I really make
such a fleeting impression?
But then, I suppose,
that was rather the point.
Don't be silly.
Someone else is holding the rifle.
I don't like getting my hands dirty.
I've given you a glimpse,
Sherlock, just a teensy glimpse
of what I've got going on
out there in the big bad world.
I'm a specialist, you see.
Like you.
Dear Jim...
..please will you fix it for me
to get rid of my lover's
nasty sister?
Dear Jim, please will you fix it for
me to disappear to South America?
Just so.
Consulting criminal.
Brilliant. Isn't it?
No-one ever gets to me.
And no-one ever will.
I did.
COCKS GUN
You've come the closest.
Now you're in my way.
Thank you.
Didn't mean it as a compliment.
Yes, you did. Yeah, OK, I did.
But the flirting's over, Sherlock.
SINGSONG
Daddy's had enough now.
I've shown you what I can do.
I cut loose all those people,
all those little problems,
even 30 million quid, just
to get you to come out and play.
So take this as a friendly
warning... my dear.
Back off.
Although I have loved this,
this little game of ours.
Playing Jim from IT. Playing gay.
Did you like the little touch with the underwear?
People have died.
That's what people do!
I will stop you. No, you won't.
Are you all right?
You can talk, Johnny boy.
Go ahead.
Take it. Mm? Oh...
..that? The missile plans.
Boring!
I could have got them anywhere.
Sherlock, run!
HE LAUGHS Good!
Very good.
If your sniper pulls that trigger,
Mr Moriarty, then we both go up.
Isn't he sweet? I can see
why you like having him around.
But then, people do get
so sentimental about their pets.
They're so touchingly loyal.
But oops!
You've rather shown
your hand there, Dr Watson.
Gotcha.
Westwood. Do you know what happens if you
don't leave me alone, Sherlock? To you?
Oh, let me guess. I get killed.
Kill you?
No, don't be obvious.
I mean, I'm going to kill you anyway, some day.
I don't want to rush it, though.
I'm saving it up for
something special.
No, no, no, no, no.
If you don't stop prying, I'll burn you.
I'll burn the heart out of you.
I have been reliably informed
that I don't have one.
But we both know that's not
quite true.
Well, I'd better be off.
Well, so nice to have had a
proper chat.
What if I was to shoot you now?
Right now?
Then you could cherish
the look of surprise on my face.
Cos I'd be surprised, Sherlock.
Really, I would.
And just a teensy
bit...disappointed.
And of course, you wouldn't be able
to cherish it for very long.
Ciao, Sherlock Holmes.
Catch you...later.
No, you won't!
DOOR CLOSES
All right? Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine. Sherlock...
Sherlock!
HE GASPS
Oh, Christ.
Are you OK?
Me? Yeah, fine. I'm fine. Fine.
That, er...thing that you...
that you did,
that, um...you offered to do...
that was, um...good.
I'm glad no-one saw that. Mm?
You ripping my clothes off
in a darkened swimming pool.
People might talk.
They do little else.
Oh...
Sorry, boys. I'm so changeable!
It is a weakness with me,
but to be fair to myself,
it is my only weakness.
You can't be allowed to continue.
You just can't.
I would try to convince you,
but everything I have to say
has already crossed your mind.
Probably my answer has
crossed yours.
Sherlock.1x03.The_Great_Game.HDTV_XviD-FoV
English SRT Subtitles - UF (v1.00)
Original Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd
E-mail subtitling@bbc.co.uk