Hold it. Hold it.
Hold it. Just wait.
Holy shit.
Appreciate the lift.
No problem.
Where's the Cutlass?
Oh, it's at the hospital.
Still not running right?
It's running okay.
This worry I'm getting here,
that have anything to do with that
car that's been following us?
The compact parked
halfway down the block.
Tara!
What the hell's going on?
That A.T.F. agent that's
been looking into you guys—
I think he's here for me.
What are you talking about?
I was with him in Chicago.
It got violent. I tried to end it.
He started stalking me.
- Jax. Don't. He's dangerous.
- Go back inside, Tara.
Lock the door.
Vandalism. Deadly weapon.
That's six months
in County, asshole.
Violating a restraining order.
You'll be in the cell next to me.
They teach you how to
suck a dick in A.T.F. school?
Badass biker.
You guys gave it your best shot.
You got nothing on Sam Crow.
And you harassing Tara,
that ends here,
or next time it won't be a piece-of-shit car
I'm draining fluid from.
You threatening a federal agent?
I'm threatening you.
Go away.
It's my last warning.
You better rein in
your A.T.F. boyfriend.
Agent Kohn isn't on my payroll.
I don't keep tabs.
Yeah, well,
maybe you should.
He's not here
for Sam Crow, Hale.
He's here for Tara.
What the hell
are you talking about?
This guy was
stalking her in Chicago.
Thinks she came back
to Charming to be with me.
I'm telling you, this guy is nuts,
and he's gonna hurt her.
Jesus Christ. That's who she had
a restraining order against.
You knew?
No, but it makes sense now.
Hale! Let's go, hotshot.
Water and Powerjust dug up
some old bones out on 44.
Be there in a minute.
Kohn is my problem.
I will handle it.
You better, man,
or I'm gonna.
- Half-Sack, boombaye! Get in there, kid!
- Hands up, Lowell.
Keep your hands up, Lowell.
Now you're getting cocky.
Anyone can beat up a junkie,
prospect. It doesn't mean shit.
Where did you learn
how to fight like this?
You know, I was junior
lightweight champion.
- Armed Forces boxing competition.
- Ooh, that's so hot.
Things all better
with the little missus now?
My balls are still attached.
Shit, Lowell.
Get out ofthere.
- Whose idea was this?
- Tig's.
- Bobby's.
I don't mind it, Clay.
I'm just helping the Half-Sack train.
Yeah, well, you killed
enough brain cells.
- Come on. Come on. Back to work.
- Okay. Thanks.
How's he doing?
Well, the latest round of
rehab seems to be sticking.
He hasn't missed any work.
If I could get A.A. to kick up a vig,
Lowell could make us all rich.
He's always been a freak.
Damn good mechanic though.
I guess you taught him that.
How's Sugar Ray One Nut
looking?
He's working fast.
Got a great right hook.
How much money
gets thrown around
at these bare-fist things?
The purse is okay, but it's
the betting that's gone crazy.
I know a couple of guys last year
who made six figures each.
- Really?
- The prospect can knock any one
ofthose lightweights out...
any day ofthe week.
Absolutely.
- What'd we pull together for McKeevy?
- A hundred and 20.
You ain't thinking
about betting on the prospect.
If Half-Sack takes
his first five fights...
and looks strong
going into the finish,
we control how it ends,
it could be a huge payday.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
But I do know there's no way we're
raising 80 grand in the next four days,
so it might be our only shot.
- I'm in.
- I'm in. Done.
- All right, I'm in.
- Take 50 grand.
I wanna see it triple.
You're gonna train him.
No booze. No weed.
No pussy.
That include
the Nevada sweetbutt?
Till I'm up a hundred-K, that little
cherry tart can cool on the counter.
- Let's go. Hit that bag.
- Hey, Bobby.
What?
Do me a favor.
Push up on that thing, will ya?
- Really?
- Really.
Halfy-Sack is
all about that now.
Well, I wanna see if she's all about him.
And go at it hard.
- I ain't mad at that.
- Half-Sack's gonna lose his mind.
Well, that kind of anger
we can really use.
Hey, and call Unser.
See if he wants in on
some ofthis fight action.
Clay, he's out on the job.
Water and Power dug up
some old bones this morning.
Where?
Out on 44.
What?
I don't know.
- Wheeling out two bodies.
- There should be three.
I'm afraid to ask.
Don't be. There it is.
Is this us?
Yeah.
Aw, shit.
And all three ofthem
were Mayans?
Yep. Back in '92,
Mexicans tried to expand their Oakland
dope base, set up a charter in Lodi.
We couldn't let that happen.
It was a bloody two years.
Bodies dropped.
Yeah. I remember.
That was right around
the time my old man died.
- That's right.
- We got to stop the P.D.
from I.D.'ing those bodies.
If they flag the Mayans,
we're their next stop.
Well, we can pull teeth to stop the I.D.,
but they can still D.N.A. test.
Forensic tests on three bodies?
That would blow half
of Unser's yearly budget.
But if Hale thought
it would hurt us,
he'd get his new fed buddies
to float the costs.
Shit, man, that was pre-O.J., right?
We weren't thinking
about D.N.A. back in '93.
What kind of clues we got buried
with those Mexicans?
If they don't know they're Mayans,
they won't take it any farther.
We stop the identification,
we stop the investigation.
So, uh, there's
a 1 5K purse on the line...
and a lot of ringside action.
Yeah. I'm ready.
This ain't no army boxing, kid.
This is street brawling.
No. It's cool.
Cherry pie.
What?
It's time to go.
What are you talking about?
Go where?
- What are you doing, Bobby?
- Relax, prospect.
- She's gonna stay with him till the fight.
- No, I'm not.
Oh, yeah, you are.
Why?
No booze.
No dope.
- No pussy.
- You'll love my place. It's very cozy.
Get your hands off me.
Quarantine.
Back off.
Clay, no sex before a fight's
like an old wives thing.
Did—
Did you just insult
my old lady again?
No. I—
Jump.
Why didn't you tell me
it was Kohn?
Jax told you?
I did not know that Kohn
was the guy that was stalking you.
I could have—
You know, I tried
getting help in Chicago.
Complained to his superiors-
Made things worse.
I went through three precincts
before someone would even
give me that restraining order.
I doubted you
could do anything.
Tara.
Kohn's boss doesn't
even know that he is here.
This guy is in deep shit.
He is done.
Really?
He is leaving Charming.
I promise.
And I am sorry.
Town's talking about the skulls
that rolled out ofthat hole.
I'm sure they are.
Have you thought
about damage control?
Tig's the only one
that knows the truth.
Everybody else thinks
all those bodies are Mayans.
And how do you stop
that truth from spreading?
I've got it covered.
All right?
Don't worry.
This shit stays
in the rearview.
So I talked to Trammel.
The Sanwa County coroner's
clearing space,
but bones stay local tonight.
Good. Now I have to get into
the lower level ofthe hospital.
You, uh, think the old squeeze
might be able to hook a brother up?
I'll see what I can do.
All right.
Sorry. Clay? I, uh—
I just asked Gemma.
Wanted to make sure it was cool
with you that I have Moby here.
Only during my break.
He— He likes to watch me work.
Sure. It's fine.
Hey, Lowell,
you're doing good work.
Thanks, man!
All right.
Tara's not here.
What do you wanna do?
Lab coat on the chair.
Can you distract
the doctors?
Yeah. No problem.
Excuse me, ladies.
Oh. How you doing?
Uh, you're doctors, both ofyou?
Yeah.
Oh, thank God.
Um, a Doberman pinscher
took a chunk.
Ah, Jesus.
Hang on. A chunk of my ass.
I— Can we-
You need to go
to the E.R.
Distract them.
I said distract them,
not scar 'em for life.
Shit. I'm serious.
I think it's infected.
Orderly to the nurses' station.
Hey.
Managed to steal a key card
from an intern.
Hopefully it gets us below.
Yeah. Me and Tig'll take care ofthis.
Why don't you stay here
and run interference.
Why?
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
Kid looks strong, huh?
Yeah.
Well, you have
a good night, all right?
You too.
Nurse said you wanted to see me.
Yeah. I was just checking in.
You okay?
Yeah. I talked to Hale.
He assured me Joshua was leaving.
Thanks for handling that.
Ah, you're welcome.
You won't have to worry
about that guy anymore.
I'll find us some gloves.
Okay.
Hey, freako.
We ain't here
to find you a date.
I know. I know.
It's just— You know.
You ever?
What? Cold pack?
Yeah.
Nah. Not my thing.
I know it's a little
bit creepy at first,
but then something happens,
man, I'm telling you.
This soothing coldness.
This stillness.
It's really a beautiful thing.
Please.
Please, stop.
Goddamn it. It's all right.
Keep looking.
I thought I told you
to wait upstairs.
Well, there's
no interference to run,
and I figured you could use
the extra pair of hands.
Is that all right?
I got 'em.
All three.
Hold the head. Tight.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
It's already been I.D.'d.
Lowell Harlan Sr.
This is Lowell's old man.
Cookie time.
I made 'em.
Especially for you.
No, thank you.
Stop, please.
Come on, girl.
You ain't no old lady yet.
You—
do this for me—
I'll make sure you get
the thumbs-up from Clay.
Stop, 'kay? Please.
Come on.
Stop! God.
I'm not a sweetbutt.
Oh, yeah, you are.
No, I'm not.
I came here for Kip. I'm not gonna be
passed around anymore. All right?
I'm done with that.
Come on.
Seriously. Ew!
Oh, Jesus.
Okay.
- Okay?
- I said okay.
Relax.
Have a cookie.
Why was Lowell's dad
buried with the enemy?
Casualty ofwar.
Mayans took him out.
He worked at T.M.
He wasn't patched.
Mayans went after everybody.
Family, friends.
Didn't matter.
Lowell thinks his dad just split.
Poor bastard's convinced
he's still out there.
I know.
So why the same grave?
Disrespect.
I know.
It was a crazy two years.
I didn't have time to think
a lot of shit through.
Is that why you didn't want me
in the morgue? Protect that secret?
I got no secrets from you.
You know,
with the Mayans I.D.'d too,
I can only imagine the poison
Hale's gonna pour in Lowell's ear.
I'll handle Lowell.
Sounds good.
Is it cool if I work on it
before my shift?
Yeah.
Is everything okay, man?
I want you
to hear this from me.
What?
Something happen to Moby?
I left him with Anita.
No, no, no. Your kid's fine.
Those bodies they, uh,
pulled out ofthe hole on 44—
one of 'em's your old man.
My dad?
Oh, that—
that don't make sense.
I'm sorry, son.
No. He ran off
when I was, like, 1 5.
He just split. Everyone told me that.
You told me that.
I know.
Well, the son of a bitch was
already dead to me, right?
What, uh—
What happened to him?
Mayan war.
Wrong place, wrong time.
The, uh, other bodies
they found in the hole—
those are the two Mexicans
that killed your dad.
Vengeance was meted out.
The cops—
they're gonna try to lay
all those bodies at Sam Crow's feet.
That's bullshit.
I know. It ain't
a matter oftrue or false.
Hale is gonna try
to screw with your compass.
I don't want you losing true north.
Inside the club there had to be truth.
Our word was our honor.
But outside,
it was all about deception.
Lies were our defense,
our default.
To survive, you had to master
the art of perjury.
The lie and the truth
had to feel the same.
But once you learned that skill,
nobody knows the truth...
in or outside the club.
Especially you.
Oh, my God.
Holy shit.
Two bodies were Mayan captains.
It had to be SAMCRO.
Well, 1 5-year-old
Mexican bones give us nothing.
Even with D.N.A., there's no
murder weapon. So it's ancient history.
The U.S. Attorney's Office
won't touch it.
Look at this.
Dead mechanic worked
for Teller-Morrow.
History of drug abuse,
domestic violence.
His kid's on the way in.
Following his old man's footsteps.
Close to SAMCRO.
How close?
I'm not sure.
- Any word on Kohn?
- Checked out of his hotel.
He turned in his rental car.
He may already be gone. Here we go.
You, uh—
You wanted to see me?
Yeah.
Have a seat, Lowell.
I'm June Stahl, federal agent.
I'm here helping out
the deputy chief.
Oh, yeah?
You helping out with what?
We have, uh, some sad news
for you about your father.
Yeah, I know.
They found him in that hole off of 44.
Well, you don't seem
too surprised by that, Lowell.
Well, you live
by the sword, you know?
He was a mechanic,
not a gangster.
Why was he buried
with outlaw bikers?
I don't know.
- Your old man worked
for Teller-Morrow, right?
- Yeah.
So the Sons ofAnarchy
must've trusted him.
He was a friend.
Did Clay tell you that?
It's true.
He was a friend,
and I'm a friend.
Right.
Just like your dad.
You're just a chip
offthe old spoon.
Let's just hope we don't find you in
a ditch on a county road somewhere, huh?
Who do you think killed him?
You know, they found
three bullet holes in his head.
Now, what could
a mechanic do that would
incite such a gruesome death?
I don't know.
He was buried
with the enemy, Lowell.
He was not a friend.
He did something to piss off Clay.
No.
He was in the same grave
because he had the same killers.
Use your head, Lowell.
SAMCRO killed your father.
- That is not true.
- Yes, it is.
What's going on in here?
Who the hell are you?
A.T .F .
Just what we need.
You guys wanna rent
a goddamn wing?
Aren't you spunky.
- You done with him?
- For now.
Get out of here, Lowell.
Go ahead. Go on.
Pleasure.
Bad enough I got to see the other one
every time I get a hot shave.
Now I got to deal with Mrs. A.T.F.
chewing on my last nerve?
When did you last see Kohn?
I just left him.
At Floyd's.
Who did this?
A.T .F .
Why?
Tara.
- That stupid bitch.
- How is this her fault?
- This guy's dead.
- At least.
Yeah. Kohn's still in town.
I know. He's at Floyd's.
I'm taking care of it.
Yep.
You wanna go to war with me,
you sick piece of shit?
This is bullshit.
- He attacked me.
- No one backs your version, Kohn.
- He put me through a goddamn window.
- Right.
Apparently after you stabbed him
with some scissors.
- No.
- Don't thinkJax is pressing charges.
Oh. Shit. Great.
Thank you.
But you will be facing charges
in Illinois...
for violating a restraining order.
I'm not stalking Tara.
I'm protecting her.
Come on. We all know what happens
if she hooks up with Teller.
You know I'm right.
We're all on the same team here.
No, Josh.
Not anymore.
You're in breach of about
a half a dozen federal statutes.
You've been stripped
ofyour creds, and O.P.R.'s
gonna meet you at O'Hare.
I hope that the stalk
was a good rush,
'cause, uh, itjust
killed your career.
Wait.
She came back here because
she was afraid of me.
I pointed her at SAMCRO.
I can't fix that mistake,
but you can. Both ofyou can.
Please.
Barber says you
came in for a haircut.
Agent Kohn attacked you
with a pair of scissors.
So you pushed him through
a plate glass window. Self-defense.
That's what Floyd saw,
I guess that's what happened.
That's fantastic.
Tell me.
Are they all
just afraid ofyou...
or convinced that you
are a necessary evil?
You charging me?
No charges.
Why does Kohn have
a hard-on for you?
You know why.
You're right. I do.
Tara Knowles.
The charming ingenue.
High school sweethearts,
right?
Yeah.
She fears for her life,
so she comes back home...
to the only man she knows
loves her enough to protect her,
a guy who would have
no problem...
putting a fed through
a plate glass window.
That's beautiful.
Really, it is.
I wish I had that kind
of pull over someone.
You're a lucky man.
You done?
Yeah.
She's done.
First fight of the afternoon. Round one.
Let's go!
Come on! Hit him!
Whoo!
She's getting under his skin.
I can feel it.
It's bad for us.
I'm keeping an eye on it.
I'm not gonna let anything turn Jax
away from Sam Crow, especially pussy.
Tara's not pussy.
He loved her.
Probably still does.
Whoa.
Hey. Anita just called.
Lowell? M.I.A.
She just found Moby in the apartment,
crying and locked in the bathroom.
Shit.
Yeah. He probably went
to Lodi looking to score.
It's not your fault, baby.
You've been taking care
of Lowell since he was 1 6.
You done everything you could.
Just some shit you can't escape.
It's like father, like son.
Yeah.
Looks like
it's going that way.
Got to remember what's important.
- Big picture.
- I'll call the Vista, see if he checked in.
No one blames you
if Lowell don't come home.
Come on, Lowell.
Open up. I'm taking you home.
It makes no sense.
It's no sense that my dad
was buried with them wetbacks!
How long you been taking care of me,
Clay? Huh? Why are you here now?
I made a promise to your dad.
What, before you killed him?
You kill him, Clay?
Why would you do that?
I lied to you, son.
Don't you call me that.
I am not that.
Your father wasn't killed
by the enemy.
He was the enemy.
No.
He was a friend.
He was a loathsome piece of shit.
Treated you and
your mother like dirt.
Cared more about the junk
than he did about his friends,
his family.
Sound familiar?
I'm not that.
No?
Then what the hell are you?
You can't stay clean.
You abandon your kid.
Moby.
I killed your old man.
I killed him 'cause he was a rat.
A weakjunkie rat.
I'm not a rat.
Look at you.
Ten minutes with Hale,
you turn inside out. You run away.
You don't give a shit
about your kid!
- I'm sorry, Clay.
- Next time maybe Moby
drowns in that bathtub.
Or maybe you tell
Hale and the feds...
all those secrets you been hearing
at Teller-Morrow.
I can't deal
with it anymore, Clay.
My point.
Oh, shit.
I'm my old man.
I'm Lowell.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry, Clay.
I know that you tried to help me.
You help Moby.
You save him from me.
Do it, please.
You help my little boy.
This is it, prospect,
your final fight.
How you feeling?
I'm good, man.
This asshole
looks half dead.
Well, he's had a tougher climb.
It's a beautiful thing.
It is a beautiful thing.
You're looking like a champ.
Everybody's betting on you,
except for us.
What do you mean?
You want me to lose?
Shit. No, come on, man.
I can beat this guy.
I can win this whole thing.
Ifyou win this, we get 1 5 grand.
You lose, we walk home with 1 0 times
that much. So you lose.
You're gonna take a dive,
Kippy, for the club.
Go get him.
Sort of.
Come on, son!
Come on!
Get 'em in there!
Why aren't you at the fight?
I've had my share for the day.
Yeah.
Your leg okay?
Where's the doctor?
I don't know.
Where you going
with that, Jax?
Nowhere.
I don't believe that.
I've seen the two ofyou together.
See how you act
around her.
She's still got ties in you.
You know what?
I don't give a shit what you think.
What I do, what Tara does—
it's not your business.
Cleaning up piss
and broken cribs,
that's my business?
No one asked you
to take this on.
This house, this kid.
It's not your burden. It's mine.
Shit.
You deal with that Lowell problem?
Call Anita. Tell her she's gonna be
watching Moby for a while.
All right.
Give it one more round,
and then he falls.
I understand you, uh,
declined Bobby's request
for some comfort.
Yeah. I did.
I'm not about that anymore.
If I was to ask for some comfort,
would you be about that?
No. I'm sorry.
But your old lady would
turn us both into chum.
Yeah, that's a good point.
If, uh, Half-Sack patches in—
which is a big "if"—
it's all right with me
ifyou stick around.
That is, if he wants you
as his old lady.
Thank you.
Oh, shit. Shit!
Half-Sack, don't!
What's he doing?
What the hell's he doing?
Gonna K.O. this guy.
- Shit, I'll kill him. I'll kill him.
- No, no, no. My bad. My bad.
Get him out ofthere before
we got to bury another Mexican.
Come on!
Hey, hey, hey!
Chill! Relax, you muppet.
Whoo!
Clay, I'm really sorry.
You know, I just lost it. I don't—
You owe the club 35K.
Really?
Hey.
At least you got the girl, huh?
Come on. Get out of here
before I rape both ofyou.
Tig. Hey.
It's just an expression.
Term of endearment.
We're gonna need
the hundred and 1 5 by Friday.
Gonna be a busy week.
You said it.
He's a good mechanic.
Jesus. Are you okay?
Yeah.
Hale told me what happened.
Kohn's gone.
I watched him leave town.
Thank you.
What is it?
You left Chicago 'cause you were afraid
this guy was gonna hurt you.
One ofthe reasons.
Did you come back here
'cause you knew I'd hurt this guy,
do what the cops wouldn't do?
God, no.
I had no idea
he would follow me.
I— I didn't know
you'd even still be here.
That doesn't sound
like you, Jax.
It sounds like your mother.
Well, you're safe now.
How'd it go, baby?
Where is he?
Sam Crow rehab.
What'd you tell Jax?
About the bodies.
Some ofthe truth.
And Lowell?
A little more.
The rest stays buried.
Yeah.
And rest in peace.