* Cryin' on the corner,
waitin' in the rain *
* I swear
I'll never, ever wait again *
* you gave me your word *
* but words for you are lies *
* darlin'... *
Seriously? The president?
At this level,
there aren't that many people
he can trust.
How do I know
you're not making all this up?
* ...my heart *
* I'm gonna swallow my tears *
* I'm gonna turn
and leave you here *
Oh, my God.
* All of my life
I've been waitin' in the rain *
So handsome.
The things I'm telling you...
You don't joke around about.
It could be dangerous.
Dangerous. Mm.
* I'm gonna harden my heart *
* I'm gonna swallow my tears *
You know, most people...
They get into their warm beds
at night.
They have no idea
what really goes on out there.
The sheer number of people
working to destroy
our way of life.
You... you know why
I've dedicated my life
to stopping them?
Why?
Because...
You ready for this?
Oh.
I don't know.
Think about something else.
Take deep breaths.
It's just...
They used to tell stories
about this guy, you know?
He killed a lot of people.
You know how guys like him
kill people?
They plan it for weeks, and
they always come up from behind.
Fighting face-to-face,
that's a different story.
I heard once
he got in a bar fight
with the entire
Japanese olympic judo team.
Took out four of 'em
before the rest of 'em ran.
Which year?
Because '64 to '72 were pussies.
They didn't even medal.
I need to look out
your living room window
for a few minutes.
Time?
Minus 22.
No, what time is it?
Um... It's 9:15.
Mm. The capitals are in L.A.,
start soon.
You follow the NHL?
I like football.
She's in.
Third floor, three east.
He's at the corner.
Immigration!
We just want to talk!
Help! Help!
Help!
Don't get too close!
Watch the corner!
Ugh!
* Tusk *
* tusk *
I know you're not
supposed to kill me.
I don't think you understand
how unpopular you are.
I could deliver you
in a hundred pieces.
They'd give me
a separate medal for each one.
He's not police! He's not police!
He's not police!
- You have the right to remain silent!
- He's not really police!
- Help! Call for help! Call for help!
- Anything you say and do will...
can and will be used against you
in a court of law!
Ohh!
* Why don't you tell me
who's on the phone? *
Hey, hey! Keep your eyes open.
All right. It's okay.
Deep breaths.
Look at me. Rob? Rob?
Keep your eyes on me.
Heavy bleeding,
he's got 10, 15 minutes.
Arlington Methodist,
then 66 to the beltway
to the drop site?
No, we blew our whole window
on the chase.
We won't make it.
So? Parkway to the beltway.
He dies, and 50/50
we miss the hand off anyway.
No, the mission comes first!
I can help you.
I can make you rich.
Shut up!
You go in a John Doe.
If you live,
do not go back to Boston.
Assume they're on you.
All right?
You got to walk from here.
You were trained
to surmount any obstacle.
Go!
* Don't say that you love me *
Back is clear.
Time?
Minus 7.
There's another way, please.
Listen to me.
We can all sit down...
Shut up!
* Tusk *
* just say that you want me *
* don't tell me that you *
* tusk *
* real savage like *
Why is everyone so punctual
in this business?
Re-sync by wilson0804
Corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
Counter Intelligence is the place
you wanna be right now Stan.
I mean, what's it take
to rob a bank?
Stick a couple fingers in your pocket
and say, "give me all your money"?
In C.I, we're up against
the most sophisticated enemy
in the world.
I'll tell you one good thing
about bank robbers...
they speak English.
They got me in beginning Russian
four days a week.
Ugh. You got an ear
for languages?
Ah, you know, I had a very
attractive French teacher
one year in high school.
I got a B-plus.
Oh, coffee.
Ah, just what I need.
We getting started soon,
there, boss?
Timoshev isn't here.
He's 20 minutes late.
Maybe he had a little too much
vodka last night.
I have been working with him
since he defected.
He hasn't been 20 seconds late
for anything.
Where's he coming in from?
I don't know.
He only deals with the director
and the A.G.
I don't even know
where he stayed last night.
Mormon.
Since Reagan got elected,
he starts these meetings
at 7:00 A.M.
Reagan's not a mormon.
Fundamentalist, whatever.
The goal is the same...
to wear down the enemy by
waking up earlier than they do.
Who's Timoshev?
He's this ex-KGB colonel.
Blew the whistle
on these Directorate "S"
undercover agents
supposedly hiding
all over the U.S.
Super-secret identities...
no one has any idea
who they are.
What, you don't buy it?
There's not a single piece
of evidence.
Look. You get these guys
like Timoshev, right?
They come over.
They get these huge
resettlement packages.
We're talking
millions of dollars.
So, they say things to us
to justify it.
They make up stories
to make us happy.
Super-secret spies
living next door.
They look like us, they speak
better English than we do.
According to Timoshev,
they're not allowed to say a single
word in Russian once they get here.
I mean, come on. Someone's been
reading too many spy novels.
We're talking figment
of the imagination.
You understand
you make any noise,
I will kill you immediately.
FBI paid me $3 million
when I came over
and more since as a consultant.
You can get twice that!
$3 million
as the most valued of defectors,
a Directorate "S" officer.
Another $3 million
for returning me.
Just go to the FBI
and tell them...
Car won't start!
We're gonna have to take the bus
to the Metro.
- Oh, dad.
- Yeah?
Maruk got two goals and an
assist last night versus L.A.
Did they win?
Uh, no. It was a tie.
I'm not going in today,
so you're gonna have to handle
Portland rotary
and call Swissair.
Do you know how much
they paid that asshole?
$3 million.
Henry was looking
for his skateboard.
It's not in the garage, is it?
No.
- Let's go, Henry.
- Huh?
- Bye.
Bye, guys.
What, no coffee for you?
Uh, no, thanks.
We have to get rid of him
tonight.
I just coded the message,
I'll drop it on the way to work.
You don't have to stay here.
He's secure in there.
There were witnesses.
If they figure it out,
I mean, they could be looking
for him in a couple of hours.
- I'm gonna stay. - Yeah, told
you... we should have built
that secret underground chamber
in the basement.
You mean the wine cellar
you wanted to put in
under the laundry room?
I did say
it could have other uses.
Anyway, $3 million?
He can buy himself
a diamond-plated coffin.
1-7. Show me on this location.
Show me canvassing.
Multiple callers,
unknown direction of flight.
What do you got?
I got a female witness.
She saw a guy
knock the victim down,
grab the purse,
and run this way.
Give me that, uh... description
one more time, please.
We didn't get
a full description.
Male Caucasian, black hair,
unknown complexion, unknown age.
All right,
if you do have a victim,
have them respond
to this location...
north end of Dupont Circle.
All right, did you
notify Parks?
Again.
Harder. Focus.
Yeah.
Okay. Again.
So, what we have?
Captain...
I did not know you are back.
You two are working late.
She has great promise.
We are putting in extra work.
Leave us.
I will teach her how we do it
in the field.
Go.
Now, my dear...
again.
I am sorry, Captain.
I'm sorry.
Use the contraction.
Now... faster.
Ugh!
Watch!
Don't overcommit.
Nyet!
Remember me, Captain?
How's the game?
Uh, Jughead is
in serious trouble.
Okay, well, do some reading
and some stirring for me, okay?
- Paige, what are you working on?
- Social studies...
a paper on how the Russians
cheat on arms control.
Hmm.
That's, uh, Henrickson, right?
- Yep.
- Yeah.
I don't know how
you can look at him all day
with that... that harelip.
Mom, that's his handicap.
So, what's the trouble
with these guys?
Well, Betty and Veronica
were hosting a charity drive,
- and...
- Yeah?
- So Jughead...
- I'm home!
- Oh, dad!
- Yeah?
We launched
our rocket today in science.
- Wow! Was it manned or unmanned?
- Unmanned.
But tomorrow, we're gonna give
Commander Stafford a plaque
to commemorate the mission.
Well, I'm sure
he'll be very honored.
Go look out the window.
I made the drop in the park.
No response.
Maybe he can move in with us
permanently.
I can fix up
the spare bedroom for him.
I have a meeting later.
We'll know more then.
Holy shit!
That's the coolest car ever!
Henry! Language!
Don't fall in love with it.
It's only a rental
until the Oldsmobile gets fixed.
I said that word once, and
you guys grounded me for a week.
Whenever you're ready.
Here we go.
Dad's gonna start this up
right here, right now.
Ice-cream Olympics.
Take your time.
- Eyes on the cone.
- Be the cone.
Eyes... eyes on the cone.
Don't feint too early.
Know your distance.
Oh, no!
All right, Henry, you're up.
War... paint.
Here we go.
War paint.
Let me see your war face.
Spike it.
Eyes on the cone.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Ease up. Remember the training.
Ohh!
The big nose cone!
- Mom, you're up.
- No, thanks.
Come on. Just a... just a...
I don't want... no, thanks.
Little one?
Come on. Let's see. Ohh!
- Sorry.
- Stop.
Maybe we can have a Checkers
round-robin when we get hone?
Um, I'm just dropping
you guys off.
I got to...
got to meet a client.
Why are you meeting
a client so late?
He's coming in on a late flight
and wants to grab a drink.
You know, that's what business
is all about, honey.
Anyone can make
travel arrangements,
but you keep
the executives happy,
you keep the accounts.
How have you been, Martha?
Fine, Clark.
Would you like to come in?
So, referencing
our meeting this evening...
obviously, you understand
it's been classified Top Secret
by the the Internal
Affairs Division
of the Committee to oversee
United States'
counterintelligence agencies.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth,
- et cetera, et cetera?
- I do.
Great. So, big day
at FBI Counterintelligence?
Yes, it was.
Obviously, we know most of it,
but I just want to hear
the details from you,
because a crisis
can provide an opportunity
to uncover the leaks
that we have been looking for
in your office.
So just tell me what you saw.
Thank you.
Well...
I-I know
that a man was kidnapped.
He was supposed to speak
at a conference this morning,
but he didn't show.
Mm-hmm.
And did there appear to be
a centralized response
to the kidnapping?
They were
in the secure vault all day.
Did you get a look inside
this time?
They don't let me in there.
And you know that.
I know. I'm sorry.
Please go on.
Um...
well, the man that
they kidnapped was Russian.
He was someone very important
in the KGB, I think.
- Right.
- By early afternoon,
they had tied it to a police
report in northeast D.C.
about a man who was kidnapped
last night.
And they have
a vehicle description,
'77 Oldsmobile, gold,
with D.C. plates
and bumper stickers.
And descriptions
of the kidnappers?
Two men and a woman.
One of the men...
average height with dark hair.
And what specific actions
did Agent Bartholomew order?
Extra agents were sent
to surveil the Soviet embassy,
agents went out to all the ports
and train stations.
They thought the Russians
would take the man
out of the country.
How would you best describe
Agent Bartholomew's mood?
Angry?
Um...
but I-I don't want to get him
in trouble.
No, no, no, no. Not at all.
Our counterintelligence units,
they safeguard the security
of our nation, Martha.
So, we have to safeguard
their security.
Tell me what you want next.
Oh. I don't know.
How about... this?
Oh, I... oh, I don't know.
I don't... oh!
Oh, yes!
You mean to tell me
a girl never put her finger
up your ass before?
That's right.
Yeah, yeah. Now you got it.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, God.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Oh!
There's something...
I mean, if I... if I were
gonna see you again...
I'd want you to be a little...
What?
I don't want to hurt
your feelings.
Tell me.
But just maybe...
Stronger, maybe?
Do you know what the KGB is?
Um... I've heard of them.
Well...
Well, this weekend,
I am giving $100,000 cash
to a KGB defector
who's coming to town to...
The Reagan administration
revealed today
that after a month-long review,
it will honor the agreement
with Iran
that led to the release
of the 52 American hostages.
So...
FBI have the car description
with the D.C. plates.
They haven't connected it
to a stabbing victim
at Arlington Methodist yet,
but I don't think
it will be long.
They're all over our guys
at the embassy,
who must have made
the surveillance,
which is why they can't get out
to pick up my message
or respond.
So, I think we have to assume,
with the feds
all over them like that,
they're on full operational
stand-down.
We should just
take care of him ourselves.
What's the rush?
On an operational stand-down,
we're authorized to make
our own decisions.
Yes, but why do you want
to kill him so badly?
I want him out of my house!
He's putting us all in danger,
and they're just gonna kill him
back in Moscow anyway.
I think we should at least try
and finish the mission
the way it was assigned.
Oh, now you want to complete the
mission the way it was assigned?
I mean, you should have
thought of that before, Philip.
He shouldn't even be here.
Well, if you're
that worried about him,
maybe we could just defect
ourselves.
At least we'd be millionaires.
Hmm? We wouldn't have to worry
about going to jail
and leaving the kids all alone.
A lot of our problems
would just go away.
Pkew!
That's very funny.
Let's see
what we hear tomorrow.
You sure
you don't want to come?
Haven't even seen
the new mall yet.
It's a mall.
See you, ma.
Yeah, I know, but this one has
fountains and skylights.
Bye, mom.
When we went to dinner
last week,
wasn't she wearing a sweater
with a bunny rabbit on it?
Oh, my God.
* Playing with
the Queen of hearts *
* knowin' it
ain't really smart *
Really?
Just call your parents.
Tell them you're sleeping
at Lisa's house.
Do you think I'm gonna get
in trouble?
* Laying out another lie *
* thinkin' 'bout
a life of crime *
* 'cause that's
what I'll have to do *
Thanks.
* to keep me away from you *
* honey *
* you know it makes you mad *
* why is everybody tellin'
everybody *
* what you have done? *
* baby *
* I know it makes you sad *
* but when they're handin' out
the heartaches *
* you know
you got to have you some *
* playin' with
the Queen of hearts *
* knowin'
it ain't really smart *
* the joker ain't the only... *
Whoa.
I like that.
You look nice, darlin'.
You want to come with me and Dee
to shop for makeup
after you pay for those?
Errol, she's 13.
13?
I don't know, daddy.
She sure looks ready to me.
So long, honey.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Come on.
You're, uh, getting older,
so...
I know, I know.
It's... it's no use
fighting guys like that.
Oh, God,
I wouldn't want you to.
You don't have to be a cowboy
to wear cowboy boots.
Jaden says you do.
No one wears
cowboy boots anymore, dad.
You know, dad,
she does have a point there.
I met the new neighbors.
We're gonna over later
to say hello.
What, do you think
I killed him?
Just checking.
Stop.
You're my wife.
Is that right?
Oh, hi. You came!
Just for a second,
to, uh, bring over brownies
and welcome you
to the neighborhood.
Well, come in. Come in.
Can I offer you guys
a drink or...?
- No, no, no, no, no.
- No.
This place is a mess.
Please, please,
don't do anything.
We just wanted to bring over
the brownies.
I'm so sorry.
We can come over and help.
Actually, Henry can come over
all day tomorrow if you want.
- Oh thank you. Um, this is my son Matthew.
- Hi.
Do you know
where your father is?
Uh, he's upstairs.
What, do we have visitors
already?
Uh, yeah. This is Stan.
Hey. Phil Jennings.
How you doing? Stan Beeman.
Uh, my wife, Elizabeth,
Paige, Henry.
- Hi.
Hey, Henry.
Hello.
- Ooh, are those brownies?
- Homemade.
- May I?
- Mm.
Your mom's a good cook?
Yes.
Okay.
- I should've taken them.
Thank you. - Mmm.
- Oh, that's a good brownie, hon.
- Yeah.
So, this is a pretty good
neighborhood we moved into, huh?
Wouldn't live anywhere else.
You know? Safe, clean.
Commute to D.C.'s not too bad.
Do you work in the city?
I do.
What do...
what do you do, Stan?
I'm an FBI agent.
FBI? Wow! What... what, do you
catch bank robbers and stuff?
Actually, I work
in Counterintelligence now.
Counterintel... that's...
that's against spies, right?
Exactly.
Oh. I'll have to make sure
I don't do any spying
around here.
Oh, you better not,
especially for those Russians.
Oh, yeah. They're the...
they're the worst, right?
Oh, they certainly are, Philip.
They certainly are.
It's probably a coincidence,
FBI agents
have to live somewhere.
Or they're onto us.
And this is what?
The end game.
They're... they're trying to
make us do something stupid.
Either way, we get rid
of Timoshev tonight.
I almost did it myself
this morning,
but I thought you'd be pissed.
If they are watching us,
the last thing
you want to do is kill Timoshev.
That's life in prison.
That's no deals, nothing.
We take those risks every day,
Philip.
That's what we do.
May...
maybe there's another way.
Look, maybe this is
an... opportunity.
Maybe this is the perfect time
for us just to think about...
living the life
we've been living
but just really living it.
Just... being us.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying we might be blown.
And I'm saying
if they are watching us,
we can't kill Timoshev.
I'm also saying we are
Philip and Elizabeth Jennings.
We have been
for a very long time.
So why don't we get ahead
of this
and why don't we make
the first move
and offer ourselves to them?
We could get a lot of money...
$3 million for Timoshev,
$3 million for us.
We just get relocated,
take the good life,
and be happy.
Are you joking?
Is this a joke?
No.
You want to betray our country?
Well, after
everything we've done,
I don't think
it's such a betrayal.
Defecting to America?
America's not so bad.
We've been here a long time.
What's... what's so bad
about it, you know?
The electricity works all the time.
Food's pretty great.
- The closet space...
- Is that what you care about?
- No, I care about everything.
- Not the Motherland!
I do, but our family
comes first.
So, Paige and Henry, uh...
- What exactly is your plan? - We'd have
a great life because we would have money.
What would you tell them,
Philip?
The truth.
You swore.
We swore
we would never tell them!
To let them grow up
and live their own lives.
They're not to be
a part of this.
They're not
to be a part of this.
They will be American,
and you can't stand that.
I see it every day.
I'm not finished with them yet.
They don't have to be
regular Americans.
- They can be socialists.
- They're not gonna be socialists.
- They can be trade-union activists.
- This place doesn't turn out socialists.
To know that it was all a lie?
They would never speak to us
again, Philip.
And what are we even
talking about?
There would be no future
for any of us.
- They would kill us all!
- They'd never find us.
- They would never find us.
- Have you looked in our trunk?!
He was a fool.
He came back to give speeches.
Left clues
about where he was staying.
We'd... we'd be more careful.
Colonel.
Come.
Philip...
I'd like you to meet Elizabeth.
Elizabeth...
this is Philip.
Pleased to meet you.
Likewise.
I'll leave you two
to get acquainted.
There is so much to talk about.
Your lives up until now.
Philip and Elizabeth's lives.
Not the other ones...
those should never be discussed.
It would be easy
to believe in the Elizabeth
who grew up in Chicago,
Illinois, Philip,
if you don't know
any other story.
Elizabeth, you'll be less likely
to make a slip one day
if there is no other version
of this man
you're hiding away
in the back of your mind.
Please.
Sit.
Would you like some tea?
Yes. Thank you.
Please.
Arlington Methodist.
County liaison.
How can I help you?
Sergeant Vaugn,
Fairfax Sheriff Department.
I'm looking for a John Doe...
would have come in
Thursday night.
Male Caucasian, 5'10",
knife wound to the stomach.
Let me look.
Oh, I'm sorry, Sergeant.
He expired that night.
Okay, thank you.
Hey, neighbor!
Hey, Stan.
How's the move-in coming?
Oh, you know,
it's long way to go.
- You want a beer?
- No, thank you.
But I could actually use some
jumper cables if you have them.
My wife's car didn't quite make
the trip from St. Louis.
Sure, come on in.
Oh, great.
You sure no beer?
Oh, I'd love to, but I got
to go in to work.
You don't even get
a day off to move in?
You know, we got
this real shit storm brewing.
Looks like I'm gonna be
working seven-day weeks
for the foreseeable future.
You having car trouble?
Oh, nothing major...
cracked PCV hose.
This is an Oldsmobile Delta,
huh?
Yeah.
'77?
Mm-hmm.
I wanted the Coupe.
She wanted the Sedan.
So we settled on this
with a V8.
Beautiful styling
with these stacked headlights.
GM can't make these
fast enough, huh?
Yeah, it's a great car.
You weren't, uh, tempted
by one of those
Japanese upstarts, huh?
I don't think I'd fit in one.
Oh, yeah, I hear you on that.
Oh, great. Thanks.
You bet.
Well, I got to get back.
Of course. After you.
What's it called?
A piroshki.
It's like a meat dumpling.
They kind of like them.
I kind of like them, too.
They're juicy. They're doughy.
Mr. Beeman.
This is Agent Gaad,
my former deputy.
How you doing?
He's detailed
to a CIA Counterintelligence
task force
at Langley.
He's going to bring them
up to speed on Timoshev,
and hopefully
they can help us out.
Hi, Chris.
Frank.
Agent Beeman, do you think
there's any chance
that Timoshev is still alive?
Uh, he's been here
about 10 minutes, Frank.
Well, it's my understanding
he has some special insight.
Yeah,
my bank-robbery assignment,
the last three years,
I was undercover.
Undercover? With who?
A white-supremacist group
out of Southern Arkansas.
24 principals
currently awaiting trial.
No shit. You were living it,
the whole nine yards?
Yeah. I barely saw my family.
That's one thing
we haven't had around here...
someone with that mind-set.
I thought you were here
for your good looks.
On Timoshev, sir...
when you're betrayed
by one of your own...
Psst. Hey.
When you're betrayed
by one of your own,
you're not inclined to put him
out of his misery fast.
I would bet the Russians
would go to considerable lengths
to get him back there
so they can look him in the eye
before they blow
his brains out.
If you grabbed him
but you couldn't get him
out of the country right away,
where would you keep him?
Well, I wouldn't take him
to the embassy.
I wouldn't want to get near
any Russians,
where we might be looking.
Um, I wouldn't want to be
on the street,
as much as I could avoid it,
or anywhere
I didn't usually go.
I would probably make a beeline
to my house,
to tell you the truth.
It's really the safest place you
can be, strange as that may sound.
And I would just follow
my regular routine,
keep him there
till the heat died down.
Well, if he's at somebody's house,
we're never gonna find him.
No, I wouldn't think so, sir.
Well, thanks.
So, were you, like,
burning crosses and shit
with those guys
or like, "Heil Hitler"?
It was a little deeper
than that.
Like... like what?
Hey, dad, can we get a racing
stripe on the Oldsmobile?
Uh, I don't think your mom
would like that.
Why not?
She doesn't like new things.
* The bombs bursting in air *
* gave proof
through the night *
* that our flag
was still there *
* o say does
that star-spangled banner *
* yet wave *
* o'er the land of the free *
* and the home of the brave? *
Falls Church middle school,
please welcome
a true American hero...
Commander of Gemini 9
and Apollo 10,
Astronaut Thomas P. Stafford.
Whoo!
Listen.
Aah!
You're such a pain in the ass.
I'm trying to make a deal.
Come on, we don't have
much time.
What's going on?
I'm taking him to our neighbor.
- You are?
- Yeah.
I was gonna drive him out,
hand him off further from home,
but you seem to have taken
the distributor cap.
- So you were leaving me.
- I'm gonna make a deal
where you don't have to talk to the
Americans if you don't want to,
if you think that'll
make you a traitor,
but you will come with me
and the kids.
It won't be exactly what you
want, but you'll adjust.
So you're just deciding
for both of us.
- Yeah, one of us has to.
- Why you?
Because we're running
out of time!
Why can't we
do things together?
Because I am a KGB officer!
Don't you understand that,
after all these years?
I would... I would go to jail,
I would die,
I would lose everything before
I would betray my country.
Now I'm finishing this.
Philip, don't!
Come on!
Sorry.
I never meant to hurt you.
They let us have our way
with the cadets.
It was part of the job...
A perk.
What are you
talking about?
What are you talking about?
How... how did you hurt her?
How did he hurt you?
Do what you want with him.
Take him to the Americans,
if that's what you want.
* I can feel it *
* coming in the air tonight *
* oh, lord *
* and I've been waiting
for this moment *
* for all my life *
* oh, lord *
* can you feel it *
* coming in the air tonight? *
* oh, lord *
* well, if you told me *
* you were drowning *
* I would not lend a hand *
* I've seen your face before,
my friend *
* but I don't know
if you know who I am *
* well, I was there,
and I saw what you did *
* I saw it
with my own two eyes *
* so you can wipe off
that grin *
* I know where you've been *
* it's all been a pack of lies *
* and I can feel it *
* coming in the air tonight *
* oh, lord *
* well, I've been waiting
for this moment *
* for all my life *
* oh, lord *
* I can feel it *
* coming in the air tonight *
* oh, lord *
* well, I've been waiting
for this moment *
* for all my life *
* oh, lord *
* I can feel it
in the air tonight *
* oh, lord *
* well, I've been waiting
for this moment *
* for all my life *
* oh, lord *
* I can feel it *
* coming in the air tonight *
* oh, lord *
* and I've been waiting
for this moment *
* for all my life *
* oh, lord *
* I can feel it
in the air tonight *
* oh, lord *
* oh, lord, oh, lord *
* well, I've been waiting
for this moment *
* for all my life *
* oh, lord, oh, lord *
* I can feel it
in the air tonight *
* oh, lord *
* oh, lord, oh, lord, lord *
Good.
* I can feel it *
No, it's too swollen to hide.
We're gonna have to clean
the trunk later.
We made the planets.
And which planet
did your class make?
We made the Sun and Earth.
Sun? No, sorry.
This is the Sun.
Well, that was the Earth,
with the Moon, of course.
But did the Commander
land on it?
- On the Moon?
- Yeah.
Uh, no, he didn't land
on the Moon,
but he got close to it.
You know,
the Moon isn't everything.
Just getting into space is
a remarkable accomplishment.
It's true.
You better hustle off.
Hello?
I want to go to the Moon.
Me too. That'd be awesome.
We got a 7:30 ice time.
What are you doing up
so early on a Sunday?
Oh, it's these crazy shifts
I'm working.
- I've been up since 5:00.
- Ouch.
Yeah, I might as well
just skip sleeping altogether.
- Right?
- How you doing, Henry?
- Good, how about you?
- Good, thanks.
- Whoa, what happened to your neck?
- Uh, shaving.
Two band-aids?
What are you, a butcher?
I got to change
my blades more often.
You know what you get your dad
next Christmas?
What?
- An electric razor.
- Okay.
- Have a good practice.
- Take it easy.
Thanks.
Mom?
Yeah?
Can we, uh, go
to the drugstore?
Sure.
I like that guy, Philip.
Really? You do?
Yeah. I do.
I mean, there's something
a little...
I don't know, there's something a
little bit off about him, maybe.
But I think he's a good guy.
Something a little off?
Yeah, I don't know. Maybe.
You know, I actually have been
feeling that, too.
- Excuse me.
- You have?
Yeah, I mean, you don't have
to spend three years
with the Gold Legion
to have instincts.
It's just kind of a vibe
he gives off.
- Yeah.
- Right?
You know, I was
actually feeling it
with Bill Westerly
from the condo board, too.
- Did you get that from him?
- No.
Yeah, when he was talking
about the assessments,
I was like, this guy is
running drugs in this place.
And the mailman, I just have
kind of instinct, is a pimp.
- Okay, okay.
- Or something.
- I could never really...
- Okay, y-you made your point.
You're... honey, you're back
in the regular world, okay,
so you need to stop
those alarm bells
going off every 10 minutes.
You're officially
now surrounded here
by the most normal, boring
people in the world.
- So enjoy it.
- Okay, we'll enjoy it.
Okay.
* yeah *
* ooh *
* all right *
* Gonna catch
a flight to Nevada *
* leave her friends
at home in L.A. *
* seven come eleven
or Blackjack *
* Gamblin' night and day, yeah *
* 'cause she's a roller, now *
* a high-roller baby, she is *
* mm, she's a roller, yeah *
* a high-roller baby *
* all right, whoo *
No more little girls,
or I'll be back,
and I'll stick that
in your heart.
* Ooh, she likes to play... *
General Zhukov.
Where is the traitor?
He tried to escape.
We killed him.
You missed the hand off.
Your comrade died.
Now the traitor is dead
instead of in our hands.
The Centre is worried enough
to send me here to see you.
- General, I...
- Please sit, Elizabeth.
Thank you.
The American people
have elected
a madman as their president.
He is expanding their military
forces on a massive scale.
He is against
nuclear arms-control agreements.
He makes no secret of his desire
to destroy us.
Our war is not so cold
anymore, Elizabeth.
What happens behind enemy lines
will determine the outcome
of this struggle.
You reported several times
over the years about Philip.
Can we trust him?
Yes. I was wrong.
It was nothing... a little...
a phase in a person's life.
So he is not responsible
for the mess this mission
has become?
I was the one
at fault, General.
I am very sorry.
Don't let that happen again,
Elizabeth.
I may not be able to protect you
if you need me.
These times bring out
the worst in our people.
I am fighting now
against comrades
in our own organization
who are starting to act
like they did
in our darkest days.
I understand.
If I am not here,
you are to fight on.
Our enemy
is strong and capable.
We must meet the challenge.
The orders are
going to change now.
The risks
are going to be greater.
Your comrade who died
was a hero.
We are going to need
more of those now.
We won't let you down, General.
You were just a child.
Is there anything new in here?
We got
a new State Police report.
- Anything on the weapon?
- Not yet.
Our deceased John Doe
from Arlington Methodist
is proving very difficult
to track down.
Either he's
a KGB directorate "S" officer
who got killed
while kidnapping Timoshev,
or he's a drifter who got
stabbed in a fight in Arlington.
His picture's out
to every police department
in the country,
- but it's a needle in a...
- Don't say "haystack."
Mr. Deputy Attorney General.
The Attorney General and I have
just come from the White House.
President Reagan is outraged
that the KGB thinks
it can kidnap someone
with impunity on American soil.
The President has signed
Top Secret Executive Order 2579,
authorizing the Federal
Bureau of Investigation
Counterintelligence Office
to take all necessary measures
to neutralize
Soviet Directorate "S"
sleeper-cell agents
in the continental
United States.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are going to war.
It is a war that will be
fought quietly,
by the men and the woman
in this room.
It will not be short.
And it will not be easy.
But we have truth and justice
on our side.
And we will prevail.
So, why didn't you tell me
about Timoshev?
We aren't supposed to talk
about our other lives.
It wasn't really
your other life.
It happened in training.
It was a long time ago.
I put it behind me.
Things are
about to change, Philip.
It's gonna get uglier,
more dangerous.
We'll be fine.
Don't forget, we've been
doing this a long time.
I was born in Smolensk.
My father died fighting
the Nazis at Stalingrad
when I was 2.
There was a picture of him
in his uniform.
He was pale,
with bushy eyebrows.
He was smiling,
although, of course,
he was going off to die.
My mother was a bookkeeper
for the local Party Committee.
My name is...
was... Nadezhda.
Thank you.
My God, the climate.
Yeah.
It's an air-conditioner.
Is it cold air?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
I'm not ready.
No, I... we're...
supposed to be married now,
that's all.
They'll expect us
to have children, eventually.
Or... I don't know...
maybe you just...
maybe you just don't
find me attractive.
What do you think so far?
You know, they tell you
everything, but...
I don't know...
when you see it,
it just seems... brighter.
There's a weakness
in the people.
I can feel it.
* Why don't you ask him *
* if he's gonna stay? *
* why don't you ask him *
* if he's going awa-a-y? *
* why don't you tell me *
* what's going on? *
* who's on the phone? *
* ooh, oh, oh, oh *
Re-sync by wilson0804
Corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com