No, Bubs. I mean, there's gotta be rules,
or else things get fucked up.
Ain't no rules with dope fiends.
When the police got you shackled up,
you make a move, right?
You help yourself out.
- But to just start snitchin' for no reason...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Let me track this. You hypopulatin'
that you can tattletale when you locked up
but you can't do it
straight up for the money?
I mean, no offense, son,
but that's some weak-ass thinkin'.
You equivocatin' like a motherfuck.
OK, so a snitch is a snitch, right?
- There you go.
- So why be one, man?
We're gettin' by with our capers.
We gettin' by out here rippin' and runnin'
and ain't got shit to show for it.
It's part of bein' a soldier, right?
That's what you say.
That's why I put all this mileage in these feet.
You wait till you ain't a pup no more.
See if you ain't lookin' for something
a little more steady for your own self.
What the fuck? You ill already?
It's ain't even past morning.
I'm cool, man. I'm fine.
Look, we hook up with my girl Kima,
we get paid, you gonna be better.
Fuck that, Bubs, all right?
I'm not a fuckin' snitch.
You know, I could argue the other side -
say if you drop dime
to duck a charge, you a snitch.
You do it as a living, you a professional.
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
You see that ladder right there?
Just like old times, man.
I'll be the bad guy, you be the Lone Ranger.
Leave that man be.
We get paid more hooking up to my girl.
But that's cash money right there.
With the white man, I best be the bad guy.
That way he ain't confused.
All right, meet me in the alley.
Fuck.
- Yo, mister.
- Yo.
Throw down your wallet,
or I'll jerk this ladder right out.
- What? No!
- I ain't playing.
- Throw down the goddamn money.
- No, please. Help!
OK!
Hey!
Leave that man alone!
Oh! Thank you.
It's crazy, man.
- What's that guy doing?
- Shit.
- Here.
- I can't.
No, you saved my ass.
It's appreciated, you know.
Yo, Bubs, you won't fuckin' believe this.
Bubs.
When you walk through the garden
You gotta watch your back
Well, I beg your pardon
Walk the straight and narrow track
Walk the straight
and narrow track
If you walk with Jesus
He's gonna save your soul
You gotta keep the devil
Way down in the hole
He got fire and the fury
Fire and fury
At his command
Well, you don't have to worry
Hold on to Jesus' hands
Oh, we'll be safe from Satan
When the thunder rolls
Oh
You gotta keep the devil
Way down in the hole
Way down
Dennis, you up? Dennis!
Mee-maw, hey.
- Guess you're not workin' today, huh?
- I'm workin' nights now.
At a bar. Workin' the door.
You know, it's just...
- Just till I find something a little bit better.
- Yeah?
Reminds me.
Your friend called again this morning.
She said for you to remember
your appointment.
Says there's a job in it, if you still lookin'.
So Marlo, right?
He got this one boy watchin' his back,
name be Chris Partlow.
Bartlow with a B?
"Part" like white people got in their hair.
- And "low" like a low-bottom dope fiend.
- Partlow.
- Yeah, what I said.
- So he's Marlo's muscle.
So, what...
- How much is that worth?
- Five, if I can work up a photo ID.
- The boy, Fruit, he used that.
- Fruit who runs one of Marlo's corners?
- Careful, it got prints.
- Prints?
Look at you, gettin' all CSI on me and shit.
A burner with prints,
that gotta mean cash money, right?
If I could pull a print, get Fruit ID'd,
I can go to $10.
And if I show you
where Marlo hides his Mercedes?
Benz would go for 15.
You don't know it, but these are hard times.
You killing me out here, girl.
All right. 25 for the Benz.
You good peoples.
So let's total up. We at 40, right?
- Here, bank that for me.
- Bank it? For what?
Got me a plan, girl.
The hoppers here only be
wearing them big white T-shirts
a couple of times before they chuck 'em.
So I'm thinkin',
while I'm out here working for y'all,
I sell them shirts on the corner.
I'll make my nut comin' and goin'.
I don't know what more
you could have done.
Charlie's right, boss.
- You tried.
- Fucking hoodleheads won't cooperate.
You give them their own block or two,
offering them a place to sell drugs in peace,
and do they listen?
It's a damn shame too, 'cause if it worked,
you might have had a positive effect
on the community.
Shift commander,
call the front desk.
You guys are some lying sacks of shit.
- I'm saying, sir...
- I'm guessing...
that you have some thoughts
on where we should go from here.
Well, sir, we were thinking
a modified zebra operation.
Jump-outs from sector to sector,
and a zero-tolerance approach.
We detail a couple of men from each shift,
build a flex unit,
double up on head-knocking
and corner-clearing.
- More of the same, you mean.
- But better.
Better?
Better than nothing.
Ah, fuck this bullshit already.
Man, they gave us 15 cases of legal
but they shorted us on the colored bonds.
What's going on, man?
Yo. I got this.
- Officer.
- Detective, String.
You remember. Bird trial.
Detective McNulty.
You want something copied, man?
Search warrant, court papers?
- Anything I can do to help, you know.
- I ain't seen you around the way.
I'm not around the way no more.
You wanna find me, I'm right here.
- Right here, huh?
- Mm-hm.
This and some real estate
I'm working on is all.
More than enough to occupy me, really.
- Say, where you livin', man?
- Where am I livin'?
If you thinkin' of comin' downtown,
I got some condos
about to come on the line in eight months.
You say the word, I'm gonna hook you up
something nice by the Hippodrome.
Loft apartments. Real nice.
You disappoint me, String.
I had such fuckin' hopes for us.
Have a nice day, Officer.
You see this shit?
Remember that kid who got shot
in Lake Clifton a couple months back?
Drug feud, right? What about it?
Last night,
they just found the only eyewitness
in an alleyway, bunch of holes in him.
- And?
- What do you mean, "And?"
You're talkin' about a state's witness.
You let a witness get killed
in a case like this, it says...
- "The city's broke and can't be fixed."
- Uh-oh.
- Sounds like we found an issue.
- Fuck the politics for a minute.
This is something
we all need to be on the same page with.
I'm serious, Tony.
You let shit like this stand,
pretty soon you got nothing left.
You gonna go public
and bang the mayor with it?
You gonna bang Burrell
and the state's attorney, then?
I ain't gonna bang nobody.
Like I said, fuck the politics for once.
But there is a problem here,
and I'm gonna help fix it.
You want your cape
and the little red underpants?
Or you stash that shit in the phone booth?
I always wondered about that.
- Man, I'd like a piece of that.
- You'd like any piece at all.
- Nigger, I'd like a piece of your mother.
- Stop fuckin' around.
I ain't started that shit.
Yo, now she got our boy
with his nose wide open.
He's stealing from us
and she most likely the reason for it.
Y'all stay with the girl.
She'll soon enough show us the money.
Where you goin'?
I got something I gotta do.
You supposed to be here with us.
Y'all stay with the girl.
I'll get back with y'all down the way.
- Say what?
- I made a date a while back,
got to keep.
Man made a date, got to keep.
We find out he pussy-whipped
like this motherfucker over here.
Now, once again, from the data,
- when are most cars stolen?
- Sir, at night.
And your unit, which I believe is charged
with deterring the theft of autos,
when do you work?
The day shift, eight to four.
But, sir, as I tried to explain...
You effect more arrests of car thieves
during the daylight than at night.
You see, our ears work, we heard you.
But the question becomes -
- why the fuck can't you hear us?
- Sir, I don't...
The Commissioner is attempting to move
this department into the 21 st century.
That means preventing crime
by relying on computer-generated data,
not on your
fly-by-your-fucked-up-ass instinct.
Give me the auto-theft numbers
for downtown parking lots on Friday nights.
Sir, I have to check that.
Where are we with the gun?
Colonel, I was made to understand
that recovering Officer Dozerman's
weapon was a priority.
The gun, yes, we're on it, sir.
Making progress as we speak.
Lieutenant?
Sir, I now understand
that prevention is the way to go,
and we'll immediately
change our hours to reflect the data.
All right, Lieutenant.
Fecal gravity.
You beat on the right people
and the shit rolls down the hill.
- Dennis, is it?
- Cutty works for me.
Cutty, then.
So it's just gonna be us here?
- You know, I mean, Grace...
- Sister Grace called on your behalf,
but to my knowledge,
she didn't plan to be here.
She's a beautiful woman.
A man might say things he didn't mean
to stand closer to a woman like that.
You're in the job market, though,
I understand.
A couple of questions.
You got a high-school diploma, GED?
Any work experience?
I worked in a warehouse
for a couple of months back in, like, '86.
How do you see the church helping you?
Maybe get me some jobs or put my name
on a list or something. I don't know.
To tell you up front,
we don't do that here.
You want a job,
you'll have to work to get it.
We'll help, but it's gonna be your sweat.
With that said, then, the first thing
is to get you enrolled in a GED program.
Look, I don't mean to put you out,
but this...
this ain't how I thought it was gonna play.
Me, Oscar, a bunch of the guys...
we seen it.
Couldn't help it.
They practically ran right past us.
And the victim, the girl, had a gun.
Whose side was she on?
Couldn't tell.
They weren't doin' slow motion.
Did any of 'em have a big scar?
Do you think you'd be able to recognize
any of them?
- Just Omar.
- So you know Omar?
Omar came up around here.
That's good, Bruiser, very good.
- You do know Omar has a scar, right?
- He do?
We better go to my office,
put this down on paper. Come on.
Officer. Excuse me, Officer.
Is this North and Pulaski?
Cos I could fucking swear Dozerman
was shot up at North and Pulaski.
No, wait, let me guess.
The pursuit of your fellow officer's
service weapon
has led you to this fine citizen.
Tell me, kind sir, do you know
the whereabouts of said officer's weapon?
I didn't think so.
Calls from the detention center.
Some kind souls begging to assist you
in your foundering investigation.
Oop!
Let me just grand-jury my man here,
lock in his story.
Now for the gun. Later for his story.
And that's your sergeant talking.
Wipe your nose, yo.
- What the fuck?
- Oh, shit.
Motherfucker, you scared the shit out of us
comin' up like that.
This shit do make you paranoid, yo.
- Go on, nigger, hit this shit.
- No, man, I gotta drop urine tomorrow.
You worried about that?
Go ahead, nigger. We got that covered.
Oh, you got that covered?
What, you think
you're the only motherfucker on parole?
- Yo, nigger, give me that shit.
- There you go.
- All right. What was her day?
- She caught a hack up to Towson Town Mall.
Hit two jewelry stores
and came back with bags from both.
By the time she caught up with our boy,
she was wearing one of them shits
around her neck.
- Gave the other one to him.
- You know, his and hers, like.
Yeah, Cutty. She was on that shit, man.
It's been a week, McNulty. Either you got
something on Stringer or you don't.
He tried to sell me a condo.
Cocksucker.
Might as well join the Rotary
and take up golf or some shit.
Running with the hounds,
but I bet his heart's still with the fox.
Stringer's out of the game?
Mr. Bell has become the bank.
The bank?
The bank plays it legit.
He generates honest income.
But at the same time,
his money finances packages
that he himself will never touch.
He won't go near the street. He's insulated
from the everyday operations of the corner.
The money that comes back
is then laundered through
enough investments
that there's no way to trace it.
A player gets to that point,
there ain't no way in hell
a working police
is gonna tie a can to his tail.
Oh, man.
So, Kintel Williamson,
the prince of Pimlico.
- Where we at on this mope?
- DNRs on a couple of payphones.
That got it?
About right.
You gonna help or what, boy?
Might as well not even take a whistle
if I'm just standin' in the fuckin' alley.
Back's where you belong.
Thataway I ain't got to worry
about getting my head blown off
'cause you all scared and shit.
Enough!
Y'all hear me? I said enough.
Come over here and put some pumpkin balls
in this shotgun, man. Kimmy!
Both of y'all learn to live with it,
or y'all out, man.
Now, this time we gonna do it right.
Y'all feel me?
Boss, you gotta let this go.
It ain't gonna work.
You said in COMSTAT shit rolls down.
We tried to talk to all the hoppers.
What can they do about anything?
We need to bring it to the dealers.
Sergeant.
I need a list of names of all
the mid-level dealers running my corners.
Sir?
You are my DEU sergeant, right?
I need a list of names.
Maybe narcotics downtown
has something like that. I don't know.
We're knockin' heads, takin' bodies. I didn't
know I was supposed to be doin' a census.
Hey, yo, miss.
Where the pee-pot at?
Thanks. Come on, this way.
My man need to drop a negative.
- $5.
- Motherfucker, they was just two.
You try findin' clean piss in Baltimore.
Five a go.
- How I know it's clean?
- I get mine from daycare.
I need you to put the chicken
in the oven at 375.
Yes, and then I need you
to help me put your sister down...
Excuse me, miss.
Put your thumb on the scanner.
Hold on a second.
- What's your name?
- Wise, Dennis Wise.
Take one of those.
Go around the corner to the second door.
No, you cannot go outside.
Are you listening to what I'm saying?
That's all we got on the West Side dealers.
George. I'm lookin'
at a sprinklin' of rap sheets here.
You tellin' me nobody know
who controls West Baltimore corners?
Rawls has my people doin' street rips.
You want info, try the intelligence unit.
- Shit, they sent me to you, George.
- What the fuck can I tell you?
With all the street work, ain't nobody left
doin' high-end drug stuff.
From what I'm hearing,
the guy comes in of his own accord
and he gets betrayed by us.
Protection in this city amounts
to nothing more than getting dumped
in a fleabag joint on Route 40
and calling it a plan.
No monitoring, no assistance.
Nothing. Just a bundle of clothes
and a toothbrush.
- Jesus.
- No way to treat a cooperator.
I could get a lot out of this
with the press.
But fuck that, because that way everybody
gets defensive and nothing gets fixed.
- I'm coming to you with this, straight up.
- Agreed.
Where do we stand on this?
You've already called a meeting on it
with the state's attorney
and the Police Commissioner.
It's penciled in for next Wednesday.
No, Tommy's right on this.
We need to act quickly.
I'm glad you came to us with this.
I'll light a fire, believe me.
All right, thanks.
- Uh, you will keep me in the loop on this?
- Absolutely. Councilman.
- Slow up, we need to talk.
- Yeah, sweet thing.
- We met before?
- No, baby, but that can happen.
We ain't met, excuse me.
- It's just talk, baby.
- Get the fuck out the way.
Look, girl, all we need you to do is talk.
- Is you deaf or just stupid?
- Hold on, girl...
Damn.
Now we gonna talk.
How the fuck is this little runt of a unit
holdin' all this drug intelligence?
At headquarters I came up with jack,
and y'all holdin' all this.
You run a couple of wiretaps,
you fill up a file cabinet pretty fast.
This is great. Thanks.
Oh, shit! God damn it!
I heard this was where you landed.
This pretty boy, I broke his ass in.
I wrote more on ID complaints
on bushy top here
than on the whole goddamn squad.
That's till he scuffed himself up.
- Now where you at, McNulty?
- 1911 South Clinton Street, first floor.
There you go.
Yeah. I know you gotta keep him close
but still, that's a good goddamn police
right here.
So what brings you to our shop?
I'm tryin' to find out
who running my corners.
My own DEU is just about street rips,
and headquarters wasn't no help, neither.
- Y'all saved my ass, though.
- You tell him about your boy, Marlo?
It's in the files, along with
every other mid-level player we know.
You don't mind me askin',
what are you gonna do with all that, Major?
Well...
we'll round up these young men...
and put a little COMSTAT on their ass.
Gentlemen. Ma'am. Bushy top.
Bushy top?
Uh, point of order and shit.
Chair recognize the esteemed rep
of the Veronica Avenue boys.
All right, look, we done talked this shit
to death, all right?
- When we gonna vote?
- Rick do have a point.
All right, then.
All those in favor of goin' together
so we can get the best discount
on a New York package, raise up.
- All right, then.
- There it is.
Look like we gonna make
more money, together.
I'm proud of y'all
for putting aside petty grievances
and puttin' this thing together.
For a cold-ass crew of gangsters,
y'all carried it like Republicans and shit.
Remember, man,
talk this shit up when you hit them bricks.
Best way to get more involved is to tell people
about the benefits of this here thing.
No beefing, no drama, just business.
Anybody got problems
with anybody else here,
we bring it to the group.
We ain't gotta take it to the streets.
All right. Let's do it.
Yo.
Motherfucker, what is that?
The Robert Rules say we gotta have
minutes for a meeting. These the minutes.
Nigger, is you takin' notes
on a criminal fuckin' conspiracy?
What the fuck is you thinking, man?
- That's cool.
- Dad, he's cheating.
Michael, take it easy on your brother.
How are you two getting along
with Mom's new friend?
- We call him Dennis. He's not new.
- OK, how are you doin' with him?
Mom says we can't talk to you
about family stuff.
Dad, you going to the open house?
Yeah, I'll try.
I've been real busy at work, though.
- New case and all.
- Mom says you have to go, Dad.
All the other kids' fathers are gonna be there.
Get his legs.
Aagh!
Argh!
- Steal from us, motherfucker?
- Get the ring too, yo.
- Shit won't come off, yo.
- Drop him.
Arrrghh!
You know the man works for us.
You keep goin' like that,
ain't gonna be nothin' left of him
to make right what he owes.
Bitch got to pay.
- Check his pockets, yo.
- Right.
- That's mine, yo.
- Fuck off! Get the fuck off!
This is command to security.
What's up, baby?
Man, I been here for 26 months,
you come pick me up
in a motherfuckin' Ford?
I'm just fucking with you. What's up, baby?
What up, man?
I'm feeling good to be
out of this motherfucker.
There's a sign on the other side of this gate
that say, "Never again."
That's the only fucking thing
I'm gonna take with me from here.
- First things first. Let's get you lookin' right.
- You got my shit.
Yes. Yes. Good-looking, baby.
Start with Sector One.
Bring as many as you can down to
Vincent Street by the end of the shift.
Don't use your wagons.
Bring as many as you can in your cars.
The hoppers wouldn't listen.
What makes you think these guys will?
These are lieutenants running the corners
and I personally feel their pain.
Now, middle-management means
that you have just enough responsibility
that you got to listen when people talk
and not so much that you can tell anybody
to go fuck themselves.
471, 471...
Get in.
Look, my major just wants to talk.
That's all, I promise.
- We'll bring you right back.
- Ain't gonna happen.
What the fuck you say?
What the fuck you mean,
it ain't gonna happen?
Let me tell you something, motherfucker.
We got orders to bring you
for a sit-down with our boss.
We're prepared to take you with us now.
- We can either do this the easy way...
- Brain-dead fucks.
It's up to you.
- Hello.
- Prez, it's me.
I think we got a little situation here.
Stay with me. 10-6.
Major wants the dickhead, you gotta go.
I think he gets a pass this time.
You sure? I mean, you want, he goes.
Another time, Herc.
We're on the major's clock here.
Don't forget the face, cocksucker.
It's gonna be here tomorrow.
- You need me to call dispatch?
- No, it's OK. I'll tell you later.
I say we get the troops
and fuck these assholes up.
- Come on, let's go again.
- Come on, Tommy, it's just a game.
Look, sounds like you got what you want,
anyway. From the mayor, I mean.
Yeah, well, he's played me before.
But so help me, if he farts around on this,
I'm goin' after him, big time.
- For real?
- Trust me on this.
He keeps ducking me,
I'm gonna fuck him good.
That's the good part.
It's what I call the carrot.
Now, you move your people
into any designated area I told you about,
and you'll have immunity
from arrest and prosecution.
You're free to make your drops, collect,
won't nobody bother you.
You got my word on it.
- What do you get outta this?
- That's a fair question.
I want to salvage
what's worth salvaging in my district.
I can't do that with a bunch of hoppers
scaring the hell out of decent people.
Now, these kids ain't gonna listen to me,
but they will listen to y'all.
You tell them to move down here
and they will.
So the way I got it figured, I motivate you...
and you motivate them.
Nah, this is a trap.
No, you check out the spot.
There ain't no cameras,
ain't no microphones, nothing.
Any cops you see
going to be down right on the perimeter.
Just to make sure there's no violence.
And you watch.
You see if it don't work out the way I say.
Nothing personal against you, Chief,
but what happens if we buck?
You remember the carrot, right?
Well, you choose the stick instead...
you gonna feel that stick
like you ain't never felt before.
We gonna indict every corner, every day.
I got over 200 sworn personnel
and I plan to free up every one
to knock every one of y'all down they can.
You on a corner in my district,
it ain't gonna be about no humble,
it ain't gonna be about no loitering charge,
nothing like that.
There gonna be some biblical shit
happening to you
on the way to that jail wagon.
And while you buckin' the new system,
the smart ones among you
gonna be down here,
makin' money hand over fist.
So think it over.
But I swear to God, come Monday,
your world and mine
ain't gonna be the same.
I thought you said
these goddamn houses were vacant.
We must have missed her.
That's one more thing I gotta do, then.
Little man, up on B tier,
one of his boys in the dormitory,
his brother's tight with the girlfriend
of the boy that shot that police.
Little man saying,
"If you sprung the three of us,
"we can get her talking."
You know, find the gun.
Yo, I'm hearing the boy Dink
got that man's gun.
Now, I ain't sure yet
if that Dink be Dink Dink
or Inky Dink or maybe Fat Dink.
Then again, it might be Flatnose Dink.
No, wait.
Nah, that can't be him, that Dink dead.
Look, man, I can help you,
but first you gotta get me
out of these murder beefs.
How many murders are we talking?
Look, man, do it have to be the cop's gun?
Cos if it's guns you want,
I can get you guns.
I remember this. Sixth grade.
Miss Holley's science class.
Box lunches. Taste like shit.
You got something so important
you can't use the proper channels?
Well, no. I don't know.
I just figured if I told anybody but you,
you might think I'm riding the rock.
What makes me think you ain't?
Yeah, right. That's a good point.
Look, today, me, Tuckie, Little Mikey,
man, we all, a bunch of us
got scooped up by the police.
Well, you shouldn't sell drugs.
- All right, all right.
- See, they didn't take us to the station.
They took us down to Vincent Street
where all the houses is boarded up,
and they let us out.
And then, on top of all of that,
the whole while they was being
all like decent and shit,
and you know that fucked me up.
And then, like,
the police chief, he come out -
and this is the crazy part -
he say that he got it set up
so where we could sell stuff in certain spots
and the police won't bother us.
I know, I know. It's fucked up.
But I just thought you should know.
- That's it?
- Yeah, just that and the boy Marlo.
Yeah, I'm on it.
Yep.
Speaking to officer at
5-Baker-25 on the northern channel.
23-03 to KGA.
Have Foxtrot meet me on six, Adam.
- Foxtrot, 10-4.
- 23-03 to Foxtrot.
- Foxtrot, standing by.
- It's a black Mercedes, pulling out the lot.
Copy that, we got the eyeball.
This here the spot? Cos Tuckie says
we supposed to set up shop here.
Huh?
- Hamsterdam.
- Yeah, this is it.
Set up anywhere inside
where we got the white flags.
- I'm ready to roll out.
- You just got here. What's wrong?
Ain't nobody around to buy.
Good point.
- Man needs customers.
- I'm sayin'...
No. I mean, you can't make me.
I'm a sworn fuckin' police officer.
What's up, man?
You got that Body Bag still? Two.
Narco.
Give it up, motherfucker.
Money comes back, right now.
You fuckin' up. You didn't let me cop
before you snatch me up.
Is that some fuckin' rule?
- You call, we haul. You clean?
- Yeah, of course I'm clean.
Stupid-ass rookie
didn't give me a chance to cop.
This corner's indicted.
You move over to Vincent Street,
or we come back with the bracelets.
Anybody available
for complaint at...
- What you got?
- 10-11 me at Riggs and Calhoun.
Despite unforeseen delays,
we will begin an academy class
this January,
which leaves us in good shape
for the coming year.
Thank you, Commissioner.
The chair pleases,
I have a couple of questions.
Commissioner, you are aware
that a state witness
in a recent city homicide prosecution
was killed.
Uh, we are treating that incident
with the highest priority.
Homicide has set up a task force
and Narcotics is working
the informant angle.
We have also asked both the FBI
and DEA for support.
It sounds like a full-court press,
but you must admit
it's a bit like closing the barn door
after the horse is out.
The shooting of the boy
at Lake Clifton School
was a high-profile case,
wasn't it, Commissioner?
Yes, it was.
And yet a key witness in the case
was allowed... One moment.
Excuse me, but the chair reminds me
that you have a pressing engagement.
So if it's all right with you,
we can continue this at a later date.
Meeting adjourned.
Did you see Burrell sweat?
- The man's collar almost melted.
- What the hell got into you?
You did, old buddy. You did.
10-8, 23.
End of the line, all out.
We got that Rockefeller, yo.
We got that Rockefeller over here, yo.
- Over here we got that Rockefeller.
- What the fuck?
Yo, yo, we got that Rockefeller, yo.
We got that WMD. Right here, right here.
- I hear the WMD is the bomb.
- WMD. Right here.
WMD.
Give me two, yo.
WMD. Right here.
WMD, right here. Right here.
Right here.
We got that Rockefeller over here.
We got that Rockefeller, yo.
- What do we got?
- There's binoculars on the floor.
- Marlo makin' a move?
- Just watch.
Forget everything the boy Bodie told you.
Forget the beating, it ain't about that.
You smart, man, I can see that.
I wanted you to choose somewhere safe
for us to speak, but God damn...
only bugs in this motherfucker
gonna have legs.
Now, I appreciate smart,
but you gotta know in this game, man,
it ain't enough.
You a student of history?
You know this town had its share
of smart players, man?
Melvin, Little Wil, Big Head Brother,
Peanut, Warren.
All real smart, man, real smart.
But you know,
soon as their names rang out...
bam, the feds was on them.
You know what I mean?
Government ain't want you to be organized.
They want you scrimpin' and scrapin'
and killin' each other on the corner
on some bullshit. Not me.
That's why me and Prop Joe,
we getting ready to put this co-op together.
Different crews, one package.
Best dope, best coke.
Share and share alike.
- Been hearin' about that.
- You been hearin' about that?
That's good. That's a start, right?
You know that Mercedes
you got ridin' out there,
you got that titled in your aunt's name
or some shit?
Now, when they come get you,
that straw purchase out there
gonna come bite you in the ass, boy.
That's what they do.
They turn your money against you.
Now, you,
I'm thinkin' with the corners that you got...
- you close to a mil, right?
- I'm doin' all right.
You doin' all right, but all right
ain't got your name on a crib, right?
Ain't got you a little spot for you
to wash that dirty money.
That's what I'm offering you, man.
- Come on, who's he in there with?
- I told you, keep watching.
Bunk put you up to this?
Tell you what, how about a case
of that PBR piss you drink
against a touch of the Irish
that he went out the back
and you're watching that house for nothing?
Here comes your nothing.
Whoa!
Oh, ho ho ho ho!
I like my piss in bottles.
Any way you like, darlin'.
Chris. Tell our people to tool up.
I'm on it.
WMD. Got that WMD.
They get
comfortable pretty quick.
It's like we ain't even
standin' here.
The hoppers call it Hamsterdam.
Like from Amsterdam.
Hamsterdam.
The use of
integrated match concepts,
such as algebraic reasoning and
number sense, geometry and probability.
Very impressive.
Now what we try to do is keep
the class size under ten, 12 at the most.
- And there are three levels?
- Yes, so that...
Sorry, I'm Jim McNulty.
I'm a little late, developments at work.
Mr. McNulty.
I have some concerns
about the integrated math program.
In their previous schools,
Michael took introductory algebra
but I hear you're doing
something different.
- We are. The integrated program...
- I'm thirsty.
Can I get either of you something to drink?
The integrated math program consists...
Not much of a spread
but you can't go wrong with crudités.
Crudity?
I'm sorry. I came straight from work,
or I'd have changed.
No need to call names, right?
- What do you do, Mr...
- I'm on the board at Legg Mason.
Jim McNulty.
Legg Mason?
Either that or I'm a cop in the city.
I keep forgetting.
Terri D'Agostino.
I'm an alumni and one of the school's
dreaded fundraisers.
The math program
offers tutoring possibilities.
So if Michael has difficulty adjusting,
we can have classes
on Tuesdays and Thursdays.
- So how do you find the school?
- It's good.
Good.
My ex and I are thinking
of sending our boys here.
- Any problems, difficulties?
- No, not really.
I mean, there's the math integration class
for my oldest.
He's in sixth, seventh, and...
I'm just not sure he's ready, you know,
for all that math.
Aagh!
- Careful, I'm only a country boy.
- Shut up.
Hey, sweetie. Welcome home.
How you doin'?
What's up, man? How you doin'?
Welcome back.
Hey, sis.
Man, I just wish I wasn't the only one
coming home, you know.
I know.
Enjoy tonight. We'll talk later.
- Welcome home.
- What up, Prop? How you doing, man?
- You lookin' fit.
- Hell, yeah,
I've been working out.
That's all you do.
Might be a good place
for a fat man to find his inner self.
Yo. I got some downtown suits
who wanna holler at you real quick.
Ah, shit. Takin' me to see suits?
I'm tryin' to see some skirts.
So what do you do?
You should get dressed.
I got a lot of work here.
It's a long day for me tomorrow.
I'll be really quiet.
You never know,
you might get bored workin'.
I gotta work.
You gotta go.
What Stringer has done
with all that property downtown, Avon,
I cannot tell the profit you're looking at
once the federal redevelopment
money lands.
That whole Howard Street thing
will take off
and you'll be right there to cut the pie.
Any dollar you spend now
is gonna come back to you ten times.
And the thing is, I know
you don't wanna go back to them streets.
Not after what you been through.
I know, 'cause I'm from them same streets.
And once I had the chance
to play a different game
it wasn't a question in my mind how to go.
Government's will look at you hard too.
No sense giving 'em
what they're looking for.
You take what you have, you build on it.
It's all good. Just put it up on the calendar.
We should meet.
Yo, Slim.
You see them two niggers right there?
They over there getting high
in the middle of all this.
Now where the fucking discipline at, yo?
Fuck, toss them niggers.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Don't you know not to stare at me like that?
Yo.
I gotta show you something.
Pardon me, sweetie.
Yo, man.
You know I've been locked down, man.
You gonna love this. Trust me.
Oh, OK.
Uhh-huh. Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Shit, this ain't my little place
down in Jessup.
But what the fuck is, right?
This is all you, B.
All you, in your name too.
You know what I mean?
This piece of paper right here make it legit.
Keys to the Navigator in the basement.
It's just a rental
until you pick out something nice.
Damn, all this, huh?
You did good.
We makin' so much straight money, man,
we can carry shit like this out in the open,
in our own names.
Yo, you remember when we used to sit
on the top of 734 building, man,
lookin' at the city,
used to talk about what we gonna do?
And you was all heavy
into that black pride bullshit
talking like you gonna get two grocery stores,
make motherfuckers proud.
Sure was, man,
you was out hunting on a AK-47
talking about "I'm gonna go get warrin'."
Man.
- We brothers, B.
- Always, baby.
Always.
Just one more thing, though, man.
I don't mean to be picking with you,
especially not after you did
all this shit for me,
but, look, man, I've been locked down.
You know what I mean?
You know what?
I gotta take this meet.
I'm gonna get at you. Welcome home, man.
Hey, yo, it's me, man. I left something.
Shit. My man.