(singers harmonizing)
(light, upbeat melody joins
singers harmonizing)
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la
la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la
la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la... ♪
(singers resume harmonizing,
melody building)
(elevator bell dings)
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la
la-la, la ♪
♪ La... ah... ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la
la-la, la ♪
♪ La... la... ♪
Nice to see you again.
♪ Ah... ah. ♪
(door closes)
Let me know if I'm not in frame.
I can move down.
I'm not wearing a camera.
Oh, how considerate.
Let's skip
the hostility, please.
She went out of her way to
make us look like bigots.
I think I'm being pretty
friendly, considering.
I can see you went
with diversity in hiring.
How are Biff and Skippy?
Mike and Brian.
What can we do
for you, Monica?
I can't imagine that
you're here to apologize.
A friend of mine was
recently run out of business
by a giant tech company.
I'm bringing suit.
And you don't have the resources
to pursue the case on your own?
You said to call
if I needed help.
You've complicated
our relationship
since I made that offer.
True.
But at least we know we can
be direct with each other.
Besides, it could be
good for your image.
How?
The company
I'm suing is even
more lacking
in diversity than yours.
And what company is that?
Chumhum.
And you want us to help?
Well, actually, I need Lucca
to help, but I know you two
have this Bert
and Ernie thing going.
Well, why me?
Alicia's the one
that's worked with Chumhum.
Well, it's a racism case.
And, uh, my firm's
a little pale at the moment.
What an honor.
My parents would be so proud.
Who's suing?
WOMAN: We used to book up
weeks in advance.
Our venison pot pie was
written up in the Trib.
We were Zagat rated.
Then people just stopped coming.
It's hard not to take it
personally when it's your baby.
And why is Chumhum
responsible?
Their maps program--
Chummy Maps--
it's supposed to help
users stay safe
by giving them directions
to avoid the dangerous
parts of the city.
Green's safe, yellow's so-so,
and red means "stay away."
When the filter's on,
driving directions
avoid the red areas.
The filter is always
on by default.
You have to manually
turn it off.
So you lost your foot traffic?
And this--
watch when I
toggle the filter on and off.
MONICA:
It doesn't show businesses
in the red parts of the map.
When this came out, it
was like I didn't exist.
It says this is an unsafe area?
Yes, a red zone.
It doesn't feel unsafe.
MONICA: Yes, except
for one thing.
Too many people of color.
MAN:
Our maps are not racist.
It's run by an algorithm.
And math is not racist.
Chumhum is very proud
of its diversity and openness.
DIANE: And yet their
Safe Filter
deters people
from patronizing businesses
in African-American
neighborhoods.
LUCCA:
Chumhum is not responsible
for the actions of those
who respond to its software.
It was Ms. Feldman's choice
to open a four-star restaurant
in a marginal neighborhood,
not ours.
It isn't a marginal
neighborhood,
It's a black neighborhood.
Well, it's both, which really
isn't that uncommon.
Wait, what?!
Well, he's not saying
anything that unusual.
Look at crime rates.
Look at home values.
And look at the biracial lawyer
pimping for a racist system.
Excuse me?!
Are you actually saying--?
(all talking at once)
Let's not make this personal,
guys. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hey, wait.
Chumhum will admit
no wrongdoing.
But in the spirit of making
this world a better place,
Mr. Harman is willing to
offer Ms. Feldman $50,000
to open a new restaurant
anywhere she wants.
Consider it a gesture.
MONICA: What
gesture is that?
The finger?
Chumhum is worth 300 billion.
I know how much my company
is worth, thank you.
CARY: Is that because your
stock's dropped 22%
since you became COO?
HARMAN: Wow, seriously?
Okay, Cary, you don't
need to go there.
Want to fight dirty now?
You know what?
No, we're done!
Your guy's a piece of work.
Unfortunately for you,
the law's on his side.
We'll see.
PAIGE: You're kind of
in love with her,
aren't you?
Who?
Alicia.
(scoffs)
No.
You just talked about her
for the last 30 minutes.
Occupational hazard.
You have to be obsessed
with your candidate,
or you're not doing your job.
"Candidate"?
Well, the question is
will the voters think
she's still tainted
by her scandal?
You're staring at me.
I can feel it.
I can't help it.
You are very sexy
when you're writing a check.
(laughs)
$50,000?
Convene a focus group.
See if you've resurrected
St. Alicia.
ALICIA:
But above all else,
I am a mother,
and it's as a mother
I am asking for your support,
Webster City.
I know ethanol can make
a difference for our children.
So please remember,
a vote for Florrick
is a vote for family.
Really?
I feel like I'm pandering
to housewives.
Anyone who knows me will smell
the bullcrap a mile away.
Yes, but it's Iowa.
All they smell is bullcrap.
Look, these e-mail blasts
aren't meant to be subtle.
They're a sledgehammer.
So don't pull back.
Okay, what's
the next city?
Three, two...
Hello, voters
of Sioux Center.
I'm Alicia Florrick.
As the mother
of two incredible--
(door opens)
um...
(door closes)
kids... I, um,
love and adore...
Do you need a minute?
Yeah, it just...
thanks.
Hey.
Hi.
What's wrong?
Uh, nothing.
All right,
so I have something to say.
Okay.
Now, we agreed that I would
stay freelance, right?
Yes.
That's how I keep
my fee low.
And part of that
freelance work has taken me
to Lockhart/Agos.
I know.
Well, clearly
you have some
hard feelings toward them,
but, Alicia,
I would never use
information gleaned
from here--
Oh, no I never
thought you would.
But if you have some sort of
issue with this arrangement,
then we should talk,
because I need to know
whether I can
continue working here.
I want you to work here.
Even if freelancing
takes me to Lockhart/Agos?
Yes.
Good.
I have something
for your motion to dismiss.
Oh, I thought
you were gonna say
you were going to Lockhart/Agos
for this case.
No.
Unless you want me to.
No. Shut up.
(both chuckle)
Uh, here.
(laughs)
Thank you.
JUDGE MARX:
You're suing Chumhum
for tortious interference
with prospective
economic advantage?
Yes, Your Honor,
Chumhum's Safe Filter
creates a racist geofencing
effect that disadvantages
business owners in African-
American neighborhoods.
Your Honor, tortious
interference requires
proof of either purposeful
or knowing interference.
And there is none here.
We believe there is, Your Honor.
I'd like to call
a witness to show
that the intent requirement
is not met.
Mr. Harman, is it possible
for Chumhum's Safe Filter
to have a racist intent?
No, the filter is powered by two
things, and two things only:
objective third party
statistics--
uh, crime rates, for example--
and user-generated
feedback data.
Like comments and reviews?
Yes, exactly.
Which is entirely
in the users' hands.
I mean, there's no way
that anyone at Chumhum
could use a Safe Filter
to purposefully interfere
with plaintiff's business?
No, not even if we wanted to.
Thank you.
DIANE: Mr. Harman, is it
true that Chummy Maps
is only available on cOS--
Chumhum's own operating system?
Yes.
This is a recent study done
by the Internet
Research Foundation.
Could you read
what it says right there?
Uh, "cOS users are 71%...
Caucasian."
DIANE: And what percentage of
cOS users are African-American?
Does it say?
Eleven percent.
DIANE: And do these numbers
match your own
market research?
Chumhum is not to blame
for socioeconomic disparity.
Our products cost more because
they are better products.
So you knew about the disparity
between white and black users?
HARMAN: Again, our products
are not intentionally
targeted toward
Caucasians.
Yes, but if your
user-generated feedback data
is being generated predominately
by white users,
doesn't it follow that
the results will be skewed?
Objection, speculation.
JUDGE: Perhaps.
And yet I'm still curious.
HARMAN: Would the results
be skewed? No.
DIANE: Really?
If you allow
one racial group to
dominate a discussion
about what neighborhood
is safe, you don't think
the results will be skewed?
ALICIA: Objection!
Asked and answered.
You're right.
I'm just giving him
a chance to rethink.
But it seems
he doesn't want to.
Withdrawn.
Purposeful
or knowing interference
doesn't just mean
the defendant knew
his product could
have a disparately
racist effect.
It also means...
he should've known.
We lost.
Mr. Harman admits he knew
their data was being generated
primarily by Caucasians,
so an argument can be made
that he should have known
what would result.
Ms. Quinn, Mrs. Florrick,
your motion
to dismiss is denied.
Request full discovery,
Your Honor.
Your Honor!
Plaintiff is only asking
for full discovery
in order to force us to settle.
Poking around
all of Chumhum's products
would compromise trade secrets.
JUDGE: But you can't shut
them out entirely.
I'm granting
the discovery motion
and limiting it to items
related to racist references
and Chummy Maps.
(gavel bangs)
What do you think?
Small.
You don't get
claustrophobic in here?
I'm actually
starting to like it.
Yeah, Stockholm syndrome.
I meant what do you think
about the focus group?
You want to run her
for a senate seat?
To start.
Alicia Florrick.
Wife of the Illinois governor?
A woman who stood by her husband
during his worst moments.
Housewives--
Republican and Democratic.
And independents.
How large a sampling?
Whatever I can get for $50,000.
But we have to have
ironclad waivers. Nobody
can know we're doing this.
Especially not Alicia.
Why not Alicia?
Because I'm using it
to convince her.
(laughing)
Yup, good old Eli.
(phone rings)
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Gina, could you come in here?
Do we need the
Cone of Silence?
Alicia and Jason Crouse.
I have no idea what that means.
Jason Crouse.
Alicia's investigator.
I know who he is--
Are they having an affair?
No, of course not.
No.
He came by the apartment
while I was filming
Alicia's Internet ads
and she touched him.
Touched him where?
His arm.
Like a massage?
No, not like a massage.
Then let it go.
She touched his arm.
People touch each other's arms.
She was smiling at him
like a schoolgirl, Eli.
And not just in front of me--
in front of the whole crew.
Eli, I want to be clear here.
They were touching
in front of strangers
with cameras.
Okay, let me look into it.
Now, we both know
Peter's campaign
wouldn't withstand
the fallout
of something like this.
And Alicia's rehabilitation
would certainly
become a wasted effort.
Okay, let me handle it.
Oh, Eli, you didn't even know!
I said I'd handle it!
(quietly):
Oh, damn.
♪ ♪
ALICIA:
Judge Marx has ordered
limited discovery,
confined to "racist references"
and "Chummy Maps."
We'll split up
Chumhum hard drives
and review all e-mails,
software specs
and memorandums.
Mark them as either
responsive or nonresponsive.
Uh, how narrowly are we
interpreting "responsive"?
Well, don't want to do
the opposition any favors.
Well, any disagreements,
we'll discuss.
Good.
Call me here.
And good luck.
(upbeat pop intro playing)
♪ And I looked ♪
♪ Away from you ♪
♪ And I found ♪
♪ A better way to do it ♪
♪ And I've seen ♪
♪ Some younger people happy ♪
♪ As can be ♪
♪ La-la, la-la, la, la, la ♪
♪ But not especially ♪
♪ Happier than me ♪
♪ Happier than me... ♪
♪ Happier than me. ♪
(song ends)
Uh-oh.
What?
March 5 of this year:
"Why do we include
home ownership rates?"
In reference to...?
There's no subject line,
but it's in a thread
about the Safe Filter.
Who to who?
Chummy Map coder
Kip O'Neill to his super,
Larry Melanie.
Damn. I think
this one's responsive.
But did they include
home ownership rates
into the algorithm?
No.
So...?
They were considering it.
CANNING: So?
They didn't do it.
Mark it as non-responsive.
ALICIA (over phone):
Come on.
They discussed including
home ownership rates
in the design
of Safe Filter.
I mean,
that would automatically
disadvantage
poorer neighborhoods.
It's a proxy for race.
CANNING:
Yes, but, again, they didn't,
and so it wasn't.
Well... let's let the judge
rule on its relevance.
Anyway, you sure you're not
misinterpreting this e-mail?
It says,
"Why do we include
home ownership rates?"
H-How else
do we interpret that?
Maybe the emphasis is on "we."
"Why do we have to be the ones
who have to do this?
Why can't somebody else
to do it?"
There's an easy way
to find out what he meant.
KIP O'NEILL:
Apricot thyme granola
or rose pistachio pepita?
We rotate every day.
Almond milk?
We make our own.
No, thanks.
We're good.
So about those
home ownership statistics?
Yeah, that was
just in beta.
Uh, what was in beta?
Our use of home
ownership stats.
To determine which
neighborhoods were unsafe?
Yeah,
but only in beta.
See, we had to show users
something on day one,
before there was
any user feedback,
so we used other data
just to start it off.
So what percentage
of the results
is currently shaped
by user feedback?
100%.
We realized that
if we kept it completely
in the users' hands,
we would avoid
another "Animal" incident.
Okay, a what incident?
Just something
that happened last year
in the imaging department.
We were this close
to causing a major
you-know-what storm.
I'll show you.
Uh, no, no. No, no, no.
I've got my computer...
No, just stop.
It's okay.
Stop.
Well, we just can't
pretend he didn't
say something.
No, but he didn't
say Chummy Maps.
Um, does this thing that you
were about to show us...
The "Animal" incident?
Right.
Does it have to do
with Chummy Maps?
No, but we were all worried
we were gonna...
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
No, no... Don't
say anything else, okay?
If it doesn't
have to do with the maps,
then we don't
have to look at it.
And we really
shouldn't look at it.
(scoffs)
What?
Something
in the discovery?
No. The reader comments
on Safe Filter.
"Super shady street!"
Exclamation point.
"Heard gunshots,
never going back!"
Sad face.
You think it's racist?
Do you?
He heard gunshots.
It's not racist.
My guess is he thought
he heard gunshots.
More discovery from
Chumhum. We'll take half.
Oh, good.
Thank you.
So...
Biff and, um, Skippy
are working out well for you?
Yes, they are.
And how is that not
reverse racism?
How is what not--
making fun of their names?
Yeah,
calling them
white stereotyped names.
Is that what
Biff and Skippy are?
Country club names from
some bad skit somewhere--
polo outfits and tennis
racquets-- don't pretend
like you don't know
what I'm talking about.
We don't want to be having
this conversation.
We already are.
Yes, reverse racism--
that dangerous
contagion that's
taking hold of society.
It doesn't have to be
a contagion to be true.
So how is is that
not reverse racism?
Because harm is necessary
for racism to be... harmful.
But you think they're idiots
because they're big white guys?
No, I think
they're idiots
because you hired them
instead of me.
(Monica laughs)
Can I see your laptop?
Why?
Because I want to steal it.
What?
Banner ads.
This one's my
Chumhum account.
And this
one's yours.
I get...
soul food
and you get...
skiing.
Meaning?
Maybe we can
expand the discovery.
(doorbell rings)
Alicia's out.
That's fine.
I'll wait for her.
You doing some work?
Yup.
Mind if I ask you
a few questions?
That depends.
On what?
The questions.
(scoffing chuckle)
Married?
I am not.
Girlfriend?
Kids?
I've had girlfriends.
Not had kids.
I have a daughter.
Divorced.
Me, not my daughter.
(forced chuckle)
Sorry for my nosiness.
I just like to
know about Alicia
and her life.
No problem.
You know, they're
actually paying me now,
so I'm gonna get back to work.
She's getting
close to you.
Isn't she?
I think these are questions
for Alicia, not for me.
You understand
why I ask?
Her husband is
running for president.
There's a lot more
attention being paid.
I think these
are questions for Alicia,
not for me.
Good talking to you.
CARY:
The ads you're seeing are for
things you might like, right?
Things you search for
or shop for online.
That's right.
And the ads you see
are different from
the ads that I see?
Yes, they are.
LUCCA: Your Honor, the ads
are just targeted.
Advertisers
tell Chumhum
they want to reach people
of a certain age, gender,
ethnic background,
and Chumhum obliges.
That's nothing more
than retailers wanting to reach
their customer base.
Opposing counsel's
missing the point, Your Honor.
Am I?
Tell me.
The point isn't that
white people get white ads
and black people
get black ads.
Because you haven't made
that point.
CARY: The point is the ads
that appear
on Chummy Maps
extract user data
from the entire
Chumhum product suite--
search engine, e-mails,
chat sites, news feeds,
shopping-- all of it.
DIANE: Chumhum
is a fully integrated
platform.
Therefore
our discovery shouldn't
be limited
to Chummy Maps alone.
It should include
all of Chumhum.
Your Honor, that's
a hysterical escalation.
It would be a ridiculous
amount of material.
Good thing
we can handle it.
To honor
your discovery ruling, judge,
we must
see everything.
They're right,
Mrs. Florrick.
Full discovery
of Chumhum is granted.
(gavel bangs)
Who's side is the law on again?
(sighs wearily)
Eli, I just had my ass
handed to me in court.
I do not have the bandwidth
for any campaign talk.
This is not about campaign talk.
Okay.
I know you want me to ask you
why you are here, then.
But I'm not going to.
Jason is in your office,
working.
Uh-huh.
Seems like a nice guy.
He reminds me of...
Actually, he doesn't
remind me of anyone.
Very strong.
Man of few words.
Which is odd because most
of the people I deal with
who you know...
use a lot of words.
Yes.
I've gotten over words.
How'd you find Jason?
Eli, what?
What?
What are you after?
What are you trying to say?
I know your private life
is none of my business...
but when it begins to...
spill into your public life...
You're telling me,
when I sleep with Jason
you'd rather I kept it private?
(wry laugh)
You're joking... right?
You're making fun of me?
Okay, I think you
are making fun of me,
but I still need to be clear.
(clears his throat)
This is the speech
I normally give
to the candidate,
but I will adapt it for you.
Lucky me.
Rule number one-- no
touching in public.
Ever.
If Jason is on fire,
let him burn.
Touching in private--
no such thing.
Nowhere is private anymore.
Clearly.
Rule number two-- if you have
to go out together, make sure
there's always a third party
present, preferably female.
Rule number three-- even if
you go out in a bigger group,
never, under any circumstances,
let it be in a hotel, a bar...
...or a hotel bar.
Eli...
you didn't talk about any
of this with Jason, did you?
What?! No.
Okay.
This is the first and last time
we discuss this.
I'm not sleeping with
my investigator, but if I were,
this conversation between us
could never take place.
I would never let it take place.
Please just tell me
you heard me.
No, Eli,
I didn't hear you.
I won't hear you.
You can show yourself out.
ALICIA: I'm not sleeping with
my investigator, but if I were,
this conversation between us
could never take place.
I would never
let it take place.
ELI: Please just
tell me you heard me.
ALICIA:
No, Eli, I didn't hear you.
I won't hear you.
You can show yourself out.
Bad news-- they got
full discovery.
Okay.
New ball game.
Yeah, a lot
tougher one.
(outer door closes)
You want a drink?
I'm getting
better at it.
No.
But thanks.
Everything okay?
No.
Full discovery.
Oh, right.
Well, maybe we're just
on the wrong side of this one.
Maybe.
I'll see you.
CANNING:
The judge has granted
full discovery.
Now, this complicates our job,
but it doesn't alter it.
We still split up the materials.
We still decide what is
responsive and what is not.
Okay, so, go to it.
We have a problem.
Already?
An e-mail to Chumhum
customer service.
"Dear Chumhum, your
search results suck.
"When I type in my name,
"it auto-completes
to some seriously
racist crap."
What seriously racist crap?
When he typed in
his name-- Jamal--
the auto-complete offered
to finish the sentence
with "Jamal stole my car," or
"Jamal arrest record."
Okay, that's not good.
But it's non-responsive.
ALICIA: Really?
How do you figure?
It's customer based. I mean,
the auto-complete is based
on most used search requests,
so, obviously, more people
who typed in "Jamal"
were interested in arrest
reports than anything else.
So, Chumhum's not racist...
its users are?
Well, one could argue
that it's racist
to override the results.
Okay, we need
to deal
with the "animal" incident.
I don't like
the sound of that.
Chumhum has
photo-identifying software.
It sorts your photos
into categories.
Camping trip,
Disneyland, graduation.
LUCCA:
One of the customers
pointed out that it had
tagged photos of her friends.
Oh.
WOMAN:
Alicia Florrick was
was willing
to forgive her husband
when he stumbled.
She deserves at least
that much understanding.
And they put her
on that election board, right?
They wouldn't have done that
if she hadn't
turned herself around.
The election board, sure.
Is there anything
Mrs. Florrick has said
or done that influences
your view of her?
Her episode of
Mama's Homespun Cooking.
It was so... raw.
Like she's a real person,
with crap to deal with.
Oh, this is good.
All right, well, let's stay
on that topic for a minute...
Yeah.
NORA: Eli?
I'll be right back.
Real people who have to overcome
real issues in their life.
Show of hands: How many of you
would value those qualities
in a political candidate?
I have a mission for you.
A mission? Really?
Sounds very...
mission-like.
Actually, it is.
Mr. Agos?
Cary's fine.
Cary. I was checking up
on the background
of the coders over
at the Chicago Chumhum office.
Which coders?
Kip O'Neill.
The guy who created
the Safe Filter.
I went through his
on-line postings.
In 2013,
a year before he created
the filter, he got mugged.
He didn't say where, but he said
it was a "sketchy neighborhood."
If he were mugged by...
You can say it.
If he were mugged
by African-American people,
it's evidence
he was racially motivated
in the creation
of the filter.
Good. Do we know if he was
mugged by African-Americans?
No. I checked
for news reports. Nothing.
Okay... That's
good work, Brian.
Whew!
That is pretty
good work by Biff,
don't you think?
MAN:
It's really not my team--
imaging and tagging.
I'll bring Josh over.
Where's Jason? I thought
he was meeting us here.
Oh, yeah, he called.
He thought you might want
to limit his hours on this?
KIP:
This is Josh.
He can speak a little more
specifically as
to, uh... yeah.
Yeah. So... the photo
wasn't tagged by a person,
it was tagged
by an algorithm.
And the algorithm can't
tell the difference
between an African-American
woman and an animal?
Well, it can now, but, uh,
three years ago, we hadn't
given it enough examples.
It had real trouble
with light and shadow.
It got a lot
of other stuff wrong, too.
Just nothing else
that looked so...
Racist?
Right.
It's gotten better.
Google had this problem, too.
ALICIA:
Did the algorithm
ever mistake a white person
for an animal?
Why would it do that?
LUCCA:
Because it mistakes
white people for
polar bears or white seals.
(laughs)
No. Not so far.
Why not?
Why does it have trouble
identifying
African-Americans,
but not Caucasians?
I guess because we hadn't
given it enough examples.
We're not racists.
I'm not saying you are.
I'm just looking
around your workplace.
ALICIA:
It's clearly responsive.
CANNING:
I disagree.
It's not racist. It's a
technical shortcoming.
It's implicit bias.
Look, no one at Chumhum
is actually racist.
They just code what they know.
That's why the tagging software
never misidentifies white people
as animals.
The software has
been corrected.
You yourself said no one
there is actually racist.
This is non-responsive.
Click it.
He's wrong.
He's also paying our bills,
so, I think we
have to click it.
(door closes)
(doorbell rings)
Nora, hi. Eli's not here.
I know.
The campaign sent me.
They sent you? Why?
In case you need anything.
Oh. Well, I don't.
I'm fine.
Oh, hey.
Back to the grindstone?
Yeah.
Tough boss.
Cary Agos called.
He wants to meet.
Why?
I don't know.
Maybe he wants to make a deal.
Okay, give me second.
No, he just asked for me.
I'll call you.
(thud)
I'll just wait in a corner,
in case you need anything.
Nora, I'm fine.
It's okay.
I have a book.
CARY:
Thanks for coming in, Lucca.
Anything to settle this.
We just found out one
of your coders, Kip O'Neill--
he was mugged in 2013.
I wanted to see
if you knew about this.
This is why I'm here?
Yes.
He was mugged the year
before he created Safe Filter
in what he called
"a sketchy neighborhood."
Why call me?
Why not Alicia?
I thought
you'd be more helpful.
You're implying
the assailants were black?
(laughing):
I'm not implying anything.
I thought
you could ask your client.
Next time,
call Alicia, too.
It just seems like something
both our sides would need
to address if it turns out
to be race-related.
Good-bye.
It wasn't a negotiation.
We might have a problem
with Kip O'Neill.
Okay, I got it.
Jason's here.
I'll ask him.
Kip O'Neill
was mugged in 2013.
It's on his profile page.
We need to find out the race
of the culprits.
All right.
I'll see what I can do.
Jason, did Eli talk to you
before, when you were here?
Yup.
About us?
What do you mean, "us?"
Us working together.
Yes.
I don't want...
things to be uncomfortable
between us.
Me, neither.
Well, then,
don't let Eli
make them uncomfortable.
Here's the thing:
I used to have
a very different life.
A very...
uncomfortable life.
I didn't like it.
So now, there is nothing I do
that makes me uncomfortable.
Nothing.
Even if I want something...
(door opens)
Is everything all right in here?
Do you need anything?
We're fine, Nora. Thank you.
(door shuts)
You said, "even if you
want something..."?
Yeah, you know, that's...
It's okay.
Jason...
look, I just,
I like things simple.
All right? Work simple,
home simple, life simple.
And isn't it?
It was.
I have to get back to work.
I'll call you.
(sighs intensely)
How did we go from mugging
victim to possible racist?
If the guys who mugged him
were black or Latino,
Cary and Diane
will say racial bias
was motivation
for the Safe Filter.
So cynical.
Here he is.
CANNING: So?
Good news.
The attackers were white,
one was a redhead,
so as long as that hasn't been
categorized as a new race...
We dodged a bullet.
JASON:
What do you get
when you cross a black
and two Mexicans?
Excuse me?
It's a joke.
Kip e-mailed it to his teammates
four weeks before
they launched Chummy Maps.
Which I'm guessing gives Diane
and Cary their bias.
Damn.
KIP:
I'm not a racist.
And I'm sure some
of your best friends
are blacks and Mexicans.
The joke was just me
breaking up the drudge work.
Apparently, work around here
gets pretty drudgy.
There are dozens
of these jokes here.
Then you've seen
the white jokes, too.
That... really
doesn't help, Kip.
Look... we work
a hundred hours a week.
We sleep on the floor here
half the nights.
It was a meta joke--
a joke about joking.
Like dead baby jokes.
CANNING:
So they were just a bunch
of immature frat boys
blowing off steam.
Pretty much.
But it's gonna be hard
denying any knowledge
of racism to Judge Marx.
You're right.
Y... You're finally
agreeing with me.
It's been known to happen,
Alicia.
(sighs):
Okay...
then I will tag
every Chumhum e-mail
with racist jokes "responsive."
Not just e-mail.
Tag every racist joke
on the Internet.
I'm sure a Chumhum search will
turn up a billion Web pages.
Just mark all "responsive."
You're gonna bury the e-mails.
Of course not.
I'm just following
the judge's directives.
DIANE: This is their discovery?
50-terabyte hard drive.
Picture all the contents
in the Library of Congress,
and then multiply
that by five.
Congratulations--
we've just been hit
with what may be the
largest document dump
in American legal history.
Go away. What are
you doing here?
You're supposed to
be with Alicia!
No,
I'm supposed to be working.
That was work.
No, that was
the most embarrassing thing
I've ever done, Eli.
And I've done your laundry.
Where are they now?
Eli, they're not shtupping
at 11:00
in the morning.
Shh!
Courtney can't know.
You are a horrible employee.
(quietly):
And you're a monster.
Yeah, uh... okay, yes,
I'll-I'll see what I can do.
Thank you so much.
Mm-hmm.
Everything all right?
Yes.
Can I call you later?
About the PAC?
About the PAC.
RUTH: Eli.
You rang?
What's this?
A file on Jason.
Skeletons and such.
Show it to Alicia.
No.
It won't work.
You haven't read it.
Alicia doesn't scare.
Not when it comes to men.
All women scare.
Use it.
Here he is again.
What'd you find, Brian?
I've been going
through the algorithms.
I thought you were digging
through the discovery.
Sometimes it's best
to look in the math.
What'd you find?
A patch-- pretty
crude, hastily done.
I don't know what that means.
It's embedded in the
photo-tagging software
It was altered so
the word "animal"
could never appear
in a photo tag.
Why would they do that?
To hide something?
Plaintiff has a motion
to compel?
DIANE:
We do.
This, uh, photo shows
an African-American woman
who was mistaken by Chumhum's
photo-tagging software
and tagged as an "animal."
Yes, it does.
We discovered this photo
when we noticed a patch
in Chumhum's
photo-tagging algorithm.
A patch in
the software?
So it wouldn't
happen again?
Yes, but rather than...
fix the underlying
problem,
they simply... patched it
to prevent one instance
of the problem from recurring.
Was this included
in discovery?
We don't know, Your Honor.
Chumhum's counsel
sent us 50 terabytes
of discovery--
it will take my firm
six years
to work through it.
I see.
Mrs. Florrick...
did you include this photo
in discovery?
No, Your Honor.
Were you aware
of the photo?
We were, Your Honor,
but we found it nonresponsive.
Really?
So you found
50 terabytes of data
responsive...
but an African-American woman
being mistaken for an animal
didn't make the cut?
We believed it did not.
No, you will provide
all responsive documents to
plaintiff's attorneys today,
and you have been found
in contempt, ma'am.
Your Honor,
this was not my...
You will pay $5,000
to the Clerk of
the Circuit Court
by end of day Friday,
as well as any plaintiff's costs
and attorney's fees
incurred in pursuing
this violation.
And if there are any
more games like this,
the sanctions will be doubled.
You understand?
I do, Your Honor.
(gavel bangs)
(sighs):
All right, look...
you have any more questions,
you ask Alicia, all right?
I'm a guest here.
I don't have a question.
Good.
What's that?
A file on you,
from the campaign.
You serious?
I'm not,
but the campaign is.
She knows all about my
criminal record.
I don't pretend like
it doesn't exist.
Take a look
at the back page.
Does she know about that?
Why are you
investigating Alicia?
It's none of your business.
Actually, that part is.
I was going into business
with her.
I wanted to know more
about my prospective employer.
I don't believe you.
And I seriously
don't give a damn.
This stuff...
this is your life,
it's not mine.
Eli...
do not make it mine.
Now, get off my car.
(car door opens, shuts;
siren wails in distance)
Okay, we're listening.
One: Effective 9:00 a.m.
this morning,
Josh Shelby's employment
at Chumhum was terminated.
The Photo Coder?
Yes. Two:
The Safe Filter has been
changed from a default setting
to an opt-in--
users will have to activate it
if they want to know
areas to avoid.
And the business icons
should not be switched off.
We agree.
CARY: Fine.
And how much you offer?
Zero.
We were under
the impression
this was
a settlement offer.
These are Little Dokebi's
financial records.
The restaurant
was struggling.
Ms. Feldman was
slashing costs
almost as much as 35%
because business
was going soft.
She started doing this
two months...
before the Safe Filter
went live.
Restaurant business
101, Ms. Feldman--
your business tanked because
you skimped on quality.
Mr. Canning...
That's not true.
DIANE: How did you even get
these documents?
Ms. Feldman stored them
on Chumhum's cloud-based
spreadsheet service.
Which is private...
Actually,
users authorize Chumhum
total access
when they agree
to the terms of service.
It was a free service.
Divya probably wanted
to save some money.
Mr. Canning...
(others arguing)
I have never skimped
in my life.
(all talking at once)
Sorry, but I'm not sure
what we can do.
So your client isn't racist--
they're just omnipotent.
Keeping us all safe.
You want to celebrate?
In what manner?
In any manner you desire.
(dance music blaring)
♪ ♪
So, is this your place?
Let's go dance.
I don't...
I don't really dance.
♪ ♪
Too bad.
Whoo!
♪ ♪
Screw it.
I'm sorry to bother you so late.
We need to talk
about Jason.
No. No, we don't.
He has a file on you.
What does that mean?
He has a personal
file on you.
He has looked into your past.
♪ Doot-doot, doot-doot,
doot-doot, doot-doot... ♪
doot-doot, doot-doot ♪
♪ Doot-doot, doot-doot,
doot-doot, doot-doot... ♪
doot-doot, doot-doot ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la... ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la ♪
♪ La... la-la, la, la, ah ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la, la ♪
♪ La-la la-la la-la... ♪
♪ La, ah, ah. ♪