GUY: Damn, girl!
That's what I'm talking about.
[Dance music playing in club]
GUY: Come on, girl!
[Whistling and cheering]
GIRL: Don't stick that in my man's face.
GUY: Who are all these white folks?
GUY: Yeah!
Yeah.
How can she even move like that?
DANNY: That's what the guys like.
Sir...
You've had too much to drink.
GUY: Who are you?
DANNY: I'm a cop.
GUY: You undercover?
Security. So behave yourself.
KERN: Everybody! Put your hands together
for all the ladies shakin' it up in here!
Word up!
Word up, y'all. Yo, love to everybody.
I wanna thank you for coming
to my album release party.
Back from the Ashes,
you know what I'm sayin'?
It feels good to be back behind the mic!
RONDELL: Hey, yo! Kern!
Do that duet with Tyesha.
Rondell in the house!
Where's Tyesha at?
Where's Tyesha at? Come here, ma.
This is Kern's party, y'all.
My release party ain't gonna be
for another month.
Trouble.
TYESHA: You can hear me sing then.
T-BONZ: Where my money, Kern?
THUG: There go the thief right there!
I want my money, homey!
Where my money, Kern? I want my money!
RONDELL: Back off!
T-BONZ: My beef ain't with you.
What? If it's with Kern, then it's with me.
DANNY: This is a private party.
LEMONHEAD: Back off.
You can't be getting into trouble.
DANNY: You hear me, or do I have to
call in the cavalry? Step back.
Police can't protect you forever, Kern.
Remember that!
DANNY: Get out of here. Go.
It's T-Bonz, homey.
RONDELL: Get outta here, man.
DANNY: You heard me. Go.
GUY: Get lost, bitch.
THUG: Who you callin' a bitch?
LEMONHEAD: Get down!
[Guns firing]
DANNY: Get down!
Stay down!
LEMONHEAD: Get down!
Everybody get down!
LEMONHEAD: Danny, you all right?
GUY: Those fools are shootin' up in here.
- Lemon!
- Somebody call 911!
Rumble in the jungle.
What happened?
Two dead. Six wounded.
T-Bonz and his crew
were looking for a fight...
...and Rondell and some of Kern's guys
gave it to 'em.
VIC: Don't tell me...
LEMONHEAD: Rondell was the shooter.
VIC: That's just what we needed.
DUTCH: Hey, Vic.
You're missing all the fun.
VIC: Dutch...
How many times I gotta tell you,
you can't feel up the women?
- Took one in the ass, but it's...
- Not the first time. Right.
That's a good one.
VIC: Look who's the last one
to a shots-fired call.
All safe and secure, Captain.
Shooting's stopped.
Nothing to worry about here.
You two were moonlighting?
LEMONHEAD: Our shift commander
signed off on it.
Any suspects in custody?
The night is young. Let me do my thing.
You don't mind if I include others
in this investigation, do you?
You sign the checks.
Pete and Dutch, team up.
Strike Team will assist as they see fit.
Any problems with that?
Just that time's a wastin'.
I won't put up with shooting galleries
in Farmington.
Find out who pulled the triggers
and bring them in.
Knute Rockne he ain't.
ACEVEDA: I may have to put up with you
working under my roof...
... but it's still my roof.
So just do your job...
...and stay out of my way.
Sounds like good advice for both of us.
Let's get to work.
[Theme music]
So, the guy throwing the party...
- Kern Little.
- And this T-Bonz...
...they weren't the shooters.
Not that I saw. Just their pals.
Can you ID any of them?
I can look through the books.
VIC: This thing will spill
onto the street quick.
We better tell both generals
to stand down their armies.
- Starting where?
- Kern Little.
Who's Kern Little?
Listen, Dutch boy...
...don't get your clogs all dirty.
We'll deal with Kern Little.
[Knocking]
RONDELL: Who is it?
VIC: Open up, Rondell!
RONDELL: Whassup, Vic?
Why'd you shoot up
The Chez Club last night?
RONDELL: Hey, man.
T- Bonz and Kern got this war going on.
I'm just backin' up my boy.
VIC: Who's that? Kern?
This thing hi-def?
RONDELL: Yeah.
Don't get your prints on it, man.
LEMONHEAD: Sweet.
RONDELL: Yeah, look.
We been hangin' since we was kids.
We're still tight.
Don't you mean Kern financed your entry
into the drug business?
Yeah, no comment.
But that's the rumor.
What's the beef between Kern and T-Bonz?
T-Bonz used to be on Kern's record label.
Then he blew up,
started selling a lot of discs.
T- Bonz split, started his own outfit.
Bad blood ever since.
LEMONHEAD: What's with
all the vinyl here?
RONDELL: It sounds better.
Would you put those back
the way you found 'em?
That's my Blue Note collection.
I got 'em chronological from...
Did you hit anybody last night?
Look. If somebody got smoked,
it wasn't me.
I was just shootin' to be shootin'.
VIC: Gimme your piece.
Come on. Just give it to me.
[Sighs]
VIC: Keep your dealers inside
until I give the all-clear.
I don't want any more targets on the street.
Vic, man, come on.
Business gonna take a big hit.
Then take it.
You get to deliver product
only so long as this area...
...doesn't resemble
the goddamn Gaza Strip.
That was our deal. You remember?
Yeah, I remember.
VIC: Set up a meet. Me and Kern Little.
- Why you need me to do that, man?
- You two are buds.
I want it to be on friendly terms.
RONDELL: Anything else, man?
VIC: Yeah...
I need two shooters from your side.
Come on, man. You can't... No.
Is it gonna be you?
When I run your gun through ballistics?
Or you got some names for me?
VIC: Welcome to the barn.
LEMONHEAD: Make yourselves at home.
Just doing my job
and staying out of your way.
ACEVEDA: You look great.
AURORA: Stay focused.
He owns three different car dealerships.
Him? A chain of grocery stores.
ACEVEDA: There's more money here
than in Mexico City.
Which one's Machado?
AURORA: Right there.
This whole thing is his baby.
You better say hi before he disappears.
ACEVEDA: Okay.
You remember how we talked about it.
- I'll wing it.
- David...
ACEVEDA: I'm joking.
This could be our one chance. Don't joke.
AURORA: Ready?
ACEVEDA: As I'll ever be.
Señor Machado. I'm David Aceveda.
MACHADO: Our young Police Captain.
Welcome.
ACEVEDA: It's an honor, sir.
This is my wife, Aurora.
What a wonderful housing development.
Gracias.
It's a step forward in improving
our neighborhood.
- I'm glad you both could come.
- Thank you for including us.
I'm in your debt.
Don't think me overly generous, David.
As you'll discover,
I often have ulterior motives.
You see, you're actually
in a position to help me.
How so?
My nanny hasn't seen her husband
since he left the house a few days ago.
He's a day worker.
Waits for jobs by the home improvement
center in your district.
Is this absence unusual for him?
Not exactly.
They are an emotional couple.
They fight. He leaves. He comes back.
But he's never been gone this long.
My nanny's quite upset,
which means my wife is upset.
Which means, well...
I don't have to tell you what that means.
Just give me the pertinent information.
I'd be glad to help.
Looks as if I am now in your debt.
[R&B music playing]
KERN: You listening to this?
LEMONHEAD: It's sweet.
VIC: Sing me a song about last night.
KERN: Man, that'd be a short-ass song.
I mean, as soon as I seen them dudes
comin' out with them guns...
... I just got Tyesha the hell up out of there.
Nice place.
Told everybody my first studio
gonna be in Farmington.
KERN: You can't record
a hard-core hip-hop song...
...working in Bel Air.
Gotta keep it in the hood, baby.
TYESHA: How am I sounding, baby?
KERN: Hot.
KERN: Like 2 million CDs. Double platinum.
KERN: Tyesha, this is officer...
VIC: I'm Vic.
VIC: Just call him Lemonhead.
TYESHA: This is Rocco.
It's a madhouse out there
since the shooting.
How'd you guys get past
the photographers?
VIC: We called ahead.
Kern let us use the security entrance.
Kern's not under arrest, is he?
Unfortunately for those tabloid hacks, no.
We just needed his statement.
KERN: Which I gave.
- And his help with this war.
- Well, it's not Kern.
It's his boys trying to protect him.
'Cause T-Bonz is just plain crazy.
Everybody knows that.
LEMONHEAD: Don't worry about T-Bonz.
We'll deal with him.
I need you to give the word to your crew.
The war's over.
KERN: Right after T-Bone gives his word.
I mean, T-Bone's the one
that spilled blood on my turf.
I'm nothin' if not a man of peace.
Dutch?
I'm hunting known associates
on those shooters Mackey brought in.
Are we ever getting DSL around here?
This is Ellie Ruiz.
I need you to help her out.
I'm working the Chez Club.
ACEVEDA: Shockley can handle it.
I need you to help find
Ellie's husband Manuel.
Gracias.
I can't believe we're doing this
for some fat cat's nanny.
- You'd be happier if it was his mistress?
- It's abuse of power.
You're upset you got pulled off a big case.
DUTCH: We're Aceveda's errand boys.
Meanwhile, watch him cash in
on our hard work.
CLAUDETTE: Looking for
a missing migrant isn't important?
DUTCH: You do all the talking.
CLAUDETTE: Why me?
You speak Spanish.
How can you be a cop in LA for 12 years
and not speak any Spanish?
All my partners spoke Spanish.
DUTCH: I know a phrase or two.
CLAUDETTE: Right.
"Yo no se."
Means ''I don't know.''
You hear it enough, it sinks in.
DUTCH: Missing hombre?
MAN: Yeah, mucho hambre.
Si. McDonald.
CLAUDETTE: Manuel Ruiz!
CLAUDETTE: Ha visto este hombre?
There.
DUTCH: Hey, you. Amigo.
DUTCH: Amigo.
CLAUDETTE: What's your name?
Yo no se.
Come on. You wouldn't be
trying to sneak away if yo no se.
Now, you know Manuel, don't you?
Yes.
VIC: I don't believe it!
LEMONHEAD: What?
VIC: Back up.
[Tires squealing]
VIC: Aaron! Don't you make me
break a sweat trying to catch you.
What the hell are you doing out?
AARON: Business.
VIC: Rondell ordered you off the street.
Not us.
Run on home.
What am I gonna tell the boss?
I am the boss.
What am I gonna tell Rondell?
Don't worry. I'll tell him for you.
Whassup, man?
VIC: I saw two of your guys on the street.
RONDELL: It's a free country.
VIC: Nothing's free. I'm your landlord.
I let you use space that I own.
You can't follow by my rules,
then I'll find someone who can.
VIC: You got me?
Gotcha.
Now, smart-ass...
...who else you got dealing, and where?
Manuel got picked for a job on Tuesday
along with another man.
DUTCH: Eduardo Salcido.
CLAUDETTE: Salcido.
ACEVEDA: Any connection between
Manuel and Eduardo?
- They were best friends in Mexico.
- Snuck into the country together.
But something happened
on that truck ride over.
Ever since, Eduardo's been telling people
that he's gonna kill Manuel.
ACEVEDA: We know
who hired the two of them?
CLAUDETTE: A truck loader
said Jamison Contracting.
Track it down.
Find out if they ever showed up for work.
[Radio chatter]
DISPATCH: All units, code 2-13.
Intersection of Alvarado and Pine.
LEMONHEAD: Our corner.
VIC: Goddamn it!
He had to leave his guys on the street.
Punch it.
[Continuous car horn blaring]
[Distant rap music playing]
VIC: Police!
[Rap music from car]
[Horn stops blaring]
KID: Down there.
VIC: Call EMT!
VIC: Jesus.
Man.
[Police radio chatter]
The mayor knows the little boy, Vic.
You're shitting me.
Belongs to his golf buddy's second cousin
or some such thing.
Whatever. He's invested.
GILROY: Any word on the kid's condition?
VIC: He's busted up pretty bad.
So I got nothing good to tell the Chief.
How do I explain these four dead thugs?
VIC: A war. Two rappers.
I know who they are.
Look, I'm handling it.
I told the Chief that the Strike Team
would make a difference.
That these things would stop happening.
I'm not seeing the difference.
Temporary setback.
GILROY: Chief allows me to
appropriate funds for you based on results.
If I can't defend you, I can't afford you.
SHOCKLEY: Vic.
- I thought you should know.
- Know what?
Kid was DOA.
I'm handling it.
Knock, knock.
Have a seat.
VIC: All right.
Tough guy.
VIC: This war ends right here
with a handshake.
T-BONZ: This fool
stole my money and woman...
...and you expect me to be a gentleman?
LEMONHEAD: Tyesha was your woman?
T-BONZ: Hell, yeah.
VIC: We're not signing autographs here.
GIRL: Okay.
So, basically, this is a dick-wagging contest
over a piece of ass?
This ain't about no piece of ass.
This is about $2 million that fool
right there owe me.
KERN: $2 million?
VIC: What $2 million?
T-BONZ: Tyesha's money from the last CD.
I broke her.
Where my cut?
First up, calm down, money.
I'm a businessman. I can be fair.
But $2 million?
You must be smoking crack.
I'll give you a finder's fee or something.
Straighten you out.
T-BONZ: I was doing your ass a favor.
You owe me at least $10 million.
KERN: You know what, T?
I'm gonna keep it real with you.
Tyesha wasn't even sellin' records,
till I hooked her up.
And that's real.
T-BONZ: Is that real?
VIC: Look...
Your 10 lawyers can do battle
with his 10 lawyers...
...or we can settle this right here. All right?
- I'm gonna get my money, bitch.
- Over my dead body, bitch.
T-BONZ: Damn, that sound like a good idea.
VIC: Shut up!
VIC: Here's the deal.
Kern...
You take tonight
and come up with a number.
You revise yours down a bit.
You bring me the numbers.
I'll decide what's fair.
And who you supposed to be? Judge Judy?
[Laughing]
I'm an impartial arbitrator with the power
to throw both of your asses in the can.
Now...
I'm calling a 24-hour cease-fire.
Your boys break it, I break you.
Same goes for you.
This war ends here.
They come here of their own accord.
Nobody's coercing them.
A family of five moving to another
country just to eat isn't coercion?
DUTCH: You know why they come here?
Five words. "Free markets. Rule of law."
You have those two things,
it creates prosperity.
Prosperity creates jobs people want.
$40 for a full day's work
isn't prosperity, son.
It's exploitation, and you wouldn't do it.
DUTCH: Excuse me!
JAMISON: Can I help you?
Yeah, we're looking for
a worker named Eduardo.
Throw a rock. You're bound to hit one.
Have you seen this guy?
JAMISON: Yeah. Jose.
Manuel.
JAMISON: He showed up a few days ago...
...worked for one day, got paid.
Never saw him again. What'd he do?
Do you have any idea
what happened to him?
Don't know. Don't care.
Mind if we ask around for Eduardo?
JAMISON: Ask away.
DUTCH: Thanks.
[Spanish music playing]
DUTCH: Eduardo?
WORKER: Yo no se.
CLAUDETTE: Eduardo?
CLAUDETTE: You got an Eduardo?
WORKER #2: It's not me.
I think he's working down over there.
[Dutch and Claudette calling]
Hey!
DUTCH: Stop right there! I said stop!
DUTCH: Eduardo! Hey!
Hey! San Salvador's that way!
ACEVEDA: These the triggermen
at the Chez Club?
DANNY: Some of them, I think.
It happened fast.
Rondell Robinson.
You saw him firing a gun in the club?
Yeah.
Beautiful.
You know who he is?
Yes, I do.
RONDELL: Let's make this short and sweet.
Wherever you think I was, I wasn't.
Whatever you think I did, I didn't.
ACEVEDA: That's your story?
Cover to cover.
- I wouldn't plan on selling the movie rights.
- I'll just have to settle for starrin' in it.
You're a murder suspect, Rondell.
I've got a witness who saw you pull
the trigger at the club last night.
RONDELL: Yeah, right.
What witness?
A cop.
And a jury's gonna love her.
I got a phone call comin', right?
ACEVEDA: You've only got
one thing left to deal.
And that's who's giving you protection.
RONDELL: I don't need protection.
Even if we can't tie you
to one of the dead bodies...
... discharging a firearm in a crowded club...
Bye-bye, Rondell.
So, about that phone call?
If you think...
...that you can sell drugs
and commit murder in my district...
...because a cop's protecting you...
...you're dead wrong.
VIC: I thought I told you to lay low.
I was kickin' it, listenin' to Miles Davis
when this captain shows up.
- He get anything?
- No.
I always keep my crib clean.
But he's got a serious bug up his ass
about some cop protecting me.
Just keep your mouth shut.
I'll handle Aceveda.
ACEVEDA: We have indications Manuel's
disappearance may have involved foul play.
MACHADO: Really?
You don't know for sure?
We have a suspect.
He won't be able to elude us for long.
Once we capture him, we'll know more.
Thank you for making this matter
a top priority, David.
You'll keep me apprised?
Of any developments.
Is there something else?
At the risk of having
an ulterior motive myself...
MACHADO: Yes?
I know that police officers
aren't accorded the same respect...
...in this community
as they were a decade ago.
An unfortunate development.
However...
...Latinos are a plurality in Los Angeles...
... and in this district.
There is going to be a seat opening up
on the City Council next year.
It's traditionally been filled
with a black candidate.
I think it's our time.
I agree.
With your backing...
...I could win that seat.
I could be of great use to you.
I like you, David, quite a bit, but...
...I don't think I can sell a cop
to these voters.
MACHADO: Not here. Not now.
Who knows, maybe in time,
things will become much different.
Until then, I'm sorry.
ACEVEDA: What do you think
of a man who exposed corruption?
Brought down dirty cops
from inside the department?
I'd think he was committing
professional suicide.
But could you sell him to the voters?
Absolutely.
- We got a call about a kidnapping.
- They took my boy Thurmon.
JULIEN: When did you find out?
DOTTIE: Today.
I got a ransom call asking for $10,000.
I don't have it!
DANNY: When did you see him last?
DOTTIE: Three weeks.
- How long has he been missing?
- Since last night.
- The last time you spoke with him?
- A month ago.
DANNY: How do you know he's only
been missing since last night?
Cemetery called.
Somebody dug up his body.
- Thurmon's dead?
- Goin' on three weeks.
Code 4. Cancel that backup, please.
DISPATCH: Roger that, 10-4.
DANNY: Ma'am,
if the kidnapper calls back, call us.
You're not gonna help me?
To be honest,
they'll just push it to the bottom.
Detectives...
They have more important things to do.
But it's a crime, isn't it?
Digging up my son, holding it for ransom.
Yes, ma'am.
So you two will help me, then, right?
Julien, you stay with her.
I'll ride solo.
Ma'am.
[Door buzzes]
VIC: Hey.
I got a little problem.
- What's that?
- The guy you ID'd today?
He's a C.I. Of mine.
Really?
VIC: Yeah. He's the guy who gave me
the other shooters.
He was firing in self-defense.
None of his shots killed anybody.
I was hoping maybe your memory
could get a little fuzzy on this one.
DANNY: I don't know.
Aceveda's already all over this one.
VIC: But if it ever goes to trial...
I don't know.
Let me think about it.
That's all I ask.
That's Thurmon right there.
JULIEN: I went to high school with him.
Did you know him?
JULIEN: He and his friends used to
beat me up all the time.
It's okay. He made a better
student out of me.
You know, I hid out in the library
until I grew nine inches my junior year.
He was killed robbing a liquor store.
Thurmon?
He was a thief. He did drugs.
I was afraid to tell you.
I would've helped you anyway.
JULIEN: Maybe he didn't
find his path here on earth, but...
...he's with Jesus now.
You believe that?
I know that.
[Phone rings]
Hello.
MAN: [Distorted] You get the money?
Yes, where's my son's body?
MAN: Bring the money to the cemetery
at 10:00 sharp.
What?
MAN: Bring the money to the cemetery
at 10:00 sharp.
I can't understand you.
MAN: [Normal voice] Bring it
to the cemetery at 10:00...
... or Thurmon's body will be chopped up
and you'll never see him again.
Henry, is that you?
COP: Face front.
[Prisoners muttering]
JULIEN: Did you hate her that much?
HENRY: No.
She's all right.
We dated for a while.
Then why'd you do it?
- Why'd I do it?
- Yeah.
Why'd I do it?
Knew she had life insurance on her boy.
Wanted to take my new lady
on one of them cruises.
But Dottie spent all the insurance money
on Thurmon's funeral.
[Grunts]
CORRINE: Can you make it Thursday?
VIC: How many problems
could a 5-year-old have?
CORRINE: Enough for an appointment
with a developmental pediatrician.
[Matthew barking]
Matthew thinks he's a dog now.
A German shepherd. So what?
You're not here all the time.
You don't see everything.
VIC: See what?
CORRINE: The problems.
Why do you have to fight me on this?
VIC: I'm not.
[Matthew screaming]
Okay, I'll try.
I'll try, okay.
[Barking]
CORRINE: I'm really losing it.
Why don't you go take a bath?
I'll put the kids to bed.
Okay.
[Corrine giggles]
DANNY: Good night. Thanks.
DANNY: Hey, I'm a cop!
THUG: Get down.
THUG: Don't scream.
DANNY: I said, I'm a cop!
THUG: And I'm a cop killer...
... but not tonight.
Tonight's just to show you
how we gonna do it.
What do you want?
THUG: Forget what you saw at
the Chez Club. Understand?
Yeah. I understand.
THUG: Come on.
You piece of shit!
Somethin' wrong, officer?
You think you can get to me.
RONDELL: You better take some kind of pill.
Damn.
You listen to me. I'm a cop.
You don't scare me.
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
You do look scared, though.
DANNY: I'll catch you outside.
JULIEN: Meet you out there.
What was all that between you and my C.I.?
Did you tell him that I was the one
who ID'd him?
Of course not.
- What's goin' on?
- He sent guys after me last night.
They put a gun to my head and told me
to forget what I saw at the club.
- You should take the day off.
- No, I should go after these pricks.
Let me take care of this.
You know what? I can take care of myself.
[Door slamming]
VIC: You went after a cop?
RONDELL: Vic.
I just scared her, man.
VIC: Cops are off-limits.
RONDELL: I'm not goin' away for shootin'
at somebody who shot at me.
VIC: I was taking care of it.
RONDELL: I didn't know.
I had to do somethin', man.
VIC: Take your drug money
and bail yourself out.
RONDELL: And then what?
In the year and a half it'll take
for this thing to go to trial...
...l'll make it go away.
RONDELL: I can't take no chances, Vic!
VIC: The biggest chance you could've taken
was to piss me off...
...and that's exactly what you did.
You see him?
CLAUDETTE: Nope.
But I got you a Spanish-English
phrase book. My gift to you.
Muchas gracias.
Third day you're checking
the real estate section.
- What's the deal?
- None ya.
DUTCH: What's that, Spanish?
CLAUDETTE: English. ''None ya business.''
- We're partners. Come on, share.
- Wanna share? Here's the sports page.
I'll find out. I'm a detective.
DUTCH: There he is.
CLAUDETTE: Bingo, gringo.
DUTCH: Eduardo Salcedo?
[Reading Miranda rights in Spanish]
[Guys laughing]
DUTCH: You and Manuel
were on the same truck.
DUTCH: You went to work together.
EDUARDO: Si, por Jamison.
DUTCH: Did you kill him after work ended?
EDUARDO: No.
So you killed him on the way to work, then.
No.
DUTCH: Where is he, Eduardo?
- How come his wife hasn't heard from him?
- Yo no se.
Spare me the yo no se's. We know.
EDUARDO: You know?
DUTCH: About the garage.
You hated Manuel.
You told people you wanted to kill him.
[Speaking Spanish]
EDUARDO: He my friend.
DUTCH: Used to be.
Until the trip.
CLAUDETTE: What happened on that truck?
EDUARDO: What truck?
DUTCH: The one that snuck you and Manuel
across the border.
DUTCH: Why did you want to kill him?
EDUARDO: Nothing.
DUTCH: You fight? What?
EDUARDO: Nothing!
DUTCH: He did something.
Nothing happened!
CLAUDETTE: Was it personal? He hurt you?
EDUARDO: I didn't kill Manuel.
So Manuel is dead.
Yo no se.
CLAUDETTE: Stay here, Eduardo.
- You ask me, he was raped.
- What?
CLAUDETTE: I sound like Dutch
with one of his theories, but...
...my first few years on the job...
...I practically lived in hospitals
taking statements from rape victims.
He's got that look.
ACEVEDA: The look?
Nervousness, isolation.
But it's mostly in the eyes.
Raped in a truck sneaking into the country?
How is that possible?
It's possible.
What do you mean,
sounds like one of my theories?
[Vic chuckles]
What's with the getups?
Avoiding cameras.
So what's the problem?
This is the goddamn problem.
He poisoned my baby.
Gave him some meat over the fence.
He choked to death.
VIC: T-Bonz?
TYESHA: Of course.
TYESHA: He's got to pay.
KERN: She supposed to be
finishing her album.
TYESHA: How can I work after this?
Look at him!
TYESHA: Game-over for T-Bonz. Be a man.
KERN: I know.
You know how much
this setback is costin' me?
Get that thing off my table.
TYESHA: The goddamn bastard has to pay.
KERN: That's T-Bonz breaking the truce.
TYESHA: Will you be a man,
or do I have to find someone else to do it?
KERN: Look...
I told you, this is why we're here.
I know what I gotta do, all right?
All right?
I just need you to help me do it.
- Do what?
- Do the deed.
KERN: T-Bonz.
I know where he's holed up at.
But I can't get to him.
A man with a badge could, though.
Why would I do something like that?
Money.
I'll make that rent Rondell payin' you
look like chump change.
Pay you double if I get to watch it.
Look, you want this war to end, right?
Then help me end it...
... or more blood is gonna get spilled.
Give me the address.
- Was Manuel the only one who raped you?
- No rape.
DUTCH: He hold you down?
EDUARDO: It not happen.
- Catch you sleeping, you wake up...
- No!
DUTCH: If somebody did that to me...
...l'd smash their head in.
I'd stab 'em, shoot 'em, push 'em off a roof.
CLAUDETTE: He raped you, didn't he?
DUTCH: We'd understand if you killed him.
I murder Manuel.
You killed Manuel.
Good.
Where?
Working con el Señor Jamison.
We were on the roof, and he fall.
DUTCH: You pushed him.
EDUARDO: No. He...
EDUARDO: We were carrying...
[Speaking Spanish]
An air-conditioning unit.
[Rambling in Spanish]
''Look out, Manuel.''
But he didn't hear him.
He slipped, and he fell.
That's not murder, Eduardo.
That's not what Mr. Jamison say.
What else did Señor Jamison say?
JAMISON: This is private property!
This is private property!
It was an accident.
CLAUDETTE: A man
was accidentally buried here?
JAMISON: I asked about Manuel's wife,
his family...
...and no one seemed to know.
He had no papers. He was illegal.
Burying a man on your job site is illegal.
- I wanted to alert the authorities...
- Too much of a hassle?
Would have shut down business for weeks.
Put these guys out of work, right?
I mean, what would they have done then?
DUTCH: Please. You told Eduardo
he was guilty of murder.
CLAUDETTE: This is plantin' rice and beans?
JAMISON: I told you not to talk, asshole.
Goddamn it!
DUTCH: You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can be used
against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney.
T-BONZ: This ain't no police station.
What's up?
Man, please.
Whatever you're thinking about doin',
don't do it.
VIC: What happened to that trash-talker
I fell in love with?
T-BONZ: Come on! I'm beggin' you!
T-BONZ: Come on, man.
LEMONHEAD: Come on, let's go!
VIC: You broke the truce. Time to pay.
T-BONZ: I'll give you money.
Hook you up.
It's no problem.
I just gotta make one phone call.
I'll give you whatever you need.
Let's end this. It's over, dude.
Why you cryin', T-Bonz?
T-BONZ: Why is he here?
KERN: I paid for front-row seats.
T-BONZ: Mackey. Please.
Please.
T-BONZ: Come on, Mackey.
VIC: Get in.
You, too, Kern.
What?
The two of you are shackin' up.
- Are you crazy?
- Yeah, he's definitely crazy.
VIC: You two are so keen
about killin' each other. Fine.
I'm just cuttin' out the middleman.
- We had a deal.
- I'm never for sale.
Now you know.
- I respect that, man. But I'm sayin...
- Shut up!
Get inside!
VIC: You can't make peace,
I'll see one of you in the morning.
KERN: That's how you gonna do it, man?
VIC: Close it.
KERN: Mackey, come on!
- I should have thought of this yesterday.
- Yeah.
[Vic sighs]
FREDDIE: Why you gotta be such a bitch?
DANNY: 'Cause of pricks like you.
FREDDIE: I got rights, you goddamn dyke!
DANNY: Hey, save it
for your new roommate!
Rondell Robinson just made bail.
VIC: Yeah? Well, that's his right.
ACEVEDA: $100,000 in cash.
VIC: Wow.
Lot of money for a kid from the ghetto.
Maybe he's got a rich uncle.
JULIEN: Are you all right?
DANNY: I'm fine.
JULIEN: You just been
a little jacked up today.
DANNY: Well, I'm fine.
If you don't want to talk about it,
that's cool.
But I'm gonna say a prayer for you tonight.
Thanks.
VIC: Heard you made bail.
LEMONHEAD: Your peaches
are about to go bad.
RONDELL: Where's my stuff?
Where's my TV, man?
VIC: Donated to the Lyndwilde Boys' Club.
You should have seen the look on
these kids' faces. It was like Christmas.
My goddamn records, man!
You went after a cop, Rondell.
You should thank me. All right?
I talked him out of doin' a lot worse.
ACEVEDA: The District Attorney is content
that Manuel's death was accidental.
I see.
This Mr. Jamison, what is his punishment?
CLAUDETTE: He's guilty of tampering
with evidence. Be fined and released.
Señora Ruiz,
I am truly sorry about your husband.
This man Jamison work
for a large company, no?
Yes.
Then I can sue them for much money.
Mucho dinero.
MACHADO: Thanks again, David.
ACEVEDA: I'm glad I could help.
I've given some thought to your proposal.
- And?
- I'm intrigued.
MACHADO: I have a few months
before I decide who I'll back.
Show me what you can do.
EDUARDO: They don't think
I murder Manuel?
No.
Muchas gracias.
Tell me something.
You hated Manuel.
You made threats against his life.
Why go on the same job with him that day?
The truck come.
They pick Manuel. They pick me.
[Speaking Spanish]
I have to work.
So, what's next, Eduardo?
Yo no...
I don't know.
The reason I ask is...
...l've got this retaining wall
that's crumbling...
DANNY: Lookin' for me?
VIC: Heard you were
kickin' some ass today.
No more than usual.
VIC: Do you trust me?
What?
With your life. Do you trust me?
Yeah.
Then you'll believe me when I tell you...
...you don't have to look
over your shoulder no more.
I took care of it.
- You took care of it?
- You got no more problems.
So now what?
[Phone ringing]
VIC: Hello?
What?
Where?
All right, I'll be right there.
I gotta run.
[Door closes]
Nurse, hi. I'm...
I got it.
VIC: Okay, where's Megan?
She's getting x-rays. Mom's with her.
He didn't mean it.
CORRINE: A 5-year-old does not bite
his 18-month-old sister...
... on the face and make her fall on her head.
Go be with Megan.
It's gonna be okay.
Your sister's gonna be all right.
[Train horn blaring]
LEMONHEAD: I don't hear nothin'.
VIC: Assholes like these
don't get up before noon.
VIC: Reveille!
LEMONHEAD: T-Bonz!
KERN: Ain't nobody else comin' outta there.
Told you he was a bitch.
I'll have my cleanup crew
come clean that mess up, man.
Shit.
LEMONHEAD: Gimme that.
VIC: Fine.
I'll take care of this.
[Vic sighs]
VIC: You hungry?
KERN: Goddamn starved.
[Birds singing]
[Theme music]