Previously
on The Blacklist...
Reddington's missing.
Samar, I need you
to trace his location.
I search-traced Mr. Reddington's
burner to a location
in West Virginia.
You knew where they were.
You didn't tell me.
I want you gone
by the end of the day.
My father died
for his principles.
It was a trap, set by
the crookedest cop of all.
- Tommy Markin.
- [ Gunshot ]
[ Strained voice ]
Tommy Markin.
I found Karakurt.
Karakurt's willing
to confess?
To all of it.
Agent Keen tells me
you have Karakurt.
Yes. And I intend on
turning him over
- as soon as possible.
- Don't.
I have a better idea.
Sana's all yours.
You will have your meeting.
I'll be in touch
when I'm ready.
We have to give him
the care package.
We need it to clear your name.
[ Siren wailing ]
- Elizabeth, no!
- [ Shouting indistinctly ]
[ Panting ]
Elizabeth Keen,
you're under arrest.
[ Keys jingle, lock clicks ]
- [ Chains rattle ]
- Just so you know,
I'm not ashamed
of what I did.
You shot the Attorney General
of the United States.
- He was a terrorist.
- He was unarmed.
Well, I'm glad you have
your convictions.
I just don't wanna die for them.
You said she'd never be caught.
I'll arrange her transfer
to CIA custody.
It won't be that easy.
We haven't put
safety measures in place.
Wait, Laurel. Laurel.
You said you took care of
the Reven Wright situation.
I did, but certain protocols
were set to activate
- upon Keen's arrest.
- What kind of protocols?
Cynthia Panabaker kind.
Yeah. She's White House Counsel,
and a real pain in the ass.
She's drafted an executive order
mandating Keen's transport
to the Federal Courthouse
for a closed hearing
- with Judge Trotter.
- How much time do we have?
Three hours, maybe less, Peter.
If she tells her story
in open court, then--
She won't.
♪♪
You know, this entire airport
novel started
when you overplayed your hand
with Raymond Reddington.
It's time for you to close
the book on Elizabeth Keen.
Permanently.
Three hours to make
one woman go away?
We've collapsed entire
governments in less time.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
_
[ Dialing ]
- Ressler.
- Where is she?
You don't have to worry
about Keen's safety.
- I've taken measures to--
- Your measures will fail.
Mine won't.
Oh, so now you're gonna
share your plan with me
now that I've arrested
your partner in crime?
Face it, Reddington.
I beat you.
There are no beatings here,
Donald.
No winners or losers.
There is only Agent Keen's life.
I have been working on
a meticulous campaign
to clear her name.
But I need a day to put
one final piece in place.
Go for it.
You know where we'll be.
I wish that were true.
But you're about to witness
the full force
of a shadow government
working in concert to crush you.
And now that they know
you have Elizabeth,
they will stop at nothing
to steal her.
You and Agents Navabi
and Mojtabai
must remain by her side
and guard her with your lives
- until you hear from me again.
- Thanks to you,
Navabi's no longer a member
of this task force.
Then it's all on you, Donald.
Keep them away from Agent Keen.
And, Donald,
I assume you have Dembe
and are being hospitable.
[ Cell phone beeps ]
[ Siren continues wailing ]
You'll get a fair hearing.
You and I both know I'm never
making it to that hearing alive.
_
[ Birds chirping ]
I mean,
this place should be safe.
- You know, there's--
- Yep.
Perfect place to sneak away
and be alone.
- [ Rattling ]
- What's that for? I'm cooperating.
Well, I cut into your chest
with an old bean can, my friend.
So I'm not giving you the chance
to return the favor.
[ Door closes ]
You got anything to eat
around here? I'm starving.
I'm sure Charlene knows
her way around the kitchen.
Really, Harold?
We gonna do this right now?
I'm driving you
to your sister's.
It's not safe around here.
I wanna get you away
from Karakurt.
The Cabal will stop
at nothing to kill him.
Stay here. Guard the asset.
I'll get back as soon as I can.
Beans?
[ Cell phone rings ]
[ Ring ]
Agent Mojtabai.
- Have you heard about Agent Keen?
- Mr. Reddington.
Listen to me, Aram.
The Cabal will come for her.
If they reach her,
it'll be the last time
you ever see Elizabeth again.
At this point, only one person
can keep her alive. You.
Me? Um... okay.
[ Telephone ringing in distance ]
How?
[ The Kills' "Sour Cherry" playing ]
[ Gate thuds ]
♪ shout when you wanna
get off the ride ♪
♪ 'cause you crossed my mind ♪
♪ you crossed my mind ♪
♪ oh, make my blood thump,
7, 8, 9 ♪
♪ make my heart beat
double time ♪
♪ now I'm the only sour cherry
on the fruit salad... ♪
Excellent work, Agent Ressler.
♪ only sour cherry
on the fruit stand ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
♪ oh ♪
At 3:00 PM,
US Marshals will arrive
to escort you to
a federal courthouse
where you'll be held pending
your arraignment tomorrow.
Whatever happens,
I don't blame you.
Until that time
you'll be held here
under the authority
and protection of Reven Wright.
- ♪ we could be movers ♪
- [ Velcro rips ]
♪ oh, oh ♪
♪ or we could be shakers ♪
I'll keep you safe.
I promise.
♪ if we could just shake
something out of the blue ♪
♪ and get off the ride ♪
♪ I'm the only sour cherry
on the fruit stand, right ♪
on your fruit stand, right ♪
♪ am I the only sour cherry
on your fruit stand? ♪
I've called her four times.
How is it possible that
you haven't gotten in touch
with her?
Listen, when you do,
I want you to get her to call me
as soon as possible, understand?
[ Cell phone beeps ]
Take him to holding.
[ Telephone ringing
in distance ]
Hi, Dembe.
Nobody's heard from
Reven Wright since last night.
I don't like this.
[ Door opens ]
[ Door closes ]
You promised me that Agent Keen
would receive a fair hearing.
Something's wrong.
Excuse me.
Hey. What do you think
you're doing?
Oh, Agent Ressler.
Congratulations
on your arrest.
We're moving your prisoner.
You don't have
the authority.
Homeland has actionable Intel
from inside Russian borders
that a terrorist attack
on US soil is imminent.
Keen is a Russian agent.
We need to question her.
I'd like to see a copy
of that Intel.
Well, I'm afraid
you are not cleared.
You know Reven Wright
will never allow this.
By the way,
where is Mrs. Wright?
I haven't seen or heard
from her all day.
Excuse me.
- I won't give you the codes.
- Oh, you don't need to.
The FBI Director can be
very helpful
during acts of war.
Almost as if we are
all on the same team.
[ Steady beep ]
You changed the code.
No.
Find a way into this box.
[ Sea birds calling ]
[ Cell phone ringing ]
Agent Ressler.
How's our girl?
You were right.
I can't protect her.
Slow down and tell me
what's happening.
Look, I can't move Keen
to the courthouse
for another two hours,
but the Director's here
with his own transfer order.
It's just luck that he hasn't
been able to
break into that box yet.
I've always believed luck
to be a function of intent--
in this case, mine.
When these dark clouds
were gathering,
I took measures to keep
Agent Keen safe
to ride out the storm.
Are you ready to do
your part now?
- I won't let him have her.
- I'll take that as a yes.
The best way you can help is by
continuing to guard Elizabeth.
And when the time comes,
make sure Karakurt
reaches the FBI safely.
Karakurt. The Russian?
What does he have to do
with this?
He's agreed to confess
his sins to the US government,
including the ones he committed
on behalf of the Cabal
to frame Agent Keen.
Cooper and Tom Keen
are holding Karakurt
in a cabin near Lake Yvonne.
I can have him in the city
within the hour.
Cooper and Tom?
He tried to tell you, Donald.
You didn't listen.
Apparently, you have
a disregard for Tom Keen
that exceeds even my own.
I have to meet someone.
Remember, guard Elizabeth
and keep Karakurt alive.
- [ Phone snaps shut ]
- Donald.
I find him so stiff
so much of the time.
He doesn't appreciate
life's trimmings.
Take yourself, for example.
It's my understand he fired you
for helping Elizabeth
come to my rescue.
He had every right.
I went behind his back.
I'm willing to take
responsibility for my actions.
Watch out. That's the kind of
spirit that could save America.
Thank you for meeting me,
Samar.
What do you want?
We're going to clear
Elizabeth's name.
It'll involve
a sizable drug haul,
an FBI heist in
the US Treasury Department.
But first, I need to
make an appointment.
An appointment with whom?
With the Foreign Minister
of Venezuela.
How long is this gonna take?
I'd say about 20 seconds
and we should be there.
Okay. Good.
[ Machine whirring ]
I'm-- I'm going to have to call you back.
[ Door closes ]
- Where's Reven Wright?
- That's what I'm trying to find out.
This is not like her.
I'm... I'm worried
something's happened.
Wanna know what I think?
I think the Director has
- something to do with this, because--
- You are talking about
the Director of the National
Clandestine Services here.
You threw him
out of here once.
You gotta do it again
before it's too late.
If he has intelligence,
I can't just overrule him.
[ Sighs ]
Look, Reven said
I could trust you.
And without her here, it's--
I need your help.
Do you remember Karakurt?
The Russian assassin.
Harold Cooper's holding him
at a cabin near Lake Yvonne.
He's willing to talk,
and when he does,
it'll clear Keen
of all terrorist charges.
But if the Director gets--
I've already asked my sources
to confirm the Director's Intel.
If we can show that
there's no credible threat,
I'll make sure he backs down.
As for Reven Wright,
last time we talked,
she mentioned an associate.
Um, what was his name?
Tommy Markin.
Maybe he has something to do
with her disappearance.
Does that name mean
anything to you?
Tommy Markin.
No.
Never heard of him.
[ Phone ringing in distance ]
Reven Wright's not coming back.
How do you know?
Tommy Markin.
Was a guy I told
Reven about, only Reven,
and Hitchin just asked
about him.
Laurel Hitchin
is in the Cabal.
And I just told her
where to find
the only person
who can save Keen.
She just told the Director.
Okay, okay.
Uh, glass half-full.
There's someone who can
save Agent Keen?
Karakurt.
Cooper's hiding him at a cabin
near Lake Yvonne.
He's not answering.
I gotta get him
to move Karakurt
before the Director's goons
get there.
Go. She'll be fine.
You know better than anyone,
they can't break in there.
What if they figure out
the code?
- They won't.
- How do you know?
I'm the one who changed it.
US Marshals are gonna be
here in three hours.
- If I'm not back, you let Keen
out for them, only them. - Okay.
_
[ Horns honking ]
- [ Gun clicks ]
- Rafael!
Reddington,
what are you doing here?
[ Laughs ]
Rafael.
- [ Camera shutter clicks ]
- Oh!
[ Lowered voice ]
It's time to meet with your boss.
I need to meet with him today.
I can't. It's not possible.
Oh. Ooh! This is for you.
Happy birthday.
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
My birthday was in August.
My goodness.
Well, time flies when
you're on the run.
Please,
let's get out of the open.
[ Laughs ]
[ Sighs ]
There's nothing I can
do for you.
The Foreign Minister,
he's traveling today.
You see that lovely woman there?
The one with the camera?
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
She's a stringer for UPI.
Dear, dear friend.
Shoots my Christmas card
every year.
She has a wonderful eye
for composition and detail.
An intuitive sense of timing
to capture the moment.
A warm embrace
between old friends.
The exchange of a gift.
The intimacy of
a quiet conversation
in the backseat of a car.
But the curious thing is,
pictures never tell
the whole story.
For instance,
the only story here will be
your friendly meeting with
an international criminal
wanted by
the FBI, Interpol.
I wonder how long you'll
survive once that story
hits the Venezuelan press?
[ Laughing ]
I'm sorry. I can't help myself.
It's a photo album
for your press clippings.
Rafael.
The meeting
with the Foreign Minister
will happen today.
Is it set?
The Foreign Minister will be
making a fuel stop
at Kirby heliport
at 3:00 PM today.
I'll have 15 minutes
with him.
What's our next move?
Rendezvous will be fruitless
unless we can retrieve
a certain care package.
The FBI took it
into custody this morning.
That package is the ticket
to Elizabeth's freedom.
What's in the package?
El Dorado.
The lost city of gold?
It was never a city.
When Spanish explorers
reached South America,
they heard stories about
a gold-dusted tribal chief
dumping vast piles of treasure
into Lake Guatavita
as an offering.
The Spaniards actually
drained the lake.
Of course, all they found
was a handful of trinkets.
So they killed
all the natives,
and El Dorado
came to represent
the fantasy
of boundless wealth--
and that is what's inside
the package.
I don't understand.
You will, once we steal it
from the FBI.
I mean, how many times
do I have to tell you?
It wasn't about sex.
If it wasn't about the sex,
then why'd you have sex?
Why not invite him
to join your book club?
- [ Cell phone ringing ]
- Because I hate my book club.
And the only reason I joined
that book club
is because
you were never home.
Doug was just, you know,
company.
With a series of regrettable
mistakes along the way.
For god sake, Harold, would you
please answer that phone?
[ Ringing continues ]
[ Beep ]
- The cabin. Karakurt.
You have to leave now. - What?
- How do you know about Karakurt?
- It doesn't matter.
The bottom line is the Cabal
knows you're stashing Karakurt
in the cabin near Lake Yvonne.
- Look, can they track it down?
- Yes.
My neighbor owns the cabin.
They'll search
our phone records.
Take Karakurt out now.
I'm not with him.
Tom Keen is.
- So call him.
- I won't get through.
That's the whole point
of the cabin.
It's remote.
No cell phone coverage.
- How far away are you?
- Hour. Minimum.
All right, I'm closer.
Look,
just text me the address.
- I'm on my way now.
- [ Phone beeps ]
So when they determine
the stress points on the box,
then what?
Liz:
Not having much luck?
No, we'll find a way in.
He'll come for you.
Reddington?
Yes, I expect he will,
now that his prima ballerina
is trapped in a jewelry box.
- Did you ever find out?
- Find out what?
His connection to you.
It's always been curious
to me.
Follows you around
like a faithful bloodhound.
But you still don't know.
Well, that's too bad.
It's-- it's a very
unsatisfying way to go out,
don't you think?
Red: How much time
do we have?
The FBI in West Virginia
would've taken the care package
into their custody this morning
when they arrested Keen.
But there's no FBI
field office in West Virginia
to store evidence,
so they would've sent a team
from their Pittsburgh
field office to collect it.
They should be on the road
back to Pittsburgh by now.
We need to intercept them before
they reach their field office.
The trick is to purloin
the package
without them knowing
we've taken it.
For that, we need more
stolen evidence.
[ Door rattles ]
You keep a storage locker
in West Virginia?
I keep a storage locker
filled with useful items
- in most states.
- [ Switch clicks ]
- Two or three in the Red States.
- Steaks?
Bistecca alla Fiorentina,
sourced from a breed of cattle
in southern Tuscany.
The ultimate expression
of beef,
with a bowl of fagioli,
a '96, '97 Barolo.
These need another month
to cure.
[ Pounding ]
[ Grunts ]
- I never took you for a--
- Drug dealer? Absolutely not.
Well, not really.
I've made a rather healthy
investment in a consortium
that supplies medical marijuana
to facilities in Colorado,
Oregon, Washington,
District of Columbia.
But simply as an effort
to diversify
into more legitimate
businesses.
As for consumption,
I must admit to a fondness for
any well-appointed opium den,
and a bit of hashish goes well
with just about anything.
But stimulants,
I have no taste for.
I prefer that slight curve
at the small of the back,
the swell of a breast,
the soft nape of the neck to
quicken my heartbeat.
Nonetheless,
after a rather contentious
and messy negotiation
in Cartagena,
this was all that was left on
the table, so I took it.
Cocaine still remains a valid
currency to some of my clients.
Especially in England.
The wealthy Brits?
They are cocaine mad over there.
Go figure.
Why don't you grab some kilos
off the top
and let's go stage
a crime scene?
♪♪
[ Engine turns off ]
[ Laughs ]
This is fun.
Who had the pleasure?
That would be me.
Head on.
35 miles an hour.
Just like my uncle Vic
on a Saturday night.
[ Siren whoops ]
[ Brakes squeal,
engine turns off ]
- Sorry about the short notice, Morgan.
- [ Car doors close ]
Chuck. Nice paint job.
Thanks.
Careful. It's still wet.
Well, gang's all here.
Let's get to work.
♪♪
My name is Agent Morrison
in the West Virginia office.
Yes, I called this in
two hours ago.
I need someone here
from evidence recovery ASAP.
[ Sighs ]
That's right.
30 bags of cocaine, exit 129A
off the I-64.
Can you get them here now,
please?
I've been babysitting
this evidence all day.
- [ Car door closes ]
- Thank you, guys.
Time to run.
As soon as you get the package,
bring it straight to
Kirby heliport.
The plan hinges on that package.
I'll be there.
Hey. You okay?
I've been better.
Okay, you're almost there.
In an hour, Ressler will
move you to a holding cell
at the courthouse.
You'll be safe there.
I'm having trouble breathing.
Just the man
I'm looking for.
One of my technicians
figured out why the, uh,
code box does not work.
Apparently it was changed.
Coincidentally enough,
just prior to our arrival.
That must be...
What?
A mistake?
Yes, probably.
But we can't prove it.
- Technology being what it is and all.
- [ Gasping ]
And you are the tech guy.
Aram, I can't...
I can't breathe.
[ Exhales sharply ]
What's happening to her?
- [ Gasping ]
- I'm sure I don't know.
Losing oxygen in there?
I'm sorry.
We don't have the door code.
I'll have one of my men
look into it right away.
[ Breathing heavily ]
That would be a tragedy.
She'd better be worth it.
Who's that?
Huh. The girl.
You know, the one who annulled
your marriage.
[ Chuckles ]
I know about you two.
I know you're risking your life
for someone who doesn't want
anything to do with--
[ Door closes, footsteps ]
[ Gun cocks ]
Hey, don't shoot.
Don't shoot.
It's Donald Ressler.
All right, open it.
[ Door opens ]
- What are you doing here?
- Cooper sent me.
Look, we gotta get him
out of here.
- [ Door closes ]
- Like hell we do.
The Director knows
you have Karakurt.
The Cabal is coming.
No offense, but I'll wait
for Cooper to tell me that.
Hey.
[ Engine rumbling ]
Hey. Hey!
Someone's out there!
[ Vehicle approaches ]
[ Vehicle doors open
and close ]
The Cabal's not coming.
They're already here.
[ Click ]
Okay, breathe slowly and steady.
It doesn't make any sense.
Even if they shut out
the air,
I should be able to breathe
in here for hours, right?
Nitrogen.
He's pumping nitrogen
in through the vents.
It would-- Oh, my God,
it would strip the oxygen out
in minutes.
You wouldn't be able
to smell it either.
[ Wheezes and coughs ]
Oh...
What, are you guys just gonna
watch this happen?
She can't breathe.
The Director said he's working
on the problem.
He is not, and you know that!
Do something.
Do something!
Okay, right. Okay, Agent Keen.
Okay, hang on.
I'm just--
I'm gonna see if I can access
- the ventilation system from my terminal.
- [ Breathing heavily ]
Okay? It's, um,
it's gonna be okay.
I'll be right back.
How did the Director know
that we had Karakurt?
How about we focus on
the problem at hand?
We gotta put down these targets
so that I can get back to Keen.
- Where is she?
- FBI custody.
The Cabal is trying to
get at her.
You're just a one-man
justice league, aren't you?
You know you're gonna get us
all killed before this is over.
- [ Glass shatters ]
- Get me out of here!
[ Hissing ]
[ Gunshots ]
Keen!
[ Coughing ]
Clear!
[ Coughs ]
- You okay?
- I'm not!
Least you could give me a weapon
so I can defend myself.
Not if it's aimed at our backs,
no way.
[ Gun clicks ]
[ Typing rapidly ]
[ Beep ] _
[ Resumes rapid typing ]
I can't access the air system,
but I'm trying to override it
with a Rombertik.
It's gonna take a little bit
of time, Liz.
- Oh, my god. Liz, I have to let you out.
- [ Gasping ]
Please!
[ Coughs ]
Damn it,
are you even listening? I--
I'll go to the press.
I don't care!
There are witnesses here.
I will tell the world
what you're doing here.
Fix the air!
I don't know about this,
Peter.
It'll go down as
an equipment malfunction.
And there is no one
to trace it to.
Yeah? And what if
he opens the door?
Well, we return to
the original plan.
We take Elizabeth Keen
to an undisclosed location
for questioning, from which
she will try to escape.
And then... we'll be forced
to shoot her.
In any case, you are looking
at a ghost.
[ Engine turns off ]
Do you have any idea how long
I've been standing out here?
Hey, tell it to Dispatch.
We were halfway to Pittsburgh
before we got the call
to come all the way back.
Okay, let's just load up.
You know we can't let you
handle the evidence.
And I'd advise you
to check your watch
because I've been out in
the sun on my feet all day
without a bite to eat
since 6:00 AM.
We offered her a doughnut.
[ Radio chatter ]
Hey, I've been meaning to ask
one of you federal boys.
What does it take
to be a g-man?
See, I got this lazy eye.
It's got a mind of its own.
You suppose that would be
an issue?
No offense, but we're short
on time ourselves today.
Here.
- Are we good?
- What?
Hey. I need your assurance
that nothing in that van
is going to go missing.
Are we good?
Yeah. Relax.
It's as safe as can be.
[ Men shouting indistinctly ]
Let's go!
[ Men shout indistinctly ]
Man: Take the left!
Ah, this isn't gonna be pretty.
[ Breathes heavily ]
I'm the one who tipped off
the Cabal
- about this hunting cabin.
- [ Chamber whirs and clicks ]
Are you kidding me?
Why would you do that?
[ Gun thuds ]
Trusted the wrong person.
I mean, yes, you were just doing
what you thought was right.
Even if you were dead wrong.
[ Men shouting indistinctly
in distance ]
My father was a cop.
He died because he wouldn't
go on the take.
Was set up by his own partner,
Tommy Markin.
You know,
I spent all these years
wanting to believe that
he died for the right thing.
I'm not so sure now.
Principles are a bitch, man.
I avoid them at all cost.
[ Rapid footsteps approach
outside ]
I just hope your old man
taught you how to shoot.
[ Wheezing ]
Hang on, Liz.
Come on, you have to.
Come on, a little longer.
Come on. Liz?
I, uh, I'm afraid
we're out of options.
Can't seem to figure out what's
wrong with this air system.
Liz.
Liz?
[ Clatters ]
Liz? Wake up!
Liz!
Navabi.
[ Sobs ]
What's that, son?
The pass code--
it is "Navabi."
It's "Navabi"!
Open the door.
N-A-V-A-B-I.
Open the door. Open the door!
Do it!
Open the door. Come on.
- Come on. Open it!
- [ Keypad beeping ]
[ Door whirring ]
Oh... oh...
Come on. Okay.
Come on, Liz. Come on, Liz.
[ Grunting ]
- [ Gasps ]
- Yeah, yeah.
You're okay.
Liz. I'm-- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. So sorry.
Gracias.
[ Sighs ]
Mr. Foreign Minister,
thank you for altering
your itinerary to meet me.
And how is El Presidente?
- He has irritable bowels.
- [ Laughs ]
But what can you expect?
We just borrowed another
$5 billion from China.
So, what is this about,
Reddington?
I was told a matter
of national interest.
Indeed.
I believe I can help your
President's stomach condition.
Oh, you're gonna erase
my country's debt?
No, but I can give you some
walking-around money. Please.
Gentlemen!
We can preserve the quiet
tranquility of these woods
if you just send Karakurt
out now.
You have 30 seconds before
we begin shooting.
- There's no way we're sending him out.
- Agreed.
Then how 'bout
giving me a weapon?
It's not like I can run.
Come on, give him a gun.
[ Inhales sharply, groans ]
Solomon: 15 seconds!
[ Chains rattle ]
[ Grunts ]
The Cabal,
the ones coming for Liz...
- They're not gonna get her.
- [ Gun cocks ]
Let's just get it over with.
♪♪
[ Gunshot, casing clatters ]
[ Gunshot ]
- Uhh!
- [ Thud ]
[ Little Scream's "The Lamb" playing ]
♪♪
♪ once when you were young ♪
♪ pedaling through the sun ♪
♪ the light streamed through
your body like a glass ♪
♪ but then the changes come ♪
♪ things are good undone ♪
♪ and the things you lose,
they don't come back again ♪
♪ so you want to go back again ♪
[ Gunshots continue ]
♪ Amahl ♪
[ Gunfire stops ]
Check for survivors.
♪ Amahl ♪
♪ listen ♪
[ Gunshot ]
♪♪
[ Gunshots, men grunting ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Gunfire continues ]
Knees!
[ Gunshots ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
I'll just, uh, take that.
Let's get out of here.
[ Cocks gun ]
I won't let you take her.
Aram, put the gun down!
They'll shoot you
without thinking twice.
[ Breathing raggedly ]
- I don't care.
- I do.
You've done enough.
No, I didn't.
[ Breathing heavily ]
I opened the door.
- Agent Mojtabai, stand down.
- [ Hammer clicks ]
Liz:
Aram. Aram, look at me.
Look at me.
I don't blame you
for letting me out.
I don't.
Now please put the gun down.
Director: Let's go.
Excuse me!
Where exactly do you think
you're taking this young lady?
Mrs. Panabaker, right on time.
I believe punctuality
is a virtue,
as is following orders.
My orders are to make sure
Elizabeth Keen
is transported safely
to the E. Barrett Prettyman Courthouse.
And I have actionable Intel
that requires us
to move agent Keen to
Fort McNair.
I am aware of the Intel.
So is DNI,
who's reviewed it
and upheld
the original agreement.
As National Security Advisor,
this is my call to make.
Not according to this.
Oh, don't take my word
for it.
Get the Director of National
Intelligence on the line.
Oh, well, then I guess
I'll call him myself.
Why would Venezuela ever agree
to such a ridiculous proposal?
Why, to stick it to
the United States, of course.
They've been trying to topple
your regime for years.
If we do as you suggest,
the United States would just
impose more sanctions.
Our shelves are already bare.
This would hurt my people
and my economy
- for generations to come.
- [ Vehicle approaching ]
This meeting is over.
- [ Engine turns off ]
- Diaz, I told you I could put money back
in Venezuela's Central Bank.
And I've told you,
you couldn't possibly
give us enough money
to make what you're asking
worth the risk.
Do you know the story
of El Dorado?
Thank you, my dear.
[ Door closes ]
[ Latch clicks ]
Those are chromium-plated
master-printing plates
for the $100 bill,
created using
the US Treasury Department's
own software upgrades
plate design,
encoding techniques--
Where did you get these?
[ Laughing ]
Oh, well...
There was this plane
that fell out of the sky,
a group of anti-capitalists.
Terrorists in funny masks.
But I digress.
The point is
I'm giving El Jefe
the ability to print as much
money as he'd like to print.
You son of a gun.
I've been called worse.
Found a ride.
[ Gun cocks ]
Your weapons on the ground.
Or I'll kill him.
He'll kill me anyway,
so just drop him.
Just drop the son of a bitch.
Come on, man, you're FBI.
You never put your weapon down.
Just... second he shoots me,
drop him.
Drop him!
All right, you win. Okay?
[ Gun thuds ]
Did you even go to
the Academy?
- You should've listened to your friend.
- [ Grunts ]
[ Thud ]
I figured you two
could use some backup.
[ Exhales ]
Good morning.
[ Laughs ]
Cooper: Agent Ressler,
listen to me.
Put the gun down.
- You should leave.
- [ Gun cocks ]
Stop.
Do you know the damage
you've done?
That your organization has done
to this country, to my friends?
I don't care about your friends,
and I hate this country.
Well, "Hate's" a strong word.
I like the part
where I make bail
and catch the next plane
to France.
You're not gonna live to see
the inside of a courtroom.
[ Laughs ]
Sure, I am.
And not just any courtroom,
but a courtroom of my choosing,
with the judge of my choosing.
- God bless America.
- Agent Ressler.
You're not gonna do this.
- You deserve to die.
Cooper: - Put down the gun.
I know he does,
but not by your hand.
Since when did you grow
a conscience?
I don't know. Since I've been
hanging out with you.
I'm not happy about it either.
Ah, he's right.
We bring him in, he walks.
He doesn't pay for any of this.
Your dad.
You wanna know if he died
for nothing.
Whether he did or didn't
depends on whether
you pull that trigger.
Matias Solomon,
you're under arrest...
for the attempted murder of
a federal agent,
a material witness
in a federal investigation,
treason, espionage...
Conspiracy to--
You know what?
Why don't I get you
a penal code?
It would be easier to figure out
what you haven't done.
[ Grunts ]
Yes, sir.
I understand.
[ Telephone ringing
in distance ]
I stand corrected.
I have never seen
two people so disappointed
that the country
isn't under attack.
Yeah, well, I'm not convinced.
So let's get Agent Keen
transferred, shall we?
My men are on site.
And they will stay on site.
I consulted with Reven Wright
before I drafted the order.
Keen isn't going anywhere
without one agent,
Donald Ressler present,
to oversee her transfer.
Uh, Agent Ressler isn't here.
[ Door whirs ]
Sorry I'm late.
Bring him to holding.
Elizabeth Keen, I'm here
to escort you downtown,
where you'll be held safely
pending your arraignment.
[ Whispers ]
It's about time.
[ Chains rattling ]
I know what you did.
I know you killed Reven Wright.
[ Telephone ringing
in distance ]
This isn't over.
And you.
I want you gone
when I get back.
[ Whispers ]
Thank you.
[ "Gamble Everything For Love"
by Ben Lee playing ]
[ Chains rattling ]
I need to come around here
more often.
♪ gamble everything for love,
gamble everything ♪
♪ put it in a place you keep
what you need ♪
♪ you can gamble everything
for love if you're free ♪
♪ you gotta gamble
everything for love ♪
♪ baby, are you cold?
are you cold, baby? ♪
♪ I could wrap you up,
wrap you up in my love ♪
♪ if you wanna, you can gamble
everything for love ♪
Am I free to go?
Agent Ressler's orders.
♪ ...in the places that you
never knew to get through ♪
♪ tell me are you gonna cry
all night? ♪
♪ tell me the truth,
and I'll tell you the truth ♪
♪ if you gamble everything
for love ♪
♪ you're gonna be all right ♪
♪ all right ♪
[ Door closes ]
♪ make a list of things
you need, leave it empty ♪
♪ except for number one,
write love, gamble everything ♪
- ♪ keep it under lock and key ♪
- [ Lock clicking ]
♪ if you wanna, you can gamble
everything for love ♪
[ Cell phone chimes ]
♪ we can find a place to start
to gamble everything ♪
♪ we can set this thing apart ♪
♪ 'cause we're gonna, gonna
gamble everything for love ♪
She still alive?
♪ tell me the truth,
and I'll tell you the truth ♪
♪ if you gamble everything
for love ♪
♪ you're gonna be all right ♪
♪ all right ♪
For what it's worth,
I believe you were framed.
♪♪
♪ ooh, you can go
your own way ♪
♪ ooh, you gotta go
♪ if you gamble
everything for love ♪
Come closer, Aram.
[ Crickets chirping ]
There's nobody down there.
Not at the moment.
So then...
why did you ask me to meet you
at an empty grave?
There are...
foundational elements
in our lives.
People...
that form the brick and mortar
of who we are.
People that are so
deeply imbedded
that we take their existence
for granted
until suddenly,
they're not there.
And we...
collapse into rubble.
I've stood over the open grave
of someone I've loved...
too often.
Once for my mother.
And then... the others.
I needed to recall
this feeling because...
I'd be staring at another body
right now if not for you, Aram.
It wasn't weakness
that prevented you
from watching your friend
die today.
It was hope,
and thank heavens you were
in a hopeful mood.
You saved Elizabeth.
I'm forever in your debt.
Now gather your team.
It's time to take down
the Cabal.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com