Previously on The Bridge...
Who are you?
Marco Ruiz.
Chihuahua State Police.
Who are you?
Sonya Cross.
El Paso Homicide.
Whoa!
Oh, shit!
White arms, brown legs.
There were two women on the bridge.
Two different women.
- Cut in half?
- Yes.
Do you have a girl that
matches this description?
Cristina Fuentes is only one of 250 girls
who disappeared last year.
So you have a serial killer.
There are five murders a year in El Paso.
In Juarez, thousands.
Why is one dead white woman more important
than so many dead just across the bridge?
What's in there?
What is it?
It's a tunnel.
Where does it go?
Across.
To Mexico.
Karl was running drugs?
No, señora. Illegals.
I... I need to see it.
Cesar, I need to see it.
O____
W___
Who else knows about this?
Nobody.
Just Señor Karl and, uh...
Who's on the other side?
I don't know.
I know this wasn't Karl's idea.
We should go back.
It's not good to be down in here.
What is that?
It's an altar.
What is it doing here?
Somebody died.
Here?
Sí, señora.
There was an accident.
Just get rid of it.
Board it up.
I don't think that's a good idea, señora.
Please, Cesar, I can't
deal with this right now.
S___
Y___
I___
N___
All right, out!
Let's go!
¡Vámonos!
Fin del camino, folks.
This is as far as I go.
Adios, amigos.
T___
How 'bout this deal,
I don't scatter your
brains all over the desert?
¿Comprende?
Do it the old-fashioned way and walk.
W___
D___
B___
Y___
H___
S___
I'm___
W___
N___
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
What would you do if
you were locked in a car
with a bomb
and had five minutes to live?
He didn't have five minutes to live.
No, just imagine.
What would you do?
Would you pray for a miracle?
Would you make right with your life?
I'd try to get out.
Yeah, but boom!
The bomb goes off.
Well, five minutes wouldn't make much
of a difference then, would they?
Hmm.
You want some?
No. I want to work.
Okay, so...
let's go talk to Daniel Frye
You can't interrogate him.
No, I'm just gonna ask him some questions.
You can interrogate him.
Come on.
Hey.
Detective Sonya Cross.
Oh, Detective Marco Ruiz.
You're the bitch on the phone.
Just doing my job.
I could've died.
But you didn't.
Your car was used in a double homicide.
Yeah, and then the nut job stole my car
and put a bomb in it.
Why don't you guys go find him, huh?
We are trying.
Well, that's great.
Then I'm gonna leave.
We searched your place.
Sit down.
Come on. Sit down.
You can't do that.
Well, we can and we did.
And guess what, we found
your stash... the pills.
All right, what is this shit?
How did the killer
get access to your car?
Let's see.
I, uh, worked until about midnight
and then I went over to the
bar and I had a couple pops
and I went back to the
office and I crashed.
After that, I don't remember.
Why is that?
Tequila.
Okay.
So you've written about Judge Gates, right?
You already asked me that question.
We're asking again.
immigration,
some professor grabbing another
professor at the university,
the cancer walk, the
Building Commission meetings,
Puppypalooza.
Whatever crap story my
editor wants to put me on,
that's what I write about... it's my job.
There are five murders a year in El Paso.
In Juarez, thousands.
Why?
Why is one dead white woman more important
than so many dead just across the bridge?
Recognize that?
Nope.
You two have your work cut out for you.
Why did he pick you, Frye?
Why don't you two figure that out
and then I'll write the story.
Huh? That's what I would
call a win-win situation.
Oh, uh, for the record, Officer,
your bedside manner sucks dog balls.
Why did you lie about searching his place?
We needed him to talk, right?
Lying's bad.
He's not going to trust us now.
He's a reporter... you
can't trust 'em anyway.
They lie.
What's that?
Sorry about the drama,
but it is hard to make
oneself heard these days.
Cristina Fuentes died 14 months ago.
Nobody investigated.
Nobody cared.
Just another dead girl.
Another pink cross,
another victim of the border.
Well, ain't that a
well-stacked brick of cow shit.
He's only getting started.
Yeah, looks like it.
I'm going to Juarez, Hank.
What for, Sonya?
It's where the case is, and...
No, that's not a good idea.
I'm going.
N___
P___
She's here with me.
Sonya sends her regards.
Okay. Bye.
My wife says hi.
I didn't say hello.
I don't know her.
No, you will meet her.
She's very curious about you.
Why?
She wants to know how we're getting along.
How are we?
Good.
So far.
Is that why she called?
No.
Doesn't she know you're working?
Yes.
She just wanted to hear my voice.
T___
Not everything is in the system.
Some stuff we just keep in the boxes.
Let's see what we have here in this file.
It's a motel key.
You've studied the case?
It's not my job.
It's okay.
The other victims were cartel killings.
Yup, tortured, shot
and dumped.
Just business.
The men were all killed at the same time.
Cristina a month before.
Okay.
What's in the box that's not in the system?
Rafa Galvan,
Fausto Galvan's brother.
So, there was another body?
His body was taken from the morgue.
And his name...
erased from the system.
23 became 22.
I'm sorry. How does that happen?
Galvan made a call.
He didn't want his rivals
to have the satisfaction.
So, you buried it?
Not me.
Captain Alejandro Robles.
You must be Detective Sonya Cross.
Yes.
Welcome to Juarez, Detective.
Oh.
How are they hanging, Detective?
Muy bien. Muy bien, Capitán.
Straight and true.
That's not what I've heard.
Oh.
Perhaps you can show us
how the Americans do it.
Oh, no, Capitán.
The task force is only for Cristina's case.
I know what the task
force is for, Detective.
The Chihuahua State Police
doesn't promote fools.
Hmm.
Why wasn't this case investigated?
What case?
23 cartel members
dumped in the same house
as Cristina Fuentes.
22.
Not 23.
Isn't that right, Detective?
Sí señor.
Okay, well, why wasn't it investigated?
I___ Sí señor.
Oh.
Nice meeting you, Detective.
W___
No, señor.
A___
She's only interested in the girl.
- Y___.
- Yes, sir.
K___
- Sí, señor.
- Understand?
Sí.
You can't come in here and
ask those kind of questions.
We're investigating a murder.
No, no, no, no, it doesn't
work like that down here!
Is this about Fausto Galvan?
You're going to get me killed.
I have a family.
A man like Fausto Galvan can take my wife
and my kids out into the desert,
burn 'em alive and make me watch.
What does he have to do with this case?
¡Nada! ¡Nothing!
Why was her body dumped in that house?
That's it, that's it. I'm... I'm done here.
I'm... I'm taking you back.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, let's go, I said!
Y___
- L___.
- No!
A___
P___.
W___
Y___
- Sí.
- W___
Y___.
Un gringo.
H___.
¿Que?
T___.
B___.
- A___.?
- No.
A___.
- Are you sure this is right?
- Verbatim.
Wow.
You stumbled into a story, Daniel.
- No shit.
- What was it like?
What do you think it
was like? It was awesome.
So, why did this nut job pick you?
I like to think he's a loyal reader.
Okay, the police are gonna be watching you.
They already are.
We're gonna have to be
very careful with this.
Come on, grow a pair.
Run the story. It's good.
You know, I haven't seen
you at any meetings lately.
Just been going to different meetings.
You're a shitty liar.
Hey, uh, Mendez? Come here.
Okay, you're gonna be
working this story with Frye.
Hey, bullshit.
- I am not working with some cub reporter...
- Spare me the résumé recital,
Daniel, please.
You're gonna download the story to Mendez,
you're gonna write the main story
about the killer's manifesto,
without explaining how we got it.
Of course.
You're gonna write the
sidebar about what it was like
to be in that car.
Did you piss your pants?
You know, that sort of a thing?
Okay?
File anything over 850,
I'm gonna cut it down to size myself, okay?
You have one hour. Go!
Car is clean.
We still have nothing on the
power outage on the bridge.
Cooper's traced the judge's
credit card movements.
We got her buying gas.
Security camera.
How did it go with you and Marco?
Good.
Good in as, you're working with him?
He's mad at me.
How come?
I ask too many questions?
Yes, you do.
Does Carmen ever call you for no reason?
Yeah, she does sometimes.
His wife called
when we were working...
just to hear his voice.
It seems like such a waste of time...
I got him.
You got... Oh.
We know Judge Gates
- stopped for gas in Sonora, right?
- Right.
She goes inside.
Winner, winner, chicken dinner.
He was waiting in the backseat.
He must have followed her.
Play that bit again.
Excuse me. Miss Charlotte,
there's a man here to see you.
I'm busy.
He's not going away.
Monte P. Flagman, Esquire.
- I'm very sorry for your loss, ma'am.
- Thank you.
It's a lenticular.
Stars and Stripes?
Turn it, you get the Lone Star?
My wife insisted on making her
three bean salad for the wake.
Looks like a cyclone blew through here.
You ever seen a real one up close?
It's a hell of a thing.
I'm sorry. How do you know my husband?
Did some legal work for him.
He never mentioned your name.
This is about the tunnel, isn't it?
Yes, ma'am.
I want to make you
aware of some obligations
- Karl had to my client.
- Karl's dead.
You've come a long way since meeting Karl.
Waiting tables in Miami,
or was it the Keys?
It was Tampa.
Technically speaking,
this is still Karl's ranch.
It could take a while for the estate
to settle out with the lawyers.
Then there's Karl's
daughter Katie to consider.
Those probate hearings
can be kind of tricky.
What's your point?
Karl had good taste in horses.
What'd he call this one?
Rio.
Those bloodlines cost money.
Horse like that'll cost
you a hundred grand, easy.
My client gave it to him.
What is your client's name?
I'm not at liberty to say.
I simply want to point out
there is a prior obligation
between your late husband and my client.
Okay.
See, I don't know if Karl told you,
but he took a real bath in the crash.
Kind of got out over his skis, as they say.
I just wanted to introduce myself.
You have my card.
Y___.
S___.
C___.
G___!
Y___?
Get out!
I___.n.
W___.?
I___.
T___.
Y___.
G___.
I___.
W___.
F___.
H___?
1___.
Y___?
C___.
H___?
A___,
o___.
B___...
S___.
S___?
Y___?
T___.
Hmm?
S___.
Hi.
- You waiting for someone?
- No.
Can I buy you a drink?
No.
Okay.
Hey.
Why'd you walk away?
I just didn't want a drink.
Okay.
Want to have sex with me?
We can go back to my place.
What, is this some kind of joke?
- No. Why, you married?
- No.
Want to have sex, yes or no?
Yes.
Good.
You're late again, Steven.
Yes, I know that.
Traffic.
They found that judge up
on the Bridge of Americas last night.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I saw that.
It's just terrible.
Well, I don't know.
Maybe she had it coming.
Nobody has that coming.
You don't mean that, Steven.
I know. No, you're right.
I guess that's just my politics.
What's new?
Valentina's got her court date.
Big John's talking about the river
and Emmy Lou again and not taking his meds.
Mrs. Nelson wandered off.
Toilet's leaking.
Felipe found a dead rat in the cooler,
another in the storeroom.
When did she come in?
Night before last.
Refused to see the nurse.
Possible 51-50. Bowl of
soup and she was gone.
What happened to your hand?
It's nothing.
You go on home now.
You get some rest.
Make sure Felipe sets rat traps.
I will set them myself.
Drink first?
Okay.
Have you done this before?
Yeah. You?
Yeah.
Okay, let's go.
Faster! Fast!
Oh!
Hey...
- D___.
- Gracias.
K___?
S___
a___.
H___.
I___.
T___.
Bien.
What the hell is that?
- Work.
- Work? What do you do?
Detective, El Paso PD.
You want me to go?
You want to stay?
You can sleep.
Who is that?
Corpse.
Yeah,
- maybe I should go.
- Okay.
Here you go.
Thank you.
T___.
S___
a___.
F___.
T___
e___.
T___.
Y___.
E___.
I___.
W___?
A___?
- Sonya?
- Hmm.
¿Que?
S___?
Eh.
S___.
A___.
I___.
N___.
W___? H___?
- I___...
- I___.
- A___?
- Sí.
H___?
W___.
I___.
There's something there.
Going back with Marco.
Yeah, there's a bunch of rocks there.
Did you stare at those
photographs all night?
Not all night. I had sex.
I don't need to know that, Sonya.
Did you at least dance
with the fella first?
Hey, boss, you see that yet?
It's the killer's message verbatim.
How'd he get this?
I played it for him.
Cooper?
What can I do you for, Hank?
I'm sorry, am... am I
interrupting your snack time?
I'm just topping off
my good bacteria, boss.
You got good and bad
bacteria in your stomach,
and they're at war.
Yeah, well, now they're in the trash.
I want you to follow this reporter.
Our killer chose him for a reason.
I want you on him.
Like a hair on a biscuit.
I'm sorry, Hank.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Sonya, it's okay.
Just, um, shh... It's okay.
- Just check with me next time.
- Okay.
W___.
N___.
T___.
What the hell...?
Of course, I saw you pass by.
What is this?
Coyote.
It was disturbing the crime scene.
So you killed it?
Yes, ma'am.
Scare off other vermin,
predators, what have you.
Yeah, can't have the
crime scene contaminated.
What are you doing here?
I was on a stakeout.
A stakeout?
Yes, sir.
Killers sometimes revisit
their crime scenes...
I read it in a book.
So I've been watching.
Yeah. Good work, Deputy.
Yeah.
As you can see, I...
preserved the field of evidence.
The blood's intact.
Thank you. Gracias.
I understand a task force is imminent.
Yes.
I'd like to be part of it, being
I was first one on the scene.
We'll keep you in mind.
You okay?
Uh, it's, uh, oh, migraine coming on.
Whoo! It's a head buster.
What's that?
A bead.
Don't worry, Jose... I'm gonna bury 'em.
Railroad doesn't have a leg to stand on.
Now, you go home, take you some ibuprofen,
get that pretty wife of yours to
rub some liniment on your neck.
Miss Millwright.
I see you found us okay.
This is three bean salad.
And this is money.
And I don't want it.
I was a hostess, not a waitress.
I stand corrected.
Ma'am.
W___.
- W___?
- ¡Vengan!
I___.
D___.
N___.
A___?
___.
It's a bead.
He left it for us to find.
There's a man here.
He says he's responsible for the message.
Can we help you?
Excuse me.
Sir.
Good to finally meet you.
- Don't move!
- Show me your hands!
Let's see your hands!
What's the matter?
Don't move!
I do over 33 impressions.
Community theater.
Maybe you remember me as Falstaff?
No.
You're an actor?
When I saw the paper,
I couldn't believe it.
Who asked you to record the message?
I don't know.
The script came with a note as
to how they wanted it recorded.
No name, just a P.O. box return.
And you didn't think the
whole thing was strange?
The letter said that it was
for an art performance or something.
How'd you get paid?
Money order, if I remember right.
Do you still have the script
and letter with the P.O. box?
No.
Why not?
It's been a long time.
Recorded it three years ago.
Howdy.
Give it.
Yeah, the car matches, the time matches.
It's the dude.
He said he's in Juarez for the señoritas.
So, you, uh, got your address there, amigo.
You know, I had no
reason not to believe him.
We're good, right?
Hey.
- Want some?
- No.
Aw, come on, you've earned it.
Front page of the local newspaper.
Wires'll pick up.
You think?
It's good. It's good stuff.
You sure?
I'm okay. Thank you.
Hey, sorry about being such a dick earlier.
Why are you such a dick?
I was born that way.
Shit. Hey...
How much you want to bet that's a cop?
With that moustache.
That hat.
That's weird.
- This is Frye.
- Hello, Daniel.
- Are you listening?
- Yes.
It's the killer... give me a pen.
Pen, pen...
Uh-huh, yeah, I'm listening.
No, just wait one... one sec.
Okay?
Okay, I'm ready.
Three, one, six, zero, six,
zero, two, five, one, zero, six,
zero, two, six, three, zero, six.
Okay, is that... is that it?
Hello?
That was the killer.
What did he say?
He told me to pay attention
and then he gave me this number.
Look, three, one, six, zero, six.
Code just keeps going.
Give me the pen.
What the hell does it mean?
It's a GPS coordinate.
Longitude and latitude.
How do you know that?
Father was a surveyor for Pemex.
No shit.
See?
East of town, down by the border.
What do you think you're doing?
Buenos días... señorita.
Buenos días, my ass.
I'm calling the cops.
Where is Steven Linder?
I don't know.
He took something from me.
I want it back.
God have mercy on you.
Maybe.
It's almost dark.
Better for the story.
"Two Reporters Lured to Their Death"?
Hopefully one of us lives.
The other one can write the story.
I smell a Pulitzer.
So, what's your deal?
What are you, uh, community college?
You write a blog or something?
U.T. Austin.
Boyfriend?
What, you want to get to know me now?
Not really.
Oh, hey, stop, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop, stop.
What?
It says, "Go right."
It's just down here.
Down where?
Holy shit!
Oh, my God.
Aw, hell.
Dangerous crossing.
The fence forces them out here.
Nine bodies.
It's him.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -