We left something undone.
We gotta fix it.
He and I were on
a case in Erath.
A girl comes forward and
says she was chased
through the woods
by a spaghetti monster
with green ears and I think
that this is our man
with the scars on his face.
What happened to
Billy Lee Tuttle?
I staked
his places out for weeks.
Found those in the safe there.
There was a videotape.
No!
Out of all these
kids running around,
you remember one that maybe had
scars all across the bottom of his face?
I think that was
Mr. Sam's grandchild.
Could you have a look at
something for me? One thing.
You know Carcosa?
Did some backtracking
on the Marie Fontenot stuff.
Sheriff didn't take the original
complaint, deputy did.
Steve Geraci.
I said all I remember
about the girl,
and don't ask again.
I ain't gonna ask you.
He is.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
[The Handsome Family's
Far From Any Road playing]
♪ from the dusty mesa ♪
♪ her looming shadow grows ♪
♪ hidden in the branches ♪
♪ of the poison creosote ♪
♪ she twines her spines up slowly ♪
♪ towards the boiling sun ♪
♪ and when I touched her skin ♪
♪ my fingers ran with blood ♪
♪ when the last light warms the rocks ♪
♪ and the rattlesnakes unfold ♪
♪ the mountain cats will come ♪
♪ to drag away your bones ♪
♪ then rise with me forever ♪
♪ across the silent sand ♪
♪ and the stars will be your eyes ♪
♪ and the wind will be my hands ♪
True Detective - 1x08
"Form And Void"
[Birds chirping]
MAN: Them flies
are gettin' thick.
Somebody ought to give you
a good hosin'.
Hmm. Heat ain't helpin'.
Eh, reckon you'll keep
another day.
Be good, I'll bring you
some more water round noon.
Bye, Daddy.
[Whistling a tune]
[Dog barking]
Hey!
Come on. Come on.
- [Barks]
- Come on.
CARY GRANT ON TV: What the
devil is all this about?
Why was I brought here?
JAMES MASON ON TV:
Games, must we?
Not that I mind
a slight case of abduction
now and then, but I have tickets
for the theater this evening,
to a show I was looking
forward to, and I get, well,
kind of unreasonable
about things like that.
With such expert play-acting, you
make this very room a theater...
WOMAN:
You have a good walk?
[British accent]
Yes, my dear.
Top-notch walk
this morning.
Top-notch constitutional.
[Grunts, sighs]
It's been weeks
since I left my mark.
Would that they had
eyes to see.
Hey! Don't you get Miss Billie
in here with them dirty feet!
[Dog yelping]
[Dog panting]
Sorry, old chap.
[Dog whining]
You want to make flowers today?
Now, Betty,
I have very important
work to do.
My...
ascension removes me from
the disc and the loop.
I'm near final stage.
Some mornings,
I can see the infernal plane.
You haven't made flowers
on me for maybe 3 weeks.
Makes me sad is all.
[Irish accent] Ah, come
up in me lap, lass.
Here, and let me comfort
ye in your distress.
[Giggles] You're make
fun of me again.
Heh heh! Now, why'd I do
a thing like that, huh?
Is it because you're
ne so bright?
Because of your head bein'
so slow and like? Ha ha ha!
Oh, you better let me go
'cause I'm burn your eggs.
Hmm?
Mmm.
[Pants]
[Normal voice] Couldn't
you tell me about Grampa?
Mmm.
Ah!
I was in the cane fields,
and he caught me
when I was alone.
And the dirt was warm.
I felt the dirt warm
on my back.
[Moans]
♪
_
COHLE: You're gonna lose a kneecap
if I got to ask you again.
Take it out of the bag
and put it in the machine.
COHLE:
Don't look at me.
Look at the TV.
GERACI:
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Why are you showing me this?!
[Geraci screams]
[Exhales sharply]
That little girl is the one you
said went to see her daddy.
Marie Fontenot, circa 1990.
I took a m-missing
juvenile report.
[Gulps]
And when I went back
to follow up on it,
the file said,
"Report made in error."
I never wrote that.
So I marched it right in to
the sheriff, Ted Childress.
He's dead now.
He did it.
What'd the sheriff say?
He said he'd changed it,
that he knew the mother
and the father,
the aunt and the uncle.
It was a niece once removed
from him or somethin'.
It was the chain of command.
No reason to change it.
I just... follow what
the big man says.
It's...
how this all works.
I-- I tried to get back
with the mother.
I tried to get back with her.
She was gone! She split!
The file was gone!
Nobody said a word!
Later that year, I was in State
CID, on Ted's recommendation!
Nobody ever gave me
a reason to second-guess it!
It's chain of command!
Right?
What do you think?
I don't think he's lying...
as far as he knows.
As far as I know?
What the fuck is
with you, man?!
Might be a whole lot safer
if we staged
something, Marty...
sent the Maserati
over the guardrail.
[Whistling same tune]
[School bell ringing]
[Children clamoring]
Whoa!
Boys, slow down.
WOMAN:
Be careful out there.
I can get you a cafeteria
lunch if you're hungry.
That's all right, Miss.
I've got to get on
with my work.
Lots to do today.
Oh, all right.
[Resumes whistling]
[Stops whistling]
COHLE: We're gonna hang onto
your phone and your gun
till we get safe and mail them
to you once we know we are.
That work for you, Steve?
You can bet your ass
it doesn't.
And it's Sheriff Geraci
to you, shitheel.
Now, look, Steve, you're gonna want
to swing some dick on this thing.
I'm gonna give you a couple
reasons why you won't.
First off, we found this
tape in your possession.
It's a video of the little girl
that you said was not missing.
Second off, all findings are with
lawyers, ready to be forwarded
to media outlets, feds,
CID, US Attorneys,
should either one of us
get sworn a warrant or
if either one of us just fall off
the face of the fuckin' earth,
as people are wont to do
in your neck of the woods.
So you just think about
that little girl, Steve.
What about your boat?
That ain't my boat.
- You know whose boat that is?
- I never seen it before.
It's gonna come back
on you, you assholes,
one way or another.
You just think about
that little girl, Steve.
For quite some time, I'm gonna
be thinking about you, Rust.
Hey, one other thing, Steve.
Got an old sniper
pal, all right?
Contract's already been paid.
Me or Marty, we see
cuffs or coffins,
you're gonna end up
in the dirt.
Then we're gonna
smear your name.
I got something coming
for you, baby.
Your psycho bit
don't cur me, boy!
You hear me?!
[Gunfire]
GERACI: What the fuck?! Hey!
[Gunfire stops]
I strike you as more of a
talker or a doer, Steve?
That's my fuckin' car!
God damn it!
L'chaim, fatass.
You motherfuckers!
GERACI: Fuck you!
♪
COHLE: This old
Sheriff Childress.
He's got no kids, no location
on any of his relatives.
You think they could have
wiped out birth records?
HART:
I don't see why not.
I mean, half those hospitals
along the coast are gone now.
HART: You know,
we got a dead end
on the relations and, uh,
what else is there?
Case files.
You want pre-'98
or after?
After.
We're gonna have to be looking at
these records with fresh eyes, Marty.
All right?
Like we're totally green.
Why green ears?
I mean, assuming
that's our guy.
[Sighs]
I don't know, exactly.
My thinking was it was probably
leaves of some kind, you know,
'cause we do know that he came
at her through the woods.
Why?
What you thinking?
Looking for '95 Dora
Lange canvassing photos
from Erath.
Why?
Well...
Rust.
Come over here.
Now, you think, back
then, does that--
does that look like a fresh...
paint job to you?
- The green ears.
- Yeah.
HART: Maybe they were
sticking out of his hat.
Maybe he painted that house.
I'm going to look up
old addressees.
[Hart taps table]
Fuck you, man.
♪
Something's been bugging
me the last 10 years.
Not every day,
just now and then.
We went at it,
day you quit.
Were you holding back?
No, I don't see how I could've.
Oh, yeah, you do.
You-- you've
always had such
an inflated idea of yourself.
Meaning what?
Meaning it seems
pretty damn arrogant
to hold back
in a fight with me.
You think you could
have put me down?
Ah, I don't know.
Hell, I'd have had to kill you.
You were so goddamn mad.
Yeah, um... ahem.
You know, when she
told me, she said
not to blame you, that
it wasn't your choice.
You, uh, were drunk and...
she made it happen.
Everybody's got
a choice, Marty.
Shit, I sure blamed you.
Blamed me? For what?
[Swallows]
For pushing a good woman
to the point where
she had to use me,
use our partnership
to get rid of you.
For just being
a lying sack of shit.
You know, she couldn't have
used you, you didn't want some.
There you go.
Everybody's got a choice.
And yet, she still
cares about you.
You went to see her, I take it.
- She came out to the bar.
- What?
- When?
- Yeah, she was just checking on you,
wanted to make sure I wasn't
getting you in any trouble.
You should have
fuckin' told me.
Yeah, maybe. I guess.
I reckoned it was best
to just avoid her name.
Didn't want to invite judgments.
You never liked being judged.
No, you're right,
I don't. Not by you.
Well, I didn't say a word.
Well, I could read it
all over your face.
Well, then the problem's
with your face,
not mine.
[Sighs]
It's hard to find
something in a man
who rejects people as much
as you do, you know that?
I never told you how
to live your life, Marty.
No, no, no, you just
sat in judgment.
Look, as sentient meat,
however illusory
our identities are,
we craft those identities
by making value judgments.
Everybody judges, all the time.
Now, you got a problem with
that, you're living wrong.
What's "scented meat"?
♪
[Knocks on door]
MAN: Can I help you?
COHLE: Did you happen
to live here back in '95?
No, we didn't live
here back then.
- This is my grandma's place.
- Mm-hmm.
Grandma, she still with us?
- Alive, you mean?
- Yeah.
Yeah, she's in
an old folks' place.
Abbeville.
HART:
Mrs. Hill, now,
this is a very
strange question,
but, um, do you remember
back in the winter
of '94 or '95,
did you get your house painted?
I did. Yes, I did.
A nice green.
Don't remember what
they call it anymore.
Do you happen to remember
who it was that
painted your house?
Well, yes.
I don't remember the name,
but they were nice men.
They worked for our parish.
Yard work,
house-painting.
My church, they got a discount.
- Good work for fair pay back then.
- Mmm.
Do you remember, by any chance,
names or just any
other details?
Um...
I remember they charged $250
for the whole house exterior.
- Hmm.
- And one of the men--
the younger one-- he had
scarring all along
the bottom of his face.
Mm-hmm.
COHLE: Miss Lilly, back then,
did you or your husband work?
My husband, Butch,
he's always worked.
He was offshore
for City Services.
Did he pay his taxes?
Always. Heh!
A lot of good it did him.
HART:
Thank you so much.
- You've been really helpful.
LILLY: - Thank you.
HART: There you go.
Husband took the write-off.
December '94.
$265 paid by Butch Hill
- to Childress and Son Maintenance.
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Yes, yes.
Here we go.
Business license first issued
to Billy Childress, 1978.
Same name as that--
- Sheriff.
- Yeah.
Uh... OK.
Business license not renewed
since 2004.
OK.
Name comes up a lot
in public records.
Looks like they had
a lot of parish contracts.
Public, state property,
landscape, yeah.
That's what I want. I want
to know where he was.
OK.
[Types]
All over the coast, OK?
It looks like
they did maintenance
for a lot of schools,
playgrounds,
cemeteries--
Run a background on Billy Childress.
Find his son.
OK.
[Types]
Here we go.
William Lee Childress,
born to Lizbeth Childress,
1944, Erath.
No son showing.
Address-- DMV,
old license--
Highway 27 South.
[Heavy breathing]
[Betty moaning]
[Dog barking]
[Betty and Childress grunting]
CHILDRESS:
Get out of here! Go on!
BETTY: Oh! Oh!
Can you smell
the flowers, Miss Billie?
COHLE: One to the feds,
one to State CID,
one to State Attorney, one
to US Attorney.
Two to national papers,
two to local papers, two
to national channels.
It's the whole story,
near as we got it.
There's a copy
of the tape in each one,
the case files,
our depositions--
everything we got.
Now, 24 hours passes
and I don't stop you,
mail 'em all out.
Then lay low a while.
Ah.
HART: So how's that case
going, uh, Lake Charles?
None of your fucking business.
Your old partner
give you anything yet?
None of your fucking business.
Why'd you call me?
Why not my partner?
You, I can read.
Him, I can't.
And why would you
need to do that?
What have you two been doing?
All those late nights. Your
offices the last month.
Christ, and that's it?
That's all you got?
Ain't for you to know,
but I know you been pulling case
files all over south Louisiana.
It's about
Cohle's theory, way back?
He's fucking with you.
He's a manipulator, sociopath.
You know this.
[Sighs]
Do you know about Sam Tuttle,
all the branches of the family?
The, uh, marsh cult,
devil worship,
child sacrifices?
You sound like Cohle.
It points in every
direction but him, huh?
- Man, I knew you were gonna say that.
- You know something,
- you're obstructing.
- We don't know,
but we're following up an idea.
May be nothing,
but--
ahem-- time comes,
we-- we know
we got something,
you get a call, you gonna
do the right thing?
You speak in riddles
to me, white man.
You sound like Cohle, again.
We get something,
do you want the call
or you want it to go
to someone else?
Give it to me.
Just make sure
you come runnin'.
♪
That taste.
[Sighs]
What?
Aluminum,
ash.
I've tasted it before.
You still see things, ever?
It never stops, not really.
What happened to my head, it's
not something that gets better.
Uh, this is it.
♪
Call Papania.
Shit.
Can't get a signal.
I'm gonna ask to use the phone.
You know what?
I'll go ask.
Marty.
This is the place.
[Door creaks]
[Knock on door]
[Heavy breathing]
[Dog barking inside]
Hello.
BETTY: Aw, damn it!
Oh, pardon me, ma'am.
Uh, we're
professional surveyors
and got lost on these back roads
like a couple of greenhorns.
Uh, cell phone is
getting no service.
Is there any way
that I could, uh,
use your phone?
- We don't have no phone, Mister.
- Oh.
- That's too bad.
- Yeah.
No, I said!
Stop it over there
or I kick you!
HART: Could I trouble you
for a glass of water?
[Heavy breathing]
[Dog continues barking]
BETTY: The water around
here is not real good.
Sit, I said! Stop it!
I'm gonna kick you!
Where's Billy Childress?
- Old Bill?
- Yeah.
He's in this house, Mister.
HART: Oh, th-this isn't his?
[Betty giggles]
Well, who-- who do you,
uh, who do you live here with?
I think you should go now.
Mm-hmm, uh, hey,
where is he?
All around us,
before you were born...
- [Barking]
- and after you die.
No! No!
Get out of my house, Mister!
[Dog barking]
[Dog yelps]
Marty, clear the house!
[Panting]
Don't move!
On your knees, now!
On your knees! Now!
No.
[Whispers]
Fuck.
♪
[Betty giggling]
[Whispers]
Ohh.
[Betty giggling]
Everybody has a phone.
Where's yours?
He's gonna come for you.
He's worse than anybody.
[Cocks gun]
No, you--
- Where's your fuckin' phone?!
- [Crying] No!
♪
[Distantly]
Come with me, little man.
Come in here with me.
[Flies buzzing]
Rust?
COHLE: Yeah!
- Rust!
- Here!
CHILDRESS: Come on inside,
little priest.
To your right, little priest.
Take the bride's path.
CHILDRESS: This is Carcosa.
You know what they did to me?
Hmm?
What I will do to all
the sons and daughters of man.
You blessed Reggie...
Dewall.
Acolytes.
Witnesses to my journey.
Lovers.
I am not ashamed.
Come die with me,
little priest.
[Exhales sharply]
Rust?
Rust!
[Footsteps]
[Rustling sound]
[Rumbling]
Now, take off your mask.
[Groaning]
[Cohle groaning in the distance]
[Gunshot]
[Grunts]
Rust.
[Cohle groans]
Aah!
Oh, fuck.
Ah, he cut me
pretty good, Marty.
No, Rust.
It ain't bad.
[Sirens approaching]
Oh.
[Police radio chatter]
- Get me a forward team in the house.
- Yes, sir.
- Get me a second team on that back house.
- Going around back.
GILBOUGH: Deputy,
light up those woods.
[Flare hissing]
Here!
[Flare pops]
Here! We're here!
Hey!
HART: That's the last thing
I remember.
I was on the ground.
Sirens.
Saying my friend's name.
[Monitor beeping steadily]
GILBOUGH:
The girl's a nut.
She talked some, but...
This group of guys,
pedophiles in Sulphur.
PAPANIA: Voodoo worship.
Man Cohle shot dead was
the old man's son.
No records.
Girl was at least
a half-sister.
- DNA comparison--
HART: - Stop.
Really, man. Stop.
I don't want to hear it.
Well, we're still
cataloguing everything,
but knife casts came
back from that shed.
One of them matched our
Lake Charles case,
another matched
Dora Lange's wounds.
Had his prints.
HART: Hmm.
Look, man, we owe
you on this collar.
How's Rust?
Hasn't woke up.
Been in a coma since surgery.
[Footsteps approach]
They came by,
you first got here.
MAGGIE:
Thank you, Ted. No.
GILBOUGH: Ma'am.
Hi.
It's so good to see y'all.
I... I didn't expect you.
AUDREY:
How are you?
Oh, good.
I'm fine.
Yeah, I-- I'll be fine.
I mean... I-- I am...
fine.
[Sobs]
FEMALE NEWS ANCHOR:
And now the latest news update
in the case of alleged
Louisiana serial murderer
Errol William Childress.
It's a story that first broke
nationwide two weeks ago,
when two former
police officers,
now private detectives,
released information
to a number of news
and law enforcement agencies.
Our last update confirmed
physical evidence
at the suspect's home
proved connections
to dozens of missing persons.
In the meantime, the State
Attorney General and the FBI
have discredited rumors
that the accused was in some way
related to the family of
Louisiana Senator Edwin Tuttle.
[TV clicks off]
♪
[Monitor beeping steadily]
[Slurping loudly]
What are you doing here?
Nothin'. Nurse said
I could come in.
Are you watching me sleep?
Well, you know what?
I just got here.
I was gonna leave,
but then you woke up.
Jesus, what's your
fuckin' problem?
Nothing.
What's your problem?
Not a care in the world.
[Slurps]
[Sighs]
I saw him, Marty.
He was mowing that schoolyard
on Pelican Island in '95.
I couldn't tell how tall he was
'cause he was sittin'
and his face was--
it was dirty,
but I... I saw him.
That's what's bugging you?
Tuttles, fucking men
in the video.
We didn't get 'em all.
Yeah, and we ain't
gonna get 'em all.
That ain't what kind of world
it is, but we got ours.
I'm not supposed to be here.
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
Well...
I'll come back by
tomorrow, buddy.
Why?
Don't ever change, man.
♪
HART: Ahem.
Doc said, uh,
probably get out in a few days.
I'll make sure you got
a ride, place to stay.
Yeah, I'll figure it out.
Well, it's already
been figured out.
Oh, hey.
I brought you something.
[Distant siren]
Are we getting engaged?
If we were getting engaged,
I'd have got a nicer ribbon.
- [Chuckles]
- You remembered.
Yeah.
Ah, let's get out from
under this roof, huh?
Good idea.
Hey, I can push two
goddamn wheels on my own.
Yeah, I ought to let you and rip out
your fuckin' stitches. Stop it.
Feeling better?
Your head, I mean.
Ah, I shouldn't even
fuckin' be here, Marty.
I believe "no shit" is
the proper response
to that observation.
Nah, I don't mean like that.
It's something else.
Well, so...
talk to me, Rust.
[Sighs]
There was a moment--
I know when I was
under in the dark
that something...
whatever I'd been reduced to,
you know, not even
consciousness.
It was a vague awareness
in the dark,
and I could--
I could feel my definitions
fading.
And beneath that...
darkness, there was another kind.
It was-- it was deeper,
warm, you know,
like a substance.
I could feel, man,
and I knew, I knew my daughter
waited for me there.
So clear.
I could feel her.
[Voice trembling]
I could feel...
I could feel a piece
of my-- my pop, too.
It was like I was
a part of everything
that I ever loved,
and we were all...
the 3 of us, just--
just fadin' out.
And all I had to do
was let go...
and I did.
I said, "Darkness,
yeah, yeah."
And I disappeared.
But I could--
I could still feel
her love there,
even more than before.
Nothing...
There was nothing
but that love.
[Sobbing]
Then I woke up.
Hey, uh...
[Sobbing]
Didn't, uh...
didn't you tell me
one time at dinner
once, maybe,
about you used to...
you used to make up
stories about the stars?
[Sniffles]
Yeah, that was--
that was, um,
in A-Alaska,
under the-- under
the night skies.
Yeah, you used to lay
there and look up,
yeah, at the stars?
Yeah, and you remember I...
I never watched
a TV till I was 17,
so there wasn't much
to fuckin' do out there
besides walk around
and explore and--
And...
and look up at the stars
and make up stories.
Like what?
[Sighs] I tell you, Marty,
I've been up in that room
looking out those windows every
night here and just thinking...
It's just one story.
The oldest.
What's that?
Light versus dark.
Well,
I know we ain't
in Alaska, but...
appears to me that the dark
has a lot more territory.
Yeah.
You're right about that.
[Grunts]
Hey, listen, hey.
Yeah, what?
Why don't you point me in the
direction of the car, man?
I've spent enough of my
fuckin' life in hospitals.
Jesus. Oh.
You know what?
I'd protest,
but it occurs to me
that you're unkillable.
You want to go back,
get clothes or anything?
No, anything I left back
there, I don't need.
You know, you're looking at it wrong,
the... sky thing.
How is that?
Well, once,
there was only dark.
If you ask me,
the light's winning.
[Hart chuckles]
♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com