Previously on Veronica Mars:
It's been a year since my best
friend, Lilly Kane, was murdered.
Everyone remembers reading
about the bungling local sheriff.
That bungling sheriff was my dad.
Duncan Kane. He used to be my boyfriend.
Then one day, with no
warning, he ended things.
What do you think Mom was doing at
the Camelot Motel with Jake Kane?
I told you to stay away from that case.
Do you know what your joke cost me?
- You, say you're sorry.
- I don't want his apology.
- Forty-four Adam.
- Forty-four Adam, affirmative.
I look back over the past week and wonder
if things could've turned out differently.
If I hadn't met the girl, if I hadn't
initiated the case, if I hadn't interfered...
would tonight be just another dull,
quiet night in our apartment complex?
Miss, out of the way.
Is it my fault a horrible crime
played out its final chapter here...
or was what happened inevitable?
Sync by vNaru
- Hey, Rocky.
- Hey, Veronica.
- Hi, neighbor.
- Oh, hey, Veronica.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, fine.
Oh, your Snow Patrol CD. I'll get it back
to you, I swear. I've just been so into it.
I know. I can hear it through the ceiling.
Oh, God, you can hear us
fighting, can't you? I'm sorry.
- What was the fight about?
- Oh, it was nothing.
You're right, it's not my business.
No.
It's just stupid. I...
My journal's missing. I think he took it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
He somehow got it into his head
that I have a thing for my boss.
Suddenly, the journal disappears.
It's sort of my diary/sketchbook.
But it's got some way
personal stuff in there.
I hope it turns up.
Hey, Killer.
- Do you mind if I...?
- No, go ahead. He lives for the attention.
You are so lucky he's your dog.
I would immediately put him
in a little sailor's outfit.
Veronica, can I ask you a favor?
I have a doctor's
appointment Tuesday morning.
I'm getting some test results.
- Do you need a lift?
- And maybe some handholding.
Of course.
Mr. Echolls, I was wondering
if I could have a word.
"Anthropomorphic. " All yours, big guy.
Your father has generously offered
to donate a pair of boots...
for our school fundraising auction.
Not the ones made for walking?
God, I love those boots.
The pair he wore in Hair Trigger.
We're hoping we'll be able to
pay for our new scoreboard...
with what we'll make off of them. I
haven't been able to reach your father.
I was hoping you could remind him.
I'll have my assistant call his assistant.
Let's see, Carrie Ann Leski
went on to be Miss California.
Of course, then she went
on to gain 40 pounds.
Oh, and Jake Kane. Big computer
mogul, and I sat next to him in typing.
Surprisingly slow, typing-wise.
He's a brilliant man.
Ronald Toolen, of Toolen Motors.
Are you married? Because
I hear he's separated now.
Veronica. Just the girl I was looking
for. I'd like you to meet Evelyn Bugby.
Aren't you cute?
Evelyn is from the alumni
association. She can use help...
putting together a photo
display for a class reunion.
If only I had the spare time.
Bob Patton, is that you?
Class of '79.
Think of all the bad clothes you can
mock: Velour shirts, platform shoes.
- Okay, I'll do it.
- Great.
Your first assignment is to scan and
print all of the photos Mrs. Bugby tabbed.
And please keep her away from me.
Very nice. Oh, excuse me, I have to go
talk to her for a second. Did you say...?
And somewhere, amidst the Most Likely
to Succeed and Class Sweetheart...
my mom, Lianne Reynolds, Most Likely
to Disappear off the Face of the Earth.
They teach you manners in ESL?
If I was gonna cheat, don't you
think I'd pick somebody smart?
If you was gonna.
Alas...
you both get zeros.
No talking during tests.
Guess Mrs. Daniels ain't
giving it up at home, huh?
The glow of your father's wealth
and celebrity may be enough...
to sustain you through high school...
but do you know what it will
get you in the real world?
Please say "high school English teacher."
Mr. Navarro.
I wonder if you'll find Mr. Echolls
so amusing 10 years from now...
when you're pumping his gas.
See me after class, both of you. I'll
tell you where to report for detention.
You know what I love?
I love that I get a zero for talking when
you were the one who was talking to me.
You get detention for dissing the
teacher in front of everybody...
and I get detention for laughing.
- Let me ask you something, man.
- Jesus, is this detention or hell?
How do you people not
make yourselves sick?
I mean, it's like you walk
on water in this school.
For what? It's nothing that you do.
All that matters is
who your parents are...
and the zip code your mom shot you out in.
But if I donate to the United
Latino Pain-in-the-Ass Fund...
will you shut the hell up?
You like playing with yourself?
Or you wanna make things interesting?
What did you have in mind?
You're almost as bad
an actor as your father.
You know that you don't need a
diploma to steal hubcaps, right?
I mean, why do you even show up here?
Promised my grandmother.
I don't break my promises.
And I mean this:
Is this Reno or detention?
Would you believe the best of both?
- Oh, come on, man.
- What the hell?
Dude, we're playing a game here.
This is punishment,
gentlemen, not party time.
Well, that would explain the
absence of balloon animals.
The two of you may not have
learned respect in the home...
but you are going to learn it here.
And you now have a full week of
detention for me to teach you...
without luxury time for playing cards.
- Why did you tell her?
- I assumed she knew. She's your mother.
I didn't want her to know about the baby.
I can't believe you told her where I was.
- You're just being hormonal.
- Shut up!
Go spend the night with Joanna!
Maybe then she'll stop calling here!
Get over it, Sarah! Grow up!
- Did you hear something last night?
- What kind of something?
Like a loud thump from upstairs.
Well, no. But you know me, I can
sleep through an earthquake. Why?
I don't know. It sounded like a
falling body. It really freaked me out.
- A falling body?
- Yes, a falling body.
Would you describe the
sound as Hitchcockian?
I'm glad you're able
to entertain yourself.
Oh, sweetie, don't sell yourself short.
I find you completely entertaining.
You're dressed awfully early.
I'm taking Sarah to the
doctor before school.
- Well, that's mighty neighborly of you.
- I'll see you back at the ranch, partner.
Sarah?
Sarah, it's Veronica again.
Give me a call when you get this.
I'm just getting a little worried.
The people that say high school
years are the best years...
are usually on the yearbook staff.
I just pray that bake sales and pep
rallies aren't as good as it gets...
and that the prom isn't the most magical night
of my life, like it was for this golden...
Oh, my God.
- So how's life with the movie star's kid.
- Oh, he makes juvie hall seem like vacation.
Yeah? You should tell him you spend
some quiet time with Lilly Kane...
his precious girlfriend.
I'd love to see the look on his face when he
finds out you tapped that fine, white ass.
You shut your mouth with that, man.
You don't know what you're talking about.
And it wasn't like that, all right?
What? What'd I say?
Hey, what's up?
- I've got a little Neptune High trivia for you.
- Yeah?
Did you know that your dad and my
mom were king and queen of the prom?
Which, I guess, means they were,
like, a couple or something.
Did you know about that?
No.
It's weird, huh?
The boy does have a gift for evasiveness.
Last year, he broke up with me
without so much as an "it's over."
What's going on?
What's going on is I had lip gloss on
my teeth for, like, all of first period.
Why is Duncan pretending
I no longer exist?
Because he's a freak. I don't know.
I'm his sister, not his shrink.
It's like he's broken up with me, but
hasn't gotten around to telling me yet.
He has been weird the past few days.
Maybe his right hand finally said no.
Can you not see I'm
really upset about this?
God, Veronica, please,
will you stop, okay?
He's going through, like,
a phase or something.
You two are meant for each
other. He's not that stupid.
- Fine, I'll talk to him.
- Thank you.
You know, I don't know what
you people would do without me.
Is this a joke?
No, Mr. Echolls, this is detention.
I meant the car.
Oh, my God.
It's not yours, is it?
Seriously, I don't think it's school
policy to have students do chores.
Seriously, would you like to hear the
school's policy on gambling, Mr. Echolls?
It's considerably detailed.
Hi, I'm looking for Sarah.
Me too. She didn't show up today.
I'm her neighbor. She's been missing since
this morning. I'm getting really worried.
- You might check with her boyfriend, Andre.
- Do you know him?
I feel like I do. She
talks about him ad nauseam.
"He's such a brilliant artist. " "He's
so down-to-earth. " "He has magic hands."
I'm sensing you don't like him very much.
They fight all the time.
And I know for a fact
the guy's got a temper.
A couple weeks ago, she
spent the night at my place.
It was storming out, she didn't wanna
drive. Andre absolutely flipped out.
They fought on the
phone like Sid and Nancy.
Thanks for the info.
This isn't like her. She hasn't missed
a day of work since she started here.
Do you know where I can find Andre?
Hello?
- What are you doing here?
- Have you seen Sarah?
Not since this morning. Why?
I was supposed to take her to the doctor
this morning, but she wasn't around.
- She didn't show up for work either.
- She'll turn up.
You're not concerned?
This is what she does. When things
get a little rough, she runs.
What was the fight about?
I told her I found her friends annoying.
Something about you telling
Sarah's mom she was pregnant.
Well, if you know the
answer, why ask the question?
Sarah's mom didn't know she was pregnant?
They hadn't spoken since Sarah left
Ohio. I told her that Sarah was pregnant.
She said she wanted to come
be with her. Sarah freaked.
- Freaked and ran off.
- Yeah.
So get these dark
fantasies out of your head.
She'll come back as soon as she's
processed it all. It's her way.
I heard a noise come from
your apartment last night.
- A loud thump.
- Thump.
Must've been when I cracked
her head with a candlestick...
and she crumpled to the ground. No, wait.
- That was Professor Plum in the study.
- I am seriously worried.
You are seriously
paranoid, is what you are.
I didn't hear a thump.
Maybe I slept through it.
Look, why don't you go back
to playing field hockey...
or whatever it is you usually do
after school. I can handle this.
Actually, what I usually do after school
is work at my dad's detective agency.
You remember, he used to be sheriff.
He still has a ton of
contacts in law enforcement.
Well,
la-di-da.
Who's the girl?
She's the head of our
neighborhood-watch program.
I wasn't aware this
was clothing-optional.
Let me know when you're
ready for me, Picasso.
See you, neighbor. Thanks for dropping by.
Dogs. Nature's psychic detectives.
They know it in their bones
when something is wrong.
Now I've got the corroboration I need.
Hey, Killer.
Killer?
Killer.
Killer, where are you, bud?
Oh, hi.
What the hell are you
doing in my apartment?
I couldn't study. The little guy was
barking his head off. I tried the door...
it was unlocked. So I
came in and checked on him.
I never leave my door unlocked.
Oh, well, then Sarah must have
done it. That's possible, right?
Possible? Yeah, that's possible.
Look, I don't know who you think you are,
but you need to stay out of my business.
- Am I being clear?
- Crystal.
Nice chatting with you.
Well, we definitely don't need this one.
I have no idea who this
is, so, what does that say?
Oh, perfect. We have
to have Doris Landers.
She was Class Sweetheart, in more
ways than one. But a very nice girl.
- What about Lianne Reynolds?
- Who?
She's my mom.
Oh, my God. Of course, look at you.
I thought you looked familiar.
You look just like her. How is she?
I love this picture of her.
Oh, she was just gorgeous. And
Jake. They were a beautiful couple.
- So they were a couple?
- No, they were the couple.
Very lovey-dovey. Practically
connected at the mouth in the hallway.
Everyone thought they'd get married.
But everything worked out for the best.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be here, right?
Right.
They were something, though,
like a couple in a movie.
Aaron Stellman. I think he went to jail.
It's just high school. What
happens here doesn't mean anything.
I was part of a perfect couple.
It was part of my perfect life.
It's amazing how fleeting
perfection can be.
Yesterday, you said we
were made for each other.
I don't... I really... I don't
wanna be in the middle of this.
What is "this"?
- I think maybe you should just move on.
- What?
I can think of a half-dozen guys...
that would be a better
match for you than Duncan.
What did he say? Did I do something?
No, it's not you. It's just... He
needs some time alone for a while.
Would you stop walking?
What is so horrible
that you can't tell me?
Can you trust me?
It's for the best, Veronica.
I know that it doesn't seem
like it right now, but it is.
You deserve better.
Alphabetized by author, and then by title.
For example, Shakespeare would come
after Poe, and before Wordsworth.
And then within Shakespeare,
Macbeth after Hamlet.
- Should I draw a diagram?
- Please. That would be helpful.
If you get this wrong, I'll
simply have you do it again.
Come on, amigo. Let's get to it, huh?
Heads up. My bad.
You obviously have no
appreciation of literature.
Would that it were Mr. Daniels' head.
I was thinking more like that
scene in Casino, with the Vise-Grip.
See, I'm more of a purist. You know,
less blood, more emotional distress.
I'd rather see him locked in a room,
padded, crapping himself in the corner.
You know, he's an English teacher,
he'd appreciate the poetic justice.
I think I've got your poetic justice.
- Meaning?
- Meaning I've got a plan.
Tick, tick, losing interest.
If I thought you had the cojones
to pull it off, I'd tell you. But...
Never underestimate
the size of my cojones.
Where the...?
- You know how to get back to your hotel?
- Yeah.
I have one more thing.
Where do you think she is?
No idea.
Look, I have your number at the
hotel, so if I hear anything...
I'll give you a call.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
Excuse me. Are you Sarah's mother?
Yes. I'm Emily, and this
is her stepfather, Randall.
My father's a private detective, and he's
really good at finding missing people.
I can give you his card.
- Come on, check it out.
- Thanks again for the ride, Lisa.
Let me know if you need
me to take you home.
Oh, jeez, what's the problem now?
All right, people, break it up. Break
it up. What's the big attraction?
Son of a...
Get back to class.
Come on, move it! Go to class!
Go to class, people!
Mr. Navarro.
Interesting artwork you left
at the flagpole this morning.
Artwork? Looks to me like Mr. Daniels
has a little drinking-and-driving problem.
Spare me your indignation,
Mr. Navarro. We have a witness.
Yeah, sure you do.
The only thing that's gonna make this easy
on you is if you tell us who helped you.
All right.
You guys wanna know who helped me?
Ask your witness.
You believe this?
- Tell us who helped you!
- Tom.
Easy.
I've called your grandmother.
She's been informed that, as of today,
you are expelled from Neptune High School.
- You are no longer a student here.
- And you had so much potential.
Okay, then, a security guard will
escort you to clean out your locker.
Wait.
Does this mean I can't try
out for the soccer team?
I didn't know they expelled
people at our school.
Well, not our people.
- They expelled him?
- Security escorted him off the grounds.
I was in the office changing my schedule.
You could hear Daniels just blowing a fuse.
You know, "Tell us who helped
you! Tell us who helped you!"
If he starts selling oranges in front
of my house, I'm gonna be pissed.
She was a very sweet girl.
Lighthearted. An angel.
And then, around her
senior year, I saw a change.
She was secretive...
always picking fights with me.
Thank you.
I think she was angry because I
remarried after her father died.
I don't know, she had a knack for
attracting troubled, young men.
Come on, Emily, you make
her sound worse than she was.
She was a teenager. They have moods.
We shouldn't kid ourselves, Randall.
Then one day, last year, she took off.
Didn't finish high school.
Never even said goodbye.
Emily, she's only been
gone a couple of days.
We'll find her. That's why we're here.
I'll do my best.
So here's what I'm thinking:
The boyfriend, Andre, he knows something.
If we lean on him, put
the fear of God in him...
Veronica, I'm handling
this case from here on out.
I brought them here so
you could be involved.
- And I'm handling this case without you.
- No. Dad, she's my friend.
No, she's a girl you talked to in
the laundry room from time to time.
Look, sweetie, young, attractive
girls who take up with troubled men...
disappear without warning...
I've handled a hundred of these cases
in my life, and they often end badly.
Prepare yourself.
I convinced Dad to let me keep working
on the case if I stayed away from Andre.
Hi. This is Sarah Williams.
I'm just wondering if I can get
my test results over the phone.
Right, the DNA test. Could you
explain to me what that means?
Sarah's baby, it wasn't Andre's.
- You got a sec?
- Mr. Echolls. What can I do for you?
Man, I tell you, Mr.
Clemmons, I am pissed off.
I need for you to use appropriate
language in here, Mr. Echolls.
Now, what's got under your skin?
It's that Weevil kid.
- He is no longer a student here.
- Yeah, I know.
But the problem is, he's
getting all the credit...
for sticking Mr. Daniels'
car on the flagpole.
Now, all of a sudden, he's,
like, the biggest badass in...
Rad dude here at Neptune.
People are gonna be talking
about that punking for years.
- I don't think I understand.
- I mean, I want my share of the credit.
You're confessing to helping Eli Navarro?
You can't just get away
with this, young man.
Yeah, I didn't think I could.
So, what kind of punishment
are we talking about?
I'm not really
understanding your question.
Well, if Andre's not the baby's
father, do you know who is?
It's not mine, if that's
what you're suggesting.
No, I'm not, but you
work with her every day.
- You might have picked up something.
- I hate to think this...
but maybe the guy that raped
her is the baby's father.
- She was raped?
- Yeah.
It's one of the reasons that she left
her hometown and followed Andre here.
- She told you that?
- Yeah.
Like you said, we spend
a lot of time together.
- Did she say who it was?
- Never.
I should get back to work. But if I think of
anything else, I'll be sure to give you a call.
You stole the diary.
- What?
- How did that work?
She was sleeping at your house that
stormy night, and there it was...
just poking out of her bag. You had to
find out if she had a thing for you too.
You realize you're paranoid.
I do. Everyone reminds me.
But it doesn't mean I'm not right. I want
the journal. It's gonna help me find her.
I told you, I don't have it.
- Looks like we're in a bit of a standstill.
- Looks that way.
Excuse me.
Hey. It's Veronica. Hear you
have some free time on your hands.
You wanna do me a little favor?
- We heard there was a sale.
- Yeah.
Everything's on clearance.
- What do you guys want?
- I don't know.
Sometimes girls get put
off by this old jacket.
Do you think something in suede
might make me seem more accessible?
Could you...? Could
you please not do that?
Yo, W, it looks like the
new Prada line came in.
Guys.
Remember, no white after Labor Day.
Nathan, did you happen
to find that journal?
What the hell?
- You going somewhere?
- What's it to you?
Strange time to take a trip,
with your girlfriend missing.
- And how is this your business?
- I was hired by her parents to find her.
Something tells me they wouldn't be keen
on the idea of you skipping town right now.
Well, that's just it, pal, I'm not skipping
town. I'm just dropping off a friend.
- Track number three. All aboard.
Can I go? They're boarding now.
I appreciate you humoring
me. Go catch your train.
- I'll be right here waiting for you.
- Well, I'll be right back.
I'd like to take this opportunity to remind
you both that you're getting off easy.
This will go on your permanent
record, but you're fortunate...
that you're not being
suspended or expelled.
Does it go on my permanent
record that I was un-expelled?
Don't push your luck, Eli.
I'll take this one.
- Hey, man, what are you doing?
- Hey, what the hell is that?
- It's my arm, dog.
- Why do you have Lilly's name on your arm?
- You really wanna know?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I really wanna know!
Lilly's my little sister's name, man.
That okay with you?
Put your hands on me again,
you'll lose one of them.
Yeah, I think I just peed myself.
If you keep a diary, you have
to consider the possibility...
that someone could find it and be
privy to your every intimate secret.
At least, that's what I told myself as
I pored through Sarah's private thoughts.
There were no details of the
sexual assault, only its aftermath.
Sarah didn't handle it well. She
felt she couldn't talk to her mother.
She couldn't relate to her
friends. She ran away from home...
and started sleeping in her car.
Bingo.
The one bright spot was Andre.
She met him in an art class
and followed him to Neptune.
Sarah?
- You found me.
- Everyone's worried about you.
- Are my parents here?
- Yeah, they're back at the apartment.
I'm gonna miss all this.
- I found her.
- I know.
Word's out in the complex.
I'm very impressed.
- Think I've got a future in the biz?
- You've got a future as a highly paid...
Ivy League-educated
executive of some sort...
who never thinks about private
investigation again in her perfect life.
Now, let's do something normal
fathers and daughters do.
- Buy me a pony?
- I was thinking I'd watch TV...
and you'd rub my feet.
- Yeah, that's normal.
- Have you seen my keys?
- You're not leaving, are you?
No, Sarah, I'm not the
one who's always running.
Look, I spent the past two hours
making small talk with your parents.
- They didn't come 2000 miles to see me.
- I told you, I don't wanna deal with them.
Yeah, well, you're gonna have
to deal with them sometime.
- You're right.
- I'm gonna take Killer for a walk.
- I'll be right back. I love you.
- I love you too.
Come here, buddy. Come on.
I have to say, I still
really don't trust Andre.
I don't know.
I mean, he knows about the DNA
test, that the baby's not his.
And he said it didn't matter.
Which, in itself, is
all sorts of freakish.
Or it's a testament to
how much he loves her.
A man's gotta be pretty
committed to a woman...
to agree to raise another man's child.
Do you know who the real father is?
Hello? Earth to Mars.
What?
- Where did you go just now?
- Nowhere. What did you just ask me?
Who the father is.
Oh, Sarah.
What's wrong?
Mom, there's something you should know.
- Why didn't you tell me she was raped?
- I just found out.
- He raped me! He raped me!
- These are lies! You are a liar!
- Why are you trying to hurt me?
- Shut up and listen to me for once!
Your husband raped me!
Just stay here.
- No, I'm done keeping quiet.
- That's enough.
- Sarah.
- You're not gonna hurt me again.
- Oh, no.
- Open up!
Randall! No!
I'm so sorry!
- How is she?
- She's resting.
She's gonna be okay.
So I guess I'm grounded.
I'm gonna let you slide on this one.
But can I let myself slide?
Sure, the real tragedy happened
long before I came along.
I just brought it to the surface.
But are some things better left buried?