[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[SIREN FADES AWAY]
[TAPE RECORDER REWINDING]
[OVER TAPE RECORDER]:
This is Detective Jack Mosley.
Shield number 227.
I guess this'll be
my last will and testament.
This is for Diane.
When this day is over,
they're gonna come and...
talk to you about this,
and they're gonna...
they're gonna tell you
what happened, Diane.
But what they tell you is not
really what happened here.
So I hope that you get this.
I was trying to do a good thing.
[LIVELY LATIN MUSIC PLAYS]
[MAN SINGING IN SPANISH]
Police! Get Down!
Everybody down!
Down! Down!
Go, go, go! Come on!
Clear!
Police! Get down!
Seal it off!
Agent Sinclair,
we're all secure.
All right, we're out of here.
[CAT MEOWS]
[GARBLED RADIO TRANSMISSION]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[LATIN MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MAN COUGHS]
[GROANS]
Couple of hours.
We got to move now.
Would you turn that thing off?
All right, who's downstairs
we don't need?
[HORNS HONK IN DISTANCE]
[EXHALES]
All yours. Good luck.
Hey, I hate to do
this to you, Jack,
but I need you
to sit on this
until uniforms
get here.
All right.
Just hang until
you're relieved.
All right.
Don't touch anything.
[HORN BEEPS OUTSIDE]
[QUIET, MELANCHOLY THEME PLAYS]
♪
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[LOCK BUZZES]
MAN:
Any word on the suspect, sir?
[INDISTINCT RADIO TRANSMISSION]
Anything for me?
Breath mint.
Sergeant Kenoble called.
Wants you to write up,
uh, this wire request.
Said to make sure
that you get the right dates
on 'em this time.
The particulars
are on your desk,
and he needs it
by tonight.
All right.
[MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
[LOCK BUZZES]
[EXHALES]
Hey, hey, Jack,
I forgot to tell you
the lieutenant's
looking for you.
He wants you to find him
right away.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Mosley.
Mosley!
Yeah?
Grace tell you to find me?
Yeah. Uh, just
a minute ago.
All right, I need a favor.
Got to get this guy
from lockup
and run him over
to Center Street.
The D.A. needs him ASAP--
he's got to be
in front of a grand jury
before 10:00.
Ah. I signed out.
You signed the sheet?
Well... not
technically, no,
but I mean,
I'm signed out...
Well, then
consider yourself on overtime.
Captain Dribble called me.
We need this thing done.
Don't you have some regular
mutt that takes care of this?
I got Keenan, but he's
still on the Verazano.
He's behind
some overturned truck.
[SIGHS]:
I'm tired.
I mean, look, normally, you
know me, I don't say no...
Yeah, I know
you've been working
all night, Jack, but...
I'm just tired.
who's the detective
and who's the lieutenant here?
I mean, Jack,
I got nobody else.
It's a nothing thing.
118 minutes to get
a little hemorrhoid 16 blocks.
I'll let you come in work
late tomorrow.
Yeah, yeah.
[LOW, OMINOUS THEME PLAYS]
♪
MOSLEY:
Edward Bunker.
Yeah, that's me, Officer,
Eddie Bunker,
right here, down here
in the last cell, right here.
Come back in an hour.
What do you mean,
come back in an hour?
He's supposed to wear
a suit when he leaves.
And?
It's not here yet.
Just get him out here,
all right?
They said he'd wear a suit.
BUNKER: No, yeah,
I'm-I'm supposed to get a suit.
It's a three-piece suit,
it's gray.
It's got, wait, yeah,
it's-it's, uh,
three buttons, it's gray,
it's got cuffs
on the pants.
They brought
the catalog down,
I picked it out
of the catalog.
I'm not supposed to leave
without it. Wait.
They said I'm not supposed
to leave without that suit.
You tell it to him. Come on.
No, I'm not supposed
to leave without that suit.
That's why they brought
my shoes in earlier.
Yeah, yeah. Come on, come on.
I'm not supposed to leave.
Yo, yo, you take
the old lady, right?
Yeah? You sure?
Yeah, the old lady goes
into the car,
otherwise she dies, man.
Oh, yeah, you think so?
Yeah, man.
If that's what
you wanna...
I don't know,
you got to figure out
the answer for yourself.
Hold...
Everybody just calm down.
Officer, I'm going
to court.
I'm supposed to have a suit.
Hey, shut up.
I got to get...
Here's your property.
Hands behind
your back.
Hold on, I'm just...
I'm trying to get my...
Hands behind
your back.
I'm trying to get...
I don't have my... all my...
prop...
Wait one minute... Ow.
It's not right.
They promised me the suit.
Came on, picked out the catalog.
Wait, wait, my book!
I can't leave without my book.
My book's very important to me.
What book?
Why are we rushing
like this?
Let's go.
Not a good sign.
Hey.
What's the damn answer?
Hey!
Shut up!
I hate police, man.
MAN:
Half a tank.
You know, you could've had
a little more patience
with the suit, man.
Probably don't mean
nothing to you.
You probably have
a bunch of suits.
Whole different
thing to me.
[ENGINE STARTS]
♪
These cars don't
never change, huh?
Traditional cruisers.
The same retarded hump
in the middle.
Smell... the same way.
Like Lysol and vomit.
[HONKING HORN]
Hope nobody vomited
back here.
They probably did.
Hey, man,
let me ask you something.
I'm trying
to figure this out. Uh...
You're driving along
in a hurricane, right?
There's three people
at the bus stop.
You know,
one is a old lady.
She's sick,
she about to die.
The second one
is your best friend.
He saved your life.
Right?
And the third is
the girl of your dreams.
Right? But check it out.
You only got space
in the car for one person.
[HONKING HORN]
Right? Who do you take?
You know, I-I mean,
it's a ancient riddle
that's supposed to tell
what type of person you are,
like where you at in your life.
It's a hypothetical
question, man, damn.
It is a hypothetical...
[MUFFLED]:
Good. Fine, good.
I guess that's my answer.
♪
[WHISTLE BLOWS IN DISTANCE]
Hey, man, why don't you
get on the loudspeaker.
Put the-the-the Hawaii five-oh
light on or something.
Use your police power.
Put on a little siren.
Make-make 'em move,
make a hole.
You see what I'm saying,
make a hole, make a hole.
[CHUCKLES]
Gonna make a hole.
[HORNS HONKING]
BUNKER:
Signs.
Everywhere, signs, signs, signs.
All over, man.
I-I used to not even see
nothing like that, man,
and then...
I start seeing 'em.
You know, I start
looking for 'em,
and everything just started
falling in place.
It'll be all right,
where I'm supposed to be.
I-I ain't got my suit, but...
once I give my testimony,
they drop my charges, I'm free.
It's making sense to me.
I believe in that.
Being in the right place, being
where you're supposed to be.
You believe in that?
I believe life's too long,
and guys like you
make it even longer.
Life's too long?
Man.
That's some cold shit, man.
I never heard nobody
say no shit like that.
Usually you hear
about people trying
to make their life longer,
you know?
Trying to stay alive
a little longer.
[HONKS HORN]
You sound a little...
depressed or something--
you all right?
We're s...
we're stopping.
This ain't the courthouse, man.
What you doing?
Yo.
Yo, why are you stopping?
You gonna bust me out to court,
and now you... you stopping?
What are you... Hey!
Hey, man, hey, man,
listen, man,
I got a important appointment
[CAR ALARM CHIRPS]
as to my court date, man.
That shit ain't funny, man.
Come on, man.
It's not a game, man.
Yo!
Bullshit, man.
Hey! Hey!
Nah, man,
it ain't Miller time, man.
[OMINOUS THEME PLAYS]
WOMAN [ON RADIO]:
The weather will be clear
all morning,
but the rest of the day...
Sam. Hey, Angela.
The usual.
So we are looking
at a hot, humid day.
Looks like temperature
might reach
a hundred degrees,
so don't forget to...
Add a pack of these in there.
I knew this dude smelled funny.
I got the wrong dude, man.
SAM:
$17.50.
Hey, don't open it!
Mm.
Oh, this is...
8:11.
That's a good sign,
that's a good sign.
I'm on my way, I'll get there.
[KNOCKING]
Huh?
Want change?
Uh, you keep the change.
Keep the change.
All right, you have a good day.
Smile. Cheer...
I don't want the change.
Bye.
Nah, man, I can't do nothin'
for you, man, you understand?
Hey, you better
give me that change.
I-I'm gonna need that.
You see my situation
right here? No, no, no!
No, no! No!
[BOTTLE SHATTERS]
[CAR ALARM BLARING]
[ALARM SLOWS DOWN, DISTORTS,
BECOMES MUFFLED AND DISTANT]
[DISTORTED, DISTANT SCREAMS AND SHOUTS]
[DISTORTED, DISTANT CLANG]
[MUFFLED, DISTORTED GUNSHOT]
[MUFFLED DISTORTED SHOUTS]
[SOUND WHOOSHES BACK TO FULL VOLUME]
[SILENCED GUNSHOT]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Hey!
[HORN HONKS, GUNSHOT]
[HORN HONKS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[PANTING]
[SILENCED GUNSHOTS]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[GUNSHOT]
[BUS HORN HONKS]
[GASPING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
BUNKER [GASPING]:
Get me out!
Come on!
My book!
Go, go, go!
Left!
[GASPING]:
Oh! Oh!
Oh!
Wait!
In here! Come on!
Shit!
Oh, sh...
Hey!
Get out of here!
Now! Go on! Go!
Come on, let's go.
That way. Let's go. Go, go.
[LOUD BOOM]
[GASPING]
Right here. Here.
Let's go, let's go.
Dominic, you better
get your people
out of here right now.
Jesus, Jack,
what the hell's going on?
Everybody. You, too.
All right, all...
[SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE]
Let's go.
[MEN SPEAKING SPANISH]
Come on, come on, come on.
Que paso?
Hey, yo!
Come on,
get going!
Come on! Come on, move it!
Yeah, uh, this is
Detective Jack Mosley,
uh, shield number 227.
Uh, I am
10-13 at, uh...
Hold on a minute.
Dominic?
Yeah?
What's the
address here?
133 Mulberry.
At 133 Mulberry.
Mulberry Street.
[DOOR CLOSES]
All right.
[GROANS SOFTLY]
Is they comin'?
I don't know
why you stopped, man.
why you would do that, man.
[MOSLEY SETS BOTTLE ON BAR]
[SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE]
He says you're a nobody.
I ain't nobody.
Shut up.
You're a wino.
You need to stop drinking,
that's what you need
to stop doing.
Shut... up.
[CAR PULLS UP]
[CAR DOORS OPEN AND CLOSE]
Jack?
Frank.
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Well, we were
over on Mott
when the, uh,
call went out.
Heard it was you.
Got here as soon as we could.
Oh. Hi.
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Uh-huh? Uh-huh?
You having fun?
No.
No?
Oh, no.
You got to have fun.
What's up, Jack?
Hey, man. Hi.
You did a... you did
a really great, great job here.
You got yourself a bad guy.
Mm? Been a while, huh?
Yeah. We got the, uh,
we got the second shooter
half a block from here,
so... it's done.
Sure you're okay?
Yeah. I'm just...
getting my wind.
I was running.
Oh.
Why don't you... why don't you
let us take it from here?
Oh. Yeah.
You know? We'll get the kid
where he belongs,
and you don't have
to worry about a thing.
We'll get you home.
BUNKER:
Yes, please.
Please, please,
Officer, that's
a very good idea,
'cause honestly,
I don't think this dude
is doing too good.
I told him not to stop,
I asked him not to stop,
please not to stop--
he just had to stop,
and that's when
everything happened.
That's when the dude
came up to the window.
I have a very
important appointment
at...
Jack?
Hey, Shue.
FRANK:
Come on.
Why don't you take this.
Come on, man.
We'll get you out of here;
got a car waiting, all right?
Get some sleep.
Jack.
[QUIETLY]: The kid was gonna
testify against Jerry.
He saw Jerry doing
some business.
Now, we both know
that Jerry
has never been a standup guy
like you and me.
He'll roll over,
they indict him.
We can't have that.
[QUIETLY]:
No.
He's gonna hurt
a lot of us.
Come on.
See, this whole thing
caught us...
it caught us
completely unaware.
FRANK:
You know, it was supposed to be
Teach's nephew driving him.
But he got stuck
out there in traffic,
who knows where, and...
so your lieutenant,
he picked you.
[RACKS SLIDE ON GUN]
You know...
just the wrong time
and the wrong place
for you today.
All right?
Now, you know that...
I would never put you
in a position like this, right?
You know that, huh?
And I never figured you'd
cap one of those guys.
That's what I get for
hiring drug addicts.
MAN:
Grab the gun.
MAN: Come on.
Frank?
Huh?
Here we go.
All right, here we go.
Jack.
MAN:
Squeeze the trigger.
[GUNSHOT, CLATTERING]
All right, let
go of the gun.
Let go of the gun.
FRANK:
I figure it like this.
You, uh,
you popped the guys
trying to spring the kid.
The kid, well,
he got your gun.
And he takes you hostage.
So we came in
and saved the day.
He died. You lived.
Now, this could be
a good thing for you, Jack.
Get you back
where you belong.
Are you still with, um...
you still with, uh...
what's her name?
MAN:
What are you waiting for?
What's her name?
[GUNSHOT, GROANING]
[BUNKER GASPS]
[WHIMPERING]
[MAN GROANS IN PAIN]
Caroline.
It's Caroline.
This changes everything, Jack.
Over here.
Come on, Frank.
Kid... get up.
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS, MAN YELLS]
All right, Jack,
it's 8:25.
Stay there.
Listen to me, the jury's tenure
ends at 10:00, all right?
The kid gets there
one minute past,
all this...
...it doesn't matter.
All right?
And all you got to do
is look the other way.
All right?
We still got options here.
Okay? We just want the kid.
[WHISPERS]: Jack, Jack,
Jack, Jack, Jack,
just let me help you.
All right?
Back up.
FRANK:
Jack,
once you go out that door,
I can't help you.
Please back up, Frank.
Just back up.
[DOOR RATTLING LOUDLY]
[PANTING]
He shot a cop.
What the hell did you see?
Huh?
What'd you see?!
That cop back there,
I seen him around my way
holding a gun on this...
this little
Puerto Rican kid.
Come on. Let's go.
He said he'd kill his mother
if he testified.
Hey, what'd you
do that for?
We need that!
The shell in that gun
was over 20 years old.
What?
Lucky it went off at all.
They didn't tell you
Jerry Shue was a cop, right?
No, they ain't tell
me he was no cop.
They showed me a
picture, that was it.
They ain't say nothin'.
Well, congratulations.
'Cause you're about to testify
against one of New York's worst.
What?!
FRANK:
All right, fellas,
look, the clock's ticking.
We know he's got to be
at the courthouse by 10:00.
We know where he's going.
Okay? Mulvey,
you're coming with me.
You all know
where you're going?
Go.
We'll take the north side.
You got it. Let's go.
Captain.
Where are we, Frank?
We're putting descriptions
out over precinct channels.
No names, but
one's a cop.
It'd help to have
some eyes.
How long can you
sit on this?
Shot a cop?
You're the precinct
captain, Dan.
How long?
I don't know.
Hour. Maybe a little more.
Who's on this with you?
Well, my guys.
Ortiz and Maldonado
from the, uh, 66.
Twohy and Kaller from
the 111, couple others
you don't want
to know about.
[HORNS HONK IN DISTANCE]
The guy was your partner
for 20 years.
What the hell happened in there?
Is he drunk?
I don't know.
We woke him up.
Hopefully, he'll do
what he always does
and we can all
go back to work.
If he doesn't?
We got to quash
this thing,
before he gets
his legs back.
These are his streets.
This could get ugly...
for all of us
if that kid talks.
He can't talk.
He won't talk.
Look, man,
I-I appreciate
what you did for
me back there,
but I'm starting
to think that
you're not the dude
for this job.
I mean, you're out of...
you're out of breath,
you're hung over,
your leg is gonna
give out any second, man.
I got someplace I need to be
at 12:00, you understand?
In order to be there,
I need to be finished
at court by 10:00,
or I'm not gonna get
where I'm supposed to get.
I got to be finished
in court by 10:00.
You understand
what I'm saying?
All right, I understand.
You're not listening
to what I'm saying.
Wait, wait.
Come here.
[MOSLEY PANTING]
Hung over...
Bad leg...
No gun...
[INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO TRANSMISSION]
[HANDSET BEEPS]
Bobby.
Yeah?
You thinking
what I'm thinking?
Already there.
[RATTLING DOORKNOB]
[MOSLEY GRUNTS WITH EFFORT]
Oh, God.
[PANTING]
Come on, let's go.
Listen. Please,
stay put right here.
I'll be right back.
Come on, man, don't take long.
Man, we gotta go.
Hurry up.
Hey, where
your bathroom?
What?!
Your bathroom.
Where your bathroom at?
Down at the end
of the hall.
Yeah.
That's what you look like
when you smile, huh?
You was... probably
drinking there, too.
Yes, indeed.
Redhead.
Cute. That ain't bad.
Hey, hey, man. Come on, man.
Don't be stopping to get high
or nothing like that, man.
We gotta go.
Make sure you lift the seat up
before you go.
It's up already.
Maybe you left it
like that, huh?
[WATER RUNNING]
[INHALES AND EXHALES]
[SHELLS RATTLE]
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
[WHISPERS]:
Come on.
Hey, Jack.
Jack Mosley.
Why you do that?
Do what?
Shoot that cop.
Cops... they won't shoot
other cops.
Especially over nobody like me.
It's a long way to go
for a stranger, you know, um...
Um... thank you.
I never had nobody...
Aw, hell, man,
you know?
I don't rock with the police,
you know what I'm saying, Jack?
[COCKS GUN]
[QUIETLY]:
Finger off the trigger.
Here you come.
Y'all bail me out.
[GUN CLATTERS TO FLOOR]
BUNKER:
You want a vigilante...
Let's go.
BUNKER:
Whatever it is...
BOB:
Jack...
MOSLEY:
Put your arms around the pole.
I really don't know
what to think, Jack Mosley.
Here, cuff yourself.
What are you doing, Jack?
BUNKER: ...a little
strange, you know?
By any definition,
you see?
All right, kid. Good.
Huh, okay.
Okay.
Okay, okay...
Uh... okay.
Okay.
[PHONE BEEPING]
You should've done
what you always do, Jack.
[PHONE BEEPING]
Where's your phone?
It's on the left-hand side.
[BEEPING]
They know I'm here;
if I don't answer it...
Jack?
Let's go, kid. Come on.
[PHONE BEEPING]
[BEEPING]
Bob...
MOSLEY: Bob's a little
tied up right now, Frank.
All right, I'm impressed, Jack.
Did you shoot him, too?
Send someone
to check on Bobby.
[GRUNTS]
Jack, you're not up to this.
All right? It's going
to end bad for you.
Oh...
You lost the kid, didn't you?
Huh? He bailed on you.
Well, you know what?
That is the best thing
that could've happened to you.
So why don't you go home,
and forget about what happened,
and we'll take it from here.
Now, you're just looking
around for him, aren't you?
And you can't find him.
We're going to find him.
All right?
All right, Jack?
Now you can hang up.
[WHISPERS]:
Where are you, kid?
All right.
Now let's see
which way he went.
Did he go up?
Or did he go down?
In or out, Jackie?
Which way'd he go?
Let's see if he went down.
BUNKER: Excuse me, sir,
do you mind swipe...?
MAN:
Get a job!
Excuse me, ma'am, would you mind
swiping me in, please?
Ma'am? Ma'am, would you mind
I have a very important
appointment I have to...
Excuse me, ma'am,
would you...
WOMAN:
No, I can't help you.
Would you mind... somebody mind
swiping me in, please?
I'm trying to get
to an important... appointment.
Somebody help...
somebody help me.
Somebody help me.
OFFICER:
Hey.
Huh?
Come here.
Come on. Go.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Hey!
BUNKER:
Oh, no...
MOSLEY:
What are you doing?!
What did you run away for?!
What do you want
from me?!
It's too much, man.
Look, I'm doing the rest
of this on my own, okay?
I'm doing what I said
I was going to do.
I'm getting
out of here.
If I can find you,
they can find you.
they can find you!
Eddie, listen to me,
listen to me.
Listen to me!
I am your only friend
out here, all right?
No, you ain't my friend.
I can do this, Ed.
Listen to me!
You're my friend?!
You don't even know me!
And get me where?
Boy, you gonna get me shot!
Ever since I been with
you, people been trying
to shoot me-- people you know!
Look, man, I got
someplace I need to be.
I got something I need to do,
and unless you're gonna shoot me
or arrest me right
here, I'm going.
I can't let you leave.
Do you understand?
Thank you, Jack Mosley.
I'm going.
You cannot leave!
Thank you. Yes, I can.
Thank you, Jack Mosley.
Stop! Don't do that!
Stop!
I am not joking!
Let me... come here!
Stop!
Eddie!
Okay, okay, okay,
we got to go.
Move! Move!
Out of the way!
[PANTING]
Here, come on.
What are you doing?
Taxi!
Hey!
Hey! Taxi!
It's Kaller.
Just missed him
at the Canal Street Station.
Where, where, where, where,
where, where, where?
Shit. Where the hell is he?
Goddamn it.
We're going to find you.
Yeah, this is Detective Nugent.
I need a triangulation
on Detective Torres'
cell phone.
Area code 917-935...
[COUGHING]
That cop back
at the apartment,
he said you should do
what you always do.
What'd he... what'd
he mean by that?
You're not...
you're not doing
what you always
do, huh?
Jack Mosley,
I get it.
I seen the sign.
I'm wh... I'm where
I'm supposed to be.
I was wrong.
You're the right guy.
I could've got
another guy,
did something different,
but I got you.
I appreciate it.
You're the right guy, okay?
Okay, okay.
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
This is contact. Over.
Yeah, go.
This is Nugent.
Uh, GPS indicates
they're on Bowery.
Repeat, Bowery moving south
towards Pell.
Speed indicates they're on foot.
Are you hearing this, boys?
He's in Chinatown.
Let's move in.
[WOMAN SPEAKING CHINESE]
[HORN HONKING]
What's the deal
with that book?
It's my
business plans.
I'm moving
to Seattle.
My sister's already living
out there.
I'm going to open up a bakery,
but it's only, like,
a specialty bakery.
You know, like birthday
cakes for little kids.
There's a lot of
money in that.
Well, how about this?
When's your birthday?
I'm going to send you a big
birthday cake on your birthday.
I hate birthday cakes.
What do you mean,
you hate birthday cakes?
What kind of person...
The first thing that
doesn't go your way,
you're going
to be slipping
into Carol's
Clip and Curl,
stealing all
her hair care products,
because you're a thief.
And that's what
you are, Eddie.
You're a thief.
No, no, no, I ain't.
You're always going
to be a thief.
People can change, Jack.
Days change,
seasons change,
not people.
Yes, they do.
People don't change, Eddie.
You know what?
I'm going to get you
that cake, and you know
what it's going to say
on the top of it, right?
"Jack Mosley,
ha-ha-ha, eat this."
I'm going to make you
eat your words,
lick your fingers, too.
Subject's moving west on Pell.
Subject now moving south
on Doyers.
Still moving south on Doyers.
All right, Bobby,
you take Doyers.
We got Pell.
And, Kaller,
you close up Bowery.
Let's squeeze them.
KALLER:
Copy that. On my way.
Let's pull up. Pull up.
[HORN HONKS]
[PEOPLE SPEAKING CHINESE]
[MAN SHOUTS IN CHINESE]
[STREET BAND PLAYING DRUMS]
MOSLEY:
Sorry.
You can't
go in there.
Oh, sor-sorry.
[DRUMS BANGING IN DISTANCE]
[DOOR CREAKS]
Look, man, I-I-I got to...
I got to be down there.
All right?
You understand?
See, I got to be
down there that way,
and there's streets
and shit in between there.
Um, do you have
some sort of plans?
Police plans
or something?
See you limp
backing up there.
You really ought to get
that checked out, man.
I had a buddy of mine
walking around with a
limp just like that--
he didn't want to go
to the doctor, though, right?
Finally, he go.
They say it's a
fracture, right?
And now it's
infected.
They got to cut it
off at the knee.
Wasn't so bad, though.
He had no more pain.
Matter of fact,
he ended up
moving to Jersey,
working for the PATH,
being a motorman.
Got a pension
and shit now.
Guess everything
happened for a reason,
you know what I mean?
You're a sunny little shit,
I'll give you that much.
[GUNSHOT]
[SHOUTING]
Get in here!
Get in this door!
Pull me in! Help me in!
Come on, come
on, come on!
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait!
♪
[GATE CREAKING]
You all right, man?
Yeah.
[PEOPLE SPEAKING CHINESE]
[FOOD SIZZLING]
Hey, what are we doing?
Where are we going?
[MOSLEY GROANS]
[MAN SHOUTS IN CHINESE]
BUNKER:
Hey. What's up?
Where we going, Jack?
Out of the way.
Okay.
Jack, how do we know
that Center Street Courthouse
is in this direction?
Jack? Jack?
We got to know...
[GUNSHOTS]
MOSLEY:
Get down!
[SHOUTING]
Go!
[GUNSHOTS]
MOSLEY:
Come on!
[SCREAMS]
Kaller!
Push it!
[GUNSHOTS]
[GROANS]
[GASPING]
[DOOR CREAKS]
[GUNSHOTS]
[PANTING]
You all right, Jack?
[GROANS]
I was aiming for the kid,
if that makes you feel better.
You missed!
[GUNSHOT]
FRANK: That kid is
gonna get you killed.
He worth that?
[GUN CLICKING]
I got all day.
How about you?
You got all day?
[GROANS SOFTLY]
FRANK: Jack, you still there?
Yeah... still here.
Well, this is awkward.
When I started this day...
I never figured on trading
nine-mils with my friend.
I think we stopped
being friends
right around 8:25,
in that bar.
No.
No, that's not going to erase...
20 years together.
We're still friends.
[SIGHS]
FRANK:
Look...
a lot I'd take back,
but I can't.
Well... so you move forward.
Next day,
next case.
Lines were crossed.
What lines?
MOSLEY:
You hear me?
Lines were crossed, Frank.
What lines?
There are no lines!
There's getting it done
and not getting it done, period!
You put the
bad guys away
no matter
what it takes.
Now, you're going to ruin
the lives...
of six cops.
Good cops.
Good men.
Are you ready
to sacrifice their lives
for that kid?
Hey, Frank...
Frank!
Yeah?
This is not
about me ruining
anybody's life, okay?
This is about you.
You hear me?
Yeah.
You look at that kid's jacket?
Hmm? I did.
Armed robbery,
assault...
I never had no armed robbery!
I-I never...
I never even used a...
One time, I used a...
Shh, shh!
Shut up, shut up.
FRANK: Oh, no, don't
tell him to shut up.
No, Jack, listen to him.
Oh, that kid, he's, uh...
he's sharp.
Yeah, he's playing you.
He's sharper
than you are.
He's telling you
stories, right?
He wants to be a good citizen,
go to church,
buy his mother
a house.
But he has spent
more than half
his life in prison.
Two hours ago, he was sitting in
a cell for weapons possession.
[WHISPERING]:
Wasn't me, Jack.
FRANK:
He is always going
to do what
he has done.
He is a career
criminal.
That's who you're protecting.
You all right?
Yeah. Frank's got him
on the other side.
He's got my gun, too.
FRANK: If you can't see
how wrong this is,
I promise you, I will
speak from my heart...
when I give the eulogy
at your funeral.
So...
you believe the kid?
Or do you believe
your ex-partner?
[PHONE RINGS]
[WHISPERING]:
Frank,
we're right on the
other side of the door.
'Cause...
if you believe the kid...
...you've got
a choice to make.
You go through
your ex-partner...
...or do you choose
door number two
to go back to
where you came
with your gimpy leg
and your shot-up hand?
Huh?
You're not going
to get very far,
and what if
your ex-partner
is right, Jack?
What if he is right,
and you wasted
your whole miserable life?
[GUNSHOTS, BULLETS RICOCHETING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Frank?
You all right?
Yeah.
They're in the elevator.
Seal the building.
Come on, Bobby.
Come on, get down there, Bobby.
Everybody out! Police!
Everybody out!
Hey, Brian.
I hear them coming up.
All right, come on, come on,
come on, upstairs.
Seal the stairwell.
All right.
Bobby, find the back stairs.
Check the roof.
Come on, Mal, this way.
Maldonado.
Okay.
Seal it up.
MALDONADO:
Gotcha.
[KNOCKING]
Hello?
Hello? Hello?
No, no, nothing.
No answer. Not there.
Come on.
OLD MAN:
I never open door.
Please, please...
please help.
Come on.
See? Hey.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
MOSLEY:
You saw that, right?
You heard him, right?
MOSLEY: Yeah.
He never opens the door.
Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you.
Y-You heard him,
right, Jack?
Shh! Not now, Eddie.
Keep your voice down.
He said he never
open the door.
You-you know what
that mean, right?
[WHISPERING]:
Oh, my God.
There's signs everywhere.
Yeah, um,
I need Ann McDonald, please?
WOMAN:
May I tell her who's calling?
Yeah, tell her it's the guy
who's got her witness.
[KNOCKING]
You're driving a car
through a hurricane, all right?
Like... [WHISTLING]
Hurricane.
And there's three
people at a bus stop:
a old woman...
Yeah.
...uh, a friend,
like my friend here...
Him-- he'll
save your life--
your friend.
It's Detective
Mosley for you.
Mosley.
Yeah.
Where the hell are you?
Where's my witness?
I'm about seven blocks from you.
There's about a ton of cops
between me and you,
and they all want this kid dead.
Not to mention the fact
that you got a leak
in your office.
Somebody's talking
to these cops, you hear me?
[WHISPERS]:
Shit!
Well, what did you think
was going to happen
when you pinched Shue?
You think they're all just going
to lay down and go away quietly?
We thought if we went to the
grand jury, Shue would fold.
He bent but didn't break.
We were going
to throw it away
until we ran
into Edward Bunker last night.
Jury's tenure ends at 10:00.
Without that kid,
they'll vote no bill,
and it all goes away.
He's an eyewitness.
He makes this work.
Where are you?
I'll send my squad.
Richard! Ken!
[LINE CRACKLING SOFTLY]
What room?
[GROANS]
[STAMMERING]:
So... a-are they coming?
Yeah, they're coming.
Good, 'cause I got...
I got to be somewhere, man.
I got something to do.
I got to be
someplace by noon.
I-I got... I got to
go get something.
It's real important.
Oh, shit.
Yeah.
Ortiz, I'm coming
in the building.
Frank?
All right.
Twohy and Kaller
are taken care of.
Good. Go find Bobby.
He's on the back stairs.
Eddie, here, come here.
Put this on.
Here, come on, put that on.
Put it on.
I don't wanna put this...
It's a big, hot wool shirt.
It's hot... it's summer.
You're dressed like a criminal.
Oh, you want me to... you
want me to change my...
Okay, I get it.
But let me put that on.
What about this one? Look. Look.
What about that one?
What's wrong with this?
It's just the pattern.
He don't even wear that shirt.
Just put the... Here...
Never mind.
What about this?
This is... Is this all right?
Mass transit blue?
BUNKER:
When I was locked up,
they had me working
the kitchen, right?
So, one day, little
dude walk up to me,
say, "Hey, man, you think
you bake me a cake?"
I say, "Yeah, I'll
bake you a cake."
You know, I ain't tell him
I ain't never baked a cake.
You know, I... but I ain't got
shit else to do, so, uh...
You know, I read
the instructions.
I bake him a cake, you know,
for his daughter's birthday
when she come up there to visit.
And it say:
"Happy Birthday, Angel," right?
He go crazy.
He can't get enough, you know.
He say, "Oh, Eddie, man,
hook me up, man, you the man."
And I start doing that
for good, you know.
I had a skill; people looking
at me different and start...
You missed a button.
Did I?
The buttons are all crooked.
Come on.
Come on, man.
All right.
[PHONE BEEPS]
Nugent.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
You're a prince.
[PHONE RINGS]
FRANK:
Word is 5-E, boys, 5-E.
Got it.
Then I started doing
my research,
doing my
due diligence,
I find out, you know, it's
good money in birthday cakes
for kids, you know?
That type of thing
like Tweety Bird
or Bugs Bunny or something like
that... or... or Yu-Gi-Oh.
You ever heard of Yu-Gi-Oh?
[CHUCKLING]:
Yu-Gi-Oh!
Kids love that, man.
You don't know Yu-Gi-Oh.
You got to get out more, Jack.
Yu-Gi-Oh hot.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm gonna make money, Jack...
open up my bakery.
You're gonna see.
You're gonna eat your words
about me, Jack Mosley.
How do I look? Look all right?
[SHOUTING]:
Police!
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
Frank, they gave us
the wrong apartment.
Put it down.
[GUN CLATTERS ONTO STEP]
Can't get lucky all the time.
You can be smart
every day, though.
All right,
give me the gun.
Hold on.
MOSLEY:
What are you doing?
This place is crawling
with cops, Eddie.
Hey.
Look at me.
[GUN COCKS]
MOSLEY:
Eddie...
What are you doing?
How's it feel?
You're a baker, right?
FRANK:
Eddie...
listen to him.
Pull that trigger,
you go to jail for life.
[PHONE RINGS]
BOBBY:
Frank, we're on our way down.
Frank, do you read me?
[GRUNTS]
You can't stop me.
Time to go.
Can't stop me.
You gave him a loaded weapon.
Frank?
Bobby, get these
things off me.
Did he take your gun?
They went south.
Get outta here.
Cruise it.
Ortiz, Ortiz,
gimme a piece.
Gimme a piece!
Get over here.
Make a hole, make a hole.
Come on, make a hole.
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Speak to me.
Come on, somebody speak to me.
Turn around.
Excuse me, excuse me!
Excuse me! Open up!
[SHOUTING]
Open up!
Keep moving.
Go... go, go, go.
On the bus!
Let's move.
Just keep driving.
What are you doing?
I'm a cop.
Lock the back door.
He's got a gun.
[SCREAMING]
No stops.
Tell 'em to hang on
to something, Eddie.
BUNKER:
Hang on.
Don't worry, please.
Please, he's a police officer.
Everything is gonna...
Hang on!
It's gonna be fine.
Everybody just hang on.
Don't worry.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[SCREAMING, HORNS HONKING]
Right, right,
right, go right!
MAN:
Stop this thing!
[PASSENGERS SCREAMING]
[SHOUTING]
ORTIZ:
Get away from the bus!
Away from the bus!
[CAR ALARMS WAILING IN DISTANCE]
MOSLEY:
Stay down, stay down.
[PASSENGERS SCREAMING]
Stay down.
Where the hell are you?
We're out back,
the construction site out back.
He has hostages.
[MURMURING AND SHOUTING]
[SIREN WAILING]
Listen!
[MURMURING STOPS]
Everybody stand up.
They're not gonna shoot you.
Stand up in front
of the windows.
They won't shoot you.
You-You stay down. Stay down.
[SIRENS WAILING]
Fill in the blanks,
fill in the spots!
Scoot over, scoot over.
That's it.
All right,
get Gruber down here.
[SIREN STOPS]
Hey!
All right, seal off that end.
[SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE]
There's a busload.
Jesus, this shit
just gets deeper. Bobby?
Gruber's on his way.
All right, we got to get
our stories straight.
All right?
Right.
We getting
our stories straight?
Here.
Thought we could handle this
quickly and quietly,
Commissioner.
The guy shoots a cop, takes
a grand jury witness hostage
and we're supposed to make nice?
Commissioner?
Look, sir...
this is just an
unfortunate accident.
Look, this is
my fault, all right?
I used to work with
Detective Mosley,
so I asked the cap
to let me handle it.
I thought
that I could bring him in.
I just didn't realize
how far gone he was.
OFFICER:
Stay on tach two, boys.
Move over to command.
Here we go.
MOSLEY:
That's it, cover them up.
Good, okay.
Great job.
Thank you.
[DUCT TAPE TEARING]
Commissioner, sir.
Captain.
FRANK:
Hi, Mike.
What do we got?
Cop.
20-plus, flipped.
Suicidal?
He's been to the farm twice
the last four years.
Been to the farm twice?
Twice. Nothing
like this, though.
What do you
know, Detective?
Well, like the captain said,
he flipped.
After he nailed Detective Shue,
he started spouting
all this crap
about making headlines.
There's no way that you're
getting this guy out.
[OVERLAPPING INDISTINCT
RADIO COMMUNICATION]
Smart cop.
Okay...
BUNKER: Jack...
You're all gonna be okay.
We're gonna get
you out of here.
Please just move
to the back of the bus.
Just move to the back
of the bus, please, right now.
I-It's okay.
You're gonna get off the bus.
I am a police officer.
Jack, it's Mike Sheehan.
We worked that barricade deal on
the concourse a few years ago.
I'm gonna put this thing down.
Okay?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that I got you
in this situation.
SHEEHAN: You know the drill--
no weapons!
Just keep your head down.
I'm just gonna step in here,
nice and easy,
and hand you this phone,
so we can talk.
Okay?
Make sure we got
no injuries in there.
Jack, just open
the door, okay?
I need to...
Just throw it, Mike.
Okay, okay, you got it...
Throw it.
Here you go.
Jack?
[MOUTHING]
[PHONE RINGS]
SHEEHAN:
Jack, can you hear me?
How many people you got
in there, Jack?
[SIGHS]
Count how many people
are here.
Everybody put your
hands up, please.
OFFICER [DISTANT]:
NYPD. We got a situation here.
We need you people
back on the sidewalk.
Stay behind the barricade.
BUNKER:
...26, 28...
Okay, thank you.
That's everybody?
Please...
[WOMAN SOBS]
Don't cry, don't cry.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Just... just relax.
Stay calm, okay?
Thank you.
Thirty-one.
And what is it?
Okay, we have, um...
uh... about 40 people
on the bus.
Okay, that's good.
You know, it's important
that we're clear
with each other, Jack.
ESU and HMT are in place.
The block is sealed, Jack.
It's a frozen zone.
So let's work this out...
so everybody can go home,
all right?
That's all we want to do--
just... just end it
nice and easy.
Jack?
This is as far as you go, buddy.
Keep talk...
Is e-everybody okay?
Yeah.
Hi, how are you?
Good.
How are you?
My name is Eddie.
Hi.
Everybody's okay?
What's your name?
Christina.
That's a pretty name.
H-How old are you, Christina?
Seven.
Seven years old.
OFFICER [ON RADIO]:
Tach units on standby.
Now, my strawberry recipe,
I know I got one. Let me see...
Where's my
strawberry recipe?
Angel food cake recipe
right here.
Here we go.
Strawberry fan.
You see right here on the top?
I put a fan on the top.
You know like, um...
like-like...
like a Chinese fan?
I-I can do that.
When's your birthday?
September 22.
Oh, so-so you gonna be
eight years old, huh?
It's gonna be
a good day for you.
When's your birthday?
Uh, today, actually.
[PASSENGERS MURMURING]
Yeah.
WOMAN:
Happy birthday to you.
[MURMURING]
Yeah, e-every day is somebody's
birthday, you know?
That's gonna be the-the-the
motto for my shop:
"Every day is
a birthday," you know?
I didn't know
my birthday's
gonna turn out like this,
but, uh...
yeah, I'm glad to be,
you know, here alive, you know?
[PHONE RINGS]
Right here, Jack.
Yeah, Sheehan?
Commissioner,
Commissioner, sir?
Sheehan?
Right here.
All right, this
is what I want.
I want you to get me Assistant
District Attorney McDonald,
a court stenographer
and somebody from TV--
somebody that I would recognize.
I want them to come on the bus
and record sworn testimony.
When I get what I want,
I let everybody out... safely.
Jack, that's a tall order.
That's gonna take...
Just do it.
I'm not in the mood, okay?
Get these people here
in 15 minutes,
or I'm gonna start shooting
these passengers one at a time
and throwing them out the door.
Jack, be cool, okay?
Let's not do
anything rash.
This thing can end
without bloodshed, okay?
15 minutes.
We can work this...
[LINE CLICKS]
Jack? Jack?
He's gone.
All right,
everybody on your feet.
BUNKER:
Jack, what are you doing?
Got to get these people
off this bus.
Wait, wait, wait.
But you just made the call.
You called the DA; they said
they're coming, right?
Nobody's coming, okay?
Nobody's coming.
What do you mean,
nobody's coming?
Eddie, they're gonna breach this
bus in less than five minutes.
They're gonna kill me,
they're gonna kill you...
Jack, what about testifying?
We're right here. We can go.
We can end this,
we can testify...
Nobody's testifying.
It's all over, Eddie.
We lose, kid.
Hey, Ray...
Frank.
Yeah.
You, uh...
you guys going in?
Commissioner hasn't given
us the green light yet.
Well...
I don't need to remind
you that he shot two of us.
Enough said.
We got maybe 40
civilians on that bus.
Get them out.
I don't want anybody hurt,
including our guys.
Nobody's gonna get hurt,
Commissioner.
These guys know
what they're doing.
OFFICER:
We have movement.
Move in.
[INDISTINCT VOICES]
Hey! What?
When you get outside...
Happy Birthday.
Thank you.
...they're gonna take
you to a holding area.
It's gonna be hectic...
Well, everybody's
out there...
Listen to me.
Once you get outside that
perimeter, you just get lost.
But what if they...?
Keep moving, you just
keep moving, all right?
Come here.
You look great.
Hey, great suit.
All right?
Got your gray suit.
Hands in the air, folks.
Don't look back.
[SHOUTING, SCREAMING]
Hands in the air.
You'll be all right.
[PASSENGERS SHOUTING]
Thanks. Sorry.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, let's go.
What the hell is he doing?
How the hell
should I know?
I'll let you know when I know.
I'll let you
know when I know!
Out of my face!
[SHOUTING]
OFFICER:
Carla, give me a hand with this!
Keep 'em moving!
FRANK:
Bobby?
Right here, right here,
right here, right here.
That's him!
Hey, hey. Hey, man.
It's not him.
Oh, the dude.
He changed.
He changed. It's not me.
What?
He's in a suit.
Suit. A gray suit.
Suit? Gray suit.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
[SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[TAPE REWINDING]
We count 31, Commissioner.
That leaves eight
people on the bus.
No, no, no, no, no.
I was the last one off the bus.
The only person
left on that bus
is the guy with the gun.
Then go. Do it.
Let's go. Let's go.
Get your people
out there, let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Mosley is still
on the bus,
and that kid
is here somewhere.
I already checked...
I don't care, Bobby.
I don't care
what you checked.
Check it again.
Now, go.
[CLICK]
This is Detective Jack Mosley.
Shield number 227.
[HELICOPTER PASSING OVERHEAD]
[PANTING]
I guess this will be
my last will and testament.
[HELICOPTER HOVERING]
♪
[SIGHS]
BUNKER:
Don't shoot!
Hold your fire!
Do not shoot!
[OVER RADIO]:
Who is that?
Hold your fire!
[OVER RADIO]:
Is that Weir from the 3-2?
Get on your goddamn radio.
Find out who the hell that is.
Get down! Hold your fire!
[SHOUTING]
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Don't shoot.
[TAPPING BUS]
Don't shoot. Don't shoot!
Do not move!
Don't shoot!
Hold your fire!
Get away from the bus!
Do not shoot!
Hold your fire.
Jack? Jack, it's me.
Hey, Mosley.
It's me, Eddie, Jack.
Chuck Berry.
Chuck Berry...
he got locked up
for armed robbery.
He changed.
Barry White, he
stole 300 ties.
Can you pic...
Can you picture
big Barry White
stealing 300 ties?
He changed.
You said, you said
people don't change.
People change.
Eddie...
What?
You're killin' me.
Team three, breach the bus.
Repeat, team three,
breach the bus.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
[BUS ENGINE STARTS]
[SCREECHING, GRINDING]
Stay out of the way.
[GLASS SHATTERING]
Head down!
Cover your ears and your eyes!
Finish it! Go! Go!
[OVER RADIO]:
Fire!
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Is that shots fired?
Shots fired.
[GROANING, SCREAMING]
[RAPID GUNFIRE]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
Let's go! Move! Move! Move!
Move up! Move up!
Take it. Go.
[HISSING]
[GLASS CRACKLING]
[PANTING]
The bus is empty.
They went through the bus doors!
They're in the goddamn building!
Seal it off!
It's all clear.
The bus is empty.
They've entered the building.
Seal the building,
start the search.
Heads up.
He just shot two cops. Careful.
[SIREN WAILING]
Jack, I got
to tell you something.
Hey, man, Jack,
listen to me, man.
Jack, I want to tell
you something.
Hold on, hold on, wait.
I got to tell you something.
It's important.
Get up, get up.
Oh, shit... Oh, shit...
Hey, sir, sir, listen, I'm a
cop, all right? I'm on a job.
Look, I need that phone from
you, let me have it from you.
Look what they
did to my suit, man.
I told you you was
gonna get me shot.
It's me.
I need your help.
All this started 'cause my
friend Maurice came by my house.
[CHAINS RATTLING]
A few days ago, Maurice
came to my house.
He came all excited.
He got a shoe box,
he got a gun.
He talking about, "Hold this
for me for a little while."
I'm, like,
"I'm on a parole."
He, like, "Me, too."
Next day,
somebody shot him.
$32,000 in that shoe box.
That's a sign, huh?
MOSLEY:
Yeah, that's a very big sign.
[BUNKER GROANING]
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
Yeah.
You know how much it's gonna
take me to open the bakery?
$31,000.
Jack,
I got so nervous,
I ran out the house,
I went to Port Authority
and I put the money in a locker.
[GROANING]
I get back to my house,
my parole
officer's there.
In my house.
He got Maurice's gun
in his hand.
He lookin' at me, like,
"That's it, Eddie."
And he talking
about 15 years, man.
I was so scared.
Then the DA came to my cell...
He showed me
the picture of that cop.
Then I met you.
Jack...
they clean them lockers out
every 24 hours.
I had a little
schedule going, man.
Court at 10:00,
[VOICE FADING]:
Port Authority at 12:00...
Hey, hey, look at
me... wake up.
You ain't gonna
die on me, are you?
I don't know,
I never died before.
It's not gonna
happen today.
Hey.
Thank you for coming.
What's going on?
Look.
Shot through here.
I think it
went in and out.
Yeah, let's get him in.
[BUNKER GRUNTING]
I know you.
Come on.
I was at your house.
You were at
my apartment?
Had to get my gun.
Big mouth.
Yeah, it was very nice.
Very clean.
[GROANING]
Police were grilling me
for an hour at the hospital.
What'd you say to them?
That you're
a self-medicating,
depressed individual,
and that you don't care anymore,
about anything or anyone.
Oh, that's honest,
straightforward.
That's sexy, I like that.
[GROANS]
[BUNKER GRUNTING]
What'd you do
this time, Jack?
He saved my life
a couple of times.
Hey, he's
a good dude.
You gotta give
him another chance.
I don't know what he did,
but you got
to give him another chance.
He got to have somebody
to talk to.
I'm not gonna be around.
Eddie, this is my sister, Diane.
What?
She's your sister.
Mm-hmm.
Aw, man.
I just started having
a little hope for you, man.
Your family don't even like you.
I got a sister, too.
She lives in
Seattle.
Supposed to go out there
and start my bakery.
I supposed to go out there
today, see if...
[MUMBLING WEAKLY]
Look, I can stop the bleeding,
but he's got to get stitched up.
He's got to get to a hospital.
We got to be at the courthouse
in less than 20 minutes.
You're gonna
have to do it.
be fine, Eddie.
It's not as bad
as it looks.
What happened to your hand?
I got to ask you one more favor.
Just a little favor.
[INDISTINCT RADIO TRANSMISSION]
Hey, is today
really your birthday?
[CHUCKLES]:
No.
No, I only said that
'cause the little girl,
she was all scared.
She was cute,
right?
When's
your birthday?
I don't know.
What do you mean
you don't know?
No, for real. I don't know.
You know, 'cause I came up
through foster care.
Had a lot of birthdays.
Didn't you say you, you got...
You got a sister, right?
Yeah.
That you're going to see.
Yeah, I just found out
about her a couple months ago.
Never met your sister?
No.
Wow.
So I'm going
out to Seattle
to meet her.
I'm looking forward...
Maybe she turns out
to look like Angelina Jolie.
Shit, if she do,
I hope she ain't my sister.
[LAUGHS]
Hey, man, what you want
on your cake, man?
You never told me.
I got to send you one, man.
I don't want no cake, Eddie.
Damn it, Jack, come on, man...
Hey, I can't think of anything
that has happened in my life
that I would want
written on a cake.
Nothing?
I'm not a good guy, Eddie.
I'm not a good guy.
Yeah, me neither.
Diane.
Frank.
Give me the keys.
Stay in the car.
A little out of your
sector, aren't you?
Saving lives
knows no bounds.
You should
know that, Frank.
You look good.
You look a little desperate,
Frank-- it doesn't suit you.
Open the door.
Open the door. Open the door.
Sorry, Jack, this
is the closest I can get you.
Like I said, you're
looking good.
[GROANS]
Hey, come on, let's go.
No, hey, hold on.
Hold on a minute.
Why are we stopping?
We're on Fourth.
This is as far
as you go, too.
Aw, come on, man.
Listen to me, Eddie.
What?
Listen.
Those guys you were going
to testify against...
those cops...
Yeah?
I was one of them.
You were going to testify
against me, too.
I did what they did.
We did some bad things.
I did another bad thing
when I used you.
I was going
to let you do
what I should've done...
what I should've had the courage
to do six year ago.
I'm sorry.
You know, if
you didn't, uh,
come and get me today...
I'd be dead right now.
Right.
So...
I was supposed to meet you.
That was the sign.
You saved my life, kid.
Take care of yourself, kid.
Thank you.
Make cakes, Eddie the baker.
[GROANS]
Oh, yeah.
You give the car keys
to your best friend
and you let him take
the old lady to the hospital.
You stay at the bus stop
with the girl,
because she's the girl
of your dreams, right?
So everything's going
to be okay.
Right?
Yeah.
Have fun in Seattle.
Say hi to your sister.
Yeah.
[QUIETLY]:
Get him down to
the Port Authority.
Make sure he gets on
that bus, all right?
Yeah.
Carl, thanks.
No problem.
All right.
♪
Hell of a morning, huh?
Where's the wit?
You're looking at him.
I let the kid go, Frank.
You're not going
to get to him now.
Bullshit.
Wouldn't do that.
[MINTS RATTLING]
So, uh...
what do you think you're
going to tell them?
Hmm? Are you going to
tell them everything?
Are you going to tell
them about you, too?
You think that's going
to make you feel better?
Nothing's going
to make me feel better.
Then why?
Look, Jack,
you and me...
we... did our business...
in a certain way.
You never
complained
when we cleared
the tough cases.
It didn't bother you
doing any of that until...
Listen to me,
all right?
You listen,
all right, Jack?
Really listen.
Whatever you think
that you are going
to do up there...
it is never
going to happen.
You are not
going to make it.
Is that what
you think, Frank?
You're going to shoot me
down here; nobody knows?
Like the Ling family, huh?
Like they never knew.
He was a
stupid old man
who wouldn't keep
his mouth shut.
All right,
so I stuck
a gun in some guy's mouth,
he had a heart attack, he died.
So what?
So what?!
Look, if it
hadn't happened
the way that it did,
if he hadn't died,
you would have
been patting me
on the back saying,
"Good job."
Collateral damage--
it is a fact of life
in this business.
He took his last breaths
while you were wiping
the fingerprints off the gun.
He was gonna
take down our case.
He was an innocent man.
He was gonna take
down our case.
He was somebody's husband.
He was going to
take down our case!
He was somebody's father.
He was gonna take
down our case!
What were we
supposed to do?!
If you wanted to,
tell the truth.
Fuck the truth!
Frank...
♪
I not gonna need this anymore.
[ELEVATOR CHIMES]
♪
[HANDSET BEEPS]
Bobby, he's on his way up.
Take him out.
[ELEVATOR CHIMES]
[PHONE RINGING]
♪
Mosley's in the building!
Get the ADA! Freeze!
OFFICER: Hands in the air!
Get on your knees!
Don't shoot.
Don't move!
I'm not armed.
Get down on your knees!
MOSLEY: Don't shoot.
I'm not armed.
Lower your weapon.
Just call ADA McDonald,
please, on the radio?
Get ADA McDonald
down here right now!
MOSLEY:
Don't shoot. Don't shoot me!
Just get ADA McDonald.
Jack, come on!
MOSLEY:
Lower your weapon.
Come on, do it, get down!
Mosley!
OFFICER:
Hands up!
McDONALD:
Where's my witness?
Where's Edward Bunker?
He didn't make it.
I'm going to
take his place.
Please lower
your weapons.
Hold you fire and stand
down, both of you.
Back off.
I have information...
...regarding your ongoing
witness tampering investigation.
The dates, cases that
include extortion,
manslaughter
and possible homicide
involving members
of the 14th Precinct.
These charges include
Captain Dan Gruber,
Detectives
Jerry Shue,
Edward Maldonado...
Bob Torres...
Jim Mulvey...
myself...
and Detective Frank Nugent.
What's this about, Mosley?
What do you want?
I want Edward Bunker's
record expunged.
Done. What else?
Nothing else.
You can substantiate
all this, Mosley?
Yeah.
Gun!
[SCREAMS]:
Oh!
Hold your fire.
I fired that shot.
MOSLEY [ON RECORDER]:
...down here; nobody knows?
Like the Ling family, huh?
Like they never knew.
FRANK:
He was a stupid old man
who wouldn't keep
his mouth shut.
All right, so I stuck a gun
in some guy's mouth,
he had a heart attack, he died,
so what?
So what?
FRANK:
Look, if it hadn't happened
the way that it did,
if he hadn't died,
you would have been patting me
on the back saying, "Good job."
Collateral damage--
it is a fact of life
in this business.
He was gonna take down our case.
He was gonna take down
our case!
He was gonna take down our case!
What were we supposed to do?!
MOSLEY: If you wanted to,
tell the truth.
FRANK:
Fuck the truth!
[SIREN BLARING IN THE DISTANCE]
McDONALD:
Let's get you to the jury.
Thanks a lot.
Thanks.
[TAPE RIPPING]
MAN:
Hey, happy birthday.
MAN 2:
Happy birthday, Jack.
Welcome back, Jack.
Two years in the
pen is enough.
Thanks for that, man.
Thank you. Thank you.
Happy birthday, Jack.
WOMAN:
Happy birthday.
Welcome home.
I hate birthdays.
You know that, right?
Sorry, sorry.
Happy birthday.
[LAUGHTER]
This came with it.
BUNKER:
Dear Jack Mosley,
I hope you're doing well
and everything worked out
like it was supposed to.
I'm doing great.
Seattle is different,
and I like it a lot.
I-I'm not sure I ever smelled
fresh air before I got here.
It's a trip.
Sometimes I can't
even believe it.
It's the best feeling
I've had in my life.
I'm busting my ass,
but I'm happy, though.
The bakery is now open.
Three cheers.
I put my name first 'cause
I'm doing all the hard work.
These ovens are hot, man.
Hope you like the cake.
What'd I tell you?
If you ever in town,
you got a friend.
Thank you for doing
the right thing, Jack Mosley.
God bless you.
Keep in touch.
Peace.
Come on, take one more.
You know how this guy...
I was talking.
Take one more.
[LAUGHTER]
BUNKER:
Happy birthday, Jack.
♪ My darling, I
♪ Can't get enough of your love, babe ♪
♪ Girl, I don't know, I don't know why ♪
♪ Oh, some things I can't get used to ♪
♪ No matter how I try
♪ It's like the more you give,
the more I want ♪
♪ And, baby, that's no lie
♪ Oh, no, babe
♪ Tell me, what can I say?
♪ What am I gonna do?
♪ How should I feel
when everything is you? ♪
♪ What kind of love is this
♪ That you're giving me?
♪ Is it in your kiss
or just because you're sweet? ♪
♪ Girl, all I know
♪ Is every time you're here
♪ I feel the change
♪ Something moves
♪ I scream your name
♪ Do what you got to do
♪ And, darling, I
♪ Can't get enough of your love, babe ♪
♪ Girl, I don't know,
I don't know, I don't know why ♪
♪ I can't get enough of your love, babe ♪
♪ Oh, no, babe
♪ Girl, if I could only make you see ♪
♪ And make you understand
♪ Girl, your love for me is all I need ♪
♪ And more than I can stand
♪ Oh, well, babe
♪ How can I explain
♪ All the things I feel?
♪ You've given me so much
♪ Girl, you're so unreal
♪ Still, I keep loving you
♪ More and more each time
♪ Girl, what am I gonna do?
♪ Because you blow my mind
♪ I get the same old feeling
♪ Every time you're here
♪ I feel the change
♪ Something moves
♪ I scream your name
♪ Do what you got to do
♪ And, darling, I...
♪ Can't get enough of your love, babe ♪
♪ Oh, no, babe
[SPOKEN]:
Baby, it may take...
all of my life...
to find you.
But you can believe
it's going to take
the rest of my life...
to keep you.
♪ Oh, whoa, babe
♪
♪ And... my darling, I
♪ Can't get enough
of your love, babe ♪
♪ Girl, I don't know,
I don't know, I don't know why ♪
♪ I can't get enough
of your love, babe ♪
♪ Oh, my darling, I
♪ Can't get enough
of your love, babe ♪
♪ Oh, babe
♪ Girl, I don't know,
I don't know why ♪
♪ I can't get enough
of your love, babe ♪
♪ Oh...
♪ Darling, I
♪ Can't get enough
of your love, babe... ♪
[SONG FADES OUT]
["BESAME" LATIN INTRO PLAYING]
♪
[MAN SINGING IN SPANISH]
[SONG ENDS]
[BRIGHT FANFARE PLAYS]