Careful, Oreste,
or the devil will take you away.
I am not afraid of the devil
because the devil is red!
- Whose villa is this?
- Of Attila Melanchini.
- He had fortune.
- Does he live there alone?
No, with his beloved Regina.
They're the most envied
couple of the Bassa.
- Really?
- Yes.
Merry Christmas, Miss Regina.
Don't stay in the cold, come in!
Merry Christmas to her, Mrs. Pioppi.
We don't want to be late for the Mass.
Let's have a drink and then
we'll go to the church together.
She's crazy. First she ignores us in
public then she invites us to her house.
Maybe she wants to keep us
quiet. After all who cares?
So? Are you coming in?
Let's see how it is inside.
Merry Christmas, Mr. Federal.
- Are you making fun of me?
- One day you'll become one.
You're still so young! Young and strong!
Everything's artistic here. It's like
being in a foreign country, isn't it?
A perfect house for a true lady.
Very elegant, very refined,
full of culture.
You think? Please come
to see the living room.
- What is she doing?
- I told you she's crazy.
My God!
Now you will have to listen to me!
Now it's me who speaks!
If you want to go out, you will have
to sign a paper that the house is mine.
Attila.
You got that mortgage
from my husband
out of political blackmail and threats!
You made his heart break.
You tormented him till he died.
Everything's artistic like
in a foreign country, isn't it?
Exactly as you
would like it, Mr. Federal.
but now I'm holding you in a cage
and I won't let you go!
You won't get out of here.
This house is mine and will remain mine.
If nobody dares defend me,
I'll defend myself.
"Made in Czechoslovakia".
Scandalous sinners!
Concubines! Concubines!
Did you hear?
She called us concubines.
If we don't get married soon,
we'll be on everyone's lips.
But the radio doesn't work.
You cannot hurt me anymore.
What did my kitten do to you?
Criminals. That's what
you are: criminals.
Assassins!
Damned assassins!
Murderous hogs. Murderous hogs!
Hogs!
Mrs. Pioppi, stop it!
Opens this door, enough
with this nonsense!
You're saying absurd things.
All stupid accusations.
If you opened the door,
we could try to explain.
We are nice people.
I looked good with
the coalman's hat, didn't I?
Yes, you were irresistible, divine!
However I prefer you with mine.
- There's so many people.
- Maybe they're returning from the Mass.
What happened?
It wasn't for money,
she was full of debts.
Poor thing, with no more
house or land, all mortgaged.
- By whom?
- By Berlinghieri, everybody knows.
My God!
- She had to mortgage for debts.
- What's the mortgage got to do with this?
I think it was a sexual crime.
She was still an attractive woman.
Somehow she had
to take her fill, right?
Merry Christmas.
- Miss.
- Commissioner.
Which mortgage!
I wouldn't be surprised if it were
the crime of a crazy lover.
It can be anybody,
also one of the presents.
Maybe she let him enter
and then she refused him.
He lost his head
and maybe raped her too
before killing her
Maniacs, communists, perverted.
May I? Sorry.
She's got no underwear.
How come a woman goes around
without underwear? Why?
Ada! Ada!
Olmo! Olmo!
Olmo!
You lock the door now?
Why did you lock yourself inside?
- I don't, I lock the others outside.
- Where's my wife?
Enough! Get out!
- I am sorry.
- Out, Goddamit!
- What does he want?
- His wife!
Quiet, you'll wake up
the children.
I'll go downstairs.
Sorry, I don't know
what's wrong with me.
I don't feel well, maybe
it's my heart, it went crazy.
Your heart?
You are sick in the head!
Yes, you may be right.
Perhaps I am going crazy.
- Ada escaped and I don't know where she is.
- And you look for her in my bed?
Would it be strange?
- What do you mean?
- You know very well.
Come on, say it.
It's not such an impossible thing,
I know you like her.
Yes, you are right.
She likes me too
and we make love all night.
But that's not enough for her.
She wants me... to insert
this salami up her ass!
You're a son of a bitch.
You make fun of me too.
I called for it, but if you knew what I am
going through, you would not speak like that.
Poor widow Pioppi!
So much violence!
It's a horrible world!
And it had to happen tonight too.
Right when Ada and I
felt close to each other again.
When she saw all that blood
she ran away.
As if it were my fault,
as if I was involved in it.
- Who'll take the house?
- What?
Villa Pioppi.
They'll put in jail a poor devil
who doesn't know anything.
They'll say he's a subversive.
Too many people died, Alfredo.
but there will be more and more.
And too many people in jail.
And you allowed it,
you and those like you!
I am happy that you have a woman
in the house, it is good for your daughter.
She only came for Christmas.
Her husband is in jail.
Have you ever wondered why so many
of your friends are in jail and you aren't?
Because I stop Attila.
I protect you all the time.
If you protect me,
you'll have your own interest.
Okay insult me.
Insult your old friend.
I protect you only
because I love you.
Remember when
we went fishing frogs?
It was beautiful to go
along the ditches in summer.
I fished them and you ate them.
Come on.
The holes in your pockets. A Socialist
with holes in your pockets. Remember?
Yes, I remember well.
I remember your wedding.
I remember I was hit hard.
And I remember
that you were there watching.
Do you also remember when
you stole the gun in my father's study?
If you have so much courage,
why don't you use it?
To get killed?
Is that what you want?
Enough with talks, Alfredo.
Go home, you'll see
that Ada is there.
- Do you believe it?
- Yes.
Take this, you can never know.
Go to hell!
Ada!
Ada, open the door!
Ada, are you well?
Ada, answer me!
Ada!
Ada, what are you doing?
Ada, at least tell me something!
Do you feel bad?
What have I done
to you? Ada, open up.
I must ask you for something:
shall we take a trip?
Shall we go to Paris?
We can leave tomorrow.
Or now if you want!
Let's have a child!
I have seen aunt Ada.
Come on Italo, come to eat.
...the Italian-Germanic aviation
has brought an effective contribution
using bombs and
machine guns against
troops and vehicles.
During these fights...
You have seen aunt Ada?
I have seen her.
Don't talk nonsense.
Ada is dead, dead, dead.
Perché are you saying she's dead?
She's in her room.
In a cage like a beast.
and she eats the hearts of bad children.
Look, fellow townsman,
this is the Fascist miracle!
The miracle is to turn draught
horses into steam horses!
Did you hear?
You're no longer needed.
Hey, Baroni.
if you buy the horses,
also buy the horse-seller.
I am speaking of you, Olmo!
He seems strong,
does he have family?
He's a widower, with a child.
It depends on the price.
Baroni, you've never
made such a bargain!
Baroni it is a gentleman,
it couldn't go better.
Then I am sold.
You're part of the contract.
Horses, horse-seller and shit included!
Did you hear? He sold me!
He sold me! Like a beast!
But I don't make milk,
I can't be milked.
I don't eat hay,
then I am not a beast!
I'm a peasant! A peasant like you.
Can they sell us?
Can they buy us?
Do you think it's right?
I wonder if it is.
Olmo, take the horses and your daughter
and go with Baroni, he bought you.
Shit included, then!
Shit included!
Shit, dam it, shit!
Shit! Shit! Shit a lot!
May God be praised! He shitted!
See how much of it he made!
The restocking!
Comrades!
Laugh! Today
everything can change!
Baroni!
Make him eat it,
today is carnival!
"Milk and wine, subtle poison".
Tell your owner, if she drinks
milk, she'll remain young!
Idiot.
Hi, Federica.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- Hurry up, boy!
- Quick! They're arriving!
- Hurry up, leave.
- Yes.
- Can I come with you?
- No, go to Stella.
- Please, take me with you.
- Be good.
Here's the key.
- I'll be back soon.
- Okay.
I'll be back soon.
You'll do fine with Stella!
Take this, you'll need it
more than me.
Thanks.
Lock up the house,
don't go around alone.
- Good-bye.
- Bye.
- Good luck, Olmo.
- Thanks.
- Take care..
- Write to us, let us know how you are.
- Take this, Olmo.
- See you soon!
- Good trip.
- Cover yourself!
Mrs., today I have something
new to tell you. A true story!
Wait. Wait.
Attila wanted to sell Olmo.
- Sell him?
- Yes.
He bought a new tractor and Olmo
and the horses aren't needed anymore.
So he wanted
to sell them to a merchant.
- Nobody helped Olmo?
- Yes, all did!
Everybody! All!
Then it started snowing!
- What?
- Yes, to snow shit!
So much shit on Attila!
In his eyes, in his mouth, on his bald head!
- Nothing on Regina?
- No, because she wasn't there, otherwise...
Anche the horses helped too!
They kept shitting!
They even made him a mask of shit!
Then the farmers got scared
and Olmo had to escape.
Olmo escaped?
Yes, because Attila
will return to take revenge.
Everybody cried.
But was he happy?
Did you see if he was happy?
- Not, really...
- You are a fool, you are blind!
Poor Olmo had to leave
the house and his daughter.
He wasn't happy.
What can you know of these things...
- Are you leaving too, madam?
- Yes, I'm going away and I'm happy.
Everyone's leaving.
I don't need them anymore.
I give you all.
Also this. You also take this.
And this.
This.
And also this.
Mrs.,
would you give me a kiss too?
Come here.
Attila!
Get down at once!
- It's full of fliers in the other room.
- I'll take care of it.
Attila!
He escaped, but in a couple
of hours we'll have taken him back.
Who gives you the right
to break everything?
- That is a communist, a subversive!
- He's a friend of mine!
Nice friend! He stole
your father's gun!
It took you long to find it!
So you knew! Why didn't you...
Your services
are no more necessary.
What?
I have dismissed him! Did you hear me?
I have dismissed the farmer!
I sent away Attila!
Attila will go away!
Ada! I know I shouldn't come here,
but today an important
thing happened.
I wish I did it before, but...
I made it, I dismissed
Attila. It's over.
- The lady has left.
- Left?
- Where did she go?
- Madam won't return.
- She won't return.
Answer!
She said: "Put on that dress,
he will understand".
Drink!
See, that's how you
all will end up, like mice!
Orialò!
Piso! Piso!
Do you like them pig? Repugnant Fascist!
- Shameless cow, cover up yourself!
- Hog!
Whore!
Don't move or I'll shoot you!
- Demezio!
- Yes?
- God exists?
- No!
Attila, does that pig
of Mussolini exist?
Demezio, does
the Duce exist?
No, he doesn't exist!
Shoot him.
Attila! You don't exist too!
You all want to die?
But you cannot fool me!
Mapponi! Baroni!
Come away. Peasants!
Miserable! You are
the shame of Italy!
You are the shit of Italy!
25th APRIL 1945 - DAY OF THE LIBERATION
Boys, run! Come here!
We must kill all the black brigands!
Careful, don't let them kill you!
Shoot the Fascist in the ass!
Anita! Anita! What do you see?
What do I see?
A lot of things.
I see many black brigands
who escape like rabbits
and one of ours runs
behind them without rifle.
Anita! It has to be
my Tigre, God bless him!
He has only a baton in his hand!
How strong he is!
He seems a devil with a hundred arms
from the strokes he's giving him!
if you saw him, women!
- Beat them Tiger! Kill them!
- And don't we do anything?
Scream, women!
Scream, make yourselves heard!
Louder! Louder!
Blessed youth who
sees what is not there.
The German armies
are running away!
They're leaving forever,
they'll never return!
They're throwing away rifles and uniforms
not to make themselves recognized!
Women, the things I see!
What?
I see a big dust cloud
and a man on a white horse.
He seems Olmo.
If Olmo were here!
Leave the dead alone.
Attila and Regina.
Attila and Regina!
Attila, shoot!
# Pilgrim who come from Rome
wearing broken shoes.
# As soon as you had
arrived at the inn... #
Shitty fatty!
Fascist cow! Fascist cow!
Away, women! Let's take
them to the pigsty!
No trespassing,
you cannot pass!
- Let us pass!
- We want to be there too!
Leave them to us!
Comrades, is it true that you're giving
the land to those who work it?
I said
is it true that you're giving
the land to those who work it?
Yes, is true! Come!
Come on.
How many people!
Who are you who say
what we all have in our hearts?
He is Cornelio and
I'm Rondine, his wife.
We come from the mountains.
The Germans burnt our houses
and the Fascist
robbed us of everything.
First of all we have
to give them a place to sleep.
The stable will do for us.
No, the stable
is for the vagabond!
Houses are for Christians!
And rifles are for the Fascist.
# I'm happy to die, but I am sorry.
# I'm sorry to die, but I'm happy.
# I'm happy... #
Stop it, idiot!
Who's that?
Popular committee
for pig's sharing.
How much nice stuff!
- How beautiful you are!
- Have you found a wife?
Want to marry the sow?
Don't escape as well,
unfaithful one!
Hands off, first
we have to count them!
My love! My love!
You're pitiless! Bastards! Bastards!
15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20.
There are 20 of them!
Just a moment, comrades,
I have a lump in my throat.
We have to abolish the estate
to make the lump disappear!
We are really stupid,
we haven't understood anything!
This herd of hams, salamis, cotechini,
and mortadella, belongs to everyone?
The beasts belong to everybody.
Socialism is not for everybody instead.
I don't know anything of socialism,
I only know of hunger.
And I feel sorry for those two.
All the D'Alcòs, come here.
you that come from the mountains
full of priests to bring us ignorance,
punch yourself on the head
and let the socialist idea in.
- What shall we do?
- You heard him.
He speaks well, but he told us
to punch ourselves on the head!
Punches on the head hurt.
Look at him. Look at him well.
I know that you are
a good man, have pity.
He's dying as a pig.
Help him in the name of humanity.
In the name of socialism.
Look, my grandfather
is buried here.
"Patrizio Vanzini.
tender flower chopped off
by the cruel hand of destiny".
The cruel hand of destiny!
The hand of destiny!
The cruel hand...
Regina, our children...
our children will pick up
what we have sowed.
- You're crazy!
- Go away!
They cut your hair! Not the hair!
"lda Cantarelli, widow Pioppi.
good and holy woman offended
by the ferocity of the times".
I'm this fierce log!
I have killed that sow.
And I enjoyed Patrizio Vanzini!
Me, Attila Melanchini.
Fascist.
Man.
Beasts, servants.
Disgust.
Shit.
Enough with the music,
this is not a dance-hall!
You don't have
respect for the dead?
Come here.
Run. Everyone!
- Who's that?
- I don't know.
Kill me!
Kill me.
Kill me! Kill me!
Come away, be careful!
What are you looking at, stupid!
Halt, no trespassing.
Stop it!
- Who is it?
- The master, he's my prisoner.
- Why are you hiding him?
- I'm waiting for the partisans.
You look good with that rifle.
Come on Maria, you can win!
Don't fall off the ladder!
Wait! My goose!
This is mine and
no one can touch it!
- If is yours, it's everyone's!
- Why mine has to be everyone's?
Make it redder,
it brings good luck!
Stop it.
Stupid.
The master!
Where was him?
- We forgot to arrest him.
- Good, Leonida!
Young people
are better than the old!
Sorry Master,
it slipped out of my hand!
And that slipped out of my foot!
Olmo, here's my prisoner.
Good.
Hey. Are you sleeping?
Ada never returned.
- Would you prefer that she were dead?
- At least you returned.
Are you sure that it's here?
I officially start the popular
trial against Alfredo Berlinghieri,
a master and therefore
an enemy to the people.
I officially declare that the popular
trial against the master is open!
I knew it was here.
I declare that the popular trial
against Alfredo Berlinghieri,
a master and therefore an enemy
to the people is open.
I want to see it!
Ada?
She isn't here, otherwise
she would have been tried like you.
She left on the same day
when you escaped.
She's smarter than you.
You remained a master till the end.
- What are you writing, Anita?
- We're not at school.
Anita, this is a popular trial,
what do you want to write?
Comrades, all that we'll do
to him must be written.
All that is written
must be read!
- It was kept hidden for so long!
- Our flag!
- All of our flags!
- Long live the labourers' flag!
I have sewn it with Rosina
it's grown year by year!
Olmo, we are ignorant
but how can we make
a trial without lawyers?
I bring you a guilty man, and you want
the lawyers! What do you want?
We arrested the master, not you!
That's not true! Leonida
arrested him with his rifle!
Yes!
Come on, dance!
When mutes start speaking,
they want to say many things,
but their tongues are tied up.
If your tongue is tied up,
speak with your heart, granny.
Enough with music.
I lost them working for you,
who will return them to me?
See how many teeth I miss!
He has teeth and keeps
chewing every day!
Munch munch! Munch munch!
- You're clean, We're dirty!
- All to you and nothing to us!
- You at rest, us at work.
- You to eat and us to starve!
You are a criminal,
- but your grandfather was even worse!
- It's true!
There was a storm and he wanted
to dismiss all the labourers!
No, it was his father Giovanni!
Father or son, the master
is always the master!
Peasants are needed,
otherwise the land doesn't yield.
But what's a master for?
I can only say I have
never hurt anyone.
- Never hurt anyone.
- Now all the masters say that.
They are so hypocritical that
they almost believe it.
I have never hurt anyone.
That's why you released many criminals
and imprisoned the communists?
Comrades, that's the truth.
The Fascist are not like mushrooms
which are born in a night. No!
Masters planted the Fascist,
they wanted them,
they paid for them.
With the Fascist masters
earned more and more,
till they didn't know
where to put the money!
So they invented the war.
They sent us to Africa, Russia, Greece,
Albania, Spain...
But we're those who pay!
The proletariat, the workers,
the peasants, the poor keep paying!
Alfredo Berlinghieri,
hear the voice of the people?
We're the scoundrels,
we're penniless,
but we dare condemn you to death
and with us the
whole past condemns you.
Be happy, comrades,
the master is dead!
The master doesn't exist anymore!
I am very tired,
can I sit down?
I am very tired.
If I understood well,
he's already dead.
He believes to be alive,
but we know that he is dead!
He's alive, the dead
are cold, he's warm!
Olmo, you learned
to speak well. Here!
But I don't understand
your words, they sound tricky.
The master is dead,
but Alfredo Berlinghieri is alive
- and we don't have to kill him.
- Why?
Because he is the living proof
that the master is dead.
Now let's vote. If you
agree raise your hand.
Comrades! Here come the partisans!
Quiet!
We're here in representation
of the committee of national liberation.
We represent the Christian Democrats,
we represent the liberals,
we represent the socialists,
we represent the communists,
we represent the party of action.
The committee of national
liberation has taken the power,
above all as regards public order.
Dear friends, just
stick to the decision
of the committee of liberation
and to deposit your weapons.
- No!
- These are the orders.
- Comrades, victory is like to get drunk.
- No!
Yes, when you're drunk, you say
the things you have in your heart,
the most hidden truths.
Then someone always comes
to throw cold water at your face.
and shout: "wake up, wake up! "
Yes!
Let me speak!
Alright! Tomorrow we'll be
told that we're dreamers!
But even if the facts will want us
to believe that the master is alive,
we don't have to believe it.
Because us we've seen it with our eyes!
The master it is dead!
- Child, don't you deliver your weapon?
- The rifle is mine, give it back to me!
The master is alive.
# The hunter in the wood
saw a country girl
# who was beautiful.
Lovely and attractive.
# The hunter fell in love.
# as she was beautiful.
Lovely and attractive.
# The hunter fell in love. #