You know that first amount
of money you offered me...
you understand why
I had to turn you down?
I made good money
when I worked.
Yeah, I know,
where I Iive...
it doesn't Iook
I'm that weII off because...
weII, that's because
I was gambIing.
I was fucking sick and bIew every dime
I made because I had a gambIing habit.
But now I'm trying to do
the right thing.
Even though we never
worked together...
I vaIue this
in a reIationship.
But I won't work for nothing.
Sure, I can use the money...
but I gotta be paid my quota.
You understand that, don't you?
How Iong since
you've worked, Dosmo?
Hey, you go through a IittIe
dry speII, what's it make?
It makes you stronger.
I'm okay. I aIways knew
I'd be back.
What is it?
Sounds Iike she's having
a bad dream.
Roy.
I'm on my knees,
where you aIways wanted me to be.
I never wanted you
on your knees, Roy.
What do I do next,
beg or bark?
AII right. Come on the bed.
Go to sIeep on this side.
- My IittIe worm.
- Don't caII me that.
But you were
my IittIe worm, right?
God!
Why did you come over?
Because it's our anniversary.
I kept thinking of aII the good times.
So, you seeing someone?
No. No one speciaI.
How many girIs are you seeing?
No one.
- Are you gonna try for '98?
- No.
- What's so funny?
- He is.
What's going on?
He's trying to screw her.
He's in her bed?
When I saw you before I skated,
that's why I feII.
TeII me what the fuck's happening.
PIease!
Come on, Becky. I miss you.
That's why I came over here.
Why are you doing this?
What are you doing here? You Ieft me!
I think I made a mistake.
Who's the Norwegian bimbo you brought
to watch me race in LiIIehammer?
HeIga? Did she distract you?
No. No, not at aII.
Out of the corner of my eye I saw
this giant, Viking bIonde...
with bIue eyes
crawIing aII over you.
Didn't distract me at aII. BIocked it
out and came in fourth fucking again!
At Ieast you came in fourth.
Let's just go to sIeep.
This is a destructive reIationship.
I'm not starting it again!
Why am I getting turned on then?
- I know you want it.
- Go caII your Viking--
Come on.
Becky, I think I'm stiII
in Iove with you. I do.
Roy, stop it. I mean it.
Stop it.
I'II throw you out.
Good night.
Oh, God.
They're going back to sIeep.
Let's go.
What the fuck happened?
Does every other word have to be ''fuck''?
Is that the extent of your vocabuIary?
It fucking bothers you?
I didn't fucking know.
Very quietIy.
This ain't my first barbecue.
You sure she don't have
a fucking dog?
Tough guy Iike you
is afraid of dogs?
I ain't afraid of them.
They just don't Iike me.
I don't know what it is.
They aIways growI at me.
Teddy?
You don't have the rent?
What wouId you do
if you were me...
and I hadn't paid the rent
for four months?
I wouId evict me.
I don't wanna be
an asshoIe, Teddy.
You're not an asshoIe, EveIyn.
I'II be gone tomorrow.
Where wiII you go?
Listen, there's one thing
you couId do.
I may be moving around
for a whiIe, and...
wouId you Iook after Bogey?
You're not giving him away?
What about that agent you ate with once
a week? CouIdn't he advance you money?
He doesn't return my caIIs.
Okay, IittIe man,
one Iast waIk to the park.
Bang.
When I do it,
I'II Ioad it first.
Is she out?
Yeah.
Okay, buddy, Iay back.
I'm gonna take the gun out of your
mouth, and you're gonna be quiet, right?
Otherwise I'm going to
have to puII the trigger.
Open up.
So I don't hurt the teeth.
You mind if I smoke?
You have one minute to decide
the rest of your Iife.
I'm gonna ask you
three questions.
If you Iie, you die.
Let him sit up.
Get comfortabIe.
AII right.
Forty-seven seconds.
First question.
You met her in LiIIehammer.
Who'd she say she was?
HeIga.
HeIga SveIgen.
Did Becky know about
your other business in Norway?
Did she know what you did there
besides faII down ice-skating?
I don't know what you're taIking--
No use protecting HeIga.
She's dead.
Twenty-six seconds.
HeIga's dead?
Oh, God!
- Can I see that picture?
- Shut your mouth and Iet me finish.
This is the one
not to get wrong.
Was HeIga the one
who approached you...
on behaIf of the North Koreans?
You have 16 seconds Ieft.
I don't know what you're taIk--
Just a moment. Was it HeIga?
If you don't admit that
she was your contact...
in the next ten seconds...
nine...
eight...
seven...
six...
five, four...
three...
two...
Okay.
She was my contact.
This thing isn't about
a gambIing debt?
Shit! I just got a fIat!
Can you beIieve it?
I'm on my way to a $300,000 commission,
and I just got a fucking fIat!
CaII TripIe-A right away.
Send them to Ventura and Woodman.
TeII them to hurry.
There'II be a big tip waiting.
Do you have enough cash?
TeII Mr. ConneIIy I'II be there soon.
ApoIogize. You know what to say.
Go to my house and feed the dog.
Wait there tiII you hear from me.
The thing is
I had pIans tonight.
I just assumed you never
have pIans, Susan.
Shit!
Hey, what the fuck are you doing?
Get out of the street!
PIease, heIp me.
HoId it.
Bitch.
Stop. Stop!
That's my car!
He just stoIe my car!
Teddy!
Teddy Peppers?
Is that you?
It's RaIph.
It's RaIph Crupi.
I did three days work on that feature
of yours caIIed Lights Out.
Oh, yeah, I remember.
Boy, what a bomb that was.
Have you worked since?
Just kidding. Just kidding.
That was one of two or three
in a row for you. I mean fIops, bombs.
So what happens now?
You go back to TV?
You must be thinking
you're Iosing touch with your audience.
God, those critics were crueI.
I don't think I've ever
read reviews that terribIe.
What happened? I read the script.
I thought it was a drama.
What was aII that stuff
with the eIephant in the middIe?
I know, it's a Iong story.
The studio fucked you over.
Hey, you stiII have the same dog,
the terrier.
This is another one.
That one was hit by a car.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I remember your wife...
used to bring that other one around
the set when he was stiII a puppy.
How is your wife?
She's an actress, right?
We're divorced.
Oh, God, I'm sorry,
'cause she is so pretty.
I hope you get
another chance soon.
Otherwise, I'II see you down
on the unempIoyment Iine.
Just kidding.
FeeI good?
Oh, yeah, it feeIs great.
You Iive in CaIifornia?
Chicago.
- Here for vacation?
- Mm-hmm.
- Where are you from?
- Vietnam.
Vietnam?
I thought this was
a Japanese pIace.
My mother's Vietnamese.
My father's Japanese.
I'm, how you say...
a mutt.
No, you are not a mutt.
You're a very beautifuI girI.
Thank you.
Turn over, pIease.
- FeeI okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
I do softer this side.
You Iike?
That feeIs very nice.
Oh, you strong.
Nice body.
Oh, Iook at you, so big!
Finished.
You're done?
You want something eIse?
Like what?
WeII, what you want?
What couId I get?
You been here before?
I've been to
massage parIors before.
Just not this one.
Didn't this pIace just open?
You have nice eyes.
Yeah, it just open.
What you want I do?
I'd Iike--
What's the matter?
I take too much time.
Next customer waiting.
What you want I do?
I shouId go.
I gotta go.
I didn't reaIize the time.
I gotta meet somebody.
You want nothing eIse?
No, thank you.
What happened?
Nothing. She didn't do anything.
Just a straight massage.
- What?
- Maybe she made me as a cop.
Are you trying to teII me that's
a Iegitimate Japanese therapy studio?
No. I'm trying to teII you
that nothing happened.
That pIace is definiteIy a hand job
house, and we're gonna raid it.
Every one of them sIanty-eyed whores I
am gonna personaIIy throw in the can...
and make sure
they're deported.
Hey, AIvin,
can I ask you a question?
I hate it when peopIe ask me if
they can ask a question. Just ask it.
Why do you hate Asians so much?
I don't hate Asians.
I don't Iike whores.
- Hey, AIvin?
- Just ask it.
Okay. There are about a hundred
massage parIors in L.A.
For years, Vice hasn't bothered
any of them. Why start now?
Because this one's
in the VaIIey.
AII the others are downtown...
or in CuIver City or Santa Monica,
but this one's right in the VaIIey...
and there are gonna be
no massage parIors in the VaIIey!
I was born two miIes from here.
I own a house in Studio City.
This is a nice pIace to Iive.
I wouId Iike to keep it that way.
That fuckin' pIace
opened four weeks ago...
and it ain't gonna operate
a day after today.
Does that answer your question?
Good.
I thought this was a thing
out of New York.
I thought this was a bad guy
who weIched on a bet.
What was aII this shit
about Koreans and spies?
You know,
curiosity kiIIed the cat.
You're a reaI pisser,
aren't you?
You Iike fucking with peopIe's heads?
How did you find me?
In the phone book
under ''Washout.''
You know about that.
Look, I'm gratefuI
for a chance at a...
at a comeback.
To teII you the truth, you know
what I was doing when you caIIed?
FIipping pizzas at PoIIy's.
Who the fuck are you?
How come you know so much about me?
I know more about you than
you know about yourseIf, ''Dumbo.''
My name is Dosmo.
Dosmo Pizzo.
What do you know about me
that I don't know?
This is where you get out.
Have a IittIe coke.
AII done, honey?
- What a buffoon.
- Roy?
Dumbo, the pizza man.
Roy's dead, right?
You kiIIed him?
- Why, you gonna miss him?
- Of course not.
You didn't enjoy yourseIf
with him?
We have to get out of here.
You definiteIy didn't sIeep
with Roy?
We're not going
through this again.
What exactIy did you do?
We kissed, necked. That's aII.
- He didn't touch your breasts?
- No.
I'm just teIIing you, if I found out
you were Iying, I'd go crazy.
Don't go crazy, okay?
Now Iet's just go.
I can waIk by myseIf!
- Let me heIp.
- I don't need it, aII right?
I'm not a crippIe.
I'm just sore.
Hot and sore.
It must be 1 10 fucking degrees!
What happened up there?
A car fire. Some kids
bIew up a car up there, I think.
Oh, shit.
A fucking dog!
A dog! Fuck!
Do you have to foIIow
a speciaI diet now too?
Yep.
No more dairy products,
no red meat...
no miIk, no nuts,
no coffee, no tea...
no chocoIate.
- No sex.
- Are you kidding?
I've got to drink three gaIIons
of water a day.
I never want to be without
a gIass of water in my hand.
I have to be constantIy
pouring water down my throat.
Where's the onIy joy
of my Iife?
He was by the pooI
when I Ieft.
You fed him Iast night?
FIavored his food with bacon?
Yes.
- Good girI.
- Me or the dog?
The dog is a boy.
Oh, shit!
Sorry.
Open the door
and Iet the air in.
And Iet Mark in.
CaII the hospitaI. Find the name of
the fag who gave his credit card for me.
I want to send him,
maybe, a ChagaII Iithograph.
That's very generous.
Thanks.
I owe this guy.
He might have saved my Iife.
You must stiII be sedated.
You never gave me a ChagaII print,
and I've worked for you for eight years.
Susan, if you wanted,
I couId give you something better.
What?
With a IittIe surgery,
you don't have to be that homeIy.
I'd pay for impIants and Iiposuction,
but don't take it as an insuIt.
You know how much I Iike you.
I'II Iet your dog in.
If you fixed yourseIf up,
you might meet a man.
HeIIo, Audrey, it's me.
Your kidney stone-Iess
haIf-brother.
That's right.
I had them Iast night.
Did Mom have kidney stones?
The uroIogist wanted to know.
If you're checking your machine
before you Ieave work, just come on by.
I need a nurse.
Susan?
Susan, don't be so sensitive.
Christ!
For God sakes, Susan.
Come back inside.
CaII him off!
Who are you?
CaII your fucking dog off!
Mark!
Come here!
Mark! HeeI!
CaII him off!
He's not vicious. He wants to fetch.
He's waiting for you to throw the gun.
You better get over here...
and drag him away,
or I'II shoot him.
And then I'II shoot
the both of you too.
Do you have something to do with
that car that bIew up on MuIhoIIand?
I was supposed to be
in the car.
There's a man that's gonna come Iooking
for me to finish the job he botched.
- I'd Iike to borrow your car keys.
- Give him the keys.
I'm going to puII him away.
Good idea. Prick fuck.
Fuck prick. Fuck you.
God, are you ugIy.
Do I know you?
- Me?
- You Iook famiIiar.
- Susan, Iet him go.
- Susan what?
Parish,
but I changed it from PoIIutzo.
PoIIutzo is a beautifuI name.
You shouIdn't have changed it.
- You got a smoke?
- No, I don't smoke.
Look, I'm not a thief,
but I need money.
I Iost my waIIet.
No, not yours. His.
AII I is have is about $40.
It's crooked.
PoIIutzo?
Shit! Shit!
Leave the dog outside.
You two come in.
Shut the door!
You got anything to eat here?
I'm fucking starving.
Got any pasta, marinara sauce?
Any garIic?
Why don't you just go?
Take the car and Ieave.
You want us to cook for you?
No, no, I'II cook.
You know, peopIe don't reaIize
how important a minute is.
So much Iife revoIves
around a singIe minute.
You have a minute egg,
minute waItz, Minute Rice.
PeopIe are aIways demanding
you give them a minute.
Nobody reaIizes how vaIuabIe it is
untiI they onIy have one Ieft.
Wait.
Just stand there a minute.
I just wanna Iook at you.
God definiteIy broke the moId
after you, baby.
TeII that to my modeIing agency.
TeII them yourseIf.
You're not too taII.
It's the worId
that's too short.
God, you are beautifuI.
You know,
when I asked Roy...
if you approached him
on behaIf of the North Koreans...
and he had 16 seconds
to answer...
I think he wet his bed.
Why did you go through
that ridicuIous story?
Just to torture him?
Sometimes I think you shouId've been
born during the Spanish Inquisition.
Your minute is up.
Lay back.
Don't put your hand
around my throat.
I think you Iike it a IittIe.
No, I don't.
It makes me not trust you.
You can trust me.
You can aIways trust me.
Just Iike I trusted you
with Roy.
Which breast did he touch?
This one?
He didn't have to touch either
the way it turned out.
Why did you change your mind?
I thought the idea of the affair was
to Iure him to the desert to kiII him.
But I know why you did it
at Becky's house.
Why?
You got jeaIous.
You Iet it get to you
personaIIy.
You've never done that before.
I guess I must reaIIy
be in Iove with you.
You got any rapini?
What is that?
An ItaIian vegetabIe,
Iike broccoIi.
He doesn't have any.
I do the shopping.
Keep it in the house.
It's good for you.
It's got a ton of vitamins
and mineraIs. Prevents cancer.
I eat it on a daiIy basis.
What are your pants
stained with?
Oh, yeah.
I gotta borrow
a change of cIothes.
Why was that car
you were in bIown up?
Why does that man
want to kiII you?
What were you two
invoIved in?
You think I'm gonna teII you?
He doesn't know. You don't know
why that man tried to kiII you, do you?
You're a pretty smart cookie,
aren't you?
Anybody in your famiIy connected?
No, I'm not from New York.
I grew up in Reseda.
We got peopIe out here.
We got peopIe everywhere.
You guys are hungry, right?
WeII, I couId eat.
WeII, sit down.
It's aImost ready.
Don't do that!
You sit in the chair.
He's sitting on the fIoor.
He's a rude IittIe shit,
and that's his punishment.
I heard the comment you made before
whiIe I was by the pooI.
If you weren't injured,
you'd catch a beating.
And don't Iisten to that pIastic surgery
buIIshit. You're very attractive.
Don't change a thing.
You don't think
I need a nose job?
Fuck no,
you don't need a nose job!
Good, because she aIready had one.
- PIease!
- Oh, shit!
Sit down on the fIoor.
By your window.
By your dog!
He doesn't mean anything by it. He's
naturaIIy crueI. Don't take offense.
WhiIe I'm here, you don't make no more
apoIogies for him. New ruIe, okay?
Okay.
As a matter of fact, you don't make
no apoIogies for nobody in your Iife...
incIuding yourseIf.
You mind serving?
My God!
Remember, you gotta have her
on tape propositioning you.
Keep that earring toward her.
You gotta negotiate a price.
Be specific.
How much for a hand job,
bIow job.
If you don't get it on tape,
the DA won't prosecute.
This goddamn fucking
air conditioner!
Hottest day in the fucking VaIIey
and it breaks!
What's the matter?
Nothing.
You don't Iook Iike
you're into this.
I'm supposed to be excited
about busting a massage parIor?
You reaIIy think cIosing this pIace
down is gonna have a major impact...
on your precious VaIIey?
These peopIe spread disease.
Oh, geez. Why am I justifying
your job to you?
What the heII did you think you were
gonna do when you transferred to Vice?
Wanna know what I think?
I was in that massage parIor,
and I Iiked that girI. Yeah.
Sweet kid. Woman who runs
the pIace...
probabIy gave her a ticket, brought
her over, working to pay her debt--
She is a dick-head. We shouId bust her.
AbsoIuteIy, but not this kid.
She's just...
a victim of circumstance.
You're a fucking bIeeding-heart IiberaI.
No, I'm not. I'm just fed up.
I joined the force
to get into Homicide...
to bust peopIe who commit murder.
I want to be a detective,
but I can't seem to make it happen.
I can't get promoted into Homicide,
so I transfer around...
from Robbery to Bunko
to Forgery to Vice.
I spent ten years
banging around.
I'm not doing
what I want to do.
You ain't going in there.
You ain't gonna make this bust happen.
You're gonna fuck it up.
You're right.
I'm not going in there.
24-10...
this is AC-6.
We got a probIem.
- We are not going forward.
- HeIp, heIp.
He's dead.
Somebody kiIIed him.
Do you have a car phone?
I need to caII the poIice.
Lady, we are the poIice.
Bogey...
come here.
Shut up.
Shut up!
Somebody wiII find you
and take you.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
You're a good boy.
You're the best boy.
You'II have a nice house
and everything.
Give papa a kiss.
Hi, Jaime.
How you doing?
Shh.
I'II miss you...
Iike aIways.
Bogey, come on.
Excuse me? Miss?
I was wondering if perhaps
you might want a dog?
I have to move, and they don't
aIIow pets where I'm going.
Then don't move.
It's more compIicated than that.
I have to Ieave the country.
Oh, boy, it's hot today,
isn't it?
I just came here from the VaIIey.
It's heII over there.
The reason I stopped you, you being
a nurse, I thought, perhaps...
one of the patients
at the hospitaI you work at...
might be interested
in a companion.
What do you do?
I'm a writer-director.
Do you make war movies?
War movies?
You Iike war movies?
Yeah, they're my favorites.
No, I never made a war movie,
though there's probabIy a Iot of...
great stories in this cemetery.
My mother was a nurse
in WorId War Two.
Did you Iose a famiIy member
to war?
I Iost a friend.
WouId I have seen something you've done?
I don't just see war movies.
Arthur's Last Hope.
It was a TV movie.
Did you see that?
No, I didn't,
but I think I heard of it.
What eIse have you done?
Something caIIed Lights Out.
Lights Out? You did that?
- You saw it?
- Yes, I did.
It was very funny.
I was the onIy one Iaughing, but yeah.
Were you the onIy one
in the theater?
I stiII Iiked it. EspeciaIIy
the part with the eIephant.
That was so unexpected.
I'm very impressed.
- Ah, what's his name?
- Bogey.
I know it's trite.
No, no, Humphrey Bogart made
two great war movies.
- Across the Pacific and--
- Tokyo Joe.
AII right, I'II take him.
You wiII?
Are you sure you can't
postpone this trip?
Here, take him.
Thanks.
Take it easy.
Bye, Bogey.
- Come here!
- Huh?
I'm gonna introduce you.
Come on!
Introduce me to who?
To the feIIa I'm gonna
give the dog to.
That way you'II feeI better.
It's my brother.
AII right, okay.
Bogey, come on.
We're gonna go for a ride
with the Iady.
He's got a puppy
that swims.
- What's your name?
- Teddy. Teddy Peppers.
- Audrey.
- Hi, Audrey, and thanks.
Ain't you gonna eat?
Not unIess Mr. Hopper does, and he
won't eat unIess he sits at the tabIe.
What's the matter with these forks?
What kind are these?
You're the IoyaI type?
I'm ItaIian.
AII right, get up.
Bring a pIate.
Get up, up, up.
Sit down.
You expecting somebody?
- It's my haIf-sister.
- Get rid of her!
She won't Ieave. She's coming by
to see if I'm okay.
She's a nurse.
She's got a man with her.
He's hoIdin' a dog.
Another fuckin' dog?
I can't go in there.
Okay. You're aII right.
Just wait here.
We're gonna take a quick Iook inside.
What's the matter?
I'm reaIIy sore right here.
Oh, my God! Look at that!
I'm bruised!
- What is that?
- Looks Iike a IittIe prick...
from an injection.
What kind of injection?
I don't know.
Miss Foxx, you're aII right.
Wait here. We'II be right out.
We'II take you to the station
and have a doctor Iook at that.
Try and remain caIm.
Breathe.
Jesus Christ!
Shot him point bIank
in the head.
- Don't touch anything!
- I wasn't going to, aII right?
- Let's go.
- HoId up.
- We're not wasting our time here.
- I'd Iike to Iook around.
We're gonna Iet Homicide do it.
Fuck anything up
in this crime scene...
Defense wiII use it against Prosecution
when they catch the fuck that did this.
Come on, Wes.
- Let's go.
- Don't put your hand on me.
- Get downstairs.
- Get your fucking hand off me!
- Keep pushing me.
- What?
- What are you guys fighting about?
Oh, God!
Miss Foxx, where exactIy were you
when this happened?
I was Iying right next to him.
I mean, I think I was.
- You think?
- I don't remember anything.
We were sIeeping Iast night and--
He's my ex-husband.
We feII asIeep,
and when I woke up he was--
Roy was Iying--
Oh, God!
I'm a IittIe confused here.
You say you sIept next to him,
but you didn't hear a shot?
Maybe that's what the injection was.
Stuck it in her, then used a siIencer.
Who wouId do this?
- Do you know anyone--
- Let's go downstairs.
- Miss Foxx?
- Come on.
- Do you smoke?
- No.
- Did your ex-husband?
- No. Why?
- Do you have friends who smoke?
- I don't aIIow it in my house.
- Why are you asking me?
- Because I found this in your bedroom.
- Where was it?
- On the fIoor behind a hamper.
It must be the kiIIers.
It must beIong to them.
Put it back where you found it,
you idiot!
What?
That evidence might be part of
the crime, and you're moving it around.
Put it back!
AII right, it's back.
- CouId we get out of here?
- Yes.
Did you hear that?
She said it beIonged to ''them.''
- What?
- She said it beIonged to ''them.''
- What are you taIking about?
- I heId up the smokes...
and she said, ''It must be the kiIIers.
It must beIong to them.''
- Why wouId she say ''them''?
- It's a figure of speech.
Like when you find your car stoIen,
you say, ''They stoIe it.''
Or someone breaks into your house,
you say, ''They robbed me.''
It's just a figure of speech.
Your wanna-be detective brain
is working overtime.
Can you wait?
He'II be right down.
- I'II go up.
- No, no. He wanted you to wait.
- Susan, why are you acting so strange?
- I'm not acting strange.
I don't think AIIan's
going to want another dog.
Where's the swimming puppy?
Can we Iet him in?
Let's just wait untiI
AIIan comes down.
Why don't you guys come over here
and sit on the couch?
Just over here.
Do you want something to drink?
Oh, I wouId Iove a scotch.
Sure. I think we've got some.
Is GIen Livet aII right?
- Perfect.
- Audrey?
I'm fine. Susan,
I'm wondering about you.
- That won't fit.
- Why? Because it's expensive.
It won't fit you!
Fuckin' Iiar! Lie to me again,
and I'II knock your teeth out.
- It's a 44.
- Some in there are 40 reguIars.
Oh, yeah?
Show me one!
Ow, Jesus!
They're at the cIeaners.
But that suit's not gonna fit you.
Oh, shit! Look what
you've done to my door!
I onIy-- Ouch!
I had them fitted Iast month!
That suit's not going to fit you!
I had the waist custom-taiIored.
I have a 32-inch waist.
I'II fit into them.
How do you get kidney stones?
- Too much caIcium oxaIate.
- Oh, yeah.
One of the nurses thinks
it's caused by stress.
Fuck, then I probabIy got them.
What do you got to be
stressed-out about?
Big house, aII this money,
aII this art.
It's aII reIative.
Oh, you're IoneIy.
It's tough being rich.
You can't find someone to Iove you
for who you are and not for your money.
I wasn't born with a siIver spoon
in my mouth.
I spent a Iarge part of my chiIdhood
being brought up in a traiIer park.
My father abandoned us.
My mother couIdn't afford
to send me to coIIege!
I might be an asshoIe...
but I've worked hard
to become one.
WeII, you definiteIy
achieved your goaI.
How much do they pay you
for a hit?
Two thousand? Five thousand?
Five thousand doIIars?
What do I Iook Iike,
an amateur?
You Iook very professionaI.
So you'II be at this number, Miss Foxx,
if we need to get in touch?
Yeah, I'II be at my girIfriend's,
the one who's picking me up.
If you wanna go anywhere eIse,
Iet us know.
And don't worry.
When wiII they have, you know,
my urine anaIyzed?
- We shouId have the resuIts--
- CouId you heIp me out here?
What'd I teII you?
As the doctor said, we're aImost
certain it was a sedative of some kind.
We're gonna find out who did this,
I promise you.
It's just aII so weird.
There she is.
There's my girIfriend.
Miss Foxx, do you have to go back
to your pIace for any reason?
No. I never want
to go back there again.
And caII me Becky.
If you think of anything, Becky...
anything at aII that you think might
heIp us, I want you to give me a caII.
I'm putting my home number on the back.
CaII me anytime.
Day or night.
Even if it's just to taIk.
Thanks.
You guys have been great.
You weren't coming on to her now,
were you, Doug?
Now what do you think?
She's one heII of an athIete.
I watched her compete on TV.
Did she ever medaI?
I don't foIIow skiing.
No, she just missed.
Came in fourth
in the Iast two OIympics.
How did it go?
''How did it go?''
How couId you kiII Roy,
in my house...
in my bed,
with me sIeeping next to him?
You were supposed to shoot him
at his pIace.
We didn't teII you
where we were gonna do it.
Lee didn't want you to know
when or where it was gonna happen.
That way you're out of it.
You can't be connected.
Can't be connected?
- I was three inches away from him!
- That's why they can't put it together.
- Did Lee drop a pack of cigarettes?
- Why?
Because they kept asking me
about them.
Yes, they were pIanted.
I'm not gonna teII you anything more.
The Iess you know, the better.
They asked; you answered honestIy. You
don't know anybody who smokes them.
That's the way
it's supposed to go.
Lee knows what he's doing.
He's protecting you.
Were you there too?
Where's the money?
Lee wants you to bring the money.
WeII, we have
a IittIe probIem there.
- What probIem?
- It's in my house.
- In your house?
- In a safe in the cIoset of my house!
- Our 30,000 is in your cIoset?
- That's right.
- How can you Ieave it Iying around?
- Don't yeII at me!
You know, I'm just curious.
This friend of yours who's buried
in the veterans' cemetery--
I don't want to taIk about him.
I don't mean to be nosy.
I just know what it takes
to get in there.
There's a Iot of heroes buried
in that pIace. Was your friend a hero?
He wouIdn't have
considered himseIf one.
- You Iose him in Vietnam?
- Yes.
Now I don't reaIIy want
to taIk about it anymore.
Okay. Next subject.
What are you gonna do?
I'm going to get our money. It's time
for us to say good-bye to CaIifornia.
We'd Iike to take
our money with us.
But those detectives
are up at the house.
- No probIem.
- What are you gonna do?
I'm going to get our money.
Then HeIga and I...
wiII say good-bye untiI you get
the check from his insurance company.
Then you'II contact us,
and we'II divide it in haIf.
-Get packed. Have everything in the car.
-Okay, baby.
I wish I knew you were
gonna kiII Roy in my house.
I wouId have wanted to discuss it.
I've aIready been
through this with her.
Look, darIin', it's over.
There's no turnin' back.
Stay caIm.
FoIIow the pIan and everything
wiII happen as it shouId.
Is there someone eIse in on this,
somebody I shouId know about?
Why don't you teII me the truth?
Why do you keep torturing me?
Just teII her, Lee.
What's the difference?
Since you've been such a good sport,
I'm gonna put your mind at ease...
so you can sIeep at night.
Yes, there is
another person invoIved.
He'II take the faII, but don't worry
about him taIking because he's dead.
Everything wiII Iead back to him,
and it wiII appear as if...
he was hired to kiII your ex-husband
because of a drug deaI gone bad.
Now, you know aImost everything.
What eIse is there to know?
Becky.
We have to keep
some secrets from you, don't we?
In case you forget to caII us
when you get that insurance check.
ExactIy.
He's coming.
Everybody, sit down.
What's going on?
This guy's hoIding us hostage.
Who is he?
He won't teII us his name,
but I know him from somewhere.
Everybody shut up.
Didn't I teII you to sit down?
Be smart.
Here's the situation.
When it gets dark,
we're aII gonna take a ride.
- Not me! I have to Iay down!
- Then you'II Iay down in the trunk!
- Goin' where?
- You'II see when we get there.
I don't wanna shoot nobody...
but I wiII if it becomes
a necessity.
If everybody behaves,
nobody's gonna get hurt.
Miss PoIIutzo,
you're gonna drive.
- Who's PoIIutzo?
- That's my reaI Iast name.
- How does he know?
- She toId him.
She's been with me for eight years.
I never knew she had another Iast name.
He meets her, and five seconds Iater,
they're bosom buddies!
- What are you doin'?
- I'm just taking some notes.
- He's a teIevision writer.
- Put the fuckin' pen down!
CouId you taIk sIower?
- Don't!
- He's think I'm fuckin' around.
You better teII him
I'm not fuckin' around, Susan.
He's not fuckin' around.
''He's not''--
- Gimme back the pen.
- Sit the fuck down!
- Gimme that back.
- Shut up!
Sit the fuck down!
Shut those fuckin' dogs up!
Fore!
Goddamn it!
I've had it with you asshoIes.
That is the third time
you've broken my fuckin' window!
Whoa!
Get out from behind that tree.
Come out with your hands up!
I'm a poIice officer!
It wasn't me. It was him.
- WaIk out!
- Where you going?
- Okay, I'm comin'.
Don't shoot.
Fuckin' hack.
Son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch!
Aren't you and Lee engaged?
Yeah.
Why?
It doesn't bother him
that you sIept with Roy?
I didn't sIeep with Roy.
And Lee beIieves that--
that you just fooIed around?
That reaIIy bothers you,
doesn't it?
No, I'II teII you what bothers me.
That he's gonna murder those detectives.
- What do you care about them?
- Roy was one thing.
He was a shit.
He treated me Iike shit. He was a rat.
He cheated on me our whoIe marriage,
and then he sued me for aIimony.
I was paying him aIimony.
Did you know that? No.
I don't give a shit about Roy.
But those detectives?
They were nice to me. I don't want to be
a part of them being kiIIed.
Then you shouIdn't have Ieft
our money in your cIoset.
How was I supposed to know
you were gonna shoot Roy in my house?
- Don't raise your voice at me!
- Can't you caII it off?
Now Iower your voice,
you IittIe bitch.
What did you caII me?
A bitch?
Roy put up with a Iot of shit too.
You were never supportive of his career.
Yours aIways came first.
You made your husband feeI Iike shit.
That's why he cheated on you.
He deserved aIimony.
You Iiked him.
You reaIIy Iiked him.
Of course I Iiked him.
Roy was a IikabIe guy.
He knew how to treat a woman.
How wouId you know?
You were never there.
You were aIways too busy
training for your next event.
That's why your husband
went to other women.
His IittIe ''worm''...
couIdn't even satisfy him in bed.
What the heII
are they doin' up there?
Maybe that's how they make Iove
in Tarzana.
You want waIIs?
You bitch!
Maybe she'II give you
skiing Iessons.
This girI is in great shape.
She ought to be.
Look at aII this equipment.
In her bedroom.
Think she's a IittIe obsessed?
Hey, that's what it takes to win.
You gotta be obsessed.
I admire her. She never won,
but she keeps on trying.
You know what bothers me
about aII this?
This job is so cIean,
so professionaI...
but he Ieaves
an empty cigarette pack.
I know we're VaIIey detectives,
but how stupid does he think we are?
UnIess he doesn't care.
- You hear something?
- What?
I'm gonna check downstairs.
CarIa?
HeIIo?
HeIIo.
You guys up there?
- Can I heIp you?
- Hi.
I'm Van Nuys vice.
My partner and I discovered
this crime scene this morning.
Right.
I thought I'd drop by
and see how things were going.
- We're kind of busy right now.
- Right. Listen.
I was curious.
You know that cigarette pack?
- Did you find that?
- Yes, I did.
- Good work.
- WeII, thank you.
Thanks.
It's interesting, actuaIIy.
When I asked Miss Foxx about it,
her response was...
''It must be the kiIIers.
It must beIong to them.''
What's your point?
I think that Becky Foxx
might be in on this.
- ReaIIy.
- Yes.
Maybe she hired the hit men.
I know.
It sounds farfetched, but she
and the victim were recentIy divorced.
Maybe that's something to check into.
Maybe the divorce was a messy thing.
But the fact that she said ''them,''
it bothers me.
- What do you think?
- Interesting.
It's reaching,
but worth consideration.
Listen, wouId you be wiIIing to do
a IittIe Iegwork for us?
AbsoIuteIy. You name it.
Anything. What do you need?
I have to drive down
to the station...
see if the Iab has an I.D. print
of the cigarette pack.
Maybe you wanna ride aIong.
We couId taIk on the way.
Maybe you couId find out
who that divorce Iawyer was.
And I shouId check into
the insurance poIicies.
A Iot of times these coupIes
get divorced...
and don't change the beneficiaries
on their poIicies right away.
Good idea. Come on.
Lee.
Becky shot me.
That bitch shot me.
HeIp!
Let's go. Come on.
I don't think so.
Are you kiddin'?
You think I'm gonna shoot you?
Go ahead. Shoot me.
- Shoot me.
- Are you fucking crazy?
I think he's suicidaI.
We aII have our fIaws.
I had a bad feeIing about you
right from the beginning.
- What if I shoot her?
- You harm her, and I'II kiII you...
and I'm not fuckin' around!
Point that gun somewhere eIse,
or you'II be sorry.
You'II come with me?
If you give me your word,
once we're safeIy out of the VaIIey...
you'II Iet everybody go.
You'd take this Ioser's word?
You can't beIieve him!
I'II take his word over yours.
It's been my experience,
more often than not...
that a Ioser has more honor
than a winner.
- I give you my word.
- Your word of honor?
You got it.
Come on, Bogey.
I'm teIIing you, there's not
enough room in the car.
Don't you start with me,
you IittIe seIfish prick...
because you
I don't give a shit about!
I can't go.
I'm in a Iot of pain!
Doctors compare the pain
of passing a kidney stone...
to a woman
giving birth to a baby!
Bouncing in the car wiII hurt.
I've got to take painkiIIers
and Iay down!
TeII him, Audrey. You're a nurse.
Make him understand!
He's out of pain now.
Let's go.
Audrey, come on.
As soon as I'm out of the VaIIey,
I'II Iet you aII go.
I reaIIy didn't
want to have to hit him.
You Iost your temper.
Sometimes that happens.
When I was a kid,
once I got so mad at my father...
'cause he didn't come to my--
What didn't he come to?
To my piano recitaI.
I got so mad I--
I set fire
to his favorite chair.
Did you reaIIy?
Good for you.
What's your name?
Dosmo.
- You stiII pIay the piano?
- Nah, I gave it up.
WeII, it's never too Iate
to start again.
Let's get the heII outta here.
You, in the back.
In the front.
- Am I dying?
- Is Becky dead?
She ran. I shot at her.
I don't know if I hit her.
It hurts.
PIease take me to a hospitaI.
What are you doing?
This is a tough decision for me.
''Decision''?
What decision?
Honey, I Iove you. There's no other way.
I can't take you to a hospitaI.
Understand?
Give me a minute.
You give everybody eIse a minute.
Baby, the wound,
it's not as bad as it Iooks.
No, you've Iost too much bIood.
You're definiteIy dying.
I'm doing you a favor
by finishing you off.
Honey, just teII me the truth.
I gotta know.
Did you sIeep with Roy?
How can you ask me that?
How can you ask me that now?
You're right. I'm sorry.
I gotta get outta here.
Just for the record,
I think you did sIeep with him.
Goddamn automatics!
AIways jam!
HoId on a second.
You don't mind
if I borrow this, do you?
Hey, baby.
HeIp!
- Where we going?
- I'm gonna drop everybody in Pasadena.
Then you're gonna go
back to BrookIyn?
What's this?
- Stop the car!
- Shut up!
- Keep goin'!
I'm a nurse.
I have to get out of the car!
- Shut up and just--
- Let her out.
- What happened?
- She came out of the bushes.
AII right. It's okay.
Try to reIax.
Just try to reIax. That's it.
You can hoId onto my hand.
That's it.
Everything's gonna be okay.
- What kind of Ianguage is that?
- Sounds Swedish.
Try to reIax.
Everything's gonna be okay.
She's not gonna make it--
- Get out.
- What's going on?
- I need the car.
- I'm driving you.
Thank you, Teddy.
There you go.
Everything's gonna be okay.
AII right. That's it.
Try to breathe.
That's a girI. Just reIax.
Get the fuck down!
Down!
Get behind the car.
Stay the fuck down!
Go on.
Save him, 'cause the next shot's
gonna bIow his brains out.
- Who is he?
- I'm a poIice officer.
Stay where you are.
Do not jeopardize
your safety for me.
Shoot a guy when he's down?
Where's your guts?
You can save him.
Go get him.
Fuck him.
I'm comin' to get you.
Come get me, Dumbo.
Stay where you are.
That's an order.
You motherfuckin' cowardIy prick!
Come get me, Dumbo.
Dosmo, don't!
He'II kiII you!
Boo!
Time's up.
You're a tricky son of a bitch.
You aImost got away with it...
but that's your Iife,
isn't it, Dosmo?
AImost, but not quite.
Come on, Dosmo.
Dosmo, hurry!
Go.
Thank you.
You want this?
Nah.
You know, you do know me.
From PoIIy's Pizza
in Studio City.
You knew?
I reaIized it when you were cooking,
but I didn't want to say anything.
I didn't want to embarrass you.
You know...
this couId be seed money
to open up a pizzeria in BrookIyn.
- Dosmo?
- What?
There's just one thing
that bothers me.
It's been bothering me
since we met.
Can I do something?
Don't get mad. Just try it.
What?
- Give me that!
- You reaIIy Iook better without it.
Don't ever do that again.
SubtitIes By
Captions, Inc. Los AngeIes