Action!
Move! Move, damn it!
Damn it, move!
This is the opening of
"24: Live Another Day."
We start with CIA ops chasing somebody.
The series begins running, you know?
Freeze it right there.
That Jack Bauer has survived,
intact, to live another day
is good news for a lot of people.
What the hell have you been
doing the past four years?
I was really excited
that "24" was coming back.
I couldn't believe it.
There's fireballs. There's action.
It's all good, "24" kind of stuff.
It's a high-octane thriller
with, literally, time ticking down.
- It's a self-destruct program.
- Damn it!
Why is he here? Why is he back?
Jack Bauer is a traitor and a psychopath.
Is he here to harm the president?
Is he here to help the president?
We don't know.
If an American president is
assassinated on foreign soil,
you're looking at a world war.
London and the CIA will never be the same.
Man: Action!
It's Bauer.
This year, we have some
crazy stuff coming up,
stuff we haven't done before.
Coto: It's a story that starts
from moment one, this season.
The train is already moving,
and you got to run to catch up.
And you're on for a ride from
episode one all the way through.
There's not one letup.
Simone: Help me!
What's wonderful is it is "24,"
but it's a new iteration of "24."
The show is set in London, England.
And it's the first time we've
actually shot fully on location.
What brings Jack to London
is he's been out of the United States
since the very end of season eight.
He managed to escape to Eastern Europe,
where he's been underground
for 4 1/2 years...
Man: Target acquired.
And has resurfaced because of
the circumstances of the day,
to protect the president
of the Untied States.
Katz: James Heller,
played by William Devane,
was formerly in the series
as the secretary of defense.
President Heller, In
this case, is in London.
Man: People have never been comfortable
with our using drones for
targeted assassinations.
Mr. President?
I'm thinking I don't blame them.
Devane: We're here to negotiate
a treaty... a drone treaty.
It's a precarious situation,
so I have to come and
actually do it myself.
James: I think the most important thing
is for the prime minister
to hear the news from me.
Katz: And while he's there, of course,
Jack emerges with news of an attack.
The question being asked in the
initial part of the series is,
"is Jack Bauer there to
assassinate the president?"
Gordon: Jack is an international fugitive,
and he's wanted, not just by our country,
but by every country.
I know How many lives you've saved,
but they're just gonna
see a man who snapped,
who went off on a... a revenge spree.
A man whose country labels him a criminal.
Coto: Fans of the series remember,
you know, Jack left off as a fugitive.
You were really something...
in your time.
Basically, CTU was turned off,
and Jack was left in the darkness.
And now a CIA team is hunting down Jack.
[Groans]
Man: Cut!
But Jack is onto something,
and there's much more than
just him having been caught.
There's a larger mystery
that he's trying to uncover.
Cassar: Why is he here? Why is he back?
Does this have something
to do with the president?
And does it have something
to do with these drones?
So, really, that becomes our mystery.
Two weeks ago, I intercepted intel framing
an assassination attempt
on President Heller
supposed to take place
in London... here, today.
- You're gonna help me.
- I'm afraid I can't do that.
But you don't have a choice.
Gordon: Despite being hunted
and... and being made a pariah,
Jack is still a hero.
He cannot help himself.
Has anyone ever mentioned
your rather... spectacularly rude habit
of asking for favors accompanied
by the threat of a gun?
Sutherland: What brought me
back was really Howard Gordon,
who was our lead writer.
Called me up and said, "Look,
I've... I've had this idea
"for about 12 episodes for a while,
"and it's kind of just gnawing at me.
Would you be interested in doing it?"
Gordon: We really wanted to see Jack Bauer.
Look, it's really like
seeing an old friend again.
And I have to say, when we saw the dailies
of Jack Bauer for the first time,
we just all smiled and
looked at each other.
Katz: He really looks great. He's cut.
He looks like someone who's been living raw
and on the edge for years.
You know who I am.
Trigger an alarm, and
I'll blow your head off.
I think he found Jack again pretty quickly.
Kiefer and Jack Bauer are pretty
well connected at this point.
We didn't waste any time.
Our first week,
we were just stock blocked
with action and dialogue,
so he had to fit into and he
had to do it quickly, and he did.
Sutherland: And it is very
exciting to be Jack Bauer again.
Move!
Gordon: It is not just Kiefer, of course.
A good number of the old
team are back together.
It was like the band
came together for this.
Evan is a... is a... is a veteran.
He's the most veteran writer on the show...
was there since season two,
and I came in at season five.
Katz: We're lucky enough
to get John Cassar back,
who was our producer
and director for years.
Cassar: I've done 58
episodes and the TV movie,
so to have it come back
again is very exciting.
Sutherland: Jon directed so
many of the seasons of "24"
that I really do rely on him greatly.
Action!
We're gonna push this as hard as we can.
If we lose the base,
those men will have died in vain!
Look, I'm not saying we quit.
I'm just suggesting that we withdraw,
wait until the rancor dies down.
I don't have time.
Katz: We're doing 12
episodes, instead of 24.
This is a special-event series.
Here we go!
Those 12 episodes
are still gonna represent one full day.
Somewhere within it,
we're going to skip an hour
or two, or maybe a big chunk.
Sutherland: We're not
trying to change the show.
Jack is not gonna be skipping.
You know, it's not gonna
be a romantic comedy.
He's gonna have a crappy day,
and he's gonna fight his way through it,
and... and... and that's what the show is.
Certain dynamics are different,
but the show isn't different.
You're going after the wrong guy.
Cassar: I think all the
action and special effects
are what you usually expect on "24,"
and, really, that's what I'm going for...
and maybe a little beyond what you expect,
and that's what we always,
I think, expect our
audience to expect from us.
Action!
Cut. Yeah, baby!
[Claps] That's the one.
[Beeping]
This year may be my favorite
cast that we've ever had.
It's extraordinary.
Cassar: First, we've got some characters
that you loved that we've brought back.
My God. Chloe.
Woman: What happened to you?
Coto: The notorious Chloe O'Brian.
Chloe's not nearly the same individual
that we saw in season eight.
Rajskub: Chloe is with the group
that believes in information being freed.
They have no qualms
about letting out secrets.
It's the opposite of how
Chloe used to believe.
Coto: She has turned anti-government.
She has become
kind of like a darker
version of Edward Snowden.
Intelligence agencies keep secrets
because what they're doing is criminal.
That's naive, even for you.
You're smarter than that.
You don't get to judge me,
not after what I've been through.
Rajskub: Chloe and Jack start out at odds
because Jack has kind
of come out of nowhere
and wants her to go with him
and help him to stop this
plot against the president.
Jack, in four years of hiding,
doesn't really trust anybody,
and Chloe has gone
through her own evolution.
And they don't start off
as the best of friends.
We're not the same Chloe
and Jack as we were,
and we're not seeing eye to eye.
Chloe: Why are you doing this, Jack?
Some fantasy that, if you save Heller,
all will be forgiven?
You knew Heller. You know he's a good man.
No, I don't know that.
William Devane is reprising
his role as Heller.
Devane: I'm now the president,
the most powerful man in the free world.
Katz: His daughter Audrey,
who Jack was deeply in
love with, and she with him,
but who ended up going to
China and being tortured
for information about Jack.
Audrey is a lot better than
when we last saw her. [Chuckles]
Audrey is working again with her dad.
I know that look.
What's your problem?
Devane: She's like the
lady of the White House.
Her mother passed away years ago,
so she basically does everything with me.
It's sort of that thing, you know,
when someone has gone
through a really hard time,
I think people are fragile around her
and kind of protecting her.
Katz: She's also married
to his chief of staff,
the man who helped her come back
from... from a near-catatonic
mental breakdown.
Donovan: I play Mark Boudreau,
and he is the chief of staff
to the president of the United States.
Coto: Tate Donovan is a great
character this season, Boudreau.
He's operating purely from
pain in his opposition to Bauer,
who he sees as a threat,
not only to the country
but to his wife and to her
well-being, to her sanity.
The president should be made aware.
You weren't there.
You didn't see what
Bauer did to his family...
what he did to Audrey.
He really does not like Jack Bauer.
As long as she lives,
she's never gonna hear the name Jack Bauer.
Donovan: In the first episode,
I order his death or something terrible,
and, you know, that doesn't
bode well for a character,
if you order Jack Bauer's death.
[Laughs]
Coto: So, it's an interesting triangle
that's kind of cracked apart
when... when Jack appears.
Katz: With Tate Donovan,
we have several new people that feel like
they were born to be on the show.
Where in God's name have you been?
Chloe is working with the
leader of a hacker group.
His name is Adrian Cross, and
he's played by Michael Wincott.
And he's a charismatic,
almost prophet-like figure
who presides over this group of misfits
who help him dig out
information about governments
and spread it.
We acquire and disseminate
information... nothing more.
You make it sound like
what you do is benign.
We both know that's not true.
Gordon: The CIA station
chief is Agent Navarro,
who's played by Benjamin Bratt.
Bratt: For me as an actor,
to be invited to come on
board and... and participate,
to really jump on board this roller coaster
that is a global phenomenon
has been a real thrill.
Man: Cut!
With "24," you can never be certain
that someone is what they say they are.
But what I know of who
I play, at this point,
is that he is a calm leader.
He's cautious. He's very thorough.
Hey, um...
sorry I shut you down.
Strahovski: I play Kate
Morgan, the CIA agent.
When we meet her, she's packing
up because she's being demoted.
Coto: Her husband was
revealed to be a traitor,
selling secrets to the Chinese,
and she's about to be
transferred back to the States.
Strahovski: Before that, she
was a pretty great field agent,
very impulsive, and one
of the best that they had.
- Katz: She sees capturing Bauer
- Bang! Bang!
- As her way of redeeming herself.
- Drop your weapon!
- Turn around!
- Bratt: She has instincts that
are very in sync with Jack
Bauer when he was a young agent,
and goes a long way to proving herself
to be reestablished as part of my crew.
I'm the one that got inside Bauer's head...
not you, not Erik, not anybody.
She has to go
head-to-head with Jack,
and that's not easy to
do, for anybody to do.
Erik: What is she doing here?
I reinstated her, Just
until we get Bauer back.
Erik Ritter arrived at the station
to take Kate's job when she transfers out,
and he's impatiently waiting.
She might be trying to prove herself.
I don't care.
But you don't expect me
to work with her, do you?
I expect you to do your job
without questioning my orders.
Gbenga, who, of course, everyone
knows from "The Wire" fame,
is Erik.
Erik thinks that Kate
is not fit to do the job.
She may have been at one
point, but not any longer,
and he is, and he'll do it well.
Navarro: Kate Morgan isn't there.
She's not even on the books.
This goes bad, it's on you.
When it looks like she's gaining traction,
he's very threatened at first.
Cut them loose!
Kate: Leave him.
Are you out of your mind?!
He's coming with us. He knows something.
This was not your fault.
Margot, our main
antagonist, our main villain,
is a woman who swears her
revenge on President Heller.
Margot is a driven,
motivated, passionate woman
with a cause in mind,
and her cause is revenge.
This family has worked
too hard for too long
to let anyone or anything get in its way.
Katz: Margot's daughter,
Simone, has been raised
with not only radical politics
and to believe in terrorism,
but to obey her mother
and do whatever her mother asks.
Simone has a very strong set of beliefs
that she's been brought up with.
She would stop at nothing.
She is ruthless, in a way,
but I don't see her as,
in any way, a bad person.
I think she just genuinely
does what she thinks is right.
Simone: That man is trying to kill me!
Help me! Help me!
Man: Leave the girl alone!
[Grunting]
Sutherland: "24" really
is an ensemble show.
It can only be as good as... as
the cast that takes you there,
and we couldn't have asked for better.
Erik: I will shoot you in the
back of the head... I swear to God!
There is something about the UK...
in many ways, our relationship to the UK
is so special and so deep
that it felt like the right place.
And it's iconic.
Cassar: This is really
the first time we've taken
the whole production to another
city, so it's very exciting,
and I think we picked the right city.
I just love this city.
London's filled with history.
The visuals speak for themselves.
You can point the camera
almost anywhere, and it's great.
Our first day, we were
right in central London,
you know, right off of piccadilly circus.
I was born here,
and I was about 3,
so there's a kind of a
nationalistic pride I have
about England.
Not only will it be exciting,
as it has been for me
to work here as an actor and for our crew,
I hope for the viewing audience,
it'll be like going on a trip.
You know?
We're gonna show you London
in a very different way.
B-marker.
Erik: Stop where you are!
Stop! Get on the ground!
We shot right on the Thames.
We were just on the beach.
And we had boats coming up
with guys with machine guys
and guys coming down the wharf
and another guy coming over down the beach,
and so I was in the middle of kind of
playing all of that action
and getting focused on that.
Man: Cut! Excellent!
And then I looked up,
and you could clearly
see that it was London.
Man: Eight camera, right
here. Exact same thing.
One of the interesting
things about "24" was,
even when we were in Los Angeles
or in New York or Washington,
it was never a show about
monuments and big buildings.
It was always... it took place
in the back streets and alleys,
and... and that's also
applied here in London.
Action.
We shot in the back alleys.
We were at a block-housing project.
So, that's all part of "24," also,
because people are hiding,
and people are undercover,
and so you can't be always
right in the main streets
with all the people.
Man: I've got a confirm on the target.
Hooded sweatshirt, 30
feet from the south wall.
Man 2: And go, go, go!
London has been very cooperative
about letting us shoot places.
So, we shot on the tube,
and we do some terrible things on the tube,
but they would not let
anyone jump the fare barrier
and... and... and get on for free.
- That was the one restriction.
- One step too far.
- Not having any of that.
- Yes. Yes.
He's coming your way. He's probably armed.
Cassar: We're doing,
you know, big shootouts,
and right on day one,
the armorers were showing us guns
that I'd never even seen before.
We've got quite a lot of
weaponry on this series,
and we're gonna start with Jack's gun.
We've updated it for this series of "24."
He used to have a HK USP Compact.
We now have a HK P30.
He also uses other agents' guns throughout,
particularly the Glock 17,
which is our CIA weapon.
We've also provided gun
cameras, which fit on the front,
give something visual for
the director to read off.
Our different tactical agents,
when we see them in the field...
they have a HK MP7.
They also have an M4 derivative,
and this is a bit of fun,
which is a corner shot
9-millimeter Glock 17,
but if I show you how it operates,
it just comes up like that.
Come back around...
and you can fire around corners.
Camera mounted on the
front with a monitor here.
- Drop the weapon! Put it on the ground!
- Putting the weapon down!
Get on the ground, Bauer!
- [Gunshots]
- Aah!
Here we go. Action!
[Screams]
My name's Mark Mottram.
I'm the stunt coordinator on "24."
Jon moves so quick.
He knows where he's going, knows the shots.
We just got to be on top
of everything, you know?
And it's got to be ready.
If I'm holding him up,
he's kicking me up the butt.
Do you know what I mean? So...
Kiefer picks it up so quick.
Do you know what I mean?
I mean [Scoffs] he's
done this a million times.
It's like driving a car to him, you know?
We literally set a few moves.
He comes in, picks it up
like, you know, nothing,
which is really quite cool, yeah.
Mark and his team, I
think, are really good,
and they really are a team.
They're shooting at us! Move! Move!
They've had a very busy
episode one and two.
[Indistinct shouting]
It was filled with fights and action,
so they've hit the floor running,
and... and the poor guys, I don't think,
are gonna get much of a break.
I think... I think
they're gonna be very busy
through the 12 episodes.
3, 2, 1, action!
Cut!
Man: All right.
The guys that do our special effects...
they've been a crack crew.
It's very important for "24."
We blow things up. It's
what we're known for.
And so, coming to the UK
was not gonna change that.
Bullet hits, things breaking,
atmosphere, obviously, in all our sets,
which is smoke and water.
In the first two episodes,
we've already had, I think,
probably over a dozen explosions.
Man: Cut! That was awesome!
[Indistinct shouting]
Gordon: "24" sort of was
created in the context of 9/11,
but Jack really has become, in some ways,
the lightning rod and the litmus test
for this very complicated
world we're living in.
So I think, culturally,
he really came to be
this reflection of what
we hoped a hero could be
in these very complicated times.
- We all wish
- They're shooting at us! Move!
we knew a Jack Bauer, had
a Jack Bauer protecting us.
He really is A pretty
classic American hero.
Jack Bauer is the kind of character
that has universal appeal in
that he is a man of principles.
Come on, Mr. Bauer.
His principles drive his every action.
Now or never.
Katz: The character has taken on
kind of a little bit of a mythic status,
a little larger than life.
There's a lot of speculation
about what's happened to him,
who he is after he fell off the deep end
at the end of season eight.
Kiefer's playing it
with an incredible amount of intensity
and need to succeed
and a need to be a hero.
The character is... it's like a kind of
this fantastic long-lost friend, you know?
And so we got to see each other again.
Fox was very, very gutsy
to... to do a show like "24."
Raver: "24," for me, was really a catalyst
for how television was
viewed and is viewed.
"24" was one of the sort of first,
like, binge-watching of shows.
Classic "24" kind of had
that addictive, you know...
all the plots leading to
the end of that episode.
You couldn't wait... you
know, the binge-watching.
And now that's become the model,
and we have so much great programming
that came after that.
Television, to me, is
the most exciting medium,
and I'm telling you this
as an actor who does films and television.
For all of those reasons
that television has become
as exciting as it is,
"24" was one of the aspects
that helped shape that,
and for that, I will always be proud.
Cassar: We were fortunate to just be
right at the leading edge of that wave.
It was kind of a new age
of... of, you know, television.
It was really exciting to
keep pushing the limits,
and... and I don't think that's gonna stop.
I mean, I think "24" is
still one of those shows,
and... and even though we're
coming back after being,
you know, after being laid off for a while,
I think we're still gonna
be on that leading edge.
Rajskub: What's cool, I think, about "24"
is that it reflects the
issues that are going on today.
Cassar: "24" was always
dealing with stories
that were ripped right
out of the headlines,
and so I think that's always
part of what we give you
when... when we give you "24."
Katz: Several things that
really have become bigger issues
in the four years since
the show's been on...
drone warfare, the advent of WikiLeaks,
and hyper-government surveillance
and people revealing that.
It's thrilling that there are
so many story lines started
and in gear right here in this first hour.
It's just amazing.
Certain facts have been covered up by us.
I think, you know,
most television would
like to be this relevant.
You don't need to have
watched the show before
to watch the show now.
We're designing it so that you can just,
you know, get on board the moving train.
Cassar: It's very quick.
- It gets your heart racing.
- Get down! Get down!
It's been described as
a soap opera on crack.
Sutherland: We shoot it
faster. It's more instinctive.
It's just simply more exciting.
Coto: It becomes an
edge-of-your-seat experience.
This is gonna be so
satisfying to the fans of "24."
The show's coming back,
and there's nothing we can do to stop it.
Hey!
They want blood!
Stop, stop.
Jack: This is bigger than President Heller.
They're planning a full-scale attack.
[Projectile whistling]
[Beeping]
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com