Some fun tonight?
Come.
What would you like to drink?
This way.
Hello.
You are...
Young At Heart 69.
Password?
Purity.
Shut up.
He's a paying customer.
Sit down, please.
Do you have the money?
Yeah.
Can I see your Sasha first?
You don't trust me?
It's a lot of money for one hour.
Your first time in my country?
You don't talk much.
Makes me a little nervous.
You want to make me nervous?
Oh, no.
No.
"No." That's good.
- "No."
- No.
Sasha.
He's a good boy.
Speaks English, a little.
One hour.
I have friends,
friends all over the world,
even in that little bastard's shit village.
And my friend there just called
to tell me that Sasha's mother
has some rich cousin in America who has,
how you say, very deep pockets.
And this uncle has hired a man,
a very serious man,
to get the kid back.
That hurts,
not only my feelings,
but my reputation, my business.
I just want the kid. I will pay more.
I love to bargain, but we have a problem.
- You've seen our faces.
- We have the same problem.
You've seen mine.
It's okay.
I will not hurt you.
Your mama sent me.
Your real name is Victor, right?
I'm here to take you out. We go home.
You ready? Let's go.
A subtitle made possible by R3V0LV3R.
Come on, come on.
Sit.
We got a problem. No one leaves.
Something's wrong. No one leaves.
- You like fireworks?
- Yeah.
Hey, over there!
Hello?
The car is waiting for you downstairs.
Get here now.
- You owe me.
- What?
I stuck my neck out for you.
Gave you intelligence.
Risked my career,
the lives of my family.
And this is what you do?
It's what I do. I got the child out.
That's good.
What about this child?
She was, what, 14?
And her?
She was nine, maybe 10.
Do you know what these fuckers do
when they think they're being raided?
They hide the underage girls in the walls.
Then you, last night, out here blasting.
The first thing they do
is shove the kids in the crawl space.
And then you turn the parking lot
into a fucking inferno.
Well, guess what?
Fire spreads.
Most of them died from smoke inhalation.
I know you mean well.
But you're not a cop.
You're a soldier.
And this is not Africa or Afghanistan.
You might be used to collateral damage,
but I'm not.
Are you arresting me?
And what?
Lose my career when they start digging?
Here's my advice.
Leave police work to the police.
Stick to what you know.
Go back to your shop.
I mean, up until recently,
Moldova wasn't even a real country,
it was part of the Soviet Union.
So, is there like a Moldovan language?
Officially, yes, but from what I read,
it's a Romanian dialect.
Apparently, a lot of people
speak Russian too.
Well, I just hope that
they speak some English.
- Is that for us?
- Only the best for my girls.
Nice. Now all we need are paparazzi.
You want paparazzi?
Hold on, princess, I'll give you paparazzi.
There. There, nice. There we go.
- Oh, yeah, I like that.
- Okay, come on.
Yeah, you are a natural.
Oh, no. No photos, no photos.
The lady doth protest too much.
Go.
That's it, that's it, perfect.
One more like that.
Okay, come on, let's go.
Andrew, I've been awake for 20 hours.
- All right, princess, come on. Mommy's tired.
- Daddy's a Jackass.
But he's our Jackass.
You know, you might actually experience
the place a little better
if you stopped a moment
to really look at the city
with your eyes.
Last week, Laurie Perkins
posted pictures from Paris.
I figure I can outdo her in uniqueness,
if not in grandeur.
Admit it, old people suck at technology.
I land this fight, I promise you
Paris is not that far behind.
Let's not worry about Paris.
Let's just focus on getting
and winning this one.
Yes, ma'am.
Fuck!
That's the guy they want you to fight?
The white guy.
He's good.
He's a monster.
Sweetheart, what's the matter?
You know,
I read you could earn
good money as a trainer.
Oh, Becky, I'm good at what I do.
Come here, let me show you something.
See this guy?
See how he only favors one side?
Right leg, right jab, boom, boom, boom.
Now, that's a weakness
his opponent is not exploiting.
He's not thinking long term.
And you do?
You betcha.
Put me in a cage with this guy,
I'd take him out two rounds, easy.
- I'll tickle him to death.
- Okay. I get it, I get it.
You're a pro.
Ready for your comeback.
You betcha.
Okay.
Now can you use your superpowers to do
something about the wireless in this place?
I'm trying to upload the pictures,
but the signal keeps dropping.
Dad.
Yeah, go try the balcony.
You might get a better signal.
Okay.
All right, I'm going to take a shower.
If it's not fixed when I come down,
I'll have them move us to a different room.
Okay.
Oh, and we need ice.
Mom said she'd get some,
but she passed out.
All right, well, let her sleep.
We'll go downstairs
and get some later, okay?
Okay.
- The signal here sucks.
- Oh, yeah.
It's best on the second floor,
near the ice machine.
Sorry I startled you. I'm Amalia.
Becky. Nice to meet you.
- You here on vacation?
- Sort of.
- My dad's on a business trip.
- Let me guess.
A lawyer?
He's a fighter, actually. MMA.
You're kidding me.
See, now that's cool.
It has its good days.
Hey, princess, how'd it
go with the internet?
Becky?
Becky.
What's wrong?
Did you let her go out by herself?
What? No.
You've reached Becky.
Tell me something good.
Becky, will you please
come back to the room?
And call me on my cell
to let me know you got this.
- How long she been gone?
- I don't know, I was in the shower.
Ten minutes, less. She
knows not to do this.
She'll be back in a minute.
Is there an ice machine on this floor?
I don't know. I'm gonna go look for her.
Call me if she comes back
so that I can kill her.
Excuse me. I'm looking for a 14-year-old
girl, about this high, blonde.
- You seen her?
- No.
Is everything all right?
Yeah, it's just my daughter.
She wandered off.
Is she missing?
No, no, not really.
- Hi.
I'm in 846.
Has my daughter been down here?
- 846, Mr. Fayden?
- Yeah.
That's my daughter.
She was looking for ice.
I haven't seen her, sorry,
but there are some ice machines...
Yeah, I already checked those out.
I'll ask my colleague.
I was busy with the ambulance. Sick guest.
- Was that a girl?
- No, an older lady.
Mr. Fayden.
Is there a problem?
Mr. Fayden is looking for his daughter.
When did you last see her?
About 30 minutes ago.
So, would you like me to call security?
Yes, yes, thank you.
Becky.
Becky!
Oh. Sorry.
What the hell?!
I'm looking for my daughter.
Have you seen her?
No. Sorry.
In international news,
the mysterious disappearance
of Becky Fayden,
the daughter of former MMA champion
Andrew Fayden,
continues to stump police.
The 14-year-old American teen went missing
only a few hours after landing in Moldova
on August 31st,
where her father was in talks
about a comeback fight
with European fight promoter
Roma Entertainment.
At a press conference this morning,
Fayden and his wife Monica
made an impassioned plea
for their daughter's return.
We beg anyone with information on this case
to please come forward.
My promoter has kindly offered
a $10,000 reward for anyone
with verifiable information
on Becky's whereabouts,
and our friends and family
have generously doubled that offer.
Becky, if you're out there,
know that we're gonna find you.
And we're gonna bring you home. Thank you.
We're closed.
We're not here to buy meat.
We're looking for...
Samson Gaul.
He's dead.
Are you sure, 'cause they
just gave us this...
The man you're looking
for is no longer here.
You were in the Legion.
You're Samson Gaul.
Sorry, ma'am. I can't help you.
Look, buddy,
I don't know what your problem is,
and I don't even care,
we need your fucking help, man.
Our daughter is missing.
She's just a child.
The police say they found nothing.
The cops are your best bet.
Money? You want some money?
'Cause, you know, look, that's okay.
It seems like everything else
in this country is for sale,
so is this enough motivation?
The man from the American Embassy
suggested that we talk to you.
Do I look like the man who can help?
Come on. It's a waste of time.
Mr. Gaul, please.
We were told that you
were the best at this.
Look, if you want a steak, come to me.
If you want to find your daughter,
go to the cops.
Believe me, you're better without me.
The man from the embassy,
that would be you?
Who else?
Since when do you babysit tourists?
It's a small embassy. We all help out.
Look, these people need you, all right?
The cops have nothing.
The raids do nothing.
The real bad guys are protected.
Your friend, the inspector?
Well, let's just say he's got the finesse
of a bull in a china shop.
Why don't you dig around?
I'm a paper pusher with security clearance.
I don't have your flexibility
or your skill set.
Sorry, I can't. You know I can't.
The girl is 14 years old.
It's been over 24 hours.
Dad, she's running out of time.
She needs you, all right?
- Plus, you need this.
- I can't!
- Stay out of it.
- Do you enjoy seeing dead people?
Do you? Do you enjoy seeing dead people?
Hey, if I want bullshit psychology,
I'll call your mother.
Well, if you don't help people anymore,
then all you are is a goddamn butcher.
Your grandpa was a butcher.
People need meat.
This girl, have you seen her?
She's my daughter.
My name is the right money.
You've seen her?
Thank you.
Hey, sweetie, you want to buy me a drink?
- No, thanks.
- Okay.
Excuse me.
Yes?
This girl, have you seen her?
Nope.
Are you sure? Take a better look.
The woman outside, the gypsy lady...
No such thing as gypsy lady.
They're all whores.
- And thieves.
- Thieving whores.
Sorry, I did not see her.
Why would the lady outside
say that she saw her?
Mister, that gypsy witch outside
has not been sober in three years.
Also, it's an easy mistake to make.
They all blondes here.
You see? Golden girls.
That's what we call the place.
Have you seen her anywhere around here?
Wow. She is... How you say...
Hot.
She's my daughter.
Why you let her come to a place like this?
I tell you, American economy, very bad.
Sending kids to make extra money.
If your daughter come here,
you're not very good father.
What'd you say to me?
Come on, partner, time to go.
Come on, I got you.
How'd you find me?
Finding people, it's what I do.
Plus, it wasn't hard.
Not many Americans running around clubs,
pissing people off.
All right, so now you want to help?
Are you sober?
Until I find your daughter.
Then, we'll see.
Why'd you change your mind?
It's the right thing to do.
One more thing, I work alone.
You're a good fighter...
But you make lots of noise.
I can see you coming miles away.
What, and they can't see you?
They never do.
We have a lead.
Your daughter was most likely
taken out of the hotel in the ambulance
that you saw when you
first ran down looking for her.
They said it was an older lady.
They were either mistaken,
or the kidnappers dyed your daughter's hair
when they drugged her unconscious.
We now know that
the guest listed as calling the ambulance
never actually stayed at the hotel.
And you're just figuring this out now?
It's been two days!
Mrs. Fayden, I share your frustration.
Do you?
Becky could be halfway
across the world by now.
And no one's asked for a ransom.
So the chances of this being a trafficking
case are 80 to 90% more likely!
Mrs. Fayden, the statistics on
the internet, they are not...
The recovery rate for kidnapped children
after 24 hours drops to 46%!
That's less than half!
Constantin, give us a moment.
Mr. and Mrs. Fayden,
let me, as you say, cut to the chase.
I have learned you have hired
a private consultant.
Mr. Samson Gaul.
At this point, we can use
all the help we can get.
- I would not place your trust in this man.
- Why?
Because he might actually get some results?
Make you look bad?
He is not a detective.
He is an ex-mercenary. A hired killer.
Do you really want such a man
working for you?
I'll hire the goddamn devil himself
if it gets my daughter back.
I hope you do not come
to regret your decision.
His last recovery effort resulted
in the deaths of four girls.
Two the same age as Becky.
Two younger.
Although we may not be moving
as quickly as you imagine we should,
I want you to know,
it is my number one priority
to get your daughter back to you safely.
I just thought you should
have all the facts.
Well, we'll take that under advisement.
I understand.
I will send someone to take you home.
I will call you later.
- Good evening.
- It's a little late for delivery.
I know, but the overtime is worth it.
Please.
Sign here.
Guys. Keep your eyes open.
Something's up with the monitors.
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Who's guarding the back?
Up.
What the fuck?
- Boss, come on, let's get you to the vault.
- Who are they?
I don't know, but we can't
take any chances. Come on!
It's the fucking Russians! Gotta be.
Get more guys over here.
Done.
You may not feel it yet, but you will soon.
It's a reminder of the most important
person in your life as of right now.
You know who I am?
That's why I'm here.
I want the man in charge.
Where is she?
American girl.
- Not my thing.
- Then who?
I don't know.
Never touch Americans. Bad for business.
Fucking cops raiding my clubs for days now.
Competition.
- Who wants to hurt you?
- Russians.
Always trying to move in.
The only reason you're alive
is because you have a job to do.
- I told you...
- Shut up.
You run the city.
You find this girl as quickly as possible.
And you bring her back to her parents
by this time tomorrow.
If not, I'll come back here
and I'll carve out your eyes one by one.
Am I clear?
Yeah.
Your passport is proof of who you are.
You're no one now.
I pay good money for you,
so now you work for me.
Take it off.
Everything.
Is there a problem?
Please. I can't.
The next time you don't
do what you're told,
I take this knife...
You know the drill.
Test them out and put them to work.
Da?
Your retard cousin is drawing too much heat.
Shut him down.
The Al Khabiri thing
could be worth millions.
I've made up my mind.
It's not worth the risk.
Shut it down or I'll find
someone else who will.
Hello?
It's me. I need a GPS
trace on a cell phone.
That's not easy. I'll have to go into work.
Okay, get moving
and I'll text you the number.
I'll also need any information
on someone or something called Al Khabiri.
Fine. Anything else, Dad?
You want me back? This is me back.
What's going on?
Come on, what's going on?
Change of plans, we're shutting down.
What?
- Bogdanov wants out.
- No! The money's too big.
That old fuck's just too rich and scared
to follow through.
- I see who's got the balls around here.
- Fuck off!
- You shut the fuck up.
- Who needs Bogdanov?
We've got the merchandise.
A virgin. American blonde.
We have exactly what they wanted.
You see this? It's our ticket.
We call the guy. We make our own deal.
Shut up.
Do you want to be a lackey
for the rest of your life,
or are you ready to make some real money?
Tell you one thing, cousin,
you sure got yourself a live one.
Stop, stop, stop!
I told you, smart women are trouble.
Please.
Now what do I tell your mother?
Hold.
Let him through.
- The girl?
- Well, see for yourself.
One of Bogdanov's recruiters
and his sometime girlfriend.
In here.
Her face is gone. You sure it's her?
We're checking the DNA samples
from the parents.
It's Bogdanov. He shut it down.
I heard him giving the order.
And you did not think to call us?
Of course not. Always the cowboy.
Stick to what you know, butcher.
Did the coordinates work? Was she here?
Yeah.
I just don't understand.
Why would they...
I mean, if it is her...
Why would they want to...
it seems that whoever took her
felt under pressure.
Afraid that they're going to be found out.
Someone pushed them too hard, I guess.
I'm sorry.
The DNA match is positive. It's her.
It's not your fault, Dad.
It's not your fault.
Come on, let's go.
- You can go. I'll be fine.
- I think it's better if I stay.
You put me up to this.
You knew I was no good!
A girl is dead now!
It's your fault, too!
It's not my fault.
It's not your fault either, Dad.
Get away from here!
Get the fuck outta here!
A butcher with feelings. Who knew?