ALEX:
There was me.
That is, Alex,
and my three droogs.
That is, Pete, Georgie and Dim.
And we sat in the
Korova Milk Bar...
...trying to make up
our rassoodocks...
... what to do with the evening.
The Korova Milk Bar sold milk plus.
Milk plus vellocet or
synthemesc or drencrom...
...which is what we were drinking.
This would sharpen you up...
...and make you ready for a bit
of the old ultra-violence.
[MAN SINGING DRUNKENLY]
ALEX:
One thing I could never stand...
...was to see a filthy,
dirty old drunkie...
...howling away at the
filthy songs of his fathers...
...and going "blerp blerp "
in between...
...as it might be a filthy old
orchestra in his stinking guts.
I could never stand to see anyone
like that, whatever his age.
But more especially when he
was real old, like this one was.
[GUYS CHEERlNG]
MAN: Can you spare some cutter,
me brothers?
[GUYS LAUGH]
Go on! Do me in,
you bastard cowards!
I don't want to live anyway.
Not in a stinking world
like this.
Oh?
And what's so stinking about it?
It's a stinking world because
there's no law and order anymore!
It stinks because it lets
the young get onto the old...
...Iike you done!
It's no world
for an old man any longer.
What kind of a world is it
at all?
Men on the moon.
Men spinning around the earth.
And there's not no
attention paid...
...to earthly
law and order no more.
[SINGING DRUNKENLY]
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[WOMAN SCREAMlNG]
MAN: Right. Get her clothes.
WOMAN: No!
ALEX: It was at the derelict casino
that we came across Billy-boy...
...and his four droogs.
They were about to perform
a little of the old...
...in-out, in-out on a weepy
young devotchka they had there.
No!
[BOTTLE CLATTERlNG]
ALEX:
Ho, ho, ho!
Well, if it isn't...
...fat, stinking...
...billy goat
Billy-boy in poison.
How are thou...
...thou globby bottle of cheap,
stinking chip-oil?
Come and get one in the yarbles...
...if you have any yarbles...
...you eunuch jelly, thou.
Let's get them, boys!
MAN:
Yahoo!
[SlRENS WAlLlNG]
[ALEX WHlSTLES]
ALEX:
The police!
Come on. Let's go!
ALL:
Yahoo!
ALEX: The Durango 95 purred away
real horrorshow.
A nice, warm vibratey feeling
all through your guttiwuts.
Soon it was trees and dark,
my brothers...
...with real country dark.
Whoo-hoo!
[TlRES SCREECHlNG & HORN HONKlNG]
Yahoo!
[SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
[TlRES SCREECHlNG & HORN HONKlNG]
ALEX: We fillied around with other
travelers of the night...
...playing Hogs of the Road.
Then we headed west.
What we were after now
was the old surprise visit.
That was a real kick...
...and good for laughs and
lashing of the old ultra-violent.
[GUYS CHEERlNG & SHOUTlNG]
[DOORBELL RlNGS]
Who on earth could that be?
I'll go and see.
[DOORBELL RlNGS]
Yes, who is it?
ALEX: Excuse me, can you please help?
There's been a terrible accident!
My friend's bleeding to death!
Can I please use your telephone?
We don't have a telephone.
You'll have to go somewhere else.
ALEX: But, missus, it's a matter
of life and death!
Who is it, dear?
WOMAN: A young man.
He says there's been an accident.
He wants to use the telephone.
I suppose you better let him in.
WOMAN:
Wait a minute, will you?
I'm sorry, but we don't usually
let strangers in--
[GUYS LAUGHING]
[GUYS CHEERING & SHOUTING]
What do you want from me?
[ALEX WHISTLES]
ALEX: Pete, check the rest
of the house. Dim....
[ALEX SINGING GENE KELLY'S
"SINGIN' IN THE RAIN"]
WOMAN:
Ah!
[ALEX HUMMING]
[ALEX RESUMES SINGING
GENE KELLY'S ""SlNGlN' lN THE RAlN""]
DlM:
Ready for love.
Viddy well, little brother.
Viddy well.
[MAN GRUNTING]
ALEX: We were all feeling a bit
shagged and fagged and fashed...
...it having been an evening
of some small energy expenditure.
So we got rid of the auto...
...and stopped at the Korova
for a nightcap.
Hello, Lucy.
Had a busy night?
We' ve been working hard too.
Pardon me, Luce.
[FLUID TRICKLING]
ALEX: There was some sophistos from
the TV studios around the corner...
...Iaughing and govoreeting.
The devotchka smeched away...
...not caring about
the wicked world one bit.
Then the disk on the stereo
twanged off and out.
And in the short silence
before the next one came on...
...she suddenly came
with a burst of singing.
[SINGING FROM BEETHOVEN'S
""9TH SYMPHONY""]
ALEX: And it was, like,
for a moment, my brothers...
...some great bird
had flown into the milk bar.
And I felt all the malenky
little hairs on my plott...
...standing endwise.
And the shivers crawling up
like slow, malenky lizards...
...and then down again.
Because I knew what she sang.
It was a bit from
the glorious "9th " by Ludwig van.
[MAKES FARTING NOISE]
[GRUNTING & GROANING]
What did you do that for?
For being a bastard
with no manners.
Without a dook of an idea about how
to comport yourself public-wise.
I don't like you should
do what you done.
And I'm not your brother no more
and wouldn't want to be.
Watch that.
Do watch that...
...if to continue to be on live
thou dost wish.
Yarbles!
Great, bouncy yarblockos to you!
I'll meet you with chain
or nozh or britva anytime.
I'm not having you aiming
tolchocks at me reasonless.
It stands to reason,
I won't have it.
A nozh scrap anytime you say.
Doobidoob.
A bit tired maybe.
Best not to say more.
Bedways is rightways now.
So best we go homeways
and get a bit of spatchka.
Right, right?
PETE & GEORGlE:
Right, right.
ALEX:
ALEX: Where I lived was with
my dada and mum...
...in municipal flat block
18-A, Linear North.
ALEX:
It had been a wonderful evening.
And what I needed now
to give it the perfect ending...
...was a bit
of the old Ludwig van.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO]
ALEX:
Oh, bliss!
Bliss and heaven!
It was gorgeousness and
gorgeosity made flesh.
It was like a bird
of rarest spun heaven metal.
Or like silvery wine
flowing in a spaceship...
...gravity all nonsense now.
As I slooshied...
...I knew such lovely pictures.
Alex. Alex!
Alex?
What do you want?
MOTHER:
It's past 8, Alex.
You don't want to be
late for school, son.
Bit of a pain in the gulliver, Mum.
Leave us be,
and I'll try and sleep it off.
And then I'll be as right
as dodgers for this after.
But you've not been
to school all week, son.
ALEX:
Got to rest, Mum.
Got to get fit.
Otherwise, I'm liable
to miss a lot more school.
MOTHER: I'll put your
breakfast in the oven.
I've got to be off meself now.
All right, Mum.
Have a nice day at the factory.
He's not feeling too good
again this morning, Dad.
Yes. Yes, I heard.
You know what time he got in?
No, I don't.
I'd taken me sleepers.
I wonder...
...where exactly is it
he goes to work of evenings.
Well, like he says...
...it's mostly odd things he does.
Helping-like...
...here and there, as it might be.
Hi, hi, hi, Mr. Deltoid.
Funny surprise, seeing you here.
Alex-boy.
Awake at last, yes?
I met your mother
on the way to work, yes?
She gave me the key.
She said something about
a pain somewhere.
Hence, not at school, yes?
A rather intolerable pain
in the head, brother sir.
It should be clear
by this afterlunch.
Or certainly by this evening, yes.
The evening's the great time,
isn't it, Alex-boy?
-Cup of the old chai, sir?
-No time, yes.
Sit, sit, sit!
To what do I owe
this extreme pleasure, sir?
Anything wrong, sir?
Wrong? Why should you
think of anything being wrong?
Have you been doing
something you shouldn't?
Just a manner of speech.
Yes, well, it's just a manner
of speech from your...
...post-corrective advisor to you
that you watch out, little Alex.
Because next time it's not
going to be the corrective school.
Next time it'll be the Barley place,
and all my work ruined.
If you've no respect
for yourself...
...you at least might have some
for me, who sweated over you.
A big, black mark, I tell you,
for every one we don't reclaim.
A confession of failure
for every one of you...
...who ends up in the stripy hole.
I've been doing nothing I shouldn't.
The millicents have nothing
on me, brother.
Sir, I mean.
DELTOlD: Cut out this clever
talk about millicents.
Just because the police
haven't picked you up...
...doesn't mean that you've not
been up to some nastiness.
There was a bit
of nastiness last night.
Some very extreme nastiness, yes?
A few of a certain Billy-boy's
friends were ambulanced off late.
Your name was mentioned.
The words got to me
by the usual channels.
Certain friends of yours
were named also.
Nobody can prove anything
about anybody, as usual.
I'm warning you, little Alex...
...being a good friend
to you as always...
...the one man in this
sore and sick community...
...who wants to save you
from yourself!
[ALEX GROANlNG]
What gets into you all?
We've been studying the problem
for damn well near a century.
But we get no farther
with our studies.
You got a good home here.
Good, loving parents.
You've got not too bad of a brain.
Is it some devil
that crawls inside of you?
ALEX:
Nobody's got anything on me.
I been out of the millicents'
rookers for a long time.
That's just what worries me.
A bit too long to be safe.
You're about due, by my reckoning.
That's why I'm warning you...
...to keep your handsome
young proboscis out of the dirt.
Do I make myself clear?
ALEX:
As an unmuddied lake, sir.
As clear as an azure sky
of deepest summer.
You can rely on me, sir.
Ugh.
[GROANS]
[TAPPlNG CANE]
ALEX:
Excuse me, brother.
I ordered this two weeks ago.
Can you see if it's arrived?
Just a minute.
Pardon me, ladies.
Enjoying that, are you, my darling?
A bit cold and pointless,
isn't it, my lovely?
What's happened to yours,
my little sister?
[GlRL LAUGHS]
Who you getting, bratty?
Goggly Gogol? Johnny Zhivago?
The Heaven 1 7?
What you got back home
to play your fuzzy warbles on?
I bet you've got little
pitiful, portable picnic players.
Come with Uncle
and hear all proper.
Hear angel trumpets
and devil trombones.
You are invited.
-Hi, hi, hi, there.
-Well, hello.
He are here!
He have arrived!
Hooray!
Welly, welly, welly,
welly, welly, welly, well!
To what do I owe
the extreme pleasure...
...of this surprising visit?
We got worried.
[DlM LAUGHlNG]
GEORGlE: There we were, waiting and
drinking at the old knifey moloko...
...and you had not turned up.
And we thought
you might have been, like...
...offended by something
or other.
So around we come to your abode.
Appy polly loggies.
I had something of a pain
in the gulliver, so I had to sleep.
I was not awakened
when I gave orders for wakening.
DlM:
Sorry about the pain.
Using the gulliver
too much-like, maybe.
[DlM CHUCKLES]
Giving orders and
discipline and such, perhaps.
You sure the pain is gone?
You sure you'd not
be happier back in bed?
[DlM CHUCKLES]
Let's get things nice
and sparkling clear.
This sarcasm,
if I may call it such...
...does not become you,
my little brothers.
As I am your droog and leader...
...I'm entitled to know
what goes on.
Yeah.
Now then, Dim.
What does that great big
horsey gape of a grin portend?
All right, no more
picking on Dim, brother.
That's part of the new way.
New way?
What's this about a new way?
There's been some very large talk
behind my sleeping back, and no error.
If you must have it,
have it, then.
We go around shop crasting
and the like...
...coming out with a pitiful
rookerfull of money each.
And Will the English
in the coffee mesto...
...saying he can fence anything
any malchick tries to crast.
The shiny stuff. The lce!
The big, big money's available,
is what Will the English says.
Big, big money.
And what will you do
with the big, big, big money?
Have you not everything you need?
If you need a motorcar,
you pluck it from the trees.
If you need pretty polly,
you take it.
Brother, you think and talk
sometimes like a little child.
Little child, yeah.
Tonight we pull a man-size crast.
Tonight's a man-size crast!
ALEX:
Good! Real horrorshow!
Initiative comes
to thems that wait.
I've taught you much,
my little droogies.
Now tell me what you had in mind,
Georgie-boy.
The old moloko plus first.
Would you not say?
-Something to sharpen us up.
-Some of them moloko plus.
GEORGlE: You especially.
We have the start.
Yeah, we got a start on you!
Yeah, moloko plus, eh?
[LAUGHlNG]
ALEX: As we walked along
the flatblock marina...
...I was calm on the outside,
but thinking all the time.
So now it was to be
Georgie the General...
...saying what we should do
and what not to do.
And Dim as his mindless,
grinning bulldog.
But suddenly I viddied that
thinking was for the gloopy ones...
...and that the oomny ones
used, like...
...inspiration and what Bog sends.
For now it was lovely music
that came to my aid.
There was a window open
with a stereo on...
...and I viddied right at once
what to do.
I had not cut into any
of Dim 's main cables.
And so with the help
of a clean tashtook...
...the red, red kroovy
soon stopped.
And it did not take long to
quieten the two wounded soldiers...
...down in the snug
of the Duke of New York.
Now they knew who was
master and leader.
Sheep, thought I.
But a real leader knows
always when, like...
... to give and show generous
to his unders.
Well....
Now we' re back to where we were.
Yes?
Just like before,
and all forgotten?
Right, right, right?
Right.
Well, Georgie-boy...
...this idea of yours for tonight.
Tell us all about it, then.
GEORGlE:
Not tonight.
Not this nochy.
Come, come, come, Georgie-boy.
You're a big, strong chelloveck,
like us all.
We're not little children,
are we, Georgie-boy?
What, then, didst thou
in thy mind have?
GEORGlE:
It's this health farm.
A bit out of the town.
Isolated.
It's owned by this rich ptitsa...
...who lives there with her cats.
The place is shut down
for a week...
...and she 's completely on her own.
It's full up with, like,
gold and silver...
...and, like, jewels.
ALEX:
Tell me more, Georgie-boy.
Tell me more.
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
WEATHERS:
Oh, shit!
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
WEATHERS:
Who's there?
ALEX:
Excuse me, can you please help?
There's been a terrible accident!
Can I please use your telephone
for an ambulance?
I'm frightfully sorry.
There's a telephone in the
public house a mile down the road.
I suggest you use that.
ALEX:
But missus, this is an emergency!
It's a matter of life and death!
Me friend's lying in the middle
of the road, bleeding to death!
I'm very sorry...
...but I never open the door
to strangers after dark.
ALEX:
Very well, madam.
You can't be blamed
for being suspicious...
...with so many scoundrels
and rogues of the night about.
I'll try and get help
at the pub, then.
I'm sorry if I disturbed you.
Thank you very much.
Good night.
ALEX:
Dim, bend down.
I'll get in that window
and open the front door.
[DlALlNG PHONE]
Hello. Radlett Police Station?
Good evening. It's Miss Weathers
at Woodmere Health Farm.
Hello. I'm sorry to bother you, but
something rather odd just happened.
It's probably nothing at all,
but you never know.
A young man rang the bell,
asking to use the telephone.
He said there's been
some kind of accident.
The thing that caught my
attention was what he said.
His words sounded like those quoted
in the papers this morning...
...in connection with the writer
and his wife who were assaulted.
COP:
When did this take place, ma 'am?
Just a few minutes ago.
I think we'd better send
a patrol car around to see you.
If you think that's necessary.
But I'm quite sure
he's gone away now.
He'll be there in a few minutes.
-All right, fine.
-My pleasure, ma 'am.
Thank you very much.
WEATHERS:
Ah!
ALEX:
Hi, hi, hi, there.
At last we meet.
Our brief govorett through the
letter-hole was not satisfactory.
Who are you?
How the hell did you get in here?
What the bloody hell
do you think you're doing?
Naughty, naughty, naughty!
You filthy old soomaka.
Now listen here,
you little bastard!
Just turn round and walk out
of here the same way you came in.
Leave that alone!
Don't touch it!
It's a very important work of art.
What the bloody hell do you want?
To be perfectly honest, madam...
...I'm taking part in an
international students' contest...
...to see who can get the most
points for selling magazines.
Cut the shit, sonny...
...and get out of here before you
get yourself into serious trouble.
I told you to leave that alone!
Now get out of here...
...before I throw you out!
Wretched, slummy bedbug!
I'll teach you to break
into real people's houses.
Fucking...
...Iittle...
...bastard!
WEATHERS:
Ah!
[POLlCE SlREN WAlLlNG]
[CATS MEOWlNG]
ALEX: Let's go. The police are coming!
DlM: One minoota, droogie.
[GUYS CHEERlNG & LAUGHlNG]
ALEX:
You bastards!
I'm blind!
I'm blind, you bastards!
I can't see!
[POLICE SIREN WAILING]
It's no good sitting there in hope,
my little brothers.
I won't say a single solitary
slovo unless I have my lawyer here.
I know the law, you bastards.