(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(PANTING)
(SCREWS ON CAP)
(SETS BOTTLE DOWN)
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
GUNTHER: Yes.
JAMAL: I picked him up
from the airport this afternoon.
I know.
(JAMAL SOBBING)
You know what I need?
(JAMAL SIGHS)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(JAMAL SNIFFLES)
(HANGS UP)
(EXHALES)
(TRAIN PASSING)
(WHISPERING PRAYER)
(WOMAN ANNOUNCING
INDISTINCTLY ON PA)
- (GRUNTS)
- Oh!
ABDULLAH: Are you afraid, my friends?
Of us?
Of Islam?
People are suffering throughout
the Muslim world.
In Palestine, Afghanistan, Baghdad.
But do I believe terrorism
is the justifiable consequence
of this suffering?
No.
Violence against
the innocent is not the way of Allah.
My charities are set up around the world
to stamp out poverty,
as well as promote religious tolerance
and understanding.
We rely on your generous support
to continue our work.
- Thank you.
- (AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(TYPING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Yes, Maxi.
- GUNTHER: Maxi? What have you got?
- Yeah?
Around 11:00 a.m. police received a report
about a suspicious figure
in the central train station.
They were sent this image
taken from a mobile phone.
The quality's not great
but good enough to make a match.
Karpov, lssa.
Chechen, 26.
Classified as an escaped militant jihadist.
- GUNTHER: Hmm.
- MAXIMILIAN: Potentially violent.
Approach with caution.
Pull that down.
MAXIMILIAN: Security footage has
him returning to the station
five times during the day.
GUNTHER: Do we know that guy?
NIKI: Not yet. Working on it.
- Ah. Give me the hands.
- MAXIMILIAN: Uh-huh.
RASHEED: Some sort of note?
Currency maybe.
MAXIMILIAN: That's our last sight of him.
GUNTHER: Who else knows he's out there?
NIKI: The cops haven't made a connection.
Mmm. And upstairs?
Mmm-mmm, doesn't look like it.
If not yet they will soon.
Karl, Rasheed, start with the mosques,
homeless shelters, don't break anything.
Niki, try the railway station.
Find out who the hell
that scrawny bastard is.
NIKI: Mmm-hmm.
Great.
Thank you.
Issa Karpov.
A Muslim first name and
a Russian last name.
What does that tell us?
That the boy is confused.
And no patronymic.
Is he the son of nobody?
Issa... Jesus no less.
Maybe he's the son of God
and he's come to save us.
- Save me.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
(GUNTHER SPEAKING ARABIC)
(REPLYING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(CHUCKLES)
(MAN PRAYING IN ARABIC)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Doner plate.
Coffee, black.
SERVER: Coffee, black.
- One euro.
- Cheers.
Salam.
Thank you.
(SIGHS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hmm.
Hello.
That scrawny bastard,
they call him the Admiral.
He's drinking at Silbersack Bar.
- I think you know the place?
- Ah.
Better than I should.
I'm looking at the receipts
from Abdullah's trip to Dubai.
Why make a four hour layover, in Cyprus,
on your way back from Dubai, to Frankfurt?
When you can fly direct?
I don't know, Gunther. Air miles?
(IRNA CHUCKLES)
With my luck that's probably all it is.
Oh, "Seven Friends."
IRNA: Is that all you have, Günther?
GUNTHER: Oh, l wish.
It's a shipping company based in Cyprus.
Okay, I'll check it.
All right. Bye-bye.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Admiral.
Hmm.
Herr Dinkelmann.
Missing persons.
THE ADMIRAL: Strange boy.
Nervous.
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
He asked me to find someone for him.
A banker.
And this banker,
did he have a name?
You don't want it?
Brue.
Monsieur Tommy Brue.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Word is Mohr is on to something.
His boys are hitting the streets.
Gunther?
They found Karpov.
Hmm.
Ah, good.
Keep him walking.
(CAR REMOTE BEEPS)
Karpov, the Russian, he's ours.
Am I to understand you've found him?
I remind you that your license
to operate in Hamburg
is contingent on your co-operation
with my office.
I am co-operating, Dieter.
I want this kid to talk to whoever
he was told to talk to,
pray wherever he was told to pray,
sleep wherever he was told to sleep.
I don't want anybody else getting close
to him before we do.
And if this kid lets off a bomb?
(SCOFFS) It's in your hands, Gunther.
Thank Christ it's not in yours
- because if it was you'd fuck it up.
- Mmm-hmm.
Then I want it in writing,
your signature on the letter,
because when the bomb goes off in Hamburg
I want you there to see the blood
on the streets.
Have you ever seen blood on the streets?
Clown.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
(KEYS JANGLE)
(FOOD SIZZLING)
(UTENSILS CLANKING)
LEYLA: Melik. We have a guest.
This is lssa, from Chechnya.
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
(UNSCREWING CAP)
GUNTHER: That's the kind of face I make.
Weddings.
Every time I attend one,
I see another good woman going to the wall.
Well, what about the man?
The man is the wall.
Oh.
The apartment belongs to a Leyla Oktay.
Turkish national, German resident.
A widow.
- One son, Melik.
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, Michael.
They have a citizenship
application pending.
Michael.
MICHAEL: You've upset Dieter Mohr.
Really?
It probably has something to do
with the terrorists you're allowing to
walk the streets of Hamburg.
GUNTHER: We're on a wait and see approach.
And what are we seeing?
Enough to keep waiting.
Don't underestimate Mohr.
He's got a lot of friends here in Berlin.
Why don't you give him the Chechen?
Let him shine while you
stay focused on Abdullah.
GUNTHER: I think he's moving the money to
a shipping company.
Are you sure?
Not yet, but close.
I need more time.
I'll do what I can, Günther,
but watch your back.
Word is the Americans
are taking an interest.
- Thanks for the warning.
- (HANGS UP)
(SARCASTICALLY) Whoo-hoo! Whoo!
Americans.
Günther Bachmann?
Martha Sullivan. US Embassy, Berlin.
I know you by reputation, of course.
That can't be good.
Men with good reputations
usually aren't much use to me.
What about women?
This is my colleague lrna Frey.
- Hello.
She sails and spies.
I don't sail.
Hamburg's a long way from Berlin.
What are you doing here?
Me? I am just an observer.
I have been observed by Americans before.
It usually doesn't end well.
From what I'm hearing, we're not the ones
you need to be worrying about.
OTTO: Good morning, everyone.
Herr Mohr has compiled a report.
Our investigations confirm
that lssa Karpov
is a member of a militant Salafi group
of Chechen jihadists.
Karpov was arrested soon after the capture
of the group's leader earlier this year.
Where did this information come from?
We have excellent resources
inside the Russian state security system.
After 24 hours of questioning,
Karpov confessed
to taking part in attacks on gas pipelines,
transport, infrastructure, police stations.
After 24 hours of Russian questioning
any one of us would admit to anything.
Are you contesting this report?
No. Yes.
Maybe.
We've not yet had the
benefit of reading it.
(SIGHS) The report concludes that
the terrorist Karpov has come to Hamburg
seeking to make contact
with lslamist cells operating in the city.
They hide among us.
- Really?
- OTTO: Yes.
Karpov is a wanted man.
If you have knowledge of his whereabouts,
you are obliged to follow
due process under the constitution.
You mean arresting him?
Issa Karpov is indeed seeking
to make contact in Hamburg,
with a banker.
We've had no briefing on this.
Well, if you were doing your job,
you wouldn't need one.
We're not policemen.
We're spies.
Issa Karpov may be of value to us.
All I'm asking for is more time.
Our unit was set up to develop
intelligence resources
inside Germany's Islamic community.
- That's why we're here.
- Oh.
And I thought you were here
because you fucked up in Beirut
and your friend Michael
Axelrod had no idea...
This banker, do we know
what Karpov wants from him?
Not yet and if we move against him now,
the chances are we never will.
I think he knows what he's doing, Otto.
Maybe you should let him get on with it.
You have 72 hours to bring
this matter to a resolution,
if not, we will,
with or without your co-operation.
- OKay?
- OKay.
ANNABEL: Where should we go?
CO-WORKER: Meet at the place
on the corner?
Okay.
Uh, I'll catch up with you later.
Okay, we'll see you there.
Melik?
Did we have an appointment?
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
Annabel Richter, Mama.
Hello, Leyla. How are you?
Welcome to our house, Frau Annabel.
Nice to see you again.
Come in. Come in please.
ANNABEL: Thank you.
LEYLA: (WHISPERING) The boy is good,
Frau Annabel. Do you understand?
If he has done something wrong,
- it's because he had no...
- (DOOR OPENS)
Hello, lssa.
Uh, my name is Annabel Richter.
I am a lawyer.
I work with an organization
called Sanctuary North.
- Mmm, please?
- Okay.
Are you seeking asylum in Germany?
I make coffee.
There has to be a reason.
Either you cannot return
to your country of origin
because your life would be in danger
or you have been tortured.
Yes.
Yes, what?
I have been tortured.
Forgive me, but this is my job.
I want to believe you,
but people make this claim all the time.
I have to...
Who did this to you?
Roosskie.
ANNABEL: I cannot help you unless
you are honest with me.
It's only a matter of time before the
German authorities will find you.
It's better for your case
if you go to them first.
- We can make a formal...
- I will never, never go back to Russia.
Please?
You will contact this man.
He will help me.
Mr. Thomas Brue.
Colonel Grigori Borisovich Karpov,
stationed in Chechnya, 1986.
He was involved with organized crime.
NIKI: Big time. Drugs for arms.
White slave traffic.
You name it he was in to it.
Karpov died two years ago.
- And?
- He had a son.
Ivan.
Born, 1986 in Chechnya.
Mother unknown.
Good.
ELLI: Fraulein Richter?
Please follow me.
Please.
What exactly is Sanctuary North?
I'm a lawyer.
Our clients are people
who have left their place of birth.
They are effectively stateless.
They are often traumatized.
What is it you want, Miss Richter?
A donation?
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
That was insensitive.
I'm here on behalf of a client.
His name is lssa Karpov.
Is the name known to you?
Karpov?
Mmm-mmm. No.
He is in possession of a letter
written by your father to his.
It makes reference to a Mr. Lipizzaner,
as in the Spanish horses which are
born black but gradually turn white.
Yes.
This is a process I'm guessing
your bank is familiar with?
The letter contains a number.
Does it fit?
Does it fit what?
Is the number an account reference
in use at this bank?
(SIGHS) I'm afraid my bank
doesn't broadcast the manner
in which it does its business.
I'm sure that suits your clients very well.
But if this number does pertain
to an account held at this bank,
it would have been established
quite some time ago.
I will need to check our records.
Once I have done so I will call you.
When?
My client's situation in Hamburg
is extremely sensitive Mr. Brue.
I'm sure.
He trusts you.
As, judging by the contents of
the letter, his father trusted yours.
Big boy.
Six...
Ah.
3448.
"Grigori Borisovich Karpov."
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(ANNABEL AND WOMAN
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Sorry.
That's all right. I've given up.
Yeah? Good luck with that.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yes?
Okay.
The Atlantic.
I'll be there.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- Good evening.
Have something to drink?
Uh, glass of wine?
Uh, still water please.
WAITER: Still water. Of course.
You frequent the Atlantic?
Uh...
Not your scene?
You said your client's situation
was sensitive, hence the hurry.
I can confirm that the reference number
you supplied
does pertain to an account
held at Brue Freres Bank.
Then he intends to make a claim.
Then tell him to bring a large suitcase.
Of course he will need
to establish his identity.
My client entered the country
in difficult circumstances.
He has the letter.
- I will need to see it.
- Of course.
And in addition, he will need to
provide a certain instrument.
Which is?
I'm afraid I can't say,
but if your client is legitimate
he will know what I am talking about.
And if he has this instrument?
I see no difficulty in proceeding.
She's coming out.
Attractive.
Not my type-
What is your type, Gunther?
You are, lrna. You know that.
(SIGHS)
Johannes-Brahms-Platz.
Hello, Tommy.
And you are?
My name is Bachmann.
I head an anti-terror unit
not many people know about
and even less like.
Let's walk.
(GUNTHER CLEARS THROAT)
Hamburg is one of
the great ports of the world, Tommy.
For centuries it opened its arms
to every foreigner
who washed up on its shores.
Now, since 9/11,
in the eyes of every dark-skinned man
we see someone who wants to kill us.
Problem is some of them do,
but the question is whether
lssa Karpov is one of them.
The lawyer.
Lawyer?
Annabel Richter.
The one you met at the hotel.
The one you'd like to fuck.
What? Not true?
You're too old for her, Tommy. We both are.
See her, love her, but
you'll never get her,
not even with all that black money
you've got tucked away in your bank vaults.
As far as I am aware,
Miss Richter represents
a client with a legitimate
financial interest with my bank.
Your bank does business
with the Russians, right?
It did. In my father's time.
Mafia?
Military mainly.
(STAMMERING) What's to stop me
from just walking away from this?
Whatever this is.
How about we start with
a full audit of your books?
But your father wasn't
just a banker, Tommy.
He was a laundryman.
You're threatening me?
Just sympathizing.
You've been left to clean up the mess.
(TAPS CIGARETTE)
(SIGHS)
We have a job to do, Tommy.
You're going to help me do it.
TOMMY: Do what exactly?
Save Annabel Richter, for a start.
From what?
From all of it.
MITZI: Hmm. I wasn't expecting you.
TOMMY: No?
Who were you expecting?
Bad day?
A few surprises.
Enjoy your scotch, Tommy.
And try not to fall over
on your way to bed.
(SIGHS)
(INTERCOM BUZZES)
(DOOR BUZZES)
lssa, it is somebody for you.
- TOMMY: Good morning.
- ANNABEL: Good morning.
Thank you for coming.
Of course.
(DOOR OPENS)
lssa.
This is Mr. Brue.
Morning.
Perhaps you could show him the letter.
"My dear Karpov,
"as discussed, please accept this letter
"as assurance from one friend to another,
"that in the unfortunate
circumstance of your death
"I should be pleased
to acquaint your own dear son,
“Ivan Grigorevich Karpov,
"with our friend Mr. Lipizzaner.
"He need only present this letter,
"together with the necessary instrument
"currently in your
possession for me to act.
"In case of my own death,
"my son Thomas will fulfill
my promise to you."
Forgive me.
It's correct signature of your father?
TOMMY: It is.
Should I address you then as lssa or Ivan?
Issa.
It's my Muslim name and I like.
But not the one your father gave you?
My mother was Chechen.
I wish, sir, with your help,
to make an honorable life in Hamburg.
Very good, (SIGHS)
but first, you understand
there are certain questions of fact.
I bring your attention
to the matter of the instrument.
May I ask how you came
to be in possession of this?
It was given to me by my father's lawyer.
So it seems I am being asked
to fulfill one father's promise to another.
It's true. Karpov was my father.
TOMMY: You weren't close?
My father was a murderer.
He has Chechen blood on his hands.
And yet you seem
willing enough to take his money?
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
I understand you came here from Turkey,
by an informal route, shall we say?
May I ask, what you were doing in Turkey?
I was in prison.
And before that?
I was in prison in Russia.
- Why?
- You don't need to answer that, lssa.
Why not?
Because it is immaterial.
To what, Fraulein Richter?
Your client...
He's your client, too, Mr. Brue.
Your client lays claim
to his father's account,
yet he has no passport,
cannot prove his identity.
(WHISPERING) He has the key and the letter,
what more do you want?
(SIGHS)
We couldn't hear everything so well, Tommy.
So exactly how much are we talking about?
(SIGHS DEEPLY) I can't tell you.
Not exactly.
A ballpark figure?
10,000, 100,000, 500,000?
We're talking
upwards of 10 million euro.
At least.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- Coffee.
- Yes, sir.
- Black.
- Right away.
I wasn't sure you'd come.
I want to make one thing clear.
I don't owe you anything.
What happened in Beirut?
You know what happened in Beirut.
My networks were blown.
So Hamburg is a punishment?
Depends on whether you like Hamburg.
Unless that's what you
want people to think?
Take some of the heat off you so you can
get on with the real game.
Which is?
Dr. Faisal Abdullah.
Come on, Gunther, we probably
know as much about him as you do.
What do you know, Martha?
We know you've been
watching him for months,
and we know you're under pressure
to get results.
And we know that the man moves money
through a network of Muslim charities
and every time he does,
some of it goes missing.
Dr. Faisal Abdullah is everything
we want him to be and a little bit more.
He's tolerant, enlightened,
engaged with the West.
But every good man
has a little bit of bad, doesn't he?
And in Abdullah's case,
that little bit
just might kill you.
You know all that, how come he's still
walking the streets of Hamburg
and not rotting in some cell in Guantanamo?
(SIGHS)
Because we think, we don't know.
The money leaves
and we don't know where it goes.
Anyways, on German soil
he's got the protection of German law.
That hasn't stopped you before.
We don't do that anymore.
You want us to do it, then.
I'm more interested in knowing why
you haven't done it already?
(COINS JINGLING)
Please work with us on this one, Gunther.
I don't trust you.
(CHUCKLES)
Old habits die hard.
That's what I'm worried about.
I was talking about yours.
Have a nice day.
You too.
I got your text.
I...
I can't do this anymore.
Someone's going to find out. I can feel it.
I'm frightened.
They are looking at me.
All of them.
I'm done. It's over.
I am not your spy. I am a student.
You cannot make me do this.
I never made you do anything, Jamal.
And I never will.
You know that.
When we first met,
you remember what we talked about?
You remember that?
Family, the future.
Most of us don't get to
choose, but you did.
You made the right choice.
It's not easy.
But there's no going back,
for any of us.
We can't undo what's done.
Look at me.
Come here.
You're my ears, Jamal, and my eyes.
I need you.
You're important to me.
Good.
(SIGHS)
(LINE RINGING)
- TOMMY: Hello?
- Tommy?
Yes.
You need to give lssa Karpov what he wants.
(TOMMY EXHALING)
Uh, Miss Richter?
Can we talk?
Perhaps we could go for a tea?
What do you want?
I've reconsidered your client's position.
My bank is prepared to honor his claim.
Why have you changed your mind?
Perhaps you convinced me.
I thought you'd be pleased.
Okay.
I'll be in touch.
Annabel?
We should take care.
All of us.
ABDULLAH ON TV:
It is our religious obligation to give.
This is the holy practice of Zakat,
one of the five pillars of Islam.
Through our adherence
to this practice of charity,
- we are drawn nearer to God.
- (DOOR OPENS)
Gunther, the banker called. He did it.
Good.
Issa! lssa!
Wake up.
(GROANS)
(MELIK SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
Where will you take him?
It's better if you don't know.
We have to go.
It's not safe to stay here.
For you or for them.
There are clothes in here.
(OPENS BAG)
There's also some scissors and a razor.
Issa, they know what you look like.
Come on, lssa.
(INAUDIBLE)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(ENGINE STARTING)
They're moving.
(KEYS JANGLE)
Where are we going?
My brother Florien has an apartment
that's being renovated.
He's arranged for them
to stop work for a week.
(MAN ANNOUNCING INDISTINCTLY ON PA)
(EXHALES)
(CLOSING SIGNAL BEEPING)
(GRUNTS)
Where's the next station?
Okay.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
ANNABEL: We get out at the next stop.
We have to find another taxi, okay?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
TAXI DRIVER: Hey.
You're blocking the street!
Hey-
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(PANTING)
Oh, fuck!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
- (POUNDING CONTINUES)
- (SPEAKING TURKISH)
Hello?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
OFFICER: Against the wall!
Check the other rooms!
Ow! Stop!
Bedroom clear.
(GROANING)
We're nearly there.
I wish to talk to Mr. Brue.
ANNABEL: I spoke with him earlier tonight.
Issa, he says the bank
will honor your claim.
I do not want the money.
What?
Father's money is bad money.
But without it you have nothing.
I have God.
I brought you some food.
There's a sleeping bag
and some more clothes.
- I'll be back first thing in the morning.
- (KEYS JANGLING)
It is not a prison.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
This was the best you could do, huh?
I am a cave dweller.
I'll leave the rooms with a view to you.
You let Mohr off the leash?
He doesn't need me
to give him a reason to piss you off.
You've lost Karpov, haven't you?
I need the lawyer to move freely.
(SIGHS)
I don't have that kind
of influence, Gunther.
We both know you have
all the influence you choose to have.
Look, if you want me to help you on
your way, you've got to tell me.
Tell me which way you're heading.
Last month a cargo ship left Cyprus.
It was carrying 1,000 tons
of donated grain bound for Djibouti.
It stopped to re-fuel
on the south coast of Yemen.
When it reached its destination
there were 900 tons left.
At the same time 100 tons of grain
mysteriously hit
the open market in the Yemen.
The money from its sale was
used to buy rocket launchers
for lslamist militants.
I think the shipping company
is an al-Qaeda front.
I think that's where the missing funds
from Abdullah's charities are going.
You think, or you know?
Come on, Gunther. Share.
Abdullah's not the bad guy.
He's our way to the bad guy.
A man supplies money
that buys weapons that kills Americans
and you're telling me he's a pal?
So maybe he's not waving
the flag of freedom and democracy
as enthusiastically as you'd like.
Okay.
- But he sees his people...
- Spare the lecture.
He sees his people
being fucked over from here to eternity.
I've heard that before, so...
Maybe a little bit of him
wants to return the favor,
but it's that little bit
that makes him so valuable.
Don't you see?
Okay. I understand.
But that's not what my people would say.
What would your people say?
Take him out? Kill him?
And then what have you got?
A great big fucking hole,
and who's going to fill it?
Nobody knows. You least of all.
So we all start looking again,
and tap-tapping around in the dark.
You want to own Abdullah,
is that what you want?
A man with your reputation
and your resources.
How are you going to do that?
Karpov has access to money.
That may be of interest to Abdullah.
And the lawyer?
He trusts her.
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- (INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
- (GUNTHER GRUNTS)
- (MAN GROANS)
(STAMMERING) It's okay.
It's okay?
Dance.
- Trying to impress me, Gunther?
- No.
Listen, I'll put Mohr back on the leash,
but now you owe me.
Hey, Annabel.
Good to see you. How's Ursula?
Um... (SCREAMING)
No, no.
(PANTING)
Let go. Let go of me!
(GRUNTING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yes?
(WHIRRING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Okay?
- Yeah. Good.
- Yeah.
- Rasheed?
- Mmm-hmm?
You can't do this. I'm a lawyer.
This is criminal.
Sit the fuck down.
Lawyer?
You're a fucking social
worker for terrorists.
(SIGHS) Cigarette?
That's right, you've given up.
Is that it?
Is that all the fight
you're going to give me?
Pacifist.
(DRAGS CHAIR)
We know about you.
Left-wing lawyer.
Wealthy family.
Father's a judge.
Everything you do says "fuck you" to him.
Is that the best you can do?
Can I go now?
Go where?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Hmm?
Back to your self-righteous friends
at Sanctuary North?
But no one's going
to saw off their heads, are they?
Nobody's going to blow up their kids
because you're on a beach in Bali
or riding a train to school
in Madrid or London.
How fucking dare you?
How fucking dare me?
Tell me I've broken every rule in the book?
That I've trampled
on the essence of the constitution?
You want to spout that crap?
Yes?
Do you know where you are?
No, you don't.
This is the real world, Annabel.
We are fighting against the radical
off cuts of a nation called Islam.
You've crossed the line.
You're on their side now.
(DOOR LOCKS)
(CHUCKLES)
Hello.
(CHUCKLING)
I don't care what you do to me.
But you're not the one
we're talking about, are you, dear?
Issa must be worried sick.
Wherever you've hidden him,
he's probably wondering
if you're ever coming back.
I hope he doesn't do anything foolish.
Come, sit with me.
Come on.
IRNA: There are people out there
who want to arrest him.
You know that of course.
We're concerned that they
will find him before we do.
There is a difference between them and us.
They want to hurt him.
We want to help him.
You see, Annabel, we're not your enemy.
We're your solution.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(DOOR LOCKS)
Good.
(SIGHS)
You know what my guys told me?
When they pulled you off the street?
You didn't put up a fight.
Not really.
You struggled a bit.
Screamed a little, but
you let them take you.
It's almost as if you wanted it to happen.
You needed someone to
take it out of your hands
because you are out of your depth, Annabel.
You know you can't save him,
not on your own.
Your choice is between us
and nobody.
The clock is ticking.
You know they'll find
him, and when they do,
he'll be on the first plane back to Russia,
unless the Americans want him
and then we won't know
where he is and nor will he.
He doesn't want the money.
He just doesn't want it.
Half radical, half
rich kid.
Half Russian, half Chechen.
Loves his mother, hates his father.
You and I both know
lssa Karpov has no idea what he wants.
There is something else
you and I both know, don't we?
We both know he's innocent.
So what do you want?
I want to help him.
(KNOCKS)
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
(DOOR LOCKS)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
lssa?
(METAL CLATTERS)
lssa, I'm sorry.
I had a dream.
They took you. They tortured you.
And what happened?
Did I tell them where you were?
No.
You are stronger than I was.
You tell them nothing.
(EXHALES)
Go and put on something warm.
I want to show you something outside.
(EXHALES)
(PAPER PLANE CLATTERING ON VIDEO)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Okay.
Right.
IRNA: Look at him.
He's safe.
There's a bed for you here.
It's better that you don't go home.
Herr Mohr and his boys
are still out looking for you.
(LAUGHING) Are you trying to get me drunk?
Yes.
How's Karpov?
Getting there.
And the lawyer?
I already got you all the time I can get.
Beirut was our mistake.
One of our agents
blew your network and I know you shared.
We messed up.
Just thought you needed to know that.
We make that kind of mistake.
I can understand why you don't trust us.
Your agents and contacts were compromised.
Men who trusted you died,
and that stays with you always.
And all that damage
we leave behind.
All those lives,
all those empty rooms,
what would they have been for?
You ever ask yourself that question?
Why we do what we do?
Mmm-hmm, sometimes.
But I always come back to the same answer.
And what is it?
Make the world a safer place.
Isn't that enough?
(CLICKS TONGUE)
- ISSA: Mmm-mmm.
- Mmm...
Move your queen.
Just because you're Russian,
doesn't mean you're a better
chess player than me.
I'm Chechen.
Okay, so you're good at chess.
Tell me something else about yourself.
You said your mother is Chechen?
She's dead.
I'm sorry.
My father raped her.
She died when I was born.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
She was 15.
(JINGLING)
it was my mother's.
It's beautiful.
(EXHALES)
ISSA: You must go.
IRNA: You can push him a bit more.
Try to get him emotional.
If it happens naturally, lose your temper.
But he doesn't want the money.
I know.
But he wants you.
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Gunther?
You should take care.
Maybe we're pushing too hard.
Don't go soft on me, lrna.
There's no room for that on this one.
Tell me one where there was.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Morning.
Seventy people died in a market
in Baghdad yesterday.
ISSA: lnsha Allah.
God's will?
Or just a man who
was arrogant enough to kill in his name?
She's good.
Leyla and Melik have been arrested.
They may be deported,
because they were kind to you,
because they invited you in to their home.
Explain it to me, lssa!
God's will?
Explain to me why that man who killed
those women and children in Baghdad
is any different from your own father?
ISSA: I came to Hamburg to make a new life.
ANNABEL: No. You came to Hamburg
to find Mr. Tommy Brue.
You came to claim your father's money.
I told you, I do not want his money.
Hmm.
(SIGHS)
Forgive me.
Maybe
there's a way to leave
your past behind, lssa.
- Take your father's money...
- GUNTHER: Take your father's money,
- and turn it into something good.
- ...and turn it into something good.
(GARAGE DOOR OPENS)
Your goat is tethered.
It's just an ordinary pen.
Looks like a pen,
writes like a pen and listens like a pen.
Take it apart, it's still a pen.
Are you clear?
- Are you clear?
- Mmm-hmm.
You are acting on behalf
of a wealthy Muslim client.
We've been over this.
You are acting on behalf
of a wealthy Muslim...
Several times.
...who has come in to
a considerable inheritance
and the source of the
money is questionable.
He seeks to distribute these funds
in a spiritually correct manner.
For Christ's sake!
I'm not doing this for you.
Whatever it takes, Tommy.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(GATE BUZZES)
Hello.
Put your arms up.
Bag?
Hi.
(SPEAKS ARABIC)
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Mr. Brue?
- Yes.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
I'm Jamal.
My father is expecting you.
- Can you take off your shoes?
- Of course.
I'll take care of the coat.
(MAN SPEAKING ARABIC ON TV)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Mr. Brue.
- Mr. Brue.
- An honor.
You have met my son Jamal?
Yes, and, uh, another
at the door, I believe.
Please sit.
Please.
As explained to you,
my client's situation
in Germany is delicate.
These are the details of his offer.
As you can see, there are specific requests
for some money to be sent to Chechnya.
Hospitals and schools.
Perhaps this is a joke?
You have added a zero to test me.
The figure is correct.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Where did this money come from?
It has come to him
in the form of an inheritance.
My client has come to regard it as unclean
and seeks your guidance in disposing of it
in a manner befitting your religion.
You're an honorable man, I believe that.
But tell me, why should I trust you?
TOMMY: We must trust each other surely.
I am willing, under my
client's instruction,
to arrange for significant funds
to be transferred to you.
You are known as a religious man.
A trusted man.
I accept you will direct this money
to the purpose he intends.
Why this urgency?
My client's legal status
in Germany is insecure.
I would recommend you accept this gift now,
because he may not be in a position
to offer it much longer.
(BOTH SPEAKING ARABIC)
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
Mr. Brue.
- Here.
- Thanks.
(DOOR OPENS)
TOMMY: Doctor, this way, please.
Dr. Abdullah, may I introduce
your benefactor, lssa Karpov,
and his lawyer, Miss Richter.
(BOTH GREETING IN ARABIC)
I wish to speak with lssa alone.
Of course.
Miss Richter?
ABDULLAH ON VIDEO: Please tell me,
why you have decided
to make this generous gift?
- (SNIFFLES)
- Are you under duress?
No.
Look at me.
It is unclean money, sir.
It belongs to a man who
has done great evil.
(SNIFFLES)
My father.
I wish to be free of him.
Whose sins do you renounce
by making this gift?
The sins of my father.
And your own sins?
(SIGHS)
I believe you feel lost,
without God or love.
You must choose the path of Allah.
Only then will you be truly
free of this burden.
(DOOR OPENS)
I am satisfied, Mr. Brue,
that his offer is genuine.
Wonderful.
This is a list of charities,
with their banking details,
for your verification.
Please.
It seems in order.
ABDULLAH: I will await further instruction.
Michael.
Welcome to Berlin.
Everyone got my report?
Yes.
You need to concentrate on Burgdorf,
Ministry of the Interior.
The final decision will be his.
I'm going to need passports
for Karpov and the Turks.
We don't do passports.
He gave the lawyer his word.
GUNTHER: I did, and this time
I want it to mean something.
It's up there.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
We've checked every name
on the charity list.
They're all clean.
Herr Bachmann, please.
You're looking at me, at us,
but we don't exist,
not legally, not officially,
because German intelligence
needs a job to be done
that German law won't let it do,
so me and my people we stay small.
We stay on the streets.
We make the weather.
Our sources don't come to us, we find them.
Uh, we become their friends.
Their brothers, their fathers,
their lovers, if we have to.
When they're ours, and only then,
we direct them at bigger targets.
It takes a minnow to catch a barracuda.
A barracuda to catch a shark.
I don't fish, Herr Bachmann.
MICHAEL: It's a metaphor, Erhardt.
Just a metaphor.
We take our time.
We watch. We wait.
We see what Allah provides.
Uh, well, this time Allah has provided
lssa Karpov and his ill-gotten millions.
As you can see from the report
my team has compiled,
Dr. Abdullah has provided
an extensive list of his favorite charities
to be the recipients of those millions.
Each one of those charities
has been CIA cleared.
It is my belief he will replace
one of the names on this list with another.
Seven Friends Navigation Company.
What kind of proof can you show us?
Proof is what we're looking for.
If this Abdullah,
if this barracuda,
if I've understood the metaphor,
takes the bait,
with what leverage
will you secure his cooperation?
On the negative, uh,
threat of prosecution, prison,
uh, public humiliation,
discrediting of his charities,
um, deportation of his wife and children.
I choose the positive.
Amnesty, citizenship, for which he
has applied half a dozen times.
Now we are offering
citizenship to financiers of terror?
You are all familiar with
the operational plan?
We have three hours
to apprehend Abdullah and make him ours
and get him back home
before anyone notices.
And if he does not comply?
Then he's yours.
Do with him whatever you need to do.
And lssa Karpov?
He's to be left alone.
In my eyes it's unacceptable.
Find someone else to parade
before the cameras.
That was agreed.
He has our protection.
Martha, what is the American perspective?
Maybe if you could define for us
what you think
the long-term objective would be.
What are we trying to achieve?
To make the world a safer place.
Isn't that enough?
Mr. Brue?
Tomorrow morning.
Thank you for letting me know.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
How are you feeling?
Good.
You drop him at the bank
and then you disappear.
Do you understand?
You are forcing me to betray my own father.
You are not betraying him.
You are saving him.
That is an act of love.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(PLAYING SOFT CLASSICAL MUSIC)
(ANNABEL EXHALES)
He's been granted asylum.
It was the best I could do.
ANNABEL: I gave you lssa.
Issa gives you Abdullah.
What's next?
What will you do to him?
To Abdullah?
Yes.
Nothing bad.
I promise.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Look.
What does this mean?
It means you can stay.
I have something for you.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
- TOMMY: Doctor.
- ABDULLAH: Hello, Mr. Brue.
TOMMY: This confirms the receipt of funds
From Mr. Karpov
in to your new account we've set up here.
These are the charities
you specified with their bank details.
Each of the transfers is logged in
to our system and is ready to go.
Oh.
Would you please check all the details?
The name of the account holders
and the money assigned to each recipient
and then authorize each one
with your signature.
I would like to make a substitute.
I need to change a name.
TOMMY: Seven Friends Navigation Company?
ABDULLAH: Yes.
It is a shipping company,
but one whose business is charity.
We can have all the aid in the world
but it's worthless unless you can get it
to the people who need it.
Mmm-hmm.
Yes.
All right.
Your final signature.
Ah!
(EXHALES)
(EXHALES IN RELIEF)
(MAXI SIGHS)
ABDULLAH: Thank you very much.
Excuse me.
(LINE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Unfortunately my son is delayed.
Allow us to call you a taxi.
- I'm going in.
- MAXIMILIAN: Good luck.
GUNTHER: Right.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yes.
Taxi for Brue Freres.
(DOOR OPENS)
A pleasure.
As-salam.
My direction, Blankenese.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- (HORN HONKING)
- (GASPS)
Ahhh!
Stay back!
(GRUNTS)
Wait.
Stop! What are you doing?
- Wait.
- ANNABEL: No!
No. (SCREAMS)
lssa!
- ABDULLAH: What's going on?
- ANNABEL: No!
No!
MAN: Stand up.
ANNABEL: No!
(GRUNTS)
No!
- (GROANS)
- Issa, no!
Stop it! No!
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- No, lssa!
(GRUNTING)
- Ahhh!
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
Fuck!
(WHEEZING)
Ahhh! Fuck!
(CONTINUES WHEEZING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(ENGINE STARTS)