I am retiring tomorrow.
From past few weeks,
many people have asked me..
.. that Mr. Prakash Rathod police
commissioner of Mumbai..
.. that which was the most challenging
and interesting case of your life.
I ignored this question.
Every time.. but every time
I remembered only one case.
This case is not registered
in any file anywhere.
There is no record anywhere.
But it is in my mind..
.. and some people who were involved
in this case unwillingly.
That bastard.
That bastard just had guts to walk
into our lives and blow it apart.
It was a Wednesday.
Hello! Where are you going?
To file a FIR.
To the right. Room number 3.
Who hit you?
- My wife.
I wanted to file an FIR. -Then what
is there to be embarrassed about?
How? - With a cooker.
I want to file a complaint.
Wait for a while.
I will call you. Have a seat.
Why did she hit you?
The problem was.. that..
Come on. Speak up. There
are other people waiting.
I just told her that there
was more salt in the food.
She just flared up.
There was a cooker to her right.
She picked it and hit
me on my left side.
Sir please.. just warn her once.
She keeps hitting me.
You should never ever say
such things to your wife.
Go home and say sorry.
Or else instead of salt she will
put something else in your food.
Did you understand?
Don't take it too seriously. Go on.
Sir, but file a report at least..
- Get lost!
Hey mister, hello..
Mr. Jammu Kashmir please come.
What happened?
- I lost my wallet.
How? What do you mean by how?
How do things get lost?
I mean, where was it lost?
- I don't remember.
When I checked it wasn't with me.
What were its contents?
A photograph of my wife,
driving license. PAN card.
Easy, easy. Sorry.
PAN card, ATM card,
and credit card...
...A railway pass.
Some cash. My wife's photograph.
You have already said that.
- What?
You have already told me about
your wife's photograph.
How much cash was in it?
- Around 300-350 rupees.
Where is the washroom?
- What's your name and address?
Rajesh Kumar Sharma. 301,
Mansarovar Society.
S.V. Road, Borivali (west).
Telephone number?
- 9832456784.
Take this.
Call up tomorrow and enquire.
The washroom is to the
right over there.
Thank you.
Sir, it's always a number from
Karachi that flashes on my mobile.
initially, he used to address
me as brother, sir or boss.
He had said his name was Imtiaz.
He said he watches my
films many times..
.. and that he was
a great fan of mine.
Then he called today and
asked me to pay up 25 lakh rupees.
Said it was an emergency.
Mr. Arjun Khanna,
what exactly did he say?
Crush, scene 20, shot 20, take 20.
Help me, please!'
'Please! Help me, please!'
Thank you so much.
Get up!
Cut it!
Oh god.
Hey get the table. Good shot.
- Yeah thanks!
Hello! -
Why aren't you signing Desai's film?
He is my special friend. If I don't
get any good news by noon.
I will pack
- up your shooting forever.
And keep 25 lakh rupees on hand.
I will call you up later and
tell you whom to give it to
25 lakhs!
And why the hell do you delay
so much to take the call?
Make sure that you pick it up
within two rings the next time.
Hello? - Just checking. '
Hang it up now.
Where is Jai?
You know that I don't like your
traveling in the train with the baby?
If I go by road
I will reach tomorrow.
Why do you go to your
mom's place so often?
This is the first time I am
going since she was born.
But she'd come to our house
just last week. - So?
She was also there the
week before that. - So?
This should stop.. Or else
the sub-inspector in..
.. your mom's area is a
good friend of mine.
Why are you so scared of my mom?
Am not scared. Just
jealous of her..
.. that she spends so much more
time with you two than me.
Ok I will take your leave.
Bye. Take care. Bye.
Call me up. - Yes, I will
call up on reaching there.
Okay bye.
- Bye.
See you. Take care.
Just 20 rupees! Where is your
pollution certificate?
Come on, sir. Keep it.
Not even one document you have.
Take out the money.
Where is your license? Look you
don't have license with you.
Now come on, give me Rs. 500.
Come on sir, take it. Keep it.
Hello sir.
What are you doing?
Sir, I have stopped asking. But
they keep bribing me willingly.
Ask him... Wasn't I telling
you not to give me anything?
Sir, what can I do if they
give it with so much love?
Too much of such love
has made you plump.
And you still want some more.
- Sorry sir.
How much did you take? - 20 rupees!
Give it back!
- Take it.
Give him 20 more. - What?
You should also share your
love with others. - Okay sir.
Did you just give me money?
Father was right and I was wrong.
Times have changed. The New Age
is here - All right, go on.
This is good! This is good!
This is good!
Come on move aside! Move aside!
Ready to move in! Three!
Two! One! Go!
Thank you, Deepak.
This is the same electric
pole to which..
.. a man had been stuck to for
15 minutes and still survived.
Yes. Shambu fell down
in this pothole..
.. while returning from
work last evening.
Because of this live wire
he got stuck to this pole.
And it is a miracle that
he is still alive..
.. after receiving electric shock..
.. of such high voltage for
15 minutes. consecutively.
So let's talk to Shambu who had
experienced this incident.
Mr. Shambu, how do you feel?
I feel good.
Tell our viewers how
did you feel when..
.. such high voltage shocks were
passing through your body?
Call for technical snag
in ten seconds.
Naina, repeat the question.
Tell us how did you feel when..
.. high voltage shocks were
passing through you?
Great! I felt very good.
Now people call you
'The Electric man'.
How does that feel?
Very good.
- Cut it!
What is it, now?
We'll do it again in five minutes!
Give him something to say.
He seems to like everything.
He gets drunk and falls down.
The other day we both
drank together..
.. and we both fell together
in the gutter but..
.. nobody cared then. Now look
at him, he has become famous.
Get me out of here.
They beat me up every day.
Two guys came in my cell
yesterday and beat me all over.
You'd said I would be okay
if I turned informer.
But look what happened?
I was put to rot in here and you
were transferred to the ATS.
Arif, either get me out
of this place or kill me.
But don't leave me here.
My family is threatened every day.
The constable who is supposed to
protect my family harasses my sister.
I have heard that you are going to
get transferred somewhere else?
I heard it too.
If the department doesn't care
about you why will it care for me?
Can I get a cup of tea?
- Right away sir.
You want to go to the hospital?
- Sure.
Stay there for some days. I
will take care of the rest.
You trust me, don't you?
- I have only you to trust.
Thank you, brother.
Who is on duty at your house?
- Badge number 1275.
Sir, I feel that I am
being targeted..
.. because I belong to
the minority group.
Minority! Mr. Ajay Khanna, how can
you belong to a minority group?
The Khan's are in majority
in our film industry.
it’s just Mr. Amitabh, Abhishek
and I on the other side.
That's true.
Sir.
Mr. Khanna, this is sub-inspector
Jai Singh.
He will handle your case. Be rest
assured, we will crack this soon.
Sir, I just hope nothing
will happen to me.
C'mon! You are a hero.
Does anything ever happen to
our heroes in our films?
Sometimes it does.
Just in case anything
happens to you then..
.. I assure you that we
will not spare them.
Sir, what are you..?
Relax! Go to work. Nothing
will happen to you.
Thank you sir. Thank you very much.
It is okay.
My brother. My brother.
Thank you! Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
- Yeah, mention not.
These are our heroes. One phone
call and he gets a stomach ache
Some kids from Shanti Nagar
are playing a prank on him.
Patwardhan knows them.
Ask him to stop them or else he
will be wasting our time needlessly.
Right sir.
Shambu, who is responsible
for this incident?
I feel they did a good job by
putting up an electric pole.
But they should not have
dug this hole.
The government should think
twice before digging..
.. that a common man like me
can fall into this pothole.
Look around! Today there
are potholes everywhere.
I mean are there potholes in the
city or this city is in potholes?
This government should take
responsibility for these potholes.
So what do you feel? Why does
the government do such things?
The government likes to dig.
So this was Mr. Shambu. k.a.
Electric man who..
.. has given Death itself
a very big shock.
This is Naina Roy with cameraman
Raj for UTV news.
Sir.. sir, why are you hitting me?
Sir, why are you hitting me?
Yes, tell me!
- Don't get annoyed but..
.. I just found out that
I don't have..
.. some ingredients to
make the rice pudding.
You know very well
Ishaan loves rice pudding.
While coming home bring
some almonds, raisins..
All right I will bring
all those things.
Don't forget to buy those tomatoes.
- No I won't.
I am sorry. Are you angry with me?
Just a bit. But then, I have the
whole city to vent it out.
When will you come back?
Around 7 o'clock.
Come back and we'll talk.
- Yes.
The government should think
twice before digging..
.. that a common man like me
can fall into this pothole.
Look around! Today there
are potholes everywhere.
I mean are there potholes in the
city or this city is in potholes?
This government should take
responsibility for these potholes.
Sir, please forgive me.
Hello.
- Is it Commissioner Prakash Rathod?
Who's this?
Mr. Rathod, don't interrupt
and just listen.
I have planted bombs at 5 different
locations in the city.
All these bombs will
explode at 6.30 pm.
But this can be avoided.
I will call you up 30 minutes later..
.. with my demands and I want to talk
or negotiate with only one person.
Until then you can decide
on that person.
Hello!
Find out who had called
on my mobile just a while back.
Jai, where is the chief minister?
Hello.
- Miss Naina Roy?
Yes, who is this?
It doesn't matter.
I just wanted to ask you..
.. whether you are interested
in some serious news.
What? Is this some kind..
- Just answer me Naina.
This is big. Are you interested?
Yes or no?
Yes.
Then come to the Mumbai Police
headquarters with your cameraman.
This is going to be the most
important day in your life.
I will call you again.
Raj!
I know this is an unknown number.
Keep trying. I want to know
that number within 5 minutes.
And ask Khatri to tap my mobile
phone immediately. Okay.
Yes Tiwari, I am putting him
on the line. Right away.
Sir, it's Tiwari.
Mr. Tiwari!
- Yes, Mr. Prakash, tell me.
Where is the CM?
He is in Bandra to attend
an important meeting.
Put Mr. Patil on the line.
Mr. Patil is also in a meeting.
Tell me, what is the matter?
It is a very minor thing.
I cannot bother you with it.
Put Patil on the line.
Sir, I hope you understood.
Sir, he wants to talk to you.
Excuse me.
- Okay.
Yes, Mr. Prakash.
I don't know how but come to
my office within 15 minutes.
But.. - Within 15 minutes.
it’s an emergency.
Jai, tell Chouhan, Ramesh and Aakash
to come into the WAR Room.
Right sir.
Sir. It is a prepaid mobile number.
It is registered to
one Jignesh Sheth.
He lives in Malad. I have informed
Malad police station.
This number is unreachable
right now. - Okay.
Attention guys!
This matter should not
get out of this room.
Does anyone of you wants to
call anybody or warn anyone?
No sir!
We have just 4 hours left.
Chouhan, talk to Abbas at intelligence
and find out what they have.
Tell them you need this information
for verification.
Yes sir!
Vatkar, find out from
our sources whether..
.. there has been any movement
in any terrorist module.
Get me any information on explosives
being taken in and out of the city.
Get in touch with your informers.
Right sir.
Aakash, we need to trace
the call the next time.
Put your best men on the job.
Yes sir!
Mr. Rathod, how are you?
- I am fine. And you?
Fine. Tell me.
Just a while back I received
a call on my cell phone.
One man..
Oh god. Excuse me.
It could also be a crank call.
We can't take any chances.
Where is the CM?
He is on his way.
Hello!
Yes, Mr. Rathod. Who is
going to talk to me?
Mr. Roy. He will be here soon.
Until then you can talk to me.
I will only talk to the person who
has the authority to take decisions.
I will call you again
in five minutes.
By the way let me remind you that
you are wasting your own time.
Take my advice. You shouldn't
buy time on this.
Too short to trace. But this is not
the same number as the previous one.
Excuse me sir.
There was a call from
Malad police station.
Nobody named Jignesh Sheth
lives at that address.
Do one thing, tell Solanki to
alert all the police stations.
Sir, the CM is on the line.
Good afternoon, sir.
- Good afternoon.
Who is this Roy?
- Nobody.
Who is negotiating with
him from our side?
Sir, you will. We will patch
his call to you from here.
Why? -Because you have the authority
and you know how to negotiate.
There is a lot of difference between
giving a Speech and Negotiating.
This is not a political rally.
What about Patil or Tiwari?
Oh my God!
Prakash, I have never seen you
running away from responsibility.
There is a reason for it.
If this man is telling
the truth then to stop him..
.. we require a person with
unlimited authority.
There shouldn't be any
red tape or protocol.
He would need absolute
and complete freedom.
He should not be questioned
about anything.
And I know that this is not
possible and that's why..
.. I was running away from
responsibility Sir.
Patil, this operation will be
headed by Prakash Rathod.
I don't want any complaints
from him. Do you understand?
I'll be there soon.
Yes, sir. Should we
inform the center?
This is our problem and
we have to solve it.
Okay sir.
Come on guys, back to work,
everyone.
Excuse me.
- Yeah.
Hello.
- Mr. Rathod?
Mr. Roy won't be here. I will
negotiate instead of him.
How can he come there
if he doesn't exist?
What do you want?
Ibrahim Khan, Iqlak Ahmed, Mohammed
Zaheer and Khursheed Lala.
Who are these guys?
You yourself had caught two of them.
And the ATS got the other two.
I hope it is not difficult.
Why would it be? We are used to it.
First we put our lives at
stake and catch them and..
.. then when a phone call
comes we set them free.
You will do the same thing today.
They all are in different places
right now. I'll call you in an hour.
Till then it is your job to get
them together at one place.
On whose behalf are you doing this?
What is the name of
your organization?
Do you suspect that this
is a crank call? -
I do.
Mr. Rathod, you must
know by now that..
.. Jignesh Sheth had died
in the last bomb blast.
The next number belonged
to Sanjay Singh..
.. who had died three months back.
The current number that you
will trace belongs to..
.. Shabbir Ahmed who has also
died a long way back.
Any Tom, Dick and Harry can do this.
Yes I agree. But any Tom,
Dick and Harry..
.. cannot blow away
the police station..
.. which is just opposite
your Police headquarters.
What do you mean?
It means I have also planted a
bomb in the police station..
.. opposite your headquarters
just to prove..
.. my mettle and your helplessness.
You have 20 minutes to
find it. So go find it.
Or else an hour later I may
have to talk to someone else.
Mr. Prakash, can we go
out for half an hour.
Jai!
- Yes sir!
Are you afraid?
- No sir.
Are you married?
- Two years ago.
Do you have a kid?
- I have a 3-month-old daughter.
What happens if you die?
- I don't care.
I want that bomb found within
ten minutes. - You'll get it, sir.
Give me your radio. - Sir.
Hello.
Naina Roy, someone
has planted a bomb..
.. in the police station opposite
the headquarters.
I thought you'd be interested.
Oh God!
Relax guys! This man wants
us to find the bomb.
He wants us to take him seriously.
He wants us to find it.
We just have one hour. I don't
want to talk to this man again.
Sir, Chouhan is on the line.
Chouhan, tell me.
Sir, the intelligence has
no information about this.
That's consistent.
Chouhan, step up security at airports,
rail stations and bus depots.
Search everything and everyone.
Send them in batches of 4
to the multiplexes as well.
I want you to cover up as
much ground as possible.
If someone asks tell them
it is just a police drill..
.. or tell them it's the CM's orders.
Get on it now!
All units alert, sir.
Deshmukh, where is my bomb squad?
Aakash, call up Arif. I
want him here a. s. a. p.
And I want an update on Ibrahim
Khan, Iqlak Ahmed..
.. Mohammad Zaheer
and Khursheed Lala.
You've got ten minutes.
- Yes sir.
Then send them here!
Bomb squad! Come in!
Has nobody seen Baburao?
Yeah Mhatre, come in.
Copy that.
What is it?
- Sir, it is RDX.
Come here! A bomb was
placed right under nose!
What the hell were you doing?
Who is the shift in-charge?
Sir, there was a shift change
just half an hour ago.
I don't know anything.
Find him in 5 minutes and
send him to me. - Okay sir.
Sir! We have located the bomb.
It is RDX.
He had planned to trigger
it with a cell phone.
Good.
Sir, please come this way.
I have solid information.
There has been a pull-up
from the underworld.
He had supplied 6 kgs of
RDX couple of days back.
He has not opened his mouth yet.
On threatening him he
said he has taken..
.. his painkillers
just this morning.
That's a new one.
Sir, I don't know anything!
Did I ask you anything?
Nobody has confirmed this
information but..
.. suddenly there is a lot of
activity in the police station.
You can see the bomb squad
and the sniffer dogs here.
They have just come out.
But we have been denied
any information about it.
We would like to inform our
viewers once again that..
.. we had received information..
.. about the bomb via
a telephone call.
Seems that the bomb has
been found and diffused.
We have not received
any confirmation yet.
But we will keep trying.
From Mumbai this is Naina Roy with
cameraman Raj for UTV news. - Over.
I want the forensic report
immediately in the WAR room.
Sir! - Okay sir.
Thank you.
Mhatre come in. copy.
Sir, the Psycho has arrived.
Someone's going to die today.
Hello.
- Are you busy?
Yes. Not really.
We have reached here safely.
How is mom?
- She is fine.
Give it to me.
What is the matter?
Are you worried about something?
Not at all. - I'll call
you before leaving.
Okay. Take care. Bye.
There was no direct
contact with me.
I only gave the delivery.
I got a message to deliver
that bag to Rafiq.
He was Rafiq's customer.
I asked Rafiq who he was.
He said, your place is behind
and asked me to shut up.
Where can I find Rafiq?
Sir, I don't know.
If I had known I would tell you.
Believe me. sir, I would..
Bohri Market. 4th Lane.
Where are you these days?
I am with the ATS.
You had got me transferred.
Yes. Arif, I want that man and
the information that he has.
Vatkar will tell you where
to find him. Don't kill him.
I just need the information.
Okay sir.
- Okay.
Yes.
- Sir, the bomb has been diffused.
Who was on duty?
- Prashant.
Tell him to go home. He will receive
his termination letter tomorrow.
Tell Kailash to take over.
The media is here. UTV news.
Bring them upstairs.
- Right sir.
Ibrahim Khan. He has links
with the Al-Qaeda.
He was head-of-operations
in India since 92.
This is his designation
on their website.
He has started 45 madrasas
in the country..
.. where little kids are taught
the meaning of Jihad.
On his capture they will
be weakened and if..
.. he is set free then they will
be completely rejuvenated.
This is their second
attempt to free him.
He is extremely dangerous.
Iqlak Ahmed. Al Qaeda again.
Right hand of Ibrahim Khan.
He is a former ISl agent.
The theory is that..
.. when you had nabbed him
he wanted to get caught.
So that it would be easy
to free Ibrahim Khan.
He was directly or indirectly
involved in all..
.. the terrorists attacks in India
in the last three years.
He is equally dangerous if not more.
Mohammad Zaheer. He is the number
2 agent of Laskar in India.
He is a former ISl as well
as former Al Qaeda member.
He was a software engineer.
Due to systematic brainwashing
he went to Pakistan.
From there he went to Afghanistan.
He acquired his training over there.
He has designed a lot
of websites for them.
One of his websites is called
www. indiakitabaahi. com
Very basic but very effective.
It registered record number
of hits the day it opened.
He is in our C-Zone hospital
since last week.
He had complained of chest pains.
Khursheed Lala. He is an arms pimp.
He is not connected to just one
organization but with all of them.
If you need arms and explosives
then this is your Guy.
He will supply any
quantity you want.
No matter it is 1993 or 2006.
Lala is behind the bars or free.
He doesn't leave a trail.
Sir, you may remember that
even when you had arrested him..
.. we had only found
a blue-print of..
.. the Mumbai city and
a revolver on him.
Very soon he will be out on bail.
Sir, Here is a speculation.
Look at this. We don't know his
name but he is everywhere.
He has succeeded to
remain out of sight.
Our intelligence agencies have
no information about him.
There are only rumours.
Some say he is their CEO and others
say he is the chief strategist.
Sir, he is one among the crowd.
Even his wife doesn't know
what he really does.
This man could be behind this call.
He may belong to Laskar, Al
Qaeda or some other outfit.
We don't know whether he
is in the country or not.
There must be a couple of people
with him in this operation.
They have already targeted the
stock exchange..
.. buses and local trains.
I suspect this time they
will go a step further.
That they have come so close
to the police headquarters..
.. has business written all over it.
Aakash, this man is in the city.
We have to catch him.
Sir, what should we do
about the other four?
We are always two steps behind
them and if they are freed..
Let them be where they are.
It doesn't make any sense
to free Lala now..
.. he is going to get free as is.
And by doing this Lala will be
regarded a certified terrorist.
Maybe they need Lala right now.
Maybe.
Uncle! Three tea.
Hey, send money to me.
When did you receive
the first call?
Ok Alright then you and
your cameraman will remain..
.. in custody until you come
out with the truth.
He had called up at
around 2 pm and..
.. he had asked me to come here.
He had also said that
this would be..
.. the most important day of my life.
He is using you.
He is watching our situation
and our panic Live on TV.
You are his bloody eyes.
Sir, he is around 50. Tall
man. Wears a spectacle.
He looks like a clerk.
There is an under
construction building..
.. in Malad west behind Pritam
Nagar. Om constructions.
I had delivered the
goods on the 12th floor.
Vatkar! - Yes sir. - Take him away.
Hello.Sir, this is Arif.
Yes I got it.
There is an under construction
building in Malad.
Patkar is bringing Rafiq
to the headquarters.
Should I send Jai?
- There's no need.
I will nab him and get
him to speak to you.
What was your name again?
Naina.
Naina, I want you to do me a favour.
Sir, until you don't tell me
everything I can't help you.
Okay. Come here.
This matter should be only
between you and me.
Three. Two. One. Go.
We have just received
information that..
.. four terrorists whose
names are Ibrahim Khan..
.. Iqlak Ahmed, Mohammad Zaheer
and Khursheed Lala..
.. are being shifted to
some other location.
The police says it is because
of security reasons.
Right now we have Senior
inspector Jai Singh..
.. who will give us full information
about this matter.
What is the reason behind shifting
these four to some other location?
There are some security reasons.
We have orders to do so.
But why such an order?
We have received orders to do so.
Can you tell us whether there is
any threat to them and from whom?
It is because of some
security reasons..
.. that we have received
orders to shift them
As you can see, the police is not
giving us any further information.
And they are trying to
avoid our questions..
.. by calling it a security reason.
From Mumbai this is Naina Roy with
cameraman Raj for UTV news.
Cut it!
Sir, please don't do this again. My
wife watches the news channels.
That was good Jai.
Thank you Naina.
Once again India approached America
with regards to Pakistan issue.
The government is spending
crores of rupees to save..
.. but due to legal reasons,
they are..
Now, for the latest news let's move
to our correspondent Naina Roy..
What is the reason behind shifting
these four to some other location?
There are some security reasons.
We have orders to do so.
But why such an order?
We have received orders to do so.
Arif, tell me.
Sir, there is nobody here. But
he wanted us to come here.
There are tags of 'Do
not disturb' in here.
Come back.
- Yes sir.
Jai
We have to shift these four
terrorists to a single location.
Start the process.
- Sir.