Lord Ganesh!
Shambu, we've got the
license for the salt factory.
Go tell Master Sir, run along...
Hello Landlord! Greetings Landlord!
- Master Sir's here!
- Hello, master.
- Greetings Master!
- Bless me, Master.
Hello Mr. Landlord!
What's the matter Sir?
They seem to
honouring you more than ever!
Oh... what are you saying?!
Sister, Viju's here.
Viju, go for it!
Very good! Very good!
- Go for it.
- Master... Sir, look!
- Suhasini.
- What?
Very good!
Surya, this isn't enough.
It's enough for you.
Surya, everyone has a
right over this money.
It must be distributed equally.
Smartass! You take your share...
Don't worry about the others.
Don't be a hero!
I insist, equal distribution!
Get lost!
Equal distribution, you wish!
Let's go.
Surya...
Vijay, stop. What are you doing?
Vijay... I said stop.
- Father, that is our money...
- Vijay.
Vijay, you don't have to cry...
Then what do you want me to do?
Beg and plead to people?
No, you shouldn't do that either.
So you want me to
live like a coward then?
I broke the pot, and he
took away all the money.
Is this what your Gita preaches?
If I see him around,
I'll punch his face.
And then what will happen?
He will punch your face, then
you'll punch him back again...
and then he'll punch you back.
And it will never end.
"An eye for an eye makes
the whole world blind..."
Mahatma Gandhi once said...
Mahatma Gandhi wasn't born in Mandwa!
My son has a lot of
anger inside of him.
You only preach to me.
Why don't you tell the others?
Because you are my son.
Come...
come now.
It isn't wrong to
care about the world...
but before the world
comes your own family.
And this is why I'm
looking out for my family.
I'm not telling you
to be a coward, Vijay.
It is important to have power...
the question is how you use it.
The weak can't say that they
have forgiven the powerful.
For that, the weak must
themselves become powerful.
Then whether or not to
forgive is up to you.
If you do forgive, you
will be hailed as great.
If not...
then you will be nothing.
And till you become powerful,
you get beaten up everyday.
Says who?
Keep reciting the verse with me.
I've done it a million times, father.
So what? Do it once more.
I derive my strength from this.
You shall too.
There you stand, a tall tree.
You are well-laden and tall.
But don't ever ask
for even a little shade.
On the path of fire.
You will never tire
you will never rest.
- You...
- Father...
You will never look back.
Take an oath.
On the path of fire.
Life is but a great scene.
That man is walking on.
With tears and sweat.
Soaked in blood.
On the path of fire.
You have ruled over
Mandwa for years Sir.
Earlier, you were the king and
the people were your subjects.
The Master is becoming the king now.
Do something sir...
or even you will
become one of the subjects.
School textbooks are growing
more important than our Registers.
When does Kancha get here?
Tomorrow morning.
Hey baldie!
No... no... I don't want mirrors...
No... I don't want mirrors.
- Kancha! Kancha! Kancha!
- I don't want mirrors. I don't want.
No, Kancha my son... My child.
Father... everyone looks at
me and calls me a ghost!
Father, do I...
do I look like a ghost?
Don't worry.
You are but my own father.
But then what's a father, a mother,
a brother or a sister?
What did you get with you...
and what will you take back?
Only one will survive...
the supreme...
and all powerful...
Kancha...
You should have held
up for a while longer.
I would have been dead. Sir...
Here's your share... 600 only.
Take it.
- 600.
Now it's his turn sir...
- now your turn... yours... yours. Come.
- Go for it!
Two hundred...
- three hundred...
- Three hundred...
four hundred...
Sir...
Sir... he will die...
Sir... He will die...
- Sir, what are you doing?
- I don't want.
Sir... he will die...
What are you doing?
Sir... Sir... Sir...
Sir... he will die...
Master...
Life is a lot more
precious than this game, Kancha.
Life is submerged underwater Master...
it's begging and pleading.
Because today life means...
money...
Sniff it Master...
you'll know what bliss means.
You've stepped into Mandwa
after a long time Kancha.
Let Mandwa respect you properly.
What respect are you talking about,
Master? I would've...
- taken it in my arms.
- Sir...
But the earth has heated up Master...
embracing her would be fatal.
Do you understand
what I mean by fatal...
an illness...
destruction...
disease.
And this disease will spread Master...
in front of your very eyes,
it will spread.
Brothers...
I've come here to
repay my loyalty to Mandwa.
I will set up a salt factory here...
Factory!
Our salt will sell outside...
It will command unheard of prices...
- and we will earn unforeseen revenues.
- Fantastic!
But for that...
I need your land on lease.
- Lease.
- What's lease?!
- I mean loan! Loan.
- Loan.
Loan!
I mean it will be on loan with me.
The profits of the land are yours...
the revenue is yours...
only the factory is mine,
and the money it makes is mine.
What do you say?
We accept!
Do you have faith in your Master?
Yes, we do.
Then promise you won't
loan your lands to Kancha.
Oh rain come to me,
I shall give you a bribe.
The bribe you have accepted,
the storm has arrived.
He's taking your land on
lease for a hundred years.
Which one you will
live that long to see...
what he actually
does with your land?
When it rains...
the land of Mandwa sprouts a plant...
coca!
Our own salt factory is
enough for Mandwa's progress.
We shall be both the owners
and the workers of that factory.
All it'll take is a little
patience and hard work...
From Coca, Cocaine is made...
whose taste causes a
man to forget himself...
whose smell makes a man feel
like he's flying in the sky...
it sells in the outside
markets for millions...
and it's been here all along...
yet you dimwits couldn't see it.
So tell Kancha that you
won't give him your land.
We won't!
Landlord, Sir...
the Master is conducting a meeting
with the villagers under the tree.
Master...
Surya said you wanted to see me.
I remember switching the lights off...
Suhasini, I'll be right back.
What's the matter?
Where are you going?
I guess I left the school lights on.
Viju, go along with your father.
Father, wait for me.
Soorti.
Father...
Wait here.
Bindiya...
Bindiya... What happened?
What happened?
How did this happen?
Bindiya...
Tell me, how did this happen?
Vijay...
why are you still there?
Get your mother, quick!
Hurry up!
Yes... tell me...
How did this happen?
Bindiya... open your eyes.
Uncle...
something happened to
Bindiya in school...
Listen to me...
Don't spare him!
Mother...
Mother, something
happened to Bindiya in school...
Father, has called you.
Mother!
Viju...
Bindiya...
Where is Bindiya?
- Bindiya. Bindiya.
- Master, where is she?
There is Bindiya.
- Bindiya...
Bindiya, how did this happen?
Bindiya, what happened?
Bindiya! What happened?
Speak up, dear. What happened?
Why did you come here? Who called you?
Answer, who called you here?
- What happened?
- What happened, my dear?
- Master...
Master...
what did you do to this little girl?
I didn't do anything...
Master, Bindiya is
pointing towards you.
Bindiya...
Master, how could you?
- Darn you!
- Wait!
- Have you lost it?
- Of course! You are the Master's disciple!
Listen to me...
So... Master, what did you do?
- Speak up?
- What are you insinuating?
What did you do to her?
Will you at least listen to me.
Darn you, master! How
could you do this, Master?
Viju... be careful, my dear...
You killed our daughter!
Kill him...
- What are you...
- You killed our daughter!
- Kill him.
- Wait...
Wait...
Step back, I say.
Step back...
Mother...
Go to your father...
Go to your father.
Father...
- Son.
- Let my father go...
Father...
You see, Vijay...
your father has committed a grave sin!
He doesn't deserve to live!
- He is the scum of our village...
- No!
Father!
You will pay for it, Master!
Your ghost will hang from the tree!
- Kill him!
- Father!
All of us honoured your father...
and he has put our honour to shame...
today we will kill your father!
We'll kill him and
hang him from this tree!
Hang him on the banyan tree.
Father!
A little jolt on the path of
Mandwa's progress and well-being.
Father...
What did you get with you...
and what will you take back?
There's no need to worry...
and no need to be afraid of anyone...
Who can kill you?
The soul is neither born nor dies.
Father...
Father!
Dead!
The master is dead!
Farewell Master!
Father!
- He got what he deserved.
- The master is dead!
Father!
Nobody will give wood for his pyre.
Let him hang here.
Master, you won't
even have a cremation!
Let him rot.
Mandwa has been rid of this demon.
Vultures.
Leave him hanging...
Nobody will give wood for his pyre.
Mother... Mother, what happened?
Tell me, mother. Mother!
Mother, say something!
Mother, what is it?
What happened, mother?
I don't know what's
happening to my mother...
Please help!
Get lost kid!
It's time for business, so scram!
Somebody help my mother!
Get lost!
What the...
I don't know what's
happening to my mother...
She is in pain... I
don't know what's happening!
- Where is your mother?
- There!
Mother... are you alright?
Is my mother alright?
She will be okay, right?
She is having labor pain.
Kali what are you staring at?
Hurry up and get Ashatai!
Oh God!
What happened, Lachi?
Nothing yet, but something sure will!
- Take a look!
- Mother!
What are you crying for?
Take him away from here.
Take him away... go!
Dulari, we need cover!
- Vijay!
- Mother!
All of you, what are you
staring at? Come fast!
Take a deep breath, my dear...
Mother!
Step back.
Go away.
You have a sister.
Here...
be careful.
What about my mother?
You mother is fine.
Mummy's boy!
Not like this!
This is how you tie it.
This is the problem with new people.
See how it's done.
Help! Help!
Get us out of here!
Take a look at this
fine specimen, gentlemen.
Leave me!
Fresh as a rose.
- She is mine!
- I want her.
I guarantee everything about her.
By the grace of Allah, if
you treat and feed her well...
in a year she will blossom.
May I have the bids...
Thirty thousand!
Forty thousand!
Lala bhai, sixty thousand!
Sixty thousand!
Sixty thousand, once...
Sixty thousand, twice... Sold!
Sold!
No!
Where is the stuff from?
Afghanistan.
Let me ask again...
where is the stuff from?
How does it matter?
It's genuine stuff.
Where are you growing it?
I want to sell my stuff in Mumbai.
State your demand.
I never liked hide and seek.
Whether the girl is of
eleven or sixteen...
I buy her.
The catch is I
should know her real age.
Now listen...
very carefully...
The fact is, Kancha...
I don't seem to like your face.
It's not because you are ugly.
I've seen worse.
But your face is disgusting...
disgusting.
And another thing...
business is conducted among equals.
Equals.
Kancha...
who 15 years ago, was merely a
small time crook in Mumbai...
nobody knows who his mother was...
probably is a bastard, probably not...
but the Police have a
picture in their record...
which is nothing like your face now.
Kancha, leave Mumbai or else...
Bloody Joker!
Joker!
I'm letting you go.
Today is my younger son's birthday.
Don't come again tomorrow.
Tomorrow it isn't his birthday.
Viju...
my mother has sent this.
You got your cut.
Now get lost.
Where is Tatya?
No. Don't do that.
No. Spare me.
My children are very small...
Kancha paid you to kill me...
and you accepted!
You accepted!
This bastard took money to kill me.
- Suleman!
- Yes?
I heard they eat dog
meat in some country...
So have I, bhai...
This dog accepted money to kill me.
I'm sure he has a large heart...
Let's rip it out and sell it.
We'll get a good price.
You...
Who are you?
- Vijay.
- Vijay?
Never saw you before.
How could you, if I wasn't here?
Smartass, huh?
Hey...
and who are you?
She is my daughter.
Oh...
she's all grown up and
I haven't noticed...
that's a wonder!
Those whores aren't going to testify.
Lala has cut their tongue.
But there is a twelve year old boy...
he was present at that time.
Then get him to testify.
Come on and don't you dare lie.
Tell us everything you saw
that day, just speak the truth.
Take it easy.
How old are you?
Twelve.
What's your name?
Vijay.
Don't be afraid.
Look carefully...
was it one of them?
It is important to have power...
the question is how you use it.
Don't be afraid... say it.
No.
The Police is with you,
don't be afraid.
No.
Vijay, this is Rauf Lala.
He killed Tatya in broad daylight.
I said it is none of them.
Don't lie, Vijay.
A child's words are the
voice of God, inspector.
Who can go against that?
So... can I leave?
Come on.
See you.
I want Mandwa...
back.
Everybody fears Lala...
And one day everybody will fear me.
And that very fear will
help us return to Mandwa.
We won't live here any more.
We will go away.
To a place where you won't
get these wild thoughts.
I'm scared, Vijay.
Scared for you and
your sister Shiksha.
Do you hear what I'm saying?
Viju... Viju, Shinde
is looking for you.
He wants to know why you
refused to identify Lala.
He is beating up my mother.
Viju, please come.
You whore...
where are you hiding the boy?
Because of what that boy did,
I had to face a lot of flak.
Get lost.
You know who I am, don't you?
Bloody rascal...
I've been looking all over for you.
Viju, don't...
Look at him...
threatening me with a gun.
Viju, the gun will go off!
He is only a child, let him go.
You want to shoot me?
Go ahead.
Shoot... what's wrong?
You will pay for this.
You will pay.
You want to shoot me...
you little prick!
Hey, this is not a toy gun.
Son, give me the gun. Give it to me.
Vijay, throw the gun away.
Throw the gun away.
Take a look, Lala bhai...
this is nice and fresh.
Let me see...
okay, cut it.
I want another one.
Look over there... Yusuf...
Woman trafficking
has gone up in Mumbai.
Additional commissioner, Mr. Gaitonde.
Are the Mumbai police sleeping?
Speak in turns.
Rauf Lala is connected
to almost every gang war.
Sir, don't you have
any evidence against him?
The police department is aware that...
under the guise
of Alif Meat Export...
Rauf Lala smuggles
drugs and traffics women.
But he gets wind of our
action before we can make a move.
And if somebody dares to
give witness against him...
he doesn't survive.
This reflects the
failure of our system that...
a small time trader
has become the mafia...
and rules over the
biggest slum in Asia.
By getting the unemployed...
and the homeless to work
for his illegal activities...
Lala has provided them a job
and a roof over their head.
In return he has bought
their unflinching loyalty.
And they are willing to
lay down their life for him.
There is another name
connected to the gang wars.
Kancha.
The police has been successful
in keeping Kancha out from Mumbai.
So where does Kancha
run his operations from?
Across the coast to the south
west of Mumbai is an island.
Mandwa.
That is his empire.
He runs Mandwa like
Hitler's concentration camp.
Kancha is in Mandwa but...
his roots have penetrated the system
here a lot deeper than Rauf Lala.
Five years ago the Mumbai
police carried out a raid on Mandwa.
Scores of innocent
residents died in the cross firing.
And we had a tough time facing
the Human Rights Commission.
Kancha still harbors
an unfinished dream...
Mumbai.
But as long as I am alive,
I won't let him have it.
Who is Vijay?
Is this a joke, Gaitonde?
I'm sorry but this is his
only official photograph...
in the police records.
Vijay Chauhan.
He has become a force to
reckon with in the last ten years.
He is Rauf Lala's right
hand and is very shrewd.
15 years ago, Rauf Lala had
bailed him out in connection...
with the killing
of a sub-inspector.
That was my case.
Since then the police hasn't
found any evidence against him.
Getting someone to give witness
against him has become a joke.
Everything he earns goes
into a charitable trust.
The trust operates a
number of ambulances in Mumbai.
Vijay Chauhan...
He looks simple...
but is the most complicated of all.
At an age when he
should've been playing with toys...
he learned to play
with guns and bullets.
It was as if he were at
war with law and order.
He leads a very low profile life...
and lives in a small
room in Dongri chawl.
Everything he earns, he gives away...
It's like he doesn't earn
money but earns people instead.
But his sights are set
on an unknown goal...
Something that only he knows.
Something that he wants to achieve...
at any cost.
Viju go for it!
Lift here...
A little higher... slowly...
How's it looking?!
Babban...
wait, wait...
like this...
You look just like Madhuri Dixit.
Yeah right!
Move it. Madhuri Dixit, right!
She is my darling Kaali.
You look so much like Silk Smita...
Silk Smita!
Oh my Kaali!
Why are you talking about her, Laxmi?
I'm happy to be Kaali.
Kaali Gawde.
Take a look at my staff.
Come on, stand in a line.
One... two... three... four.
Viju, over here!
They are imported.
Got them from Singapore...
pure Chinese!
What do they call you at home?
- Chabeeli.
- Hey... she speaks Nepali!
Darn you! Shut up!
They live in Nepal, but
they are pure Chinese.
Say you are Chinese.
I am Chinese... but I live in Nepal.
See that?
Laughter channel,
let's have some claps.
Why are you here?
You have to cut the ribbon.
Ruby, clear this crowd.
Come on...
Here, take this.
- Iqbal bhai!
- You're late, Iqbal bhai.
Okay, go in...
be careful of the ribbon.
The camera should
focus on me... a close-up.
Okay?
Let all of Dongri know that...
a Chinese Beauty Parlour should
be like Kaali's and no one else.
I should be all over cable TV.
I've taken the onus of
making Dongri beautiful.
You cut the ribbon!
I have yet to give my speech.
Rupees four thousand...
five hundred, sixty one.
First day collection.
And this is your share.
You helped me with the finance.
And no friendship in business.
What can I say, Viju...
I swear...
I've been dreaming
about this all my life.
To make others beautiful...
and look beautiful too.
I'll deck myself up in such a
way that people won't stop staring.
And they'll say, "Isn't that Kaali,
who owns the parlor?"
Tell me...
am I not shining bright?
So bright, I can feel it out here.
Groucho!
Oh, yes give me this.
What?
My wedding fund.
Only if I start saving now can I...
I mean there are so many things...
clothes, jewelry...
You've gone so quiet, it's as if
I got you in a Police encounter.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm sorry, Viju.
Sorry.
I said too much.
I remember everything...
I understand everything.
You don't want to get married but...
what can I do?
Sometimes,
unknowingly I end up dreaming.
But don't worry about me.
I'm fine, just the way I am.
Hello, Viju sir.
- Hello, Viju sir.
- Hello.
You wanted to see me?
Yes, come in.
I'm retiring this year.
But I don't have to tell you
that I won't go away empty handed.
Yesterday there was
an encounter in Kurla.
We shot dead six.
Four from Shantaram's gang and...
two from Rauf Lala's.
How is mother?
Don't you know?
I know.
If you know then why...
Tomorrow Shiksha will turn 15.
And I'm still the same old Vijay...
who came to this city 15 years ago.
Along with your
mother and unborn sister.
Who then left you and went away.
Who don't live with you.
You look at them from afar and...
try to console yourself
that you also have a family.
But you still haven't worked
up the courage to meet them.
To gain something, you have
give something up, Gaitonde sir.
What do you want to achieve?
Tell me!
They are your family.
Don't you feel like meeting them?
Can I leave?
Shiksha, hurry up or you'll be late.
Yes, mother.
Come on...
- Come on... hurry up.
- Mother, I think I'm forgetting something.
No, you are not.
I think I'm forgetting something.
No, you are not, now come on.
Mother I've forgotten my bottle.
There you are!
I've been waiting
since morning for this.
And finally it's here.
Who has sent this?
Tell me, please!
I... I don't know.
I just work at the store.
I don't know.
Mother, who sends
this for me every year?
Why are you here?
I don't want your world
to influence my daughter.
He was my father too!
How dare you take his name!
You think I'll forget
everything if I don't take his name?
What are you going to do?
You want another dead body?
Because of which you are
bent on making this world hell?
This world is hell, mother.
Without power...
If your father were alive...
But he isn't!
And it is such people who killed him.
They don't deserve to live.
They will have to die.
Will that bring your father back?
At least I will be
able to die in peace.
"Hum away."
"Hum away. "Hum away. Hum this song."
"Get rid of all the disappointments."
"Blow out the evening
candle and enjoy the night."
"You didn't learn
but I have taught you."
"The potent remedy
that I have tested."
"Just let go of all the
tears and pain and have a blast."
"Hum away. "Hum away. Hum this song."
EROS
"The burden you are carrying."
"Let me carry it and
lighten your burden."
"All the pain that
leaves you sleepless."
"Go throw all of them in the fire."
"There is more of
sorrow in your life."
"We'll bribe and get an
extra dose of happiness."
"Hum away. "Hum away. Hum this song."
"When you make a long face,
even the sun begins to set."
"When you smile, the moon
starts to illuminate radiantly."
"When you are silent,
life seems unmelodious."
"When you talk, it's
like music to my ears."
"Why are you holding it all inside?"
"Come on. Pour your heart
out to me. Hum away. Hum away."
"Hum away. "Hum away. Hum this song."
"Hum away. "Hum away. Hum this
song." Where is he going? Viju.
"I'll let my hair down and enjoy."
"I'll borrow some peace from you."
"I've learnt what you've taught me."
"I too have tried that potent remedy."
"I have let go of all the
tears and pain and had a blast."
"Hum away. "Hum away. Hum this song."
According to unidentified sources...
Rauf Lala carried out these
attacks because a drug deal fell apart.
Sir, what information does the
police have about these killings?
Their names are Karthik and Ramesh.
They work for Shantaram...
who actually looks after
Kancha's business in Mumbai.
The very same Kancha who has
challenged Rauf Lala and...
wants to control the
drug market in Mumbai.
Home Secretary Borkar,
when will Kancha be arrested?
Now, listen to me, you are
moving away from the main point.
Right now, Kancha isn't our target.
Rauf Lala is.
Rauf Lala who conducts
the drugs business...
behind a cloak of
public activities.
We have to rid this evil
called drugs from our society.
Sooner or later, we will do it.
Get him to stop.
Nothing... nothing Azhar.
Idiot!
Borkar, that bastard!
Kancha's slave.
Nothing's wrong, I'll be right back.
Salaam, Lala bhai.
Everything alright, Tony?
Alright?
How many years have we
been doing business together?
What's the matter?
For the first time, we are
going back empty handed.
Your little boy over here
is quoting sky high prices.
You won't get this
quality anywhere in Mumbai!
And you will have to pay a price.
Take it easy, Mazhar.
You take it easy!
Don't talk to me like that!
The price remains the same.
Alright, Lala bhai.
We'll see you after the 20th.
Father, these bastards...
You don't do drugs
while conducting a deal.
Never!
Once that's over you
can do hash or cocaine...
I don't care.
We lost this deal.
Father, I know for a fact that...
Tony has already made a deal for the
cocaine he wants to get from us...
and now he doesn't have the cocaine.
So?
He said the 20th...
which means he will
get the cocaine by then.
He isn't buying from us.
So then, who else can give
him cheap cocaine in Mumbai?
Maybe an outsider...
Kancha.
That means Mandwa.
100 percent pure cocaine
and a lot cheaper than us.
Gaitonde has covered
every nook and corner.
He won't let Kancha's
stuff land in Mumbai.
I'm sure there's a place.
I know someone who can tell us.
See you later.
What are you doing?
Save me!
I'll fall.
- Remember anything?
- I can't hear you.
Are you trying to kill me?
Do you remember?
I don't know anything.
Who will look after my Pappu?
What will happen to my Pappu?
Now do you remember?
Trust me, I don't know anything.
I am done for.
Help me...
Are you trying to kill me?
Wait!
I'll tell you.
Where is Kancha's stuff landing?
At Home Secretary
Borkar's home in Goa.
Don't ask me who I am, Gaitonde sir...
but I have news you could use.
Everything good at the factory?
Borkar sir, all good, thanks to you.
You don't need to thank me.
I'm only a public servant.
I'll be right back.
Where's the torch?
Go away from here, quick!
Hey! Inspector!
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Isn't this a lot?
Borkar...
you won't get a better opportunity
to prove your loyalty to Kancha.
Come on.
Come on quick!
Hurry up!
If you could help me
with a few bottles of feni.
I have to go all the
way back to Mumbai.
You want me to call Kancha?
Okay, okay... Borkar.
It really is very hot today.
You...
What are you doing here?
I'm here as a guest.
Where's your hospitality?
I'll show you...
Don't waste time. Gaitonde
will be here any minute...
with his entire force.
Gaitonde?
What's he doing here?
The Home Secretary of Maharashtra
is having a ball of a time in Goa!
You like to party in style, Borkar...
Music, dance, booze...
and cocaine!
What...
what are you talking about?
Shantaram has left and...
Gaitonde is outside.
He will come in any minute now.
Here he gets his
hands on the cocaine...
and there your
Government collapses.
What... what do you want?
Now listen...
carefully.
Gaitonde...
what is the meaning of this?
There's cocaine here, sir.
We have information.
Cocaine?
Have you lost it?
You do know you could lose your job.
That's precisely why I'm
here with a search warrant.
I got it over night.
Guess you weren't informed.
Come on.
- Open it!
- No, no...
there's just some old stuff in here.
Actually... actually... some of
my personal things are here.
I said open it!
There's nothing here.
Happy?
You've crossed your
limit this time, Gaitonde.
I'm the Home Secretary of Maharashtra.
You got a search warrant for my house?
I'm going to get you fired
or else I'll change my name.
He's going to kill me...
Kancha is going to kill me.
I have to do something...
or Kancha is going to kill me!
I got it.
I'll kill Gaitonde.
Have you lost it?
If you kill Gaitonde...
the entire police
force will be on your tail.
His record is so clean,
even I won't be able to help.
If you want to kill someone...
kill Vijay.
Hello.
You remind me of my father.
He would say...
"The weak can't say that they
have forgiven the powerful."
"For that, the weak must
themselves become powerful."
Today begins my
crusade to become powerful.
What are you trying to say?
Hello...
Hello... Vijay?
Let me go...
The more you suffer...
the closer will your death be.
Let me go...
I'll die!
- You let me live...
- Leave me.
And I'll let you go!
Let me go.
There, I let you go.
Now, ask why.
No.
Ask!
W... Why?
Because I don't want
Rauf Lala's charity.
I want all of Mumbai.
And, you can help me with that...
you and your Kancha.
Be prepared to prove
your loyalty to me...
I've spared your life.
And tell Kancha that...
a year later, stuff from Mandwa
will be sold throughout Mumbai!
We'll decide on the profit,
when we meet.
Agreed?
I suggest you drink less.
By defeating Kancha, Vijay has
once again upheld my position.
And so, this gathering here is
witness to my proclamation that...
from today you can ask
me for anything, anytime.
I present you with the
territories of Bakri Adda and Dongri...
and I announce that...
from now on the people pledge
their loyalty and support to you.
May Allah bless you with
strength to defend it.
So be it!
There's yet another reason to rejoice.
I've decided that...
my son, Mazhar will wed Mr.
Qureshi's daughter Saayra.
Congratulations!
The ceremony will be held
on the 3rd of next month.
- There will be a feast.
- Congratulations!
- Congratulations. Congratulations.
- Thank you so much.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Father...
- Yes?
Those areas were rightfully mine!
So?
I should've got those.
And you will get them.
But you need to
control your addiction.
What do you mean?
Do you see that crowd?
He has earned it.
With his own hands.
So, it belongs to him.
You are mine.
My own blood.
So, you belong to me.
I still don't get it.
Let him rule.
The throne belongs to you.
When you feel the time is right...
take over it.
What about Vijay?
Who can tell what will happen next...
whether Vijay will live or die...
Lala bhai, your shoes.
Whose shoes are these?
These aren't mine...
Vijay!
Yes, father?
Son, I think you wore
my shoes unknowingly.
- I'm really sorry, they looked the same. So I messed up.
- No. It's okay.
How could you not?!
Mazhar!
Hey! Vijay!
Catch him. Vijay. Come on.
Get the car. Hurry up.
My dear, be strong.
Allah is great.
- Boss. Boss.
- Out of the way!
Move. Move.
Please wait here.
Please move out of the way.
Doctor...
he is the reason I'm still alive!
When you bring him out,
I want him alive!
What's his condition?
He's alive, sir. He will survive.
Any information? About the shooter?
Nothing, sir.
But there's something you should know.
What is it, Doctor?
You are still over here?
Please wait over there.
He is our patient. Let us do our work.
Who do you think you're talking to?
He is talking to you.
To all of you!
I want this corridor
to be cleared right now!
You think there's a circus here?
Take it easy.
Doctor, how's he doing now?
He is better now.
Doctor, give me a minute.
Okay.
What are you trying to do?
What do you mean?
Let me explain...
You were shot with a .22 bore.
Shot from an ordinary
gun from the front...
that too on the shoulder!
What are you getting at?
Assasins don't use a .22 bore weapon.
Especially...
when their target is Vijay Chauhan!
Their target was Mazhar.
That thought can impress Rauf Lala.
Not me.
You weren't shot at.
You've been kept alive.
And the questions is... why?
Gaitonde sir, I don't
understand what you're trying to say.
We got an empty whiskey
bottle from that building.
We have taken the fingerprints and...
it will take us no longer than a
week to identify the fingerprints.
Make the most of this time.
Hey... what about my sherwani?
Where is my sherwani?
I got it made myself.
You'll look like a star.
A hero!
Right?
You're the hero, in my eyes.
Trust me...
I'm indebted to you, brother.
Now, I don't have two but three sons.
And together you
will rule over Mumbai.
- Okay?
- Sure.
But one of us is to
be sacrificed today.
Of course!
The groom!
Lala bhai, the guests have arrived.
They are asking for you.
Okay... tell Yusuf
to get the car ready.
Vijay, get Mazhar
dressed and bring him.
I'll take Azhar along. Come on.
And don't be late. The
guests have arrived.
See how good it will look on you.
Bhai, the next sherwani will be yours!
Mazhar bhai, call for you.
He won't take any
calls today. You answer it.
He has the information.
About the shooter.
What?
He says... he'll only talk to you.
Well then, give me the phone.
Yes?
Bastard!
Mazhar!
Shantaram shot you that day.
- On Kancha's orders.
- Shantaram?
Yes! The bastard is alone
at his factory right now.
Mazhar, wait. I'll go.
I won't get married
until I shoot him dead.
It's your wedding today, Mazhar!
I swear on Allah...
until I see his body,
I won't get married.
Mazhar!
EROS
"You have the magnificence and
grandness that befits an emperor."
"You are the chosen one."
"You can turn mud into
gold with a mere touch."
"The enemy stands no chance
when you wield your sword."
"God has bestowed you with His grace."
"Even the angels bow down to you."
"You are the messiah and the savior."
"Whatever you saw becomes the law."
Come. Get in.
Bastard!
Let's get out of here.
"The heavenly sight is
before your eyes today."
"The apple of your eye is
your shadow. Your reflection."
"Everyone has
blessings for him today."
"He is the successor to
the throne of your kingdom."
"May ever loss be
slower than your victory."
"Destiny is nothing but a toy to you."
"The enemy stands no chance
when you wield your sword."
"You are the messiah and the savior."
"Even the angels bow down to you."
"Whatever you saw becomes
the law. Glory to Allah."
"No common man is common."
"And no one's a king."
"I am the emperor..."
"...only because you've
accepted me as your king."
"No common man is common."
"And no one's a king."
Brother...
brother, the gun...
Bastard!
Son of a bitch!
Father called you his 'Son' today.
My suspicion was right.
You had your sights
on father's empire.
Shoot me...
Shoot me or I will kill you!
Shoot!
Shoot me...
He's gone!
"Stick those strong shoulders out."
"They are God's own children."
"The lines on their palms..."
"...are the maps of your worlds."
"Life takes a new
course at every step."
"This is what I believe."
"Those two mean the world to me."
"Stick those strong shoulders out."
"They are God's own children."
"The lines on their palms..."
"...are the maps of your worlds."
The first pillar of Rauf
Lala's empire has collapsed.
Hey...
what are you doing?
Alcohol is bad for health.
Leaving an empty
bottle at a crime scene...
is even worse.
What do you mean?
I mean...
I don't need Rauf
Lala to get to Kancha...
and now...
not even you.
"Glory to Allah! Glory to Allah!"
Shantaram was Kancha's
right-hand man, sir.
My question is...
with Kancha running
his empire in Mandwa...
doesn't the Mumbai
police have any power to...
I believe, Home Secretary Borkar
is better equipped to answer that.
Once we have his orders...
we will attack Mandwa.
Listen...
for some reason, the permission
hasn't been given all this while...
The last time police attacked Mandwa,
some innocent civilians were...
Just for the sake of a
few civilian lives...
we cannot put the whole
of Mumbai in jeopardy.
I want your permission.
I promise, I will give the
permission on a priority basis.
We want results, not empty promises!
- Listen...
- We don't want to listen.
Mr. Gaitonde...
we want you to
comment on this, please.
Well, we have some leads...
and it seems that due
to these gang wars...
the underworld is shaken up.
As we speak Rauf Lala is in the ICCU.
Can we expect that...
Lala's rule of terror is over now?
Who do you think is next
in line to be the heir?
Considering Rauf Lala's son,
Azhar's mental health...
there is only one obvious choice...
Vijay Chauhan!
I guess you've heard my name...
Kancha.
I have.
I'm sure you've also heard...
What did you get with you
and what will you take back.
Impressive, my
reputation precedes me...
So, what will you take back?
I shall give...
something...
to you.
What do you mean?
We'll talk when we meet.
Well, I can't come to Mumbai.
I'll come to Mandwa.
Even after you killed Shantaram?
You don't need minnows
in the long run, Kancha.
Very true... Very true.
Come then...
we'll prepare ourselves to honour you.
Mandwa awaits you.
Surya...
Vijay Chauhan is coming to Mandwa.
Really?
After having killed Shantaram?
Shantaram's are meant to die.
What do you mean?
Vijay could've worked
out a deal on the phone.
Why would he want to
come here for that?
That's what I'm asking, Kancha sir.
You asking amounts to nothing...
you good-for-nothing.
It's I who should ask.
Right?
It's I who should ask...
There was a school there...
and a master as well.
Master...
Bindiya!
Bindya what happened?
Why are you still there?
Get your mother, quick!
Kancha is waiting...
let's go.
Vijay!
Viju!
That is the Master's house.
His son broke my nose.
So I burnt down his house.
Tit for tat.
I set fire to the house.
Kancha is waiting...
Let's go...
He doesn't deserve to live!
He is the scum of our village... Scum!
Master! Your ghost
will hang from the tree...
Mandva has been rid of a monster.
Nobody will give wood for his pyre.
He won't even find a place in hell!
Master, you won't
even have a cremation!
Let him rot.
A man like him should be
treated like this only!
Kancha sir!
Father!
EROS
Silky siren. Silky siren!
"My eyes are so full of venom."
"My wink kills.
Darn this dainty waist of mine."
"Can kill a millions with a jerk."
"My eyes are so full of venom."
"My wink kills.
Darn this dainty waist of mine."
"Can kill a millions with a jerk."
"Have come here for change
for thousands of rupees."
"Have come to light cigarettes and
cigars with the fire of my body."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
You remind me of someone...
Who?
I can't tell...
but you definitely
remind me of someone.
Why did you kill Mazhar?
Shantaram killed Mazhar.
And, why did you kill Shantaram?
To get in touch with you.
And if I were to kill you...
right now? Then?
Then you'll never get Mumbai.
You carry Mumbai in your pockets?
No, in my shoes.
"I'll go crazy in the jungle today."
"I'll play with hungry lions."
"I'll carry burning coal..."
"...on my butter like palms."
"I am the fish of the
deep waters, darling."
"I have roamed
different sea and shores."
"I have lost to your stare today."
"My charisma kills."
"But it appears to be sweet."
"I'll serve it for you
with love. Come, get it."
"This is just a trailer."
"I have come to show
the entire movie."
"Have come to light cigarettes and
cigars with the fire of my body."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Fun has come visiting
this barren neighborhood."
"So very interesting is your face."
"Your colors have
colored my intentions."
"it is deep and will not fade away."
"My beauty is like the butter knife."
"Cuts through all the curtains."
"My nights are lonely."
"I will share them with you."
"My words are a signal."
"In them lies the game."
"My words are a signal.
In them lies the game."
"Break open the
treasure and plunder it."
"I have come to heal your
wounds by kissing them."
"Have come to light cigarettes and
cigars with the fire of my body."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
"Here comes the silky siren.
Quietly and alone."
"After downing a peg or two."
A nobody from the
chawls of Dongri is here...
to sell Mumbai to me.
There must be
something you want in return.
What?
Mandwa.
You've asked Ravan for his Lanka.
Wait!
If you had asked for anything else...
you would find how generous Kancha is.
Come on.
If you are through
with the welcome parade...
can we get down to business?
There's definitely
something about you.
You know I can't kill you.
At least not now.
No weaknesses...
no troubles...
No relationships
tugging at the heart...
finally I get who you remind me of...
Myself.
Then it's agreed.
Mumbai is mine.
Because Rauf Lala isn't there.
His empire is no more.
Who is still there?
Oh yes, Gaitonde.
I want Gaitonde dead.
And I'll give Mandwa to you as a gift.
Kancha sir...
The deal is done, Vijay.
Congratulations!
Congratulations, Vijay!
Deal is final.
Surya, our deal is done.
We have a deal, Vijay.
Congratulations!
Take this away!
Lala isn't cripple!
Greetings Lala bhai...
Lala bhai...
the night Mazhar was shot
another body was found there.
Shantaram's.
Where is that bastard Vijay?
He's gone to Mandwa to meet Kancha.
Falling into such deep sleep
can be injurious to health.
You didn't tell me
that you have a sister.
Your father has
regained consciousness.
Lathi charge...!
It's an emergency, sir.
I need the orders.
I will need to call for a
cabinet meeting, it will take time.
You calm down Gaitonde...
Sir, more than two thousand
people are gathered there...
to watch the girl being sold.
I need your permission to open fire...
sir...
Viju bhai...
Rauf Lala has taken
Shiksha to lmamwada.
Even the Police can't get through.
Where is Laxmi?
Let you go?
I'll display you before the market.
Stand up!
Only then will my
son's soul rest in peace.
- Vijay, help.
- That Vijay will beg and plead before me!
Leave me!
Stand here!
Gentlemen!
This is the finest quality!
- Leave me!
- And I demand a price to match.
Gorgeous face...
Complete in every way.
- Uncle...
- May I have the bids, gentlemen!
Lala bhai... one hundred thousand.
Two hundred thousand!
Gentlemen, this stuff
deserves more than that!
Look at her glow...
Look at her color. Look at
the radiance she exudes.
And innocence demands a price!
Lala bhai, five hundred thousand.
Five hundred thousand!
Now that's something!
Five hundred thousand, going once...
- Going twice...
- No.
Going thrice.
- No. Leave me.
- Lala fell for your ugly face!
I'm sure you won't
even leave the bones.
Come, take your winning!
Here...
Shut up!
Stand here!
Amazing Lala bhai...
No, please, let me go!
This time you've got
something exceptional.
Enjoy! Have fun!
No.
Khalid, fire!
Let me go, please!
Please, leave me.
No, brother! Let me go...
Father!
Don't call me father, you bastard!
Lala is my name!
Rauf Lala.
And Rauf Lala never leaves the
market without selling the girl.
Let the bidding start again!
I said, step back.
Come on, step back.
Bloody son of a bitch...
you'll never forget that...
for a moment I made
you go through hell.
Give my girl back!
Worthless... traitor!
An object like this
doesn't Hit the market everyday.
If I squeeze her...
a sweet scent will ooze out from her.
Sweet scent will ooze out.
Dear. I'll make a
scent out of this girl.
Vijay...
Vijay, let him go.
If I weren't mourning for my son...
I swear, I would have
taken her to bed myself.
Vijay...
Mother!
Vijay, stop!
Shiksha!
Vijay, let him go!
Vijay, don't!
Mother, how do you know him?
Vijay, let him go!
Mother, who is he?
Mother...
Tell me. Why don't you say something?
Mother, who is he? Tell me.
- Mother... Answer me!
- He is your brother!
He is your brother!
Hurry up.
And bring two packets of
Nikhar dye. Dark black.
Shiksha?
Shiksha, what are you doing here?
Are you here to see Vijay?
Wait here.
Pappu, come here.
Tell Vijay, his sister Shiksha
is here. Repeat what I said.
Tell Vijay, his
sister Shiksha is here...
Go, come on go!
Tell Vijay, his
sister Shiksha is here...
Tell Vijay, his sister
Shiksha is here... Tell Vijay...
Vijay's sister Shiksha is here?
Tell Vijay, his
sister Shiksha is here...
- Shiksha is here.
What happened?
Vijay's sister Shiksha is here?
Ashatai, Vijay's
sister Shiksha is here?
Look at how all of
them are staring at you?
Hey...
don't be afraid.
They are all Viju's family.
Come out. This is my mother.
Are you really Viju's sister?
Isn't your name, Shiksha?
Of course, she really is our Shiksha.
Do you know it is in these
very hands that you were born?
- She looks exactly like Viju.
- I am...
- I am Ashatai.
- She has come from a school.
- You remember, don't you?
- Oh come on Ashatai!
How will she know?
Why won't she?
This is the same lamp post.
I... I am Lachi, remember?
Mother, please!
You remember, right?
There, she remembers.
Viju is here...
EROS
"There is still somewhere..."
"...some life left in me."
"I see a new ray of hope."
"This tells me I am still alive."
"A crushed wish lies
buried in this moment."
"Where had this moment been?"
"it's right in front of
me now. Let me feel it."
"Do I die or live a little?"
"Do I embrace the
happiness or shed tears?"
"Do I die or live a little?"
"A body that was
scorching in the sun...
has found a shade."
"As if an miffed child..."
"...has got his smile back."
"This is somewhat like
my heart feels now."
"Feels like my old
wounds have healed."
"Where had this moment been?"
"it's right in front of
me now. Let me feel it."
"Do I die or live a little?"
"Do I embrace the
happiness or shed tears?"
"Do I die or live a little?"
"Do I embrace the
happiness or shed tears?"
"Do I die or live a little?"
Take care.
Brother, see you.
When can we meet next?
Anytime you want to.
- Day after tomorrow after school.
- OK.
- Here...
- Bye Kaali.
Bye.
Take this as well.
You have everything, don't you?
Shiksha...
tell him he should stay for dinner.
I already ate.
Tell him...
I know that he hasn't eaten yet.
Begin.
And you?
I'll eat later.
Brother, you shouldn't
have water while eating.
Why not?
What will happen?
Is it an insult to food?
It's a blessing...
that you remember
some things at least...
Brother... tell me
something about our father.
Shiksha!
You shouldn't talk while eating.
What do you want to know?
Every little thing!
Whenever I ask mother,
all she says is...
father was a teacher in Mandwa.
And we moved to Mumbai
after he passed away.
- And...
- That's it!
Shiksha! Stop talking and eat.
She is only asking about her father.
It's not a sin.
Our father was a self-respecting man.
He was against stealing.
He was against dishonesty.
"Fulfill your Karma...
don't worry about the reward."
- Life is but a great scene...
- Life is but a great scene.
That man is walking on.
- With tears and sweat...
- With tears and sweat.
- Soaked in blood.
And that's how he died.
With tears and sweat.
Soaked in blood.
I called you here only to eat.
And I'm talking about the
man who taught me to eat.
Viju...
People spat on him and walked away.
They said...
"Master Dinanath's
life was worthless...
and his death a waste."
The one who walked the path of fire...
didn't even get fire for his pyre.
Stop it!
The only reason I am alive is
to one day honour his death.
And for last 15 years the
only thing mother has said is...
stop it, stop it...
Get out of my house!
Viju...
Viju, your mother loves you a lot.
She just doesn't know how to show it.
My whole life has gone by, Kaali.
And she hasn't been able
to show her affection yet.
After all these years...
if she would just give me a hug...
Look at this, Kaali...
this is my mother's
love that I hunger for...
the last fifteen years...
fifteen years.
"A pain lies hidden in this moment."
"Where had this moment been?"
This time the attack
won't be like in the past.
A special division has been deputed.
- Gaitonde will come here himself.
- Of course.
He has taken the oath of getting rid
of the drug mafia before retiring.
Nobody can stop him now.
We only have time till
the Ganesh festival.
The Ganesh festival!
Praise Lord Ganesh.
But what role is the great
Ganpati essaying in this Mahabharat.
Viju... Viju...
there's someone here to see you.
Who is it?
What are you doing here?
Kancha sir thought
you could use my help.
And I'm here to help you.
Listen...
We have to kill Gaitonde...
before the Ganesh festival.
Get it?
Listen, there's
someone here to see you.
How are you?
Forget about Kancha, sir...
or he will have you killed.
And he has hired you
to do fulfill this task?
Aren't you afraid?
You have a family...
The day I accepted
the police uniform...
I let go of fear.
But I am pleased to see
that you still feel afraid.
Even though it's for someone else.
Come now, the pooja is about to begin.
Kancha sir...
Viju won't kill Gaitonde.
I saw him leave Gaitonde's house.
Shall I kill him?
"Hail Lord Ganesh."
"Anyone who has You in his
heart has fire in his belly."
"He doesn't care how it
starts and how it ends."
"The sky and earth call out
and rid him of any evil eye."
"Ever fear fears the one..."
"...you protect. Hail Lord Ganesh."
"Hail Lord Ganesh."
EROS
"The reward for your reverence."
"Anyone who earns it is wealthy."
"Lord, the one who
is unknown to you..."
"...is like a boat without the sail."
"The rat is your vehicle as such.
You protect everyone."
"Sins have never been
able to stand up to you."
"He makes his own destiny."
"The one who devotes himself to you."
"The one by whom you stand."
"Hail Lord Ganesh."
Name... Vijay Chauhan.
Vijay Dinanath Chauhan...
full name.
Father's name...
Master...
Dinanath...
Chauhan!
From...
Village Mandwa.
"Hail Lord Ganesh."
Sir, I want to see Mr. Gaitonde.
He is very busy.
I'm Vijay Chauhan's mother...
Suhasini Chauhan.
Look...
look, that's Surya from our village.
From Mandwa.
That's why it is
critical I see Mr. Gaitonde.
Alright, I'll inform him.
Yes... His mother's
name is Suhasini Chauhan.
She is the wife of some
Master Dinanath Chauhan.
She is from your village...
Mandwa.
Kancha sir?
Kancha sir? Can your hear me?
Can your hear me?
Vijay Chauhan...
Vijay Dinanath Chauhan...
Vijay... Dinanath Chauhan...
He will kill us.
Kill us all.
He will kill all of us.
Remember... we had killed his father?
We?
What are you capable
of killing, father?
You relax, father.
Save me...
Just relax, will you.
Now I shall write the
19th chapter of this story.
Vijay Dinanath Chauhan...
must die.
If people near and far...
if people who are dead...
the undead... and I, myself,
have cast an evil eye on you.
Lord, please take the evil away.
Viju, who cast a black eye on you!
Take a deep breath.
Go bring something
to offer Gaitonde sir.
Quick... hurry up.
I'm sure Surya's body
reminds you of your childhood.
For the past 15 years I was
taking an aim in the dark...
and who would've guessed
that the bulls-eye was Mandwa!
Vijay Chauhan...
a village teacher's son...
wants to become the ruler
of the Mumbai underworld.
But why?
To carry on his charitable activities?
Surya's body gave away a
lot of clues about you.
Ruaf Lala was merely a facilitator.
Your real goal was Kancha...
Kancha!
You did save my life...
but by getting rid of Surya...
you have wrecked the
fine balance of time itself.
Kancha won't remain silent.
More people are set to die.
It is enough, Vijay!
You saved my life, that's why...
In this lifetime, the onus
of repaying your debt...
is entirely mine, Gaitonde sir.
You'll have to wait
for another lifetime.
Gaitonde sir left?
Even I should leave.
There's a lot of work to be done.
To top it all,
Sushila left early today.
Kaali...
There's work to be done, I
have to shut the parlour.
Kaali...
Kaali!
I know the time has come...
for you to leave.
I get it.
And I won't stop you.
Don't you worry about anything.
I'll take care of
everything in your absence.
You can even stop worrying
about your mother and Shiksha.
I'll look after Shiksha's
education and even get her married.
I'll take care of day to day things.
The beauty parlour is there and..
I've sort of figured how
to manage the business.
Go...
just go...
Viju.
I know the place you're going to...
has your death waiting for you.
Your mother can see it.
Gaitonde sir can see it.
But from where I see it...
there is nothing...
but you.
Only you.
Therefore...
the way my life is
and however it is...
I am fine with it.
But for now, let me go.
Please let me go.
Kaali, wait.
What?
Well, this is my wedding fund...
let's add your fund and
mine and see how much it is...
"The stars and moon..."
"...that were always
missing from my sky."
"You've changed the
course of the clouds."
"All of them have returned today."
"My beloved."
Viju...
Kaali...
Please forgive me, Viju...
Don't go...
Please don't go...
I lived my entire life...
in this one moment.
Viju...
Where is my umbrella?
Kancha sir, Vijay
Chauhan is still alive.
Vijay Chauhan is alive?
Vijay Chauhan is still alive?
You...
you killed his father.
Now...
now he will kill your father.
And he will kill you too.
Kill you too!
He won't spare anyone.
He'll kill everyone.
He will kill everyone.
He won't spare anyone.
Kancha sir...
We found an abandoned
boat near the coast.
So Lord Ram has set foot on Lanka.
Go and check if...
he has also brought an army along.
Yes sir.
Come on move it.
Go quickly and look there.
Run!
Kancha sir, there has
been a big blast there!
Run, save your lives!
Kancha sir, Mandwa is burning!
Your Lanka is burning, Kancha.
Now go and recreate
a new one from hell.
You've kept me waiting
a long time, O Lord.
My eyes have grown weary.
I'm such an idiot.
For fifteen years, I've wondered
why the banyan tree withered away.
It's because I hung your father on it.
Your father's face
reflects in your eyes.
Your father, he
wanted to change Mandwa.
He couldn't.
But I did.
In fact, you should be grateful to me.
What are you doing, my son?
I told you...
he will kill.
If he gets up, he will kill.
Kancha, I told you.
I told you so!
You are nothing like me.
How I wish you were!
No fear, no desire...
no attachments...
Just pure bliss.
But you have attachments and desires.
Some affection... in you...
Vijay Dinanath Chauhan.
Brother...
Vijay! Vijay!
Vijay!
Brother!
It's a good thing you
didn't burn my mansion.
Otherwise just as you've
been mourning for your father...
you would be mourning for
your mother and sister as well.
Viju!
Master's wife?
Hey, she's the master's wife!
The master's wife!
Let me go!
Mother...
Vijay...
He is Vijay, the master's son.
Vengeance after fifteen years.
Brother!
And this eerie calm...
That seems to say a
violent storm is brewing.
Kancha, spare him.
The universe is about to explode,
Vijay Chauhan.
And you will be born again.
But for that you must
allow death to embrace you.
No. No. Spare him.
Somebody help him.
Somebody please help my son.
Why are you asking
them for help, mother?
That night they said nothing
when my father was killed.
What do you expect them to say now?
They won't say a word.
Because they have chosen the devil.
Now the devil is their
god and also their ruler.
They have no one else but me.
So let me fulfill my Karma.
Brother!
Viju!
Save your breath...
we have to go to the banyan tree.
Let my brother go!
Viju...
Go beat him up!
Kill them!
Kill all of them!
And till you become powerful,
you get beaten up everyday.
Says who?
Keep reciting the verse with me.
I derive my strength from this.
You shall too.
There you stand, a tall tree.
You are well-laden and tall.
But don't ever ask
for even a little shade.
Don't ever ask.
You will never tire
you will never rest.
You will never look back.
Take an oath.
Life is but a great scene.
That man is walking on.
With tears and sweat.
Soaked in blood.
On the path of fire.
Father!
Viju...
Mother...
Brother...
Mother, I did the right thing?
Mother, I did the
right thing, didn't I?
I shall pray to the Lord
that in my next birth...
I want to be your mother again!
Brother...
Mother...
The path of fire