Do you want to know what this is all about?
You can say it's about drugs, or guns
disaffected youth or....
Whatever you like...
But this whole thing is about parenting.
It is about taking care of your children.
You take care of yours, I take care of mine.
I'm sorry I don't understand
What does that mean?
That's all I have to say about that subject.
Next question?
You're son was a drug dealer?
Drug dealer? No.
Did he/she sell a little weed? Yeah.
A little weed? He was a major supplier
in the San Gabriel valley.
I don't know anything about that.
What about the D. A. 's assertion that
your son got his marijuana from you...
and that you have tied to organized crime?
What is this amateur night bullshit?
That isn't an interrogation.  Alright?
I am a taxpayer and I'm a citizen.
And you are a jerk-off.
Did I tell you that?
Crac
Come on Johnny, why don't I feed you behind
if you're busting hard work I'm fucking your
Mom and your sister....
ahh Shit! What's that Tiko?
What did you say?
I heard you say you want to suck my cock right?
Primero would have to grow.
Shit, mines got so big it's got a name
5 foot, 3 hung like a flea.
It's hot out there
-What you doing, Elvis? Is it dark outside?
-What?
I'm paying you for a full day right?
I've been here since 10 o'clock this morning.
I hate that shit.
I asked you a question.
D'you see the fucking moon, Elvis?
-It's definitely daylight.
-Hey! I'll show you my moon.
Johnny, I did everything that you say.
The house is clean. I went to the store.
There is food and beer in the fridge.
The wash is done. Adolf's fed.
The grass is cut.  It is all done, man.
Well, I guess you shouldn't finish so fast huh?.
Shut the fuck up!
-Hey, never mind that!
-Never mind that!
Get back to fucking work!
You want something to do. .
Go wash the floors, scrub out the toilets. .
or better yet pick up all the dog shit
that's in the back yard.
And if you finish too fast...
-dump it out and...
-Pick it back up again
-Shut the fuck up, bitch!
-Get you a pooper-scooper
-Touchy
-It's messed up, man.
-What?
When am I going to get my money, Elvis?
When?
I get my cheque on Thursday
Well, how much is the cheque?
I don't know. It depends on the hours.
Well, how many hours did you work, bitch?
I can't remember.
Fucking dead beat, man.
Go on! Get the fuck outta here!
The walk of shame...
The walk of shame, man.
-Robby?
-Hold up, bitch!
$8, 500
All of this, huh?
Surprise! Surprise!
-Yeah
-Okay
So?
So. . I've got this guy
He wants 5, plus my regular 2.
So, I figure I'm gonna need 7.
I don't know.
I don't like having that much shit out
I'll see my guy Monday and
I'll clear you right out, man.
He's good for it, Johnny
You don't need to tell him
I'm good for it, man.
I'm not looking for any fucking favours, JT
If it makes sense. Do it!
If no, fuck it.
Alright
We'll try it.
-Where you going, Ray?
-That's what I'm talking about
But come Friday....
I don't want to hear any fucking stories.
You won't.
Be ready, be ready.
Nice. Nice.
Its big league stuff right there, baby.
I will throw you a couple.
-Hey!
-Hey.
-What you say, Tarzan?
-I need 7.
-7? 7 to who?
-Bobby 911.
-That could be put together.
and when you're picked off.
-Alright
-Knows where he's been?
-Yeah... I know. . it feels good.
Alright.  It's on you anyway, right?
Always is, pop.
Look at this kid, how handsome he is.
Look at this!
You must be knocking them dead.
Are you knowing them dead?
No. Let go!
What you doing tonight?
Chasing tail?
No. I'm just chilling.
On Friday. night?
-Sonny?
-I know.
You make me wonder about you, kid.
You sound like half a fucking fag.
-I always had my suspicions.
-Just make the fucking call!
Wait a minute, ok?
Remember what I told you...
Men are not supposed to be 'monopulous'
It's in our nature to spread the seed.
Yeah, very poetic. Come on
Angela is a nice girl but you
gotta plough some fucking fields.
Do ya hear me ya fucking fruitcake
-He is a great kid.
-Yeah, he is
Hello? Hi.  I didn't expect to see you
Come on!
-Howard
-Yeah
There's plenty of food.
-I like your hair, Jakie.
-Thank you.
-You look handsome with a little hair
-How is going on with the job?
-I had a lot of sales.
Busy, everything's going really... great
How is your mother?
Wonderful. Thank you.
-Tell her I said hello
-And Wanda?
She's fine and err...
could I talk to you for a second. . ?
Yeah.  Sure.
Excuse us.
I need to borrow money.
-I thought we'd talked about this.
-Yeah.
You haven't paid me back for the last time.
I know.  I'm sorry.
It's not the money,
you know that don't you, son?
I just can't keep bailing you
out all the time.
I know. Do you...
You think I would fucking be here is
this wasn't the last stop on earth?
How much?
$800.
-What is going on?
-Dec wants to borrow money.
How many times are we going to do this, Bud
The kid comes in here, stoned out of his mind
and you keep throwing money at him because
you don't want to deal with it.
I'm working.
I have a job
I'll pay you back.
No. No, I can't do it, son.
Right. Sorry. Go back to
your perfect little family.
-That that's not fair.
-Don't touch me
Hey. Can I come with you?
No, kid.  Not tonight.
I've got some shit to do.
Are you ok?
Are you alright?
Yeah.
Okay. Well, page me later.
-Yeah. Yeah
-OK
-I love you.
-Yeah.
Punk ass bitches
Look at those fucking stupid fucks
With their fucking guns and
their fucking gold chains.
-They're nothing-Worthless
-Shit
The only thing those mother fuckers
are shooting are music videos, dog.
-That's what I am saying
-The same thing
-That's what I am saying, dog
-That's what I am talking about
-Now I am feeling it.
-Now you're feeling it?
-No Shit!
-Don't want that shit. No
Dance! Dance!
You wanna call me out?!
-OK. I'll call you out
-Shit
-I wanna call you out
-That's disgusting.
-You know he has herpes, right?
Bring it on.
Fucking high, you know
I can't even see right now
Come on, Elvis. Come here.
You can't dance, bitch!
Come here.
Give me a fucking beer.
Will ya get a beer?
I'll get you a beer.
Don't worry, Angie.
I got it. I got it.
I got it, Johnny.
-Run, bitch!
-I'm thirsty
Look at that slave-ass mother-fucker
"I got it, Johnny"
He's like a spook, man.
You loves Johnny
He does.  Don't you, Elvis?
Mother-fucker!
Johnny, yeah I loves him a lot.
I owe him a lot.
I do.
No, no, no, no.
I don't mean like that.
I mean you fucking looooove him.
-You'd fucking do anything for him.
If he asked you to sucks his cock,
you probably would.
Shut the fuck up.
No, no, no.
Tell the truth, Elvis!
Tell me you wouldn't drop to your fucking
knees and suck Johnny's cock in two
seconds if he asked?
You give it a kiss on the tip....
-No, I wouldn't.
-You wouldn't?
-Johnny? Come on.
-Ahh, you see that?
Full on, dick in the mouth, balls across
the nose, dildo up the ass...
You're a faggot!
100 percent
Don't talk to me anymore, ok?
I fuck bitches.  You're a homo.
Don't!.  That's it.
Shut the fuck up!
-Suck my fucking cock!
I'm dead serious.
Suck it, bitch.
-Suck my fucking cock!
-The fucking door!
I got it.
Come on do it!
-I got it, alright?
-Suck my cock!
Pretty soon it is gonna come out, Elvis.
-You're gonna come out, Elvis.
-That you're fucking gay.
What's up, Jake?
Try calling a mother-fucker before
you just show up, ok?
You Jews just don't have no respect.
Can I speak to you for a minute?
Yes, it is Friday.
Let's go in here.
So, what's going on homie?
You know that thing I told you I was going
to take care of for you down in San Diego?
-Yeah
-It's a wash out
Really? What Happened?
Well.  I go down there and put the screws on him
and tell him something bad is gonna happen to him unless
he comes up with your money
and like . .  FAST...
Which he doesn't because he is fucking tacked.
But he is scared so he rings round his neighbour and
I'm walking the guy for a hundred and fifty bubs
So?
So, the bubs are no good
The X was fucking punk.
And I had a line to take it all, man. We would
have made so much money on that shit.
But you said that you would take care of it.
You said it was your debt.
-Are ya coming here trying to nigger talk me?
-Now, what could I do.
I couldn't exactly go back to the guy I
ripped off and say 'you're shit was no good'.
Okay, but I still gotta get paid.
No.  Come the fuck down.
I got $800 here and I thought...
-that we could split it
-You thought we could split it?
Fuck that. You pay me!
All of it.
-I'm trying.
-How?
You make dog give ya a fucking job
-Be careful Johnny. I'm not fucking Elvis.
-Yeah, well you're short asshole.
Watch you're fucking mouth ya little fucking bitch
I'm not one of your little faggot friends.
Remember who you're talking to.
Get this fucking bitch off.
Who you think you're messing with
you fucking cock-sucker.
Leave me.
Sit the fuck down! You crazy bitch.
-Piece of shit
-Hold it! God damn it, man.
Hey, come on man.
You pointing that thing at me
you better pull the fucking trigger.
Well, come on you fucking pussy!
Do it!
Come on, bitch!
-Don't you fuck me
-I will
-I love it
You have everyone else fooled around
here but I ain't fucking buying it.
Get this fucking piece of shit
outta my house!
Get the fuck out bro.
Alright Johnny.
Ain't no turning back now.
-Get the fuck outta here.
-Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
Woooah!
Fuck me.
Shut up!
What's going on?
-Who's there?
-It's Zack.
-Who? It's fucking midnight.
-It's me, Zack.
Get in here!
What ya doing you fucking maniac?
Okay, go put on some clothes.
Heil, sir.
-Do you want a drink?
-Yeah.
...and she is always telling
me what to do
...like, what clothes to wear and what girls
she thinks are pretty...
Like, I couldn't fucking figure
it out for myself.
That's you're Mom.
It's Olivia.
Come on.  She loves you
You're her baby.
Yeah. I know.
It's embarrassing
Do you know that we have
"home work parties"?
-What?
-Homework parties with little hats.
-noooo. Like...
...for birthdays
Yeah.
Another thing...
I was sleeping, right...
...and she'll wake me up
by looking at me.
Like, I open my eyes and she'll be right there
looking at me, like...
Fucking 'A'
It's god damn creepy you know.
Like she is in love with me
and breathing on me
You're lucky, you know that?
I mean, my Ma she never...
...boohoo of me.
Yeah, I know.
But...
I would trade you.
I gotta get out.
I gotta smoke.
Well...
...look at the boy Zackie, all grown up.
Is that one header or stress weed?
Shut up.
Take a drink!
Like a pro.
One minute.
-It is Olivia.
-No, no fucking...
Alright...
Yeah he's here.
No, we're talking.
I said we are talking.
Don't get you're panties all in a waddle
I'll drive him home later.
Yes, I do know what time it is.
Thank you.
crack
Yeah, okay
Okay.  Alright!
You've gotta get home.
-No.
-Wait, stop.
Tonight, we ride.
Shit.
Let's go.
Jake... hey, Jake.
-Am I fine?
-Yes sir
-You're the best.
-Yeah?
-hmmm.
No, you're the best.
You wanted him.
You got him.
Bye.
You're a real son of a bitch, you know that?
Let's go.
I was fucking my dog, and...
No, no, listen.
Look at the ass of that one
I could crack it open like a peach.
You fucking kidding me?
You are a fucking dinosaur , Cosmos.
Come on! You're dead.
You can't do anything.
Ya balls are all wrinkled up.
What?
What? You deaf fucker
I said you're old.
I'd knocked the bottom outta her.
You don't even know where the bottom is.
You don't know what to do.
Hey, waitress.
-What can I do for you?
-What have you got in mind?
Just get another round of drinks.
-You haven't finished the last one.
-I didn't ask you that.
-Just get us some more fucking drinks.
-Get us some drinks, bitch
I pay. Hey, I got it.
-You got it hey?
-Yeah
It's a special occasion
-Come on, Cosmos, let's go.
-Come on!
Johnny, watch yourself.
-Say Jake that we stopped by.
-Oh! I will.
When I told Jake what happened he fucking
flipped out and I had to calm him down.
He's gonna kill Johnny. Jake's like that.
He is a very passionate person.
But I told him: if you're gonna do something
you've gotta fucking hit him where it hurts.
Johnny had a class storm
I mean two of the quantities
...he was trying to collect on
the insurance money...
Jake comes in. Salts the whole fucking deal.
Sharon's company catches wind of it
They don't pay out.
Cost Johnny 30, 000 dollars.
'cause Johnny had to retaliate...
It's fucking business.
Mr. Johansson wants to see you.
Want to see me?
Sit down!
What's up Pete?
You're probation officer called.
Mr. Lampington?
It thought he was out of town.
Yeah, well I talked to him.
He said you've been getting
into trouble again.
Breaking into houses. .
Using drugs... speed mainly.
It's not true.
-Yeah, it is.
-No, it's not.
Pete, I swear to God.
Dude. Dude!
It's.... .
I feel you.
I'm right here...
Don't look at me that way.
I'm telling you the fucking truth.
I'm totally fucking straight, man.
I mean I'm a litt...
Mr. Lampingtons' so full of shit...
He's outta fucking town
How would he know what I am doing?
You disappoint me.
Pete.
-Pete, I swear to fucking God
-Need you to take a drugs test.
Pete, come on...
I need the job.
-I really need this job.
-Fill it up.
I need this fucking job.
Fuck you!
-Fuck off!
-No.
Get the fuck outta here.
You're fired
Get out!
Don't come back in here.
Get the fuck outta here.
I will take a gun to your fucking head.
I will take you to hell with me.
Do you want to play some (?), Truelove?
Let's play some fucking games.
You called my PO (probation officer)
You called Mr. Lampington?
Mother-fucker!
Fuck that!
Where's the mother-fucker?
-Where you at?
-Johnny.
-Check the bathroom.
-Johnny
Jake.
Truelove.
-Shit, look at his fucking TV.
-Fuck the TV
Shut the fuck up!
Fuck the fucking dog, man.
What the fuck are you doing, man?
Fuck. You shitted.
Be careful, you'll step on the shit
fucking cock suckers
That asshole pays me.
Let's go.
The neighbourhood is safe again
Yes, mother fuckers.
Are we ready?
Ohh. What the fuck, dude?
We're moving, bro
-Moving?
-God damn right!
Too many assholes know where I live.
Did ya see this?
Holy Shit.
Johnny, what happened, man?
Came home last night...
My windows busted and my TV's missing
-Fuck, right?
-Fuck.
-Tell him about the shit!
-The shit?
Crac
Fucking crack head Mazursky took a
sideways shit on the living room carpet.
-What? Where?
-Right here.
On the wet spot
A big fucking steaming crap.
Long ways, like this.
Then it left.
-That's fucked up.
-Is that nuts or what?
What's the mother fuck wipe his
ass with...? His hand?
I don't know fucko
I told you I wasn't here.
Whatever, that is fucking nasty, man.
Check this shit out
Sunday 12 AM
This is just the beginning, baby
This is shooter.  Thanks
I know where ya fucking lives
D'ya hear me, you're fucking dead
Domination. Domination.
-Mazursky right?
-Can you believe that shit?
After everything I've done
for that mother-fucker.
Look, Johnny!...
Fuck him.
Let's get the hell out of Dodge
and go to fiesta, fuck some bitches.
-That's what I'm talking about.
-Right?
Let run through some shit.
Schmidt, we're gonna go the Springs for
a couple of days.  You stay here and get
everything boxed up.
I don't want to see shit
here when I get back, Ok?
-Alright.
-Alright. I want a receipt too.
Yeah and maybe if you guys are still
there when I get finished...
-I'll cruise down there
-Okay and maybe, you can blow me
Fuck you, bitch.
I want to come
Yeah, yeah, just make sure you get
the shit smell outta the carpet. Bitch!
I don't get it.  What are we doing?
Go break this fucking guys head.
Mazursky.
He's not here.
I'm telling you he's gone.
Look his cars not even here.
Don't give me shit.
There aren't even any fucking lights on.
How can the lights be on?
It's the middle of the fucking day
What the fuck are we doing?
I don't know but I am not standing
here like a fucking idiot
-What are you doing?
-I'm kidding.
Well stop fucking around.
Hey, OJ
Check it out!
97 miles per hour, mother fucker
Let's see what you got
Manny Ramirez, mother-fucker
You guys are fucking idiots.
Ooh, Jesus! Make more noise!
He's 15. Remember when you were 15?
For once in your life,
your tennis match will wait.
Why do you have to be such a fucking
pussy? What are you thinking?
-What are you getting crazy about?
-I am not crazy...
If you were ever here, you
might notice that.
Great! Let's just let him turn
out like the other...
Like what, Olivia.  Like Who?
Say it! Like Jake?
Hey.  What's going on?
Come here.
Your Mother found this in your room.
It's a pipe
I know what it is. It's a bone.
Want to tell me about it?
-No
-You smoking pot?
-Now look at me, we have to talk.
-I don't want to fucking talk.
-We that's too bad.  Sit down!
Dad! I just fucking woke up.
God Damn! Wait 'till I put
some fucking clothes on.
God! Fucking dick!
Yes, we should punish him.
Do something for God's sake.
You never do anything.
Zack come down here!
Zack.
-Are you fucking kidding me?
-What?
-That's his brother.
Pull over!
Hey, what's up?
Come here!
Come here, fuck-face.
What the fuck are you running for?
Come on, let's go.
What the fuck you want?
I didn't do anything.
Shut the fuck up and get in, Bitch.
Fucking idiot.
Just take him to your place.
I can't take him to my place.
My Dad's there.
I thought you said he was cool?
Bitch, he is cool, but you didn't
tell me we would be bringing
along a fucking hostage.
He is not a hostage, alright?
I told you I don't know what I
am doing right now, alright?
-I'm thinking.
-Well, think!
Hey, we've got to take him some place.
Alright.  I know somewhere we can go.
But you have got to be fucking cool.
What is there?
-Hey, what's up, man?
-Chucky
-A lot of dudes, bro.
-I know that.
Bring 'em in.
Hey, Chuck.  This is Truelove;
the guy I was telling you about.
Hey, what's up, man?
Do you have a room we can use?
-A room?
-Yeah
Yeah, I've got one down to the left.
Thanks
So, what's up, man?
We're just chilling, man.
-Getting high, getting ready to go to fiesta.
-Smoking weed.
Thanks, man.
So, how you been?
Been good. Chilling, ripping
waves, hanging out.
What the fuck is going on back there?
Do you want me to go check it out?
Yeah, I mean, 4 dudes I have never
met are in my fucking bedroom.
Give me the tape!
What the fuck are you doing, man?
Are you nuts, you can't do that.
You guys are out of your fucking mind.
-What the hell is this?
Who the fuck are you?
-Shut up
Hey Chucky, they got a kid tied
up in your room.
-Calm down
-He's a kid
-Johnny is just a little crazy right now.
-A little crazy right now?
We stole this kid...
I thought I told you to shut your mouth?
And you: Mind your fucking business.
Mind my business?
This is my fucking house.
Frankie, you better put your boy in check.
Tell him what fucking time it is.
-Like that huh?
-Just like that, bitch.
I get it. Hey, Lump...
Let's get out of here.
I'm going to fucking fiesta...
when I get back, none of you
Mother-fucker better be here.
-Let's get out of here girls.
-Let's go!
Fucking shit-head.
Chucky, man... I'm really sorry
about all this, bro.
What's going on?
Why aren't you guys ready.
What are we going to do with the kid, man?
Who cares.
Leave him in the fucking closet.
Pick him up then. I don't give a fuck.
Johnny, I have a date back in the valley.
I have to get back, man.
Me too.
You've just remembered now, huh?
-Yeah
-Yeah, man.
My girl gets mad if I don't fuck her.
You pussies wanna go home?
Fine! Take the fucking van.
Listen! You don't have to do that.
You can put me in a fucking closet.
I'm not going to run anyway.
Do me a favour: Shut up, before I
shut you the fuck up.
Why is this mother-fucker talking anyway?
I thought we taped him up?
He couldn't breathe.
Just drop me off on the strip.
I'm going to fucking fiesta.
I'm not going to let this little
mother-fucker spoil my weekend.
-What about me?
-No
-No, what?
-He stays with you.
-What?
-I said fucking queer as a deaf mother-fucker
-Why me, dude?
-Because I fucking said so.
Don't fuck around man.
I can't fucking take him to my
Dad's house like that.
Well then, untie him, genius!
You heard the kid...
-You aren't running are you?
-What?
No.
Go home, tell Juergen that he's your new little
butt buddy and he is spending the night.
Meanwhile, I'll talk to Mazursky.
He must be going crazy, right now.
Hey, what's going on?
It's a mad house.
Your brother is scaring the shit
out of all of us.
Did they call the friends?
Maybe he has a girl?
We tried everything. Friends,
cops, hospitals... nothing. .
Don't you think the kid is out
just fucking around?
I mean you can't keep the kid
locked in the house forever
Maybe, I don't know.
We did have an argument this morning.
OK, well that's what it is then, right?
I hope so.
-Well, what do you think?
-I don't know.
But...
We can't rule anything out.
I'll have to ask you a few questions, ok?
Do you know anyone who
would want to hurt Zack?
-No.
-You?
-Me what?
-You've a beef with anyone
I oughta know about?
That person you owe money to?
You owe somebody money?
Jesus! Just tell me how much and
I will write the cheque.
-It is not really like that, Olivia.
-Really? What's it like?
Tell me what it's like, god damn you!
Fuck. Bring him back.
Please relax.
Bring him back!
Back here!
I am going to find him.
I promise you.
I promise.
I will find him.
Where are you going?
Where's Johnny?
Don't know Dog, is he here?
-That is what I am asking you dog
-Excuse me. We were talking.
Klemash, where the fucking kid?
I ain't seen him, dude.
What the fuck is that?. . Behind your back
when you turn away from me?
-What's the problem here?
-Shut your big ass
Don't touch her!
Asshole!
If anybody sees...
Johnny Truelove...
Tell him that Jake Mazursky
is looking for him.
Thank you.
Back the fuck off me, man?
I am informing you.
-I want a beer. Do you want one?
-Yeah, sure.
Here you go.
-Cigarette?
-No. I don't smoke.
Fuck that! It's good for you.
Hey, man...
...what if I said; you could walk
over there right now...
...jump on a bus, catch a ride home...
I turned my back and tell Truelove...
...you fucking ran away or something...
What do you think about that?
I don't know, Frankie.  I mean...
I don't wan to cause any problems
for my brother, you know?
So I think; I'm just going to ride it out.
See what happens
Alright?
Alright.
Right.
Dad.
Frankie?
Good to see you, boy...
-My little son loves his dad.
-Don't.
Let's go to bed.
I love you.
-I want you to meet...
-Alright
-Hi.
Give the kid a kiss
Dad!
Dad, No...
Leave me be.
Come on, smoke with your old man.
-Have a drink?
-No
Something?
No. Come on.
Who is your little friend?
Are you babysitting?
Fuck you.
Use the sofa.
Wake up.
Come on you've got chores to do.
Let us go!
-Hello
-I fucking hear you
There's coffee but Bessy got up late so
I need you to straighten up the house.
I'm supposed to clean up after your party?
I know I moan like a bitch.
Don't argue with me. I am in no mood.
Look, I came home yesterday and
your shit is all over the house.
We had a deal remember?
Get a job, pay rent...
Alright! Fuck!
Get out of my room!
Nice fucking mouth.
Fucking dick.
Hey. Don't worry about it.
I'll help you with the work.
Juergen is botanical. He grows
everything we eat right here.
Tomato, cucumbers, corn.
Fucking spices and shit.
Fucker is a full blown alcoholic,
smokes like a chimney...
...but, Goddamn, if we don't eat healthy.
Look at this shit right here.
Daddy's pride and joy.
Cause the greedy bastard will smoke 'em
all but it's Frankie's job to take care of them.
Water them, throw some egg shells
on them every now and then.
Well fuck it
Let's get to work.
Shit. I'll be right back.
-Hey Girl!
-What's going on?
-Nothing. Working.
Are you guys coming over?
You got that shit?
You know I do.
Mom.  I'm going to Frankie's.
-Did you talk to him?
-It's all good.
-When will you be home?
-I don't know. Late probably.
Darling, can you stay with Julie
and Sabrina tonight? It's your father
and my anniversary
Anniversary!
-You gonna have a little sex or some...?
-That's disgusting.
Whatever! I'm interested.
I mean, really, are you going to go down on him?
-Give him a little tube stick boogie?
-No!
Oh come on! Live a little.
You guys have been married what. .
...500 years?
Keith Straten! I will knock the
shit out of you, you little skunk!
OK We're leaving.
Get your keys? Lets go get
Sabrina and Julie.
Yo! Youngblood.  Come here, man.
Ladies...
Dick Wad, Fuckweed
Susan.
Hi.
Sabrina, Julie,
Dick Wad
OK.  OK, let's go smoke some
fucking weed, man!
But, hey, listen.
No-one messes up my shit, alright?
This house ain't never been
so fucking clean
You fucking blow this game.
I don't fucking blow. You just died, man.
-I thought I was the other guy.
-That's me.
I thought I was playing the other dude.
-Suck my balls!
-Fuck you. Suck my balls, man
You suck it bitch.
So, how old are you?
How old do I look?
About 12.
Well, I am 17, but I do look really young.
I am going to kill your ass, kill your ass.
-Stop the game.
-No! Go answer your phone.
Suck it!
Fuck you
Yo Johnny! What's up?
Did you talk to anybody?
-Not yet, why?
Look, man, I can't keep the
kid here much longer.
-Why? What up?
-Nothing, just having some people over.
-Who?
-Nobody. Shut up
Nobody, just some people.
Chill Out, dog!
-Get them the fuck out of there.
Alright, alright, I'll clear it up.
I need you to do a favour for me, bro.
Johnny is coming and I need the house.
Will you watch the kid for me for a little while?
Watch him?
Keep an eye on him, no phones...
...and no leaving him alone.
No phones?
I don't get it.
Alright, look, if I tell you something
can you keep your fucking mouth shut?
Yeah, 'course, man.
Yeah.
The kids brother owes Truelove money...
...and Johnny's holding him like a
marker or something until he gets paid