'There are some gaps for sure, which
will show us new things. ' Yavuz Tanyeli
'There are some gaps for sure, which will show us
new things. ' Yavuz Tanyeli Inspiration forthe film
Last night the moon was out.
I couldn't even look up.
The moon reflected on the water.
I hear sounds.
Perhaps I heart he leaves falling.
Sometimes small animals walk around.
Some of them are on me.
I'm not scared.
It's peaceful here, maybe that's why.
What if I laid down like this forever?
Why not?
As long as they don't hurt me.
"He" brought me here.
First all the sounds disappeared.
Then I heard the forest.
Now let's get to the bottom of this.
The first thing we say to newcomers
in the homicide department is;
If you look at things from one
perspective you only see one thing.
Will what you see bring you...
...to resolution or does it
get between you and reality?
Sounds complicated, doesn't it?
Let me rephrase it.
You look and you see this.
You say; 'This is it!"
"This is the murderer. "
What if it isn't?
Could you be wrong?
Of course!
Maybe you can't figure it out
from where you're looking.
Dead end.
What do we do?
- We change our position.
- How?
We exit the dead end enter another street.
Find a road where we can see ahead.
That's right.
We will change our perspective.
We will find an opening and
look through there to see reality.
- Your name is Hasan, right?
- Yes, it is, chief.
Observe the people around you.
Try to guess their criminal potential.
A painter looks at the paint on the walls...
...when they first walk into a house.
That's called perception.
The homicide cops...
...always seek the suspects.
Suspicion, always suspicion!
That's all for today.
Send this as soon as possible,
understood?
Report back to me once it's sent.
- Yes, sir.
A hand was found
in the swamp forest in Selamli.
Go there immediately and
report to me on the phone...
- We're not on duty, sir.
- I know, dris.
But the team that's on
duty is collecting another dead body.
They can't be in two places at once.
- Are you convinced?
- Murat ne speaking.
You can't keep your mouth shut!
Life talked, take him in right away!
- Sir, Tahir Aka called.
- Which one was that?
We found his son's body in
the backyard, in the chicken coop.
- I remember, what about it?
- Will you join the interrogation?
- Sir, are we going to talk?
- What?
- Are we going to talk?
- Go to my office. I'll be there.
Call me in for the interrogation.
- What about the phone?
- Muharrem Buhar talked. He confessed.
Hopefully he won't change his mind
when his lawyer is around.
- And there's the other case.
- Sir, tea?
Whose case are you on?
- His dad was killed inside a car. His son.
I think he did it. He's crying too much
after him. Too much.
- Done?
- Done.
Why are you still here?
The prosecutor is Macit Hakman.
Don't let him come after me.
I don't like that man. Go now!
We'll go but what shall we do
about the staffing?
What staffing?
We've been short-staffed for two months.
We've been working day and night.
dris is right, sir. We can't keep up.
Choose from one of the newcomers.
We need an experienced...
- Go get that boy.
- Which one?
The one who answered my question.
His name was Hasan, I think.
Why him? Is he suitable?
Is he a good fit? Who is he?
dris, just bring me the boy!
Fine, fine.
- Tell me son.
- What should I tell you, sir?
What did you study? Where do you
come from where do you go?
- Before the service?
- Yes.
I studied anthropology.
- I'm currently writing my thesis.
- What is your thesis about?
About serial killers in Turkey.
That's why I chose the homicide.
And thankfully they chose me, too.
There are serial killers in Turkey
that we don't know about?
No there isn't. That's what my thesis
is trying to answer. Why not?
My thesis is called;
An Anthropological Evaluation...
...of Serial Murders as a
Unique Product of Western Society.
That's a very flashy name but
you didn't need to go to university...
...to find out why there are no
serial killers in Turkey. We'd tell you.
- Are you married?
- No.
- Girlfriend?
- Yes, sir.
- Is it serious?
- Kind of.
Is she also an athropopopologist?
Is this really important?
- Stay close to me, write everything down.
- Okay.
- Greetings.
- Greetings Serdar. Hello everyone.
dris, how are you?
- Thanks. Kadir isn't around?
You finally made it.
We've been waiting for you.
You're right but
the traffic was really bad.
Prosecutor Macit, we're not even
supposed to be on duty today. Hi doctor!
Let me introduce. Anew addition to
our team, Hasan Rifat Adigzel.
Best of luck to you.
Should we call you Hasan or Rfat?
- Hasan would work, sir.
- Fine. What's the situation?
Suspicious death.
So far we only found a mutilated arm.
- The search is ongoing.
- The team is great.
- No other body parts?
- Nothing.
- Who found it?
- This guy saw it.
The waiter at the teahouse across.
He called us during the day.
He didn't see any suspects. Not many folks
come here during this season.
Let me take a look at this hand.
Let's pray that the other body parts will surface.
It's tough just one hand.
Hasan, say hi to the hand.
What are you doing, this is evidence!
Can I have a look?
What kind of a cut is this doctor?
I think it's a knife cut...
...but I'm just saying that without analyzing.
It looks like it was cut after death.
The blood had left the body.
The bruises confirm it, too.
- Looks like a kid's hand.
- Could also be a young girl.
- There is nail polish.
- Right. It's a young girl's hand.
We need help over here.
Give us a hand, please?
Let's go Hasan, you said hi to the hand...
...and now comes
a brand new experience.
You held on well.
I saw a lot of newbie's faint
on their first day.
I found a bone.
This is probably an animal bone.
What are we looking for here?
Anything that might count as evidence.
The arm has been cut with a knife.
Start with the knife,
then the syringe, underwear, lipstick...
...bag, driver's license, ID.
They didn't teach...
...this stuff to you?
Go ahead.
Where am I?
I'm in a lot of places.
I'm everywhere.
I'm scattered.
I disappeared.
- I'm done watching the game.
- What happened?
The team is not even walking,
let alone running.
Trabzonspor is a different story.
That's in my blood.
dris, tell Crime Scene Investigation...
...that there are boot and wheel prints here.
Tell them to take pictures and molds.
- Don't forget about tomorrow night!
- What's tomorrow night?
Detective Mustafa's retirement night.
At Halit Brother's coffee house.
Follow the forensics.
How about a drink after work?
I don't want to make Kezban wait.
She's waiting on the missus all day.
Just one drink.
Newby you, too.
- How's your wife?
- She's doing ok.
First we're going to set up
the investigation format.
You brought me along
without setting up the format.
The format takes just two minutes.
Let's just enjoy this.
I washed my hands and face
many times and it still smells.
It'll stink for a while. The smell
of a corpse stays.
Let's drink.
Don't worry about it. All in due time.
So your mom is in Ankara.
- And your dad?
He passed away.
My mom lives with my sister.
Is your girlfriend here?
Does she have a job?
Yes. She owns a restaurant,
also a butcher.
A restaurant owner and a butcher.
Interesting.
Her father owns a meat restaurant.
It's in the family.
- Do you happen to be married?
- No need to be so formal with me.
He was married but he's crazy.
Couldn't keep the girl.
You, too?
And it is me who held their wedding.
Yes, why don't you tell him.
He kidnapped thru poor girl.
No, first start with
"They didn't allow the wedding. "
Then you tell the story, we'll listen.
He kidnapped Asiye but
her family went after him.
They decided to shoot dris.
His family is also strong-willed.
They're from the Black Sea Region.
Bunch of crazies.
They were about to have a feud.
At the time I was doing my service
in their hometown.
His father and I became really close.
He was teaching me how to build boats.
We used to go out fishing together.
So anyway.
Cemil, his father said;
I fit was up to me I'd say shoot him,
he'll learn a lesson.
But his mom would be very upset.
He said "Could you do something about it?"
He said
"Go do something not could you?"
I'd do anything for Cemil,
so I talked to both families.
They forgave him. I saved his ass.
May God bless you.
After my father died in the sea,
Ferman became like a father to me.
Thanks to him I'm in the service.
I could never pay him back.
It's hard to make a marriage work
with this job.
Asiye is a little crazy
but she's a nice girl.
I made her suffer a lot.
We were trying to make it work but
it didn't, with all the fighting.
Sorry Kezban, I'm a little late.
Don't even mention it.
How is she today?
You know she can be a little tired
on days like this.
- Could I leave?
- Of course.
God bless you.
- Good night.
Bro, could you look over here?
- You guys had a few drinks?
- That crazy guy, he insisted.
- How was your day?
- As usual.
- We found a hand.
- What? A hand?
Oh my God, I don't believe it.
What did you do with the hand?
It was sent to the forensics
in a package.
- It smells in here.
- Really?
Mr. Arda, excuse me.
It smells in here.
That's not possible.
You're right. There is a smell.
Pelinsu I'm talking to you.
Nanna I'm on the phone.
Just give me a break.
Come and gather your things.
Nanny! I'll call you back later.
You never listen to what I say.
We spend our lives trying to understand
what you're saying.
What kind of language is that Pelinsu?
What kind of language?
I don't speak her language.
You better send me to learn it,
maybe then I'll understand her.
You don't know what you're saying.
You're starting to sound like your mom.
Efecan did you eat?
You're done eating but I haven't eaten.
Go to your rooms, right now.
Pelinsu you, too.
- But dad, there's a show on TV...
- I said, right now.
The boy never comes home,
the girl is always on the phone.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- dris, what happened?
- Nothing mom.
Things happen every day. Robbery,
kidnapping. Is this what you worry?
My hand is not pretty.
My mom's hands are pretty
but they smell like onions.
My dad's hands smell like cigarettes,
they're black.
They become more black when he's angry.
My granddad used to say hands tell tales.
My granddad used to tell tales
with his hands.
People used to stare at his hands.
He used to say each hand has a story.
He could see it, I guess.
When I look at my hands...
I only see bitten nails
OK, I get it, but?
We'll move forward after we hear
what the forensics and CSI say.
The forensics are working on the hand,
CSI is looking for the rest of the body.
We saw the hand.
The fingertips have been really damaged
by the water.
Fingerprints will be hard to get.
All we know is that the arm was cut
with a knife...
...and belongs to a young girl.
And was mutilated after death.
Doctor, give me good news!
I stayed up all night,
but I got the fingerprints.
Doctor, you're great!
Fingerprints need to be transferred
to the CSI.
We'll take care of it.
According to the girl's bone development
she is about 15 or at most 16.
Death took place about
2 to 5 days ago.
There were pieces of skin inside
her finger nails.
I'll check the DNA.
Hopefully,
the skin belongs to the attacker.
I beg you, please hurry up.
Good news.
The doctor got the fingerprints.
And he found some skin fragments.
He'll check the DNA.
Death took place
at the most 5 days ago.
Okay. Good luck with the work.
- Is this the new guy?
- Yes.
- How is he?
- Good in theory not so much in practice.
Hasan go to forensics, right away!
Get the fingerprint flee...
...and take it to CSI.
Then, read the files on the other cases.
Take notes.
I'm going to ask questions.
Read very carefully the case of the son...
...who is suspected in his father's death.
dris, your wife is here.
What are you doing here?
What have you done?
What kind of a man are you?
- What are you taking about?
- You hospitalized the poor man.
- Are you crazy?
- Are you just realizing that?
Life got really hurt
he should report it to the police.
You bandit!
You beat him up and
then you show him your badge.
How can he report you?
I'm going to lose my job because of you.
Don't mess up with my job.
I can't survive on the alimony
you give me.
Then stop wagging your tail.
I don't wag my tail to anybody.
Besides I'm single, I live as I wish.
- Don't drive me crazy.
- You're already crazy.
- I swear I'll kill you.
- I dare you to kill me.
Don't come for the kids this weekend.
I won't give them to you.
What do you mean?
There is a court order!
F**k the court order!
You're not a man!
Tonight, we're sending off
a beloved colleague from our service.
There's a lot to be said
But it's best to keep it short.
Best of luck to you. This service
will never forget you.
Here is a little something to remind you
of us, from all of your friends.
I'm not much of a talker but
I'll say that...
...I'm leaving my heart behind.
Don't forget me.
Long live the Homicide Department!
I wish we could all retire like this.
He was one of the toughest guys in the job.
The man who owns this coffee house,
him, too.
The man next to Hunter is your namesake,
They're among the legends at the Homicide.
Of course Hunter is the greatest.
- Why do they call him Hunter?
- Why do they call me crazy?
Because I get crazy and he hunts.
- Hello?
- How's it going?
Good. What's up?
My dad wants to meet you,
He said it's about time.
When are you free?
My security firm is looking
for new people.
Let's give you a job there.
You can't live on your retirement pension.
Mustafa, I'm fed up.
I spent my whole life chasing after criminals.
You remember
the case of Ragip from Eyp?
You got him in the end.
I got him in the end but I lost 14 kilos.
- 14 kilos!
- Ok.
- Your girlfriend?
- How did you know?
You slouched, you glanced sideways,
looked a little surprised.
Your face got red.
Your whole body says it.
Mustafa! Cheers everyone!
Cheers everyone! 1, 2, 3
Oh, my head. It's killing me.
Barely made it to the morning.
It happens when you drink that much.
Thanks.
We kept on drinking. I blacked out.
I don't remember how I made it home.
- Where is he?
- Who? - The newbie!
At the crime scene department.
He'll be back soon.
They found the case from
the fingerprints.
- Wow.
- That's it. We got it.
Her name is Pamuk. Pamuk Seyhan.
Arrested for selling drugs...
...let go for lack of evidence.
There is an address,
no identity number.
She's just a kid! Only 16.
She might be just a kid
but she means business.
She looks real innocent to me,
poor girl.
You're the kid!
Show me a woman who is innocent
and I'll slit my wrists!
Let's go and visit this address...
...and see what we can find.
Go to the car.
I'll be there after I inform Chief Murat.
Even a dog wouldn't stand this smell.
- Yes?
- Police.
- What's it?
- Could we come in?
Excuse the mess.
- What's the purpose of your visit?
- What's your name?
Kamuran, sir. Kamuran Tora.
Do you know this person?
- Sure I do. This is Pamuk.
- Does she live here?
- No.
- How do you know her?
She used to come by my workplace!
- What do you do?
- Bartender. Pamuk used to hang out at the bar.
She was underage
but the boss didn't mind.
- We became friends overtime.
- Was she your lover?
- No, I'm gay.
- Do you have her phone number?
Of course! - She gave the police
your address as her residence.
We'll, she has a boyfriend, Acid.
What do you mean?
His nickname is Acid. He sells drugs.
Acid mer. He used to sell at the bar.
He's a total jerk.
He would beat her up all the time.
Pamuk would come stay with me for a day
or two...
...then she'd go back to that asshole.
They arrested her for selling drugs...
...she had no idea
what was inside her purse.
That jerk was using her.
They let her go.
She must've given my address
at the station not to give him up.
She's going to get me in trouble!
Here's her number.
You got Acidt's number?
No. He changes it frequently.
He is around a lot but
no one knows where he lives.
- How old is he approximately?
- Definitely older than Pamuk.
Perhaps between 20 and 25.
dris, let's get information
from the narcotics about Acid mer.
- No one there.
- Did Pamuk have any other boyfriends?
No, she was madly in love with that jerk.
She's from the ghetto and all but
she's real soft, Pamuk.
She's soft like cotton.
- Will this Acid guy come to your place tonight?
- He will!
Life does, call us at this number.
We'll be around.
Hasan, get the bar's address
and number too.
Is there a problem?
Did something happen to her?
Lift did, who would've done it?
- Of course that asshole Acid.
He was beating her up a lot.
He was really mad
when Pamuk refused to sell drugs.
He put his cigarette out on her chest,
right in front of my eyes.
Can you open up your wrists?
- Sorry?
- Can you show me your wrists?
Did you get information on Acid?
Yes it's there.
What if he doesn't call?
Then we're gonna stay up all night.
What if he doesn't call tomorrow night?
Then we're here on duty
every night until he calls us.
Our job is patience, young man.
You know I'm really curious about
this anthropology thing.
What are you curious about?
First of all, why would someone study
something with such a complicated name?
Second, what is anthropology really?
First of all it's because...
...I was placed into it but...
...I started liking it then
I couldn't find a job after I graduated.
That's why I'm a cop.
What is anthropology?
We can call it the
study of humans, roughly.
And more finely?
We'll let me put it this way;
Anthropology studies why
Americans show the middle finger and...
...Turks place their thumbs
between two fingers.
That's what anthropology studies.
You got your answer.
Chief if you allow me...
Alright.
- Yes, Yasemin?
- My dad is inviting you to dinner.
Really, what did he say exactly?
In your restaurant?
OK, then.
You better watch out. The people
in the service don't like your behavior.
What was that all about with you
and Asiye, the other day?
- I'm suspicious.
- What are you suspicious about?
That's not a good feeling to have.
You taught us suspicion.
You said; "Be suspicious.
Don't believe what you see.
If you can't see,
change your perspective. "
I changed my perspective towards Asiye.
Tell that to the people in the service.
Yes?
Ok, we're on our way.
I'll call you later.
Hasan, you stay here. Watch the door.
If you see anyone running away,
you follow.
Acid! Stop!
Police! Stop!
I got you. We're not done with this
anthropology thing.
dris watch where you're going.
Take down the license number.
I did.
34 VS 4621, did you write it?
I am.
First anthropology, then serial killers.
- Please, don't!
- I gave my doctorate in that field.
- dris, you want me to drive?
- Of course, not.
He turned right.
- He turned right, right.
- Stop.
- Get out of the way.
Move it.
Don't you see the police alarm?
Police!
- Didn't see it.
- Don't you see?
Don't you see it?
- Where the hell did he go?
- This is where you end up if you bullshit...
...and distract yourself.
- You saw it, the car cut in front of me.
- I'm talking to you.
- Hi, chief.
Come back.
Stop. Isn't that
the car in the distance?
- Chief, how did you see it?
- He is the Hunter, he sees.
Don't go in. Let him think
we lost him.
Park here.
Let's silence the radios and the phones.
There are bulletproof vests in the back.
This neighborhood is shady.
He is here.
Let's call for support.
He will fly away until support shows up.
- I say we go in.
- We have no idea what's inside.
It's too risky without the support.
45-28. Station 45-18.
- The bastard's about to leave.
- He says we should wait.
But the guy is as sly as a fox.
He smelled danger.
Support is on its way.
Sir, let me have a quick look around.
- Just wait, they're coming.
I don't feel good about this.
We catch him tonight or
we don't catch him at all.
- He is going to drive me crazy.
- Don't move.
Come on, let's take a walk!
Don't let anyone in or out.
And don't take any risks.
- Hey brother.
- Police!
Stop.
We'll done! Your really f**d up!
What are we going to do now?
- Ok. Let's wait for support.
- Listen to me!
We're not narcotics police.
We're from the Homicide Desk.
We don't have a problem with you.
We just want to talk to mer.
That's all.
Give us mer and we'll go.
Goddamn you!
Why are you not listening?
I said we'll leave after we get Acid.
Stay where you are.
I thought I put you on silent.
Yes Yasemin?
We were going to meet my dad on Sunday.
- Yes!
- Let's make that Monday.
What's all that noise?
- Fireworks.
- What fireworks?
Where are you?
- Can I call you back? I'm really busy.
Stop. I said stop. Police.
Turn around. Slowly! Slowly!
Chief what are you doing?
I raised my hands.
I beg you.
- Are you OK?
- I'm shot.
- What?
You're ok.
The bullet is stuck on the vest.
You have the right to remain silent.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you don't have a private one...
...the state will provide you with one.
You ask for support
but you don't wait for it.
Is your duty to be in a crossfire?
Your duty is to catch murderers.
One dead, one injured.
Two detectives under your care.
You risked their lives. An experienced
officer shouldn't do that Hunter.
You're absolutely right, sir.
I made an error in judgment.
I can resign right away.
My retirement is coming up anyway.
Do as you see fit.
Now excuse me.
Take a look, it's Acid's file.
I got you in trouble, didn't I? I'll go talk to
the chief and tell him what really happened.
You got used to acting out on your own dris.
I am still the leader of this team.
When I retire you can do whatever
the hell you want.
But while I'm here you're going
to speak when I allow you to.
You understand? Get yourself together,
come to the interrogation room.
Are you ok?
What about you?
- A person died.
- A newbie's life was saved.
He was out of bullets.
Look, this is a dirty job,
there is garbage, dead bodies...
bodies torn into pieces,
bad smells.
We deal with dead people.
If you can't handle it,
don't do it.
Go get some sleep now.
Are you hungry mer?
You want me to get you a sandwich?
- No, thanks.
- You know her?
- Yes!
- Her name?
- Pamuk.
- Pamuk what?
- Pamuk Seyhan.
- How do you know her?
We were together once.
Once upon a time.
Why were you surprised
to see her?
Perhaps because he didn't think
he would be seeing her again.
- When and how did you meet her?
A few years ago.
At one of those ghetto discoes.
She used to hang out there. And I...
And you needed someone
to sell drugs for you.
First you got her addicted.
She was allergic to all kinds of drugs.
She didn't do drugs.
Besides we were really close.
We really loved each other.
If you really loved her
why did you beat her up?
- Not true, who's making this stuff up?
- You know her family?
- Yes.
- You know her house then.
Yes, I'll give you the address.
You can give the address
after you tell us what happened.
- What happened?
- You look like you could tell us the truth.
We've been up all night.
Just tell us so we can go home.
Please, chief. I didn't do anything.
If you didn't do anything,
why did you run away, you bastard?
Chief I thought you were narcotics.
I had trouble with them.
We know everything.
You even used a knife.
Knife? Do you mean she is killed?
Don't play with us.
As if you don't know.
What knife?
I can't even slice bread.
I swear to God
I have nothing to do with this.
I didn't kill her.
She was my lover.
I loved her and she loved me.
What did she find in you to love?
My eyes are blue.
That's what she used to say.
She loved you and you beat her up.
I beat her up but that was it.
I didn't hurt
You motherf***er. You put your cigarette
out on her chest, you psycho!
Just talk.
I was on a pill. I was high.
I don't even remember.
I haven't seen her for a while.
Show me the most important person in the
world and I'll swear on them I didn't do it.
But you know who did it!
There is someone you suspect.
Alright, if you're not gonna say anything...
...I'm gonna have your
whole life get scrutinized.
I'm gonna talk to the prosecutor...
...to keep you locked up forever.
And declare you
as a narcotics informant.
For now you have 3 days inside
to think about it.
We'll see if you go something to tell.
dris get the girl's address from him.
Get all his phone calls looked at.
And show me your wrists.
Flip. Open up.
Don't you know that all of our men...
...are the same, with attitude.
That's not true.
dris change a lot.
His job ruined him. Each murder
made him crazier than before.
Whatever I did, wherever I looked,
he was suspicious.
He started following me.
He was looking for a hidden meaning
in my every word.
Is it a thing to do?
Who can endure such a torment?
How can you live with a paranoid husband?
Paranoid?
Look, two days ago we found
a young girl's hand.
Perhaps she was running away
from someone as well.
Maybe if her parents were a little
more paranoid it'd be different.
Pray that the same
thing won't happen to you.
I don't want to go dumpster diving
for you corpse.
And I told you. You can't have the kids.
I'm not giving them.
- How come you don't give them?
- I just don't. Good bye!
See mom?
He's really crazy!
- See what he's doing?
- Listen to me!
You punish the children not your wife.
They want see their mom.
Stop acting like this.
Yes, sir?
I'm at home.
- Yes?
- Come right away!
- You never sleep?
- We never sleep.
Can you tell me why you're here officer?
Mslm Bey, we ask the questions here
and you respond.
I'm listening.
Anyone else in this family
besides Pamuk?
She has two brothers.
Abbas and Vakkas.
- Where are they?
- They're at work.
Do you know where your daughter is...
...Hatun Hanim?
- No, officer.
Did you report her as missing?
Why? She's not missing.
- Then you know where she went.
- We do.
God bestowed her with a great
place to go...
...but she didn't appreciate it.
- Don't talk like that.
Why? Is that a lie?
- She didn't live here?
No.
She got married.
She lived with her husband.
How did a 16 year old get married?
Battal Bey got her age changed to a
year older and then married her.
Opened his house to her,
did everything she wanted...
...but there was something
evil about her...
...she gave all that up
to go be with that good-for-nothing man.
This man, does he nave a name?
mer. He's a loser, good-for-nothing.
There was something
between them before.
We did everything to keep them apart.
I broke her bones.
Her brothers beat her up but
she kept seeing him in secret.
Then we were blessed with Battal Bey.
But now we're disgraced.
Especially against Battal Bey.
- Mr. Battal?
- He's our benefactor.
I've been his gardener since Adana.
My wife used to clean up his mansion.
- Pamuk used to help.
- He must be very rich.
- You don't know him?
- Should we?
Everyone knows Battal olakzade.
This Battal olakzade
is that the Battal olakzade?
Yes. Owner of olakzade Holding.
Yes. He owns hundreds of frms. He was
the chairman of the chamber of commerce.
He's very rich.
He's our benefactor.
My dad was his dad's gardener.
He brought us to Istanbul
before Pamuk was born.
My youngest son is helping
his new gardener.
Big family. Sons and daughters.
- Wait a second, wasn't he married?
- He was...
...but then he fell for our daughter.
That's how God wanted it.
Police officer, tell me.
What happened to my daughter?
Hatun Hanim we believe that your
daughter is dead.
We think she has been murdered.
God give the and taketh away.
She got what she deserved.
She lived a life deserving death.
It's our duty to find out who did it.
We'll share the details at the station.
The detectives will talk to the neighbors.
- Did she have a room?
- Of course!
After she got married I never
touched my sweet one's belongings.
Can I look around?
Show me your wrists.
There are still mosquitoes
buzzing around.
Nothing's changed.
You can't fall
asleep because of the sound.
I smell the gutter.
I smell the onion on my mom.
I don't like that smell.
My mom is a part of the kitchen,
always at the
stove, with a wooden spoon.
In my room I imagine things.
I write stories.
I become a ghost. I disappear.
Then my dad's hatred,
my brother's violence...
...the grocer's sweaty smell,
screaming kids...
...gossiping neighbor women,
they all disappear.
I escape into tales.
I become a ghost. I disappear.
Poor girl, they forced her to
get married at age 16.
Yes but why did Battal
have to change her age?
A girl at 16 can marry
with her family's consent.
Guess it wasn't enough or
else why would he bother?
There is a very important player
in the game now; Battal olakzade.
He's connected to ministers, parliament
representatives, high-level bureaucrats.
Secret phone calls will be made
they'll try to scare us.
Go after Battal olakzade, take him
in for an interrogation. Be careful.
You can leave now.
Ferman don't let dris...
...get out of control.
My two sons manage 5 meat restaurants.
I manage 3.
We're a chain. I don't count my daughter,
she does her own thing.
But our business is meat not
the restaurant. This meat.
My sheep feeds on the grass from
Bursa and Balikesir...
...and my cattle feeds on the grass
from ankiri.
Why is that? Those grasses have thyme.
Thyme makes meat delicious.
My animals never move.
Why?
Cause animals that don't move get fat.
Animals that move,
they get muscles.
My animals stay put.
Dad, are you done talking about meat?
We're you expecting someone else?
- What are you talking about?
- I don't know.
Your hair, your make-up, your clothes.
You look dolled up.
dris why are you here?
What do you want?
First go get something to wear.
Yes, I'm listening.
dris, what is it?
Why do you look like that?
dris what's wrong with you?
Oh my god.
The power went off.
dris get up and get the flash light
from that drawer.
- dris get up.
- Calm down.
- Where is it?
- Inside that drawer.
If you know where it is,
why don't you get it yourself?
As if you don't know
I get so scared of the dark.
But you have some
wind in your sails. Coward hero.
- Which drawer?
- That one.
You were afraid of the dark when you were
a little kid, you're a big woman now.
- The battery is dead.
- You see? I'm scared.
- dris?
- Yes?
There are candles in that cupboard.
dris, go grab them.
dris, that's enough.
Come closer.
What did you call me?
Coward hero?
Is there anything else
you know...
...that I am scared of?
- Thunder.
- That was when I was a kid.
What about from me?
I was never afraid of you.
Crazy people are not scared of each other.
See how my heart's beating.
Maybe I'm a coward.
I came here to kill you.
Why?
Then kill me.
When I'm gone
I know you. You don't take care of
yourself.
You're forgetful. You're careless.
You ignore things
That's why I made a list of things
for you to do when I'm gone.
I'm writing it down as I remember.
Marriage certificate,
identification cards...
...insurance policy are at the top drawer.
Stomach medicine is in the kitchen.
Don't miss the expiration date,
Your underwear is at the top drawer
on your side of the bed.
Abbas, Vakkas, don't get lost!
We'll look into everything you said.
If you lied then you're gonna pay for it.
Show me your wrists.
Ok, go.
Are the brothers involved?
Abbas used to only beat Pamuk.
Maybe he beat her to death.
He says Acid mer did it.
He's sure of it.
I even pressed his button.
"How can you let that man roam around,
your sister ran away with him?"
He said; "If we'd found him
we wouldn't let him live".
Vakkas said about the same thing.
He says Acid and nothing else.
It's obvious they've
worked on the testimony.
Vakkas works as a gardener for
Battal olakzade.
- That's interesting but why are you grinning?
- It's nothing!
They're really big.
Roads, construction, textile,
dam building, automotive...
We know all that. More importantly,
can we reach anything...
...personal about Battal?
I have 80 firms that make
4 billion liras a year.
I have hundreds of thousands of workers.
Construction, energy, textile.
We have over 20% of the market share
in all of them.
But I chose retirement.
I passed the business
over to my children.
It's my time for silence.
I will tell you one last story.
Maybe you get it, maybe you don't.
They say I'm a rude man.
Be it.
But don't forget in business...
...no one pays for politeness.
Intelligence is money.
They know I like hunting.
It's a habit I take after my father.
He used to take me to the Taurus Mountains
when I was a kid. We're from Adana.
We used to hunt whatever we could.
I mean, my dad
was hunting and I watching.
My dad shot a deer once and...
I watched
the deer die right in front of me.
His eyes were staring into mine.
I started crying.
That was the first and last time
my dad slapped me.
He said; 'Son,
if you're gonna cry don't come hunting.
Death is a part of the hunt. '
He said;
"Life is a hunt.
Either they hunt you or you hunt.
Make a choice. "
That slap was a lesson.
I never cried after that.
Not even in game hunt or human hunt.
That's the essence of the system.
There are hunts and hunters.
You have to decide;
Are you going to be the prey
or the hunter?
- Thank you.
- You chose a great subject.
I'm glad you like it. Thank you.
- Glad you could make it.
- You speech was really good.
I'm retired now. You can call me
whenever you want. I'll come running.
Thank you Battal Bey.
Sir, we are from the police service.
We need to speak to you
in connection to an investigation.
- Right here and right now?
- Wherever and whenever you want, sir.
Let's go to my house then.
We'll have some tea.
Follow us.
- You wait here.
- Why, sir?
Wait.
Wait a minute.
Come in.