PRAGUE.
My job takes me to alot of places.
It's got its downsides.
I sleep alone... I eat alone,
I'm used to it though.
I'd like to meet someone.
But it's tough when you
live out of a suitcase.
I go where I'm told...
Do what I'm told.
I shouldn't complain...
The work is steady,
the money's good.
But it's not for everyone.
My name's Joe.
This is what I do.
You're late.
Sorry Mr Lindsay,
they're closing off streets.
You are leaving?
I need the phone.
- Um... I can help with the bags, sir?
- No, I can handle it.
If you ever come back, I can...
I can use the money.
Goodbye.
I was taught 4 rules.
One: Don't ask questions.
There is no such thing
as right and wrong.
Two: Don't take any interest
in people outside of work.
There is no such thing as trust.
Three: Erase every trace.
Come anonymous,
and leave nothing behind.
Four: Know when to get out.
Just thinking about it,
is a waist of time.
Before you lose your edge,
before you become a target.
So you look for the right oppurtunity.
Nothing too risky.
Get the money,
and disappear forever.
This is it, 4 hits in one location.
The last job.
Purpose of your visit
to Bangkok, Mr. Windsor?
Holiday.
Bangkok...
it's corrupt, dirty and dense.
All my clients
have one thing in common.
They feed off the people.
There's big money in misery.
Where there's money
there's competition.
And the guy paying me
usually wins.
How will we know when he's arrived?
We'll know when he arranges the pick-up.
You're sure he's reliable?
The Russians swear by him.
How do you swear by...
a man you've never met?
We don't know him,
he doesn't know us.
It's better for us that way...
It always starts the same way.
Just like I was taught.
Secure a safe location.
Somewhere off the beaten path
where you have privacy.
But you stay invisible too long...
the human race
looks like another species.
So you venture out, you observe...
and then you return to your
invisible world.
Like a ghost.
- Hey, look Larry...
- What?
Over here.
I've been here a couple of times.
Hello gentlemen how are you?
- First time in Bangkok?
- Yep.
Rolex good quality...
Yes, yes, look, good, good Rolex...
Watch out, Larry,
you wanna bet, it's counterfeit.
- Good, good.
- No thanks, no thanks.
No, no, no, nevermind, nevermind...
You want girls?
- I can get you girls.
- No, pal...
No girls, how about boys?
You like boys?
- No...
- You don't like boys?
- No, I'm sorry, pal.
- Hey, how about you, huh?
5000 bath, you have the special...
money back you're not satisfied
with pussy guarantee, hey?
Whatever happens in Bangkok,
stays in Bangkok.
Wanna find garbage,
go to a garbage dump.
I look for three qualifications.
They have to speak
a little English.
They have to wanna make money.
And above all:
They have to be disposable.
You wanna make some money?
I have work in town.
I need some help.
What work?
Pick things up, drop things off.
Maybe some translation.
About a month's work...
Two thousand a day.
- Dollar.
- Baht.
Bullshit, uh.
Five thousand, eh?
Twenty-five hundred...
Four thousand?
2 thousand, 9 hundred and fifty-two-fifty...
I do it, huh?... What'd you think? Come on.
We'll round up... 3 thousand.
You get paid at the end of the week.
No deal.
Uh... okay, okay, uh...
how about, uh... half...
half now half at the end of the week, eh?
- What's your name?
- Kong.
Kong?
You can keep that
in the wallet you stole.
Pier 21 Santaham Road,
tomorrow 7pm.
You come alone, or you don't get paid.
Yes boss.
- Take off the shades.
- Huh?
Glasses... off.
Keep that with you at all times.
- I have good phone.
- Now you have two.
You answer whenever it rings.
If I call and you don't answer,
you don't get paid.
Time... it's very important.
If I tell you to be somewhere
and you are a minute... late...
you don't get paid.
You understand?
- Birdshit foreigner.
- In English.
I understand.
- You know the Caribbean Club?
- High class ass.
Ask for a dancer named Aom.
You give her this... make sure
the X is facing up like this.
She's gonna give you a package.
Don't... open it.
- What's in it?
- It doesn't concern you.
Then you go pick it up.
I'll find someone else.
Okay, okay, okay...
I... I do it, I do it, I do it.
Come straight back here.
You don't stop for anything.
What if I have to piss? uh?
- If... you ask me one more question...
- And I won't get paid, I know that.
- Okay I go now.
- Hey...
Take the cell phone.
Duck fucker.
Hey, excuse me...
I came to see Aom in here?
The girl in the front.
Thank you.
What you looking at?
Fucking, cops.
- You're late, huh?
- Give me the case.
- You don't get paid for today.
- Why not?
"Ran from the police".
You told me not to stop.
I do what you say, don't stop...
don't stop for nothing, not even for piss.
From now on I don't want anymore police.
You understand?
Fuck your mother.
The human face can mislead
in a thousand different ways.
But the eyes never change.
I was taught
to start with the eyes.
I'm Kong.
Heroin?
Yeah, heroin.
Give him what he needs.
Hey, wai... wait... wait.
The elephant.
The trunk... huh, the nose
you see pointing down.
Bad luck.
No good.
- Bad luck for you.
- Good night.
I'm checking on a wire transfer.
Account code 651-4346.
Thank you.
Hello.
Um... I have a... a cut...
and I need some...
medicine... disinfectant.
Do you speak English?
How many?
Huh... one.
In... huh, in the morning?
In the morning!
One... before bed.
Two hundred and fifty-five cents.
- Thank you!
- Thanks...
Oh, I have it.
Excuse me... excuse me.
How much are these?
Those are 20 thousand Baht...
20 thousand.
- 20 thousand, eh?
- Yes.
They're beautiful.
Where's my money, damn it?
- You're late.
- Sorry boss.
Don't be sorry. Be on time.
What happened to your face?
Some assholes tried to mug me.
Like twenty of them.
But I kicked their asses.
I'm so sorry boss.
So sorry.
They... they take...
It's been opened.
Not me. It's them...
They broke it.
But I won't let them have it.
I got it back for you.
I don't let them have it.
There's a beer in the refrigerator.
It'll take down the swelling.
- He's a bad man, huh?
- Who?
The man in the case.
You're going to kill him?
Can you teach me?
- Teach you what?
- Everything.
I can help you.
Please?
Show me.
Again.
Good.
That was your first lesson.
Why didn't I kill him?
Maybe it's because...
And this is strange...
somehow...
when I looked into his eyes...
I saw myself.
So I became his teacher.
The best way to defend yourself...
You have to learn,
to read your surroundings.
See that man in the red jacket?
What man?
You're living in a city of mirrors.
Store windows, glass office buildings,
polished steel...
eyes in the back of your head.
Ahh...
Eyes in the back of my head, eh boss, huh?
I got you now boss.
I'm not your boss,
I'm your teacher.
So I call you a dandy
- Ready?
- Yeah.
How is he bad?
This man. He has many country girls...
from the north.
He buys them from their parents...
and sell them. Young girls, man.
He as same like devil, huh?
This guy.
Notorious gangster Pramod Juntasa,
was found dead last night.
Ahh...
Mother fucker...
he got what he deserved.
How many people have you killed?
I don't think about that.
Do the police know who you are?
No one knows who I am.
No one knows where I am.
I know.
- How many jobs in Bangkok?
- Four.
Four?
Roulette right.
You like?
Huh...
Um, I...
Can you... can you help me?
Can you tell her,
that I wanna take her to dinner.
Oh, right.
It's... huh, hot.
That's just...
Just eat it?
It's cooling it down.
It's hot again...
It's really hot.
Oh, the whole thing.
Now, that's better.
You don't pull the trigger...
you squeeze it.
- It's yours.
- What?
Congratulations.
It's best if he doesn't know us.
But we should know more about him.
Where... where?
In...
Okay...
- Boss!
- Yeah?
I come as a problem,
I think they been following me.
Be at the chow pride ferry station
in twenty minutes.
Okay boss.
- Wait for my call.
- Yes, boss.
Okay, listen carefully...
Open the case, 65-32-15.
Put your cellphone in the case,
and leave it.
Got it.
The case has returned.
- Yes?
- Put your boss on.
- Yes.
- We had an arrangement.
If I see your people again,
I'll kill your wife.
We'll try again.
Thank you very much.
Where is he from?
America, I think.
What is his work?
I don't know, ask him.
Ah, sir...
- Well... what is your work?
- Oh, ah...
It's banking.
- B... Banker?
- Bank... Banker, yes.
A good job.
I'll leave you two alone.
Rain.
Rain...
is you?
Your name means rain?
This... is your name.
- Bad man?
- Bad for somebody.
Floating Market.
Where is Damnoen Saduak?
Ratchaburi province.
Hour and a half by car.
Get some sleep.
We leave early.
Dock the boat up on the right.
Hey mister you buy something?
Buy something?
Come on buy something, buy something,
you buy... buy something...
Buy... buy... buy...
Get us outta here. Get us out!
Dock the boat on the left.
- Come on, faster. Hurry up.
- Forward, let's go.
Get me over there.
Move!
Shit.
Fuck.
God, no!
Take it to the club.
- He's same like you, you know.
- Who?
This guy, on TV.
He fights bad guys,
and helps the poor.
Thai people love him.
He's a very good man...
Same like you. Bad guy.
"FIFTY COINS - FIFTY WISHES"
"I am happy together with you"
Freeze!
Four: Know when it's time to get out.
Three: Erase every trace.
Boss?
Two: Don't take any interest
in people outside work.
One: Don't ask questions.
"He's a very good man,
same like you"
Political assassination
wasn't in the contract.
So there are two ways to go.
Refuse the job and walk away now...
or... do the job and walk away rich.
The truth is...
almost anyone can take out a politician.
It's not the hard part.
The hard part is getting away with it.
He wants more money.
It's a big job. There's risk.
Yes. He knows who we are.
If he were caught...
it could lead back to us.
What about the messenger?
We should erase every link.
The girl too.
Just to be safe.
I'll take care of it.
- I gotta go.
- He can wait.
He's counting on me.
Kong.
Be here tomorrow at 6pm.
- Last job?
- Yeah.
- Bad man?
- Bad for somebody.
See you tomorrow boss.
Call him, or we do to your sister...
what we did to you.
Call him!
Aom?
Kong!
I'm sorry.
Where is he staying?
Aom.
Tell me where he is staying!
Or I'll cut her tits off! Huh?
He fights bad guys,
and helps the poor.
Thai people love him.
When the nightmare becomes real,
you don't hesitate...
you don't think.
You just run.
Anyone in the way goes down.
It's pretty simple.
You're the target now, leave the
country, or you're going to die.
Where is Kong?
Why the fuck you care?
- He's my student.
- Go to hell.
Where is Kong?
Surat.
He's with Surat.
Still no answer.
Maybe he killed them.
He's only one man.
Hey! What's wrong?
Look, he's right there!
Let's go!
What's happening?
He's out here, let's find him,
don't let him inside.
Can you see him?
What's happening down there?
Somebody turn on light!
Where is Kong?
I had to tell them.
Take her into the street.
And clear the way.
I got one more job.
- Surat?
- Yeah, he's very bad.
Come on.
What're you doing?
Get up! Do something! Come on.
Let's go!