Oh, God.
Well, what the hell happened?
- We're an old married couple.
- Mmm-hmm.
Was it the pot?
I don't think so, because we brought it
with us from New York.
- Yeah.
- It's the same.
What was that...
What was that old movie?
You know, Blame it on Rio.
It has to be that, it has to be that.
You got to feel my heart.
Are you going to make it till dinnertime?
After dinnertime.
Oh, God.
God, I'd love to live like this.
Yeah.
I'm willing, if you have enough money
to stay in Brazil for the rest of our lives.
I'll think about it.
Okay.
Do you think that's it, being away?
- Yeah.
Hey, babe.
Where did you go?
Don't do this to yourself.
Everything is wonderful.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
I don't feel like such a fuck-up
when I'm here, that's all.
Good luck.
See you in a bit.
I love you.
Okay.
Don't touch anything.
Don't say anything. Back up.
Turn off the lights. Turn them off.
Are you... Don't even think about the buzzer.
Get in the corner.
Is the cash in here? Open it up. Open it up!
Quicker. Get over here. Get over here.
You want me to fucking shoot you?
Open it up. Open it up.
Get over in the corner. Get over
in the corner. Keep your hands down.
Keep your fucking hands down.
All right?
Come over here.
Get over here so I can see you.
Come over here. Stand at the corner.
Come over here.
Put your hands down. Put your hands down.
Oh, shit! Is this all you got in here?
I'm watching...
Stay away from the fucking buzzer, all right.
Fucking shit, it's all she...
Get back in your corner.
Get back in your fucking...
Get back in your corner!
All right, keep your hands down
by your side, all right. I'm watching you.
I will shoot you, all right.
I'll fucking shoot you in a second.
This is all shit.
Diamonds.
Where's the fucking keys for this case?
Where's the...
Where are the keys for this case?
- In the drawer.
- Shut up, all right.
These are them?
Don't fucking move, all right.
Don't move.
What, are they all the same?
Are they?
Fucking stupid bitch.
I'm watching you.
Which fucking key... Which fucking...
This is bullshit!
What the fuck is up...
What type of glass is this...
Fuck is up with this glass?
Fuck this...
Bullshit.
Fuck, no.
Fuck you, you motherfucking stupid fuck.
Fuck.
My gun.
Fuck! Andy!
Hank, you're so stupid!
Fucking Andy!
Shit.
Hey, two for four. You're batting. 500.
No, Dad, the second one was an air...
- No, no. It was a perfectly placed bunt.
- Good game, sweetheart.
- Good game.
How many you got?
Yeah, who's going to want seconds?
Uncle Andy, can I have another hot dog?
Yeah, the way you played today,
I'll buy you the whole stand.
No, her mother doesn't want
her eating junk, all right?
That's not junk, that's all right.
That's a hot dog, right, honey?
What do I owe you?
Hey, Hank,
your money is no good here.
No, I got it, okay.
- I got it.
- You sure?
- That was a good game.
- Yeah.
Hey, give me a kiss. Give me a kiss.
- All right. I'll see you next weekend?
- I love you.
All right, be good. Here's your ball.
- You didn't feed her junk, did you?
- No, of course not.
I don't want her to develop
bad eating habits.
- She looks puffy.
- She doesn't look puffy, all right.
- You look puffy.
- Fuck you.
- She wore sun block?
- It was cloudy, Martha.
There are rays, Hank.
Hey, you got my money?
Oh, Christ, Martha. Do you have any idea
what that school is costing me?
You're the one
who wanted to send her there.
Yeah, because it is a damn good school
and she wanted to go there.
- You owe me three months.
- I don't owe you.
- I owe Danielle.
- Don't get semantic.
- Bye.
- April, May and June.
No, I promise, all right.
What's up, Hank?
Piece of shit!
Fuck you. All right.
Can I borrow your cell phone?
I don't have one.
- Just...
- It's brain cancer. There's a pay phone
- over there by the bathroom.
- No, it can wait.
What's happening with you?
I used to think you had
the world by the balls.
Now, I'm not sure if you even got any.
I got them when I need them, all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, smart and funny.
What I always admired about you, your wit.
- You're a prick, Andy.
- I always was.
- So, let's see if there're any left.
- What?
Cojones.
Well, you need money. So do I.
Let's solve it.
- What are you talking about?
- Well, there's a place we can knock off.
Know it like the back of our hand.
Easiest money you'll ever get.
What are you saying?
It's worth about 600 grand.
And it's insured, so it's a victimless crime.
I offer that in case
your faggoty little conscience bothers you.
I weigh it off on 20 cents on the dollar.
That's 60 grand each.
Give or take.
I can't believe this is you that's talking.
Believe it.
So, it's safe, nobody gets hurt,
everybody wins. It's perfect.
Why?
What do...
- Do you need money?
- Of course, I need money. But this is...
This is serious crime, Andy. I'm not
a serious crime kind of a guy. I got a kid...
You've got shit.
You have a whole lot of shit.
You said so yourself.
All the time. Every day.
You know what?
It's not as serious as you might think.
You're my little brother. Now, trust me.
God, Andy.
That's why you called me up?
That's why you wanted
to spend the night together,
- talk me into something crazy?
- That's why I called you up.
Talk you into something crazy.
Well, what's the place?
No, not another word till you commit.
Fuck.
It's all right.
So, how's the wife?
Hey, Hank.
Hey, I got an appointment.
- I'll be back in a few, all right.
- Of course, you will. It's Thursday.
- You're early.
- Well...
You know my days are so busy.
Just tell me that you'll think about it.
But I thought about it already.
And I came to the conclusion
that you're crazy.
I'm going to go where with you?
I mean, you've got child support.
You've got Danielle's school,
you've got the rent...
- The mortgage...
- Come on.
...you're up to your ears in debt, Hank.
- I can solve all that. I know I can.
When are you going to grow up, Hank?
We have a really good thing going,
and you should just enjoy it.
We have a really good time in bed.
I don't ask for anything.
I love you. I want more.
So does Oliver Twist.
Can I help you to seconds?
Or do you really, really, really
have to get back?
Huh?
"The weight of this sad time we must obey.
"Speak what we feel
and not what we ought to say.
"The oldest hath borne most.
"We that are young shall never see so much,
"nor live so long. "
Bravo! Bravo!
You were great. I'm so proud of you.
You were wonderful.
Grandpa and I thought you were wonderful.
Excuse me, I'm sorry. It's just...
I have to have your autograph.
- Dad. No.
- What, you were incredible.
- No, stop it.
- What?
- I messed up some of my lines.
- No, you didn't. I didn't notice.
- Did you notice?
- I didn't notice at all.
Honey, you were great. What?
Mom, can I go see The Lion King
this weekend?
- There's a class trip, everyone's going.
- Did you ask your father?
- Can I, Dad?
- Yeah, sure. I got some money.
Well, it's $130.
But we're staying overnight
and that includes hotel and everything.
Okay, great. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Hey, man. Can I talk to you?
- Where are you?
- I'm down the hall, by the coffee.
- How about my office, 30 seconds?
- All right.
Hank, the super at 111 Riverside
says the boiler's really kaput.
He needs you to... Hello?
So?
- That place that you were talking about.
- What place?
- The one that we were going to...
- To knock off?
Yeah.
To rob?
You say it.
Tell me about it.
I'm not going to tell you about it
until you say you're in
and once you say it, there's no way out.
I'm in.
Let me see your hands.
- Just say it again, "I'm in. "
- What're you talking about?
Just say it again, "I'm in. "
I'm in.
What?
I just wanted to see if you were pulling
any of that chickenshit baby stuff
like when we were kids, you know,
"It doesn't count.
I had my fingers crossed. "
I'm in. What're we doing?
- And when?
- It's a jewelry store.
- Does this ring a bell?
- No.
What if I tell you it's got
a Foot Locker on one side
and a Claire's Accessories on the other.
Yeah, that's right. You got it. Now, listen.
We don't want Tiffany's.
We want a Mom and Pop operation,
in a busy place,
on a Saturday
when the week's takes go in the safe.
We both worked there.
We know the safe combinations.
We know the burglar alarm signals.
We know where everything is.
I figure, between the week's take,
the jewelry and the cases,
the vault, there's a $500,000 haul.
I figure probably six.
That old dumb old lady that works there,
she's alone till noon.
She's not going to be a problem.
Andy.
Yeah?
That's Mom and Dad's store.
That's what I said.
A Mom and Pop operation.
- You can't do that.
- Yeah, we can. Think about it.
It's perfect. It's perfect.
In and out in a minute.
Insurance takes care of Mom and Dad,
so they're not hurt. Right?
No one's going to give a shit.
After a week the cops
- will put it in the back of the filing cabinet.
- Jesus, Andy. I...
Why did you even want me in on this?
Well, it'll solve everything for both of us.
What has to be solved for you?
Same as you. I need money.
I'm going to start over again.
What do you mean?
What the fuck kind of...
It's none of your business.
I just want out. I just want to... That's all.
I'm getting out,
I want to help my little brother.
Come on.
Yeah.
No, I don't think I can do this.
I don't think I can...
Yeah, you can. Yeah, you can.
I just...
That's $2,000.
It's an advance.
See what just that much does for you.
And,
imagine the rest.
Five, six, seven, eight,
nine hundred dollars.
You still owe me May and June.
Yeah, Monday. All right.
Everything on Monday.
- That's what I said.
- Such a loser.
You're such a fucking loser.
I come over here with $900.
- Yeah, well, if it was for me, maybe.
- And I'm the fucking... All right.
- May and June, asshole.
- Bye, bye, bye.
Danielle, dinner.
No, please don't put me on... Jesus.
- Yo, Bobby.
- What's going on?
- Hey, here, let me buy you a drink.
- I'm working.
- I ain't loaning you no more money.
- No, come on, man. I'm flush.
- You don't exactly...
- Yeah, something like that.
Look, you just...
If you're free tomorrow morning,
I got a proposition for you.
- Later.
- All right.
- What if there is a security guard?
- There isn't.
- Why?
- No, it's a Mom and Pop place.
Who ever heard
of a Mom and Pop jewelry store?
- What the fuck is that?
- It's in the suburbs, all right.
It's not in the city.
I don't know.
We drive out there, we check it out,
if anything looks off,
you know, we just drive away.
We say, "Fuck it,"
we drive our happy asses home
and I keep the money anyway.
Yeah, fine.
You keep the money anyway.
- Hanson?
- Yeah, that's me.
All right.
- Yeah.
- Bobby, for Christ's sakes,
- Bobby, we got to go.
- Just come on in.
I just got to throw on some clothes.
It'll only take a second.
We got to go.
- Just give me a second.
- God damn it.
Jesus Christ, Bobby, it's so fucking early.
Boo wakes up, you fucking sit up with him.
- I told you it was work.
- I don't give a fuck what it is.
Chris ain't used to getting up this early.
Oh, Christ.
Come on, babe. Here.
- Thank you, baby.
- Yeah, just keep it down, okay?
You wake Boo up, I'll kick your ass.
- All right.
- Yours, too.
All right.
Come on.
All right, let's do it.
Are we there?
- No.
All right.
Who the fuck are you supposed to be?
Look, I used to work there, all right.
I used to work there
and I can't take a chance
on being recognized. Don't... Look...
- You ain't never done this before, huh?
- Yeah, so?
I got to tell you something,
you look like a fucking asshole.
- Yeah, all right, look...
- I'm going to do this on my own.
- Really?
- You do the driving, I do the thing, all right.
- What if you need help?
- I got all the help I need.
There's no shooting.
- I ain't looking for it.
- There's no shooting.
- You do the driving.
- Hey.
- I do the thing.
- No shooting.
You ain't got the balls to do the thing.
I got the balls
- and I got a gun. That's the deal.
- Listen, no shooting.
- Or else I'm leaving right now.
- Hey, no!
Just no shooting, okay?
Okay. Ten more minutes.
What the fuck is this?
You can listen to that faggoty shit
all the way home.
Right now, I got to get into character.
- Right?
- Okay.
Okay.
This is it.
You ready?
Car out front. Door open.
I jump back in. You take off.
- Simple as a pimple, all right.
- Right.
- Right?
- Let's do it.
- All right.
Yes, hi, hello.
Is Andrew Hanson available, please?
Uh...
Mooney. Mooney.
Okay, yeah, tell him it's Mooney.
- Yeah.
- There's a Mr. Mooney on line two.
- He sounds like some nut case.
- Okay.
- But...
- All right, I'll take it.
It just came apart, Andy.
Oh, my God, Andy.
What the fuck am I gonna do?
No, honey, no, don't worry.
It's just some mistake.
It's either the bank's or mine.
Maybe I didn't put enough money
in the joint account.
Yeah. No. Listen, don't worry.
Of course, we have the cash.
I'll call, I'll take care of it. Okay?
Yes, okay?
- Andy?
- Yeah. Yeah.
We're waiting for you
in the conference room.
Okay, I'll be right in.
Jesus.
Okay, next.
The auditors.
Some of you guys might have heard,
we're getting hit with an IRS audit.
The auditors will be here on Monday.
They'll spend a day or two
with each department.
On Monday, they'll start with payroll,
so you're up first, Andy.
Great. Great. No problem.
How are you doing today, sir?
Thanks a lot.
Hungry?
Have a drink.
Right, tonic water.
You know,
the thing about real estate accounting
is that you can,
you can head down the page
or across the page,
and everything works out.
So, every day, everything adds up.
Well, the total is always the sum of its parts.
It's clean, it's clear, neat, absolute.
But my life, it...
It doesn't add up. It's...
Nothing connects to anything else. It's...
I'm not the sum of my parts.
All of my parts don't add up to one...
To one me, I guess.
Get a shrink or a wife.
- I got a wife.
- Get a shrink.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Was it me, honey?
What difference does it make?
It's another strikeout.
I swear it would make a lot of difference.
- You're all I want.
- Yeah, well...
I'm a lousy cook. The house looks like shit.
I'm a lousy lay,
I don't know why you wanna keep me.
You weren't in Rio.
I wasn't what?
Lousy lay.
Well, like you said, just blame it on Rio.
Suppose I could get us back there.
What?
Rio.
- To live?
- Absolutely.
- You're just crazy. Crazy.
- No. It's not crazy.
The real estate market's booming in Rio.
There's a lot of new money.
And they're going to want
the same as Europeans, Arabs,
everybody wants real estate in New York,
in America and I know the market here.
You don't even speak the language.
I'll fucking learn it. Jesus Christ.
You know when...
When you met me, my biggest prospect
was inheriting a Mom and Pop jewelry store
in a fucking shopping mall in Westchester.
Now, I know it's not Trump Plaza, and...
But just take a look at how we're living now.
Now, I took that lousy job in that,
that real estate office,
I was practically a fucking gofer,
and I'm pulling down six figures now.
I'm smart.
I know the angles.
- Yeah.
I bet you do.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
Well, because there is
no extradition agreement
between Brazil and the United States.
How the...
How the hell do you know that?
I saw it in a movie.
Yeah, I guess I saw the same movie.
So, what are you thinking?
What are you thinking?
Don't ask, don't tell.
I just want us to get back there.
I've seen Heaven, Gina,
it's a nice place to stay.
- Okay? All right?
- Uh-huh.
- What language do they speak there?
- Portuguese.
I speak a little Spanish.
That's... I'm sorry, sweetheart,
that's not the same language.
- Yes, it is.
- I'm sorry, it's not.
- Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
- No.
- Yes, it is.
- Cómo se llama?
- Me llamo...
- Cómo? Me llamo...
Gina.
Why'd you come to me?
I know you from way back,
I know what you do.
You're a cop.
No, I'm not a cop,
I just want to make sure you're still around.
I'll bring you what I've got soon,
either you take it or you don't.
But I know you will.
You could work for the cops.
Check me out.
I'll be back.
That's $2,000.
It's an advance.
See what just that much does for you,
and imagine the rest.
- Yeah, so how do we start? Oh, fuck.
- It's
not we, you.
Me?
What the hell do I know
about robbing a jewelry store?
You'll learn it there.
On-the-job training, you know.
Cut it out, man, this is serious.
You know, I'm serious as a heart attack.
Listen, number one, I can't...
- I can't go up to the mall.
- Why not?
Oh God, three months ago,
I had to walk the whole goddamn area
with a Home Depot representative,
'cause they were thinking of buying up
a lot of space.
We own a lot of land in the mall,
and I'm getting a lot of big handshakes.
"Andy, baby, how are you?
"I haven't seen you in so long
since you left. "
And telling me all that bullshit
because they figure I'm making a killing,
because a big chain wants to buy them out.
I'm saying someone's going to
just recognize me too easy.
So we postpone, just...
Yeah, we could, you know, wait a year.
I mean, I don't know about you,
my problems are pressing.
Jesus, Andy, I... Andy!
- I wouldn't even know how to start, I mean.
- Well, you can stop being a baby.
- I'm not being a...
- Yeah, you're being a baby.
Get a gun.
You get a toy gun in a kid's store.
Right, that old lady that works on Saturday,
what's her name?
- Doris?
- Yeah, Doris, Mom's friend.
She's what, 60, 70? She's blind as a bat?
Look at me. Blind as a bat.
All right, those toy guns,
they look so real, they fool cops all the time.
All right, you go in at 8:00 a. m.,
just as she opens up.
You put her old ass in the back room,
you empty the vault,
the cash, the trays
and you dump it in a fucking sack.
All right. You don't gotta be neat about it.
Jesus, Andy, I don't know.
I don't know, I don't... I...
I don't know.
Okay. Come on.
You can do it.
Anybody can.
- I just think...
- I know, I know. It's too late to think.
It's too late.
This is our future.
Okay.
- Yeah.
- There's a Mr. Mooney on line two.
He sounds like some nut case. But...
Okay, I got it.
It just came apart, Andy.
Oh, my God, Andy.
What the fuck am I gonna do?
Could he be in a different wing?
If you just pipe down a second, sir,
I'm trying to help you.
- What are you doing here?
- Keep quiet one minute.
Dad called me, all right. I just got here.
- This lady, she doesn't...
- Look, Miss, our father... I got it.
- I got it. I know, but you might...
- I told him, we've got no Charles Hanson.
Wait a minute, I got a Nanette Hanson.
- What?
- There's a Nanette Hanson.
- Brought in about three hours ago.
- What?
Gunshot wounds.
- Where is she?
- Emergency ICU.
Hey. Now. Hey, hold it.
Wait, are you related? Sir? Are you?
Dad?
She's unconscious.
And they...
She's...
They...
They say...
So, how are you feeling?
Yeah, I feel old.
I've been studying all week,
and I can't retain a thing.
Come on, you're going to pass
with flying colors, Dad.
That's how I'm going to spend my birthday,
taking that stupid test.
Have you spoken to your brothers?
Few weeks ago.
Yeah? How are they?
Busy.
You know, Dad,
Hank is Hank and Andy's Andy.
No more cramming, birthday boy.
It's the moment of truth.
What time is Doris coming to the store?
She said 12:00 at the latest.
She has to baby-sit for her daughter.
I'll pick you up right after my test.
Come on, come on.
All right, all right, all right.
- Perfect score, Mr. Hanson.
- Bingo!
Congratulations.
If you'll take this to Window C,
they'll give you the eye test.
I might not do so well on that one.
- I've been studying hard, of course. Thanks.
- All right.
That's my store!
- What happened? What's happening?
Let's go!
- Sir, sir, just stay behind the yellow line.
- What's happening?
- I want to know what's happening.
- Behind the yellow line.
- Where's my wife? Where's my wife?
- Calm down. Please calm down.
I love you.
There are more tests we can do, but from
what we've seen so far, it's very unlikely.
There's no brain activity.
And statistically speaking,
there's very little chance for recovery.
Why was Mom working?
I thought she didn't work at the store
anymore, that's what Katherine told me.
Doris had to baby-sit, I had to get down
to the DMV, get my eyes tested.
Today's my birthday.
Where's your brother?
He...
He says he can't take it. To let him know if...
If he can help,
but he just can't see her like that.
He's 28 years old.
He's a goddamn punk from Red Hook.
Red Hook. What was he doing up here?
What in the fucking world? What he...
I mean, did he put a map on the wall
and throw a dart?
It's so absurd. It's so goddamn arbitrary.
Why me? Why her?
What was this goddamn kid doing?
You belong in hell.
Yeah. I understand. All right. Thank you.
Look, it might be better if you call,
make an appointment?
Well, I'd rather wait.
Please. Steve...
Dad.
You have to make a decision, Dad.
The gun was bought in Texas.
Stolen Texas driver's license, his ID, fake,
the gun turns up in New York, a year later.
- Mom needs you to make a decision, Dad.
- Andy, just leave him alone.
Well, something has to be done,
he has to make a decision.
Just leave him to his grief for one minute.
- Mom is in the hands of Jesus.
- Now, will you cut it out with that crap?
You shouldn't push Dad to make a decision
he doesn't wanna make.
Well, he has to make a decision.
Hey, Patrick.
We know it's difficult, Mr. Hanson.
Let her go.
"Almighty and ever living God.
"Remember the mercy with which you
graced your daughter, Nanette, in this life.
"Receive her, we pray,
into the mansions of the saints.
"As we make ready
our sister's resting place
"Look also with favor on those who mourn.
"And comfort them in their loss.
"Because God has chosen
to call Nanette from this life,
"commit her body to the earth,
for we are dust and to dust we shall return. "
I'm so sorry for your loss.
She was a wonderful person.
- She was a wonderful woman.
- Yes.
- I'm so sorry.
- You have my deepest condolences.
She was a dear friend.
So sorry for your loss,
your mother was a good person.
I'm so sorry.
God bless you.
There's no way I can make this scene, Andy.
He was always such a baby.
Yeah.
I can't really talk right now.
I can't, I...
I have to go. Andy needs me.
22nd precinct.
Detective Barrett, please.
Just a moment, sir.
I'm sorry, he's not in right now.
Is there anyone down there that knows
anything about the Nanette Hanson case?
- Who's speaking, please?
- Charles Hanson, yeah.
Just a moment, sir.
Sergeant Sullivan.
Yeah, good morning, Sergeant.
I've been trying to reach Detective Barrett
but he doesn't return my calls.
Would you like to leave a message, sir?
No, I wouldn't like to leave
another message.
Doesn't anyone down there give a damn?
Doesn't anyone down there
work for a living?
Would you like to leave a message, sir?