McCaleb.
Whatever happens,
it'll be his face on the front page.
What do you have?
I've had hemorrhoids for a while. You?
Victims five and six.
Code Killer strikes again.
You're not a vegetarian, right?
How do you like your steak?
Big, red, juicy?
Neighbor came over to complain about
the noise. He got run over at the door.
Neighbor said he saw this
from the door.
Bachelor number one hasn't been dating
lately. Apparently, he's a bed wetter.
You're sick, you know that, Arrango?
- Neighbor says he didn't see a thing.
- This might be important too.
The maid quit about six years ago.
She didn't like the neighborhood.
We're calling him Chuck Taylor.
Oh, how's that?
Well, the prints. Look.
Converse. High-tops.
Chuck Taylor.
You get it, right?
You don't know who Chuck Taylor is?
Basketball coach. Stanford Cardinals.
We got the remains
of two or three people.
One of them could be a midget.
In any case, it's a hell of a gangbang.
Once you joke about it,
you shouldn't be doing it.
Another love note.
Maybe the two of you ought to get
a room someplace.
Was another message left for you?
Why is he singling you out?
I can't comment.
Are there numbers this time?
He loves it.
What does the message say?
Why does he focus on you?
- Do we have numbers this time?
- Were there numbers?
- Why does he single you out?
- What does he want?
Chuck.
You got a motive?
Clear.
Almost there.
Good. Coming out.
Good, Terry. You did good.
Are you taking your pills?
Yeah.
Yeah, all 34 of them.
- No fever at all?
- No.
All clear of that.
- No diarrhea?
- No, nothing.
Good.
- Blood pressure and pulse?
- Right on target.
You're not working too hard
on the boat?
No, just enough to keep it afloat.
That's all.
I'll be back in a bit.
I'll check this blood work
and get the tissue to the lab.
Okay.
Don't start running laps yet,
but I'm very pleased.
No rejection.
All your blood levels are good.
- I might lower your prednisone next week.
- Thank God.
I'm tired of shaving
three times a day.
Lean forward.
- May I ask you something?
- No, don't talk.
Sit up.
Okay, come around.
All right. What did you want to ask me?
The kid in 218...
...what's his blood type?
It's different from yours,
if that's what you wanted to know.
- How long has he been waiting?
- About half as long as you did.
What are his chances?
Maybe 50-50, maybe less.
What's bothering you, Terry?
I don't know.
When I was at the Bureau, we had
to qualify once a year on the range.
You know, shoot at targets,
stuff like that.
We had a thing where you shoot
a circle around a heart.
It was called the " 10 ring."
That was the highest score.
Typical.
You wait for a heart for two years...
...almost don't make it, then wonder
if we should've given you that heart.
Know what that is?
B.S.?
Exactly. Go home and enjoy your boat.
See you next week.
How are you doing?
Morning, Terry.
Morning?
It's 2 in the afternoon, Buddy.
As long as my dad sends those checks,
it's whatever time I say it is.
- Whatever.
- Heads up, by the way.
Somebody's on your boat.
Been here 10 minutes. Looked harmless.
I didn't say anything.
Looks better than harmless!
May I help you, miss?
I'm looking for Terry McCaleb.
You're looking at him.
Graciella Rivers.
I have read about you in the paper,
in the "Where are they now?" column.
You know, in the Metro section.
You're not the first person
to try to find me.
I can recommend a good
investigator who won't rip you off.
The article said you're the best
and you hate when someone gets away.
If you read it, you know what happened
and that I'm retired, Miss Rivers.
Graciella.
I think you could help me.
How's that?
- Maybe even help yourself.
- I don't need money.
I'm not talking about money.
Sister?
- And her son.
- Which one?
- Excuse me?
- Which one's dead?
My sister.
Gloria Torres. Glory.
And her son's name is Raymond.
- I don't think I can help you.
- Just look at it again, please.
Just one more time,
and I'll leave you alone.
Just tell me if you perceive
or feel anything.
Miss Rivers, I'm a retired FBI man,
not a psychic.
- Do you want this back or not?
- I have a double.
You know, two for the price of one.
- You'll want to keep that one.
- Why is that?
Your heart, Mr. McCaleb.
It was my sister's.
- How do you know that?
- Newspaper.
You two have the same blood type,
AB with CMV negative.
You were operated on the day she died.
My number's on the back
if you change your mind.
Miss Rivers, this is Terry McCaleb.
Yeah, I'm sorry about it
being so late...
...but I wanted to tell you I'm going
to the police to see what's going on.
Don't thank me.
Don't get your hopes up.
I'm just gonna have a look.
I owe your sister that much.
May I help you?
- Detective Arrango and Waller around?
- Your name?
McCaleb.
I'm here about the Gloria Torres case.
It's McCaleb.
Down the hall, up the stairs,
first door on your right.
Thanks.
Well, Mr. McCaleb.
Detective Arrango.
I thought you were dead
or retired.
I hear you want to talk
about Gloria Torres.
Can we talk privately?
About what?
- I'm looking into her death.
- Here we go, same old shit.
I'll give you five minutes, that's it,
before I toss your ass right out.
- My partner will be here in a minute.
- Want a doughnut?
I want to know who you're working for.
Her sister, right?
That's right.
I knew it. Son of a bitch.
Let me see your ticket.
I don't have a license,
if that's what you mean.
Is it stuffy in here?
Is it hot?
No.
Just get a little air.
Let me give us some air
and make it more comfortable.
Okay, let me get this straight. You're
conducting a homicide investigation...
...into the Gloria Torres case?
That's true.
You don't have a license to practice
as a private investigator in California?
That's right.
Do you know it's a crime to practice
as an investigator without a license?
Will you knock off the crap?
I just wanted to have a talk.
Knock off the tape too.
- He's blocking the microphone anyway.
- Why didn't you say?
In the three years we've
interrogated here, maybe I forgot.
Come on, fellas. I'm just
here to help. Have a doughnut.
How do you know Graciella Rivers?
She's an acquaintance.
I told her I'd look into it. That's all.
If you guys aren't gonna have one,
I'm gonna have one.
Look.
I don't care what her sister told you,
Mr. Former FBI Profiler.
This ain't the type of case you like.
This ain't a glamorous case
that will get headlines.
This isn't Charles Manson
or Ted fucking Bundy.
This is an ordinary
convenience-store robbery.
Some idiot with a gun...
...with the right ratio
of balls to brains pulled the trigger.
I told her I'd check it out.
You've been on this a while,
and a fresh pair of eyes won't hurt.
I won't grandstand anybody.
I'll give any information to you first.
I'm not trying to one-up anyone.
What do you want?
A copy of the murder book
and a video walk-through of the scene.
I was always good with crime scenes.
- No can do.
- Why not?
How often does the sister call you?
Every day, weekends, holidays...
Believe it or not, we got feelings.
It hurts me to tell her there
are no leads or suspects.
I can get her off your case.
I tell her I looked into it, you're
doing a good job, she stops calling.
You were always good at a crime scene.
But the key word is "were."
Are you still?
You just give me a copy
of the tape, that's all.
We got more than
just the crime-scene tape.
We've got the crime.
Bring the doughnuts. Come on.
That's Kyungwon Kang, the owner.
He's about to make his last sale.
She comes in to buy a candy bar.
Yeah, for her kid.
And here he is. Ba-da-bing! Pow, pow.
He picked up all the shells.
Won't see this on
America's Favorite Videos.
- There's no sound on that camera?
- Right. He's just talking to himself.
- Could you run it in slow motion?
- Hold on. It's not over.
This guy coming up we call
the Good Samaritan. Watch.
This guy goes up and down the aisles,
looking for bandages, I guess.
Couldn't find any, so he used paper
towels to wrap her head.
The camera never really
gets a good look at him.
After he's finished, he goes outside,
he dials 911...
...and splits.
The voice was Latino. We figure
he was illegal, afraid to stay.
Yeah. That's too bad.
He probably got a look
at the car or the shooter.
We put out fliers, went on all
the Spanish stations. Nothing.
- May I?
- Knock yourself out.
Pushing the pause button
ain't gonna help her.
$32 in the cash register.
Look at that. He winked.
What?
Yeah.
Well, there you have it, Mr. FBI Guy.
Tell us something we don't know.
The shooter's been
in the store before.
He knew the placement
of the camera.
He's from the neighborhood,
or he just cased the place.
This isn't the first time either.
No emotion, no panic,
policed up his own brass.
This guy's done it before.
What?
How many others?
Let me look at the murder book.
We have to talk to our lieutenant.
We'll be in touch.
- When?
- Give me a number. We'll be in touch!
You guys can keep the doughnuts.
We don't need your doughnuts
or your shit!
We got enough of our own!
- Mrs. Kang?
- Yes? I know you?
No.
I heard what happened here.
Your husband and all. I'm sorry.
Yes, thank you.
The only way to keep evil out
is not unlock door.
We can't do that.
- We must have business.
- Yeah.
Thank you, ma'am.
You gonna pay me, or should
I drive you somewhere else?
Nearest public library.
Detective Winston said to wait here.
She'll be right with you.
Well, well, well, Terry McCaleb.
- Hi.
- As I live and breathe.
Look at you.
I hear you got a new ticker.
That's right. I'm all right, though.
How are you doing, babe?
Me? You know, same old, same old.
So, what's up?
You on a private ticket now?
No. Just doing a favor for a friend.
What case is it?
James Cordell. ATM holdup.
Let's see.
January 22. Newspaper says he was
shot by a guy wearing a ski mask.
Who's this friend you're
doing the favor for?
Graciella Rivers. Her sister was
shot in a store two weeks after.
Also a man in a ski mask.
Am I right? Are they connected?
Yeah. Same guy.
Out of your orbit, though.
Scumbag with a gun.
Three-strikes shit, that's all.
What do you mean?
Guy has two felonies,
third puts him away for life.
So he kills any witnesses.
Robbery, murder, it's all the same
sentence for him either way.
I talked to the boys over at LAPD,
and they showed me a tape...
...but they wouldn't copy
me the murder book.
I'll bet they copied you, though.
Come on, darling,
you owe me just one little one.
I know that.
When you handed me
the Cemetery Man bust...
...you were my membership into
this boys club. I haven't forgotten.
Does that mean yes?
Terry McCaleb.
Lucky for us the bank
had two cameras on this.
The shooter's back there.
I'm betting the mask isn't on yet,
or Cordell would have run.
H&K 9mm, same model used
in the Valley tape.
Hold that.
Back it up a little bit.
Back up there.
Look, he's saying something.
Like in the Valley tape.
He talked there too.
Yeah, he's a real chatterbox.
Did you get a lip reader in?
I'll get on it.
What about his cartridge?
Did he pick up his brass?
Yeah, there he is.
James Lockridge.
Pulled into the bank lot,
almost got sideswiped by a sedan.
Says it was a white guy,
but nothing else.
He called for the ambulance.
Cordell died going to the hospital.
You got any leads at all?
No, I'm following
the three-strike thing.
I think the man in the ski mask
is one of those.
What about the gun? H&K's
expensive for a holdup man.
That's weird he'd keep
it after the first killing.
I thought about that. I figure he
stole it, but that lead me nowhere.
I don't know. I think we'll need
fresh blood to solve this one.
Well, Jaye...
...why don't you get me
a copy of the book?
Both yours and L.A. Could you?
I'll ask the captain.
I don't see why not.
He was the lieutenant
on the Cemetery Man case.
Yeah, I kind of remember that.
Oh, well. I'm glad
someone got promoted.
- Right here.
- Thanks.
Mr. Lockridge, Terry McCaleb.
Thanks for seeing me.
Are you a policeman?
No, retired FBI. I'm investigating
a related case for a victim's family.
- Good. Because police are stupid.
- Why?
- Didn't they tell you?
- No.
Why would they? When I found
the guy, I call 911, right?
- Yeah.
They sent the ambulance
to the wrong place.
Took them 20 minutes.
He might have made it
if they hadn't screwed up.
- Those things happen.
- No.
They screwed up. A guy died.
End of story.
I'm busy. I agreed to see you
because you're already here, so...
...what do you want?
I thought you'd give your
statement to me firsthand.
For the love of God.
I needed cash.
As I pulled up, the guy
driving out almost hits me.
All I saw was a car.
There were no plates, no face, nothing.
I walk up to the ATM,
and there's this guy bleeding.
I figured he got it right before
I got there, so I called 911.
Ten minutes later, they come,
driving right fucking past us. Past us.
Any other details?
It could've been me.
Could've been him finding me...
...with the ambulance driving
right on fucking by. Good stuff.
You done?
Yeah.
Hey, Buddy.
Here's to you. Semper fi,
auld lang syne, keep on trucking.
You look like a skunk.
- What are you doing tomorrow?
- Same as always. Big, fat goose egg.
I could use a driver.
$10 an hour and meals.
- What's up? An investigation?
- I just need a driver, not a partner.
Okay. I'm in. Whose car?
If we take yours, I'll buy gas,
or I'll sit in the back in mine...
...because of the air bags.
- Your chest, right?
Yeah.
Let's take mine. That way
I won't feel like a chauffeur.
See you in the a.m.
You look tired, Terry.
You should get some sleep!
You don't deserve it.
First of all, I have no idea
where your heart came from.
All BOPRA tells us is they
have an organ...
...with a match to someone on the list.
In your case, we told you
what we knew.
Female, 32, perfect health,
perfect blood typing, perfect donor.
She was murdered.
Murdered?
What are you talking about?
She was shot during a robbery and lived
long enough for me to get her heart.
How do you know? You're not
supposed to know about the donor.
Her sister found me.
She read about how I had a rare
blood type like her sister...
...and that my surgery
was on the day she died.
What does she want? Money?
I'm glad you can find it funny.
She wants me to find out who did it.
She wants me to solve the murder.
Shit. Give me this woman's
name right now.
- You're not thinking of doing this?
- I started yesterday.
And today you're running a fever!
You are 60 days post-transplant!
As your doctor,
I'm ordering you not to do this.
- Respect the gift you were given.
- I do, I do. It was her gift.
She'd be dead either way.
You don't owe her.
It was supposed to be an accident.
99 out of 100 of these are head
injuries that end up fatal.
This one is different.
How is it different?
A heart's a heart!
An accident is fate. Murder is evil.
Please.
I wouldn't have this gift if somebody
hadn't done this hateful, evil thing.
You're not making sense.
She goes into a store
to buy a candy bar for her kid.
I can't explain it.
Terry, sit down.
- You know that little boy in room 218?
- Yeah.
He's waiting for a heart that
isn't coming. That could be you.
This is your one chance, Terry.
You tell that woman no.
You save yourself and tell her no!
I can't.
You're gambling with your life.
You get infection or rejection,
there's nothing we can do.
- I have no choice.
- Neither do I.
I can't be your doctor.
I won't be around for this.
Come on, doc.
I'll have your records ready
in the morning.
Good luck, Terry.
Graciella. Make it quick.
Hello?
This is McCaleb.
What's going on?
Tell me about her.
What do you mean?
Just tell me something about Gloria.
The more I know, the more
I can get a handle on this thing.
Do you have a kitchen on the boat?
A galley, yeah.
Is it big enough to cook a real meal?
Yeah, sort of.
So...
You want to know my sister,
you'll have to meet her son.
He's everything that was good
about her. It's in him.
I'll bring him by later,
and I'll make you dinner.
Good. I'd like that.
Okay. Then you can
give me an update.
Look, just so you know it, these cases
usually turn on some small detail.
Something someone forgot
or didn't think was important.
That's the key.
I'll have to find it.
You have Glory's heart.
She'll guide you.
Yeah. Thanks.
Quick enough?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Huh?
- Dandy.
I'll tell you what. Let me stop by
the In-N-Out on Victory.
I don't think they serve
hamburgers here. What's up?
The sheriff's office listed all
the three-strikes robbery suspects.
They also made a list of every H&K P7
pistol stolen in the last few years.
I charted that list
plus the address...
...and the work location
of every man on the list.
- A cross-reference to check overlap?
- Exactly.
One guy stands out like a whore
in church, and that's Mikail Bolotov.
He's a two-time loser, lives a mile
from where Gloria Torres was shot...
...and works four blocks from where
an H&K was stolen in December.
Why didn't they arrest
this Polo, Bolo...?
- Bolotov.
Oh, a Russian son of a bitch!
They don't know about the pistol.
It seems he has a good alibi.
It's his timecard. He punched
out after the Cordell murder.
- A friend could have done that.
- Yeah, true.
I still don't know why we're here.
This is where he works.
I'm gonna go have a talk with him.
- Cool.
- Where are you going?
You go after him, I pull you off.
Good cop, bad cop?
- No. Stay with the car.
- Come on, man. Starsky and Putz.
What are you expecting in there?
Nothing. This is just for show.
Hold this. Thanks.
Can I help you?
My name is McCaleb.
Following up the sheriff's department
investigation of February 3.
Just a minute, please.
Mr. Toliver? A Mr. McCaleb from
the sheriff's department is here.
- We're awfully busy, Mr. McCaleb.
- I'll get right to the point, then.
A few months ago, some deputies
asked you about an employee.
- Bolotov?
- Yes.
I'm on the case.
I'd like to get a few more points.
I'll tell you what I told them.
Bolotov was working that day.
You can see his timecards.
How many employees
do you have here at one time?
Eighty-five.
Is it possible that one of them might
have punched his timecard for him?
We've been in business 16 years.
It's happened.
Is he here today?
Yes, that's him over there.
Bolotov. That's Russian, right?
They're good workers
and don't complain.
They don't mind being paid shit.
- I'd like to talk to him.
- In here?
You want to maintain your cooperation
with the sheriff's office, don't you?
Yeah, all right.
Bolotov, up in the office.
Mr. Bolotov.
Have a chair.
Where were you on the night
of January 22?
I told them before.
I worked that night.
I know, but we know things
now that we didn't know then.
What things?
There was a burglary on Mason Street,
about four blocks from here.
- Is that where you got the gun?
- What gun?
And February 7, I suppose you
got an alibi for that night too.
I don't know that night.
'Course you do!
That's the night you went into Kang's
grocery store and killed two people.
Who are you?
You're not a cop.
Cops goes twos. Who are you?
I'm the Lone Ranger. Now sit down.
No badge. See? No cop.
"Terrell McCaleb."
Maybe one day, I pay you visit.
Yes?
Not now. I'll get back to him.
Bolotov's alibi isn't solid.
Think about it.
Even if you had a badge,
it'd be the wrong one.
I like him for this.
Bolotov's an ex-con. He could have
done that for any reason.
You should still put out a pickup.
- Who the hell are you?
- Buddy, Terry's partner.
- Sort of.
- Great.
Let's get back to Bolotov.
I've already sent a car to his
apartment. He's gone.
I hit a nerve.
Remember my lieutenant, who's
now my captain? He's unhappy.
He doesn't want to hear
from you again.
Terry has worked very hard on this.
We both have.
Shut up.
Also...
...he wants the tapes and murder
books back first thing in the morning.
Will that give you enough
time to copy everything?
I've already done that. Thanks.
Go home, you look like crap.
Wait a minute.
Lip reader is 90% certain the shooter
was saying, "Happy Valentine's Day."
Happy Valent...
That doesn't sound like your average
three-strikes guy, does it?
What's the average these days?
Not much, man.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Do you see the boat?
I told you.
- How much homework do you have?
- Three questions.
- Hey.
You forgot, didn't you?
Sort of. I kind of got lost
the last couple hours.
We can do this another time.
No, we're having dinner.
Come on up.
- Is this Raymond?
- This is Raymond.
This is the man I was
telling you about.
- How are you doing?
- What's The Following Sea?
That's the one that you have to
watch for, the one right behind you.
- Where's the kitchen? I mean, galley?
- Right in here.
- Can you fish off this boat?
- Yeah, you can.
Come on back,
I'll get you a fishing pole.
Jesus.
I didn't want you to see that.
Was she...?
Was she ever scared?
No, she never knew anything.
What I've asked you to do,
it just isn't fair.
Is it?
There's a restaurant in the marina.
Good atmosphere, view of the sunset.
Why don't I just take you
to dinner there.
Why do you live on a boat?
I hate mowing lawns.
Why do you live onshore?
Because that's where my warm,
cozy apartment is.
You were right, though.
It's a great sunset.
Yeah, you never get tired of it.
Does he stay with you?
Yeah. His dad isn't around.
He's a great kid. Your sister
must have been a good woman.
Thank you.
So how is it going, McCaleb?
Any hope?
Start thinking about your sister...
...who her friends were,
where she went, all of her routines.
- All right. How come?
- That's just an angle I'm working on.
Did she ever know a James Cordell?
- Cordell?
- Yeah.
No.
- You sure?
- Positive. Why?
It may be nothing.
It might be premature...
You think this James Cordell
killed her.
No, nothing like that.
Stop, McCaleb, with the prematures
and the angles. What?
Cordell was killed at an ATM machine
two weeks before your sister died.
We think it's the same gunman
in both cases.
Why would she know Cordell?
They were both in the wrong
place at the wrong time.
This investigation's being conducted
under the theory...
...that the locations were chosen
and the victims were random.
It's the other way around. It's not
where that's important. It's who.
- Gunman took money, so it's robbery...
- Bear with me.
Cordell and your sister
were connected.
There's some intersecting link
between them and the killer.
I'm not following you.
At the Bureau, we used to call
this a full-field investigation.
- That's what I'm conducting here.
- Full-field investigation.
Okay.
Come on!
You know, there was one thing
that's always bothered me.
- What?
- Nothing, but...
What is it?
Glory had this piece of jewelry she
always wore. Like a good-luck charm.
She never took it off. When the police
brought me her effects, it was missing.
What was it?
It was a single earring,
a dangling crucifix.
Okay. So, what does it mean?
Nothing. Some killers take
souvenirs, I suppose.
- That's sick.
- Yeah.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I gotta get back to the boat
for my medicine.
We have to get going too.
Raymond has some homework.
Raymond?
We've gotta go!
Say thank you to Mr. McCaleb. Come!
Thank you!
- Give me that schoolbag.
- Okay.
- Say thank you.
- Thank you.
- See you later.
- Give me the school bag.
And he takes the earring.
Hey, Buddy!
What's up?
You're working tomorrow, 6 a.m.
Cool. Whatever.
Who wants to go to the desert anyhow?
We go where the clues lead.
Don't any clues lead to the beach?
They lead where they lead. Usually
pretty close to where they started.
I have to ask, Terry.
How did it feel?
Back in the day, when you were
going up against all those sickos?
That was my job.
Come on, man. I mean,
driving a truck, that's a job.
All those killers
you used to hunt down.
I read in the paper some used to leave
you messages. That ain't truck driving.
Only one, actually,
ever left me messages.
Sorry, I'm sticking my nose
in it, I know.
Connected.
What?
When I was at the top of my game,
I felt connected to everything.
The victim, the killer,
the crime scene.
Everything.
Just felt like it was all part of me.
It's beginning to feel that way again.
Cool.
I'll tell you what. Driving is okay
because I would shit my shorts.
I would.
But that's why you're a famous cop
and I'm a boat bum. A loser.
Buddy, you're not a loser.
It's okay, Terry.
Only my mom has to tell me that.
My friends can tell me the truth.
Mrs. Cordell?
I'm Terry McCaleb. I called you.
Is this a bad time?
- As opposed to a good time?
- Poor choice of words. Can we talk?
Is that your partner in the car?
Yeah.
I wanted to hire an investigator,
but I couldn't afford to.
Couldn't afford to find out
who killed him.
You work for the police?
No, I'm a retired FBI agent.
I'm also a friend of the family
of the woman killed in Canoga Park.
We think it's the same gunman.
I see.
I'd like to tell you I'm sorry.
That's hard coming from a stranger...
...but I went through the files, and
James seemed like a good man.
Funny hearing him called James.
Everyone called him Jimmy.
And he was a very good man.
How can I help, Mr. McCaleb?
See this photograph?
Does this woman look familiar to you?
- Is that someone he might have known?
- I don't think so.
- Is that the victim from Canoga Park?
- Right.
Is that her son?
I don't understand.
How could he know her?
Are you suggesting they...?
- No, nothing like that.
- Then, like what?
We think your husband and Miss Torres
may have crossed paths with the killer...
...sort of the relationship between
the victim and the gunman.
The smallest detail of them coming
in contact is very, very important.
Something like dining at the same
restaurant, for instance.
- A restaurant the killer went to?
- Yeah.
That sounds like stalking,
not robbery.
To be honest with you, we're not sure
robbery is the motive in this case.
When they brought back his effects,
was it all there?
Was anything missing?
Rings, watches?
No.
You're sure he couldn't have been
in the Valley two weeks before?
No, he spent a month in Northern
California, working on the aqueduct.
And when my husband wasn't
working, he was home with me.
- Is that his car?
- Yes.
Any personal effects in that?
A picture on the dashboard.
- Still there?
- I don't know. I would think.
The sheriff's department drove
it home. I haven't been in it.
Can I...?
There it is.
Right here, yeah.
Any of this stuff your husband's
favorite knickknacks?
No, sorry.
Could you jot down your
husband's routines for me...?
- His sunglasses.
- What?
They hung from the mirror on a cord.
They're missing.
What kind of glasses?
They were Wayfarers.
He had them for years.
- Wayfarers?
- What do you think it means?
I said, what do you think it means?
Probably nothing.
Thanks, Mrs. Cordell.
I'll call you if anything comes up.
Easy, Mac. What's the matter?
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
I saw the killer, Buddy.
At the bank, at the ATM,
where Cordell was killed.
Wait a minute, that's crazy.
That's the last place he would be.
No, it fits the profile.
Profile? What profile?
Take me to the L.A. County
Sheriff's Office.
No, wait! I don't get it.
Why would the killer go back?
Okay. Never mind, I'll just drive.
- Now you're starting to get it.
- This goes any longer, I want a raise.
How about workmen's comp?
Detective Winston's in the field.
Can I take a message?
- Tell her McCaleb was by.
- Hey.
She wanted to see you, Mr. McCaleb.
How about that?
It's McCaleb, Jaye.
I'm en route. You should get
yourself down here ASAP.
What was that first part?
I said, we've got Bolotov.
- Stay there, Buddy.
- This sucks!
Trash collectors found him.
We think he's been here since early a.m.
- What are they doing here?
- This alley is the line.
The line?
South side's LAPD,
north is sheriff's department.
We're not sure who
has jurisdiction yet.
Congratulations, old man!
You shook him out of his tree.
Dumb bastard killed himself.
H&K 9mm.
Same as both murders.
I bet ballistics confirms it.
- What are you talking about?
- He's saying this case is closed.
Bolotov, he doesn't fit the profile.
- Of what?
- A serial killer.
This guy stalks his victims
and kills them on camera...
...then he takes trophy items.
- What are you talking about?
I was at the ATM crime scene.
The killer was behind me.
He had Cordell's glasses on,
and he had Gloria Torres' earring.
Did they look like these?
This? And this?
I don't care what you call him.
We got him.
- I don't know, his hair was long.
- Maybe it was a wig?
Maybe.
- You wanna sit down?
- I'm fine, goddamn it.
- Why don't you lay down?
- Arrango, shut up!
There's something in his mouth.
- It's a bullet.
- No way it came from a 9mm.
- Looks like a.38 to me.
- Why'd he put a.38 slug in his mouth?
Same reason he died
on the jurisdiction line.
Somebody's trying to jerk us all off.
Personally, I like being jerked off.
This case is closed in my book.
You're just worried, aren't you?
- Worried?
- Yeah.
About what?
That I might bust this case.
You don't care who gets hurt or killed.
- As long as I don't bust the case.
- What the fuck is it to you anyway?
Gloria Torres, that victim
you didn't give a shit about?
I've got her heart. That's what.
That's right.
I'm alive because she's dead.
That puts me in this bigtime.
You're an asshole, and you can't help
it, but I'm on this case for a while.
I'll be along until we get him.
I don't care whether it's you, him
or whoever. I'm in this.
Stay out of my city!
Go get yourself a dick transplant!
Conflict of interest.
- Ever think about that?
- Pain in the ass.
- How much do I owe you?
- I don't know, 200 or so.
That sounds right.
- Take a check?
- Yeah, sure.
You look like shit.
You should take a nap.
Yeah, thanks. I will.
- Who do I make it out to? Buddy?
- Jasper. Jasper Noone. N-O-O-N-E.
I know the Noone part. But Jasper?
I look more like a Buddy
than a Jasper, huh?
Yeah.
Take a nap.
Ray, stay out here. Be careful
of the edges. I'll be right out.
- Hi.
- Hey.
So is it true?
What?
I heard it on the news. They said
that they found a Russian man...
...who may be the killer.
I don't know.
I don't think so, but I don't know.
They said they had evidence that
could link this guy to both murders.
That may just be two cops
trying to grab headlines.
I don't know. Sorry.
You're starting to sound like L.A.P.D.
I need some answers.
Because no one knows...
No one has a clue what that boy goes
through every night without his mother.
I'm sorry.
I did what you asked.
I made a list of all
of Glory's routines.
That's good.
She used to go to that market
almost every night.
She'd take Raymond
to McDonald's a lot. Too much.
The one on Ventura and Reseda.
And she would go bowling,
but not lately.
She used to visit an aunt
every Thursday...
...because our aunt was in a
nursing home in Culver City.
Like a responsible person,
she never missed a day of work.
She gave blood every month,
took her son to school...
...and I wanna understand
why she was killed!
What?
She gave blood?
Yes, McCaleb. She's the same
blood type as you are.
AB with a CMV negative.
The hospital would have paid her,
but she wouldn't accept money.
- That's the connection!
- What are you talking about?
That's the link between Cordell
and your sister. Blood.
Wait a minute. Blood?
I'll cover tomorrow's shift.
Yeah, thanks.
- Don't you ever use a cell phone?
- I don't believe in them.
I always stay with a hard line.
Mrs. Cordell wasn't home.
Is there another way to find out?
If he gave blood often,
he'd be on the computer.
- Which computer?
- The BOPRA computer.
For rare blood types.
There's one at L.A. Memorial.
- All right. I'm coming with you.
- Get somebody to stay with the kid.
What do you think?
What do you mean, babysitting?
- Yeah.
- Fuck me.
How much?
I don't know. Beer.
A case of beer an hour.
You got it.
Hey, doc.
Terry. What's wrong?
Nothing. Is there a place
we could talk privately?
I need to talk to you.
You have five minutes.
Who's this?
Graciella Rivers,
the one I told you about.
She's the one who put you up to this.
Look at him. Look at his color.
Look at the lines under his eyes.
A week ago, he was perfect.
- I am sorry.
- It was my choice.
Shut up! Sit down.
Open your mouth.
Lift your shirt up.
- What do you want?
- We wanted to know...
- Keep that thermometer in your mouth.
- My sister was murdered.
So was another man.
It was the same killer.
McCaleb found a link between
my sister and this other man.
- They both gave blood.
- What?
She was the same blood type
as McCaleb, AB with CMV negative.
McCaleb says that's 1 in 200.
101.1. Shit.
What do you want?
I want you to access
the BOPRA computer.
If Cordell's on it,
I wanna know his blood type.
That's unethical.
You've gotta help. If I'm right,
the killer already has access.
I don't know...
If you can't protect the integrity
of the system, there's no system.
All right.
I'll do it on one condition.
What's that?
Let me run blood work on you.
- That will take all day!
- Yes or no?
- Yes.
- Sit down.
I'll get the nurse.
Very still now.
We're almost done.
I want you to stop, McCaleb.
Stop what?
Everything.
I was wrong to bring this to you.
No.
Yeah.
Glory gave another person life.
- That's really all I need to know.
- No.
Look, I got a new heart, but...
...I didn't necessarily
get a new life.
I don't know what you mean.
I lost a little something...
...but knowing you and
working with you on this...
...I feel a little bit coming back.
Okay.
It's a list of the local AB CMV
negatives. Cordell's on it.
Same blood type as Torres.
What's the D stand for? Deceased?
No, donor. Organ donor.
They were both organ donors.
Both organ donors?
Cordell died on the scene,
and Gloria lived just long enough.
- That's crazy.
- What are you saying?
I missed it, damn it.
I didn't think Gloria had anything
anyone wanted, but I missed it.
What did you miss?
Her blood.
It made her unique.
It made what was inside her
very valuable. To someone.
Someone like me. Anyone who could
benefit would be a suspect.
Wait a minute. You're saying that
she was murdered for her organs.
The autopsy report had both
bullets going through the frontal lobe.
That could leave them brain dead,
but not die right away.
Of course, Cordell... 911 screwed up,
but your sister had the Good Samaritan.
Who?
That's the customer who came in,
bandaged her head and called 911.
- You can't get back until...
- Can I use your phone?
Get a list of where all
the organs went, will you?
Detective Jaye Winston?
Graciella Rivers. He's inside talking
about surveillance and numbers.
This is Arrango from
West Valley Homicide.
Badge 141 10. I'd like a 10-20
for a surveillance commencement.
That's 17:14:39.
Thank you. 17:14:39.
I'm out of my jurisdiction,
and you're way out. What's up?
The surveillance camera's three
seconds behind the CCW clock.
- That's the one 911 uses.
- Okay, so?
So did you bring the tape?
This is the 911 operator.
The girl is shot very bad!
She needs help!
Who was shot, sir?
The girl is shot!
Kang's Market, Sherman Way!
Sir, please stay on the line.
That's 10:40:58.
All right. At 22:41:37...
...Gloria is shot.
Jump down to...
...22:42:55, and here comes
Good Samaritan.
That son of a bitch.
What? What is it?
This guy here...
...this unidentified Good Samaritan,
who tried to help Gloria.
There's just one problem.
What's that?
The clock on the surveillance camera
is three seconds behind the 911 clock.
All right, and...?
We think he made the call
before he killed her.
No.
No, that doesn't make any sense,
because the numbers...
The caller.
It's the same guy.
He called an ambulance
before he shot her.
Yeah.
See, Cordell, his organs
were no good.
This time, the shooter would make
sure the ambulance got a good lead.
So he shot Gloria, then
he comes back with bandages...
...and tries to keep her alive.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
Could this Good Samaritan be the same
guy you saw at the ATM machine?
I don't know.
Put a wig on him, maybe.
A little dark makeup, he's Hispanic.
You got those ATM tapes?
No. You only told me
to bring this one.
Yeah, well...
The ATM thing. The shooter probably
had them on the way anyway.
They went to the wrong address,
so it doesn't matter.
What do you think about
Lockridge for this?
I don't know, maybe.
Whoever got the list of organ donors
had to hack into the BOPRA computer.
Lockridge is a computer man, right?
And he lives and works in
my jurisdiction. Let's go.
I have to go with you.
No, get back to Raymond.
Take my car. I'll go with Jaye.
Why don't you pop the trunk?
I'll put this stuff in the back.
What the fuck is he doing?
McCaleb! What are you doing?!
You're killing me here.
What's going on?
- You okay?
- Yeah. You okay?
- Yeah.
- Let's go find Lockridge at work.
What do you mean?
We just shot up the Valley.
Did you hit anyone?
- No, thank God.
- Neither did I. Let's go.
Fuck.
Mr. Lockridge didn't
come to work today.
- Is he ill?
- He hasn't called...
...and he didn't come
in yesterday either.
Come here and look at this.
Doesn't that look like
probable cause to you?
Let's go.
See if I remember how they did this.
Shit.
Her throat's been slit.
She's been here a good 24 hours.
You okay?
Yeah.
We got an APB out on Lockridge.
I might get suspended,
but you did real good, McCaleb.
Real good.
I hope so.
I guess I'd better get home
and get my pills.
Want some coffee?
No, go home. Get your pills.
You still got company.
How much beer do I owe you?
Seven cases...
...but since he's a good kid
and a great fisherman, I'll take two.
I'll get you the check in the morning.
That's what they all say.
Good night, Terry.
- Hey.
- Hey, Mr. McCaleb.
Howdy.
- Hey.
- How are you?
Me and Buddy caught so many fish
he had to get more bait.
- I caught six all by myself.
- Really? It must be a harbor record.
It's "Buddy and I."
Finish your homework, Ray.
So?
I'm not sure yet,
but it's looking good.
Okay. When will you know?
Soon, hopefully.
Thank you.
For everything you've done.
I'm impressed.
That's my dad.
He used to take Glory and me fishing.
A lot.
When we were kids.
You know, they're all gone.
But I'm glad I can still smile
about her, you know?
I couldn't at first.
This is a cool gun, Mr. McCaleb.
- Raymond...
- It's all over. Don't, no.
You never, never touch a gun.
See? You can look at it.
This is an eight-shot
Smith & Wesson.
We don't touch it.
I shouldn't have left it out.
You never play with this,
so stay right there. Understand?
What's this?
Oh, that's some code I was supposed
to break, but I never could do it.
- There's no one.
- What?
There's no 1.
"9-0-3-4-7-2-5-6-8."
It's all the numbers, but no 1.
How about that? No 1 s.
Little man, come on.
We have to go. It's getting late.
- Can I stay?
- No.
- We gotta go. It's getting late.
- I don't want to.
We have to. Okay?
Were you just going to let me
sit here and eat alone?
Raymond loves this boat, and he was
wondering if he could spend the night.
Yeah, there's a berth in front
you can both share.
You don't have to hide it.
Show me your heart.
Show me.
- Somebody's up on deck.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know. Somebody's up there.
- Raymond.
No, too heavy for him.
- You son of a bitch!
- What the hell is going on here?
Jesus Christ! We came because the
captain wants you at the crime scene.
When this is over...
...you better get an ass transplant
because I'll tear you a new one!
Damn, it's cold.
Out of the way, please.
There's McCaleb. Mr. McCaleb,
did you think this was over?
I can't comment, I don't know
anything about anything.
- Oh, no.
- What?
This is where I had my attack.
Lockridge.
James Lockridge, the guy who
found Cordell at the ATM machine.
Looks like your Code Killer's back.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Way to make a comeback.
Some people get flowers,
some people get chocolates.
You get a dead guy.
- Hey!
- What's going on?
It's all right.
Paper said something you didn't like?
Ballistics will match this slug
with the one in Bolotov's mouth.
It was the Code Killer.
Torres, Cordell, Bolotov, all of them.
What does that mean?
I shot him two years ago. The slug in
Bolotov's mouth is the one that hit him.
Now I'm back...
...and so is he.
Every second we're talking, you could
be trying to get this son of a bitch.
We got a lot of good
people out there.
You're right.
Better chance of breaking
this with you in here.
- Fuck you, Bureau man!
- Enough of that, detective.
Yes, sir.
This Code Killer likes to impress you.
Any idea why?
I had a media profile, so did he.
I guess he missed the matchup, me
and him on the news every night.
I thought once these guys started,
they didn't stop.
But your Codie's been
down for two years.
What do you make of that?
I don't know. I shot him. I always
figured he crawled off and died.
- What do the numbers mean?
- Don't know that either.
We ran it by the computers at Cal,
by the code breakers at the NSA.
Nobody comes up with anything.
Except...
Except what?
There's no digit number one.
No 1, whatever that might mean.
Guys, step out. Give us a minute.
Okay.
Just cop to cop, what's going on here?
Cordell, Gloria Torres...
He did them for me.
Keep talking until I understand.
He missed the action. Me and him.
In order to get it back,
I needed a new heart, so...
...Happy Valentine's Day.
Holy shit.
Now the love letters are gonna start,
hot and heavy.
You might have the captain fooled,
but not me.
You got Torres' heart.
That makes you suspect number one.
What a waste of a good
Mexican's heart!
Get out of here.
Graciella?
Raymond?
Hey, Ter!
Welcome to Davy Jones' locker.
Have you seen Graciella and Raymond?
They got tired of waiting for you.
They left about an hour ago.
You're all over the news, brother!
How long we been neighbors?
I don't know. I moved into the marina
about a week after you.
- Raise up your shirt.
- What?
Raise it up.
Now.
Come on, turn around.
I'm the following sea, man.
I'm the one you need to watch out for.
When did you figure it out?
On the check.
"No one."
I had a little trouble
with the Jasper part.
I could've killed you if I wanted to.
I was behind you at the ATM.
I followed you to Kang's Market,
just like I followed Gloria Torres.
You sick son of a bitch.
I studied her. I chose her.
She was my valentine to you.
I gave you life.
What else you wanna know?
That necklace belonged to a girl
named Sunny. Lockridge's wife.
There's a story for every piece
of crap on that tray.
Come on, man.
You're mine forever.
Every breath you take belongs to me.
Every beat of that stolen heart is
the echo of my voice in your head.
Every day.
Always.
It depends on you. Pull that trigger,
you'll never see them again.
- What?
- Kill me, no one will find them.
They will die. Alone.
In a black hole.
And that will be on you.
You know me. You know I have them.
- What do you want?
- I want you to live.
I want me to live.
I want it all to start again, you know,
the battle between good and evil.
Can't you see I've been getting you
back to where you need to be?
I'm not interested.
Bullshit. That day in the car,
what did you say you felt?
What was the word?
You felt "connected." Shit.
I almost came when you said that.
Because that's us, Terry.
That's you and me.
It's us. We were meant to be.
We're Cain and Abel.
Kennedy and Oswald.
We are shit in the bottom
of somebody's shoe.
I have to leave now.
And you're not gonna follow me.
You're not gonna scrape me off.
You'll sit by that pay phone and wait
for me to call you from time to time...
...and when I'm relocated and ready,
I'll let Graciella and Raymond go.
Then you and me, we can start again.
I hope you think of me
as often as I think of you.
God. Crazy!
Call an ambulance!
You're gonna take me to them.
Keep that tight. That will pinch the
artery, and you won't bleed to death.
- Now, show me.
- Okay.
What's it like having a chick's heart?
You start watching soaps?
Get cranky at the end of the month?
Hear some love song on the radio,
you start crying?
Plus it's a spic heart.
She was a wetback.
You wake up going, "Arriba! Gotta get
me some enchiladas for the cholita."
Shut up!
When they were girls going
to Sunday school...
...do you think Gloria Torres
ever thought that her heart...
...would be pumping blood through some
guy that was banging her sister?
You don't look so good, Ter.
You don't look so good
yourself there, Buddy.
Ran aground in that storm
last year. Remember?
Salvage company's gonna demo
it next week.
Till then, it's a perfect prison.
Better than Alcatraz.
My little shop of horrors.
Just so you know...
...I would never hurt that little boy.
See, he's the same blood type.
He's the backup.
In case anything happens
to his mom's heart.
Come on.
Do you think you have a chance?
With Graciella?
You think she can love you?
After her sister died for you?
That's tough for her to get around.
Let's go. Let's get going.
You can put the belt in your teeth.
Follow me.
In there.
The key.
- Hey.
Come on.
I knew you'd find us, Terry.
He may be on the boat, but I'm not
sure if he's dead or alive. Let's go.
Did your father teach
you to run a boat?
- Yeah.
- My boat's at the end of this gangway.
Wait a few minutes,
then go on down there.
Use this knife to cut the lines.
Back off about 100 yards or more
and wait till I call you.
- All right?
- Yeah.
If I don't call you in a half-hour,
get the hell out of here.
Okay. Get going.
Let's go. Come on, honey.
I'm sad, Terry!
Get inside. Hurry up.
Get down below, Raymond!
Come on, man.
We're connected.
Think of what you're doing.
You need me.
No, Buddy.
Remember how you said I was your
friend and I could tell you the truth?
Well, I don't need you at all.
Ten ring.
I saved you.
- Right next to you the whole time.
- Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Never felt better.
You got his ass.
Yeah, there's "no one" anymore.
Give me a day to catch my breath,
I'll write you a full report.
I want to see it.
Two of them okay?
Yeah, if everyone will
leave them alone...
...not get them any more involved.
- I'll see what I can do about that.
- That's a pal.
How are you planning
to deal with all this?
Well, I've got Gloria Torres' heart.
I'll probably just let that guide me.
- You got anyone, Jaye?
- Excuse me?
Police work can get
kind of heavy on you.
You got anyone at home?
Yeah, I got someone.
Good.
McCaleb!
That's it! I'm sick and tired of your
grandstanding bullshit!
- You're out of your jurisdiction.
- Maybe.
But just because you got a Mexican's
heart, it don't make you one of us!
Arrango?
Next time you come around this dock,
this Mexican will kick your ass.
What? You're out of your
goddamn mind!
All my life, I've had the shitty jobs.
You got him talking to himself.
I didn't even know he spoke Spanish.
Poor baby, he's been
at this all morning.
I wish I could get a big, fat marlin
and put it on his line.
[ENGLISH]