- So long. We'll see you again.
- Goodbye.
Give me your money. Do it.
- Splendid.
- Thank you.
Blue 439.
- Blue 439. Over.
- Blue 439, go ahead, please. Over.
Phone Weston 0-219.
Tell him I'm on my way, will you?
Roger Wilco. Stand by.
- Hello, love.
- Hello.
- Get that stuff developed, will you?
- Yeah.
Right away.
Here I am.
Ready?
- I've been ready for nearly an hour.
- Good.
I'm catching a plane for Paris
at 11, so I can't...
Can't what?
It doesn't matter.
Who the hell were you with last night?
Reg.
Reg, leùs have some noise, can we?
Right.
Thaùs good. Thaùs good.
Hold that.
Reg.
Give it to me now.
Come on. Thaùs good.
Hunch. Hunch more.
Thaùs it. Thaùs good.
Thaùs good. And the hair back.
And the hair back.
Thaùs great. Thaùs great!
Thaùs good. More of that.
Now give it to me. Really give it to me.
Come on, now.
As fast as you can, give it to me.
Come on, right forward.
Thaùs good. This side. This side.
Lean right forward. Hand up.
Thaùs great. Just touch the face.
Thaùs very good.
And again around this way.
Touch the face again.
Good. Now the hair.
Marvelous. Thaùs great.
Good. Yes, the hair.
Much more. Much more.
Good. Yes, thaùs great.
Thaùs good. Yes. And again. And again.
Oh, hold that.
Hold the hair back. Again. Good.
Okay, Reg, 50.
On your back. On your back. Go on.
Yes. Now really give it to me. Come on.
Come on. Work, work, work!
Great. Great. And again.
Go on. Back. Back. Arms up.
Stretch yourself, little lady. Great.
And again. Go on. Go. Go.
Thaùs great.
Thaùs it. Keep it up. Lovely.
Yeah, make it come. Great.
No, no, head up. Head up.
Now for me, love. For me.
Now! Now! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Hello?
Yeah, hold on.
Iùs Peter.
Hello?
Yes.
Yeah, I've got it somewhere.
I know I have.
Yeah, hold on.
Reg, take down the address
of that bloody junk shop, would you?
Why, they're fabulous. Go on.
Yeah.
Yeah. Great.
Here. You can burn that lot.
Reg!
- Get the birds down, will you?
- Okay.
No chewing gum. Get rid of it.
And not on my floor.
You, arm down.
Right.
Six millimeter.
Terrible.
How about the leg
a little further forward?
Put the head up.
Just go. Mouth open. Yes, good. Good.
No, you're all wrong. Start again.
Rethink it. Rethink it.
Stripes, let the dress just fall down.
Keep the stripes straight.
Just let your arms
go up and down.
Yes, very tasty. Yes, I like it.
I like it. Go on.
Yeah.
All right, change position.
Yep.
Wake up!
You can thank your lucky stars
you're working with me, can't you?
All right, one more.
And leùs smile now. Come on.
Smile.
God.
I asked you to smile.
Whaùs the matter?
Have you forgotten what a smile is?
Hey?!
All right, you're all tired now.
Go on, relax.
I can't see your eyeballs anymore.
They're just slits.
Go on.
Close your eyes.
And stay like that.
Iùs good for you.
Close your eyes.
That must be five or six years old.
They don't mean anything
when I do them. Just a mess.
Afterwards, I find something
to hang on to, like that...
Quite like that leg.
Then it sorts itself out and adds up.
Iùs like finding a clue
in a detective story.
Don't ask me about this one.
I don't know yet.
- Can I buy it?
- No.
Will you give it to me?
There.
Tight-faced bastard.
He won't float me
one of his crappy paintings.
I'll creep down one night
and knock it off.
Don't stop, iùs lovely.
You look tired.
I've been all night in a doss house.
They say they've been
asked to come here.
- Not by me.
- Well, we weren't exactly asked.
Sorry, I'm busy.
They're printing some snaps
for me upstairs. Go and fetch them.
Couldn't you give us
just a couple of minutes?
A couple of minutes?
I haven't even got a couple of minutes
to have my appendix out.
- Well, when can we come then?
- Don't.
- The others still waiting with their eyes shut?
- Yes, they're waiting, but their eyes are open.
Good.
Tell them to shut them again.
Get rid of that bag. Iùs diabolical.
Can we come back this afternoon?
- What do you want?
- Just looking around.
There are no cheap bargains here.
You're wasting your time.
Well, I'll just have a look.
What are you looking for?
- Pictures.
- No pictures.
What kind of pictures?
- Landscapes.
- Sorry, no landscapes.
Sold. All sold.
- You the owner?
- No, the owner is out.
Expecting him?
What are you doing?
Stop it! Stop it!
Give me those. You can't
photograph people like that.
Who says I can't?
I'm only doing my job.
Some people are bullfighters...
...some people are politicians.
I'm a photographer.
This is a public place. Everyone has
the right to be left in peace.
Iùs not my fault if there's no peace.
You know, most girls would pay me
to photograph them.
I'll pay you.
I overcharge.
There are other things
I want on the reel.
What do we do then?
I send you the photographs.
No, I want them now.
No!
Whaùs the rush?
Don't leùs spoil everything.
We've only just met.
No, we haven't met.
You've never seen me.
- Hello.
- My agent saw you about this shop.
- Did he?
He's a man with a cigar.
Throws ash everywhere.
I expect I remember him.
I probably asked
for too much money.
Money's always a problem, isn't it?
Tell him to come back.
Why are you selling?
I'd like to try something different.
Get off somewhere.
I'm fed up with antiques.
Get off where?
To Nepal.
Nepal is all antiques.
Is it?
Perhaps I better try Morocco.
- How much?
- What?
The propeller.
You can have it for...
...8 pounds.
- Right. You're in business.
- Have you got a van?
- You can't take it now.
I must.
- I can't live without it.
- Hard luck.
Thaùll teach you to fall in love
with heavy things on Saturday mornings.
- Is that it?
- Thaùs it.
You can't treat it like that.
Iùs not a delivery van.
- Who cares?
- Leave it to me.
Something will turn up.
Yes. All right, but it
better turn up today.
Blue 439. Blue 439. Over.
439, go ahead, please. Over.
Hello, this is...
Get me Flaxton 2-249.
Mr. Walker. Mr. Peter Walker.
Tell him I saw the junk shop.
Iùs pricey, but the kid will come down.
Let him ring her right away, then...
...nobody else will get it.
Roger Wilco. Stand by.
Blue 439. Blue 439. Over.
Blue 439. Blue 439. Go ahead, echo.
Blue 439, message passed. The number
stored. Your caller doesn't like it.
Tell him to get stuffed.
What about all the buildings
going up around the place?
Already there are queers
and poodles in the area.
I saw some in the couple
of minutes I was there.
- Iùll go like a bomb. Over.
- Blue 439. What is in the area? Over.
- Forget it. Over.
- Roger Wilco. Standing by.
You want to use the lot?
Don't you like them?
They're great.
We'll use three or four.
Spread through the book?
No. All together.
Yeah.
- And a pint.
- Yes, sir.
Which one last?
None of this lot.
I've got something fab for the end.
In a park. I only took them this morning.
You'll get them later today.
Iùs very peaceful, very still.
And the rest of the book will be pretty
violent, so iùs best to end it like that.
Yes.
Thaùs best.
Rings truer.
I'm going off London this week.
Why?
It doesn't do anything for me.
Yeah.
- I've knocked up a few captions.
- Yeah?
I'm fed up with those bloody bitches.
I wish I had tons of money.
Then I'd be free.
Free to do what?
Free like him?
Someone we know?
Thaùll be all right.
Hello. Could you get me Frobershire 3-229,
please? I've only got a sixpence.
Park 1296.
Hello. Iùs me.
Weren't you supposed to be
going off to Hurley?
Listen, stay where you are.
Call me soon at home.
I've come...
I've come for the photographs.
How did you manage to find me?
Do you live here?
Drink?
Whaùs so important
about my bloody pictures?
Thaùs my business.
The light was very beautiful
in the park this morning.
Those shots should be very good.
Anyway, I need them.
My private life's already in a mess.
It would be a disaster if...
So what?
Nothing like a little disaster
for sorting things out.
Have you ever done any modeling?
Fashion stuff, I mean.
You've got it.
Hold that.
Not many girls can stand
as well as that.
No, thanks. I'm in a hurry.
You'll get your pictures.
I promise.
I always keep my word.
Come here.
Show me how you sit.
Who is it?
Oh, yes. Thaùs right. Hold on a second.
Is it for me?
Iùs my wife.
Why should I speak to her?
Sorry, love.
The bird I'm with won't talk to you.
She isn't my wife, really.