Hey, boy!
What are you doing with my mama's car?
Wait there!
Ain't you ashamed?
Trying to steal an old lady's automobile?
What are you talking about?
I've been thinking about buying me one.
Bull!
You ain't got money for dinner,
let alone buying a car.
Well, ma'am, I'll tell you something.
I've got enough money for a Coca-Cola...
...and since it don't look like
you're going to invite me inside....
You'd steal the dining room table if I did.
You want to go into town with me?
How would that be?
I'm going to work, anyway.
You're going to work, huh?
What kind of work do you do?
None of your business.
I'll bet you're a movie star.
Huh? A lady mechanic?
A maid?
What do you think I am?
A waitress.
What line of work are you in...
when you're not stealing cars?
Well, I'm looking for suitable
employment right at the moment.
Oh, yeah, but what did you do before?
I was in State Prison.
State Prison?
Well, I guess some little old lady
wasn't so nice.
It was armed robbery.
The things that turn up
in the street these days.
Hey, what do you all do for a good time
around here? Listen to the grass grow?
I guess you had a lot more fun
up at State Prison.
- I'll tell you. See my right foot?
- Yeah?
I chopped two toes off that foot
with an axe.
What! Why?
- To get off of work detail. Want to see it?
- No!
I surely don't intend to stand
here in the middle of Main Street...
...and look at your dirty feet!
Boy, did you really do that?
What's it like?
What do you mean, prison?
Armed robbery.
It ain't like anything.
Shoot. I knew you never robbed any place,
you faker.
Bet you wouldn't have
the gumption to use it.
You just wait right here and
you keep your eyes open.
Hey, what's your name?
Clyde Barrow.
Hi, I'm Bonnie Parker.
Uh, pleased to meet you.
Hey, hey, hey, slow down,
slow down, slow down.
Take it easy, you've got my hand trapped.
Cut it out! Cut it out!
All right, now.
I might as well tell you right off.
I ain't much of a lover boy.
That don't mean nothing
personal about you.
I never saw no percentage in it.
Ain't nothing wrong with me.
I don't like boys.
Boy! Boy! Boy!
"Boy," what?
Your advertising is just dandy.
Folks would never guess
you don't have a thing to sell.
You'd better take me home now.
- Now, wait a minute.
- Now don't you touch me.
All right, all right...
...if all you want is a stud service,
you get on back to West Dallas,
...and you stay there, the rest of your life.
You're worth a lot more...
...and you know it, and that's why
you're comin' along with me.
You could find a lover boy on
every damn corner in town.
Don't matter to them
if you're waiting tables or picking cotton...
...but it does make a damn to me!
Why?
"Why?" What do you mean, "why?"
Because you're different, that's why.
You know, you're like me.
You want different things.
You've got something
better than being a waitress.
You and me traveling together, we could
cut a path clean across this state...
...and Kansas and Missouri and Oklahoma,
and everybody would know about it.
You listen to me, Miss Bonnie Parker.
You listen to me.
How'd you like to go
walking into the dining room...
...of the Adolphus Hotel in Dallas...
...wearing a nice silk dress and
have everybody waiting on you?
Would you like that?
That seem like a lot to ask?
That ain't enough for you.
You've got a right to that.
When did you figure all that up?
The minute I saw you.
Why?
Because you may be the
best damn girl in Texas.
You were born somewhere
around east Texas, right?
Come from a big old family.
You went to school,
but you didn't take to it much...
...because you were a lot
smarter than everybody else...
...so you just up and quit one day.
Now, when you were 16... 17,
there was a guy who worked in a....
Cement plant.
Right. And you liked him...
...because he thought you were
just as nice as you could be.
You almost married that guy, but then you
thought no, you didn't think you would.
So then you got your job in a cafe.
And now you wake up every morning
and you hate it.
You just hate it. You get on down there
and you put on your white uniform....
It's pink.
Those truck drivers come there
to eat your greasy burgers and...
...they kid you and you kid them back
but they're stupid and dumb boys...
...with their big old tattoos,
and you don't like it.
They ask you for dates and sometimes
you go, but you mostly don't because...
...all they're trying to do is get in your
pants, whether you want them to or not.
So you go on home and you
sit in your room and...
...you think: "Now when, and how...
"... am I ever going to get away from this?"
And now you know.
Change that. I don't like it.
You're a knock-out!
- Hey, that ain't ours.
- Sure it is.
No, but we came in this one.
That don't mean we have to go home in it.
Where have you been keeping yourself?
I slept out by the car.
These accommodations ain't
particularly deluxe.
If they're after us, I want the first shot.
Now, you come on out here.
We got some work to do.
You're good!
I ain't good. I'm the best.
And modest.
Now see that?
Set her spinning.
It's all right, all right.
Come on, try it again.
Try it again, now this time
come down slow, slow.
Now, how about that?
Now, ain't you something? I tell you.
I'm going to get you a Smith & Wesson.
Go in your hand easier.
- I want you to try something now.
- Hey, you!
No, sir! No, sir!
Y'all go right ahead.
It used to be my place.
But it's not anymore.
Bank took it.
Yes, sir, they moved us off.
Now it belongs to them.
Why, that's a pitiful shame.
You're damn right, ma'am.
Me and him put in the years here.
Y'all go right ahead.
We just came by for a last look.
Y'all mind?
Hey, Davis! Come on over here!
That's right.
Go on.
Much obliged.
My name is Otis Harris. This is Davis.
We worked this place.
How're you?
This here's Miss Bonnie Parker.
- Glad to meet you.
- I'm Clyde Barrow.
We rob banks.
Look, I don't want you
to worry about nothing.
This is going to be
the easiest thing in the world.
Your mama could take this bank.
You just be ready if I need you.
What are you waiting for?
This is a stick-up! Just take it easy
and nothing's going to happen to you.
Give me the money.
What money, mister?
There ain't no money here.
What are you talking about?
This here's a bank, ain't it?
Well, it was a bank,
but we failed three weeks ago.
All right, now, you get on out here.
You get on out there and tell my girl.
Come on, come on,
you tell her what you told me.
We've got $1.98, and you're laughing!
Let's see now.
A loaf of bread, a dozen eggs...
...quart of milk, four fried pies.
Come on now, you sure
you ain't got no peach pies?
Get the hell out of here!
Go ahead! Go ahead!
He tried to kill me. Why'd he try
to kill me. I didn't want to hurt him.
Try to get something to eat...
...and some son of a bitch
comes up on you with a meat-cleaver.
I ain't against him.
Now, you just tell me
what was wrong with that, boy.
Dirt.
Dirt?
Dirt in the fuel line. Just blowed it away.
Excuse me, ma'am,
is there anything else I could do for you?
Well, you're a smart feller.
You sure do know a lot about automobiles,
don't you?
Yes. I guess I do.
Would you know what kind of car this is?
This is a four cylinder Ford Coupe.
Huh? Sure, sure is.
This is a stolen, four cylinder Ford Coupe.
Hey, you ain't scared, are you? Huh?
I believe he is.
That's a pity. We sure could've
used a smart boy like that...
...who knows such a great
deal about automobiles.
Are you a good driver, boy?
Yeah, reckon I am.
No, he's better off here.
What's your name, boy?
C.W. Moss.
Well, I'm Miss Bonnie Parker
and this here is Mr. Clyde Barrow.
We rob banks.
There ain't nothing wrong with that,
is there?
Clyde, he ain't the one. Let's go.
You think you got the guts
for our line of work?
What are you talking about?
I spent a year, a year in reformatory.
A man with a record!
I know you got the nerve to short change
old ladies coming in for gas.
What I'm asking you is have you got
what it takes to pull bank jobs with us?
Sure, I do. I ain't afraid,
if that's what you think.
Prove it.
You're gonna be all right.
I'm afraid we're overdrawn again.
This is a stick-up!
This here's a stick-up!
Leave it there. Leave it there.
Come on, come on, everything.
Get it up here.
Clyde, where's the car?
What the hell you doing, parking the car?
Stop that car!
Up ahead, cut left! Left!
"We"re in the money, the sky is sunny
"Old man depression, you are through,
you done us wrong
"We never see a headline,
about a bread line, today
"And when we see the landlord,
we can look that guy right in the eye
"Oh, we"re in the money,
come on, my honey"
You ain't got a brain in your skull.
On account of you, I killed a man.
And now we're all going to be wanted
for murder, and that's you too, boy.
Dumb head! Stupid!
What were you thinking about?
Do a dumb-ass thing like that again,
boy, I'm going to kill you.
If you boys want to talk,
why don't y'all go outside?
Honey, come on, I want to talk to you
for just a minute. Sit down.
This afternoon we killed
a man and we were seen.
Now, so far, nobody knows who you are...
...but they know who I am and they'll be
after me and anybody who's with me.
And that's murder.
Now it's going to get rough.
I can't get out, but right now you still can.
I want you to say the word to me...
...and I'll put you on that bus
back to your mama...
...because you mean a lot to me,
and I ain't going to make you run with me.
No!
I ain't a rich man.
You could get a rich man if you tried.
I don't want no rich man!
You ain't going to have a minute's peace.
You promise?
Huh, at least I'm not a liar.
I told you I wasn't no lover boy.
Now, let me look at you boy.
Oh boy, you can do better than that.
Hey, hey, hey, how's Mama?
Oh, fine, fine.
Sister, Sister sent her best to you.
Filling out. Must be that prison food.
No, no, no, it's married life...
...and, you know what they say, it's...
...it's the face powder
that gives a man interest, but...
...but it's the baking powder
that keeps him home.
I want you to meet my wife, Blanche.
This is my baby brother.
How're you doing?
It's really nice to know you.
How do you do?
I hear you're taking real good care
of the baby of the family....
I'm just so glad to meet you.
Come on over here.
I want you to meet my wife, Blanche.
Hey, everybody, this is C.W. Moss.
My brother, Buck, and his wife, Blanche.
Howdy, everybody. Howdy, you all.
Howdy, Mrs. Barrow,
or may I call you Blanche?
I sure am pleased to meet you.
How did you find us here
in this neck of the woods?
Boy, you sure picked a good day for it.
Oh, is that a new Screenland Magazine?
Any new pictures of Myrna Loy in there?
She's my favorite picture star. May I?
Hey, let me get the Kodak here.
We'll take some pictures.
Put your pants on.
We're going to take some pictures.
Come on Blanche, get out of there!
I'm a mess. Been driving all day, honey.
Did you take my picture, Buck? I declare
I asked you not to take my picture.
Hey, Buck, get one of this.
Hey, Brother, I want to talk to you later on.
You got that?
You take one of me and my missus,
here, Clyde.
Honestly, I don't want a picture taken.
Be serious. Be serious.
Hey, let me take one of Bonnie alone.
Come on, honey.
Hey, honey, a little smile.
Don't want to smile, eh?
I want to have a chat with you.
C.W., take the girls' pictures.
Why don't you step in there with Bonnie?
What did you think of her?
She's a peach.
Now, now tell me true.
Is she as good as she looks?
She's better.
Hey, listen, it was,
it was either you or him, wasn't it?
The guy that you killed, you had to do it.
Was either you or him.
He put me on the spot. I had to.
You had to do it, right?
I know you did.
Don't say anything to Blanche about that.
That time you broke out of jail,
is it true she talked you into going back?
Yeah. You hear about that? Huh.
Well, I won't say nothing
to Bonnie about it.
I appreciate that.
We're going to have ourselves a time, boy!
We surely are.
What are we going to do?
I figured we all drive up to Missouri.
They ain't looking for me up there.
We find a nice little place to hole up in.
We have us a regular vacation.
No trouble now.
I ain't looking to go back to no prison.
I heard in prison that you had
a little trouble there.
You were cutting on your toes.
You heard about that, eh?
I did a little toe cutting.
That ain't but half of it.
I did it so I'd get off of work detail.
You know, breaking those damn rocks
with a sledge hammer night and day.
And you know what?
The very next week I got paroled.
I walked out of that
God-forsaken jail on crutches.
Ain't life grand?
Hey, you want to hear a story,
about this boy, he owned a dairy farm....
And his old ma, she was kind of sick,
you know.
And the doctor,
he called him over and said...
"... Listen, your ma, just lying there,
she's just so sick and she's weakly...
"... I want you to try to persuade her
to take a little brandy, see.
"Just to pick her spirits up, you know."
"Ma's a teetotaler," he says,
"she wouldn't touch a drop."
"Well, I'll tell you what you do."
That's the doc.
"Now, I tell you what you do...
"... you bring in a fresh quart
of milk every day...
"... and you put some brandy in it, see.
And you try that."
So he did, and he doctored it all up
with the brandy, fresh milk...
...and gave it to his mama,
and she drank a little bit of it.
So next day he brought it in again,
and she drank a little more, you know.
And so then, it went on that way,
the third day just a little more...
...and the fourth day she took
a little bit more.
And then finally, a week later,
he gave her the milk...
...and she just drank it down,
she swallowed the whole thing.
And she called him over and said...
"... Son, whatever you do,
don't sell that cow."
All right, you got the keys now,
haven't you?
I gave him a month's rent in advance.
We're all set. Let's get inside.
Honey, lamb, I'm taking you
to our first home.
"Here comes the bride"
What do you think, honey? Huh?
Just perfect.
This is your first home.
He gave me the grocery number.
4-3-3-7, please.
Hi there, Speedie's Groceries?
I want to order up a mess of groceries.
And a Frigidaire, not an ice-box.
Eight pounds of pork chops,
four pounds of red beans.
About eight bottles of Dr. Pepper.
You sure can play checkers.
You need a haircut.
You're looking just like a hillbilly boy.
You are just like an old man.
Playing checkers all the time,
don't pay any attention to your wife.
Boy, you ain't going to ever beat me,
but you just keep trying, you hear?
Oh, Daddy, you sure do need a haircut.
Why, you look like a little old hillbilly,
I do declare.
Oh, mercy me, don't.
Don't talk that way when she's
right there in the next room.
There's always somebody in
the next room, in this room...
...or in every other kind of room.
Don't you ever just want
to be alone with me?
Well, I always feel like we're alone.
Do you, baby?
I'm hungry.
Groceries, ma'am.
- How much?
- Six dollars and 43 cents.
Let me help you, those bags are heavy.
No thanks, I'll get them.
Uh, just get the door.
"But few of them really are justified...
"... if you get right down to the point.
"You've heard of a woman's glory
being spent on a downright cur."
Did you write all that yourself?
Do you want to hear this or not?
"Still you can't always
judge the story as true...
"... being told by her.
"Now Sal was a gal of rare beauty...
"... though her features
were coarse and tough... "
I knew that old gal.
She was cock-eyed
and she had a hare lip and no teeth.
"Now Sal was a gal of rare beauty...
"... though her features
were coarse and tough.
"She never once faltered from duty,
to play on the up and up.
"Sal told me this tale on the evening...
"... before she was turned out free.
"And I'll do my best to relate it,
just as she told it to me... "
Hey, hey! The laws are outside!
They're blocking the driveway.
- Please get us out of here.
- Shut up!
They got us blocked.
We've got to get the car out.
Where's Blanche? Where's Blanche?
Damn it, you almost got us killed!
What did I do wrong?
I thought you'd be happy if I got shot!
Yeah! Yeah, it would have saved us all
a lot of trouble!
Buck, don't let that woman
talk to me like that!
You shouldn't have done that, Blanche.
It was a dumb thing to do.
Oh Buck, please, I didn't marry you
to see you get shot, honey.
Let's leave. Let's get out of here and leave.
Tell him to please stop the car
and let us out.
I killed a guy. Now we're in this.
Will you shut up!
Just shut up your big mouth!
At least do that, just shut up!
Cut it out, Bonnie!
Stop the car. I want to talk to you.
Get, get rid of her.
I can't get, she's Buck's wife.
Then, get rid of them both.
Why? What's the matter with you?
She is what's the matter with me.
She, she's nothing but a dumb,
stupid, back-country hick.
She ain't got a brain in her head.
What makes you any better?
What makes you so damn special?
You were just a West Dallas waitress.
Spent your time picking up truck drivers.
Oh, big Clyde Barrow!
You're just like your brother!
Ignorant, uneducated, hillbilly!
The only special thing about you
is your peculiar ideas about love-making...
...which is no love-making at all.
Oh, Clyde, please, I didn't mean that.
Listen, it, it was just all, all that shooting...
...and all those guns. I got so scared.
Please, honey, I didn't mean it.
"Law enforcement officers...
"... throughout the Southwest
are frankly amazed...
"... at the way in which the
will-o'- the-wisp bandit, Clyde Barrow...
"... and his yellow-haired companion,
Bonnie Parker...
"... continue to elude
their would-be captors!
"Since engaging in a police battle,
on the streets of Joplin, Missouri...
"... and slaying three of their number.
"The Barrow Gang has been reported
as far west as White City, New Mexico...
"... and as far north as Chicago.
"They have been credited with robbing...
"... the Mesquite Bank
in the aforementioned White City...
"... and the J.J. Landry Oil Refinery
in Arp, Texas.
"The Sanger City National Bank
in Sanger, Indiana.
"And the Lancaster Bank in Denton, Texas,
on three different occasions.
"In addition to these robberies,
the fast traveling Barrows...
"... have been rumored to have had a hand...
"... in the robbing of two
Piggly Wiggly stores...
"... in Texas, and one A&P store in,
in Missouri.
"Though Chief Percy Hammond, who first
identified Clyde Barrow's brother, Buck...
"... as a member of the gang.... "
We ain't going to see another toilet
for another thirty miles.
Why don't you pull up over here?
Over here.
Hey, now, here's something.
"Lone cop arrests two officers
in hunt for Barrow.
"Police Officer Howard Anderson's heart
turned faster than his motorcycle...
"... when he forced to the side
of the road a roaring black V-8 sedan...
"... in which were three men and a blonde-
headed woman, yesterday afternoon.
"He was certain he'd caught Clyde Barrow,
Bonnie Parker...
"... and maybe Buck Barrow...
"... and the third unidentified
member of the gang.
"It took a lot of telephoning
and explaining to convince...
"... the motorcycle cop that his captives
were two highway patrolmen...
"... and a blonde-haired stenographer
from the highway patrol."
Sheriff!
I've never seen such shooting!
All right, now you just get on right over
to that car.
Well, now, look here. We're
in the custody of Captain Frank Hamer....
And, Frank here is a Texas Ranger.
Say, peace-maker, I believe you got your
spurs all tangled up there, haven't you?
You're in Missouri,
do you know that, friend?
He's lost, this Texas Ranger.
I don't think he's lost.
Those banks have been offering
extra reward money for us...
...and I think Frank
just figured on some easy pickings.
You know, Texas Ranger,
you ain't hardly doing your job.
You ought to be home
protecting the rights of poor folk...
...not out chasing after us.
Why do you want to take it
so personal for?
Well, all right, we've got to discourage
this bounty hunting for the Barrow Gang.
What do you want
to do with him then, huh?
Shoot him?
Hang him.
Uh-uh. Take his picture.
Listen, we take his picture...
...we send it to all the newspapers.
And then everybody's going to
see Captain Frank Hamer...
...of the Texas Rangers
with the Barrow Gang...
...and all of us just as friendly as pie.
Now you know, we are just about the
friendliest folks you'd ever want to meet.
Big old Texas Ranger waves his gun at us...
...and we just welcome him
like he was one of our own.
Hey, Buck, get the Kodak.
Now see what came of your mischief,
not doing your job?
You know, down in Duncanville last year...
...poor farmers kept you laws
away from us with shotguns.
You're supposed to be
protecting them from us...
...and they're protecting us from you.
That don't make sense, do it?
Get right in there!
When his Texas Ranger friends see this,
he's going to wish he was dead.
Well, I'm mighty proud to have
a Texas Ranger in the family.
How's this?
We're going to put that picture
in every paper in the country!