Miss Theresa.
Your father is waiting for you.
I know.
Right now, my sweet.
I don't want to go.
Poor thing.
Your father wants you immediately!
Who is the father?
No!
Alfredo Garcia!
He was like a son to me.
I'll pay a million
to whoever brings me
the head of Afredo Garcia.
Bring me the head
of Alfredo Garcia.
Bring it to me!
-Do you care for a drink, sir?
-Uh, later.
Excuse me.
Welcome to Camino Real, sir.
-Thank you.
Enjoy your stay.
Mirado first, and then
la Munica, Goldendrina, and Toro.
Sing it, brothers.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...the bus us ready to leave in
two minutes. Please, let's go.
Good-bye my brothers from Ohio.
Good-bye my brothers from Norway.
Take your wooden hearts out
and find the soul in Mexico.
And bring back money.
Spend money all over, folks.
Have a good time,
but remember the Tlaquepaque.
Four tequila.
-Good evening.
We are looking for an old
buddy of ours. A padre named Alfredo Garcia.
Does anyone here know him,
if you please.
Mrs.
Miss?
You're sure, huh?
How about you?
No, Senor.
First drink's on the house, gentlemen.
Whatta you like to hear?
Take care of those gentlemen, Paulo.
Your wishes, gentlemen?
-Tequila.
-Uh, Tequila and a beer back.
Good evenig.
Something, uh, for the ladies.
Come on, whatta you wanna hear?
Who knows?
What would you like?
How about,
uh, 'l Remember April'?
I remember April. Yeah.
-Excuse me.
What's that?
Oh, it's just an old song.
Now, how about buying you a drink?
Crazy. Gimme a double
Jack Daniels on the rocks.
We've got a live one here.
Take me to your leader.
Well, cheers, money...
How do you like that beer?
You know they brought, uh,
German Burgermeisters over here
back in about eighteen
hundred and something.
Who knows? Long time ago.
Some of the best beet in the
world comes from Mexico.
How good you are.
How you guys like baseball?
Take her away.
I'm beginning to like basketball lately,
it's a faster game,
you know what I mean?
How about that Bill Russel on the
Celtic, Nineteen sixty-nine?
Now, there was a ball player.
You've, uh, worked around
here quite awhile, huh?
Yeah, about six years.
Started up in the Black Cat in T.J.
Now there was a nice place.
Classy place, classy
people came in there.
One night Paulette Goddard came in...
and asked me if I knew...
You know a lot of
studs around here?
Who you looking for?
Well, like I said, an old buddy
of ours, a very close chum,
like to meet up with him again.
He's quite a ladies' man.
His name is Alfredo Garcia.
Maybe you can help is find him.
He's about thirty. Sometimes
he calls himself Al...Garcia.
He speaks English,
Spanish and a little French.
Quite a stud, huh?
I'll be a son-of-a-bitch.
You got me.
I do recognize the name.
You know the name Garcia?
Sure, it's like Jones or Smith.
We're at the Hotel Camino Real,
if you come up with anything
we'd be glad to see you.
Bring that with you.
Well, don't worry,
if he's alive, I'll find him.
Uh, alive isn't our problem.
Well, uh, how about dead or alive?
How about that?
Dead, just dead.
What would you like to hear?
I didn't catch your name, Mister?
Dobbs. Fred C. Dobbs.
Paulo!
What's up?
When was the last time
Al Garcia was around?
One week. At the most a week.
You know anybody around here that...
might know where he is?
Elita.
He has stayed with her.
No shit?
I'll be dammed.
Ola, Benny.
Smiley. Long wat from Durango,
aren't you, Pard?
Ah, lemme see.
Things have changed.
Hey... put my shoe back.
Get up.
Excuse me.
What are you doing here so early?
It's later than you think, Chula.
How'd you like a black eye?
What have you been drinking?
You're a lying, cheating,
no-good two-bit bitch.
How's your, how's your cold?
What cold?
The one you had last week when
I couldn't see you for three days.
Ha, what'd the matter?
Ha, waht's the matter... Benny?
Ah, good evening.
Yeah, well, give me a double
bourbon with a champagne back
and none of your Texano bullshit...
now shove off.
Three days... and three nights.
Alfredo Garcia.
Si, Alfredo.
I feel very bad, uh...
Give me a chance I'll
explain it to you, olkay?
Do... it.
Well, he was here and
we spent some time together.
We were saying goodbye...
forever.
It took a little time.
If I ever get my hands on him
I'm gonna kill him.
I'm afraid it's too late.
When he left here he was very
drunk, and, uh, near Salti1 19...
his car refused the road
and the rocks killed him.
Jesus Christ.
-Amen.
I gotta go, Elita.
-Do you have to go?
-See you later.
Pardon.
Come in.
Glasses.
Give him your number.
Eleven. Lucky.
Bet you guys didn't expect
to see me so soon, huh?
You're wasting our time.
What have you got?
You don't mess around, do you?
Right down to business.
It's really very simple.
If you give us the information we want,
as to where we can find Alfredo Garcia,
we'll give you a thousand dollars.
If your information is wrong... you,
too are wrong... dead wrong.
Well, you see,
he's uh, friend of a friend.
And I'd like to know
what you want him for.
Well. that's not true. Uh, I mean,
I gotta tell somebody something right?
You're interested in money, aren't you?
Money you can spend.
Yes, sir. lndirectly.
I mean, there are other things.
Like I'd like to stay alive.
A loser.
Nobody loses all the time.
I don't like the money.
How much is it worth to you?
We can go five thousand.
-Ten thousand.
-I go all the way or I pass.
-l... gather by that you mean dead?
That's right.
That's what I got in mind.
Well. my friend, one must
do what one must do.
All we require from you...
is physical proof that Garcia is dead.
What kind of physical proof?
We're well aware of the problem and
we're prepared to settle for his head.
Yeah, but the, uh...
head must match the picture.
It's a deal.
But I want five thousand dollars in advance.
I'll need some operating cash, right?
You don't have to kill
him with kindness.
Give him two hundred dollars.
Well, thank you, gentlemen.
You've got four days.
And Benny... after that
we come to find you.
Ow! Goddammit!
Change the sheets, darling.
I got another job. You hear me?
Get up!
Come on, honey.
It's your room.
-Don't!
-Up and at 'em, Goddammit!
-Oh, don't.
-Hey, Elita!
Don't. Cut it out.
Hey, I saw those guys that were
looking for Alfredo... yesterday.
Did you tell them he was dead?
No.
Why not?
In this house we know nothing.
I wanna see his grave.
Tell me...
did he give you a good head?
You... dirty man.
You dirty, lousy, son-of-a-gun.
Oh, don't hurt me.
Now... pack a lunch.
No, you pack. You pack, you hear,
'cause we're going on a picnic.
Oh, no.
I'm gonna find a golden fleece, baby.
What is all this, Benny?
Just get up.
-Oh, okay.
Get up! Get up, come on.
All right... I am up!
-Up, up!
-Can't you see?
Get up.
Oh, no. Oh, don't play with
my hangover, please, Benny.
Come on.
Do you want one?
Oh, yes, the paper is in the, in the...
Goodbye.
Goodbye. Hope everything
goes well. Have a nice trip.
Let me pass.
I have a heavy load.
Stop here for your ice cream.
Give me a little kiss, coyote.
Jesus... Christ.
It doesn't matter, baby...
as long as I'm with you
I don't give a damn.
Enough already, Chalo.
Have pity, Chalo?
-Enough.
-It's not bothering.
Hungry, baby?
A little. But not for corn.
Meat in the pot, honey.
Bravo... bravo.
-Hell, I wasn't trying to hit 'em, you know.
-I know... you weren't.
I used to shoot a lot of pistols
when I was in the army.
You're a nice gringo.
You didn't have a thing
to do in the army, anyway.
Oh, you'd be surprised, honey.
-Don't bug me about it.
-You are a stupid son-of-a-bitch.
Let's go.
Then we'll go to Cozumel,
after that the lsle of Mujeres.
-You ever been there?
-No.
I haven't either.
Hell, I've never been anyplace I went to
go back to that's for dammed sure.
I was once at a place
I'd like to see again.
Yeah? Absolutely, baby, you name it.
It's called Guanajato.
With a G. Guanajato.
Guanajato.
Yes. It's very good.
It's a beautiful...
old Spanish town.
It's, uh, sixteenth century. Lemme see,
sixteen, uh, seventeen century.
I dunno. I get mixed
up with the centuries.
Yes, because...
This town, oh, well, never... mind.
You know, and they have
tunnels built all over the town.
And on top of the tunnels
there's the, the houses built.
You can see the little windows,
you know, hanging out.
-Yeah.
-Beautiful, you'll like it there.
I was there once with a...
Yeah, with who?
I forget.
Can we go there? Sometime?
No, we'll go someplace new.
Can we find a new place?
With Alfredo's help we
can do anything, honey.
Uh, we're not doing bad.
I'll go on doing commercials and,
pretty soon you can buy your place.
Bullshit, baby, that's not my place.
Just a pit stop for a bunch of tourists.
-This time I'm moving up.
-My son.
We're moving up.
And most important, at last to me is,
we're together, Benny.
We're together.
And we marry some day.
In a church.
Yeah, We'll marry
some day in a church.
Bullshit, Benny!
-Naw, I mean it this time.
When?
Sunday.
Why so?
Why?
Because I figure Al's worth
about ten thousand bucks.
I don't understand.
Your primera amor, my darling,
has, uh, made a mistake.
And some people... want him dead.
l... You're kidding?
No, I'm not kidding.
And we're gonna get some proof.
Jesus, y...
Well, l... Not with me, huh? You don't want
me to be part of that, do you?
You are a part of it.
For you or for me
or do it for Al.
He wants you to be happy, but...
Didn't he always watching you happy.
Yes, I would be happy...
Well, it's good knowing
what you want, Benny.
But it so happens
I don't know what I want.
You see, uh... we, we,
women have so many ways.
l, I'm just shocked.
Salud Alfredo.
Salud Alfredo, right?
I guess he'd want
me to be happy.
Yeah.
Yeah...
Benny?
Yeah?
Have you really thought
about marrying me?
I mean seriously?
Have you?
Yes, I have.
How come you never asked me?
I don't know,
but I do now.
Ask me again.
Ask me.
Will you marry me?
Coyote! Coyote...
Let's not sleep in the city tonight.
I brought some blankets and food.
Everything we need.
I'll fix a dinner for you and
we can sleep under the stars.
I wanna make you
so happy tonight.
We butting in?
-Yeah, a little bit.
Well, we'll leave if you want us to.
That fire looks mighty good, though.
Hey, I think I got a cold from
that chick... last week.
She was hacking like
a Goddamn coal miner.
Play anything?
Not much. My wife does.
No kidding? Hey... you know an old
song called Cielto Lindo...
Yes.
How about that? Hey...
could she play it?
If you please.
Say, that guitar is like a woman.
Just like a woman.
She'll be good
if you can get her.
She'll tremble when you touch her.
Okay, man, knock it off.
But she just keeps on getting better.
Looky what I got.
you wanna borrowie it?
Yeah.
Well, I think I'll just borrow... yours.
It's all right, Benny.
It's all right.
You two guys are...
definitely on my shit list.
He's a rotten sport, your old man.
Let's get out of here. Come on.
I'm gonna kill you one day,
you gringo son-of-a-bitch!
Oh, no, you won't, Benny.
I've been here before,
you don't know the way.
What the hell, she can handle it
a lot better than I can.
She sure can.
Please don't.
Please.
Gimme that bottle, Goddammit!
Son-of-a-bitch!
Hey! You're dirt!
Come on. Let's get out of here.
Come on.
I don't know what to say.
Dammit the hell,
You did all right.
I will tell everything to the police.
No chance.
You're gonna take me to find Alfredo.
And that's our ticket outta here.
Jesus, I don't know how you
can get money from a dead body,
I mean, I don't believe those
people and what they say.
I take 'em proof.
His head.
-His... head?
-For proof!
But it's a crime, Benny...
you're mad!
He's dead! Shut up!
Well, you want me to desecrate a grave?
Don't give me that crap!
There's nothing sacred
about a hole in the ground...
or a man that's in it... or you, or me.
Listen, the church
cuts off the feet, fingers,
any other Goddamn thing
from the saints, don't they?
Well, what the hell, Alfredo's our saint.
He's a saint of our money.
And I'm gonna borrow a piece of him.
All right...
I'll take you to him and then
I'm gonna go, you know.
Cause I figure everything
is gonna be over with us.
I don't want any more of that.
Oh, please, please.
Let's put it together,
just... make it round and let's go back
and forget about the whole thing.
We'll never talk about it again.
Jesus, just being together is,
is enough!
No, it's not, baby!
It takes pan, bread... money.
We need a room for the night
with a double bed.
I'm sorry, sir, but this
hotel does not allow...
Now, listen...
Mr. and Mrs. Benjamin...
from Mexico City.
And we're very, very tired.
And you pluck out one of those keys
while I sign the register.
Understand?
Best room in the house, please.
I love you.
Where are we?
We can ask for him at a place
they make furniture.
That's it. There.
-Buenos tardes.
-Yes.
What's he say?
No luck.
Yeah?
No luck at all.
I guess we came all the way for nothing.
Lemme tell you something, baby,