Are you Japanese?
Want me to introduce you
to some good-lookin' babes?
Asshole doesn't even speak English.
Is this all right, sir?
Thank you, sir.
Are you going out, sir?
Please don't bother, sir.
You already gave me a tip.
Please see the gentleman
to this address.
You got it.
He worked here a while ago.
Heard he got himself into some trouble.
So I fiired him.
He says he quit.
Excuse me.
Yamamoto lives near here.
Go three blocks that way
and then turn left.
He lives above the Trade Building.
He's into some bad business
with some black guys.
Better be careful.
Damn. Where the fuck are your eyes,
motherfucker? Huh?
What you gonna do about my wine,
motherfucker?
Ain't some old cheap-ass wine either.
It's gonna cost you at least $200.
Shit.
Hey.
Hello. Good day, sir.
The big boss wants to go out?
Yes. Please wait a moment.
Hey, move your short legs.
Excuse me.
We're in the middle of a war now.
Got it.
Hey, go upstairs.
Yes, sir!
Keep it open, asshole.
Get out.
Please.
Any new girls?
The same old faces.
A pack of cigarettes.
What about her?
Come on.
She's Mr. Yoshida's girl.
Right.
I haven't seen him for some time.
What about him?
Oh, Jun.
He was introduced
by a liquor vendor.
- Shall I?
- No, no.
It's great to get out of the house.
Lots of great women here.
No fun at home
staring at the old bag.
Come on, drink up.
Take the boss home.
Big Boss, please.
What? We're leaving already?
- Let him pass.
- Spoilsports.
Too weak, sir?
Too strong.
Brother...
shouldn't we call a truce
with the enemy?
You're getting soft.
Can't be so headstrong.
We're not young anymore.
Cops are already here.
Dump it somewhere.
Hope the boss went home.
And not to his mistress's.
Why the fuck are you here?
That's how it is...
So might as well
come to an agreement.
We don't want it to get out of hand.
Better to disband the family.
He says he'll look after you.
Goddamn it, this is a wake.
Shit happens.
"Shit happens"?
What's with this tie?
Back off, punk.
"I have a wife and children...
and my men.
I cut off my fiinger.
So let me join the family
that killed our boss.
Please, brother?"
Don't "brother" me!
I don't want this!
I should kill you!
You traitor!
You call yourself a Yakuza?
He's doing it for us.
Please kill me instead.
Please forgive us. Please.
You stay out of this.
Sorry, brother.
Never mind.
I'll talk to Aniki for you.
Well, see you.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
You're out of line.
I declare this to Mr. Harada and
the ten men who will become dependents.
As you drink
the sacred sake before you...
you will become members
of the Hisamatsu family.
As you may already realize...
in the strict world of the Yakuza...
Even if your boss tells you
white is black...
You must put aside all reservations
and agree to his view.
Damn Hisamatsu.
Why is he taking that bastard in?
I think the police pressured him.
There was no alternative.
This way, our enemy is fiinished.
Aniki doesn't fit in.
It's like he's not needed.
'Cause he's an outsider.
After all, you were enemies.
It can't be helped.
I've been told to kill you.
You're a pain in their ass...
and they don't trust me.
Then kill me.
Come on.
We're sworn brothers.
Could you leave the county?
I'll take care of eveything.
I could go to America.
My kid brother's there.
Impossible for a Yakuza?
Brother, would you really go?
The Chinese guys
can make up a passport.
I'll get you some money too.
Please.
I owe you one.
Hey, I'm supposed to die.
Who is he?
A bum named Sakamoto.
Let's see his face.
Doesn't look anything like him.
Hey, put these clothes on him.
Destroy his face and hands.
Burn his back.
And plant the driver's license on him.
Yes, sir.
Give me booze. Booze.
What a dirty bag.
We were too busy getting the money
to get a better bag.
So, my name's Sakamoto.
When you sign your name,
please use these characters.
The PIN numbers are there.
What's this 1-2-3?
Big Brother Harada's birthday.
Says he wants you to remember him.
That idiot.
Hey, who the hell are you?
Aniki (big brother)...
My friends, Jay and Mo.
This is my big brother.
- What's up?
Where's Denny?
How come he's not here yet?
He must be gambling again.
All right, let's go.
We don't need him.
We've got something to do.
Stay here.
We'll get something to eat later.
Let's go.
You're supposed to be brothers,
but you don't look alike.
We are half-brothers.
I don't know the details.
We were abandoned.
Isn't that right, my brother?
We were orphans, huh?
We were put in some funny institution.
My brother paid for me
to come here and study.
And you end up pushing drugs.
Don't say that in front of my brother.
But he doesn't
understand English anyway.
Is there anything you need, sir?
Do you have water?
I'll get you some right away.
And what time will you
be leaving tomorrow, sir?
Damn. No tip this time.
Aniki, you shouldn't
tip the hotel maid $100.
He gave the maid $100
to make his bed.
He must be really loaded.
Then the maid left him
$95 dollars change...
and this note saying...
"You shouldn't spend money like this."
"Five dollars is enough."
If it were me,
I'd have kept it.
Hell, yeah.
Hey, Denny.
What happened?
Some joker cut me up yesterday, man.
Who?
Fuck if I know.
Chink.
SomeJap motherfucker, man.
- Why?
- Must've tried to bank another tourist.
You don't give up, do you, nigger?
Denny, this is my big brother.
He's here from Japan.
Your brother didn't
run into me yesterday, did he?
He's not the one
who fucked my eye up, is he?
What?
Didn't meet him yesterday, right?
Didn't cut his eye, right?
All Japanese look the same to you.
You can't tell one from the other.
Maybe so.
Well, shall we go?
Yo, y'all gotta roll without me, man.
This shit is hurtin'.
All right. Then you can
hang out with my brother.
But he doesn't speak English.
- What am I supposed to do with him?
- Drink beer, kill time.
How much beer
are we supposed to drink?
Let's play.
Check it out.
I'm betting at six-to-one odds,
all right?
So if I win,
that's six times.
I bet ten dollars,
I get $60 back. Okay?
Roll the dice.
Let me think. Three.
It's gonna be three.
I know it. I'm hot.
Six.
Oh, you bettin' too?
All right, all right.
Well, if you win, you get $60 dollars.
Let's see.
Ain't that a bitch?
All right,
let's do it one more time.
This time, I got two and four
at three-to-one odds.
So if I get one of'em,
it's three times.
All right, let's see
what you got now, player.
Come on. Come on.
What? What?
Six.
Ain't nobody gonna get six
twice in a row!
You're crazy, man.
What is it?
Ain't that a...
There's somethin' wrong
with these dice, man.
Cheatin' or somethin'.
Goddamn.
Fuckin' lost $20 dollars, man.
Where you going, man?
Tobacco.
What?
Cigarette.
Oh. Tobacco.
There's a store right out there, man.
Check it out.
Cheatin'-ass mother...
What the hell?
Oh, now ain't this a bitch?
Oh, yeah.
Fuckin' hole in the cup?
Son of a bitch.
A hole in the cup.
It's the oldest trick in the book, man.
I can't believe this shit.
Hand over the money
for the last batch.
All right.
What the fuck is this?
Fifteen hundred, right?
No. Three G's.
Hey, that's too much.
- That's the price.
- We can't make any money at that price.
Take it or leave it.
I didn't tell you to sell drugs.
- What are we supposed to do?
- Shut up!
You cheatin' son of a bitch.
Where's my money?
I'm leaving.
Don't go, Aniki.
His thugs will get you.
Got any guns?
Some old ones.
Bring them.
Mo, get my brother
back to the hotel, please.
- All right.
- Be careful.
What is goin' on?
Ken's brother
just beat the shit out of Victor.
That's tight!
Are you the Jap
that beat up the boss?
Come with us. Come on.
- Yo, hold up, man.
- Don't follow him, or we'll kill you.
Hold up.
Then why'd he hit Ken?
Look what they did to me.
I want them shot.
I'am fucking pissed.
They'll fucking respect me.
What the fuck do you want?
If you kill him in one shot,
he'll give you ten bucks.
What'll we do?
Take their turf.
We'll have trouble with the Mexicans.
Then it's war.
My brother says...
we are going to war with the cholos.
Aniki, do we have
to stay in here forever?
No choice.
We go out, we're dead.
Hit men may be here already.
Yeah?
Aniki.
Kato?
What's going on?
I'm at war in America, too.
What exactly did he do in Japan?
He was a gangster.
Who's the other guy?
His lieutenant.
Aniki.
They contacted us.
- What did they say?
- Want to meet us tomorrow.
Where?
At the Sunset Square Hotel at 10:00.
Hide them.
All right.
I'll check the conference room.
Where we gonna hide these?
Take 'em out of the bag.
- Will it fiit?
- Yeah.
Wait a minute.
Okay.
Do you think you can get away
with what you did?
They're asking if we think
we can get away with it.
So, want a war?
What you gonna do,
go to war with us?
We'd wipe you out!
They say they'd kill us.
Tell them ty it.
Bring it on. Come on.
Just relax, okay?
Let's discuss this like gentlemen.
We'll give you the territoy.
We didn't like those guys anyway.
From now on you're gonna be in charge,
just as it always was.
You don't have
any objection to that, right?
They say they'll give us the turf.
Say we accept.
Okay, we accept.
Okay, go.
You told them
you'd let them have the territoy.
Now, why would you do that
to these fuckin'Japs?
Why not?
We're gonna massacre 'em all
later anyway.
It was occupied. Couldn't get them.
What are we going to do?
Feel under the table.
Good to have insurance.
I understand "fucking Jap," asshole.
Where did Aniki say we were going?
He said he's meeting some woman.
A date?
He's interested in women now?
I'm sory I'm late.
Hi, guys. I'm Marina.
Nice to meet you.
Can't make out
if she's pretty or ugly...
but she's sure got class.
What the fuck!
Just joking.
She's beautiful.
He's just joking.
Thank you.
Hey, where's Denny?
It's his mom's birthday,
so he's at home.
Doesn't his mom work anymore?
She got money now. She don't need
to be nobody's maid anymore.
Right. Right.
- Thanks for comin' by.
- No problem, man. Free food.
Hey, Ma, these are my friends.
- Hello.
- Happy birthday, Mrs. Turner.
This is for you from my brother.
Oh, from your brother?
Thank you.
He's not my brother.
He's not here.
Okay. All right.
Listen, would you guys
help yourself to some cake, please?
Help yourself.
There's a lot for eveybody.
Go on.
Oh, look at this.
Oh, this couldn't fit me.
This must... Is it? Okay.
- Come here.
- For me?
Yes. Here, Latifah.
Oh, my goodness.
You know how to put this on?
That bitch took Aniki.
She took Aniki.
This is nice.
I know when I'm gonna use this.
Your friends
have such wonderful taste.
There.
- That's really nice.
- Let's ty this one.
Okay, how do we get this off?
Here we go.
Oh, now this is interesting.
What's in this?
They know what to get you,
don't they?
- Wow.
- Look at that.
Oh, man!
- Don't ty to be too cool.
- All right.
All right.
Higashiyama, pass the ball.
Higashiyama, to me, to me!
It's my ball.
Isn't it my ball?
Don't you know the rules?
That's it, Higashiyama!
Over here! Over here!
Pass it to me.
That's why the Americans beat you.
All right. Over here.
Hey, Minamino, over here.
I'm open. See?
Pass it.
What's the matter with you?
Hey, Moose.
Moose! Moose!
Hey, come here. Come here.
Hey, Higashiyama, come here.
You're out.
Because you won't pass.
All right, Moose, you're the helper.
I'm telling you to pass to me.
All right, Moose.
Pass to me.
Come on, to me!
I told you to pass, you bastard.
Ouch!
Hey, you... Damn it!
To me! To me!
All right, all right.
Out of the way.
You fucking bastard.
Give me the ball, you bastard!
Why do you like this place?
I lived in this kind of place.
Must have been poor, then.
Shut up.
Let's go.
Come on, relax.
I'm Michael Jordan.
- What?
- I'm Michael Jordan.
No, you're more like Michael Gordon,
not Michael Jordan.
Don't get it twisted.
Michael Gordon. That's you.
I am Michael Jordan.
You know what I mean?
Y'all got Michael Jordan?
Not our Michael Jordan.
- I am Michael Jordan.
- Oh, okay.
The same Michael Jordan.
No, not the bald-headed Mike.
You're like Shaquille O'Neal.
That's Shaquille O'Neal right there.
That's who you like.
What's that?
- You're like Shaq.
- I'm Michael Jordan.
Man. Man.
Woman.
Man.
Man, even if I
raise my handicap to 20...
how much more could I win
in an hour?
Woman.
Damn.
The same woman is going back and forth
down the street.
What's going on?
That's Aniki's woman.
Ken, would you sign this?
All right.
Sign, please.
You're spending too much.
What are you doing?
Hury up! Do some work!
Checkmate.
That was my piece
until a little while ago.
Once we take it, it's ours.
Oh. Oh, I get it.
Kind of like you.
What's that?
This guy isn't paying up,
so I'll send this to his house.
Show me.
Then he'll have to pay up.
Hey, how's it going?
That whore hasn't called yet, sir.
- How many whores do you have?
- Five, sir.
Business is slow, huh?
Control your whores, faggot.
Nice fuckin' shirt.
Japs and Niggers.
Big fucking deal.
Hey, wanna play some dice?
- Okay.
- All right. No cheatin'.
I've gotta call my mother real quick.
Hey, what's up, Ma?
Yeah, it's me.
I'm gonna be late, all right?
Got some things I gotta do.
I love you too. Bye.
Aniki?
Drop the gun, or I'll kill him.
Denny, shoot. Shoot.
- Shoot.
- Drop the gun.
- Put the gun down.
- I'll kill him.
- Shoot! Shoot!
- Drop it! Drop the gun!
- Put the gun down!
- Drop it!
- Shoot!
- I'll kill him!
Oh, shit.
Aniki.
He needs rest.
All right.
Sorry, Doc.
Hope this is okay.
Thanks.
What the fuck did you do?
Keep your eyes open.
Don't you think it's time
for your brother to move?
He likes it here.
What about you?
I'll go with you.
How is he?
Much better.
He's fooling around with Denny.
We caught the pusher who ran away.
They caught the runaway pusher.
What shall we do with him?
Have him cut off his fiinger.
What are you doing? Stand up.
Go to the sushi bar.
Get knife and cutting board.
Yes, sir.
What are you guys gonna do?
Cut his fiinger off.
What happens
if you cut his fiinger off?
He can't swim straight anymore.
How's that?
You can't feel anything, can you?
Do it.
Do it!
I'll show you how to do it!
Stick your fiinger out!
Wait, man, wait!
I'll give it back. Just stop this shit.
Don't cut my fuckin'...
Oh, shit.
You mother... Fuck!
Who's the boss of Little Tokyo?
We can expand, if he joins us.
- Hey, Mo.
- Yeah?
Who's the boss of Little Tokyo?
Some player named Shirase.
Should I tell Aniki...
if we got together...
like, join up with them...
our family will be bigger?
What do you think?
A guy named Shirase.
Let's talk to Aniki.
Joining forces with Shirase
is a bad idea.
Why?
He's way too dangerous.
So are we.
You want me to get you
some cigarettes?
No, thanks.
Why?
My stomach hurts.
I'm sory, man.
just joking.
You're messing with me, man.
You wait here.
Don't give me that bullshit!
Be sworn brothers with him?
Be Yamamoto's henchman?
What the fuck.
I've come this far by myself.
I haven't had any help from anyone.
Why doesn't Yamamoto come himself...
instead of a punk like you?
Who the fuck does he think he is?
Aniki's not good at things like this.
This? Fuck him.
These fucking guys
want me to be a henchman.
What should I tell them?
You won't reconsider?
No way.
If we joined up,
we'd be better off and bigger.
I can do that on my own.
Get out!
You motherfucker!
We can crush you anytime!
Just ty it.
- Didn't work out.
- Thought so.
He's impossible.
Let's go.
Hey, we're going.
- I have something to do.
- What is it?
- Nothing much.
- Let's go.
- My appointment.
- What is it?
What do you want?
About what we discussed...
I said the answer is no.
We really want you to join us.
If you like, you can be
equal brothers with Yamamoto.
That's bullshit.
I'd stake my life for Aniki.
What are you talking about, asshole?
A line from a gangster movie.
Oh, yeah?
Let's see if you mean it.
Lend me your gun.
Go ahead. Stake your life.
I count on you, "uncle."
Stop.
I'm all yours.
Aniki.
Kill them.
The boss says we don't need you.
What is this bullshit?
You need me!
You wanna fuckin' expand, you need me.
I'm the man.
You know how many people I killed?
I got a long list of bodies.
You fuckin'Japs cross me...
you'll be on that
long list of dead...
You.
Come upstairs.
- You did it this time, boy.
- How's your friend feel?
You want some
Come and get some
Where you from?
Take care now.
Who are they?
Crooked cops.
They're on the take.
Get out of here.
Shirase, aren't you overdoing it?
For Brother Kato's sake,
we have to make this family bigger.
I'm going all the way.
Don't smoke that thing
in front of me!
Sory, sir.
He's in a bad mood.
What happened?
What's this dirty bag?
Shut up. Go home.
There's a letter for Mr. Kato.
It's from Mr. Harada in Tokyo.
I'll take it.
How are you doing?
How's Brother Yamamoto?
I've had troubles...
but I have my own family now.
I owe it all to him that
I've come this far as an outsider.
That's some finger
you had made.
With that on, you won't
be thrown out of golf clubs.
Excuse me, sir.
Mr. Harada and my boss
sure are prosperous.
Being an outsider,
it wasn't easy.
Because of your efforts...
we've grown bigger.
Keep up the good work...
and no rivaly.
Yes, sir.
But, Boss.
Since there's
an outsider among us...
it's hard to tell
what he's hiding inside him.
Matsumoto,
are you talking about me?
Do you want to take a look
at what's in my stomach?
Bring me a knife!
Yes, sir!
See for yourself.
Take him away.
Matsumoto,
you tarnished this celebration.
I demand you take
responsibility for this!
Sory, sir!
Please forgive me with this.
The Mafiia is harassing us.
Should we give them a share?
They're demanding half,
aren't they?
Well? Sugimoto?
20% is the limit.
We got your woman.
Come to the Sixth Street Bridge.
Come alone.
Where is he going?
Home, I guess.
Shouldn't you take him home?
He doesn't want me
to know where he lives.
Ah. That's playing it safe, huh?
Isn't Aniki coming?
No. He's got something
to take care of.
Shit.
You know, he should be paying
more attention to the family business.
Hey, the Mafia says
20% is not acceptable.
- They want 50%.
- Well, fuck them.
What shall we do?
It's war.
Fuck with the Italians,
we'll be askin' for trouble.
Yeah. We'll all die.
I'm a yakuza
from the old school.
If I have to die, so be it.
Freeze!
- Bring him over here.
- Yes, sir.
Who sent you?
Which family?
Aniki?
Are you okay?
You don't look so good, man.
You gonna eat?
Denny...
run away.
What?
Where to?
Here. Eat it.
Really?
All right.
So, it's war.
Hey, boys.
Here's to the boss.
- Here.
- Thank you.
We just killed Geppetti,
so it's war.
You better be ready.
The Mafiia will
torture you to death.
If you get caught...
take one of these.
You'll die quickly, without pain.
Aniki.
You and l,
we don't need this shit, right?
It's over.
We'll all die.
What a terrible thing to do.
Clean it up.
Yes, sir.
Aniki.
We are going to avenge
Aniki's death.
Don't even think about running.
- Denny, give me my 9-millimeter!
- Okay, buddy, let's go.
Colin. Colin!
So he's dead.
Let's go.
Mr. Sugimoto, you can leave now.
We're closing the offiice.
I want to update
the books through today.
- What's that?
- Clothes.
- What is it?
- Some clothes.
Let's go to
my mother's house for now.
Okay. Go.
Wait here.
Ma!
Oh, God!
Aniki, we're fiinished.
I'm leaving town.
Up to you.
What about you?
I'm staying.
Oh, God.
Jay, run!
" DEATH"
There's only one of'em.
Let's go.
Aniki, you don't have
to do this, you know.
This is my business.
Denny, okay.
Go ahead.
Oh, God!
Aniki.
So, what you wanna do with him?
All right, here's how it works.
Now, one of these five strings
is attached to the trigger.
You get to choose three.
If none of'em pull...
we'll let you go, honestly.
All right?
Now go ahead, choose three.
Come on.
Pick one.
The first one on the left.
This one? All right.
All right.
Choose another one.
Come on.
Uh, fifth one.
Fifth.
One, two, three...
Pretty lucky guy.
All right, last one.
- Come on!
- The second one.
Second one.
Goddamn son of a bitch!
You motherfuckers!
Get out.
Get out!
Come on. Come on!
What are you doin'?
Here. Take it.
Run away.
Denny, your eye...
I did it.
Yeah, I know, my brother.
You even kill
one of your own men.
You evil son of a bitch, you.
Are you Japanese?
Here on business?
You Japanese are so inscrutable.
For the repairs.
Run away?
Fuckin' run away?
Where the fuck am I supposed to run to?
Where the fuck am I supposed to run?
These motherfuckers are gonna kill me
no matter where I go!
Fuckin' shit.
My whole life is fucked up, man.
It's just fucked up.
Oh, shit.
I was better off dealin' on
the fuckin' corner, I swear to God, man.
What the fuck am I doin'?
And you give me some
fuckin' stink-ass gym bag...
full of stinky-ass clothes, huh?
What the fuck are you tellin' me?
To die in clean underwear or somethin'?
Fuckin' sick Japanese tradition
or some shit?
Oh, you fuckin'... Fuck!
What the fuck
is in this shit anyway?
Oh, shit.
Holy shit.
" Here's the $60 I owe you
for cheating...
plus interest for you.
Your brother, Yamamoto."
Oh, shit.
You son of a bitch.
Goddamn, I love you, man.
I love you, Aniki,
wherever you at, man!