This is before she had us.
Before she started drinking.
Who took care of you
as a child?
Orphanage.
Me and Linda.
And that's your sister?
You know, we're not so
different as you might think.
Yeah, I was abandoned
repeatedly as a child.
My mama would drag me along
to some new town,
so she could take up
with another man she'd met.
Night after night, she'd lock
me in the hotel room alone.
Mama would turn the latch
and tell the staff
not to let me out
no matter what.
And I was terrified.
And I’d scream my head off...
until finally I’d collapse
on the carpet next to the
door and I’d fall asleep.
Then after years of this,
she just left me
with relatives in Alabama.
Who raised you up?
My aunts.
And that's where I met Nelle.
And she lived...
she lived next door.
Your mother was Indian?
Cherokee.
So drinking was not
a good thing for her.
No tolerance for it.
We're on, uh, suicide watch.
That's why they leave
the lights on at night.
I hope
we're past that now.
I do.
Be careful of Ricardo.
I think he wants you
all to himself.
All right.
But he's
naturally mendacious.
Not to be trusted.
If he had $100, he'd steal
a stick of chewing gum.
Perry, I want to take
your notebooks with me.
I want to read them.
If I leave here
without understanding you,
the world will see you
as a monster
always.
I don't want that.
'Cause he trusts me.
I mean,
that's why he gave it to me.
And he-he's given me
absolutely everything.
And he wants so badly
to be taken seriously
to be held in some esteem.
Do you?
Do I what?
Do you hold him
in esteem, Truman?
Well,
he's a gold mine.
And he's told me
his entire life.
His, uh,
his dead mother.
Uh, he had a brother
and a sister kill themselves.
Awful.
Did you tell him
your mama did the same thing?
See, I can't tell him
everything.
We've been talking our
heads off for the past month.
And sometimes when I...
when I think how good my book
can be, I can hardly breathe.
Anyway, th-this is... this is
what I wanted to read to you.
Uh,
"if called upon
to make a speech... "
to make a speech"?
I mean, this is exactly
what I’m talking about.
A speech, just in case he's ever
recognized for an achievement.
"I can't remember what I was
going to say for the life of me.
"I don't think ever
before have so many people
"been so directly responsible
"for my being
so very, very glad.
"It's a wonderful moment
and a rare one.
Thank you!"
There's... there's an exclamation
point at the end of that "thank you"
in case you didn't catch it.
Where'd you go?
I guess it
stopped being funny.
I... I never said it was.
But, wait,
listen to this.
I was 14.
One day I said to him,
"mom's dead. " I could see it.
A week later we got the news.
She finally drunk
herself...
...found her shivering...
she hit me so many times
with that flashlight,
she broke it.
That night, I... I dreamed
about that big yellow bird.
Clawed that nun's eyes,
bright like the sun.
Lifted me to the sky.
Sometimes you see a thing
how it really is.
Well, you're nothing
if not hardworking.
Hey, you look good.
Healthy again.
You know, I’ve decided
on a title for my book.
I think you'll like it.
It's very masculine.
In cold blood.
Isn't that good?
And that refers to the crime
or the fact that you're still
talking to the criminals?
Oh, the former,
among other things.
I see.
I wanted to ask
if you'd let me look
at your investigation notes.
That lawyer you helped find
for your friends
got them a hearing at
the Kansas supreme court...
yeah, I heard this morning.
...on the issue
of inadequate counsel.
Alvin,
I mean, do you not want
me to look at your notes?
You are permitted to say no.
I'll tell you what.
If those boys get off,
I’m coming to Brooklyn
to hunt you down.
I have to be in court
at 9:00,
but you call Roy Church and he'll
show you what you want to see.
Thank you.
It's as much for me
as for anyone.
I couldn't bear the thought
of losing you so soon.
We're gonna be able to
use your book for our case.
You... you'll write we never
got to raise an insanity plea.
You wrote how terrible
the lawyers was.
I... I haven't written
a word yet.
What have you been doing?
Research. Talking to you.
All right.
I... I had hoped...
wh-what are you calling it?
The book?
I have no idea.
Perry,
if I’m going to
write about you,
if I’m going to determine
how to write about you,
we need to talk about,
you know, why you're here.
And,
you know, the murders,
and that night
at the clutter house.
Do you worry
what I’ll think?
Is that it?
Dick says you know
Elizabeth Taylor.
I know a lot of people.
Perry, I have invitations
to be in morocco, Greece,
and I prefer to be here
with you.
Jack, be patient with me.
I'm just missing
this one piece.
Well, how long
is that gonna take?
Why don't you just try
leaving him alone for a while?
Come to Spain.
You can always
visit him later.
I don't know.
Well, I’m off. I'm just...
I’ve got my own writing to do.
Well, do it in Brooklyn.
Wait for me.
There's too many
people around. I've...
I’ll leave the address
on the kitchen table.
Well, think about what I
said, and join me when you can.
I will.
Ok?
Bye.
Hi.
Truman.
We never intended
on killing that family.
Capote,
will you get that straight
in your book, please?
No premeditation.
What are you doing?
I have to fly back east.
When?
An hour.
I miss you already.
Write me every 5 minutes.
Hey, you know, we never did
intend on killing that family.
Capote?
What?
Truman,
I’ve not been able to tear
myself away from your book.
It's that good.
It's... it's not good,
it's astonishing.
This first half is
astonishing. Oh, thank you.
When will you be done,
do you think?
Yes, I... I’m already
well into the third part.
But I...
I can't finish that
till I convince Perry
to describe the night
of the killings to me.
I was... I was planning
to visit this fall, see?
Then I think you need
to talk to him now.
And we all need to see how
this ends for the final part.
I... I... I can't finish the book
till I know what happens.
If Perry and Dick
are executed, it's one thing.
And if not, weli...
Truman,
you've got your ending.
I really don't know.
The Kansas court
denied their appeal.
It came over the wire
on Friday.
I mean, you need to
talk to Perry now.
He'll be dead by September.
I mean, I’m sorry. I know how
much you've come to care about him.
Right. Yes, right.
So I want to set up a reading
for you in the fall, in New York,
and, uh, well,
we'll build some interest,
and we'll publish
in the fall.
Thank god.
There's nothing in the house.
Why aren't you working?
Well, I knew you couldn't be
counted on to stock the kitchen.
What are we going to feed
our famous guest?
Oh, Jesus,
I completely forgot.
Plus, I, uh,
finished my novel yesterday.
What?
When was the last time
you wrote to him?
I don't know.
What's this?
It's a letter for Truman
I was asked to deliver.
It's from Perry.
Let's have it.
"Dear friend Truman,
where are you?
"Read this item
in a medical dictionary.
'Death by hanging
is caused by asphyxia,
'by fracture of
the cervical vertebrae,
'by laceration
of the trachea. '
"Not too comforting,
as we lost our appeal.
"Missing you.
"Alone and desirous
of your presence.
Your amigo, Perry. "
Mr. Shawn told me about the
court decision yesterday.
I was wondering why you were
in such a good mood.
That's
a terrible thing to say.
I... I write him all the time
I’ve just...
I’ve been so focused on-
- on the book lately.
So Jack thinks
I’m using Perry,
but he also thinks I fell in love
with him when I was in Kansas.
Now, how both of those things
can be true is beyond me.
Thank you.
Well, did you?
Did you fall in love
with him?
I don't know
how to answer that.
Truman.
It's as if Perry and I
grew up in the same house,
and one day he stood up
and went out the back door
while I went out the front.
Are you kidding me?
No.
Listen, you be nice to Jack.
Sometimes I think he's
what I like about you best.
I'll see you
at the reading in New York.
16th.
Adios.
What was he in jail for?
Well, they said it was
for not paying his taxes,
but really,
for being an outsider.
Refusing to go along.
Lowell, you're being moved.
Why?
You're going to final holding. No.
Come on, Lowell.
Open the door.
Stand up.
Put your arms
behind your back.
Ok, last chance.
Well, get up.
Ah!
Turn around.
Put your arms
behind your back.
Now Dick and me,
we're next in line.
I'm so sorry I’ve been away.
It was a long time.
I know.
How's the book coming along?
Oh, very slowly.
Will you show it to me?
I've hardly written anything.
Good evening, New Yorkers,
and thank you for coming
to the first public reading,
the first offering
of any kind,
of Truman Capote's new work,
in cold blood.
Hello.
My name is Truman Capote.
For this...
for this evening's program,
I’m going to read, uh,
some passages
from the first 3 parts
of my new book.
"The village of Holcomb
"stands on the high wheat
plains of western Kansas,
"a lonesome area that other
Kansans call 'out there. '
"Until one morning
in mid-November, 1959,
"few Americans, in fact, few
Kansans, had ever heard of Holcomb.
"Like the waters
of the Arkansas river,
"like the motorists
on the highway,
"exceptional happenings
never stopped there.
"Perry Smith's voice
was both gentle and prim.
"A voice that, though soft,
"manufactured
each sound exactly,
"ejected it like a smoke ring
issuing from a parson's mouth.
"The 4 coffins,
which quite filled
the small,
flower-crowded parlor
"were to be sealed
at the funeral services,
"very understandably,
"for the effect
was disquieting.
"Nancy wore her dress
of cherry-red velvet,
"her brother
a bright plaid shirt.
"The parents
were more sedately attired,
"Mr. Clutter in navy-blue flannel,
his wife in navy-blue crepe.
"And it was this especially that
lent the scene an awful aura,
"the head of each was
completely encased in cotton.
"A swollen cocoon
"twice the size of
an ordinary blown-up balloon.
"And the cotton,
"because it had been sprayed
with a glossy substance,
"twinkled like
Christmas tree snow.
"One Tuesday at dawn,
a carload of strangers,
"ignorant
of the local disaster,
"were startled by what they
saw as they crossed the prairies
"and passed through Holcomb.
"Windows ablaze.
"Almost every window
in almost every house,
"and in the brightly-lit
rooms, fully-clothed people,
"even entire families,
"who had sat the whole night
wide awake watchful, listening.
"Of what
were they frightened?
It might happen again. "
Thank you.
And I slipped
and I ripped a hole
from the bottom
of my scrotum...
All the way up to the top
of the crack of my ass.
And I sat there.
And I didn't know it.
All I felt was a...
I... I didn't know it. All I felt was
a cool breeze you know, between my...
Sorry. If I may, uh...
yes.
Your portrait of those men
was terrifying.
Terrifying.
Thank you.
Stop that man!
Come back here!
Dad!
Have any of you
met my father?
He hasn't spanked me
in years.
George didn't come backstage.
He had... he had a...
something that his wife
had to rush him off to.
But he made a point of...
yeah, well, I’m still wal...
I’m still waiting for a call.
It was beautiful. And everybody
came. Hmm. Tennessee...
everybody came.
Tennessee loved it.
Of course he loved it.
Should we do more?
No, we... we just sit and wait
while people talk about it
and we let them do the work.
I mean, this... this book is
going to change everything.
It's gonna change
how people see your writing.
I think it's going to Chan
how people write.
Are you gonna be finished
by October?
I think so.
You know, they're scheduled
for next month.
To hang.
Yeah.
We're gonna commit as many
issues as it takes to publish.
Whatever it takes.
Well, I’m going to Kansas
tomorrow, and...
and I’ll get Perry to talk.
What's he got to lose?
Sorry, but...
hey, this may
sound strange to you,
but I’m going to miss him.
You'll be able to finish now.
Need to check your
papers, sir.
This is what we've been
waiting for.
A stay of execution
to make a federal appeal.
All thanks to you.
Thank you!
They're not gonna
corner me now.
Not unless the U.S.
Government says so.
Kansas has had it in
for me for 10 years.
They can't corner me now.
Mmm-mmm.
Hey, Perry, sit down
for a minute.
I... I need you to talk to me.
We've got all the time
in the world to talk.
I've been
thinking about Ricardo.
You really need to stop
sending him those trashy books.
I won't even
mention the pornography.
Now, I realize that
Dick probably can't grasp the
literature that you gave me.
Uh, the books you
send him only...
they only exacerbate
the problem.
They only heighten
or intensify it.
Maybe we can get him
started on a program. Perry,
I know what
"exacerbate" means.
Ok, well, just thinking...
there... there's not
a word or a sentence
or a concept that you
can illuminate for me.
There is one singular reas
I keep coming here.
Truman.
November 14, 1959.
3 years ago. 3 years.
Hmm?
And that's... that's all
I want to hear from you.
Now I asked you not to. Ever.
This is absurd.
Do you know
what absurd means?
I'm ready.
I have a plane to catch.
I found your sister
in Tacoma.
Maybe she'll talk to me
about something useful.
Please don't go out there.
Hey, this is my work, Perry.
I'm working.
And when you want to tell what
I need to hear, you let me know.
June's dead.
Frank shot himself.
Now Perry did what he did.
I used to love him.
He was my little doll.
He scares me now.
When was the last time
you saw him?
10 years ago.
10 years.
Could I borrow
one of these pictures?
Take the whole thing.
I don't want them anymore.
Don't be taken in
by my brother.
He's got this sensitive side
he'll show.
You believe he's gentle
and so easily hurt,
but he'd just as soon kill you as
shake your hand. I believe that.
Hello, handsome.
What's the name of your book?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
"Truman Capote read last
night before a packed audience
"from his nonfiction
book in cold blood.
"The true-crime novel tells
of killers Richard Hickock
"and Perry Smith,
who brutally murdered
a Kansas family 3 years ago. "
Wait, who sent that to you?
That's not
your goddamn business.
It is my business,
because it's not true.
The organizers of
the reading needed a title.
They picked one,
a sensational one, I admit,
to attract a crowd.
They picked it?
Yes.
It's not your title.
Perry,
I haven't chosen one yet.
How could I choose a title
when we still haven't
talked about that night?
How could I?
I couldn't possibly.
You pretend to be my friend.
I'm sorry.
I should have told you.
And I couldn't pretend
to be your friend
'cause the truth is,
I can't help wanting to be.
You don't have to
tell me anything...
if you don't want to.
I have something
from your sister.
She misses you.
Look at my belly.
There must be something wrong
with us, to do what we did.
We heard there was
$10,000 in that house.
Once we tied up everybody
and searched all over,
I knew the guy
that told us about it was...
was wrong. There was...
there was no money.
Dick wouldn't believe it
so he went tearing
through the house,
banging on the walls
looking for a safe.
When he was done, he...
said he was gonna go up to Nancy's
room and have his way with her.
I wouldn't allow it.
And I told him that.
So I sat with her.
Dick came up and got me.
We turned off the lights
and went down to the basement
where Mr. Clutter
and the boy was.
He kept saying,
"no witnesses," but I...
I figured
if I waited him out, he'd...
he'd give up and we'd
leave them tied up there.
And we'd drive all night.
They'd never find us.
We tied Mr. Clutter's wrists
to a pipe over his head.
And he... he looked hurt,
so I cut him down.
I... I put a box out there
so he'd be more comfortable.
He asked how his wife and daughter
was and I... I said they were fine,
and they were getting ready for
sleep, and it wouldn't be long tili...
till morning
when they'd find him.
He was just looking at me.
Looking into my eyes.
Like he expected me
to kill him.
Like he expected me to be the
kind of person who would kill him.
I was thinking, "this... this
nice man is scared of me. "
I was so ashamed.
I mean, I thought
he was a... a very nice...
gentle man.
And I thought so right up
till I slit his throat.
I didn't know what I did
till I heard the sound.
Added up,
how much money did you get
from the clutters that night?
Between $40 and $50.
I mean, the truth is,
I’m desperate
to be done with it.
I've spent 4 years of
my life on this book.
They got a stay of executive
yesterday.
Another, yes.
Supreme court.
It's harrowing.
Me, all I want to do is to write the
ending and there's no end in sight.
No, thank you.
"Dear friend Truman,
"haven't heard from you
in such a long while.
"Please help find new lawyer.
"If not,
Dick will have to write
"the supreme court brief
himself.
"Our last appeal.
"What a pair of
wretched creatures.
"Please help.
Your amigo? Perry. "
Just put it with the others.
You know, at least for Nelle
you should...
you should try and pretend
you're having a good time tonight.
I thought
I’d find you here.
Oh, Nelle.
Nelle.
Thank you.
I'll have another,
please.
How are you?
Terrible.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I mean,
it's torture the way...
what they're doing to me.
And now
it's the supreme court.
And can you believe it?
If they win this appeal,
I wili...
have a complete
nervous breakdown.
I may never recover,
and I’ll just pray
that it turns my way.
It must be difficult.
Oh, it's torture.
They're torturing me.
I see.
And how'd you like the movie,
Truman?
Yeah...
I frankly don't see
what all the fuss is about.
Hello.
Mr. Truman Capote?
Yeah.
I have a call
from Mr. Perry Smith
in the Kansas
correctional system.
Will you accept charges?
Yes.
Mr. Smith,
you're on the line.
Hello.
Hello?
Hello, Perry.
They let me make a couple of phone
calls before I go down to holding.
Y- y-you heard the supreme
court rejected the appeal?
No, I... I didn't.
I hadn't heard that.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Yeah. They let me make
2 phone calls.
We got a date set for the
warehouse, Dick and me.
2 weeks and finito.
April 14.
Will you visit me?
Truman?
It's... it's him again.
It is utterly inappropriate
for me to talk to him.
Yes?
I'm sorry,
he won't be able to make it.
Hello?
Mr. Shawn, it's Nelle.
I just got this telegram.
Has he seen it?
He won't read it.
Would you put him on,
please?
Nelle, he won't talk.
Mr. Shawn, if you have to hold him
down and put the phone on his ear,
I need to speak to him.
All right.
Um,
um,
it's Nelle.
Truman.
"Miss Nelle Harper Lee
and Truman Capote.
"Sorry that Truman was unable
to make it here to the prison
"for a brief word
prior to necktie party.
"Whatever his reason
for not showin' up,
"I want him to know that I
cannot condemn him for it.
"Not much time left,
"but want you both to know that
I’ve been sincerely grateful
"for your friendship
through the years
"and everything else.
"I'm not very good
at these things.
"I have become extremely
affectionate toward you both.
"But, harness time.
Adios, amigos.
Your friend, Perry. "
Well, I didn't expect
to see you again.
You can visit
for a few minutes.
Yeah.
No.
5 minutes.
Well, well.
He returns.
I don't know
what you must think of me.
Well, you haven't been
foremost on my mind lately,
as you can probably imagine.
You got the letter?
Yes, I did.
It's true.
I understand why you
didn't want to come.
I wouldn't be here either
if I didn't have to.
You got that right.
You know Ricardo donated
his eyes to science?
Next week, some blind man will
be seeing what Dick used to see.
Yeah, you could be walking in
Denver or somewhere, Truman,
and suddenly these eyes
will be staring at you.
That would be something,
wouldn't it?
It would be. It would be.
You'll be watching?
I don't know, I’ll be...
do you want me to?
I'd like to have
a friend there.
Ok. Then I will.
It's all right.
I did everything I could.
It's ok.
I truly did.
I know.
It's time.
Mr. Capote.
Goodbye.
You're not rid of us yet.
We'll see you
in a few minutes.
I wish I had...
Mr. Capote.
Goodbye.
Nice to see you.
Perry Edward Smith.
For the crime of murder
in the first degree,
by order of the cour
t of Finney county
and the supreme court of the
sovereign state of Kansas,
you are sentenced
to hang until you die.
"I will fear no evil:
For thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me. "
You can say something
if you want.
Is there anybody
from the family here?
No, Perry.
Well, tell them...
I can't remember what I was
gonna say for the life of me.
Our father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread.
...as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
It was a terrible experience
and I will never get over it.
They're dead, Truman.
You're alive.
And there wasn't anything I
could have done to save them.
Maybe not,
but, the fact is,
you didn't want to.