Hey, Ebony!
Ebony!
Open up!
Jesus, Ebony,
get this guy out of here!
There's no more room,
Ebony.
We've got to use this cell.
Cool it, or there'll be trouble!
l'll kill Dagger!
Lula was gonna knife him in
the back, the son of a bitch!
''Was''?
l still will!
Dagger! l'll kill you, you hear?
Stick you like a pig.
Ebony, Lula's freaked out,
says it 's his right to kill Dagger.
Lula needs to be taught a lesson!
Whatever's happened, it 's not for
you to decide, you little shit!
Dagger's gonna die!
Gonna die! Gonna die!
Calm down!
So you think you're gonna decide this,
Pimenta? Come on, then, l'm ready.
Shut up, Dagger!
Gonna die! Gonna die!
Like l said, l've got no one
waiting for me on the outside.
l'm in no hurry to get out.
Anyone wants a fight,
let 's get on with it.
l'll crush all of you.
So what are we
waiting for?
What the fuck's wrong with
you guys?! Let 's cool it, here!
What 's going on, Dagger?
Lula attacked him from behind,
Ebony! He's a bad ass!
-He was within his rights!
-He went for Dagger from behind!
Right out of line, man!
Let 's cool it,
man, calm down!
''Calm down'', my ass.
He's gonna die!
Gonna die!
-You locking me in there, Ebony?
-First get in there, then speak!
-Don't throw Dagger in here, Ebony!
-We don't want trouble.
Get the hell out, damn it!
So? l'm all ears.
How come he's so mad at you?
You heard, Lula came out of nowhere
with a knife and tried to kill me.
l dodged, and we scuffled
till they broke us up.
The rest you know.
Good morning, Mr. Pires.
l do apologize for this
disgusting behavior...
which has invaded
our household today.
Only this idiot Lula, a young,
inexperienced con...
suddenly got this attitude, without
even asking permission!
Dagger killed my father!
He killed my father! lt was him!
l sure did, kid.
And not only him,
l've killed plenty more besides!
Ebony!
Mr. Pires!
Dagger killed my father
in front of my mother.
He's been telling everyone he
recognized her on Visitors Day.
You gonna deny that, asshole?!
Are you gonna deny it? Are you?
Ebony, please.
What?
Tell the kid he doesn't know
half the story. lf he did...
Son of a bitch!
l'll kill you!
Tell him to ask his mother if she
was really as upset as all that.
Or was it a relief when l came
and grabbed his belt from him?
Lies! That 's a lie!
Like hell it is!
l saw it for myself.
He'd have
thrashed her to death!
Hey, Lula!
l thought you'd have
heard by now, kid!
Your mother paid me
to kill your father!
Get it now?
lt was your mother wiped him out!
Hear that?
He's calmed down!
l want them both out
here in their underwear.
Hey, Lula...
as far as l'm concerned,
we're quits.
Let 's forget it, shall we?
You've put me to shame, and on the
day of the doctor's first visit.
So, Lula, what brought
you back in here?
l left here, went home and found
my wife in bed with someone else.
The son of a bitch had the
nerve to tell me, ''That 's life''.
l shot him three times just
to prove the contrary.
You should know that whatever goes
on outside gets settled outside.
ln here,
anyone who behaves...
knows we'll do what we can
to show him the front door...
where his family is waiting.
But anyone who's proud of being
a criminal, with blood in his eye...
we'll do everything to
prolong his life in here!
We usually forget people
like that in here.
Doctor, this is Ebony.
Yes, Doctor,
Ebony's got a problem.
My kitchen knife
is still missing!
Whoever took it,
l'll give you one chance...
return it, or there'll be
one prisoner dead every day!
l'd like to ask our visitors
to turn their backs...
since there's an ashamed
crook present.
But...
when l turn around...
l sure would like
to see that knife.
l'll count to three.
One...
two...
l'm turning...
Three!
-From your kitchen?
-Yes, sir!
This is the yellow wing, Doctor,
because they're afraid.
lt 's like a jail within the jail.
They're locked up here for their
own safety. They're scared.
Career killers, rapists, stool
pigeons, bad payers.
ln here, you know,
prisoners never forgive.
Mr. Pires, don't these people
ever get sun? lt 's so musty!
Anyone want to go outside?
Take a walk in the yard?
Get some fresh air?
Mr. Pires, what do these
people do all day?
They come and go all day long,
think they're busy...
but it gets them nowhere.
Doctor, 7,OOO men in jail!
There are 1,8OO
in this pavilion alone.
lf they knew how AlDS is spread,
that 'd already help.
They catch the disease, then have
sex with their wife, girlfriend...
so there's no stopping
the epidemic.
The only ones who'll listen to your
advice are the really smart ones...
who only want to get out alive
in order to keep robbing.
That 's their whole life.
Maybe. But they're living
at the center of the disease.
They're the prisoners here.
Prisoners? They own this jail.
The only reason...
this place doesn't explode
is because they don't want it to.
God bless you, child.
l didn't know you had a family.
l thought l'd lost it.
My whole life in jail, but even
so, l raised 18 kids...
and not one of them has even been
near a police station.
That girl, my youngest, she said
she no longer remembers my face...
so she's decided
to come and visit.
l'd like you to authorize
me to see her...
on a day other than Visitors Day.
l don't want my daughter
around all the scum.
That 's going to be tricky.
What if the 7,OOO others
ask me the same thing?
Excuse me.
Good morning!
Need anything, Doctor?
Coffee, sugar, chocolate?
Soap, toothpaste?
Joints are only two packs
of Marlboros each. Want one?
-l don't smoke.
-Too bad. Commerce, Doctor!
Makes the world go round!
Easy now...
that 's it.
He can't spit there.
Tuberculosis. Anyone steps
on that spreads the disease.
Doctor, if he had the strength,
he'd go to the sink.
lt 's not easy.
He must be isolated.
But where, Doctor?
-Name?
-Everyone calls me The Beard.
Why are you here?
Well...
my brother was killed.
Two days later, the murderer
had a little meeting with death...
so suspicions fell upon my
good self. Some said l did it...
and others came along and
said they saw it wasn't me.
So what with some saying it was
me and others saying not...
here l am, five years now...
waiting for the judge to decide.
So, Beard, do you have
sex here in jail?
Anyone who denies that is a liar.
Use condoms?
lf l've got one, l do.
-lV drugs?
-How dare you, Doctor?!
l wonder, Beard!
What 's that mark on your arm?
Beard's next!
My name's Alipio.
Do you use drugs?
Needles?
No way, Doctor, l got AlDS from
all the ass l've had in jail.
Plenty of ass.
ls it still worth
taking the test?
l listen, give advice, a little
tenderness, hold them tight...
and then they always give us
something nice in return...
a pack of cigarettes, some candy,
a slice of cheese.
So many men shut up
in here, Doctor...
without our feminine support.
Yeah, l've got AlDS, Doctor,
but l didn't get it in here.
l brought it in off the streets,
Doctor, and l can't complain.
You come in here sick and they
treat you with respect, dignity...
and that 's the greatest thing
in a crook's life.
l'm a junky and dealer.
ln my business, if a guy doesn't
pay up, l can't take back...
what l sold him. The bastard's
already smoked it, snorted it.
l take whatever he's got, and
if he's got nothing, l kill him.
The other day, l tried to get an
extra banana from the guy who...
delivers lunch. The bastard
said only if l kissed his banana.
So what the hell,
l'm just crazy about bananas.
Doctor, everyone in my cell's
got this itch. lt 's unbearable.
Scabies. l'll give
you some medicine.
So how are you getting along?
Doctor, after shooting cocaine
in the dark with a blunt needle...
drawing blood with this rig
is hardly fair play, Doctor.
Too bad!
-Who are you?
-l'm the Doctor.
l was in the infirmary
taking blood samples.
Just ask...
Oh sure, like you have
to tell me who to ask!
l'm calling the duty officer.
Wait here.
lf no one can identify you...
you're staying
right where you are.
Don't take it personally, Doctor.
lt 's their job to escape
and mine not to let them.
Doctor!
You coming back?
I knew many of those men hadn't
shown theIrvIctIms any mercy...
but socIety has its judges.
And Iwasn't one of them.
At the same tIme,
what dId I have to do with aII that?
I had two choIces;
forget or go back.
Take a deep breath.
-Smoker?
-Just cigarettes, Doctor.
-No crack?
-Never.
Sleep well?
Hardly, Doctor.
The mind never stops...
what with one guy trying
to settle a score outside...
another collecting a debt,
another trying to dig a tunnel.
And there goes another day.
You still got much time to do?
A few more years.
-And why did you come here?
-Legitimate self-defense, Doctor.
That lands you
in jail nowadays?
lt did in my case.
Here's what happened, Doctor.
lt was Christmas, the bells
ringing, snow in the windows.
Me, Bristles and Fatso arranged
to do a jewelry store job.
Neat work, Doctor.
Never even fired a shot.
The problem was later.
How are we going to split it up?
Fatso and l will make three
piles, and you choose first.
Son, not now.
Get out! Go on!
You fucking moron!
We're splitting the loot...
and you come at me with
your hand covered?
lt 's his own fault he died.
What the fuck's going on?
So you shot him in the heat of
the moment, but we'd agreed...
for me to shoot you,
so we could take your share.
So shoot!
Go on, fire away!
l can't, damn it.
Give me your rod.
Oh my God!
Being betrayed by your buddy for
nothing, Doctor...
like Judas, the guy who
spat in the face of Jesus!
So how does the story end?
lt ends with me in here,
before your very eyes, Doctor.
Fatso was arrested
in under two months.
Doctor, ever seen a fat man
being beaten?
They even spill stuff they
weren't asked.
A man was killed here.
Did you see anything?
No.
Jesus, Fatso, you turned
me in for Bristles' murder!
You could have just squealed
about the robbery.
l fingered you for murder
because Bristles' brother...
was going to kill me.
We left his place together
for the jewelry store...
then l came back alive,
and he got back dead.
l'm very upset.
l could turn you in as
an accomplice...
but l won't.
l'll back your story up...
l killed him and threw him
in the river all by myself.
Thanks, Ebony!
l knew l could count on you.
l'll forgive you,
but you owe me one.
And did Fatso ever pay his debt?
No way! Fatso died
trying to escape.
They spent two years
digging a tunnel.
Let 's go, come on!
Go on, Fatso.
Hurry up you big pile of shit!
Cadao! Give me a hand!
l'm stuck.
Breathe in, man.
Suck yourself in.
What do you mean?
l can't!
Go back, then!
Go on!
Gimme a break, Cadao.
Pull, go on, pull!
Shit, Fatso, l told you! Eating
everyone else's leftovers!
Pull, go on!
-Please!
-Get him out the way!
Fatso's frustrated
brothers knifed him.
Hell of a way to die,
eh Doctor?
Right under the Virgin Mary, and
not even she could protect him.
Too bad.
What about this pain?
Your problem, Ebony, is stress--
what big shot executives get.
Take one of these before bed.
They'll help you sleep.
lf you don't get better,
come back.
God protect you, Doctor.
Doctor, come and see Chico's
balloon, quick!
lt 's the old man's obsession,
Doctor.
Oh, too bad.
May l?
Hi, l'm Lady.
Lady Di.
l've come to take the test.
Please, take a seat.
First l'd like to ask you
a few questions, Lady Di.
l've seen this movie before,
Doctor.
l've never needed
a blood transfusion...
and l never pierce my veins.
The only drug l use is
a joint now and then...
when l watch
TV or for a little romance.
And partners, how many?
Oh, about 2,OOO.
May l?
Lady, the silicone you
used isn't meant for that.
As if l had the money for
something better, Doctor.
Ever taken hormones?
No way!
Hormones are dreadful!
You take them and
nothing happens.
And what our clients really like,
maybe you know, is to play the girl.
Well, Lady...
l think the time's come for you
to find out whether you're sick.
l'll do it, Doctor.
-Will it hurt?
-Not much.
Get out of here.
Get out, man!
Any room in there?
Sure.
Only it 'll cost you 2OO.
Pay for a bed?
l'm in jail, man!
So you lived for free
on the outside, did you?
lf you want to stay,
sleep on the floor.
Deusdete ain't sleeping
on no floor.
He already has a place.
Deusdete...
just like l said,
right brother?
You ended up doing something
you shouldn't.
And the rat?
l smashed it against
the wall about ten times!
Damn thing wouldn't let go!
Sweet Mama, pray for me!
lt died?
Like hell it did!
So l grabbed it tight and stuck
my teeth into its brain.
Then l just brushed my teeth,
and that was that.
Easy, man!
You've been beaten with iron bars
and never made a sound.
Cut your finger, Highness?
Jesus, Lula, smoking crack?
You can't operate like that!
Sorry, Doctor, only l operate
better when l smoke.
What?! You can't keep
a steady hand on crack!
Ah, that 's where
you're wrong, Doctor.
l see the veins all
shining and fluorescent.
Looks like that casino
in Las Vegas!
Take it easy, man!
See, steady as a rock, and hardly
a millimeter between stitches.
God protect you, Lula.
God bless you, God bless you all.
That 's enough of God, Highness,
you're not kidding anyone!
What, you married twice?
Well, Doctor, to me life's
a merry-go-round...
and just the one horse
isn't enough.
That one there, that 's Dalva's,
my princess!
Honey, score a goal for me?
Please?
Like it?
Yeah, l bet you do.
Do you believe in love
at first sight?
What?!
Come with me. l'm going to ask
your parents for your hand.
Get out of here!
You don't even know me!
-You're wrong!
-Wrong? You don't know me!
Sure l do.
l know you just love spicy...
-Sausage...
-Sausage!
And l know you look gorgeous
in that pretty dress...
And l know you deserve better
than that klutz over there.
-My fiance!
-Fiance?!
You're wasting your time.
Look what a great blend!
We'll have one kid of each color.
l'll be waiting in the car.
Were you serious?
Never been more.
What the hell's going on, Dalva?
What are you doing here?
Go on, go away, will you?
What?! Honey, who is this?
-l'm her husband.
-Husband?
Sure. We're marrying.
Don't grab me like that!
Stop it!
Get out of here, go on!
See?
lf he were in love with you,
he wouldn't have run off!
Jesus! Letting some
guy steal his girl!
Tomorrow at eight,
get your family together...
and l'll ask for your hand.
l'd rather my daughter were dead
than marry a thieving nigger.
You offend me, sir.
You've only just met me.
l know enough to know you're
nothing but a lazy nigger!
-Look here, sir, l came here...
-Forget it!
You're too old to be
falling for some black man.
Get down there!
Go on!
Easy now!
Down you go.
Come on!
I marrIed her rIght there.
I took my Iove with me ;my bIack
fIst In hercotton-white hand.
Best thing that could have
happened to me, Doctor.
Dalva gave me a family.
So you stopped stealing.
Of course not, Doctor! With her
by my side, l went up-market.
Took imported cars and
drove them to Paraguay.
With cash in my pocket, l returned
to the peace of home life.
Any kids?
Three with Dalva.
And one with Rosirene.
You know how it is, the devil
only tempts those close to God.
That ever happened to you?
Uncontrollable passion?
What 's with the babe over there?
What do you think?
She's over there.
Don't you dance samba, miss?
What am l, a monkey jumping
around for nothing?
Looking for something
to jump to?
Seems like you're the one wanting
to jump-- jump ship.
Look, l'll take my wife home.
Get your bikini, and
l'll come and fetch you.
We'll go and spend the
weekend at the beach.
Does that sister know you
belong to me?
Ease up, Dalva!
l was only going to the john!
Like hell you were. And that,
why's that so hard then?
Doesn't look like it 's being
properly cared for.
Watch your mouth,
you stinking black bitch!
Get away from my man,
or you'll be sorry!
Hey, handsome! So l guess
the beach is off, then?
So what happened
to the black girl?
Ah, now that 's where l had
to do a bit of juggling, Doctor.
From Monday to Thursday, Dalva.
And the rest, Rosirene.
l rented a little room for us
near the old bus station.
We had this great love affair
going, Doctor.
Morning!
Give me that!
lt 's mine!
Stop, you're messing me up!
Don't let go of me, Highness.
Don't let go!
Thanks, Powder, see you around!
You just can't quit this life,
can you?
l thought l told you
l'd take care of you.
l've always earned
my own money.
And that guy you were with,
know who he is?
What are you doing here?
l thought it was Snow White's day.
Don't change the subject!
You know who he is?
Sure!
So what?
So l told you-- do your
thing if you have to...
but don't screw a friend of mine,
or l'll break your neck!
Powder's your friend?!
Highness, you're a nobody.
He said that when he leaves
his wife, we'll move to Miami.
-l'm off!
-Where to?
To Miami, honey!
Well you're taking a souvenir
of mine with you!
That was rough, Doctor,
screwing a friend of mine...
and the two of
them making plans!
That night l went back to the
room and what do l see?
Jesus...
get out of here!
No way.
Get out of here right now!
l won't go.
Get out, damn it!
No way, l'm staying.
Come on, Highness, bite me.
Come on, bite me...
bite me the way l like it.
Bite, go on, bite!
Bite harder...
harder!
lt 's over!
There, that 's so you learn
not to take what 's not yours!
You arsonist bitch!
Slut!
Well, you might as well know that
this slut is expecting his child.
No!
Son of a bitch whore!
l'll kill you!
You haven't heard
the last of this, Highness...
you son of a bitch whore!
Son of a bitch!
Get your hands off my son!
To keep DaIva out of troubIe,
I took the bIame forthe fIre.
Only the law was already
on my back for other stuff...
so l got 16 years for the fire,
reduced to 1O.
And was it worth it?
But Doctor, the black chick put
a spell on me. l'm outta here!
Therefore,perfectIy caImIy,
we shaII overcome the nIggIIng...
IrresponsIbIe and IyIng attempts
to InvoIve the government...
and presIdent In accusatIons
by faIIures who onIy survIve...
through statements
Impregnated with jeaIousy...
fabrIcatIons and resentment.
TIme wIII reveaI the absurdity
of these attempts...
and the Iaw wIII punIsh
those truIy responsIbIe...
forthe IrreguIaritIes, for any
wrongdoIngwhIch took pIace...
and the creators of the faIse
accusatIons.
Letter from Franci?
Your sister mention me at all?
Course she does, right?
Hey, Deusdete! What does
your sister say about me?
She asks if you're okay.
That all?
What do you think? lf she knew
what you've been up to...
she wouldn't even be asking that.
l think she would...
but you think you know better.
Wasn't it you used to say,
''lf you sell it, don't use it''?
May l?
So what 's up?
Come to settle your debt?
Hey man, right now Ezequiel's
in a tight spot.
So he thinks to himself,
''Zico's a reasonable guy...
He'll take the surfboard
as collateral for the debt.''
Then Ezequiel can have another
little rock of crack, right man?
Wrong!
Pay what you owe!
Don't drink that, it 's blood!
Shit!
l thought it was water.
Doctor, this guy was
sweating all night long.
l've put him on antibiotics,
but if you ask me, it 's no use...
it 's AlDS.
Doctor! Doctor!
Who took away his oxygen?
l don't want to die.
Get me out of here, please!
That 's hardly likely.
He's 213, rape.
To us he's a patient.
Doctor...
send me
to the yellow wing.
l need to get somewhere safe.
l don't want to die!
l'm sorry, Doctor,
l'm against the death penalty...
but not for rape.
lf you ask me,
it 's just too bad.
So that 's it, Doctor.
Come on, old man,
it 's past lock-down.
Get a move on!
What is it, what
are you looking at?
You think your kids will jump
over the wall?
You were asking for it this time,
weren't you, Chico?
See you in 3O days.
Doctor, we're here to make
our relationship official.
You understand,
Doctor...
so we can be more open.
lt 's not the same with a rubber.
There's not much sense,
her taking the test and not you.
See? l told him, Doctor,
but he's scared.
-Scared of what?
-Scared of injections.
Too Bad?!
lt 's not that.
So you're scared
of getting married!
Doctor, you're needed, urgently!
Down you go, come on.
lt 's all right now, Doctor.
l blacked out, Doctor.
Giving us all a fright, Zico?
lt 's just as well, Doctor.
Maybe he'll learn what drugs do.
Tell him!
What 's there to tell?
Drugs kill.
-And you, who are you?
-That 's Deusdete.
We grew up together.
You know, Doctor, one day
my mom didn't come home.
l was left alone.
l waited and waited...
until he and his sister,
Franci, came...
and took me to live with them.
We grew up together.
Come on, Zico!
Wait, Zico!
Help! Help!
lt was Zico saved me, Doctor.
That 's right, Doctor, l've always
looked after him, from early on.
Then you went the wrong way.
Doctor, what 's wrong with buying
some dope in Pernambuco...
and selling it to folks
who like it?
lt wasn't even that much!
Another two years, and l'm free.
But l've never killed anyone.
Unlike Deusdete, here.
What was your crime?
Answer him, Deusdete!
To tell you the truth, Doctor,
he's not even a real criminal.
So what are you in here for?
One night, l was at home...
when my sister arrived,
acting strange.
What 's wrong, Franci?
What happened?
Franci!
Franci, what happened?
Open up, come on!
What happened?
What happened, Franci?
Tell me!
What happened?
There were two of them.
They grabbed me...
lifted my skirt...
one said he wanted to suck me.
l told him to go suck his mother!
-What did they do to you?
-They beat me.
What else, huh?
What else?!
-That 's all, Deusdete.
-Who was it?
l just ran off!
Hey, Zico!
Deusdete! What are you
doing here, man?
l need to talk.
Excuse us.
ls Mother all right?
lt 's not her. Some guys
messed with Franci.
What did they do to her?
Nothing much, she says. But l
reported it to the cops, anyway.
The cops?! You think
the cops'll do anything?!
The problem is, the guys found
out, and now they're after me.
Leave it to me.
l'll sort them out.
No, Zico. Not your way.
l don't want that.
l just want a gun,
to defend myself.
Take your pick.
Even with a gun, Doctor, l never
thought anything would happen.
But...
it was my destiny.
And theirs,
when they found me.
So! Where's the stool pigeon
off to tonight, then?
l'm not looking for a fight.
Let me go home!
Sure thing, but first we're
going to caress you...
just like we did
your little sister.
Hey, man!
Give me a Coke.
You know how old l'll be
when l get out of here, Doctor?
Forty-eight!
There!
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight!
Found it!
So it 's Visitors Day, is it?
lf you like, you can go now.
Ebony...
l've got a problem.
l need to talk.
This problem got a name?
Ezequiel.
He still owes me, and now he's
even trying to get more on account.
He comes to my cell, raises his
voice, what 's he playing at?!
-And you?
-Me?
lf l don't get paid,
l can't pay Highness.
l want your permission
to kill the bastard.
This goes on much longer, l'll
start losing respect around here.
Cool it!
l'll tell Ezequiel to get
the money from his family.
lf he doesn't pay,
you can go ahead.
This man has already lost a lung...
and the other's in pretty
bad shape.
Take the medicine, man, go on.
See, Doctor?
He won't take it.
What are you, a kid? You won't
get better if you don't take it.
Come on, that 's right.
Come on.
That 's it.
Right.
Good.
And on the outside?
What did he do?
We used to rob armored trucks.
Just the two of us, we planned
everything, remember?
Doctor, we'd spend six months
just gathering information.
We'd even make friends
with the guards' families.
And that paid off?
Sure, plenty.
Although we'd
only use half the money.
The rest we'd put aside
for a rainy day...
or to bribe the cops.
lt 's coming.
Right, get over there!
Come on!
Stop!
Come on! You going to sit there
on top of other people's money?!
lf you don't come out, it 'll be
too bad for your widows.
Open that door,
for Christ 's sake!
Come on, get out!
So we paid off the others...
and each went his own way,
back to the family.
So anyway, Antonio,
what 's on your mind?
Miro...
your wife's cheating on you.
With a cop.
Says who?
Says no one.
l saw her.
They were making out
in a squad car.
Near the old bakery.
Dina doesn't buy bread there.
Miro, l saw her. And it
wasn't bread she was after.
Celia...
is Antonio Carlos gay?
What a question, Dina!
l'm sorry, but he made
up this story...
and told Miro l've been
going out with a cop.
Like hell l made it up.
l saw you crawling all over him.
You nibbled his ear, damn it!
Then it 's me he's really after,
honey.
You forgot the best part:
how you asked me to run away
with you and dump Miro...
and that l turned you down
because l love my husband...
and your wife's my friend!
Liar! Evil slut!
Miro, you don't believe
that bitch, do you?
Man, how many jobs have
we pulled off together?
And our agreement!
Celia, see if you can't keep
your man around the house.
l don't want him pestering
me in the street anymore.
Miro!
Miro...
Bastard! You dirty bastard!
You've never fooled me...
l always knew you
had a crush on her.
Can't even respect your best
friend's wife, you dog!
-Calm down.
-Dog!
Miro, l'm telling
you the truth!
l lost my friend and partner.
The first robbery without him...
there were so many cops, Doctor,
it looked more like...
-a military parade.
-What about him?
l only found out when
he arrived here.
l thought l'd gone to hell,
Doctor, but him?
Come here, come on.
Come here.
Miro, don't you think
it 's time you quit?
Take what you've got and start
a decent life someplace else?
Give the kid a better chance.
Stop!
Police!
Party's over, Miro!
l'll cut you in. lt 's cheaper
for me to cut you guys in...
than give it to a lawyer.
You don't get it. We're taking
the lot. Everything.
Hand it over, the dough,
come on, quick!
Too bad, a smart guy like you
trusting his own wife.
Some guys are born
to be cheated on.
Are you all right?
Doctor...
do small kids remember
everything we do?
No, not a thing.
Doctor...
let him go.
And with you now,
our untamed diva of dance...
the woman who lives in all
thieves' hearts...
here at the Detention Center...
the one and only
Rita Cadillac!
Hello!
l know you all fool around
a lot, right?
But do you take care
of yourselves?
Our friend the doctor
came here today...
and he's taught me enough
to teach you, too, right?
That 's right!
Okay, so some of you are
careful, and others forget...
so l'm going to teach you
what to do.