Police on scene
are approaching the suspect.
This chase started
at approximately 1:30 a.m...
...in the Mercer Island area...
...and has ended here
at Pearl Street Bridge.
--responding to a 911 call...
...in an apparent carjacking
by an African-American male.
--name is Lisa Reane...
...youngest daughter of
Congressman Richard Reane.
Suspect has been
preliminary ID'd...
...as John Curtis, who's wanted
for armed robbery, drug--
Shots have been fired.
We have shots fired.
The suspect and
his hostage are down.
Police are moving in.
If you chose to believe
a traitor's testimony, fine.
But in the same situation,
I'd do it again.
I'm not gonna apologize
for doing my job.
I'm not gonna
apologize for doing my job.
Simply put, just
because you're a cop...
...doesn't mean the laws
don't apply to you.
It's not the wild, wild West anymore.
Not the wild, wild West anymore.
Wild, wild West anymore.
That's 5 and....
Everybody get the fuck down!
Get out of here!
Let's get moving! Move! Move!
Get off that chair,
you stupid bitch! Let's go!
Get off the phone!
Put the phone down!
You people move forward!
Move! Move! Move!
Get out your phones!
Get out your cell phones!
In the bag!
That you don't wanna do.
Shut the fuck up.
Oh, y'all picked the wrong day
not to use the ATM.
Get down.
Do what you're told when you're told...
...you may live.
But I make no guarantees.
-I'm in.
-You, up.
-You, out.
-Let's go. Move.
Your security system, you can
electronically seal off the entrances.
Yes. Right away.
Fabulous.
Oh, what a wonderful attitude.
You and I are gonna
get along just fine.
It's done.
-We're locked down.
-Smashing.
Gonna be late for work.
Fire in the hole!
-What do you think you're doing?
-Fucker set off the alarm.
Don't you think it would have made
sense to shoot him before he set it off?
Probably.
Jesus. All right.
The alarm's been tripped.
We're on a clock.
Let's get these people out of here.
Next time, if you're gonna
do something, do it right.
This is Detective Galloway.
Gonna have to go back that way, sir.
Back that way.
I want all points of entry
identified and covered.
Nina, you need SWAT here now.
Have emergency crews standing by.
Didn't take them long.
Come on, man.
-Set a perimeter. Move them back.
-How far?
Portland.
Detective Callo.
Hey. Got him on the line.
-We're on.
-This is Detective Callo, Seattle P.D.
-Who am I speaking to?
-No questions.
I'm in control of this facility now.
Complete control.
Nobody gets in or out
without my say.
I will execute
every man, woman and child...
...if my needs are not met.
All right, don't test me.
-I'm a man of zero tolerance today.
-I'm listening.
All right. Well, try not to
screw this up, huh, detective?
I only have one demand,
and one demand only.
Do you have a warrant?
I need to speak to you, Quentin.
That's where you're shit out of luck,
because I don't need to speak to you.
It's important.
Do you live in a barn?
That's Detective Shane Dekker.
Doesn't look like much of a detective.
I could say the same about you.
-Charming.
-Shane just transferred from Tacoma.
-You might be interested to know--
-Save your breath.
I really don't care.
Just get to what's on your mind.
We got a hostage situation
over at American Global...
...and he won't talk
to anybody but you.
-No shit?
-No shit.
So we need you to do this.
Why should I?
Because people's lives are at risk.
Yeah, like the kid said.
Say I did wanna help, I'm suspended.
Or did that slip your mind?
Well, as of right now,
you are back on the force.
-Just like that.
I won't, however, unleash you alone.
Always a catch.
Shane here is your new partner.
You can consider him
a younger version of me.
How nice.
-You'd have been with your partner--
-Ex-partner.
On the unemployment
line long time ago.
You know, for a moment,
I thought you cared.
Where are you going?
Yep. I'm here now.
I'll let you know.
-Could we have a few words?
-Yeah. I'll give you two: Blow me.
Need a follow-up comment,
let me know.
-Terrific.
-Talked to him about 9:30.
Nine-thirty. All right, 9:30. Okay.
Teddy, Vincent, nice to see you both.
Okay, so Conners has been reinstated
to full active duty, and it's his scene.
Last time this guy headed
a hostage situation...
...an innocent civilian died.
I was not responsible.
Well, you never are.
That girl would be alive today
if it wasn't for your cowboy antics.
You destroy lives.
Well, look who's talking
about destroying lives.
I seem to remember that's
your fucking specialty, Callo.
Ladies, please.
I was first on the scene,
and I have seniority.
-Decision's been made, Bernie.
-Don't do this, Martin.
Don't cave in to this guy.
Bernie, I need you to take a hike.
All right? We'll talk about it later.
Fine.
I'll watch the train wreck from home.
Bye, Bernie.
Okay, SWAT,
because of special circumstances...
...we'll defer to Conners.
He's in charge.
First I heard SWAT defer to anyone.
Now, I want you to do the folks
in the bank a big favor...
...by proving me very wrong
about you, okay?
Oh, that's an order.
Anything questionable happens today,
I wanna know about it, okay?
Yes, sir.
Looks like you got yourself
a babysitter.
We have approximately
four to seven heavily armed men...
...holding an unspecified
number of customers...
...and employees hostage.
You're just a wealth of knowledge,
Vincent.
Their only demand so far
has been to speak to you.
Get me a line into the bank.
Let's see what they want.
Okay.
Well, well, well.
If it isn't Detective Conners.
Who am I speaking with?
Well, for now, call me Lorenz.
Okay, Lorenz. How we doing in there?
Get you anything?
Food, medical supplies perhaps?
We heard an explosion.
Everyone who matters is fine.
Of course, I would have preferred
the authorities not be involved at all...
...but since Seattle's finest
needs a presence on the scene...
...I'm glad it's you.
-Oh, well. My fame precedes me.
-Don't be flattered.
I needed to have someone who's been
through this experience before...
...because, detective,
I plan on living a long, full, rich life.
However, I am surprised
that they found you so quickly.
-I thought you were suspended.
-I was.
But I'm back. Your information's old.
You never get what you pay for.
Well, I guess you wanna know
about the hostages?
Yes.
There's approximately 40,
and they're doing just swell.
Well, all of them except one.
Someone's dead?
Theory put to practice
isn't always perfect.
You can't keep the hostages in check
if you let a bad deed go unpunished.
They might just randomly revolt.
Chaos has some order to it.
What else will I be looking for?
Demands.
Wouldn't be too much to ask for you
and your colleagues just to bounce?
Safe to say.
All right. Well, you just stay
by the phone, and I'll-- I'll contact you.
-Hey, wait, Lorenz.
-Don't worry.
I don't have any plans
until sunrise tomorrow.
Relax. It's gonna be a long one.
Hey, come on, Lorenz.
This conversation's not finished.
Patience, detective. Patience.
We don't want this to be another
Pearl Street Bridge, now, do we?
He's out.
This standoff
is reaching two hours now.
We've been told detectives have
made contact with the perpetrators...
...but whether specific demands
have been made, we cannot confirm.
When we're in the know,
we'll let you know.
I'm Karen Cross live
for Channel 2 news.
Where's our fearless captain?
He went uptown to brief
the commissioner.
And you're here in his place.
-What's that?
-Nicotine gum.
-You quit smoking?
-Caffeine, too, if you must know.
-What? A man's capable of change.
-Yeah.
-Don't worry. I still have a vice or two.
-Detective, 15 rings. No answer.
Try again in five.
-What are they doing in there?
-Wasting our fucking time.
Precisely.
He knows police protocol, not to
mention the shit in our own precinct.
He's disguising his voice.
Probably means he's got a record
and has done this before.
Dropped that hint about sunrise.
He's buying time.
-Why?
-He's trying to figure out his move.
-He wasn't expecting us.
-He wasn't expecting you.
He said he thought
you were suspended.
Probably thought it'd take all day
to find me, giving him time he needs.
-He's stalling.
-He almost has what he came for.
We're going in.
-Where is the SWAT commander?
-I'll find him.
That's a big call.
You thought about what you're doing?
-Are you questioning me, Teddy?
-Unfortunately, yeah.
Well, I question how you can fuck
that asshole...
...and still manage
to look in the mirror.
Look, the hostages
are in imminent danger.
They've confessed to killing. That's
an automatic murder-one charge,
Life sentence,
a needle for all of them.
So why keep witnesses around
to testify?
The longer we wait, the greater
the risk. We need to go in. Now.
Quentin.
-So, what we got?
-Snipers up top.
Ten soldiers on the ground.
-What's the best way in?
-Tear gas. Blow the doors.
Hey, hold on. No explosives.
We got 40 civilians in there.
It's too great a chance.
Any other way?
No. There's no pussy way in.
The doors are locked electronically
from the inside...
...and we ain't getting in
without force.
What if we cut the power?
That'll disable the system.
We can open the locks manually,
go in that way.
That'll work.
So we'll take the pussy way in,
commander.
Cut the power
and we go in at 11:15 sharp.
The banks are equipped with
generators. Once the power's down...
...they'll kick back on
in approximately three to six minutes.
Be over before then.
-Commander, your men in position?
-Standing by.
Call for the power to be cut.
Once down, wait for my signal.
Nobody moves until I give the go.
Understood?
Yep.
You, come here.
Come here.
Come on. Get up.
No!
Will you just shut the fuck up?
Here they come.
Stand still. I said don't move.
Okay, let's go around the horn.
-One, check.
-Two, check.
-Three, check.
-Four, check.
Here we go.
Cut the power.
What?
Now.
Hey, hold on. Hold on.
What just happened?
Holy shit.
Shit. Come on, guys.
Let's get a move on.
-We're moving in.
-Stand the fuck down, commander.
-It's a trap.
-No, you stand the fuck down.
-This is my show now.
-Repeat, do not go in.
On my count. Three, two, one.
Move!
Go!
Round up all the hostages!
Anyone that comes out, you grab
them! Every single one of them!
Got the emergency crews over here.
Secure the area.
Medics! Paramedics here!
Anyone in the bank!
-You see anybody come your way?
-No. No one went by us.
Detectives, we found these.
Gloves, masks, vests.
We let them walk right past us.
Fucking beautiful.
Okay, we-- We got the one teller dead.
The two that were strung up, they're
alive, but they're in critical condition.
Few of the SWAT took burns,
but that's the worst of it.
Depending on who you talk to, there
was between five and nine perps.
Nobody saw them, because
they were wearing their masks.
I got Dax collecting
all the security tapes...
...so that's at least gonna
give us a firm number.
Want background checks
on every hostage.
They're all suspects until they're not.
-Excuse me.
-Yeah?
I need to hear that conversation
between Conners and Lorenz.
-Well, you'll have to wait.
-How long?
An hour, maybe more.
Can you show me
how to play it myself?
Now, look, it doesn't work this way,
okay?
I don't take orders from you.
I don't know you
and no one touches my stuff, okay?
You'll have to wait. Excuse me.
What the--?
What the hell are you doing?
Are you ADD?
Along with whatever they stole
and this war zone they left behind...
...a man's dead
and the killers are running free.
I don't have time to wait. I'll figure
it out myself. Thank you for your help.
Okay, wait. No. Just-- No, no, no.
This is a dat recorder. You know what
that is? Digital audio-tape.
It's just like a regular tape player,
right? Play, stop, rewind.
The headphones jack straight in.
Tape's already inside. All right?
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Just don't break anything, okay?
So everyone's been cleared out
at this point except for those two there.
What about this one?
That's a camera in the vault.
It got blown in the first explosion.
And here comes....
That's when you cut the power.
So we can't ID them.
There's a four minute, 52-second gap
before the image returns.
Yeah. They're long gone by then.
Go to the tapes when they went in.
Document each move made...
...for the two hours they were inside.
Oh, hey. Awful lot of news cameras
outside.
Maybe one got a good look
at them coming out.
Have Vincent check it out.
Conners, better come out here.
Oh, shit.
Feds.
Detective Conners.
Join us, would you?
Someone's dead?
Theory put to practice
isn't always perfect.
You can't expect
to keep the hostages in check...
...if you let a bad deed
go unpunished.
They might just randomly revolt.
Chaos has some order to it.
Prince Amar Al-Aban is one of the
wealthiest and least popular Arabs...
...in the Middle East. There's been
threats, but for better or worse...
...he's an ally to the United States.
Last month in Charlotte,
North Carolina...
...the Crown Valley Bank was hit.
Prince had a safe-deposit box
there too.
-So, what was in the box?
-We don't keep records.
Boxes are private.
Since 9/11, we screen for
live tissue, viruses and explosives.
If it passes those tests, we don't ask.
Look, this is fascinating shit.
What about the money?
Bank robbers still like cash,
don't they?
Cash drawers don't appear
to be touched.
Neither does the cash vault.
So they broke into a bank
and didn't steal any money?
We believe the prince's box was the
target. We're trying to reach him now.
Sir, may I have a word with you,
please?
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
I'm curious.
Are you familiar with the term
"franchise-sized fuckup"?
What, this is my fault, huh?
I'm beginning to understand why
they wanted to deal directly with you.
You think you're smart, Quentin,
but, man, are you stupid.
-You got played.
-Oh, that's not fair.
Everything was according
to standard procedure.
You came to me. I didn't ask for this.
The commissioner's office
is scrambling to make sense of this.
If they need a scapegoat,
I got zero problem serving you up.
Thought so.
You wanted this to happen.
Good God, I did not.
If it had to be somebody....
Theory put to practice
isn't always perfect.
You can't expect
to keep the hostages in check...
...if you let a bad deed
go unpunished.
They might just randomly revolt.
Chaos has some order to it.
I think this Lorenz was
trying to tell us something.
Oh, really? You don't say.
The way he spoke.
He paused before certain words.
Have you ever heard
of the chaos theory?
Edward Lorenz invented
the chaos theory in the 1960s.
It's the study of phenomena
that appear random...
...but have an element of regularity...
...which can be described
mathematically.
Try that again.
Pretty much, initial state of events
may seem unrelated and random...
...but eventually a pattern emerges...
...and in the end,
all the pieces fit together.
Anything else, officers?
No, that'll be all. Thanks.
So you're a college boy.
Which one?
Someplace I've heard of...
...or one of those inbred
state schools no one's heard of?
U. Dub.
So it's the latter.
How'd you end up on the force?
It's kind of the family business.
Oh, your dad's dad and so on back?
Listen, do we really need
all this "get to know you" crap?
Couple of hours ago,
you didn't give a shit.
You've grown on me.
Besides, I'm entrusting my life to you.
I should know something about you.
I would think you'd like to know
a little about me.
I know about you, detective.
Everyone does.
You don't say that
with much enthusiasm.
Not much to be enthusiastic about.
Listen, my reputation
often precedes me.
You, however, have no reputation
at all, a fact I need to deal with.
If you've been through the shit I have,
then you can judge me.
Now, we can try to work together
and make the best of a bad situation...
...or we can compare
dick sizes all day.
It's up to you.
Since this is your first day here,
today, mine's bigger.
Conners, come in.
Go ahead.
I got something
you're gonna wanna see.
Lastly, I don't like the Pac 10.
It's overrated.
Come over and see this.
Detective. Just can't stay away
from me, can you?
Can you roll, please?
Yeah, Okay. Right there. Perfect.
Damon Richards.
Career loser. I busted him
a couple years ago...
...on attempted robbery.
Stupid bastard never learns.
What's he doing back on the streets?
He gave up his partners
and cut a deal with the D.A.
Got an address?
The only thing on file's in Spokane,
but I think I remember...
...that he had a girlfriend in town.
Gina, I think.
Gina, it's the police. Open up.
Step back. Now.
Gun!
Shots fired. Officer down.
We need an ambulance and backup.
Oh, shit.
Are you hit?
I'm fine.
I got her.
I got her. Stop, Gina.
Teddy!
-You like that, huh?
-Yeah.
I'm a police officer.
That guy's a murder suspect.
I need your bike.
What?
Go ahead, dude. It's all yours, man.
Look out!
Son of a bitch.
I want my fucking lawyer.
Fuck your lawyer.
He's unconscious but stable,
with a nice knot on his forehead.
-Three officers are watching the room.
-He wakes, they call.
Hey, Quincy, come on.
Give it a rest. I'm fine.
Quincy was a coroner.
You might be bruised,
but you may have a cracked rib.
You should get to a hospital.
Should do a lot of things.
You sure you're all right?
I'm fine.
Gina Lopez, 28, done time
for possession, has two kids.
Am I interrupting?
No.
Excuse me.
Gina claims she doesn't know
anything about a bank robbery.
Of course she doesn't.
-Vincent.
-Yeah?
Have them put Miss Lopez...
...in interrogation one
and turn the AC on full.
Let me know when her nipples
can cut glass.
Sorry, detective. I didn't--
When we first met,
I didn't realize who you were.
I worked with your dad briefly
right after I got out of the academy.
It was an honor.
Thanks, Vincent.
Father was Harry Dekker.
Detectives, ready for you.
Somebody going on a trip?
Looks like it, don't it?
You're looking well, Marnie.
Heard you were back, Conners.
Keep dreaming.
You, on the other hand:
-Hi. Marnie.
-Shane.
You know, I got a bike myself.
Maybe we can go for a ride.
Or maybe I could just ride you.
Can we get back to work now,
please?
We have passport, suntan lotion,
Bermuda shorts, thong bikini--
Hopefully hers.
--and this.
Must be 50 large, his cut.
-You'd think, right?
-It's not?
Well, don't put words in my mouth,
but two things jump out at me here.
First of all, every bank
has their own money bands...
...and these are not
American Global's.
After checking, we find they belong
to World National Financial.
-Sounds familiar.
-Months ago, half a million dollars...
...was stolen in an armed robbery
there, smash-and-grab job.
But they caught the guys.
They recovered about 400,000.
Now, they've been in jail ever since
and their trials are still pending...
...so that brings me
to point number two.
Smell that.
-What is that?
-When evidence comes in...
...any physical contact
can make it hard to lift prints...
...so now to mark the bills...
...we spray a scented
solution directly on them.
-Is that new?
-Yeah. Wave of the future.
You try and keep up with the times,
eh, Conners?
So this money's not from our bank.
Oh, no. No, this money's from
the World National Financial job...
...and our evidence room.
For a list of things
you can put in my mouth.
Conners.
Do you remember who headed up
the World National case?
I think it was Callo.
Why?
Oh, no reason.
Just thinking out loud. Come on.
When you said it was your family
business, I didn't realize.
Guess I just didn't connect the dots.
Don't worry about it.
Your father was a hero.
Yes, he was.
First I thought maybe you
were related to the captain.
No. No relation.
We found the money, Gina.
The money was Damon's.
That money came
from our evidence room.
I told you, I know nothing
about a bank robbery.
Whatever Damon was into,
I know nothing about.
So where were you going?
Vacation.
This isn't possession
or solicitation, Gina.
This is felony murder one.
If you're protecting him,
you'd get life.
I didn't do nothing.
It's "I didn't do anything."
"Didn't do nothing" is a
double negative, infers the positive.
The grammar
in this country's terrible.
Look, this isn't going away.
You wanna walk out of here...
...with some semblance of a life,
you tell me something.
I'm done talking.
I want a lawyer now.
Fine. Then it's two phone calls
I'll make.
The first to the
public defender's office.
The second will be
to children's services.
What?
Simple. You insist on a lawyer,
I'll take your kids.
Wait. You can't take my kids
away from me.
What do you care? You were ready
to fly the coop with shit-for-brains.
Fuck you!
You can't treat me like this!
I have rights, you know.
You can't take my children
away from me!
I can and I will.
Just tell me what I wanna know.
-Not exactly useful information.
-You believe her?
I think for the first time in the girl's life,
she's telling the truth.
Once she asked for a lawyer
anything she told us...
...would have been inadmissible.
Yeah? Who would've known?
Would've been her word against mine.
And who do you think
the jury would have believed?
Justice by any means,
even if you cross the line?
The only line around here
is the blue line.
You cross that one,
then you got problems.
Ask Callo.
He knows what I'm talking about.
Those serial numbers
Marnie faxed me...
...according to our computers,
that money should be downstairs.
Moving on to basketball...
...Sonics defeated the Trailblazers
last night, 85 to 72.
Buzz us in.
Gotta sign first.
Heard you were back.
Kind of liked not having you around,
Conners.
Have another doughnut, Harry.
That fat fuck is the sole guardian of the
city's greatest source of contraband.
Drugs, weapons, cash.
Millions just sitting here for the taking.
Yeah, but you'd have to have
some major firepower...
...not to mention an extra-large set of
balls to knock off the police station.
Not if you're a cop.
Could just walk right in and...
...take whatever you want.
Here it is. Line 17.
Bernie Callo.
No one takes anything out
of here unless they sign for it.
So, what?
He showed you a warrant, what?
He must've.
What, lost your fucking memory,
Harry?
You know how many times someone
signs shit out? I see the same guys.
I can't remember one instance
from two weeks ago.
If that's his signature,
that means he signed for it.
Take it up with him.
The money from Richards' place
traced to the World National heist...
...a case Callo headed up.
Bernie signed the money out
of evidence himself two weeks ago.
How much?
Four hundred and thirty-three
thousand dollars...
If it is Callo, it would explain
how they knew police protocol...
...and how our department operates.
Explains why he was
pissed this morning...
...about being replaced by Conners.
He doesn't need another
reason to be pissed.
What about motive?
-Do we have one?
-Pressure.
Could have been getting to him.
He's been getting a big cold shoulder
from cops...
...since he testified about Pearl Street.
No. I don't buy that.
He was also getting divorced.
About a month ago, he told me
he and his wife might be splitting...
...asked if I knew a lawyer
who wouldn't clean him out.
I didn't think it was this serious.
I don't know. Bernie's a first-rate cop.
He was a boy scout, for chrissake.
This just doesn't
make any sense, guys.
They never do, captain.
Come on.
The facts speak for themselves.
No, they don't.
Why, if Callo's involved--?
Why didn't they ask
for him at the bank?
Jenkins.
And you arrived home at what time?
Mrs. Callo, do you feel okay
to continue?
Yes, I'm fine.
Just a few more minutes.
Wife came home approximately
45 minutes ago, found him here.
None of the neighbors
heard anything.
There was no forced entry...
...and no one saw anyone
else fleeing the scene.
Guys, blueprints from the bank.
There's pictures, schematics.
There's at least a dozen Internet
articles on the Saudi prince.
So that's it.
You've reached the Callo residence.
No one can get to the phone.
Please leave a message.
Detective Conners.
Are you starting
to connect the dots?
Putting all the pieces together?
Is the pattern starting to emerge?
They wouldn't punish you...
...but I will.
Vengeance will be mine, detective.
Then come and get me,
you piece of shit.
What they told Callo was the plan
and what the plan was...
...must have been
two different things.
Obviously this wasn't part
of a plan Callo would've agreed with.
You'd think a cop would be smarter.
Come on.
As cops, we come across...
...every temptation in the book.
Money, drugs, power.
We all like to think we can resist
any urge, but we're not saints.
So Callo was involved,
and now they're dragging you into it.
-Why?
-Man said he wanted vengeance.
Piss anyone off lately?
Me?
So I just got off the phone
with Agent Doyle...
...and apparently after
the Charlotte break-in...
...the prince withdrew
all his possessions...
...from every safe-deposit box
in the country.
-They didn't touch the cash.
-No.
-Or the safe-deposit boxes.
-Nope.
So they break into a bank,
blow it up, and steal nothing?
Still make sense to you?
Nothing about today makes sense.
Excuse me.
Return to the earth now...
...if your mind is troubled
and your heart is uncertain...
...for it is by returning to the beginning
that we can clearly see the path.
He's your find.
Detective, wanna say that again?
We go back to where this all started.
We go back to the bank.
The tapes are confirming five bad
guys, but since the vault cam blew...
...what they did in there
is a total mystery.
I've been through these tapes
20 times. I'm telling you--
Shut up, Dax.
Wait. Hold on a second.
Do you see that?
-See what?
-Go back a little.
-What?
-Look closely at the camera angles.
They're all fixed, right?
They don't rotate or pan.
Okay, play it.
Now, Camera 8 dominates our
attention because of the explosion.
But while that's happening,
check out Camera 2.
Where are you going?
Changed the angle.
Watched it 20 times, eh, Dax?
What's in that corner
they don't want us to see?
So are you at all concerned there's
some wacko trying to get you?
If I worried about every threat made
against me, I'd never leave the house.
Watch your eyes.
Lots of prints here.
Check them all. Anyone's got a record,
I want an ID.
You got it.
-Dax.
-Yes, sir?
You hack into this?
Hack into a nationwide
bank security system?
Yeah, I'd love to.
Hang on. Hang on.
So, what do we do
in the meantime?
Do you like Italian?
As if we didn't get in the way.
You never know with you guys.
What was that thing you were saying
at the house...
...about returning to
the beginning path or something?
Yeah, it's a Buddha story.
We're all ears.
One day, the Buddha
found his heart in turmoil...
...so he retreats to the forest,
to the earth...
...to the base of a great tree.
And I'm paraphrasing...
...but this elephant comes up
and tells Buddha...
...he doesn't like
seeing him discouraged, and....
He can talk to an elephant?
He's the Buddha. He's attained
the sixth level of consciousness.
He's capable of communicating
with plants, trees, even rocks.
Rocks.
-You asked.
-Come on, guys. Please. Continue.
The Buddha was troubled.
He goes to the beginning.
He goes back to where he came from
to find the path, the answer.
So when you hit a dead end...
...go back to the beginning
to find your way.
Or something like that.
We have a genuine philosopher
in our midst.
Are you--? Are you a Buddhist?
No. Just something
I picked up along the way.
But you're religious?
Not particularly.
Excuse me.
-You guys are all pretty tight?
-We've been through a lot together.
-Yeah.
-I guess I just thought--
I don't know.
With him being in so much trouble...
...coming back from the suspension,
everyone might treat him differently.
You can't really believe
what you read or see on TV.
I mean, if anything,
our tie to Quentin's gotten stronger.
Even when things
got pretty wild today...
...and everybody else panicked,
he was in control.
Now, that just doesn't happen.
He's just-- He's that good.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
I realized something today.
Being around you,
all that's happened, I can't--
I think I made a mistake.
It's too late.
You made your choice.
Now live with it.
They got a match.
-Got a name?
-Chris Lei.
Prick used to work for some big-time
software company...
...till they caught him
pirating programs.
Couple of years later,
he was busted for hacking...
...into the pension plans
of retired cops.
I'd say for a genius,
he's a fucking moron.
This was your case, you and York.
You made the bust.
Why didn't it stick?
We were in the middle
of the Pearl Street fallout.
His lawyer put us on trial,
said we were crooked, abusive...
...and that we planted evidence.
Jury bought it.
Was it true?
The guy was guilty. He was scum.
That's the truth.
There's something
they don't teach you.
The system breaks down,
you have to compensate to get results.
That gives you the right
to break the rules?
Bend, not break.
It means justice absolutely.
Another thing they don't teach you.
Come on.
Shit.
Fare thee well, Chris.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
Shit.
That should do it.
You can put your shirt back on.
Look at that. First day in the city,
and you've already been shot.
Just grazed him.
Why don't I just graze you
with a bullet, see how you feel?
Hey, Damon Richards's awake.
Take five, guys.
Hey, Damon.
How you feeling?
What? No flowers for me?
We got you dead to rights
on murder and armed robbery...
...and you're there cracking jokes.
-You fucking idiot.
-Fuck yourself.
Detective.
May I?
You remember me, don't you, Damon?
Thought so.
Now, we're only
gonna give you one chance.
One chance to tell us what we need
to know and help yourself.
Really?
Just one chance?
I was skiing about three years ago
in Aspen.
Beautiful country.
You ever been, Damon?
Never mind.
I hit a mogul...
...landed on a sheet of ice,
and slammed into a tree.
Broke myself up pretty bad,
kind of like you did today.
I was in a hospital bed
for three months.
Had it not been for--
Here it is, morphine.
Without this stuff,
I wouldn't have made it.
This I.V. drip administers
a small dosage every minute or so...
...makes you feel nice and relaxed,
calm, no pain...
...but...
...if I were to inject this whole thing,
that'd be all she wrote for Damon.
This equipment malfunctions
all the time, Damon.
Overdoses are quite common.
Besides, I don't think the DA's...
...gonna launch a full-scale
investigation over a scum like you.
You don't have to tell us anything.
Plead the fifth.
Roll the dice.
Okay. Okay. I'll talk.
You're a fucking hypocrite.
Question my interrogation skills?
At least I don't threaten them
with a lethal overdose.
There's never been a case
in recorded medical history...
...of someone overdosing
on 5 ccs of saline.
Bend, not break.
That's what you said, right?
Damon Richards testifies that
Lorenz's true identity is Scott Curtis.
He's wanted in connection
with three other bank robberies...
...extortion and kidnapping.
He's also the brother of
John Curtis...
...the perp Conners shot
on the Pearl Street Bridge.
We have the names
of two accomplices...
...Lamar Galt and Xander Harrington.
Everybody was supposed to
meet up tonight at 10...
...and we have that address.
Now, after finding Callo and Lei
dead today...
...doesn't take a rocket surgeon
to figure that Curtis is eliminating...
...his accomplices one by one.
Doesn't matter what he told
Galt and Harrington.
He's planning on
finishing them off tonight.
Never think of the repercussions.
Suspect's mother, father, brother.
How your decision affects them.
Had murder in his eyes.
John Curtis?
It was pouring, lights everywhere.
If he had only done what I said:
"Drop the weapon."
But it was not to be.
My dad died when I was 12.
He walked into a liquor store
in the middle of a holdup.
Guy just opened fire.
He didn't even have time to react.
They said he was a hero.
Know what that means
to a 12-year-old?
Because he dies on the job,
he's a hero?
Never made sense to me.
So why become a cop?
Finish what he started.
Every day, he went out
trying to do some good...
...tried to help the people
who couldn't help themselves.
"Just give them a chance,"
is what he always said.
Didn't always work out, but he tried.
You tried to help
save that girl on the bridge.
If you weren't there,
the girl still would've died.
-How long we gonna sit here?
-I don't know.
Come on.
It's 25 after.
How much longer we waiting?
We go now, all we get
is Galt and Harrington.
Want Curtis.
Now relax and keep the line free.
Fucking prick's driving me mad.
Shit.
-What?
-I'm out of gum.
-Look, man, call him. Okay? Fuck this.
-Shut the fuck up, all right?
I'm not sitting around here
all fucking day, man.
We can't let him walk.
We gotta go now.
No. Stand down.
We bust him now, we got something.
We let him get in that car,
we got jack squat.
We got three cars and uniform backup
in all directions.
If they ride, we'll reel them in.
I want Curtis.
Nobody goes into the house
until I say.
He ain't answering.
Gotta be fucking out here.
-Turn it off.
-Shit!
Trigger-happy sons of bitches.
All units, shots fired! Officer down!
Send an ambulance!
Take them alive.
-Take the back, Shane.
-Got it.
Teddy.
Oh, my God.
Jesus.
Drop the gun.
Last warning.
Get out of the house!
Get out of the house now!
Get down!
Hey, where's Conners?
Back up that line.
Little more?
-Okay.
-Need more morphine?
No. Yeah. Be great. Thank you.
Get that entrance in the back.
Check it out.
It's just-- It's-- It's hard to take.
I mean, you know, if it had to happen
to somebody, well....
Oh, you son of a bitch.
Teddy?
You've always been jealous
of him, Martin.
Jealous?
It's because he wasn't just
a better cop, he was a better man.
Detective, go home.
Is there something you wanna say?
No, sir.
She said it perfectly.
You okay?
Conners was right.
We should've never gone in.
How fucking dumb are we?
Detective.
I know what they were doing
inside the bank.
Here's a record of transactions
from the bank.
An average day produces
about 3- or 400 pages, give or take.
Today there were over 3000 pages.
Meaning?
We've just witnessed
the largest bank heist in history...
...about a billion dollars.
Come again?
They planted a computer virus.
It randomly withdraws money
from all the accounts...
...and deposits it
into the bad guys' account.
Now, if you look at all the transactions,
no two amounts are the same...
...and none of them are over $100.
You see, most security systems
work on the size of the money...
...not the amount of transactions...
...so you wire out a million dollars
from a handful of accounts...
...red flags pop up...
...but wire out less than $100
from, say, 10 million accounts...
...no red flags.
-Where's the money now?
-I don't know.
What do you mean you don't know?
Well, the virus set up a host
of phantom accounts, right...
...where the money sits
until it transfers to another account...
...and another and another.
It's never in one place long enough...
-...to get an accurate fix on it.
-The money's moving around?
Yeah. Any withdrawal or deposit
from any bank...
...doesn't normally go through
till the next business day...
...so all these are just gonna float
around till 9 a.m. tomorrow.
-Or 6 a.m. Pacific time.
-Sure.
Sunrise.
Why break in? If they're wiring money,
couldn't they do that from anywhere?
No. See, that's the regional manager's
computer terminal.
From there, you have unlimited entry
into the bank's mainframe...
...so there's no more working
around passwords, no hacking in.
It's straight in, nice and clean.
A billion dollars is missing,
and we're only discovering this now?
Ironically, when you guys
shut off the power...
...it helped hide the virus
and bought it time to work.
They weren't trying to make it look like
they were robbing to rip off a prince.
They were making it look like they
ripped off a prince to rob a bank.
Chaos theory.
What you gonna do now?
I think this is beyond our jurisdiction.
-Hello.
-Detective, there's a call for you.
-Says it's urgent.
-Put it through.
Good evening, detective.
My compliments on a fine day.
You are an unexpected
and challenging adversary.
-It's not over yet.
-Wishful thinking.
No, my wish is to catch you.
You're a murderer,
a cop killer at that.
I didn't kill anyone
who didn't deserve it.
Callo was insignificant...
...and Conners, he deserved his fate.
I know about the money.
You steal a billion dollars,
they will find you.
A risk I'm willing to take.
Sir.
It doesn't add up.
What doesn't add up, detective?
Why would he say
Callo's insignificant?
Who?
Lorenz. Curtis called me.
Really?
He said he didn't kill anyone
who didn't deserve it.
He said Callo was insignificant,
but he wasn't.
Without Callo, he doesn't have
the knowledge of the department...
...or the front money
to hire the crew.
-Curtis called you?
-Yeah.
Well, now he's screwing
with your head.
You did good today, Shane.
Father would be very proud.
Get some sleep.
Be more bad guys
for you tomorrow.
I was in bed already.
This couldn't wait till tomorrow?
Sit down.
How did he come after you? It's the
only thing that doesn't make sense.
What are you talking about?
All day long,
we thought Callo was the dirty cop.
All day long, we were wrong.
Here's the sign-out sheet
from the evidence room.
Here is one of Callo's reports.
Here's another one...
...and another one.
They're not the same signatures,
Harry.
They're not even close.
Maybe he got a cramp in his hand.
I don't know.
Here's your file.
You were reprimanded
one month ago...
...when you confronted Callo
outside the courthouse.
You punched him.
-That ring a bell?
-And I'd do it again.
Cops who testify against cops...
...shouldn't be breathing
the same air I do.
-There's a line you don't cross.
-So you set him up.
You forged Callo's signature...
...you gave him money
and you helped him with his plan...
...because you thought
he got the raw deal...
...and don't deny it because I know!
Of course he got a raw deal
at Pearl Street Bridge!
Everybody got a raw deal!
You're helping a cop killer, Harry.
You're a year
away from your pension.
-Is this how you wanna go out?
-My conscience is clean.
This has been a very long...
...day.
And I'm tired, Harry.
It's like we're chasing
a phantom here.
Just when we have him...
...he disappears.
He's been two steps ahead
of Conners and me all day.
Of course he has.
Who knows Conners
better than him?
How the hell does Curtis
know Conners better than anyone?
We're not talking about Curtis,
are we, Harry?
Who would know Conners
better than anyone?
Who would you protect?
And who in your mind got the raw deal
at Pearl Street Bridge?
Drop the weapon!
One more step and the girl dies.
That you don't wanna do.
Think about it.
You kill her, where you gonna go?
It was York who was the dirty cop.
He assumed Scott Curtis' identity
to throw us off the trail.
York plays his old partner,
knowing all his moves.
Cut the power.
Now.
Frames his enemy for the crime.
Kills him too.
Look at this.
Blueprints from the bank.
There's pictures, schematics.
There's at least a dozen Internet
articles on the Saudi prince.
And pulls off one of the biggest
robberies in history.
You do what you want to me.
He called me to tell me he's going
and you ain't gonna find him.
Watch me.
The number that York used to call
Harry Hume is his cell phone number.
Ran it through
all the service providers.
-Nextel got a match.
-Can they get a location on him?
Should trace his location
within 100 meters or less.
-Great.
-Oh, hang on.
Hello.
Got him. Excellent. Thank you.
That'll be 8.48, please.
Keep the change...
...doll face.
Thanks, mister.
Jason York, this is the police.
Put your hands in the air
and get down on the ground slowly.
-Do it now.
-Don't shoot, okay?
Just be cool. Okay.
Get down on the pavement.
You win.
Oh, Jesus. Okay.
-Get down on the pavement now.
-Look, I'm cooperating, okay?
I give up. Be cool, okay? All right?
-You win. I'm putting my hat down.
-I didn't ask you to.
Put your hands
where I can see them.
I said I give up, all right?
Final warning.
Take the back.
Was it Harry?
-It was Harry, right? Oh, that fat fuck.
-Drop the weapon and let the girl go.
-It's over.
-Nope.
If you wanna bring me in,
you gonna have to work for it.
That you don't wanna do.
Well, isn't that interesting?
That's exactly what I said to him.
I mean, do you see the irony here?
You see it? Or am I the only one?
Two months ago
I was in your shoes.
Yeah, standing there
with some punk...
...holding a gun
to an innocent girl's head...
...asking myself,
"What should I do?"
What would you do?
You'd do exactly what I did.
You'd try to make a difference.
Let's roll, baby.
Everybody out! Get out!
-You all right?
-Yeah. I'm fine.
Which way did he go?
He went towards the pier.
You really screwed yourself.
Jenkins is gonna expect these kind
of results from you every day.
FBI's got a team of 40 technicians
working on Lei's virus.
They'll break it.
Your conviction would be admirable.
It's just that it's so sad.
Get it through your head, man.
The cavalry ain't coming.
No, no.
No hero's coming to save the day.
Oh, no.
The bad guy wins
at the end of this story.
But I have to admit, though.
You have turned out to be
quite the little thorn.
I think Conners
would be sorry that you died.
Not me.
Come on.
I have come too far to be denied.
We used to spend all day Sunday
just reading in bed.
I would read the paper.
He'd read one of his
thousand books.
I didn't deserve him.
I knew that...
...but I still loved him.
Did we all get shot today?
Yeah, they said the city
would be busy.
Every day like this?
Yeah, pretty much.
Great.
I wonder what's next.
Excuse me.
So how much?
Do you really think
I'm gonna charge you after all that?
-Go on.
-Thanks.
Smell that?
What is that?
Well, when evidence is taken in...
...any physical contact can affect
our ability to lift prints...
...so now to mark it, we just spray a
scented solution right on the bill.
Lastly, I don't like the Pac 10.
It's overrated.
Where is it?
Shit.
This Lorenz is trying
to tell us something.
Really? You don't say?
You ever heard of chaos theory?
Edward Lorenz invented the
chaos theory in the 1960s.
It's the study of phenomena
that appear random...
...but have an element of regularity...
...which can be described
mathematically.
-Try that again.
-Pretty much, initial state of events...
...may seem unrelated and random,
but eventually a pattern emerges...
...and in the end,
all the pieces fit together.
You tried all of them?
Nothing for Conners or Lorenz?
I don't know.
No. Maybe--
Maybe he's not on a flight.
Try again...
...but try Gleick, James Gleick.
I need to know if passenger
James Gleick has checked in.
One moment.
We're gonna have to check.
Quickly, please.
Hello.
There's a passage
in the Surangama Sutra...
...which roughly translated means:
"Things are not what they appear
to be, nor are they otherwise."
Conners.
Think about that a minute.
Doesn't that blow your mind?
What gave me away?
Ten bucks.
Fuck. The diner. That's right.
And it was Harry that gave up York.
Harry and a phone call.
He called me, said that Callo
was insignificant...
...threw up all kinds of red flags.
That wasn't him.
That, my friend, was my mistake.
I called you.
No, my wish is to catch you.
You're a murderer,
a cop killer at that.
I didn't kill anyone
who didn't deserve it.
Callo was insignificant.
You know, York always thought
the plan was flawless.
If he'd only done what I said instead
of going off the deep end like he did.
I told him you have to leave room
for error.
You know, you can't always predict
how things are gonna play out.
A random camera catches
an image of Damon Richards.
The scent on the money.
You.
The chaos theory.
When you got that, I was impressed.
All day long we were trying to
figure out who the inside source was.
It was you.
Surprise.
What if we cut the power?
That'll disable the system.
We can open the locks manually,
go in that way.
That'll work.
A billion dollars is missing,
and we're discovering this now?
Ironically,
when you guys shut off the power...
...it helped hide the virus
and bought it time to work.
Yeah, Teddy's pretty devastated
about your death.
She'll get over it.
Get down!
Hey, where's Conners?
So the corpse in the morgue
with your name on its toe?
Scott Curtis won't be bothering
anyone again.
You're a serial killer.
Oh, yeah? Well, who got killed?
Curtis, Harrington, Galt, Lei.
All fucking hoods.
World's safer with them gone.
You said they were all hoods.
What about Callo?
Callo deserved his fate.
It's his fault.
So this is all Callo's fault.
If it weren't for him, York and I
would never have done this.
One random act causes another,
causes another...
...and in the end, the pattern emerges.
That is the chaos theory.
Oh, look at that.
It's after 6. The money's cleared.
I'm a wealthy man.
Lei, for all his evil,
was one smart son of a bitch.
The feds will be tracing false leads
for weeks.
You tanked Lei's trial on purpose.
They should have suspended me
after I testified.
What did they expect?
So why not kill me?
You had plenty of opportunities.
This wasn't about killing, Shane.
This was about standing up
for what matters.
Besides, you kind of grew on me.
-You're not gonna get away.
-I already have.
I'm not even here now.
This is a very valuable lesson
for you to learn.
-It's good you have learned it.
-Yeah? What's that?
You don't always win.
All your years of service for nothing.
You're a hypocrite.
I'm an opportunist.
I would have gladly died in the line
of duty, but they took that away.
They'd been as faithful to me,
none of this would have happened.
The system broke down.
Good luck, detective.
It would have been an
interesting partnership.
But I have to go now.
Conners.
Attention, please.
Final call. Flight 1182 to Mexico City
now boarding at gate 23.
Enjoy your flight.
Thank you.
I'll let the captain know we're ready.