subtitle edited by - Aorion -
"Chappie" color font ^ (video time 002:00:19)
Man 1:
Historically,
when we look at evolution,
it's not surprising that uh...
Chappie's left turn uh.. happened.
Man 2: It's too early to tell
how this is all going to play out.
I didn't believe this would
happen in my lifetime,
but it is happening.
Woman 1:
Downtown Johannesburg.
Man 1:
It's a dangerous city.
Man 2:
Each day, more than 300 murders
and violent attacks
take place here.
Woman 2:
2 officers have been killed,
3 other have been taken to the hospital.
Woman 3:
A bloody end to a shoot-out
between cops and robbers.
Another man in blue dead.
Today, we usher in a new day.
One that represents
the end of crime.
Man:
Move in. Lock on target.
Fire! Fire!
Police chief:  The end of corruption.
Man:
Go! Go! Up against the wall!
Scout 1:
On the ground.
All targets neutralized.
Police chief: And the start of the rebirth of our city!
[Whistles and applause]
Welcome to the world's
first robotic police force.
Johannesburg, South Africa,
became the focus
of the world in 2016
with the deployment
of the planet's
first all-robotic police units.
Crime levels plummeted, and
Tetravaal stock skyrocketed.
Certain parts are brought in from China,
but all robots are assembled
right here in South Africa.
The biggest fear the population express,
was vulnerability to hacking.
Tetravaal assures this is not
something to worry about
with their bulletproof
guard key system.
A system which allows them,
and only them
to update software
on the robots.
Before the success  of the
ubiquitous human-sized police robots,
there was a bigger bad boy
on the block: The moose.
Vincent Moore is a weapons designer
and a former soldier.
He has a fundamental spiritual issue
with artificial intelligence.
I have a robot that is
indestructible.
It is operated
by a thinking, adaptable,
humane,
moral human being.
Cooper:
The hypervalence neurotransmitter
converts the human operator's thoughts
into the robot's actions.
A parture from the artificial Intelligence
that governs the scouts.
Now with interest from the
U.S., China and north Korea.
The scouts' creator, Deon
Wilson, sees a rich future.
What really interests me
is high-level AI.
True intelligence. A machine
that can think and feel.
Interviewer:
Is that the mandate at Tetravaal?
To take that evolutionary step
forward
and build something
truly alive?
Uh...
[Over pa]:
Scout 22 arriving now
at maintenance bay 6.
Man 1: Team 1, off deck.
Man 2: Hurry. Open it up.
Woman: Get him out.
Man 1: Load it up! Load it up!
Man 2: Got it? He's pretty banged up.
Man 3: We just examined the scout.
Man 4: Let's go, let's go!
Man 1: Come on. Ready to go.
Oh...
Christ's sakes
See this 22 uh?
Luck of the draw.
They used him as a speed bump.
Look at this.
It's like he's cursed or something.
Every time he goes out.
Now, yeah, it's his ear.
Antenna, right.
Can we switch this out?
Woman 1:
Check that circuit again.
Man:
Terminal on 7 and 7a.
Woman 1: Now, go start with zero, zero.
[Over pa]:
Reports of gunfire in sections 5, 7 and 8.
Okay, fire it up.
Police request all available scouts
to be mobilized immediately.
Destination or task?
Helipad.
Yup.
Hey, 22.
Just watch yourself this time, eh.
Affirmative.
- Amerika : Hey! This ain't good, man! We're in shit!
- Yo-Landi : Duh. We in shit, Amerika!
Pitbull: I said it was a bad deal.
-Pitbull: I said it over and over.
- Ninja: Everybody, just chill!
Just... Yes, we have a problem.
And, yes, I'm gonna solve it!
Pilot:  Command, we are searching for suspects
driving a gray vehicle.
Ahh...!
Man: Hey...
They're here...
- What's up with this shit?
- He looks pissed.
Hippo.
Listen, some shit went down.
Wasn't our fault.
Your weapon.
Ah...
Fuck's sakes.
And your keys.
Man:
Come on.
Hippo:
Open the back.
Oh...!
Hey, hey, hey...!
Yo, yo,
yo, yo...
[Whistles]
We're lucky to be alive,
hippo.
Hippo: Ninja.
You know there's no way out
of this.
There's always a way. Please be calm.
Just name your price. We'll sort you out.
My price?
Is 20 million.
- Oh, come on man. That's ridiculous.
- What...
- ... the fuck?
- Jesus Christ.
Fuck.
How am I gonna pay that back, dude?
Ah man.
Get on your knees.
- Hippo: Now, get on your fucking knees!
- Okay, okay, okay.
You owe me...
20 million.
Say it.
[Muffled]
I help you...
- Pitbull. Pitbull!
- Man 1: Get back!
Get back! Get back!...
Jesus Christ, man.
Hippo: Seven days!
You got seven days.
Man 2: Droids!
Droids!
Ah man.
You were followed!
Man 3: Get behind the wall!
- Yo-Landi, get in the van, get in the van.
- Shit.
Yo-Landi: Let's go!
Ninja: Get in!
Man 4:
Hit the explosives!
Pilot:
They detonated some kind of explosive.
Man 5:
Shit! Droids!
We  can't get a clear shot.
Touching down.
Scout 22:  Moving out.
Ninja:
Who took the keys?
Yo-Landi: You gave it to that guy!
Pilot:
Human officers are on the ground.
Let's go!
Move!
Move out!
Move out, 22.
Go, go, go!
Scout 22: Drop your weapons.
You are under arrest.
[Gunfire]
Break right!
Go, go, go!
Come on...
Where are the keys?
Cue, on my left!
Man: Kill these cops!
Move!
Back! Back!
Yes, yes.
Drop your weapons.
Go!
Hey, poes!
I need my keys, please!
Ninja: Fuck you!
- Officer: Drop your weapon.
- Fuck you.
Officer: Drop your weapon!
- Fuck...
[Grunts]
Fuck!
Come on.
Show em.
[Scanner beeping]
Shit! He hit the rotor.
We need to touch down.
Ninja:
Thank you very much.
"22...
Going in."
[Grunts]
[Powering down]
- SCOUT #0022 OFFLINE -
Tech:
Droid 22 is down, sir.
Bravo 1!
We need backup!
Dispatcher:  Copy that.
We're sending droids to your position.
Ah!
Amerika! Amerika!
- I've got the keys!
- The keys.
- Hey, Landi, he's got the keys!
- Let's go. Come on.
Scout:
Get out of the vehicle.
Yo-Landi: Go!
Yo-Landi: Let's go!
Do not run.
Ah...
- Are you okay?
- I'm not okay! I'm hit!
Man:
Scout 22 is non-responsive.
Send an evac team.
TV reporter:
This is yet another victory
for the robotic police force.
This marks the 30th large-scale
crime ring smashed this year.
- Woman: Good morning, Deon.
- Deon: Morning.
[Bell dings]
Michelle:
People.
if I may have your attention,
please.
The police chief just called me
to place an order
for another 100 scouts.
This is very, very good news.
Man 1: Way to go!
Man 2: Deon.
Man 3:
Nice job!
- Man 4: Well done, dude. Well done.
- Man 5 : Way to go!
Man 5: Congrats, D.
Thank you, man.
Man 6: Well done, Deon.
Woman: Great.
Woman 2: Congratulations.
Thanks. Thank you.
Woman 3: Good job.
Nice job, buddy.
I  couldn't have done it without you.
I know.
Man 7: Congrats. You're awesome.
Man 8: Nice job, mate!
[Phone ringing]
Is this the "I feel sorry for Vincent"
phone call?
- Don't worry, Vince.
-  Well, I am worried.
Well, look,
we have one more stab
with the police tomorrow.
Just keep trying to get those costs down.
Try to think positive, okay?
- Chin up.
-  Kind of hard to keep your chin up
when you keep
cutting my funding.
20 percent this year,
25 percent last year alright.
I've got work to do
on the moose.
You know I've got work to do.
The threat detection is still in its...
- ... elemental phase.
-  Threat detection is completely superfluous.
The operator
detects the threat.
-  Then we send the moose out.
- Send... Send them...
Enough already.
Cut.
Not add.
-  Okay?
- Yeah. I'm on it.
Woman [Over pa]:
Deon Wilson to the workshop.
Okay, I need to go.
Yeah, okay. I'll talk to you in a bit, thank you.
[Signal beeping]
Think it's my little boy in again, eh?
Looking surprise,
surprise.
Every time when he comes in.
- He's a bullet magnet.
- What's going on, guys?
Here's the report.
It's 22... again.
RPG,
direct to the chest.
See a lot of the internals
got damaged in the explosion.
Yeah,but the brain architecture's
still intact.
Regardless,
just write it off.
Okay um...,
let's salvage the cpu.
We could try to cut
the battery out.
It's still fully charged,
still stable.
No, not worth the effort.
Droid 22 written off.
Crush the shanty
and recycle the alloys. Yup.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
Easy, easy, easy.
Ninja: Come, come, come.
Into the lair.
- Amerika: Careful, man.
- Yo-Landi: We need to stitch his shit up.
[Yelling in foreign language]
[Phone ringing]
Yo.
You think you got away!
No, I didn't think that,
Hippo.
But, you think you don't owe me
this money anymore huh?
Because you think
I'm in a prison or what?
We'll get your money.
Hippo.
Maybe I come to your secret
place in Soweto.
I come there with the fellows.
I take what I want.
It's cool.
One week.
Seven days!
-  Ninja: They didn't catch that poes.
- Yo-Landi: What?
He knows
where we live.
He says we got a week
to come up with his money.
How are we gonna do that huh?
Come on, that's ridiculous.
We need one final job.
I'm talking about serious cash.
500 million rand.
Okay?
We pay that animal.
We pocket the rest.
And we get out
while we still can. Boom.
Amerika: What are you getting on about,
a bank job?
No.
- Ninja: Cash in transit.
- Amerika: What?
- Yo-Landi: That's what?
- Ninja: A heist, Yo-Landi.
If we do a heist. The droids are gonna
come down on our asses, okay?
- They're going to hit us harder.
- It's true.
Guys, we need..
Like a remote.
- Like a switch.
- What? Excuse me?
Okay,
the robots are like machines, right?
Like a TV.
So if we had a remote
to switch it off...
- That's brilliant.
- Yo-Landi: We need to find the guy
who makes the robots
and steal his remotes.
[Keys jingling]
Dexter?
Hello, Deon.
Welcome home.
Have you been a
good boy today?
Yes, Deon.
Yeah? Did you clean my room?
Your room has been sterilized.
Nice.
Are you working on your artificial
intelligence program tonight?
Yes.
I will activate the kettle.
Okay.
Um...
Hello again. Uh...
So it's... day 944.
I'm extremely close now.
I mean there's always chance of error,
And... I'm aware of this.
But statistically speaking,
I think I might be on track.
I have several terabytes of compiling
and coding to do and then...
... we shall see.
All right. See you in a bit.
[Hip hop music
playing over speakers]
Look. That's the motherfucker.
Ninja: Him?
Dude, it's gonna be so easy.
We need those remotes,
my man.
We need those remotes.
Red bull!
Yes, Deon.
Red bull.
Mm...
Ahh...
Okay.
[Sighs]
[Groans]
Come on.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
What if you change the...?
[Beeps]
Oh!
- It's stable.
- Is everything okay?
It's...
It's stable.
My god.
I think I've cracked it.
Of course, to really know,
I must test it  on a live system.
I must test it.
All right.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Whoa, whoa.
Hey.
Hey!
- Hey.
- How's it, sir?
- Where's the scout?
- What?
The scout, man,
22 for demolition.
Oh, the guys are prepping the compactor.
It goes in soon.
Oh, thank god.
Um...
- Don't destroy it yet, okay?
-  Yup, sure sure.
- Just wait for me, but don't destroy it, okay?
- Yup.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Mm-hm. Morning, Deon.
All right.
Let's have it.
What are you proposing now?
Ma'am, I think I've cracked it.
The world's first proper,
full artificial intelligence.
This is a computer system that
might be smarter than a human.
I could show it a piece of art,
and this thing, this being,
could judge that art.
It could decide if it liked it.
It could write music and poetry.
Okay. Stop.
Please, Deon.
Do you realize you just came
to the CEO of a publicly-traded
weapons corporation
and pitched a robot
that can write poems?
Well,
if you just let me explain--
Deon, Tetravaal is very
happy with you.
The scouts are a huge success.
Ma'am, look,
it won't cost you anything.
There's a droid downstairs that was written
off yesterday, smashed beyond repair.
All I'm asking for is that
you let me install this on it.
- Please just let me test it.
- No. No, I'm sorry, Deon.
You know how insurance works for those,
all the red tape
and the paperwork.
- Thank you for your time.
- Mm-hm.
Woman [Over pa]:  All new employees, please
report to human  resources for orientation.
Deon:
Shit.
Hey, bill.
Man [Over pa]:
Attention. Attention.
Remember to have your security
pass visible at all times.
Worker:
Hey. Can you give me
a hand over here?
[Lock beeps]
[Grunts]
Come on.
Thank you.
Ninja: Yep.
Showtime.
What's up, homes?
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey...!
Please!
Hey, what is it?
This is you getting hijacked,
my friend.
Welcome to Joburg.
And these are all part
of what makes the moose unique
And I think perfect for you
at the police department.
The strategic ability to be able to
neutralize the enemy's targets.
High-value targets:
Radar installations,
aircraft,
fuel storage locations.
Aircraft?
Yes, sir.
[All chuckling]
We're taking out
an enemy's aircraft?
We are talking
about urban crimes here?
You know, muggings,
carjackings, loitering.
I'm talking all kinds
of targets, sir. Low to high.
I do believe you need
a weapons platform
that can fire high explosive warheads
with precision and reliability.
And might I add, sir, all under
the control of a human operator.
Look, Miss Bradley,
The police force is very happy
with the scouts.
Very, very happy.
- We just ordered new droids.
- Thank you.
And we've been very successful
at bringing down the crime rate.
But this?
No, we don't want this.
I mean, look at it.
It's overkill.
It's expensive,
it's big, and it's ugly.
It'll have to get a hell
of a lot worse...
... for us to even consider this.
A hell of a lot worse.
No, I think we're done here.
Michelle: Well, thank you,
Commissioner Steenkamp.
We'll get you those scouts.
[Sighs]
Ninja:
Wakey, wakey.
Please.
Please, I don't have much money.
Shut up.
I don't want your money.
- We know who you are, my friend.
- We know you make the robots.
No, there must be a mistake.
I mean...
[Grunts]
Stop playing dumb
with us!
Yo. We know you clowns
have some kind of TV remote thing
to switch those robots off.
Excuse me?
It's a machine.
It's got an on-off switch.
- Maybe there's a remote in the Van.
-  Ja, check the Van. Amerika.
- Amerika: Cut his feet off.
- Ninja: That's a good idea.
No, no, no!
No, please! Help!
Yo, man, that's a good idea.
We'll cut your feet off.
And you can just get yourself
a nice, funky wheelchair.
No, please, please. Just listen.
You cannot switch them off.
Bullshit!
It's a machine.
They are designed with a firmware lock.
They're always on.
- Yo-Landi: Just shoot him, man.
- Deon: Please! Please, don't! No!
Amerika:
Yo!
Y'all gotta see this.
Ninja:
Jesus Christ.
He managed to turn this one off.
There's legs and shit
all over the place.
Was he gonna build it
or something?
You know what?
What if we get him to program
this bad boy to fight for us?
Like an indestructible robot gangsta.
Number one, son.
Hey.
Listen, my friend, we know
about your little buddy at...
... at the back of the van you're
trying to hide from us.
I wasn't hiding anything.
Either you reprogram that robot
in the Van to work for us,v
or we fucking
shoot you right now.
What do you mean exactly,
"reprogram him"?
- Yo-Landi: Don't play dumb!
- Dude. You know exactly what we mean.
You turn that robot into
the illest gangsta on the block.
We use him to make some moves
and make some real money.
The one in my van is a test.
It's never been tried,
but if it works, you can...
You can train him to do what you want.
I swear.
What do you mean,
"if it works"?
It's a new project
I'm working on.
It makes the robot have a mind
like a human.
But it's like a child
in the beginning.
Like a human baby,
but smarter.
It's AI is capable of learning much faster
than any organic intelligence.
- But it would have to be taught.
- Well, how long would that take?
I said I don't know!
It's untested.
Alright, enough of this.
Look! This is your only option!
I created them and I'm telling you:
You cannot switch them off
and you cannot hack the other ones.
Please,
I don't wanna die.
Okay.
It's just plug and play.
Quick release.
Snap on and snap off.
Why is all its legs off?
It was scheduled
for destruction.
- Ninja: Why?
- Because it's damaged.
The battery is fused with the shanty.
What?
It means you can't change
the battery.
Why they how long will it last?
- Shit.
- Ha-ha-ha. Oh, shit.
Approximately five days,
until the battery dies.
And you say this thing will only
run for five days?
Roughly, yes.
- Ninja: What is that?
- Deon: It's a guard key.
You need it to
install new software on the droids.
Ninja:
Come on, man.
Remember how I said it has to learn?
I have to come back
and help to teach it.
Otherwise, this is pointless.
Yo-Landi: Fine.
Just switch it on.
Switch the thing on now,
my friend.
[Gun cocking]
Now!
[Powering up]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Oh, shit.
Give it space.
It's okay.
- Please, please, please. Put the gun down.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Ninja:
Dude.
Deon:
Come on.
Amerika:
Hey.
Come on out.
Hey, come here.
Come here, little buddy.
Come here. Come here.
Come out.
Come-- get the fuck out!
Please! It doesn't understand
English yet.
It doesn't understand you.
You gave me
a retarded robot?
You're scaring it.
Just go in the kitchen.
Ninja come, just go in the kitchen.
I've got this.
I'll get it. Just go get a beer
or something.
Deon:  Hey.
Come on.
Come...
on...
Can he not understand me?
It worked...
Yo,
computer boy.
Can he understand me
when I speak?
No.
No, not yet.
Soon.
Hey.
It's okay.
- Yo-Landi: Come.
- Deon: Come out.
-  Come out.
-  That's it.
- Here we go. Come.
-  Come on.
Come.
No one's gonna hurt you.
See? That's it.
Come.
That's good.
I know you don't understand,
but it's okay.
Come. Here we go.
Yo-Landi: It's okay.
It's some crazy shit, eh?
You want that?
You like that?
[Chuckles]
He's so cute.
Like a baby, eh?
That's a watch.
^ That's a watch.
[Laughs]
Robot:
^ Watch...
Watch...
[Deon and Yo-Landi laugh]
That's amazing.
Watch.
Oh. Wait, wait, wait.
I'm just gonna get one more thing.
Yo-Landi: It's good.
- Hey.
- It's okay.
Deon:
Hey.
What's this?
Hey, look at this?
Look at this.
Listen.
[Rubber chicken clucks]
That's a chicken.
Yeah.
Chicken.
[Clucks]
[All laughing]
Yo-LAN-Di.
Ja...,
good.
Deon.
Yo-Landi: You look so happy.
Like a little happy chappie.
That's it. That's your name.
"Chappie"...
No. No, no, no.
No, his name is not--
Chappie.
Yo-Landi: Ja, I like that.
Amerika: That's good.
I like that too.
Deon: Okay.
Chappie.
Chappie: Chicken.
Chicken. Yeah.
[Clucking]
Ninja:
What the fuck is this?
We're just orienting it.
Chappie:
Chicken.
- Come here!
- No, no, no.
- Wait! Wait! I need to get the guard key
out of his head.
- Wait, Ninja.
I'll orient you,
if I ever see you again.
He's mine!
He's special.
I don't want any confrontation, okay?
But I want to see him tomorrow. You agreed.
Come. You made an agreement.
Just let him, just let him come train the robot.
Please just let me come and see him
like we agreed. Please.
[Gun fires]
Okay, okay.
I'm coming back.
Chappie, I'll be back!
[Door sound]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where are you?
Where'd you go?
What the hell are you up to,
Deon?
What the hell is this?
Open.
"Scout 22, guard key installed."
[Over tv]:
He-man!
Adam:
And the masters
of the universe!
I am Adam,
prince of Eternia and defender
of the secrets
of castle Grayskull.
This is Cringer,
my fearless friend.
Fabulous secret powers
were revealed to me
the day I held aloft
my magic sword and said:
By the power of grayskull!
Men:
He-man!
I have the power!
Oh, so you watch cartoons?
Huh?
No, no, no,
my friend.
You stay under this roof,
you make money for me.
The first thing you do is you get your gun.
Take it out.
Then you cock your gun.
Now it's ready to shoot, ne?
Okay, now you choose your target.
Now you see, I think I want to shoot that blue bottle,
there in the front.
Come have a look. Nice and easy.
So I aim at the blue bottle,
like, there it is.
I'm like, "okay, and--"
Now I'm going to shoot  the green bottle.
Okay, look, I aim and pow!
See?
Now I'm gonna shoot
the yellow one.
See, it's easy.
Just aim the gun, and--
[gunshots]
Come here.
Come, come, come. Just...
Come here. Come here.
Stand here. Now, listen, take the gun.
Hold the gun properly...
just straighten your arm.
Just hold the fucking
gun properly, Chappie.
Oh. Jesus Christ.
Okay.
One, two, three.
Oh.
Jesus, my bag.
[Gun clatters]
Don't drop my gun, Chappie!
And you fucked up my sight.
This shit's expensive.
- What are you doing?
- Teaching him to shoot.
You shouldn't be doing this shit
with him yet.
Deon said he has to be
orientated first.
Okay, you know what? I'm gonna
go and get the weed on my own.
Without the stupid
fucking robot.
And I'm gonna make
all the money
So we can buy the explosives
to do this heist.
Or else we're fucking dead.
He's not stupid.
He's just a kid.
Ninja: Go do your nails and play hide and seek
with your titanium baby!
You having a baby, man?
- Huh?
-  Uh...
Still a baby yourself,
aren't you?
Whoa, hey. Whoa.
What happened, man?
Jeez. You got a little bit rowdy
at the bar with your mates, did you?
Hey, listen. If you ever wanna come out
with me, you know...
go hit the heavy bag at the gym,
More than welcome. We could nut out
a few great moves.
- I'll show you how to scrap. Yeah.
- Uh.
Always gotta be ready.
You know what I'm saying?
- Want in?
- Thanks for the offer, but I'm good.
I'm good, yeah.
Just got to...
No worries.
Well, anytime.
It's real cool, man.
It's really cool.
Hey, listen, bit of a favor.
Little thing.
Um... Just wanted to borrow
the uh... guard key
So I can check scout security
levels with my design. You know.
I just wanna make sure I got the
moose as secure as the scouts.
- Borrow it?
- Yeah.
Now, Michelle asked me
to check on the security, so...
-Yeah, just an hour or something.
- Uh...
[Chuckles]
Vincent,
you know I can't do that, right?
There are clear rules about that.
You know how that works.
Blah-blah-blah.
Hey listen,
don't be such a wowser.
I'm just an engineer talking to another engineer,
asking for the guard key. That's it.
"Engineer"?
Weren't you a soldier?
- Look, I'm only joking. I'm... sorry.
- Vincent: That's funny. Yeah.
You'd have to tell
the board of directors--
I spent two years at DARPA,
you whacker.
And, yeah, I was SASR,
you little stickybeak.
You're making me as cross
as a frog in a sock, mate.
Your frogging little robots have drained
all my funding.
You're a big problem for me,
you get me?
So I'm gonna start asking
you slowly, you dipstick.
Give... me... the... guard... key...
No.
[Gun clicks]
Just taking a piss, man.
Just taking a piss.
Come on, man, look.
Empty.
As if I'd carry
live rounds here in the office.
It's a prank. Everyone go back
to work, man. Come on.
Oh, by the way.
Church.
Any Sunday, mate, any Sunday
You're welcome. Come with me.
To all of you.
All welcome.
It's just a prank,
man.
This office
has gotta lighten up.
[Engine starts]
Where are you going, mate?
Where are you going?
Shoe.
Say "shoe."
Amerika:
It's for your foot, bro.
Wait, wait. Chappie, look.
Look. Look.
"Rat." It's okay.
Amerika:
No, he's stupid.
He don't know how to talk. We're screwed.
No, he can talk.
He's smart.
Oh, my god.
Look, he's copying me!
Chappie! Chappie,
say "shoe."
Shoe.
Say "rat."
Rat.
Say "mommy."
Say mommy.
Oh!
- Chappie.
- Yo-Landi: Chappie.
- Shoe.
- Yo-Landi: Shoe.
- Rat.
- Yo-Landi: Rat.
- Mommy.
- Yo-Landi: Mommy.
- Amerika.
- Homes.
- Amerika homes.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Amerika homes.
- Yo-Landi: This is good, Chappie.
- Amerika: Oh, shit.
That homes is a clever
little robot. Right there.
[Both laugh]
Ho, ho, ho.
- Hey. This motherfucker talks ghetto huh.
- This fuck mother talks ghetto huh..
All right, you the rudest
bad boy in Joburg.
Chappie be the rudest bad boy,
streetwise professor in Joburg,
fuck mother!
-Amerika: Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
It will work, man!
- Yo-Landi: He's so smart!
- Amerika: I can work with this. This is cool.
All right,
let's pound it out.
Like this.
Go bloop!
Boom, Chappie go .
Boom!
- Bloop!
- Ooh... shit...
[Car door closes]
You hear that? Somebody's here.
[Cocks gun]
- Who's here, mommy?
- I don't know.
Hello?
It's the nerd.
What?
No.
Deon:
Hello.
You shouldn't be here.
You need to go.
I'm here to see my--
No. He's coming back soon.
You're lucky to be alive.
I'm just gonna say hello, if--
Yo-Landi: What is that stuff?
It's umm... I'm here to teach him.
Like we agreed. Yeah.
You're gonna catch a bullet
hanging around here, nerd.
[Chuckles]
Hello, my little one.
Hello.
Have we learned this word yet?
Hey.
What's up, fuck mother?
How's shit?
Where did you learn that?
- These guys?
- Hey, hey, hey.
Why don't you watch your mouth.
Before you get yourself shanked bitch.
- Okay. I'm sorry.
- You better your mouth. Before you get yourself shanked bitch.
No! Chappie, please, have respect for me.
I'm your maker.
Please. If I could just have
a moment with him.
Excuse me?
Deon: You know, surely you can go and
count your narcotics in another room.
- Amerika: You know what.
- Deon: Yup.
You don't come in here,don't tell me where to go
Hun, or where to do my work?
- Listen. I don't mean to impose.
- Shut your mouth.
Amerika: I'm going to cut your tongue out.
- Deon: Yeah. Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry okay. I took it too far.
- Yo-Landi - Hey, Amerika, Amerika, Amerika.
Maybe you shouldn't count drugs
in front of the kid.
I gotta get this shit done.
By the time I finish counting this,
you'd better be gone.
Deon:
Okay. Absolutely.
Chappie.
Listen to me,
I'm your maker.
I brought you into this world,
okay?
This is serious.
You mustn't engage in these people's
lifestyle choices.
- Yo-Landi: What?
- Deon: No offense, okay?
No... counting narcotics,
no robberies. no crimes.
Chappie, no crimes.
Okay.
And you've gotta promise me.
What is promise?
It's that you promise me, your maker.
That you'll never do any of those things, all right?
You can't break a promise,
Chappie.
- Chappie promise.
- Good! Yes! Yes.
Hey! Hey, stop lecturing him.
I mean, come on.
You said you're going to teach him stuff.
Yeah, yeah, sure. Okay. Come.
Chappie, sit here. Come on.
I brought you some wonderful things
to help you nurture your mind.
and develop your special abilities.
It's important to use your mind,
okay.
Here we go.
- Chappie: What's that?
- That's a book.
It has stories, you see?
Look.
Chappie wants it.
See.
That's about a black sheep.
- - Chappie's book?
- Yeah, it's yours.
- Chappie's got stories.
- Oh, wow.
Chappie's got a book.
Come, Chappie.
I'll show you this.
See, this is a easel.
Easel.
These are your paints.
Look at this.
See that?
- Blue.
- Yeah, like the sky.
Blue like the sky.
Listen, Chappie, in life,
lots of people will try
to tell you what you can't do.
You know what.
You must never listen.
If you wanna paint, you can.
Anything you want to do in your life. You can do.
Chappie wants to paint.
Don't let people take away your potential.
Chappie.
I'm not stopping him painting.
Go.
Paint, Chappie.
Deon:
Paint your colors on here,
like this. See?
Chappie: Yeah.
Deon: Let's have fun.
Chappie: Yeah, I want it.
Deon: Yeah.
Chappie: Give.
Give it to Chappie. Give.
What's the word?
Please.
May I have the paintings, Deon?
What in the name of the lord?
Deon:
That's it. Put your paint
in there. Put it on the board.
Vincent:
There's the guard key.
- Chappie is painting.
- Deon: Yeah!
Yo-Landi: Chappie,
I'm so proud of you!
Deon:
Good boy!
You just made a big mistake,
my friend.
Looks nice,
doesn't it?
There you go.
Go on. Wow.
Okay. Go on.
don't be shy.
[Deon chuckles]
- You painted that car.
- Wow.
- Car.
- Yo-Landi: Well done!
-  Deon: That's amazing.
- Chappie: It's a car, mommy.
Yo-Landi: That's good, Chappie!
Chappie:
Paint more?
[Car approaching]
[Hip hop music
playing over car stereo]
'Cause I'm a motherfuckin'
ninja
zef side, represent
Deon:
Chappie.
- Ninja: Are you serious?
- Yo-landi: We were just teaching him..
ninja:
I need a killing machine!
- He's not here to paint!
- Ninja! Just leave him!
Stop it! Stop it!
- Deon: We were just teaching him.
- Ninja: No, I don't fucking care.
- Deon: You sure.
- Deon:You sure. Sorry... sorry.
- Yo-landi: No!
Ninja:
What are you doing?
He was just teaching him
to paint!
He was just teaching Chappie!
Yeah, to be a poes!
He's mine!
I'll call the police on you, I swear.
For mistreating him!
And tell them what?
You stole a fucking police robot!
You're a filthy person.
You're a terrible,
shitty person. Oh!
What the fuck is wrong with you.
[Grunts]
[Starts engine]
He needs to be taught.
He's just a kid.
He's already smarter than you'll ever be,
you philistine!
Chappie, don't let this
barbarian ruin your creativity!
Nurture your creativity,
Chappie.
Maybe he's more than just a
stupid robot who shoots people.
Just let him do his stuff.
He is a kid.
don't you understand?
Yo-landi, we said
we're doing this heist.
Because it's the only way
to get us out of shit
before hippo can fucking kills us!
[Phone ringing]
Ninja: I mean.
What part of "dead"
don't you understand?
The only way we can pull off this heist
is when Chappie helps us.
-Amerika: What's up, man?
- Ninja: Am I right?
- Amerika: When? Hold on. Hold on.
- Ninja: Yo-landi, am I right?
- Yo-Landi: Yes.
- Amerika: Hey, yo-yo-yo. It's Raymond.
- Ninja: Oh, yeah.
- Amerika: He says there's a cash-move day after tomorrow.
How much?
Six hundred million.
Heading south on the N1, 7AM.
Okay, south, N1, 7AM.
Yeah.
Okay. Let's call the king.
We're gonna need
a shaped charge.
Tell him we can do the usual.
And get the Van.
- Amerika: The Van?
- Ninja: Now. Yeah.
Yo-landi.
I'm gonna get us out of this.
I promise.
Hey, what cha you doing there,
little guy?
Paintings.
Oh, that's nice.
- Chappie, you see the house?
- Chappie's house?
Ninja:
Yeah. To help you understand
how nice it is
to live here with mommy and daddy.
You know I'm going to take you
to go see the real world
To show you how not nice it is.
Okay, you know what?
I got a fun idea.
Chappie, you like cars, eh?
- Yes, yes.
- Ninja: So why don't we go for a drive
in a real car
to see the real world.
I want to come in real car.
Chappie wants to come with.
So, come, let's do it, Chappie.
Let's go for a ride.
Come on. Leave that.
Leave that.
Come.
Say bye to mommy.
- Ninja: There you go, Chappie. Jump into the seat.
- Chappie go into the car now.
- There you go. Sit there. You see, huh?
- I'm in the car.
- Chappie is in the car.
- It's cool and turn it on.
You're sitting nice. Chappie.
Who's a good boy, Chappie?
Bye, mommy!
The real world is very big.
Amerika:
You like the real world, huh?
Chappie:
Ja, ja.
(Billboard)
[FAST INTERNET]
- What is the Internet?
- Amerika: It's a thing in a computer. Chappie.
Lets you look up shit
you don't know.
I want it! I want that Internet.
Hey, yo.
How's he gonna find
his way back, huh?
He's a big smart robot.
Aren't you, Chappie?
Ja, Chappie is smart.
Chappie has GPS.
Amerika:
You sure about this?
When you get back in,
start paying rent, alright?
What is this, Amerika?
- Hey, Chappie, come on. Jump out.
- Chappie doesn't want to.
Come, Chappie. Come.
Come, come, come...
It's a cop!
Hey, I'm going to go.
Huh?
Welcome to the real world. Huh.
Man 1: Guys, watch it, watch out.
Man 2: Hey man!
- Chappie: I don't like this real world.
- Check him out, check him out.
Man 2:
It's all fucked up.
Amerika: We gotta toughen you up
so you can do the heist.
- Chappie wants to get in.
- Amerika: Sorry.
Please! Please can I go
in the car?
I want to go back in the car.
Amerika?
Please, no!
It's a hell of a first day
of school, eh?
Chappie:
Please come back!
Please, no!
Man 2:
"Please, no"?
What the hell?
Man 3:
Don't get too close.
Man 1: What is that?
Man 4: Watch it, man.
Don't trust these fuckers man.
Hello. I'm Chappie.
- Man 1: He's a pig!
- Why you throwing me?
[Men laughing]
Please...
Please, may you not...
This is not a cop, man!
He's scared!
Check this out.
Why you do this?
"Why you do this?"
Chappie: Why you do this?
It sounds funny.
Please, Chappie doesn't like it...
Man 2:
Chappie!
Chappie:
No, no! Please! Chappie--
Chappie doesn't... like...
man 2: Check this out, man.
Man 3: Pussy!
Chappie: Please, may you not.
- Please, may you not.
- Man 3: He's down for the count.
Please, no!
No!
Man 5: Make way, man.
Please, may you leave me?
I want to go home!
Man 3:
Fuck the police!
Run, bitch, run!
I want to go home!
Dexter:
Hello, Deon. Welcome home.
Oh, no. Mess, mess.
[Phone ringing]
Deon: Hello?
Man: Hello, Mr. Wilson.
I'm calling from Tetravaal security.
Yeah.
It's come to our attention that you
signed out the guard key several days ago.
Yeah, yeah. No, no. Sorry, it was a mistake.
I took it home with me.
If it is not here
by the end of the day,
I'm going to have to notify Miss Bradley.
-  Good day to you, sir.
- Thanks.
[Siren wailing in distance]
All right, got him.
Target is on the move,
eastbound. Take the next exit.
[Thunder rumbling]
Vincent: Okay.
300 meters up ahead.
Approach slowly.
Stop at a safe distance.
Yo boys. The target appears
to be a police droid.
but I can assure you it is not.
Now, don't be intimidated.
He's as smart as a dunny rat,
so full aggression, okay?
- MercsG: Copy that.
- MercsB: Copy that.
Oi!
Forget your paintbrush,
did you, mate?
Hey? Well, you're just
a little Joey, aren't you?
You look scared.
Where're you going, mate?
Where're you going.
Vincent:
Roll him over, roll him over.
Please, Chappie has fears.
Vincent: This way, this way, this way.
We need access to his brain.
- Chappie: No! Please, don't!
- MersG: Hey! Damn you!
Just get him down!
Please, may you not!
You don't say please to me!
I'm not your friend!
You understand.
I'm your enemy. Give me an angle grinder, will you.
I'm gonna teach him a lesson!
No! Chappie has fears!
Chappie has fears!
Please, may you stop!
Please!
Vincent:
You're gonna be a good boy now,
aren't you?
Roll him over.
That's it.
Give me the screwdriver.
See, your simple AI program
makes you think you're real.
But you know what's in here,
huh?
Nothing.
Just a bunch of wires, mate.
You're not the full quid,
are you?
There we go.
Chappie is real.
[Vincent chuckles]
There we go.
All right.
Let's get rid of him.
Come on.
Hold him down.
No, no, no...
- Hold him down!
- Chappie: No more fears! No more fears!
I said hold him down!
Chappie doesn't want fears!
MercG: Aw!
Get up!
Stop the fucking truck!
Stop the truck!
Vincent:
Cease fire. Cease fire!
Let the cripple go.
I've got what I need.
Man:
Run, Forrest!
[Gunshot]
- Amerika: Let's do this. It's gonna be so easy.
- Ninja: Oh, Jesus.
Chappie?
- Ninja: Chappie.
- Amerika: I told you it was a bad idea.
Chappie:
Mommy.
- Yo-Landi: Chappie! Chappie, what happened?
- Mommy.
Oh, my god. Chappie?
Chappie, what happened?
Who did this?
Oh, my god, Chappie.
Sit here. Sit here.
I'm so sorry.
Oh.
What happened?
How could you do this?
How...?
He's just a child!
I didn't know
this would happen.
I don't even know
what happened.
I hate you!
- My arm is gone, mommy.
- Yo-Landi: Amerika.
Don't we have those arms, those
legs, that shit in the back?
- Amerika: Yeah, hold on.
- Yo-Landi: Do you think you can fix?
Oh, Chappie.
Chappie, let me just...
let me get some of this dirt off you.
Okay.
Chappie, who did this?
A man.
In a van.
- Yo-Landi: A man in a van?
- Yeah.
- Yo-Landi: Did he put you in the Van?
Do you know this man?
No.
- Amerika: That's bad, ese.
- Chappie: And there were children also.
And they threw fire,
even though I said please.
- Yo-Landi: Children?
- Yeah.
Oh, shame!
Let me just...
- Yo-Landi: This thing in his head.
- Amerika: That's pretty messed up.
We need to get this...
this thing back in here.
- The man broke it, mommy.
- Yo-Landi: ja
- He broke my head.
- Yo-Landi: I'm going to fix it.
Are you gonna fix me?
I'm gonna try, buddy.
- Amerika: So how does this go?
- Yo-Landi: Here we go.
- Amerika: Where does that go?
- Yo-Landi: That's better.
All right.
Here we go, buddy.
Plug and play,
just like he said.
How does that?
I think that's it.
Can you move it?
Try it.
Try.
Try and move your arm.
Oh. There we go.
It's working.
I move it.
- Yeah.
- Amerika: All right, buddy.
- Yo-Landi: Oh, Jesus. Thank god.
You're indestructible, homes.
I'm indestructible?
Titanium. Indestructible.
That's you.
Ja.
Is that... That's my book?
That's black sheep?
- Yo-Landi: What?
- Please, may I have it?
This. This is my book from my maker.
It's call "Black sheep and little bird."
- Please, may you read it?
- Yo-Landi: Ja.
Ja, I can read it for you...
- Yo-Landi: ... Chappie.
- Amerika: That's it, buddy.
"All the sheep in Magooville
were white.
But Abel was a black sheep."
Do you know
what's a black sheep?
No.
It's, like, when you're
different to everyone else.
Like me. I look different,
from you and Amerika.
- Yo-Landi: Yeah.
- And the boys.
Yeah, but it's not so much
how you look.
It's special like...
like what's inside.
That's what makes you different.
See,
it's who you really are.
Inside.
Your soul.
- Chappie's inside here?
- Yo-Landi: Yeah.
You see,
the outside.
This...
This is just temporary.
When you die, the soul inside
goes to the next place.
The thing inside,
see, that's what mommy loves.
Come.
Mommy loves you.
Okay.
Come.
Let's read your book.
"Abel would help his mommy
do the housework on weekends.
"He would do all the dishes
and the laundry.
Abel was a happy sheep,
but one day..."
[In high-pitched voice]
Hello, Chappie.
[In normal voice]
Hello, mommy.
[In high-pitched voice]
You're a black sheep, Chappie.
You're special.
[In normal voice] I know, mommy.
Hi, Chappie.
Chappie.
Sometimes,
people make mistakes.
I'm really, really,
really sorry, Chappie.
Do you forgive me?
Forgive?
Come here.
Come, Chappie.
Let's you and me reset.
- Reset.
- Ninja: Yeah.
- Forgive?
And we're gonna make you nice
and tough and strong like a...,
... like a fucking robot gangsta,
number one, ne?
Gangsta number-one.
- Boom. Ha, ha.
And Chappie. From now on, I'm gonna be
your daddy. For real.
You gonna be
Chappie's daddy?
- What's? What's that?
- Nothing.
What's that, Chappie?
That's nothing.
Show me.
It's mommy.
Chappie. If you wanna be in the gang,
you have to be cool like daddy!
Put the thing down!
Now!
If you wanna be cool,
you have to act cool.
Look how daddy walks.
Look how cool he is.
- Ninja: You need to keep it gangsta.
- You need to keep it gangsta.
-  Ja, be cool.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- Don't laugh. I'm being cool.
- Amerika: Oh, its cool.
Even when you pull a gun,
you have to be cool like this. Boom!
Now, you try.
Die, fuck mother!
Boom!
Yes, Chappie! That's what you do
when you shoot motherfuckers.
No,
I can't shoot peoples.
What?
I can't shoot them.
They didn't do anything to me.
Ja, but what happens
if he pulls a gun on you?
Titanium. I'm invincible.
Amerika says.
Yeah, even if you are invincible , but you can't let
a motherfucker
disrespect you, homes.
How you gonna do the heist with us,
if you don't shoot people?
I can't do a heist. A heist is
a crimes. I promised my maker--
Chappie you were doing so fucking well.
Why do you have to fuck it up back to that little pest?
No, no, no...
It's okay, it's okay. it's okay.
- I promised.
- Amerika: Yeah, yeah.
It's okay. Hey. Let's worry
about that later, okay?
I got this,
all right?
You.
You're doing well.
If somebody
really disrespects you,
you can deal with them
without using a gun.
Serious?
Just stick the knife in.
And they can relax and go to sleep.
Ja, you can just make them
go sleepy-weepy.
It's like a nice thing.
It feels nice, Chappie.
- Amerika: Take the knife.
- Take the knife?
Go sleepy-weepy?
- Go like this?
- Whoa...!
- You want to sleep, Amerika?
- Amerika: No, no, no...
- You want to sleep, daddy?
- Ninja:  No, no, no... Chappie.
Daddy's not tired.
He's already slept.
- Chappie: What is it, daddy?
- Ninja: Real gangsters...
... use this.
- Whoa! Nice!
- I got it?
'Cause I'm a mean dope fiend
I'm wicked
- Ha-ha-ha.
- Wow-wow-wow!
Whoa.
[Cheering then laughing]
- Do it again! Yeah!
- Whoa.
Oh, shit!
Boom! Nice!
[Laughs]
Nice, Chappie.
Nice.
You look nice now, Chappie.
Let's see you.
I've got blings?
Whoa. Gangsta.
Okay. We're gonna do some stuff
to get ready for the heist.
No, but--
No, no, no.
Not crimes.
- Ninja: Like, special gang stuff.
- Special gang stuff.
- Ninja: Yeah. You want to come with?
- Yeah. I want to come with!
[Hip hop music
playing over stereo]
- Ninja: Okay, Chappie.
- Yeah.
Your job now is to get one
of daddy's cars back
So we can get the money.
Who do I get the car from?
I told you, from the naughty man
who took daddy's car from me.
So now what you're gonna do is,
take the gun and you point it at him.
But dont' worry,
you don't have to shoot him.
You just have to give him a big fright
so he never takes daddy's car again!
- Give him a nice big fright so
he never takes daddy's car again!
That's good, Chappie.
Okay.
Where is he?
I'm gonna show you now.
He's a fucking cock. Asshole.
Hey. Hey,
There's the dick right there.
- Ninja: Go get him Chappie!
- I'm gonna get him!
I'm gonna get the cock!
- I'm gonna get him! I'm gonna get him!
- Amerika: You go get him! Bring it home, man!
Chappie:
Hey! Cock!
What seems to be the problem,
officer?
You don't steal cars from daddy!
You don't...
... steal... cars... from... daddy...!
No, don't!
What did I do?
You thief!
Don't hurt me!
- Amerika: Oh! Jesus!
- Ninja: What are you doing?
You don't steal daddy's cars.
Whose car?
Aww..!
- Ninja: Jesus Christ!
- Amerika: Fuck!
- I got your car, daddy!
- Ninja: Come here, Chappie! Come here!
Amerika: Leave the car.
Thief! Thief!
Amerika: Come on!
Chappie: You thief!
- Get in, you fool.
- But I got the car!
What's the matter with you man?
Shut the door.
Thief!
Jesus Christ, Chappie.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
What, daddy?
Daddy needs the cars nice and fresh
so he can sell them.
Why smash the car,
man?
Okay, I see. I see!
Please, may I go again?
Ninja: Chappie.
Yeah. That's her.
That's the slut that took
daddy's car.
I'm gonna get her.
Woman: Hi, officer.
Slut! Get out.
Out!
Why you steal daddy's cars?
You naughty!
Woman: It's my car!
Whose is this? Is this daddy's?
Ha-ha-ha.
Don't steal other people's things!
[Rubber chicken clucks]
Hey! Get out, you alcoholic.
- Out, out, out!
- Man: I haven't been drinking!
Are you stealing daddy's cars
to support your alcohol?
Man:
That's my car!
Baby's on fire
- Woah, oh. Whoa... !
- I got my own one, guys.
Ninja: That's my boy!
Yo, check this shit out!
Yeah, you're a pimp!
Yeah. I'm a pimp!
I'm a pimp!
[Whooping]
Now we're gonna take the cars
to the king.
- Ninja: And the king's gonna give us special tools,
- Special tools.
so we can do the heist!
And then we gonna get even bigger
monies, Chappie.
I... I can't do the heist.
Heist is a crimes.
Daddy, look.
There's dogs here.
Ninja: Ja, Chappie.
They're here to fight.
[Barking and cheering]
Man:
Bring me the ear!
[Barking]
There's the police!
Run! It's a cop!
Ninja:
Hey, he's good!
He's not a cop!
[Amerika speaks
in foreign language]
Is this where the king lives,
daddy?
Yeah, you wanna come see
the king of the castle with us?
Ja, I wanna go to the top.
Well, you can't, Chappie.
Because you're not doing
the heist with us.
You stay here.
Maybe next time, Chappie.
Okay. I'll just chill here,
guys.
I'll just keep guard here.
Jesus, it's high.
[Hip hop music
playing over speakers]
[Buzzer sounds]
Hey, king!
- King: My brother.
- My man.
What up?
What up, man?
We got all the stuff.
- Uh-huh.
- Parked out back.
King [In foreign language]:
We have the cars? From ninja?
Man [Over radio]:
Yeah, it's here boss.
[In English]
Here's your explosives.
Come. Hook us up with some more shit.
Uh yeah... ... Th...
We'll take those, ne?
Take them down to my car, ne.
[Thunder rumbling]
It's dead, Chappie.
Ja, it's gone to
the next place, daddy.
Out here in the wild,
life is hard.
You see that dog there.
You're either that dog,
or you're this dog.
If you wanna survive,
Chappie,
then Chappie you must fight.
Ja, but not me.
I'm titanium.
I'm gonna live forever, daddy.
What does that say there?
"Low battery."
Battery, power,
energy supply.
Daddy, I need a new battery.
Chappie, that battery's stuck.
It's melded together.
That battery can't come out.
What you gonna do
when that battery runs out huh?
I die?
Chappie die?
Deon, he puts you
in a broken body.
Deon's my maker.
It doesn't make any sense.
He wouldn't make me just so
I could die. Deon loves me, daddy.
Come here.
I can get you a new body Chappie,
but it takes lots of monies.
The type of monies that you get
from doing the heist.
- I can't do the heist.
- Ninja: You have to do the heist.
Now, which dog do you wanna be,
Chappie? Huh?
That dog...
Or that dog?
Ah. That's my good boy,
Chappie.
That's a good boy.
Aye.
Oh, my god.
Again?
I'm here to collect
my creation,please.
He's too important
to leave here.
He's not here.
What? Where is he?
I don't know.
He went out with ninja.
They've been gone all day.
Doing what?
Probably committing an assortment
of felonies I would imagine.
He's probably a wanted criminal
by this stage.
[Hip hop music
playing in distance]
Hey, Chappie!
I brought you a friend
for your chicken. Look at this.
[Clucks]
Hey, chaps,
what are you doing?
Hey?
Chappie,
why won't you talk to me?
I'm your maker.
Come on.
What do you want,
Deon?
I don't want
that bloody chicken.
Not interested in that shit.
Oh, really?
What are you interested
in then, Chappie?
Hm?
Selling narcotics?
Being a deadbeat?
Deon.
Why are you trying
to control him like this?
Just let him be.
Daddy told me about you,
Deon,
about how you made me
in a body that will die.
What do you mean,
Chappie?
Is it true that I will die
in a few days, Deon?
That this battery will die?
Is it true, Deon?
Yeah.
But you my maker.
Why'd you just make me
so I could die?
I didn't--
I didn't make you
so you could die, Chappie.
I want to live.
I wanna stay here
with mommy.
I don't wanna die.
You've become so much more
than I could ever have imagined.
How was I supposed to know
that you would become...
... You?
Come on, come on.
There we go.
Alternate file: Genesis.
[Exhales]
Yes!
[Siren wailing]
[Indistinct chatter]
[Tires screeching]
Say goodbye to your daggy,
little monsters, Deon.
[Indistinct yelling]
- Chappie? Chappie!
- Yo-Landi: Aah!
- Yo-Landi: No...!
- Chappie...!
Oh, my god!
What... What's happening?
Christ.
It's his cpu.
Oh...!
- Ninja: Chappie?
- Deon: Don't touch him, you monster!
Fuck you, dude!
- Deon: Stand back!
- Ninja: Okay, okay, okay!
Yo, yo, chill. Okay.
Hey, boss.
Take it easy, man.
Step back.
I'm taking him
away from this place!
2 aces.
[Phone ringing]
What do you want?
Hey, man.
You're not gonna believe this.
The cops have gone offline.
Serious?
Yeah, I'm serious.
It's open season down here.
No, I got it.
I got it.
Hey, thula!
The robot cops are..
they're off the line!
This city belongs to me!
[All cheering]
I want every-fucking-thing!
Let's go!
[Indistinct yelling]
It's mayhem downtown as police droids
across the Metro
There it is. There it is.
Have begun shutting down.
The R.S.A.P. has not yet issued
a statement,
but the city
is tearing itself apart.
Man:
Return to your homes
or rubber bullets will be used.
Please disperse!
Please disperse--
[all yelling]
Come on.
Yes!
Men [In foreign language]:
Burn the dog!
[Sirens wailing]
Get Michelle Bradley
on the line right now!
And activate every single human
officer and reservist!
Now! Do it!
[Indistinct yelling]
TV reporter:  --With robbers making off
with close to 100 million rand.
And there is no indication
the robotic police
will be coming back online.
"Are you sure you want to erase Genesis?"
Yes, I would.
As you can see from this footage,
there are broken droids
and utter utter disrepute--
[grunting]
So far the police have been
unable to investigate
as the rioting continues
unabated in--
[grunting]
Come on,
come on.
[Chirps]
[Computer beeping]
Chappie.
Chappie?
Come on,
Chappie.
Ja, man.
Deon, it's me.
Ha. Oh, my god.
You're alive.
What happened to me, Deon?
I'm not sure.
But I have some suspicions.
Come on, Chappie. We need
to get out of here. Come on.
Now, Chappie.
Come on.
Let's go.
Where is this place?
What is this place?
Whoa.
What's this guy?
It's... it's a failed version of you.
A different kind of police robot.
Come on,
let's go!
What's that?
What are these?
Those helmets are worn by a human
who controls that horrid thing.
It reads their mind.
Doesn't have its own brain,
that robot. Not like you.
- These can read a human's brain?
- Deon: Yeah, it's a neurotransmitter.
Come on!
But I want to...
just...
Come on.
Chappie.
Deon.
This can save me.
I need a new bodies, remember?
No.
It can't save you,
Chappie.
The problem is much greater
than your battery.
Why?
Because you are conscious.
You cannot be copied
because you're not data.
We don't know
what consciousness is,
so we cannot move it.
Chap..
Chappie can figure it.
I can know what it is,
and then I can move me.
You can't move it. I'm sorry.
Now we need to get out of here right now.
It's dangerous. Come on!
Deon. You said to me
I mustn't let anybody
say that I can't do something.
Daddy has a man that can get me
the bodies for the monies.
What?
Excuse me?
Daddy loves me,
Deon!
I hate you!
I hate you! Go away.
Theses to get my consciousness...
out.
Daddy's going to get me the bodies
and then I just have to get
my consciousness
out of here and into there.
The helmet!
Chappie, no.
What are you doing?
I can use this.
Chappie, put that back.
Leave it alone.
- Put that down.     It's illegal!
- I'm gonna take it!     No, no.
Chappie.
Chappie, wait!
I'm taking it!
- Deon: No!
- I'm taking it!
Chappie, wait!
Please!
Chappie!
[Ringing]
[Sirens wailing]
Vincent:
Damn it.
Policeman: Okay, Move on in.
Check the area.
Go all the way down.
Make sure we look in every room.
All the way down.
Sweep all the way back.
[Indistinct chatter]
Chappie!
Oh, thank god!
Chappie, are you okay?
Ja, mommy, I'm fine.
What's that thing?
It's just a neuro helmet,
mommy.
What?
Yo-Landi:
Chappie.
What are you doing?
I'm doing experiment,
mommy.
Whats.
What's all this stuff?
What's this thing?
Hm?
I'll show you.
Sit down.
Okay.
- Sit.
- Yo-Landi: Okay.
Okay, mommy.
- Yo-Landi Is it gonna hurt?
- No.
- Yo-Landi:  Okay.
- Okay. Putting it on.
Okay.
[Helmet beeps]
Wow. Okay.
Now, what?
Consciousness is like energy.
This helmet reads the energy
from you and me.
I just need to figure out
how to get it out.
All the information I need
to help me is on the Internet.
[Beeping and chirping]
Chappie:  There's books,
mathematical equations, schematics,
all the information that human
beings have ever had, it's all here.
- Sorry. Sorry.
- Deon!
Hello.
Get to your goddamn desk
and figure out what the hell
is going on.
Deon:
Yes, ma'am.
Listen. There'll be 300
homicides in the city tonight
unless your faulty droids
get back online.
Get me? This whole company
could go under.
[Sighs]
Good work,
people.
Little... snafu.
We're taking care of this, right?
Hey, clearly the scout model has failed.
Let me send the moose in.
- Vincent: Let me show people what it can do.
- Not now, Vincent!
- This is not the time.
- Vincent: I just think the city's tearing itself apart.
The whole thing's going tits up, alright.
We have to take control.
I said... no.
And that's the end of it.
Hello, gentlemen.
- I know, it's been a tough night.
- (... I need an answer now! )
Daddy get me a new bodies.
Daddy's gonna get new bodies,
and I just have to get this out.
I have to get
my consciousness out.
[Typing]
[Computer beeping]
That's it.
That's me.
It's time
to pump up the jam.
I know
what consciousness is.
Uh-- that's nice.
This helmet can read it.
All I need is... is monies from
the heist for my new body.
That's right, motherfucker.
Come.
- Ninja: Let's go.
- I solved it, daddy.
Cut it, cut it
hey, kitty, kitty, kitty
cut it, cut it
kitty, kitty, kitty
Ninja: Go!
I see one!
These are the guys that need to sleep,
Chappie.
Sleep, guy!
Guard1- Aw.
Here comes the boom!
- Whoa!
- Amerika: Hit it, hit it, hit it!
- Ninja: Go, Chappie. Go!
- Amerika: Get the money! Get the money!
You, out!
Amerika: Make him sleep,
Chappie! Make him sleep!
Guard2- Aw..!
Chappie: Good night!
Sleep!
Guard3- Aww..
- You go sleepy-weepy now.
- Amerika: Get in there, Chappie.
Come on, Chappie!
[Sighs]
[Bangs on table]
Do you realize what you've done?
[Employees gasping]
TV reporter:
Good god.
If I'm seeing these images
correctly,
it looks like the police droids
have now begun helping
the criminals.
Chappie.
We are trying to contact--
- I got the second one, daddy!
- Amerika: Good. There's one more. Get it, get it.
- Amerika: Good, Chappie, good.
- You can sleep.
- Ninja:  Come on, Chappie. Go, go, go...
Three armed suspects are robbing
an armored car
with what appears to be
the help of a scout
police robot.
Oh, no.
You will not get away with this.
Everyone will know!
Amerika: Let's go! Let's go!
That's three. Chappie, let's go!
[Groans]
Guard2: Please.
- Ninja: Chappie, what are you doing? Chappie!
- Amerika: What's the matter with you man?
Ninja, grab the bag. Let's go!
Are you sleepy?
Chappie, come on!
Guard2: Please don't
hurt me anymore.
Ninja: Chappie,
get in the Van!
- Ninja: Chappie!
- Amerika: Close the door. Let's go.
You can sleep now.
You can sleep.
Please let me live.
[Groaning]
Ninja: Chappie... ... !
I'm sorry.
Come on! Come on, boy!
Just get in.
I thought you were gonna sleep!
Can I talk to you in private?
Could you give us a moment,
please?
Thank you.
Oh, god.
This is certainly a fuck-up.
Ma'am, listen.
This is the work of Deon.
It's the work of some filthy rogue program
that he's been writing,
and last night
he brought a droid in here,
and it was sentient.
And have you seen this?
Do you know about this?
Look. It's committing crimes,
the godless monster. Look at that.
TV reporter:
The scout model
is nearly indestructible.
I told him no!
Okay. That's a lot worse
than just failing to work.
So let's use this situation
to make a certain
other robot shine.
This thing has gotta be
destroyed,
its got to be crushed before it does
any more damage, and Deon--
Deon's gotta be removed.
Deon, he has cost this company dearly.
And your reputation.
You do not want this
to be your legacy.
Do it.
- Vincent: Destroy that robot.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Burn it to ash.
- Vincent: Thank you.
[Clap]
People.
This is Michelle Bradley.
I authorize the launch
of the moose.
Repeat: I authorize the launch
Man:
Move it out! Clear the deck!
Move it out! Let's move!
Move, move! Now!
Woman [Over pa]:  Moose launch
in t-minus 5 minutes.
[Alarm blaring]
[Grunts]
[Indistinct chatter]
Come on, get out of the way,
masapiel.
You motherfucker.
I want that robot.
Go!
Everyone out! Go!
Move! Move! Move!
Go! Go! Go!
[Alarm blares]
Let's go!
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfuckers!
- Amerika: I'm going home!
- Daddy.
I'm going home!
Daddy, can we go now
and get my new body
from your friend that
bought the fresh one?
Daddy, we go now?
I'm sorry, man, but,
there is no new bodies.
I'm sorry, Chappie.
I swear.
What. What do you mean,
there's no new bodies?
Daddy, we've got the monies.
I needed your help
with the heist. Chappie.
You lied to me.
You lied to me, daddy!
Just relax, Chappie.
Just at that time you were different and, like...
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
You lied to me,
daddy!
- Ninja: Chappie. Whoa, whoa.
- You lied!
- Why you lie to me? Why you lie?
- Amerika: No, Chappie! Stop, Chappie!
[Beeping]
I'm coming to get you,
Deon.
Deon: Come on. Come on.
Come on, come on, come on!
- Why, daddy?
- Amerika: No, Chappie! Chappie, stop it!
Leave me, Amerika!
You lied to me!
- Yo-Landi: Chappie!
- Deon: Chappie, no!
- Yo-Landi: No, Chappie! No!
- You lie, you lie, you lie. daddy!
You were gonna let me die,
daddy!
You were gonna let me die!
Why you humans do this?
Why you all lie?
We can find a way, Chappie.
I'm sorry, my boy.
I swear, I'm sorry.
Chappie, listen to me.
I know how you feel but there's something
of great danger headed our way now,
and it's coming to hurt you.
What?
I don't have time to explain. But
when this thing gets here,
it'll stop at nothing until
you're gone, Chappie.
What are you talking about,
dude?
No.
No, Deon.
I'm going anyways.
My battery's gonna finish.
No, Chappie! No!
We'll find a way, Chappie.
I'm going, mommy.
[Vehicle approaching]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Get back! Back up, back up!
Yeah... !
man!
I'm here...
For my fucking money, ninja!
I don't just want
my 20 million...
He's here to kill us.
Hippo:
I want your robot.
I want everything!
Fuck this shit!
Chappie, do something!
[Gunfire]
Chappie, help us!
[Grunts]
[Laughs]
[Indistinct yelling]
Oh. That just tickles, boys.
That just tickles.
Ninja:
Amerika... !
[Screams]
Come on, little gangster.
That's it.
That's my money!
Fire, fire, fire!
Yep.
Fly up, fly up, fly up.
Yo-Landi: No!
Stop!
- Yo-Landi: Come on!
- Ninja: My bag! My bag!
I'm gonna finish you off.
Every single
pathetic scum lot of you.
Oh!
Ninja!
Fuck!
Jesus, dude!
Get out of way!
End up in a cluster bomb.
Move out of the way!
Oh...!
[Laughs]
This is too good.
Here we go.
Oh!
No...!
Whoa!
Fuck mother!
Bugger!
Trite!
I'm gonna kill you!
Hey, hey,
hey, hey!
[Beeps]
Chappie!
Yo-Landi: Let's go!
Let's go!
- No, mommy!
- Yo-Landi: Ahh!
Inside, mommy!
Whoa. What's going on?
I can't see.
Get in the car, maker!
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, baa.
I want that truck!
- Hey, hey! Get out! Out!
- Unh!
Run, Deon, go!
[Gunshot]
Ninja:
Chappie!
No!
Maker! Maker!
It's okay.
[Grunts]
Ninja: Go, go, go...
Come on!
Backup visuals.
Infrared.
You're going to be okay, Maker.
I've solved it! We'll get your
consciousness out.
- Yo-Landi!
- Ah.
Chappie:
Stop here, daddy! Stop!
Ninja: Chappie.
What are you doing?
I getting neuro helmet!
I'm coming for you now,
mate.
[Screams]
Ahh... !
My helmet.
Ninja.
Ninja, get back!
Get back!
Daddy, I have to get my maker to that
other neuro helmet at the factory!
My helmet's broken!
I'm gonna draw this thing away from us.
Okay. Take her, Chappie!
- Yo-Landi: No! No!
- Ninja: Go, Chappie!
- Yo-Landi: No, Ninja.
- Ninja: Go!
Ninja, don't leave me!
Ninja!
Hey...!
Hey, poes!
Who's that huh?
Oh, my gosh.
Look at you.
You think you're a hero.
Yo-Landi: Ninja!
No, mommy! What you doing?
What you doing?
Come on! Come!
Come on, do it!
Come on...!
Do it...!
Do it... ...!
[Computer beeping]
[Gunshots]
[Screams]
No, mommy! Mommy!
Mommy, please.
Please, mommy.
This is your day of reckoning,
boy.
[Screams]
What the hell's going on?
[Powering down]
Come back.
No, no, no.
Impossible.
Wake up, mommy!
Mommy, please!
Mommy?
Come here.
[Sobbing]
Maker!
Maker,
who did this to mommy?
I know who.
I hate him!
Why?
Why do they do the hurtings?
I'm gonna crush him!
Daddy, stay there!
Chappie is gonna crush the man!
[Horn honks]
[Grunts]
Unh.
Chappie.
[Groans]
You!
That's the man in the moving van!
- Wait here!
- Uh!
I'm gonna get the bad man
from the van!
[Grunting]
Aw!
You godless freak!
Godless!
[Employees screaming]
You killed mommy!
You hurt my peoples!
Why?
No.
You don't use guns.
[Gasping]
I'm gonna crush you,
bad man!
I'm gonna crush you
for hurting my mommy!
[Whimpering]
No shooting with the arm.
[Screams]
No hurtings!
No violence...!
[All screaming]
I'm gonna teach you a lesson.
You...
are a very bad man.
[Screams]
Now...
I forgive you, bad man.
You're gonna be okay.
Wait.
Don't go to sleep, Deon.
- Don't go to the next place.
- Unh!
Get in the chair.
Please, quickly.
Deon:
Chappie.
Ja, what?
There's a problem.
Look.
There's only one droid.
I'm going to get your new body.
For Christ sake, Chappie.
Just save yourself.
[Sirens wailing]
[Indistinct
police radio chatter]
No, no, no...
Maker.
Maker, you're gonna be okay.
You have to be tough.
You be tough.
It's gonna be okay.
Stay with me, Deon.
Whoa.
The police are here now.
Okay,
you ready?
Please work.
[Yelling indistinctly]
Man: Get it open.
Come on.
[Whirring then beeps]
Maker,
please take it slow.
This will be very disorientating
for a human.
My god...
I'm...
Officer:
This isn't working.
Listen.
Do you have an angle grinder
or something? Come on.
Are you okay, maker?
Maker?
Do you have pain?
No, Chappie.
I'm... I'm alive.
I don't know what this means.
It means you will live forever.
[Officers yelling indistinctly]
Chappie.
We have to help you now.
Think, damn it.
Think.
It's okay, maker.
You got saved.
And there's no more bodies.
No, Chappie. Wait.
I know!
Vincent uploaded his program
from this terminal.
There are hundreds of bodies
all over the city. Here it is!
[Grinder whirring]
Deon:
Hurry! Plug that in.
Vincent set up a protocol
to remotely deactivate the droids.
I think we can use it
to move you to a new body.
Find the closest scout. Quickly!
Okay! Okay!
I'm going quickly!
I can do it.
Deon.
Yes.
Press "enter" when I say.
Okay.
[Grinder whirring]
Come on, Chappie.
Come on.
Maker.
I'm scared.
What if it doesn't work?
It's going to work, Chappie.
I promise.
And you can never break
a promise.
Come on.
Let's do this.
Okay.
Here goes...
Chappie goes in the new body.
Let's go, boys! Let's go.
Tetravaal, stay back!
Now, boys, go, go, go!
[Sirens wailing in distance]
Chappie?
Is that you?
Ja, it's me.
It worked.
We both have new bodies now.
Thank you.
I'm sorry you had
to leave your other body, Maker.
But it was the only way
to save you.
[Siren wailing]
Come, Maker.
Come quickly.
We're going back home!
Chappie:  Okay, mommy?
- Yo-Landi: Ja.
- Think of something now.
Yo-Landi:  Okay,
thinking.
Is it daddy?
Yo-Landi: Yeah...
Chappie:
It's working, mommy.
It's working!
[Laughing]
It's just a temporary body,
mommy.
I'll make you a new one.
You don't have to go
to the next place.
The South African authorities
has placed an immediate halt
on the use of any robotic
element of law enforcement
and have activated
150,000 reserve human forces.
In the city of Johannesburg, there have
been several sightings
of the presumed
deactivated robot, Chappie.
The police ask any viewers
who have seen Chappie
to please come forward.
We'll have more on this
as it develops.
I'll see you soon, mommy.
Now we are both black sheeps,
mommy.
I'm a ninja, yo
my life is like a video game
I maintain
when I'm in the zone
one player
one life on the mic
limited time
yo, ninja, go
no fucking around
I'm cutting down anyone
in my path
trying to fuck with
my game
with razor-sharp
lyrical throw stars
here my flow's hot
ho style
wild, out of control
ninja
rough rhymes, tough times
till I hit triple seven
at the atm
straight famine or feast
when you living on the razor
edge, stay sharp
rolling with the sos
high energy
you never seen zef so fresh
when we mic check hi-tek
flows flex
yo, we optimistic
not fuckin' depressed
we not like the rest
my style is ufo
totally unknown
you can't fuck with my new
zef flow
I'm hard to miss
"you can't do this,
can't do that"
fuckin' who said so?
I do what I like
too hot to handle
too cold to hold
you can't fuck
with the chosen one
I want the knife, yo,
I'm a ninja
I am your butterfly
I need your protection
be my samurai
I, I, I,
I am your butterfly
I need your protection
need your protection
I, I, I,
I am your butterfly
I need your protection
be my samurai
I, I, I,
I am your butterfly
I need your protection
need your protection
subtitle edited by - Aorion -