I said, ''Look, Iady, the seats haven't
gotten smaIIer...
...your ass has gotten bigger.''
I'm sorry, sir. This cabin is
restricted to first cIass.
Are you Iooking for this?
Can I get you anything?
Scotch. BIended. Straight.
This is your captain speaking.
We았e got a report
ofsome turbulence ahead.
Please return to yourseats
and fasten yourseat belts...
...and remain there until we release
the fasten-your-seat-belt sign.
I hear birds can't fIy this high.
I hear onIy angeIs can.
Where's the bomb?
I am the bomb.
-ShaII I pour your scotch?
-No, I'II take the bottIe.
Another movie from an oId TV show.
What are you gonna do?
WaIk out.
Very funny.
No, it isn't.
What are you doing?!
What are you doing?! Get off of me!
HeIp me! HeIp me!
HeIp me! Be carefuI!
Nice fIight?
You crazy bastard!
I think you mean ''crazy bitch.''
What is this?
What's going on here?
Damn, I hate to fIy.
No way! No way!
What's with that?!
Who are you peopIe?!
Once upon a time, there were three
very different little girls.
...who grew up to be
three very different women.
--making her a five-day champion.
Way to go, NataIie.
They have three things in common:
Theyre brilliant, beautiful...
I'm going to be aII over you!
You wiII be kissing my ass--
...and they work forme.
My name is Charlie.
-Let's go this way.
-No!
This way!
Wait. I'm not a yo-yo!
Good morning, Starfish.
Good morning, Chad.
Sweet Chad.
I figured we couId have a IittIe
breakfast.
And then, maybe, after...
...we couId have a IittIe Chad.
HoId that thought.
Yes, I'II be right in.
Isn't that just the Iuck?
I can make something besides eggs.
No, it's not the eggs.
Is it the boat?
It's not the boat. I have to go.
Is it the Chad?
It might be the Chad.
It's the Chad!
Eduardo, move me.
Good morning.
I signed the waiver, so feeI free
to stick things in my sIot.
Thanks.
No probIem.
Hey! I'II be right in.
l want to get one thing straight
between us.
Go ahead. Were past keeping secrets
at this point.
This is going to be long...
...hard and rough.
Sometimes when it's rough,
I just get there faster.
If you don't defuse this bomb,
L.A. wiII be an underwater attraction.
Which wire?
The red one or the bIue one?
That is not heIping.
Ooh, my muffins.
This is stupid, anyway.
Why wouIdn't I just yank the wire?
They're dummy wires, honey.
The reaI mechanism is inside.
Trip the externaI feedback circuit,
the bomb wiII detonate.
Wow.
For a bikini waxer,
you know a Iot about bombs.
Isn't it amazing how much information
you can Iearn off the Internet?
I'II be right there.
When do I get to meet this CharIie?
CharIie's not a very sociaI person.
But CharIie's a chick though, right?
I mean, definiteIy a woman, right?
l can앖 keep up this fa網de
with Jason anymore.
Who wants a man who압 intimidated
by a strong woman?
They come on nice untiI they find out
I can shatter a bIock with my head.
I Iove that trick.
BIueberry muffins.
I made them from scratch.
Yum.
Sounds good.
These Iook great, AIex.
Oh, my God.
What's this?
Chinese fighting muffin.
Nothing to Iaugh about.
My buddy took a fighting muffin in the
chest, he went home in 4 ZipIoc bags.
They're not Chinese. They're not
fighting. They're bIueberry.
Are you okay?
She's having secret-identity troubIe.
Aren't we aII?
Scoot.
AIex...
...aII my AngeIs...
...the heart is a muscIe.
In bodybuiIding,
we exercise the muscIe...
...and it grows bigger and stronger.
It's the same with the heart.
I must have the heart of a rhino.
You do. Be proud of it.
Mes Anges...
...these IittIe hurts wiII heaI.
And at crunch time,
your hearts wiII be so buff...
...you'II be abIe to cIean
and jerk his Iove...
...three sets, 1 0 reps each.
Thanks, Bos.
Excuse me.
I have to take a phone caII.
Good morning, Angels.
Good morning, CharIie.
Dylan, Alex, Natalie, l hope youre
ready foryournext assignment.
Meet Eric Knox, a brilliant engineer
and founder ofKnox Technologies...
...an up-and-coming communications
software company.
Last night, Knox was kidnapped...
...and his voice-identification
software was stolen.
Who's the Iady?
Vivian Wood,
president ofKnox Technologies.
Oh, she did it.
I guess we can aII go home then.
AngeIs, meet Vivian Wood,
our new cIient.
She's hired us to find Eric Knox.
HeIIo.
Who'd have the most to gain
from Knox's disappearance?
Me, probabIy. I'm his partner.
Before we were partners...
...we were friends.
Does Knox have any enemies?
Roger Corwin. He압 owner...
...ofRed Star, the largest
communications satellite firm.
Six months ago,
he tried to buy Knox TechnoIogies.
When Knox refused to seII,
Corwin Iost it.
Charming.
Was there a ransom demand?
Nothing. But I know he's stiII aIive.
I'II study the garage footage.
Something may be there.
So Corwin is our onIy Iead.
HopefuIIy, he'II take us to Knox.
Corwin gets a weekly massage
at Madame Wong압 House ofBlossoms.
That압 our chance to feel him out.
He said what?
''Over my dead body''?
I can accept those terms.
It's getting a IittIe chiIIy in here,
Yoko. I couId use some warming up.
At your service.
Good.
CouId we get started this miIIennium?
Banzai!
Ooh, yeah.
You're hoIding a Iot of tension...
...in your 4th and 5th vertebrae.
I know.
Let me see if I can work that...
...out.
By activating the right energy points,
you can increase circuIation...
...aIIeviate pain...
...or even...
...render a man unconscious.
Okay, Iet's go.
PaIm PiIot.
Got the car key.
I got his scheduIe.
You must have dozed off.
You're very good...
...with your hands.
I couId use someone
Iike you on my staff.
Thanks for the offer, but my hands
aren't going anywhere near your staff.
If Corwin is behind Knox's
disappearance...
...someone eIse
is doing his dirty work.
How's it coming
with the kidnapping footage?
I'm enhancing a refIection
from the car window.
May l take your order?.
Three cheeseburgers, three
French fries and three cherry pies.
What do you guys want?
Here's one of the kidnappers.
Creepy Thin Man.
Now we just Iook for him.
And see if he works for Corwin.
What's Corwin doing tonight?
Who's up for crashing a party?
Bos.
-Thanks, Nat.
-No probIem.
It's a mic-transmitter.
Put it on your back moIar.
I know. It's a mouth-mic.
We'II be abIe to aIways stay in touch.
We're in deep cover now, so if...
...you can't remember John David,
just caII me J.D. Think of....
-JeIIy doughnut.
-Jack DanieIs.
-JuveniIe deIinquents.
-John DeLorean.
There's your date, J.D.
Excuse me, Iadies.
Roger Corwin. WeIcome.
John David Rage, seIf-heIp guru.
John David Rage?
Relax, Bos. Ordera drink.
Excuse me. Miss?
Hi...miss.
-A hammerhead, please.
-No problem.
Any creepy thin men?
Lots of creepy, none thin.
-I was wondering if--
-No.
-So there's no chance--
That's incredibIe.
What is?
Your smiIe.
Thanks.
This pIace, it's Japanese, is it not?
It's a 1 3th-century Shinto tempIe.
I had it....
I had it FedEx'd from Kyoto.
BIowfish?
Isn't that poisonous?
It's a rare deIicacy for the man who
has no fear of an excruciating death.
TechnicaIIy, 1 in 60 is fataI.
Tastes Iike chicken.
That wouId go
very niceIy with broccoIi.
The man Iaughs at death.
Good work, Bos.
Get him to taIk about Knox.
At Iast, a worthy adversary.
Let's see if you can survive
a test of intuition and judgment.
Nat, that bartender is cute.
I'm working.
He Iikes you.
Go back and fIirt a IittIe.
That was fast.
I'm not caIIed BaIIs-Out NataIie
for nothing.
Right.
I never saw you working here before.
I'm new. I'm Iike a virgin.
I mean, it's my first time...
...here at Corwin's.
Oh, boy. She's going down.
No way. He's into her.
Justpick up the tray and walk away.
No, no. Stay. Stay and taIk to him.
FIip your hair.
FIip your goddamn hair.
Excuse me. I don't usuaIIy do this,
but I was wondering--
UnIess you're aIready
seeing someone eIse.
Yeah.
-Of course you are.
-No!
I'm not seeing anyone.
Free.
Okay, Thursday?
My favorite day.
Great. I'II get tickets.
I Iove tickets.
What do you know?
A guy who speaks NataIie.
Where's J.D.?
WiII somebody heIp me up, pIease?
HeIIo, girIs? Are you hearing me?
Thin Man, 1 0:00.
Why do they aIways run?
Watch it!
Nat!
Brace!
Jump!
Check them aII!
-CIear!
CIear!
Knox.
Great work, Angels,
but ourjob압 only half-finished.
There압 still the matter
ofMr. Knox압 stolen technology.
What's so speciaI about your software?
It's.... It's reaIIy quite amazing.
We deveIoped a program. You see,
everyone's voice is unique.
It has a unique signature...
...Iike a snowfIake.
And it can be mapped--
Audio DNA. It makes it impossibIe to
disguise or scrambIe a voice signaI.
Which is why Corwin wants it.
Of course. AII Red Star's sateIIites
have gIobaI positioning systems.
Combine that
with voice identification--
--any ceII phone couId be a homing
device.
No one couId hide.
Imagine how dangerous this wouId be
in the wrong hands.
The end of privacy.
That압 where you come in, Angels.
Corwin is premiering his Red Star
racerat the California Speedway.
Our chance to pIant
a hidden camera on Corwin.
Looks like it압 off to the races,
Angels.
When Roger Corwin first got
invoIved in the worId of racing...
...a Iot of peopIe said it was
a stopgap for my waning Iibido.
I had them aII fired.
What's so funny? I did.
Thanks for coming
to this IittIe test run.
Nat...
...I'm going in.
But what can I say?
It's a Red Star day for me.
Then it's back
to the day-to-day grind...
...of worId domination
and ensIavement.
Hi.
Work your magic.
It's hot out there.
It's hot in here too.
Maybe I can make
you more comfortabIe.
Oh, I've come undone.
That feeIs good.
Thank you.
I Iike what you've done with it.
Ours has bigger mirrors.
I Iove cars.
You Iike fast cars?
I Iike fast everything.
Oh, my God.
Thanks for the ride.
You're weIcome.
Mission accompIished. Tomorrow,
Corwin wiII give us a tour of Red Star.
Ride 'em, cowboy. Make me proud.
Nat!
What압 going on?
We got a friend on the track.
That creep from Chinatown.
Creepy Thin Man.
It's a round track.
He's not going anywhere.
She's going after him.
The microcamera has allowed us
to study Red Star압 layout.
The mainframe is right behind
that door.
That's where my software wouId be,
but the security Iooks incredibIe.
-Restricted access.
-Fingerprint I.D.
RetinaI scanner.
Angels, break it down.
OnIy two Red Star directors
can access the mainframe.
To gain access, they have
to synchronize their entrance.
A geIatin scanning pIate
takes exact fingerprints.
A Iaser accurate to .009 miIIimeters
scans the retina.
It is accessibIe onIy through
a monitored airIess antechamber.
There's onIy one way to get through
undetected: Be invisibIe.
The fIoor is rigged
with pressure sensitivity.
Any contact exceeding .25 seconds
triggers the aIarm.
Sounds impossibIe.
Sounds Iike fun.
Director 1
Director 2
Mein Siegenbock ist sexy!
They got the wrong address.
You ready to whip them into shape,
Alex?
You must be Miss Aarons. I'm Doris.
Sorry about the confusion.
I had you scheduIed for next week.
I don't know what happened.
That's what I'm here to find out.
You are the efficiency expert.
Yes.
I am.
Bitch.
I heard that.
Your methodoIogies are antiquated
and weak.
Your procedures of approvaI ensure
that onIy the Ieast radicaI ideas...
...are rewarded.
MeanwhiIe, your competition is
innovating!
Ow.
You.
What was the Iast
suggestion you made?
To make the Coke machine free.
Why?
Caffeine heIps us program.
Perfect. Smart...
...simpIe and IogicaI.
What did your boss say?
He said no.
Question!
Who buiIds this company's products?
You do.
Engineers do.
Not managers.
They shouId be answering to you,
not you to them!
Who eIse has an idea
Iike this man's Coke machine?
AII right! TeII me.
Better yet...
...can anyone show me?
Red Star Mainframe LeveI 4
It's not working.
There압 only one way to get through
undetected: Be invisible.
The flooris rigged
with pressure sensitivity.
Any contact which exceeds .25 seconds
will trigger the alarm.
Thank you, sir.
I hope you don't mind
if we Iook around.
So we have compIete access
to Red Star's computer.
And they have no idea
we can peek inside.
You guys are tremendous. Thanks.
I need evidence of Knox TechnoIogies
software in the Red Star system.
-Where is it?
-BosIey has it in the Iaptop.
It has a direct Iink
to the Red Star mainframe.
BosIey?
Maybe we shouId be doing
our own anaIysis.
SureIy Eric wouId be
the best person to--
Our goaI was to Iearn if Red Star
had stoIen your software.
It wouId be unethicaI
to Iet you access their systems.
If we get proof, we'II teII you.
That makes sense.
That's cooI. Right?
Right, Viv?
You know, Knox may not be
out of danger yet.
SmiIe. Don't panic the cIient.
One of us shouId check
security at his house.
AbsoIuteIy. I agree.
-Everything okay?
-Yeah. Nothing up here.
Wow, that was cooI.
Who's the Green Beret?
My dad.
That's nice.
That's the guy who kiIIed him.
Yeah. They were
in Army InteIIigence together.
This was his best friend
and he turned on him.
I'm sorry.
Thanks.
Why do you keep it?
To remind me: Be carefuI who you
trust. Don't take any wooden nickeIs.
What about you?
Did you ever have parents?
I mean-- I know you have parents,
but I mean--
Where's your mom?
She died when I was 6,
and I never met my father.
You never met your father?
Now you work for...
...a man you've never seen.
That's an interesting trend.
That was smooth.
Want to pIay ScrabbIe?
Don't worry about it.
I got somebody--
That's okay.
What are they caIIed? You know....
So, okay.
-This is a panic button.
-Okay.
If you just press it,
then any one of us...
...whoever's cIosest, wiII be here
if there's any probIem.
Like that? Okay.
Right now, that wouId be you.
But you don't have a probIem.
Yeah, I do.
I don't know...
...how to make chicken.
ScrabbIe?
Shake 'N Bake?
I'II shake, you bake?
I want to shake.
-Hey, Pete.
-How's it going?
-Good. How are you?
-Good. It's good to see you.
-You want your ticket?
-AII right!
-Thanks for giving me a chance.
-I wanted to see you.
-ReaIIy?
-Yeah.
-You Iook great.
-Thank you.
I've thought a Iot about us.
No, no, no.
I know you have something to say...
...but I have something to say too.
I've been thinking a Iot about you
and me and, weII, us.
And I know that we have these crazy
Iives, but I can't heIp it.
I Iove you.
Searching Red Starmainframe
forKnox Technologies software.
Software not detected.
Coming.
HeIIo.
Trick or treat for UNlCEF.
That's a very nice costume,
young Iady.
It gIows in the dark.
I hope you Iike to dance.
Are you kidding? I Iove to dance!
You. You want to dance on-stage?
Us?
Yes!
No, the stage is for the Iadies.
Oh, never mind. I'II just find
a spot on the fIoor.
No, no, wait.
This is Soul Train's highest honor.
I won't Iet you not go up there.
Yeah, she'II go.
ReaIIy? I've aIways wanted
to go up there!
Have a great time.
Okay. I'II be back.
Ms. Wood, there are some Iines
that I never cross.
Lines have never stopped me.
It's ''Miss.'' And it's ''Vivian.''
Okay. Miss Vivian.
Okay, Miss Vivian. You're a pro.
I mean, you're not a pro,
but you're an executive.
We must keep our reIationship
professionaI.
May I?
I'II get you a gIass.
She's pretty great, isn't she?
I said, she's pretty great, right?
You guys are in reaIIy good shape.
DefiniteIy. DefiniteIy.
AII right. The Robot!
Go, white girI!
That's oId schooI, right? DefiniteIy.
I'm Pete. How are you?
The Running Man! Look!
IncredibIe! It was great!
I'm having so much fun!
This is so exciting!
You know, I have to go number one.
Look...
...what I'm trying to say is...
...wiII you marry me?
Oh, no, baby! Baby?!
Baby?! God, no.
Damn you, SaIazar.
Damn you, SaIazar!
Cut!
Was that over the top?
It feIt over the top.
No. That is the best shot, the best
scene, the best movie on the pIanet!
Hi.
How was your day? Great.
You know how superheroes have these
secret identities, where they--
No. No superheroes.
You're an action star.
I get a Iot of action.
That is so Iame.
Hey, girIs, you having fun?
I'm having so much fun
I couId just die.
Jason, I'm one-third of an eIite
crime-fighting team...
...backed by an anonymous miIIionaire.
Yes, that's it.
What are you doing here?
Perfect.
Come on! Go! Hit it!
Murphy O'Meyer...
...that does it.
Who sent you?
Who?!
Woo-- Woo--
-Who?
-Woo--
-Vivian--
-Spit it out!
Vivian Wood!
You bitch.
I Iove a fire.
Hey.
Oh, my God! You're hit!
No. I mean, the squibs hurt a bit
when they go off, but I'm fine.
What happened to my traiIer?
I haven't been honest with you.
Were you in there when that happened?
Look at it.
I'm not a bikini waxer.
Bummer. I mean, that was
kind of a turn-on.
I have to go.
-CharIie?
-Yeah.
I have to go,
but wiII you caII me tomorrow?
-Of course.
-Great. Thanks.
Excuse me.
You're bad.
Guys, finaIIy you warm up a bit.
DyIan? It's Nat. Vivian Wood
is a fake and an aII-around bitch.
Her assassin just paid me a visit.
We gotta warn Knox.
I'm at his house now.
You are?
You know what?
Call Alex and meet me at the agency.
DyIan! Shit.
Don't stand next to the window,
it's not safe.
Toga.
Listen, I just found out that--
Who's that?
Working undercover?
It's a fuII-service job.
I'II bet.
I can see by your ''gown''
that you're unarmed.
Some maniac couId just stroII in
and bIow you both to bits.
Viv, you're obsessed. AII work
and no pIay makes Viv a duII girI.
I have to tie up some Ioose ends here,
so take a seat.
Want some champagne?
''Enemy.''
I know.
Sad news.
Your girIfriends are dead.
And Corwin?
I don't think it's gonna work out,
you and me.
Which is a reaI bummer,
since you, DyIan...
...are a tomcat in the sack.
Let me get this straight. You're a
woman. Women have naturaI intuition.
And you're a detective. And you had
no idea that this was going to happen?
-I knew.
-She knew.
And I know what'II happen next.
TeII her, baby.
AII the AngeIs are going to heaven.
And BosIey?
We'II keep him. We Iike him.
And his computer.
He's speciaI.
Corwin had nothing to do with this.
No. But I never reaIIy Iiked him.
-And the kidnapping was a setup.
-Afraid so.
And Red Star was a setup.
You got it aII figured out.
Any other questions?
Why?
Ask your boss.
CharIie?
You're after CharIie.
CharIie, CharIie, CharIie.
They say that in death...
...aII Iife's questions are answered.
WiII you Iet me know?
Let's go get CharIie.
Come on.
Are you aII right?
-What's going on?
-Something's going on.
Where's DyIan?
They say in death,
aII Iife's questions are answered.
WiII you Iet me know?
What are we doing?
House of Pancakes? SizzIer?
You are the cheapest man
on the pIanet.
What did it Iook Iike?
Oh, I don't know. It was, Iike,
aII cooI and stuff.
You've never seen a booby.
-Have too.
-Have not.
-I've seen Iots of boobies.
-Yeah, right.
A IittIe heIp?
Don't ask.
Where's Knox? Is he okay?
Oh, he's great. He's the bad guy.
The kidnapping was a setup.
He's behind it aII.
What? Why?
He wasn't exactIy forthcoming
when he shot me out the window.
BosIey!
He's safe! Knox aIready has him.
Wait a minute.
Let me get this straight.
BosIey's with the man...
...who tried to kiII us. That's safe?
He won't kiII BosIey
untiI he kiIIs CharIie.
KiIIs CharIie?
Oh, Jesus.
I don't know what his pIan is,
but I know that we can stop him.
If Knox thinks we're dead,
why bIow up the agency?
Why does he want CharIie?
We do know that he wanted us
to break into Red Star.
Imagine how dangerous this wouId be
in the wrong hands.
Knox used us to access the mainframe
not to get back his software...
...but for control of theirglobal
positioning satellites.
Knox's software can match CharIie's
voice over the phone.
And use Red Star sateIIites
to track him.
But why wouId Knox go to so much
troubIe to find CharIie?
That's the guy who kiIIed him.
They were in Army InteIIigence
together.
His best friend turned on him.
Knox thinks CharIie kiIIed his father.
So if he can intercept
CharIie's caII...
...he can Iocate him.
But Knox has to get CharIie
on the phone first.
-But the onIy one CharIie caIIs is--
-BosIey.
May I have some ice water, pIease?
FIy to me, AngeIs! PIease come!
PIease fIy to me, AngeIs!
I had a Iong taIk with a squirreI once.
Longer than I've taIked to most humans.
HeIIo?
HeIIo. HeIIo out there.
Any sign of BosIey's Iaptop?
They must have taken it.
-We shouId check Knox's pIace.
-Let's go.
I'II drive.
Angels?! Angels, help me!
BosIey?
Angels!
We begin our broadcast day!
Come and get me, girIs!
lfyou can follow the sound
ofmy voice, then draw some...
...triangles orsomething...
...to get to this
location and save me!
Is there a way to trace him?
Even with our equipment,
he'd have to be within 20 miIes.
The pIace I'm in Iooks
Iike Cher's bedroom.
And it stinks.
TeII us where you are.
lt smells like the ocean.
And if I Iook out the window,
I see the ocean.
He couId be anywhere
this haIf of North America.
Jack...
...teII them where I am.
What?
It's a Sitta pygmaea!
A pygmy nuthatch!
They onIy Iive in one pIace!
CarmeI!
I can't teII you anything eIse,
except...
...this feeIs Iike the first day
of the Iast of my Iife.
Or the Iast day of the first
of my Iife, or something.
I have a Iighthouse, two hoteIs,
seven manor houses...
...one owned by the NationaI Parks,
one by Nick Xero Corporation--
-Is that speIIed with an ''X'' or a ''Z''?
-''X.''
It's an anagram.
Rearranged, it's ''Eric Knox.''
ScrabbIe freak.
An oId tunneI Ieads down to the shore.
A sea approach is the best way to get
in undetected. We'II need a boat.
And a cover.
We can't use the speedboat.
Head to the marina.
Chad, does this thing go any faster?
We're in a hurry, and I couId
open it up if you Iet me drive.
I'm sorry, friend of Starfish. There's
onIy one captain of this Iove boat.
That captain is me...
...the Chad.
The Chad.
Chad, captain of the Iove boat.
We're kind of in a hurry.
I'm the Chad.
Knox Technologies voice identification
software download confirmed.
Red Starsatellite network uplink
confirmed.
Revenge is fun.
I have to say, Starfish,
I am honored...
...that you've taken an interest in my
work. And I think you're very pretty.
Starfish?
Where are you going?
Starfish, are you going swimming?
Where are you going again?
Starfish?
Was it the Chad?
No! The Chad was great!
The Chad was great.
I'II tap the signaI from the roof.
-I'II deaI with Knox.
-I'II bring our BosIey back.
''I don't know how to make chicken.''
Jerk.
DyIan.
Thank God you're aIive.
You know my better haIf.
It figures I'd meet the perfect guy
and he'd aIready have a perfect girI.
HeIIo, bIondie.
Her girIfriend's here.
Jimmy, PauIie, go secure BosIey,
wouId you?
Like now, now, now, now.
Bos?
-BosIey?
-NataIie?
NataIie, is that you?
Behind this door.
BosIey, I'm so happy to see you!
We're aII here. I'II get you out.
Red wire.
BIue wire.
GPS phone tap.
Pygmy nuthatch.
-I'm getting tickIed.
-Who's caIIing now?
It's Pete!
HeIIo?
Hi, Pete. How are you?
Good. You said you wanted me to caII.
I did want you to caII.
I mean, I do want you to.
Ask if he can caII you back.
I'm so happy to hear from you.
I wanted to taIk.
I Iike spending time with you.
I'd Iike to see more of you,
maybe in a continuous bIock.
I know. It's just been crazy
this week at work.
Watch your back!
Use the sIeeper.
Never send a man to do a woman's job.
-Nice work, NataIie.
-Thanks, BosIey.
Pete? Hi.
You know, under different
circumstances...
...we'd have made a great coupIe.
If you hadn't shot me out a window
and tried to kiII everyone I Iove...
...we couId have had a chance.
Can you keep a secret?
I mean, you can't teII anyone.
That you're disgusting?
You have the fuIIest, sweetest...
...most Iuscious...
...Iips I have ever...
...kissed.
I just gotta take this caII.
Nine o'cIock, CharIie. Right on time.
Enter. Come on.
Mr. BosIey's phone,
Eric Knox speaking.
Mr. Knox? This is Charles Townsend.
l앐 delighted the Angels helped you.
Are you in the office?
Hang up, CharIie.
He's aImost got you.
We're aII at the beach,
having mimosas. Can you join us?
I'II take a rain check, Eric.
Is BosIey there?
He went to the men's room.
He'II be right back.
No, wait. He's coming.
BosIey?
Okay, here we go.
That's not him. Sorry.
Can you hoId on one second Ionger?
Not a problem.
Pete? Can you hoId on a second?
Sure.
I Iike him so much.
Hey, Bos.
BosIey?
He's coming, sir.
Sorry, not him.
Can I take a message?
Just tell him l called, as planned.
Gotcha.
Just one more sec.
Is this a bad time?
You seem a IittIe distracted.
Is this the famous CharIie?
No, this is Pete.
Hey! I Iike that guy!
That man's got a beautifuI
teIephone voice.
That's one more daddy
you'II never know.
Bad news.
I have to Ieave.
I gotta go torture and kiII your boss.
Mikey, Jerry...
...you guys Iike angeI cake?
Do you know how hard it is to find
a quaIity man in Los AngeIes?
Don't take my Iighter.
Wait, wait, wait!
I have something to teII you.
By the time this is over...
...aII of you wiII be facedown
on the fIoor...
...and I'II moon-waIk out of here.
You're not Iistening to me.
First, you're going to heIp me
out of my chair.
Then I'II Ieapfrog over you...
...before I break his nose.
Since my trusty Iighter...
...isn't working, I'II do aII this
with my hands tied behind my back.
Get her!
King Kong paIm.
Buddha on Iotus.
And that's kicking your ass.
AIex!
Thanks, Bos!
Come on, we'II miss happy hour.
He's heading north,
just past Paradise Cove!
Oh, boy, they found him.
That's CharIie's cabin.
-You've seen it?
-You've seen CharIie?
I am his trusted friend and empIoyee.
You've met CharIie?
What do you mean, ''met''?
You've seen him with your own eyes.
I saw his hand.
It couId have been anyone's hand.
Let's see if I can win the teddy bear!
Sorry, CharIie.
Get DyIan!
The missiIe's making a round trip!
DyIan!
Let's go!
CharIie.
You guys...
...we're finaIIy meeting CharIie.
Do I Iook okay?
ShouId we knock?
CharIie?
Good morning, Angels.
Sorry l couldn앖 stick around.
We're so happy you're okay, CharIie.
l앐 just fine, Angels.
Mission accomplished?
I think the cIient was bIown away.
Eric Knox was born John McCadden.
lt seems his life압 mission
was to bring me down.
His dad was in myArmy lntelligence
unit, working as a double agent.
When he was discovered,
the otherside killed him.
I guess that's not
the story Knox heard.
CharIie, I've reaIIy enjoyed
working on this assignment...
...and I eagerIy anticipate
returning to work.
BosIey's had one too many Buddhas.
He's definiteIy had a few.
l have a team rebuilding the office.
lt앏l be better than new
when you get back.
Thank you, CharIie.
Is there any chance
you'II be joining us, CharIie?
I'd Iove to, AngeIs.
But I have some precious treasures
to watch over.
Come on, CharIie, it'II be fun.
We're drinking from coconuts
and Buddhas.
How wiII we ever know
you truIy exist...
...unIess you come
have a coconut with us?
Faith, Angels. lt압 called faith.
To CharIie.
Let me toast you Iadies,
with some ice cubes!
Safe!
I have to go. I'm so sorry.
I shouId go. I reaIIy shouId.
Let's see if I can win the teddy bear!
The Chad is great.
He's great. He's great.
The Chad is great. He's great.
The Chad is great.
The Chad is stuck.
I'm having heImet probIems.
I'm having serious heImet probIems.
Nice!