CITY OF GOD
Fuck, the chicken's got away!
Go after that chicken, man!
Go on, for fuck's sake!
Get that chicken!
If it 's a good photo,
I'll get a job at the paper.
- You think so, Rocket?
- Gotta take the risk.
You'd risk your life
for a picture? Forget it!
You think I want to meet up
with that motherfucking hood?
Get that chicken, bro!
Motherfucker! I told you
to grab that chicken!
Outta my way!
Get that chicken!
If Li'I Z' catches you,
he'll kill you.
Yeah, well,
he's gotta find me first.
Hey, kid! Get that chicken!
Get that chicken!
Shit! The cops!
Don't fucking run off!
Give me that.
Hey, Melonhead! You fucking fag!
A picture could change
my life,but...
in the Clty of God,if you
run away, they get you...
... and if you stay, they get you too.
- They're coming for us!
It's been that way
ever since lwas a kid...
THE SIXTIES
You're useless, man!
- Go get the ball!
- Fucking useless!
Hey, kid!
Give me the ball, I wanna play.
- It 's not yours.
- You wanna mess with me?
Fuck off.
- What 's your name?
- Sorry,I forgot to introduce myself.
- My name's Rocket.
- Some advice, Rocket...
Don't let Li'I Dice
touch that ball. He sucks.
- You lose, pal.
- Go, Shaggy!
That's Shaggy.
To tell the story of the Clty of God,
I have to start wlth him.
8, 9, 1O, 11...
But in orderto tell Shaggy's story, I
must tell the story of the Tender Trio.
Well, Shaggy? The gas truck's coming.
What are you fucking around for?
You're not gonna chicken out...
THE STORY OF THE TENDER TRIO
The notorious Tender Trio
was legendary in the Clty of God.
Shaggy...
Clipper...
and Goose.
Tagging alongwere always
Li'I Dice and Benny...
Shaggy's brother.
I never had the courage
to follow my brother,Goose.
Okay, let 's go.
Come on, Goose.
Let 's go!
Stop! Stop!
Stop this fucker!
Stop or I'll shoot, motherfucker!
Get out!
Hurry up, asshole!
Gimme the money!
Who wants gas?
More! You wanna die for your
boss' damn money?
Shitloads of money here!
You see, asshole?
Asshole!
Fuck! The cops!
Let 's get outta here!
Clear out! The place is
crawling with cops!
- Shaggy!
- The ball, Goose, it 's yours!
Back then,I thought
the guys in the Tender Trio...
were the most dangerous hoods
in Rio.
Here! Buy some new balls.
But they were just amateurs.
- Even my brother,Goose.
- Rocket, give this money to dad.
But don't tell him it 's from me.
Okay?
- Hey, Stringy!
- Yeah?
Look how much I've got.
We came to the Clty of God
hoping to find paradise.
Many families were homeless
due to flooding...
and acts of arson
in the ghettos.
- A light post!
- We'll have electricity!
The bigwigs in government
didn't joke around.
Homeless? 0ff to Clty of God!
There was no electriclty,
paved streets ortransportation.
But forthe rich and powerful
our problems didn't matter.
We were too far removed...
from the picture postcard image
of Rio de Janeiro.
Do you think I can become
a lifeguard one day?
I don't know.
Being a lifeguard is better
than a fishmonger.
I don't want to sell fish.
It stinks.
- Are you insulting your father?
- No.
So what do you want to be?
I don't know.
- Not a hood or a policeman.
- Why not?
I'm scared of getting shot.
Put that thing away, kid.
Are you nuts?
Pointing that gun at me?
Take it easy with the kid, Goose.
Li'I Dice is with me.
Right, I'm a gangster too.
- That gas truck didn't bring much.
- So what?
- We rob gas trucks every day.
- One today, another tomorrow.
No, we need to rob
some rich guy's house.
That 's the only
way to get outta here.
Hell, no. What you need
is to follow my plan.
That 's it.
The little fart 's getting
too big for his britches!
He gets high and starts
talking bullshit.
You two junkies aren't worth
half as much as that kid.
What you got in mind, Li'I Dice?
To be a real hood you need
more than just a gun. You need ideas.
And Li'I Dice had them.
- Is that the motel?
- Yeah.
We go in, grab the money and
get out. No killing, got that?
- I need this.
- Don't touch my gun, kid.
Don't ever do that again.
- Don't point at me.
- Fuck you.
- Don't point your finger at me!
- Stop acting like a baby!
Here's yours.
- Awesome!
- Let 's go!
- Not so fast!
- What?
You stay here and keep watch.
If the cops come, shoot that
window over there.
- Why me? Let that dork do that.
- Look...
I gave you this great plan, for free...
While that guy's absolutely useless!
- You just had the idea.
- Exactly!
You're just a kid, remember?
You cover us, okay?
You'll get your turn, so cool it.
Stop trying to rush things.
You stay there.
This is a hold-up, bitch.
You should be studying or working.
You don't even look like hoodlums.
Instead, you ought to be
working or studying, boy.
Shut up!
What a pain in the ass!
Okay, Clipper?
Shall we go in?
I didn't order anything.
It 's on the house, sir.
Hand over the money!
Keep calm, all I want
is your cash.
- Don't point that...
- Your wallet...
Hey, man...
What kind of whorehouse is this?
- You from the church?
- Yes, brother.
Give it to me!
Slut!
You're old, fat and flabby!
Wanna take her place?
What 's going on?
- The cops! Let 's beat it!
- Let 's go!
Take that car.
I'll go get Li'I Dice.
Jesus, what a car!
- Something fucked up. Li'I Dice's gone.
- The cops are shooting, let 's go!
Slow down! Hold on...
- You said you knew how to drive.
- I do, so cool it!
Turn! Watch out!
You fucking asshole!
Hey, I didn't do it on purpose.
No one saw anything.
So keep your mouths shut, understand?
Hold on, I twisted my ankle.
Goose fucked up his ankle.
It fucking hurts.
Take him into the woods.
I'll shoot to distract the cops.
- In God we trust.
Pass me the telephone, Penguin.
Shorty is another notorious guy
in the Clty of God.
But It's not yet time
to tell his story.
- It fucking hurts, Goose.
- Shut up.
- Wait up...
- You sound like a damn sissy, man.
- Give me your hand! Climb up!
- No one saw anything?
How odd! A car crashes
into a bar and no one saw a thing.
I suppose you didn't see
anything either?
As usual, no one saw,
no one knows.
So what 's up, Shorty?
They're hiding in the woods.
- Hello, Melonhead.
- How are you doing?
I have this feeling that
they're out in the woods.
- The motherfuckers.
- They're out in the woods.
Felipe, lock up the car.
Rangel, come with me.
I can't see a thing.
How the hell can they see?
Fucking jungle.
- They stole a fortune at that motel.
- I know.
What if we took the money?
Are you crazy?
I'm not getting mixed up in that.
I want to exterminate these guys.
What? Since when is stealing from
niggers and thieves a crime?
It won't be hard to nab them.
I have a stoolie in the City.
- Did you hear those shots?
- Lf I catch one of them, I'll kill him.
Maracana!
Open the door.
- What 's the matter?
- The cops are after me.
Shaggy!
- Shaggy!
- The cops are on my ass!
- Hide me!
- Quick, come in.
Shit... I thought the cops
would be down there all night.
I had a vision, Goose.
You been smoking something?
- You've had a job, right?
- Yeah.
What 's it like?
What do people say?
I worked with my father.
And fathers talk a lot of shit.
You know what, Goose?
I'm getting out, I don't want to die.
- This gangster's life isn't for me.
- Wait! The cops are still down there.
I don't give a shit.
I'm going back to the church.
He that dwells in the secret
place of the most High...
shall abide underthe shadow of
the Almighty. Iwill say of the Lord...
He is my refuge and my fortress,
in Him will I trust.
Fear not the terror by night,
northe arrow that flies by day...
northe pestilence that walks
in darkness, northe destruction...
- Stop, motherfucker!
- Don't move!
Stop, or I'll shoot!
... shall abide underthe shadow
of the Almighty.
The hold-up at the motelwent down
as the bloodiest in history.
The destinies of the outlaws
then took different paths.
I don't think this guy
was involved in the heist.
See here?
- He's a worker, not a hoodlum.
- I'll make him one now.
Destiny put Clipper
back into the hands of God.
Shaggy was in Bernice's hands.
And Goose was
in my father's hands.
Why do you do these things?
You think I'm a fool?
From now on,
you'll work with me.
Your younger brother
will keep an eye on you.
You listen to me.
If I catch you with money that
isn't yours, I'll kill you.
That goes for you too. Get changed!
You start work immediately.
Having a hood as a brother sucks.
You always end up footing the bill.
Don't worry.
Dad's mad at me...
but he'll get over it.
Give me that, Rocket. It 's not
for you. You have to study.
- Getting shot doesn't scare you?
- I'm a hood because I got no brain.
But you're smart.
You should study.
I go to school because
I don't like physical work.
Promise me something... That you'll
never touch this gun. Promise?
Let 's shake.
We'd better hurry.
I'm gonna sell a lot of fish.
And don't laugh.
You grinned when I got slapped.
- Who, me?
- I saw you.
What is it, Shaggy?
Cat got your tongue?
Your fidgeting behind me
makes me nervous.
- I'm thinking of what to say to you.
- You're thinking, as well?
Don't. It 'll be your downfall.
My heart has chosen you.
And I follow my heart.
Are you pulling my leg?
You never heard of
love at first sight?
- Hoods don't love, they desire.
- You cut down everything I say.
Hoods don't talk,
they smooth-talk.
Well, I'll stop wasting
my breath on you.
Hoods don't stop,
they take a break.
Talking to you about love
sure is complicated.
It 's not love,
it 's a con game.
It 's just that I love you.
You just might end up
convincing me...
Afterthe hold-up, there were
constant police raids in the ghetto.
Every day,someone went to jail,
someone was nailed.
But no one had seen anything.
No one knew anything.
No one blabbed to the cops about
where the thieves were hiding out.
3 MONTHS LATER
Shaggy...
Why don't you change your life?
Get a job instead of
lying around in bed all day.
- Good-for-nothing!
- What do you mean?
You think you can make money
working? Go ahead.
That 's right, Shaggy...
what do you think I do all day?
Take it easy, baby... you know all
I want is to be with you, have kids...
and a farm, raise chickens,
grow pot and get high.
Sure! For me, that 's
nothing but smooth-talk.
What? I almost got
rich with that motel job.
Are you kidding?
The cops are still looking for you
because of the deaths in the motel.
What deaths?
What are you talking about?
Did you see anything?
You don't know shit, so shut up.
You weren't there.
I didn't kill anyone.
I bet it 's those fucking policemen,
and I'm the one taking the rap.
They even nabbed Li'I Dice.
So don't bring it up again!
- I don't care who did it.
- It wasn't me.
Let me just say... I don't want my
kid's father to be a hoodlum.
You're all alone, Shaggy.
- All alone?
- That 's right!
- Clipper's gone religious.
- Hallelujah!
- Goose is working.
- Ass-kisser!
- And you?
- I haven't changed. So what?
They've deserted me,
that 's all.
Then I'm deserting you too.
I'm splitting, Shaggy.
Come with me, if you want.
Otherwise, I'll go alone.
Fish for sale!
My brother had promised
to stop messing around.
But a hood doesn't stop,
a hood takes a break.
Goose began messing around
wlth Shorty's wife.
I have trout. But for special
customers like you...
I also have a kisser fish.
Hey, that 's a mullet!
Doesn't your husband...
go down on you?
No.
Mine, before entering me,
has to use his tongue.
For about half an hour.
And from behind? Do you let him?
- Good God, no. Doesn't it hurt?
- The first few times.
Then you'll see, it 's fantastic.
But you need a banana.
What for?
You're missing the good things
in life, girl!
You take a banana, warm it up...
Put it up your thing, while he
takes you from behind.
It 's a real rush!
Ask your husband.
I couldn't. You don't know him.
He's liable to beat me.
Try him. Men go wild
for smut like that.
Motherfucking nigger!
Slut!
Whoring bitch!
Rocket, give me your shorts.
Quick!
- Take them off, dammit!
- I'm not going naked in the street.
You want your brother to die?
Give me your shorts. Now!
Give me your shirt.
Your shorts! Hurry up!
I knew it. It 's always me
who forks up for that bum.
The bastard ran off.
That 's his brother.
- That brat there?
- I'll castrate that fucker.
Fish! Fish for sale!
Hey, kid, come over here.
- Where's your brother?
- He's not working today.
- Oh yeah? Get in.
- I didn't do anything.
- Get in!
- What about my fish?
- Hurry it up, kid!
- I don't want to lose my fish!
- Forget your fish.
- Sit your ass down.
- My father will kill me.
- That doesn't matter.
Let 's go.
There's nothing here.
That day,my father swore he never
wanted to see my brother again.
Let 's go, Felipe.
And he never did. No one ever
saw him in the ghetto again.
The story of the Tender Trio
was coming to an end.
Li'I Dice? Shit, man. I thought you
were a goner at the motel.
- You're fucking loaded!
- Don't, Benny. That 's our money.
Fuck you. Cut the crap
and give me the money.
Benny... Tell your brother Shaggy
that Shorty is squealing.
- I'm leaving the ghetto.
- But Shorty had his hands full...
Let 's go see, Stringy.
A neighborcalled the police
before sunrise.
The tabloids went to town:
"Man Buries Wife Alive
in the Clty of God"
Alongwlth reporters, the place
was swarmingwlth cops.
The hoodlums took off.
- You wanna die?
- It 's you who's gonna die...
if you don't do what I say.
And show the lady more respect.
Let 's go, dammit!
- There are cops ahead.
- Fuck them, let 's go.
- Where to?
- Anywhere, just go.
- What 's the matter?
- Have mercy!
- This car's a piece of junk.
- My ass! Start the damn thing!
It needs a push.
Push, Shaggy!
Push!
You?
You want to arrest the thieves?
Over there...
Nab that guy over there!
Run, Shaggy!
Stop the car!
- This way! He's over here.
- We got that sonofabitch!
- The bastard!
- He's a murderer.
0n the day Shaggy died
I rememberthe crowds...
and a camera.
I'd always wanted to have one.
Let 's go to school.
- Well?
- Let 's go to the beach.
But we have an exam.
So what?
Everyone else is at the beach.
Come on, let 's go!
She's in a bikini,
but doesn't want to go.
What 's that saying you have?
The sun is for everyone. The beach,
for those who deserve it.
THE SEVENTIES
- Over here!
- I bought my first camera...
when lwas 16. Like all poor people,
I started at the bottom...
wlth the world's cheapest model.
So, Rocket?
How are things going?
Any luck getting laid yet?
Zilch.
- Angelica. Iwas crazy about her.
- So, Rocket, still clicking away?
She was gorgeous and the only
girl in our gangwho screwed.
Iwanted to lose
my virginlty wlth her.
With her, buddy?
She's got a guy.
- So? I'm not jealous.
- Her father's a sergeant.
No one's perfect.
Closer together!
Iwas the official
photographerof our gang.
The gang of groovies. Everyone
paid to have copies of the pictures.
Thiago, move back a little.
- Is this okay?
- Perfect.
I need a joint.
Instead of smoking, man,
you should snort coke. It 's far out.
You snort, Thiago?
I prefer a good toke.
If you like,
I can get it for you.
You can? Then go on,
move your ass!
But the choice stuff is coke.
That 's a real nercotic.
Narcotic!
- Your mouth is all salty, Thiago.
- Screw you.
You want to be
a lifeguard, Stringy?
- You're never in the water.
- My dad's a lifeguard.
- I'll bet you a beer I swim better.
- You're on.
If you like, I can go get you
a joint at Blacky's.
I'd have done anything
to please her...
Buy her pot,coke...
I could go to the top dogs to buy
quallty stuff at a good price...
because the local boss
was a formerclassmate: Blacky.
- Who is it?
- Rocket.
- How are things down there?
- Fine.
- And the kids?
- Fine too.
- You want to buy or smoke a joint?
- Buy.
Come in, buddy.
Who is it?
This was Blacky's turf.
But It hadn't always been his.
- Hey, Blacky.
- Fuck, Li'I Dice.
- You show up like this at my place?
- Who said it was your place?
THE STORY OF THE APARTMENT
Dona Zelia began selling drugs here...
when her husband died,
in orderto raise her daughters.
She also gave away drugs to boys at
times in return for special favors.
Her favorlte was "Big Boy".
0ne day,he grew very big!
Zelia's operation was so amateurthat
he had no trouble seizing It from her.
Big Boy used the neighborhood
kids as dealers.
- What about my pot?
- Stick it up your ass.
The best dealer...
... was Carrot.
- Can I have a sip?
- Sure.
He earned Big Boy's trust...
was promoted,and moved up to
become a manager.
Blacky, 2O for us and
5 for you, okay?
0ne day a buddy of Carrot's
showed up.
- His name was Aristotle.
- My wife needs an operation.
His family had taken Carrot in
when he was down and out.
He couldn't refuse to help
a brother in need.
Here's the dope. I want
the dough no later than Friday.
- You've bailed me out, brother.
- Friday.
He's my buddy, practically
my brother, Big Boy.
Give him another week.
- Either you kill him, or I'll kill you.
- Carrot had no choice.
- I said Friday.
- Don't do it, man.
Carrot wanted to kill Big Boy,
but It wasn't necessary.
Big Boy hadn't paid off the cops.
He died in jail.
Carrot took everything
that belonged to Big Boy...
but didn't want the apartment...
the place was ill-fated. Carrot gave It
to his most trusted dealer...
- Here. 15O bags.
- Blacky.
Give me more. This place
is crawling with druggies.
That's how he took over
the local trade.
But not for long...
Who is it?
Go see.
- Hey, Blacky.
- Fuck, Li'I Dice.
- You show up like this at my place?
- Who said it was your place?
Yeah, who?
- Something wrong, Li'I Dice?
- Li'I Dice, my ass.
My name is Li'I Z' now.
THE STORY OF LI'L Z'
Li'I Z' had always wanted
to be boss of the Clty of God...
ever since he was Ilttle
and was called"Li'I Dice".
They're having fun,
and not me?
I want to get out of here.
What, kid? Your friend took
everything. What do you want?
That night,Li'I Dice
satisfied his thirst to kill...
though he knew Shaggy would
never forgive him.
To avoid being punished
he left the Clty of God.
He had to work hard for peanuts.
- Yeah, Benny!
- Li'I Dice and Benny managed well.
They had the gift of crime.
- You have more money than me.
- It was my idea.
The only problem was running into
an older hoodlum...
... like my brother,Goose.
- Li'I Dice?
Shit, man. I thought
you were a goner at the motel.
You're fucking loaded!
Don't, Benny. That 's our money.
Benny, tell your brother Shaggy...
that Shorty is squealing.
I'm leaving the ghetto.
Goose!
From Shaggy. You'll need it.
From one hlt to the next,
Li'I Dice grew up.
At 18,he was the most
respected hood in the Clty of God.
You're of age now, watch out!
He was one of the most
wanted robbers in Rio.
Li'I Dice, how's it going?
Happy birthday.
I'm so glad you've turned 18...
- Get lost, Tuba!
- Excuse me, amigo...
Give me a beer!
Didn't you see me, prick?
- Sorry, man.
- Up yours!
The next time,
I'll waste you, asshole!
Fag!
Li'I Dice was ready for anything.
I wanna talk.
- And he was Itching to start.
- Who are the fattest cats here?
- There are tons of them.
- Look at Jerry Adriani...
gold chain, snazzy clothes.
Look at Pereira
and the chick he's with...
- Bernice. She was my brother's girl.
- Check out his car.
Then there's Blacky.
Covered in gold.
Gold chain, gold watch...
Look at Carrot, and his car.
- They're all dealers.
- They're all fucking loaded.
Hold-ups bring in chickenshit.
- The big bucks are in drugs.
- I see.
Especially in selling coke.
- But you need money.
- Not really...
We'll kill these clowns
and take over their business.
- When do we start?
- Now.
Exu-the-Devil is the light
that shines forth.
He brought you here.
Why remain in the City of God
where God has forgotten you?
I know what you want.
You want power.
I have something which will
give it to you.
To change your fate,
I give you my protector, boy.
But you mustn't fornicate
with the amulet...
otherwise...
you'll die.
The boy is no longer called
Li'I Dice...
but Li'I Z'.
Li'I Z' will grow up.
You stick with me,
I'll stick with you.
Li'I Dice became Li'I Z'
and he began to kill.
He started one morning,
taking overJerry Adriani's racket.
By that night,almost all
of the rackets in the ghetto were his.
The only business he didn't
touch was Carrot's...
since he was a friend of Benny's.
All that was left was the apartment...
But that would be easy.
Who is it?
- Hey, Blacky.
- Fuck, Li'I Dice.
- You show up like this at my place?
- Who said it was your place?
- Something wrong, Li'I Dice?
- Li'I Dice, my ass.
- My name is Li'I Z' now.
- His name's Li'I Z', see?
- You're a goner, bastard.
- Don't kill him. He understands.
Right, Blacky?
It 's all yours, I don't want anything.
I don't want no trouble, okay?
I should have taken this chance
to avenge my brother's death.
You'll live, but you'll
work for us. Understand?
That's easy to say...
- Where are you going?
- He's clean, Li'I Z'.
What 's your name, kid?
- Rocket.
- He's Goose's brother.
- Goose?
- The late Goose.
Quick, kid. Run along.
Tell everyone that this business
now belongs to Li'I Z'.
And that we'll be selling coke.
Got that?
Cocaine.
- Where's the turf?
- Over there, on the left.
Selling drugs is like any
other business.
The supplier
delivers the merchandise...
which is then
packaged on the premises.
It's done in an assembly line.
Boring as hell...
Pot is wrapped up in "lids".
Cocaine is put into packets...
and then into bundles
of 10 or 100.
You can even make a career
in dealing drugs.
The kids start out
as delivery boys.
They're paid to run errands
and take messages.
Then they become lookouts.
If the police arrive...
the kltes disappear
and everyone scrams.
Later,you become a dealer
or a "vapor".
When the heat's on, the
"vapor"quickly evaporates.
Moving up the ladder,
you have the "soldier".
And if the guy is good at math,
he can become a manager...
the boss' right-hand man.
The police receive their part
and don't make trouble.
Since Li'I Z' killed off
all of his enemies...
there were no shoot-outs in the
Clty of God. You could drive there...
The playboys felt safe
buying their drugs there.
The Clty teemed wlth addicts
and Li'I Z' grew rich.
- Is it okay?
- It 's a deal.
- I can't decide which to wear.
- This one's cool.
If dealingwere legal,Li'I Z'
would have been man of the year.
But things were risky for me.
Iwas afraid of him.
- And he was everywhere.
- What a drag this guy is.
Whenever lwanted to smoke a joint
I had to go see Carrot.
Half a lid. Thanks.
But It was worth It.
I only smoked wlth Angelica.
She and Thiago had spllt up,
so I made my move.
- Iwas about to win herover...
- These pictures are really great.
- You think so?
- I look good here.
- You look beautiful everywhere.
- I'm serious.
Me too.
A setting sun,
a deserted beach... a long kiss...
Iwas sure this was It...
But the Runts arrived.
Can I have a toke?
Here.
I'm going. See you later.
Hold on, Angelica.
- Your joint, man.
- Keep it.
What a cool guy.
That was my first run
in wlth the Runts.
- Steak and fries, Benny.
- Great! Here...
- A tip for you.
- Really? Thanks.
- Wanna eat something?
- No.
- Wanna trade this watch?
- After Angelica left him...
Thiago began snorting
more and more.
- Is it your grandfather's?
- No, my dad's.
When a guy is really hooked
he ends up in the hands of the dealer.
- Two bags of ten.
- One of ten.
- Okay, one bag.
- For Thiago,It was different.
- Watch out!
- Sorry, godfather.
Godfather, my ass.
Did I baptize your kids?
- I'm sorry.
- Now beat it.
Blacky, lend me your bike.
Hey, wanna race?
- Where to?
- Up to the highway.
- Okay.
- Ready? Go!
- Pretty tough, wasn't it?
- Yeah, you're good.
Where'd you buy those sneakers?
- Not far from here.
- The shirt, as well?
- No, uptown.
- Cool.
It 's a designer shirt.
If I give you money
can you buy me one?
Shorts and a shirt?
Buy whatever you can.
- What size are you?
- Measure me.
- With what, man?
- Shit, with your hand.
Shoe size? Turn around.
- Hey, Benny!
- You got the digs?
- Just one pair of pants?
- No, there's more.
- You like it?
- Yeah.
There's some change.
- Keep it.
- Cool.
This is Benny.
- This is Rocket.
- Hi. I know him.
I've become a playboy.
Hey, gangsters, listen to this...
Watch out...
Groovies shake their asses
before laying a big one.
Oh, yeah?
Fuck off, you bastards!
Making fun of me?
Asshole!
Benny, didn't I tell you to shoot Carrot?
He's endangering the ghetto.
- Cool it. Go talk to him.
- I'm gonna kill that fucker.
- Stop trying to wipe out everyone.
- I'm gonna kill him.
Don't worry, Angelica.
The guys in here are cool.
Sure, I'm not worried.
You gonna dance, Benny?
What about Carrot?
Go on, buddy. Go talk to the guy.
Benny was the coolest hood
in the Clty of God.
He gave away pot,
paid for drinks.
Li'I Z' was the opposlte.
He had one obsession:
To be the boss of the ghetto.
He wanted an excuse to take over
Carrot's racket.
- Hey, Carrot.
- What 's up?
You shouldn't let the Runts
do hold-ups in the ghetto.
You look after your section,
I'll look after mine.
Got that? I'm gonna get a drink.
- Hey, Rocket! How's it going?
- Great.
- Hey, Benny!
- How's it going?
- Hey, Thiago. How are you?
- Good.
- May I?
- Sure...
Wanna dance?
- Is it okay at your place?
- No problem.
My parents are out.
You'll be all alone with her.
- You can lose your virginity tonight.
- Not so loud, man!
Everyone will hear.
- You're beautiful.
- Thank you.
- Shit!
- Nothing's happening.
Look, man, I know the Runts
are associated with you.
Think I'm a sucker, you little brat?
You want to take my racket?
I want to talk to you
because you're fucking useless.
Get your hand away!
The Runts are screwing up
our security, man.
Give the baby his bottle.
Carrot, just ask the kids
to cool it, okay?
Carrot 's useless. He lets the Runts
do hold-ups in his section.
The police come around and
that 's bad for business.
I'll do it only because
I like you.
But you need to change
that baby's diapers.
I'll show you who's the baby...
Tell the kids that in my ghetto
no one robs or rapes!
No wonder you're "Little" Z'!
The Runts were kids who didn't
respect the laws of the ghetto.
They would mug residents,
hold up bakeries...
especially in Carrot's section.
What are you doing?
- You rob me all the time!
- But they didn't know...
that the Clty had a boss now.
THANK YOU FOR CHOOSING US
The Clty had become
much safer for residents.
There were hardly
any hold-ups now.
You just had to go see Li'I Z'.
- Let 's go.
- Don't hurt the Runts.
I won't touch them.
- Hi, Steak.
- How's it going, Li'I Z'?
- Wanna take a walk, Steak?
- With you? Hold on...
Mom, I'm going out with
my friends.
That 's the best chicken
I ever ate.
- The old guy was scared shitless.
- Feeling sorry for him?
You're crazy, man!
Why not stick up
a bank or a supermarket?
- Peanuts. Drugs are where it 's at.
- Yeah, selling drugs.
But you have to start out as a delivery
boy. You wanna be a delivery boy?
It 's a rip off.
It takes a long time to move up.
You have to wait till an older guy
gets killed to move up.
I don't wanna wait till some guy
croaks. I'm gonna do what Li'I Z' did.
I'm gonna wipe them all out.
Talking about me, kid?
The boss is here.
Come back, you brat!
- They're quick, those kids.
- They run fast.
They're all gone except you.
Any others?
You're gonna pay
for the ones that escaped.
You choose. Shall I shoot you
in the hand or foot?
Come on, choose!
Hand or foot?
Choose, for fuck's sake!
- Hand.
- The little hand, eh?
Cool.
Hey, Steak'n'fries,
let 's see what you're made of.
Choose and then kill
one of them.
- Leave it. I'll do it.
- Butt out, Tuba. This is for him.