It's about 5pm
and as you see
the fans are rushing into the concert hall
It's an incredible demand
A demand that you only
know from big pop concerts
A demand, which could have
been calculated before
But many people didn't expect this
,because it is not David Bowie
who is performing tonight
it is not Phil Collins
not Robbie Williams
It is Daniel Küblböck!
The pop-phenomenon of the year
who is starting his big solo tour tonight
with which he will
tour germany for one month.
Phenomenon is the keyword
ladies and gentleman
because "phenomenon"
is a word free of value.
With "phenomenon" you can register
something either positive or negative
[Fading] that you can evaluate yourself
Daniel the sorcerer
[Crazy teenage girls doing countdown]
[Crappy 'Thus spoke Zarathustra' ripoff]
""""Visual FX""""
[Balthasar] Look at this, Tom!
Such a kind is getting famous.
Poor germany!
Ah ah ah ah ah ah!
What do you think of this, Rike?
[Rike] Such a pussy
[Tom] Neither boy nor girl
What is he, Balthasar?
[Balthasar] Dead is, what he is
He is dead, if it's up to you.
Dead as a dodo.
[original musicvideo playing in background]
[???] ROCK ROCK ROCK!!! [???]
"If it's up to us, he is dead as a dodo"
Were you serious, Balthasar?
Of course, what do you think?
Someone has to do the dirty work
don't you think?
How do you picture something like this?
How I picture it....
Real easy: Bang bang, basta!
the end, finito.
[The director, Ulli Lommel]
[Tom] There is his father
[Rike] Then Daniel isn't alone
We wanna try it nevertheless?
[Tom] Did you bring the pistol?
[Rike] Nope, you should have brought it!
[Tom] Shit!
[Rike] Then we must do it without a pistol
[Tom] How? Maybe with a knife?
[Father] Ok, lets do it, Daniel
Now comes your favourite activity
[Daniel] Dear Daniel
I can't tell you, how much you mean to me
Unfortunatley I can't come to your concert
in Circus Crown.
But maybe it will work next time.
I just wanted to thank you.
[Old lady fan] I was so close
to end my life.
I wish you the best
and that you stay healthy
and that you will bring happiness and luck
to many people for many years to come.
Finally i can feel joy again
And that is because of you!
You have saved my life
with your persona and music.
[Daniel acting]
I don't know, Grandma.
I can't deal with it
So much responsibility...
... you know what i mean?
[Grandma] Yeah, sure...
...you have much responsibility now!
All the fans who love you!
[Daniel] But what if eventually...
... I dont want to do it anymore?
Just... over.
[Father] Bullshit, you are overthinking.
Here, continue writing your cards...
... or we won't finish 1000 fanmails today.
[Grandma] Should I help you?
[Daniel] Noooo,noo... It's okay.
[Grandma] I did it one time for Grandpa.
I have a similar handwriting to yours anyway.
[Father] Yeah, Grandpa was nearly the same as Daniel!
He always amazed people!
[Grandma] Yeah, he also made music
Didn't you know?
:-C
Daniel got his talent from my husband
He wasn't sinking over night [???]
He was a great musician!
He played!
Til his death.
[Daniel] Hm!
:-P
One more writing, who would love to kill me
[Father] Let me see
If I catch you on TV once more
it means head-off, KüblbE(!)ck.
And don't dare to [???] on your tour.
Well, I'll give this to the police.
[Grandma] Well, we need bodyguards for him.
I always told you.
Some really strong bodyguards
[Daniel] I don't want bodyguards
It's absurd.
[Father] I dont think bodyguards are a bad idea
[Grandma] I don't understand all the rage
Gosh, you aren't harming them!
All this useless hate
It's really absurd!
[Daniel] Dear Daniel...
I think it's awesome...
Wow, what a bad handwriting!
...that you are like half girl, half boy
I love you, Daniel.
Yours truly, Sabine from Vaterstetten.
This is positive!
[Grandma] On the other hand...
...he has millions of fans, who would go trough hell for him
Such a career, as Daniels has done...
.... is absolutely rare.
If ever!
They should see you and get to know you
If they could see, what kind of show he puts on...
...how he is putting on his show!
How he is standing on stage, two hours!
Well, they would change their minds.
Right, eh?
[awkward pause]
You know, bodyguards wouldn't be bad.
[Father] That's what I'm saying all the time
Bodyguards!
[Grandma] Maybe you will go to America, one day.
To... to Las Vegas!
That would be something.
[Daniel] In America there are better people
They surely don't need me there
[Grandma] You can never know!
Don't say it.
You can never tell, what's going to happen
[Father] Las Vegas... yeah...
...wouldn't be too bad.
[Grandma] Say, whats up with your singing teacher...
...Mr. Meisner?
I think you should work a bit on your voice
Don't you think? [lol]
You just have to work!
Working on yourself, real hard! Day and night.
[Tom] Maybe we should wait at the forrest
and just shoot him.
With a good gun and scope.
[Rike] What?
Really, no! I think its much too cowardly!
[Tom] You always have such a big mouth, Rike.
I'm gradually fed up with you.
[awesome Daniel singing]
[Rike] Just listen to this shit.
Worst thing i've heard in my whole life!
[Tom] Somehow I can't see anything, Rike.
[Rike] There isn't anything to see.
It's enough to only listen to Küblböck!
[sad song :-( ]
[ I don't know where the tiger is coming from]
[Or why there is a tiger in general]
[Mr. Meisner] Daniel, that was neat!
[Mr. Meisner] It's no problem, you can hold it.
Hey, what are you doing there!
Vanish
Go away!
[???]
Let's start over again
We can manage the stuff with the notes.
[Daniel] Okay :-/
[Tom] To our Küblböck, who we hate beyond measure.
Be quiet, I have to write this letter to Küblböck.
[Rike] Man!
[Tom] Don't think, that we will fall for
your faked love for the poor tigers. [again, wtf?!]
By the way, my girlfriend and I
don't live far from you, in Passau...
...which you will visit soon.
Well, this won't happen, because we intent to...
put an end to this tragedy.
[one of the greatest scenes of the movie-history incoming]
8-]
[Balthasar] Something wrong?
[Mysterious man] Dont you recognise me anymore?
[Balthasar] Not that i remember...
[Myst. Man] Munich. Oktoberfest 1965...
[Balthasar] Wait a moment... Johnny?!
No... He is long dead...
[Myst. Man] Who are you talking about?
[Balthasar] About Johann. Also called Johnny.
[Myst. Man] I am exactly that Johnny.
[Balthasar] Yeah yeah, sure thing...!
Have a nice day...
[Johnny] About Daniel...
You can get it out of your head, Balthasar.
[Balthasar] How do you know my name?
[Johnny] If you, or your fellowship...
... harm Daniel...
...you will have to deal with me...
[Balthasar] Quit playing games.
Johnny has been dead for at least 30 years.
[Johnny] Ghosts can also be dangerous!
[Balthasar] Hehe! I'm sorry.
I don't believe in ghosts.
[Johnny] I'm protecting Daniel...
...and I always did.
[Johnny] You don't need to be afraid, Daniel.
Hm?
Tell me...
...you can dream, right?
Just start dreaming...
... and the rest...
...will come automatically...
[Balthasar] Even if you're right...
... you will solely face a huge superior force...
Millions of people, who hate his guts.
[Johnny] Do you know small Petra?
[Balthasar] Petra? What Petra?
[Johnny] You see?
You have no idea...!
Love...
... will prevail.
>:-/
[?????????????????????????????????]
[Grandpa Winter] Is this supposed to be music, Petra?
this is unbearable.
Is this the lunatic Küblböck, or what?
[Petra] His name is Daniel, Grampa.
Also his music is super-duper!
[Grandpa Winter] Nothing but pure garbage!
Lousy stuff!
I've had enough, turn it down.
It's enough!
[Petra] If you didn't forbidden me to go to his concert...
...you wouldn't have to listen to it now!
[Grandpa Winter] !!! Concert!
Well... I... He is stupid... he didn't learn anything...
... he doesn't know anything about music!
That jumping-jack!
That... poor devil! [literally: poor sausage]
In my shop... no-one likes that shit!
Am i right, Miss Selig?
[Selig] I totally aggree with you, Mr. Winter.
That Küüüüüüüblböck!
He is our cultural downfall!
It's a 100% total shit.
[Grandpa Winter] W-what is this?
Küblböck!
Unbelievable!
Küblböck the whole year, only Küblböck?!
That's impossible!
HEY HEY! I'M THE MAN IN THE MOOOON!
WATCHING YOUR WORLD FROM A BIG BALLOON!
[Fun Fact: The character "Grandpa Winter" is played by this movies producer Peter Schamoni]
[Director Lommel first saw Daniel on TV and decided to visit his concert in Zirkus Krone.]
[He was amazed at Daniels atmosphere and charisma and decided to make a movie about him]
[Producer Schamoni couldn't understand Lommels fascination with Daniel at first...]
[... but was soon won over by Daniels positive energy!]
[Thats why he included himself playing the part of  "Grandpa Winter"!]
[But will Daniel win over "Grandpa Winters" heart, as he did Schamonis? We will see...]
[This song should be over soon...]
[Soon...]
[Real soon...]
[wow!]
:-P
[Finally!]
[Petra] Dear Daniel...
My Grampa ownes the Cafe Winter...
... in your hometown Eggenfelden.
It would be nice of you to visit us.
We even bake our own cakes!
I live without my parents...
My Grandma also died last year...
I'm thinking about you a lot.
And that makes me happy!
I love your music.
And I always enjoy watching a new musicvideo by you
See you soon!
And lots of positive energy!
Best wishes, Petra.
[Balthasar] Where is the little cockroach?
Did you change your minds?
Did he convert you?
... made you cry?
Are you Daniel Küblböck-fans after all?
[Rike] Are you nuts?! Never!
[Tom] We will get him.
But it has to be spectacular.
[Balthasar] On sunday is his last concert this year.
In Passau. His home.
He will fall in front of God and the world.
Pew, pew!
[Tom] And we will sit front-row!
[Rike] Bang, bang!
[Balthasar] And you will be more famous, than every superstar!
[Rike] Sounds great!
[Balthasar] Feels good!
[Tom] No more Küblböck!
[Rike] No more!
[Balthasar] No more Küblböck! Thats right!
[???]
[Mean bullies] Look, what is he doing here?
How d-d-did you m-m-anege to become famous?!
[???]
[??????]
[Daniel] Such piggy-asses!
[Father] Just ignore...
We have to talk!
Hollywood called, they wanna do a screentest
[Daniel] For real? (acting surprised)
[Father] Also Las Vegas is interested.
[Daniel] Las Vegas, for real?
[Father] yeah, they wanna invite us.
But I don't think Hollxwood is bad. [??????]
[Have fun with the english parts]
[Woman] And what are you doing here?
[Daniel] A screentest.
[Woman] Screentest for what?
[Daniel] For... Hollywood! :-)
What about you?
[Woman] I am Marie.
Aren't you afraid?
[Daniel] Afraid of what?
[Marie] That I'm chasing you.
That I wanna kill you.
[Daniel] Did I do anything to you?
[Marie] No! The opposite!
You saved my fathers life!
[Daniel] For real?!
[Marie] He nearly drowned in Steinberger See!
But then you appeared to him as an angel
[Daniel] Hm!
[Marie] Lots of people like you...
...though they don't know you.
[Balthasar] Don't get intimidated, Rike!
You shall stalk him...
...without attracting attention.
We always have to pretend...
...to be die-hard fans of him.
Until he is in our trap!
Til he is ours...! Ours alone!
And don't you forget, Rike...
...Küblböck is nothing more,
than a laughable one-hit-wonder.
A crazy scarecrow!
And we!
We are the true superstars
You must never forget, Rike!
Never!
[Marie] Bullshit!
Don't let them tell you what to do.
Such bullshit!
[Marie] Danny-boy? What is your deal?
He is Daniel KÜblböck, OK?
[Daniel] I'm not Indiana Jones...
[Marie] Well, I wouldn't participate, Daniel.
You have to remain true to yourself.
Only then you can be succesful in Hollywood.
From Eggenfelden... to... Hollywood
[Balthasar] Hm, Hollywood!
Don't make me laugh,
they will eat him alive.
Daniel in the lions cave!
[Johnny] Usually, one should not overuse magic...
...but right now... i would love to...
...make you a cockroach!
[Balthasar] Then do it!
Show me, what you are able to do!
In the end,
are you just another ridiculous phony?
I thought you were a one-armed-monster!
Johnny! What did you do?!
Undo it!
[Johnny] What does a good boy say?
[Balthasar] I wanna be human,
not a cockroach!
I wanna be human, like you!
[Johnny] Bullshit, I'm not human!
I'm a ghost.
[Balthasar] Come on, help me!
[Johnny] "I am..."?
"I am a...."?
[Balthasar] I got it! "I am a celebrity!
Get me outta here!"
[Popular TV Show in germany, Daniel was in it]
Really funny!
But you know, he who laughs last...!
I'm gonna get you!
You and your miserable Küblböck!
[Grandpa Winter] This is the last time, Petra,
that you play this KüblbOck-bullshit aroudn here!
You know, how many complaints i got?
Dozens, hundreds!
[Petra] I don't care!
[Grandpa Winter] You don't care, but I do!
It's a catastrophe, if my costumers run away!
What should I do?
Once and for all, this shit has to end!
There!
T-t-thats him!
T-thats Küblböck!
[Selig] The boy put his finger in all cakes!
Ugh, yuck!
[Winter] Did you put your dirty
fingers in my cakes?!
I see! This is...! What kind of...!
I should call the police! Impossible!
[???? Heavy bavarian dialect]
[Daniel] All five cakes!
I buy them all.
[Winter] T-thats impossible!
[Petra] Why not? If he is paying?!
That about... 35,50€
[Winter] That's out of the question!
- Im packing it up, ok?
[Winter] Are you nuts?
[Petra] But only if i get your signature.
[Daniel] And your name is...? Petra!
For Petra, from Daniel.
[Petra] Thank you.
[Daniel] Will you come to my concert in Passau?
[Petra] Of course!
[Winter] Bullshit!
[Daniel] Here, 2 free tickets!
[Petra] For real? Thank you.
That so nice of you!
[Daniel]...and my cake?
[Petra] Oh, I nearly forgot!
[Winter] You will give back the tickets, now!
[Petra] Don't bother me, i have to work! Dont' you see?
- No respect! The youth!
Unbelievable!
[Selig] That's right, Winter!
[Daniel] Come here. Maybe we will see each
other on the concert?
*bump*
[??????????????]
[Real clips of a TV Show Daniel was in]
[Passau]
Positive Energy!
[Winter] Say, is this pop-music,
or like rock-music?
What is it?
[Petra] It's Küblböck!
[Winter] So it's Küblböck-music, yeah?
Well, if you say so...
[Daniel] Did I do something wrong?
[Johnny] Not at all.
[Daniel] Where have you been the whole time?
[Johnny] But I was there all the time.
Didn't you feel it?
[Daniel] Somehting must have gone wrong.
Why is everybody hating me?
[Johnny] I think you are doing your
many fans injustice, Daniel.
They are all very proud of you
Me too, by the way.
You are 18 now, Daniel.
It's time for the little wizard-apprentice
to become a real wizard.
[Daniel] Then I haven't passed
my exam yet?!
[Johnny] Exams?
Do you mean the snakes, spiders
and cockroaches in the jungle?
[referring to the TV Show]
That was... all fun!
But now it's serious.
And soon you have to show,
what you're made of.
[Daniel] Is something... terrible
ahead of me?
Please, tell me...
Do I have to die soon?
[Johnny] You just have to believe
in yourself, Daniel.
Then nothing can happen to you.
When will it happen?
[Johnny] When you are least prepared for it.
>:[
[Rike] Do it!
Finally do something!
You are coming with me, Küblböck!
Don't worry, Küblböck, you won't freeze.
We nearly arrived.
Come on!
Help me a bit,
or I'll have to beat you over the head.
Pussy-cat.
Weakling.
Superstar.
Come on. Sit down.
Make yourself comfortable.
Your time is up,
if you haven't noticed yet
You will sit down, got it?
Hello, Tom?
Yeah, he is with me.
Yeah, sure... good.
Hurry up.
[Daniel] I'm scared.
[Johnny] We talked about this...
... about 12 years ago...
[Daniel] What do I do?
[Johnny] You mustn't lose heart.
[Daniel] My father...
He must to worry a lot.
[Johnny] It's not about your father
right now, Daniel.
This here, is your big test.
And YOU have to pass.
[Daniel] I don't understand anything.
I want out, on my stage.
[Johnny] This here is your stage now.
And YOU have to play your new role now.
And convincing.
[Daniel] I hate these guys.
[Johnny] You mustn't hate!
[Daniel] Please help me out. I beg you.
You have to help me.
[Johnny] I'm expecting of you
to not disappoint me.
[Rike] Who are you talking to, Küblböck?
Are you nuts? Are you crazy?
[Daniel] Could I also have a cigarette?
[Rike] Sorry, nothing left.
:-P
[Father] Hello, my dearest audience.
There are technical difficulties.
Nothing dramatic, the show will go on soon
Please be patient.
In the meantime time,
the band will serve you music
and keep you entertained.
Thanks for your understanding.
[Petra] You think something
happened to him, Gramps?
[Winter] Why?
What could have happened to him?
Don't worry. Nononono
[Petra] Can't we go backstage and talk to him?
[Winter] Talking? W-w-with wh-wh-who?
Y-you w-wanna talk to him?
[Petra] Why not? Are you still a hater?
[Winter] Nooo, I think hes pretty good.
Better than Heino with his glasses
[Famous german singer]
You think we should....?
Aren't you the father of Küblöck?
[Father] Yeah.
[Winter] I'm the guy from Cafe Winter. The owner.
Tell me, can we help you?
We know Daniel very well, a nice young man.
And you know, he's always buying cake.
Huuuuge amounts of cake.
So we thought me may help.
[Father] Very friendly.
[Winter] Anything happened?
[Father] No no, it's ok.
[Balth.] I won't come up there to you.
You gotta do it alone
[Tom] What? You bail on us now?
[Balth.] I have nothing to do with it.
It's your business
YOU wanted to get famous
Tell me, Balthasar...
Something is funny here...
[Balth.] Funny? Why? What?
[Tom] He put a spell on you, heh?
Right?!
That's it!
[Balth.] Yuck! Bullshit!
Do your part and we will see...
[Tom] He is dangerous, I see...
He's got something...
Slowly i start understanding his fans.
There is something to him...
[Rike] Finally, there you are!
So, turn around.
We make short work with you.
We will put a small pellet in your neck.
Got it?
But because we pity you a bit...
we will do it from behind.
So you don't have to watch it.
How many bullets are in here?
-5 or 10, doesn't matter.
[Tom] Well, it will be enough.
I shoot...
and you record.
[Rike] Ok, no problem!
Dot it, Tommy!
Or should I do it?
[Tom] Ok, if you insist!
I'm better with the camera anyway.
- Coward!
[Tom] Don't be silly, Rike!
[Rike] Loser.
[Tom] Come on, don't put on a show!
What is happening?
You aren't able to stay cool, typical.
[Rike] Tell me Tommy, what are you doing?
What are you fingering around?
[Tom] Something is wrong with the camera.
Did you break it?
[Daniel] At my home all hell always broke lose
My mother was drinking.
And I was always taken for a fool.
And my brother was a Neo-Nazi!
- Shit!
[Tom] In my case it was my stepfather,
who always beat me.
Day and night.
But one day I punched back, it felt great.
It was so much fun!
[Rike] Here, it's workign again.
[Daniel] I learned one thing in my life.
To NOT punch back.
[Rike] Turn around at last, Küblböck!
[Tom] So, camera is running.
It's your turn, Miss Regisseuse.
[Wordplay on Regisseur(director) and the female ending -seuse]
[Rike] The gun is jamming.
Do you wanna try?
[Tom] I'm filming right now!
You do it. Just pull the trigger.
:-P
I had a guitar once...
an old and broken one.
And they stole it.
I didn't have money to buy one again.
But I would love to play.
[Daniel] I could imagine...
...that you could also dance and sing...
If you wanted to.
[Rike] Gosh, am I crazy?
Did you lose your mind, or what is happening?
[Tom] Maybe it's not so bad...
Maybe we should give him one last chance
[Rike] Okay... You know what?
You can do this on your own!
Including all the consequences, okay?
I'm going home,
making myself a nice evening.
How about this?
-Not bad!
I didn't ask you for an answer,
Daniel Küblböck.
[Tom] I'm okay with this.
[Rike] Good, that's how we do it, then.
[Rike] And if you kill him, all glory to you.
All alone. Is it fair?
[Daniel] Yeah, that's fair.
[Rike] Shut up!
[Tom] I'll call you later.
[Rike] What's on TV tonight?
Deutschland Sucht Den Superstar
[Germanys version of Americas Idol.
Daniel became famous in it]
[Rike] Very funny, Daniel, really.
[Tom] Yeah, uhm...
I'm gonna call you later, then
:-P
By the way, I liked that one song
by you quite a bit.
The new one.
Such a damn bullshit!
Now I'm stuck in this shit.
[Daniel] How about a deal?
[Tom] A deal?
You let me go... I'll leave...
And will tell no one where I've been.
[Tom] I don't believe you!
[Daniel] Then you have to kill me...
... or run away yourself.
[Tom] Things are, how they are.
All shit.
And I am the biggest asshole.
I will never achieve something big.
My stepfather always said so,
and he was right.
I should have never been born
into this shit world. Never!
[Daniel] Just cry, if you want to.
Boys are allowed to cry.
[Tom] Then please,
get otut of here
Impossible!
[Father] Daniel! Are you crazy?
Where have you been the whole time?
My god, where have you been?
[???]... can't explain.
[All concert footage is real, by the way]
[Petra] Dear Daniel,
Your concert in Passau was wonderful.
My Grandpa is a big fan of you now, too.
And sometimes acts like a teenager again.
Thousand times thank you
for the invitation.
Yours truly,
Petra
Positive energy!
[Winter] Yeah yeah yeah... positive energy.
Well you gotta sleep now.
Positive energy isn't bad,
better than negative energy, heh?
Sleep well, you have school tomorrow.
And eh... yeah,
you need positive energy then, heh?
Sooooo, sleep well then.
-Good night.
-Good night!
[Daniel] And...
where is my christmas present?
[Johnny] Since when do you
just think about yourself?
[Daniel] I don't get it.
Didn't I do everything right?
Haven't I passed my exam?
[Johnny] You forgot something.
Something very important.
[Daniel] What?
[Johnny] Tom and Rike!
They haven't receiced
a Christmas gif from you.
[Daniel] A gift from me for them?!
[Johnny] I want you to give them something...
that you like very much.
[Daniel] They wanted to kill me!
[Johnny] Oh yeah, well...
That's a long time ago.
But now you are friends.
[Daniel] I don't know...
you can't really call us friends...
I think you are going a bit far with this!
[Johnny] Not at all!
*sqeak*
You will give them your guitar,
got it?
[Daniel] What?!
My guitar? Never!
[Johnny] Well. Then you are just an
itsy-bitsy tiny wizard apprentice.
[Daniel] Come on...
I beg you.
[Johnny] A wizard often gives that away,
that he loves most.
And you wanna become a wizard...
a real, big wizard. Right?
I got something for you!
[BEST SCENE EVER]
[Balth.] That was dirty little trick
of you, Johnny!
And that thing with your arm!
Sometimes you got, sometimes not!
Is that just one more dirty spell,
or is it a prothesis?
[Johnny] You can pick your answer,
whatever you want it to be.
[Balth.] Ok then. Maybe i lost the battle.
But the war isn't over yet!
I'm betting on it!
[Johnny] I wouldn't be so sure about that.
[Balth] You must give him your magic-wand,
don't you?
[Johnny] Why do you ask?
[Balth.] :-D
Then you will lose your magic power.
Three times cockroach [???]
I know magic well enough for this.
In the corner. Broom broom it has been.
My little Johnny. Then we get rid of you.
[???]
And can the little wizard even handle
his new magic powers?
I doubt it a little.
[Father] What's that?
[Grandma] That's something very special!
[Father] Isn't there a letter with it?
[Daniel] ...from the one-armed.
[Grandma] One-armed?
I only know one one-armed.
It was Grandpa! My husband.
- Exactly!
We first met on Oktoberfest 1965.
I was 16!
He sometimes came to my tent,
where i worked as a waitress.
So I fed him, he couldn't
do it himself, with one arm only.
And... yeah... well...
I fell in love with him.
[Daniel] And what does he look like,
Granny?
[Grand.] Well, real dark hair,
just like you.
And brown eyes.
Have I never shown you the pictures?
Well, probably because
I still miss him.
I didn't have the heart to show you.
Look. That's him!
Do you like him?
[Daniel] What did you say,
where is he now?
[Grand.] Dead. For along time.
Somewhere in heaven.
[Daniel] In Heaven?
[Grand.] Yeah, in heaven.
[Daniel] Incredible!
[Grand.] So sad you didn't
get to know each other
[Daniel] Granny, please don't cry.
[Grand.] You would have so much fun,
you two!
Well... that's life!
Tell me, do you believe in
miracles... magic?
[Daniel] Im not sure
[Grand.] What did he look like?
Did he wear a dress-coat and a hat?
And white gloves?
[Daniel] Yes, Granny!
[Grand.] And did he have s silvern
metal-instrument with him?
[Daniel] Yes, exactly.
Grand.] Then tell him
greetings from me, next time.
Tell him I love him.
And I was always loyal.
And now go up and sleep.
And seet dreams!
And with the magic-wand...
It's important...
... you must only
use it to help others.
But I'm sure he already told you, eh?
You... WIIIIIZAAARD!
[Daniel] I will do it, Granny.
[Grand.] This stays a secret, ok?
[Daniel] Deal.
[Reporter] We are standing in Cannes,
Ladies and Gentleman.
In front of the festival palace,
as you can see.
And here will be premiered
the movie of Daniel Küblböck.
It's worldwide premiere.
Who would have thought...
[Balth.] Küblböck must die,
KÜBLBÖCK MUST DIE!
[The headlines are based on the real event
of Daniel crashing into a cucumber-transporter.
He was injured in real life]
[Johnny] You don't need to
be scared, Daniel.
MY LIFE IS MAGIC!!!