dad
Mom. can I have breakfast?
I don't know
- Mommy, Daddy!
Get up.
I love you!
oh u have so many knees.
- Upcoming!
Okay, yes. Charlie,
I'll make you over breakfast.
I am ... up.
Here we go.
- It begins.
mom, can I have pizza for the breakfast?
- Yes.
Really?
- No.
Charlotte, get off the chair.
- No way.
Charlotte, I'm gonna count into three.
- No, Mom.
Here we go.
- one...
two, three ...
- Mom!
u count to three?
- It works every time.
I start off a lunches everyone.
one in a change.
subtracting at 1.42.
well, it's look like we will give you a refund about $ 600.
shut up
i,m not gonna shut up.
- You make it my lady excited!
I like you!
- i'm glad you're happy.
We'll going kiteboarding in Spain.
How sexy is that?
guys, you know what will be even sexier than that
is start a Roth IRA
oh my god, when we're there, we could like do it on
the beach like 20 times
yeah,I'm gonna go with that.
Would you do it, no?
well, toughtful thought.
As you can see the floor
are all pickled oak.
This house was originally lifted out
at 1.8 million ...
but now only 320,000.
I think it might come down more.
- so do I.
good call, better to wait it out.
Hello, my people.
the Fosters, i love them.
dad, come play Lego with me.
- yes i will, but i,m going to laps into a mini coma
for just a second...
and then we gonna have
best Lego battle ever.
How you doing, Fosters?
- Hi, Katy.
everything okay next door?
- yeah, wait , you guys tell me to babysit, right?
Isn't it a date night?
- Yeah, thats right, date night
thank you for coming, katy.
We go on date night.
- You're too tired, baby.
No, I'm good, i'm looking foward into it
the whole week.
Unless you're too tired?
- No, it'll be fun.
We should go, right?
We should go.
Taste the puree with salmon you?
- Yes, very. Thanks.
On Sunday, Ollie's freind,
Hayden having a birthday party.
Am i getting a present?
- Yes, but nothing from China ...
nothing with batteries ...
you know, i'll just get it. It's be easier
hey, what's the story?
Third date. The first one was okey,
the second one was bad ...
She gives him one more chance,
to prove that he is not boring.
And he is not succeding.
'I have a potato on my fork.
I like to eat potatoes ...
they are delicious ...
but I don't actually ever put
them in my mouth. "
that's amazing, Jeremy,
but I'm gonna go home now ...
and fart into a shoe box.
That is radiculous.
oh boy, look at this two
love bird.
no, first date.
- No, he's got a ring on. They both do..
No, married?
They are not very, sit on the same side of the booth.
they are not in married move
showing off, is what it is.
- Have you even talk to someone, sitting on the
same side of the booth.
crane your neck.
"Hi, how you, are fine "
that's was definitely a wedding ring.
This is a family place.
you need coffee or dessert for you guys tonight?
What do you say,hon?
actually, i'm so tired that i have to rest my
head on the table right now ...
yeah, just sleep for a years.
No, only the account.
Where earlier today
DA Frank Crenshaw an ...
Hey, just wait for the sport.
- I promised the city ...
to sweep the streets clean.
Let me tell you something.
This broom and I ...
we don't break our promises.
- I 'm gonna head on.
go ahead, see you in sec.
- Book Club tomorrow.
We don't break our promises !
'oh', what?
no, you put your mouth card,
which means that we not gonna ...
You know.
- No, we can still pull around.
Only if you want do it.
-no, i will love to.
let me just mm ... get the ..
okey, you know what, no.
honey, i'm totally fine if we don't.
No, I was just a... no. i will love to.
let me just get my head around.
No, it's totally cool, you know.
- are you sure?
those potatoes
give some of gassy.
We turn one on.
- are you sure?
I will light off your life.
Next time.
or we can just do old time.
- What?
do it a fast versions.
-no it's okay.
cause I can roll it  ...
- Yeah, i'm good.
Nasran feet and tender breasts ache
as she tramp throuh unforgiving train.
Blood dripped down from her leg
into the ground ...
leaving one bright red spot
of life myst of ending emptiness.
This part really spoked to me.
i mean to walk 20 miles for water ...
and then she only discover that she is
menstruating.
I could not stop crying.
- me too.I literally could not stop crying.
quite sad.
- quite sad?
sir, you have no idea what it is like to be a
teenage girl  ...
having her first period
under Taliban rule.
That is true.
And neither do you.
But ...
-hey, Phil can you help me?
Yeah, thanks. Excuse me.
My God.
Do you have your period now?
- Yes.
you should really read this.
it's about a girl get her period in the desert.
i don't know how you did this
still in bookclub.
That's marriage.
sometimes, you just do stuff you don't want to do.
not me, not anymore.
- what do you mean?
Haley and I are split.
But you guys are happy.
- No, not fully not.
Brad, why we here then, in your house
having book club?
can't tell the kids.
please keep on your head until next week
I'm gonna public with it.
don't tell Claire.
- Yes, yes.
so, what happen? i mean
- I thought everything was fine ...
really,you know what, we were stuck in this role together
and we can't break out of them.
you know, the Asian dude Sixteen Candles,
Long dick dog.
Long Duk Dong.
- That dude.
Gedde Watanabe.
-that him. He can't play ...
no matter how hard he tries.
He can't play a doctor.
No, yeah, it will be why like Long Duk Dong
dress up like a doctor.
Right! And that's us.
We're not even a couple anymore,
we're just like ...
excellents roommates.
the most excellent roomate.
- i know that Haley must be hurting right now .
And I betting you
she gonna change her mind.
My best decision i have ever made.
seriously,I've never been happier.
I can do whatever I want.
i can go dancing.
when was the last time,
you and Phil actually dance together?
i don't know, in our wedding?
-well, I want to dance every night.
And I want take my top off
and i want to get on with three guys at the same time.
Three guys at once?
that's a nightmare.
This is literally reccuring
stress that I have.
i don't understand what you want?
-i feel like, we know each other too well.
it's always the same conversation,
the same schedule ...
having a sex in the same position
twice a week
you guys having sex in twice a week?
- Yes, it was that rare.
Yes, rare. is why
I was surprised.
You are a lot like Naserin, Claire.
well, i'm not like Naserin.
- Yes you are.
Why are talking about me?
You're the one that going crazy ...
You're like Naserin because you are ashamed
of how vibrant you are.
You deserve to feel sexy, Claire.
And you need to walk among the birds.
- yeah, i don't really understand that metaphor.
It is not ...
- And Phil make me vibrant in different way ...
We have a date tomorrow night.
- Great.
okay, well enjoy the potatoes, candles, and the salmon.
walk among the birds.
Get that bird away from me.
Hey, honey.
Hey Katy. Guys
What did you learn in school today?
- Nothing.
oh, fantastic.
We have to pay for college.
Whose win?
-Do you want to change?
No, i think I'm good ...
I ...wow, you look nice.
I just throw this on it,
it's stupid ...
No, it isn't. no, you look great, fantastic.
I ...
I'm gonna to change and
i'm gonna take a shower.
We would not miss the movie.
- how about no movie?
how about i'm taking you
into dinner in the city?
We don't have to do that.
- Yes, we do.
come on, it'll done in 10 minutes.
i'm going to take you to the new Sea-Food
you read about ...
Claw? it's impossible to get in.
And the city is so far.
- No, it's not that far.
don't you tell all your perspective client,
the city was 20 minutes away?
Yes, I'm lying to them. It's an hour.
if we ready in ten minutes, we be there before
seven and get a table and no problem.
Yes? Say yes. Yes.
- Yes.
alright, i do it.
Hi, how are you doing?
- Names, please.
We actually don't have reservation.
- We've been trying to call, but we couldn't get through.
yeah, we're super duper busy.
- i figure this much, we hoping to get here earlier ...
and actually get a table.
you didn't quite make did you
- Nope.
do you have any tables open?
- Yeah ...
the things is, people made reservations like a months
in advance ...
and now it's Friday, at 7.30
on a fascinating Island of Manhattan ...
So ... No.
the thing is, my wife and i are on a date and
we hoping tonight to be sort of special  ...
So, just asking you if maybe you have
any table available?
well, i'm gonna have to ask you to wait at the bar
and if any of reserved are cancel ...
I come and get you, okay.
- Thank you.
Bye bye.
- okay, we'll be sitting over there.
okay, I already forgotten about you.
this is Claw,  your welcome.
you know what, i feel we gonna get a table.
I think tonight we gonna get lucky.
well, Good night.
- i didn't, i have no idea what are you talking about.
Thank you. you're very kind.
-you wanna have drink?
Yes, something with a great garnish,
because I am so hungry.
Hello.
-hi
Two Chardonnay, please.
can i have some.. He's really distracted.
- maybe we should go somewhere place else?
No, just give us some time.
- Tripplehorn ...
the party of 2.
i just, I want tonight to be different, you know.
i know, so do I. But it's just so hard.
Tripplehorn, the party of 2.
- take back.
No, we're good.
- look around, this place isn't us.
Tripplehorn, the party of 2?
What do you think of Tina Tavern,
a cozy table for two.
It's fine, really.
- No, it's not.
Tripplehorn, party of 2!
us!
We are the Tripplehorn.
- Great.
This way.
What are you doing, Phil?
- Trust me, it's fine.
phil, i don't think we should be doing this.
- And here we are.
Can I take your coats?
- Yeah, thank you.
Enjoy your meal.
- Thank you.
oh, look at this table.
- Honey ...
No, honey. The Tripplehorn's
here no show.
Who we heard it?
i say, we sit back, relax ...
and enjoy the present finest food of the sea.
Or I suck on a napkin.
Holy ... look at this prices.
If we gonna pay this much for crab,
the best is he sing, dance ...
and introduce us to
The Little Mermaid.
hey, here's for a great night.
anyway, isn't a bad luck to
toast to an empty glass?
I don't think, that's a thing.
I would trade our kids
for life this plan.
You're so mean.
- It would be cool.
hey, what's the story?
yes, okay, he is a successful financier ...
and she is getting drunk enough
to get through to what gonna happen later.
Because he likes to do weird stuff.
i think, he gonna call her by
her mom names.
okay, back here, what's the story?
He is a record producer, and she
is an actor he want to sign.
oh No, that's Will.I.Am.
- Okay, he ...
and she is a backup singer ...
- No, he really actually Will.I.Am.
From Fergie.
- oh My God!
If I knew anything about Will.I.Am,
I will be really excited right now.
okay, Give me your phone.
- Why?
I'm taking a picture.
- What?
Give me your phone. You're luck over there.
- No,this is dump.
And you're gonna make fool of yourself.
oh, this gonna embarassed you so much.
did you get that?
You're a freak.
i can't believe you actually did.
Excuse me, Mr. and Mrs. Tripplehorn ...
Yes?
- Well, yes.
We are the Tripplehorn.
Who might i ask are you, to
be asking us who we are?
We just wanted to have a few
word with you, if that's okay.
And what is this about?
- i think, you know.
why don't we save a lot of embarrassment,
have this conversation in private.
okay, but can i have my rest of the meal on wrap?
because these truffles are
amazing and super expensive.
Get out. Now.
Honey, get out.
Now.
Can you just move now ...
it's a very expensive bottle.
okay, it's your glasses.
yeah, moving by choice.
Watch your step.
Come on guys, what's a big deal
we didn't hurt anyone, right?
If I were you, I wouldn't
say another word, bitch.
wow, let's just take it down a little bit, guys..
hey, what are you doing?
it's my wallet.
give me my phone, get away from me ...
-i am getting seriously pissed off.
Now I'm gonna have to pick that rosatto over
the ground to eat it.
I wanna to talk to your boss right now.
-i think we both now, that's not gonna happen, Mr. Tripplehorn.
Or should I say ...
Phil Foster?
next time you make a dinner reservation
don't uses the same aliases as your ransom
notes, genius.
ransom notes?
- Did you really think ...
you can steal from Joe Miletto,
and get away with it?
okay, someone somewhere is making a huge mistake.
Guys, seriously this is ...
this is just a big goofy misunderstanding.
We are Phil and Claire Foster ...
we don't know anything about ransom notes.
I assure you.
You sitting at the table.
The girl in front said ...
that you were the Tripplehorn.
- No, no ...
Let me explain.
My husband, very sweetly, but ...
delusionaly thought that we could make it here
earlier enough, to get a table...
and we didn't, we were late.
so, they were very rude to us.
they were so rude.
- and we heard them calling for the reservation of Tripplehorn ...
and we just "us!".
We just took it.
So you just took somebody elses
reservation?
for the record, I was against it.
but my husband get his plan in his head ...
and it become like a thing.
- I'm an idiot, sometimes.
Shut up.
I  believed you are the Fosters.
- Thank you.
I also believe you go by the aliases
Tripplehorn...
and you stole my boss property ...
and now you get too scared cheatless
to admit it.
I will give you three seconds
to give us back the Flash Drive!
okay, the three-seconds game?
you know, I this play every day with my kids.
This is a different version!
- one ...
ok, big mistake, this is all, there's a thing ...
- Two ...
okay, God! no he turned sideways
kill shot!
Help!
- Three!
No, no. All right,
I got the Flash Drive!
What?
-I thought so
Where is this?
It's in the park.
- The park?
could you be more specific.
the Central Park.
okay, this is what gonna happen.
we're all gonna take a little field trip to
to the Central Park ...
and you gonna show us exactly
where it is. okay?
Okay.
- move!
Why did you bring us to
the most isolate place in New York?
i don't know, the gun was sideways!
- We gotta go to place populated.
Maybe there will be people,
maybe some reacreational games..
Night Boating?
- Yes, very popular here. i dont know you recall about it
we will be fine.
We need to go to the boathouse.
- get out.
There's nobody here.
okay, you know, the night boating thing
was in Seattle.
i think, I make a blast whole track
a little bit here.
Open the door.
i think, you gonna have to break in,
cause I don't have a key.
Stay put.
We have to get people immediately.
you tell them that you have a condition.
and we need a medicine
you left the medicine in the car
that medicine, ...
only can administered
by a doctor
god, Why?
- It's for your penis.
Intravenous penis medicine,
and you're very shy.
We have to get to a nearest hospital.
- What is wrong with my penis?
let's go.
moving, man.
Where is it?
- okay, here the the problem
Phil has kind of a serious medical issue ...
- Claire, just give them the flash drive.
Claire, just give it to them.
- We need to get to a hospital.
But your penis.
It is a two-step procedure
and it's need to be done by a nurse.
Because there is a two-step ...
- My penis is fine!
and that can be a lot of blood.
- Show me where it is!
Come on!
- be a good girl.
And listen to your husband.
- Yeah, be a good girl, listen to me.
okay, I put the flash drive over there, in the corner.
Where in the corner? Show us.
Come on, it's not a game.
you're gonna have to lift this floorboard.
in there.
This is one.
It's somewhere in here.
- Where? I don't see it.
let's go!
Come on.
Here.
get in
Come on!
crank it.
- This is crank.
Come on.
Pick it up. Run.
We are going to die!
I don't want the kids
to live with your mother!
She's awful!
- wait, can you see?
No!
How the hell, did this happen?
- They sure are not at all like they seem.
You're dead, you're hear me!
you are dead!
are you okay?
oh god. Phil, come on.
We doesn't work cardio.
I'm not in bad condition.
I'm afraid.
me too.
you're done?
let it out.
let it all out.
oh, My God, are you bleeding?
- This is the Cabernet.
i'm sorry, do you have a gum?
i'm sorry, you gonna have to forgive me
i'm been working nine hours.
so, one more time, you were at the dinner where?
- at Claw.
That place in Tribeca,
with 50 $ soup?
How that work out for you?
- Not great.
We coudn't get a table, so we ended up taking
somebody elses reservations.
You took someone reservation?
- Yup.
We took it.
- You just took a table.
Just like that?
- we know, shocking.
so, we were middle of dinner
and these guys come up ...
turned up this guy work for
Joe Miletto.
That what they said.
When didn't know it at that time.
We thought they were just guys from the restaurant.
So we followed into the alley ...
and suddenly they just grab all our stuff.
That's why we don't have our ID on us.
then,yeah, that was scary. what?
Then they start waves gun around
then the talking about a flash drive.
honey, why did you grab on my knee?
- Because i just remembered that we are supposed
to meet our friend.
who are a gay couple,
the one we met on the night boating.
oh, my God! The Bald and The Crazy.
Gay couple, shit.
We forgot our gay couple dinner.
Can I say something?
Joe Miletto is not a nice man ...
So, if you some out blinking on his radar,
we need to talk about how we can help you...
No, you do not understand.
We took somebody reservation ...
So we need to undo what we've done.
- Stop!
sit down!
Arroyo?
- Yes?
Give me a second?
okey, look, I'll be right back.
get's your story again.
go go.
oh my god, now that guys are dressed like cops.
because that guys are cops.
Why are cops
involved? What is going on, Phil?
What are we going to do?
- Honey.
They're gonna kill us.
then, they're gonna burn our bodies in trash bag.
Breathe. are you breathing?
- Only in.
honey, focus.
Your eyes look crazy.
- I know, because i'm losing what we gonna do?
What we gonna do?
- We got to get out of here, we got to go home.
We can't go home.
-what are you talking about. Phil, I am going home.
I'm going home.
- Claire, they have our ID. They know where we live.
oh My God, the kids.
hello
-do you accept to collect a phone call from ...
My God, this phone smells like a urine.
- Yes, I accept.
Katy, are the kids are okay?is everything okay?
- Yes.
okay, listen to me, I'm gonna need you to stay
a litte late tonight.
That is gonna be a problem for me.
- What?
I actually have a party to get to.
- You talk to her.
Katy, hi it's Phil. I don't have time
to talk right now, I'll pay you double.
I do not think enough.
- Are you kidding me?
I could miss the party, but I think
great pleasure to talk to someone worth than thirty.
I see them.
- An hour? okay,fine.
just, get the kids out of the house right now.
don't go out the front door, go out at the back door.
take them to your house
Now it sounds some kind i'm in a danger here.
- No.
cause, that gonna run you extra five per hour.
- Fine, just get the kids out right now.
We love them, and everything is gonna be okay.
- tell we love them.
sucker. kids.
- now what?
They are safe. We need to find a some place
with a lot of people.
This is whole night was a mistake.
We are not these peoples.
We're just a boring couple from New Jersey,
this is a crazy idea.
no, it wasn't a crazy idea.
It was a dinner in Manhattan ...
one night where we don't want to
talk about the kids the whole night
or what we gonna do next week.
- Look where it brought us.
Should we call 911?
- honey, this is Joe Miletto we are talking about.
so?
- so, those cops are try to kill us ...
they are his pocket.
This guy owns cops.
We can't trust any cops.
- What we gonna do?
We can't go home, we can't
go to the police.
Miletto, he wants the Tripplehorn, why?
Because they have the Flash Drive.
okay, what if they gave the flash drive back?
- Why would they do that?
Because we gonna find them
and we make them do it.
If they have the Flash Drive
this is over.
okay, I like that, i'm completely with you.
I just want to ask you one question.
do not judge me. What is a Flash Drive?
- Seriously?
Phil, I can't.
- okay, it's a little device that we stick on the side of a laptop.
oh, it's a computer sticky thing?
in my office, we call it computer sticky thing.
okay, we need to get the computer sticky thing
to save our lives.
How? We don't know anything about the Tripplehorn.
- That's sound entirely true.
We know where they gonna have dinner tonight.
Come on.
Hello, up here. We were in here earlier
having dinner with our friend 'Sam.I.Am.
You mean Will.I.Am?
that you call them so that's weird.
i don't like that.
We were here, and Will.I.Am thinks he
left his phone on the table, so ...
so, we need to check on the table.
- I like to check the table for the phone.
If you don't mind.
- You understand what I'm saying? Look at me.
We need to check the table fot the phone.
oh my gosh, how are you not getting this.
we need to check the table fot the phone?
- Fine.
This way.
-wow, I just wasted half my life.
check the monitor.
he left there, he say he left it on the table,
well, that was just a big fat waste of time.
The King of Siam is going be living.
Thank you for all of your help,
I'm being sarcastic.
Mother fuck.
Claw, you're welcome.
We have a phone number. How does we use it
to find their address?
I think I know someone
who can help.
wait, how do you know this guy again?
I show him a bunches houses
in the state.
It was a few years ago, but I remember
he was some kind of security expert.
anyway, he ended find a place down here
from an agent in this office.
I forgot the address, but maybe
we can find it in a file.
Got a key?
- No, i don't. can I have your coat?
Yeah, you're cold?
I think we just pick the lock.
If I had a bobby pin
be able gets the lock open.
My God, who are you?
- Here, come on.
No, hon. we gotta get out.
- It takes only a minute.
His name is Holbrooke, Grant, you check
the file in cabinets. I'll find in the computer.
Come on.
Come on, rainbow wheel.
- That's a bad sound.
I got it.
- okay,go. let's go.
here we go. let's go.
detectives.
can you join me?
Why are you mess with a nice couple
from the burbs, Joe?
Isn't that little beneath
your pay grade?
This conversation would be even better
If I knew what you were talking about.
Phil and Claire Foster.
a couple of your goongs pick them up
earlier tonight at Claw.
They put a good scare into of them too.
Joe, you know what I'm talking about.
not ringing any bells. So unless
you want my date tonight ...
don't come back until
you have a warrant.
hey Slick, do we have a problem?
This is it.
This is the place.
hi, Hoolbroke, you might not remember me.
my name is Claire Foster ...
I am a real estate agent.
I showed you some places out state.
Claire. Yeah, I remember. It's pretty late.
-No, I know, and I'm so sorry.
This is an emergency. Could I just come up for a second?
It is very important.
alright, come on up.
I can't believe out of hundreds of clients
you remember this one guy.
well, I've always been good
with names and faces.
it's amazing that you recall like that, honey.
all the people that you see,
you be able to remember ...
this one ...
I get flashbacks of all
all those empty houses we saw.
We did look in a lot.
That's me.
This is my husband, Phil Foster.
- hey, whats up man?
listen, we have some troubles, and
we really need help.
I know it's late, but if
we just could come up, for one second ...
it's a relly an amazing story, and you
might be just of kind of man that could help us.
so, please, I own you
a huge favour.
yeah, sure. why not.
Come on.
have a sit.
man, you guys are lucky to be alive.
you right Claire, I would stay away from the cops.
which is why we are hoping that you would help us.
- That's the least I can do.
i mean, you are so patient with me.
All those long drive uptown .
it's be my pleasure.
This is definitely the right place for you.
i bet, the ladies love it too,right.
- It's alright.
i bet you do all kind of right.
tell you what, we should do.
We don't have a lot of time ...
so why don't you, shirt it up
and then we will get what we need, and ...
then we'll be out from here.
- basically, we have a phone number that we need ...
to get an address from, and i remember you
that you used run your own detective agency?
yeah, sort of. I mean i do private security, industrial
intelligence for government black ops ...
that sort of things.
There's is your shirt. No wonder you
couldn't find it. It's on her.
Phil, Claire, this is Natanya.
She is Israel.
They doesn,t speak much English.
you two make sex with us?
- No, thank you.
Thank you, no.
Goodbye.
- I met her in Tel Aviv ...
when I was working with the Mossad,
she is a sweet girl.
She seems really sweet. It was very nice
her to ask us to have sex.
so, you wanna give me that number.
We haven't seen the last of
Mr. and Mrs. Foster.
Somebody trip an alarm
in a real estate office...
security cameras got this.
The computer file they looking at show
an adress of Holbrooke Grant, West Village.
What in the world, are they doing?
- What do we have?
Small burglary.
just try to be friendly, Arroyo.
- Thank you, officer friendly.
leaving time?
- Yes, sir. See you guys tomorrow.
Good night.
hey, you gonna check this up?
- Yes, definitely, let start at real estate office.
See what they are
try to looking at.
wow, where did you got all this stuff?
- Radio Shack.
seriously?
seriously, what's wrong with him?
Let me see that number.
Soft hand.
I type the number here,
and the cellphone write Thomas Felton,
Tripplehorn probably an alias.
or maybe he is a big Jeanne Tripplehorn fan.
There is no address.
well, It's a cell phone, Claire.
We don't need address.
with the number we can locates the signal ...
- That is too cool...
you are good with you instruments.
there we go, Mr. Felton's phone resigning
at 135 Avenue D.
Great. Who likes shirts?
Thanks again, really.
- no, the least I can do.
Are you expecting someone?
- Mr. Grant, this is the NYPD. We need to ask a few questions..
oh my god, that's them. Those are the cops that
try to kill us.
hey, yo. coming down in minute. I'm having sex,
I'm kind of busy.
is that supposed to be me or 'Fat Albert' or somebody?
What was that?
Is there another way out of here?
please, down to my garage, okay.
There is a service elevator by the office ...
I keep them busy.
just go.
Can we get out this way?
- yeah, i think so.
okay, they are still there. we not gonna be able
to pass them. Think..
What are you doing?
there we go
-You can't do this, Phil. this is Holbrooke's car.
we have to get out here fast.
Do you have a better idea?
That's not really driving in the city.
This is a sports car.
well, thank God for Holbrooke, right.
- Yup.
Thank God.
no, actually screw Holbrooke.
- excuse me?
screw Holbrooke. what was that? Who were you upstairs?
Who is that person?
giggly, flirty, charming person. who was that?
- What are you talking about?
what am i talking about.
when you took one look at him, you light up
like a sparkly sparkle.
-okay, that is not true.
is it true. And i get it.
because I light up too.
He is super hot. And why do you need
muscles on your shoulders ?
like that.
And I'm just the husband.
i'm just a dork who doesn't know
how to load the dishwasher.
I'm the guy who need to workout more.
who lights up for the husband?
- oh my god. you are right. I keep forgetting to light up for you.
well, that's ...
- Why do i keep forgetting to do that?
oh wait, I remember.
It's because every day i get up ...
make breakfast, go to work,
come home, clean the house...
pick up the kids, take them to
soccer, bring them back from soccer, cook dinner ...
clean them that dirt, give them the bath,
get them into their pyjamas which is ...
they fight every night,
it is a big surprise to everbody ...
every night they have to wear pyjamas,
and then after I have wash everybody elses ...
food and boggers after meal
I use whatever energy I have left ...
to physically put myself into our bed,
instead of lighting up for you.
yeah, let's pull over.
This is a great time to ...
Yes, we have to pull over.
I know you work hard, honey.
But you know what make all that hard work
ten times easier?
me.
If you just trust me to handle
things once in a while. But no, you don't.
You have to do it all yourself, your way.
you got me screw enough,
before I even got a chance to come true to you,.
but, If you just let me do something for you,
I think ...
that, I will surpurised you.
i really do
I know what's surpurising.
You think, I don't hear myself,
you think i like a total bitch?
you know, Brad and Hailey are split now.
- I know.
did you ever think about
leaving me?
No.
really, you never fantasized about
leaving me for another man?
never, no, god. If anything, i fantasized sometimes about
being alone.
What's that mean?
- just, there a times ...
when I just thought about,
of my worst day ...
just, leaving our house, just going someplace
like check in to a hotel ...
and just being in a quiet room by myself
just sitting in a quite air conditioning room ...
sitting down, eating my lunch with no one
touching me ...
drinking a diet sprite.
by myself.
- Thats sound awful.
look, I just wanna have one day that doesn't
depends on how everybody elses day goes .
It's not that i have gross sex fantasy or something.
That I would understand.
that make sense to me
mean, everybody have gross sex fantasies.
i mean, obviously, yours with Holbrooke.
Mine with Cyndi Lauper.
Really? but present.
- Any time of day.
What an interesting choice.
Brad said to me that, he and Haley were fine
And they were just really excellent roommates.
it's not we are, isn't it?
- No.
Right?
We should be going.
135 Avenue D. Here it is.
alright, I park here.
They are not home.
We'll wait.
-for how long, Phil?
The cops from the Holbrooke
could be headed over here right now.
okay, fourth floor.
What are you doing?
- If we can't find the Tripplehorn ...
maybe we can find their Flash Drive.
Come here.
We can do this.
- one night I dressed up.
here we go. Ready?
One, two, three, go!
it's on you.
Everything you doing, I'm doing in heels.
I just want you to think about that.
They stamp a chicken nugget
with a sharpy.
These are bad people.
Look over there, I look here.
Damn it, Phil.
-sshh. What?
Why don't you ever close any drawers?
- I'm sorry.
You never ever close any drawer
you ever opened.
shh. Don't move.
Who is there?
- okay, move now.
This is not what you looks like.
- yeah, look at this bitch.
oh, my neck.
- wait, stop. we can explain
stop talking.
- What the hell are you doing here?
Sit down.
move, you two.
Careful.
alright, you must be Thomas Felton?
People call me 'Taste'.
I bet people also call you
Tripplehorn.
I'm a big Jeanne Tripplehorn fan.
- Yes, she's a fine actress.
Who is this?
- I'm Whippet.
Whippet like, the dog?
No, like when you sucks nitrus,
out of the whiped cream can.
Stupid skink.
- oh my god, do you have any contact with your mother at all?
This is a nice peace.
what we gonna do have a duel with ten paces?
hey, zip your face.
- zip my face?
are you serious?
-yeah, he said "zip your face."
that's your best line?
that's your best tough guy line?
You heard me, zip your face.
- why don't you zip your vagina, Raymond Burke.
I have know idea how to respond to that.
'F' you.
- 'F' me, 'F' you.
- 'F' you, man. What are you doing here?
'F' you, mother Fr.
okay, what do you want?
- You have no idea what you've done to us.
What?
When you've miss your reservation at Claw
You've ruined our lives.
What are you talking about?
- We didn't miss anything, you dumbass.
We saw the two goongs
check the place out , so we took off.
were you the reservation police or something?
- What is to you?
We don't have the reservation,
So we have took yours.
And now they think that we're you.
You just took our reservation?
Who does that?
What kind of people are you?
Come on.
- How did you find us anyway?
I stole your number from
the reservation list.
That's smart.
- Thank you.
you used our real number
to make that reservation?
No, i don't use the home number,
i use the cell phone.
oh, wow. that's brilliant.
wow, Taste. you're just a goddamn criminal mastermind.
So, this is about how I'm an asshole all the time, ha?
I have no trust that i can pull thing trough?
Yeah.
- I can't do anything right?
I buy the wrong soda,
the wrong beer ...
I hear you, man.
- The wrong nipple clamps.
Those clamps hurt me.
And then you come home, you don't
even look at me.
I have to beg to sex with me.
like it's a gift.
And forget the back door.
Forget that.
- we've forgotten.
I am sorry, if I am a little tired,
after working all night.
to just come home, you jump on you,
and give you a free lapdance.
i am sorry. I was practically very happy stripping
and tricking at the Hippo.
It make me feel good about myself.
I got a rippen.
and no, you have to go, get all greedy. ...
and stealing everything from everyone.
- okay, that's enough.
excuse me for dreaming. like I want to spend of
the rest of my life sell the stolen wheelchair.
I think you're losing control.
what about my dream? And what about me?
- Stop arguing.
Stop arguing. stop it.
shut, everybody shut the holes.
shut the holes.
- Be quiet.
listen, These goongs were after us, because
they think we have a flash drive ...
that you've stole from them.
so, you gonna go to them...
and tell them that you are
The Tripplehorn.
Wait a second, bitch.
- Don't call me a bitch, whore.
Are you telling me that this goongs are tracking you right now?
- Have you not heard a word I said, whore?
look, that is why we are here.
You need to help us out of this.
no, we need to get out right now.
Whippet, baby, 2 minutes thrilled.
Ready? go.
let's go.
- You can't leave.
Forget Latex.
Only the essential.
Stop packing, nobody
is going anywhere.
Stop. You are over packing.
- What are you doing?
we must walk away in 30 seconds.
Bobby De Niro, a classic.
okay, no way. nobody is going anywhere.
hold on, stop. Nobody going anywhere.
pay attention to me.
wait
-here is what we gonna do.
you gonna go get the flash drive, and you gonna bring it ...
- give it him yourself.
baby, we're off.
- Yes.
yeah, I'm ready. Here.
Come on.
- Wait.
wait, maybe leaving isn't such a good idea.
This is our home.
No, it's not.
This is your home.
Come home.
hey, how we supposed to get this to Miletto?
Joe Miletto. The guy that you blackmailing.
You're far from home, aren't you?
- What's that supposed to mean?
good night.
That's gone
not at all as I had expected.
let's go. Did you see how he was tongue with her?
- Yes.
detectives, Welcome.
Are you Holbrooke Grant?
- Yes.
you want to put some clothes on, so we can talk?
- No, i'm good.
It's late and I'm pretty must said
everything that i have to say to other cops.
Wait. What other cops?
What do you think, when Taste man earlier said that
we were long away from home?
honey, his named is Taste.
I wouldn't worried to much in to it.
watch this?
- Gun.
This gun, sucks.
oh my god, be careful.
- stop yelling at me. I know what i'm doing, alright.
come on, one way.
- I'm sorry.
I am sorry, just hold on.
What are you doing?
-okay, hold on.
We need to get you out of us.
We gotta go quickly as possible, Phil.
That's not working.
- Put your jerk in reverse, you asshole.
You put your jerk in reverse.
you put your jerk in reverse.
In reverse.
oh snap, somebody pissed.
Phil. oh god
well, that's look like they coming with us.
okay
why I'm going backwards?
Take your foot off the brake.
- No.
Come on.
hey, don't put your foot on the brake.
- No, I don't want to get off.
hey, take the wheel.
- What?
Just take it.
He got to release off the brake.
No.
what do you think you are, ha?
honey, move your ass.
Move over.
we get in, now.
oh god, why did they wanna
kill us so badly?
hey, do you have a computer or a BlackBerry?
something that can read the document
I got a kindle.
- Give it.
It's a gift, don't break.
- seriously?
make me cry.
oh my god, That's  Crenshaw.
that the DA.
Claire, we got to get off the street.
- Why?
alright, you gonna take a hard right.
I got plan. wait
Now!
This is the NYPD.
The higway has been sealed.
stop your vehicle immediately.
Great, Phil.
- I gotta to try something.
I thought I had a plan.
- I love you Phil, but your plans are not work.
look here, you two are married people
are stalk together  ...
from my life is not a stake, okay.
husband, when I hit the horn,
you press it ...
wife, when gonna with the drive
you throw it.
let's do this.
- We got him!
alright, people,
one, two, three ...
Stop the vehicle.
- Now!
what did I tell you?
And now, pull over
and you can done ...
no brake.
- The brake doesn't work?
The brakes are gone.
that's is a bullshit.
I'm out, bye
alright, see you later.
I'm okay.
come. come on.
come on honey, everything will be okay.
are you okay?
- really cold.
oh, no. the Flash Drive is gone.
The Tripplehorn are gone.
We gotta nothing.
come on, let's see if Holbrooke have
a blanket or something in the car.
alright, I am dying to hear
what the hell happen.
Well, we're having some beer, okay
and then two people, that you let go...
walk into the bar.
The Fosters?
The Fosters.
You have a good memory.
they come in and next thing
i know they shooting at us.
Mr. Foster? the tax lawyer
from New Jersey are now armed?
That,s odd..
that's extremely dangerous, what it is
so we took chased.
You know what, great work, fellas.
why don't you both go home.
If you want, we just stay here
and help you find them.
good night.
we've got you.
- Say your prayers.
so, what was on that
computer sticky thing anyway?
just some ledgers and pictures.
Pictures of what?
- of services rendered.
at one of Joe's Milletto clubs
that's call a Peppermint Hippo.
that don't even matter now, the computer
sticky thing is at the bottom of this river.
which is, we're will be
those cops catch up us.
okay, walk me through this again ...
Honey!
- If I'm gonna get whack off ...
at least, i'm deserved to understand
why its happening.
What are you smiling about?
- no. you're very sweet, we're not going...
no, we're not going to get whack off.
- I think we are.
I don't think we are.
The thing is, this ledger had only
pictures and information about one client.
DA, Crenshaw.
- The guy with the broom?
The Tripplehorn, they may have
stolen the Flash Drive from Miletto  ...
they were blackmailing the DA.
which is why, Taste acted weird
when you brought up Miletto's name.
oh, Phil. I so got this.
but, something to do with Crenshaw?
yes honey, it is everything to do with
Crenshaw...
that's the key. we have to
find the way to get to Crenshaw.
well, the Tripplehorn got him
at the Peppermint Hippo.
And we are Tripplehorn
hell, yes. we are.
We gonna need some help.
- oh, wax off, of god.
Is that my tracksuit?
Yes, it was in the trunk of your Audi ...
which is now parked over by the
East River ...
and probably he need a significant repair...
for which i'm sure i'll be able to
pay you back over the next several decades...
also on my cab, i would like to add that super old gun
that i stole from your hall way...
which incidently is never useful.
He just run popped ..
- But thats not the reason we're here.
as impossible as this maybe to believe...
Holbrooke, our night has actually
gotten weirder since we saw you last ...
There were cars, then we were hook in.
one of those yours cars, anyway ...
I have an interesting night myself
and I am really tired, so ...
and its nice and worst to see you again, Claire
i put you to took a knock to somebody else's door.
no. here's a thing.
I just wanted to take my wife to dinner tonight ...
I was just hoping that we would have one night
where we could, you know, feel like new ...
but now all I wanna do is getting home.
and, i've got a plan
i've got a way to do that ...
i'm not very good with plans generally
but I got one ...
and I need help.
even though you packs
make me wanna kill myself ...
and your girlfriend is so hot, its like looking
through a jet engines ...
I know and believe that
there a real person ...
that understands exactly
what i'm going through right now.
So please, Holbrooke,
just let us come in?
will you let us explain to you
what we want ...
and will you, fill of
put on the fucking shirt?
Come on in.
Here it is, you know the plan?
- here we.
Let us tell, Its a new girl,
she is working tonight.
I don't know what you're talking about.
- I'm the new girl.
Really?
And who are you?
I'm her pimp daddy.
- You're her pimp?
Yeah ass bag, he is my pimp,
listen i go inside to start my shift ...
or should I call Joe Miletto
and tell him that his spell boy maybe late
I don't really have gum.
The locker room is on the left.
- Come on, pimp.
Wait here.
- Where are you going?
not that, just like a monkey.
Hey, I'm a man on bottom,
you want into that?
Sorry I ...
oh my God!
yah, I know,
shut up.
You look awsome.
Why it is so bright out here,
it supposed to be dark and dim...
i'm just a 40 year old stripper
mama break
look at your boobs.
- I had to put it in backward ...
and spin it.
I think I lost the nipple.
No, you look great.
- for reals?
yeah, for reals.
This is the only one long enough
to cover my caesarean scar.
I cannot stop looking at your boobs.
okay, let's go.
I want you to buy that.
This is the end of day isn't it.
Honey, I don't think I can do this.
yes you can, honey listen to me
you are a beautiful strong woman ...
you are the mother of my children.
and I want you to go in there ...
and pop that Gucci.
pop the Gucci ,
-just pop it out,
- so we can go home.
let's go pop it. come on .
- I can.
look up please.
okay, get in.
No, the both of you.
He likes you two.
well, somebody caught the pervert eye.
-no, I can't do this.
you can, because you are a beautiful
and an amazing man and the father of my children ...
you gonna get in there
walk that pole like a runaway.
There he is, over there with the sunglasses.
he has a broom with him
oh, that's a gross, why does he need that.
honey, a lot of messes to clean up in here.
Can I help you?
- yeah, we are here to see Crenshaw.
You can only close to Crenshaw unless he
he picks you.
pick us, yes.
pick us for what?
Carlton, move aside.
I want you, honey.
very wild, western, lounge shape.
minus the syphilis.
You gotta a mouth on you,
I like that.
And you brougt androgenouse
friend.
oh, Is he a man or a woman.
I don't know.
I'm gonna keep you guessing.
It's very sexy.
Why don't you two show
me what you got.
I think he wants us to
have sex in front of all.
If we have to do
we'll do the fast version.
come on, if wanna spend time with me
you have to earn it.
So, get up there.
ladies, please move to side. thank you
you know what,
we're not actually some...
we're not into dancing so much,
We rather just talk to you ...
while main relatively stealth.
We want to talk to you.
- I'm don't come here to talk ...
you wanna to leave or go you're start dancing.
one of another, whats you gonna do?
I,m not feeling what they're doing.
Carlton, please...
escort this two out.
no. alright, we're just getting warm up.
now, we are really gonna make it happen.
here we go!
- now it is on!
totally on
it is getting hot and wild.
oh my god, where he is taking her?
Phil, don't you barb on me.
don't barb?
Sex robots.
you two, come over here.
We have something that you want.
- oh, I know you do.
How much for a night?
- $ 100,000.
hah, That's a little steep isn't it. I don't know
any more minutes we can count of money.
How about one with
a Flash Drive?
How are you doing?
We are the Tripplehorn.
oh, they just keep showing up.
Why don't we take a walk
and talk about things.
in privately.
This is gonna be so good.
This is part of the plan right?
I gotta go back to subway
for a refresher.
okay, let's make this simple, okay ...
you give me the Flash Drive
or Collins is gonna breaks both your wife arms.
I put the flash drive someplace that no one
is ever gonna find it ...
part of it, Mr. Holbrooke Grant hear from us
every hour until hour, until we are safe ...
then he will release content of that
drive.
He is the ex-military
that we have questioned tonight ...
Holbrooke Grant.
What's the hell going on up here?
excuse me sir, we're trying to do a roof club thing
if you just give a minute.
No, i can't give you a minute.
This is my roof, toptouch.
okay
-It is okay Claire, we expected that.
what, oh my god
i'm so lost.
They were just about to
leave, Joe ...
you know, the guy that have said
that he have flash drive. theres no play here
Have you seen the flash drive?
oh, don't worry though,
We won't say a word about the pictures.
just, shut your mouth.
- What pictures?
Nothing.
-he doesn't know?
know what?
- oh, wow. i'm gonna pull over here.
Sorry, but I get it, i'm totally know why
you have pornographic pictures of the DA ...
you never know
what gonna coming in handy?.
just zip it, Skippy.
- you zip your vagina.
No, its okay. when he says vagina,
he means your face.
You said it what is on that Drive
was the city contracts ...
that i flow your wiped.
All this time, I've been keeping the cops of your ass...
and your stashing dirty picture of me?
- Very dirty, gross pictures.
You'll be in jail for what you done for me
So watch your tone, Mr. DA.
looks like you guys have something to resolve
So, my wife and I will be going.
no. no one is moving, so it will be a lot of
easier if someone in here.
Phil, turn the gun like we see in "The Kill Shot".
Put the gun down!
- Come on, cops.
It's gonna be okay.
- no, this is not okay. this is a bad plan.
shoot.
- they will be shooting everybody.
Claire, look at me ...
look at me!
I got this...
I have got this.
Count to three.
- What?
Just count it down.
- No, that doesn't work with grown ups.
thats doesn't work with people with gun
Trust me.
alright, I have had enough ...
my kids gonna had me in 90 minutes
so this shit ends now ...
I'm gonna count into three and everyone of you boys
is gonna put down your guns.
Does she serious?
one.
- I think she serious.
Two.
- it's just kidding, right?
Three.
This is the NYPD, put down your weapons
put your hands in the air.
put down your weapons
and hands in the air.
I'm a cop.
- No, not anymore, you're not
I told you I could surprise you.
good to see you again, Detective.
You too Mr. Foster.
- This was part of the plan?
The helicopter and the SWAT team
are all part of the plan?
he had your friend, Holbrooke called me, said to
be here 5.30 ...
you have something for me?
- Yes, i do.
I think there is enough evidence
of this wire to put those two away for quite some time.
Thank you.
Mr. Miletto, Mr. DA ...
you two are under arrest,
for obstruction of justice ...
extortion, conspiracy and I'm pretty
sure prostitution.
get them out of here.
so, you two need a ride?
Yes please, our kids must
be freaking out.
No, we've sent SWAT out there,
they are fast asleep with the sitter.
Thank God.
What is your story?
Just a boring married couple from
New Jersey.
So how about that ride.
actually, i promised my wife
to have dinner in the city.
I'm not sure but I think this
the best pancake I've ever had in mylife.
How did even begin to come up with the whole plan?
It's like that book
from the book club ...
Nasrin makes her brother and
stepfather to fighting each other ...
so she can flee the town through out
the desert ...
and menstruate in peace.
What?
- You read it? you read the book?
Of course. I read all of them
Why?
- Because it's matter to you.
I only read the first 30 pages
and the last page.
Who has time to read. I don't
like those book.
What? do i have something?
-no
I'll do it again, you know.
what, tonight, no,
it was very dangerous.
no, not tonight.us.
You and me, the kids, all of them.
I'll do it again.
I choose you, every time.
by NaJwa nash