How much?
20 cents, 5 cents added more
for bottle taken away
What's your name?
Why'd I tell you?
I've already known it
You're named...
So Lai-chun
Who told you that?
You'll see me tonight
in your dream
I didn't see you in
my dream last night
Of course,
you haven't slept at all
It's useless!
You'll see me, for sure
You look something special today
What? Nothing special
Nothing
Why do you have red ears?
What do you want?
I just want to make friends with you
Why should l?
Look at my watch!
Just one minute, OK?
Time's up, speak now
Today is...
16th
16th... April 16
April 16, 1960,
one minute before 3 pm
You are with me
Because of you,
I'll remember that one minute
From now on,
we're friends of one minute
This is fact, you can't deny it
Cause it's past
I'll come tomorrow
Haven't he remember
that minute for me?
I don't know
But I've memorized this guy
Later on, he did come everyday
We became friends,
started from that minute
...to 2 minutes
Later, we dated at least
an hour a day
How long have we known each other?
Very long... I've forgot
My cousin is going to
get marry soon
Really? Send my congratulation to her
She said that
she'd live with her husband's family
What's that mean?
I've to find some place else to live
I'd like to live with you
So, how should I tell my dad?
Tell what?
Our affair!
What affair?
Would you marry me?
No!
I'll never come back
Didi, be quick, come over here
Your mother has drunk,
she has drunk too much
I'm in a hurry
Give her a cup of tea
Are you hungry?
Do you want something to eat?
Who's that guy?
Only one pair of earring,
take it back if you want to
I don't think that it all you have stolen
I've told you many times
that I never stolen!
She gave it to me willingly
You mean she was willing
to pay for your living?
Do you think it's so easy to do so?
Don't beat me...
Then?
Stop beating me!
What?
What? Say it out...
Louder!
I stole it!
It's me, I stole it...
I don't want you to see
my mother again
you can change now
Have you seen any earring?
No, but I can look it up for you
Hey, what are you doing here?
You like this earring?
For you
Hey!
Why only one?
I'll wait for you downstairs
Who's place is it?
My home
I've never promised to
go home with you
But you've never refused
Are you living alone?
Is the rent high?
$40
Wow, my family live in a room
which costs $28 only
Do you bring girls home oftenly?
Sometimes
Let's make a deal,
I'll stay a while only
It's stuffy
Are there many families
living here?
Why it's empty?
You're nosy, aren't you?
Where's the toilet?
Let's go & eat something
Why don't you say earlier?
It's raining heavily
I'd better leave now,
take me home
Why did you come with me then?
I've just promised to stay a while,
who do you think I am?
Don't think that
I can easily go to bed with men
Don't think that you can
do anything
be sending me a pair
of poor earring
I'm different from those
flapperish girls!
Don't come over
Guess how long you can
stop breathing
Thief! Who's that?
It's me!
My friend
I've told you many times
that you'd not climb up
I don't want the lndian guard
to bother me
I don't know that you've a friend here,
I leave now
Take the stairs
Where I come, where I go
Your friend is strange,
what's he?
Don't be nosy!
Is he a thief?
What time is it?
3 am
I've to go home now
Shall we meet tomorrow?
May be
Well, call me
Do you have my phone number?
I'll write it down
Call after 1 1,
or I won't be there
Leung Fung-ying?
Aren't you called Lulu?
My colleagues don't know
my Christian name
Keep your promise to call, OK?
OK
I know you won't call me
I will
You don't even memorize
my number!
It's written down, why should l
keep this in mind then?
How about if it lost?
if it is lost,
I may be lost too
Go & lost it, if you dare!
If you lose it,
I will cut your face!
Stop saying that to me
You're great!
Where there's an illness,
there's a cure!
Are you going home?
I'll call you a cab
I don't want to go home now
Well, stay here then
Go to hell!
Good morning
Why you still sitting here?
Why don't you go home?
You haven't gone home too
I'm not going to talk to you
Hey!
Have I ever met you before?
I don't think so
But, have you ever noticed me?
You know it pretty well
What's your job?
My job?
Turn the volume of the
radio louder please
Any idea? Got it?
Not yet
Dance once more for me OK?
Do you want to take
advantage from me?
Hey... What's your name?
Call me Mimi
I've heard that there was
a kind of bird with no legs
It could fly and fly only...
When it got tired,
it slept in the wind
This kind of bird
could land only once
That was the time it died
Auntie
Come here, I want to talk to you
Excuse me
Hey, who is she?
What do you mean?
What?
Why did you beat him?
He tried to cheat your money!
Who said so?
No one
If not why should he be with you?
How old is he?
And how old are you?
You are not young!
Right, he does it for money,
but he can make me happy
Have you ever made me happy
after so many years?
Have you?
Right, I never made you
happy before
Then, let's be unhappy together
What do you want?
You know it pretty well
I've told you many times
I won't tell you anymore
You want to find your
own mother, right?
Go and find her yourself
if you can
I've taken care of you
for so many years,
Anything I want to say,
I have said it long ago
I didn't say it before because
I don't want you to leave
And I won't say it now still
Cause I don't think it's worth to
I tell you,
...what can I get if
you go to find her?
Nothing!
And you will forget me as well
Why are you starring at me?
OK, I want you to hate me
At least, you won't forget me
Come on, treat me better
Maybe, I will tell you some day
If not, never dream so
Alright, I will wait for
that moment
Is his mother rich?
I think so, she used to be
a prostitute before
You know York for long?
He lived in the flat up
above our garage
Do you know
what is in his mind?
I don't know
But I know what is in your mind
What?
Don't fall in love with me
It's so late, what're you doing here?
Waiting for my friend
What's the matter?
A girl downstairs said
that she was your friend,
you'd better go & have a look
Excuse me
Why do you come for me?
I'd like to take back my stuffs
Come up then
I'd like to stay with you
What for?
I'm not suitable for you
I don't like marriage
like the others do
I don't mind
I just want to stay with you
Why are you so attentive to me?
You can't please me
for my whole life!
You won't be happy to stay with me
Have you ever loved me?
I don't know how many women
else I'd fall for in my life
I won't know whom I love
most till the end of my life
Wait here
I'll collect the things for you
Somebody's home?
Who is outside?
Don't be nosy!
Take off you slippers
Why?
It belongs to someone else
It's hers? Who say so?
Any proof here?
Are you going to take it off?
No!
A woman comes up suddenly,
...and she claims that this is hers,
that is hers,
How can I know how many women
would come up later?
If one comes & says
that you are hers,
should I give up?
I give nothing
Once I step in here,
everything is mine
Why you come up?
I've told you to stay downstairs
I'm leaving
Well, sleep with the
slippers tonight
Are you care about the slippers?
OK, I'll return it to her
Are you satisfied?
Somehow, nothing in this
house belongs to me!
What am l? I'd better leave!
Don't come back once you step out
Do you treat all women like this?
I won't be as stupid as her!
What are you doing?
Why do you treat me like this?
Stop it, I'm hurt...
How come it's you again?
Why don't you go home?
Many trouble will be solved
after a good sleep
Can you lend me few dollars
for me to take a cab?
I've only $5, is that enough?
How can I pay you back?
Forget it
I'm always on duty around here
A chance may be, take it
It's you
I'm taking the money back to you
No hurry, it doesn't matter
Sorry about that
Thanks! Are you alright?
I'm leaving now,
I have to go to work
So late at night?
What kind of job?
I am working in the SCAA
There's games holding tonight,
I've to work in the box office
Then I can have free ticket
for football match
I like football match before,
but now, I'm busy
If you want to see
any game in future,
just come to me
Then thanks a lot
Bye
Can we chat?
I can't help you about
your boyfriend
I just want to chat
You got no friends?
I don't want others to know it
Then how about me?
If I don't...
If I don't say it out,
I'm afraid that I'd be mad
I thought that I would be OK
I always tell myself
Don't tell others that
you are unhappy
Work hard
Go home and sleep earlier
I want to go home!
But my home is in Macao
I don't know how to
kill these nights
I can't sleep
I don't mean to come back
I promise myself that
I wouldn't go back anymore
I'll hate myself if I go back again
I don't want to hate myself
Help me please
You can't be like this still
I will be OK by getting
through this night
You are cheating yourself
by saying this only
How did you pass last night?
If you had passed last night,
you wouldn't have been here
You should make up your mind
If you really can't live without him,
...why don't you tell him?
If not, pretend not
knowing this guy
from this very minute
Don't mention "this very minute"
I always think that a minute
can pass very fast
But sometimes it takes long
One day, one pointed at
his watch and told me,
...he would remember me
forever for that very minute
It was very pleasant to me
But now when I look at the watch,
...l will tell myself,
...l have to forget that guy
from that very minute
When I was young in Macao,
I dreamed to ride on a tram
Whenever my cousin returned
from Hong Kong
I would ask her when would
she take me to HK
Your cousin is from Hong Kong?
No, but she studied in
HK when young
She is great,
she got a job in an office
just after graduation
And her boyfriend is
smart as well
She is going to get married soon
Not everyone will be
in good luck
Don't compare with others
I didn't think that
I was poor before
Till I found out that
I didn't have a new uniform every year
But my classmates all had new ones
At that moment,
I realised that I was poor
What make you to be a police then?
I wanted to be a sailor
But my mother's health
was not so good
And there was no others at home
So I had to stay over to
take care of her
Don't you think it's bored
walking around all the night?
I don't think so
I'm tired, I want to go
home now
If there are anyone
who can talk to,
...come to me
But I don't want to interfere
your working hours
You can phone me then
I am here around this
time everyday
Hey, do you have enough
money for the fare?
Yes, bye
I never dream that
she will call me
But I always stop in front of
the telephone kiosk
Maybe she has returned to Macao
Or maybe she just wants someone
to kill a night with her
No soon, my mother past away
Then I changed to be a sailor