Sync and corrections by YaSh069
-=Team ExDR=-
Chicago 1990
That's it
Today there is going to be a storm.
It's a challenge
The whole world will be sunk!
Where is he?
What is this?
Magic!
Papa, it's $25 I have...
I know, the bank loan is a lot!
This will help us to save our circus
This $25 you keep it
The bank loan is a lot!
Till you have this $25
No, bank can shut us down!
Papa, why is the bank not
agreeing with your...
Papa did speak to them
Cause you are a special joker!
If, you like our act
Do not shut our circus!
Papa might if they don't like
my acting... how dare you!
They must agree with me!
Everything will be fine!
Cause you are my magician
Do you know who is he?
Yes!
Me, Sahir.
Please show your magic to the
Bank owner's will be happy!
We are god's grace!
We must not loose hope!
Sahir, don't apologize to our enemy
Do not give up hope!
We must respect our honour!
This circus is my only hope!
You are tearing it apart from me!
Bank owner's
Papa
We are god's grace!
What?
He is not answering his mobile!
It's a pressure cooker!
They asked me to hold!
You finally decide to kill me!
Yes?
Short cut I am a hero
Have you not see how handsome,
I am.
Why kill a policeman!
Your god must be saying
How handsome I am
Let him go!
Listen to your guru
Why come to my area and arrest me!
How dare you think like that!
Must I tell you the truth
Please!
Every year on the 15th august
independence day
Every person must be have
equal rights in our country!
Do you think we are equal!
My aunty... Hemamalini
Equal!
No... boss
No chance!
Why spoil the reputation
for our country!
Like good people like me
And bad goo's like you!
Who is goa wi the match!
The day you are behind jail
Have you think so much
Before coming to me!
Actually its Jai's brother's idea!
But Jai fights and the question!
When he punches you feel pain!
No, sir
I only need one back up
When he comes it's like a storm!
Ali
Hey kill them!
Ali, come
Stop!
Can not apply brakes!
Mummy help!
Come, I'll chop you both!
Ali... yes brother
Run!
Papa, I know the bank loan is a lot
to return
As log as you have this $25
No bank can shut us down!
Our circus is the greatest
on this planet!
Circus is my only dream
But, you are tearing it apart from me!
I, am back home papa.
Ali, you at a new city
Do not try and woo any girl!
Stop your glazing at girls!
No, brother
Ali became a international police!
Ali's eye is only on the thief.
And, Ali's ears... motor bike
4 cylinder... BMW!
Confirm
She can't speak Hindi
What ever English I knew
I spoke it!
How will we go!
Three, is not allowed to ride a bike
He is gone with victory
Three days she will be mine!
Only Ali
Will it be done
Yes sir
We practice for so log
Did not ever think we will be on platform
No, idea have you done this
But it's amasig!
I did not work alone
I borrow from the bank!
Where is my actress!
All the girls audition is taken
What are you looking for dude!
A girl must come like fire!
Must be brave and courage!
Must, be have some madness!
We need brain to find her!
Who is she!
She is crazy man!
I won't return today!
One chance
please
This is not a reality show
One minute
Put me down
Who are you?
The one you are I search
Please, give me a chance
o 0e audition
You have just 5 minutes
Five minute if my eyes is out
of you... then you out!
And do not return ever again!
Promise, I swear on my unborn children!
My five minute is up
Can you remove your eyes
I'm trying that from a long time
Liar
I swear on my unborn children?
Aliyah
Welcome to the great Indian circus
Aliyah!
You are fired!
Chicago police thinks the thief
is Asian!
Mr, Dixit what have you got to say
about the thief!
In, few days two robberies
I don't think he is a true thief
No, thief leaves so much of evidence!
He likes to run
My advice to him
Escape from this city!
Do you think he will loot again!
If he has the courage
People are afraid
I don't think we must fear
this thief!
He is a clown
When I get him
He will entertain in jail
Do you think you can get him
Destiny is always in police hands!
This clown is in my hand
I like to meet
Mr. Dixit
I am very pleased to meet you!
Sahir Khan
Want to tell you something!
I am the thief!
No one knows about it...
now you
I did 0t understand!
The great Indian circus
Is the name of my show!
The thief you are I search for
I have a trick for him
Which I'll be showing at my show!
2005 circus fantastic
That is me
And behind is the thief!
We are only clowns at a circus
And he is a magician!
He had no enemies
And he won't speak to anyone!
After the show he is disappeared
In his room!
He is know as Charlie
I want to take my magic else were!
Robert... sir did not like the idea!
I heard him speak for the first time
What ever he said
I still remember the words
What?
An saying must not hurt your enemy
How do you know Charlie
is behind the robbery?
Read in the newspaper
That he leaves his joker evidence!
How may circus clowns are there?
Why the bank?
If I show you suspects will
you identify them
He is always I clown uniform
Until today no one has seen
his face!
I can help you
We both are circus clowns
Difference is, I am on the stage
And he is in the open.
Charlie is a genius.
I can think like him
Why do you want to help me
I want him to be caught
He is not a thief
This is the last hope
to get him
No robbery or thief will exist
Sahir, what every one doing
its a help
At 9am we will meet
joker and clown
That is my name
Let me help you
To become a clown its serious
Everything that I do
Must be with honour and pride!
My work is not a joke
It's a battle
Victory must be like the audience is wining
But I am always the winner!
He comes from one place and return
from another... How is it possible?
If I was Charlie the loot
will be happening today
Why?
What is it today?
1st April
Clown's day
Today is my first show
my mobile will be switched off
Brother he disappear like a wind
How fast he escape
I'm a fan of him!
Come
Were too
Were he can't run
The Great Indian Circus.
You are quite brave to act strong
What is this Jai?
Quite Charlie!
Mysterious clown
Whom no one knows his identity
Your story was very good
My job is to complete the mission
But I have to concentrate on the story
I must trust those who is in front
of me!
You had a very good idea
Enter the bank and know all
the security codes
Only then I knew about the codes
Two police officers and the other thief
Me... remove your clothes
What?
A 9mm of bullet
Leaves a clue behind
Jai you are mistaken
Brother, there is no evidence
It's clean
Officer body scaer
Jai how, is it possible for a bullet
to be clean on my body
I'm a circus clown
tricks is always within me!
I had shot you with my own hand
I olny wanted to be friends with you
Thief and a police are enemies
Brother, we need to go
I feel pity for myself
That the bullet was not shot on your head
Next time I won't let that mistake happen
How did you do this?
Sorry we are not friends
If we were
I should have told you
Is the pain to much
You wont find anything
Take this and go
Let it go
Do not try and act smart
We are gods grace
We must have faith
Papa has two
One is intelligent
And the other is weak
I was the secret for papa
That day papa had one more secret
No one knew about me
You said I am the secret
No, one must come to know about me
Papa I was inside the boxes
I had no fear
Who is going to stand on your back
Who is going to tell you
Your beard is white
Everything I notice
That is why, I hide you
You are my secret
Only carry him
He is grown up... he is not a child
I am papa's angel
Angel don't walk on the ground
Say thank you
Samar, don't let go
Don't ever leave Sahil's hand
Not ever
No one can fight the bank
Bank is like a rock
That day we knew we drop the bank
Its the bank or we survive
Papa always said, "I'm his angel"
I have magic in my hand
This is my blood
The passage is very narrow
Its a secret
Sahir don't even know my secret
My secret is...
Aliyah
There is no good man for her
In this entire world
She is the best
Her name is very cute
[ Skipped item nr. 257 ]
When she is not close to me
I feel happy
Her name is cute
I feel good to think for her
Goodnight, Aliyah
Where are we going?
Going back home.
Remain quite and come with me
on the train to the airport.
Cancel our trip?
Lets begin with our operation
We are not in our home town
But we are international police
We came with respect
And we shall go creating chaos
Brother we stayed behind
Do you remember his circus trick
The way he loots
We need to understand
You tell me, What can I do?
Our answers are hidden behind
Sahir is hiding something
Playing the game is fun for me
Why did you wear my costume?
I did not have time
What is the difference?
Your costume stinks
Don't try and act smart
Why can't I be smart?
Tomorrow is sunday
Why are you so stubborn
Hello, you must send the boxes
Now days you forget a lot
Twins!
One brother Goli and the other Boli
One brother is weaker
I'll take care off him
You concentrate on Sahir
The case is much easier
like a waterfall
Now we know their secret
Have you not seen
They are twins
Being twins is not a crime
How will we get them
Sahir's strenght is his brother
And his weakness too.
Tell me directly,
What should I do?
Sunday, 14th may
Sahir always tell me a hip hop
A day I want to be Samar
Cause I go alone
He is afraid for me
I have no problem
I can take care of myself
I have a lot of fun
I live in a box
Only Sunday I feel the fresh air
My nose is funny... when its cold
Writing my name is fun
Only my name!
For two minutes I'll let out my secret
Thief thief
Hey you stop!
Stealing is very bad!
I am not a thief
Did not eat for 5 days
Happy burger
Who eats burger to be happy
Do you know who is the biggest thief
Everyone is a thief within
What do you like
Fun
Where are you going?
I only come on Sundays
Can we meet the next Sunday?
My circus
I did not make any friend
Papa I always think I can
not be a friend
If, I tell Sahir he won't like the idea
Were do he have the time
I have two secrets
Aliyah and a friend
Victoria this is call brats
Do you know Karim Bhai?
You need to research
Ali you are here to find the thief
Think about work
Not Kamasutra
Mr. Iqbal Khan
How are you?
Until I have this $25 on me
No, bank can't shut us down
Papa this is the last bank
This bank will be finish very soon
Yes I found a job
I will buy you a burger
I did not see Aliyah
"The Wonder Girl"
Aliyah is not my girlfriend
Why?
The way you both react,
Its like girlfriend ad boyfriend.
Why don't you kiss her
Hey, She is not that of type girl.
I love her.
I told you.
But she is not my girlfriend.
She don't even know, I like her
What coincidence
This can't be
When she is near you
Its like you are lover
When she looks at you
Its like she is with Sahir
When Aliyah looks at Sahir
Todays performance
I will act
You take my place
And I will take your place!
What!
Are you crazy?
No, I want to perform
You are crazy boss
Should I do the thinking
You had overreacted today
Something happened today?
A lot happened in a big way.
Something electric... between us
I still can feel it
What can we do about this electricity
Boss there are something I life
we must get hold
Everything has a moment
If you are late
Everything is finish
Can we go on a date
Are you going?
Yes, Today is not Sunday
Going on a date with Aliyah
So do you like her
Does she like you...? Yes
But who does she like
She only mine
Cause I did not give her place
We are this much from our plan
We have to succeed
And the bank needs to close
You are Papa's secret
We have only one plan
Please do not break our plan
It will cause chaos
If I don't go she will feel bad
Its only for one night
What do you think?
If you go she will be crazy for you
How will you speak to her?
You are a secret
Remember you are weak
This is why you are inside
I am outside
Two minutes she will come
to know you are not Sahir!
Just fix your brain
You a burden... bloody idiot
I am not a burden
I am Samar
And either weak
Papa has two hand
Sahir and Samar
I do the hard work
Applause go to you
And you want to become mastermind
Why me?
You are weak
Why
Do not date guys with open
Shoelace
Might if I tell you
I can't tie lace!
Nice trick to win a girl
on her, First date.
Its a fact that I don't know
how to tie a lace.
What happen?
Elecricity.
Brother from Raam and Shaam
There is one going
Follow them
If you speak like that, Everyone will think
we both are boyfriend and girlfriend
Let them think.
From both who is my boyfriend.
There are two of you
You are onee
And the other is my boss
Very nice ego
Who do you like
If you were not around nothing
should happen to me
Do you consider me as your pal
I will tell you a secret
Remember we are friends
Don't be afraid
This was a lie
Friendship was true
Friends don't speak a lie
You lied to me
The bank of Chicargo
They have been punished
The bank is not shut down
And papa is not alive
This should come to a end
I know you and Sahir are brothers
The Great Indian Circus
You are the secret!
Samar you need to help me
Come with me and give a statement
to the police
I will try and plead with the case
You are the one can save Sahir
Save Aliyah's love
Sahir the wizard
I am a clown
We cheat death
I like your trick
Observe and cheat
When the three meet its magic
Whatever you done to Samar
It was not right at all
You played with his emotions
I should have stayed to see you dead
Its my last bank loot
Our last and dangerous loot
This is going to be a storm
We are going to shut down the bank
The first time I caught a thief
during the night
If I was not a police
Surely should write a poem
Brother, let them go
We can't get them
At night its always victory for a thief
And when the sunlight its mine
I have a plan
Samar
Jai, I'm very tired of runing
And there is no place to run
I am arrested... but the court
Can't prove me guilty
This is all the evidence
This is all my crime
Let Samar go
Both of you must be punish
Not Samar.
I was the Mastermind
All the planing was mine
Samar is innocent
Let him go
Its a deal
You promise
From now onwards you don't hide
You are not a burden
You are Samar
You are not weak
We were two
We lived as one
Were are you going?
Let go, my hand
Papa said I can't let go your hand
We are gods grace
Our destiny is decide by god
The last day of Chicargo bank
remains open
Last day for western bank
There are some rules to be broken
Victory only meet for one
Real victory are for the hero's
The Great Indian Circus!
Sync and corrections by YaSh069
-=Team ExDR=-