Paris 2010.
In connection with a dramatic increase
in crime in certain neighbourhoods.
The government is implementing a new policy...
...isolating the high risk areas with walls - a modern day ghetto.
Separation Date: October 2010
Borough 13
- Thats it. I need more.
- Chill bro, it ain't ready yet.
OK, done. Take it.
Alright ladies, did I frighten you?
You didn't even notice
man's pullin up.
- Don't get smart mate.
- Relax, be cool.
This is a random visit.
Mmm... smells wicked.
Gourmet shit?
Tasty.
You want?
So where's your Boss at?
- He ain't about.
- Cool. I'll hang loose then, OK?
Easy now fellas, I ain't packin'.
Weaponless, get me?
Fuck off K2, trust me I will.
What's up with you guys?
It ain't like I come to visit everyday,
And this is the way you treat me?
Go away K2, there isn't time to get friendly.
Come back later.
When the boss gets back,
I'll let him know you came by.
Alright boys. You got a piece of paper
so I can leave him my number?
No? I'll write it on the wall,
It won't go missing.
- The wall is off limits.
- I totally forgot, property of the owner.
He lives like a real gangster.
And you're just jealous
that it ain't your yard.
Fuck off.
I spit on this shit-hole.
So where the fuck can I leave my number?
Gimme your hand.
Don't get scared! If I wanted to kill you,
I would've done it a long time ago.
Armed to the teeth,
an scared of a pen.
Chill; relax.
I don't bite.
What do you want from Leito?
He's got my things.
I just came to collect them.
You best not wash for awhile, alright?
This is pleasant & friendly ain't it?
A handshake goes a long way, bro.
- What do they call you?
- Tarik.
Gimme some skin.
Like an oath.
Shame, if you had a camera,
we could've had a picture.
- Cut it out!
- Smile, watch.
Don't worry, they're with me.
Now you fucking wanna talk, yeah?
Well it's a bit late.
You, stairs. I got the lift.
I like fast rides.
Come here.
You free for a minute?
It was terrible, why did I wait...?
- Yo, the lift's moving. Radio them.
- You do it.
Tarik, who's that coming in the lift?
Tarik! Shit it's fucked again.
- What do we do?
- Don't stress, man! This film is wicked.
Tarik, what the fuck is going on?
Tarik!
Arghh not now.
Fix the aerial.
I ain't your bitch!
Fix it yourself, you lazy dumb fuck!
Tarik, can you hear me?
Why are you so stressed?
He's probably bringing us our dinner.
Dinner, an hour early?
Something ain't right.
Well I'm not a pessimist like you.
We're looking for Leito,
What number is he at?
- 14.
- Cheers.
Shit, the doors aren't numbered!
Bust all the doors down.
- Where is Leito?
- Well he ain't here.
- I know that, but fuckin where?
- Along the corridor, last door on the left.
You're coming with me, so I don't get lost.
Turn right!
Right.
Third door.
Do you wish me dead?
I want him alive.
Is that clear to you all?
Move.
On three, yeah?
1, 2, 3.
Grab him!
Shoot!
He's at the bottom.
He's on the roof.
Motherfucker.
There he his!
Fuck!
Let's think...
At 8:00 he stole 20kg of heroin from you.
You found out who did it at 9.00...
How many of you went to pay him a visit?
- 12 guys.
- 12?
And you all came back empty handed?
- That's cool?
- We could've killed him about 100 times.
- But you want him alive.
- Are you saying its now somehow my fault?
Nah, I'm not trying to say that.
It's just that he's so...
...slippery. Soap bar.
- Slippery, like a soap bar?
Yeah.
€50 for a gram, times 20 kilos.
That's a million euro.
That's one expensive soap bar.
Well then.
I'm waiting for your proposal?
Has anyone got a proposal?
No, no need!
I've got a proposal.
K2, fantastic!
I'm all ears.
Well Leito stole our drugs so...
he's gotta pay, right?
That is not a proposition,
merely stating the obvious.
- Hold on, Wait!
- I'm waiting!
His sister, Lola, she works
in a nearby supermarket.
We grab her and he comes to us.
You see that? That's a good proposal.
Bring her here.
Back in a minute.
Come on, the manager wants you.
Let's go, are you deaf?
They are calling you.
- The boss isn't in on a Wednesday.
- What has the boss got to do with this?
My boss is waiting for you, Taha.
Taha is not my boss.
Let go, bastard.
You big animal.
Move bitch.
- Oh, a present?
- I can take care of her, we can make it work.
- Hands off!
- Can I search her?
- I already did, she's clean.
- Let me take a peek at her panties.
I'll stuff them down your throat!
If you want too,
I'm getting excited.
Here's a taste.
Fuck off man,
Taha is waiting for her.
Stop struggling,
you'll hurt yourself.
It's me.
This is a very easy gadget to use.
Let me show you.
- I will demonstrate in a second...
- K2 at the door.
...it's use.
It's very flexible...
He's come back with more excuses?
You can come in.
Inform Leito
that I got his sister.
I'd like to see his face
when he finds out.
Well here it is.
Trust me, I'll put an end to your plans!
If anything happens to me,
your situation is not gonna get better.
What do you want?
Do you know what makes us different?
You don't know what I'm thinking.
And me, I know your every move.
That's why I'm always one step ahead.
Relax, K2, it's cool.
Just chatting, calm down.
We got a lot to chat about.
You can stop stroking my hair.
Just let me know what you want!
- Two things.
- I'm listening.
Your people will not come
within a half kilometre of my house.
Deal. And the second?
Your life for the life of my sister.
I let you go and we both walk.
Your men stay here.
- You're a businessman, right?
- Talk!
- All right, I've got nothing against.
- You give your word?
- That's right?
- For the moment.
K2, let her go.
Do it, don't think about it!
Are you gonna lie down,
or do you need help?
OK, I kept my word. She's free.
- Put the knife down.
- Don't worry.
Do you think you're gonna
get out of here with me?
What makes you think
that everybody here likes you?
Listen up, boys. We've finished talking.
They are leaving and nobody else leaves.
Don't try and shoot.
I'll be right back.
Wait!
Open your mouth.
Now chew.
I like your sister's style.
Shut the fuck up, and move.
Gimme it, take it.
Easy, don't shoot.
We're gonna deliver our client.
Call the Chief!
Let us pass, before it's too late.
Shit.
Can't you two talk things over?
We are slowly packing up.
This is Taha. Taha Bemamud.
He's got a thousand warrants out for him.
I know him well,
but we are still leaving.
Orders from the Ministry.
Plus I need solid evidence.
5 kilos of heroin from his office
and 2 witnesses should be enough!
Chief, there are too many of them.
They are three times stronger then our forces.
All right, we will take this to court.
You can hand in your weapons now.
Somebody keep guard on him.
Poor Leito, so naive.
You think this will change anything?
This will be a lesson for the rest of them.
I don't need useless court cases.
Put him in a cell and you can go.
Don't let him go.
You have no idea what will happen now.
I don't care what's gonna happen here,
we are already leaving.
It's your job to end this nightmare
in our neighbourhood!
You still don't get it!
This area is surrounded by walls and barbed wire.
They've covered it from the top downwards and it will be destroyed.
Then this whole nightmare will end.
Be glad you're in this cell.
Outside, a band of zombies is waiting for your blood.
Taha, your still here?
My band of zombies could
teach you a thing or two, chief.
Don't start, Taha.
You're free, what else do you want?
- The girl.
- No!
- Take her.
Try an touch her.
- Lola! Lola!
- Don't worry, I'll take care of her.
Gentlemen, it's always a pleasure doing business.
Goodbye.
No! Noo!
Take her to my office. Inject her with
a couple of doses to calm her down.
Don't stand around, get to work lads.
I didn't have a choice.
I've spent 15 years in this neighbourhood.
My pension's coming up
and I want to end this.
I'd like it differently.
Sorry.
You gave away my sister
This is the end for you.
6 months later.
Tell me Pedro,
what has that door done to you?
- I'm not Pedro.
- Who gives a fuck what your name is?
That's my car dumb-ass.
What if I hit your stupid head with the same force?
- It's only a car.
- Not only a car.
It's my fucking car!
It cost me money,
So be careful with my car,
or I'll crack your head open.
- Do you understand?
- Carlos, don't worry, let's just go.
Stupid son of a bitch.
These latinos have no respect for anything.
Is it so difficult to shut a car door gently?
He understood. He'll be more gentle.
He's the driver, right Pedro?
- I'm not Pedro.
- That's why all the doors squeak.
I spent about 1,5 on that shit
and they still squeak.
I'll take care of it, Carlos.
You have my word.
We have a bad team selection,
Time to change. We need to have a word with Franco.
- Ok.
- Because they keep sending us these fucking Portugese.
Thick as shit,
Useless fuckers.
I'll speak to Franco.
We'll sort everything out.
For fucks sake!
I need 2 well educated guys.
We need to grab them straight from Uni.
These fuckers don't even know what a school is.
Benito, in France there are
6 million people unemployed.
Just find me 2 normal guys.
No problem, I'll get on to it.
Do I have to get the door myself?
This is what I'm saying.
Number 5 is the winner!
Place your bets.
- You haven't forgotten?
- I remember.
At the end of the week, as promised.
He really hit the bottom,
no shame or conscience.
He owes us big money,
yet he has the balls to show his face here.
A lack of a proper upbringing.
Tactless.
Follow me.
How's things, Ragbi.
- Everything alright, Sam?
- Well, not at the moment.
What's the matter?
- Problems with the police again?
- These two have been standing there for two hours.
Choosing a tin of tuna.
- They're pimps.
- Pimps? So what are they doing in the fish section?
Nothing. There waiting until 2:00.
That's when the whores have a coffee break.
You arrive at 1.10 and presto...
...What's been happening on the streets.
- Who the fuck is that?
- Pimps, but not after tinned tuna.
- What else?
- There aren't that many, but its like someone's informed them.
At the same time, when we move the cash.
- What you saying?
- 500,000 straight up. Crazy sum.
If you snitch to the cops,
you can easily earn yourself 10%.
- How do you know?
- It's my job.
- So why didn't you take it?
- How was I to know if they were really cops?
- You little shit!
- Do you want to live?
Of course.
Have I finished my studies?
- Yes, with honours.
- You understand, you see the difference?
So you think we have a snitch?
Without a doubt.
- I could sense that there was something about Pedro.
- It wasn't Pedro.
I don't a give a shit.
We are not about to start crying.
We need to take the cash and ourselves outta here.
Don't move.
Leave the money and put your hands in the air!
- Benito, what's with you?
- I'm not Benito but Damien.
Criminal police.
Carlos Montoya, you're under arrest.
- Benito, you're bald?
- You have the right to remain silent,
anything you say
might be used against you in a court of law.
Any sudden movement will be interpreted as aggression.
And I will have to use my gun in self-defence.
- What are you saying?
- If you as much as move your ear...
...I will paint this room red.
- Understood, but how do you plan to leave this room?
We stay.
Alone; tell your people to leave.
- Why are you letting them go?
- I only catch the big ones.
- Hamilion in place, begin extraction.
- Copy that Hamilion, commencing.
- What do we do?
- Why are you asking me?
- You're a model student.
- They didn't teach me this.
What in the devil is that?
- You didn't get hit did you?
- No, I'm ok.
Ok, that's good.
- Package ready.
- Copy that, thanks.
All exits covered.
What now, Einstein?
Quickly, there is gonna be a lot of heat soon.
Lower the line.
I'm all out of bullets.
They didn't take the money.
We can split it, close the door.
Ok guys, now it's your turn.
Where were you earlier?
Come on men, forward!
There you go, help yourself.
- Don't resist!
- I'll go on my own.
Excellent work.
Operation complete, home time.
- Captain?
- I've never met such a crook.
That's good.
Thanks for the compliment.
- I trusted you like my brother.
- A brother?
I had to wash your car for 6 months
before you gave me a job.
And before I forget...
Your doors.
That's the squeaking sorted out.
Like I promised.
- Captain Damien, Chief.
- Show him in.
Good morning, Damien.
I've called you in to congratulate you,
but the situation has slightly changed.
Sit.
- I prefer to stand if that's all right?
- As you please.
Let me introduce Mr. Krüger,
the Defence Secretary.
And Mr Corsini, his 2nd in command.
They are looking for someone to
take on a special mission.
Mr. Krüger, please
explain the situation to the Captain.
Late last night we were transporting
equipment in an armoured truck,
which ran into some problems along the way.
What the hell, no need for that!
Careful, you're gonna scratch the glass.
Stubborn little shits!
Oh, this is just great!
Luckily the truck has a homing device,
so we know its location.
We need your help to retrieve it.
Where is it?
And what's the equipment?
Prototype nuclear device.
What exactly?
Nuclear-organic bomb, experimental model.
A so-called "clean bomb"
built around neutron technology.
Blast radius of 8km.
The fall-out area can be
replanted almost immediately.
Contamination of the environment is nil.
Are you scared that they will
use the bomb on you?
The Eliseye Fields
is not the ideal place for the bomb.
Not ideal, I agree.
There is one more thing...
If tampered with, the bomb will self-destruct in 24 hours.
Unfortunately, the self-destruct system
was activated over an hour ago.
- In 23 hours... it will explode.
- K2?
- What?
You have to sell it to someone.
I can't help. There is not enough time.
Captain, we are not asking,
just explaining.
You know how I work.
I need time to familiarise myself with the details.
2 million people live there.
It's true half are criminals,
but the other half need our help.
Change your methods,
or have those people on your conscience.
How do you begin a mission,
that is doomed to failure?
How do I diffuse a bomb
in an area I've never been to?
- There's no way.
- Don't worry, you will have a guide.
Great, I'm gonna have a helper?
This guide was born in the area.
He knows it like the back of his hand.
- Will he help?
- You've asked him, he's been briefed?
He's clueless.
You have to recruit him.
- Leito, you're being moved.
- Where to?
You'll see.
112- in the van.
Let me go! Let go!
Fucking let go!
263- in the van.
You cock sucking, wet tampon!
- How're you?
- Super.
That fucker thought
he could treat me like that.
I'm off.
The doors don't open that easy.
My friend, you obviously don't know me.
They call me Phantom.
Phantom ain't doing an 8 year stretch.
- What you in for?
- I killed 5 guys.
But the main guy got away from me.
What did he do to you?
He killed my dad and brothers.
I won't give up until he's dead.
I'm gonna hit borough 13
and wipe that motherfucker out.
- That's where he lives?
- Yeah, and that's where he'll die.
- What's his name?
- Taha. You heard of him?
I wanted to be friends a long time ago
but I regret it now.
He lives in a bunker, a whole army around him.
Motherfucker's got some weird bitch with him all the time.
- Who's that?
- Some drugged up girl that he keeps on a leash.
Like a dog.
The girl is always fucked up on some shit.
I think she's called Lola.
The Phantom will be back in 2 minutes.
Come up front.
- Where you wanna be dropped?
- Borough 13 will be fine.
Wicked.
Damien.
Leito.
Thanks. They are out.
Plan is on course.
- Are they still together?
- Without a doubt. In the truck, we are tailing.
Excellent.
Congratulations, Chief.
Still too early. Escaping from jail is easier
than getting into borough 13.
And we don't know what kind of
guide this Leito will turn out to be.
Without him, Damien won't achieve much.
Your Captain is our last hope.
So are you gonna help me out?
What's the best route to take?
Can we get in undetected?
Yep, throw a right here.
- What are you doing?
- Why? Don't you trust me?
- Get these fucking cuffs off!
- You really want to get into borough 13?
- Yeah. I'm the Phantom now,
so do exactly what I say.
Turn right.
- And now?
- Right.
Turn right.
I said, fucking right!
I'm not fucking deaf, the steering is fucked!
So brake.
The brakes are fucked as well.
Ok, into that car, gently.
- That was supposed to be gentle?
- Look man it was the best I could do.
If you don't like the skills,
run and jump, punk.
- Let me loose.
- You can handle it, boy you got it made.
What you saying?
You're a cop.
You can't fool me.
- So you're gonna leave me here?
- You needed borough 13 and you're in, so bye-bye?
Consult your manual, chapter heading
"Fucked Situation".
Leito, are you mad.
I ain't no cop.
Get me out of here, fuck
I helped you escape, remember?
I know why you helped me.
So I can help you with something right?
Not interested in your stupid agenda.
Fuck off.
Hey, what about your sister?
I don't need your help
to free her.
Shit!
Motherfucking bomba ras, check me car, rudeboy!
Sorry, but I just got out of jail
and the brakes packed up.
I need a hideout.
Hideout?
Boy is you proper fucked up.
Where d'you think this is, Monaco?
This here is Baghdad.
- Out of the way.
- Relax. Easy.
I'm sorry about your car.
Take the truck, deal stands?
Did you dispose of the bomb?
- No, well until. Leito...
- What? Leito?
He escaped from prison.
So he'll be here soon.
Wake up!
Some news about your brother.
He's coming for a visit.
- Be ready.
- Ok.
How did you find out
I was a cop?
Your fighting style is too technical.
Training I guess?
But to fit in,
you're lacking something.
- What?
- Real anger.
I guess my training didn't cover that.
Freedom, Fairness, Family,
that's what they taught me.
- Water, gas, electric...
- You can laugh all you want.
- You're lawless.
- I want fairness and justice for everyone.
Everyone, and I'm here to make sure
everyone gets justice.
I'm not a butler,
I don't take orders.
I bite, when I see things
being done against the law.
I was born in this manor.
It's always hard to breathe here.
10 years ago they built a wall
around this place. What did I do?
I didn't break any laws, not one.
I quit school,
not for a job selling crack,
but because they closed the school down.
I was unlucky to be born here.
So you think burning cars
is gonna make things better?
You got a better idea?
Well at the moment, no.
Do you know why I'm here?
Why I let you go?
- A good deed?
- To save this neighbourhood.
There's an active neutron bomb here.
If I don't disable it,
there wont be anything left of this place.
Borough 13 no longer, get me?
Everybody dies.
If I think like you,
what good are these 2 million people?
No use to me.
But there will always be people like you,
who thought the law was on their side, get me?
So you gonna help me with this bomb,
or are you too busy with your own shit?
Is this bomb for real?
- I can't say how it got here.
- But I'm sure Taha has got it.
Yep. Your sister and my bomb,
We gotta link up.
If you're bullshitting,
I will fuck you up, believe me.
That's cool.
- You got a plan?
- I've got to get to Taha un-noticed.
As soon as I take care of the bomb,
I'll free your sister.
And I'm supposed to sit around and wait?
No, you're the distraction.
Taha will be busy with you
and I'll sort everything out.
You like that shit don't you?
- You got a phone?
- Yeah.
Give it to me.
Damn, Phantom, you're going on like James Bond.
Ring.
- Yes.
- It's Leito.
- Where did you get my number from?
- You can buy anything on the inside.
- I heard you're on the outside.
- I'm across from you, the factory.
Who you calling?
So why ring me?
I've got a cop with me.
We've got a proposal for you.
K2 will come and get you.
Are you fucking nuts?
According to the plan,
I was supposed to go in un-noticed.
Stealth like, side entrance,
not the main fucking door.
Forget your police manual.
This is borough 13.
Your laws don't apply, get me?
- And this is the only way.
- Your plan?
He who lives, wins.
Nobody dies.
We have one card to play.
- Which is?
- Curiosity.
Who's this cop?
You got the same answers
to every question, huh?
Like fucking cows.
I need info, on this cop.
Before he dies.
You have 5 minutes.
- I don't like it, too risky.
- Without me you'll die.
I always work alone and I'm still alive.
Later.
I know all the ins and outs here.
I dug one tunnel myself.
So you made good use of your hands.
I know where the bomb is.
Without me you'll never find it.
5 minutes ago you didn't even know about the bomb.
- You're fucking with me?
- Taha built a huge bunker a while ago.
And I know where it is.
- How do you know the bomb will be there?
- He don't keep shit like that in his kitchen.
Here's the deal.
I free you and you do what I say.
How about another way. You shut the fuck up
and pray my sister is alive, then I'll find the bomb.
Take these off,
or we both end up in jail.
All right.
- This is the cop?
- Damn you're observant. I'm impressed.
Shut up. If Taha lets you off
I'll deal with you myself!
Lets move, and don't try any weird shit.
The boys are a bit nervous.
- Did you come here to sleep?
- Sorry, just tired.
- Where is he?
- His place.
- Has he eaten?
- He eats all the time.
You've got a job.
Warm up.
With this arsenal,
you could take over Paris.
- That's the bomb transporter.
- So it's still here.
Wait here. I'll be quick.
No thanks.
So you're friendly with the cops now?
He ain't my friend, but only he knows how
to de-activate the bomb.
- Really?
- It will destroy everything within 8km.
So you came to rescue us?
I can stop the clock
and save 2 million people.
The Government sends a cop to save us from a bomb.
That's so noble.
Hysterical.
To be honest,
we weren't planning to keep it here.
- Do you wanna take it?
- Yes.
How much for?
If I don't enter the correct code within the hour,
this whole place blows.
I know. Although by that time
I'll have already sold it.
If you don't want to wait too long for the explosion,
I suggest you start negotiations.
- Innocent people will die.
- You should of thought of that earlier.
For example,
when you were making it.
Million euro.
Million on my right. Not much.
Anybody else eager, K2?
2 million!
Brave K2 is saying 2 million.
Any more?
- 4! - 4 million just in
time. - 4 million on my right.
- How long are you gonna barter?
- Until our lives are worthless.
Come on, tell me.
10! 10 million on my left
It's getting interesting!
So bro, 10 million.
Any more offers?
Oh well, I think the reserve has been met.
10 million going once!
10 million twice!
20.
That's a big jump up.
- K2?
- Let him have it, I pass.
20 million?
Sold!
Good buy.
For saving 2 million people,
it works out 10 euro a head...
...cheaper than a "Happy Meal".
- Payment method?
- Transfer.
Before you get confirmation of payment
the bomb will explode.
Jamel, the account number in the Bahamas.
- I need to see the bomb.
- Funny, I thought you might.
Only quick.
It didn't come with its own rocket.
Luckily I had a few stored already.
A revamped ex-soviet missile.
Ready to blast off.
Destination? Well you can figure it out.
So then, cop, you've seen your bomb.
You can start the money transfer.
Leito, I've learnt from my mistakes.
Now I'm one step ahead.
Put me in touch with Krüger; urgent.
8, 47, 35,
Sulu, Sulu, Fox, Delta, Charlie.
- Amount?
- 20 million euro.
Are you certain of the bomb's location?
It's in front of me.
48 minutes left on the clock.
Not enough in the budget.
- Please find other means.
- I'm sorry.
Fine, I'll wait.
The transfer will be ready soon.
Thanks, Sarge.
That's it, 20 million transferred
to your account. My turn with the code.
The transaction isn't done yet.
Jamel, phone the Bahamas and check.
One minute.
The bank opens in 30 minutes.
Goddamn, let's hope it does.
In this event you will have to wait.
Get comfortable. On your knees.
Faces to the wall, hands on heads.
Yoyo, keep them there until further orders.
- So now what?
- You wanted to come here.
If not for you, we wouldn't be here.
And if your Generals had transferred the money,
we would be free.
No, we would be dead.
You think, Taha would let us live?
Fuck no, but they still didn't pay.
How valuable are you to them?
Shit, they couldn't care less.
Damien, something doesn't quite add up here.
- Why is that?
- It doesn't make sense.
They lost the bomb, like it was a car key.
They want it back, but not at the price.
When it comes to money,
they stop thinking.
- And you're defending them?
- Not them, the law.
Plus human life, just like you.
How long?
37 minutes.
- We have to do something!
- You think?
- I've an idea.
- What?
- Remember the tunnel?
- The one I dug?
The same one.
The entrance is in the toilet.
Left from the lift.
You think he'll let us go to the John together?
No, we make an excuse
to talk with Taha.
And we walk past the toilet.
Sweet. So when we get to the lift, what?
- Improvise.
- That's half a plan!
- You got a better one?
- No.
Then let's go.
- Who let you get up?
- We need to see Taha, it's urgent.
All right. I see, sit your ass down,
before I put you down, fool!
You've got no sense have you?
What's your name?
What's it to you?
I'll need to tell Taha when he asks me,
who lost him 20 million.
Your name.
If you're pulling my dick,
I'll have you!
Ok.
You three, with me.
The rest, cover.
- When to improvise?
- It will come naturally.
- Backflip, on the run.
- How?
Move.
- This is our way out.
- We're gonna go through the toilet?
- I'm a bad-ass cop.
- Run.
What's up, what's happened?
Why didn't you reply?
- We were in a tunnel.
- What tunnel? You playing some kind of game?
It's cos of those two idiots.
They escaped through a tunnel.
We ran after them but got kinda lost.
Hold on, repeat that slowly.
They escaped...
Jamel, the transaction?
- I've got bad news.
- He was bluffing?
- Yes.
- I thought so.
You can't trust a cop.
Stupid of me to think I could.
He'll pay.
I'm gonna launch that bomb.
Taha, that's not all.
You better sit down.
They used our account number
to take money out of the account...
...and other accounts.
Which other accounts?
Bahamas, Riyadh, Karachi,
even London. All zero balances.
How'd they manage that?
I don't know. If I find out,
I can rule the world.
To be honest, I'm a bad hacker,
so I resign.
Excuse me.
Taha, if you're broke,
how you gonna pay us for this week?
There's money in the safe, downstairs.
They haven't touched that.
K2, gimme your gun.
My gun, why?
You're all a bunch of useless thugs.
So what now, K2?
We need to catch those two.
I'm calling a safari.
Split up.
Out of the way!
Move!
Police!
When's the bomb gonna blow?
- In 10 minutes.
- Can you disable it?
Yes. Nobody but me.
Ok, you deal with the bomb
and your friend stays with us.
- I need his help.
- He stays.
Ok, me and Leito stay here,
and you go diffuse the bomb.
9 minutes left.
Ok, both of you go.
You have to come down eventually.
If all goes well,
you'll be glad to see me.
- Who's this?
- Present from Taha.
Nice present.
Hey, big guy, let me show you a new trick!
Go!
- Were did you learn that?
- I read it in an anglers magazine.
It's ok, Lola.
It's over.
No, it ain't over yet.
No signal.
Finally.
Don't worry.
He'll free us.
- Hello.
- Captain Tomaso?
I'm at the bomb. I need the code.
- Where are you?
- At the bloody bomb! 3 minutes left.
Give me the code,
there's no time to chit chat!
Your exact location?
On top of a tall building, central borough 13.
Enough?
- Good work, we are proud of you.
- The code?
- 9293...
...709B13.
709B13, I'll call back
if I'm still alive.
B13, borough 13.
Strange that the bomb has that code.
And 9293 is our map co-ordinates.
Coincidence.
Damien, wait. This bomb
is not meant for here.
- Then why do the co-ordinates match?
- We need to disarm it anyway.
- What if it's all back to front?
- Back to front?
Instead of disarming it,
you're gonna arm it!
Are you nuts? Then why send me?
It would have exploded itself.
They had to find out if
it was in the right place.
Isn't that what the Chief asked?
If it's in the central area?
Yeah, but that's a standard question.
- It's a trap, I'm certain.
- Fuck off, don't interfere!
- I saved your life once already.
- I'm under orders to do this.
I'm sorry.
Stop, Leito, in a minute
we all blow up!
Open your fucking eyes, Damien! Are you blind
to the fact that they don't care about this area!
For 20 years they couldn't solve the problem.
They put up a huge wall,
and now they want to clean the place up.
The local authority is gone.
No post office, no schools.
Even the police have left.
- The bomb was stolen, they didn't build it here.
- They blew open the truck?
- Yeah?
- Yes!
- They sold you a lie.
- Yeah?
Then explain to me why
the truck is in one piece?
Why there are no signs of a blast?
The lack of doors?
- Maybe it was a different truck.
- You know it's the same one!
As soon as they were certain
the bomb was in borough 13
they called you,
so you could activate it. You get me?
And you nearly went though with it!
You got rid of Taha for them and now everybody else...
You can't kill 2 million people
just because of a few social problems!
How many will they kill because of
the colour of their hair or eyes?
I'm sorry, Leito.
- Sorry.
- You can't, Lola.
I prefer to die believing
my brother instead of you.
- That it?
- Yeah, this time around that's it.
No, that's not it.
I said you'd be glad to
see me again.
- You've got 5 minutes to leave.
- I'm taking this.
It's yours.
Right.
Nothing.
- The bomb was supposed to go off an hour ago.
- What do we do if it doesn't happen?
Dunno. It was supposed to blow...
then nothing happened.
- What's that noise?
- Sounds like fighting.
Check it out!
The mission was almost a success. Almost.
At the last minute
I couldn't remember the code.
It happens.
It's my fault,
I forget the numbers.
- Maybe you remember?
- Yeah.
This is a great guy.
You've taught me so much.
Without him I'd have died.
So what are the numbers?
- 9293.
- Like the area?
- Yes.
- Little coincidence.
Next, 709.
Easy to remember, today's date.
709, 7th September.
Day of delivery. Wicked, huh?
Little bomb in the right place...
and all your problems can go away.
Correct me if I'm wrong.
Back to the code.
I think it's coming to me.
The last digits are..., B13.
Borough 13.
How could I forget.
The rest you can do.
Are you crazy?
Do you want to blow up the middle of Paris?
I don't get it.
Isn't this the code to disarm the bomb?
I hope it's not a code
to arm it?
- Enough of these charades! You know full well!
- No I don't. Explain it to me.
Borough 13 is uncontrollable.
The upkeep is too expensive.
People don't want to pay for
the scum of society.
- So you clean up with a bomb?
- Yeah! Undemocratic, but it solves a lot of problems.
Bar one. Yours.
- No, no don't do it.
- But you wanna clean up?
- We'll all die.
- You should of thought of that when you built it.
No!
You believed me? That I'd blow
everything up, including ourselves?
No. There are other ways to
solve problems of this nature.
More democratic.
Can you look out of the window and wave.
How's the sound?
- What are you doing, Tomaso?
- My job, sir.
Do you know sir, what my mission is?
Law and order in this country
is equal for everybody.
And I just make sure
that nobody forgets it.
That's my job.
If you still can't understand this,
then watch the TV
and you'll find out soon enough.
...or order it over the net.
You can buy the ticket on the train.
But the counters at the station don't have any.
This situation will last for awhile.
The railway is planning a timetable,
that's needed for the
computerised system.
Borough 13 is uncontrollable.
The upkeep is too expensive.
People don't want to pay for
the scum of society.
- So clean up with a bomb?
- People don't want to pay for the scum of society.
Borough 13 is uncontrollable.
The upkeep is too expensive.
People don't want to pay for
the scum of society.
- So you clean up with a bomb?
- Yeah. Undemocratic, but it solves a lot of problems.
Bar one. Yours.
Are you sure you don't want to stay?
With your bonus you can
get a really nice pad.
I've got a pad.
It's my neighbourhood.
I was born here.
Maybe it ain't too peaceful but...
Relax, Leito.
From Monday they're gonna start tearing down the walls.
By the end of the month,
the police and schools will be back.
You glad?
It's thanks to you.
He's the best in the world.
I always knew that.
Cheer up! Why so gloomy?
I just hope the Government
will carry out their promises.
They've no other choice.
Promises made
must always be fulfilled.
There will always be someone like me
to make it happen.
- Take it easy.
- You say that like I live in a dangerous area.
Yours is more dangerous
then mine, Damien.
It's a matter of acclimatising.
Come visit.
I'll try.
He'll definitely come now.
Welcome.
Thanks.
You can pass.