Come here. I'll take him.
I'll take him. Come on.
Goodness, Chad. Don't be sensitive.
Hey, that wasn't worth all that fuss,
was it, Alex, hmm?
Come on now.
- Is he OK?
- He'll be fine.
Well, Paul. Six years, three banks
and $200 million later.
- Congratulations, Nigel.
- You, too.
Uh, Mr Wagner, it's time to rock and roll.
- Time to rock and roll.
- Good luck, darling.
Many centuries ago,
a Chinese poet foresaw a Hong Kong
that glittered like the stars in the heavens.
Today, by providing an underwater tunnel
to connect Hong Kong Island
with the mainland and the New Territories,
we hope that
we have brought that prophecy
one step closer to reality.
And so, ladies and gentlemen, Griffith
Wagner Enterprises proudly present
to the Crown colony of Hong Kong
the Victoria Harbour Tunnel.
Paul. Sure you don't want me
to follow you home?
I can get home without you, Frank.
- I'll believe that when I see it.
- We'll be fýne.
You take the night off. Hey, thanks.
Without you I could never have done it.
Now, get lost, you bum.
If you say so. Katherine, take a look
under the front seat, would you?
A little token of my appreciation.
I don't know how Paul's initials
got on there, but they're there.
That's nice, Frank. Really nice.
It's cheap and there's no cigars, but...
But it's... really great.
Thanks for everything, pal.
Hey, Frank.
It's lovely. Goodnight.
- Frank? I said take the night off.
- I heard you loud and clear.
Then that's not your car following us?
No, it's...
What's the matter?
Paul, whatever you do, don't get out
of the car. I'll be right there.
Get down! Get the boys down!
Get them down!
My babies! Please, no!
Paul!
Katherine!
Paul! Oh, no!
No! Paul! Oh, my God!
Oh, God!
Oh, my babies!
Oh, babies!
My babies. What'll happen to them?
You'll never know.
Get those kids and get out of there!
Griffith.
# Dormez vous? Dormez vous?
# Sonnez les matines
Sonnez les matines...
- # Din din don #
- Bonjour. Qui est-ce?
Oh!
25 YEARS LATER
- How do you feel now?
- Oh, it still hurts.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
OK.
- Maybe you should relax now, OK?
- OK.
Slowly close your legs.
Beautiful. Doing well.
You know, stretching is so important.
For example,
because of my big legs and karate,
I can do the splits, no problem.
Back and forth. Back and forth.
Feels good.
They're right in here.
I'll be with you in a minute.
- Chad.
- Yeah?
I'm sorry. Don't move.
Take over the karate class.
Look, Frankie.
I'm busy with those girls now.
No, this is business.
- Take over the karate class.
- Like this?
Three!
Class!
We got a little problem. Class!
- Jackie, what's wrong?
- No problem.
It's the new guy.
- How you doin'? All right?
- Yeah.
It's gotta be him.
What are you, the ballet teacher or what?
Yeah, I'm dancing, yeah. Also some karate.
- Karate, huh?
- Can You Show me one of your special kicks.
- You wanna see one of my kicks?
- Yeah. C'mon.
Shit.
Chad. Come up to my office, ASAP.
Hong Kong? Uncle Frankie. Get real, man.
We can't just cut out for two weeks.
We got a business to run.
You have another business to run
in Hong Kong.
Make this thing look
like a fucking dog pound.
Another business in Hong Kong.
Uncle Frankie...
Ah! I'm not your uncle.
- You're not my uncle?
- Uh-uh.
Suddenly, after 25 years,
you're telling me you're not my uncle.
Uh-uh. And you weren't born in France.
I just raised you there.
Any more surprises? Like maybe
I own a grocery store in Zimbabwe?
Chad.
Now, listen to me. I raised you
ever since you were six months old.
I brought you up like you were my own kid.
Have I ever given you any reason
not to trust me?
- No.
- Then trust me.
We're going to Hong Kong.
Chad. C'mon, put on your seat belt.
Wow! Look at this, Frankie.
Let's go shopping.
Frankie, check it out.
Driver. How long?
- Hotel. How long?
- We're not going to the hotel.
We're gonna go to this joint first.
Nice little joint. It's highly
recommended in the tour books.
Out. Out.
Thank you. Keep it close.
Hey, Frankie. What is this?
It's a mah-jong parlour. It's a cross
between dominoes and five-card stud.
Try a hand. I'm going to talk to this guy.
Frank. Frank. Frank. Frank.
This is you.
You wanna stay here? Beautiful.
I'll be waiting at the hotel.
I'll take a shower and shave and a sauna.
- It's going to be great,No, No, Trust me.
- we'll go together. Come here.
I want you to see something in here.
C'mon.
- Chad, trust me. C'mon.
- This place sucks.
Hey, boss. Just the way you like it.
Very hot.
For your friend, too?
What's wrong?
- What's wrong with him?
- I dunno.
- What'd he give you?
- Cash, money. I love Hong Kong.
Very nice.
Thank you.
Hey...
Me?
Go on. Go see what she wants.
I think she wants to talk to you.
Go on. I'll be right here.
Did you pick these out yourself?
I am impressed. Haircut, too.
You know,
this really is a lovely colour on you.
- What else do you have in here?
- Huh?
Silk underwear.
- Keep going.
- More surprises?
Oh, yeah. Big surprise. Huge surprise.
- Look at him. The way he walks.
- He looks like you.
- The way he touched you?
- I'm sorry. He looks exactly like you.
Look like me?
You, of all people, should know
I'd never in my life wear black silk underwear.
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Look at him. A faggot.I am Looking.
Frank. Frankie. What's going on here?
Chad. He's your brother.
Look at him. For Christ's sake. Look at him.
Just take a look at him.
He's your twin brother.
I don't believe this. My brother.
See that door? You've got both of you
10 seconds to get the fuck out.
Or the fish tank may be better.
Hear at least what they've got to say.
- Five seconds!
- Damn it, Alex.
You stay here.
Don't even think about it, pal.
Don't even think about it.
Sit down.
OK, let's talk.
You ever hear of a guy
named Nigel Griffith?
Like asking a New Yorker
if he's ever heard of donald Trump.
- What about Raymond Zhang?
- Yeah.
- What about him?
- What's this got to do with Alex?
It's simple.
The Victoria Harbour Tunnel
was built by a man I used to work for
after my tour of Nam.
Halfway through construction
he ran into money problems.
They pulled in Griffith
as an equity partner.
Griffith got his cash from a secret loan
courtesy of the Zhang family.
When the tunnel was completed, and
my employer's construction expertise
was no longer needed, they had him
and his wife exxed out by a Triad hit team.
Only, the Triads fucked up
because they had two sons, babies,
who they were gonna wipe out, too.
So they wouldn't come back
and claim what was rightfully theirs.
You're full of shit.
Paul and Katherine Wagner.
And their two sons, Chad and Alex.
- Those two men, can we find them?
- All right,Let's go after Raymond Zhang.
You've got an army waiting outside, or what?
Did you hear what he just told us?
These were our parents. Look at them.
I hear bullshit every day, pal.
You want some advice?
Take your fancy clothes and your
silk underwear and go back to Disneyland.
That's it. I guess you and I, Frankie.
Like always.
OK.
You want some real action, tough guys?
Let's do it.
This is beautiful.
- What's the piece for?
- Just in case.
In case of what?
There.
Let's say hello.
Whoa!
I don't believe this.
A smooth operator.
- Ah.
- OK.
- They don't get those cars in China.
- The UN should give you a prize.
- Cash.
- Yeah.
Right.
This is the Hong Kong Marine Police!
Prepare to have your vessel
boarded and searched!
You set us up. No Mercedes, no cash.
Drop it. Get your asses off the boat.
Chad! Get down!
This is the Hong Kong Marine Police.
- Nice going.
- Nice going?
Nice going, my ass! I almost got killed.
And the cops are still chasing us.
Trust me.
Hey, can this piece of shit
move any faster?
Frankie, help me.
C'mon, baby. C'mon.
Welcome to Hong Kong.
Chad, take a bite. Be a man.
What's it supposed to do?
Make my dick bigger?
All right, Alex. I think that Chad and I
established our credentials yesterday.
Now, what do we do about your tunnel?
- My tunnel?
- Is there proof? Any legal documentation?
There doesn't have to be, girlie.
I was there.
- I got the scars.
- Those won't carry weight in court.
Let me tell you, the only law that Zhang
knows is the law of a 12-gauge shotgun,
one of which he used to splatter
Mr Wagner all over the Victoria Peak Road!
I don't need to listen to this any longer.
Jeez. What's her problem?
She's working for Griffith
for five years now.
Oh, great. She's gonna tell him everything.
Listen here, big guy. You can spend
the rest of your life smuggling cognac
while some other guy collects
the dividends on your father's blood.
- It's your call.
- It's my call, I know.
That's my woman.
That's fucking great.
Danielle, stay.
Sorry. But if I'd sat there another
second, I would have slapped him.
The guy's old, crazy, you know?
Sorry.
Look, just check on what
he was saying. That's it.
And keep it quiet.
Shit.
Alex.
No, it's my brother.
The wrong guy.
Wrong guy.
Alex, it's so good to see you.
Mr Zhang.
I heard you had quite an adventure
the other day, didn't you, Alex?
Honestly, now. The profit of four tons
of German automobile
versus four tons of white powder.
That is what we have to seriously discuss.
Have a cigar.
You don't seem quite yourself today.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Alex, because of your
little escapade the other day,
I've got the police
breathing down my neck.
Now, if you were in my team,
we wouldn't be bumping heads
this way, would we?
You like that box?
I picked it up at an estate auction.
Together with this lighter.
It was 25 years ago.
Alex.
See some familiar faces, Alex?
They're making the kind of money
you'll make when you work for me.
On Thursday, a freighter will deliver
some cargo in Tolo Harbour.
All you need to do is pick it up
and deliver it to my boatyard
in Causeway Bay.
It's simple. And the compensation,
I assure you, is most generous.
So, what you say?
You'll do it, right?
So, what's your answer?
- Hmm?
- Go fuck yourself.
I didn't hear you.
You go fuck yourself.
Big mistake.
Alex, so sorry we couldn't do business.
Oh, by the way, if you get any more
of that French cognac,
you know where to find me.
- How many were there?
- At least eight.
I could have taken them.
Except that big
Chinese ugly mother-fucker
with a big scar on his cheek.
All right, gentlemen.
Let's quit flogging the log, here.
What's it gonna be?
I'm in, Frank. All the way.
I don't know about Alex.
I'm in.
Everything under control, Miss Wilde?
Yes. Thank you.
- Does Mr Griffith know you're here?
- Yes, of course.
Pardon me, please.
What happened?
I was going through some files
when this security person came in.
So I wasn't able to find out anything.
Look, just keep looking.
And be careful next time.
I'll try. But if I get caught
I'm out of a job.
- Where are you, by the way?
- Uh...
I'm taking my brother on a fishing trip.
Give him a big kiss for me, all right?
Big kiss? I'll give him a big kick
in the ass. That's what I'll give him.
I love you.
Big kiss.
Hey, guys!
That's the place.
Fantastic.
This place is like a goddamn fort.
Good choice, Alex.
Chad! C'mon.
Great place to hit him from, Alex.
They'll be begging us
to take the tunnel back.
C'mon, Chad. We reserved
the Marco Polo suite for you.
I've slept in worse.
Oh, Frankie...
Come on in, Chad.
Don't wait around for the bellboys.
Put your luggage on the floor.
Show me one spot on the floor
without bird shit.
Oh, sorry. We forgot to call the maid.
Very funny
No. That's very funny.
Shit.
Frankie, I dunno about this guy.
Give him time, Alex. He'll be all right.
You think so?
Boom!
Hey.
- Alex, I think they screwed you.
- Let me see.
Next time, I'll make the deal.
Look good to me.
Chad, tell me again exactly...
Chad.
- Chad.
- Yeah, yeah. I hear you.
Tell me again exactly
what Zhang told you about the drop.
Thursday night, Causeway Bay.
Watch my back.
Don't fuck up.
Psst!
Shit.
Shit, Chad!
The fucker, Chad.
Come on, let's go!
Shit.
Yeah. Yeah! Hey, bro, we did it.
Did what? You fucked up.
We're wasting our time. I've worked
for Mr Griffith for over five years.
He's as honest a businessman
as I've ever met.
Just keep looking, OK?
I'll keep looking.
I miss you.
I've got to go now.
Alex?
Mr Griffith is going to an important
meeting at the Klimax Klub tonight.
Yeah?
You know who owns that club.
Raymond Zhang.
Gentlemen, to our latest acquisition.
The Golden Glory...
which will soon be exporting
our shared bounty
to the United States of America.
Let us thank
their Drug Enforcement Agency
for their efforts to stem the flow
of narcotics from South America.
Demand is up. Street prices are up.
And we, in the Far East, are now
more than ready to fill the vacuum.
Kara, would you like to do the honours?
Thank you.
Excuse me for a moment.
Hey, Alex! Didn't think we'd see you
around here so soon.
Those scars healed pretty good,
didn't they?
Huh? You are looking well.
What's in the box?
This is the cognac Mr Zhang asked for.
Can you give this to him, please?
With my compliments.
Now, turning to a more immediate matter.
Last night, our factory was destroyed.
I know you're all aware
of this temporary setback.
Since the police are not claiming
responsibility, one can only assume
that it was the work of an outside rival.
Or worse yet... an inside rival.
Yes, I know. It's terribly bad
for the morale of all concerned
when someone isn't being a team player.
You see, we've been letting
ourselves get soft, gentlemen.
Lax in our attitudes.
We haven't been paying
sufficient attention
to all the little details.
Have we, now... Mr Ngyuen?
No! No! Not me!
More cake, anyone?
Chad, come on. Move your ass.
Hi.
- Hey, who the hell are you?
- Alex.
- Alex? Alex who?
- This is the cognac for Mr Zhang.
Just arrived from Marseilles. Number one.
- Would you like to dance?
- Yeah, why not?
You are very handsome man.
Like Sean Connery.
Uh-huh. What?
- What's that?
- French cognac, sir.
From our friend Alex.
He knew about last night's shipment.
Invite him in here.
We'd like to have a drink with him.
- Would you like to dance with me?
- Uh...
- Would you excuse me for a minute?
- OK.
More cognac, eh?
Well, guess what? The big boss
would like to thank you personally.
- Hey, that's nice. Um...
- In there.
I've got one more case of cognac in the car.
I'll be right back.
No. You don't seem to understand.
Mr Zhang would like to thank you now.
Are you hearing me?
Let's go.
There's two of them.
It's another bomb. Get the hell out. Move it.
Come On Get out of here.
We're busted. Out. Out!
Get out!
Chad, this way.
What's the big hurry?
Are you, um... hiding something?
- No.
- No?
That's good, because... I have to frisk you.
And if I don't find anything, well...
I can let you go.
And we can just forget
this ever happened. Hmm?
C'mon, now. Turn around.
That's a good girl, yeah.
And now...
you can frisk me.
Arson investigators
are exploring the possibility
that the mysterious fýres plaguing
properties owned by Transworld Exports
are the result of renewed warfare between
rival Triad families based in the colony.
We'll be back with sports and weather...
- Hello?
- Chad.
- Hey, Danielle.
- May I please talk to Alex?
Uh, Alex and Frankie...
They're in the jungle.
Hey, you can talk to me. I'm a nice guy.
Chad, I found something in the files.
An old document.
I... I really shouldn't talk here.
Chad...
I was just searched.
Searched? What do you mean,
"searched"? Who searched you?
It's not something
I care to discuss on the phone.
You're right. Stop talking.
I'm gonna find Alex
and... and... and... Frankie, uh...
We'll pick you up at Alex's place.
You go there now.
Uh... I'll talk to you soon.
Guys! Guys! Where are you?
Alex! Yo, Frankie!
Honey, we're home!
Chad!
Hell of a time to take a joyride!
- Express service.
- Where's Alex?
Couldn't find him.
I dunno what to tell you, Alex.
I'll be outside.
Frank was right about everything.
About your boss, too.
Yes, I've realised that.
- Oui?
- Is my brother with you?
Sure, boss. He's in the back room.
- By himself?
- Uh... No. Danielle, she's with him.
- Everything is OK, boss?
- Put him on the phone.
- Yes, sure. Let me just go to get him.
- Now!
Allô?
Where are they?
- Brothers.
- Brothers?
- Kara.
- What's wrong?
She works for Griffith.
She's the one who searched me.
Don't play stupid with me.
They got guns. We're trapped.
No, we're not. Help me
move this aside. Come, help me.
I love Alex.
I'm gonna kill him!
Hey, this is good.
Excuse me.
Shit.
This way.
C'mon, let's go!
C'mon!
Move!
Go!
The boat. Let's go!
Jump! C'mon, jump!
Let's move out.
Let's go.
That's it. Let's go back.
Mother-fucker!
- Frankie.
- You've got a lot of explaining to do.
And I got to ditch this boat.
Now get outta there.
What's going on?
There's been a lot of strange-looking
aircraft floating around here...
- What is she doing here?
- She realised Griffith ain't Mr Clean.
We got enough prima donnas here.
Like I say...
You got a lot of explaining to do.
Madame, your suite is ready.
This is it. Home, sweet home.
Well, well, well...
Ain't this a sweet picture?
Alex, I tried to call you.
Somebody searched me at the office.
Don't stop there, bro.
I think she likes it.
- Alex, it's not what it seems.
- You shut up.
Alex... Cool down.
Chill out, pal.
Chill out, OK?
Chill out?
Chill out.
Mr California.
Mr Silk Underwear.
Mr Perfection.
You wanna see
how we chill out in Hong Kong?
You're drunk, Alex. Stop this!
Don't even think about it.
I was waiting for that.
Alex.
C'mon.
C'mon!
- Alex, he's your brother.
- Brother. Why?
Because he looks like me?
I'm gonna change that.
- Because I'm gonna fuck up his face.
- I'm your brother.
Frank! Frank!
You're not bad for a pussy.
Come on!
Hey!
Chad! Alex! Hey!
You guys outta your mind?
Frank! Stop them!
We're supposed to be fighting
the Zhangs, not each other.
Now you, Alex, you need him more now
than you ever have.
- Don't tell me what I need.
- You're drunk.
Maybe I'm drunk. Tomorrow I'll be sober.
But he'll always be a faggot.
That's it, Frank.
I don't need him.
I don't need the fucking tunnel.
I'm out of here! Fuck him!
I'm out of here.
- Chad. Chad!
- Fuck him!
- What do you mean, "out of here"?
- I'm going home!
Los Angeles!
We're on an island on the other side
of the fucking ocean.
I'll swim!
- Hey!
- I'll swim!
Damn.
Alex, he is your brother.
Who was there for me,
when I was on the street alone, huh?
Nobody helped me.
I don't have a brother.
I don't have a brother!
Oh, mother-fucker.
Where are they?
- Where are the twins?
- Fuck you.
Stop! They've gone. They've left the island.
She lies. They could take us
somewhere else.
If you find them,
bring back their bodies.
I think Griffith would love
to speak to this one personally.
Welcome home.
They've got Frank and Danielle.
- Where?
- I was just about to ask him and...
I hope he'll talk.
He'll talk. Trust me.
So we don't have
the entire cabal in custody?
But we will before the day's over.
- Are they cooperating yet?
- No, sir.
Hello, Frank.
Are you ready to talk?
Or are you ready to scream?
Like I said... fuck you!
Hey, where's your brother? Huh?
Where's your brother?
He's late for the party.
My brother hates parties, man.
You don't know what side your bread
is buttered on, do you, you silly bitch!
Think of all the kindness
I wasted on you over the years.
Move.
Go!
Chad.
What's going on up there?
It's painfully obvious, Raymond.
Would you give me the phone?
This is Nigel Griffith speaking.
Good evening, lads.
Not in a conversational mood, are we?
Fuck you.
Perhaps a word or two from a friend
might serve to break the ice.
Kara, make him scream.
- Stop it!
- Chad! In the boiler room!
In the boiler room!
They know where we are now.
That's good.
We can stop wasting time.
Ring the area with your men. Hurry!
We're still waiting for you, lads.
It's not terribly polite
to treat your friends this way.
If you don't hurry, one of them
might have to depart our company.
Which one would you prefer it to be?
The young lady?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Mr Frank Avery...
Don't fall for their trick, Chad!
Don't fall for their trick!
No!
One down, one to go.
Do hurry, lads.
Griffith...
You're dead.
You're dead!
They're on their way.
Good!
Oh, don't worry, Frank.
Next time we'll make it real.
Come on.
Shit.
Come on!
Mr Griffýth! Cargo hold number two!
It's gone! And everybody in it!
- The twins. What about the twins?
- Everybody. They're all dead.
Goodbye, Frank.
Get away!
Don't touch me! No!
- Come on. This ain't gonna hurt.
- No!
Oh, shit!
Alex.
Alex!
It's you and I, dickhead. Come on!
Kill him.
Go on, kill him!
Kill him!
Chad!
Chad! Take care of Frank! And Danielle.
Yeah!
He's mine!
Zhang!
C'mon. Stay with me.
Griffith!
C'mon.
Zhang!
Chad!
Come on.
Chad or Alex or whichever one you are.
Alex, what's this really about, anyway?
Is it the tunnel?
You know, Alex. Griffith - he's too weak.
Don't worry about Griffith.
My brother. He's taking care of him.
Good.
Alex... if you're in with me,
I'll give you half... of everything.
Everything.
What about my father?
Come on, come on.
You've got to breathe, haven't you?
Griffith!
Yeah.
What about my father?
Alex... It was Griffith. I swear.
Hey!
Help me!
Stop it!
Alex.
# Jump back and get ready
# 'Cause I'm gonna even the score
# You thought I wouldn't be back for more
# But I feel the fýre burning in my soul
# That kept me holding onto my goal
# And I'm sure that now you know
# You're gonna get what's coming to you
from me
# I'll make you see you never
should have done me no wrong
# 'Cause this time I'm twice as strong
# My aim too true for you to overcome
# You don't even know what I hold inside
# Ha! And that's why
# I'm gonna make you feel the impact
of my soul
# Feel the impact
# Feel the impact of my soul
Feel, feel, feel the impact
# Feel, feel, feel the impact
Feel, feel, feel
# I've been waiting
# For this moment for all my life
# I'm gonna take everything
that I've got in my heart
# And let it all out
# I'm gonna make you feel the impact
of my soul
# Feel the impact
# Gonna feel the impact of my soul
# Gonna feel the impact
# Feel it
# Feel the impact
Feel, feel, feel the impact
# Feel, feel, feel the impact
Feel, feel, feel
# Feel the impact of my soul
# Gonna feel the impact
# Gonna feel the impact of my soul
# You're gonna feel the impact
# Jump back and get ready
# 'Cause I'm gonna even the score
# You thought I wouldn't be back for more
# But I feel the fýre burning in my soul
# That kept me holding onto my goal
# And I'm sure that now you know
# You're gonna get what's coming to you
from me
# I'll make you see you never
should have done me no wrong
# 'Cause this time I'm twice as strong
# My aim too true for you to overcome
# You don't even know what I hold inside
# Ha! And that's why
# I'm gonna make you feel the impact
of my soul
# Feel the impact
# Feel the impact of my soul
Feel, feel, feel the impact
# Feel, feel, feel the impact
Feel, feel, feel
# I've been waiting
# For this moment for all my life
# I'm gonna take everything
that I've got in my heart
# And let it all out
# I'm gonna make you feel the impact
of my soul
# Feel the impact
# Gonna feel the impact of my soul
# Gonna feel the impact
# Feel it
# Feel the impact
Feel, feel, feel the impact
# Feel, feel, feel the impact
Feel, feel, feel
# Feel the impact of my soul
# Gonna feel the impact
# Gonna feel the impact of my soul
# You're gonna feel the impact
- # Feel the impact of my soul
- # Feel the impact
- # I can take control
# Feel the impact
# You're gonna feel the impact
Feel the impact
- # Feel the impact
- # You better watch it #