Driver: There's a hundred thousand streets in the city.
Now, you give me a time and a place.
I give you a five-minute window,
anything happens in that five minutes and I'm yours...
No matter what.
Anything happens in either side of that,
then you are on your own.
Do you understand?
Good.
And you won't be able to reach me on this phone again.
Hey, there you are!
She's down there.
Plain Jane boring, just like you asked for.
But, I dropped in 300 horses on the inside,
She's gonna fly.
You look like a zombie kid.
You get any sleep?
Can I offer you some Benzadrine,
Dextradine, Caffeine...Nicotine ???
Oh you don't smoke, that's right.
You're better off.
There she is!
'Chevy Impala'
most popular car in the state of California.
No one will be looking at you.
Police P.A: All units be advised,
possible 731 in progress.
10:10 shots fired at 421 South Alemida.
Car 52 what's you twenty?
Car 52 to dispatch, currently at ten pager on 7th,
ETA approximately one minute.
All unit be advised,
possible vehicle in question;
late model, silver impala.
Car 16 to dispatch,
We sealed off south parameter
and moving on.
- Which floor?
- 4th please.
Director wants to see a rollover.
You okay with that?
Remember, If you don't feel good;
just abort the shot.
There's no shame in that,
Alright?
You're doubling for the star.
It's not like you are A player or anything.
And I got you $500 more. Huh?
Of course we split that.
You okay? Ready to go?
Alright, I'm counting on you.
Oh Kid!
That's fantastic.
Just fantastic!
Okay, How're you doing?
You okay?
Good, that was perfect.
Where should I put these?
In the kitchen.
Thank you.
Scary.
Hey, You want a tooth-pick?
- Sure.
You want a glass of water?
Okay.
Thanks.
So, did you just moved to L.A?
No, I've been here for a while.
You are just new here?
- Mmhmm.
That's Benicio's father.
Where is he?
He's in prison.
What do you do?
I drive.
Like a limo driver?
No, like for movies.
Doing all those car chases and stuff?
yeah.
Isn't that dangerous?
It's only part time.
Mostly I work at the garage.
- Where?
Receda Boulevard.
I gotta go.
Well, thank you.
Thanks for the water.
Say bye.
Chicken Chowmein?
And, some peking duck.
Where are the chopsticks?
- uh ...the guy
- go get 'em. I don't want that.
Chopsticks and a fortune cookie.
Put out the fucking cigrette,
I'm eating.
Sorry.
- What's the matter with you?
You run a perfectly good business.
I don't know, why you wanna change that.
You know how much
my business made last year?
30 grand.
I can build a car in six months
and in six seconds these jerks write it off as a stunt
that won't even make it to the movie.
See, all i need is a hard used start car.
that's all.
I figure we start off small town circuit;
we work our way up.
Once we get to the show,
we are talking millions.
So, you still haven't give me your number.
Alright, Four hundred thirty thousand dollars.
Oh...!
Mr.Ross, I wouldn't come to you with this.
Unless, I'm absolutely sure about it !
How can you be sure, Shannon.
What do you got that
the professional race team don't?
I got a driver.
You just told me there're half a dozen drivers.
Not like this one.
This kid is special.
Been working with him for a while,
I've never seen anybody like it.
If I had the money,
I'd back him myself.
Yeah, but you don't have the money.
Mr.Ross,
You put this kid behind the wheel...
there's nothing he cannot do.
What are you doing eating
chink food in my fucking restaurant?
What's a Jew doing running a pizzaria?
You remember Shannon?
Take a fucking hike.
I wanna talk to my partner.
Hah, I'm just fucking with you.
How're you doing Shannon.
How's the fucking leg?
I've paid my debt.
I'll think about it. Okay?
But I wanna meet the kid first.
That's all I ask.
C'mon, I want you to meet somebody.
Whatever you do like about the car,
don't say anything.
I want to drive the price down a little bit.
Kid, I want you to meet Mr.Bernie Ross.
Nice to meet you.
My hands are a little dirty.
So are mine.
Good driving out there.
- Thanks.
So? what do you think?
Do we get the 400?
I'll give you 300 for 70 percent.
Done!
you won't be sorry!
Hey pal, just drop it down here.
We're pushing it alright.
We wanna push her into number three.
The car. Not you.
- Oh good.
Hi...
- hi.
uhh...You two know each other?
- Don't.
Oh look at that.
We're neighbours.
- Neihhbours, very good.
Well, we'll try to be neighbourly too.
You blinked.
What?
Can I call a cab from here.
- Yeah, sure.
What am I talking 'bout.
You and the kid are neighbours, right.
He can take you.
Oh no.
I feel bad.
No, no...Don't even think twice about it.
He'll be happy to do it.
He's a good guy.
You know, he walked into my shop here
about five or six years ago...
right out of the blue,
asking for a job.
So, i put him to the test,
to see what he could do.
The kid is amazing.
So, i hired him on the spot.
Boom!
At about half the wages i normally pay.
He didn't even blink an eye.
Hey kid,
come over here for a sec will you.
And I have been exploiting him ever since.
Don't tell him.
Looks like we've bigger problem
than I thought.
We're gonna have to keep
the car here for a few days.
So, I offered your services to take,
Benicio and Irene home.
Would that be okay?
Yeah sure.
I don't have wheels...
in my car.
It's one think you should know about me.
Well put the tyres on.
You got about five minutes?
- Yeah.
Hey, do you wanna see something?
Yeah.
okay.
You did good.
We had a good time.
Me too.
Sorry, if I put you on the spot or anything.
It's okay.
I'm not doing anything this weekend.
If you wanna go out or something.
Don't worry about these bumps and bruises.
Thats easily replaceable.
We coat a paint  on there with sponsors detail.
Look at the thread on the tyre,
still good huh, we are in business.
You paid 300 fucking grand for this piece of shit?
I paid for it.
Out of my own pocket.
This is just the shell.
It's the inside that counts.
Not the outside.
Right, Shannon?
You are correct sir.
Fuck that shit. If I paid 300 for something.
I want everybody to see it.
Of course you do.
Now this.
That is one motherfucking fine ass pussy mobile,
motherfucker!
Damn!
Shannon, sell him that car.
He won't be able to find a pussy
in a whorehouse.
You know what?
This car will make you even good looking.
How's it going?
When's our first race?
uhh, pretty soon.
You gonna be ready?
I hope so.
huh...I hope so.
Hey no false modesty.
I got a lot of money on this.
Did Shannon ever tell you how we met?
I used to produce movies.
In the 80's.
Kinda like action films and sexy stuff.
One critic called them 'European'.
I thought they were shit.
Anyway he arrange all the cars for me.
Did all the stunts.
I liked him. I like having him around.
Eventhough, he'd overcharge the shit out of me.
His next business venture.
He got involved with some of Nino's friends.
They didn't go for the overcharging bit.
They broke his pelvis.
He's never had a lot of luck.
The reason I'm telling you this is,
He's got a lot invested in you.
So do I.
So. You need anything...
You call me.
We're a team now.
I'm excited.
Let's get out of here.
Nino.
You see the bad guy?
- Yeah.
How can you tell?
Cos he's a shark.
There's no good shark?
No... I mean,
just look at him.
Does he look like a good guy to you?
That was my hausband's lawyer.
He's coming home in a week.
You know, we're here celebrating.
Its a shameful thing...
what I did.
And I have a lot of making up to do,
to everyone.
But second chances are rare.
Right?
And that's worth celebrating.
So, I want to make a toast.
To that lady right there.
Thanks for staying.
I love you, Inny.
Salud.
Hey?
Hi.
Sorry about the noise.
I was gonna call the cops.
I wish you would.
Oye, getting heavier.
Hey, how are you doing?
- Hi.
This guy has been telling a lot about you.
He says, you've been coming around and
helping out a lot.
Yeah? helping out.
Is that right?
That's very nice.
That's nice of you.
Than you.
- You're welcome.
You drive for the movies?
- Yeah.
I can take that.
- No, no. I got it.
Let mommy talk to her friend.
You have a good night.
You're Shannon's buddy, Right?
We met last year.
You drove me and my brother
back from palm springs.
We hired another wing man.
I spend six months in jail and
my brother got himself killed.
I've got a sweet job coming up.
How about this?
You shut you mouth.
Or I'll kick your teeth down
your throat and i'll shut it for you.
Nice seeing you again.
come here.
Don't be scared.
Look, don't tell mommy. Okay?
Okay, it's a secret between us boys.
Oh fuck.
Who are they?
What the fuck are you gonna do?
You gonna go and beat them out for me?
Huh, stunt guy.
Why the fuck do you
wanna know who they are?
There's some guy who want me to do a job for him,
But I'm not gonna do it.
What's the job?
He want me to rob a pawn shop in the valley.
Why?
Cos i owe them protection money,
for when i was in the inside.
It's two thousand bucks.
and as soon as I got out.
Oh it's five thousand bucks.
Oh it's actually, Ten thousand dollars.
Twenty thousand dollars,
tomorrow I don't know what it's gonna be.
What are you gonna do?
That's a very good question.
They said they're gonna come after
Benicio and Irene next.
You okay?
You want something to drink?
What' s that you got there?
Can I see?
One of those man gave you this?
- Mmmhm.
They told me not to loose it.
You want me to keep this for you?
Okay.
How's Benice?
- Good.
You just saying that?
No, what do you mean?
I saw that Standard...
was in an accident.
Yeah.
What happened?
He got beat up.
Why?
Just drunk kids.
You should come over.
You should come and see him.
You wanna...
You wanna hear a story?
You wanna hear how mommy and me met?
- Yeah.
We're at a pary.
And she was nineteen years old.
- Seventeen.
- You're not seventeen.
- I was.
Wow, so that's illegal.
Alright, so I illegally walked over
to a seventeen year old girl.
I walked up and I say....
"Hello Miss"
What is your name?
And she didn't say anything.
And I said, well...
my name's Standard Gabriel.
Then what did you said.
I said...
'Where's the deluxe version'
Oh man, that killed me.
And then a year later,
You popped out man.
Best day of my life.
If I drive for you, you'll get your money.
That's a guarantee.
You tell me where we start,
Where we're going...
Where we're going afterwards.
I give you a five-minutes when we get there.
Anything happens in that five minutes
and I'm yours no matter what.
Anything a minute either side of that...
then you are on your own.
I don't sit in while you're running it down;
I don't carry a gun...
I drive.
You look like you are hard to work with.
Not as long as we understand each other.
What's there to understand?
I cannot do this thing alone.
You got Blanche.
C'mon man.
She's beautiful,
Look at her.
What the fuck are you rolling your eyes at for?
You know get the fuck out of here.
Get up!
Standard, take her with you,
and go get her a fucking coke.
Okay here's the deal.
This much for Blanche,
This much for that asshole...
Minus what he owes me.
And this much for you.
You're still interested?
Good!
Anything else?
When you get your money,
His debt's paid.
His out for good.
You never go near his family ever again.
Do you understand?
To my family.
To my new friend.
And toast to the future.
Our future.
I'll see you in five minutes.
See you in four.
How much did Cook said,
we're gonna get?
- Fourty Grand.
Stay here.
Cop: When was the last time you saw your hausband?
Can you answer...
the question?
Benicio: Hello?
Benicio, Is that you?
- Yeah.
Your mother there?
- Uh she's sitting down...
talking to a police.
Okay, just tell her I'm gonna call her back.
Okay?
Okay, bye.
TV reporter: He's been identified as Standard Gabriel,
Of Echo Park, L.A.
Other details are unclear but...
the owner of the pawn shop, told the reporter
that Gabriel acted alone.
and that, the items he had stolen
has been recovered.
If he saw you take the money...
and saw you get in the car;
then why didn't they say anything?
- I have no idea.
Did you have any idea that
there would  be a second car?
I already told you, I didn't.
Now, you've just got a little boy's father killed.
and you almost got us killed.
and now, you are lying to me.
So, how about this?
From now on, every words out of your mouth is the truth.
Or i'm gonna hurt you.
Do you understand?
Now, what did Cook tell you?
He said there'd be another car hold us up.
But he didn't say anything about all these money.
he didn't say anything about anyone
getting killed.
And he was gonna rip us off?
What's his real name?
He said it's Chris...
But i just call him Cook.
You're gonna take me to him...
right now.
Do you understand?
- Yeah.
This guy Cook,
he have a real name?
Chris.
Maybe.
I'll ask Bernie,
see if he knows him.
Jesus!
I can't stop thinking about...
what we could do with all that dough.
Would you stop?
- Alright!
You know, a lot of guys messing around
with married women...
but you're the only one I know who robs a joint,
to pay back the hausband.
Crazy!
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
Where's Cook?
He's in the dressing room.
Where's that?
It's over there.
You're a fucking dead man.
Whose money do i have?
Don't worry...
they're gonna come and get it.
Call them.
Somebody call Nino.
Do you remember this?
Hello?
Nino?
No, sorry pal.
Why don't you call back later, we're closed.
I could, but i think Nino would be upset
that you made him wait.
- Can I ask what this is about?
I have something of his.
- And that would be?
A million dollars.
- Please hold.
Nino: You have something that
fucking belongs to me.
Seems that way.
- And you're calling me...
-  Why?
-  You're expecting to buy my own shit back from you?
I'm not selling it.
I'm gonna give you a time and place,
and you're gonna come and get it.
Do you Understand?
- What are you getting out of it?
Just that.
'Out of it.'
- And your partners are happy with that?
I don't have any partners.
- you discuss this with anybody else?
No, just with you.
- You're not very good at this.
Are you?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
- I can't talk,
I have to go.
Can I just walk with you...for?
I have to tell you something.
Standard was into some...
guys in prison for a lot of money.
And it would ruin you and benicio
if he wouldn't pay it.
He asked me for my help.
It just went wrong,
you know.
I'm sorry.
I still got the money.
You can have it,
if you wanted to.
You can take Benicio...and.
I just thought,
we could get out of here. If you wanted.
I could come with you.
I could look out for you.
Sorry...uh...
Wrong floor.
He came into my apartment, Shannon.
How did they know where I live?
- I told you,
I was gonna call Bernie.
I just want him know that...
that it wasn't about that,
you are not interested in the money.
and that you just did it for the girl.
You told him about Irene!!!
I just wanted him to know that...
as soon as you return the money,
that was the end of it.
I didn't know.
How was I suppose to know that?
Okay?
Look, let me just talk to Bernie..
Why did you have to fuck everything up, Shannon?
Why did you have to fuck everything up?
They're gonna come looking for me.
and they're gonna come for you.
Do you understand?
You gotta get out of here.
and you gotta get out now.
Listen to me.
Listen to me, Shannon.
You get out of here and you never fucking come back.
You never come back.
What are you gonna do?
I already gave you my advice.
You should've taken the money,
and left the guy alone.
- It's just not that simple Bernie.
No! of course not!
Now everything's bounced up in your face!
You know, I owe you this guy.
Just give me a little time and I'll get rid of him.
Shut the fuck up.
You fucking monkey!
The money, belongs to some half-assed wise guy,
out of Philly. Now...
I got tipped off...
he was stashing a million bucks in a pawn shop;
He's gonna invest it here in L.A
He was gonna set up a rival operation.
So, you stole from the east-coast mob?
No! I stole from some jump up punk.
He was trying to step on our action.
Yeah... then why didn't you come to me,
before you set up this dummy robbery?
Before you hire this piece of shit.
This was something on the side, Bernie.
I didn't wanna involve you on this.
Well, I'm involved now!
Let me tell you something...
Anybody...anybody!
Finds out you stole from the family, we are both dead.
What fucking family?
The family who still calls me a fucking kike?
To my face!
You know, I'm fifty nine years old Bernie,
they still pinched my cheek like i'm some fucking kid.
Family.
The money flows up, easy.
You know that.
That's why this driver's gotta go, Bernie.
He's gotta go.
and your pal, Shannon.
it's these two guys,
that can tie me to this robbery.
Now, it's your turn to clean up after me.
All this priceless cars...
One would think you'd have better locks.
Doors is always open to you.
Going somewhere?
I was thinking about it.
I'm looking for your driver.
You breaking in here,
I figure its bad news.
No, Shannon.
It's bad luck.
Two thousand  heist a year in this city,
he has to pick the wrong one.
He tried to put it right.
Well, he picked the wrong guy for that too.
My partner is a belligerent asshole,
with his back against the wall.
Right now, so am I.
If I don't set this straight,
I'm in big trouble.
Any idea where he might be?
Mexico.
or maybe it was Balise.
really?
I was excited about this whole thing.
my name on a car!
I mean, look how beautiful.
I wanted to see my name on this thing.
I think we would've made a go with this business.
Don't worry.
That's it.
It's done.
There is no pain, its over. Its over.
Nino.
Nino???
You know who this is.
Where's Nino?
He's gone.
I think this has gone on long enough.
You see any reason for this to continue?
What do you say we meet?
Why would I wanna do that?
Well...
You, me and your girlfriend are the only players left.
How's that for a reason?
When?
Tomorrow.
There's a place on Sherman Way...
there's a restaurant called ' The Great Wall'
You know it?
I'll find it.
Can I talk to you?
I won't keep you long.
I have to go somewhere now.
I don't think I can come back.
I just want you to know...
Just getting to be around you...
was the best thing that ever happened to me.
Did you bring the money?
Here's what I'm prepared to offer...
You give me the money,
the girl is safe.
Forever, nobody knows about it.
She's off the limits.
I can't offer you the same.
So, this is what I would suggest.
We conclude our deals...
we shake hands.
You'll start the rest of you life.
Any dreams you have,
plans or hopes for the future;
I think you got to put that on holds.
For the rest of your life,
you're gonna be looking over your shoulder.
I'm just telling you this,
b'cos I want you to know the truth.
But the girl is safe.