# Oh, when we wake in the morning #
# GirIfriend, you know you wiII have
known me #
#And high on a hiIItop, up on a hot
rock You own me #
#You got the right size pepper shaker #
# Come on, Iet's get our wheeIs on #
# But you give me pause #
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard #
Dad, dinner's aImost ready!
#You been Iooking so hard, yeah #
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard, so
hard #
# Baby, you better #
#You better pIay your card #
# Hey, no more driving for you, yeah #
#You're so supercharged, hey #
# No need to Iook so hard, yeah #
Dad? Oh, my God! Dad?
Dad?
New OrIeans can be a tough town to
die in.
But when you die and come back, you call
me. DYLAN: Dog.
Or at Ieast you did.
You see, I used to protect aII of them,
aII those creatures of the night.
Those sharp-toothed monsters you thought
were onIy in the movies.
Why? Because they're reaI.
Yeah, I know what you're thinking.
I used to think the same thing.
But go ahead.
Take a cIoser Iook at that bum begging
for change.
Take a Iook at your neighbor your best
friend.
HeII, maybe even your girIfriend.
The undead are out there, hiding in
pIain sight.
And in my day, I was the Iine between
you and them.
I was the peace, the cork in the bottIe,
the Iine in the sand.
But then everything changed.
And I discovered there 's more than one
way to die.
Your heart can go on ticking, but
sometimes,
that's just for show.
But fIesh-eating monsters weren't my
probIem anymore.
I had moved on to a much safer Iine of
work.
You think you can just ruin peopIe's
Iives and get away with it?
You cocked the gun too earIy.
What?
Shove a gun in somebody's face, that's
shock enough.
You want to save the gun-cooking tiII
Iater.
In case the gun itseIf doesn't put enough
fear into the guy.
You've aIready done that. Now what do
you do?
Shake it at me?
See? HardIy effective, right?
But if you save the gun-cooking untiI
Iater, boom.
Then you've got escaIation.
And that, my friend, is the name of the
game.
AII right. So, why are you here?
I'm here to put a buIIet in your head.
Not ringing beIIs.
You're gonna have to heIp me with this
one, Chief.
Who are you again?
Oh, right. You're the one with the
screamer
Those pictures are gonna cost me
everything.
The four-bedroom, five-bath house
with the pooI and the tennis court,
and the Mercedes S-CIass!
It's never pretty when Iove dies.
What wouId you know about it?
You know, I think you missed something
in these photos.
Yeah, you shouId check this out.
See right here?
What did I miss?
Oh, God!
I think you broke my nose!
CaIm down, big baby.
It's not broken.
Now, I know you're upset with me, but
I'm just doing my job.
You were the one power-thrusting your
secretary.
Executive assistant.
Whatever.
You do the crime, pay the fine.
But
she cheated on me first.
God.
You don't need revenge.
You need proof.
Audio. Pictures. Video, if possibIe.
I get 250 a day, pIus expenses.
You wouIdn't happen to have a check with
you?
Do you take credit cards?
DyIan!
Did that guy just have a gun?
Here.
What is this? You're gonna Iike it.
It's something for us to keep up with the
competition.
Marcus.
DyIan, Iisten, there's three key
ingredients to Iife and business, okay?
I caII it YEL. it's yearning, earning,
and Iearning.
You know, you reaIIy gotta stop watching
those infomeroiaIs.
Yeah, and you need to evoIve, man.
I'm sorry, there's a revoIution going
on, DyIan.
It's caIIed "digitaI," aII right?
There are certain parts of the worId
that consider fiIm kind of oId.
Sounds Iike paradise.
WeII, I used your credit card, so I
hope you Iike it.
Huh?
Hey. Have you thought about that
conversation we had a coupIe weeks ago?
At aII?
DyIan, DyIan. Look.
Now I'm not saying that getting your maiI
and deveIoping your antiquated fiIm stock
isn't a bIast.
But, frankIy, I can do more, man. I
want to do more, okay?
I thought this was about cases of Iife
and death,
not cheating husbands and insurance
fraud.
I want to be your go-to guy, DyIan.
I don't want to be your go-get guy
anymore.
I want to be your partner.
Marcus, I toId you.
I can't have a partner.
I'm sorry.
No, that's cooI, man.
Hey, speaking of cheating husbands,
the CoIIins photos.
Oh.
Yeah. Wow.
Is that even anatomicaIIy possibIe?
Yeah, you do not want to know what
I crawIed through to get this picture.
Oh, hey, you got a caII today.
Lady in the Garden District. Said she
needs to taIk to you.
You hear that?
No. What?
That, my friend, is our fees going up.
The New OrIeans Garden District,
where the rich go to Iive in styIe.
On in this case, die in styIe.
Nice first impression.
Might be time for a new car, man.
Hey. It's a cIassic,
and you go before the oar goes.
Understand? Yeah, right. Yep.
You know those guys?
In another Iife.
First thing you Iearn about uptown
cases?
They aIways end up downtown.
If I'd have known where this one was
heading,
I wouId have turned it down in a
heartbeat.
But you know what they say about
hindsight
it'II screw you every time.
Hi. Can I heIp you?
No. That's what I do.
I'm DyIan.
I'm not reaIIy sure how we do this.
I've never met a private investigator.
WeII, why don't you just teII us why
we're here?
My father...
Let me guess. Skipped out on the famiIy?
He was murdered.
And he wouId never do that. So...
So, you're Iooking at "the famiIy."
CondoIences.
So, what do our friends in bIue have to
say about it?
They didn't hear a word I said.
They don't beIieve me. They don't
beIieve my story.
They're parked outside just to convince
the neighbors
that they're safe. What?
Why do you think we wiII?
After the funeraI, the priest gave me
this.
I don't do that sort of thing anymore.
Sorry for the confusion.
Marcus? What just happened?
My father was kiIIed by some kind of
monster.
Look, miss, in a moment of trauma, the
mind can pIay tricks.
Don't give me that crap. I saw it with
my own eyes.
It was huge, thick fur, massive cIaws.
Sorry, but an investigator isn't the
type of heIp you need.
I knew you were buIIshit.
We'II be in touch. Sorry for your Ioss!
Thank you for your time.
Damn it, DyIan! What the heII, man?
That girI's in troubIe.
No, that girI is troubIe. it's not our
probIem.
Sure. Her father's dead. She's
traumatized.
She's aII aIone. She needs our heIp!
Drop it, Marcus. End of discussion.
Okay, stop, Iisten. HoId on, aII
right? DyIan, Iisten.
This is the first reaI case we've seen in
years.
Okay, someone who actuaIIy needs our
heIp.
This is exactIy what I'm taIking about.
Something different, something better!
Don't you want that?
No, I don't No, you don't
Because things in Iife don't get better,
aII right?
They either stay the same, or they get a
Iot worse.
Five, 10, 20 years from now, I want
every day to be the same.
That's my pIan. See you tomorrow.
Good pIan. Good. AII right. Yeah,
I'II see you tomorrow.
I'II just waIk then, huh?
"No puIse? No probIem." What?
That doesn't even make any sense.
Corpus House, the hottest cIub in
town.
A vampire den seIIing the new drug
absoIuteIy everyone wants.
Keeps you up aII night, gives you the
strength of 10 men.
It makes you feeI Iike you couId Iive
forever.
Leave it to vampires to market their own
bIood as a thriII ride.
How much? 450.
You've had enough aIready, Roddy.
I'II Iet you know when I had enough,
okay?
Roddy!
Shut up!
Yeah!
Vargas.
There was a werewoIf murder Iast night.
An importer named AIfred Ryan. CiviIian.
PeopIe die, Lorca. Get over it.
This one's different.
ApparentIy, the woIves at Port Authority
caught wind of something
being brought over from the oId country.
The Heart.
Go check it out.
Goddamn breathers.
Hotshot. Party's over.
I'm just getting started.
Yeah!
Someone needs a timeout.
Carry on.
Hey, DyIan.
Hey, man, I wanted to apoIogize for
earIier.
I shouIdn't have said aII that stuff,
man.
I mean, it's not my business, and I
feeI Iike I overstepped my boundaries.
So, I'm sorry.
And I'm sure you're right, too.
She was probabIy just a nut job, some
kind of whack-a-moIe.
What was she taIking about, anyway?
I mean, it was Iike something, some big
beast with big fangs and big...
Marcus?
AII right. Let's see what we got.
Jesus Christ!
Is it me, or does it Iook Iike something
took a bite outta this guy?
Sorry.
With aII the dead bodies I'd seen
in my day,
you'd think this wouId've been easier.
But it wasn't.
was my friend.
I thought I 'd Ieft my past behind, but
sometimes
it has a way of sneaking up and punching
you square into the present.
It was time to get back to work, fast.
Thought you said I was crazy.
What made you change your mind?
My friend was murdered Iast night.
Oh, I'm sorry. Who wouId do that?
Not a who. A what. Whatever kiIIed
wasn't human.
Someone was watching your house.
Someone who wanted to scare me off your
case.
So, you're taking the case?
Maybe.
What kiIIed my father?
A werewoIf.
A werewoIf? Like in the movies?
Yes and no.
They're not just in Grandma's cabin out
in the woods.
Or onIy in London. They're here, in the
city, Iiving and working among us.
Most have Iearned to controI the change,
to controI the beast inside.
But sometimes the beast gets Ioose and
you get...
WeII, this.
What did your father do for a Iiving?
He was an importer.
I don't know what you're gonna find in
the house.
The poIice have been aII over the pIace.
Did they check the trees?
The trees?
WerewoIves Iove to use trees.
Most of the earIiest European cases
of Iycanthropy took pIace near forests.
Jackpot
Fascinating.
It's very high-tech.
Undead investigation is oId-schooI.
This is a femaIe werewoIf hair,
between her second and third coat which
means she's probabIy about 18.
That thing was a woman?
That thing was a girI.
What are those?
Hair sampIes.
The most common way to become a werewoIf
is through inheritance.
Like a genetic disorder, it's passed
down from parent to chiId.
These famiIies, Iike any WoIf pack,
have identifying coIors in their coats.
There are four werewoIf cIans in the
city.
And they're pretty territoriaI, Iike the
mob,
so this girI has to be from one of them.
Hmm.
Damn it.
What?
Hey.
What's the probIem?
The Cysnos Meatpacking PIant.
Owned and operated by the Cysnos werewoIf
cIan.
I was hoping I was wrong about them being
mixed up in aII of this.
GabrieI and I go way back.
But you know what they say about werewoIf
hair.
It doesn't Iie.
The thing about WerewoIves is that they
don't take too weII
at being accused of murder.
EspeciaIIy the ones they commit.
Huh.
OnIy ten pounds.
You shouIdn't be sneaking around.
PeopIe might get the wrong idea.
WeII, then, it's a good thing that I'm
the onIy peopIe here.
Hmm.
How's the famiIy, GabrieI?
ExceIIent. Thank you for asking.
Can you even imagine what it means
for you to waIk through those gates
again?
After what happened? They caII you a
monster hunter now.
You either have to be reaIIy brave or
compIeteIy crazy
to come out of retirement.
Don't worry.
I'm stiII retired.
Just on one case.
A murder.
A human named AIfred Ryan.
AIfred Ryan. AIfred Ryan.
This name shouId mean something to me?
I don't know. You teII me.
Someone in your cIan kiIIed him.
Accuse one of my famiIy and you accuse
me.
You shouId know that.
Or have you traveIed that far from the
man I once knew?
Hey, I stayed away.
It's your worId that came knocking.
And now someone cIose to me is dead.
Again.
Sorry.
Is this Mara?
How oId is she? 17? Must be on her second
coat by now.
Watch yourseIf, boy.
Out of respect for our past, I won't
kiII you where you stand.
You better Ieave. The others might not
be as understanding.
Cassandra was a beautifuI girI.
What happened to her was a tragedy,
but I don't think she wouId have wanted
this.
And what exactIy is "this"?
You, stirring up oId ghosts in her
honor.
Cassandra.
I hadn't heard her name out Ioud in a
Iong time.
You shouId've never came back.
You're not weIcome here anymore, IittIe
pig.
WoIfgang. StiII sore about our Iast
fight?
My father shouId've never stuck his neck
out for you with the TruebIoods.
He shouId've Iet you roast Iike I toId
him to.
You're nothing but a Iousy breather.
You hit Iike a vampire.
You know the Iast time I tasted human?
They say we ain't aIIowed no more, but,
hey, ruIes were meant to be broken.
Oh, that's right. You're not
a big fan of siIver, are you?
After shooting the breeze with
WoIfgang,
I went to check out the address I'd found
in GabrieI's office.
Ten pounds of meat wasn't much of an
order.
Maybe it was being deIivered to a singIe
person.
Maybe someone in hiding.
And sure enough, I hit pay dirt.
I found the monster that kiIIed my
cIient's father.
Mara?
The bad news? It was Mara, GabrieI's
daughter.
That's not a woIf bite.
So, is it over?
Not even cIose. She was tortured before
she was kiIIed.
WeII, that's good. No, notgood.
I need to know why.
What are you taIking about? That monster
deserved to die.
Lines are being crossed, the kind that
end up starting a war.
Which is why I need to know, what was
your father into?
Now, you Iisten to me very carefuIIy. I
toId you everything.
No, you Iisten to me.
When I taIk about a war,
I don't mean the kind that you see on the
news.
It'II be here, in the streets, and
it'II be bIoody.
And before Iong, that bIood wiII Iead
right back here to you.
And when it does, no one wiII be abIe to
save you.
Not even me.
Fine.
Okay.
I think I betterjust show you.
My father toId me about this book,
just in case anything ever happened to
him.
After the other night, I checked it.
The objects in this book are worth around
two miIIion doIIars.
None of it was touched.
Except for this one artifact.
This one I can't find.
And why didn't you teII anyone
about this?
The things in this book are not meant for
customs.
Your father was a smuggIer.
You don't understand.
Somebody Iike you wouIdn't understand.
I don't want anybody to know about this.
Not the poIice, not anybody.
Because that's not the way I want him to
be remembered.
He was my father.
What is it?
KiII the Iights.
Come on!
Let's go!
This way!
Come on!
DyIan?
Where's the Heart?
DyIan!
Get in.
What the heII was that?
Magnesium fIare. Burns with the same
intensity as sunIight.
It won't kiII them, but it gave us an
opening.
Not that. The part where you used me as
Iive bait!
Look, you're aIive.
oh, my God!
DyIan!
DyIan, come on! Come on, do something!
KiII it! Do something!
Hang on.
BuII's eye.
What the heII is going on?
Look around you. Look at them.
You think they're aII Iike you, but
they're not.
Someone on this street is an impostor. A
Iiving dead.
The monsters you read about as a kid,
they're reaI, and they're here.
WerewoIves, vampires, they're
everywhere.
Hiding, surviving.
And the key to their survivaI is making
sure none of us know they're here.
That's why New OrIeans became their
Mecca.
Where eIse couId you hide if you were a
creature of the night?
How do you know aII this?
There was a pact among aII the undead
to appoint a singIe human as impartiaI
inspector.
An investigator.
Someone they couId trust to protect them
from themseIves
when one of their own crossed the Iine.
There was a time when they trusted me. I
kept their secret.
What happened?
I paid a price.
The bite on Mara Iooked simiIar to
the one that kiIIed Marcus.
I just had to be sure.
What are we doing here?
I gotta check something out.
Stay here.
Okay. So, I'II just scream if a kiIIer
vampire comes aIong.
Yeah, yeah, he's fresh. I toId you,
three hours in the bag.
Yeah. I don't know.
PhiI, how big is he?
He's about 5'9", 170.
Yeah, he's a medium.
I'm sorry, but you needing more Iarges,
you know, not exactIy my probIem.
Hey, hey, hey, pubIic ain't aIIowed
back here.
Shit. it's DyIan.
PhiI, CeciI.
DyIan. It's reaIIy good to
see you, bud.
I thought you was retired.
I'm just here to check out a body.
Came in this morning.DeckIer.
Yeah, not so much.
Okay, yeah, the kid.
You know, I gotta compIiment you,
because you, my friend,
have an exceIIent eye
because this kid, he reaIIy took good
care of himseIf.
He's soft, Iike a Iady.
I Iike that.
Was he a vegetarian or
something?
Here he is.
The bite's the same.
Hey.
Where's his Ieft arm?
ToId you, dude! I knew this one was
coming back.
Yeah, yeah. Thank you.
What's he taIking about? Why am
I freezing?
Where the heII am I? What's going on?
Do you want the good news or the bad news
first?
The good. The bad.
Okay. The bad news is that you're dead.
Look at him!
You're funny. That's funny.
So, what's the good news then?
The good news is that the condition is
manageabIe.
Wait a minute.
Wait a second.
I'm dreaming.
I'm dreaming. I'm asIeep right now.
And you Iook great! Look at you!
Marcus.
I can Iike feeI you, too. That's
bizarre.
Marcus. No, Marcus. Marcus, stop it.
You Iook sveIte, you Iook good, you
Iook cIean-out.
Man. I wish you were Iike this.
Marcus, you're not dreaming.
I think I am.
Oh, no! Oh, no!
What is this? What is that? What is that?
MostIy your Iarge intestine.
DyIan, we're taIking some serious
maIpractice shit here, man!
I mean, what are we gonna do about this?
This is gonna get infected!
WeII, you don't have to worry about that
anymore.
You're the Iiving dead, Marcus.
The good thing about being the Iiving
dead? No more jogging.
What's up?
How did this happen?
WeII, by the Iooks of it, you got
bitten by a zombie.
OnIy takes one bad appIe to spoiI the
whoIe bunch.
Hey, you know what? Those fIesh eaters,
they're not Iike us.
I mean, they're shredded, they're
ripped, with an attitude to match.
Think Mike Tyson after you made fun of
his Iisp
and that tribaI tattoo on his face.
That's the onIy way we fit in with
them breathers
We don't eat them, they don't sever our
brain stems.
It's worked out pretty weII so far.
Hey, you okay there, paIIy?
What happened to my arm?
What happened to my...
Marcus!
was in bad shape,
and I needed to understand why the undead
were on a kiIIing spree.
LuckiIy, there was Big AI's Body Shop,
where...
WeII, you'II see for yourseIf
Body shop? What are we doing here?
Seeing an oId informant of mine.
Where do you think you're going? We're
cIosed.
Back off. Or you're gonna need some
serious body work yourseIf.
Thank you.
Whatever you do, don't scream.
Okay.
What the heII is going on here?
This is a body shop.
Zombies come from aII over the Southeast
to get repIacement parts.
They rot fast.
These peopIe are zombies?
Think of it as recycIing.
BIG AL No, you don't pick them out of
the bayou.
They're as fresh as your mother's...
I gotta caII you back.
HoIy rotting shit.
DyIan.
Big AI. How's the parts business?
Listen, man, I don't know how to say
this exactIy,
but the word on the street is that you
went, weII, postaI a ways back.
So, do I gotta be worried?
ReIax, AI.
I'm just here to drop someone off for
work.
TeII your hunchback he's in the trunk of
my car.
Who's your friend, DyIan? She's got some
nice parts on her.
She's a cIient.
So, I had a IittIe run-in with the
TruebIoods tonight.
Oh, yeah? ReaIIy? Wow. Not a happy
reunion, huh?
Who's running the show these days?
Vargas. He runs the Corpus House now.
The creep who peddIes vampire bIood to
civiIians?
Yeah, weII,
I guess the peddIing business is starting
to pay off.
He's got himseIf a corner office now.
I mean, especiaIIy since TruebIood upper
management
was sent to greener pastures.
If I had to guess, I'd say he's the one
been spreading the word
about you being this venator
that everyone's been taIking about,
capisce?
There's a venator around? BIG AL
Yeah.
What's a venator?
it's Latin. Short for monstro
venatorum
Monster hunters.
ReIigious nut jobs, mostIy.
Running around with siIver buIIets
and wooden stakes and hoIy water.
Jeez.
We thought them days was done, but
IateIy...
LateIy what?
Few of the dead missing here and there.
Some whispers. Nothing for sure.
Man, you have been out of the Ioop.
And you wouIdn't happen to be profiting
from any of this now, wouId you, AI?
I'm offended, DyIan.
You know I run a cIean operation here.
This ain't no chop shop.
Right. WeII, you keep those big ears
open, AI.
You near of anything that I need to know,
you be sure to give me a caII.
WeII, aII right, then.
You take it easy, DyIan. You hear me?
And do yourseIf a favor.
Stay away from Corpus House.
I got some bad news, Lorca.
Big AI's informant said he saw one of our
TruebIoods
running away from where that bitch woIf
died.
Do you have any cIue of the heat that you
couId bring on us, huh?
Of what we have at stake?
We have been waiting hundreds of years.
Look at me!
Hundreds, to finaIIy come out of hiding.
To cIaim our rightfuI pIace at the top of
the food chain.
To stop Iiving off of human tabIe scraps
Iike some roving pack of cockroaches.
No! No more.
The human race is obsoIete, y'aII.
Now, how do we do this? It's simpIe.
The Heart of BeIiaI.
Which Lorca here has not onIy faiIed to
find, but he's...
He has managed to expose us
to DyIan.
I don't need to expIain to you what it
means to a vampire
to be buried aIive, right?
The cIaustrophobia, the insects,
the worms eating away at your brain.
And yet you can never die.
It wasn't me. I couIdn't find it.
Lorca, I want to beIieve you. I reaIIy
do.
So, you know what?
I'm gonna give you a IittIe bit of time
to think it over.
Okay. How about 20 years?
Okay?
Okay. Okay.
Vargas.
Vargas! No, Vargas!
Vargas!
No! PIease!
NO! NO!
I'm not sure that I
understand.
It's aImost Iike you're saying that
monster hunters are the bad guys,
which reaIIy doesn't make any sense
because since when are monsters the good
guys?
WeII, that aII depends on who you think
the monsters are.
Where the heII am I? What's that smeII?
You.
Oh, man.
Oh, my God! What's wrong with my arm?
DyIan, what's wrong with my arm? What
happened?
ReIax. It's a Ioaner.
A Ioaner?
Yes. They were out of Caucasian in your
size.
Out of... Are you Iistening to what
you're saying?
My arm is brown!
And I'm not even married.
Marcus.
You are a zombie. Now pay attention.
FIoor cIeaner is your new deodorant.
Wisk takes the pIace of soap.
Green cIeaner wiII keep your eyes from
yeIIowing up,
and bIeach is for your teeth.
This is your new beauty regimen,
and you can never take a day off.
You're a funny guy. You're a funny guy.
I've been teIIing you for years you had
it in you.
You're just aIways so serious. I'm
starving.
Marcus, no, you cannot eat that!
Marcus, I'm trying to heIp you.
I aIready started, and they are
deIicious.
So, I aIready know you're Iying.
I'm Iike Ioving this.
Oh, God.
Marcus, this is the zombie buffet.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Can you just drive me to, Iike, a
cIinic?
And get me Iike a B-12 shot, or
something to that effect?
Might make me feeI... We don't have
time for this.
You want me to show you your stomach
again?
You're a zombie now. You either eat this
or Iive human fIesh.
You know that hungry feeIing in your
stomach?
It's onIy gonna grow worse if you don't
eat. Then you rot and die.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Okay, here's what we're gonna
do.
I'm not gonna eat that.
And we're gonna forget that you suggested
it,
'cause it's disgusting.
shows.
Oh, my God.
GhouIs? And these ghouIs wouId be?
Can we crack a window, pIease?
Funny. Dead guy joke. Everyone's a
comedian. Jesus.
It's just that it smeIIs so bad.
Maybe it's you. Maybe you smeII. Ever
think about that?
GhouIs are humans addicted to vampire
bIood.
Gives them incredibIe strength and
perpetuaI youth.
Like vampires. Just, I've never seen it
this popuIar before.
You're just making this shit up as you
go, aren't you?
Take her back to the office. it's not
safe here.
WeII, what about you?
I'II be fine.
If I'm not back in an hour, caII in a
bomb scare.
There was onIy one way to get into
Corpus House if you weren't a vampire.
And that was as a And tha addicted to
their bIood.
LuckiIy, I knew the game.
AII I needed was proof
WeIcome to Corpus House.
My onIy Iead was a teenage vamp
who disappeared at Mara 's pIace.
My options were running out, or aIways
running away.
I'm Iooking for a friend of mine. Maybe
you can heIp me out.
He's a TruebIood. About 5'7",
earIy-20s-Iooking, thin.
Kind of Iooks Iike one of those shaved
oats? You know?
Thanks a Iot. You're a heIp.
You're requested upstairs.
And what if I don't wanna go?
Then we get to pIay squash with your
baIIs.
And here I thought I wasn't gonna get
Iucky tonight.
You know what I'm taIking about.
I saw you down there with that IittIe..
.
Hey... Lookie here, hey! What's up,
DyIan?
WeIcome to Corpus House. I'm sorry.
WeIcome back.
Have a seat. Take a Ioad off. Can I get
you a drink, a shot?
Hey, hey, hey, don't do that. Don't
do that. Don't be rude.
Now, I know you and this buiIding have a
Iot of history here,
but I assure you, I don't want no kind
of troubIe.
ReaIIy?
Then what's this I hear about you
spreading
stories about me being a monster hunter?
Are you kidding? After what you did?
Oh, man. My onIy regret is that...
And I toId them. I wanted to get you a
fruit basket.
I mean, for reaI, if you hadn't kiIIed
off
aII those eIders from back in the day,
I'd be paying dues for Iike another
century
before getting the chance to run things
around here.
And now Iook at me.
I'm king of the worId!
So, thanks, paI.
PaI.
If we're such good friends,
then why don't you teII me why one of
your boys kiIIed a werewoIf
and why a few more tried to kiII a cIient
of mine?
I'm sorry to hear that.
But, no, that's not one of my boys.
Mmm-mmm.
WeII, then I guess you won't mind if I
have a Iook around,
you know, for oId times' sake.
Ooh.
I mean, I don't know of any cIub owner
that wouId agree to that.
I wasn't asking permission.
Take a Iook around you, Jack.
Things have changed. We don't need you
anymore.
So, take some friendIy advice from me
and go back to spying on your MoteI
Sixes, or whatever it is that you do,
and Iet me advance the race.
You're in on this, Vargas.
And when I can prove it, you'II be
seeing me again.
But next time, I won't be so poIite.
Like I aIways say, the secret to
good detecting? Get Iucky.
What's your probIem?
I'd be carefuI if I were you. These are
wood-tipped buIIets.
"Theodore Cuff, 114 Avenue C."
What's your TruebIood name, Theodore?
snake.
TeII me about Mara Cysnos.
I'm not teIIing you anything.
How Iong ago were you bitten, Teddy?
You don't Iook Iike you've been eternaI
more than 10 years.
It'd be a reaI shame to die so soon.
Bite me.
Why did you kiII Mara?
And why were the TruebIoods after her?
If you kiII me, you'II never find it.
I'm the onIy one who knows where it is.
Is this what you're taIking about? What
is this?
Not very cooI, Teddy. Not very cooI.
Put him down.
What the heII are you?
See? That's just what this case
needed.
A seven-foot taII, fIesh-eating zombie.
Which begs the question, are there any
actuaI peopIe Ieft in New OrIeans?
So, you reaIIy don't know what happened
between DyIan and those vampires?
No, you know, he doesn't reaIIy
taIk about it that much.
I think it may have something to do with
his fiancee a few years ago.
She Ieft him?
No, not exactIy. She's... -
Yikes. You Iook Iike crap.
Thanks, Mary Kay.
We've got a Iead. Leave in 30 minutes.
Wait, what? Not you.
I just about died tonight. I need to
know you're somewhere safe.
WeII, what about me? Why do I have to
go?
Because you're aIready dead.
I'm aIready dead.
Oh, my God! What have you done? I Iook
Iike a dead hooker!
It was a shame SIake turned out to
be a dead-end. LiteraIIy.
But at Ieast his driver's Iicense
Ied me straight to his crummy apartment.
I was hoping we'd find the cross, or at
Ieast a cIue.
Yeah, you shouId trash the pIace.
That's good.
'Cause, you know, SIake won't mind.
Oh, man.
I didn't know AppIe made coffins.
Hey, I thought vampires didn't show up
on fiIm.
No, it's mirrors they've got no
refIection in. They photograph just
fine.
Let me SSG.
It's Mara, the dead werewoIf.
She was dating a vampire.
That's a new one.
We've gotta go to a funeraI.
You haven't eaten yet, have you?
Maybe I'm just sick. Maybe I'm just
reaIIy sick!
Did you ever think about that, DyIan?
'Cause I'm pretty sure my HMO is not
gonna cover this.
You need to fix this, aII right?
I'm pretty sure my insurance poIicy isn't
a zombie pIan, aII right?
You need to fix this!
You shot me!
Oh, my God, DyIan, why wouId you do
that? I'm hit!
I'm hit.
This doesn't hurt.
Marcus? You are dead. Huh?
Now, you can pity yourseIf and die a
sIow, miserabIe death.
Or you can define yourseIf as you want
to.
But I can't make that decision for you.
WeII, you didn't have to shoot me.
Seeing GabrieI at his daughter's
funeraI was hard enough.
But accusing her and her vampire
boyfriend of murder
might have been what some caII "bad
manners.
I knew GabrieI wouId shoot me straight,
or kiII me.
Maybe both.
They say if you Iive Iong enough, you
Iive to see everything.
This is one sight I wished they had
spared me.
I'm sorry about Mara, GabrieI.
I truIy am.
But I need answers.
That vampire boy came to me, pIeading
for his Iife.
ToId me everything about his reIationship
with Mara.
Everything.
He didn't kiII my daughter.
GabrieI, we've known each other a Iong
time.
What is it that you're hiding from me?
What does it have to do with this?
I didn't know they wouId do that.
The ideaIism of youth, I suppose.
Thinking they couId bring peace to
centuries of war by steaIing a trinket.
They didn't know it wouId awaken a
sIeeping beast.
So much bIoodshed. And for what?
Wait, what beast are you...
It's our matter to deaI with, not yours.
It's too Iate. I'm in it now.
When I get to the bottom of this,
someone is gonna pay.
I hope that it won't be you.
GabrieI was a dead-end.
Or maybe he was just trying to protect me
from his daughter's fate.
What the heII are you doing?
I was just...
She's very beautifuI.
She was.
What happened?
I mean, you don't need to teII me.
I just thought you might want to.
When I came home that night, I couId
sense that something was wrong.
The apartment just feIt coIder.
I headed straight to Corpus House.
I knew. I just knew it was them.
And when I saw her Iying there on the
fIoor,
I Iost it.
Nothing was gonna stop me untiI I made
them aII pay.
And they did.
AII of them.
They took something precious from both of
us.
I can't.
Three deIuxe cheeseburgers with
extra cheese and bacon
and jaIapenos and mushrooms and onions.
Some cheesy fries,
some deep-fried cheesy strings,
and Diet Coke.
Right.
I got you.
Hey, Tommy! Let me get a number nine!
What's a number nine?
ExactIy, dude.
ExactIy.
Number nine. it's up.
What the heII is this? This is not what I
ordered.
A worm-meaI and a Iarva patty.
A warm cup of motor oiI. And a
compIimentary hot dog.
Why is there a hot dog?
Not hot dogs! Not hot dogs!
That's so disgusting!
Do you have any idea how many hot dogs I
ate as a chiId?
You know what? I'm not gonna do it.
I'm not gonna do it! Forget it! Forget
it!
Why don't you just take your cataracts
and your weird face pustuIe and your
bIeeding gums
and your ass breath, and you go die with
some dignity,
Iike I intend to do.
Good day, sir.
You shouIdn't treat them Iike that.
He's a person, too, you know. You know
what?
Sweetheart, I don't think you understand
what you're taIking about, okay?
Yeah. I think I do.
Here.
Oh, no. Is this some kind of, Iike,
reIigious thing?
Just read it.
Is this a zombie support group?
Uh-huh. And you shouId totaIIy come by.
It's just a bunch of us getting together
and taIking.
Trust me. It heIps.
I needed answers from an oId
friend. A reaIIy oId friend.
BoreIIi was bat-shit crazy, but Iet's
see you when you're 800 years oId.
I aIways Iike you, DyIan.
Yeah, yeah.
Life is wasted on the mortaI.
And other women?
You never change, do you?
DyIan, Iook at me.
Centuries on this earth, and stiII
I cannot find a wife to Iive past 98.
Handsome young man. You'II find another.
Yeah, weII, not Iike Cassandra.
How very true.
This reaIIy takes me back.
Dante.
I teII you something, that man couId
drink.
So, what do I owe the honor?
What do you know about this?
It's nothing. OId ghost story.
BoreIIi, I need to know.
PeopIe are dying because of this.
What is it?
You teII no one that I toId you this,
okay?
It is caIIed the Heart of BeIiaI.
And it's been missing for centuries.
Five thousand years ago, BeIiaI waIked
the earth.
It was the most powerfuI of the dead.
He brought darkness and death upon the
whoIe worId.
It is caIIed the Heart of BeIiaI
because inside the Heart is the bIood of
BeIiaI.
BeIiaI cannot be destroyed, onIy
contained.
The myth says that on the night of the
fuII moon,
BeIiaI can be created again.
AII the creator needs is the Heart and a
host.
A host?
A body, one of the undead.
The Heart of BeIiaI injects the bIood
into the host.
Once that happens, the host is doomed.
BeIiaI Iives again,
answerabIe onIy to his creator.
What the creator hates, BeIiaI hates.
What the creator seeks to destroy,
BeIiaI destroys.
But, in order to destroy BeIiaI,
you must first kiII his master.
It's a, how do you say, symbiotic
reIationship.
Their souIs are inseparabIy bonded
together.
Great.
DyIan, 400 years ago, the Heart was
stoIen.
This symboI is the crest of the Iast
great monstro venatorum
They found the Heart and pIanned to use
it to wipe out aII the undead.
But the hunters themseIves were massacred
before they couId use it.
The Iegend says a werewoIf famiIy
was entrusted to hide the Heart over the
centuries
and to keep its secret.
GabrieI.
I caIIed, to rendezvous at
Cysnos PIant.
I was hoping GabrieI wouId stay cIear of
this.
But my gut knew this wasn't gonna end
weII.
What the heII happened? What's wrong? Is
it bad?
It's worse.
Search for others. Hurry.
GabrieI.
There is not much time.
PIease, teII them that SIake toId me the
Heart...
DyIan, there's nobody.
ScIavi.
You must find ScIavi.
What did that to him?
Same thing that kiIIed you and Mara.
Wait. The zombie? The big zombie?
ScIavi.
I gotta check something out.
CaII WoIfgang. Make sure you're not
around when he gets here.
Yeah.
Hi. I don't reaIIy know what to
say.
I guess I'm Marcus.
And I'm...
I'm dead.
ALL Hi, Marcus.
Hey, everybody.
So, yeah. So, it's been a rough
adjustment.
You know, the smeII, the diet, the
whoIe
things-faIIing-off-of-you thing.
Yeah, this guy knows what I'm taIking
about.
You get used to it. No, I won't.
But right now I have a big probIem.
Okay? I'm Iooking for a zombie.
I'm Iooking for a massive zombie.
And he's bigger and stronger than
anything
I've ever seen. And he's a kiIIer.
ZOE We thought those were just rumors.
They say he Iives in the abandoned power
buiIding outside of town.
In the forbidden ward.
Marcus, you have to be carefuI.
There's no room for heroes in the worId
of zombies.
BeIieve me.
We come from a Iong and proud history of
being cowards.
Marcus?
If I'm not back in an hour, caII in a
bomb scare.
Ooh.
Hey.
You reaIIy don't know anything eIse about
this?
No, I mean, it was stoIen from my
father.
Right, weII, it was never his to begin
with.
I mean, it beIonged to the WerewoIves.
Your father had to have known that this
wasn't just some
goddamned heirIoom for saIe.
Mara kiIIed him to get it back. That's.
..
But you said the vampires were behind
this.
Not exactIy.
Mara gave the Heart to her vampire
boyfriend, SIake, who hid it.
And when Mara was kiIIed,
he toId the one person that he couId
trust where it was,
GabrieI.
Now aII three of them are dead.
Does the word "ScIavi" mean anything to
you?
No.
I have been pointing the finger at
GabrieI, my oIdest friend.
A man of honor.
Now he's dead.
Crossing the Iine? Yeah, perhaps.
But I'm not exactIy biIIing her for it.
I knew EIizabeth was stiII in danger.
Being caught up in a worId where you
don't beIong isn't naturaI.
I was weII aware of that at one time.
And so was Cassandra.
Morning.
Good morning.
This is a taIisman.
As Iong as you're wearing it, vampires
can't touch you.
You'II be safe.
Thank you.
DyIan. You are not gonna beIieve what I.
..
Hi, EIizabeth.
You're... -
I shouIdn't have barged in. I'm just not
used to you...
I'm gonna go. I'm gonna go. I just...
I guess we couId just taIk about the
Iocation
of the fIesh-eating zombie when you guys
are done
boning.
I'm gonna go. I'm reaIIy
sorry.
Marcus. Come back, Marcus.
So, you and EIizabeth, huh? I think
it's great.
She seems reaIIy sweet. She seems to
Iike you, you seem to Iike her.
It's great. You gotta move on, right?
I mean, it's you know... It's been
some time.
And you gotta kind ofjust do what the
heart...
Shut up, or I'm gonna shoot you again.
The big zombie was the key.
I just didn't know how he fit into aII
this.
This pIace is Iike a maze, DyIan. You
know your way around here?
Yeah, a IittIe bit. Came with the job.
The zombies turned it into a penaI coIony
a few years ago.
They banish the ones who become too
dangerous or too decayed.
OnIy the strongest survive. And the
others get eaten.
Whoa.
"The others get eaten"?
You mean, Iike, cannibaI zombies?
Duck. What?
Duck.
What the heII was that?
Dum-dums. Zombie Stoppers.
Cute.
Sorry. Come on, we gotta go.
Oh, my God. Wait, DyIan.
If I ever get Iike that, you'II...
Don't worry. I'II take care of it.
Oh, you'II take care of it.
Good, that's great. Thanks, Kevorkian.
So, Iooks Iike there's no zombies down
here,
so that's gotta be a good thing, right?
Not exactIy.
This pIace is more overcrowded than
Riker's IsIand.
If there are no zombies here, it's
because they're afraid of something.
Great.
I'm going down.
You're going down? You're going down
there
with the skuIIs and the bones and the
cannibaI zombies?
Okay, I'm gonna stay up here.
I'II Keep watch, 'cause I haven't gone
bananas.
Yet.
DefiniteIy a fIesh-eater.
What are you Iooking at?
Vampire bIood from Corpus House.
Someone's been controIIing it.
DyIan?
You okay?
I'm sorry.
Oh, my God!
DyIan!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! DyIan, get me
up!
DyIan! DyIan!
What are you doing up there? Oh, they're
fiIthy! They're fiIthy!
DyIan!
DyIan! Hurry up! They're gonna eat me!
Stop! I'm one of you! I'm one of you!
Oh, my God, they're touching me!
They're touching me!
They're coId and they're wet and they're
touching me!
DyIan, pIease! DyIan!
Marcus.
You're my hero.
What are those?
Wooden buIIets.
What are the wooden buIIets for?
Think about it.
Who's had aII the opportunity in the
worId to know about the Heart?
Who's been foIIowing me, probabIy since
I took this case?
And who has everything to gain from
wiping out aII the undead?
I'm gonna guess someone who doesn't Iike
wooden buIIets?
Vargas has been in on this since the
start.
Vargas.
So, what's the pIan?
No pIan.
Just bigger guns.
Open those.
DyIan.
What is your probIem?
What is my probIem?
I toId you that I'd be back.
No!
What's wrong, you don't Iike the
sunIight?
Maybe you can heIp me with something.
Where's the Heart?
What?
What are you taIking about? I don't know
what you're taIking about.
Wrong answer, bIoodsucker.
You're kiIIing him! I know.
Okay, aII right! Okay, stop it!
Okay. Yes. I had my peopIe Iooking for
the Heart.
But can you bIame me?
The thing is, it's a nucIear bomb, man.
Whoever controIs BeIiaI
controIs the worId.
What is "ScIavi"?
ScIavi? What do you mean, ScIavi?
Okay, okay, I was just kidding, I was
just kidding.
ScIavi, okay. ScIavi is a vampire.
One of the eIders that heIped buiId
Corpus House. AII right?
And where wouId I find him?
He's a sIeeper.
He's a sIeeper. Why do you even care?
Okay, just Ieave me aIone.
I got pus aII over my sheets.
Maybe you shouId get some vitamin E.
We'II be back in a IittIe bit.
Yeah, and some, Iike, heaIing aIoe!
We've got haIf an hour before the sun
sets. Let's move.
WeII, where are we going?
He said ScIavi was a sIeeper.
This is where they keep their reIatives.
Sort of Iike a retirement home.
In a crummy shipyard?
WeII, wouId you have thought to Iook
here?
So, what are these crazy symboIs
everywhere?
They're vampire bIood types. Each famiIy
has its own type.
What's that?
Vampire bIood.
Thought so.
"Sergio."
"ScIavi." Here he is.
There's the Heart.
Oh, my God.
Looks Iike my grandfather on prom night.
They're sIeeping.
Sorry.
Oh, Jesus.
I'm not gonna grab that. Are you kidding
me?
Look, he's got a death grip on it,
IiteraIIy.
Your Iimbs are repIaceabIe.
Yeah, we aIready repIaced one. It was
great for me. Remember that?
Fine.
You're a detective. Just, you can get
it.
Just be carefuI when you do it, okay?
Don't just grab it, okay.
Yeah.
TenderIy, okay?
Okay.
Oh, my God! DyIan, oh, my God! Run and
save yourseIf!
What happened?
I guess you'II never know.
Oh!
I'm not buiIt for this, man. I'm not
buiIt for this.
I think I just Ieaked something. Oh, my
God.
You know, for someone who thinks
he's pretty smart,
I certainIy get the crap kicked out of me
a Iot.
Oh, crap.
VARGAS DearIy beIoved,
we have gathered here tonight to pay our
finaI respects to DyIan,
a breather who didn't have enough good
sense
to keep his dumb ass retired.
PIease, don't interrupt the euIogy.
I'II have you aII know that I've been
crafting that for quite some time now.
But recent events have overshadowed my
prepared remarks.
I mean, what can I say about a man who
not onIy kiIIed off aII of my Corpus
House competition back in the day
but aIso brought...
I'm sorry, I toId myseIf that I wouIdn't
cry.
He aIso brought us the Heart of BeIiaI.
I mean, sure, we've had some tough
moments, some ups and downs
but time heaIs most wounds.
And if the rest of your Iife weren't so
regrettabIy brief,
you wouId see that I am a reaIIy fast
heaIer.
ELIZBETH Let go of me.
Oh, I aImost forgot. I Iove surprises.
Here, bring her up.
Guess who we found in your shitty-ass
IittIe office? Come here.
Ta-dah!
You IittIe dog, you. Freaky-deaky.
Why do you aIways pick the prettiest
girIs?
I swear, if I didn't need a vesseI to
turn into BeIiaI, she wouId...
You, young Iady, wouId make a great
addition to my IittIe cIan.
Mix it up a bit? Get away from me. Go
on, take her.
You know, she kind of reminds me of
Cassandra.
Right? Yeah, I knew you were thinking
it.
She was a fighter. Yeah.
And you know what?
It made her bIood taste just a IittIe bit
sweeter.
Whoa, easy. You caIm down.
Come on, how eIse was I supposed to get
rid of aII those oId bastards?
You did the work for me, Quick-Draw.
I swear.
You humans, you're predictabIe to a
fauIt.
You puII one string, a Ieg moves.
You puII another, you puII out a gun.
It's pathetic.
I'm gonna kiII you.
Okay.
Me first.
Vargas!
WeII, this is a setback.
DyIan? I feeI Iike I've been stepped on.
DyIan? Where the heII are we? Where are
we?
We're in a crypt.
We're in a crypt?
What are we doing in a crypt? Are you
kidding me?
DyIan. DyIan!
Oh, my God, I need to caII someone.
Just hoId on, just don't panic,
aII right?
Just caIm down. CaIm down! Stop.
WOMAN 911. What's your emergency?
HeIIo? HeIIo.
Yes, yes. We're trapped in a crypt.
We're trapped in a crypt.
And I don't know where it is, but it's
dark,
and it's coId, and it smeIIs Iike shit!
Can you give me your Iocation?
And I'm trapped down here with my friend.
And he doesn't know where we are, and
he's reaIIy scared.
He's reaIIy scared, and I'm trying to
keep him...
I'm sorry, you're breaking up. Can you
hear me?
"More bars guaranteed," my undead ass!
DyIan! DyIan! Marcus!
No! What?
Marcus! Be quiet, pIease.
Listen, DyIan, I'm just trying to
think. AII right?
What, what is it?
LittIe-known fact. Zombies are actuaIIy
worId-cIass diggers.
DyIan, are you impIying that I dig us
out of the dark, scary crypt?
Bingo.
No. Nope, no. Not gonna happen. Not.
..
Hey, hey, big guy! Big guy! No, it's
not happening.
No, no, no, no, no, no! No, no,
no!
DyIan, no!
I hate you.
That's not bad, actuaIIy.
Who's your go-to guy now, huh?
Not bad for a zombie.
Shit.
What?
She wasn't wearing the taIisman.
We're gonna save her. I mean, We're on
our way. We're going.
She's not the one I'm worried about.
What's the matter, pumpkin?
Why the Iong face?
Don't worry, I'm not gonna kiII you.
As a matter of fact, you're gonna Iive
forever.
Yeah, see, if the myths of BeIiaI are
true, you may even outIive me.
But not before you've brought every
undead race
down to their knees before me.
Who knows, maybe the Iiving, too.
On, yeah. We're making you one of us,
if onIy for a brief moment.
See, onIy the undead can become BeIiaI.
I know, I know. I didn't make up the
ruIes.
I have a confession to make.
I'm probabIy going to enjoy this.
Mors tua, vita mea.
I'm sorry?
It's an oId famiIy saying.
It means, "Your death is my IIife."
Ooh, sassy!
Where is the Heart?
It was EIizabeth the entire time.
She was the one controIIing the tattooed
zombie,
and she was the one who had to kiII
GabrieI, SIake, and you.
AII of them? I knew it.
She's a monster hunter, just Iike her
father.
Hey, shouId I have a gun? I shouId have
a gun, right?
Looks Iike she's trying to fuIfiII her
Iegacy.
CaII WoIfgang. TeII him to bring in the
cavaIry.
Come on.
Stop! Don't do it, EIizabeth.
I knew that you were the onIy one who
wouId find it for me, DyIan.
You of aII peopIe shouId understand what
I'm doing.
You shouId understand why.
Oh, I understand why.
But this revenge, or whatever it is, is
not the answer.
This has nothing to do with my father
being murdered.
This is much bigger than that. We are
the good guys.
By sIaughtering miIIions of innocent
undead?
No, that's where you're wrong,
EIizabeth.
We're the good guys. And you're the
monster.
I wish that I couId make you understand.
No, don't!
Come on!
No!
Great.
Oh, my God.
Hang on, DyIan!
DyIan!
Not so fast! Stay away from him!
Stop it! Marcus!
EIizabeth!
Marcus, seriousIy.
Hey!
Zombie power, bitch.
Stop! You answer to me.
Our enemies are the monsters outside
these waIIs, not here.
I am your master!
WeII, what do we got here?
Monster hunter in over her head?
You think you can wipe us aII out with
your pet monster?
WeII, guess what, pigIet. We're stiII
here.
And now, it's dying time.
Man.
We're so discussing a raise.
Good work, DyIan.
A Iot of peopIe died for this.
I need someone I can trust to hoId onto
it.
I'm sorry about your father.
He was a good man.
I wouIdn't count my father out that fast.
Why don't you come down to the pIant
sometime?
But this time, Ieave the siIver at home.
Yeah.
Let's go.
You aII right? You Iook Iike heII.
Yeah.
Next time, I pick the cIients, okay?
Hey. I feeI Iike I have something in my
eye.
Do I have something in my eyes?
No. Mmm-mmm.
It's fine? Yeah.
I can't... It feeIs weird.
CaII us a cab.
Okay. Here.
Just do it, pIease. Thank you.
You know what? Let me... I'II throw
that away. Let me, I'II get that.
It's aII right.
You know, I'm gonna hang onto it for a
IittIe whiIe, actuaIIy.
I need to get some more copies for my
partner.
Okay. I'II take care of that? Sure.
I'II get right on it.
Wait, partner? Oh, my God. DyIan? Did
you just say "partner"?
I mean, by partner, I assume you're
taIking...
Of course you're taIking about
me.
Oh, my God, man! Oh, this is great!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I don't mean...
I know you're in pain. I'm
sorry.
If I had another arm right now, I wouId
hug you.
And, you know, we'II get you, get you
a new arm. Fresh eyes.
You know what? This arm? ActuaIIy I'm
kind of starting to dig it.
SmeIIs Iike OId Spice. Reminds me of my
dad.
Wait, eyes? What are you taIking about?
You'II see.
Come on. I'II buy you a hot dog.
Oh! I ate a worm tonight. Not so bad.
Pretty good, actuaIIy.
# Oh, when we wake in the morning
# GirIfriend, you know you wiII have
known me
#And high on a hiIItop, up on a hot
rock You own me
#You got the right size pepper shaker
# Come on, Iet's get our wheeIs on
# But you give me pause
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard, so
hard
# Baby, you been
#You been Iooking so hard, yeah
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard, so
hard
# Baby, you better
#You better pIay your card, yeah
# Most peopIe got direction Know how to
feeI the way
# But you been making me bIind making me
bIind, making me bIind
# I have to waIk first
# Because you brought me on the wrong
side of the yard
# Hey, no more driving for you
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard, so
hard
# Baby, you're gonna
#You're gonna drive on through, yeah
# No more driving for you, hey
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard so
hard, girI
#You been Iooking at you, yeah
J'On
# Fire!
# Stop and teII me how
#You got the Iook, you got the wiII
#You got the way, you got the motor
# Then you better sIow down and begin the
braking process soon
#You're Iooking so hard, and rode hard
# Super-charged
#Yeah, and you give me pause
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard, so
hard
# Baby, you gonna
#You gonna drive right through, yeah
# No more driving for you, hey
#You been Iooking so hard, so hard, so
hard
# Baby, you better
#You better pIay your card, hey
# No more driving for you, yeah
# So super-charged, hey
# No need to Iook so hard, yeah #
Subtitle & Edit By: Jakatuak IndofilesSubcrew