Let's do this.
Where the fuck you been, kid?
I'm starving here.
Oh, shit!
-ReIax. Take it easy.
-Shut your fuckin' mouth!
Nobody move, nobody get hurt.
Put the money in the bag.
Lay your ass fucking down!
Put the money in the bag!
Where the 100s at? Where the 100s at?
In the fucking bag. Lay it.
What you got over there?
OnIy ones. Fucking fives.
Check the back, man.
You make one move
and I'm gonna bIow your head off.
You, stop fucking moving, aII right?
Lay down.
Where the big biIIs?
What y'aII got in there?
Come on, hurry up, hurry up.
-Yo, where's the rest of the Iottos at?
-Hundreds.
See now, I'm trying reaI hard
with you motherfuckers!
I'm trying to understand you!
Where's the fucking Iottos at?
Where's the money?
You know DeIgato?
You know who you're fucking with?
Yeah.
You know who you fucking with?
You fucking with Majestic's crew.
-Bitch, come here.
-No. Let him go.
-No! No!
-Come here.
Which one's your fucking mama?
Hey, bitch, this your kid right here?
Now, I'm gonna count to three...
and then I'm gonna
bIow his IittIe head off, okay?
-One.
-That's enough. Let's go.
Two.
-Where's the money?
-Let's go! Let's go!
I said, Iet's go.
Oh, baby, come on!
How you gonna do this shit right now?
I toId you, don't shoot nobody.
The first thing you do when we waIk in
this motherfucker is shoot somebody.
'Cause that's what I do!
I kiII motherfuckers, you know that!
You know, tiII I met you...
I didn't even get no respect
from anybody, you know?
None worth, you know, mentioning....
But I fucking Iove you!
I'd do anything for you.
-This motherfucker's crazy.
-I'm your fucking man!
-Where's the fucking money?
-I said, Iet's go, nigga!
Now you go
and caII me a fucking nigga, man.
You gonna caII me a nigga in front of
these motherfucking CoIombians?
-Where's the fucking money?
-I said, I don't know.
I said, Iet's go.
AII right. 'Cause that's aII I am?
A nigga?
Take your fucking money...
and you shoot this nigga
and go on with your bitch-ass Iife!
If you gonna be a man, be a man
and shoot me, motherfucker!
Do you understand?
-No, no, pIease.
-Take it easy.
PIease.
-Then caIm the fuck down right there.
-Take it easy.
Get your ass back in there.
PIease.
-Come on.
-Fuck that bitch, Iet's go!
You coward. I'II kiII you.
Fucking crazy-ass bitch!
I fucking Iove you!
Come on.
Yo, yo, yo.
Lying there...
staring down the barrel of that nine...
l knew l was about to die.
l don't know why l was
expecting my father to rescue me.
l realized l had been looking for him
all my life.
Marcus!
This is my search.
That's my mom.
Those were the days.
Things you do
That keeps me satisfied
Problem was,
everyone was in love with my mom...
so anyone could be my dad.
One thing l was certain of,
l didn't have a white daddy.
And sure as hell, he wasn't a cop...
black or white.
Spent a lot of time
at my grandmother's.
That was a crowded house
with eight mouths to feed...
not including me.
Anybody know
how these things work, huh?
Hey, Marcus.
Hey y'aII.
HeIp your granddaddy.
Show me how that work, huh?
-What you want, footbaII?
-Yeah, footbaII.
There you go.
Boy's a genius, huh?
Can you watch him for an hour?
Katrina, you know I'II watch him.
Thank you.
-I don't want that money.
-Come on, Mom.
Katrina, I said I don't need that money.
He's famiIy.
Why you keep
Ieaving him Iike this, Katrina?
Bye.
-Bye.
-Take care.
That's my Uncle Deuce.
-You Iook after him, okay?
-Pay you back.
He was the oldest and the meanest.
What's going on, homie?
You okay?
It's Saturday.
Mama's gotta work
to buy you those sneakers.
SmiIe.
Oh, baby, I Iove you.
-I Iove you, too.
-I gotta go, okay?
Okay.
-Hey, Marcus, you coming out?
-Can I go out?
-Go on.
-Yo, Marcus!
Come on, Marcus. Come on.
Hey, how you doing?
Come on, Iet's go, Marcus.
Bye, Mom!
-Bye.
That boy got the bug bad.
Hey, right here. I'm open!
l knew my mom sold drugs...
but it didn't mean nothing to me
but good sneakers and school clothes.
Yes!
She always made sure
l had the best of evertyhing.
You know what's really happening
lt's happening
'Cause this is my crew
and it's happening
And this is how we do
when it's happening
Cause it's happening
Couldn't get next you
Listen
When you're ready l'll be ready
So you let me know
Any way you want to go, girl
l'm down to go
Young Caesar busting through
with the incredible flow
You ain't never heard an MC
like this before
Turn the boombox up
Let the sounds play
Run DMC, Cool J, NWA
lf l was your best friend
l'd want you around all the time
Best friend
Girl, l wanna make you mine
Girl, you know l think you're fine
Best friend. Together, me and you
Hey, Mom.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
It is?
-So who's your best friend?
-Nobody.
Anybody.
A girI.
Promise me...
that you are gonna treat the girIs right.
-What?
-Promise me...
that you're gonna treat the girIs right.
Okay.
Are you aII right, Mom?
But l know l can't live without my radio
Fucking SIim. What's he doing here?
That's the purest coke right there.
Don't get out of the car.
What's going on? What you doing, huh?
-I'm handIing my business--
-You handIing your business?
Get the fuck out of here!
What the fuck are you doing?
I got shit on my boot, bitch.
Get the fuck out of here!
-Get your ass--
-What the fuck?
-Stay there.
-Get the fuck off!
I'II kiII your ass! You hear me?
-I'II shoot your ass, bitch! You hear me?
-KiII my ass?
I'II kiII you.
I'II chew your ass up and kiII you, bitch!
Majestic toId me
I couId work this corner.
-You hear me, bitch?
-Stay off my fucking bIock!
-I said, fuck you!
-Hang on. Hang on.
-I said, fuck you! Fuck you.
-Get the fuck out of here.
Fuck out.
Rick James-Iooking motherfucker!
-Hey, what's wrong with you?
-Fuck you, bitch.
Katrina, caIm down. Look--
-Get the fuck off of me!
-Katrina.
-Shut the fuck up, Majestic!
-Hey, wait.
Go back to prison.
Why did you get out of the car?
I was going to protect you.
Baby boy...
don't grow up too quick.
Come on, Iet's go.
I don't know.
That motherfucking nigga SIim,
trying to pIay me...
and then Majestic's bitch ass
tried to come in and....
I mean, where the fuck has he been?
The thing is,
parents think you see nothing.
You see evertyhing.
l think you're fine
Mom, that's private.
First we get to talking
Then we get to touching
When we get past the phone games
We'll be humping
l kiss like the French do
Put my tongue in your ear
Do it like the dogs do it, girl
and pull on your hair
For me different scenery
just means a different position
ln the bushes, hide and seek
l could get next to you, listen
When you're ready l'll be ready
So you let me know
Any way you wanna go, girl
l'm down to go
Young Caesar busting through
-Where did you get this?
-Marcus.
I hate you.
-See you Iater.
-Okay.
I'II be back tonight.
Charlene's stepdad sent her away
to live with her grandparents.
My mom was supposed to
come pick me up that night.
But she never arrived.
Neighbors said they heard
voices raised in a jealous rage.
Soon after that,
the dogs were heard barking.
And after that...
flames were seen
coming from the window.
CIass, move right in. Move right in.
Hey, Mr. Matthews,
I brought my homework.
"Yea, though l walk through the valley
of the shadow of death...
''I wiII fear no eviI, for thou art with me...
''thy rod and thy staff they comfort me.
''Thou preparest a tabIe before me
in the presence of mine....''
l was wondering whether
my father would show up to the funeral.
''...my head with oiI,
my cup runneth over.''
Maybe even her killer.
''...mercy shaII foIIow me
aII the days of my Iife...
''and I wiII dweII....''
For all l knew,
they were the same person.
...concIudes the service
for this afternoon. Thank you.
You okay, B.G.?
She was a speciaI Iady.
You gonna have to Iet her go.
I'II never Iet her go.
You're a good son.
Come on.
-He Iooked Iike Rick James.
-Who?
SIim.
-What size are you?
-Six.
-Who did these beIong to?
-Your UncIe Deuce.
Dear Lord, thank you for this food,
and bIess it to our bodies.
-Amen.
-Thank you, Ma.
SmeIIs good.
Hey! Come on, man! Yo!
You gots to be quick.
Gimme some of that food.
More bread, Ma.
Move over, man.
Take your foot out my face.
I don't have any room.
-CaIm your ass down.
-Shut up.
-Come on, move over, man.
-CaIm your ass down!
-I said, come on, man!
-Move over!
-Go to sIeep. SIeep!
Oh, fuck! What the heII!
Shit! I'm gonna skin your ass!
-What was that?
-What happened?
Hey! What the heII is going on here?
Cut it out!
-Look, get up.
-He poured a bucket of water on me!
Kid's crazy, just Iike his damn mother!
-Shut up, or I do it again!
-Just Iike your damn mother!
Hey! Hey! Get upstairs, Deuce!
Come on!
TeII me now,
who's your daddy, Marcus?
Get upstairs! Go on, you, upstairs.
Don't know who your daddy is, huh?
You gonna be aII right here
for a few years?
Yeah.
Don't worry about it, Marcus.
You'II get those shoes one day.
-Don't worry about it. They're jerks.
-I'II see you Iater, Antwan.
lt was time to join the family business.
-What's up, man?
-Two dimes.
AII right.
And he said, no way!
-Here you go.
-Thank you, man.
-Where you from?
-Jersey, baby!
I can teII, man. I can teII.
Hey.
-What you want?
-What you got?
-I got dime bags.
-Twenty.
AII right. Here you go. Yo, man!
What the fuck you doing? It's my corner!
AII right, man. AII right.
What you want? You want some of this?
You fucking through, nigga!
-You fuck off....
-Fuck off, man.
Hey, hey, hey.
-Come here, Jake.
-He's steaIing our corner!
-CooI it. Hey, come here.
-Get off!
-Matt, get out of here.
-Yeah, I'm gonna kick your ass!
Come here.
-What the fuck are you doing out here?
-Come on, we out.
Look at me.
You know what time it is, huh?
Where'd you get this shit?
I can't teII you that.
Oh, you can't teII me that?
Get in the car.
You know what you are, kid?
-You're an entrepreneur.
-Just Iike his mama.
But you can't just go waIking up
on other niggas' territories Iike that.
Respect is the most important thing
in Iife.
Your respect can go a Iong way.
What you doing out there, anyway?
You stiII going to schooI?
You know what you gonna get out there,
don't you?
It's fuII of Iong, IoneIy nights. Hard days.
-Is that what you want?
-I'm in it for the money.
-How much you get?
-Enough.
Enough?
-For what?
-Sneakers.
You need anything eIse?
A gun.
What you need a gun for?
I don't know.
l didn't know what l wanted a gun for,
but l got one anyway.
-What's up, IittIe man?
-What's up, man?
-Looking for some heat?
-Yeah, what you got?
This is what I got for you.
You Iike that .357, huh?
That's gonna run you $250.
AII right. It's aII there.
Yo, hoId up, hoId up.
Let me teII you something, IittIe nigga.
You get busted,
you didn't get this from me.
Listen to my 9 millimeter go bang
Gangsta, gangsta
That's what you looking at
They call me Uncle Deuce
After Tupac, everybody wanted to be
a gangsta rapper.
And if Tupac wasn't dead,
Deuce's rapping would've killed him.
l might take your bones
and suck your marrow
Suck your....
Man, that's fucking wack, yo.
Give me the damn fucking weed.
Fucking ''marrow'' shit.
CannibaI buIIshit.
Yeah.
I can't take this.
I'm gonna do the Iaundry.
Ready to pop off my deuce deuce
'Cause l'm a gangsta gangsta
l'm the realest shit
l'm from the Bronx, yo
Don't make me have to come up
and run up on you, yeah
lt's Deuce Deuce running this live
Yo, yo!
Passing through.
Okay, where's the detergent?
Goddamn detergent.
Ma, where's the detergent?
-Why are you going through my stuff?
-What?
Why you going through my stuff?
What are you doing with a Ioaded gun
in my house? Come back here!
l wasn't thinking straight when l went
back to school that afternoon.
You'II pay a fine of $500.
I hope you're proud of yourseIf.
-It's your fauIt I got caught.
-My fauIt?
If I didn't have to hide who I was,
I wouIdn't have got caught.
-Then who are you?
-I'm in fucking heII!
Living in a basement
I can't even stand up straight in.
You'II wind up just Iike your mama.
At Ieast mama's not here on her knees,
washing fIoors Iike you.
-Roy, stop!
-Don't you speak to me Iike that!
I've got her bIood in my veins. My mama
ain't Iive Iike no second-cIass nigga.
I'm a gangsta, Grandpa,
and I'm proud of it.
-You son of a--
-Let him go, Roy.
If you reaIIy want it, you can have it.
Are you reIated to Mr. Majestic?
No.
l had my own space...
and l could concentrate
on my dream of being a rapper.
Young Caesar, first tape, first song.
Gotta Get Outta Hell.
Fire at my feet, fiends all around
Don't cross the yellow tape
Homicide's in town
Homicide's in town.
Fire at my feet, fiends all around
Don't cross the yellow tape
Homicide's in town
Homicide's.... Homicide's in town.
Why the fuck I ain't write it down?
Damn, I'm fucking hungry.
After three hours,
l gave up my career as a rapper...
and went back to selling coke.
The thing about being a coke dealer
on the corner...
it was lousy pay.
And if you added up all the hours
and time spent waiting around...
it was like minimum wage.
And if you added in the time
you were likely to spend in prison...
it was less than minimum wage.
But then, one day...
-Baking soda.
-...evertyhing changed.
Good.
Watch that shit.
-Add that shit to that.
-What you gonna do with that, yo?
Done fucked up now.
See how she moves?
Dance for daddy. That's right, baby.
Put in some ice.
Yeah.
-Stir that shit up a IittIe.
-What the fuck is that?
It's a refreshing drink, that's what it is.
Make that shit chiII.
There you go. That's right.
-Damn, nigga.
-What is it caIIed?
-See that?
-What's that supposed to be?
-I don't know, man.
-Go figure it out, man.
-Pure crystaI.
-Yeah.
Now the nigga got his own
drug-manufacturing company...
just Iike Merck.
See this shit?
This gonna take us out of the ghetto.
But there are ruIes to the house.
RuIe number one:
Never Ieave this product in the house.
RuIe number two: Get your own crew.
Number three: Gotta have discipIine in
your crew, trust. Gotta be tough on 'em.
RuIe number four:
Don't praise a nigga too much...
otherwise he gonna think you soft.
RuIe number five: Don't show no Iove.
Love wiII get you kiIIed.
See this?
It's Iike a bitch.
You fuck a bitch,
don't Iet a bitch fuck you.
You a man?
You don't need nothing
or no one to get you through.
This bitch....
This bitch wiII take your souI.
Y'aII niggas ain't got no famiIy,
aII you got is respect.
Don't ever forget that.
RuIe number six: Don't ever
take the panties off of this bitch.
AII right, Iet's get out of here.
Everybody had their own territory.
Ours was right next to the Colombians.
What the fucking heII are you doing
on my fucking bIock?
on my fucking bIock!
What are you doing
on my fucking bIock?
What the fuck are you doing
on my bIock?
on my fucking bIock, I asked you!
Hey, hey, hey.
Yeah, that tough guy shit's
out the window now, right?
Get the fuck out of here.
I kiII you, motherfucker.
Hey, I Iike what you did back there,
but if you need me to....
-What?
-Know what I mean?
You trying to threaten me?
No. I'm just saying if you want me
to do something for you, I'II do it.
He know me.
You know this nigga?
Seen him around?
Justice.
What's up, boy?
Good to see you, Antwan.
The last of my crew was a fat nigga
named Keryl, who was fast on his feet.
So that was the crew.
Antwan, Justice, Keryl and myself.
Four niggas dedicated to one thing
and one thing only...
getting paid and getting laid.
-It's pumping out there? Huh?
-Voila.
-What the fuck y'aII doing?
-What it Iook Iike, man?
-What the fuck is this?
-What the fuck?
You smoking crack up in here?
What the fuck's wrong with you?
-Get the fuck out.
-It's aII good, man.
-Come on, Iet's go.
-What the fuck's your probIem, man?
What the fuck, man?
We got it going on, man.
-What the heII's your probIem?
-What the fuck wrong with you, nigga?
ReIax. Back it up.
CaIm down, nigga.
You know where you at?
You soId me this shit.
What the fuck's your probIem, man?
ReIax, man.
We seII it. We don't smoke it.
Get the fuck out. Come on.
Sit your IittIe ass back down
and enjoy your brew.
Nigger, this Marcus' pIace.
Don't ever disrespect this shit.
-What the fuck wrong with you?
-AII right, nigga. AII right, man.
Peace.
Is this the Dangerous CD?
This guy is iII.
You don't wanna battle me in the street
with my heat
Them things'll bust
with Dangerous
I need some space...
'cause y'aII are riding Dangerous' nuts
a IittIe too hard over here.
This is street life, all right
The only life l know
Bag it up, hit the block
Watch the product go
l got supreme clientele
So it's sale after sale
Fire at my feet, fiends all around
Don't cross the yellow tape
-Let's go.
-Why?
Y'aII gotta go, too. Come on.
We gotta go to work.
l was always the first up.
No matter how hard we partied...
l made sure my crew worked
twice as hard.
The busiest days for us
were the 1st and the 1 5th...
when the welfare checks came in.
Hey, hey, man.
You're damaging my merchandise.
-You Iike cars?
-Yeah.
You know, we couId use some heIp
around here, maybe washing cars...
since you Iike
putting fingerprints on things.
-No, I ain't washing no cars, man.
-So what you wanna do?
-I wanna buy it.
-Yeah? You got a Iicense?
-No.
-I teII you what.
You get you a Iicense, you get you
some money, come taIk to me.
Oh, I'II get the money.
Crack meant money,
money meant power...
and power meant war.
Yo, come here, man. Come here.
We shot the Colombians.
They shot us.
Crackheads robbed the Korean store
so many times...
poor guy went crazy.
Things got so hot after the death
of those innocent kids...
that even Levar Cahill
had to show up to the funeral.
But his real intentions were
to cool things down...
with the Colombians.
Listen, everything's gonna be aII right.
Look at this nigga OdeII.
How much money you think
his motherfucking teeth worth?
$100,000? $200,000?
I got someone I want you to meet, man.
Yo, Marcus.
There's the nigger motherfucker, man.
-You know who this is?
-How you doing, Mr. CahiII?
-Who's this IittIe nigga?
-This here our empIoyee of the month.
-Yeah, he a worker bee.
-He Iooks famiIiar.
-Remember Katrina?
-Katrina?
Trina.
This here her baby boy.
Ain't this a bitch?
So you out there grinding,
making some money for me, huh?
Yeah.
Mr. CahiII...
you Iike a god to me.
Like a god.
Son...
I am God.
God, AIIah, Buddha...
aII roIIed up into one big nigga.
Five-O.
Motherfuckers got more shit on me,
put me away for 20 or 30 years.
That's why I got to pay them
so much money.
Levar put his arms around Delgato...
and just like that, the war ended.
Yes, that is it.
That's what I want, right there.
Okay, Iadies, this time what I want,
you're with Dangerous....
And how did you get invoIved
with Dangerous?
Kid Iost his chain, man.
Out here in the streets,
Iose your chain, Iose your baIIs.
I found it, gave it back to him.
That's what I do.
I protect him, you know?
Try to Iook out for him.
-What about those guys?
-Right there is your American dream.
Hey, yo, Marcus!
Go take a picture.
-Dangerous.
-Yeah, what's up?
-Mind if we take a picture with you?
-AII right, man.
Ladies.
AII right, you guys
are the baddest gangstas in the city.
Do your thing.
Let's see what you got.
That's it, be hardcore.
-You want to--
-Hey, hey.
-I gotta taIk to you.
-Can you Iook this way?
AII right. That's enough. We got it.
We got it.
DeaI with the fucking crackhead.
What's up, buddy?
How you doing, man? Come on.
-Come on with me. That's cooI.
-I can't right now.
Get your fucking bitch-ass over there.
What the fuck you doing?
Hey, man, I got money, see?
You know I don't take no coins, man!
l would take coins.
Hell, l'd take pennies
if that's all a fiend had.
Back again?
Hey, you need anything eIse?
Go get some deaIer pIates.
That's what I'm taIking about, man.
Can't wait tiII niggas see me in this.
What?
What you say?
What the fuck did you say?
I'II kiII you, nigga.
Hey, why don't you get
the fuck out my car?
l had it all...
but still something was missing.
I'II teII you one time,
don't sIeep on Dangerous, though.
That's aII I'm saying...
is he's hot, so you shouId stick with him,
aII right? That's aII I'm saying.
-Yo, yo. What's up?
-It's cooI. It's cooI.
-HoId on.
-I just wanna give you my tape.
It's my demo, man. It's good, man.
Check it out.
-That your ride?
-Yeah.
-HoId on a second. S500?
-Check it out, man. You gonna Iike it.
-AII right.
-Where he get that fucking ride?
-Where do you think?
Hey, nigger, what's the sense of getting
money if there ain't nobody to see it?
-What's up, baby?
-Hey, what up?
-What?
-Are you for reaI?
Think about the pussy
we aII gonna get with this.
I shouId have
put some panties in the window...
so they know this is not my mama's car.
Whatever.
I think I stiII have it.
Look at that right there.
She got her shit aII--
Hey, yo!
Hey!
Stuck-up bitch.
-I guess she too cooI to taIk.
-I'II be right back.
CharIene!
Yo, nigga,
we're in the middIe of the road.
I'm gonna drive.
CharIene!
-Marcus?
-Yeah.
-Marcus Greer?
-Yeah, what you doing around here?
-How you doing?
-Hi.
What you doing around here?
I just came to see my mother.
We were teaching a dance cIass
over at CharIene's oId schooI.
Wanna introduce me to your friend?
Oh, yeah. This is Destin.
Destin, Marcus.
-What's up, man?
-How you doing?
So, you hungry?
You were so shy.
You didn't wanna pIay me
that song you wrote...
in front of me, remember?
It's a miracIe.
-Praise the Iord.
-HaIIeIujah!
-You aII right?
-You get a nurse?
-What?
-He's not working.
What you did to the boy, huh?
You okay?
-Yeah, I'm aII right.
-I mean, you okay?
I'm aII right.
UsuaIIy, he driving us Iike sIaves.
-Y'aII work together?
-No, we work for him.
-You the boss, Marcus?
-Yeah.
This is Justice, that's KeryI,
and you know Antwan.
-Yeah, man. Wha'gwan, baby?
-Wha'gwan.
-So what do you do?
-I'm a gangsta.
No, reaIIy. What do you do?
I'm a rapper.
-SeriousIy, Marcus, what do you do?
-I'm a gangsta rapper.
Marcus is the gangsta-est rapper
there is.
-So what do you caII yourseIf?
-Young Caesar.
-StiII?
-Yeah.
-ReaIIy?
-Justice.
-Maxine.
-Justice used to work here.
-You stiII do.
-Sorry about your daddy, CharIene.
-Thank you.
What she taIking about, your stepdad?
No, my reaI father.
You shouId Iet me take you out.
-I shouId?
-Yeah, you shouId.
Forget Levar, he's too sIow.
-Five minutes--
-Hey, Majestic. It's Marcus.
I'II give you a caII. Yeah.
Fuck Levar, man.
-What's up, man?
-Come on. You seen me at the window.
What take you so Iong
to open the door?
-I was opening the door.
-What you got for me, man?
-There's $20,000 in here.
-$20,000.
-Need to count this?
-No, you don't need to count it.
-Yeah, how much you need?
-I need a fuII bird.
-FuII bird.
-Yeah.
FuII bird.
You deserve a drink.
This is the hardest-working nigga
in drug business.
-Working that crew hard, huh?
-Oh, yeah.
Come over here, Junebug.
-LittIe Henny?
-It's 10:00 in the morning, man.
What, you pIanning on fIying a pIane
or something?
No, but he pIanning on driving
that Mercedes he just bought.
What you taIking about?
I got me a new.... New joint.
-Fuck, where is it? Out there?
-Yeah, out front.
What the fuck is this shit?
Look at him aII bashfuI and shit.
Let's see, Iet's see.
Shit, what's my nigga got?
You got that? Come here.
Take them shades off, man.
-Look at that shit.
-Shit.
That nigga making me Iook good.
We're going aII the way
to the top, right?
-Oh, yes.
-Shit.
-Nigger, you got your Iicense?
-No, deaIership pIates.
That's 'cause you the deaIer, right?
See that, Junebug?
You work your ass hard,
that's what your ass get.
Yeah. You can be Iike me.
I'm big in the hood with this right now,
man, I'm teIIing you.
I don't even know my name no more.
They caIIing me ''Handsome.''
Make a right up here, man.
Where we going?
Levar's.
-That shit ain't right, man.
-What?
Cops sitting on Levar's house
Iike he's some kind of punk.
What can you do about it?
-What do you think?
-Sit tight. Let it bIow over.
Damn right.
Let it bIow over.
Taught your mama how to drive.
Parking Iot out by the beach.
Used to come out there in the winter.
It was aII icy and shit.
She'd be sIiding that thing
aII over the pIace.
You heard anything more about SIim?
No, nigga went
down south somewheres.
TeII me again what happened
that night--
I toId you
a miIIion fucking times aIready.
Why don't you stop thinking about it?
The minute you see him,
you gonna Iet me know, right?
Listen, either stop taIking about it,
or do something.
How am I gonna do something
if I don't know where he at?
Then Iet it bIow over.
-Get up.
-What?
Get up, bitch. Move.
-What's up, man?
-What's up?
You aII right?
-Who your girI, man?
-Who, CharIene?
CharIene?
Why don't you bring her backstage,
meet Dangerous, man?
We're straight right here.
We gonna hang out for a IittIe bit.
-AII right, man. Do your thing, boy.
-AII right.
Hey, yo, man.
It's that fucking spic, RaouI.
Where's KeryI and Antwan?
Come on, girI, Iet's go!
-I'm aII right. I'm aII right.
-Just don't try to move him.
-Lay back.
-I'II get a ambuIance.
Lay back.
Forget about that.
Just bring the car, man.
Doctor said he's gonna make it.
Amen.
Put your arm around me?
Want me to take you home?
I don't wanna go home.
Can you turn a Iight on?
It's grimy in here right now.
It's cIeaner in my room.
I can see why
you wouIdn't turn the Iight on.
Watch your step.
-You Iike Rick James?
-No.
-Is this okay for you?
-Yes, thank you.
Your mother was so beautifuI.
-That's me and you.
-Yeah.
I can't beIieve you framed this.
Young Caesar.
Don't go.
-You remember the words to that song?
-What song?
lf l was your best friend
l'd want you around all the time
Could l be your best friend?
lf you promise you'll be mine
lf l was your best friend
l'd want you around all the time
Best friend
Girl, l'm gonna make you mine
I remember.
I've been thinking about that song
for 10 years.
Sing some more.
First we get to talking
Then we get to touching
When we get past the phone games
We'll be
l kiss like the French do
Put my tongue in your ear
Do it like the dogs do it, girl
and pull on your hair
Did you know what that meant,
back then?
No.
My stepdad did.
-Are you my best friend?
-More than that.
Hey, yo.
-What up?
-Hey.
-What's up?
-SpinaI cord.
He ain't gonna waIk no more.
Who toId you that? Doctor toId you that?
Yeah.
Man.
-Let's go take care of this shit now.
-Oh, we gonna take care.
He can't waIk. Can't waIk no more.
Look at him, man.
He's crying aII night and shit.
-I don't wanna hear that shit.
-We gotta send a message.
-Damn, man.
-It's your crew. Your own crew.
AII right. AII right. CharIene.
-What's up?
-I gotta go handIe something.
-What?
-I gotta go handIe some business.
That's not gonna
make him waIk again, Marcus.
Come on, give me my hat.
Hey.
-Is that cIean?
-Yeah.
-Where'd you get it from?
-Majestic.
-Majestic cooI with this?
-Yeah.
PuII over to the Ieft.
I don't got a good feeIing about this shit.
-There's four of them.
-Yeah. It's fucked up. Let's go home.
-Go.
-Give me the gun.
-Huh?
-Give me the gun!
What the fuck...
Who's this nigga?
What the fuck you want?
Don't do it, pIease!
PIease don't fucking do it!
Don't fucking do it!
Don't fucking.... Papa!
Oh, fuck!
-You okay?
-Drive.
...we were complicitous ,
as a country, in narcotics traffic...
at the same time
as we're spending countless dollars...
in this country to try to get rid
of this problem.
lt's mind-boggling.
What's up?
ln 1987, Oliver North was investigated...
for his role in a covert
money-for-arms operation.
You're aII right.
Breaking out.
It's time for bed, huh?
-What happened?
-Nothing.
Don't Iie to me.
You got bIood on your shoes.
Maybe this Iife isn't for me.
-Did you kiII him?
-No. I shouId've.
Men hide their emotions.
You bury yours, Marcus.
You're you and I'm me, CharIene.
The cops didn't find that gun
they came looking for.
They found something else instead.
-What's this?
-That's your shit.
My shit?
Why wouId I keep my shit here?
You're fucked, man.
Man, that shit ain't ours!
What the fuck, man!
Never seen him before.
Yeah, never seen him before.
AII right, y'aII, settIe down.
Listen up and pay attention.
My respect has been taken from me.
Who authorized the CoIombian hit?
AII right.
Without getting too bibIicaI and shit,
vioIence onIy begets more vioIence.
It does not beget more money...
which is the reason I thought we were
aII here in the first fucking pIace.
Now, I'm going away
for a short period of time...
to pay a poIiticaI debt
to our iIIustrious poIice department.
And whiIe I'm away,
I don't want no fucking drama...
on our streets...
about anything...
by anyone that's going to draw heat...
or attention to us in any way...
unIess you have my fucking permission.
Is there any nigga here
in PeIham HaII...
that is uncIear about
what the fuck I just said?
Good.
So now, for aII you
hearing-impaired motherfuckers...
whiIe Levar's down...
I'm number one.
So now, if you have any probIems...
come see me.
Marcus. Come here.
WeII, then...
my brothers.
Now, next time you have a probIem,
you come see me.
See, now you gonna have
to take the faII for this buIIshit.
-Cops, man, they pIanted that shit.
-No, they didn't.
We know who's doing what.
See, now be carefuI
who you Iet in your house.
'Cause someone cIose to you
is using.
Soap up.
Being reaI cheap on the soap.
And y'aII can turn the water up
a IittIe bit in here.
Yo, man! Guard!
Fight! We got a fight over here!
You saved my Iife.
Let's go.
Hmm-hmm.
This way. Keep going.
Why?
I don't know.
Looked Iike you needed saving.
What's your name?
Marcus.
Bama. Nice to meet you.
-Bama. You from AIabama?
-No, North CaroIina.
North CaroIina?
So why they caII you Bama?
I didn't want foIks caIIing me Lina.
Somebody wanted me to kill myself.
Thought about it.
Thought about my mother.
l was in a tomb, just like her...
and l had to find a way out.
l went forward...
made my mark.
lt was either express myself or die.
l know l did a lot of bad things
in my life...
but from that moment on...
l decided to tell the truth.
And l wasn't gonna back down.
Levar was not expecting
things to change.
DeaI with it, okay?
But after the shooting, he wasn't
gonna pay a little political debt.
He was gonna pay with his life.
Majestic set him up...
and blamed it all on Odell.
This nigga been working
for the CoIombians.
Betrayed Levar. Cost us money.
Now, how he gonna pay?
Let's pay him in diamonds and goId.
You right, motherfucker.
Them shiny-ass motherfucking teeth.
I can't trust you?
Are you working with the CoIombians?
Nigga, you the one set up Levar, nigga!
That was you who set up Levar, nigga!
Come on, man!
That was you that set up Levar!
Oh, shit.
Everybody reIax. We're aII friends here.
Levar fucked your bitch!
You got a Iot of mouth on you, OdeII.
Levar fucked your bitch, nigga!
-Yeah, babe?
-Levar fucked Katrina.
Majestic began his rise to the top...
and Dangerous crowned it all
with a song.
People got shot.
People disappeared.
And Majestic felt like
nobody could touch him.
Yeah, turn my music up.
Turn it up in my headphones
a little bit, son.
Yeah, we're gonna have to see.
What up? Yo, Majestic! You!
What up, baby?
Yeah. Yeah. lt's like this. Come on.
Niggas that pull their heat
And get shook, die on the streets
You can't look weak
Niggas'll lay you down six feet
And when you lay down
You keep an eye open when you sleep
We took the food out your belly, nigga
How you gonna eat?
You want me
You can find me on the block
See you in the morning.
And l will squeeze off rounds and watch
them slugs split your hairpiece
We run these streets
Where murderers and gangstas meet
Black skull, nigga
We pull the ice and gold
Straight out your teeth up in the NYC
Now you Iisten, gangster. Listen.
-Where's Majestic?
-No, man, no, man!
TeII Majestic we caIIed.
You know, I ain't never trusted foIks.
See, where I grew up...
there was a whoIe bunch...
of jeaIous cats.
They used to be mad
'cause I was Iight-skinned, you know?
They used to grab me after schooI
when I was in first grade and be Iike:
''Smack him and watch him turn red.''
So I got me a screwdriver and started
carrying that with me to schooI.
They ain't smack me no more.
-What's wrong with you, man?
-I just wanna kiII somebody.
-Who?
-Anybody.
There's a whoIe Iot of anybodies
in the worId, man.
You know,
I had this image in my head...
of Rick James kiIIing my mama.
I mean that.
I know Rick James ain't kiII my mama.
He just favored this dude named SIim,
you know.
WeII, what you got in your head now?
AII kinds of images.
lt usually goes down
over money and whores
But lil' homie, in my hood
When it rains it pours
This is real
Lil' homie, when it rains it pours
Hollow-tips and Talons
When it rains it pours
You caught in lead showers
Just because
Niggas ain't playin'
When it rains it pours
The Colombians hit back at Majestic
by cutting off his supply of drugs.
Eventually, just like Levar...
Majestic had to go
shake hands with Delgato.
But neither were happy about it.
One shot, one kill, what's the deal?
Yo, what's the deal?
Listen, lil' homie
When it rains it pours
Hollow-tips and Talons
You caught in lead showers
Just because
Niggas ain't playin'
When it rains it pours
Niggas get set up
'Cause when it rains it pours
End up wet up
What's up?
-You need a manager.
-A manager?
ln my hood, when it rains it pours
Ain't nothin' changed
Niggas doin' the same old shit
Them new hollow-tips
And them same old clips
These foIks feeIing you, man.
-Come on, Iet me get in my house.
-Let me be your manager.
Man, Iet me in my house.
Stop pIaying and shit.
I'm teIIing you, this shit hot, man.
You're Iooking good.
Thank you. I did it for you.
-Did you miss me?
-Yeah, I missed you.
Yeah?
How about you? How you doing?
I'm cooI. Been staying to myseIf.
You know.
I ain't been doing much taIking.
You aIways have so much to say
in your music.
How come you're quiet now?
It's a different part of the brain.
The part you never Iet anyone see?
I Iet you see.
-Do you Iove me?
-You know I Iove you.
-Are you stiII in Iove with me, though?
-Yes.
I'm pregnant.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
You gonna keep it?
Do you want me to?
Yeah.
But, you know, I was just thinking,
what about your career?
I just know you Iove dancing.
You won't be abIe to dance.
I couId aIways dance for you.
-Yo, Marcus! I'm out, man.
-You out?
Yeah. If you ever in CIeveIand,
you Iook me up, aII right?
Take care, man.
Turns out l didn't have to go
to Cleveland to meet with Bama.
Yo!
My nigga out?
-What's up, man?
-What's up?
I want you to be my number two, man.
I'm out the game, man.
-What out?
-I'm out.
-You out of your mind, you know that?
-I'm gonna rap.
Justice, teII your boy, man. He taIking
about he wants to be a rapper.
A rapper?
Yeah, I was writing music
whiIe I was in there.
Bama.
So, they Iet the big oId
bIack buzzard out, huh?
Yeah.
They don't know what they did.
Shake up the worId.
-Who this nigga?
-He's my manager.
First of aII, I ain't nobody's nigga.
I'm his manager, okay?
-Marcus.
-ChiII, reIax, yo.
-Get in the car, man.
-Shut the fuck up, nigga.
-Who the fuck you taIking to?
-Just reIax, man.
-You don't know me.
-ReIax.
-You aII right, man?
-Yeah, it's cooI.
I see you got that
IittIe NapoIeon thing going on.
I'm gonna be in the car
if you need me for anything.
-You aII right?
-Yeah.
I just wanna, you know, just do my thing.
You know, when you get out that chair...
Junebug gonna sit in it.
You know that, don't you?
I need to watch my back?
You know, you're Iike famiIy to me, yo.
What's up?
He's roIIing with Levar.
-Why don't you Iet me deaI with that?
-Shut the fuck up.
Whatever we do,
we gotta be sensibIe about it.
Yo, man, now that we out of the game,
how we gonna eat?
We gonna eat. Don't worry about that.
-Management gonna handIe aII of that.
-Management?
Yeah.
-What you doing back there?
-What?
What you back there fidgeting for?
It's your car, B, I'II be stiII.
You're moving again.
What?
There you go. You stiII at it, man.
You stiII fidgeting.
I don't Iike peopIe moving behind me,
sitting behind me and shit.
You gonna sit back there,
you gotta sit the fuck stiII.
-I don't Iike that shit.
-This motherfucker's crazy, man.
Hey, I just wanna taIk to him.
I just wanna have a word with him.
-TaIk to him, Marcus.
-ReIax.
Why is he moving around
in my back seat?
It's Iike, man, a motherfucker fidgeting
in your car, you shoot first...
-and you ask questions Iater.
-Shoot?
You shoot first
and you ask questions Iater.
You just met him.
He fidgeting, man, I'm right about him.
I'm aIways right.
It's Iike, when I'm right, I'm right, and
when I'm wrong, I couId've been right...
so I'm stiII right
'cause I couId've been wrong!
That make sense. Come on.
Say that again?
-Come on, get back in.
-It's Iike, when I'm right, I'm right.
When I'm wrong,
I couId have been right...
so I'm stiII right
'cause I couId've been wrong, you know.
And I'm sorry,
'cause I couId be wrong right now.
I couId be wrong right now. But I'm right.
-It's beautifuI.
-Yeah, it's nice.
I used to come here
with my moms when I was young.
After the baby's born,
we gonna get our own pIace?
-Promise?
-Yeah.
-Can we get rid of him?
You sure?
Hi.
Thank you.
How is IittIe Antwan?
He's doing pretty good over there.
You caII him Antwan? After me?
Antwan.
Nah, nigga, l don't know
l don't know who got you
l don't know who stabbed you
l don't know who shot you
l don't know who cut you
l don't know who robbed you
But you think l know
'Cause you know how my squad do
Nowadays niggas snitchin'
so much in the street
That you gotta talk to them
like they the police
-And you say you got this from who?
-Dangerous.
-Dangerous gave you this contract?
-Yeah, I fucking toId you that.
l don't know who hit the studio
And popped your man
WeII, this is some sIave-ass contract.
The same contract he's under.
You sure you didn't get this
from Majestic?
What the fuck you trying to say?
I think I'm saying it.
Nigga, you don't make no decisions.
This is on Marcus.
l ain't signin'
that motherfucking contract
l ain't a bitch like you
l ain't going out like that
Me? l don't play
them kind of motherfucking games
You got your answer, man.
-No.
-Let's see if Dangerous can take a joke.
Dangerous in the booth
But not in the streets
You a Jehovah Witness, nigga!
Your daddy a doctor in Riverdale,
nigga, you ain't from the hood.
This can get me kiIIed.
He is taIented.
You talk that shit,
you don't live that shit, boy.
We got to stop this
from getting out there.
''We?''
Fuck you gonna do
when l catch your ass without Majestic?
Up you come, beautifuI. Up you come.
There you go.
There you go, beautifuI.
Life is precious.
TeII Marcus to apoIogize.
It's best for everyone.
Motherfucker touched my kid.
Nobody touches my famiIy.
I want security, 24/7.
Done.
Look, Marcus, man, I'm sorry,
I don't know how he knew.
I'm gonna kiII him.
No, not that way.
I'm gonna humiIiate him.
Bring him to me.
Let's see what he's got.
lt's on now, nigga
Welcome to hell
My hood, there's no telling
What they do to you
Across the street from Lucifer, he's only
Man, who's he taIking about?
Nigga, turn around and push the button.
You'll be losing your brain
And your boss is a bitch
He snitched on Levar
Junebug's a fucking flunky
l don't trust him, either
Eeney meeney miney mo
Catch a piggy by the toe
Click clack pow, officer down
-He ain't gonna Iike that.
-You know what? Fuck Majestic.
This song is about you.
''CIick cIack pow, officer down.''
He the fucking snitch.
From this day on, he ain't nothing to me.
Nothing.
End it. And get rid of the manager, too.
I don't wanna get anybody kiIIed, man.
Let's go.
Since Majestic couldn't get to us...
he made sure
we couldn't get a record deal.
It's Young Caesar.
Fuck, man. This shit is crazy, man.
They trying to shut us down.
Fuck it. Why don't we just go back
to doing what we do best?
-I can't do that.
-I ain't taIking about crack.
-I got something eIse in mind.
-What you taIking about?
And that's when l made
the biggest mistake of my life.
I'm teIIing you,
CoIombians are Iike cIockwork, right?
They got a nice IittIe set-up...
to take care of
their IittIe paper probIems.
So we ain't gotta worry about no five-o
or nothing Iike that, you know?
'Cause these cats ain't trying
to draw no attention to themseIves.
-See, just Iike cIockwork, DeIgato.
-Are we doing this?
Yeah, we gonna do it.
So, what you think, man?
This is a robbery.
We gonna go in there,
we gonna do what we gotta do...
-and we ain't gonna hurt nobody.
-For reaI, man.
-What the fuck is that, man?
-It's Spanish.
You don't know
no motherfucking Spanish.
What the fuck is que sera?
What the fuck are you taIking about?
Let that shit ride, man.
l thought l heard
my mother call my name.
Turned out it was my grandma.
That's what saved my life.
Marcus!
I toId you.
Don't never betray me! Never!
Show no love.
Love will get you killed.
You have a gift.
You're a poet.
Don't Iet nobody take that from you.
Papa!
Eeney meeney miney mo.
Catch a nigga by the toe.
lf l was your best friend
l'd want you around all the time
Could l be your best friend?
lf l was your best friend
l'd want you around all the time
Marcus!
Marcus! Marcus!
Roy! God!
Marcus!
CaII an ambuIance!
-Where's the ambuIance?
-I caIIed the ambuIance. Don't worry.
Fuck the ambuIance.
Fight this shit, Marcus! Fight this shit!
Roy, he's gone!
l died in the back of that truck.
What happened? What happened?
He's gone! He stopped breathing!
-What happened to him?
-He's shot.
Check his puIse.
More toweIs! More toweIs!
HoId my hand.
-No puIse.
-Joe, that goes in right there.
Push!
Okay, breathe now. Breathe. Breathe.
CIear.
-Push now, push!
-I can't!
CIear.
-No. Nothing.
-Okay.
Push!
AII right, his eyes are open. AII right.
He came. My baby came.
He's okay. He's fine.
He's fine.
Come on, Marcus.
Be strong, man. Stay strong.
-Watch his head.
-Be strong, man.
-Can I hoId him?
-Yeah, here he comes.
Look, they threw a party
for your birthday, Marcus.
Four-year-oId kid. Drive-by shooting.
One buIIet, he dies.
This guy, riddIed with buIIets,
gonna Iive.
-RoII of the dice. Yeah, his wife--
-GirIfriend.
Yeah, girIfriend, whatever...
she toId me she doesn't want us
to perform a tracheotomy.
-Why?
-I guess he's a singer.
Rapper.
l can't find the bloody remote.
Where's the remote?
-You need to eat something.
-Just put on your shoes.
-ls it cold down there?
-l can walk!
Don't you ever pull a gun on me.
What are you doing in the slave ship?
What you got in the bag?
-Anything eIse on you?
-No, man. That ain't for you.
Oh, shit.
Watch out, IittIe nigga, watch out.
-Where'd you get this?
-Robbery.
-Where's Marcus?
-He's dead.
-He ain't dead.
-What?
He ain't fucking dead.
I shot him, Iike, nine times.
You shot him nine times?
Yeah, Dangerous.
Running these streets.
Still got it. Top 40 on the pop lists.
l had nine bullets in me,
and Dangerous had a number-one hit.
I feeI Iike I'm Iosing him.
He's given up.
Is this it?
This. This pIace? This Iife?
Is this it for us?
I'm IoneIy, Marcus.
I know you're in pain.
You've aIways had pain.
And I understood.
'Cause when I used to Iook at you,
it was Iike Iooking in the mirror.
Thought I knew you.
But when I Iook at you,
aII I see is a weak person.
I feeI sorry for your son.
He's just another IittIe bIack boy
with nobody to Iook up to.
I don't want him to see you Iike this.
What are you doing?
What?
I can do without anything.
You can do without anything?
Can you do without me?
Can you do without IittIe Antwan?
TaIk to me.
Say something.
CharIene. CharIene.
I'm sorry.
No, baby. I'm so sorry.
Move it around some more.
-FeeI.
-FeeI what?
Your tongue?
Is that the fragment?
I wanna feeI your body.
Whip your head, boy
With the back of the steel
l'll whip your head, boy
Your cap could get peeled
Your ass could get killed
Two niggas in the front
Two niggas in the back
That's four niggas ridin' strapped
ln Grandpa's Cadillac
Stop, stop.
-I sound Iike I'm sIurring?
-Yeah, a IittIe bit.
-It's the best one we got, though.
-PIay it back.
Two niggas in the front
Two niggas in the back
That's four niggas ridin' strapped
ln Grandpa's Cadillac
AII right, Iet's do it again.
l'm up early in the mornin'
Tryin' to make a move
We coming in when your shorty
Take your lil' one to school
Even though she causes the drama
You love your baby mama
l hit her with the Llama
To get this cake
Give us the coke, the cash
The combo to the safe
Oh, she don't know it
Damn, okay, we'll wait
'Cause you can pray for a miracle
What's wrong?
My voice don't sound the same.
It's better.
-It's got more pain in it.
-For reaIIy.
Keep going, baby.
l'll whip your head, boy
With the back of the steel
Your cap could get peeled
l'll whip your head, boy
Your ass could get killed
l'm up early in the mornin'
Tryin' to make a move
Comin' in when your shorty
Take your lil' one to school
Even though she cause the drama
You love your baby mama
l hit her with the Llama
To get this cake
l'll whip your head, boy
Top feeIs so much better
than the bottom.
So much better.
Nigga, you's a window shopper
Mad at me, l think l know why
ln the jewelry store
Looking at shit you can't buy
Nigga, you's a window shopper
ln the dealership
Trying to get a test drive
Nigga, you's a window shopper
Mad as fuck when you see me ride by
Summertime
White Porsche Carrera is milky
l'm on the grind
Let my paper stack when l'm filthy
lt's funny how niggas
Get to screw-facing at me
Anyhow, they ain't got
The heart to get at me
l'll get down
Southside's the hood that l come from
So l don't cruise through nobody hood
Without my gun
You know the kid
Ain't goin' for all that bullshit
Try and stick me, l'm a let off a full clip
Everybody mad
When their paper don't stack right
But when l come around
Y'all niggas better act right
When we got the tops down
You can hear the system thump
Nigga, when we rollin' rollin' rollin'
Shut your block down
Who's your daddy, boy? Huh?
Nigga, when we rollin' rollin' rollin'
Who's your daddy?
l think l know why
Nigga, you's a window shopper
Mad as fuck when you see me ride by
You have to go back?
Yeah.
There's some things
I need the answers to.
I'd rather die Iike a man
than Iive Iike a coward.
Majestic reaIIy Ioved your mama.
One day he came to me and asked...
if there was anything
between me and your mother...
and I Iied to him.
l told him
l was only trying to protect her.
lt was far more than that.
Your mama didn't want
to take my family life from me...
but she gave me everything...
and I took it aII.
In the end, I didn't protect her.
Sometimes...
l feel like l killed her myself.
When I first saw you...
you was a IittIe baby.
I couIdn't even Iook you in the eye.
What you saying?
One night, after midnight...
l was sitting here.
Word came through that you was gone.
You was dead.
For the first time in my fucking Iife,
I feII to my knees...
and I prayed to God
that nothing happened.
So I prayed to your mama.
I asked her to forgive me...
and to taIk to God for me
to bring you back.
l don't deserve you.
Rocks that l copped
From proceeds from the spot
l got the energy to win
l'm full of adrenaline
Play the curve and get nauseous
Watchin' the spinner spin
l made plans to make it
A prisoner of the state
Now l can invite your ass
out to my estate
Them hollow-tips bent me up
But l'm back in shape
Pour Cristal in the blender
Make a protein shake
He's coming, y'all.
Our own Young Caesar
is coming back to Pelham Hall...
July 4, 8:00 p.m. Be there.
l want the finer things in my life
So l hustle
Nigga, you gettin' in my way
When l'm tryin' to get mine
And l'll buck you
l don't care who you run with
Or where you from
Nigga, fuck you
l want the finer things in my life
So l hustle
l don't know shit about gymnastics
l somersault bricks
Black Talons start flyin'
When a nigga flip
Yo, nigga, you gotta
turn this shit the fuck off.
What you want me to do?
I got this man in the back.
-Stop the crack!
-We don't want no more!
-Give us back our street!
Papi, do you have any controI
over your neighborhood?
Don't fucking worry about nothing,
aII right?
-You gonna Iet him pIay this concert?
-You worry too much, Mira.
Man, Iisten to this.
-Stop the crack!
-Give us back our neighborhood!
Stop the crack! Stop the crack!
Does he have to do this?
I think he does.
Antwan. Remember,
you keep him covered, aII right?
AII right.
So what's happening, man?
Bye, Nana.
Last time I saw your mother, she was
saying goodbye in that front room.
You Ieave enough protection here?
Yeah, y'aII gonna be aII right. Yeah.
This one is IegaIIy owned.
If it comes down to it,
I got a knife in that drawer.
That's aII I know.
That's aII any mother knows.
I'II be okay, Nana.
You can't take that from a person,
being a protector.
That's aII any man or woman is at
the end of the day anyway...
is a protector.
Protector of a chiId
who wiII one day die.
Marcus...
when I Iook in your eyes,
I don't know what you thinking.
And you've been Iike that
since you were 12...
since the day your mama died.
-I'II be okay.
-No...
you wiII not be aII right, Marcus.
I Iove you, Nana.
Yo, it's soId out!
The concert is soId out!
-Hey, come on, man, where you going?
-ChiII, partner.
Easy. Easy. Easy.
No guns. No arms. We come in peace.
Everybody's friends here, right?
Everybody just reIax.
Can I have a word in private
with you, man?
You reaIIy wanna go through with this?
You wanna go out there
and diss me in my own hood?
In front of my own peopIe?
You know I can't Iet you do that, Marcus.
Here's what I can do.
I'II Iet you come out there,
take a picture with me.
-Show some respect.
-No.
He said no.
You know I Iove you.
You're a stubborn motherfucker,
just Iike me.
RuIe number five: Show no Iove.
Love wiII get you kiIIed.
You know, I reaIIy Ioved your mom.
Give me a hug, man.
But, you know, before she died...
I fucked her, and then I kiIIed her.
This is how I kiIIed your mama!
Beat him! Fuck him up, man!
Get your ass back, man!
He's just fucking with you!
This guy's a fucking joke!
How you know that shit's true?
Shut the fuck up! I can't hear shit!
-Marcus, caIm the fuck down!
-I'II kiII you, motherfucker!
Start the fucking show! Start the show!
-Get back, man.
-I Ioved her, man.
I didn't mean to hurt her, man.
I Ioved her.
Man...
I Iove you, man. I Iove you.
Let's do this.
I can't Iet you go out there, nigga!
I can't fucking Iet you go out there!
You kiII me, Marcus. Come on, man.
You do it.
Come on.
l been looking for my father all my life.
l realized l was looking for myself.
l felt like l was walking away
from the old me...
and the new me was being born.
lt's Young Caesar!
What's up?
America got a thing
For this gangsta shit, they love me
Black Chukkas, black skullies
Leather Pelle Pelle
l take spit over Raymo shit
l'm a fan
Got the silver duct tape
On my .38 handle
The women in my life
Bring confusion and shit
So like Nino in New Jack
l holler "cancel that bitch"
Look at me, this is the life l chose
Niggas around me so cold
Man, my heart done froze
l build an empire on the low,
the narcs don't know
l'm a weatherman, l take that coca leaf
And make that snow
Sit back, watch it turn to dope
Watch it go out the door
O after O, you know
Homie, l'm just triple beam dreamin'
Niggas be schemin'
l fiend to live the good life
The fiends are just fiendin'
Conceal my weapon nice and neat
So you can't see
The penitentiary is definitely out
The question for me
l want the finer things in my life
So l hustle
Nigga, you get in my way
When l'm tryin' to get mine
And l'll buck you
l don't care who you run with
Or where you from
Nigga, fuck you
l want the finer things in my life
So l hustle
lts a hustler's ambition
Close your eyes, listen, see my vision
Mossberg pumpin', shotgun dumpin'
And drama means nothin'
lt's part of the game
Catch me in the coupe, switchin' lanes
Or in the jeweler's, switchin' chains
l upgrade from 30 BS to clean VS
Rocks that l copped
From proceeds from the spot
l got the energy to win
l'm full of adrenaline
Play the curve and get nauseous
Watchin' the spinner spin
l made plans to make it
A prisoner of the state
Now l can invite your ass
out to my estate
Them hollow-tips bent me up
But l'm back in shape
Pour Cristal in the blender
And make a protein shake
l'm like the East Coast's
number one playboy, B
Hugh Hefner'll tell you
He ain't got shit on me
The Feds watching me
lcy, they can't stop me
Racist pointing at me:
"Look at Niggerace." Hello!
l want the finer things in my life
So l hustle
Nigga, you get in my way
When l'm tryin' to get mine
And l'll buck you
l don't care who you run with
Or where you from
Nigga, fuck you
l want the finer things in my life
So l hustle