. . .gringo border patrols
in pursuit
Load these guys in our car
The bags too
And put this shit out!
Luis, let's get
the fuck out of here!
It's procedure!
Fuck procedure, let's go!
No IDs
This guy's dead !
Check your guns,
you know the rules
Give me your shoes, bitch !
You'll have fun
in here asshole
This will be
your home for a while
and we your family
In a few hours
you will be moved
into the main prison
You'll have some freedom
but remember. . .
this is still a prison
Use what you've learned
in this holding cell
and don't make trouble
for us or yourselves
Or, as the saying goes. . .
small town. . .
large hell
Welcome
This is "El Pueblito"
God bless you
Get up you lazy bums!
Move it, move it!
You can talk later,
let's move it!
Move it!
You too gringo,
get the fuck over there!
Let's go, let's go
Heads up gringo,
here they come!
Lunch !
I just lit it for him !
Let's go
What did I tell you about
the fucking cigarettes!
Nothing's free!
Please! We have
nowhere to go!
You could stay with me
You won't let me help you
C'mon kids,
hurry up, let's go
Get out, cabrón !
All good General?
Take care of him
Why aren't you in bed?
I didn't want you
walking home alone
King Rat
30 pesos for fifteen minutes
Go play kids!
Calm down,
there's enough for everyone
That's the kid,
give him a hand !
What's wrong with you?
Tough guy, eh?
Shut the fuck up!
Touch him again
and I'll cut your balls off
Now fuck off!
What do you mean why?
He's stealing from us,
and he's an idiot
Carnal is family
He's a liability
You straighten him out,
I don't want to deal with it
You may not have a choice
He's getting out of hand
People hate him
What do you
want me to do. . .
kill him?
Just get him off real estate
It's a big job,
too much money
Give him an assistant
Mom !
A sight for sore eyes
Aunt Flor
And your cousin?
He's coming
How's his health?
Is he drinking?
Don't worry so much
I'm holding you responsible
Let me remind you. . .
that all the money raised. . .
will go to the family fund
here at El Pueblito
So cough it up!
Straight from Juarez. . .
the King of the Skies. . .
You got a visitor!
That's my watch
Hey kid !
Where are you going?
Come here you prick
What?
Come here you little fucker
Fucking Indian
Damn !
Hey, cabrón !
Give me!
Where'd you get it?
I found it in the trash
It's mine
I'm going to tell Caracas
What are you looking at?
What's up?
What do you want?
The money
You trade rent
payments for sex
Others pay you with drugs
You're out of control
You're a disgrace
We never should have
given you this job
Tough shit. . .
it's a family business
Maybe you're the fuck up
If I was in charge,
no one would steal from us
Enlighten me
I was robbed
By whom?
I don't know
There are
a few thieves in here
You and your fucking lies
Don't bullshit me
The money, or the fucker
who robbed you
You're my cousin. . .
but if you don't deliver,
you're finished
Fuck off,
I'm not your bitch !
The money, fucker
When did you get robbed?
Who knows
When I got my watch back?
I don't know!
Maybe
Do you think I'm an idiot!?
Where'd you get the watch !?
I found it!
Did the gringo help?
No, it was just me!
Get him !
Caracas.
Think you can fool me
you little fuck!?
Get off her,
you son of a bitch !
I'm not done with you !
What did you idiots do!?
This room was built for me!
Now you're bleeding
all over it
He had the mom. . .
He was going to kill the kid
Son of a bitch !
What the fuck did you do?
Idiot!
Answer me!
Now what?
Javi !
It's Aunt Flor
Answer it
Answer it, man !
Hi, Aunt
He can't talk right now. . .
he's lying down
Okay, bye
It's going to
break her heart
What could I say?
If the gringo hadn't
killed him, I would have
What about the gringo?
What about him?
He's not family,
he's not Mexican. . .
I'd kill him
Fucking gringo!
One of those was my cousin !
I need a drink
Cut him loose!
He knows about my liver
He knew about
our problems with Carnal
He seems to know
what I'm thinking
Who is he?
I don't know
Armando doesn't know either
So he's in here with no name,
charges, or fingerprints?
You're in charge
of security!
How does this fucking gringo
know everything?
So kill him then
You idiot!
Don't be hasty!
First, find out who sent him
Find out who he is
Then we kill him
Number three
Get Vazquez and Romero
And bring the money too
That's Javi's share!
I was going to
give Javi his cut!
Leave them there
I told you the gringo
would be trouble
He stole big time
from Frank in San Diego
Frank knows we have his money
You need to slow down
My big brother. . .
always worried about me
You keep drinking
and smoking like this. . .
and the kid's liver
may not be enough
Go get the gringo
There's three of them
Will the watchtower
be covered?
Have we ever failed you?
Three guys
are coming for the gringo
Cover them
They'll be easy to spot
Fucking gringos!
Idiots!
Just kill him already
That's not a good idea
There are two reasons
not to kill me
You never mentioned
you speak Spanish
Nobody asked me
I need practice
Frank is now
a big problem for you
And what's
the second reason?
I can get to him
I did it once already
Don't do me any favors
It's in your best
interest as well
This is too much, Javi
A shootout!
Inside the prison
If you get me out of here. . .
I'll kill Frank
I'm not joking !
This bloodbath
will have consequences
Armando. . .
You chose sides
a long time ago
We can change that
if you want
No problem
But why don't you clean up
the mess out there instead
Get the fuck out!
Okay
Go kill him
But don't come back
The money you stole
is the price for your life
I'll need a little cash. . .
guns. . .
and a car
Okay
Hurry up!
Javi's waiting for you !
We need to talk, Javi
You look worried
The shootout was
the final straw
The government
is closing the prison
They've tried that before
It's a surprise raid,
even I don't know when
2000 soldiers. . .
police. . .snipers
I have to get out of here
It won't be easy
If Armando lets you out. . .
they'll go after him. . .
then the Mayor,
all the way up
I can't go to another prison
Maybe for a while
until things calm down
No, I can't risk
losing the kid
I need that liver transplant
And I'll be too weak to move
So get me an ambulance
and barricade this place
Nothing interrupts
the operation
What do we do with Barnes?
Have our boys up north
kill him once Frank is dead
What if he doesn't
kill Frank?
Give him forty-eight hours. . .
then kill him
Regina, it's time!
Move it!
Get in
Don't come out,
no matter what
I admire your courage
I didn't expect any less
You know we'll kill you
and find the kid
Why waste more time?
I treated you well
Took care of you both
I tried to find
someone else
But time ran out
But I'm tired
You want my liver?
Here's your fucking liver
Ladies
Here
. . .but you got
the money, right?
I paid you, fucker!
They're here
Go fuck your mother!
Make sure Armando
has the ambulance ready
Leave that open
for a quick getaway
Nobody gets in here!
Park over there
Go fuck yourself!
He'll be okay
Thank you
They were assholes
Just like my husband
Stop!
It's an emergency!
Help us to the ambulance!
Be careful
What happened?
Male, ten years old
Under anesthesia
for liver transplant
Vital signs are stable
He needs to get
to a hospital
We're in a hurry
To us
Can I bite you?
Yes
Only if it's really hard
And don't leave any marks
Come
Hurry up
I'll be back
Forced Subs by voodoo