2306, please.
Hello, honey.
How you doing?
Good.
What did he say?
Uh-huh. Is he still there?
How long ago did he leave?
Uh-huh. I'm stopping here,
then I got a little meeting,
and then I'll...
I would if I could.
As soon as I can.
Let me get off and l...
let me get off and I prom...
I promise you it'll be okay.
A bunch of bullshit.
Waste a good man's time.
Hi, could I speak
to Dr. Lowenstein, please?
It's rather important.
Could you get him for me?
Bunch of bullshit trying to make
a living on these deadbeat leads.
I swear to God, Shel,
I'm on a sit today...
Hello, Mrs. Swoboda,
this is Dave Moss.
Yeah, we spoke yesterday.
Now on the Rio Rancho Estates,
we've had a situation just come up.
The president of our company
is in town just one day,
- And he has certain parcels...
- Doctor...
well, could you get...
what do you mean?
He's not there?
I have to speak to him.
Yes, it is fairly urgent.
Mr. Levene.
No, I can't be reached.
I'll get back to him.
He has certain parcels...
certain choice parcels
which he's given me
a hold on for the next 48 hours.
What would be the best time to get
you and your husband together?
Say, tonight, at 10:00,
or tomorrow at 8:00?
Okay.
Okay, what would be
the best time to do that?
Look, you sent in the...
no, no, listen to me now...
I've got 48 hours
to make you a lot of money.
Well, when will he be home?
Fine, I'll call you back in 10 minutes.
They don't give you the leads,
they don't give you the support,
- They don't give you dick.
- Yeah.
Then they're yanking us in
on some sales conference.
When's the last time anybody
learned a goddamn thing?
All it does is some jerk
shoots his mouth off.
I swear to God, Shel, I got half a mind
to go across the street.
I got half a mind to go
with you if they'd take me.
You never know... I was talking
to Jerry Graff last week.
I got to call
these deadbeats back.
I can't make a goddamn
dollar with these leads,
and you're killing my ass
on the street.
- I'm sorry you aren't happy here.
- That's cute,
but you're running this office
like a bunch of bullshit.
You're on an override...
you make money, we make money.
- I'd like you to make more money.
- Then don't go waste my time.
- A sales conference?
- The strategy comes from downtown.
Oh, the strategy?
The strategy?
- Well, I think I'll pass.
- I wouldn't.
- Why is that?
- When you come, then you'll see.
- Shelly.
- John.
Are you ready
to do or die tonight?
Oh yeah,
always ready, John.
Always ready, John.
Now, one thing...
we were talking about the leads.
We got some new ones?
That's what we're going
to talk about at the meeting.
We are? Because I'm running
into a bit of a snag.
Yes, I've seen
your sales figures.
That's the leads.
You give me a better lead...
That's what we're going
to be talking about.
I'm in a bind...
personal problems.
- I could use a leg up.
- After the meeting.
- I hear the new Glengarry leads...
- After the meeting, Shel.
- Hey, Ricky.
- Hello, John.
- Wet out there tonight.
- Huh?
- Uh-huh.
- Maybe it'll break the heat.
- Yeah.
Al, give me a quick J&B, huh?
Double.
Cutty, Al.
- They say...
- Huh?
they say it was so hot
downtown this afternoon,
grown men on the street corner
were going up to cops
begging the cops
to shoot them.
They say you should not drink
alcohol when it's so hot.
- Who says that?
- Something I read.
For they say
it dehydrates you.
They say
you should drink water,
but I subscribe to the law
of contrary public opinion.
If everyone thinks one thing,
then I say bet the other way.
Added to which,
you know they're wrong.
That's what I'm saying.
- Slow tonight.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, I guess
everybody's staying home.
If my daughter calls,
anybody calls,
I'm over at the office.
Thanks.
I had a woman
in White Plains on the hook...
five units, Mountain View...
what happens?
She has to check
with her lawyer.
- You let her check with her lawyer?
- What could I do?
- I dunno.
- Shelly.
- Huh?
- Who's the guy?
Couldn't tell you.
I don't like the whole thing,
because all I need is a lead.
- They won't give out...
- Uh-huh.
The rich get richer,
that's the law of the land.
Who belongs
to the BM...?
It is 7:30.
So who is that?
And where is
Mr. Roma?
Well, I'm not a leash,
so I don't know, do I?
Let me have
your attention for a moment.
You're talking about what?
You're talking about...
bitching about
that sale you shot,
some son of a bitch
don't want to buy land,
somebody don't want
what you're selling,
some broad you're
trying to screw, so forth.
Let's talk
about something important.
- Are they all here?
- All but one.
I'm going anyway.
Let's talk
about something important.
Put that coffee down.
Coffee's for closers only.
You think
I'm fucking with you?
I am not fucking with you.
I'm here from downtown.
I'm here
from Mitch and Murray.
And I'm here
on a mission of mercy.
- Your name's Levene?
- Yeah.
You call yourself a salesman,
you son of a bitch?
I don't got to listen
to this shit.
You certainly don't, 'cause
the good news is, you're fired.
The bad news is you've got...
all of you've got...
just one week
to regain your jobs,
starting with tonight...
starting with tonight's sit.
Oh, have I got
your attention now?
Good...
'cause we're adding
a little something
to this month's
sales contest.
As you all know, first prize
is a Cadillac Eldorado.
Anybody want to see
second prize?
Second prize is
a set of steak knives.
Third prize is you're fired.
Do you get the picture?
Are you laughing now?
You got leads. Mitch and Murray
paid good money.
Get their names
to sell them.
You can't close
the leads you're given,
you can't close shit,
you are shit!
Hit the bricks, pal, and beat it,
'cause you are going out!
- The leads are weak.
- The leads are weak?
The fucking leads are weak?
You're weak.
I've been
in this business 15 years.
- What's your name?
- Fuck you...
that's my name!
You know why, mister?
Because you drove a Hyundai
to get here tonight,
I drove an $80,000 BMW.
That's my name.
And your name
is "You're wanting."
You can't play in the man's game?
You can't close them?
Then go home and tell your wife
your troubles.
Because only one thing
counts in this life...
get them to sign
on the line which is dotted!
You hear me,
you fucking faggots?
"A-B-C."
A... Always,
B... Be, C... Closing.
Always Be Closing.
"Always Be Closing."
"A-l-D-A."
"Attention, Interest,
Decision, Action."
Attention...
Do I have your attention?
Interest...
Are you interested?
I know you are,
because it's fuck or walk.
You close
or you hit the bricks.
Decision... Have you made
your decision for Christ?
And Action.
"A-l-D-A."
Get out there...
you got the prospects coming in.
You think they came in
to get out of the rain?
A guy don't walk on the lot
lest he wants to buy.
They're sitting out there
waiting to give you their money.
Are you gonna take it?
Are you man enough
to take it?
Crap.
What's the problem, pal?
You... Moss.
You're such a hero,
you're so rich,
how come you're here wasting
your time with a bunch of bums?
You see this watch?
- You see this watch?
- Yeah.
That watch costs
more than your car.
I made $9 70,000 last year.
How much you make?
You see, pal... that's who I am,
and you're nothing.
Nice guy?
I don't give a shit.
Good father? Fuck you...
go home and play with your kids.
You want to work here...
close!
You think this is abuse?
You think this is abuse,
you cocksucker?
You can't take this, how can you
take the abuse you get on a sit?
You don't like it, leave.
I can go out there tonight...
the materials you got...
make myself $15,000.
Tonight... in two hours!
Can you?
Go and do likewise.
"A-l-D-A."
Get mad, you son of a bitches.
Get mad!
You know what it takes
to sell real estate?
It takes brass balls
to sell real estate.
Go and do likewise,
gents.
The money's out there...
you pick it up, it's yours,
you don't,
I got no sympathy for you.
You want to go out
on those sits tonight and close...
close... it's yours.
Not, you're gonna be
shining my shoes.
And you know
what you'll be saying.
Bunch of losers
sitting around in a bar,
"Oh yeah, I used to be a salesman.
It's a tough racket."
These are the new leads.
These are
the Glengarry leads.
And to you, they're gold.
And you don't get them.
Why?
Because to give them to you
is just throwing them away.
They're for closers.
I'd wish you good luck,
but you wouldn't know what
to do with it if you got it.
And to answer your question, pal...
"Why am I here?"
I came here because
Mitch and Murray asked me to.
They asked me for a favor.
I said, "The real favor...
follow my advice
and fire your fucking ass,
because a loser
is a loser."
Bunch of fucking nonsense...
treat people like that.
The fuck is he going
to get off?
- Mickey Mouse sales conference.
- He didn't mean it.
I'm sure he didn't mean it about
trimming down the sales quota.
Where is Roma?
Where the hell is Mr. Ricky Roma?
All the while we got to sit here,
eat this nonsense?
Hello? Mr. Levene.
How's she doing?
Uh-huh, yeah.
Is she awake?
Oh, the doctor came by.
What did he say?
Uh-huh.
I can't come in tonight.
I think... I know she is.
I know that she is.
I've gotta go out. Will you please
tell her when she wakes?
I've got to go out.
Tell her I'll call her from the road.
Thank you.
Gentlemen,
you heard the man.
What is this in aid of?
- As of tonight...
- What is this? Excuse me.
What it's in aid of
is that Mitch and Murray...
Fuck Mitch and Murray!
I'm doing my job,
I got to put up
with this childishness?
I don't make the rules.
I'm paid to run the office.
You don't like the rules, Dave?
There's the door!
Two lead cards for tonight,
two lead cards for tomorrow.
As you heard,
end of the month,
top salesman on the board
gets the Eldorado.
- Next man down the...
- What about the good leads?
- The leads I've given you.
- But these leads are shit.
They're old...
I've seen that name 100 times.
- The leads are assigned randomly.
- What about the new leads?
The new leads...
the Glengarry leads.
I've got them.
I'm going to hang onto them.
And they'll be
assigned to closers,
based on the sales volume,
first to Roma.
- Where is Roma?
- Don't worry about Roma.
He'll get his leads,
you've got yours.
He's top name on the board,
so he don't have to be here?
That's correct!
And as the hour is waning,
I suggest you... those of you
who are interested
in a continuing job with
this organization, get to work.
That's garbage.
Bullshit.
- Thank you for your attention.
- Bullshit!
How am I supposed to close these?
Look at this.
I've had this guy before.
I've been to his house twice.
l... I can't...
I can't close this stuff.
Shelly, how am I
supposed to...
They're going
to bounce me out of a job.
Hello, Mr. Palermo?
I'm sorry.
Mr. Speice?
Mr. Robert Speice?
Yeah,
this is George Aaronow.
I'm with Rio.
I spoke with your wife earlier.
I'm the vice president of Rio Rancho
Properties in Furman, Arizona.
Yes. I'm calling from the airport,
and consulting my map,
I see that you and your wife
live near the airport.
I have some rather...
rather unusual,
rather good information
on the property...
Hello? Hello, this is
Sheldon Levene.
Please listen closely...
I only have a moment or so.
I can speak only
to a Mrs. Nyborg.
Oh, this is Mrs. Nyborg.
Please listen closely, Mrs. Nyborg.
I'm calling from Consolidated
Properties of Arizona.
Our computer has chosen you
from all of the many thousands
who write in requesting
information on our properties.
Now by federal law,
as you probably know,
the prize must be awarded to you
even if you are not engaged
in our land
development plan.
The only stipulation, of course,
is that you and your husband
must sign at the same time
for the receipt of your prize.
Now, I will be in the area
tonight, possibly tomorrow.
What do you think might be
a convenient time to meet
with both you
and your husband?
Of course I'll hold.
- Bunch of fucking nonsense, huh?
- I can't close them.
- Nobody can close 'em.
- They're old.
They're ancient...
a bunch of fucking nonsense.
Get some jerk
to come in here...
Sometimes I think,
"I wonder if I belong in this business."
Send a guy out there...
no support, no confidence.
Then I say,
"Nobody can close 'em."
- Then I look at Roma.
- Roma... fuck Roma.
Had a freak...
a little run of luck.
The leads are garbage.
Then I say,
"Why give him the good leads?
- He doesn't need 'em."
- You going out?
Yeah. I have to go out.
I can't make a sit.
- Have you tried?
- Yeah. Something's wrong with me.
What is it?
I can't push through.
Get your coat on.
You're coming out with me.
- Something in me.
- Forget it.
- I try, I try.
- I said forget it, come on.
I can't close 'em.
Life.
I swear to God,
you work all your life...
- Forget it, George.
- Roma, so on...
- So gifted.
- Gifted, my ass!
- The guy gets a string of luck.
- No, no, no.
The thing of it is,
money's tight.
When times are tight,
it don't do no good
to throw around,
"Just go out and sell."
Threaten a man all you want,
you can't whip a dead horse.
- Nope.
- All this garbage...
"Sell 10,000,
you win a Cadillac;
you lose, we're gonna fire
your ass"? It's medieval.
- Yes.
- It's wrong.
- Yes it is,
and you know
who's responsible?
- Who?
- You know who it is.
It's Mitch and Murray,
'cause it don't have to be this way.
- No.
- Look at Jerry Graff.
He's clean, he's doing
business for himself,
he's got that list...
with the nurses?
You see? That's thinking.
Why take a 10% sales commission?
Why are we giving the rest away?
What are we giving 90% for?
For nothing.
For some jerk in the office,
telling us, "Get out there and close,
go win a Cadillac."
Graff goes out and buys.
He pays top dollar.
- You see?
- Yes.
For the leads... that's thinking.
Now, he's got the leads,
he goes in business for himself.
That's what? That's thinking.
Who... who's got
a steady job,
a regular job,
a couple of bucks nobody's touched?
Nurses.
Graff goes and buys
a fucking list of nurses. One grand...
he paid two, I'll eat my hat.
4,000 or 5,000 nurses.
- He's going wild.
- He is?
- Yeah, he's doing very well.
- I heard they were running cold.
- The nurses?
- Yeah.
You hear a lot of things.
He's doing very well.
- With River Oaks?
- River Oaks, Brook Farms.
All that shit. Somebody told me...
you know what he's clearing, himself?
- 14, 15 grand a week.
- Himself?
That's what I'm saying.
Why? He's got the leads.
He's got the good leads.
What are we?
We're sitting
in the shit here. Why?
Because we got to go to them
to get them.
90% of our sales we're paying
to the office for the leads.
There's our leads, there's overhead,
phones, a lot of stuff.
What do you need?
A telephone?
Some broad to say, "Good morning"?
Nothing. It's the leads.
The whole thing is the leads,
you understand me?
You can't sell to a void...
you got to get a goddamn person.
You get a lead, you get
a person... I'll go sell 'em.
Otherwise, what do they want
from my life?
Hello, Danny?
Dan, it's Shel Levene.
Yeah, we spoke...
last May I called you.
I was in town from my estate
in Rio Rancho, and...
Arizona.
I wish we could have
gotten together at that time.
Danny, that piece of property I had
for you has increased in value...
Grace, Grace,
what was that figure? $ 76,000.
Oh, Danny, I wish you could have
been in on it with me.
Look, I'm here overnight...
I have to go home tomorrow,
and I thought, after the interest
you showed on the last trip, that...
Hold it, Grace. Danny,
I know that you're serious,
and because of that, I am going
to shove my appointments around
and make sure...
oh, gee, I wish that...
All right, Danny.
Yeah, all right.
Going out tonight,
Shelly?
What is this bullshit
with the sales promotion?
It isn't bullshit.
It's the way it is.
You're going to fire
the bottom men on the list?
That's the way it is
and I don't make the rules.
- The rules come from downtown.
- I got a problem here, John.
- I'm closing up the office.
- Come have a drink with me.
- I've got to get home.
- Do me the courtesy... five minutes?
I am trying to get home
for two hours.
I got to go home, grab one hour
with my kids, come back here,
see if any of you closed
a contract, take the contract...
- How about one minute?
- What is it?
- I can't close these leads.
- Then move on.
Don't jump! Don't jump out
of your manager bag a second.
It's just two guys talking,
am I right? We're just talking.
You got the new leads.
If you would give me... just hold on.
The Glengarry leads are to be
assigned only to closers.
Hold on a second.
If you give me the good leads...
You blew the last good one
I gave you.
No, no... hold on,
will you?
I did not blow 'em.
One kicked out. One, I closed.
- You didn't close it.
- Would you listen to me?
I closed that cocksucker!
His ex! John, his ex!
I didn't even know he was married.
The judge invalidated it.
Shelly...
What was that job, huh?
Bad luck. That's all it was.
I pray you never find it...
it runs in streaks.
That's what it's doing,
that's all it does... streaks.
I pray that it misses you
and that's all I have to say.
Shit, I've got to eat.
Williamson...
Iook at the sheets.
Look at the sheets.
198 7, '88, '89...
six months in '89... who's on top?
- Roma.
- Under him?
- Moss.
- Oh, bullshit, John!
April to September it's me...
it's no fucking Moss.
Due respect,
he's an order-taker.
Talk... talks a good game,
but look on the board, it's me.
- Not lately it isn't.
- Not late...
Well, lately...
kiss my ass "lately."
You call Murray and you call Mitch...
when we were on Peterson,
who do you think bought the new car?
Call Mitch. The Seville?
He came in here...
"You bought that for me, fella."
And out of what? Hey, look at me!
Out of what? Nothing!
Cold calling.
You want to talk about a sale?
You are really
beginning to burn my ass, kid.
I can't get a lead, you...
it was skill, John.
It could be working for you...
you want to throw it away.
- It isn't me.
- It's not you...
I wonder who it is.
Who the fuck am I talking to?
- I need the leads to sell.
- After the contest. After the 30th.
Bullshit,
"After the contest."
If I'm not on that board by the 30th,
they're going to can my ass.
I need those leads
and I need 'em now or I'm out.
You're going to miss me.
I swear to you, you will miss me.
Let me tell you
something, Shelly.
I do what I'm hired to do...
you might do the same.
- Jesus.
- Now wait a second!
I'm hired to watch the leads,
to marshal my sales force.
I'm given a policy.
My job is to do that.
Marshal your sales force?
Anybody falls below
a certain mark, I'm directed.
I'm not permitted
to give them the premium leads.
How do they rise
above that mark? With dreck?
With this toilet paper
you're giving me?
You give me
one premium lead...
Do you know what
the premium leads cost?
Do I know what
Yeah,
I know what they cost.
I generated the sufficient
dollar revenue to buy them.
But I cannot sell shit!
Jesus. And I've seen
these before, you know.
Christ, I saw these back...
Homestead...
1985, we pitched
these cocksuckers Baywater.
They couldn't buy a fucking toaster.
They're broke. They're deadbeats.
Just give me some leads that don't
come out of a phone book.
You give me something hotter
than that and I can close it.
It's just a streak.
I'm gonna turn it around.
Hey, I need your help.
I can't do it,
Shelly.
John...
I'll give you 10%.
- Of what?
- My end... what I close.
You give me the premium leads,
you're in for 10%, what I close.
- And what if you don't close?
- I will.
- What if you don't close?
- I will close.
What if you don't,
you understand?
Then I'm fucked. You think you're
the only guy with a family?
- You see what I'm saying?
- John...
I step out and you don't close,
then it's my job.
- Then I'm fucked.
- I will close!
Now, 10% John...
I can get hot, you know that.
- Not lately you can't.
- That's defeatist... fuck it!
Go with me. Get on my side
and let's do something.
You want to run this office?
You heard what the man said...
"Attack."
Let's do something.
- Huh?
- 20%.
- All right.
- And 50 bucks a lead.
- No?
- Oh!
Oh, shit.
Listen...
I got to talk to you.
Permit me to do this a second.
I'm older than you.
A man acquires a reputation
on the street.
What he does when he's up,
what he does at other times...
I said, "10," you said, "No."
You said, "20," I said, "Fine."
Now you want to throw
this 50-buck thing in.
John, a good deal... has got to be
one where both parties...
Okay, okay, okay, fine...
20%, 50 bucks a lead. It's done.
Let's go out.
We make some money.
I got bills to pay.
I want two sits tonight
and I want the good leads...
the Glengarry leads... two.
Two, John, because
I am going to close 'em both.
It's a long road
with no turning, pally.
Huh? Okay.
Now, let's go.
I've got to go back
to the office to get 'em.
Go on, let's go.
This is what I was saying, John.
All you need, a little boost,
you turn a streak around.
Am I right? Good, huh?
Huh, good?
What?
- What?
- Two leads, 100 bucks.
- Now?
- Now, yes. When?
- Shit, John.
- I wish I could.
You fucking asshole.
I don't have it...
I don't...
I'll bring it in the office
in the morning.
- I'll be coming with the sales.
- Nope.
I can't fucking
believe this.
All right, here's...
20... 30, and...
Jesus, here's the 30.
I'll bring the rest in tomorrow.
We got to do this, huh, pal?
For Christ's sake!
No.
- My daughter...
- I can't do it, Shelly.
I got to tell you something.
It wasn't so long ago,
I'd pick up the phone
and call Murray... I got your job.
"Murray, the kid is burning my ass."
"Shelly, he's gone."
You are gone before
I'm back from lunch.
Bought him a trip
to Bermuda once.
- I've got to go.
- All right, hey.
Give me... I'll take two more
of the old leads.
- I gave you two today.
- One is a bust-out, John!
- The other ain't home!
- Shelly...
I promise you,
I've been on the phone... I know.
No more leads today...
two per day. You've got yours.
All right.
- All right?
- Sure.
We will do that...
other thing.
I guess I left
my wallet in my room.
Deadbeats.
Deadbeats, all of 'em.
My mistake.
I shouldn't have took the leads.
- You had to.
- Yeah? Why?
- To get on the...
- To get on the board, yeah.
How am I gonna get on the board
trying to sell a doctor?
Two regular,
two chocolate donuts.
Give me the same thing to go.
And don't try and sell an Indian.
I will never try to sell
an Indian.
These names come up...
you ever get 'em..."Patel"?
- You ever get 'em?
- I think I had one once.
You had one,
you'd know it..."Patel."
They keep coming up.
I don't know.
They like to talk to salesmen.
They're lonely.
They like to feel superior...
never bought a fucking thing.
I don't know.
Come down the line...
doctors, lawyers, Indians...
times are tight. It's tight.
Pressure's just too great.
Man can't work all of 'em.
You go in the door... I got to close
this fucker or I don't eat lunch,
or I don't win a Cadillac.
We work too hard, George.
Remember when we were... when we
were selling Glen Ross Farms?
Didn't we sell
a bunch of that?
- They came in...
- They fucked it up.
- They did.
- They killed the goose. And now...
- We're stuck with this...
- Stuck with this fucking shit.
- This shit.
- It's too...
- It is.
- You get a bad month...
they put you on this board.
Some contest board.
- It's not right.
- It's not right to the customers.
I know, it's... hey. What did I learn
as a kid on Western?
Don't sell a guy one car.
Sell him five cars over 15 years.
- That's right.
- You're goddamn right, it's right.
Guys come in..."Oh, the blah,
blah, blah. I know what I'll do.
I'll go out and rob everybody
blind and go to Argentina
'cause nobody ever
thought of this before."
So they kill the goose
and the man's worked all his life...
- That's right.
- He's got to cower in his boots...
Boots, yes...
For some fucking "Sell 10,000,
win the steak knives."
- What do you do?
- What can you do?
What can you do
if you don't have the leads?
If you do not
have the goddamn leads!
Mr. Spannel?
Sheldon Levene.
I was speaking
to your wife earlier?
Come in.
- "Cats and dogs," huh?
- Yeah.
Oh, "cats and dogs."
Oh, I see you're
interested in fishing.
- Yeah.
- I've fished myself... many years.
Muskee, Wisconsin.
Ooh, a beauty.
- Where's the missus?
- Out at the PTA.
- Ahh.
- What was this in reference...?
I spoke to your wife
earlier on the phone.
I called, I'm in town
with Rio Rancho.
Yes, I'm sorry. She said you had
some sort of award?
Yes, I was speaking to the people
in my sales organization...
my representatives in this area...
and Mr. Spannel...
your name is Larry.
Mind if I call you Larry?
All right, Larry.
We had a consultant,
and he made me...
he made me an offer.
He offered me $230,000
to promote a sales plan...
to present investment opportunities
in Rio Rancho to the public.
Well, I said, "Hell,
let me save you the 230,
and pass the savings
along to the investor."
My people immediately said,
"Whoa, how do you do that?
How can you present
investment opportunities
without television,
without magazine ads?"
I said, "You take
something this good,
you go to a man...
has invested in the past...
you go to him direct and offer
the money to him... rebate.
And don't give it
to this expert."
So you're here
to sell me some land?
No, I wouldn't try
to sell you...
I leave that to the salesmen
and people who want to own land.
I think something
has to be fed,
watered and painted,
but don't invest in it.
That motto has stood me
in good stead.
- Mister...
- Just call me Shelly.
I have never
been afraid of familiarity.
I'm walking out the door.
I've got to pick up my wife at the...
Let's take my car.
We'll pick her up together.
Spoke to the little woman
on the phone... can't wait to meet her.
No, we're going
over to our relatives'.
- She didn't say anything about that.
- I'm sure she forgot.
- I'm on a plane to Florida...
- I'm sorry if we put you out.
You didn't put me out.
I'm just trying to think, Larry.
You know, that's the only parcel
that I've got.
You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna go back to the computer,
I'm gonna pull another one, and we're
gonna speak to your relatives, too.
- No, no, no.
- C'mon, you're a busy man, so am I.
My God, I'm in the act
of giving a gift away.
Look, I don't want to buy land.
I don't want to invest in land.
I have nothing. She took the call
without my knowledge.
I have no business
that I wish to transact.
I don't want to tell you
how to handle your wife.
My wife filled in a form, and we
have been plagued for the last year...
That's the situation
I'm trying to alleviate, Larry.
No, no.
Do you understand?
Thank you. No.
- Roma, man... he don't care.
- He don't care.
He's sitting on top of the world.
He's got good leads, good prospects.
- Sales, sales.
- Sales contests.
- That's what I'm saying.
- Times turn hard, they bounce you out.
If they bounce you with no
confidence...
That's what I'm saying.
That's what I'm saying to you.
If they get you
on a bad beat...
and you got to go out there,
get a new job...
- With no...
- With no confidence...
Yes.
I'll tell you what the hard part is...
to stop thinking like a goddamn slave.
You say the Nazis
in Europe...
"If they came in my door"...
bullshit, the time is now.
What do you do now?
Some guy pissing in your face.
Cocksucker...
wants to break your rice bowl.
Mitch and Murray, fuck you.
What I say... fuck you!
Sitting on the good leads.
George, we're men here.
Yes.
And I'll tell you...
I'll tell you what the hard part is.
- What?
- Starting up.
Standing up.
Breaking free of this bullshit,
this enslavement to some guy,
'cause he's got the upper hand.
This is the difference...
listen to me, George.
Now Jerry Graff went
into business for himself.
He said, "I'm going on my own."
And he was free, you understand me?
I'll tell you... I'll tell you
what somebody should do.
What?
Somebody should stand up
and strike back.
Somebody should do something
to them.
- What?
- Something to pay them back.
Someone should hurt them,
Mitch and Murray.
- Somebody should hurt them?
- Yeah.
- How?
- Someone should do something
- To hurt them where they live.
- What?
Someone should rob the office.
That's what I'm saying.
If we were that kind of guy
to hold up the joint and trash it,
it looks like robbery,
we take the leads out of the files
and we go to Jerry Graff.
And we take the fucking
Glengarry leads! Huh?
Yeah, Mr. Nyborg? Ah, Mr. Nyborg,
Sheldon Levene.
I was speaking to your wife earlier.
That's right.
I'd like to speak to you
about awarding you your prize.
We're coming to the end
of our fiscal year,
I'd really like to get it
off the books before...
yes, the prize
for Consolidated Properties.
The information you requested
on Rio Rancho.
Now, I'm in town only for...
well, let me see.
I suppose I could
swing by tonight. Yes. Uh-huh.
When do you think
it might be more convenient?
As I said,
I could swing by tonight...
well, of course,
you speak to your wife.
Grace, I'm gonna need
a first-class seat,
passport, 10,000 in cash,
put that with the negotiable
papers, if you would.
And put me
on the telex hookup... yes?
Well, when do you think
Mrs. Nyborg might be back?
All train compartments
smell vaguely of shit.
It gets so you don't
mind it.
That's the worst thing
that I can confess.
You know how long it took me
to get there? A long time.
When you die you're gonna regret
the things you don't do.
You think you're queer?
I'm gonna tell you something.
We're all queer.
You think you're a thief? So what?
You get befuddled
by a middle-class morality?
Get shut of it.
Shut it out.
You cheat on your wife,
you did it. Live with it.
You fuck little girls,
so be it.
There's an absolute morality?
Maybe.
And then what?
If you think there is,
go ahead, be that thing.
Bad people go to hell?
I don't think so.
You think that,
act that way.
A hell exists on earth?
Yes. I won't live in it.
That's me.
Did you ever take a dump, made you
feel like you slept for 12 hours?
- Did I...?
- Yes.
- I don't know.
- Or a piss?
Great meals fade
in reflection.
Everything else gains.
Do you know why?
'Cause it's only food.
This shit we put in us,
keeps us going...
it's only food.
The great fucks
you may have had,
what do you remember
about them?
- What do I remember?
- Yeah.
I don't know.
For me,
I'm saying what it is,
it's probably not the orgasm.
Some broad's forearm
on your neck,
something her eyes did.
There was this sound she made.
Or it's me in the...
I'm telling you...
I'm in bed the next day,
she brought me caf au lait,
gives me a cigarette,
my balls feel like concrete.
Eh?
What I'm saying,
what is our life?
Our life is looking forward
or it's looking back.
That's it.
That's our life.
Where's the moment?
And what is it
we're so afraid of?
Loss. What else?
The bank closes, we get sick,
my wife died on a plane?
The stock market collapsed?
What of these things happen?
None of them.
We worry anyway. Why?
What could we get
for them?
- For them?
- For the leads.
What could we get
for the leads?
I don't know. 10 bucks a throw.
15 maybe. I don't know.
For the leads, you're saying?
Say somebody took them,
- Went to Jerry Graff?
- Yeah. How many leads do we have?
The Glengarry?
The premium leads?
I've got to think they've got 500.
Say 500 leads.
You're saying a fella could take
those leads and sell them to Graff?
The leads to Graff.
Yes. I was saying... yeah.
A guy could take...
like anything else, it seems to me,
that is negotiable,
a guy could sell them.
- How do you know he'd buy them?
- Because I worked for him.
- You didn't talk to him?
- No. What do you mean?
- Did I talk to him about this?
- Yeah.
Are you just talking about this,
or are we just talking about it?
- Just speaking about it.
- Speaking about it as an idea?
- Yes.
- We're not actually talking about it.
- No.
- Talking about it as a robbery.
As a robbery? No.
- Well...
- Hey.
So all this...
you didn't actually call Graff?
- You didn't talk to him?
- Not actually, no.
- You didn't?
- No, not actually.
- Did you?
- What did I say?
- What did you say?
- I said, "Not actually."
Fuck you care, George?
We're just talking.
- We are?
- Yes.
- Because it's a crime.
- Robbery. That's right.
It is a crime.
- It's also very safe.
- You're actually talking about this.
- That's right.
- You're going to steal the leads.
- Have I said that?
- Are you?
- Did I say that?
- Did you talk to Graff?
- What did I say?
- What did he say?
What did he say?
He'd buy them.
You're gonna steal...
you're gonna steal the Glengarry
leads and sell them to Graff?
- Yes.
- What's he gonna pay?
He figures there's 500 leads,
let's say 10 bucks apiece,
- That's $2,500 each.
- Each?
- "Each"?
- That's right, George.
- You're saying me?
- No, you and me.
Yeah. That's exactly
what I'm saying. $2,500 apiece.
You and me for one night's work,
and a job with Graff
- Working the premium leads.
- A job with Graff?
- Is that what I said?
- He'd give me a job?
He could take you on.
Yes.
Hello?
I was dialing the direct line
to my daughter's room.
Sheldon Levene.
She's in...
well, yeah, I'm sure she's asleep.
But... where's the duty nurse?
They canceled her...
well, let me talk...
who am I speaking to?
I'll have the money there
tomorrow.
It's a big decision,
George.
At times a guy
has got to make one.
It's a big decision
and it's a big reward.
$2,500 and a job, it's a big reward
for one night's work.
Yes.
Sometimes a guy...
sometimes, a man
if he wants a reward...
That's absolutely right.
He'll do one thing,
one thing on one night.
That's absolutely right.
The thing is, it's got to be tonight.
What?
What, what?
The leads ain't going to leave?
They bring those leads up,
wave them under your nose,
tomorrow they take them downtown,
parcel them out.
A guy wants those leads,
he's gonna have to get them tonight.
Tonight is the thing.
Talk about a chance.
It's when a chance
presents itself.
You got to go
in there tonight.
- You.
- I'm sorry?
- Me?
You have to go in.
You have to get the leads.
- I do?
- It's not something for nothing.
I took you in on this.
You have to go. It's your thing.
I've made a deal with Graff.
I can't go in.
I've spoken out on this too much.
I've got a big mouth.
"The fucking leads," et cetera,
"the tight-ass company," blah, blah.
- They'll know when you go to Graff.
- What will they know?
That I stole the leads?
I didn't steal the leads.
I'm gonna go to the movies.
Then I'm gonna have a late drink
- At the Como Inn with a friend.
- Dave.
Yes?
You want me to break into the office
tonight and steal the leads?
- Yes.
- No.
- Oh, yes, George.
- What does that mean?
Listen to this. I have an alibi.
I'm going to the Como Inn.
Why? Why?
The place gets robbed,
they're going to come looking for me.
Why? Because I probably did it.
Let me ask you this...
are you going to turn me in?
What if you don't get caught?
They come to you,
are you going to turn me in?
- Why would they come to me?
- They're going to come to everybody.
- Why would I do it?
- You wouldn't, George.
That's why I'm talking to you now.
They come to you,
- Are you going to turn me in?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
Uh-huh. George...
when they come to me,
if I have to go in there,
and if I get caught...
- They come to me...
- You don't have to go in.
I have to go in, see?
That's something I have to do.
- Why?
Are you going to give me $ 7,500?
75? I thought we were
splitting five grand.
I lied, all right? Your end is 25,
my end is my own concern.
Now, stick with me here.
If they come to me,
I'm caught, they're going to ask me
who were accomplices.
- Me.
- Absolutely.
That's ridiculous.
To the law, you're
an accessory before the fact.
- I didn't ask to be.
- Tough luck, because you are.
- Because you told me about it?
- That's right.
Why are you doing this
to me, Dave?
Why are you talking this way to me?
I don't understand.
- Why are you doing this at all?
- None of your fucking business.
Just in or out?
You tell me.
You're out,
you take the consequences.
- I do?
- That's right.
- And why is that?
- Because you listened.
Well, when will
Mrs. Nyborg be back?
You know, I hate to keep
calling you this late, Bruce,
but I feel a responsibility,
I must say. When you have...
You know, they say,
"You don't buy it, you rent it."
- Huh?
- The thing.
You really...
what do you keep?
I mean, you don't keep
anything, really.
- No.
- Security.
Things. Things.
- You know?
- Mm-hmm.
It's just... you try
to stave off insecurity.
You can't do it.
- No.
- No. That's what I'm telling you.
Stocks, bonds, objects of art,
real estate, what are they?
An opportunity.
To what? To make money?
Perhaps. To lose money?
Perhaps.
To indulge and to learn
about ourselves? Perhaps.
So fucking what?
What is it? They're an opportunity.
That's all they are.
They're an event.
A guy comes to you,
you make a call. You send in a card,
I have these properties
I would like for you to see.
What does this mean?
What do you want it to mean?
You see what I'm saying?
Things happen to you.
Glad I met you.
I'm glad I met you,
James.
I want to show you
something.
It may mean something to you,
it may not.
I don't know.
I don't know anymore.
What is that?
Florida.
Glengarry Highlands.
Bullshit.
And maybe that's true.
And that's what I said.
But look at this.
What is this?
This is a piece of land.
Listen to what I'm going
to tell you now.
- What happened?
- Where do you work?
I work, yes.
I work here.
- What is it? What happened?
- Robbery.
Williamson. Williamson,
did they get the contracts?
All right, tell me.
Now. Tell me.
- They stole the contracts?
- Excuse me, sir.
- Did they get my contract?
- Excuse me, fella.
- Did they?
- Would you excuse us?
Don't fuck with me, fella.
I'm talking about a Cadillac car
- That you owe me.
- They didn't get your contract.
- I filed it before I left.
- They didn't get my contracts?
They got... excuse me.
Fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Williamson!
- Williamson, open the fucking door.
- Who are you?
- They didn't get the contracts.
- Did they?
They got... listen to me.
They got some of them.
- Some of them?
- Who told you?
Who told me?
Who told me we had a robbery?
We got a fucking board
up on the window.
Who is this? Yes.
Yes, I confess. I did it.
Now, leave me
a second here, please.
- Okay, now, talk to me.
- I'm still trying to sort it out.
- So far...
- Talk to me. Talk to me.
They got some
of the contracts?
Lingk. James Lingk,
which I closed last night.
- You closed it last night?
- Yes.
- I filed it. It went down.
- You filed it?
- James Lingk?
- Yes.
- It was sent downtown?
- Yes, all right?
I filed it last night.
It went to the bank.
- It went downtown, all right?
- You filed it?
Then I'm over the fucking top,
you owe me a Cadillac.
- I don't...
- I don't want to hear any shit.
I don't give a shit.
Lingk puts me over the top.
You filed it. It went downtown.
Now you owe me the car.
- The robbery makes difficult...
- Fuck you! You owe me the car!
See, 'cause this is how
we keep score, "bubby."
You told me, "Close thus,
and so you get the car."
- I got it.
- Would you excuse us, please?
You hear what I said?
Do you hear what I said?
Hey, pal!
Your excuses are your own!
"Recontact James Lingk.
6:00 p.m. Morton Grove."
Ah-ha.
When do you expect
her in?