How long you gonna be?.
Be right out,
you're a pain!
Hey, American.
I'm still here, gettin' a manicure.
Things okay?.
Gettin' tanned?. Don't get burned!
Bruno's here too.
You got a crap body!
Is Bruno here?.
He's over there.
You doin' a lamp?.
It's 2,000.
How much are you
supposed to get this week?.
9,200.
Sure?. It was less last week.
Yes, Don Ciro 9,200.
Another 2,000 euro and we're even.
Don Ciro, don't take all day.
He's slow.
Hurry, so we can go home.
Things okay out there?.
Keep your eyes open.
That's it.
Put paper cups in.
Toilet paper.
- Then, Mom?.
- Some shampoo.
A mozzarella...
Shampoo, not bath oil!
You're rushin' me!
And you're drivin' me crazy!
Hurry up, there are
more groceries to deliver.
- Nothing else?.
- No.
- Be back later.
- Don't get yourself lost.
- Simone.
- Toto, what's up?.
- What's happening?.
- I'm workin'.
Know what happened?.
They arrested Vitale and Bon Bon.
Really?.
- Got somethin' to eat?.
- Yeah, but it's not mine.
Bye, see you.
Carmela, ma'am!
Hi, Boxer.
Two doses, two doses!
Please, give me a dose!
Gaetano, check it!
One, two, three...
Goodbye.
Don Ciro, be more punctual.
I'll pass it on.
Eleven and twelve.
See if he wants coffee.
No, but thank you anyway....
I'll show you out.
Have a good day.
Four hundred...
Five hundred.
The same amount again?.
I've said a hundred times
I can't manage like this.
Don Carlo...
Did you tell them I can't manage
on this chickenfeed?.
I have to pay rent, lights, water.
I can't survive,
I'm strapped with debts.
- I'll pass it on.
- You always say that!
Are you mockin' me?.
I don't get it!
Listen,
I've got a son to support,
for forty years
I've kept him off the streets,
he's unemployed.
What can I do,
go over to the other side?.
They know, I served you honestly
for forty years.
My wife's in jail,
is this the thanks we get?.
Are we crazy?.
Do I have to raise hell?.
Silvana!
May I?.
Come on in!
Maria!
The bill?.
Talk to Mom.
Put this in your pocket.
Thank you.
Carabinieri on the street!
He's comin' out!
I'm the best, number one!
So?.
Go, Marco!
- I'll blast these roaches!
- Who do you think you're fighting?.
I'm number one! Tony Montana!
The world is ours!
You don't know
who you're up against!
I'm Tony Montana!
- I'm the powerhouse!
- Yeah!
Come here.
Shit Colombians,
they're everywhere.
See, Colombians everywhere.
You really looked like Scarface.
You were good.
Now it all has to be ours,
the whole world.
Miami, all of it.
My friend, got stuff?.
You got stuff?.
- Got good stuff?.
- You got money?.
- Sure, you got coke?.
- What do you want to pay?.
Me?. 50.
- 55, can you do it?.
- No, 55 is too much, 50.
You sure?.
Wait here for me.
Where's Smarty?.
Hey, kid!
Give him the money.
- Is it all here?.
- Yeah.
- Okay?.
- Yes.
- Want to see it?.
- I want to try it.
I gave you the money!
Wait!
Open your hand.
It's good.
Give me all of it!
Grab the money!
Giovanni, I brought the kids.
Come in.
You know very well why you're here.
Too much ruckus going on in my area,
because I'm the boss here.
That's just you sayin'.
If I had you come here, I know.
No back-talk
or I'll smash your face!
- What happened?.
- For the moment, nothing.
Get me?.
I can't be made to look bad
because of two kids like you.
The next time
I hear anything about you,
I'll blow your heads off.
- If it's like you say...
- Shut up when I'm talking.
Then if I come to realize
you're worth something,
which I'll determine and I'll decide,
you can work for me.
Is that clear?.
Show them out.
"I'll smash your face!"
And I'll tear your beard!
Without a T-shirt.
"Sweet Pea", looked like a bum.
A real bum.
He is a bum! Did you see
who he sent to get us?.
If that guy's the boss here,
then here we can be the bosses.
If a guy like him is boss here,
this area is ours!
I'll live for 30 years
if he's boss here.
Sure, because he's a retard!
Get it?. I'll live for 30 years.
But he could at least shave!
Shave!
"I'll smash your face!"
Let's go have a snort to spite him.
We've got everything,
we can do like we want.
Anyway, he's a fat shit-ass.
He bugged you?.
He showers once a week!
"I'll blow your heads off! "
Roberto!
Let's go, it's too small.
- But the methane one's big.
- No, it's small.
- Can I finish measuring?.
- No, we're wasting time.
- I have to take some shots.
- What a bore with these pictures!
Let's go!
Just look at this.
It's disgusting down there.
Here is perfect.
It's perfect.
We're near the highway,
the trucks can get really close,
they dump the earth
and cover all the water.
Perfect.
Franco, it's 85 meters.
Get the length too.
Come here.
Dante.
Hello, everything okay?.
This is Roberto.
- It's time we made room for youth.
- We need new energy.
Take a few more shots.
Did you hear?.
They bombed me,
at the cement plant.
A whole wall came down,
slowly.
Be careful.
Zio resolved it.
I'd forgotten to pay
for some land I'd bought.
- An injunction against payment?.
- Yeah!
- What do you think?.
- It's fine.
- Can we fill this quarry?.
- Sure can.
Tell Zio it's fine.
Remember, everything clean:
terracing, solid stuff...
Or the redevelopment agency
will break our balls.
Don't worry,
you emptied it and I'll fill it.
All the pieces have to be cut
and the sizes worked out.
They want 120 of these.
Six and seven are identical.
Here the satin is cut on the bias.
It's all hand-hemmed.
Is it tough?.
The models aren't hard,
I can do it.
Eight hundred items in two months,
is our request.
Keep in mind
we start at 50 euros per item.
You've seen the models,
the price is good,
estimate and make your offers.
Thirty euro, 30 days?.
Don't go any lower.
This is high fashion,
it's not pret-a-porter.
Forty-five, in two months.
- Ms. Zamarion!
- Yes?.
Thirty-eight, forty.
That's a very interesting proposal.
Thirty-five, thirty-five,
excellent workmanship
and delivery times respected.
Thirty, thirty!
Please,
we're not imposing anything!
Did we say thirty, thirty?.
At this point
twenty-eight, thirty!
Thirty, twenty-five!
I can't lose this bid.
Come here, there's some bubbly!
Are they coming?.
- I don't think so.
- Why not?.
Five days less for delivery,
we'll have to work overtime,
and I'll do nights...
What's odd about that?.
They're talking overtime pay.
They'll get it!
Am I scared of a little overtime?.
Like the last time?.
Don't worry,
this time it's a sure thing.
- They've lost their trust.
- I know.
- I asked you to talk to them.
- You do it, please.
You're on closer terms,
they respect you.
Do me this favor.
Don't say no, go talk to them.
You know I'm fond of you,
I'll have to make
a gold statue to you!
I'll go down and see the accountant
for the money.
Sorry, how much is this?.
Ten thousand.
It's not enough, I need more.
Twice that at least.
Mr. Enzo,
you're already "complicated".
Yes, but for personal affairs.
I need this for work.
I'll give it back in three months.
But this isn't enough.
If you don't need it
and it's not enough,
I'll take it back.
It's best for you.
Don't be like that, listen,
I need at least double!
It's no risk,
you'll earn from it, right?.
What can I say?.
I'll pass it on,
can you make-do for now?.
Yes, I'll take it.
Congratulations, Mr. Pasquale.
Thank you.
We met yesterday.
I need your help.
I am having trouble with work.
I have to get into
haute couture right away,
but for me
it is very difficult.
I need help.
You are
a great master,
you are very important for me.
You teach ten lessons
to workers in my factory.
I pay you in cash,
2,000 euros a lesson
for ten lessons.
We work together,
but no one knows it,
just the two of us.
I need your help.
Think it over.
- What's the cloth like?.
- Come and see.
I've got nothin'!
Don't move!
They must have gone over to his side,
or they'd have arrested
me first and then those other guys.
Believe me?. All of them were there
when I called you.
I said: Check out this car,
it's suspect.
This stuff here is ours.
My gun!
Check this stuff out,
there should be fifty-six.
Good, Toto, this is for you.
How can I get working with you?.
We'll let you know.
- Did you turn off the water?.
- Of course!
- Can I help out?.
- No, you'll get wet.
Doesn't matter!
Come and see.
Careful not to slip.
- Is it coming from the well?.
- No, I think it's from the pipe.
Careful, water's coming in.
See if you can close it.
It's closed,
but it's the pipe that...
I'd give you a hand, but...
What a great day!
Push it all in one direction.
I thought I'd be having coffee!
- Nice coffee, huh?.
- I'll have some next time.
Totore, things okay?.
- Can I say hi?.
- No, you gotta leave.
Go down with these bags!
You have to move!
Ma'am, go around the other way.
- What's going on?.
- Everything's fine, leave.
Lucia?.
Come closer.
- What's your name?.
- Luigi.
- Are you scared?.
- No.
- Sure?.
We'll see.
- Are you strong?.
- Yeah!
Let's see how strong you are.
Why are you shaking?.
No?.
- See how strong this kid is.
- Come closer!
- Are you scared?.
- Yes.
Now you're a man.
Nothin'! Everything's okay!
When I did my piercing,
I got an infection.
Let's see.
You went and did it there?.
- I'd like to have it on my eyebrow.
- Stinks.
It's nicer there, you're right.
It's gonna rain.
Everything's okay!
A car's coming!
It went in!
It's going in!
Check out this other one!
Everything's okay!
Sorry I'm late, the Councilman,
City Hall, the traffic...
- My father.
- How do you do.
I'm glad he's with you
you're a good person.
He's in your care.
He's a clever guy.
I don't doubt that but...
- Having work is important to him.
- Of course.
I tried so hard
to find him work in Naples...
- Where do you work?.
- In the hospital, intensive care.
A bad division.
I tried to get him in,
but I have no connections.
He's all set now.
You did something no one else did.
I thank you, you raised him well.
Have you always worked in Naples?.
No, also in Trieste, Udine,
- Venice...
- That's where we're going.
I told him about Venice.
He's excited, it's his first time.
Dad, we have a plane.
Did you bring some things?.
What's that, your gym bag?.
- Goodbye.
- He's in your care.
- What do you pay for disposal?.
- Today I'm paying 50.
Your offer?.
We can halve your costs,
25 cents a kilo.
That's good,
but is it all "clean",
like they say in the United States?.
Since it's toxic waste,
certification,
storage and transportation.
- Is there a contract to look over?.
- Of course.
In case you're wondering,
the disposal cycle
goes to the disposal area
in Marcianise.
I'm telling you in fairness.
Thank you for the information,
but my only concern
is that it's "clean".
You can rest assured of that.
We can dispose of all the waste
that you produce in a year.
Eight hundred tons.
It's not a problem.
That's a lot.
My concern is disposal.
We serve various companies,
you can check.
I already have!
Don't worry.
As far as I can see,
there's maximum transparency.
Absolutely.
- The warehouses at Teverola?.
- We use them for tires.
Exactly.
Will we put the tannery waste
in the quarry?.
- Don't talk foolishness.
- Where then?.
Check the European catalogue.
Here they are, 04.
The ones in red,
are among the most dangerous.
"Exhausted degreasing baths
with solvents, no liquid phase."
No, no good.
Then 4-11:
"Waste containing halogenated
compounds from operations
of manufacturing and finishing."
These are good.
It's stuff the earth absorbs,
we'll mix it with compost.
Fertilizer!
All that leaves is
Milan's sweeping refuse,
that's 60 trucks.
- The quarries at San Felice?.
- They're too small.
I don't think so, look.
Let me see.
They're too small
and they're shallow,
they're no good.
Yes... I've got
ten contracts out of ten.
Is he near you?.
Put him on.
I'll talk to him.
I told him, everything's okay.
- Do you like traveling?.
- Sure!
We'll take more trips.
Everyone here works in boats?.
Everyone, firemen, ambulances...
- Funerals.
- I've already seen two.
Even the dead go by boat!
Wow, they've got so many!
Steady me.
There's nothing here.
Nothing?.
Are you sure?.
Oh God!
Look what's here!
See?. It's like you said!
Look here!
A Beretta 93!
A Kalashnikov!
See if they're loaded.
- Check.
- It's unloaded.
Look, an M12!
This is the 921.
That bearded bum!
We'll see how
he blows my head off!
Enough for Casale di Principe!
Everybody!
Won't blow my head off now, eh?.
Should I put two in?.
And Nikita's?.
And the 38?.
- Want to see how I can shoot?.
- Show me!
Show me!
Aim there!
I hit it!
We'll blow
the Colombians' heads off!
That's good.
Everything okay?.
With love and feeling.
- What is it?.
- Your wife's on the phone.
Tell her not to wait up.
Don't get tired out, need anything?.
No, thanks.
- You'll lock up?.
- Yes.
Goodnight.
Xian?.
I have been waiting for you.
- I got lost.
- I am happy you came.
Please sit down.
We are cooking fish.
I've already eaten.
Try a typical Chinese dish.
Okay?.
Just cooked, it is good.
Meat with bell peppers.
I've already eaten.
Taste.
We use chopsticks.
- I don't know how to use them.
- Try!
I am pleased,
we have a little toast.
We go to the factory.
Why not?.
I put a pillow in here.
It's dangerous.
I already told you,
no one can know, just us.
It's better for both of us.
- Won't I need air?.
- No, there's an opening.
I'll open the front window,
so air will come in.
Forgive me.
Are we sure?.
It is best for both of us,
because it is dangerous.
- Does air come through here?.
- Yes.
And I'll open the window too.
Please come in, Mr. Pasquale.
All are waiting for you.
All are very happy.
I told them who you are
and all are happy.
What a nice factory!
More than 80 people.
I'm moved.
What can I say?.
To do this work
you need lots of patience...
...and lots of love.
For the first lesson...
...I'll cut out a bodice.
Let's begin.
You must place patterns carefully.
Spread the cloth well...
Maria, are you asleep?.
Where have I been, in China?.
They were all bowing to me.
Master!
They called me "master"!
- Did you know the Chinese can cook?.
- The Chinese?.
Darn right!
They cooked a delicious bass!
There were boxes everywhere
and they put me in the trunk!
Both coming and going.
I need some sleep.
Here.
I have to sleep a few hours.
What's this money?.
Where did you get it?.
I have to sleep.
Help me understand.
I talked to my son this morning,
he said: "Mom I'm leaving,
I'm going to be a secessionist."
Really?.
What did you say?.
He's convinced,
he said: "We're great,
we'll win the war,
the others are nobodies".
War?. A bunch of morons
warring against us?.
You have to stop him.
This side is the right side.
Have you seen what's happening?.
There are killings every day.
Don't say anything to anybody,
not even your husband.
Who'd ever tell him!
When he gets out, what'll he do?.
Father and son will kill each other?.
No, because your son
will stay right here.
They'll all come to a bad end.
Do you feel so sure about that?.
I don't.
I do.
When will we see each other again?.
When you change sides.
Want to stay faithful?. Go ahead!
You go your way and I go another.
But we can still have
a pizza together with friends.
I'm telling you again,
friend, enemy.
We've known each other for so long,
why go with them?.
Remember when we were brothers?.
Now we're enemies.
I'm telling you, if you don't
change sides, we might kill you
or you might kill us.
Because we're at war,
people are dying every day.
- You could have stayed with us...
- What for?.
I'm best on the other side.
Bye, Simone.
Want a little Sambuca?.
You'll be right off, don't worry.
Takes time.
Careful when you go out.
Thank you.
Gaetano, show him.
- It's big.
- You're right.
- Enzo!
- What?.
Do I have to tell you?.
It's awesome.
I like it.
Like it?.
You look great.
Toto, show it off.
It's really nice.
- How many so far?.
- 45 doses.
Okay.
It's good stuff.
How many so far?.
Fifty-two,
plus four that guy's still got.
- Understand?.
- Yeah.
I'll get back to you later.
- How many?.
- Fifty-two and that guy's got four.
Then we'll total it.
Hello!
Nice, eh?.
Hi, gorgeous!
Girls!
Beautiful!
Alessia?.
What are you doing here?. Get out.
I don't want to see you around here.
We have to go crying
at the prison gates?.
What I went through with your father
was enough for me.
Good morning, Jacob.
- Are you alright?.
- Fine, thank you, and you?.
Have a good trip?.
A very nice trip.
- Do you have documents?.
- It's humanitarian aid.
Yes, it's humanitarian aid.
- Everything okay?.
- Yes.
They've already called an ambulance.
Get back to work!
Go back to work!
What happened?.
As they were dumping,
two drums opened
and spilled on a truck driver.
- Have you already called zio?.
- No!
- They wanted to call an ambulance!
- I'll take care of this.
Pay the truckers
and tell them to fuck off.
- Who'll drive the trucks?.
- Don't the blacks know how?.
Can you drive?.
They can't even ride bikes!
I'll handle this.
Don't let them touch the trucks,
they're ours.
Roberto, wait here.
Calm down!
You made a mistake, you had us doing
a job we shouldn't have!
It just happened!
- I'm taking the red one.
- No, that's mine!