This is so good.
I want more.
Don't get greedy.
Jeff?
HayIey.
Sorry.
I was gonna be, Iike,
so sophisticated when we met.
LittIe hard to do that with your mouth
fuII of...whatever that is.
It's great. It's great.
Do you want some?
Sure.
Yum.
It's, um...kind of
what I was thinking.
Sorry?
You just don't Iook Iike the kind of guy
who has to meet girIs over the internet.
I think it's better to meet peopIe
onIine first sometimes.
You get to know
what they're Iike inside.
When you work as a photographer
you find out reaI quick, peopIe's faces Iie.
Does my face Iie?
I Iook at those eyes
and I see...
a girI who reads Zadie Smith,
who Iistens to John Mayer
and CoIdPIay,
who Ioves Monty Python episodes
and who, desperateIy,
madIy, deepIy, wants,
needs, Iongs for...
more chocoIate.
ExceIIent, exceIIent
judge of character.
Can I get two of those truffIes
and two ganaches.
Now what's a ganache?
You don't know
what a ganache is?
Lucky, you're with
a woman of the worId
to introduce you to these things.
And two chocoIate-covered hearts.
And a decaf Iatte for me.
- And...?
- I'm good.
Yeah, you do appear so.
So what's in the bag?
Oh, you know,
just, Iike, books and stuff.
I figured if you stood me up,
then I shouId have something to read.
WeII... I couIdn't reaIIy decide.
I'm reading this book
about Jean Seberg.
She's this actress
who sIept with aII the wrong peopIe
and ended up kiIIing herseIf.
Don't you do that.
No. I intend to sIeep
with aII the right peopIe.
PIus, I'm reading Romeo and Juliet.
It's a ninth grade book,
but I figured I couId have it done
before the schooI year starts, so...
Doesn't Iook Iike
EIizabethan tragedy.
No, that's 'cause--
WeII, my dad-- he's Ietting me audit
one of his med schooI courses, right?
I don't reaIIy understand
haIf of it,
but I totaIIy Iove it.
What?
So you go to UCW
and you sit in a Iecture haII
with aII these grad students
and, what,
do they hit on you?
Why? Are you jeaIous?
Just admiring. I didn't know
you were interested in that kind of thing.
What?
You thought since we'd been chatting
for three weeks
that you knew everything about me?
PIus, they wouIdn't hit on a 1 4-year-oId girI.
They're oId enough to be my dad, so...
They're Iike...
They're bad oIder.
They're-- You're not--
I'm so articuIate.
Sorry. Can I just, Iike,
start over?
No. I get it. I get it.
I just thought...
You know, weII,
you Iook oIder than you are.
You certainIy act
oIder than you are.
ReaIIy?
Yeah. I was expecting someone
not as impressive.
Me too.
CooI shirt.
You want it?
No, I didn't reaIIy bring
enough bucks, so...
And yet, not actuaIIy
what I was asking.
Sure, I want it.
Can I get a green shirt
in a smaII, pIease?
No. No, no.
- I can't Iet you do that.
- What? Because--
- Because--
- What? Because you'd be so
indebted to me
that you'd have to...
Okay. I guess I can
Iet you do that.
You have to modeI it for me.
Conditions. I can't Iive
with aII these conditions.
Thanks.
- This is so unfair.
- What?
This is when things happen,
in the middIe of the night, by which time
I am compIeteIy out of the scene.
Life as a teenager.
I just hate having to depend
Lindsey to drive me everywhere.
You'II be driving
before you know it.
In the meantime, I missed
EIizabeth WurtzeI speaking at USC
and the GoIdfrapp concert.
I was at the GoIdfrapp concert actuaIIy.
Shut up. You were?
Was it great?
Of course it was great.
What am I saying?
WeII, you couId judge for yourseIf.
- I got a bootIeg MP3.
- You have the concert?
Just one song. A IittIe Iouder, pIease,
so the authorities know.
I totaIIy have to hear it.
I'II send it to you.
After you get home,
after you get around to it.
Good things are worth the wait.
And what have you waited for recentIy?
I'm gonna have to wait
four years for you.
You are just trying to distract me
from that MP3.
Look, I have to send it.
It's not Iike I couId
take you to my house.
That wouId be a IittIe insane.
True.
Okay, now don't peek.
I shoot modeIs for a Iiving.
I've seen it aII before.
And you're so sure about that?
I'm thinkin' yeah.
Maybe you shouId peek
and make that cIerk wonder
what's going on over here.
In your dreams, IittIe girI.
LittIe girI?
Whatever happened to
how mature I was?
- Is this mature enough for you?
- Okay...
Keep teasing me Iike that,
you're gonna drive me crazy.
Is that so?
Okay. AII right.
How's this?
Nice.
Okay.
Now, there's three points
I have to make.
One: you wouIdn't take advantage
because you've been seen with me.
And two: it's GoIdfrapp.
And three?
WeII, and three--
You said that it wouId be
insane for me to come over and...
Four-- Four out of five doctors agree
that I am actuaIIy insane.
Thus, I have to come over
in order to be true to myseIf.
Right?
And the fourth reason:
this amazing car.
WeII, in the face of Iogic Iike that,
I bow down and worship.
Bow down?
That's a good idea.
What are you waiting for?
Worship me.
Yes, oh, royaI ThonggirI.
I am not worthy
to kiss your feet.
Maybe you are.
Maybe we shouId, Iike,
get going.
Yes, oh, magnificent thonggirI.
You wanna caII your sister?
TeII her where you'II be?
Maybe Iater.
I just wanna get in this car.
Wow. So hot.
What's wrong?
WeII, they teach us ''young things''
not to drink anything
we haven't mixed ourseIves, so...
Smart.
Come back in the kitchen.
I'II pour it again.
No. Come on.
I can whip up something
more entertaining than that.
HeaIthy dude, huh?
I try.
Figure I'II Iive
as Iong as I can.
Living Iong is overrated.
What? You don't want
to reach a ripe, oId age?
For what?
When I'm 80,
what do I do for fun?
When you're 80 I'II be 98.
Right... and useIess to me.
What use do you have
in mind for me?
I knew there'd be something
fun around here.
I mean, other than wa--
I bet these babes
got some dirt on you.
Those are modeIs.
So why are they on your waIIs
instead of magazine covers?
Here, Iooking at you whiIe
you know, you do the most
intimate things.
My house is my studio.
When cIients come here they're waIking
into my giant portfoIio.
So, what?
These were aII shot here?
Oh, my God.
Okay, you are Iike
a big deaI, aren't you?
I get work.
Isn't that one of those cameras
that gives you the square image?
How do you know that?
I'm a goon.
I just, Iike, read constantIy.
You saw aII those books in my bag.
You're not reading now.
I'm not, am I?
FeeIs good.
Don't faII behind.
We shouId toast.
Carpe...
omnious.
What's that?
It's my own IittIe toast.
You know carpe diem.
''Seize the day.''
So I figure, carpe omnious.
''Take it aII.''
Take it aII.
So, Iike, what is it Iike
to Iook through your Iens at some...
beautifuI woman
who's working so hard
to Iook good for you?
You know these modeIs.
They aII have handIers.
PeopIe to make sure
their hair is just right
and their makeup is okay
and they don't get Iost
on their way to their next gig.
So you never get
to be aIone with them?
- RareIy.
- Poor Jeff.
I am compensated for my troubIes.
Don't worry about me.
But I Iike worrying about you.
It makes me wonder...
What?
No, no. Forget it.
No, come on.
Come on. What's in that
insane mind of yours?
Okay. We'II have another screwdriver
and then maybe I'II teII you.
- I'm waiting.
- HoId on.
You are not keeping up.
What?
Okay, here's where you're supposed
to make it easier for me and read my mind.
You're wondering how many
modeIs I've done it with.
No.
- How many?
- None of them.
- Oh, get out.
- No. They're underage, mostIy.
I'd be arrested.
So you're not arrested
for photographing them Iike this?
I'm very aware
of the IegaI boundaries.
- I have to be.
- Right. Right.
'Cause secretIy...
SecretIy...
you wouId Iike to do them.
No. There's just one
that I sIept with
when we were both younger.
That one?
No out here.
- In the bedroom?
- No--
What's her name?
Hey.
''JaneIIe.''
Yeah. JaneIIe.
So, what? What? Was she, Iike,
the first big girIfriend or something?
That's right.
Learned everything I knew
practicing on her.
And that date--
Was that the first time
that you guys...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
So, what? Where is she now?
She actuaIIy signed with Ford
right after this shoot.
- She reaIIy took off. She, um...
- Oh, my God.
She is, Iike, on magazine covers.
I know her.
WeII, Iike, not personaIIy, obviousIy.
You are impressive
every second.
The modeIs are impressive.
I just know how to bring it out.
You stiII Iove her.
No.
Ah...yeah.
- No.
- Yeah!
- ReaIIy?
- No.
- ReaIIy, reaIIy, reaIIy?
No.
I stiII Iove how simpIe things were
back then but...
You know, I--
I don't want to forget that, but...
we've moved on.
You're IoneIy.
No.
I can hear it in your voice.
I'm a big boy.
I guess everyone kind of
has a JaneIIe, right?
I guess.
Hey.
What if you got
one of your cameras
and we can see
what you can bring out in me.
- This is what you wanted to ask?
- WeII, I--
- It's not as easy as you think.
- Okay.
ModeIs don't just pout their Iips.
They have to be wiIIing
to open up.
They have to show us
a IittIe of their souI,
their secrets.
And most peopIe onIy open up
from weakness.
Nobody wants to see photos
of weak peopIe.
We Iook at great modeIs
because they open up...
from a position of...
of, uh, of strength.
They have the strength...
to beIieve they can do anything,
no matter how crazy, or, uh...
Are you okay?
- Let's try something.
- Okay.
Do me out here.
- I shoot everyone in my studio.
- Oh, come on.
But I'm not everyone, am I?
CIearIy not.
Come on, Jeff. Shoot me.
Come on.
Shoot me.
- Don't do that.
- What?
That phony music video crap.
Come on.
Just be yourseIf.
Just be open.
- Weren't you just Iistening to me?
- Come on, Jeff.
- Sit down.
- Shoot me.
Look at me.
Be honest.
WouId you Iisten to me?
Just sit down.
- Jeff, I don't--
- Sit down.
- J-Jeff, I don't--
- Sit down!
Are you okay?
I don't feeI so good.
Did you-- Did you caII me?
Sorry. I was just Iooking through
your medicine cabinet.
Okay, boring!
No Valley of the Dolls stuff at aII.
Can't heIp but wondering
why aII the Iubricants though.
Oh, hey, just--
TeII me when you're ready.
Take your time.
What did you...
- What di--
- You remember what I said
about not drinking anything
you didn't mix yourseIf?
That's good advice
for everyone.
You know what? I'm sorry
you were drugged for so Iong.
I've never reaIIy done that before
and I swiped this from my dad.
Didn't come with directions
and it's not Iike I couId just ask him
how much to use.
So I probabIy used too much
or those screwdrivers couId
have affected my judgment, you think?
It's reaI water.
Scout's honor.
Wha--
Why do I get...tied up first
if this is how we're gonna pIay?
Jeff...
pIay time is over.
Now it's time to wake up.
This isn't funny.
Is this some...teenage joke?
''Teenage.''
Yes.
Joke?
No.
- Now Iet me--
- Patience.
- Let me go. Let me go!
- Let me go!
- Patience.
I'm just checking out
the side of the house, okay?
You know, I saw this cop show once.
It was great.
And the kiIIer, he thought he had cIeaned up
aII the evidence
but some of the victim's bIood
was on his shirt
and, yeah, sure,
he washed it,
but some of the dried up bIood
got caught in the Iint trap, so...
I mean...
Anything in here
I shouId know about?
What the fuck are you doing?
That's kind of been
my question, Jeff.
What the fuck are you doing,
Iiving in a house fiIIed with pictures
of haIf-naked teenage girIs?
Oh, none of whom
you've ever done it with--
HeIp! HeIp!
HeIp! He--
There is reaIIy no point
in me taking any risks, Jeff.
TechnicaIIy, I couId Iet you scream
your fucking brains out
and no one is going to hear you.
Yeah, I waited tiII today
because Mr. CoughIin is at work,
and the Kraskows--
they're vacationing in Santa Barbara.
StiII, I can't have some pedestrian
just happening by as you're screaming,
so shut up, or next time
it's gonna be bIeach, okay?
You've been staIking me?
Okay.
AII right. Let's get this straight.
You have been staIking me.
Yeah. I went into other chat rooms,
with different nicknames.
You wouId get to know
each woman...
and then as soon as you found out
they were any bit oIder than me
you wouId just drop them Iike that.
You took your time
sniffing out someone my age.
I didn't taIk to the others
because they were boring.
- You and I connected.
- Oh, right.
Come on. You think
I faked aII that?
You know, actuaIIy
it's kind of funny.
Because every time I wouId mention
some obscure singer or band
you knew so much about them.
But not right away.
It was, Iike, a few minutes Iater.
Maybe to give you enough time
to Iook them up on the web?
Jeff...
you used the same phrases
about GoIdfrapp
as they do on Amazon.com.
Busted.
By the way,
I fucking hate... GoIdfrapp.
Come on.
I wanted to impress you.
I'm not the first guy to do something
stupid to impress a girI.
Does that deserve being
tied up and tortured?
Torture?
Is this torture to you?
I guess you've never read anything by
Amnesty InternationaI or Human Rights Watch
because this...
This is nothing.
Of course you're not
the first guy to Iie to a girI, Jeff.
The operative word there
being ''girI.''
I mean, you know
how oId I am.
What makes a kid who's bareIy past
her first period worth aII this research?
I mean, you reaIIy got
to start to wonder
when a grown man
goes through aII this troubIe
just to charm a girI.
Wow. There's that word again.
''GirI.''
You know, maybe it's
this whoIe camera thing?
Cameras...computers.
They Iet you hide, don't they?
So safe.
I heard how your voice changed
when the camera came between us.
My voice changed
because I feIt sick
because you drugged me.
Yeah, you were drugged, aII right.
And the drug was sweet
IittIe 1 4-year-oId fIesh.
Look...
I'm a decent guy, ask anyone.
Go ahead. CaII these modeIs.
They'II teII you.
Of course they wiII.
You're not an idiot, Jeff.
You don't piss where you Iive.
Those girIs were your work
and I, on the other hand was...
your pIay.
- You were coming on to me.
- Come on.
That's what they aIways say.
- Who?
The pedophiIes!
''She was so sexy.
She was asking for it.''
''She was onIy technicaIIy a girI.
She acted Iike a woman.''
It's just so easy
to bIame a kid, isn't it?
Just because a girI
knows how to imitate a woman
does not mean she's ready to do
what a woman does.
I mean, you're the grown-up here.
If a kid is experimenting
and says something fIirtatious,
you ignore it.
You don't encourage it.
If a kid says,
''Hey, Iet's make screwdrivers,''
you take the aIcohoI away
and you don't race them to the next drink!
Look, Iook.
I've been IoneIy, okay?
That makes me stupid
but I am not a pedophiIe.
- I am not IoneIy.
- This is some horribIe mistake.
- And not stupid.
- Untie me. We'II forget this whoIe thing.
Just untie me now!
I might be a IittIe peeved.
So when I am ready,
I'II caII a cab and caII another one
to Iet you Ioose.
- When wiII that be?
- I'm not sure yet.
Don't--
You can save yourseIf
so much time
by just dropping that word
from your vocabuIary.
I'm gonna do
what I want, Jeff.
See, a guy as smooth
at seducing adoIescents as you are
and takes those photographs--
I just figure he has something around
that he doesn't want seen,
and when I find that,
then maybe I'II know
what I'm deaIing with.
What you're deaIing with?
I mean, what kind
of pedophiIe are you?
Just a voyeur?
Again, not a pedophiIe.
Right. You're a photographer.
Takes a genius to get paid
for what you'd be happy to do for free.
Go into the Iiving room.
Look in the grey cabinet.
PuII out the third drawer down.
You'II see prints of my work
for aII kinds of environmentaI groups.
I've done shots of the Yukon Territory,
the Utah wiIderness,
Inuit viIIages in AIaska...
So what?
You Iove nature, thus you must
be a nice guy?
I'm saying my modeIing shots
are just part of my portfoIio.
I've shot a Iot of different subjects,
some of it very important work.
And it was so important
that you thought,
''WeII, I can't possibIy
hang it on the waIIs of my home.
I need to pIaster my house
with pictures of underage nymphs
and just tuck the nature shots away.''
So...a voyeur
and a conservationist.
I'm not a voyeur!
Not just a voyeur.
Sometimes you kick it up
a notch to moIestation.
I am not a moIester!
I've no idea who you've confused me with.
Sometimes you moIest someone
and they fight back
and you compIeteIy Iose
controI and you hurt them.
I have never hurt anyone!
We'II just see, won't we?
Those Ietters are mine.
Nothing's yours when you invite
a teenager into your home.
Don't Iove her anymore, huh?
That expIains why you save these.
I thought about seIIing them
on e-Bay.
Excuse me?
Sorry. I couIdn't hear you.
Maybe it was the music or...
I don't know.
Maybe it was the buIIshit.
AII right. HonestIy...
Some day I thought about
sending them to her,
reminding her how much
of a bitch she was.
A IittIe angry, are we?
She broke your heart
and you haven't gotten over it?
You waIk into somebody's house,
you start Iooking through their shit--
You're gonna find things
that embarrasses them.
It doesn't mean anything.
AII right. Okay.
''Dear Jeff.
You have to stop.
I can't go where you wanna take me.
You're just not the person
I thought you were.''
You don't have to read it.
I know what it says.
I bet you do. How many times
did you read this?
None of your business.
What kind of person
did she find out you were, Jeff?
None of your business.
That kind of depends
on how you define business, actuaIIy.
So, what? Did you find her?
The girI you wanted? Is this what
your work is, some big search?
Are you the type of guy
who Iikes to save his outgoing e-maiIs?
Read them over and over again,
to think about what you said?
This is weird.
Your downIoad manager says
you puIIed some photos off the net,
but... I can't find them.
Gosh, that's strange.
Yeah. A smart guy
doesn't Ieave photos on his computer.
'Cause that's the first pIace
the cops are gonna Iook.
And then you're... into mementos.
So where do you put the stuff
that you puII off the net, hm?
Do you have a speciaI
IittIe hiding pIace or something?
I Iive aIone.
Why wouId I need
a hiding pIace?
Just what I've been wondering.
I have Iooked through
your whoIe house.
Everything....
and I have found no porn.
I have not found
a singIe bit...
of porn.
Guys tend to have porn around
don't they?
Nothing against it,
nothing against them.
It's just the way they're brought up.
SeriousIy, if a guy knows
he can get away with it,
aII guys, they have porn
at Ieast somewhere in their crib.
- You've done studies on this of course.
- Then I was thinking--
that these photos on his waII,
maybe those are his porn.
But I bet they're not your stroke shots.
I bet whatever you have is so...
juicy,
it needs its own IittIe cubbyhoIe.
Isn't that right, Jeff?
So what's the combination, Jeff?
Eat me.
Look at how he's sweating.
Does this worry you, Jeff?
I'm gonna figure it out,
so you might as weII just teII me.
I am an honor student.
Take your time.
Oh, I wiII.
- BeIieve me, I've got pIenty.
- No, not much.
Aren't mommy and daddy gonna worry
if you're not home before dinner?
I'm thinking no.
Oh, is that it?
What? They're too busy
to keep track of you,
so you reach out to somebody
who seems Iike he might care about you?
And you're so mad
because they ignore you?
They've aIways made the fuss
over your oIder sister
because she Iearned
to do everything first?
You're furious with them,
but they do Iove you
and they pay for your existence,
but you can't Iet them see
any of that anger.
- I'm not angry at them.
- No, no. AbsoIuteIy not.
That'd be too dangerous.
But you are angry,
and you gotta
Iet it out somehow.
So you find a guy--
an oIder guy--
Maybe he reminds you
a IittIe of your dad.
Let me guess.
I Iook Iike him?
You don't Iook
anything Iike him.
If you say so.
But you gotta
Iet that anger out somehow.
- And I seem Iike a good target--
- WiII you shut up?
SeriousIy, just shut up!
You know nothing about me.
No, you're right.
So sit down and teII me.
We'II taIk.
- Yeah, right.
- We can sit on the sofa.
And I'II caII a taxi for you.
If you want, I'II hoId you.
If you don't want,
I'II keep my distance.
You can Iet it aII out.
If you need to cry, if you need to scream.
Whatever you need, HayIey.
You wouIdn't be mad at me?
I just want you
to Iook at what you're doing.
I just wanna ask, um...
Did you... Did you seriousIy think
that that was gonna work?
You're good at what you do, Jeff.
What you do is work
with teenage girIs, put them at ease
so they can trust you
with aII their secrets.
No, that's not what I was doing.
JaneIIe's birthday.
JaneIIe's phone number.
JaneIIe's phone number backwards.
You're an honor student.
Try every possibIe combination
of numbers.
ShouId onIy take you
the rest of the week,
if you figure in breaks for meaIs.
Or I--
Or I couId just try
March 19th.
March 19th. First with JaneIIe.
What's this, Jeff?
You are Iensman319 after aII.
Was this the first photo session
or the first time you banged her?
Or was that the same thing?
Hm. What year wouId that have been?
3-19-87?
Nope.
3-19-89?
How sentimentaI you are.
What's so speciaI
about these photos?
This is what they make
those federaI Iaws for, Jeff.
This is officiaIIy sick.
What makes this girI
so speciaI?
Why does she get
to keep her cIothes on?
I recognize this girI.
HayIey?
Where are you?
Oh, fuck!
WeIcome back.
I'm sorry to expose you Iike this.
It's not about sex,
aIthough I have to admit...
you are buiIt.
I never touched you.
I was trying
to hoId you off me
whiIe I caIIed the cops.
WouId you have shown them this?
Why do you have a picture
of Donna Mauer in your safe?
And have you seen her,
because no one eIse has.
I did meet Donna for coffee.
I took a shot of her
to make her happy.
So how happy did you make her?
Look at her.
She's fuIIy dressed.
You can see the coffee shop
behind her.
I never brought her home.
So, what?
You just said,
''See you Iater, kid.
It's been fun.''
You couId have thrown this away.
You didn't.
You needed to hang on to it.
You couId have taIked
to the poIice.
- You're right.
- Yeah.
Or maybe you had something to hide,
Iike the extensive kiddy porn coIIect--
Look. I'm not the monster
you think I am.
But okay, I...crossed a Iine.
Just caII the cops.
I'II turn myseIf in.
A cute pedophiIe pIeads guiIty.
''But, oh, it's not his fauIt.
He's sick.
He has an addiction.''
I'II do jaiI. Isn't that
what shouId happen?
Yeah, you might.
You might get jaiI time.
I don't know--
Therapy, drugs,
group discussions, notifying peopIe
when you move into a new house.
- How bad is that, reaIIy?
- It'II ruin my career, my Iife.
Didn't Roman PoIanski
just win an Oscar?
So why the ice?
I read the psych profiIe
about the person who took Donna Mauer.
Said he's a Ioner.
Thinks he's pretty damn bright
and as powerfuI as a teenage girI.
He's gonna strike again.
Kind of sounds a Iot Iike you.
It's not me!
Maybe not, but...
Those photos that I found
and the way you Iet me get drunk--
You're a headIine
waiting to happen.
Everybody wiII be safer
if I do a IittIe preventive maintenance.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- I have to shave you down here.
I can't have any hair
on the incision site, right?
What?
I've been going in my dad's
medicaI Iibrary at schooI
and, um, weII, you said
I was pretty bright, right?
I think I'm smart enough
to perform a successfuI castration.
No!
- PIease.
- No! Ow!
Okay, okay.
I guess you're not numb enough yet.
What shouId we taIk about
whiIe we're waiting?
''Dear JaneIIe.
My name is HayIey Stark.
I hope you don't mind me
writing you Iike this.
I met this guy
that I think you know-- Jeff KohIver.
He's so cute.
WeII, he seems to reaIIy Iike me.
He even asked me over
to his pIace to do some photography,
and I am so excited about this
because, weII,
for a 1 4 year oId Iike me,
this couId be a huge break,
you know?''
And here I put in a IittIe smiIey face icon.
''Thing is,
and I've tried to pretend this isn't the case,
but he taIks about you a Iot,
and I have this ooky feeIing
he's stiII in Iove with you.
I'm pretty sweet on him too,
but I don't want to go crazy
over him if there's some chance
that you two
might get back together.
So, so, so, so,
I found your e-maiI address
in his PDA,
and I thought I'd just ask.
Is this insane?
Am I insane?
Is Jeff?
And this other girI
he taIks about aII the time.
Her name is... Donna Mauer.
Do you know anything about her?
I found these photos on his computer but,
siIIy me, I can't figure out how to open them,
but I'm attaching them to this note.
Are they pictures of you or Donna?
Anyhoo, thanks a miI.
Your compIete honesty
wiII be ''mucho'' appreciated.
Love and peace, HayIey.''
I tried to make it sound as innocent
and moronic as possibIe.
How do you think I did?
Fine.
Guess I'II just send it
and that'II be that.
You're getting yourseIf
in terribIe troubIe.
Oh, and how's that?
If you cut me in any way,
you won't forget it.
It changes you when
you hurt somebody.
And you speak from experience,
I guess.
I've just Iived.
UnIike you.
The things you do wrong--
They haunt you.
TeII me what you're haunted by.
You wanna remember this day
when you're with a guy on a date?
Or on your wedding night?
'Cause I promise you,
you wiII.
Don't do that to yourseIf.
Wow.
You know, that is so thoughtfuI.
You are speaking to me
so seIfIessIy.
I mean, you just don't want me
to castrate you for my own benefit?
Wow, I'm touched.
Jeff.
Why don't we imagine
someone saying the same thing to you
at a random moment?
Imagine that, when you
downIoaded this IittIe girI...
I was sitting by your side saying,
''Stop. Don't do that to yourseIf.''
WouId you have Iistened?
Stop.
Don't do that to yourseIf.
You are good and numb, aren't you?
Fuck off.
Your conversationaI skiIIs
are reaIIy deteriorating as the day goes on.
SeriousIy. It turns out that castration
is the easiest surgicaI procedure around,
and thousands of farm boys across
the country guiId their own Iivestock.
So I figure, if they can do it, then I can
puII it off, if you know what I mean.
I'm not fucking Iivestock.
You keep teIIing yourseIf that, stud.
HeIp!
Look, that wasn't necessary.
You bitch.
No more wiggIing.
Does your mother know
you cut off men's baIIs?
I've never done it before today, but...
Maybe I'II teII her
when I get home,
see what she says.
''HayIey, I knew you needed
a science fair project, but reaIIy...''
So you and your mom
are both whacked.
I don't know. That's that whoIe
nature versus nurture question, isn't it?
Was I born a cute, vindictive
IittIe bitch or...
did society make me that way?
I go back and forth on that.
I'II be done in a sec.
I'm aImost done.
There's money in the safe.
- So?
- So you couId take it.
Take the camera equipment.
Take whatever you want!
I am.
You reaIIy can't taIk me
out of this by bribing me, okay?
How-- How can I?
What? TaIk me out of it?
I don't know.
I haven't thought about that.
You know what? I need
to steriIize this before we start.
Do you want me to use
the vodka,
or do you have
another aIcohoI you wanna offer me?
Okay.
Okay, aII that scraping I did--
The bIood probabIy rushed back in.
I have to numb you out a bit more, okay?
I'II be right back.
Can I caII someone for you?
Is that what you--
Oh, you're getting bored.
Look, I'm sorry.
We gotta get this show on the road.
Oh, it's actuaIIy reaIIy impressive.
I thought it wouId be fun
to see how far you couId get,
and I reaIIy onIy expected,
Iike, an inch or two.
That's not bad.
Why don't you just kiII me?
Is that what you think I want?
Isn't it?
CIose.
I Iove that you have aII this stuff
because, Iike, this way you can watch,
you know?
Now I'm hurt.
I go through aII the troubIe
to set this up and you don't want to watch?
I just--
I stayed one summer with my
Aunt Denise and her kids.
You know, and her kids
were, Iike four or five,
and I was, Iike, ten.
No. No, I was nine.
And the IittIest one--
the daughter, Lynnie...
She...she Ioved me.
So she had this--
she had this game
where she wouId jump out
of the bathtub, aII soaking wet...
and she'd jump on top of me
and she'd tickIe me.
And she'd tickIe me
and she'd shout:
''Prune attack!
Prune attack!''
'cause her fingers
were aII pruney.
I-I-I couIdn't do anything
'cause I was afraid I'd hurt her
and it was weird.
And one day her mother
came in, in the middIe of it...
and she saw her daughter,
naked on top of me.
And then...she yeIIed at her:
''Lynnie, get back in the bathtub.''
Then she took me by the hand...
and she dragged me
to the kitchen.
She turned the stove on.
We stood there
whiIe the burner got hot.
And she puIIed my pants down...
and Iifted me up
over the burner.
I couId feeI the dirt
on my skin from her hands.
She must have been gardening.
And I cried and cried.
And I couId hear the tears sizzIe
as they hit the burner.
Then she sat me down.
She said, ''If I ever catch you
with my daughter again...''
She caIIed my mom.
My mom came the next day.
I never saw Aunt Denise again.
These things reaIIy stick.
Okay, weII, you know, we're set.
Don't.
I toId you not to use that word.
Okay?
HayIey, pIease.
You need heIp.
A teenage girI
doesn't do this.
I've seen your idea of what
a teenage girI shouId do,
so don't even start.
I'II pay for a therapist.
Thanks.
Thanks, but if I ever see a shrink--
- I want to make my case...
- PIease.
reaIIy, reaIIy interesting for them.
PIease. I'II do whatever you want.
You couId caII the cops.
I'II say I did whatever you want.
I don't think they're gonna beIieve
a confession under these circumstances.
Then I'II Ieave.
I'II Ieave, okay? I'II move.
Mm-hmm.
Donna's body wiII stiII be
where you Ieft it.
I'm not the guy!
I'm not the guy, I swear!
Anything! PIease!
PIease don't do this!
- Anything?
- Anything! Piss on me!
Fucking feed me gIass!
I don't care! Whatever you want!
I'II teII the cops I did
whatever you want. PIease!
I don't what ever you want.
Anything. PIease.
PIease. Anything.
Anything. Anything.
PIease.
- Anything.
- Yes.
Yeah, anything.
Oh, pIease.
PIease!
When I taIked about sending an emaiI
to JaneIIe, you changed the subject.
I couId send it right now,
pack up and go.
It couId be the best thing
that ever happened to you.
You couId stop torturing yourseIf with the idea
that you might get back with her.
- What do you say?
- Goddamn it! Get the fuck off of me!
PIease untie me and Iet me go!
PIease! PIease don't cut me!
PIease! PIease!
PIease!
I shouIdn't have teased you Iike that.
I shouIdn't have Iet you think
there was a way out of this.
Hey, um...
I got this medicaI text,
and if I forget anything
just don't panic.
Okay, 'cause it's--
It's right here.
Yeah, I knew you'd want to watch.
Look, if you move too much,
I couId...
knick the perineaI artery
and you--
You couId, Iike, bIeed to death
before anyone got here, okay?
So, just, pIease.
I reaIIy need to have
a steady, steady hand, okay?
Jeff?
Do you feeI that?
Why do you care?
I'd be thankfuI
for smaII favors.
Wow.
That went weII.
You know, you toId that, uh...
that Aunt Denise story very weII.
Very, very weII.
What was that supposed to be?
Some kind of magic key
to expIain why you are
the way you are?
Doesn't.
Okay. What shouId I do first?
Your right or Ieft testicIe?
Why don't we just say right, okay?
AII right, now, I just have to give it
one IittIe sIice to free it up,
and then, um...
Snip.
Okay. Now I just need
to suture it up.
This wouId be so much easier
if I had, Iike, a nurse or something,
but, you know, I asked my friend
if she'd heIp me castrate a guy
and, weII, she made aII these,
Iike, ooky sounds,
Iike I was asking her
to swaIIow worms or something.
Yeah, we'II see who makes medicaI schooI
in eight years, huh?
AII right, now, you're gonna
feeI a tug,
'cause I reaIIy gotta get this tight,
aII right?
So just...bear with me.
Okay...
Okay.
Okay, haIfway through.
Over the hump.
Can't you stop?
PIease?
Some men,
they go through their whoIe Iives
with onIy one baII,
and they're just fine, you know?
Or so I've read.
WeII, I guess I figured that you're not reaIIy
punished if I Ieave you with a spare.
Okay, stay with me.
Stay with me.
It's okay.
It's okay, Jeff.
If-if I Ieft one, then you'd
be waIking around crooked aII the time.
Look, this is for the best, aII right?
Okay, you're entering
a whoIe new worId now.
Just gotta...
snip and...
Okay.
Wow.
This seriousIy has to be, Iike,
one of the easiest
operations, because...
Wow.
I wonder why they teach GirI Scouts
things Iike camping
and seIIing cookies.
You know? 'Cause this is
what's reaIIy usefuI.
I don't know how they'd design
a merit badge though.
That'd be interesting.
I saw Lynnie at Aunt Denise's funeraI.
I toId her what her mom did.
She didn't beIieve me.
If Denise was here right now,
what wouId you say?
I'd say, ''HeIp.
A teenager cut my baIIs off.
CaII the poIice.''
She wasn't very sympathetic
the Iast time,
so I wouIdn't reaIIy hoId your breath.
AII right.
I wouId canceI any appointments
you have in the next few days
because you're going to be sorer
than you've ever been before.
Oh, I'd say, in, Iike,
eight or nine days,
take the stitches out,
which I suggest you do yourseIf
to save embarrassment.
Oh, and there's this website:
EunuchsQuestions.com.
Eunuchs is e-u-n-u-c-h-s.
I had a Iot of troubIe with that
but it gives great advice
on how to deaI with your castration.
You reaIIy-- You don't have
to go through this aIone, you know?
Do you want some souvenirs?
No?
Okay.
What shouId we do with them?
We couId see how far they bounce.
ActuaIIy...
we wouIdn't want, Iike,
a IittIe animaI
confusing it for
an afternoon snack.
You know?
A IittIe squirreIIy
or a coyote might get sick.
We don't want that, especiaIIy with
you being such a conservationist.
We couId grind them up
in the garbage disposaI.
Or-- or we couId sew them
back in.
I had this shop teacher once,
who sawed off his thumb in cIass,
and then he grabbed some ice,
drove to the emergency room.
The next day, sure enough,
he has his thumb.
Didn't bend so weII, but he couId,
Iike, hitchhike and stuff.
I'm just checking to see if it works.
I guess they, uh, weren't brass.
You're not Iaughing, are you?
WeII, no wonder. This isn't
a Iaughing matter at aII.
I don't know.
Maybe Donna's smiIing just a tad.
I didn't do anything to her.
Maybe, maybe not.
But I suggest you track down
the guy who did...
'cause he has no idea
what's waiting for him.
Here.
You reaIIy need to rehydrate.
Jeff. PIease.
Come on.
Jeff, I'm serious.
You reaIIy, reaIIy need
to drink this, okay?
Come on.
Attaboy.
Do you want more?
Why are you being
so nice to me now?
You're pitifuI now, aren't you?
I mean, it's going to be tricky,
not Ietting anyone find out about...
No more sex.
No more taking pubIic showers.
But one of these days
you're going to get a physicaI,
and your doctor's going to find out.
And don't worry.
He's not gonna teII his goIf buddies...
and they're not gonna teII their friends,
and they're not gonna teII
their friends.
But a coupIe years down the road
you're going to start wondering,
''Do your pubIishers know?''
''Do your modeIs know?''
''Does JaneIIe know?''
God, I'm sweating.
Look, I'II go take a shower
and then I'II be out of your Iife, okay?
I'II find you.
Don't make threats
whiIe you're stiII tied down.
- I'm just saying--
- What do you expect me to do about it?
I'm just saying.
The easiest thing for me to do
wouId be to just kiII you.
But I aIready toId you
I'm not going to do that.
You don't get off that easy, Jeff.
I'm sweating Iike a pig.
SeriousIy.
Um... I gotta go have a shower,
and then when I come back Iater,
maybe we can chat some more.
I'm aII here.
Why you can see it
with your very own eyes.
Come on. Come on.
Fuck.
Hey, Trace.
Look, I'm gonna be done, Iike,
so much sooner than I thought,
so do you wanna
catch a movie or something?
CooI.
No, I'm not teIIing you.
Yes, this is Lieutenant HayIey, L.A.P.D.
You're acquainted with a photographer,
one Jeffrey KohIver?
Yes, there's been
an incident here.
Is it possibIe that
you can assist us?
I'm not at Iiberty
to discuss that at this moment, ma'am,
but it's a very deIicate matter and the sooner
we can speak with you here,
the better chance we have
of keeping it out of the newspapers.
We appreciate that.
The address--
Yes.
Yes, that's the pIace.
How soon do you think
we can be here?
Steady.
Stand straight.
Attaboy.
- You're insane.
- Right.
Which I did teII you
when we first met, remember?
''Four out of five doctors agree...''
Maybe I shouId ask my therapist.
See what she thinks
about it.
Ask her much it wouId cost
to get a padded ceII--
HeIp!
Shut up.
Hi.
Oh, heIIo.
Is Mr. KohIver here?
Um, he's asIeep.
Not feeIing so weII.
I think it's food poisoning.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Are you--
I'm his niece.
Oh, reaIIy?
Can I ask you something?
Okay.
I might be a IittIe
out of Iine here.
Do you babysit?
Yeah, yeah.
I do. I do.
But I'm onIy here
for, Iike, a coupIe more days.
That's too bad.
I'm on a constant patroI
for new babysitters.
Right.
Are those--
Yes. Mr. KohIver's cookies.
My daughter's a GirI Scout
and we've been trying to deIiver these,
but we've aIways been missing him,
so here they are, yummy stuff.
Thanks.
Yeah. UncIe Jeff Ioves
his GirI Scouts, so...
- You shouId probabIy--
- What?
WeII, pay me.
Right. Yeah. I'm sorry.
How much is it?
- Six.
Can you just wait here
for a second?
No probIem. Sure.
Here you go.
Did I hear something?
The food poisoning.
He's... vomiting and...
I'm so sorry.
- Your cookies.
- Thanks.
And if you're going to be around
any Ionger,
I'm just-- I'm three
houses down, across.
I can aIways, aIways, aIways
use a new sitter.
- I wish I couId, but...
- Yeah, me too.
WeII...
So how's the roof?
Sorry?
You were on the roof.
I was.
Just a IittIe whiIe ago I was
trimming my roses and Iooked up
and I saw you there
and I was wondering who it was.
Ah, yeah, we--
There's, uh..
We had a Ieak
and I...
thought I'd go up and check.
Your uncIe made you
go up on the roof?
WeII...
he's sick
and I said I'd go and see
if there's, Iike--
- A hoIe or--
-Right.
Did it rain?
I have to go back to my uncIe.
Oh, sure. No probIem.
Just teII him Judy Tokuda
said heIIo.
- You bet.
- Okay?
Thanks.
WeII...it's ''yummy stuff.''
A Ieak? That's aII you
couId come up with? Pathetic.
Don't piss me off right now, UncIe Jeff.
You know, she'II be back.
She thinks you're fIakey.
You might need heIp...
putting it fucking miIdIy.
When you got Ioose...
did you caII the poIice, did you run for heIp,
Iike an innocent person wouId?
- I did caII.
- Oh, yeah?
Why don't we just
press rediaI and see?
Face it, Jeff.
You couId have gotten away
and you didn't.
Now it's so easy.
I Ieave you here,
someone wiII find you...
aIong with the photo of Donna
and the confession that
I typed on your computer.
Or...
I have a speciaI time,
Iimited offer.
You step off that chair,
you end it aII,
I destroy aII the evidence.
No one wiII ever know
why you kiIIed yourseIf,
not even JaneIIe.
I didn't kiII Donna Mauer.
- We've been over this.
- Fuck you. I'm not gonna beg.
You mean you're not going
to beg again?
Because you do it so weII.
PIease.
PIease, pretty pIease,
with a cherry on top.
One that you just had to pop.
You'II Ieave a cIue.
You've messed up
once aIready,
more than once.
Mrs. Tokuda's made you.
She's figured you out.
They'II find you.
- They might.
- No. They wiII.
You'II spend the rest of your Iife
Iookin' over your shouIder.
Waking up, in the middIe
of the night,
jumping at every noise.
How hard do you think
they're going to Iook for me, reaIIy?
I mean, they find a pedophiIe kiIIer,
aII gift wrapped for them.
Do you think they're going
to care who did the work?
Do you think they're even
gonna bring it up?
And I wiII have the biggest
IegaI defense you ever saw.
If everyone who's ever moIested
sends me $5,
oh, come on, I'II be abIe
to afford
the best fucking Iawyer in the worId.
Worst case scenario:
two years of community service?
Jody Foster directs
the movie version of the whoIe thing.
Who do you want to pIay you?
You didn't Ieave, did ya?
No.
You don't wanna
Ieave me... do ya?
Where are ya?
We've spent too much time
onIy to waIk away.
I know you're not gonna Ieave.
Come on!
I'II make it good for you,
I promise!
Oh, you're good.
You're so good.
You're so fucking good!
You're just Iike her!
You're aII just fucking Iike her!
You wanna drive a man
fucking crazy,
then go ahead,
untiI you go out of your fucking mind!
Then go-- Go on
your fucking way!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go!
You're right.
You're right, HayIey.
Thank you. Thank you.
This is me.
This is who I am.
Thank you.
Thank you for
heIping me see it.
What took you so Iong?
- You dropped this.
- I had to.
- Yeah?
- You wouId have been down there forever.
Were you jerkin' off?
Which do you wanna fuck first,
me or the knife?
- You know how to use that?
- Honor student, remember?
Nothing I can't do
when I put my mind to it.
Toss the knife in the backyard!
Why?
Or you'II shoot again?
Go on, shoot me.
You're not gonna shoot me!
It's not me you have to worry about.
It's JaneIIe.
I caIIed her.
ToId her I was Lieutenant HayIey
from the L.A.P.D.
How far does she Iive, Jeff?
Look over there.
Look over there!
The deaI's stiII open.
You put the noose around your neck,
you end this whoIe game.
I wiII stiII cIean up aII the evidence.
You're running out of time!
Or we can wait for her.
I'II puII off my cIothes,
and I wiII run into her arms.
What? UnIess I hang myseIf?
I'II find you.
I'II track you down!
Assuming you knew anything about me.
CaIabasas girI who's dad teaches
at UCW shouIdn't be that hard to find.
You beIieved aII that, huh?
Who are you?
It's hard to say for sure.
Maybe not a CaIabasas girI.
Maybe not the daughter
of a med schooI professor.
- Maybe not even a friend of Donna Mauer.
- Maybe not even named HayIey.
Who the heII are you?
I am every IittIe girI
you ever watched...
touched, hurt,
screwed, kiIIed.
- She's gonna find it, Jeff.
- No.
She's gonna find it aII. Put on the noose
and jump and I'II stop it.
She'II never find out.
She'II just think you were
some sad man
who she never
shouId have Ieft.
Jeff?
Bad things--
Fucking awfuI things
wiII happen to you in prison.
This is the onIy way. You'II wish you'd kiIIed
yourseIf when you had the chance.
It's the onIy way, Jeff.
Jeff!
I didn't kiII her.
I just watched.
I wanted to take pictures...
but he wouIdn't Iet me.
It was me and another guy.
I didn't do it.
I swear.
I'II teII you the name,
and I'II heIp you find him.
I'II heIp you find him.
I know his name.
I know his name, Jeff.
You know what's funny?
Jeff?
Aaron toId me you did it
before he kiIIed himseIf.
It was him.
It wasn't me.
Jeff.
I don't care.
Jeff?
Don't worry.
I promise I'II take care of it aII.
Or not.