I was getting nervous.
I've been waiting over an hour.
I've been waiting, too, over eight years.
- The park's down there, ain't it?
- Yeah.
The park? Say, Earle, you feeling all right?
I will be, just as soon as
I make sure that the grass is still green...
and the trees are still growing.
He ought to be here now.
When he comes, you get in the bedroom
and stay there till he's gone.
I've been hearing
about Roy Earle for years.
He's a real big shot and I want to see him.
Okay, okay.
- Here they are now. Wally's brought him.
- All right, scram.
Come in.
Well, what kept you?
You ain't losing your touch, are you?
Where's Big Mac?
He's gone to California.
I'm handling things here.
- Who are you?
- I'm Kranmer, Jack Kranmer.
- A copper, ain't you?
- I used to be. I resigned.
I'll bet.
I'm okay.
You don't have to worry about me.
Since when has Big Mac
been teaming up with ex-coppers?
I told you not to worry about that.
Mac wants you to start
for California right away.
That car downstairs is yours.
Here's the keys.
Now here's your route and some dough.
The sooner you get out there, the better.
What's the setup?
I don't suppose you ever heard
of Tropico Springs. It's a resort town.
They call it the richest little town
in the world.
It has a hotel there,
gets all the top sugar.
- You're gonna knock it off.
- Am I, copper?
Now, look here, Earle,
Mac spent a fortune springing you.
You're working for him now.
He calls the tune and you dance to it.
- Hello there.
- Howdy.
Is there anything I can do for you?
No, I was just looking around.
- This is the old Earle place, ain't it?
- Yeah.
But none of the Earles have been
around here for five or six years.
You from the bank?
No. I used to live near here.
It's nice country.
- Yeah.
- Howdy, son. Any luck?
Not much.
The best place to catch them
is that hole below the Turner place.
Plenty big catfish in there.
Three or four pounds, maybe.
Three or four pounds? Gee.
Used to be, a long time ago, anyway.
Maybe it's fished out.
Why, you're Roy Earle, the bandit!
Howdy, partner. What can I do for you?
She'll take some water
and about 10 gallons of gas.
Yes, sir.
You bet.
Hot day, ain't she?
Ain't many cars coming through right now.
Little early, I guess.
You're looking at the pride
of the Sierras, brother.
Mount Whitney,
the highest peak in the United States.
14,501 feet above sea level.
Hey, I see you got an Illinois license plate.
You're a long ways from home, ain't you?
You must excuse me. I get lonesome here.
And when a customer shows up,
well, maybe I talk too much.
Lonesome, eh?
Yes, I can see
how you would get lonesome out here.
Wow, we made it!
I'd sure like to shake your hand, sir.
Jackrabbit jumped in front of my car
and I kind of lost my head.
- You sure saved our bacon.
- I saved my own bacon, too. Come far?
- Clear from Ohio. And you?
- Chicago.
I'm mighty proud to make your
acquaintance. You sure can handle a car.
Me, I'm kind of shaky at it, but Velma...
Velma's my granddaughter,
she's a good driver...
but she gets tired
and I won't let her drive too much.
- What's your name, sir?
- Collins.
Mine's Goodhue.
Velma, Ma, I'd like you
to meet Mr. Collins.
- How do?
- How do you do?
Pleased to meet you.
Well, I guess I'll be on my way.
Out of $5.
Going far?
Up in the mountains for my health.
Well, I'm going to Los Angeles.
I lost my farm back home.
But Velma's mother married again
and she sort of invited us out.
- Now, I don't know...
- $2.41, $3, $4, $5.
I hope you make it.
- Hey, you.
- Yes, sir?
I'm looking for a fellow named Hattery.
He's staying up here,
him and another fellow.
They all in cabin 12.
Are you the gentleman they expecting?
Then you'll be in cabin number 11.
Leave your car here.
I'll drain the water out of it
'cause it gets awful cold up here at night.
Get my bags. They're in the back.
I'll take care of them, boss.
Hattery here?
There's someone to see you.
You Roy Earle?
Glad to see you. I can't shake hands.
I've been cleaning fish.
Meet my pal, Babe Kozak.
This is Marie Garson.
Red, I want to talk to you alone.
See you later.
It's okay by me.
You don't like the idea of the dame, huh?
Even guys like you ought to know better.
Babe picked her up
at a dime-a-dance joint in L.A.
She's strictly okay.
She just sort of looks after things for us.
Give her some dough and send her back.
Get her out of here tonight.
Now, what about this job?
The tropical season is just starting,
and Mendoza, he's our inside man...
he says that the hotel
will be full up in another week.
And there'll be plenty of rocks
in the strong boxes then.
- When do I see Mendoza?
- He'll be up the first day he gets off.
- He's in touch with Big Mac, too.
- Oh, he is?
- He'll give you all the news firsthand.
- All right.
Say, Mr. Earle?
I wanted to tell you
that with you on the job...
we feel like we're traveling
in fast company.
I sure heard a lot about you.
One time, when I was only a kid,
I saw your picture in the paper...
You can have your Roy Earle.
He don't look like much to me.
He's getting gray.
He may be a powerhouse to some people,
but he's a blown-out fuse to me!
I'll bet he's plenty tough.
Get out of line and you'll see.
All right, I'll see.
Let me tell you something...
you're getting so
you're asking for a smack in the nose.
- Stop arguing with me all the time.
- I got bad news for you.
Roy says we gotta send Marie back to L.A.
Why, that broken-down...
- I'll tell him.
- Yeah?
Well, here's your chance.
You don't want me to go back to L.A.,
do you?
- You go and tell him.
- I don't know.
I suppose we need that guy.
But that's no reason
for him to push us around.
He's no more the boss than we are.
- He can't get away...
- Go on, keep it up.
You're gonna win this argument.
Leave her alone!
You go smacking her, I'll flatten you!
- And who else?
- Me! You think it ain't enough?
Cut it out. You'll get nothing
out of fighting but a black eye.
I don't care what you or anyone else says,
she's not going to L.A.
That's what you think. He thinks different.
I'm not gonna be sent back
to that dime-a-dance joint if I can help it.
- I'll go talk to him.
- With him, I don't think it'll work.
Can I talk to you a moment, Mr. Earle?
Sure. Help yourself.
Why do you want to send me back to L.A.?
I like it here.
- Don't play dumb.
- I don't intend to.
Oh, I know what's going on,
but I didn't get it from them.
Louis Mendoza told me.
He talks too much, and all he does is brag.
So you see, Mr. Earle, Mendoza's the one
for you to worry about, not me.
I ain't worrying about you.
It's them jitterbugs you got with you.
They'll be throwing lead over you
before long.
Oh, I can handle them all right.
Babe gets tough every once in a while,
but he's afraid of Red.
And I can make Red think what I want.
You got it all figured out, ain't you?
In a way.
All right.
Let things stay as they are
for a few days and see how it works out.
Oh, thanks, Mr. Earle.
Goodbye.
Morning. This is me, Algernon.
Anything I can do for you this morning?
You can rustle me up some breakfast.
The lady next door
got your breakfast all ready.
She thought maybe I ought to see
if you was sort of stirring around.
Where did you ever get
the name Algernon?
My old lady thought it up. Pip, ain't it?
Kind of gives me class.
How you like this dog?
- Why, he's just a dog, ain't he?
- No, sir, mighty fine dog, he is.
Watch now. Pard, ducks!
Down.
Up.
Jump.
Yes, sir, mighty fine animal, he is.
Kind of proud of your dog, ain't you?
Oh, no, sir, he ain't my dog.
He just took a liking to me
and follows me around.
- Sort of gets me worried, too.
- Why?
You see, Pard here
used to belong to a woodcutter...
who lived up here all the year round.
Last winter, a snow slide come down
on that man's house and killed him dead.
Didn't kill Pard, though.
So a man saw Pard sort of wandering
around in the snow like...
took him in. If that man
don't up and die with the pneumonia.
Great, big, strapping man, too.
So Pard got to hanging
around the lodges...
and doggone if Miss Tucker
didn't come up here...
with the...
And I hear yesterday she ain't gonna live.
So I'm just telling you about Pard,
in case you want him for your own dog.
- Can I come in?
- Yeah.
Is he breaking your heart
with the story of the little mutt?
It's the Lord's truth.
Look at him. He's a born panhandler.
Everyone here stuffs him so it's getting...
he won't eat anything else
but a New York cut.
I guess I'll get back to the stove.
Pard'll stay here with you,
won't you, Pard?
- Sit down, have a cigarette.
- Thanks.
- Where are your boyfriends?
- Oh, they're out fishing.
That's about all they do.
They never catch anything,
but they just keep on fishing.
Yes, he certainly is spoiled.
Yeah, look at him.
He knows we're talking about him.
Well, I feel pretty good this morning.
I felt rotten last night.
Nothing like a good night's sleep
to pep you up.
What you ought to do is get out in the sun.
Do you good.
Where I was before,
they didn't let me get out in the sun.
Afraid I might spoil my girlish complexion.
It must be terrible to be in prison.
Some of them are worse than others.
You get a mean guard down on you,
unless you got what it takes...
you might as well climb up
on tier two and jump off.
Some of them did.
- I don't get you.
- Top of the cell block.
It's a 40-foot drop
and you land on concrete.
I saw a guy take a dive once.
He made quite a splash.
Yeah. That must be awful.
He just didn't have what it takes.
I was doing the book myself,
but I got a break.
How was it?
I mean, knowing you're in for life.
- I should think you'd go crazy.
- Yeah.
Lots of them do.
But I was always thinking
about a crash-out.
I tried it once at the prison farm
where they sent me for good behavior.
But the fix blew up
and a screw put the blast on me.
Yeah, then the worst of it was
they sent me back behind those big walls.
We were just getting ready for another
crash-out when my pardon came.
Yeah, I get it.
You always hope you can get out.
That sort of keeps you going.
Yeah, sure, that's it.
You got it.
Well, I'll get you some more coffee.
Thanks for the chow.
You see that fellow over there?
He better watch his steps
and fish on the bank...
cause that little old dog's
got the hex on him for sure.
Gonna put the evil eye on him, huh?
Yes, the evil eye.
That little old dog's got the evilest eye.
His left eye just shines
in the dark just like a cat's eye.
Algernon, if it's in the dark,
how do you know which eye's which?
Come on, Mendoza. What are we doing,
playing cards or taking a nap?
I am sorry. For the moment,
my mind was not on the game.
That's for me. Thanks, Louis.
Dumb luck. Just plain dumb luck.
Maybe if you wouldn't kick so much
you'd do better.
- It's all in the cards.
- Yeah, that's right.
Oh, Roy, this here's Louis Mendoza.
Delighted, Mr. Earle.
Come on, Mendoza,
let's finish out this hand.
That's a baby.
There's that dumb luck again.
I can't beat it.
What does it look like at the hotel?
How soon do we go?
Oh, it won't be long now.
The racing season is starting up north.
And all the big shots
have been making reservations.
This is the layout.
I don't know.
Babe and I kind of figured
our best getaway was over the pass.
Nobody will ever expect us
to cross the Sierras to get into L.A.
Suppose it would blow up a storm?
If the pass got blocked up, then what?
Yeah, that's right.
By the way,
I dropped in to see Big Mac yesterday.
- He wants to see you.
- All right.
I'll take a look at the hotel tomorrow.
I'll drive in and see him.
I almost forgot.
Mendoza brought us a present.
Roy, I guess you're the engineer.
Big Mac gave me the machine gun.
You know how to work it?
Red doesn't, and neither does Babe.
That's a good one, that is.
- What's so funny?
- Does he know how to work it?
Yeah.
Say, you know that gun reminds me
of one time, nine or 10 years ago.
We was getting ready to do a job
back in lowa...
when one of the guys got the shakes.
Pretty soon, we found out that this guy
with the shakes had talked too much...
and a bunch of cops are waiting
for us at the bank.
But we don't say nothing.
Lefty Jackson goes out and gets his gun.
He comes back and sits down
and holds it across his knee.
The guy with the shakes
is sitting right across the room from him.
Pretty soon,
Lefty just touched the trigger a little...
and the gun went like that.
The rat fell out of his chair, dead,
and we drove off and left him there.
Yeah, the gun just went...
I guess I ought to be getting back.
- I have to go on duty at 8:30.
- What's your stunt?
You stick right through
the whole job, don't you?
Sure, I stand behind the desk
and act like I'm scared.
When you fellows get through,
I telephone the police.
We don't want no slip-ups, Mendoza.
Boys and girls, I got the idea
that our boyfriend here is no cream puff.
How'd you like the little bedtime
story about the gun that went...
- Did you get the idea?
- Do you suppose he meant it that way?
Try talking and find out.
I'll take a pack of these.
25 cents, please.
Yes, sir.
- Anything in 316?
- 316...
They don't care how they drive.
They've got no money, no insurance.
- It's murder.
- Tough luck, Pfiffer.
If he weren't an old dodo,
I'd take it out of his hide.
- He wasn't driving. The girl was driving.
- I was.
What's an outfit like that doing
in Tropico, anyhow?
- It's a State Highway, ain't it?
- The signal was on.
- He had his hand out here.
- You didn't!
Wait a minute.
Will you let me get a word in?
I was driving along...
Why, Roy!
- Friends of yours?
- Yeah. Why?
I wondered. I know I've no chance
to collect, but I'm curious.
I pull out from the curb and I get hit.
- Look at my fender.
- But you didn't make no signal.
You talk about collecting.
Be careful, you may have to pay off.
A wise guy in on this, huh?
All right, have it your own way.
I'll charge the whole thing
off to experience.
What's the matter?
I got clipped,
but I'm satisfied if this guy is.
Well, I guess if Mr. Pfiffer's satisfied, I am.
All right, come on, let's break this up.
Back on the sidewalk.
Listen, fellow.
These people ain't got any dough.
They're on their way to L.A.
And that car's all they got.
Stop it. You're breaking my heart.
- $50 ain't gonna mean much to you.
- Sorry, but not a quarter.
That's right, Mr. Pfiffer.
Saw the whole thing.
That girl was driving the car.
Look, she's a cripple, too.
I guess it was really Velma's fault.
She was gawking around,
looking at things...
and smacked right into that fellow's car.
I was sure surprised when he gave you
that $100 to give me.
I wouldn't worry about him, Pa.
He's probably got plenty.
Well, this is the second time
you saved our lives, son.
When Velma smashed into that car,
I had 13 cents in my pocket...
and a $5 bill in my shoe.
Of course, the women didn't know it.
Don't you tell them.
Pa, you're all right.
You said you came
from Chicago, didn't you, Roy?
I came out here from Chicago,
but I'm really from Brookfield, Indiana.
- Born there, went to school there.
- A little town?
- Yeah.
- I knew it.
My folks had a farm.
I said to Ma out there in the desert,
you was our kind.
Yes, sir. I can tell them every time.
- Say, Pa?
- Yeah?
Excuse me,
I suppose it's none of my business...
but what's wrong with Velma's foot?
- It's a clubfoot, she was born that way.
- Can't nothing be done about it?
One time a doctor said she could be
operated, but the last few years...
I've been so broke,
we couldn't if we'd wanted to.
We hurried with the dishes.
We knew Pa'd be talking your ear off.
Pa sure can talk.
Isn't the air grand out here?
Look at the stars.
I never knew
there were so many in the sky.
Back home
you couldn't see them like that.
It's always like this out in the desert.
You see that bright blue star up there?
Look at it sparkle.
- You see that other one?
- Where?
Right there.
Oh, I see it.
That's Jupiter.
How do you know?
A fellow I used to know,
he taught me all about the sky...
and where we was,
we didn't have much else to do.
Is that star always up there like that?
No. You see different stars
at different times.
They change with the seasons. Now, look.
You see that one twinkling over there?
Well, that's Venus.
It makes you dizzy just looking at them.
Sometimes when you're out
in the night and you look up at the stars...
you can almost feel
the motion of the earth.
It's like a little ball
that's turning through the night...
with us hanging onto it.
Why, that sounds like poetry, Roy.
It's pretty.
Well, I guess I better be starting.
I got a long drive ahead of me.
Got a business appointment in L.A.
I sure enjoyed that dinner.
And we sure enjoyed your company.
Now, don't you fail to look us up
in Los Angeles.
We might get lonesome. Especially Velma.
Grandpa, you shouldn't say things
like that. I'm surprised at you.
I declare to goodness,
the older you get, the sillier you act.
Roy understands me.
Me and Roy's old-timers.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Roy.
Lucky girl that gets him.
Come in.
I've got a swell parley
for you tomorrow, Doc.
Still a sucker for the ponies?
- Hello, Roy, old-timer!
- Hello, Mac.
- You're a sight for sore eyes.
- Yeah, I sure am glad to see you, too.
Thanks for the spring.
I was just getting ready
for another crash-out.
- What's the matter, Mac?
- Oh, I don't know. I can't eat.
Just ain't hungry. And I can't sleep.
Doc Banton says it's my past life
catching up with me.
- Doc Banton, is he out here now?
- Yeah.
I was expecting him when you came in.
He's running one of those health services
under a phony name.
Help yourself to a drink.
Well, Roy, how does it look
and what do you say?
I can't see nothing wrong with it.
If the boys don't blow up on me,
it's a cinch.
But, Mac, it's gonna make
an awful big noise in the newspapers.
Well, that's your headache, not mine.
The jewelry.
That's all I'm interested in.
Now look, Roy,
once you get your mitts on it...
keep your mitts on it.
Deliver it right here.
If you're hot, telephone.
This caper means a lot to me.
I spent a pile of dough setting it up,
and I'm in deep.
So don't let me down, Roy.
I never let nobody down, Mac.
You know that.
Oh, I know.
But I've been dealing
with such a lot of screwballs lately.
Young twerps, soda-jerkers and jitterbugs.
Why, it's a relief
just to talk to a guy like you.
All the A-1 guys are gone.
Dead or in Alcatraz.
If I only had four guys like you, Roy...
this knock-over would be a waltz.
Times have sure changed.
Yeah, ain't they?
You know, Mac, sometimes I feel like
I don't know what it's all about anymore.
Yeah, times have sure changed.
Hide the booze.
Well, hello, Mac.
Hello, Doc. Look who's here.
Well, I'll be. Roy Earle, the old boy himself.
Hello, Doc.
Last time I saw you was when I was
taking slugs out of Lefty Jackson's chest.
- Yeah, that's right.
- Oh, those were the times.
Not many of the old bunch left.
Cut it out.
Mac tells me you're doing all right, Doc.
This is the land of milk
and honey for the health racket.
Every woman in California thinks...
she's either too fat or too thin
or too something.
Same dosage, same medicine.
- Need a new prescription?
- No.
- Good night, Mac.
- Good night, Doc.
He's in a bad way, Old Mac.
Bum ticker, kidneys on the blink...
bad stomach,
like a kid's toy that's running down.
I try to keep him from drinking,
but there's no stopping Old Mac.
He'll go on doing
just as he always has done.
Well, maybe he's right.
- Say, Doc.
- Yeah?
- There's something I wanted to ask you.
Can anything be done about a clubfoot?
Some can be operated
and some can't. Why?
A good friend of mine's
got a granddaughter.
She's a mighty nice girl.
One time a doctor told her old man
that an operation could fix it.
I was just wondering if...
- Young kid, is she?
- About 20, I guess.
Twenty. I see.
My advice, Roy,
is to forget all about her foot.
- Look, Doc, I ain't kidding.
- I'll have to see her.
Will you take a look if I can talk her into it?
Sure. Of course, Roy.
I can't do any operating,
but I can get you someone who will.
- It'll cost you plenty, though.
- Okay, Doc. I'll give you a ring.
Good. Do that, Roy.
And I'll make you a present of my fee,
for old times' sake.
- Good night.
- Good night, Doc.
- I don't know, Mac, the...
- Yeah, I do.
There. I feel better. That's the works.
Now, if anything should happen to me...
read this letter
and you'll know what to do.
As the Doc told you...
if I don't lay off this stuff
it's gonna knock me off.
But I'm gonna die, anyhow.
So are you. So are we all.
Your health, Roy.
- Hello, Roy.
- Hello, Pa.
Glad to see you.
This is the Doc,
Mr. Parker, of the New Health Institute.
- Proud to meet you, Mr. Parker.
- How do you do?
- He's kind of an expert, knows his stuff.
- Yeah?
After you called up I spoke to them all...
and I think I've got Velma on my side,
but Ma is against it.
Please excuse things, the way they look.
We're just getting straightened out.
- Roy, this is Mabel.
- How do you do?
This is her husband, Carl.
This is Mr. Parker, Mabel.
How do you do?
- Hello, Roy.
- Hello, Velma.
Say, I'd like you to meet Mr. Parker.
- How do you do?
- Velma.
You say, "Mr. Parker."
Isn't he even a doctor?
I am a specialist.
You should be thankful someone's
trying to do something for your girl.
You've nothing to say about this.
Velma's my girl,
and I'm thinking, if he isn't even a doctor...
He can look at her, can't he?
That won't hurt nothing.
I don't think Velma wants him
to look at her.
- Do you, dear?
- Pa wants him to. So does Roy.
Who is this Roy, anyway?
You know all about Roy.
If it hadn't been for him...
Why does he go to so much trouble
to help strangers?
He must have some reason.
Maybe he likes Velma.
She ain't married yet, and likely not to be.
- And if you want my opinion...
- We don't want your opinion.
Look, you got Velma all upset
talking like that.
All right.
Don't worry. If you don't want him
to see your foot you don't have to let him.
But I do.
Okay. If the child's made up her mind,
I've nothing more to say.
Come along, Mr. Parker. Come on, Ma.
This way, Doctor.
If this here specialist
says he can operate on Velma, what then?
- Operations cost money.
- I'll loan you the money.
I could never pay it back. You know that.
- I ain't worrying about that.
- I know.
Anybody with eyes in their head.
She's pretty, ain't she?
And just as sweet as she's pretty.
Are you figuring on marrying Velma, Roy?
I ain't got that far in my figuring.
I don't know what's the right thing to do,
but it seems to me...
before you go putting out money,
I ought to tell you about Velma.
What about her?
She's got a fellow back home.
His name's Preiser.
He's about 30 years old
and already divorced.
He's doing good in the insurance business,
but it didn't look right...
a divorced man running around
with a crippled girl.
So Ma and me brings Velma
out here to her mother.
Now, it's my guess that
Velma's still thinking about that fellow.
Now mind,
I don't think there's anything wrong.
I'm always telling myself there wasn't.
It makes me feel better.
That's about all there is to it, Roy.
I hope you ain't sore or anything.
No, I ain't sore at nobody.
I guess it sounds funny,
and I ain't got the right words to fit it...
but it seems as if I'd been close to Velma
for a million years.
And knowing her like I do...
nobody ain't ever gonna tell me
she's ever done a wrong thing.
'Cause I know, you understand?
Now, she's not to know
you ever told me anything.
All right, Roy, anything you say.
Roy, he says it can be fixed.
There's nothing serious. We'll soon have
her walking as well as anybody.
Jiminy Cricket! Ain't that wonderful, Ma?
Now, honey, you just thank Roy.
Roy's the one.
He thought up the whole thing,
and he's lending me the money.
You, Mr. Collins? You, why, I...
I mean, I hope you'll excuse
the way I acted...
but I've been so worried about Velma,
poor child.
After all, I am her mother and...
Mr. Parker here
will take care of everything.
You got nothing to worry about, Velma.
Roy, you're so good.
Pa says you're the best man
that ever lived.
And I guess Pa's right.
Goodbye.
Darnedest fellow.
It's criminal nothing's ever been done
for that girl before.
It's a simple enough operation.
I got an in with the best surgeon in town.
The whole thing will set you back
about $400, though.
- You satisfied?
- Yeah, sure, I'm satisfied.
But I'm giving it to you straight.
You're just sticking your neck out.
She's not your kind, you know it.
And she's gonna throw an awful fit...
when she finds out
what kind of a guy you really are.
- Yeah, I know.
- You may catch lead any minute.
What you need is a fast-stepping
young filly you can keep up with.
Remember what Johnny Dillinger said
about guys like you and him?
He said you were
just rushing toward death.
Yeah, that's it. Just rushing toward death.
What's the matter, Pard,
you been hiding out?
- Is that you, Roy?
- Yeah.
- Is Pard with you?
- Yeah, he's right here.
You had me scared.
- What are you doing in there?
- Come on in.
I'm glad Pard is all right.
I was afraid Babe had killed him.
- Did he do that?
- Yeah, he went crazy.
Red tried to cool him off,
but he fought like a wildcat.
And he picked up a poker
and hit Red over the head with it.
When Red was down,
he swung at me twice.
- Were these guys fighting over you?
- Red was standing up for me.
- When was this?
- About dark.
Where are they?
As soon as Babe knocked Red cold,
he started running for the store.
Then I heard Pard barking,
and Babe threw a poker at him.
So I ran over here and locked myself in.
I found this under your pillow.
I figured if Babe sneaked back,
I could hold him off.
- He was like a crazy guy.
- Give me that. You stay here.
- You'll only get yourself in a jam.
- Shut up and lock this door behind me.
- Roy.
- Give me that gun.
- Nobody's gonna push me around.
- Give it to me.
- Is he in there?
- He's scared to come out.
- You were gonna kill him?
- He hit my head...
You wait right here. I'll handle this.
I had him hooked good. He was all
played out and I'm reaching for my net.
Good night, fellows. Here's my pal.
I guess I'll get along.
Good night, son.
I hope tomorrow you get a 10-pounder.
- Yeah, thanks.
- Good night.
- You stinking rat.
- I know, I went crazy. Marie, she tried to...
Yeah, that's right. Blame the dame. Go on.
Here he is. Mark him up.
Swing on him. Hit him with this.
No, I don't want to hurt him.
Roy, don't hurt him.
He won't act like that again.
Your car's outside. If I was you,
I'd beat it, and quick. Both of you.
Roy, we been counting on this job.
I'm giving you a chance to blow.
If you decide to stick...
I'll shoot the first one
that don't do as I tell him.
Okay, Roy. Come on, Babe.
I'm not going back to the cabin.
You better not.
Trouble would just start all over again.
Look, I found a cot in the woodshed.
I can fix it up
and sleep here in the kitchen.
All right.
I'll have Algernon get you clothes
and I'll send you home tomorrow.
No.
No, I say.
You can't hold me.
Take the gates away. I'm crashing out.
Yeah, sure.
I'll go back to the farm...
sweet Indiana farm.
But you're holding me back.
Don't hold me back.
I'll crash out, I tell you.
You can't.
No, you can't do it.
Farm's the best. Yeah, that's the best.
You can't take it away. You can't.
- Little more coffee?
- Yeah.
What, are you all packed?
I thought maybe I could...
I'll run you over to Ballard.
You can catch a bus.
I haven't got a soul in L.A.
- Where you from?
- San Francisco.
- Family there?
- Yeah.
Maybe I can stake you to a ticket.
Remember what you were saying
the other day about prison...
and the way you kept from going crazy
by thinking all the time about a crash-out?
That's the way it's been with me.
I've been trying to crash out
ever since I can remember.
My old man used to get drunk
a couple of times a week...
and kick us around.
My old lady used to stand it.
But not me.
I waited for my chance, and I beat it.
- I crashed out, just like you did.
- I got you.
Then I came down to L.A.
And got a job in a dime-a-dance joint.
It was a living...
but I got pretty sick of being pawed over.
So when Babe came along,
I crashed out again.
I thought Babe was the right guy.
I guess I was never really hooked up
with any guys that wasn't wrong.
So I had nothing to go by...
till I met you.
I'll get ready.
Go away, Pard, will you?
What's the matter?
Roy, please don't send me back to L.A.
Please don't.
I want to stay with you. Please, Roy, don't.
Listen to me.
I'm giving it to you straight.
I got plans, see?
And there's no room in them for you.
You couldn't never mean nothing to me.
Nothing special, that is.
You know what I mean?
I'm gonna take a run down to L.A.
I can't stand this waiting around.
Let me go along, Roy, will you?
I sure would like to take in a movie.
All right. Get your things
and bring my hat.
Okay. I won't be a second.
We'll be back in plenty of time
in case Mendoza calls, if he ever calls.
I don't like the way he's stalling around.
I just don't like it.
- You guys keep your noses clean.
- Yeah, sure, Roy.
Roy, Pard's following us.
- Go on home, Pard. Go back.
- Roy, let's take him along with us.
I gotta leave him sometime.
He has to get used to it.
Yeah, you gotta leave him sometime,
so let's take him now.
All right.
Here, boy.
You gonna take in a movie
when we get to L.A.?
I don't care, I just came for the ride.
I guess I'd better take care of Pard, then,
if you're going to a movie.
Where you going?
- To see some people, friends of mine.
- What's their racket?
They're not in any racket.
He's a farmer from Ohio, lost his farm.
There's him and Ma
and his granddaughter.
Granddaughter?
Yeah. Her name's Velma.
Just had an operation on her foot.
Mighty pretty girl.
Is she?
Yeah, and decent.
- Hello, Pa.
- Hello, Roy.
I'll be doggoned. Where you been?
- How's Velma?
- You wouldn't know her.
- Is she walking around?
- She's still in bed.
But the doctor says in a few days
she can dance or do anything...
and nobody would ever know
she was crippled.
Say, that's great.
Hello, boy. There's a cute little fellow.
Roy, it's about time.
Ma, cut that out.
Roy's a darn nice-looking fellow
and I'm jealous.
Come on in and see Velma.
She'll be glad to see you.
Roy, you look so good.
Mabel's husband is at work,
and Mabel's uptown, gadding around...
so you got her all to yourself today, Roy.
I hear you're all right.
- She wants to kiss you.
- Ma.
We were wondering
what happened to you, Roy.
I've been pretty busy.
Did it hurt much
when they fixed your foot?
It didn't hurt at all. I didn't even know it.
We'll never get through thanking you.
It was wonderful of you.
Say, I got a big business deal coming up...
and if it goes through the way
I think it ought to, I can quit for life.
That's fine, Roy. Did you tell Pa?
I was thinking that if this deal
goes through the way it ought to...
I'd like to take a trip around the world.
And I was just...
You see what I mean, Velma?
Yes, I see.
I was thinking if you didn't want
to a take a trip around the world...
what would you like to do?
You see, Velma, I'd sure like to marry you.
I ain't so old and I'm gonna have
plenty of dough someday.
Gee, I don't know.
You sure been wonderful to us, Roy.
And Pa says
there's no better man than you.
- But, Roy...
- You got somebody back home, I guess.
Yes, in a way I have.
He's figuring on coming out here
to marry you?
I don't know. I may go back there.
I ought to be hearing from him
any day now.
Are you crazy about him, Velma?
I guess that lets me out.
But we can still be friends, though,
can't we, Roy?
When will we see you again?
I don't know.
But I'll be walking in a few days.
You simply must come back
to see me walk.
Of course he will.
I'll come back and see Velma walk.
What's wrong, pet?
He wants me to marry him, Pa...
and I said I wouldn't on account of Lon.
I don't love Roy, Pa.
I'm not crippled anymore, Pa.
And from now on I'm gonna have fun...
dressing up and going places and dancing.
I'll dance all night long if I want to!
I know what Roy did for me, Pa.
But I don't love him.
I just don't love him!
There, there.
Good morning. A man phoned in
a telegram for Mr. Collins.
Hello, Pard. You hard-luck dog, you.
It's from Mendoza. Tonight's the night.
Here are the three hammers.
Shall I take the sledge, Roy?
I don't know. I never cracked
a safety deposit box before.
I don't see why
Mendoza can't open those boxes.
It'd be a tip-off that it was an inside job.
The cops would pinch him and he'd sing,
or I don't know guys.
Roy, what about Pard?
Take him over to Algernon
and tell him to lock him up. Here's $5.
- Why not take him along?
- Taking a dog on a caper, that's rich.
I'd watch after him.
You do as I tell you.
I guess that's everything.
Now, listen. When we get into the hotel,
don't anybody look up.
No matter what happens.
That's my business.
Nobody's gonna bother you,
and I mean nobody.
Are there any questions?
Marie and I will head to L.A.
With the jewelry in a shoebox.
You take the dough and come here.
When you hear from us,
bring the dough to L.A. All right?
I guess we're all set.
I'm glad Marie's going.
She's got more nerve than most guys.
And we'll make up her share between us.
That's fair, ain't it?
You bet. It's worth it to have someone
to watch out for the car.
I'll never forget a guy I knew
called Petty Garrison.
One day him and another creep
waltzes in to knock over a grocery store.
They left the heap outside
with the engine on.
They come out ahead of a shotgun blast.
Somebody snitched it.
So they ducks down an alley
and runs right smack into a copper.
- Brother, what a mess.
- You think of the prettiest stories to tell.
- They was just small-timers, not like us.
- We wasn't big till this one.
- I don't feel big.
- Roy feels big. That's what counts.
Cut the gab and get going.
Pard's locked in.
He knows there's something up...
he keeps scratching at the door.
That little mutt's just a plain nuisance.
- That's Pard. I told you he knew.
- Shut up and get in the car.
Wish that dog would stop howling.
Gives me the creeps.
- What's wrong with you?
- It's Pard. He got loose. He's following us.
- He can't follow us far at night.
- Roy, you can't.
Who says I can't? What I ought to do
is put a bullet through his head.
Ain't I got enough trouble
without a fool dog?
Let him in.
Poor little fellow.
Got no home, got nobody, have you?
Of all the 14-karat saps.
Starting out on a caper
with a woman and a dog.
- Lf he spoils this job, I'll...
- You're full of talk.
I think you're glad.
Shut up. One move,
and I'll fill your pants with lead.
- Get over there.
- I will, sir.
Open it up, quick.
- How's it going?
- Having a little trouble with the boxes.
How you doing?
Got a few more. This is really something.
- Quiet, peaceful little hotel.
- Nice time of night to build a house.
Get over there. Shut up. Go on, move.
Over there. Move fast.
Bob, my rings. You've got to stop them.
Look, my friend, you can't do this. I mean...
Sit down.
You won't get hurt. Hey, you.
- Yes, sir?
- Sit over there.
- Go on, hurry up.
- Yes, sir.
Heist them, buddy.
Take me with you. I couldn't face the cops.
I didn't think we'd have to shoot.
He won't croak, I shot low.
Go on, get in that car.
Police!
He's taking the wrong road.
- The coppers will go to the fire now.
- Roy, those boys.
Small-timers for small jobs.
They lost their heads.
This one was just too big.
- You feeling better now?
- Still kind of wobbly.
- I keep thinking of Babe and Red.
- There's no use of worrying about them.
If they didn't kick off,
the coppers have them.
Do you think they'll talk?
If they don't, Mendoza will.
But who cares?
I'll be giving that box to Big Mac
in a couple of hours.
He's gonna hand me a wad of dough.
Gee. Then we'll be all set, won't we, Roy?
Sure. You got quite a piece of change
coming to you, too.
And I'm gonna see
that you get it right away.
'Cause I'll be blowing pretty soon.
Going back East, I guess.
- I'm going with you.
- Don't talk like a sap.
If you stick with me,
you'll never be in anything but trouble.
Look, Roy, no matter what happens,
I'm sticking with you.
Don't think you're ever gonna
check me so easy.
We'll see. Come on, let's go.
Come on, Pard.
But remember...
if the going gets too tough,
I'm gonna have to park you for a while.
I'm glad you said "for a while."
That makes me feel good.
If I really get in your way,
you can park me.
Is that a deal?
It's a deal.
I won't be long.
- Hello, Earle.
- What are you doing here?
Mac sent for me.
I flew out a couple of days ago.
Mighty sick man, Mac is.
He collapsed last night. He's asleep now.
Want to read about yourself?
Tough about the two guys.
- It was their own fault.
- Their troubles are over.
Both of them.
Mendoza broke his collarbone.
He got knocked cold, but he'll be okay.
Police think he was kidnapped.
They haven't identified Babe and Red.
Let's show the stuff to Mac.
It might cheer him up.
- You got it in that shoebox there?
- Yeah, and it sure is heavy.
Boss, wake up. Earle's here.
He clipped them for $500,000.
I sure come through for you.
You didn't spring me for nothing.
Wake up, Mac. Earle's here.
This guy is dead.
- He's what?
- He's dead.
Yep, cold as a mackerel.
Kicked off in his sleep, I guess.
What are you gonna do with the stuff?
Mac told me what to do
in case something like this happened.
I guess he knew he'd never make it.
Don't be a sap. Mac's dead, and we're rich.
I can get a fence to handle this stuff.
Don't you see it? We're rich.
Listen, chiseler, I'm still working for him,
and so are you.
I got my instructions and I'll follow them.
Use your head, man.
This is a chance of a lifetime.
- You heard me.
- Okay, maybe you're right.
Pico, 7719.
Hello. This you, Art?
This is Earle. Mac's dead.
Yeah. He said in the letter to call you.
That you was to do the handling.
Nope. He just kicked off.
His heart.
Okay. Thanks.
Hand over that box, Earle.
You give me any trouble
and I'll fill you full of lead.
I'd be reinstated and get a medal besides.
Just what I told poor Mac.
A copper's always a copper.
This stuff's pretty hot, anyway.
Here it is.
What happened?
I was going to look for you.
- Get in the car. You gotta drive.
- What's wrong?
Bullet nicked me.
Go to Vermont and turn right.
You're mighty lucky, Roy.
A little higher,
it would have been curtains for you.
That stuff sure burns, Doc.
Tell me, Roy,
did you really crack them for $500,000?
We can't tell yet.
They always kick up the price
after a heist, but I got plenty of rocks.
You'll have to trust me
on the dough angle.
- I only got about $50 or $60 on me.
- You didn't get your cut yet?
That's all right, but I figure
this will cost you about $500.
- I'm taking an awful chance.
- $500's okay with me.
When I need help, I need it bad,
and I'm willing to pay for it.
- What about little Velma?
- I don't know, Doc.
That was just one of them things, I guess.
Is she walking pretty good now?
Perfectly. That surgeon friend of mine
did a magnificent job.
You ought to see her.
It'd do your heart good.
Maybe I will look in for a minute.
I promised the old man I would.
You'd better be going now.
Make a right turn here.
What about getting rid of the stuff?
Aren't we going to Santa Monica?
There's something I gotta do first.
It'll only take a minute.
Velma?
I promised Pa I'd come back
and see her walk.
Fine time you picked to go calling.
- Can I go in with you?
- You'll stay in the car.
I'm only going in myself
because I promised the old man.
Yeah, I know. You said that.
My foot gets stronger all the time, Lon.
Don't you think I'm dancing better?
Sure, baby. You're perfect.
How about a little drink?
No, Lon. You want me to get dizzy again
like last night?
Cootchie, cootchie!
- Do you think they'll be all right?
- Sure. Joe's a panic when he's tight.
You said it, boy. Listen, I was...
Now, look here.
I never was one to spoil a good time...
but enough's enough. That's what I say...
Who's that now?
- Roy.
- Hello, Pa.
Well, this is a surprise!
Hello, Roy! Well, it's about time
you dropped in. Where have you been?
The rest of the family's out for a ride.
They'll be sorry they missed you.
Roy, this is Mr. Preiser. He's my...
He's from back home.
Hello. Velma's told me a lot about you.
We had a couple of drinks to you
the other night.
- Did you?
- Yeah.
You haven't seen me dance yet.
My foot's all better now. Watch me.
Go on, Pard. Go get Roy. Go find him.
This is a fine party,
letting a lady dance by herself.
Come on, baby.
I declare, who's that now?
Pard, you bad dog, you!
I'm sorry. He jumped out of the car
before I knew what had happened.
Hello. You're Velma, aren't you?
- That's right.
- I'm Marie Garson, a friend of Roy's.
I feel as though I know you.
Roy has often told me how nice you are.
Has he?
Say, that reminds me,
you did a lot for Velma, Roy.
I gotta pay you back.
After all, it's a lot of money.
- Forget it. Think nothing of it.
- But I'd like you to take it, Roy.
After all, Lon and I will be married soon,
and he can afford it easily.
Getting married?
Well, that's fine.
Yeah, that's swell.
Well, I guess I'll be on my way, Pa.
I'm going back East.
I just came in to say goodbye.
Well, let's have a drink together first.
You and your little girlie,
and me and my little Velma.
Get your hands off me.
- I'm sorry.
- I don't like you.
I don't like the way you talk
and I don't like your friends.
I don't like to think of her
being married to you.
Now, come on, Roy.
You haven't got any right
to say such things!
Lon's gonna be my husband
and I love him.
You're just jealous and mean
'cause I don't want you.
'Cause I never wanted you.
I'm sure sorry.
It's all right. Maybe it's just as well
it happened this way.
- Goodbye, Pa.
- Goodbye.
Some nerve he had.
If it wasn't for you,
I'd have punched him right in the nose.
- You shouldn't have come in there.
- I had to, Roy.
You thought of her more than you did me.
I just wanted to know why.
You don't love her anymore, do you?
No.
If you weren't sure of it,
you wouldn't have asked me.
If I didn't know where they come from,
I'd think they was phony.
Poor old Mac.
There he was, laying there dead,
with $500,000 beside him.
It's all yours, and all I want is my cut.
You're gonna have to wait
a few days for that, Roy.
- What?
- Don't look at me like that.
My share you could put in your eye.
Larry's the head man,
now that Mac's gone.
- Kansas City?
- That's him.
He's flying out.
Now, you leave the stuff with me
and hide out for a while.
I can help you out a little.
Are you trying to pull a fast one on me?
Because I don't like fast ones.
Take the stuff with you
if you feel that way.
But it'll be like carrying a bomb around.
Okay. Give me a couple of $100s
and keep this.
But if I don't get my end,
you ain't gonna be around long.
You and Larry both.
Now, don't worry, Roy.
You'll get it. Here's $200.
Yeah, that's what I want.
That's a present.
Of course, you would put it
on the wrong finger.
Well?
Same old song. Nothing doing yet.
I'm gonna run out of dough
with all these long-distance calls.
You should've taken the money
Velma's boyfriend offered you.
But, no, "Think nothing of it."
That's what you said. Sucker.
Yeah. Don't look like this thing's
ever going to cool off.
Look, I've been thinking things over.
I like little Pard here as much as you do...
but remember what Algernon said
about him being bad luck?
- That's a lot of malarkey.
- Maybe it is, and maybe it isn't.
How could a poor little dog be the cause
of it all? That's just dumb!
Sometimes you get me crazy.
You think nobody knows nothing but you.
Okay, Pard's to blame for everything.
It's all his fault. Have it your way.
I only said there might be something to it.
- Shut up.
- Don't tell me to shut up, you...
Honey, I'm sorry.
It's hurting you, isn't it? You just let me
change this dressing for you.
I'm sorry.
It don't look so good, Roy. It's all red.
- Do you feel as if you have any fever?
- I don't think so.
I don't know, maybe I have.
Think I ought to go in and see the Doc?
No, you can't do that. They might get you.
You can't trust anybody, Roy.
After all, $10,000 is a lot of money.
You ought to turn me in
and live easy for the rest of your life.
Even in fun, don't ever say things like that.
Thanks, sonny.
- Morning.
- Morning, Mr. Collins.
Baby, our troubles are over.
I'm driving in tonight.
I called Art
and he said they'll have my cut ready.
- How's that?
- That's great.
Now we can go back East
where we'll be safe.
I thought they were giving me
the old runaround.
- It sure is easy to be wrong in this world.
- Honey, love me?
You bet I do.
- Let him out, will you?
- Okay.
- Pains?
- Yeah, a little.
Look, honey, I'll drive in.
Nothing doing. Suppose we get a rumble?
They're not even looking for you yet.
Still, I'll drive.
You go ahead with the packing.
- I think the car needs gas.
- All right.
Nice little Pard.
Nice little boy. Shake hands?
Nice Pard. He's a fine boy. Nice little Pard.
I want to see you.
I'm busy. I got a lot to do this morning.
That's a nice little dog you got there.
I was trying to make up with him.
What makes you think his name's Pard?
Didn't I hear you call him that yesterday?
Maybe I'm wrong.
Get in.
You know who I am, don't you?
No. I never saw you
before you came here. Honest.
- What are you so scared about, then?
- Please don't kill me.
Open that door.
Looking for that reward?
Listen to this:
"Police are hot on his trail.
"He's traveling with a woman
called Marie...
"and a little white mongrel dog
who answers to the name of Pard."
- Mendoza.
- Yeah. He squawked.
I should've taken care of him
when he followed me out of the hotel.
Look at the tag they hung on me,
"Mad Dog" Earle.
Them newspaper rats!
What are we gonna do, Roy?
Wait a minute.
- I gotta park you for a while like you said.
- Like who said?
We agreed that if the going got tough,
I was to park you.
You said it was a deal.
Now look, Roy, I can't leave you now.
I don't care what happens to me.
Let's stick together.
Let the money go. Forget about it.
We'll head East. Then we'll be safe.
Baby, you need dough to get back East.
I've got maybe $30,000 coming to me
and I'm gonna get it. Now, listen.
I got an idea.
I'll put you on the bus to Las Vegas.
Wait there for me.
I'll get my end, then I'll come after you.
Roy, please don't leave me.
I'm scared about it.
You think I want to take you in
and get you shot?
When they hang that
number-one tag on you...
they shoot first and argue afterwards.
I know.
"Mad Dog" Earle. How do you like that?
They've tied me up
with that Kranmer killing.
If they get me, I haven't got a chance.
But they ain't gonna get me.
I've done all the time I'm ever gonna do.
I'll tie that guy up.
Now, listen. You go on down to the store...
and get a big basket with a lid.
Put Pard in it and take him with you.
Okay, Roy, I'll do anything you say.
Come on, Pard. Get in here. Come on.
Get in.
When you get to Las Vegas,
go to the place I told you.
Don't ask nobody no questions.
I'll be with you tomorrow night
at the latest. Got that?
I just got a feeling about it, Roy.
I'm awful sorry for the way I've acted.
- You got nothing to be sorry about.
- Yes, I have.
Nagging at you and flying off the handle.
I wish I hadn't.
I like it. I mean, that's the way
married people ought to act.
My ma and pa fought like cats and dogs,
going on 40 years.
I wouldn't give you two cents
for a dame without a temper.
Here she comes.
Here. Take this.
That's all you got, Roy.
I don't need that much.
That's all right, you keep it. I'm all right.
You're all I got in the world.
Come on now, baby.
I'll see you tomorrow night.
Turning from the European news,
a bulletin just handed me states...
"Mad Dog"Roy Earle
has been identified as the man...
who slugged a tourist camp proprietor
this morning at Palmville on route 395.
Subject of one of the most intensive
searches in California history...
the bandit killer
and his companion, Marie...
are believed to be headed
toward Los Angeles.
- Can I help you, sir?
- Yeah. Give me a pack of cigarettes.
Don't give me trouble, I won't hurt you.
Hand over your dough.
Yes, sir. Don't get nervous now.
I'll never get myself shot up over money.
You're right. You got sense.
- John, give me a Coke.
- Look out, Tom, it's Roy Earle!
- What is all this?
- Holdup, Henry.
John thought it was Roy Earle.
Been reading too many
detective magazines.
Sure looked like Earle's picture.
If it's him, he's headed back over the pass.
Operator, give me 420.
Sheriff, Holden speaking. Paramount
Drug Store has just been held up...
and robbed by a man identified
as Roy Earle.
Yeah, looks just like him.
Okay. Patrol car 41
waiting on Highbridge Road.
Good. We'll have him bottled up
in another hour.
All right, boys, scatter
and watch yourselves. He's armed.
We better keep under cover.
Charley, Spike,
see if you can work over to his left.
- Lf he moves, let him have it.
- He'll never survive.
We've trapped him. I know this country.
Hank and Sam,
go up to the ridge and wait.
Hey, you! You have no chance!
Come on down! We won't do no shooting!
Come and get me, buddy!
What's the matter, you yellow?
Scout out the Ranger Station
and get Slim up there...
with his high-powered rifle
and telescope sight.
He's in command of several hundred feet
between him and the road.
Natural rock formations shelter him
from attacks above.
It is some five hours now
since Roy Earle took to cover on the rock...
and there's no indication
on his part to surrender.
The road up the mountain
is a jam of traffic.
Spectators are coming from all over.
As I said before,
the scene is some 60 miles from Ballard.
I must go back.
Is there another bus going back soon?
One leaves from here in about 10 minutes.
Just like all dames. She don't know
whether she's coming or going.
It's infernally cold up here.
Maybe it's nerves.
The rock above, where Earle is hiding,
looks like a huge iceberg.
Whenever the flares are lit,
the faces of the crowd...
Iook like white masks of snow.
They look dead, all but their eyes.
- Where do you think you're going?
- I'm Healy, of the Bulletin.
Let's see your police card.
Okay.
One of the many rumors
is that Earle's about to give himself up.
Another, that they've sent...
for a squadron of Army bombing planes
to blast Earle out.
While all this is going on...
the Sheriff and his men
are holding conferences.
The nerves of everyone
are getting more taut.
In fact, the crowd's getting very restless.
Huge spotlights are trained
on Earle's fortress.
Looks like they're doing something new.
- Howdy, Sheriff.
- Hello, Charlie.
- Say, Slim?
- Yeah?
- See that peak up there?
- Yeah.
Reckon you could work your way up
above where that fella's hiding?
Ain't never been done before.
Straight 1,000 feet.
I don't know. I'll take a try at it.
There's the Sheriff talking with a man
with a queer-looking rifle.
Any minute now,
it may be curtains for Roy Earle.
This seems to be the coldest place in
the world tonight. Cold and unreal.
One is awed by the gruesomeness
of this rendezvous with death.
The morbidly curious onlookers watching
as if it were a game.
The tall pine trees,
clustered around like a silent jury.
The stern-faced officers
waiting for the kill...
and up above a defiant gangster from
a simple farm on the flats of Indiana...
about to be killed on the highest
mountain peak in the United States.
What's the idea, you?
Get back where you belong.
Anybody else tries that'll get run in. See?
What are you up to, sister?
Why did you try to get through this line?
What did you mean to do?
Have you a little dog in that basket?
A little gray-white dog?
Boy.
What's the matter with her?
Earle's been traveling
with a girl called Marie.
Sure, I know. What about it?
Meet Marie.
Hey, Sheriff!
I guess Slim couldn't make it.
Listen, you. For the last time,
I'm telling you to call Earle.
If you don't get wise to yourself...
Wait a minute, George. Look, Marie.
It's dawn now,
and we can't wait any longer.
We don't want to kill your man
unless we have to.
Why don't you tell him to come down
and surrender peaceably?
If you help us now, it'll go easier with you.
I'm not thinking of myself.
Be smart. Just yell up to him and tell him
to put his gun away and come down.
Otherwise, we'll get him sure.
All right.
Go ahead and yell.
No, I won't.
- What's that?
- I won't, I tell you.
- We'll get him, then.
- He'll die anyway.
He'd rather it was this way.
Go on, kill him, all of you!
Kill him! Do you hear?
Okay, lady, we're through.
Earle, come down, it's your last chance!
Come and get me,
there's plenty of you down there!
I'm telling you it's your last chance!
That's what you say, copper!
Big-shot Earle. Well, well.
Look at him lying there.
He ain't much now, is he?
What does it mean...
when a man crashes out?
Crashes out?
That's a funny question
for you to ask now, sister.
It means he's free.
Free?
Free.
English