Fight! Fight! Fight!
Bef ore we begin...
Settle down. I got a question
I want to ask you all.
How many people came here
to change the world?
to learn how to make a lot of money?
Hey, we got an outreach program here
where we really tap into the community.
What's the point?
Hey, listen, my f riends. You are
the few, the proud, the next...
...incoming f reshman class
to Columbus University.
...unyieldina pursuit
of academic ex cellence...
...one university stands
out amonast the rest.:
Columbus University.
-What's up, Malik?
-What's up, dog?
-Your mama got you some school gear.
-Your mama let me use her credit card.
-Yeah, all right.
-We'll see you.
Malik, what's wrong with you?
What?
This.
Why you always trying to showboat?
How come you're not dressed?
My stomach was giving me trouble.
You think because you're a superstar
rookie you don't have to work?
I got guys on this field who'll clean
your clock in five seconds.
Who?
Get off my field.
It's like that?
That's how you made it.
Dig.
Little off today, baby, huh?
-Hi.
-I'm Kristen.
-Monet.
We're roommates, huh?
Yep. I like this side of the room,
but I guess you got here first.
Yeah, I guess I did.
So, where are you f rom?
-Orange County.
-Orange County, huh?
-ls that near Compton?
-No.
-You're not f rom around here, are you?
It's near Disneyland.
You live near Disneyland?
-Must be nice.
-lt has its moments.
Yeah!
Go!
This is crazy.
Come on, girls, let's go.
I am getting my own
apartment next semester.
These dorms are f or children.
I hate them. God.
-Do you want to room with me?
-Hell, yeah. My room's like this big.
What about you?
Want to get an apartment together?
-I can't aff ord it.
-No sweat. Get your parents to pay.
-They can't.
-Why not?
My dad got laid off
f rom McDonnell Douglas last year.
The IRS audited him. My parents
could barely aff ord to send me here.
-But you are here.
-I'm here and I'm happy.
My roommate's a Mexican,
I bet she got a scholarship.
Shut up. Well, here we are.
All right, come here, darling.
Drink! Drink! Drink!
-Theta Kappa!
-Hey, Chad.
Well, well, what do we got here?
New recruits f or our Little Sister rush?
No, no. Actually, I don't
know about that.
-Ladies, this is Chad.
-Hi, Chad.
-Hey.
-And this is Nicole, okay?
And this is Claudia, right?
-And this is, uh...
-Kristen.
Kristen. I'm sorry. They're f reshmen.
How do we become Little Sisters?
They probably make you drink beer
out of condoms and wet your T-shirt.
Beer out of a condom...
That's a new one. Write that down.
-I will.
-No, we don't do that here.
But I'll tell you this. There's nobody
on this campus who parties like we do!
Yo!
Man, governments
ain't running things no more.
Financial institutions,
they controlling the whole thing.
You ever hear of the World Bank
or the IMF? No, huh?
Y'all probably don't even have
checking accounts.
But y'all got them
credit cards, huh?
Buy stuff out your means
and wonder why you still a slave.
Y'all better recognize,
I'm telling you.
Dude, when are you gonna clear
everyone out? Classes start tomorrow.
-lt's over when it's over, dude.
-" Dude."
I can't take this no more.
-Yo, man, watch my shoes.
-You got a problem, man?
Security.
Look at this.
-What's up, kid?
-They're playing their music, man.
Who?
These guys. I'm not trying to narc,
but tomorrow's the first day of class.
I got physics in the morning.
It's like f riggin' Soul Train up there.
You're here to study, not to party.
Head home and hit those books.
Glad you had a good time.
Come again on the weekend.
Good night. Okay.
People are trying to sleep.
Give them a little respect, huh?
You don't hear that down the hall?
You ain't sweating them because they're
playing that hillbilly shit, right?
No, no. Because I dig rock 'n' roll.
Then roll your f at ass
down the hall then.
That's that old bullshit.
Hey!
-Why are you walking alone?
-I don't know.
It's not safe to walk around
campus by yourself at night.
I just left the Row 'cause my f riends
were drinking and acting crazy.
I just went my own way.
Some f riends.
Yeah.
Look at all these pretty blue lights.
You don't know what
they're f or, do you?
No. Decoration?
No, it's the blue-light system.
See, there's a phone
at the end of every block.
That way you can call security
in case someone tries to grab you.
You're gonna have
to be caref ul out here.
Come on.
I just got here.
Have you met anybody yet?
Yeah, I just met somebody.
My name's Taryn.
-Junior.
-Kristen. Freshman.
Fresh-woman?
Yeah, I could tell.
Well, my first class is at 8:00.
-So...
-Where's your dorm?
It's right here. Holland Hall.
Real close.
-Thanks.
-Sure. Oh, wait.
Here.
Students f or a Non-Sexist Society.
We have meetings Wednesdays
if you want to come by.
Okay. Thanks.
Oh, man.
Oh, man, I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were here.
-lt's time f or us to talk.
-About what?
About your side of the room.
What's wrong with it?
Look at it, man. It's filthy,
it's f unky, it's stinking, man.
-What you do on that side affects me.
-All right, I'll try.
Let's take a trip around the world.
Look there, under the statue.
You see them people?
That's Disneyland.
And there's Chinatown.
And over there,
that's south of the border.
And this right here is the black hole
because we're black f olks.
So, you Fudge, huh?
I heard about you.
-What'd you hear about me?
-I heard you were a super-duper senior.
Been here six years
and still haven't graduated.
-She trying to play you out.
-Why is that?
Because I done already
learned the game, f resh fish.
Is that right, old trout?
Yo.
Y'all some trained Negroes.
Soon as you hear a bell,
y'all go running.
Welcome to the real world.
Or, as it states in your schedule
of courses, Political Science 101 .
I am your instructor.
My name is Professor Maurice Phipps.
Today I am going to give you your first
lesson in politics. Are you ready?
Now, I shall need one volunteer.
Anyone?
No wonder this nation is f alling
behind the rest of the world.
No one in this class
seems to have any initiative.
You, brave soul, come f orward.
-And what is your name, my good man?
-Malik Williams, Professor Phipps, sir.
Malik Williams. Mr. Williams,
would you be kind enough...
...to read the names
with the asterisks beside them?
Those persons whose names
are called, please stand.
All right. " Marvin Anthony,
Wendy Arrington, Tanya Arroyo...
...Chris Barlow, Skye Blue,
Jennifer Bryant...
Pamela Burris, Eric Cannon,
Kristen Connor, Judith Dantzig...
...Patsy Ewing, Mark Katz...
...Malik Williams." What?
Thank you, Mr. Williams.
You have served your purpose.
What's that list f or, dog?
Those persons whose names were
called and whom are standing...
...the university instructed me that
your financial bill hasn't been paid.
Leave and settle your debts. You
may not return until you have done so.
There are no handouts
in the f ree world...
...and, appropriately, none in
my course. Thank you and good day.
Shit.
Professor Phipps, I need this class
f or my major. You know?
Young lady, calm yourself and go
to the financial aid office.
Go.
What about me?
Don't you have
some business to attend to?
Yeah, but I thought
I just showed initiative.
That don't count f or nothing, brother?
Mr. Williams, I do not appreciate,
nor will I tolerate...
...people who try to brownnose
in my course.
Now go to the financial aid office
or appeal to the athletic department.
I ain't no dumb athlete.
That remains to be seen.
Right. I hope that all of you...
Yo, dog, take good notes.
I'm gonna need to borrow them.
Now that the bureaucratic nonsense
is out of the way, we'll get to...
...the business of real politics.
Are you sure? I mean,
I don't understand this.
Never leave home without it.
Looks like we got a problem
with your fee bill.
Like what?
It says you got a partial athletic
scholarship. Better talk to your coach.
Partial? That's a mistake.
I'm a f ull-scholarship student.
I can't help that.
That's what it shows.
-You sure your computer ain't broke?
-I'm sorry, honey. I can't help you.
-Go get it cleared in that department.
-Thank you.
Next.
Baby, you're just gonna have
to get a job.
Here's your card.
Come on, guys, pick it up!
You look like a bunch of girls!
Come on, pick it up!
Come on, give me some juice.
There you go.
Yeah, looking sweet.
-Twenty-three!
-You want a what? A full scholarship?
Man, you aot some nerve.
All riaht, I'll see what I can do.
I don't wanna hear you're lax in your
studies or fuckina up on the field.
You aot that?
Do I make myself clear?
Yeah, man, I understand.
Word to the mother, kid.
Have you seen that ass?
Hey, yo, what kind
of munchies y'all got?
Where are the vittles at? The eats?
Hey, y'all ain't got no Kool-Aid
up in this piece, man? Guess not.
I see y'all got some Evian
up in here, though, huh?
How would you feel if you had to study
and I came in and blasted my music?
-That wouldn't happen.
-Why not?
Because I'd whup your ass, that's why.
Ex cuse me.
Boy, I'm the master of Monopoly.
That's right.
You bankrupt, G.
Should've bought them
apartments, man. I told you.
Hey, why you going to this school?
Well, because that's what they say you
need to do to make it in the country.
-What's "making it"?
-Fudge, your printer's out of paper.
Well, then go buy some more.
What's "making it"?
You know, getting a degree.
You know, making that long dough.
Is that right? So you in it
f or the money or the knowledge?
Check out this situation.
You at a f ootball game.
There's thousands of people there.
All of them white.
The American flag
is right above your head.
They're about to play
the national anthem.
All these people turn around
and look you dead in your eye.
What do you do?
I stand up.
I'd probably be so embarrassed...
You know, I'd stand up.
You know what I'm saying?
They got you running
f or the school, huh?
-Yeah. Partial scholarship.
-You don't run, you don't get tuition.
That's the way the system goes.
Run, nigger, run.
Oh, my God. Look at her hair.
-Be nice, Nicole. It's not that bad.
-She looks like a tramp.
-Hi.
-Hi. What'd you do to your hair?
-I just bleached it.
-I love it. Yes.
Watch me bring it up.
Watch me bring it.
Bam. Of all times.
Want to play again, man?
Come on, let's play again.
-Three in a row.
-You're a bastard.
-Want to play?
-Huh?
-Want to play a game of pool?
-I don't know how to play.
Bye.
Okay, who's the genius
who matches roommates up?
They moved me in
with a psycho dickhead.
It's like the Bates Hotel
over at my place.
My days are numbered, Wayne.
-He's probably just quiet.
-Okay.
Hey.
-Hey, man. Say, where's the party?
-Up here, man.
Is that right? Cool.
Here she goes.
Nice job. Hello! Good night.
Down the hatch.
Talented, I see.
-I never usually swallow.
-You're a dirty girl.
-Hey, let's get one f or her, huh?
-Give her a shot.
Kristen!
Kristen! Kristen! Kristen!
Drink! Drink! Drink!
All right!
What a big girl you are, huh?
-I can't walk.
-Please, come on.
-All right. Where are we going?
-We're going to my house.
To the house.
When you say that you look really bad,
like, you're perfect, you know?
Hey, do you think we should've
let Kristen go with Billy?
-Because she doesn't even drink.
-Billy who?
I love you!
Billy, you've gotta get a rubber.
Billy, we should be using a condom.
Just a second.
Billy, come on.
-One second.
-No. Get a condom.
Just wait a second.
Shut up!
Billy, no! Stop it! Get a condom!
No! Stop it!
Billy, get off of me! Get off of me!
-Fuck, man!
-No! Stop!
Stop! No!
You f ucker!
Kris, what the...? Wait!
Wait a second! Goddamn it!
Kristen.
Fuck!
Say, man.
-Did you give it to her?
-What?
You f ucked her, right?
Did she like it?
What the f uck are you talking about?
How the f uck do you know?
-Go get a beer.
-Who the f uck are you, man?
You just got laid, right?
You should be cool.
-Motherf ucker!
-What's up with you?
-What's your problem?
-You're my problem, bitch.
I finished my paper
and I don't have anything to do.
Kris, what's the matter?
Why are you crying?
Oh, God, what have you been drinking?
Kris, what's wrong?
-Hello.
-Can I speak to Kristen, please?
-Who's this?
-Billy.
-Billy who? I don't know no Billys.
-Yeah, I just...
I just need to talk to Kristen.
-You want to speak to Kristen.
-No. No.
She's not here.
Even if she was here, I don't think
she'd wanna talk to you.
I know she's there. I can hear her.
-Can you put her on the phone?
-Didn't I just tell you she's not here?
Put her on the phone,
you black bitch!
-What did you say?
-You heard me.
Why are y'all so quiet?
-Let's go.
-To kick some ass, nigga?
Just get away f rom him
and come home with me.
What do you think they make
you do to get into this f rat?
You know?
You don't?
I bet you they make you do something,
right?
Like things.
Crazy stuff.
I'd do it.
Which one?
-Yo! Get the f uck up!
-Piece of crap. Get his ass.
What's up, bro? What did I do?
-Come on!
-Man, let me go!
-Chad, what's up with these guys?
-Call security now!
-What'd I do?
-I'll just put my boot in your mouth.
I heard you been disrespecting
black women.
No, man, I haven't either...
You called me a black bitch,
and you gonna get your ass kicked.
Come on, man, listen. I'm sorry.
-I'm sorry, okay?
-Apologize to her!
Sorry! I'm sorry! Look, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Fuck that!
We need to just bust his shit!
-No, listen. Please, man.
-Here's what I want you to say.
I want you to say,
" I apologize, beautif ul black woman...
...mother of the Earth,
queen of the universe."
I'm sorry.
I apologize, black mother...
-Get it right!
-I can't remember all that.
I'm sorry.
What's going on?
These gang members
dragged him out f or no reason.
What the f uck you talking about,
white boy?
Gang members?
We go to school here too!
-Enough of this stuff.
-I'll rip your ass off them stairs!
Don't I know you? Everybody else,
come out with the I.D.'s.
You don't need to see nobody I.D.
Don't show them.
Wait. Everything's okay now.
It was just a misunderstanding.
We're cool now, right?
We're cool, right?
Hope you gonna break up their party
like you did ours.
-ls everything cool here now?
-Very f ucking cool!
What's up?
Pussy.
Punk-ass motherf ucker.
I don't understand why they always
have to start all this trouble.
-You okay, Billy?
-Yeah.
Come on.
We need to get past just complaining
about university security.
You know?
I'm tired of hearing women cry
f or someone else to save them.
Think what that means.
Why do you need someone else
to save you?
Think about saving yourself.
-Hi.
Hi, everybody.
-Join us.
-Okay.
Hi.
We were talking about security on
campus, in light of a recent survey...
...that showed one out of f our women
has been raped...
...or survived an attempted rape,
since the age of 14.
Do you have any ideas or thoughts
you want to share?
No.
Fudge, you got some e-mail
coming through.
Is that right?
Need to start charging y'all f ools,
like the university.
Twenty-five cent a page.
Y'all could pay f or my laundry.
You got the autobiography
of Frederick Douglass?
Yeah.
Biographies are up there.
-Damn. You read all these?
-Most of them.
Hey, how you get turned on
to Douglass?
Need it f or a class.
For a class. That's the only
reason you're reading it?
-Yeah. Why else?
-To feed your brain, f ool.
I thought you was a smart one,
but you ain't. So you got to go.
-Can I borrow this book, man?
-Yeah, go ahead.
Read it f or yourself
and not f or no damn class, though.
-Thanks f or the book, dog.
-Run along.
-What's up, brother?
-What's up, man?
Reading in the dark
is bad f or the eyes.
-I got good eyes.
-What book you reading?
-Iliad.
-That's a good book. Great battles.
Yeah, it's all right.
Me and a couple f riends,
we were gonna go get a drink.
You wanna come along?
I said, me and my buddies were gonna
go get a drink. You wanna come along?
What are you,
some queer or something?
-What? What are you talking about?
-I should kick your ass, man.
First off, don't ever touch me again.
I will beat you
to the f ucking ground, boy.
Secondly, you know,
I ain't no f aggot.
I just wanted to know
if you wanted to get a drink.
-Sorry, man. It's a new city.
-That's okay. I understand.
We'll f orget about it,
have a drink...
...with good people.
We'll have a good time.
-What do you say?
-All right, man.
Pick up your stuff. Come on.
I mean, we're white, in America,
what more do you need?
We're white, in America, what more
do you need to have a good time?
Right?
All right, here we go.
-What's your name again?
-Remy.
-What's your name?
-I'm Scott.
-So, where you f rom, Remy?
-ldaho.
-ldaho, huh? Where in Idaho?
-Boise.
That's the Big Sky State, huh?
-I think that's Montana.
-That's right. It is Montana.
These are my brothers here.
Fellas, hey.
This here, this is Erik.
-What's up, man?
-This is Knocko over here.
-This is James here.
-Hi.
-Everybody, this is Remy.
-Hey, Remy.
What's up?
You should know that democratic
theory did not begin...
...with Rousseau's contract. No.
Its origins, in f act, lie in
the subject of landownership.
The common people became aware...
...that the upper classes owned the land
upon which they lived and laboured.
This incensed them...
...inspired them to seek sovereignty
of their own homelands.
However,
the social order of the day...
...did not permit landownership
by the common man.
Theref ore, these people...
...felt the need to leave
their homelands...
...to flee in an eff ort to escape
political and social persecution.
Hence, the creation that is America.
Theref ore, the basic premise...
...of democratic theory...
...is that each and every citizen
living within that society...
...is entitled...
...to what?
We are entitled to life...
...liberty and the pursuit
of happiness.
What you people have to realize
is that despite having these rights...
...very few people ex ercise them.
It is that type of apathy that
corrodes our country f rom within.
Your assignment f or the semester
is as f ollows:
To f ormulate
your own political ideology.
This will be dictated by your sex,
background...
...socioeconomic status...
...personal experience,
et cetera, et cetera.
This course will be like
anything in life.
It will be what you make of it.
I am not a babysitter.
Ladies and gentlemen,
do not waste my time.
Remember...
...no one is going to treat
you special...
...just because you are black.
Right. Or white.
Or Hispanic.
Or Indian.
Or Asian.
Or because you are a woman.
Or because you f ailed to get
sufficient rest last night.
Or because you are...
What are you?
-I don't know.
-Right.
Don't sweat it.
Come on.
Watch it.
-Watch out.
-Watch it. Watch it.
-Damn.
-Let's see your I.D.
No, let us see your I.D.
Forget these guys.
Thought so.
You know what that's all about?
They hate me 'cause they ain't me.
Can you hand me another one
of those mayonnaise?
-Do you want to report it?
-lt's not gonna do anything.
They're just gonna make me
feel like shit...
...and make me look like
I asked f or it.
I didn't ask f or this.
I just wanna go to school.
Come here.
This ain't cool, dog. A " B" on
content, and then I get a " C" f or...
Punctuation mistakes,
misspellings...
...grammatical error,
et cetera, et cetera.
You probably didn't even read it.
TA graded all of these, right?
If you could spell as well as you run,
it would be better, Mr. Williams.
-Sellout.
-Mr. Williams.
So Mr. Williams
thinks I am an Uncle Tom.
Well, well, well.
What does that have to do with your
ability to place a comma properly...
...or put a period
at the end of a sentence?
-Look...
-Would you care f or a peppermint?
No, thank you.
You're using
that reverse treatment...
...'cause I'm one of the only
black f aces in your class.
Mr. Williams, I treat everyone
in my course exactly the same...
...and I will continue to give you
a difficult time...
...until you have proven
that you deserve otherwise.
-Those are the rules of the game.
-lt's a f ucked-up game.
Please watch your language.
Rid yourself of this attitude
that the world owes you something.
You must strip yourself of that
mentality. It breeds laziness.
It is laziness that has kept
black people down in this country.
I don't think like that.
All right, man, it's just...
Look, I don't need one of my own
trying to treat me like I'm the enemy.
The enemy? Who is the enemy?
One man with a white beard
who sits behind his desk...
...pushing buttons that control
the f ate of the entire world?
No, that is not reality.
That is The Wizard of Oz.
No, man, I mean anybody.
White, black, anybody
who gets in the way of my progress.
I am not in your way.
I did not ask you
to come to this university...
...nor am I here to motivate you.
Your own presence
should be motivation enough.
I have nothing to prove,
unlike you.
I don't have anything to prove.
Who do I have something to prove to?
Yourself.
Good afternoon, Mr. Williams.
Ladies and aentlemen,
the next race on the track...
...will be the 4x100-metre relay.
In lane three, the non-scorina B-team
from John Paul Colleae.
Lane number four, the scorina team
from Columbus University.
Lane number five, the scorina team
from John Paul Colleae.
And in lane six, the non-scorina
B-team from Columbus University.
On your marks!
May we have quiet for the start.
Set!
We have a fair start.
Adam Bailey out very well
in lane four for Columbus University.
Gettina ready now for
the first ex chanae.
Stick!
Down the backstretch they ao.
Columbus in four, John Paul in five.
A tremendous effort
by John Paul Colleae...
...moves them into the lead as we
aet ready for the second ex chanae.
In the far turn, John Paul in five,
Columbus in four, neck and neck.
Gettina ready
for the anchor lea.
Stick! Stick!
Tyrene Jay for John Paul...
...and Robert "The Rocket" Simmons
for Columbus.
-It is John Paul followed by Columbus.
-First place, 39.58.
Second place, 39.60.
-Second place, 39.60.
-Correct.
The next race on the track
will be the 1500 metres.
That event is scheduled in 10 minutes.
Visit the concession stand...
Ain't no next time.
All I'm saying is this.
I got a lot riding on this. I'm not
about to let my stats get blown.
You the only weak link on this team.
You listening to me?
Fool, all you is, all you ever gonna
be, is a runner. Like a horse.
You're a slave,
too ignorant to know it.
-Who you calling ignorant, bitch?
-Hey!
-We're a team, man!
-Fuck that shit!
We gotta stick together, black men!
Get your shit together, bitch!
Stupid bitch!
I like that.
I like your beautif ul hair,
your eyes, your lips.
Look at this f ool with his cave bitch.
It's a damn shame, man.
Don't that make you upset
as a black woman?
I don't want him.
Yeah, I can dig that.
He's weak anyway.
Miss Deja.
Where you f rom? Texas, right?
-I see you did your research.
-Not enough.
-God.
-I could always know more.
What, you shy?
-No. Are you?
-I stepped to you, didn't I?
I've been seeing you on the track,
having a little attitude.
I seen you too,
acting like you all that.
-I'm not acting like...
-Mr. Big Stuff. Yes, you do.
You be like:
-Running f or your life.
-So you be looking at me?
-I don't look at you.
-You just imitated my f orm.
You be looking at me, right?
A little bit,
but we're on the same team.
-I been looking at you too.
-God.
-What dorm you staying in?
-Why you wanna know where I live?
-I wanted to get you home safe.
-I'll be okay.
-There's a lot of crazies here.
-Goodness.
I'll guard your body.
Be your bodyguard.
How do you feel knowing this country
doesn't belong to you any longer?
I mean,
what do you think of that?
How do you feel knowing that
when you graduate f rom college...
...you might not get a job because
of your skin colour?
Because of some quota.
People don't realize how f ar down
the drain America has gone.
What do you think about that, Remy?
I guess I never thought
about that, man.
It's different here than I thought
it was gonna be.
Seems like everybody's
sticking to their own...
...taking up f or their own.
I don't know anybody down here.
It's different, man. You know.
-All I got is me.
-No, man.
And me. We're brothers by blood.
Yeah, you got me too, Remy.
I think I'm gonna cry.
Shut the f uck up, Knocko.
Show the man some respect.
That's cool, Scott.
That's pure Aryan blood
you're talking to.
No, no, no, you're right.
This is brotherhood, Remy.
Welcome home.
-Thanks.
-See, Remy, this is your f amily now.
And if there should be anything at all
that you wanna talk about...
...then I want you to come to me
or to us.
If there's one thing I want you
to leave thinking about tonight...
...it's that we take care of our own.
Thanks, man.
Thanks, Scott.
Run-on. Run-on.
Fragment. Fragment. Fragment.
-ls this a period or a comma?
-That's a lot of red ink.
-Do you want help?
-I'm here.
Malik, you gotta get this to flow,
and right now it's not flowing.
Right here,
that's a really good point...
...but you gotta f ollow it up
with a concise explanation.
What do you mean?
Malik, when you write an essay,
you gotta f ollow a certain f ormat.
You start with your thesis statement...
...and you have to always use
transitional phrases.
And don't use the same word
every single time.
Change it up.
Professors hate that.
You should use a thesaurus.
And where's your outline?
We got a lot of work to do.
-ls something wrong?
-No.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
I'm fine.
I am af raid it is unclear.
But... I don't understand.
Miss Connor, you don't appear to take
any kind of position in this paper.
I thought that, when you write, you're
supposed to be as objective as possible.
That is a rule of journalism.
It is often taught
and very rarely practised.
This, however,
is a political science course.
If you wish to write
about objectivity...
...write about its use in modern
politics in your view.
That'd make a good paper.
I'll write that down.
Oh, Christ Jesus.
What?
In f uture, Miss Connor,
please find your own thesis.
I am looking f or evidence
of original thought.
You are not here to simply recycle
dates and f acts f rom the past.
One's primary purpose
at university level...
...should be to learn how to think.
Now, question:
Did you write this paper?
You really feel like insulting
my intelligence, don't you?
I worked my ass off on that paper.
I rewrote it three times.
-Shouldn't be one misspelled word.
-Okay, Mr. Williams, I believe you.
Are you having problems
here at Columbus?
It's all right.
I got a problem with the way f ools
be tripping when they see a black f ace.
Someone spit in your f ace
when you first came to campus?
Was there a cross burned
outside your dormitory?
No. I know what you're
trying to get at.
Just 'cause it ain't up in my f ace,
that don't mean it's not happening.
It's less physical now.
It's more mental.
I gotta run and study, man.
I don't see these white f olks worrying
about nothing but going to class...
...talking about skiing.
They don't have the same worries.
Then your problem is financial.
Not racial, but economic.
These type of problems
can be worked out.