sub2srt by ¿­³ë(Yeolno)
http://nfou.net/
¢Ü¢Ü[Woman Singing "Ave Maria"In Latin]
[Whirring]
¢Ü¢Ü[Continues]
[Rhythmic Chanting]
¢Ü¢Ü[Ends]
[Thunder Rumbling]
- Fuck!
- It's not there.
- [Gun Cocks]
- It's in the kitchen where you left it.
How'd you get in?
You have a nice family.
They're fine. Alive.
Asleep.
- Are you gonna kill me?
- If I was gonna kill you...
I'd have done it when you walked
to the car this morning-
been gone by the time
your body hit the sidewalk.
- Then why are you here?
- To talk.
But, Mike, if you make me kill you,
you will not go alone.
Sit.
Are you a good man, Inspector?
- I think.
- And yet you've killed men.
- Yes.
- I'm gonna ask you a question.
How you answer it
will determine how this night ends.
How does a good man
decide when to kill?
The man you've been chasing
is a killer, a ghost.
Rumor has it that he works for a group
known only as "the organization."
So secret, no one knows it exists.
It takes no sides,
yet it has ties to every government.
Its sole purpose is
the training and conditioning...
of professional killers.
These men are selected at birth-
- rejects, orphans-
- [Beeping]
All of them unwanted and disposable.
They are made experts
in every aspect of combat...
and programmed for one purpose:
To kill.
The man you have been chasing
for the last three years, Inspector...
is the very best of them.
- [Man Shrieks]
- Put him there.
[Panting, Groaning]
You shouldn't have
stolen from me, Brother.
Now you must pay.
- [Mocking Whine]
- [Groaning, Panting]
[Shouts]
[Screams]
Why you do that kind of thing?
[Groaning]
Still waiting.
[Gravelly]
I'm sorry.
What happened to his voice?
He made me swallow.
What did you do to his voice?
Nothing, Ovie.
Exactly as he was delivered.
Delivered?
- [Grunts]
- You didn't find him?
No. A contractor.
An American.
Swallow what?
- [Over Earphone] Swallow what?
- A bomb.
A bomb. A bomb.
Run!
[Rooster Crowing]
We have all heard your theories, Inspector.
This isn't a theory.
This is our guy-
no motive, no forensic evidence, no witnesses.
He's a- He's a ghost.
And how long have you been
chasing this "ghost"?
Three years.
Well, thank goodness you have Interpol
to finance your persistence, huh?
You see, Inspector,
despite being the anus of the third world...
we attempt to have
competent police work here.
And it is our belief that Bwana Ovie
was killed by his own brother.
Oh, so he choked down
a pound of C-4...
and knocked on Ovie's door?
Probably.
General, this man truly is
the best at what he does.
He is likely responsible
for over 100 deaths.
Let me show you what I mean.
This is Ovie.
And these are just
the ones we know about.
Are you beginning
to get the picture?
They might kill you for that.
For what you're doing to that whiskey-
brutalizing it with ice.
But never more than two cubes.
It waters down the scotch.
- Oh.
- I-I'm sorry.
Aftermath of my pretentious
ex-husband, I'm afraid.
No.
I'm June. And you are?
This is where you tell me your name.
Excuse me.
[Woman Laughing]
[Electronic Beeping]
[Water Running]
[Beeping]
[Electronic Female Voice]
Africa job complete.
The money has been wired
to your account.
Nice work. Regrettably,
the next target date...
has been moved up
at the client's request.
And the client wishes it
to be public.
I've planned
something more... subtle.
I've made preparations.
Incumbent Russian president
Mikhail Belicoff's...
recent political shift
is in direct conflict...
with our client's interests and threatens
their control of the Russian government.
The client needs it to be public.
Do you accept the new parameters?
- Yes.
- We appreciate you breaking your normal protocol.
The specifics are being uploaded.
[Applause]
I, for one, will not let
their cowardice deter me.
[Applause Continues]
[Crowd Chanting]
Belicoff! Belicoff! Belicoff!.
[Chanting Continues]
[Cheering]
Mr. Belicoff? I'm sorry.
In light of your political positions...
do you think the hard-liners
will continue to support your reelection?
One only needs to look at-
[Screaming, Clamoring]
[Screaming, Clamoring Continue]
[Cell Phone Ringing]
[Electronic Female Voice] We have a problem.
There was a witness in Saint Petersburg.
How reliable are your sources?
Impeccable, as always.
Interpol has arranged a pickup.
- Will you intercept?
- Yes.
Uploading data.
[Man Speaking Russian]
[Chuckles]
[Woman Screams]
[Gunshots]
[Screaming, Clamoring]
I can't be sure.
He never works again so quickly.
But the Russians say that Belicoff
was grazed by a single bullet...
from over four kilometers away.
- [Man On Phone, Indistinct]
- But it definitely sounds like him.
Yes, sir.
Well, what bothers me
is that he missed.
Yes, sir.
I know what this investigation has cost.
L- I understand.
- I just need a little more time.
- Sir, you need to see this.
Sorry, sir.
I'm gonna have to call you back.
[Cell Phone Beeps]
Okay.
- He shoots the bodyguard
to get a clean shot at Belicoff.
- [Gunshot Rings Out]
Yeah. He splits these two civilians
by a couple of inches. Keep watching.
Keep an eye on the bodyguard.
See that?
Back it up.
Back it up again.
That's an awful lot
of arterial spray for a miss.
Sir, you have call.
- This is Whittier.
- [Man] Sir, they found Belicoff's shooter.
- They found him?
- Yes. Tip from a hotel concierge.
- Concierge where?
- Grand Hotel.
- They recognized him from a picture.
- A picture?
- Where the hell did they get a picture?
- I don't know, sir.
All right.
I'm on my way.
They found him.
Contact the Russian Secret Police
in Saint Petersburg...
and tell them Interpol has jurisdiction.
They're to keep him under surveillance only.
No one moves until we get there. No one!
[Electronic Female Voice]
Was the target not at the location?
[Man] The girl was there, but she was no witness.
She'd never seen me before.
[Electronic Female Voice]
We will be unable to transmit payment...
for the Belicoff assignment
as the task was not completed.
No. He took a direct hit through the nasal cavity.
I watched it myself.
[Electronic Female Voice]
Please wait.
Uploading live news feed.
The West, so afraid of my message...
that cowardly violence
is their only response.
- [Applauding]
- And that was the scene
outside of Saint Petersburg.
Who was the client?
Answer me!
Who ordered the hit on Belicoff?
If you set me up, I will find you...
and I will burn that building
to the ground around you.
Mike Whittier, Interpol.
What's the status of my suspect?
I was told you were coming, Inspector.
I am Captain Gudnayev,
Saint Petersburg Militsiya.
Please, make yourself comfortable.
- My men are almost in position.
- In position for what?
We have been informed that
the suspect intends to flee.
- My orders are to seek-
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Orders? Orders from who?
- Interpol has jurisdiction here.
- Militsiya's only responsible for the extraction.
Captain Gudnayev is not directing this operation,
I'm afraid, Inspector. I am.
I'm Chief Agent Yuri Marklov
of the F.S.B.
The F.S.B. Why the hell...
is the Russian Secret Police
involved in this?
- [Speaking Russian]
- [Woman Speaking Russian]
- They're going in.
- I advise you to get your men out of there.
You have no idea
who you're dealing with.
I assure you, these men are capable
of handling this situation.
[Speaking Russian]
Shoot on sight.
- [Speaking Russian]
- Do not give that order!
[Speaking Russian]
[Phone Ringing]
[Woman]
47, it's Diana.
I could be retired
for contacting you directly.
The client was Belicoff.
Your location has been compromised.
[Beads Shatter]
[Electronic Beeping]
[Electronic Hum]
Come on.
[Hammers Cock]
[Speaking Russian]
[Woman Speaks Russian]
[Walkie-talkie: Man Speaks Russian]
[Alarm Ringing]
Stay here. Cover the elevator.
Call me on my cell and tell me where it stops.
[Elevator Dings]
[Speaking Russian]
[All Screaming]
[Alarm Continues]
[Elevator Dings]
[Dings]
- [Cell Phone Rings]
- [Alarm Blaring]
- Yeah.
- I've got five dead bodies in the lift, sir.
- None of them our boy.
- [Dinging]
He's on the third floor, sir! He must have
opened the doors from inside the shaft!
Freeze!
[Alarm Continues]
Get down!
[Speaking Russian]
- Get down!
- [Speaking Russian]
[Gasps]
- [Grunts]
- [Shooting]
Fuck!
Sir?
We had him.
[Speaking Russian]
- How many men did you lose?
- Sixteen dead.
No! No, no.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait! Don't touch that!
[Sighs]
Where'd you get your fucking license?
I need the room, Captain.
[Speaking Russian]
[Siren Wailing]
Where does he get all this stuff?
Can you make it work?
Probably. Why?
I've been looking
for you, Inspector.
I think we started off
on the wrong foot.
Who informed you
of the whereabouts of my guy?
I believe it's time
we had a chat, you and I.
Jenkins.
Yes, sir.
[Speaking Russian]
This, uh, assassin-
my associates tell me
you believe him to be freelance.
Your associates tell you that?
You do not believe he is connected
with Central Intelligence Agency?
Why do you ask?
No reason. It just seems a bit naive.
[Chuckles]
Well, it's a theory.
Yes, a theory.
But a theory shared by Moscow.
In accordance with Article 1764.3
of the E.U. Charter...
any state matters which deal
directly with intelligence...
shall be the sole jurisdiction
of the host country.
Ah, and the lightbulb comes on.
Took me a minute.
Must be the jet lag.
You're telling me to fuck off?
[Chuckling] No, no. Of course not.
You are a good man, Michael.
One of Interpol's best.
But leave this intelligence work
to the F.S.B.
And Belicoff?
I'm sorry?
You know, there's two things
wrong with this photograph.
One, the footage
has been tampered with.
Someone inserted that civilian
to cover up what actually happened.
Hmm.
- And the second thing?
- My boy doesn't miss.
[Buzzes]
[Speaking Russian]
- Delivery.
- You're supposed to leave those at the desk.
Mr. Belicoff sent them.
[Gasping]
Make a sound, I'll end your life.
You understand?
Who else is inside?
I know you-
from the street earlier today.
- You're coming with me.
- I can't!
Okay, okay!
I'll get my coat.
[Speaking Russian]
- Where are you taking me?
- Somewhere safe.
- Get in.
- Fuck you! I'm not getting in there!
Aaah! There's a dead man in there!
[Shouting In Russian]
Get me out of this car.!
Are you going to kill me?
I'm gonna ask you some questions.
Before today on the street,
have you ever seen me?
- Why were you there?
- My boyfriend.
- He told me to meet his driver on that corner.
- Belicoff?
How, after I put
a bullet through his head...
was he able to give
that speech this afternoon?
Then you're of no use to me.
[Gasps]
Wait.! Wait.! There is something.
D-Doubles. Doubles-
Mikhail has doubles,
just like Saddam Hussein.
The man I shot was not an impostor.
Belicoff is dead.
Why'd you tattoo your face?
Because it's the only place
I knew Belicoff wouldn't hit.
[Releases Hammer]
Tell me about Udre Belicoff.
Mikhail's brother?
He runs slave girls, drugs, weapons.
Both the C.I.A. And F.S.B.
Want him dead.
- Mikhail's been protecting him.
- Get up.
- Get up. You're coming with me.
- I can't.
He'll kill me if he finds out
I left the apartment.
Belicoff hired me to kill him.
Used you to set me up.
The dead man in the trunk
was your driver.
He was gonna use it on you.
You're as good as dead without me.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna finish the job
I was hired to do...
and find out who's behind this.
- I need to talk to you.
- I need coffee.
Follow me.
We have three roadblocks.
Here, here, here.
We completely shut down
international airport.
All border security has been tripled.
He cannot get out of city.
- What about the train stations?
- Temporarily closed.
- And Saint Petersburg Station?
- There are no trains leaving Russia
from this station.
Only commuter trains
headed towards interior.
What make you think
he go further into Russia?
Because I know him
better than anyone.
Thanks for the coffee.
Go to the last platform and wait.
- Why?
- Now.
- Jenkins, anything?
- Nothing.
[Mike On Radio]
Stay sharp.
[Jenkins On Radio] I don't know, sir.
It seems odd for him to come here.
[Mike On Radio]
Trust me. This is where he'll be.
Jenkins- bench, shaved head.
[On Radio]
Got him, boss.
Fuck!
Jenkins?
I'm still on him, boss. Platform...
- number nine.
- [Static On Radio]
Boss?
[Grunting]
Gotten slow.
[Gunshot]
- [Grunts]
- [Gunshot]
Tell me why.
[Gunshot]
Why is there a hit on me?
- Stay here.
- [Gunshot]
[Shell Clatters]
How about dying
with a little dignity?
[Grunts]
[Shouts]
[Grunts, Shouts]
- [Bones Crack]
- [Shouts]
[Grunting]
[Staples]
[Breathing Heavily]
You think it's done?
It's just beginning.
[Gunshot]
[Sighs]
I told you to wait.
I know. I'm sorry.
- L- I know-
- [Clattering]
Shh.
- [Gunshot]
- Aaah!
- Freeze!
- [Shouts]
- [Groans]
- You're the one who's been tracking me.
The Russian Militsiya have got
the terminal locked down.
If you need a hostage...
take me.
Come on.
He hasn't seen your face.
He doesn't have to die.
Take me instead.
[Gunshot]
[Groans]
Please.
Stop.
She saved your life.
[Chattering]
[Speaking Russian]
- [Grunts]
- [Speaking Russian]
He said your ribs are broken.
Unlucky.
- You seem awfully calm, considering.
- Your assassin is dead.
[Chuckling]
Why are you covering this up?
You know that's not our killer.
I told you before, Inspector,
this is no longer your affair.
Now there are two ways
in which we may proceed.
One, my men will
accompany you to the hospital...
and, when you and your associate
are able to travel...
they will escort you to the airport.
Then I will write a report
extolling Interpol for its help.
Medals will probably be involved.
Or I can report your incompetence...
and disregard for my nation's laws
to your superiors.
This will undoubtedly find its way
to the state prosecutor in Moscow.
So, how do you think
we should proceed, huh?
How about...
go fuck yourself.
[Speaking Russian]
I was running out of oxygen in there!
- Don't be dramatic.
- Dramatic?
- I got rid of the body.
- I've been there for hours!
I brought you breakfast.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Chuckling]
[Thunderclap]
I'd thank you
if I wasn't so mad at you.
Look at me.
Back at the station, you interfered.
I'm sorry.
I can't allow that.
- I swear I'll never-
- Stop talking.
If you're looking
for a reason not to kill me...
I don't really have one.
I'm not a whore by choice.
Belicoff owns me.
I'm his property.
Would you like to know
how much he paid for me? 300, American.
I've tried to escape.
The last time-
[Screams]
[Sobbing]
[Speaking Russian]
It is a strange thing to wish to die.
So, are you...
going to kill me?
No.
You don't want to fuck me
and you don't want to kill me.
I've never felt so much indifference
in my entire life.
- If you ever again interfere with me like that-
- I won't.
- Are we clear?
- Yeah.
Eat your sandwich.
I need to get some sleep.
- You know-
- Nika-
- Yes?
- Stop talking or I'll put you back in the trunk.
[Speaking Russian]
Shit.
[Russian]
[Phone Ringing]
Da.
[Man Speaking Russian]
I gotta give it to you, sir. Pretty slick.
Go fuck yourself.
It was a pretty stupid idea actually.
If we get caught, we'll be making
snow cones in Siberia for the next 20 years.
Yet here we sit.
Shh!
Belicoff.
- [Siren Wailing]
- Shit! Hide that thing.
We came to see Chief Agent Yuri.
- What's the problem?
- Chief Agent is very busy man.
He asked you to go directly to the airport.
We'll escort you there immediately.
Okay.
[Chattering]
[Cell Phone Ringing]
It's for you.
After all these years,
I'd think you'd trust me a little more than this.
Tell me what you know.
[Man]
Officially, nothing.
[Over Earphone] Unofficially, it appears
your employer has thrown you to the wolves.
- Why?
- Apparently...
Belicoff's softening political stance
and his refusal...
to cooperate with the hard-liners
upset a lot of people.
They ordered the hit
and replaced him with one of their own.
Seems you and your friend here are the only ones
who know Belicoff is actually a double.
What's the C.I.A.'s position?
The company usually likes to be
on the side of whoever wins.
Take the envelope from the girl.
Ah.
Udre Belicoff,
Mikhail's younger brother.
Rumor is you'd like him to disappear.
- That is the rumor.
- I'd like to help.
How's killing Udre Belicoff
gonna help you?
- Let me worry about that.
- Well, that might be worth something.
- What do you want for your trouble?
- Small favor.
This is a small favor?
I don't think I can do this.
- Not in your time frame.
- Keep reading.
Jesus Christ.
Tell me this isn't
what I think it is.
Okay. It's not what you think it is.
But I'd expect the last thing you'd want
is for me to be arrested with that file.
[Sighs]
Okay. I'll try.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, you're welcome.
We know Udre's been planning something
with a German arms dealer named Price.
The two have never met.
That's your way in.
Intercept Price,
and you get a shot at Udre.
I'll get you his file.
They're meeting
in Istanbul in two days.
Good morning.
Have you slept at all?
Some.
You know, you could sleep in the bed.
I won't bite you.
Unless you pay me.
It's not polite to stare.
So, when are you
gonna tell me your name?
- Get dressed.
- What for?
We're going to dinner.
We need to buy you a new dress.
You know, you're really quite charming
when you aren't killing people.
- This place looks nice.
- Yeah.
- Don't you think?
- Mm-hmm.
Wait here.
Hey.! What'd you do, eat without me?
- How did you know I wouldn't just take off?
- I didn't. Come on.
We have dinner reservations at 8:00.
Jenks, how do you feel?
[Groans]
My pride hurts worse than my arms.
- Any word?
- The sketch is out to every
Interpol substation in Europe.
Train stations, airports,
border crossings and-
- What's that?
- This is what I wanted to show you.
It's every appearance
Belicoff has made within the last 12 months.
This is from the speech he made
in London on May the 7 th.
And this is from some shitty political luncheon
he had in northern Georgia.
Someone took a photo
from a mobile phone.
- Look at the date.
- May 7.
- How's that possible?
- I can't be sure...
but unless he's figured out
how to be in two places at once-
- Ha. He has a double.
- He's certainly paranoid enough.
That explains the arterial spray.
I hope he had health benefits.
¢Ü¢Ü[Man Singing
In Foreign Language]
[Nika]
When I was a little girl, I had this little squirrel-
you know,
with black stripes on the back?
- A chipmunk.
- Oh, yeah, that's right. A chipmunk.
His name was Tishka.
I'm sorry, sir,
but this is for another gentleman.
- Table 26?
- That's right.
My mistake.
You know what table that is?
I saw the layout when we came in.
- Do you remember everything you see?
- No, not everything.
What's the soup of the day?
Red lentil and mint with sauteed onions
and diced tomatoes.
The woman sitting two tables behind you-
what's she wearing?
- With the red hair and the silk dress, facing you?
- Yeah.
That's not a woman.
What color underwear am I wearing?
You're not wearing any underwear.
- [Glass Clattering]
- [Man Grunts]
[Groaning]
Come with us, sir.
Here we go. It's gonna be all right.
Nika, ask for the check.
- But I'm not done!
- Then hurry.
You scratch what I said
about you being charming.
Sorry, sir.
[Man Retching]
[Retching Continues]
[Moaning]
[Groaning]
[Man]
SheiBe.
Mr. Price...
thank you for the introduction
to Udre Belicoff.
Little help, please.
- What the fuck?
- Let's go.
- What?
- Now.
Well, that was lovely.
Right up to the time
you dragged me out by my hair.
Undress me.
[Chuckles]
So very good at firearms.
Not so good with
ladies' undergarments.
Careful. I'm not wearing any panties.
- Nika, you're drunk.
- [Scoffs]
And?
- And this is a very bad idea.
- Oh.
- You mean this?
- Yes, that.
How about this?
Definitely that.
Then...
this must be really bad.
[Shrieks, Mutters In Russian]
[Car Engine Roaring]
[Engine Shuts Off]
¢Ü¢Ü[Pop]
Give me case.
Mr. Price!
So, you took it upon yourself...
to change our appointment.
- How forward of you.
- As I told your men downstairs...
I was attacked earlier tonight
by some lunatic.
- Common sense dictated-
- Common sense should have dictated...
you not abuse my good nature.
Sit.
¢Ü¢Ü[Continues]
I was just going over
a few of my lines...
with some of your competitors.
[Chuckling]
Lines.
A few of my lines.
Do you get it?
Where was I?
He's not Price.
Da.
This is the, uh- the Kedr.
Nine-millimeter, compact.
It's, uh, less than two kilograms.
Select fire single,
or fully automatic.
- Empty-
- [Clicks]
And safe.
Or if you are looking for an assault rifle...
I have the M203 with
under-barrel grenade launcher.
A lot of third-world dictators...
got a lot of 7.62s stockpiled.
Saves them from having to buy ammo.
Everything here is
available in bulk, of course.
Prices not negotiable.
Any questions, Mr. Price?
Yeah. What about the little one there?
[Chuckles]
Here. I show you.
- This is a Makarov.22.
- [Gasps]
- A favorite of the K.G.B.
- [Woman] No. No.
Particularly effective
in the right hands.
But for a real target...
you need to find a soft spot.
- [Crying]
- Whoa. Hold up. Hey.
Wait. This is not a Kedr.
It's a Chinese copy.
In fact, I don't know if it's the drugs,
or if you're usually this inept...
but you've been wrong
about most of these weapons.
If the gun you're holding
is as cheap as this one...
even if you could manage to shoot her
in the eye-and I'm not saying you could-
you wouldn't kill her.
- [Woman Whimpering]
- [Shouts]
[Woman Screams]
[Woman]
Oh.!
[Screams]
[Shouting]
[Groans]
- Why are you doing this to me?
- I need you to help me with your brother.
Mikhail? Fine. Fuck him.
I do whatever you want.
What the fuck do you want me to do?
Just this.
You know, it says here that when
the male penguin meets the female penguin...
he knows in the first 10 seconds
whether he's gonna like her or not.
Are you listening?
I'm listening.
I read that.
These articles are full of shit.
- Why do you buy these magazines?
- For the advertisements.
What do you need
luggage like this for?
Because that perfectly holds
my Blaser sniper rifle and.245.
And a gag for irritating,
talkative little girls like yourself.
You want me to stop and get it out?
I don't know.
You think we have time for foreplay?
You know, when I was a little girl,
my father raised grapes.
And I told him that one day
I'd own my own vineyard.
It looks nice.
[47]
We need to get off the road.
[Chattering]
[Sighs]
- [Sighs]
- Jenks.
Is that his suitcase?
How did we get that?
As a consolation prize
Captain Gudnayev sent me.
Our boy's stuff from the hotel in St. Pete
in case it might help.
- Anything?
- Not much.
There is this.
What do you make of this?
[Jenkins]
"Trust unto God...
and he shall direct your path."
- It's-
- That's Psalms.
I never figured our boy as the religious type.
[Chuckles]
That's strange.
[Laughing]
Nika.
I have to go.
So much for happy endings.
I don't want you to do this.
Belicoff needs to die.
I don't care about that.
Not anymore.
As long as he's alive,
they will never stop looking for you.
[Train Horn Honks]
Take this.
At the next station,
get off the train as soon as it stops.
Move with the crowd.
But I don't even know your name.
The place I was raised, they didn't give us names.
They gave us numbers.
Mine was 47.
Well, that explains a lot.
- How will I find you?
- Don't worry.
I'll find you.
What are you going to do?
What I do.
[Buzzer Buzzes]
[Speaking Russian]
You're drunk.
You don't want to drink
with your new president, tovarich?
We are celebrating. Yes?
All the evidence is erased.
Mikhail Belicoff.
And his pathetic brother Udre.
Now I'm the one and only.
And the one man I have
asked you to kill...
the only one who can expose us...
is the one man not in this room!
So...
tell me, tovarich.
What exactly
have you done to find him?
It seems if we wait long enough...
he will find you.
Us, Tovarich Yuri.
- He will find us.
- The organization has sent in their best operatives.
I know.
Don't let your incompetence hinder them.
We will not have
this conversation again.
[Door Opens]
[Horn Honking]
Three hours ago, Belicoff! S brother Udre
was found dead in Istanbul.
They're waiting for the body
to arrive in Moscow for the funeral.
[Clears Throat]
Heads up.
Michael. How's things going?
Belicoff's brother has just been found murdered.
It's him, sir. It's our guy.
He's setting Belicoff up.
We're getting pressure from the ministry
and the E.U. To drop this investigation.
- But, sir, the Russians will-
- The Russians are the ones leading the E.U. On this.
They blatantly deny
your ghost exists...
and have filed papers
with the minister's office...
claiming you've
overstepped your authority.
Who? Who brought those allegations?
The F.S.B.
Specifically, Chief Agent Yuri Marklov.
I need you to stop.
No. You don't understand.
The F.S.B. Is covering this up.
He killed Belicoff's brother.
Now why?
- Why would he do that, unless-
- [Man On TV] Mikhail Belicoff...
announced that he would attend funeral
services tomorrow morning for the burial-
- The funeral.
- ... of his brother, Udre...
who died two days ago-
He's gonna take Belicoff
at Udre's funeral.
... some speculation
that Belicoff! S opponent-
[Door Slams]
[Coin Clinks]
[Groans]
This generator produces
over 3,000 amps-
much more than is necessary, but...
I wanted you to understand
the gravity of this situation.
At 2:30, that radio taped to
your hand will activate.
You'll have 30 seconds to order
the shooting of your friend Belicoff.
If you don't,
the generator will start.
Your skin will melt.
Your blood will vaporize.
There won't be enough
left of you to identify.
You have gone to
a great deal of trouble.
I am just a bureaucrat.
There is nothing I can do
for you, I'm afraid.
I disagree.
This is not a request.
This situation is fixed,
and you know both possible outcomes.
- [Breathing Heavily]
- Live... or die. Your choice.
Here's something to keep
things in perspective.
I picked it up last night
when I was in your house.
You bastard!
If I were you,
I'd keep that radio dry.
[Russian]
Yell all you like.
The Lord himself won't hear you.
[Russian]
[Groans]
[Crowd Chattering]
There are over 100 highly trained...
alpha Special Forces
soldiers in this cathedral.
It would be foolish
to attempt any type of violence.
A man as highly trained
as your assassin would realize this.
What if he does?
Look around you.
How much civilian blood
do you think will be shed?
We are prepared for that as well.
Gas canisters are being deployed.
If anything should occur,
the civilians will be rendered unconscious.
Now, if you will excuse me.
¢Ü¢Ü[Chorus Vocalizing]
[Camera Shutter Clicks]
[Speaking Russian]
[Electronic Female Voice]
One minute, 50 seconds.
[Russian]
[Speaks Russian, Groans]
[Speaking Russian]
My brother- he was a troubled man...
but he was not always like that.
One minute, 25 seconds.
One minute, 20 seconds.
[Mikhail] Should we choose to be kind
and let her die much like my brother?
Or should we do what is necessary...
what is hard, to save what we love?
One minute.
[Whimpering, Grunts]
- [Groans]
- I, for one, will not fail again.
Not with this country.
Not with our children's future.
Not with you, my countrymen.
[Applause]
Thirty-five seconds.
- [Russian]
- [Beeps]
- Hurry! Come in!
- Da.
Change target.
Shoot Belicoff.
[Russian]
[Yuri]
It's an impostor.! Do it.!
- Just fucking do it now!
- [Beeps]
[All Gasp]
[Crowd Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
Do not let the assassin escape.
Release the gas.
Lock down the doors.
I suggest you and your men follow me.
Let's go!
[All Shouting]
[Man Speaks Russian]
[Russian]
Your man has made a mistake.
There is no exit.
He's trapped.
Doesn't make sense.
Why would he-
"Trust unto God...
and he shall direct your path. "
Shit. He set this up
from the very beginning.
[Grunts]
[Screams]
- [Bone Cracks]
- [Screams]
Where does this key fit?
The archbishop's personal chambers.
The third tower.
Over the Muscova.
He's going into the river,
like in St. Pete.
Jenks, get our men.
Let's go.
He is in the southwest tower.
Call in the gunships.
Do not let him escape.
Seems I underestimated you.
Consistently.
A miscalculation on my part.
- [Groans]
- Who are you?
- Answer me.
- Let me help you.
- How would you do that? By having me killed?
- Ah. No.
For that I'm sorry.
It was a mistake.
And Nika-was that a mistake?
- Or did you destroy her life
for your own amusement?
- What?
You think you can take
what has cost millions...
years of planning,
for the good of this country...
and destroy that?
Then what? Walk away?
You don't really think they will let you do that.
If you kill me, they will never let you go.
They will hunt you
for the rest of your life.
You did your job.
And you did it very well.
And for that, my boy,
you should be proud.
That's it?
Yes. I'm offering you
your life back.
That is why you are here, yes?
That is what you want.
Uh-uh.
No?
No.
[Helicopter Whirring]
[Machine Gun Fire]
[Walkie-talkie: Man Speaks Russian]
Interpol! Drop your weapons!
[Mike]
We have an arrest warrant for that man.
Don't move! Hands on your head!
On your head!
- On your knees!
- Don't do anything stupid.
Just one thing.
Knowing how this ends,
was it worth it...
killing Belicoff?
Knowing how this ends?
Definitely.
- What do you make of that?
- [Tires Squeal]
What the hell?
[Tires Screeching]
[Guns Cocking]
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm Agent Smith...
of the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency.
- I need all you men to the rear of that vehicle.
- You don't have jurisdiction.
We aren't here.
Which means when we open up on you...
and shred your bodies with automatic fire,
then this will never have happened.
- Stand down.
- We have reason to believe...
you're involved
in terrorist activities.
We're Interpol.
And in accordance with section 3-
- We're transporting an international criminal.
- What criminal?
Oh, Jesus Christ.!
You know what?
I'm sorry, man.
My mistake.
- I thought you were someone else.
- You prick.
On behalf of the United States government...
I'd like to extend to you
our sincerest apologies.
Load up, boys.
[Tires Squealing]
[Cell Phone Beeping]
- So now what?
- Now you have to answer my question.
Are you a good man, Inspector?
I think.
And yet you've killed men.
So, Inspector...
how does a good man
decide when to kill?
If I think that a man means
to do me or my family harm...
then I will do
whatever I can to stop him...
but beyond that...
it's a crapshoot.
The key.
[Chuckles]
You knew I had jurisdiction...
and would walk you
right out through the front door.
I wanna be left alone.
- Just like that?
- Yeah. Just like that.
This is the man
you've been looking for.
Ballistics will confirm
he was shot by your weapon.
The magazine is in the nightstand
next to your bed.
Don't forget it when
you call your superiors.
Did you kill him here?
It's 5:00. If you wait a few hours,
until the girls go to school...
you won't have to
expose them to this.
Explains why you waited so long
before you called it in.
- I can't go along with this.
- I hope you can.
For both our sakes.
Good-bye, Michael.
[Thunder Rumbles]
I hope I never see you again.
[Exhales Deeply]
I told you to leave her alone.
You should have listened.