Shooters, come forward
to the 20-yard line.
Thanks, Joe.
Oh, shit.
Yo, K-Ro,
where you going, man?
- K-Ro, what's up?
- Hey, baby.
Somebody just shot my club up.
That's what I say, shot my club up.
What you need to know my name?
Get the police.
What do you mean you ain't coming?
I give you first shot
at making me an offer...
...on this four-bedroom
Mt. Olympus...
...and you leave me
sitting here two hours...
...and now you're telling me
you ain't... Hello?
Shit.
Gavilan.
Yeah, give me 10 minutes.
Be right there.
Yeah, it's Calden.
Oh, shit.
I'll be there in seven minutes. Yeah.
- Hi, Joe. How you doing?
- Okay, how are you?
Find anybody to buy
that house yet?
No. Showed it a couple of times
last week. There's some interest.
- I hear we got a messy one here.
- Yeah.
Joe, K.C.
- Hey, Leon.
- Hey.
I'm making you two
primaries in this disaster.
Since you've made no progress in the
Klepto murder, I figure you're due.
- Thanks for the confidence.
- No problem.
- Do you have a body count?
- Can we get a statement?
- What do we got, Leon?
- One on the floor, three backstage.
Rap group, calls itself H2OKlick.
Don't ask me why.
- Joint was full?
- Yeah.
- Nobody saw it.
- Of course not.
- Are these things on?
- They were. They're off now.
Listen, get them out of here.
Now, come on.
Let's go.
Well, what do you think?
Write this down.
Cheeseburger, well-done.
Raw onion, pickle, ketchup.
Nothing else.
Got it.
Officer.
Time to get rolling on some chow.
This is what the big dog wants.
And I want tomato and cucumber
on whole wheat...
...with only mustard
and bean sprouts.
Hey, Lou, nobody
goes in here, okay?
Got you.
It looks like one shooter came
from down there.
The other came from down there.
This poor son of a bitch
got it from both sides.
- Yeah.
- How long you had this place?
Man, I only had this place two years.
This is messed up.
- Where you living?
- At the Bel Age.
- Bel Age?
- Right up the road...
...but it's just temporary.
- Where were you when it occurred?
- In my office. Right there.
- These guys were about to break out.
- The boys was blowing up.
Sartain Records.
Antoine Sartain, that's the big man.
- These guys have any trouble?
- Some sort of turf war?
I know nothing about no
East Coast-West Coast...
...hip-hop, gangbanging bullshit.
I'm just a poor country boy
trying to get by.
- Getting by pretty well, I'd say.
- I do okay.
Hello? Hold on. Hello?
Hello? Hold on just a second, let me...
Hey, Stan.
Stan, that four-bedroom
Mt. Olympus fell through.
Can you make me an offer?
Eddie, you got those shoe prints?
Two prints.
Matching pattern, different sizes.
That's a 9. That's an 11.
Hey, you, come here.
I see mayonnaise.
Did anybody in this room
hear me say the word mayonnaise?
Read your notes.
What does it say?
Cheeseburger, well-done,
ketchup, pickle.
You call that well-done?
In addition to the mayonnaise...
...I see lettuce that somebody
tried to scrape off here.
This is a disaster.
What do they teach you
at the Academy?
You want to be a detective?
- Yes, sir.
- Don't call me sir. I work for a living.
Dump this for me, please.
I expect better.
- Joe, kid's got something.
- Gavilan.
No, 675 won't fly.
If you're gonna get back to me,
have at least 7 and change.
Diamond earring.
Could be something,
could be nothing. Good work, kid.
Did you get the piss and
the shoe prints in the closet?
Yeah, I got it, Joe.
I'm gonna go hammer
on the owner a little more.
How come you got no video
surveillance, big-ass place like this?
- What kind of security you got?
- I ain't never had no problems.
You got a problem now.
Two guys sneak in with guns.
- Who does your security anyway?
- A bunch of off-duty L.A.P.D. Cops.
That's your first mistake.
Man, why you ragging on me?
All I'm trying to do is just business.
Julius, you're making me curious.
How come you live in a hotel?
I just sold my crib.
The new one fell through.
So I'm sort of, like,
looking right now.
You're sort of looking
for a new house?
That's what I said.
Julius, look...
...in my other career
I'm a real-estate broker.
Real-estate broker?
You got two jobs?
We work a lot of overtime,
we get time off.
A lot of guys have three jobs.
- What you saying?
- What I'm saying...
...is I got a beautiful 3400-square-foot
house on Mt. Olympus.
New roof, partial view.
Owner's desperate.
Man, I don't want no crap
on no Mt. Olympics.
Well, what you looking for?
I'm looking for a big house,
something with class.
How much will you pay
for something with class?
Not a penny more than 6.
- Six?
- That's what I said, 6.
Million?
I was not soliciting.
I was doing research.
Research is not soliciting.
I've never had to pay for sex.
I have four BAFTA nominations.
Evening, Gloria.
Do you know who I am?
- Here's our dead guys.
- Thanks.
The puddle of piss makes me think
we got a witness.
- Just sit down there and shut up.
- You shut up.
I can't work here.
This place is a zoo.
Let's get out of here
before Boardner's closes.
The doctor's in. Help's on its way.
Thanks, Hank.
- Something wrong, Joe?
- What do you mean, "wrong"?
You seem down.
Down? Me?
Lately. Yeah.
We've been partners for four months.
Now you want to be my shrink?
Sometimes it helps to talk.
That's all I'm saying.
All right.
Let me paint you a picture.
Portrait of Joe Gavilan.
Seven, eight years ago,
I sold the results...
...of my entrepreneurial efforts
up to that point.
Three tanning salons...
...and two original silk-tip
nail parlors in the Antelope Valley.
And I started attending...
...weekend real-estate seminars
at the airport Hyatt.
You know, how to make
a million dollars...
...in real estate
with very little money down.
Sounds good.
Started with a condo
in Sherman Oaks.
Slapped paint on the walls.
Refaced the kitchen cabinets.
Traded up to a smoke-damaged
ranch in Tarzana.
Then a Spanish on Outpost...
...and a fake Mediterranean
in Los Feliz.
Pretty soon I had everything
I've got tied up in this...
...this monstrosity on Mt. Olympus...
...at the corner of Hercules
and, I shit you not, Achilles.
- What's the problem?
- The problem is...
...if I don't score a big commission
or get rid of this...
...piece of shit on Mt. Olympus...
Well, the word Titanic
comes to mind.
Joe, I know a girl who works
for some rich producer.
Says he might sell his place.
Maybe you can get the listing.
- Got a name?
- Her name's like Minnie or Moma.
Something like that,
I don't remember.
Not the girl, hot rocks,
the producer.
Oh, I don't know the producer.
Way before my time.
- Hey, Joe, you ready for something?
- Shoot.
I don't think I want
to be a cop anymore.
Come on, you need some fresh air.
- Put this on my tab, Hank.
- What tab?
Hey, I got it. I got it. It's okay.
Here.
If you don't want to be a cop,
what do you want to be?
I want to be an actor.
- You wanna be what?
- An actor.
What?
Okay.
- You're gay. I can deal with that.
- You know I'm not gay.
Why do you want to do
something stupid like acting?
Because it's my bliss.
And I have to follow my bliss.
Turning into Oprah around here.
I rented a theater
on Highland, Friday night.
I invited some agents and producers.
It's called a showcase.
- What are you showcasing?
- My talents.
Mr. Robert De Niro here.
Hey, detective, you're gonna say
it's none of my business...
...but when's the last time
you got laid?
None of your business.
Right.
Say it ain't so, Joe.
Oh, my God.
Jesus Christ.
- How's business, Jack?
- Wanda.
- Some trick's thumping on prostitutes.
We put our best female officer
undercover and she got hurt, so...
...I'm the bait.
Well, you look good.
Well, it never hurts
to get a compliment...
...but that's not why
I was shaking my booty at you.
You're working that bloodbath
over at the Freeway Club.
The word's out
about the shooting.
Word is one guy slid out
without a scratch.
- Got a name or anything?
- K-Ro, K-Mart or something like that.
He was the group's
main songwriter.
- Somebody writes that shit?
- Yeah, tell me about it.
Want me to drop you
back where I got you?
Yeah, I got backup to pick me up.
Just swing me
back around to Cherokee.
These heels are killing me.
Just killing me, man.
This is Ruby the psychic,
Ruby the night owl...
...waiting for your calls,
your problems, your concerns.
Want to unravel the past?
Ruby can help.
Want to sort out the present?
Want to look into the future?
Ruby can do that too.
Just pick up the phone.
Smokey, where have you been?
Busy guy, Ruby.
- Got something to share?
- Tell me about the future.
I see some financial concerns.
Is that right?
Yep.
Wait a minute. I'm seeing something
dangerous, maybe painful?
What else is new?
Whatever else is new
will have to wait.
We're out of time.
Why do you call so late?
Night owls, this is Ruby.
Mr. Sartain and I'd like to thank you.
I'm Mr. Sartain's colleague,
Leroy Wasley.
- Tell Mr. Sartain the deed's done.
- Now where's our money?
Here you go.
Oh, shit.
Tell me something, man. You think
Gavilan can figure this thing out?
Bennie Macko's not gonna let him.
He'll take him down.
Why would Bennie Macko
believe all this bullshit?
I've known Bennie a long time.
He graduated in the class
behind mine at the academy.
We were rookies together
in the same division.
He's a politically ambitious suit.
- He listens to what I tell him.
- Patience is not one of my virtues.
Let me explain something.
You can kill a street
punk like Klepto. It's no big deal.
These two bangers,
they didn't mean anything to anybody.
But you send them into an open
nightclub, and they cap four guys?
That's another mess altogether.
The last time I checked, I pay you
to run my security, not your mouth.
Let go of me,
you sons of bitches!
Stella!
Not a knickknack, knit-lock,
knock-kneed knickerbocker sock...
...off a hodgepodge, moss-blotched,
botched Scotch block.
I got more time in the third-floor
crapper than you do on the job.
You can't open my locker without
a warrant. I know my rights.
Well, I appreciate a man who knows
his rights. There you go.
- What's going on here, cap?
- This is Bennie Macko, Internal Affairs.
- You got a right to an attorney.
- This is an authorized investigation...
...within the jurisdiction
of Los Angeles.
- Oh, please. I'll open it.
- Go ahead.
- I haven't been in there in 10 years.
- You open it.
Oh, here are those shoes.
I thought I lost these.
- I love these shoes.
- Ever clean your locker?
Between finding, apprehending
and convicting murderers...
...and cleaning, I made
a decision to do the former.
- You got a lot of lip.
- A lot of lip.
- Yeah, you do.
- I got a big nose too.
Calden, open your locker.
- Why him?
- He's your partner. Go ahead, open it.
No, don't open it.
- You got something to hide?
- Yeah, kind of.
You got to do it, son.
Porno.
Commingling funds, huh?
That's my crime?
Commingling? Guilty.
My alimony, number one,
comes from money...
...commingled
with my beer money.
My refinanced car commingled with
the short-term loan to keep the...
...second mortgage paid, commingled
with my alimony number three...
...commingled with
every goddamn dime...
...I've got tied up
in my Mt. Olympus property.
My whole life's commingled.
I'm glad you brought up
Mt. Olympus.
You're attempting to sell
without disclosing you own it.
This isn't about real estate,
is it, Bennie?
What's going on here? As immediate
supervisor of these men...
...you are bound to inform me
of any investigation.
- You're informed.
- You couldn't tell me?
I'm trying to find out
what I'm guilty of...
...besides going to one too many
airport real-estate seminars.
Well, for starters, you know
a woman named Cleo Ricard?
I talk to her. Talk's cheap.
Administrative Vice, which has
been watching her for two years...
...is making a major prostitution bust...
...and you're making promises
to her to intervene.
You haven't registered her
as an informant.
- Joe, is this true?
- By itself, that's cause for suspension.
I mentioned her name to District
Attorney Gardner six weeks ago.
- Told him I was gonna make a contact.
- He denies it.
He's a liar! I haven't registered
her as an informant...
...because she hasn't informed.
I don't want to get
buried under paperwork...
...just so Vice can tell me
to back off their suspect.
It's a big case for them.
- Bigger than a quadruple murder?
- This is not your decision.
As no charges have been made,
release Gavilan and Calden...
...so they can resume investigations.
- Bennie?
- Yeah, we'll talk about it.
- When he's out of the room.
- Fuck you very much.
- What is with that Macko guy?
- Oh, he's a jerk.
Years ago, he was lead detective
on those jockey love-nest murders.
You remember, big girls, little guys?
He bragged to the papers.
I proved he had the wrong guy.
Embarrassed the shit out of him.
He's been wanting to get me since.
Now he's assigned to IA,
and he's taking his shot.
- You can't trust cops.
- Your dad was a cop.
He was killed in the line of duty
under bullshit circumstances.
No one was held responsible,
and his case was closed.
The feds investigate?
The word is they thought
his partner was dirty...
...but the report's sealed tight.
I got a pal down there
who owes me a favor.
You wanna see the report,
I'll make a call.
I'd appreciate it. Yeah.
Hey, Joe, listen, what I said last night
about you getting laid...
...it's none of my business,
you know?
It's no big deal.
Just be safe.
- Safe?
- Yeah.
That hooker last night.
That was a guy.
I don't need to know that.
That was a cop.
That was a guy cop.
A cop guy.
- Gavilan.
- "Hello, Joe?"
Cleo, I was just talking about you.
I hope it was something good.
Listen, Joe, I have a little problem.
Vice is breathing down my neck.
Yeah, well, IA's
breathing down mine.
Let's go.
Come on, big boy.
- Well, I might have something for you.
- I'm listening.
Is this the William Morris Agency?
Yeah. Hi, this is K.C. Calden.
I sent a headshot, résumé...
...and an invitation to a performance
of "Streetcar Named Desire."
Hold it while I get something
out of the trunk. Where you going?
It's on Friday.
One of the girls was a regular
for one of the guys shot last night.
She was also a regular of Klepto's.
You talk to Vice and get them
to back off me...
- "... and I'll talk to her".
- Not the way it works.
Give me the girl first.
Joe, why don't I send you over
a couple of ladies?
Big mistake. Big, big mistake.
You can have a party on me.
We'll keep it out of the book.
What do you say?
Not my style, Cleo. Call me back
when you got something real.
Yeah, I'll be playing the Brando part.
Hello?
Let's go.
I'll call you back.
- I'm gonna take him, Joe.
- No, no, no. The gun's still hot!
Stay down there. Stay down.
Stay down, man. Stay there.
Got a live gun here.
You'll get yourself shot.
What are you talking about?
It's a standard Beretta, 15 shots.
- I counted.
- And one in the spout.
- Oh, shit.
- Did you lose this?
- How do I look?
- You look all right.
Many thanks. Now the buttons.
I can't do nothing with them.
You men with your big,
clumsy fingers.
May I have a drag on your cig?
What?
- Okay.
- Who writes this stuff?
Look, it's not stuff. It's art.
In fact, it's one of the
greatest plays ever.
And it's not the words you're
having trouble with.
It's the lack of conviction.
If you give it conviction...
...we can have a back-and-forth.
I know you're playing a girl,
but come on.
- What is this about?
- Just read.
It's your turn.
You look like you raided
some stylish shops in Paris.
No, wait a second,
you skipped a line.
As a matter of fact,
you skipped a bunch of lines.
Never mind, we're here.
K.C. Calden, Hollywood Homicide.
We're here to see Antoine Sartain.
He's in recording studio B, I think.
- Is he expecting you?
- Kind of.
Homicide, I want to talk
to Antoine Sartain.
You gentlemen
have an appointment?
You off-duty L.A.P.D.?
- You giving me a hard time?
- It's called a homicide investigation.
- Well, you're not going in.
- My God, he has a badge and a gun.
Come on, get out
of the way, will you?
What? A cop's gonna
hit a cop now?
That's a good suggestion.
I'm filing police brutality charges.
Assault, harassment.
Let me help you out there.
Sergeant Willoughby. Gavilan.
How's Betty?
The kids? Okay, good.
Look, I got an off-duty cop who wants
to file a complaint against me.
Hold on a second.
There's been a misunderstanding.
Thanks a lot.
Finally, this is the take.
This is the one.
This is it, Butch.
Come on in. That's the best take.
We need some bells,
because this ain't happening.
- Bells?
- Everybody's using bells, man.
- We need some radio.
- Guys, excuse me.
- My opinion is gold.
- Antoine Sartain?
- What did I say to you?
- Hold up.
- Antoine Sartain?
- Please, hold up.
- L.A.P.D. Homicide.
- What's this supposed to be?
- Who are you, coming in here?
- I'm looking for Antoine Sartain.
Turn the music down.
Chill on the real. On the real, chill.
Because you know what?
What you want, man?
You Hollywood dicks are all the same.
Hey.
You all saw that, right?
That's police brutality.
- Don't think I won't report you.
- Help me out here.
Do you know this guy?
Help me out.
Because I don't recognize him.
These the same guys?
These your friends?
- Yeah, we know these guys.
- That's my boy, man.
Do you know where
I can find Mr. Sartain?
He just left. He's on the 10th floor.
- Elevator's over there.
- Thank you very much.
K.C. Calden?
- Silk Brown, baby. Crenshaw High.
- Oh, yeah. How you doing, brother?
I'm all right. Told you I knew this dude.
I'll stick around here and see
if I can find out anything.
Look at him!
Didn't know you were a cop, man.
Actually, I'm thinking about
getting out of this L.A.P.D. Shit.
- What you working, man?
- I did some acting in high school.
- Thinking about the movie thing.
- I knew we came for a reason.
- Baby, talk to him. Go ahead.
- Well, I did a Jell-O commercial once.
- That's right. The blue Jell-O girl.
- That was me. J-E-L-L-O.
- You did a great job. Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- She sold a shitload of Jell-O too.
- I believe that.
This is nice.
Trying to imagine what it was like
when this was all still glamorous.
It's been a long time since anything
happened at Hollywood and Vine.
- Can I offer you something? Anything?
- No, I just want to ask a few questions.
Oh, sure. Sure.
- Have a seat, please.
- Thanks.
So how long ago did you sign...
...H2OKlick?
- Five years ago.
I don't really know this music.
- Were they good?
- Most people don't know this.
But I lose money on 19
out of 20 new groups.
But one breakout...
One breakout pays for everything.
Were these guys gonna break out?
They had a chance, yeah.
You know these fellas personally?
I can't afford to get
too close to my acts.
Because, sooner or later,
I'm gonna have to be the guy...
...that doesn't renew their contracts.
- Brutal business.
Brutal business. Brutal.
So I don't have an agent right now,
but I can do accents.
I do English, I do Jamaican
and even Texas.
- And I even play the piano and tennis.
- Yeah, she real good, dude.
Silk got this script
that's off the hook, man.
I got the script with Oscar
shit written all over it.
- I'll tell you what it's called.
- Tell him.
Tell him the title. You will love
this title. Tell him the title.
- Let me hear it.
- You ready for this?
- It's called...
- Listen to this.
..."Nasty."
- Tell me that ain't hot!
- That's a good title.
I'm into titties and shit blowing up.
- But nothing exploitive.
- No, none of that.
- Gotta respect the female.
- Always.
Maybe I can help you out with this,
but you guys can help me out too.
Give me a call if you hear anything
about this H2OKlick thing, all right?
We ain't no snitches or nothing
like that, you know. Come on, now.
- No, I don't wanna ask you to do that.
- No.
You hold on to that just in case
something comes up. You never know.
How much time you spend
in the joint, Antoine?
Much too long for my taste.
My accountant let me down.
Something about
commingling of funds.
Yeah, it could happen to anybody.
Must take a lot of money to get
one of these groups up and running.
How much did you have
invested in Klepto?
Now, that was a bad investment.
He left my label. Why you asking?
I'm just fascinated
by the music business.
One last thing. Young fellow goes
by the name of K-Ro.
Did some songs for H2O.
Know his real name
or where I can find him?
- I'd like to ask him a few questions.
- K-Ro.
No, I don't... I don't even know
the guy's real name.
I mean, most of these kids
have some badass names.
They all think they're thugs.
For most, it's just an act.
Bunch of mama's boys.
First they're down with a brother,
then they're ungrateful asses.
Half of them would be dead
or in prison if it wasn't for me.
You know what I'm saying, detective?
It's just a game. Nothing but a game.
Well, we got four mama's boys
laying on slabs at the morgue.
It wasn't a game last night.
I'll let you go. Thanks for your help.
If you think of anything more...
...you let me know, okay?
- Sure.
Detective.
What, are you trying to sell me
some real estate?
- What do you got?
- I know Sartain's lying to me.
- How do you know that?
- His lips are moving.
- What do you got there?
- It's a script from the guys in there.
They say they'll call if they
come across anything.
They say they don't know about
last night. They're lying too.
You get the name of that
producer selling his house?
- I'll get it now. Just a second.
- All right.
Mimi?
Mona, right. Sorry.
Do you know the name of that
producer selling his place up on...?
Yeah.
Thank you. Yeah, sorry. Bye.
- Jerry Duran?
- Jerry Duran. Used to be huge.
- Joe, somebody's stealing your car!
- It's insured, so it's okay.
No, it's not okay!
Hey! Get out of the way!
Get out of the way!
Stop! Police!
Stop!
All right!
Get out of the car!
Get your hands up!
Stop! Get down! Get down!
Get down on the ground!
Get down!
Put your hands where I can see them.
Get them behind your back.
Don't cuff us.
We weren't stealing your car.
- We're repo guys.
- You kidding me?
Nice shot, slick.
Now we gotta spend the afternoon
booking car thieves...
...filling out paperwork.
- They weren't stealing it.
- What do you call it?
Repo.
Apparently, you're behind
on your payments.
You assholes, get out of here!
Get out of here! Goddamn it! Get out!
Shit! That was a good tire!
Hey, Roy. Joe Gavilan just left.
He was in here looking for K-Ro.
He must've been
the other guy backstage.
'Toine, listen to me.
- It's taken care of.
- No, no, it's not taken care of.
If it was, Gavilan wouldn't
be here in my face.
After tonight, K-Ro's just a memory.
Not after tonight. Take care of it now.
- By the time homicide finds him...
- Get it taken care of. Now!
K.C.!
- Kimberly, hey!
- Shawna!
You dog, you.
- Yes?
- L.A.P.D. Mr. Duran, please.
One moment, please.
You just shut up and let me
do the talking, all right?
- Gentlemen.
- Mr. Duran. Hollywood Homicide.
Detective Joe Gavilan.
My partner, K.C. Calden.
- There must be some mistake.
- I think I've got a buyer for your house.
- I won't go a penny under 5.7.
- I was thinking 6.
- So that's, what, five bedrooms?
- Six bedrooms upstairs, six baths.
Guesthouse has two baths,
two bedrooms.
And in the servants' quarters,
two bedrooms, two baths.
Now, this room's a beaut. You got
a whole view of Benedict Canyon. It's...
Hey, don't you have something
to do in the kitchen?
There's a lost wax fountain
at the bottom of this.
It's a piece of work.
You should see that.
And this is a living room.
Mr. Duran, are you still
making music and movies?
When I can, kid.
Well...
...what are you doing on Friday night?
- Friday night's a long time away, kid.
- Beautiful house, Mr. Duran.
- Thank you.
I've got a desperate buyer.
Give me a three-day exclusive listing.
- If I don't sell it in that time, deal's off.
- I'll give you 48 hours.
The great and the near-great.
I used to be huge.
- I could be huge again.
- You're still huge to me, Mr. Duran.
You got 72 hours to sell my house.
- Thank you.
- Let me show you the door.
Joe Gavilan. Look, I found you
your big house with class.
But you got to get over here
right away.
- There's a lot of interest.
- "What's up?"
I got $6 million. You been talking.
Show me the house.
3500 Shadow Hills Way, Beverly Hills.
How soon...? Within an hour?
Okay, great.
Gavilan. Yeah, Leon.
Mando's got something for you.
Hold on.
Joe, the kid who split the club.
K- Ro, born Oliver Robidoux, 5/78.
Went to Leuzinger High...
...in Compton, graduated '95.
- "Address unknown."
- Oliver Robidoux.
- I hope they do haul you in...
- Leon, that name ring a bell with you?
- Robidoux, Robidoux. Sounds familiar.
- Yeah, a Motown singer.
Olivia Robidoux used to sing backup
for Marvin Gaye and Tammi Terrell.
- Stella!
- Put Lopez back on.
Run Olivia Robidoux, will you?
Music unions, ASCAP, anything.
- Get back to me, okay?
- I hope they do haul you in...
- K-Ro.
...and turn the fire hose on you.
- You whelp of a Polack, you.
- Hey. K-Ro is one Oliver Robidoux.
I think his mom was this backup
singer for Motown, Olivia Robidoux.
- We're finally getting somewhere.
- Let's go.
Hey, look, I gotta show the house.
- Now?
- How about you cover the autopsies?
- I don't like dead bodies.
- Come on, I'll owe you one.
- You coming to my play Friday night?
- Yeah, I'm coming to your play. Sure.
Well, there's still some seats open.
All right, I'll bring some people, okay?
All right, you got a deal.
- Shawna, can I get a lift?
- Of course.
Cool. See you, Joe.
Let me take that for you.
Thanks.
It's good to see you again.
Man.
- Jesus!
- Sorry about that.
There's some towels over there, K.C.
We got a juicy one here.
- K.C. Calden, Hollywood Homicide.
- Willie Palmero, South Bureau.
Body drop in Vernon.
Couple of crispy critters here.
I think it was a professional hit,
a straight-up execution.
- And this earring?
- Off one of the guys.
I bet they were wearing work boots,
weren't they? Sizes 9 and 11?
- How'd you know?
- Jesus Christ.
Willie, I think these guys
shot those guys.
Beautiful home. Cool crib.
This is me.
The great, near-great
used to hang out here.
For sure?
Wow.
- He wants 7.
- Man, tell him kiss my ass.
No, now wait.
Here's the deal.
You offer 5.5. He counters with 6.5.
You come back at 6.
Give him 48 hours. He'll take it.
- He's desperate.
- For sure?
For sure. Excuse me.
- Gavilan.
- "Joe, yeah."
I got two bodies here in the chop
shop that could be the triggermen.
- What do you got?
- I got the earring...
...and the boots. I booked them
into evidence.
- Man, what's up?
- Police business.
- You seen the library?
- I don't need no library. I need a pool.
Turf-warfare guys do
their own dirty work.
I think these guys were capped
to cover somebody else's tracks.
- You like tennis?
- Too much running.
I absolutely agree with you.
No, not...
Look, good job, kid.
I'll talk to you later.
Yeah, okay.
So, Julius...
...what do you think?
- Okay. I'll go 5.5.
All right. My man.
Bring the left foot back.
Root it there and come up
into warrior one.
Let your arms just raise up.
Spread your arms to the sides. Exhale.
Come back down into warrior two.
Exhale. Bring your right arm down
to your knee and then sweep across.
Extreme right-angle pose.
Sweep the arms up,
move your feet to parallel.
Pull your arms back around
behind you.
And then just feel yourself open.
Very good.
Continue that on the other side.
I'll be right back.
- What are you doing here?
- I've got something for you.
- How'd you find me?
- I'm psychic.
- Really?
- No, not really.
I'm a detective, for chrissake.
I didn't know you taught this.
- You make some dough?
- Yeah, I make 20 bucks a head.
- You know, donation.
- Donation? Unreportable?
Twenty times 40...
Eight hundred bucks a whack?
Cash?
Class, all right, when you're done
with this pose, we're done for the day.
Get back here.
Some racket you got here.
Money and sex.
This is not a racket. These are real
people with real feelings.
They need me. I'm their teacher.
And I need them too.
It's called a symbiotic relationship.
You wouldn't know about that.
Have a good day. Nice practice.
Excuse me, K.C.,
do you give private lessons?
I don't. If you talk to Kimberly,
then we'll set something up.
Okay, thank you.
K.C., thank you. I feel really...
...open.
That's a good thing, okay?
See you later.
Great class.
Thanks, Shawna.
Okay.
Maybe I got into it for the sex.
But it's not about that anymore.
I mean, this spiritual shit...
...there's really something to it.
I mean,
I'm out of my body sometimes, man.
Seriously.
I mean, this stuff really works.
And then these girls come in.
And, I mean, they're everywhere.
It's spiritual.
- Deep.
- And shallow.
Deep and shallow.
This is why I came.
It's the report on your dad's shooting.
Gavilan.
Gower and Franklin.
Thanks for understanding, Joe.
What's up, Cleo?
- Have you talked to Vice?
- No, I haven't.
Not gonna talk to Vice
till I talk to your girl.
- You'll have to give me a name.
- My girl is ready to talk.
I've heard that before.
She says she was working
a Sartain Records party.
Overheard some guy smoking crack
start bragging.
About what?
The people behind the Klepto murder
were also behind the H2OKlick hit.
That's hearsay.
Hearsay to you,
pillow talk to the DA.
- You want a deal?
- I don't know.
Give me a call tomorrow,
I'll run it by the DA.
- This girl better be for real.
- Look, I gotta make this work.
Things are getting ugly.
I hear you.
What we got on Gavilan so far?
First of all,
he's still seeing Cleo Ricard.
- In fact, he saw her earlier today.
- God, it's right in my face.
He's just completely defiant.
He's clearly continuing to work her
as an informant.
That's enough to relieve him
of duty right there.
I don't want him relieved of duty.
I want him to hang.
His financials don't add up.
He's paying off three ex-wives.
He's got two kids.
Two kids in a fancy college. He's got a
great big house and a big, stupid car.
I mean,
what about his real-estate thing?
He hasn't made a sale in ages.
My source tells me he's getting money
from somewhere to keep it afloat.
- So get me more surveillance.
- Okay.
Alrighty.
- Dominique?
- Close enough.
- Where'd you get the key?
- Under the flowerpot.
How'd you know it was
under the flowerpot?
I'm psychic.
Good security for a cop.
Bad cop.
No doughnut.
- Everything okay?
- Oh, yeah.
Everything's fine.
Just a tough case, that's all.
Used to have a feel
for a case early on.
Thank you.
So you really...
...think you can
predict the future, huh?
How's that work?
Sometimes I see things.
It just comes to me.
And sometimes I flip a coin.
Other times...
...I just make shit up.
Happy anniversary.
What anniversary?
You and me.
Three weeks.
That is so sweet.
You remembered.
I didn't.
I mean, dates don't really matter,
except they do.
We think human time,
but rocks think geologic time.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
I don't.
The only date that matters is the day
I found you and left that jerk.
Does he know it's over?
Bennie's in denial.
He's hanging on like a mongoose.
It's sad, really.
Bennie?
Macko. You don't know him.
He's not in your division.
Bennie Macko?
- Bennie "The Executioner" Macko?
- That sounds like my Bennie.
He's the guy who's trying to bury me,
for chrissake!
- Does he know about us?
- Of course not.
And who cares?
It's over, we're finished.
Guys aren't like that, honey.
Guys keep score!
Gavilan.
Yeah, Jerry...
Mr. Duran.
Yeah, I can do that.
Okay.
Get the buyer and the seller
inches away from closing...
...and this guy wants...
...breakfast.
That could be great, honey. Mercury's
not in retrograde for another week.
It's good time for deal-making.
It's perfect time.
What did you ever see in...
...Bennie Macko?
I guess I just have
a weakness for cops.
Lock up when you leave.
What have we here?
Oh, my!
Nice shoes.
- Good morning, Mr. Duran, Julius.
- Good morning. Have a seat.
This is my attorney, Marty Wheeler...
...who just happens to be Julius'
attorney as well. Small world.
A conflict of interest?
Not for me.
Okay, let's talk.
Julius was ready
to go to 6.3 or 6.4...
...and you drove the price down
to 6.
Wait a second. You wanted 5.8.
Six is a score.
- You never told me 5.8 would do it.
- I was negotiating.
For whom?
Look, you wanted 5.8.
I was about to get you 6.
- He was ready to go to 6.4.
- Maybe 6.5.
But you said the price was 7.
It never was.
Look, guys, calm down.
This is a good deal for both of you.
The deal's off. I want 7 million.
Seven?
- Seven?
- Yeah.
I won't go a penny over 6.5.
Good day, gents.
Asshole!
I was that close to closing the deal
when Duran starts dicking around...
...and blows the whole thing.
Getting excited never
solved any problems.
How many girls are waiting in line for
the hot tub? That's a problem for you.
Joe, you don't respect me wanting
to be an actor, do you?
I just don't get it.
Don't you ever want to explore
all the possibilities of who you are?
I just want to pay the mortgage and
escape with my dick attached to me.
It's that one over there.
I'm a simple man. Go around behind.
- I'll give you a second.
- Okay.
Take the front.
Ms. Robidoux? Police!
Just want to ask you a few questions.
I always thought you could sing
better than Tammi Terrell.
She got the breaks. I didn't.
That's life.
Mind if I come in?
Jesus Christ.
Joe, he's around front!
Joe, he's coming around front!
I got him!
He didn't do anything!
Ms. Robidoux.
Hey!
I ain't did shit, cop!
Why you come to my mama house?
I ain't been to your mama house!
Fuck!
Jesus Christ, man!
- Get out of the water!
- Wait.
- Don't make me come in.
- I'm knee-deep in duck shit.
- There's two feet of duck shit.
- That's fine.
- Get out of the water!
- What you gonna do, shoot me?
He wants to shoot an unarmed nigger.
- Get out, man. You're under arrest.
- I didn't do nothing!
Get out of the water!
Fuck.
Hey!
Too slow, cop!
Christ!
Right or left?
Pick a way, I'm gonna catch you.
Never gonna catch me, cop!
Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha.
Stay right! Stay... Sorry,
your right! Your right, please!
All right!
Police brutality!
Don't swear!
It's not nice.
Settle down!
You got him.
See where that got you!
You're still caught and you got shit
all over you! How do you like that?
- Center yourself.
- I'm calm, okay?
- All right.
- I'm calm!
Get up!
You young-ass brat.
If it wasn't for this old man,
you wouldn't have caught nothing!
Even if you had roller skates. I can't
believe I let your old ass catch me.
- Talk to us.
- L.A.P.D:
- Lame-ass, punk-ass dickheads.
- Settle down, son.
- L.A.P.D.
- Settle down.
I ain't no snitch and I ain't no bitch.
I ain't got to tell you shit.
You are just talking yourself
into a hole.
- Take my cuffs off. I'll kick your ass!
- Really...?
Will you shut up? Shut up!
I ain't did shit, man.
All right, that's it! That's it!
Let's take this sucker
to the station, partner, huh?
Harbor Division Substation.
Crooked-ass police.
I'm gonna call Johnnie Cochran,
Chemical Ali, Robert Shapiro.
One of them.
Wait till I call my mama.
It's gonna be whack, man...
What is this, man?
This is Harbor Division, son.
Nice, quiet place.
We can reason together.
Here we are.
Harbor Division.
This don't look like
no police station.
- Get him out of the car!
- My pleasure.
- Get him out.
- This don't look like no...
- Get out.
- This ain't no police station.
Yeah, this is a special station
for special assholes.
Hey! Not again.
- Come back here. Come on.
- Goddamn!
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay. You?
Okay.
Any opportunity, right?
Somebody doesn't like you.
You're no fun to be around!
- You all right?
- Somebody wants you dead.
- He okay?
- He's okay, he just pissed his pants.
- I wanna talk to my mama.
- You're the man.
You got nothing on my boy.
We've got a puddle of piss
at the crime scene...
...and your son has a weak bladder.
- And what does that mean?
That means we take your son to the
station, we ask him what he saw.
He answers,
we book him into custody, he lives.
He doesn't, we let him go, he dies!
He didn't do it.
And he ain't getting involved.
All right, uncuff him.
Let the jackals hunt him down.
- Man, what I'm talking about...
- Hey, stop, stop.
Stop.
The young men that got shot...
...all were rappers since they were
little boys on the street corner.
And they all wanted to be with
Antoine Sartain and Sartain Records.
That was their Motown.
- I don't get the music.
- You ain't supposed to.
After a few albums,
they want to go out on their own.
They find out the producer's
keeping all the money.
The way it's always gonna be
in the music business.
Sartain goes to the joint
for a while.
Klepto, the first to rebel,
tells Sartain:
"I'm gonna hire a lawyer...
...to get out of my contract
I signed in high school."
Sartain get out of jail.
You know what happened next.
You telling me Sartain
had his own groups killed...
...because they wanted
to go on their own?
Makes a powerful statement...
...to anybody thinking
about breaking a contract.
Don't it?
I told you what the picture
looks like.
You have to put the pieces together
your own self.
We'll take care of your son
for you, ma'am.
Antoine Sartain. He was a busy guy
in the gangster network.
Had a lot of contacts on the outside.
The music guy, right?
Big time.
He was smooth,
but he was a psycho.
The guy was wired.
He had this attitude, like
he could get anything he wanted.
Any contacts, friends?
A white dude came to visit him
every week he was here.
For a whole year without fail.
- Got a name?
- Yeah.
What was the name
of the white dude?
He came to visit Sartain every week.
Wasley. Leroy Wasley.
Leroy Wasley?
"Officer Calden and his partner,
Officer Leroy Wasley...
...working undercover cocaine buy.
A standoff developed.
Suspect demanded to see the cash.
Calden demanded to see the cocaine.
Officer Calden was shot twice
in the chest.
Suspect got away with $100,000.
Some suspicion that Officer Wasley...
...may be involved
with the drug dealers."
If the feds thought
Wasley was dirty...
...why would they let him back up
my dad on a deal?
Because they couldn't prove it,
I guess.
"After an exhaustive
four-month investigation...
...the case against Officer Wasley
was dropped...
...due to a lack of evidence."
Joe, I want to kill him.
Easy. Easy.
There's a real can of worms here.
"Wasley wasn't the only backup.
There were three uniformed officers
in the alley.
Two of them took off
after the suspect.
One of them...
...came into the room to find out..."
Oh, my God!
Look at this name.
Bernard Macko.
- Bennie Macko?
- Bennie Macko.
Wasley and Macko.
Macko and Wasley.
Something's going on here.
Oh, God. I gotta be somewhere.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm good. Go ahead.
Take it easy.
Hey, Rubes.
Look, IA's on my ass.
Grab some takeout,
meet me at Mt. Olympus.
I don't want to go to the house.
Rube?
Ruby, where are you?
Oh, dear.
Detective, you found me.
You're under arrest, young lady.
Please don't put the cuffs on me.
You have the right to remain silent.
You understand?
Gavilan with Marty Wheeler, attorney
from the music business. Sleazeball.
Here's Gavilan drinking on duty.
We've got photos, date, time-stamped.
This is not criminal.
I need criminal shit.
Well, boss, this may not be
criminal shit, but...
- What is this?
- "Nice house."
You think so?
That's Gavilan's house.
That's his front porch.
It's a classic...
...whose time hasn't come.
And her car was there all night.
Where is he now?
We lost him.
Where's she?
This is a very romantic idea.
- You're a stud.
- No.
My partner's a stud.
But I've got a few...
...veteran moves.
If I take my ginkgo...
...I can still remember
where I put the Viagra.
You really like this house?
I'll offer you 675
and not a penny more.
Collateral?
You're looking at it.
Sgt. Gavilan,
we're taking you downtown.
What a night.
Just one question, asshole.
Why me?
You got no probable cause.
- I'm a good cop.
- Yeah.
You have the right to remain silent.
Here we go, Joe.
You have the right to have an
attorney during questioning.
- You understand?
- Yes.
I do understand the rights
you've explained to me.
But you know what,
I'm not gonna remain silent...
...and I do not need an attorney
because this is all bullshit!
And you can put that on the record!
There's absolutely no need
to take your tie off...
...during questioning, Mr. Calden.
Why's he taking his shoes off?
- I've got questions for you.
- Questions for me.
I got questions for you.
My first is:
How does a lightweight, needle-dick
pencil pusher get assigned to IA?
Oh, he's up on the table.
- What is he doing?
- He's on the table.
This conversation's being recorded.
This will reflect very badly...
Excuse me.
Gavilan.
What, he's got a phone?
Jerry! Slow down, Jerry.
- Excuse me!
- I'm busy here.
Okay. He's "oming."
There are some discrepancies
with your income and your spending.
You mean, like, I'm spending
more than I'm making?
Is that news?
Keep talking.
I think he's centering.
He's finding his center.
Gavilan.
What the...? What is this?
Julius, calm down, Julius.
It's not over.
Julius, it's never over.
Get him off the phone!
Guys?
Gavilan. Cleo.
- Police business.
- "Joe?"
I can't talk.
I'll call you back later, all right?
Gavilan.
Hey, Ruby.
What is going on in...?
Muscles, man. I mean, that's...
Make him talk!
I have got the most intense
compression of the L4 and L5.
We have allegations
of commingling of funds.
I've been told that some yoga
and some massage is really...
Oh, yoga, yoga, yoga.
That's great.
You can't hold out for 7.
Jerry, 7...
That's great!
I think that's enough. I'm sorry.
We're that close, Jerry.
Jerry?
That looks really hard.
His position.
His position looks really hard...
He's not even...
He's not even talking, is he?
...to do.
A tree?
Now he's a tree?
This is a setup.
And it will not hold up!
I'm sure Gavilan is
next door right now...
...maintaining complete
professional integrity.
And you know it!
What the hell is going on?
Did you say anything in there?
- Of course not. You?
- My phone wouldn't stop ringing.
Joe, K.C.!
This is insane.
Can you figure this out?
No!
But I played my last card buying you
a couple of hours, so you figure it out!
What did you want
to talk to me about?
- I like you, Joe.
- Don't bullshit me.
You didn't talk to Vice,
so I made a deal with them.
- What are you talking about?
- They agreed to back off...
...if I agree to testify.
- Testify against whom?
- You.
I was approached by Lt. Macko.
Said he heard that you and I
were involved sexually.
And maybe you and some of my girls
had, you know, relationships.
The kid too.
I don't know what you did
to piss Macko off...
...but he cut me a deal
and I took it.
And you're telling me this
because you like me, huh?
Yeah, Joe.
I thought you should know.
Fuck! Bitch!
- Gavilan.
- "Joe, listen".
Bennie's going to the DA right now,
not even waiting.
And the stakeout at Sartain's house
says he hasn't been seen in 24 hours.
And he hasn't been
at Sartain Records.
Thanks.
- What?
- This guy, Sartain.
I don't even know where to find him.
Wait a second.
I got one idea.
Hey, Rube.
You ever done any psychic work
for the police?
You gonna be home
for the next half-hour? Great.
What are you laughing at?
- It's gonna work.
- This is ridiculous.
Joe, be quiet, please.
What are you doing?
I'm getting centered,
and if you don't leave me alone...
Leave her alone for a second.
Flip a coin, make some shit up.
I don't care.
Sorry.
Continue, please.
There's a house on Sunset Plaza.
Yes?
But nobody's there.
Okay.
We must move quickly.
Move quickly.
- Turn right.
- Right?
I see Rodeo Drive.
- What happened to Sunset Plaza?
- Give her a break, Joe.
We're getting close.
Hold on, hold on. We're here.
- Here?
- Here, yeah.
- Okay.
- Here?
We're here.
Here.
- Thank you.
- In here.
- You sure?
Shut up.
- Welcome to Beverly Hills...
- I am not in the mood.
That would look so great on me.
Ruby! How nice to see you!
I love that. How much is it?
- Don't worry.
- That is cute.
She's shopping.
Let her shop.
We have it in black and purple.
I'm out of here.
Goddamn it, Joe!
- Do you have that in size 2?
- Yes, we do. But we also have...
This is ridiculous.
You gotta give her some space.
We got nothing else to go on.
- Sartain! Right there in the black SUV!
- Get the car!
Go!
Move it!
- Keys.
- Yeah, they're in there.
Hey! Hey!
- Come on!
- Hey, stop!
Stop, damn it!
- You owe me $10.
- I'll give it to you later.
Hey, stop!
Stop, goddamn it!
- Go! Go!
- You good?
I'm going!
Don't speed. You're in Beverly Hills.
Goddamn it, I don't want a ticket!
- Here we are.
- There he is!
- Jesus. Don't do this.
- Out of the way!
- This is...
Okay. Get out of the way!
That's him, Danny.
Right here. Turn!
- Out of the car!
- Easy, boss.
- Get out of the car!
- Hey, I quit!
Damn it!
Joe, you all right?
Son of a bitch!
Come on! Go! Go!
Stay with him.
I am not going back to prison
on this bullshit!
- Get out of the way!
- Jesus Christ. Stop!
- Police! Get out! Move the truck!
- Get out of the way!
Move it!
- God.
- Jesus Christ!
If it's not one thing,
it's another.
This is Gavilan.
In pursuit of possible 187 suspects.
Black Escalade, eastbound on Sunset.
While flying over the Hollywood
Freeway, we hear about a chase...
... on Sunset Boulevard.
If you're driving in Hollywood
heading to Mid-Wilshire...
... and Beverly Hills,
I suggest you stay away.
The police need you
out of the area.
- Get down!
- Watch!
- Gavilan.
- Are you okay?
Yeah. Honey, we had to go.
That guy showed up across the street.
There...
I know.
- Look, I gotta go. I'll talk to you soon.
- Take care.
We got two more black
and whites on the chase.
In pursuit of a silver Mustang,
black Escalade, Sunset Boulevard.
Doing about 50 miles an hour.
Who are they chasing,
me or them?
Both of us now!
You just committed three felonies!
Twice!
Gavilan. Yeah, Jerry.
No, I can talk.
Six... You'll take 6.9 now?
I don't know, it might be too late.
I'll make a call.
No. Go, go! Cut over!
Get out of the way!
Sorry.
Let me know when you're back
on the street.
Don't worry.
Air Six, be advised,
we're getting crowded up here.
A lot of choppers in the sky.
It is not just crazy in the streets.
It is crazy up in the air.
We have one, two, three.
I see Vera, Jennifer, York.
I see Lauren, Vera.
- Get a deal on that house yet?
- Dicking me around, but I'm on it.
Get out of the way!
- Get out...
- Watch!
I'm watching! I'm watching!
Julius, he says he'll take 6.9 now.
That's what he says.
Let me make a call. Bye.
- Get out!
- Watch! Get off Sunset!
- Go! Go!
- I got them.
Is that Joe Gavilan?
They'll try to travel
up to Hollywood Boulevard...
...where a huge crowd is in front of
Grauman's Chinese Theatre.
I don't know what's going on there,
but this is a very dangerous situation.
We'll honor him in one of the most
famous traditions here in Hollywood.
Watch it!
Goddamn it! Idiot!
That's it! I'm driving! That's it!
All right. Fine!
You think you can do better?
Go ahead. Be my guest!
- Damn it! You're trying to kill me! Idiot!
- Come on! Go!
- Kill me.
- Go ahead.
This is a tradition
that started back in 1927...
...when a little dog named Zorro...
Yeah, this is much better. Thank you.
...jumped out of Mary Pickford's car...
...into wet cement.
- Nice driving.
- Sorry.
The Mustang was hit by the Escalade
and this chase came to a halt...
... in front of Grauman's Theatre...
... where someone was getting
their star.
I got Wasley!
Get out of the way!
Get down! Get out of the way!
Police! Police! Stay down!
Mayhem is breaking out,
resulting in a foot pursuit.
They're running
down Hollywood Blvd.
They've got their weapons drawn.
"We've"...
People are scrambling out of the way.
Everyone's running. It's a mess.
Excuse me. Sorry. Excuse me.
Look out down there!
Holy shit!
Oh, God!
That was not the way I planned it.
I'm a cop. Help me up.
Thank you.
I'm okay. I'm all right. Thank you.
Hey, move, move. Move!
Hey! Get out of the way! Police!
- Get out!
- Hey, stop!
Hey!
Stop!
Shit! Hey, police.
Get out of your car.
- What the hell?
- I need your car.
- I'll get it back to you.
- My family's...
Hey, come on!
Police! Somebody help me!
Watch out! Police!
Get out of the way!
Police!
You need to slow down.
I can't slow down, ma'am. I'm sorry.
I'm chasing this guy here.
- It's kind of fun, huh?
- No, it's not!
We're gonna die.
I know we're going to die.
Yes, actually. We will die.
- No, you're not gonna die.
- I don't mean right now.
Hey! Get out of the car! Police!
Police! Get out... Hey!
- Hey, look! Come on!
- Get out of here!
- Hey! That's mine!
- Give me that!
- Bitch!
- Asshole!
Move! Police! Move!
Move over!
Goddamn it! You all right?
Watch out! Move! Move! Move!
Hey, kids,
Hindus say that life is a rebirth.
Ganesh had his head chopped off.
They put an elephant's head
on and he lived forever.
- You're crazy!
- Kids, listen to me.
It's not a bad thing
if we do die, all right?
- Get out of the cab!
- This is my cab!
My cab! My cab!
No, man, it's my cab. It's my cab!
- Get in the car!
- Police! Police!
I am the police!
For chrissake, get in the cab!
Move! Move!
If you wreck my cab, the city...
Don't worry. Sit back.
I'm a very good driver.
I don't want to die!
We're not gonna die, all right?
Shut up, okay? Please!
Oh, my God!
Wait a minute, man.
Where's my fare?
- How much?
- Ten dollars.
Ten dollars. Ten dollars.
There's a tip!
Move! Move! Move!
Hey! Hey!
Hey, cop. What about 6.75?
- I don't think that'll do it!
- Not a penny more!
Get down! Get down!
Get the hell down!
Get up! In front of the door!
Get in front of the frigging door!
Come on, come on,
come on, come on!
What are you doing?
Jerry, I've just been with Julius.
I've twisted his arm.
I have a firm offer for 6.75.
Yes, sir, 6.75. Firm.
- You will? You will?
- Oh, God.
You will?
That's fantastic.
I'll start the paperwork in the morning,
soon as I get to the office, okay?
I've gotta run now.
Thank you very much.
I'm a real-estate broker.
Hey.
Yeah, he needs a pop-out trailer,
cook, driver...
...trainer with a gym that travels,
dog walker, hair and makeup guys.
I'll fax you the rest of the perks.
- Don't shoot me, man.
- Don't shoot?
Don't shoot me.
Don't shoot, Wasley.
- Please, don't shoot me.
- Please?
Are you shitting me? Please?
You're not going to beg.
- I'm begging. Please!
- Jesus Christ.
H2O didn't beg. They screamed
and hollered. They didn't beg.
And fat-ass Klepto ran a couple yards.
You can run.
I don't even want to be a cop anymore.
I want to quit.
I won't tell anybody about this,
I swear to God. Please, don't kill me!
I don't want to die, okay?
But my father...
My father was your partner!
Just please, God, don't shoot me!
Please!
Shut up.
Don't talk about your father.
Your daddy didn't beg
when he got shot.
- He was a good cop.
- Please, don't shoot.
Don't do it!
Don't do it, Wasley. Don't!
That was a great performance.
Good enough to be
at least a Golden Globe.
I don't know about an Academy Award,
but a Golden Globe.
I believed it myself.
I mean, all the, "Don't kill me, man.
Don't freaking kill me."
I liked where you talked
about killing my father.
But it's okay.
'Cause I got it all right here.
See that?
Your confession and my performance,
all on one tape.
That will sell great.
Air Six, suspects are on the roof
of the old Broadway Building.
Shots have been fired.
Air Six, get on the horn and get
these news choppers out of here.
I can't work, I need orbit room.
Move them back.
He's telling us to get out of the way.
But we're not moving.
We're not.
L.A.P.D. Is trying to kick us
out of here.
We don't know who the good guy,
who the bad guy is.
I've never seen such drama
in Hollywood before.
We're on the roof.
Where is he?
- You want me to get him out?
- Leave him for the coroner.
- Where's the kid?
- Down that way.
You okay?
- Yeah. You?
- Don't I look okay?
Where's Sartain?
And Wasley?
Good job.
Good thing you didn't kill him.
You know me.
I don't like dead bodies.
I got arrest warrants
for Gavilan and Calden.
Hey, separate them!
I don't want them talking to anybody
until they get downtown.
Shut up and turn around, Bennie.
- What?
- Cuff him. Take him downtown.
What are you talking about?
Get your hands off me, son of a bitch!
You're making a big mistake, pal.
- You can kiss your career goodbye.
- Good.
Call my lawyer.
Great job.
You don't have to come tomorrow
if you don't feel up to it.
I said I would be there tomorrow night.
I'll be there, all right?
All right.
Damn it!
Drunk, drunk, animal thing, you!
Will all of you please
get out of here?
If you lay one hand on me...
- My sister's having a baby.
- This is so wrong. Get him out of here.
Let go of me, you sons of bitches!
Get him in bed,
put a cold towel on his head.
Some coffee would do him good
right now.
- Let's get him into the shower.
- Let go of me, you sons of bitches!
Take it easy.
- Let's get out of here.
- Poker should not be played...
...in a house with women!
Baby.
Eunice, I want my baby girl down here.
I'm just going to keep on calling,
if you...
Hey.
Stella!
Quit howling out there.
Go back to bed!
Eunice, send my baby girl down here!
She ain't coming down till you quit
or they'll set the law on you.
- Come here.
- You can't beat up a girl...
...and expect her to come back!
- You suck.
Sit down.
Have some respect
or I'll kick your ass.
Stella, come down here, baby.
- Like they did last time.
- Eunice, send my baby girl down here.
Yeah. It's Calden.
- Gavilan.
- Yeah. I'll be there in 15.
West of Coldwater?
I can be there in 10.
Stella. Oh, baby,
don't ever leave me again.
- Hey, officer, help me out?
- Yeah.
- What's going on?
- Looks like you got a 187.
- Possible 927D.
- Thanks a lot.
He says we have a body and a half
with some pieces missing.
An Easter egg hunt.
You were pretty good in that play.
You really were.
You think so?
Yeah.
I don't know if I'm much of an actor.
- I think I'm just a cop.
- What do you mean, just a cop?
You really thought I was good?
Hey, I already said you were good.
Don't go begging me.
Looks like we'll be here a while.
Let's get going on some chow, huh?
Cheeseburger, well-done,
onion, pickle, no mayo.
- No rabbit food, okay?
- I'll have the same.