You complain to the police
Same policemen gave your number and address
Now, we seen your house
Come and see my house now
What is all this?
Aunty. . .they are?
Taking her away.
lF you over react
We will take you along !
lt's not my experience!
Please take me
Listen to me carefully
Have you ever sit in an expensive
import car.
No- not at all !
Please go away!
You sit comfortable. . .they will drop
you at the gate!
Aunty,who is going to stop us!
He has courage!
Hello. . .Jai
Jai ho
Jai. . .hey, idiot go from the footpath !
You bloody bastard !
Bastard !
Run
Call more men off our's!
Call al-qaida
The old hag !
Scoundrel's will you kill me!
Mother it was a mistake
Please pardon me!
Sister we are sorry
Please pardon us
Your parent's should have beaten
you guy's in childhood !
Who is yourfather?
He is a very powerfull man !
Pandit. . .siryou sit!
Why are you here!
l came to settle your marrige proposal
Are you making fun of my mother!
She is a lady
How can i make fun on her!
Mother he want's to abuse me!
Jai
Jai, don't fight with the priest!
l think your horoscope is surely
written in my destiny!
Who is going to hit me!
These photograph's look's so beautiful
Are you interested
Remove it yourself!
Mother he called you a coward !
Why are you hitting me!
You lied to me you are going college
But rather prefer been with him !
Yes. . .because i don't wan't to
Answeryour horrible question's
Who is that guy
Jai you say something !
Geetha is out burst
Mother became emotional
Do not argue with mother!
Your marriage must be succesful
Your children must be healthy
And yourjob must be successful
Romance must be good?
As long as you live happily
Mother will offer her blessing's!
Thank you
Thank you mother
Mother and thank you
Wait. . .what is this nonsence!
Jai come
Let us go mother!
Congradulation's
What are they thinking
Am i rightjai
l, decided whomjai must marry
Thank you small boy
How are you brother
l am fine!
Respect it's indian culture!
Our rule's we can'not follow
without teacher's permission !
When he is big
He will break the record !
Wait a minute
Jai
Yes madam !
She is suman !
Someone was to help her
But did not come
Can you help her!
She is my history teacher
Help her out brother!
Ok!
Were are you going
lt's a short cut
ls,deepak in your standard
Yes
Why! were you giving him lesson's.
He alway's make's excuse's
Mr's, what isjai doing at girl's class
Have a look foryourself!
She is very intellegent
Alway's come's out first!
She will create a misary in her life!
Mr's can i have a paper and pen !
Jai,what is this?
Your sister gave this to you !
500rupees
Why,do you canteen people rob us!
Now, i understand why. . .middle
class family don't go out!
Why are you so moody!
My next door neighbour
made my life a misary!
She, always yell at me everyday!
Brother, one day i was in the shower
shejust open the door!
When you were in the shower
Did you have a cold or warm water bath !
Don't be silly
That is a silly question !
Uncle i want to go washroom
Uncle let us go
l have a very hard pee!
Aunty is wearing same colour underwear
Brotherthis is my horrible
neighbour. . .now i shall see
Suman
What happen
Mam, my brother was suppose
to come and right my exam's
Ohh,what is his number?
Hello! brother were are you !
l'm stuck in the traffic!
l'M on the way
Few minute's ill be there!
Sumanjust few minute's left
forthe exam's
Sir! . . .why so long
Uncle
What happen?
Someone has blocked the road
Suman
Her brother was suppose to right exam
But he stuck in traffic
Help her other wise she will miss
her paper. . .
Don't fear
lll come now!
Jai is also in traffic
Sir, please do something
My sister's exam
She is handicap
Please i request you !
Let me see what i can do?
Please madam help me
l am very sorry
Have you receive any new's
Police uncle we are late for school
Relax
Don't stress
Sir we held the traffic
for long
Ambulance and the school bus
And the other man is going
to right his sister's exam
Everyone is tensed !
Look at the minister's daughter so happy
Suman
Uncle can you help me to right my exam
No one is here to be at my shop
Please help me!
Suman wake up!
Can someone help me
Call a ambulance
Suman what have you done!
Suman so sorry!
She is very hard in working
And also very intellegent!
She don't think of herself weak!
She alway's come's first.
One day she will bring magic
lnspector i want to f.i.r a complain
Kavitha singh patel
Home minister's daughter
Do you no what you are doing?
What are you doing?
Who's child is this
lt's mine
Thank the man above you found
your child !
Jai you done a greatjob!
lf you guy's think we done a favour
Do not thank
lnstead help three of my mate's
And tell those three people help
anotherthree!
Son i don't understand you !
Hold onto this
l guess you help the country
Son this a big idea
We surely can help three people!
A brilliant idea
On a small complain
They must understand us
He think's diffarent
Jai i'm very proud of you
Takecare!
Yes. . . .she is gone to market!
Come over here and wait!
Hmmm, what a body!
Come
Geetha and me are family friend's
Sit down. . .ill bring cup of tea foryou.
My pinky is good in gujrathy
He woo's my pinky
Sit down
Now listen to my english
l must attend an interview
Why is this leg so heavy!
Look behind you
Masala tea
Jai
What are you doing here!
What is this
Jai
You. . .do you know her!
Come on
Kabbir is waiting !
Geetha, what your brother's occupation
He was in the army!
Mother he is scared !
l was not afraid to leave with my brother!
lt's his bravery and courage
There are children captured !
This is high commander order
Jai was suspeneded dew to high order's
Sorry sister
Been in the army
He help's the counrty alot
His a good man
What can i tell you sister
l can't think how a man can
speak so valgue language!
He spoke about simran's body
Please
We wanted to complain to police
But we decided to come here first!
This is him calling !
Brother, i am not from china
l am from nepal !
Nepal is behind that mountain !
Find out were this number
is calling from
l think it's your brother's voice!
Your work is done?
He alway's sit here!
Uncle, is there anyone with you?
lt's late night go home!
Uncle, don't mension thank's!
ls this your house!
You bring me to the right place!
After marrige it will be handy
Ashok sir, what do you have to say!
We must not bring harm to
ordinary people!
Even thou the president's are human's
He is very positive man !
Jai shake my hand's!
Jai's formular
Come and eat
The food is ready
He donated his eye's
lt seem's he will gain light
l want to tell you something !
Jai you must promise me!
Why must i chill. . .
l recently got married
And i was busy
When i have the time
l will help?
Everyone is in there own beat
l have seen the world
l will speak directly
Guy's must be carefull
Nothing is going to happen
The entire world is corrupt
Why don't you begin
Perhaps you will gainjoy
Nonsense
Sorry sir
Should not have spoken to you
Apolagise to you
JAi we will try harder
Sir i am very hungry
Please spare me some food !
Go away from here!
l won't spare you
She is my child !
Why is his mood switch off!
He faught with a man
What happen
Jai
Very disturb
A girl commit's suicide infront off me!
A kidnap child
l had to find
A poverty girl begs on the street
How far can i escape reality
Why is this happening to me!
Jai everyone notice it
Others walk away from it
l have trust in you
We also have trustjai
Drink is like poison
School is far away
Had to walk
Were are you darling
Mum i love this place!
What have you ate when you gave birth
l will call you later
He came with his family to wonderland
Mamoo afterthat day you like pink colour!
What song is this!
Kabbir it's yourtution time!
Where is he?
You had came late
He is gone
You said he is with his family!
They are inside!
Everyone out
Call your brother?
Jai
Hold onto him
Bastard
Who is this man
What happen
We came to help madev
With ten men
Only three left
Brother he is alone!
What was that noise!
His an animal !
You go home!
Who are you?
My brother is not a goon
He served his country
We don't like him to be behind bar's
But he broken the rule's
Send him out
Keep quite
Why have you broken my
men hand
Now my men will break you
What went wrong
You think and ordinary man is stupid
A common man is stupid
And ordinary common man is a tiger!
Don't interfear when it's awake!
Brother
Father what ever he done to brother
He should be paid by death
People like him must beg
for his life!
Look at my dog
Going to delhi fortwo day's
When i return
Brother what happen to father
So much happen and his quite
Brother whom open and f.i.r against you
Think what is going to happen
to thatjai
Hello,can i speak to geetha
Sister is not at home!
Won't you want to speak to me!
When are you going to meet me!
Half an hour's time
Who has call
Wrong number sister
Were is my black dress
lsn't it loose
But you like black
Are you happy
Are you comfortable with the dress
Your rascal
Why did you steel my clothe's
Pink and now black
Why do you want to woo my mamoo
Mamoo she will trap you
ls this your clothe's
That is why she is so comfortable
Mamoo if you was not here
l should have removed her clothe's
Don't want to spoil your setting?
She strech my t-shirt
ls it your's
No
You like black
Priest what kind of photo's
you are showing me!
l will get him married in ten day's
Granny he isjoking
He did not marry himself
Priest you said to me you are married
And you have two kid's
They are mine
We are devorce
lt was my mistake
When i got home
Press the bell
He can't handle his own wife
How can he get mamoo married
Hit him with this bat
Granny don't interfear
with this priest
Mamoo found a girl
what
How is she
Grandma there she is
She is very beautiful
Do your mother no her
She our neighbour
She is a witch
Grandma let us meet your
daughter-in-law
Do you like my son
lf yes. . .stay away from her
Ask her how far can we go
She is serious
lnternal bleeding
From you both whose blood with match
Mother
Congradulation's
Afamily member kidney match's
You. . .no mother
ls it rehan
Both our kidney's did not mach
But rehan's match
l wasjust selfish
Stayed away from my family
Everything will be fine
We will now live as a happy family
With love andjoy
Live as a happy family
And forget the past
What are you doing overthere
come here
Please forgive me that day
She refused to donate her kidney
to you
Heard you mother survived
Who is speaking
Kavith patel
Your mother was not involve in accident
i bumped her out
What are you going to do?
What do you think off yourself
You are not in the army
You cannot fight this battle alone
Were with this lead us to
Stop all this
Jai
Mother has came back into my life
Forget about your battle
Dought he came to apolagise
We came to solve the issue
Please pardon us
My eyesight is weak
Can you come foward
Stop!
Look at him i turn him into a dog
Are you happy
No father
How he ruine the reputation
on your son-in-law
Before you fight with my family
You should no whom you fighting with
Ajudge wanted to go against me
And we sent him off
When i was defense minister
Hey spare him
There is no aim to this
With people like you
Our country become's bad
My sister doesn't speak lies
Tomorrow l won't come
l've got to perform some
duties elsewhere
Meaning?
Meaning ! What can l say?
Tomorrow l won't be driving
Somebody else will be doing the work
Why won't you be driving the taxi?
l want to get addmission in
a good college for my daughter
How much money do you need?
leave it. . .
-No no tell me
How much of money you want?
-Too much
one minute
theres 7000. . take it. . .
and put your daughter in a good college. . .
if its with me
then. . .
thank you. .
-Don't say thank you
when you have the chance
then you help 3 people
and tell those 3 people
the must help 3 people each
You wrong Singh saab
You want to teach me
whats right and whats wrong?
We need to finish of
Jai's family
There wedding is sorted out. . .Now only
Jai's wedding is left then l'll relax in Bangkok
Small rat. . .
ls anyone at home?
No pink panther
-You very happy. . Who's getting married
not wedding. . .
engagement
Who is he talking too?
-Dummy phone call
What did you say?
Engagement. . Your uncle
he didn't give you a card?
very bad
l'm playing games with you. .
-l tought my game was over. .
give the phone to your uncle
Why did you lie?
-What lie. . Mamoo and uncle is the same
madam. . . change
-Keep it
Dont say thank you help 3 people
and ask them to help 3 other people
you go roaming sing and dancing
What are you looking at?
with me. . .
And get engaged to someone else
What happened?
-Somebody took Kabir away
-What?
-Where is Jai?
Where is Jai?
Hey don't come any closer. . .
don't come closer
What am l hearing?
Whats the situation?
The ministers son in law
was killed
contact Jai Agnihotri
-Yes sir
l want you to listen
to a short story
l got shocked with the mike
check if the child is okay?
Are you okay child?
-Yes
Are you okay?
-Yes Sir
You didn't get shocked?
l won't get shocked
my hand is artificial. . .
Don't say thank you Sir. . . Help 3 people
and ask them to help 3 other people
Where did you learn such
a nice thing
One day a nice aunty came
to a school function
Don't say thank you. . . but help 3 people
and tell them to help 3 other people
l promise that l will help 3 people
and ask them to help 3 other people
Sir . . .
l've found Jai Agnihotri's number
Phone him
-Yes
Can l speak with Jai Agnihotri?
The minister would
like to speak to you
Look Jai l know all that happened
between you and Singhsaabs son in law
Everyone knows who is wrong. . .
but you have to end this. . .
l've spoken to Singhsaab
and told him that l will bring you
No sir - This 1 time l refuse
Jai . . . Alone what can you do?
Jai we will meet this evening
-Yes Sir
Jai let me speak to Singhsaab
l'll meet you outside
What is this madness?
-lts not madness. . .
lts a prediction because you
are not gonna leave here alive
CM saab brought Jai here
it got out of control. . .
Afterthat Jai kidnapped the CM and
ran away from here. . .
My workers ran behind
to try to rescue the CM. . .
One by one he hit all of them
Look what he did to me. . .
He is speaking lies. . .
No one must know about this
Don't open the doors
his situation is getting bad
you go!
l'll show these scums
You go!
Come on. .
-You go now!
get out of the way. . .
move aside . . move aside. .
-What happened?
-The CM has reached City Hospital
What Happened Sumeet?
Where is Jai?
Look. . . Whatever is being said
about my brother is all lies. . .
my brother is a good man. . .
All he wanted was to help the people. . .
By starting a chain of not saying thank you. . .
but helping 3 people instead. . .
And those must help another 3 people. . .
this aunty said the samething that
the nice aunty had told me in school. . .
instead of thankyou help 3 people
and ask them to help 3 people. . .
Are you watching T.V.?
-Yes. . What is all this?
Don't spare him
. . .get him !
take him away. . .
Look. . . Whatever is being said
about my brother is all lies. . .
All he wanted was to help the people. . .
By starting a chain of not saying thank you. . .
but helping 3 people in need
and asking them to help 3 other people . . .
And if l am okay. . .
it is only because ofJai Agnihotri. . .
But what about what home minister
Dashrat Singh said about Jai. . .?
Dashrat Singh is a liar. . .
lt is all his fault. . .
Dashrat Singh tried to kill me
and put the blame on Jai. . .
lf there is a terrorist. . .
lts Dasrat Singh. . .
Not Jai Agnihotri
Save me. . .
Don't say thank you. . .
help 3 people who are in need. . .
and ask them to help
another 3 in need. . .
what you dreamed about
has touched many hearts
Do you want to see how many?