[Fingers Snapping]
Ooh ooh-ooh-ooh
Travellin'at the speed
Oflove
Doo doo doo-doo
Hey, yo, kids
What's up?
Remember when I used
to be dope
Yeah.!
I owned a pocketful of fame
Well, look what
you're doin'now.!
Now I know
Well, I know
I lost touch with reality
Now my personality is
an unwanted commodity
Believe it.!
Can't believe I used to be
Mr. Steve Austin on the mike
Six million ways
you used to run it.!
I guess Oscar Goldman got mad
'Cause I got loose circuits
So loose, so loose.
I be the Mother Goose with
the eggs that seem to be
Fallin; fallin; fallin
You played yourself
Doo doo doo-doo
Hey, yo, pack my bags
'cause I'm outta here
Mama don't love me
and my mama don't care
Read the papers
The headlines say
Washed-up rapper got a song
[Imitating Chicken Clucking]
Lingo's busted
while the guitar sways
B side copy for the radio
plays for somethin'
I knew I blew
the whole fandango
When the drum programmer
wore a tango
Never could be liked
Great fish won't bite
They realize
that I'm over like clover
No good luck and so Mace
beat the f... - in'beat
Hey.!
While the teenage
fan the heat
I bring it to the clues
Paid all my dues
So what's gone dead
Let me use my forehead
Easy, pack it up, man
Let me stop stallin'
'Cause everything I do is like fallin'
Fallin; fallin'
You played yourself
Doo doo doo-doo
[Woman]
Hey, Pooh Bear.
You played yourself
Doo doo doo-doo
Ahh!
A-boo! A-boo!
[Baby Squealing]
You played yourself
Doo doo doo-doo
Hey. Hey, you.
Hey, why don't you call Peggy?
She can come over
and watch TVwith you.
That, uh, that show that
you like is on tonight, isn't it? Um...
Hey! Hey, cutie.
What's the name of it?
Um...
Aw, come on, Linda.
You're making me feel
very guilty here.
Look, it's just gonna be
for a couple of hours.
I deserve this. I haven't
been out of the house
for over three months.
Three months.
Gee, that's probably exactly
how long it's been...
since I've been out.
[Dog Barking]
Looks like Mike almost
has his date for tonight.
'Cause I'm so studly.
Yeah.
Yeah?
Linda. [Chuckling]
Nobody is taking dates.
It's a bunch of guys going
to a boxing match. That's it.
What?
Wh... Why are you lookin'
at me like that?
'Cause I know your friends.
They have the hormones
of high school kids.
Don't start accusin' me
of runnin' around.
You're the only one
who has a family.
It's time you start hangin' out with
grown-ups.
My friends are grown-ups.
Oh. Sorry.
[Man On P.A. System]
If you look out of the starboard side...
- What the hell is that?
- the aging but potentially dangerous...
Mr. Frank Wyatt.!
Not since the turn of the century
has he come and vacationed with us.
Let's dust him off and give him
a big round of applause.
Oh!
- Here's one of your grown-up friends now.
- I gotta go.
Go. Go and have some fun.
[Man On P.A. System
Continues, Indistinct]
Maybe you'll stop walkin' around
with that look on your face.
... schmoozing it up with one
of the great-great-grandchildren...
of the original Chippendale's
dancing squad.!
Say good-bye.
I have no regrets, okay?
Whatever you say.
[Horn]
Bye, gorgeous.
Daddy's gotta go.
[Baby Gurgling]
I love you.
[Man On P.A. System]
Uh, excuse me.
I love you too.
We've got some family values
exhibitions here.
I'll be home early, okay?
That's actually his baby.
Yeah, Linda.
Say, around, uh, 8:00 a.m.
- Let's dust off the toddler
and take him with us.
- Oh.
Thanks. I'm on the couch
tonight for sure.
That's simple, Frank;
she hates me.
She does not hate you.
I've been married
to that woman for two years.
Ah, remember your birthday?
[Humming]
[Laughing]
She hates you.
Hey!
- Let me get rid of these bums,
I'll be back to get on you.
- Promise?
Check it out inside, man.
It's bigger than your house.
Whoo!
Prepare to have your
pleasure glands carpet-bombed.
Watch out for the floors,
'cause they're marble.
Ohh.
You guys.
Wow.
Whoo!
Cool system, man.
Thanks.
[Stereo Blaring]
Don't, uh, touch anything, okay?
[Volume Lowers]
That's not right for you.
And don't put your dirty dogs
on my clean upholstery either.
Ray, where the hell
did you get this thing?
I promoted it.
You what?
I conned the dealer into letting me
take it out for the evening.
Well, how did you do that?
Well, I was driving
past the dealership...
and I was thinking about this
evening, so I go inside and say...
"This baby is perfect for
entertaining clients and I
was thinking about using it...
to buy a few
for my sales force,"
at which time he got
on his hands and knees,
begging me to take it out.
Wait, wait.
Your "sales force," Ray?
Mm-hmm.
I may have some.
And I will.
[Laughing]
Tomorrow I'll return it and say,
"Thank you, but under
very careful consideration...
"I would have to say,
it's not big enough.
"I need a driver's side
air bag in the bathroom.
[Laughing]
And I'll see ya."
Naaah!
Ray Cochran,
the man, the myth.
[Laughing Continues]
Yes, indeed. We're running late.
Where's Eddie?
Eddie canceled at the last minute,
so I invited someone else.
- Who'd you invite?
- [Tires Screeching]
- Hey, no!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Hey, hey, hey.!
[Ray]
Who's the crash test dummy?
[Tires Screeching]
[Frank]
Hmph.!
That's your little brother.
[Laughing]
Ray, don't start. Linda's
been bustin' my balls
since I got home, okay?
Ray, give him
a break, man.
John's a good guy, bro.
He's a g...
He's a pain in the ass!
Every time you guys
get together, man,
it's like a slugfest.
[Frank]
That's not true.
[Ray]
It's not true.
- So he doesn't piss you off
every time you get together.
- He's my brother, I invited him.
[Man]
Hey, Razorman.!
That's cool.
It's nice.
What the hell is this thing?
Just get in.
Looks like
Barbie's Playhouse.
[Ray] You should know, ; you're
the one who plays with dolls.!
Mike, where you been, buddy?
Jesus, look at this thing.
Yo, bro.
My big brother
actually invites me
to go somewhere, huh?
- You sick or somethin', Frank?
- You're late, as usual.
What do ya say,
fight fans?
Crack open some libations,
let's get on the road.
- Beers are in the fridge, John.
- Ooh! Beer!
Doo doo doo-doo
[Ray] Okay, all aboard.!
[Frank]
Ray, that's a conductor,
not a bus driver.
Sit down and shut up.!
Now that's
a bus driver.!
Let me see
your transfer, miss.
[Mike]
When has any of you
been on a bus?
Let me tell you,
I've seen a few...
[All Laughing]
Doo doo doo-doo
[Ray] Yeah, all right.!
I got 600 on Davis. Yeah.
[Mike] What? You idiot.!
Davis rhymes with "save us.!"
[Laughing]
[Frank Laughing]
You should've given
the money to us.!
[Frank]
We're gonna miss the prelim.
[Ray]
The Razorman will not
be letting you down.
I don't intend to miss
one single, solitary punch.
[Ray]
Where did this kid
come from?
Your boy's about to get beat!
What's he doing?
He needs to bob and weave!
Look at that!
Thank God this thing has
a satellite dish, right?
[John] Oh, shit.!
Much better than sitting
ringside, Ray, much better!
Another day in front
of the boob tube.!
[Ray]
We're gonna be so close,
we may get blood on us.
[Frank] Coming out
of our noses, the seats'll
be so high in the rafters.!
[Mike Laughing]
[Ray]
Gimme a break.!
[John]
Oh, shit.! Yeah, yeah, yeah.!
[TVAnnouncer, Indistinct]
Look at him go!
Yeah!
Oh! Oh!
Hit him!
[Mike Yelling, Indistinct]
[Frank]
Yeah.! Hit him.!
- Hell, yeah, look at him go, man!
- [Frank] Hit him, hit him.!
[All Yelling, Indistinct]
See his feet?
His legs are bucklin'.
[Mike] It's over.
[Frank] His manager's outside
bettin'on the other guy.
Hernandez
and that Martinez kid
won't last three rounds.
- We're gonna miss the main event.
- We should just settle in and...
Bullshit. We're not
gonna miss anything.
Just shut that TV off.
- Hey, Ray, take it easy.
- Do you want to make it
to the fight on time or not?
Hmm? All right.
[Announcer]
It's a battle between
the number two...
and number three
middleweights in the world.
Mickey "Mad Dog"Davis...
[Horn Honking]
Oh, shit.
- [Tires Screeching]
- [Mike] Whoa, what are you doin'?
He's not gonna let me in.
- Hey! How about it, huh? Can we get in?
- How about what?
- Can we get over?
- Why don't you wait your turn
like everyone else, asshole?
- Forget it. Hey, stop!
- You gonna let us over?
- [John] No way, man, no way.
- Ray, this guy's not stoppin'.
Back off already.
I'm not gonna back off.
What are you doing?
[Frank] Hey, back off, man.
He's not stoppin;! Look out.!
- [Crash]
- Oh, this guy hit me! He just hit me!
- [Indistinct Yelling]
- [Ray] I don't believe this guy hit me.!
Fuck you!
What are you doin'?
You want some, come on!
Fuck you!
- [Mike] Ding, ding, ding.! Round one.!
- Kick this motherfucker's ass.
Yeah? Let's see something,
you little fuckin' weasel!
Let's see what you got!
Get off me, Frank!
Get off me!
Not tonight, man.
I didn't think so.
I can take
this motherfucker.!
[Frank]
Don't be a jerk.!
What?
- Fuck you!
- Come on, John Boy! I'll beat
the shit outta both of you!
Hey, buddy, back off.
Hey, what's this?
What do ya got...
Aaah! Aah!
Don't!
[Cracking]
Hey! It hurts, huh?
Huh?
[Woman]
Hey.!
- Leave him alone.
- Yeah, relax...
Aaah! Aah!
And take
the pretty girl home...
- unless you want me to, huh?
- [Man Grunting]
Huh? I can't hear you.
I'm sorry. What?
[Grunting] Yeah, all right.
Come on, buddy.
You're not worth it.
Nice job, buddy.
Shut up, man!
[Man]
All right, already, let's go.!
[Man] Way to go, tough guy.!
I can't believe people
in this fuckin' town!
Calm down, honey.
Married life
makin' you soft, Frank?
I remember when your brother
would've dumped that guy
on his ass.
Yeah.
What's the matter with you?
You can't get into it...
with every asshole
that looks at you funny.
There's a lot of craziness
goin' on out there.
You never know what maniac
is gonna blow your goddamn
brains out!
It happens every day
in this city!
You listen to me!
What, Frank?
What are you gonna do?
You're not
my father, Frank.
Way to go, little man.
You showed some heart.
Hey.
What did I say, huh?
You remember what I said?
I know, I'm sorry.
Don't encourage him
with that macho shit.
I'm sorry, Frank.
But he's right, you know.
What are you
talkin' about?
You're not his father, bro.
- That was really smart, baby brother.
- Enough, Ray. All right?
- Stop acting like you're three.
- Why do you always have to
say shit like that?
Hey,
let's knock it off!
I wanna have a good
fuckin' time tonight, all right?
Everybody hold on to somethin'.
We're gettin' outta here.
[Rock]
What the hell
are you doin'?
I tell you something;
I'm not gonna miss this fight.
[Laughing,
Indistinct Talking]
I hate being late!
Wait.! A cop.!
I'm joking.!
[Laughing]
Whoo-hoo.!
Here we go again
Second shot
Lookin'for a bang
with the nice hips
Gotta have a set
of them pink lips
When it comes to sex
[Mike]
Ray's the man.! Do it.!
[Mike Imitating
Barking Seal]
[Music Continues]
Whoo! Come on!
Whoo!
Yes! Yes!
Wha-hoo!
[Yelling,
Indistinct Talking]
[Tires Screech]
[Laughing]
Whoo! Whooooooo!
Oh, my God!
[Ray]
Give it up.! Give it up.!
[Laughing]
I tell you something.
Here's to me and those like me...
'cause very few of them
remain.! [Chuckling]
[Frank] Thank God.!
[Mike] An extraordinary piece
of navigation, my brother.
Thank you, my brother.
[Frank] Do you
have any idea how to
get there from here?
[Ray] We double-back
around the expressway.
How hard can it be?
[Imitates Scary Music]
I bet there's some
tremendous real estate
bargains down here.
That's great, but where's
the damn expressway, huh?
Enough of this scenic route.
[Ray] The guys that built
the expressway did it logically.
We hit the next intersection
and cut over.
[Mike]
I don't see any signs
or anything, Ray.
[Ray] If I can cross over the
one-way street we exited off,
[John And Frank Muttering]
We'll be fine.
[John] We've been around
this block a thousand times.
[Frank] Wait a minute.
[Ray] I don't care. Wejust
gotta cross the one-way street.
[Indistinct Arguing]
[Frank] I know where
we are... we're lost.!
Don't you worry about it.
A little faith, my friends.
We have never been here.
[Mike] Oh, look...
The Brothers Johnson.
[Laughing]
Ray, I'm just bein' logical.
When you're lost,
you ask for directions.
So let's ask those guys.
They look like they know
their way around.
Sure, we'll tell them we're
the Welcome Wagon and we
have baked goods for them.
[On P.A. System]
Excuse me, gentlemen.
We're the Welcome Wagon.
Can you come here for
a minute, please?
Mr. Welcome would like to ask
you something!
[Laughing]
Give me that!
- You know what? That's not funny.
- Ooh, here they come, Ray!
Ooh, here they come.
They're comin' to party!
There they go!
- How are ya?
- Show 'em, man.
Show 'em what you got.
Check it out.
All right. Watch this.
- Oh, shit!
- [Frank] Ray, what the hell are you doin'?
[Man]
Let him have it, Earl.
[Laughing]
- [Laughing]
- How is that funny? Tell me,
'cause I don't get it!
- [Laughing, Indistinct Talking]
- Get us back on the expressway.
- Jesus!
- [Tires Screeching]
[Homeless Men]
Good-bye.!
[Ray] Lock the doors.
[Mike] You got the gun.
Anybody comes through the
door, we blow 'em away.
[Ray]Just lock the doors.
[Frank]
I'll lock the goddamn door.
[Ray] I don't even
know if I'm insured
on this thing.
Whoa, wait.
What?
You really know how
to use this thing, Razor?
Beretta 9mm.
Shit happens, man.
[Chuckling]
You were right, Frank;
you never know what maniac's
gonna pull out a gun.
About the only maniac
I know is you.
Hey, you know what we need?
We need a friggin' map.
Who carries a map?
Thousands of unarmed people
who drive Hyundais
carry maps, Ray.
[Frank]
Now how about getting us
outta here?
I think there's a map
in the glove compartment, man.
Right here?
No, the one right
to the right of it.
Right.
Well... Here it is.
You're a little closer
than I am.
- Oh, hey, hey!
- [Tires Screeching]
[Grunting]
Oh, Jesus.!
Who... What was that?
[Mike] I don't know,
I think we hit somethin;
Maybe a dog or somethin;
No, we didn't.
Ray, I felt it.
I think we hit someone.
You know where the hell we are?
They're scam artists, okay?
- They make a living doing this.
- Doing what, Ray?
Run out into the street,
pretend to get hit
and blow your head off!
Somebody
might be hurt, Ray.
[Ray]
Frank, what are you doin'?
I'm gonna check it out.
What are you... Frank!
You guys doin'
the Mother Teresa show?
Wh... Hey. Hey!
Nothin' down here.
[Panting]
He's dead.
Think again, asshole.
Shit!
Be careful!
Easy, easy, easy.
Come on, don't move.
[Panting]
It's gonna be all right.
- What's happening?
- We hit somebody! Call 9-1-1!
Ohh! Oh, my God.
I don't believe it.
Aah.
[Dialing]
[Ringing]
[Woman] 9-1-1 emergency.
How long did they say
it was gonna be?
The phone's dead, man.
There's no service in this
shithole part of town!
Okay, we gotta get him
to an emergency room.
Oh, how do you
work this, Ray?
I didn't see him, man.
He came out of nowhere.
I never...
It wasn't my fault.
Hey! Bring him
into the RV!
Come on.
All right.
[Panting]
Okay. All right.
I got ya.
[Bottles Shattering]
Is he okay?
Hear me out.
Let's figure this thing out.
Move, Ray!
Move!
Aah!
Easy, easy, easy!
Careful, careful!
All right,
easy, easy, easy.
Easy, easy.
[Grunting]
Aah!
Be careful,
be careful.
[Frank]
What the hell happened?
Ray, get a towel.
[Man Coughing]
- Ohh.!
- [Ray] He's been shot.!
Put this under his head!
Be careful. Easy, easy.
Ohh!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- It's all right.
[Coughing Continues]
He's a thief, man.
The cops probably shot him.
They'll be back any minute.
- What happened, kid? Who shot you?
- Hey, leave him alone.
Goddamn it, somebody shot him!
We could all be in danger!
- We're not gonna leave him.
- Look, I've had a lot
to drink tonight, okay?
Hey, man, what's your problem?
The kid is hurt.
You want me to go to prison
because of this punk?
It is not our concern.
Yes, it is, Ray.
They're coming after me.
You gotta help me.
We won't let anybody hurt you.
- You gotta get me outta here!
- Shut up, goddamn it!
I can't hear myself think!
[John]
Ray, you shut up.!
Who the hell are you
tellin' to shut up?
No, wait!
Listen.
[Distant Siren Blaring]
[Man] You can't tell them
about the money.
[John] We'll catch 'em.
Everything's gonna be fine.
[Man]
Look, that's not what
I'm worried about, man.
- There they go, right there!
- [Ray] They didn't see us.
We gotta catch 'em!
Look, we should get
our stories straight.
If you're not gonna drive,
I will.
[Mike] Let's go.!
Get out of the way!
[Tires Screeching]
There they go!
[On P.A. System]
Hey, help, police! Help!
We got somebody shot!
Hey.!
[Siren Blaring]
They turned the corner!
Hey!
S- O-S.! Hey.!
We got wounded in here.!
Frank!
Frank, take it easy
Shit.
Where the hell are they?
[Mike Screaming]
[Mike]
Fuck.!
Where did they go?
- [Tires Screeching]
- Whoa!
Ohhh!
[Mike Coughing]
Ohh.!
Ray, you okay?
Ray? Huh?
Yeah, I'm all right.
You all right, Frank?
Yeah, I think so.
[Frank]
I didn't see 'em.
[Indistinct Mumbling]
Aah!
[Grunting]
Ahh!
What the hell hit us?
My guess?
Probably some no-insurance...
car-driving asshole bashed
into us in a fucking junker.!
Un-fuckin'-believable!
- Ray, calm down.
- Calm down?
This stuff's
gonna cost me a fortune.
I'm now the proud owner of
a nice little fax machine.
Gonna fax myself.
Might be nice for me later.
Large screen. Huh?
Brand-new piece of shit TV.
- This'll be mine. All right. Okay.
- You okay, brother?
Yeah, I'm fine.
This stuff! S gonna
cost me right here.
Uh.
We're stuck in here.
We're stuck, okay?
We're stuck in this piece of shit
which I now own, okay?
This piece of fuckin' shit!
Ray, Ray!
- Ray! Ray!
- Calm down!
Hey, Ray, why don't you
try and start this thing?
Fuck, get a window open
or somethin'.
[Grunting]
Damn thing's stuck.
Great. Wonderful.
[Engine Cranking]
It's dead.
We're not goin' anywhere.
- They're out there.
- Who you talkin'about? Who's out there?
You guys don't know
what you're messin' with.
We gotta get outta here!
We gotta get ou...
Shut up! We're doing
the best we can, all right?
All right, quiet!
[Wind Whistling]
[Slamming]
[Man]
You hear that?
I'm gonna
take a look around.
No, don't do that.
They'll blow your head off.
Ray, get the gun.
Get the fuckin'gun, Ray.
It's gone.
What?
It fell out when we hit.
It's gotta be here.
Try and find it.
[Mike]
Look for it.
[Ray] I'm lookin; man.
[Mike]
You see anything?
Nothing.
Seems okay.
I think we can all
squeeze through there...
What up, Teddy?
Playin' a little hide-and-seek?
Come here, motherfucker!
Back the fuck off!
[Teddy]
No!
- Ladies.
- No! Come on, man!
You wanna get tough with me, kid?
You wanna keep 'em, huh?
Back off, kid.
You ain't got no balls.
Now, you children sit tight
and no one'll get hurt, okay?
Crack a window.
You okay?
[Dialing, Busy Signal]
The thing isn't working?
I thought you said
there was no service.
Look...
[Grunting]
Sykes, look, no.
You know...
Shh.
[Car Approaching]
[Tires Screeching]
[Teddy] This is crazy.
Sykes, you know me.
[Sykes]
See, Teddy, the problem is,
No, there's no problem, man.!
You broke one ofhis rules.
It's not like that, man.
I didn't do anything.
All you gotta do is tell Fallon,
that's all I'm askin'!
- Tell Fallon what?
- Well, go ahead, tell him.
[Panting] Look, it's not
what you think, man.
L-I wasn't running, man.
You got it wrong. Look.
I got all the money right there!
You... You can count it.
[Sighing]
How could you steal
from me, Teddy?
L-I wasn't stealin' from you.
It's right there. All the money, man!
Only thing I hate worse than
a thief is a liar, Teddy.
You broke rule number one:
Do not steal from me.
[Grunting]
What you thinkin' about,
Teddy?
- Come on, we grew up, man.
- All you had to do was keep
the merchandise movin', Teddy.
What was the problem?
No company car?
Not long enough lunches?
[Fallon Continues,
Indistinct]
[Frank]
We can'tjust sit here.
- We're not gonna do anything!
Not one fucking thing!
- Shh! Come on!
What? What do you
want us to do, man?
Did you mention my name
to the guys in the truck?
Did you mention my name?
I didn't say anything!
Why the fuck would I say anything?
I wouldn't rat you out, man!
So what do you want me to do?
You want me to let you go?
- Then I'm supposed to conduct
business on the street.
- Who's gonna know, right?
- He's not gonna tell 'em,
I'm not gonna tell 'em.
- That's right.
- No, man, all you gotta do is...
- [Gunshot]
[Gunshot Echoing]
[Echoing Continues]
You know,
we got another problem.
How many guys
in the truck?
About four.
North Shore plates too.
Great. Just great.
Well, boys, rule number two:
No witnesses.
Come on!
- [Mike] Fuck.!
- Come on, John,
or you're gonna be next!
- [Mike Yelling]
- Fuck.
[Yelling, Grunting]
[Mike]
Come on.! Come on, Ray.!
Come on.!
- What the hell are you doing?
- [Mike] Come on.!
- Aw, shit!
- What?
- Come on.!
Fuckin'come on, Ray.!
- Where do these guys
think they're goin'?
- [Gunshots]
[Gunshots Continue]
[Grunting]
Come on, Ray!
Come on, buddy!
Shit!
Oh! Sorry, man!
That's not exactly
what I had in mind.
[Frank Chuckling]
Thanks. That's what
I'll tell the dealer.
You won't be telling
the dealer nothin' unless
we get the fuck outta here!
[Fallon]
That was great. Do it again.
That's not funny.
Hey, man, that was funny!
Shit looks like the Hindenburg, man.
Come on.!
Let's go!
[Panting]
Let's go, Ray!
[Ray Panting]
[Mike Grunting]
Stop!
Where are we headed?
[Everyone Panting]
John,
are you all right?
[Coughing]
Why? Why'd they do it?
They killed him, Frank.
They killed him.
I don't think they're
gonna follow us, man.
They won't do that.
We saw him shoot that kid, Ray.
We were witnesses.
Where the hell are we,
huh?
[Panting]
Why'd you get off
the expressway, Ray?
Are we at
the blaming stage now?
I don't remember
twisting your arm
to get off the expressway.
[Tires Screeching]
Go! Go!
[Grunting, Panting]
Hey!
[Grunting]
Forget it, Mike!
Come on!
Come on, Mike!
[Grunting]
Frank.! Frank.!
Ohh!
[Panting] Did they see us?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
[Engine Stops]
[Ray]
Frank was right.
- They do want to kill us.
- I never said they wanted to kill us!
- What are we gonna do?
- Shut up!
Well!
- Look what the cat drug in.
- [Mike] Keep your voice down.
[Fallon]
Hello, ladies.!
What do you think
of the neighborhood?
Call these "condos"
down here.
Nice, huh?
Could bejust like one of those
North Shore suburbs, huh?
Guess what?
I knew you guys would go
straight for the rail yard.
But you didn't pass "Go,"
so you definitely don't
get the 200 bucks.
You just sit tight,
'cause I'm gonna come
door to door...
like the goddamn Avon lady.
And by the way,
you fucked up my car...
and I don't have collision.
[Man]
Guy out there sounds
like he wants to do you...
bodily harm or somethin'.
[Giggling]
I'm a college graduate.
[Man]
That's Buck.
He's got the brain
of a chicken.
[Banging]
Sure would be a shame...
if he was to hear you
in... here, oop!
Shh! Shh!
Damn shame.
[Banging Continues]
They'd... They'd shoot us
and then blow your heads off.
I don't think so.
Might even be grateful.
Might give us a reward.
All right.
All right, goddamn it.
Name your price.
Uh, well, gee,
Mr. Businessman,
[Men Laughing, Murmuring]
What did you have
in mind?
- [Fallon] Don't move.!
- [Banging]
Don't whisper.
Don't even breathe.
[Banging]
Don't you hate it...
when you're tryin'
to be quiet...
and every sound...
seems to be amplified...
20 or 30 times?
[Banging]
[Fallon]
What is that?
[Sniffing]
What's that smell?
You guys wearing cologne,
or is that... fear?
Nice watch.
Go to hell.
Already there, man.
Ray, give it to him.
[Banging]
[Moaning]
[Scraping, Rattling]
[Banging]
Lucy, I'm home.!
You got some
'splaining to do!
[Scraping, Rattling,
Banging]
Don't touch me!
Don't be stupid, John.
[Murmuring]
[Panting]
All right.
That's all I got.
[Sighing]
You guys are really
startin' to piss me off!
This is eatin'
into my drinkin' time.
But I'll tell you
what I'm gonna do; since
I'm such a nice person...
and so in touch
with my inner child...
I'm gonna give you
a chance to come out,
forget about the bullshit...
we'll discuss this.!
I'm gonna count
to three.!
One Mississippi...
two Mississippi.
All right!
Opportunity knocked,
and you failed to answer!
Don't say I didn't
give you a chance!
Come on, let's talk.!
[Banging]
Let's mingle.!
All right!
Now I'm gettin'mad.!
This one's
locked up too, man.
It's possible they
didn't even stop here,
they just took right off.
It just doesn't
feel right, you know?
I'm a college graduate.
I used to play
college ball.
Ain't got my jacket
no more.
That's too bad.
Somebody stole it.
But, you know, l... I had...
I had great hands, man.
I mean,
you shoulda seen me!
"Go up high, Buck!"
[Grunting]
Buck!
Take it easy!
Shh! Shh!
What are you doin'?
I'd go out wide, man!
I could've been Walter Payton!
Sure you could.
This guy played too many
games without a helmet.
You think I'm funny
or somethin', man?
Who do you think you are...
wearing that jacket
and callin' me a liar?
Shh!
'Cause I'm a goddamn
college graduate!
[Indistinct Talking]
You think I'm some rummy
who never went to college.!
[Buck Continues, Indistinct]
What the hell do I gotta do
to shut him up?
[Indistinct Talking
Continues]
Come on, let's get out!
Come on, man, move it!
Take out time, boys!
[Indistinct Talking,
Yelling]
Let's go!
[Shouting Continues]
[Grunting]
Shit.! Hobo from Purdue.
I hate Purdue.
When's the last time they
ever won anything anyways?
Hmm, plastic.
That's one of'em.
Hmm. Bums must've
rolled 'em, huh?
Welcome to
the neighborhood, boys.
[Panting]
[Sykes] There they are.!
Come on.!
[Grunting]
Come on,
we can outrun them.
[Mike]
This way.! Come on.!
Come on, come on,
come on!
[Panting]
[Grunting]
Hold it! Shh!
[Barking]
John! John!
Get up! Let's go!
[Groaning]
Frank, listen, I can't
fuckin' keep up, okay?
You have to!
Don't leave my ass down here.
This is hell.
You can do this, man.
You take care of me, I'll
give you anything you want.
All I want...
is for you
to move your ass.
We're gonna make it,
all of us.
Okay.
Okay? Now,
I think we lost 'em.
All right.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah,
I'm all right.
Where are the cops?
Someone must've
heard the blasts.
You could dynamite a whole
city block, they wouldn't come.
It's criminal.
Look at this.
Oh, yeah.
Ohh, reach out and touch
someone, my ass, huh?
Great. Hey, wait,
there's lights on in
that building up there.
Let's go get some help.
Come on.
[Panting]
Come on.!
Come on, Ray.!
[Ripping]
[Ray]
Damn, I tore myjacket.!
Come on!
I'd be worryin' about my ass,
not my jacket!
Yeah, well, my ass
doesn't cost 450 bucks!
[Rap, Indistinct]
[Continues]
If anything happens, don't
think, just run. Okay?
Gotta find someone who'll
let us use their phone.
You really think one of
these freaks is gonna
let us use their phone?
"These freaks"
are our neighbors, Ray.
They're not
my neighbors, man.
Oh, yeah?
I bet we haven't been more
than ten miles from your
front door this whole night.
[Creaking]
What's up with that noise?
[Creaking Continues]
- I should go talk to him.
- No, no, no.
I got a better idea.
Mike!
[Rattling Door]
There's a way in
over there.
Hi, sir.
I need to use your phone.
No! No, no!
No way!
Just one phone call!
Thanks a lot!
[Man Yelling, Indistinct]
Mike, take it easy, man.
You too, buddy!
Hello, anybody home?
[Man] Who the fuck
does he think he is?
What's wrong
with these people?
They're just like you.
How is that?
They're scared.
They won't even
talk to us.
[Knocking]
Hi.
May we use your phone?
Hey, hey!
Get behind the door!
Nobody's gonna help us.
Nobody.
Welcome to
the real world, Ray.
This is it!
If you say that to me again,
I'm gonna kill you, I swear I will.
[Rap, Indistinct]
[Knocking]
Hello. Hello?
Anybody in there?
Please open the door
if you're there. Hello.
[Knocking]
Come on, please!
Wait, wait, wait.
Don't wanna scare her off.
Excuse me.
[Woman]
Yeah? What do you want?
I need to use a phone.
Just hold it right there.
Now keep back.
Keep back!
Please, just listen...
'Cause I'll bust all
your goddamned heads,
and don't think I won't!
Clarissa, you all right?
Get out of here, Rita!
Just give us a chance...
The only chance
you're gonna get...
is to get your
motherfuckin' asses in gear
before I start swingin'!
- I told you these people
didn't want to help us.
- Look.!
We saw a boy murdered tonight.
The men that shot him did it in
cold blood, and if they catch us...
- they're gonna kill us too.
- So they're following you?
- No, no, we lost them.
- [Mike] You gotta believe us.
We're telling the truth.
We just
wanna use your phone
to call the police.
That's it. We're not
gonna cause you any trouble.
Please.
Sykes, this is bullshit.
We lost 'em, man!
We're just wastin' our time.
You know something?
You are really beginning
to piss me off!
Where he goes, we go.
Now shut the fuck up!
[Kid] Yo.!
[Rap, Indistinct]
Yo! Hey, what's up?
Yo, man, these the punks
you saw, man?
No, they ain't the ones.
You punks crazy
or somethin', man?
Chill out, man.
- We'rejust lookin'for some citizens.
- He lookin' for some citizens.
You ain't gonna find nobody
down here like that, man.
This is our block.
If you got any brains...
you'll break now
and don't look back.
- We got business, that's all.
- Oh, you got some business, man?
Yeah.
What kind
of business you got?
Wait a minute, right?
I've had about enough
of this bullshit.
I'm gonna ventilate
your little cranium.
What about that, huh?
[Sykes] Now back off!
[Boy] Hey, man, you'd
better get your boy, Jack.!
- [Fallon] All right.
- I got some too, man.
Just, uh, a little bit
too much meat today.
That's all, man.
Come on, man. If you don't like what
I have to say, fuck me. Come on.
[Rap Continues]
What you smilin' at?
I understand, man.
I respect ya.
You're taking care
of your block. That's great.
But these motherfuckers ripped me off.
That can't happen.
Know what I mean?
You know.
I don't know.
If I fuck with you now, you look
like shit in front of your boys.
How much is this gonna cost?
Man, if I want your money,
I'll take it.
No, you can't take my money...
but you can... take my money.
- Go ahead.
- Money got blood on it, man.
You ever seen any
that didn't?
Now, go ask Webster
over there...
- which building those people
went into, okay?
- All right.
I don't believe this.
Ray, you're wearin' a hole
in the carpet, bro.
Cops should've
been here by now, ;
it's been 17 minutes.
Down here people die of old age
waiting for the cops.
No goddamn way.
This is bullshit.
Watch this.
I'll get their asses over here
in one goddamn second.
What's wrong, Ray?
The phone's dead.
What do you mean,
it's dead?
Give me.
It must be them.
They're here!
Maybe you didn't
pay your phone bill.
- Oh, yeah, right!
- Hey, shut up, Ray!
"Francis...
"Howard...
Wyatt."
Used to have a girlfriend
named Frances.
She had blue eyes
just like you.
- How does he know my name?
- Frank, beautiful baby!
Wow! Lucky for you she looks
just like your wife, huh?
What's your wife, Italian?
I always wanted to fuck
an Italian girl, Frank.
I tell you what, Frankie... Francis.
Since you won't meet me man-to-man...
I'm gonna take my case
to the people, all right?
The people
of the housing projects.!
I got a headline for ya.
This just in. ;
Get the fuck outta my house.
I hate this fuckin'place.
I wanna go home.
Go on.
[Baby]
Mommy.!
I wanna drink, smoke...
and play my loud music.
Honey, come here.
- So this misguided individual...
- Get the hell out of my house!
Is starting to piss me off!
Here's the deal. ;
[Baby Crying]
Give him up now
and this will not be
the worst night of your life.!
There's nothin'
on three floors.
We got two more to go.
We gotta take a break.
I told you
you should've quit smoking.
It's okay. Everything's
gonna be all right.
[Crying Continues]
- We can't stay here.
- If we go out there,
they're gonna kill us.
- [Crashing]
- These people put their lives
on the line for us!
- [Mike] Frank's right.
- Yeah, go!
[Sykes]
Open the fucking door.!
Let's do it.
[Woman Screaming]
No way!
I'm not going out there!
- Don't open it.! Okay.
- Oh, my God!
- Jesus, Ray.
- I'm not goin' anywhere.
- [Frank] You son-of-a-bitch.
- You had that thing the whole time?
- Why the hell didn't you
use it when we needed it?
- Shh! I'm using it now!
On us.
Yeah.
- Whichever one thinks you're
gonna get me through that door.
- What are you doing?
You're scarin'the kid.
The cops'll be here
any second.
Let's wait
till they get here.
Open it up.!
- The cops are not coming!
- Yes, they are.
Stay right back, okay?
I am not gonna die down here.
- [Gunshot, Yelling]
- These people weren't involved,
and they helped us.
If those bastards find us here,
they're gonna kill everybody.
Is that what you want?
[Knocking]
You gotta trust me, man.
You don't want this deal.
[Clarissa Crying]
Come on, Razor.
Give me the gun!
- [Gasping]
- [Crying]
[Mike]
Okay, let's get outta here.
Go to the roof; the kids
have a way of getting across
to the next building.
It's the only chance
you have.
Thanks a lot.
[Door Knob Turning,
Hinges Creaking]
[Sykes] Hey.!
[Woman] I have a baby.!
Please leave us alone.!
[Sykes]
Open the fucking door now.!
Seen any white guys
around here?
[Gunshot]
Sykes, come on, let's go up
to the next floor, man.
[Man]
You'd better not be lying.!
Gimme your gun.
Gimme your gun!
[Sykes] Let's go.!
[Man]
What a shithole.!
Here.
Here, use this.
[Rap]
Knock, knock, faggot.
Open the door.
Hey, take it easy, man.
[Rap Continues]
[Indistinct Talking]
Fuck.
I found it!
Jesus,
that's the escape route?
[Mike] Huh?
[Panting]
Let's do it.
[Grunting]
Easy.
[Frank] Let's go, Ray.!
[Mike]
Over here, over here.
Kids do this.
Let's go, Ray.
[John]
Hang on, Mike.
Hang on, buddy.
- Ray?
- I can't.
The pipe, Ray.
Use the pipe.
It's right there. The drainpipe.
You can shimmy down that.
[Grunting]
[Frank]
Let's go, Ray.
We used to do this kind of thing
when we were kids, remember?
What the fuck am I doing?
Just slide down.
Ray, whatever you do,
don't look down.
Thanks, pal.
I wasn't going to.
You know, Ray, I've got
a great view from down here.
Funny, Frank. I'm glad
you save your best material
for the rooftop show.
Thanks. I'll be here all week.
Come on, Ray.
That's good,
that's good.
When I get down, I'm gonna
kick your fuckin' ass.
[Both Laughing]
[Screaming]
[Grunting, Groaning]
- John, get your ass
across that ladder now.
- What are you guys doin'?
[Mike]John, there's
a way down over here.!
Let's go, Ray.
[Mike]
All right, John, come on, buddy.
Don't look down, look at me!
Okay, that's it. You know,
like the 40 yard line, man.
Come on. Here you go.
You're on the 30 yard line.
The 20. Now the 10.
[Frank]
That's it. All right. Next.
Go ahead.
I wanna follow you. You go first.
You're full of crap, Ray.
Climbing across this thing
is not gonna kill you.
Those guys are!
Come on,
I swear to God.
I can always tell when you're
full of crap, Ray, and you are
full of crap right now!
Don't make me leave you up here.
Don't do that to me!
Look, I said I would do it!
[Mike] Move it.!
You want me to put it
in writing?
I will follow you.
All right, let's do it.
Come on.
Watch how simple this is.
[Sighs]
[Panting]
[Ladder Creaking]
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
[John]
That's good. That's good,
man, all right.
This is it.
This is nothing, right?
[Fallon]
There they are.!
Come on, Frank!
- Move it!
- Come on, Frank!
Motherfucker!
- [Fallon Screams]
- There!
I don't believe
these guys got guns.
Yeah, too easy these days.
[Ladder Creaking]
[Ray]
Frank.!
Go ahead, check it out.
Frank!
[Laughing]
Nice move.
[John]
Come to me, goddamn it.
[Mike]
Come on, Frank.
[John]
Frank, come on.
Come on, Frank, come on,
buddy, come on.
Give me your hand.
[Grunting]
Come on!
Come on, Frank!
I got you. I got you.
Come on, come on. Okay.
[Panting]
Ray!
What are you doin'?
I ain't no acrobat.
I'm gonna negotiate with these guys.
What with, Ray?
I got these guys
right where I want 'em.
- Frank, come on!
- I'm the Razorman, remember?
- Let's go.
- Come on.
[Mike]
Come on.!
Easy, fellas.
Hear me out a second. Just
give me a chance to talk, okay?
What do you wanna talk about?
Something near and dear
to my heart... money.
Money. Money's good.
Yeah.
Money makes
the world go 'round.
Mike.! You fire,
they'll kill him for sure.
And if I don't?
Start talking.
There's no reason for any
of this to be happening.
Whatever happened to that kid,
I'm sure he deserved it.
That's your business.
Nobody's going to the police.
All we want to do is get home.
Home. Home is where
the heart is, right?
Uh... excuse me
for a minute.
Correct me if I'm wrong here,
but, uh... didn't you say
somethin' about money?
Yeah, I did.
How about $100,000 cash?
Then we go
our separate ways.
You can raise
that kind of money? Wow.
Yes, I can.
Let me ask you somethin'.
Those shoes, what are those,
Italian?
- [Sykes Chuckles]
- [Hammer Cocks]
Yeah, they're actually
Italian running shoes.
[Laughing]
Actually kinda working well
for me this evening.
Yeah? And your dad's what,
he's a, uh, a stockbroker?
Somethin' like that.
But I'm a self-made guy.
I'm a self-starter.
Just like you.
That's funny. 'Cause these guys
are always sayin' that to me.
That's why we hang
with him.
Self-made man.
You just name the place.
Tomorrow morning the cash
will be there.
In the meantime, how about
a little deposit?
Hmm.
[Sykes]
May I see that?
This, this is a beautiful ring.
Rhodes, take a look at this.
Check this out.
Oh, that's beautiful, man.
Take this home to your girl.
Tell me something, how much
is a ring like that worth?
Retail, that's 15 K.
But for you guys,
[Clicking Tongue]
Hmm.
Call it a down payment,
under the table.
[Laughing]
You know, I think, uh,
I think we can cut a deal here.
Oh, man,
that's beautiful.
Yeah.
[Ray] There you have it.
I can't believe this.
He's doin' it.
You're pretty good.
Wh-What's your name?
Ray. Ray, yeah.
You're a good negotiator.
You didn't even lowball me.
I'm gonna come in here
and lowball you?
Forget about that.
Well, the thing is, I gotta trust you.
There's the payment of money...
and then there's your friends
keeping their mouths shut, you know.
Now hold on.
We're businessmen, both of us.
We have an understanding.
Oh.
Let me tell you somethin',
uh, Ray.
You don't understand shit.
Okay? Nothing.
Guys like you gotta keep
checking your pants to see
if you got a dick. I got one.
You and your friends are
the kind of spoon-fed fuckin'
fruit bait that I fuckin' hate!
I don't think
you understood me.
Shut the fuck up! You speak
when fuckin' spoken to, okay?
This is not fuckin'
high school, motherfucker!
I'll eat your fuckin'friends
for fuckin'lunch.!
You know who we are? No, you have
no fuckin'idea, do you? No.
You just sail through life
reading about people like me
in the newspaper. Hey!
You're in a different place now,
motherfucker.
Yeah, $100,000 might
buy you out in North Shore.
Down here that means shit!
This is my fuckin' world!
Two hundred thousand.
[Hammer Uncocks]
All right.
[Sighing]
We got a deal?
Yeah.
This... You had...
You schooled me.
[Chuckling]
You took my heart off the ground
and surgically implanted it.
Ray. Ray.
In just a little bit,
my pulse'll be back to normal.
[Panting]
God.
Ray.
[Ray]
Music to my ears.
Absolutely.
I'm gettin' off this roof
in one piece.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
[Screaming]
- No!
- [Groaning]
- Motherfucker!
- Jesus.
- Motherfucker.!
- It's all right.
No! Let me go, Frank!
Okay, Frank, wait! Okay!
Come on, John, let's go!
[John Gasping]
[Panting]
Don't look at him, John.
Come on, he's gone, man!
[Rap, Indistinct]
[Rap Continues]
Come on. Come on.
All right.
Frank.
[Grunting]
[Coughs]
Shh.
[Whispering]
We should've done something.
Makes no sense for Ray
to go out like that.
Nothing about tonight
makes much sense.
I keep hearing him
screaming.
[Fallon]
Hello, ladies.
No.!
Well, well, well, it's
our little chicken-shits.
[John]
Go! Go!
[Gunshots]
[Panting, Grunting]
[Mike]
This way.! This way.!
[Grunting]
No!
Get off!
- Frank!
- Get down, get down!
[Mike]
Go, go, go, go,
go, go, go, go.! Go.!
Aaah! Go, go, go!
Aaah!
[Groaning]
[Mike]
This way, this way.!
Right here.! Come on.
[Metal Clanging]
[Shouting, Cheering]
[Frank]
Mike.
John.
We gotta keep moving, man.
Split up.
Man, this is stupid.
You really think we're
gonna catch these guys?
Yeah.
You comin'?
Watch your ass.
Shit.
I always do, Mom.
[Fallon Singing]
Oh, when the saints
Oh, shit!
Go marching in
These guys don't give up.
Oh, when the saints
go marching in
They're right on our ass.
We gotta get outta here.
It's hard to tell
where they're coming from.
We don't wanna run into them.
[Grunts]
[Mike]
No, no, no, no.
It's too bright up there.!
You might as well stick
a bulls-eye on your back.
What are we gonna do?
We gotta make a stand.
It's our only chance
of gettin'out ofhere alive.
I always wondered how I'd do
in combat. Could I cut it?
You ever wonder
about that, Frank?
- Guess I'm about to find out.
- [Chuckles]
- Mike, they got guns.
We have nothing!
- Screw the guns.
If we watch each other's back,
we'll be... we'll be okay.
Right? Huh?
- There you go, Johnny boy.
- Let's do it.
Hey, Frank...
let's show these punks
what we got.
[Exhales]
Right.
[Mike]
Hey, there's three ways in here,
there's three of us.
We watch each other's
backs, huh?
[Sighs]
Okay, let's go! Go!
[Travis]
Sykes.! Rhodes.!
You guys down there?
[John]
Mike. Mike.!
I got your back.
[Mike]
Hey, I'm relyin'on you, bro.
[Rumbling]
[Rats Squeaking]
[Whispering]
Frank! Frank!
[Squealing Continues]
[Grunting]
- Yaah!
- [Metal Clangs]
Where're you guys at?
- Hey, don't you move. Don't you move.
- [Sighs, Sniffs]
All right, who's
the chicken-shit now, huh?
You gonna shoot me?
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
You ever shoot anybody before?
I don't think so.
Now, if you don't
give me that back...
the same thing that happened
to your friend Ray
is gonna happen to you. Oh!
- Ohh!
- [Gunshot Echoing]
[Sykes Groaning]
Man, did you see
the look on his face?
He didn't think
I could do it.
[Fallon]
Sykes.! Talk to me, man.!
Let's move.
No, screw that! Hey,
I say we stay down here
and we finish 'em.
You know, things are a little
different now, huh?
What is the matter
with you, huh?
This isn't a goddamn game!
John, let's go.
Hey.! Hey, wha...
What happened to you, kid?
Hey! Hey, I thought
you had my back!
Hey, John,
I'm talkin' to you!
We gotta find some cover.
What the hell happened
to you down there?
Um...
Huh?
I'm sorry.
Sorry doesn't cut it.
You almost got me killed!
[Groans]
Hey! Back off, Mike.
Your baby brother fucked up.
He better not do it again!
Oh, yeah? Or what?
[Chuckles]
See, that's the Frank
I used to know.
You better believe it.
Now let's get off the street.
Yes, sir, boss.
This is great.
You know,
I don't know about you guys,
but I didn't sign on for this.
This is your fault, Fallon.
Your best buddy's dead because
of you and your goddamn rules.
Hey.! You ever hear the one
about takin'care of your own?
Huh?
You mean, you'd let these guys
get away with this, right?
No, I wouldn't let these...
Ohh.!
You know what I hate?
I hate whiners, you know.
I hate people who just
complain, complain, complain.
Had a guy in the joint one time,
cell next to me, you know.
He used to yap about everything.
Used to yap about the food,
yap about the guards.
And yap about this, and yap about
that, and yap, yap, yap all night long.
Fuckin' yap, yap, yap, like
a fuckin' 747. You know what I mean?
Like an engine stuck right between your
ears and you can't get away from it.
I don't think
he's gettin' up.
It's gone now.
[Sighs]
[Wind Whistling]
[Footsteps]
Oh, damn it.
If those assholes were
here right now, I'd, I'd...
I'd...
probably just freeze.
I tried, you know.
I couldn't move, Frank.
John, you gotta
keep it together, man.
Keep it together?
Fuck you, Frank!
I'm scared.
[Sobbing]
I'm really scared.
And I don't think
I'm gonna make it through
this fuckin' night.
I don't know
what to do.
John. Come here, come here.
No, Frank, no.
[Sobbing Continues]
Everybody gets scared.
No.
Whether they admit it or not.
I'm scared too.
[Sniffing]
Look at me.
I'm cryin'
like a baby here.
Thanks... for stickin' up
for me back there.
Yeah, well,
Mike's as scared as we are.
Hey.
There's... nobody
out on the street.
So what do you think,
boss?
Why don't you cool it
on that "boss" stuff?
[Bus Approaching]
[Frank]
You guys aren't gonna
believe this.
[Laughing]
Let's go.!
Hey! Hey, yo!
Wait! Wait!
Hey!
Hey, we're here!
Hey, stop!
Look, hey...
[Mike]
Hey, lady.!
Hey, hold up the bus.!
What are you doin'?
Hey! Hey!
[Frank]
Stop the bus.!
I don't think so.
Hey, come on!
Come back, you bitch!
Hey.!
Stop.!
[Panting]
Come back. Come back!
Mike, you're gonna
give us away.!
I don't get it.!
You used to have bigger balls
than anybody.!
Is that what this is about?
Balls? What about using
your goddamn brain?
Watch what you say to me!
What are you tryin'
to prove, Mike?
That you can get us killed?
Because that's exactly
what you're gonna do!
I got a wife and a little girl,
and I will get back to them!
You wanna go out
like a goddamn hero?
Then you do it alone.
Let's go, John.
Frank! Frank!
What, goddamn it?
Just wait up.
[Sighs]
No?
Maybe there's
another way in.
It's kinda dark.
I don't see anything.
There's gotta be
a security guard on duty.
Well, let's try and, uh,
wake him up!
[Alarm Ringing]
Hello?
We're in trouble now.
[Laughing]
[Ringing Continues]
Hello?
- [Bell Ringing]
- Hey, concierge, I need a room!
Hell of a security system.
Excellent response time.
Hey!
Yo!
Anyone home?
[Mike Yelling]
Hello? Anybody here?
We're here to rob the place.
Anybody got a problem
with that?
[Shouting Continues]
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yo, come on and get us.!
[Man]
Okay, freeze.!
[Mike Laughing]
There's two of'em.!
I said freeze!
Now, put your hands on top
of the counter and spread 'em!
Do it!
Well, anything you say.
All right,
we're freezin'.
Yeah, we're freezin' and we're
spreadin'. Anything else
you want us to do?
You frisk 'em.
I'll call 5-O.
Uh-oh, they're callin' the cops.
Hey, that's 9-1-1, buddy.
[Laughing Continues]
Tell 'em to haul their ass.
These kids are loaded.
[Ringing Continues]
[Dialing]
[Grunts, Groans]
Let's get to work.
Listen, man, the reason...
Just save it, punk.!
These guys
have been after us...
Look!
You tell it to the cops.
They get paid to listen
to your bullshit stories.
[Patting]
Hey, watch it.
Careful, I'm ticklish.
[Patting]
Uh, uh, mister,
there's one thing l...
No!
Put your hands back up
on the cooler!
Put 'em up on the cooler!
You understand me?
- Don't make a move!
- Okay.
[Fallon On P.A.]
Attention, shoppers.
We have a special...
in the frozen foods
department tonight: Dead meat.
Plump, juicy and fresh
from our North Shore farm.
Shop 'til you drop,
right, Frank?
Get back on that cooler!
Get on there! Hey, get on there!
You guys tell your friend
to get his ass down here.!
This guy's not our friend.
I'm tired of foolin'around.!
You understand me?
Motherfucker!
[Whispering]
Hey, Mike. Mike!
Come on.
[Whispering]
You go on.
[Panting]
Damn.
- Mike?
- You go on.
No way.
I'm gonna deal with these guys.
I'm gonna handle this.
[Cocks Hammer]
Would you cut
this heroics crap? And let's go!
Frank!
You got a family.
Me, all I got is you.
Mike.!
Stay there.
[Grunts, Groans]
[Yells]
[Clicking]
[Screaming]
[Groaning]
Mike?
[Panting]
[Grunting]
[Grunting, Groaning]
Hey, Frank!
- [Cocks Hammer]
- [Gasping]
- Why don't you come out
and get your friend?
- [Grunting]
[Yelling]
[Glass Breaking]
Shh!
Oh, man.
[Groaning]
[Lights Humming]
[Man]
Through good or bad
or happy or sad
Ah, let's stay together
Oooh, ooh, ooh
Oh, it's all right
with me
[Screaming]
[Glass Breaking]
[Gunshot]
[Frank]
Come on, get up.!
[Screaming]
[Gunshots]
[Groaning]
Jesus.
Jesus, Mike!
John. Oh!
[Chuckling]
You guys are unbelievable.
Get up. Get up!
I was there
and I don't even believe it.
Come on, let's go.
Let's move. Let's go!
[Frank]
Let's go, let's go.
[Groaning]
Come on, this way.
[Mike]
I'm okay, I'm okay. Uhh!
[Groaning Continues]
[Gasping]
Come on.
[Grunting]
All right.
[Mike Groaning]
Mike, you're gonna be okay.
I'm gonna go get help.
John's gonna stay
here with you.
Yes, sir, boss.
[Mike Chuckling]
Come on.
Easy, easy.
Gimme your hand.
[Grunting]
Put your hand here
and keep it there, all right?
I got it,
I got it.
You all right?
Yeah.
Hey, don't do
anything stupid.
Right.
[Glass Shattering]
Come on, Frank!
Scumbag!
Come out and meet me man-to-man.
Let's get it over with.
[Metal Clanging]
Come on.!
Frank.!
What are you afraid of?
Faggot.!
[Glass Shatters]
Come on, Frank!
I'm gonna kill your two fuckin'
pussy friends and then
I'm gonna kill you, all right?
[Groans]
You look fucked up.
[Whispering]
At least I can walk.
[Chuckling]
[Door Opens]
[Door Opens, Slams]
[Beeping, Clicking]
[Wood Creaking]
- [Wood Creaking Continues]
- [Alarm Beeping Continues]
Hey, you fuckin' scumbag!
I'm out here!
I said I'm out here,
you piece of shit!
[Hammer Cocks]
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Wind Chimes Jingling]
You know, Frank,
after I kill you...
I think I'm gonna pay a little
visit on that wife of yours.
[Creaking]
[Grunts]
[Gasps, Choking]
[Gunshot]
What did you say you were
gonna do to my wife?
What's the matter, asshole?
Why so quiet all of a sudden?
Aaah!
[Grunting]
You fuckin' dog!
[Grunts]
Ow! Ohh!
Uhh! Oh!
Jesus Christ.
You're Frank?
[Groaning]
Look at me
when I'm talkin' to you.
[Groaning Continues]
Hey!
You think you hurt me tonight,
is that it, huh?
Is that what you think,
Francis? Answer me!
Ohh! Ohh! Ohh!
Fuckin' prick!
Get up!
[Groaning Continues]
This how you're
gonna go out?
Francis.
Ohh!
You're not gettin' away...
'cause I know
where you're goin'.
[Panting]
Fuck you.
Fuck me?
I don't think so, pal.
"1922 Deadwood Drive."
That's a fuckin' riot.
Deadwood Drive.
Bet you got a nice house
up there, huh, Frank?
Hmm? Can't wait to meet
your daughter. What's her name again?
Ah, it doesn't matter.
You'll never see her grow up anyways.
No more!
[Grunting]
[Groaning]
Help me, for Christ's sake.
I knew you'd do
the right thing.
[Grunting]
Come on, Francis.
You're comin' with me.
No!
Nooo!
Come on, Francis.
[Grunting]
You're on your own, pal.
[Grunts, Yelling]
[Panting, Grunting]
And don't call me Francis.
[John]
Frank.!
Frank, you all right?
Where are ya?
Stay where you are!
Everything's all right!
It's over.
[Sighs]
[Dialing, Ringing]
[Operator]
9-1-1. May I help you?
Hello?
This is an emergency.
I need help. I need...
[Operator]
Sir? Are you still there?
[Panting]
Sir?
Look, my brother and my friend
are bleedin' to death upstairs.
Get down on the floor.
You're not listening to me!
Down!
I don't fuckin'
believe this.
Hey, Al, he's tellin'
the truth. It's like
a battleground out here.
Come on.
Don't worry,
you're gonna be fine.
[Wheezing]
Excuse me. How is he?
He's lost a lot of blood,
but his vital signs are good.
Take it easy.
Take it easy, man.
Hey, buddy, they say
you're gonna be okay.
[Gasping]
I better... I better be.
I got tickets to
the Bears game next week.
[Chuckles]
Well, you have a good time.
Wait. I got seats
on the 50 yard line.
Listen, I'm gonna be home
with Linda and the baby
watchin' the game on TV.
[Laughing Continues]
You... You're a wimp.
Hey, John.
Yeah?
Mike got you tickets
to the Bears game.
No, thanks, Frank.
[Siren Wailing]
I'm too young
for this shit.
I'll see you
at the hospital, bro.
Mr. Wyatt?
We found this inside.
You must've dropped it.
[Fingers Snapping]
It's a good-lookin'family.
Doo doo doo-doo
Mr. Wyatt, your wife's outside.
Hey, Makowski, on the double!
Doo doo doo-doo
All right, here we go.
Hey, yo, kids
What's up?
Remember when I used
to be dope
Yeah.!
I owned a pocketful of fame
Well, look what
you're doin'now.!
Now I know
Well, I know
I lost touch with reality
Now my personality is
an unwanted commodity
Believe it.!
Can't believe I used to be
Mr. Steve Austin on the mike
Six million ways
you used to run it.!
I guess Oscar Goldman got mad
'cause I got loose circuits
So loose, circuits be loose.
I be the Mother Goose with
the eggs that seem to be
Fallin; fallin; fallin'
Hey, yo, pack my bags
'cause I'm outta here
Mama don't love me
and my mama don't care
Read the papers
The headlines say
Washed-up rapper
got a song
[Imitating Chicken Clucking]
Lingo's busted
while the guitar sways
B side copy for the radio
plays for somethin'
I knew I blew
the whole fandango
When the drum programmer
wore a tango
Never could be liked
Great fish won't bite
They realize
that I'm over like clover
No good luck and so Mace
beat the f... - in'beat
Hey.!
While the teenage
fan the heat
I bring it to the clues
Paid all my dues
So what's gone dead
Let me use my forehead
Easy, pack it up, man
Let me stop stallin'
'Cause everything I do
is like fallin'
Fallin; fallin'
You played yourself.
Doo doo doo-doo
[Fingers Snapping]
You played yourself
Doo doo doo-doo
Bang your head
You played yourself
Come on, bang your head
Bang your head to this
["Another Body Murdered"]
No one's gotta murder
to murder to get away
But I get the feeling
that the fool's gotta pay
And if they pay
then they pay what they like
To watch another man
try to hold on to a life
'Cause I keep lookin'
and huntin'just like a lion
Let these suckers know
that it's them that be dyin'
I show no remorse
to the source of the terror
And if they tell, then
they're hopin'for a battle
Ah, keep me comin'and comin'
Take from my table
And if I miss I never miss
I bring my danger
I'm lookin'forward and I'm
lookin'over my shoulder
And I'm makin'sale for sale
to make them bolder
But I never rest
and rest I never see
I do a motherfucker
with this rusty piece
'Cause what they saw they
never seen or even heard of
And if they lip it's just
another body murdered
Another body murdered
Bang your head to this
I'll have to get it together
to watch a body get murdered
Bang your head
Come on, bang your head
Bang your head to this
Another body murdered
Ohh ohh-ohh
Faith No More
Boo-Yaa T.R.I.B.E.
I'll have to get it together
to watch a body get murdered
Uhh.!
I'll have to get it together
to watch a body get murdered