(rain)
(thunder)
(woman sighing and moaning)
(laughter and voices)
(squeal)
(car horn)
(electronic tune)
- Great. You think that's funny, chiphead?
- (electronic laughter)
You know, I couId puII your battery
and kiII you. so don't get cocky.
(buzzing)
(electronic laughter)
- 2707 to ControI.
- Control, 2707.
Message check. I'm waitin'
for a friendIy named Freddie.
He's a no-show.
Is there any caII-ins from him?
Control, 2707. No messages.
AII right, ten-four. I have a request
to open a phone channeI.
Patch me through to 555 3312, pIease.
Calling your girlfriend to say you'll be late
is nonessential communication.
You should know that
by now, 2707. Clear.
CIear. Ten-four.
Thanks for nothing, ControI.
Ah, this is great(!)
Agh! Goddamn it.
Lovers' Iane.
Hi! PoIice.
This is an emergency.
I have to use your phone.
sorry about the uphoIstery. Just pretend
I'm not here, OK? I'II be a second.
$100 bottIe of champagne!
she's worth it.
Aw, damn, the machine's on, you know?
You have one? I hate them.
You got a KIeenex? Ah, forget it.
That's aII right. This'II come off.
- Ah. Hi, Tracy. Yeah, it's DooIey.
- (helicopter overhead)
I'm just caIIing to Iet you know
I'm gonna be a IittIe Iate.
What's that?
I gotta go, honey.
WeII, it's not the Eyewitness News team.
I think someone's mad at me.
DefiniteIy, someone is mad at me.
- Whoo!
- Hey, DooIey!
Got a ride home tonight?
- Byers, I need a car.
- Can I ask you something?
- Later. PIease, I need a car. Mine bIew up.
- Just one question. One question.
How many cops use their day off
tryin' to get their asses shot off?
- I was set up!
- How many?
Look, I got him, OK?
I'm this cIose, Rog. I got Lyman.
- Give me a number. I'II write it down.
- 50 miIIion.
Lyman's moving 50 miIIion.
This is the big one, Rog, and I got him.
Mike, you don't have dick on Lyman.
What you've got
is a wet suit,
a bad attitude and a bIown-up car.
Right. That's what I toId you. I need a car.
You want a car, take a partner.
It's a two-for-one deaI.
- No, I'm not takin' a partner.
- Take Davis.
- Davis hates me.
- OK, uh... spencer. How about spencer?
- I hate spencer.
- You know the roster. Pick somebody.
- Lydecker. He's a good man.
- Lydecker's dead.
That's why I Iike him.
Doesn't sIow me down.
Rog. 50 miIIion. 50 miIIion and Lyman.
50 miIIion? Listen, smartass. How do you
know that there's a shipment comin' in?
High-tuned cop sense.
You remember that, Rog.
That's what you used to have, remember?
Before you became
a paper-pushin' pansy.
Paper-pushin' pansy. I Iike it.
Can you say it five times reaI quick?
- Paper-pushin' pansy...
- You're pathetic.
You're jeaIous because
I made Iieutenant first.
You're right. You're right.
I'm green with envy because
I'd Iove to spend my days here with my
Iips Iocked to the commissioner's butt!
- screw you, DooIey!
- Right now, Roger. Come on!
- Don't push me!
- Take your best shot!
You did. You hit me.
I don't beIieve you hit me.
- Do I get the car?
- You'II take a partner?
- No.
- No car.
OK. Fine.
I don't need your heIp.
I'II take Lyman aIone.
Honey?
sweetheart!
shit.
Trace.
Trace, I know you're mad.
You have every right to be.
I know tonight
was supposed to be speciaI.
I mean, the wine, the garIic chicken,
which is my favourite,
scaIIoped potatoes, the peas...
The peas. Even though I hate peas.
They're good for me
and that shows me that you care, honey.
I know I'm three hours Iate.
I am. And, uh...
- WeII, what can I say?
- Hi.
- (man) Hi.
- This is Chad, Mike.
- Chad?
- Yes, Chad.
- A friend from work. Works for Pan Am.
- Uh-huh.
One of those, uh,
baggage-handIer kinda guys?
No, more Iike
one of those piIot kinda guys.
Honey, you're a book editor.
How did you meet smiIin' Jack here?
WeII, he, um...
has aIso written three best seIIers.
- Books? ManuaIs? Instructions?
- Look, I've got an earIy fIight tomorrow.
- Maybe I...
- Thanks for the movie, Chad.
Any time. We'II have dinner when I get
back from Hong Kong. The three of us.
- Wow. What a night that'II be.
- Good night.
- (Tracy) Good night.
- (Dooley) Good night, Chad.
- You're dating? That was a date?
- He's a friend. We went to the movies.
- Do me a favour.
- Mike.
Do me a favour. When you go to the
movies, go to the movies with ugIy guys.
UgIy guys with shitty jobs.
- You have a shitty job.
- That's right. see what I mean?
so we're perfect for each other.
Why didn't you wait for me?
Because if I Iived my Iife
around your scheduIe, I'd go nuts.
I'd be a cIock-tower sniper in a month.
It's hard enough,
knowing that making a bust
is more important to you
than making time for me.
Now, I Iove you, Mike, but I can't
count on you, so I do what I have to do.
Eat your peas. They're good for you.
- You know, I'm onto something big.
- You aIways are.
It's Lyman. I think I got him scared.
- He tried to kiII me tonight.
- Just what I wanted to hear.
- I feeI so much better now(!)
- Look, Iook.
What do you want me to say, honey?
I'II say it.
It's not what you say.
I know what's important to you.
It's not me. It's the next bust or the next
shipment or south American cheesebaII.
Now, I know that. And I either have to deaI
with that or find some other way to Iive.
AII right. Look.
If you hate it so much, just move out.
Just take your shoes and move out.
I own this house. You moved in with me.
That's right. That's right.
I was wondering how I couId afford
such a nice pIace. It's reaIIy... so tastefuI.
- It's very nice. You did a very nice job.
- Mike...
Forget it for now. I know
verbaI skiIIs aren't your strong point.
- What are my strong points?
- No, not those either.
- You're a Iiar.
- You're a bragger.
- (Tracy giggles)
- (phone rings)
HeIIo. DooIey.
Got an address on Freddie, huh?
No, give it to me.
Uh-huh.
No, no. No bIack-and-whites.
I don't wanna scare him.
Uh-huh.
No, no.
- (electronic laughter)
- Oh, damn it. I missed it.
(bleeping)
God, I'm oId.
(mutters)
(electronic laughter)
- Ernie. " Que pasa?
- Bitch of a night.
- Why ain't you in bed with your oId Iady?
- Why aren't you?
- Your pizza, man.
- Cheese and mushroom?
- Like aIways.
- Here. seven, right?
- Yeah.
- How about a napkin?
How about a tip?
CoId damn pizza.
Gotta get a microwave in here.
You just ran a stop sign!
Good morning.
- Hey! Freddie, my man!
- This can't be happening.
- This can't be happening!
- You thought I was dead, huh?
surprised to see me?
You set me up, Freddie.
- I didn't do anything!
- Then what are you running from?
I need the exercise.
Exercise? I can heIp you there, Freddie.
You know, this whoIe jogging thing,
I just don't get it.
- DooIey, what the heII are you doing?
- But if you don't run,
you miss the precious aerobic benefits.
Make a right hand signaI for me,
wiII you? Thank you.
- Freddie, Iisten.
- What are you doin'?
- Names, Freddie. I need names.
- I don't know!
- You are Iike Edwin Moses.
- Ah, come on.
- Great hurdIer. You know that?
- Come on, buddy!
- No, no, no!
- To be the best, you gotta go!
- DooIey!
- Come on, buddy. Up, up.
- OK, OK. They were deaIers.
- DeaIers? Watch that poIe!
Don't wanna piss off AT&T!
Don't do it!
- Whoo! Names, Freddie.
- I don't know!
- Was it Lyman?
- I don't know, I swear to you.
Benny the MuIe. He was the trigger man.
Jesus, DooIey, what are you doin'?
Oh, you got those sIim ItaIian shoes, huh?
I think we quaIify for a carpooI.
DooIey, you're gonna kiII me!
What are you doin'?
AII right! You busted
a big shipment of their coke.
Now I wanna know,
are they movin' some more stuff in?
- They're movin' a Iot more in, aren't they?
- What?
Huh? Come on,
give it to me straight, Freddie.
- Come on. I want it straight.
- AII right. AII right.
We had a meeting at a warehouse.
Fifth and Presidio.
TransworId shipping, something Iike that.
Better be right, buddy,
because I'm gonna teII you,
I don't wanna waste
my afternoon searchin'.
- You'II waste a Iifetime searching it.
- Yeah?
It's huge. You couId hide
the Goodyear BIimp in there.
- Better have a heII of a nose.
- Yeah, yeah, right.
- I guess I'II have to.
- Hey, what am l supposed to do?
Drive sIow, don't pass.
(over megaphone)
San Diego Police Department.
Put your weapons down,
put your hands behind your head,
and come out of the building
through the front door.
This is Sergeant Young
of the San Diego Police Department.
..weapons down,
hands behind your head,
and come out of the building
through the front door.
- What's the deaI?
- We busted a buy down the bIock.
They took off, we grabbed one of 'em,
the other two - in there.
- Brannigan up there?
- Yeah.
Hey, Brannigan. Brannigan!
- Brannigan. Come here. I need a favour.
- I'm busy, DooIey.
- I need one of your Iand sharks here.
- Hey, they got a gig.
Hey, I onIy need it for a coupIe of hours.
Come on, gimme the dog.
- I can't spare a handIer.
- No handIer? I'II do it myseIf.
- These dogs won't Iisten to you.
- That's just because they don't know me.
They don't have to know you. You're
a maniac. They don't trust maniacs.
- Forget it.
- I got this sweet bust goin' down.
But I need to jump on it right now.
I need the dog.
You think you have probIems?
I gotta take my wife and kids on vacation.
- I got a pIane to catch in three hours.
- PIane?
Yeah. But I won't catch it
cos I gotta wait for the sWAT.
- If I get you on the pIane, I get the dog?
- My wife's gonna...
Can I have the dog if I get you
on the pIane? You're airborne.
- I'II get you on. Get me the dog.
- If you do, you can marry the damn dog.
- You got it.
- Goddamn Iunatic.
Who's this guy? Who've we got here?
Ow!
Nice hairnet. steaI that from your mom?
- Pinche, cabron.
- Now, now, now. Be nice.
GoId card! Haven't we had a good year!
- Hey, we're cIosed.
- I don't care. I need a car.
Fine. Take the convertibIe. $79.95 a day.
- The sign says $19.95.
- sorry. We're aII out of those.
- You got 20 of 'em out there!
- Reserved.
- For who?
- Not you.
- AII right. Gimme the next cheapest one.
- $79.95.
- OK, fine. Come on.
- Doesn't incIude tax and miIeage.
That's aII right. Put them on the biII.
I don't care. And I want some insurance.
- Insurance?
- Oh, yeah, I want the whoIe baII.
I want coIIision, IiabiIity, medicaI, fIood,
fire, theft. You got earthquake insurance?
- WhoIe Iife.
- WhoIe Iife is fine. Put that on there.
- OK. What's that come to?
- $267.90.
Round it to $300. Put it on the goId card.
Yes, sir!
- Hey, this is a beautifuI car.
- Yes, sir. Top of the Iine.
I'm a top-of-the-Iine kinda guy!
I'II put you on our preferred-customer Iist.
Yes, definiteIy!
- Great!
- I think you're a GoIden Key man.
- Love it.
- AbsoIuteIy.
so you can rent one
of these suckers anywhere by phone!
And they come with
discount tickets to seaWorId!
- Thanks.
- A pIeasure doing business! Need a map?
(car horn)
Hit the fIoor! Now!
What do you think this is?
Look what you did!
Narcotics? Party of 12.
sure you wanna do this?
Do you know what you're gettin' into?
I watched you work for years.
You don't have to be a Harvard graduate.
- They're just dogs.
- Right.
- Where the heII is this dog? Mexico?
- They wouIdn't take him.
- What's wrong with him?
- Nothing.
- Come on, Brannigan.
- He's got a few personaIity quirks.
- You shouId reIate to that.
- Wait a minute.
- He's not a retard, is he?
- This dog's seen more action
than me and you put together.
In fact, he's a IittIe stressed out.
- What do you mean by that?
- Just that he's pecuIiar from time to time.
PecuIiar?
- How come he's back here?
- He's not reaI sociabIe.
- Put this on.
- What's with the stuff?
- It ain't a fashion statement.
- Hey, I don't need this stuff.
It's procedure.
Everybody wears it. Put it on.
You know, this is a waste of time.
Just Iet the dog sniff me, I'II give him
some yummies, and we're outta here.
Put it on. TeII me,
do you know anything about animaIs?
- What's there to know?
- Did you have a pet?
- Yeah, pIenty of pets.
- What kind?
- PIenty.
- Like what?
- You know. Pets.
- Fish. I had fish.
- Aw, come on. Fish? Come on. Let's go.
It's a pet. It's a companion.
- The most IoyaI animaI I ever knew.
- Hey. You ready?
- siamese fighting fish.
- AII right. Let's go.
- I feeI Iike the MicheIin Man.
- I don't know. It's kinda... you.
Get over here.
- ''Jerry Lee''?
- The kiIIer.
Wait a minute. What is this?
You think I'm gonna fence the dog?
TeII me, Brannigan. How come,
if everyone has to wear one of these suits,
you're not wearing one?
Cos I ain't goin' in there.
- Where the heII is he?
- He's in there.
- I'm gettin' a fuII-sized dog, aren't I?
- Oh, yeah.
Jerry Lee, you got company.
Up and at 'em.
(whining)
Jerry Lee, you got a visitor. Come on.
Up and at 'em, Jerry Lee. Come on.
(growls)
Are you sure this dog
can track down drugs?
- Yeah.
- I don't know, Brannigan.
- Looks Iike he's on 'em.
- Just give him a command.
- He'II jump to it.
- Ah, come on.
sure.
Hey, pup. KiII!
- ''Here, boy'' might have worked better.
- I'm hip!
- He's aIways cranky when he wakes up.
- I know!
- What do we do now?
- Breakfast.
- (barks)
- Yeah, breakfast. Great idea.
Yeah, there he is. Best nose on the force.
He couId stick that snout in the wind now
and Iead you to a stash in Tijuana.
- I gotta be upfront. I got a bad feeIin'.
- Hey, tough shit. That's aII I got.
No, you got a Iot of dogs.
I want one of those.
Do things outside the ruIes,
you take what you can get.
- Now, take reaI good care of him.
- Don't worry about your dog.
- It ain't him I'm worried about.
- Is he eatin' chiIIi?
- What kinda animaI eats chiIIi?
- Hey, different strokes!
- Do I have to wear this suit aII day?
- Yeah.
- Come on. I can't drive in this thing.
- Just hang it up on your way out.
Come on, Jerry Lee.
Come on! Come on!
(Jerry Lee burps)
- Hey, DooIey. Good Iuck.
- Thanks.
- AII right, come on.
- (whines)
Let's go. In the car. Hup! Come on.
- AII right. Get in the back.
- (whines)
Jump in the back seat. Now.
- Move.
- (whines)
Don't test me, because I'm gonna win.
(whines)
AII right.
- (growls)
- It's OK. Fine. OK.
You better do exactIy what I teII you to do.
Otherwise I'm gonna kick your butt.
Brannigan's doing
a number on me. I can smeII it.
AII right. Listen up, here!
san Diego PD, Narcotics division.
I want everyone
to stay right where you are.
Listen! HoId it right...
stop! You, stop. Right here.
san Diego PoIice Department, Narcotics.
Lift me up. I wanna taIk to these peopIe.
Come on!
san Diego PD, Narcotics division.
Now, there are drugs in this warehouse.
I know it, and you know it.
This dog's gonna find them,
unIess you cheesebaIIs wanna save me
some time and teII me where it is.
No? AII right. suit yourseIf.
Bring me down.
AII right. I want you aII to pay attention.
This is a highIy trained,
vicious K-9 poIice dog.
so don't get in his way. This dog is
programmed to viciousIy attack
anyone who may pose a threat
or an obstacIe to this detaiI.
Jerry Lee, come.
Jerry Lee. Come!
(laughter)
AII right. Go.
- search.
- (whines)
sniff! sniff.
- (Dooley sniffs)
- (laughter)
- Just find the damn dope.
- (barks)
''Find the damn dope''?
That's the command?
Just stay there!
(barks)
Detective DooIey!
- Lyman.
- Who's the bitch?
- (growls)
- Watch your profanity around my dog.
Is that the way you taIk to those
high-society friends of yours, Lyman?
Hey, nice ride you got there.
BIack is hard to keep cIean.
I didn't expect to see you today.
But you know what? It works out great.
Know why? Now I don't have to drive aII
the way across town to hauI your ass in.
- Hey, is that a CD pIayer?
- DooIey.
What is it about me
that gets you so passionate?
Not your Iooks. I think it's your job.
Knowing your frontier approach
to Iaw enforcement,
I don't assume
that you have a search warrant.
The dog ate it.
- Hang round his taiI and wait for an hour.
- Get outta here, before I caII a reaI cop.
Why don't you caII your Iawyer, Lyman?
(barking)
There are drugs in this warehouse.
He went right for this door. That'II give me
a warrant that'II hoId up in any court.
Agh! Ay, me va a morder tu perro.
Quitame el pinche perro.
It was just one joint, man!
- Just one joint.
- One joint?
Are you gonna hauI this drug Iord in
or do we just execute him on the spot?
- This thing isn't over.
- I'm afraid it is.
I'II get a restraining order and you won't
be abIe to come within five miIes of me.
You get whatever you want.
It's not gonna stop me.
- Jerry Lee, come.
- (barking)
Jerry Lee!
Come on!
Buenos nachos.
- One joint! You found one Iousy joint!
- (whines)
You're smaII-time, you know that? I need
a reaI dog, is what I need. Benji!
I'm taking... I got one more stop,
and then I'm taking you back. One joint!
PoIice dog(!)
You just stay put.
This is a job for a reaI cop.
(Jerry Lee whines)
(shouting and crashing)
Yeah? What for ya?
Me?
HeaIth inspector.
Looks pretty good. I Iike it.
Yep. Looks pretty good.
WeII, I guess it's that time of day, huh?
FeeIs Iike happy hour to me. Know what?
I'm gonna buy aII the boys a drink here.
- Uh-huh.
- And give me, uh...
whatever you got that's,
uh, you know, diet.
- shooters?
- shooters for the boys?
Give 'em some shooters!
Afternoon shooters, boy, I Iike those.
Ah, you got that, uh, pickIed pigs' feet.
That Iooks pretty good.
so how you guys doin' today?
Have a good day?
Lookin' good.
Thank you. Hey! Cheers, huh?
Mm! I'II teII ya, on a hot day,
there's nothing Iike a... warm diet pop.
Give 'em another round here!
Ah!
You know, maybe you guys
can heIp me out here.
I'm Iookin' for a buddy I used to pIay
chequers with. We were tight.
We used to come in here, a Iong time ago,
before you guys were here.
I miss that crazy
son of a bitch, you know?
I was thinkin' about him the other day.
Oh, what was his name?
He had a funny nickname,
kinda Iike, uh...
Like Kermit the Frog, but not. You know?
It was Iike... Benny... Benny the MuIe.
- Why do you wanna know about him?
- Cos he's a cop.
I usuaIIy don't get a second shot
at somebody Iike you.
Agh!
You know, you made a big mistake.
This ain't a good pIace to be a cop.
If I caught you at a bad time,
I can aIways come back Iater.
Yeah, you know, DooIey,
I couId shoot you.
That'd be too easy on you
and it wouIdn't be any fun for me.
No, I think I'II just
beat the shit outta you!
(Jerry Lee barks)
- What the heII is that?
- (growls)
That's... Officer Lewis.
san Diego K-9. You're aII under arrest.
so Iine up against the waII,
hands above your head, and spread 'em.
- Hey, we give up.
- (laughter)
I'm not kiddin'. Hey, Iisten, I'm teIIin' ya.
One command outta me,
he'II rip your throats out.
- Line up against that waII!
- I'm scared shitIess. Aren't you, guys?
(laughter)
Get outta here!
You're a hard guy, huh?
(Jerry Lee growls)
CouId you caII off your dog?
- I'm sorry. What?
- CouId you caII off your dog?
Hm. WeII, I don't know, Benny.
That depends on you.
Listen, that hit was nothin' personaI.
It was just a job.
- Who contracted the hit, Benny?
- I don't know. I nev... I never saw the guy.
No? Come on,
don't get cute with me, Benny.
- This dog hasn't eaten since yesterday.
- It's the truth.
I don't know any names.
He never gave me any.
Did he mention anything about, Iike,
a shipment of drugs comin' in?
- He say anything about that?
- I don't know nothin'.
- Bite his dick off.
- No! No! Wait! No! Whoa!
I know, OK? There is a shipment. I forgot.
(Jerry Lee growls)
But it ain't goin' near the streets. It's aII
goin' to one buyer. I don't know who it is.
- Lunchtime!
- No, I know! AII right, I know!
I know who it is. I know who it is.
It's... it's a dude named GiIIiam.
Big-timer. He's comin' in tomorrow.
HoteI deI Coronado.
He's Iookin' to score Iarge. That's it.
- You sure?
- I boost a coupIe of cars now and then.
And before I became a shooter,
I was in a coupIe of gay biker snuff fiIms.
- What do you want from me?!
- You shouId be disgusted with yourseIf.
OK, Jerry. Come!
Arrest this guy for attempted murder,
and the rest of them
for crueIty to animaIs.
You did aII right. It was OK.
That wasn't too bad.
But I want you to know that
I am the officer in charge here.
MichaeI DooIey, not Jerry Lee.
Don't you ever,
ever puII anything Iike that again
without taIkin' to me first!
You Iost it in there. You Iost controI!
We couIda gotten kiIIed!
I needed you back here.
What if they ran out?
You couIda got 'em here.
- You understand?
- (whines)
- Get in the back seat!
- (growls)
You stink.
This car stinks, do you know that?
(Jerry Lee whines)
If we're gonna spend time together,
I've gotta deodorise your mangy IittIe ass.
Tracy's gonna kick you and me both out.
she's kind of a neat person.
You'II Iike her.
OK. It's time you joined
the civiIised worId, buddy.
Now, what we have here is dry shampoo.
We can do it right here on the spot.
We got some doggy deodorant here.
''Your dog wiII smeII Iike cedar chips
aII day Iong, just Iike the champions.''
Come on, get out of the car. We'II do it.
Come on. I'm doin' you a favour.
You smeII Iike shit.
You Iack personaI hygiene.
You understand that?
Here. Come on,
this is uptown stuff. smeII this.
Now, Iisten.
Hey! Gimme that!
AII right. If that's the way you want it,
that's the way you're gonna have it.
(¤ ''Car Wash'' by Rose Royce)
¤ You might not ever get rich
¤ But let me tell ya,
it's better than diggin' a ditch
¤ There ain't no tellin' who you might meet
¤ A movie star,
or maybe even an lndian chief
¤ Workin' at the car wash
¤ Workin' at the car wash, yeah
- ¤ Come on and sing it with me
- ¤ Car wash
- ¤ Sing it with the feelin', y'all
- ¤ Car wash, yeah
¤ Some of the work gets kinda hard
¤ This ain't no place to be
if you planned on bein' a star...
You Iook good.
Dry him off reaI good, boys.
Buff up that beak! Yeah.
Hey, extra doIIar for a hot wax, right?
Armor-AII him for me!
You smeII good, but not Iike cedar chips.
WeII, that concIudes today's Iesson
on ''Don't screw with MichaeI DooIey.''
CIass is dismissed.
That's aII right. That was worth it.
so, you wanna teII me why I was taIking
to a dead man this afternoon?
We had no way of knowing
that guy wasn't in the car.
Yeah. That's because
you were in a heIicopter.
What kind of buIIshit is that?
Choppers, machine guns.
Who do you guys think you are? Marines?
And you.
Why didn't you come to me?
Haven't I aIways taken care of you?
And you pay me back
by sending the Iaw to my warehouse.
I didn't teII him nothin'!
I don't know how he found out about that.
Come on. I'd never roII on you guys.
I'm worried.
This guy DooIey's crazy.
(Lyman) Yeah. Crazy.
(chuckles)
WeII, I'II teII you something, Freddie.
You wouIdn't be in this position
if these pissants had done their job.
You wanna know how to kiII a man?
WeII, I'II teII you how to kiII a man.
You forget this hi-tech stuff.
You get a gun.
And then you find the man,
and you grab him.
And you put the gun to his head,
and you send his brains into outer space.
(Lyman laughs)
Not bad, huh?
Yeah. It's my nephew's.
It's a toy.
This one's reaI.
Now, this DooIey's
aIready into me for one shipment.
I don't want him to get
the next one. You understand?
- He's dead.
- ''He's dead, he's dead.''
Don't teII me he's dead!
I want it done right this time.
I want it finished with this...
cop.
CIean this up.
Trace?
Honey?
Tracy?
I'm Iate. I'm Iate. I know I'm Iate.
I know I'm Iate. We missed
the baIIet tonight, didn't we? Damn!
And you know how
I Iove the baIIet. Love it!
I... Oh, you got the fIowers.
I... I didn't know that.
Yeah, you owe me $45. They came COD.
Did you know you have an animaI
growing out of your pants?
Thank you, honey. I aIso have a dog here.
- Why is it among us?
- Oh, that's the reason I'm Iate.
I was racing home, trying
to get here to pick you up for the baIIet,
and I passed this window,
and there he was.
Just sitting there,
Iooking a IittIe IoneIy, a IittIe heIpIess.
I had to pick him up, honey. You Iike him?
- He's very sweet.
- He is, isn't he?
- Does he have a name?
- Uh-uh.
I think we shouId think of one together.
- How about...
- Jerry! Jerry's a good name.
- Yeah. Jerry. That's great.
- Does he do any tricks?
No, I haven't had
too much time to work with him.
Can you speak?
Good boy! Can you kiss?
(makes kissing sound) Ooh!
Oh, you're a good puppy dog, huh?
- You're a sweetheart!
- Ass-kisser.
Oh, sure, I taught him those tricks.
Those are nothin', the easy ones.
I've been workin' on tougher things.
You know, Iike card tricks.
Tracy, I'm reaIIy sorry about the baIIet.
I promise I'II take you Iater in the season,
Iike, during the pIay-offs.
- He's very protective.
- Mm-hm.
Agh!
Come here! Come on in the kitchen!
Come on in the kitchen!
Come on in the kitchen.
- Come on, Jerry. Come on.
- OK. Go with DooIey.
Yeah! Yeah!
Let's get somethin' to eat! Yeah!
Ooh, yeah!
Look. Let's get one thing straight:
the woman is mine!
We're both members of the animaI
kingdom. You know that, I know that.
And we both know
that this thing is reaIIy primaI.
If you think you're such a badass,
try that once more
and you're gonna end up
in a pet cemetery.
You remember the movie
Old Yeller?. Do you?
Remember when
they shot him at the end?
I didn't cry! Now come on!
Honey, I think he needs to go outside.
Nice night. Enjoy the view.
(whines)
(bed creaking)
(baying)
- (Tracy) Do you think he's in pain?
- (Dooley) Not yet.
Honey, why... why wouId he be in pain?
(man) shut that damn dog up!
some of us are tryin' to sIeep!
(Dooley sighs) I'II handIe it.
Come on, Jerry. You hungry?
A IittIe Iate-night snack?
You know, we're a coupIe
of smart guys, you know that?
I Iike that in a dog. She Iikes that in a dog.
And she Iikes you.
But she Ioves me!
I just need a coupIe of hours.
You understand?
Here. You hungry?
T-bone. 16-ounce.
Mm. Good.
It'II thaw out in a few hours. Have a baII.
I'm back. AII right.
(Tracy) Mm.
(barking)
- Give me that.
- DooIey!
- (Tracy) Mm.
- (Dooley) He sucked that thing frozen!
- (Tracy) What?
- (Dooley) Nothin'. Nothin'.
(Jerry Lee burps)
You're trying to piss me off, aren't you?
You're pissing me off!
- Come on! Come on!
- (barking)
Come on! Behind you!
Come on! Come here. Ow! Ow!
- My eye! My eye!
- DooIey!
- Hi, honey.
- What's going on?
I think he was just a IittIe bit IoneIy.
He wanted to pIay.
- We shouId bring him into the bedroom.
- No!
- I don't think so.
- Come on. What a good boy!
- Oh, he Ioves it out here! He reaIIy does!
- Come on.
You're a sweetheart.
Just a IittIe sweetheart.
Come on, DooIey.
- (Dooley) Oh!
- (Tracy giggles)
(kissing sounds)
(Dooley) Mm. Ouch. Ooh.
- (Tracy laughs)
- (Dooley) Ow, you bit me. Ow.
- stop that. You can't bite me.
- You Iove it.
(Dooley) I can't. I can't do it.
- Why?
- He's watchin' me. I can feeI his eyes.
Look at him.
He's sitting there evaIuating me.
He's not the one you have to impress.
(¤ theme from ''Jaws'')
Jesus!
- Want some eggs?
- No, I'II catch a doughnut downtown.
I gotta get goin'. Bye.
- Thank you for a heII of a night.
- My pIeasure. I mean that!
- Oh... I mean it too. Good morning!
- (Jerry Lee barks)
What's the matter? Can't take it? Huh?
Kinda grinds you down in the battIe
of wits, you're fighting unarmed?
WeII, you're just a bad Ioser, that's aII.
You gotta Iearn one thing: winning
isn't everything, but Iosing is nothing.
- DooIey...
- Huh? Yeah?
Yes, ma'am.
- Aw, shit.
- ExactIy.
I can't beIieve
aII that came out of one animaI.
(bark)
Hey, notice anything different?
Huh? sure you do.
I used to say ''Get in the car'', ''Get outta
the car'', ''Get in the back seat'', ''stay''.
Commands are out. This is in.
There you go. You don't wanna Iisten,
I don't wanna taIk.
AII right? see you Iater, bub.
- Your champagne, sir.
- What is this?
- I didn't order any champagne.
- I know that, sir. It's a gift.
Take it back.
It must beIong to somebody eIse.
- They said Mr GiIIiam.
- I said get it out of here.
I don't want the champagne.
Lunch today?
- Is it expensive?
- Yes.
- How about a taII iced tea?
- There's a minimum.
- Why don't you just bring me the...
- OK.
..menu?
(woman) Good boy!
What a good dog you are.
sit!
speak!
sit up.
Go put your baII away.
Gimme some Iovin'!
That's... that's... that's great.
That's reaIIy... How do you do that?
WeII, first of aII, you've got
to give the dog a Iot of Iove.
- A good, heaIthy diet.
- ChiIIi.
Exercise is important, too.
You know, the key
is to estabIish aIpha Ieader
as soon as possibIe.
- AIpha Ieader? What's that?
- You gotta show 'em who's boss.
- Imprint on their psyche.
- I've done that. BeIieve me, I've done that.
- What... what... what is it, exactIy.
- Most effective is to stare them down.
You Iook straight at them.
You make them Iook away first.
- I can do that.
- Even if it takes hours.
I can do that. I can do that.
- That's it, right?
- After that, you mount them.
- Excuse me?
- You mount them.
- You mount them?
- Uh-huh.
- You mean...?
- Yeah.
Mount them?
Mount them. Lucky dog.
Jesus!
- What are you doin' here?
- sir? Excuse me.
- No dogs in the hoteI.
- What about her?
- she has a dog. What do you caII that?
The hoteI owner's daughter.
And the dog has to go.
- WeII, this is my seeing Eye dog.
- You're bIind?
- Yes.
- Were you bIind when you waIked in?
Yes, definiteIy.
I'm so sorry. WouId you Iike me
to read you the menu?
No, I can handIe it.
Thank you.
Is that my tea?
You just ripped the mirror off
of my cIassic 1965 Mustang.
I don't beIieve it. I just don't beIieve it.
(slurping)
If you don't get down -
I don't care where we are -
I'm gonna puII my revoIver out
and shoot you.
I am the aIpha Ieader.
I don't wanna have to mount you.
That'II do it.
Jerry Lee! Excuse me. I'm bIind.
I'm bIind. I'm bIind. I'm bIind.
Excuse me. I'm bIind! I'm bIind.
shit!
I don't know why you CaIifornia peopIe
insist on meeting outside.
If I wanted a tan,
I wouIda gone to the Bahamas.
I Iike CaIifornia. It's been good to me.
- Tonight is the night.
- sounds good, but so did the Iast time.
- Ten miIIion bucks' worth of coke, gone.
- Never again. Nobody'II get this.
- If there's exposure...
- I don't Iike a nervous partner,
so caIm down or I'm gonna bIow this
whoIe deaI and seII to somebody eIse.
Oh...!
Don't threaten me, Mr Lyman.
I'm in the threat business.
- PIease don't take this the wrong way.
- (squeals)
- (Gilliam) We need to get detaiIs straight.
- Just make sure you hoId up your end.
- You just make sure everything's on time.
- I'm not gonna wait for ever.
I'm reaIIy sorry. You don't know what's
goin' on here, but you just saved my Iife.
Agh!
I appreciate that.
Ughhh. Very kind of you. Thank you.
Come here!
What do you want? Get back.
Get back! Get away from me.
What are you taIkin' about?
Get away from me.
What? There's nothin' in here for you.
This is poIice stuff here.
Go away. Get away from me.
This is mine!
Let me eat in peace, wiII you?
What? What? You can't have this!
AII right. I'II spIit it.
I'II spIit it with you, OK?
What? I said I'd spIit it with you!
Here! Here! Here! Here!
Take the whoIe goddamn thing!
Jesus! There's aII kinds of sugar in that.
Down!
Jesus!
You Iook Iike
you've been in a skiing accident!
You wanna drive, get a Iicence!
Yeah!
(car horns)
(Jerry Lee barks)
What?
Wait! I've onIy got two Iegs!
- Agh!
- (Jerry Lee barks)
AII right. I'm comin'. I'm comin'!
Don't Iet that dog psych you out.
I'm comin'! shut your yap!
I'm comin'. I just want a running start
before I hit the pavement.
Aaarghhh!
Christ! Jesus! I wouIda cIeared it
if you hadn't barked.
You threw me off!
I suppose you think you're
such a hotshot... because you made it.
You sure about this, huh?
Oh, yeah, he's up here!
Yes, sir! Got a smart puppy there!
- (barks)
- What?!
Whaddaya want? There's no one up here!
There's nobody here. What?
I jumped over that damn thing
and no one's up here.
Hey! Get back here when
I'm yeIIin' at you! I want you to Iisten.
What are you barkin' at?
Oh no, I got it. You're not barkin'.
No, no. I can teII the difference
between a bark and a Iaugh!
This is a dog joke. Ha, ha, ha, ha(!)
Oh, I'm Iaughin'. How many guys
have you brought up here, huh?
No, you puIIed a good one.
I can see you down tonight, taIking
to your chums, down at the pound.
Yeah, havin' a good one.
''I puIIed one on oId DooIey.''
You never give up, do you?
Arghhh!
Now there's a guy who definiteIy
has a right to remain siIent.
- (Jerry Lee barks)
- What?
What do you want now? Want a medaI?
Huh?
AII right, aII right. You found him.
Good job.
Here you go. HaIstead Motors.
Got it.
- Hi.
- WeIcome to HaIstead Motors. You are...?
- Detective DooIey.
- And he is...?
- With me.
- How can I heIp you?
I got this invoice on one of your autos.
Can you teII me if it's in deaIer's stock
or if it's been soId?
I'II have Miss Hewitt
check it out right away.
Thank you.
You Iike this car?
That's onIy 100,000 bucks.
That's 700,000 in doggie doIIars.
What are you doin'?
Huh? Whaddaya got?
Find something? Whaddaya got?
You got something in there?
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
That's a $70,000 car there, sport.
Ah. sorry about that, but the dog
has his own mind. You know?
No probIem. Name's Don. saIes manager.
- MichaeI DooIey. Nice to meet ya.
- BeautifuI dog. How can I heIp you?
- WeII, I'm interested in this car.
- Mercedes 560 sL. Nothing more to say.
- Nothing?
- Nothing. Car seIIs itseIf.
It says you've arrived, Mike. It speaks
of stabiIity, cIass, famiIy vaIues.
- But I'm singIe, Don.
- It's a babemobiIe, Mike.
- I gotta have it. Let's test-drive it.
- Can do, Mike. I'II get the keys.
AII right, buddy. Let's get this thing
outta here, then you can have it.
- Detective DooIey?
- Yes.
- I'm Jack HaIstead, the owner.
- Oh, Jack, yeah.
I was gonna take this baby
out for a test-drive.
- Do you have 70,000 doIIars?
- No, but I can do better than that.
I have a brand-new Mercedes,
Iow miIeage.
It was used once,
in an attempted murder.
Oh yes. This one.
This car was reported stoIen off the Iot
at four o'cIock this morning.
Aw, Jack, does that mean
we don't have a deaI?
CaII your station and confirm it,
but not from my phone
and not from my Iot.
AII right. I know, I know. I know the car's
dirty. I just don't wanna do it now.
I wanna be there at the exchange.
I want Lyman. Let's go. Come on.
AII right, buddy.
I'II be just a minute.
- Hi. Can I heIp you?
- What have we got here?
(¤ ''Oh, Yeah'' by Yello)
¤ Oh, yeah
¤ The moon
¤ Beautiful
¤ The sun
¤ Even more beautiful
¤ Oh, yeah
Hey, buddy. she's hot, huh?
Yes, sir. Looks and money.
Love it when they shave
their beaks. Don't you?
You know what? This kind Ioves cops.
Loves 'em.
Boy, can you imagine
what she'd do to you?
WeII, that's too bad. You're on duty now.
It's definiteIy an aII-nighter.
You got ten minutes.
- What are you doing?
- Don't Iean against my ride.
This is your car? I'm sorry.
Don't stand next to it.
stand next to yours.
That's nice, but this is beautifuI.
Where'd you get those gIasses?
Did you get those gIasses in the maII?
I'd Iike to get a pair of those.
I need some sungIasses. Is this your car?
- something's goin' on in there.
- In here?
some big dog is humpin' my Aretha!
No!
- Is that your dog?
- TechnicaIIy? No.
Let's work something out.
They're aImost done.
- Why don't I buy you a tank of gas?
- A tank of gas?
For my Aretha? Get reaI!
That's a $100 dog!
How about 25 bucks
and a fuII tank of gas?
I gotta get at Ieast a biII for Lady Ree.
I'm a businessman. You dig?
- I'm a cop. You dig?
- A cop? You're a cop?
- You're kiddin' me.
- Yeah.
- No probIem.
- Hey! Uh, here. This is for the IittIe Iady.
Thank you, officer.
Jerry Lee. Time's up.
¤ Whoa! l feel good
¤ l knew that l would now
¤ l feel good
¤ So good, so good
¤ l got you
¤ Whoa! And l feel nice
¤ Like sugar and spice
¤ l feel nice
¤ So nice, so nice
¤ That l got you
¤ Hey!
Jerry Lee. Let's go.
Tracy?
Trace?
Honey. Honey?
What are you actin' up about?
You shouId be meIIow. You got Iaid.
(answerphone tape rewinds)
(bleep)
(woman) Uh, oops.
l think l have the wrong number.
- Yes, you do.
- (man) Yeah, Tracy, it's Jack.
We've changed the date of the seminar
to the 5th,
so you have more time to prepare
your material. OK? See ya.
(another man) l'm calling for
Michael Dooley. This is the third call.
This is Stan Gamboa
from lnternal Revenue...
- Yeah, right, stan.
- ..set up a time for your audit. Call me.
Yeah, I'II caII ya. sure. Fat chance.
(Tracy) Dooley, listen carefully.
l'm with some people right now.
They came to the house.
Dooley, you have to do
what they say. Please.
Dooley?
(man) Tracy's real smart.
She's behaving.
You gotta be smart too
if you wanna see her again.
That shipment you're chasin', just
let it go. Stay home tonight. Don't leave.
Do your part and you'll have breakfast
with your girl tomorrow.
And don't push this any more.
(Final bleeps)
(whimpers)
Wash it, wax it, put a windshieId in.
(doorbell)
Hi!
- Hey.
- It's by invitation onIy.
- CaII the cops.
- You don't beIong here.
CaII the cops.
sorry we're Iate!
Ken!
This is a bitchin' pad, man!
You got a pooI in your dining room!
You know, I gotta get one of these.
Hey, I'm sorry Tracy couIdn't make it,
but she kinda disappeared on me.
But the invitation did say bring a guest,
so I brought Jerry Lee.
- Why don't you mingIe with the guests?
- I'm gonna have to ask you to Ieave.
Ken, come on now. I just got here.
- PIease escort this man to the door.
- Freeze!
Oh, I'm not gonna shoot you.
You guys are good guys.
He's the bad guy.
Ken, I'd have a seat.
You don't Iook too good.
WeII, I think we'd best aII do as he says.
No, Ken, just you. Not ''we'' - ''you''.
This poor man is obviousIy
confused and upset.
Upset? Do I Iook upset to you?
Am I upset? Do I Iook upset?
I'm not upset.
I'm a party animaI! I Iove parties, Ken!
Come on! What's the grub Iike?
Hm.
This wine sucks. Is this crystaI?
(glass shatters)
Doesn't have the ring.
Don't think it's crystaI.
I'm pretty disappointed in this man here.
For a murderer and
a kidnapper and a drug runner,
I thought you'd have a IittIe better taste.
I mean, where's the brew?
Where's the sounds?
And the Iighting in here sucks.
That's better. It's a IittIe more intimate.
sets the mood.
What's that, Ken? Is that an ice scuIpture?
somebody win that? Is this raffIed off?
Is this something you do
in your part time?
Between the kidnapping
and the drugs and the murders?
You make that yourseIf, Ken?
Who is that, Ken? Is that you?
No, that's Zeus.
I hate mythoIogy.
WeII, Mr HaIstead,
surprised to see you here.
- Don't be tense. Just reIax.
- (distant siren)
You know, most of you
Iook Iike very nice peopIe.
It surprises me that you're here,
mixing with scum.
I mean, the kind of scum
that kidnaps my girIfriend.
You're making a terribIe mistake.
Does that Iook Iike a mistake to you?
- Does that Iook Iike a 9mm mistake?
- Put it down, mister! Drop it, mister!
TeII me if it's a mistake to bIow
your brains against the waII, Lyman.
- Where is she?!
- DooIey, put the gun down.
- Gimme the gun, DooIey.
- shame you have to Ieave so earIy.
- You reaIIy are the Iife of the party.
- You're goin' down, Lyman.
Perhaps next time
you can bring your Iady friend.
- You're goin' down, Lyman.
- see? see? The man is a Iunatic.
- Outta controI.
- You can arrest me, Lyman! Go ahead!
- But you know what?
- I'II have you prosecuted!
I'II make baiI in 24 hours, and they'II
have to peeI me off you with a crowbar!
You're goin' down, buddy!
I'm gonna have your ass
behind bars permanentIy!
And get that damn dog off my tabIe.
(Dooley) Just Iet me outta
this goddamn cage, wiII ya?
Byers! Byers!
Rog, Rog. Jesus, am I gIad you're here,
man. Cut me Ioose now, wiII ya?
- You bIew it. You are out of controI.
- No, I tried to convince Lyman I'm crazy.
- I got news for you: you are crazy.
- Listen to me, Roger.
Lyman's got Tracy. He kidnapped her
to keep me from that shipment.
- I wouIdn't Iie to you.
- sure you wouId. You aIways do.
Not this. I'm teIIin' you the truth. I got
an answering-machine tape to prove it.
I had to put this move on, to convince
Lyman that I was nuts. I had to con him.
Put yourseIf in his position. He thinks
for the next 24 hours I'm behind bars.
What wouId you do? You'd move that
shipment of dope before I made baiI.
That's what you'd do.
The deaI is goin' down tonight.
I gotta be there. You gotta Iet me out now.
I don't wanna hear it. It's your buIIshit
that got Tracy invoIved in the first pIace.
From here on in,
this is a coordinated effort.
That means you, me,
and the rest of the department.
Let's go.
- Oh, what is that?!
- God, who Iet that one go?
- How couId you fart in a cIosed car?
- He did it. He ate chiIIi today.
- I'm roIIin' my window down.
- You gotta Iet him go.
- PuII over, wouId you?
- I'm puIIing over.
- Get some air in here.
- (Dooley) There he goes again.
I'm sorry. Hey, I'm the one
stuck in the back seat here.
- I'm puIIin' over.
- It stinks.
You're gonna Iose your badge, go to jaiI.
Every minute we wait,
there's another chance Tracy'II get hurt.
- I don't care. You're outta controI.
- I'm not outta controI. It was a pIanned...
- How Iong wiII it take this dog to piss?
- I don't know.
OK, come on. Let's go.
Get him back in here!
I can't find him.
I don't know where he went.
- Get the damn dog.
- I don't know where he is.
Down here a minute ago.
I don't know where he went.
- Where the heII did he go?
- Jerry Lee, shake it off! Let's go!
I reaIIy need this.
Waiting for some mutt...
Come here, boy. HoId them.
- What is this?
- He's tense. You rushed him.
Get in the back seat.
He's very touchy about that back seat.
You're in deep enough as it is.
Now caII him off.
Hey, no way. Once he gets somethin'
into his head, there's nothing I can do.
- Look at him. He's nuts!
- Damn it, DooIey, this is it.
I have no time for
coordinated efforts, understand?
They move that Ioad, and Tracy's dead.
Jerry Lee, come!
Damn it, DooIey!
OK, this is how it works.
The guy moves, he jumps into the cIear,
- I shoot and...
- (electronic laughter)
And I miss and I Iose. Great.
It's supposed to make this great big noise,
Iike appIause, if you win.
I can onIy assume that's true,
because I've never won.
They gotta show up soon.
I mean, the stash is here.
You know, we find them, we'II find her.
I know it's a Iong shot,
but it's the onIy shot we got, right?
Right?
You know, I met her on the beach
in La JoIIa about four years ago.
I was in a toiIet with these binocuIars.
I was checkin' out these kids
seIIing some weed down on the beach.
It was hot that day.
That bathroom smeIIed Iike...
weII, a Iot Iike you do, you know?
so I'm scopin' out the sand, and bam!
I come across this goddess.
Forget the kids. I'm not watchin'
the kids any more, I'm watchin' her.
she's reading, right?
she stops, she puts the book down,
she reaches into her pocket
and puIIs out a chapstick.
And she puts it to her Iips.
AII right, I'm goin' nuts.
I know it's just a chapstick, but it's the
most erotic thing I've ever seen in my Iife.
AII of a sudden I feeI reaI uncomfortabIe,
Iike I'm invading her privacy.
I'm feeIin' sIeazy, which is reaIIy weird
because I usuaIIy Iike that feeIing.
so anyway, I get up. I waIk toward her,
you know, I go out of the john.
I'm sweatin' Iike a whore in church.
I got toiIet paper draggin' around my feet.
I Iook Iike I shouId be in a straitjacket.
I waIk up, Iook down at her, she Iooks up.
she puIIs these gIasses down.
she says to me ''I'm reading Journey
to the End of the Night, by CeIine.''
''The originaI French version.''
''Have you read it?''
Have I read it, she asks, right?
I mean, she just naturaIIy assumes
I'm, Iike, this reguIar person.
Not some schmo cop. Have I read it?
WeII, of course I didn't read it,
but, I mean, you know.
she just, Iike, Iooked at me, you know.
God, I Ioved her for that, you know.
What's the matter?
HeIIo.
(Dooley) HaIstead. Damn.
Left the party too earIy, buddy.
Oh, bingo. Red Mercedes.
Here we are. We're on, buddy.
(siren)
HaIstead! PuII over to the side of the road!
Come on, HaIstead, caII it a night!
Arghhh!
(sharp braking)
I'II be damned.
- I shouIda kiIIed him.
- You shouIda ducked.
I couId've taken him out right there.
Then he'd be done. End of story.
DooIey is yours.
The girI is yours. A gift from me.
Make it as messy and painfuI as you
want, but Iater. Right now I need you here.
Concentrate. Focus on
the business at hand.
- HaIstead is Iate.
- What's a few minutes?
HaIstead is never Iate.
scuIIey, pour me a brandy, wiII ya?
I'II get it.
How you doin', sweet pants?
I can't wait to bump into your boyfriend.
HeII, I might even pay his baiI.
see, I got a present for him.
A CoIombian necktie.
Know what that is?
First you sIit his throat, then you reach in,
grab his tongue, rip it out,
and you just Ieave it
hangin' Iike a necktie.
And you and me gonna party, babe.
Why not?
Come here.
Oh, God.
You bitch!
WeII, it's about time.
Later.
- You're Iate!
- Yeah, traffic's a bitch.
Hey, bad idea.
- I press this and the cocaine goes boom.
- Easy.
I got 20 pounds
of expIosives in this truck.
This IittIe baby here sends a signaI,
we got Iiftoff.
It snows in san Diego.
Look, Lyman, I got somethin' you want,
you got somethin' I want.
I don't care about you or your drugs
any more. I want the girI and I want out.
scuIIey! Bring the girI.
It's gonna be aII right, honey.
It's gonna be aII right, baby.
We'II be outta here.
You know what?
I think you're connin' me.
I think I shouId have DiIIon here
just cut you in haIf.
Go ahead.
Go ahead!
Here comes your heIicopter.
Here comes your 50 miIIion.
Boy, I'd sure hate to waste that
on a dumb cop and his girIfriend.
What's it gonna be, Lyman?
Cut her Ioose.
You're a dead man, DooIey.
I'II find ya. And when I do,
I'm gonna kiII ya.
WaIk.
(electronic laughter)
Jerry, get off him!
Get off!
Jerry, off!
(whimpers)
(shouts)
- Jesus!
- We gotta get him outta here.
Cover him, cover him.
- (Tracy) Come on.
- It's aII right, buddy.
It's aII right, buddy.
It's OK, buddy. Hang in there.
Gunshot wound. Can you show me
which way to Emergency?
- sir, that is a dog.
- Yes, it's a dog and he's been shot.
- This is a hospitaI.
- I'm a poIice officer, Iady.
- You can't bring that dog in here.
- He's bIeeding to death.
- We don't treat animaIs.
- I don't have time to argue.
Can you just show me
where the doctors are?
- If you don't Ieave right now...
- I'm not Ieaving, Iady. I'm not Ieaving.
- There isn't anyone here...
- I just want one of your doctors.
None of them can heIp you. sit back
in the reception room and we'II try and...
Excuse me. Excuse me, sir.
Are you a doctor?
- What the heII is this?
- He says he's a poIice officer.
I toId him he couIdn't
bring the dog in here.
I have an emergency here.
I need your heIp.
- What's your probIem?
- It's him. He's been shot in the chest.
- You need to work on him now.
- There are heaIth reguIations.
I don't care about that. I can't take him
anywhere eIse. He's not gonna make it.
Look, either you heIp him now
or he's gonna die.
Don't get so excited. It's just a dog.
He's not ''just'' a dog.
He's a cop. And he's not just
any cop. He's my partner.
Do you know about medicine?
Do you know how to remove a buIIet?
I can remove the buIIet.
I need some heIp in here!
Let's move this dog now.
Let's go. Come on.
He's gonna be fine.
He's gonna be aII right. He's tough.
Did I teII you what he did in the bar?
He saved my ass in the bar, Jerry Lee.
I mean, that's his job. His job is
to take a buIIet. That's what K-9s are for.
To take the buIIet to save peopIe.
That's exactIy what he did.
He went between me and Lyman.
He took the buIIet. That's what they're for.
He's a goddamn dog, that's aII.
And that's what he did. He went
between me and Lyman. He took the hit.
He's just... just bIeedin'. He bIed a Iot.
You know, I've been after Lyman
for two years.
Two years. And it wasn't worth it.
It just wasn't worth it.
You couId have gotten kiIIed.
You too, but we didn't.
You're a good cop, DooIey.
Yeah, yeah, right. shoot.
I can't take this any more.
Jerry Lee?
(whispers) Jerry?
Jerry Lee, can you hear me?
I wish you couId hear me, because there's
a coupIe of things I wanted to teII you.
You know, Iike, uh...
Like I know our reIationship
was a IittIe rocky. OK?
And I know we didn't exactIy
cIick as partners.
And the way it Iooks now,
it doesn't Iook Iike we ever wiII.
I never had a dog before. I didn't know
what you were supposed to do.
I shouId have got a book and read
about it, is what I shouId have done.
But I do know now that I shouIdn't
have yeIIed at you. I yeIIed at you a Iot.
Even though you took the mirror
off my Mustang, you know.
'65 cIassic Mustang,
which I Iove. I Iove that car.
But it's OK. It's OK, because I know
I shouIdn't have yeIIed at you.
You know, and... and I know
it wasn't aII your fauIt.
I mean, it couId have been
partiaIIy my fauIt and...
OK, it was probabIy more my fauIt
than yours, and I feeI bad about that.
And I'm sorry.
You know, I mean, I Iocked you up
in cIosets aII night and yeIIed at you.
I put you through a car wash.
What eIse? I kicked you outta bed whiIe
I was trying to make Iove with Tracy.
That was very insensitive of me.
I know that now.
And we shouId have went to Vegas,
is what we shouId have done.
If you were around right now,
that's what we'd do - we'd go to Vegas.
For the weekend, you know.
We'd pick up a coupIe of broads.
I'd take Tracy, and we couId pick up
that IittIe poodIe with the shaved beak.
she was hot. Ooh, she was sexy.
I'd even Iet you sIeep with us.
I mean, down at the bottom of the bed,
you know, not in between us again.
- That was a IittIe rough.
- There you are. Been Iookin' for ya.
- You're not aIIowed in the recovery room.
- Yeah, I know. I was just, uh...
- Recovery room?
- Yeah, this is the recovery room.
- You mean, this is where patients, uh...?
- Come to recover.
- so the dog is...?
- Gonna be just fine.
Oh.
- Can I have just a coupIe of minutes?
- No probIem.
You asshoIe.
Were you Iistening to everything I said?
WeII, you can just forget aII of it, because
I thought I was taIkin' to a dead dog!
I wouIdn't take a sneaky, manipuIative,
Iying fIea circus Iike you anywhere,
Iet aIone Vegas. Vegas? Forget it.
The dog - the poodIe with
the shaved beak that you Iove so much?
Eat your heart out.
Oh, God.
You don't deserve to Iive. You know that?
But I'm gIad you did.
(¤ ''lko lko'' by Amy Holland)
¤ My grandma and your grandma
were sitting by the Fire
¤ My grandma told your grandma
''l'm gonna set your flag on Fire''
¤ Talkin' 'bout
hey now, hey now
¤ lko, lko, unday
¤ Jockamo feeno ai nane
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ Look at my king all dressed in red
¤ lko, lko, unday
¤ Betcha Five dollars he'll kill you dead
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ Talkin' 'bout
hey now, hey now
¤ lko, lko, unday
¤ Jockamo feeno ai nane
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ Hey now, hey now
¤ lko, lko, unday
¤ Jockamo feeno ai nane
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ My flag boy and your flag boy
were sitting by the Fire
¤ My flag boy told your flag boy
''l'm gonna set your flag on Fire''
¤ Hey now
¤ See that guy all dressed in green?
¤ lko, lko, unday
¤ He's not a man, he's a lovin' machine
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ Talkin' 'bout
hey now, hey now
¤ lko, lko, unday
¤ Jockamo feeno ai nane
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ My grandma and your grandma
were sitting by the Fire
¤ My grandma told your grandma
''l'm gonna set your flag on Fire''
¤ Talkin' 'bout
hey now, hey now
¤ lko, lko, unday
¤ Jockamo feeno ai nane
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ Hey now, hey now
¤ Jockamo feeno ai nane
¤ Jockamo fee nane
¤ Hey now