We are identical twins...
but we are poles apart.
He lags behind
where as I, zoom ahead.
He stammers and...
I pronounce S as F.
On his death bed, my father said...
Charlie, always remember...
life is a bitch!
And the only way to deal with life,
is to be...
(Scoundrels)
The path we choose doesn't
screw our life...
what screws us is...
the path we leave behind!
There are two ways to
earn a quick buck!
A shortcut...
and a shorter shortcut!
Get him!
I took the shortcut...
yet my dreams got screwed.
Big time!
Blue thunder.
My dreams...
My sweet little dreams.
My life...
my whole wide world...
My booking window.
In reality...
I'm just a small time gangster.
Our gang fixes derbies.
Come on! Come on!
People bet money on the
favorite horses that win...
...but we bet on losing.
Blue thunder was
favorite in yesterday's derby.
This race was fixed.
I had bet my life time earning,
rupees hundred thousand...
...on that horse.
But the jockey double crossed us.
I had to pay a heavy
price for this shortcut.
Our booking company lots
its reputation and hazard.
The company is run by
three Bengali brothers.
This is Mujeeb and that's Shumon.
Mikhail, the third Bengali brother.
- How're you?
- The same as you!
My buddy, dearer
than my own brother.
A kid at heart but...
a maniac in the head.
Indian National Small Arms System.
In short INSAS.
The heroine of the Kargil war...
purely homebred.
A distant cousin of the AK47.
Weight: 6.37 kgs.
Range: 700 meters.
Feed: 30 round
- plastic box magazine.
How many can it kill in one round?
Sir, you'll lose count, but
the bullets will carry on.
- Some people change with time...
and how the times change for some.
Arsehole...
money can be quite the devil.
You had to pull the reins here.
Double cross Burgess!
Double cross!
- Shumon! - Yes...
The viewfinder is screwed.
Bro says the viewfinder is off mark.
Not possible, sir.
Big brother never lies!
Please don't do this.
Do what?
You screw us all over...
that's cool, huh?
The sky disappeared and...
my balls vanished from my boxers!
- You know how much we lost?
Charlie, they will kill me.
And we will worship you!
Stop crying, you rascal!
Brother says if he
aims at Burgess' head...
the bullet will hit
the clock instead.
- Not the clock... the lamp.
The lamp!
- Please forgive me!
I'm the one who is screwed here.
Royally screwed!
If I start crying,
you'll drown in my tears.
I want his name!!
Francis!
Franfif?
You're growing senile day by day.
You've absolutely lost it!
What if I were shot?
My cute little darling...
Stop flashing your pearlies!
He almost crapped in his pants!
Even you would've crapped!
Such a coward!
You really thought
he would shoot you?
You are shit scared!
What did you say?
Growing senile day by day?
You're absolutely right!
All three are nuts!
Every brother
in the world is crazy.
Just like mine!
Here comes the Love Bee
Whiplash him, Fatak!!
Here he comes- humming
Here comes the Love Bee-
Bumbling through the lanes
Hasn't found anyone
worth desiring, no, not yet
Whiplash him, Fatak!!
He deals off his friends
Look at the dandy,
the way he struts
He deals off his friends
Look at the dandy,
the way he struts
Full of swagger and all
Whiplash him, Fatak!!
Hurl him on the ground
Dare you count on him as a friend
The rogue aimlessly
tramps the streets
Dare you count on him as a friend
The rogue aimlessly
tramps the streets
This leech will always feed on you
He may go but will return soon
In every defiled droplet of blood
To nibble your life away
Look, look he returns
He returns this
illicit child of the night
Whiplash him, Fatak!!
Here comes the Love Bee-
Here he comes- humming
Bumbling through the lanes
Hasn't found anyone
worth desiring, no, not yet
Here comes the Love Bee-
Here he comes- humming
This love is not easy
The fear of AIDS hovers around
Wear your oars
This river is made of fire
Be careful, lest your boat capsizes
Be careful, lest the Love Bee stings
Jeetu, where's Guddu?
Where's Guddu?
Guddu!
We need to talk...
Listen!
Guddu listen to me...
The boat capsized...
Capsized!
- Let's do another test?
This was the third.
When did you go for the other two?
Why didn't you tell me?
- I didn't want to
stress you out... - And now?
Now where's your s... s...
Sincerity?
Safety?
- What is it? - Science!
Home science? Huh?
It was right here...
Kama Sutra condoms, a full packet.
Forget about it.
I'm a topper in home science.
- Home science?
What do you mean?
I mean...
there's no danger today.
I don't like anything between us.
Nothing!
Glad the damn thing is lost.
Let me take one last look...
- it's got to be here.
- You're such a dork.
- Let it be!
Do you know the distance
it creates between us?
You're in New... New...
New Jersey?
- New... - New Zealand?
New Delhi?
New... New...
New Bombay.
Not Bombay... Mumbai.
You love Mumbai?
- Yes, doctor. I'll call you later.
He says it will be done in a day.
I can be back in four hours...
same day.
Fix an appointment for tomorrow?
- Please say something.
- Do as you like.
I won't be part of this murder.
What do you mean?
Oh my!
Got it!
My single piece.
We'll sail through!
I'm ready to be a mother...
But I'm not ready to
become a father!
Please understand, my dear!
We don't have enough
to support each other.
How do we support a child?
Things will fall into place.
This is our destiny.
Our destiny is screwed. Big time!
I can't get married right now.
Period!
Why not?
All yours.
My life... my plan... my future...
Marriage in 2014...
and honeymoon in 2009!
Bravo Mr Sharma. Bravo!
You wanted it!
And you didn't?
No!
So I must have raped you then!?
And all those promises...
was it the booze?
"Baby! It feels as though
I've known you for ages."
Please, listen...
I'll take up a job.
But I still can't
marry you now. I mean...
"I mean... I
mean..." What do you mean?
You don't want an
abortion nor want to marry.
What do you want?
I just want to die.
Fine! Go die!
Please Guddu... please...
I can't see you die.
- I am not committing suicide.
I know but if we
don't get married soon...
you'll be killed for sure.
- Listen... my full name is...
- Sweety Shekhar Bhope.
I'm Sunil "Chopper" Bhope's sister.
Guddu...
Bho... Bho...
pe!
Hail Maharashtra!
- We sent someone to check.
She hasn't been to
college for a month.
Uncle...
- Been bunking!
- Who's the boy?
- I want a chocolate!
- Some "Guddu".
- Address? - Navi Mumbai
- Uncle, I want a chocolate...
- Shut up!
Miser!
- Get the cars out! - Chief,
listen to me...
We've got that
interview lined up for today.
It's taken us 15
years to clear our name.
Today is your interview.
Live on television.
Just relax and...
let me handle this.
Trust me on this one.
Look at that...
your blood sugar level
is down to 110.
We'll slice the boy and
serve him for dessert.
- Hail Maharashtra!
It's not my fault
that he is my brother!
The fault is that you lied to me.
Why?
Don't you trust me?
Have some water.
Add some poison as well.
Then you will die.
At least I'll be out of your way.
That's the point!
I'm as good as dead without you!
Then we will float
around as ghosts!
And your brother can't stop
ghosts from getting married.
There's a slight problem though.
Can ghosts have kids?
Idiot!
So... when do we take the plunge?
Today...
now...
Hello... hello...
Can you hear me?
Yes, go ahead.
Yes, it's fixed.
Eight o'clock? Hold on...
Is eight o'clock fine?
- For what? - Our wedding...
- Eii... eight... - Yeah...
eight o'clock.
Today?
Nope... in 2014!
Yes... eight o'clock sounds good.
When days are dogs...
Life's a bitch!
Once there was some
integrity in this business...
but not anymore!
And now, my mind is
occupied with just one name...
Franfif!
- I found Franfif...
Awesome!
He is staying right here.
Room 716.
- He fixing a race right now!
Alright, I'll inform
big bro. Leave right now.
And when I say leave,
you better leave.
- Let's go.
- Come on...
- We leave this way.
But destiny lies that way.
Mr Narang?
Hey... hi...
how are you doing today?
You know actually, we've
just forgotten the keys inside.
Do you have a master key on you?
Sir...
Please don't kill me.
I've got two little kids and...
I love my wife, Lobo Sir...
Lele Sir... please don't kill me.
- From today I'm Tashi's pet...
- Where are you?
- Where do you think?
Got the guitar?
Come over to the
Madh Island bungalow.
Cool!
Afghanibhai, is Tashi around?
- Why?
The airline guys are
offering a deal.
Hold on...
Tashi...
- the flight purser at the
hotel has something to say.
Go on...
Tashi, he wants to say that...
he is now your pet dog.
But I like bitches!
I have far too many dogs.
Shoo away... shoo...
What the hell!!
- Where are the Africans?
- In Goa.
Call them.
Tell them the guitar
has been arranged for.
Tell them to get
my twins by tonight.
They will pick you up for
the racecourse tomorrow.
The Bengalis are sniffing
you down like rabid dogs.
Anything you need, will
be delivered to your room.
Don't move out!
- Sure.
But I'll need a wakeup call.
I'll be fast sleep,
counting horses instead of sheep.
How the times have changed...
- You got your gun on you? - Yes.
Go back and give it to him.
- Okay.
Why take a chance?
- Meet me in the parking lot.
- Okay.
I want my money back. One lakh.
- He only has pennies.
Look for his ATM card.
You want to become a bookie,
don't you?
- I'll get it done in a jiffy.
Let's just give the gun and leave.
Packing the whole hotel in or what?
Help! Room Service!
This way!
Come along!
Shut it!
What was that?
Stop the car!
Damn it! Stop the car!
They're getting away!
Stop them!
Damn! Cops! We are screwed!
Don't freak out!
Steve... pass my shades! My shades!
We'll make it, don't worry.
That was close.
- You knew that guy? - Nope!
Then why did you salute him?
Because he saluted me!
Why would a cop salute you?
What!?
Hey junkies... What the hell?
Sir, seems like it was a major deal.
And it went wrong!
On the floor where we
found the dead bodies...
the security cameras were damaged
What are you doing?
- Did you have prior information?
We were expecting someone but...
did you check the
other security cameras?
- No, it's being done.
- Then do it!
You want to talk?
Okay... move it!
- Where the hell are you?
- Afghanibhai...
There's a problem.
We were leaving the hotel...
but got stuck in a
crossfire between two gangs.
- You are still in Panvel?
- Yes...
and the DCP is here as well.
It's difficult to leave.
Like I care!
We fixed the
delivery as per your time.
- I get it but...
please try and understand.
Try telling this to Tashi.
I'll hand him the phone.
Look, security is tight
and sniffer dogs are around.
What's more important?
Guitar's safety
or scheduled delivery?
Fine! Commit a final time!
Problem, safety and all that.
Tell me!
- Eight... - Eight o'clock.
Tomorrow morning?
Why don't you come over here...
and collect it yourself.
OK! But eight means eight, clear?
Loud and clear!
By the way...
- the guitar is safe?
- Should I play a tune?
- See you tomorrow. - Tune?
- Where is Sweety?
- Tear this place apart!
Tell me or I'll break your head!
He is Charlie's brother.
Charlie who?
That gambler from the train yard!
- Chief, there is
good news and bad news.
He seems to be a nice guy.
- Works for an NGO besides...
Bad! Give me the bad!
They genuinely love each other!
They're getting married.
- I could stop it if you say so.
But they do look like...
they're made for each other.
I'll get your mom hooked up
with him!
- Get me Sweety on the phone!
- Yes, Chief!
- As soon as I get there.
Damn it! What's going on!
From the frying pan into the fire...
and back into the frying pan!
Forget it.
Don't even think about it!
Just get away!
Charlie...
The shortcut...
or the shorter fhortcut!
- But...
- But what?
Don't forget!
The path you choose
doesn't screw your life...
what screws you is...
the one you leave behind!
Greetings, everyone.
Please remain seated.
- Sweety dear...
- Where have you been?
Been looking all over for you.
Greetings! I am your brother-in-law.
I consider myself an
Indian first and then a Marathi.
But what annoys me is
that my house guest...
who shares my food...
shares my wages...
drinks my milk...
saves the butter for his own toast.
How is that fair?
- Now even... - Cut!
Brother...
Why are you doing this to me?
I wanted to make your
wedding a grand affair.
Why did you hurt me?
You wanted me to marry
that builder's son...
And who is this boy?
What is his name?
- Tell me...
Sanjay...
Sanjay? Give me his full name!
Sanjay Kumar Sharma, son
of Kishan Kumar Sharma...
bows to the 25 crore
Gods and Goddesses...
Hang on!!
Come again. What is his name?
Sanjay Kumar Sharma.
Sanjay Kumar Sharma?
- Where are you from?
Barabanki.
Barabanki? U.P.
Holy crap!
Give me the phone.
Just give the damn phone!
Chief... we are screwed!
He is a bloody migrant, from U.P.!
- We've identified the dead bodies.
They belong to the K D Narang gang.
But the boy in the camera footage...
- Don't know how he
is connected to this.
Investigations are still on.
This way, Sir...
Play it.
Rewind... slower...
Get him! Closer.
Beat the crap out of him.
Bloody migrant!
Let him go...
I would've killed you right now...
You sons of bitches!
- Leave him... - Sweety get away!
Guddu, get up!
Dare not touch him!
Don't you get it?
Your chief is ready to
trade his sister for votes.
I don't want to marry
that builder's wretched son.
At least you should've
supported me.
- I'll speak to chief...
- Back off!
You...
Get the car keys. Move it!
To hell with the polictics...
that builder's son...
To hell with brother!
I'll talk to him...
Douse the fire!
They're getting away!
Awesome! Killer stuff!
Where did you get it from?
How much do I get?
How much do you want?
Ten!
You got it!
Lakhs!
For one packet?
A hundred packets!
A hundred!
You created a ruckus at
the hotel, didn't you?
I told you to leave immediately.
Leaving wouldn't have helped.
Opportunity came
knocking and I grabbed it!
Lady luck smiled on me!
A hundred packets of...
cocaine!
- And they belong to?
Us!
What will you do with ten lakhs?
I'll become a bookie.
You bloody scoundrel!
Open your mouth
- ha ha ha!
No...
- With a hundred
packets we'll make enough...
- to own the entire racecourse!
And then!
Spain... France...
Miami... Copacabana...
Psychedelic Trance! Dude!
Come on!
Let's rock!
Shake the booty!
Come, let's wring our hearts
Smash the pot of the night
Come, let's pry out some good luck
Let's break into the vault
Tiny sprouts of leafy cress,
and oil from oilman's press
Life is nothing but money's play
Let's have a face-off
on the roads tonight
Step out Life is a one way
All you get is one chance
Nothing ahead but thin air
And the romance lasts
till the breath does
This is what they say
This is what we hear
Whosoever surges ahead
Never does come back
Come, let's wring tomorrow
Smash the pot of the night
Come, let's pry out some good luck
Tonight, let's break into the vault
Tiny sprouts of leafy cress,
and oil from oilman's press
Life is nothing but money's play
Let's have a face-off
on the roads tonight
Looks like an amateur crook.
The revolver, money,
everything is still here.
Is anything missing?
This time lets play such a game
That the ocean walks
over the bridge
Then whether you
walk on the bridge or I
The city will stay under our feet
Somewhere the news are grave
Somewhere there are just graves
Hush! Let's not wake up the dead
Come, let's wring our hearts
Smash the pot of the night
Come, let's pry out some good luck
Let's break into the vault
Dhan te nan...!
I've got the tickets and passports.
Go and freshen up soon!
I'll get the first-aid box.
Hurry up!
- We will miss the flight!
What is wrong with you?
What's wrong?
I almost flunked
in the sixth grade.
What?
We sat on the same bench.
Both of us.
Who both?
Sabiha and I.
Sabiha Laeek Ahmed.
I was in love with her.
She loved hearing s...
stories from me.
Champak, Nandan...
Bela Bahadur... comics.
Then one day I realised...
it wasn't the stories she loved.