HITMAN: You gotta know what
you're doing when you go in.
You gotta have
it figured out.
Those are the rules.
How you get in,
how you get out,
how many shots
you're gonna need.
Make sure you know
where everybody is.
Make sure nobody sees you.
Don't hang around.
Don't get interested.
Then you
don't make mistakes.
[Phone ringing]
[Ringing]
Yeah.
MAN: How'd you like
to go to Detroit
and see a man in a hotel
Friday morning?
HITMAN:
I don't do that anymore.
MAN: I'll double your price.
You can do
whatever you want.
Can't hear you, chief.
I'm taking it
this guy in the hotel
is somebody you don't want
to look in the face.
I'm thinking maybe
it's the old man
with the big house
you want to move into.
Guy past his time,
and he don't like
how you do things.
Hey, fuck you.
I'll get somebody else.
You don't have
no somebody else.
You call me when your people
won't do it.
MAN: You want to leave it
all behind, chief,
here's your chance.
You have a Cadillac...
a blue one.
MAN: Yeah.
HITMAN:
Throw that in there,
you'll never see me
again.
MAN: You can collect your money
next Tuesday.
Union Station, usual place.
He'll have a girl with him.
She'll let you in.
HITMAN: Papa.
OLD MAN: Yeah?
You got somethin' for me?
HITMAN:
From your son-in-law.
OLD MAN: Oh, Christ.
I told my daughter,
"Don't marry that punk."
She don't listen.
I give him six months.
There'll be another funeral.
You want him done
sooner than that,
you tell me.
Who the hell are you?
You don't remember?
Should I?
You know
Walpole Island, Papa?
It's an Indian reserve.
My grandmother lives there.
She's a medicine woman.
She was going to turn me
into an owl one time.
I told her,
"I don't want to be no owl.
I want to be a blackbird."
That's how I got my name.
Blackbird.
You remember now.
The Degas brothers,
one killed working for you,
shot dead in the hospital,
the other one doing life
in Kingston.
I'm the only one left.
Huh.
Can she do that?
Turn you into an owl?
If she want to.
I could use
a woman like that.
I'd like to be dressed.
Is that okay with you?
Whatever you want.
WOMAN: Are you through?
Not yet.
# My, my #
# Little white lies #
# Swear I'm gonna
make it right #
# This time #
# Start the radio #
# Turn it way down low #
# Tellin' me things
I do not know #
# I know #
And it could be used equally
as a recreation room or a den.
WOMAN BUYER:
Look in here, Dan.
AGENT: Quite a lovely,
distinctive entrance hall,
which is so practical
and elegant, don't you think?
Thank you.
# Now who's to blame? #
# You used to be the same #
MAN: Wayne! Foreman!
WAYNE: What?!
What?!
# It's a suicide #
MAN: And don't bother
comin' back!
# Shut up and drive #
RICHIE: Mrs. Palino.
Richie Nix.
You were my foster mom
for a while.
I had a collection
of old Elvis vinyls
I left here a while back.
My girlfriend,
she's a big Elvis fan.
We thought we'd come by
and, uh,
pick 'em up from you.
Last time I saw you,
you drove off in my car.
Go fuck off
before I call the police.
# Tonight you will be mine #
WOMAN: It's okay.
# Tonight the monkey dies #
# Tonight you will be mine #
If you're lookin' for
your grandmother, she's gone.
We buried her last winter.
WAYNE: Gonna spend
a few weeks huntin' deer.
LIONEL: Be sure and pour
some of this stuff on ya.
Here.
Thanks.
Wayne?
Yeah?
You lookin'
for another job?
I don't know.
Try my hand
at real estate maybe.
Put you in an office
and a suit.
Ha ha! You bet!
Hey, Lionel.
Where's your cane?
I'm sorry
about your grandmother.
The band office
has been trying to locate
the next of kin
to find out what to do
with her house.
Hey, I been thinking.
When I get paid
for this job I done,
maybe I could fix
the place up.
You could sell it
the way it is.
No, I mean fix it up
and live here.
A guy like you,
used to living
in the city?
There's no life
for you here.
I could always be
a friendly Indian like you,
maybe even a guide.
You wouldn't like it.
Why not? You do.
Hey, Lionel,
come on, you telling me
I can't live here?
Hey, you ever ride
in a Cadillac?
Come on. We'll take a drive.
Go to Algonac,
have some drink.
You go.
I got to go home.
WAYNE: Hey.
Hi.
WAYNE: Didn't let myself in.
Right.
Which is kind of weird.
CARMEN: Well,
I made a start.
I thought I'd leave
the hunting things for you.
Okay.
CARMEN: Well, the guns
I understand,
but why the suit?
You gonna rob a bank?
You mind if I leave
some of this stuff here
till next time?
What's this?
Buck lure.
Oh! God,
that smells like hell.
Not to a buck it don't.
So when is next time?
Tomorrow after work?
Could be
anytime tomorrow.
What happened
to 350 Jefferson?
They want to put me
on a detail gang
on the ground.
I said no.
That's an old man's job.
# It hurts me
to see him treat you #
# The way that he does #
# It hurts me to see you
sit and cry #
# When I know
I could be so true #
# If I had someone like you #
# It hurts me
to see those tears... #
Nelson Davies Realty.
Nelson Davies speaking.
Nelson,
this is Wayne Colson.
# The whole town is talking #
# They're calling you a fool #
# For listening
to his same old lies #
# And when I know
I could be so true #
# If I had someone like you #
# Hurts me to see the way
he makes you cry #
# You love him so much #
Nelson Davies Realty.
Nelson Davies speaking.
RICHIE: Them Tanglewood homes
are goin' fast, huh?
They sure are, sir.
Let me tell you why.
RICHIE: I bet they'd go even
faster if they caught fire.
Who's this?
It can happen anytime.
Pine Ridge was
just a rearrangement.
Just a little wear and tear.
But it could happen again,
or you can pay
so it won't...
like insurance.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
RICHIE: You get 20,000
cash ready,
and I'll come pick it up
sometime.
You don't have it
when I come to collect,
you're dead. You be ready,
'cause you don't know
when I'm gonna
walk through that door
or which one that comes in
I'm gonna be.
And I'll tell you
somethin' else.
You remember a guy
worked at an Amoco station,
one up in Port Huron?
Got shot dead last year
during a holdup.
I might have read
something about that.
Yeah. Well, that was me.
20,000
when I come to collect,
or you're
a dead real estate man.
MAN ON PA: Platform 0-3,
1510 to Montreal.
Calling at Oshawa, Belleville,
Kingston, Cornwall, and Dorval.
[Phone ringing]
Yeah?
You owe me some money.
MAN: The fuckin' money's
the price
on your fuckin' head,
you piece of shit.
Who the fuck told you
to kill the girl?
She saw my face.
Who cares, she saw
your fuckin' face?!
She worked for me!
You better listen to me,
you half-breed fuckin' moron.
You're dead.
You understand?
I don't care you shoot
your own brother,
you're so drunk.
You touch what's mine,
you're dead.
[Rock music]
That's a cool car.
I'm lookin' for a ride.
Well, good luck.
No, you say,
"Which way you goin'?"
and I say, "Any way I want."
RICHIE: Don't worry.
I ain't gonna hurt you.
I just need your car
for a little business
I'm plannin'.
See, usually, I rob banks,
but 2,700's the best
I ever did up in Ohio.
This time I got somethin'
way bigger in mind.
You got Indian blood,
don'tcha?
Enough to own a casino.
You got a cool name?
A cool name?
Yeah, you know,
I mean, "Red Elk"
or "Running with the Wolves"?
Blackbird.
Blackbird?
Yeah, that's pretty cool.
Well, my name's Richie Nix,
in case you ever heard of me.
It's N-I-X.
It's not the way
Stevie Nicks spells hers.
Turn left up here.
All right.
Now let me have
your wallet.
Hey! What the hell
you think you're doin'?
You wanted my wallet.
Yeah. Nice and slow.
What's L and M Distributing?
A company
I used to work for.
Uh, what do they distribute?
Pepperoni.
Pepperoni company
gives you a Cadillac to drive?
What the fuck
you do for them?
I shoot people.
Sometime for money,
sometime for nothing.
And then I told him
about this Amoco station
I held up a while back.
One up in Port Huron.
You might have heard about it.
I told him I ended up havin'
to blow a guy away up there,
so now he's scared.
That's when I hit him with it.
20,000 cash,
or you're fuckin' dead.
I could hear the phone
shakin' in his hands.
Yeah, scare a guy enough,
he'll pay every time.
BLACKBIRD: A man's scared
don't always do what you expect.
Yeah, but...
You don't
want to talk too much,
let him know
what you're thinking.
You want to take him
by surprise.
You have something to wear,
suit or something?
You want to look the part.
See? Now, that's why I need
a fuckin' partner, man.
I mean it. I have no patience
for details like that.
You ever work
with anyone before?
My brothers.
One is in prison forever...
and my kid brother is dead.
You remind me of him.
He was a stupid guy.
So, uh, Blackbird...
how's 10,000 sound?
Bird.
Bird?
That's what my kid brother
used to call me.
All right, Bird.
We got a deal?
MAN ON PA: Welcome
to Nelson Davies Realty,
the number one agency
in the Anchor Bay area,
serving the whole community
with expertise and integrity
for over 15 years.
RICHIE: I told you
you wouldn't know
which one I'm gonna be
when I came in. Remember?
What?
On the phone.
I think you want to talk
to somebody downstairs.
They'll help you out.
You see that?
He's playin' dumb.
Yeah, he's fucking with you.
You gonna try and tell me
I never spoke to you?
Huh?
BLACKBIRD: No. I think
he said he don't believe
what you told him
on the telephone.
Show him you mean it.
Am I makin' my point?
Give me the cash,
or you're a dead
fuckin' real estate man.
Okay, you win.
It's downstairs in the car.
MAN ON PA: Welcome
to Nelson Davies Realty,
the number one agency
in the Anchor Bay area,
serving the whole community
with expertise and integrity
for more than 15 years.
RICHIE: You own this business,
you still drive a pickup?
WAYNE: I like to think success
hasn't changed me.
CARMEN: Wayne?
RICHIE: Who the fuck
is Wayne?
WAYNE: Beats me.
BLACKBIRD: Hey, let's go.
CARMEN: Wayne?
RICHIE:
What's goin' on here?
Hey, forget it.
Let's get out.
No. Give it to me.
Lock the door. Call the cops.
Aah!
Hey!
Bird!
Fuck!
WAYNE: For a job.
I said Nelson knew
I was comin' by.
It was hardly an appointment.
His wife's an employee,
and there was some talk
about Wayne dropping by.
Hence, the suit.
But you're an ironworker.
Hence, the boots.
I'm lookin'
at other things, okay?
NELSON: It's just an odd time
to appear, that's all.
Lunch. There's nobody here.
I was here.
Because I'm gonna be
making some claims, all right?
The window damages...
OFFICER: And you didn't know
these guys?
No, sir.
'Cause nobody witnessed
you arriving separately.
CARMEN: Wait just a minute.
They shot at my husband.
He probably saved my life.
Mr. Colson, you knew nothing
about these blackmail calls?
Hey, I don't know
about any calls.
What blackmail calls?
There were some calls
last week. Uh, creeps.
I told the police.
But not us?
Those creeps
had guns, Nelson.
WAYNE: Asshole.
Wayne.
CARMEN: Asshole.
RICHIE: I'm bleedin'
somethin' fierce here, man.
Let's just go to Marine City.
I want to see Donna.
Who the fuck is Donna?
She's this woman
that I'm stayin' with.
She's cool, man.
I told her about you.
It's on the way
to Port Huron.
My brothers and I
come up here one time
to kill a guy.
No shit. What'd he do?
I didn't ask.
That doesn't
make sense to me.
I gotta be pissed at a guy
I want to kill him.
Bird, why didn't you shoot him?
He was standin' right there
in the fuckin' window.
You want to learn somethin'?
The only time
you ever take out your gun
is when you're gonna
kill somebody.
Yeah? Well,
you could've right there!
It's the same as a hunter.
The guy who knows
what he's doing,
he don't take the shot
if he thinks he can miss.
See, then you gotta find
the animal and finish it,
two of them.
Are you talkin'
about the woman now?
What'd that woman do?
She saw my face.
You don't
ever leave things undone.
You don't ever think
somebody's not going
to remember you.
LIONEL: Some people were askin'
after you this mornin'.
BLACKBIRD: What people?
Said they were friends
of yours from Toronto.
What'd you tell them?
I told them
I hadn't seen you in years.
You see
my friend's face, Lionel?
Fell off a ladder.
Got cut up,
couldn't go to work.
So I said, "Hey,
let's go duck hunting."
You free to take us?
Weather's supposed to turn.
Why don't we go anyway?
Richie's never seen
a marsh before.
I've seen a marsh.
Come on, Lionel.
This won't take long.
You okay?
I... guess so.
That Indian guy freaked me out.
Walk you in?
CARMEN: So what things
are you looking at?
WAYNE: Huh?
Back there with the police,
you said you were
looking at other things?
Yeah, well,
I'm lookin' at anything.
You said it.
I'm a dinosaur.
I gotta change or die.
I never said that.
Then I'm sayin' it.
So today's the day
you decide to come in
about a job in real estate?
What? I could sell a house.
Absolutely.
Anyway, thank God
you showed up in that suit.
Yeah, dangerous suit.
Got married in it,
got shot at in it.
Well, you look great in it.
Anyway, thanks.
Anytime.
Wayne?
It's a deer.
Get some rest.
You need anything,
just call the Hillcrest Motel.
RICHIE:
I don't see any birds.
LIONEL:
You want to hunt ducks?
You watch the sky.
It looks different,
all this water.
LIONEL: Maybe you never
came down this far,
you and your brothers.
There are no cats or dogs
around here to shoot.
Last time I saw you,
you were going hunting
with some guy
in a ironworker's jacket.
Seemed like a nice guy.
What was his name?
Carl.
Wayne.
You can't remember the rest,
we'll go back and ask
your wife and daughter.
Wayne Colson.
Where does he live?
Algonac.
Is he married?
Kids?
They couldn't.
Hey, there's some!
Looks like you're gonna
have trouble with this one.
He might shoot
the wrong bird.
What's that supposed to mean?
Ducks don't land in trees.
Why don't we go over there,
stretch our legs?
Want to go first?
You know,
you really piss me off!
Tell me ducks
don't land in trees?
Aah!
I know ducks
don't land in trees.
[Gunshot]
RICHIE: Bird, you comin'?
WOMAN: Excuse me.
Uh...
This is my house.
Uh, yeah.
It's a dump.
You certainly have
your nerve.
RICHIE: Donna... ahem.
Donna, this is the Bird.
He's gonna be stayin'
with us for a few days.
What happened to your face?
I got in a fight.
We got any beers?
Well, why don't you fix us
somethin' to eat,
and I'll go get some.
Hey, don't call me
Bird no more.
Why?
What do you
want me to call you?
My name.
Armand.
Ar-mand? Armand?
Are you serious?
Listen...
when she's makin'
all that fuckin' noise in there,
it means she's pissed off.
Why don't you go in there,
give her a little pat
on the ass, huh?
You want the Weight Watchers
chicken patty or the regular?
Mmm...
two Weight Watchers, please.
Richie said you used to be
a hack in the joint.
That how you met?
I was in catering services.
Said you got fired
for screwin' the inmates.
You drive
that school bus out there?
Hey, if you could be
any kind of a bird there is...
what kind of bird would you be?
What are you doing here?
Just need a place to stay.
For how long?
Couple of days.
Got some business
to take care of.
You want some bacon
with your chicken patties?
[Noise]
CARMEN: Thanks.
Sure.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
I was busy, but, uh...
Well, I dragged myself away
from starin' at the ceiling.
Well, anyway,
it turned out to be nothing.
I'm so jumpy. I'm sorry.
- Okay.
- I'm sorry.
No, no. Go to bed.
I'll grab a beer,
at least till you're asleep.
Well, there's really no need.
Oh. Well, now you're not
scared, I can't have a beer.
Wayne, you shouldn't really
even have keys to the house.
I'm confused,
'cause for a second there,
I thought you called me.
I did call you,
and I am nervous,
but if you can just let yourself
in whenever you want...
Which I've never done.
But you could.
I don't know.
I know you've been here.
Yeah, but not when you were here.
So you have been here.
I fixed the porch light.
Carmen, I waited
till you'd gone out
so as not to get into a fight.
Which means
you were watching me,
which might be why I'm
feeling watched all the time.
Come on!
All right, you know what?
I'm thankful to you
for fixing the porch light.
Yeah, and that faucet
in the bathroom.
And the faucet
in the bathroom, too.
But this was supposed
to be a change.
Nothing's changing.
Wayne, I'm moving.
I don't like
being this person
who's blaming you for all
the things I'm blaming you for.
You know, there's no, uh...
middle, huh?
I mean, this is it with you.
You're either fine,
or you are leavin'
the country.
We don't have kids, fine.
We can't have kids, fine.
No, suddenly,
we are killin' ourselves.
We are gettin' a divorce.
We are leavin' the country.
I mean,
it's like it's zero or ten.
I mean, what happened to five?
Five's pretty great.
I'll take five again
in a fuckin' minute.
RICHIE: See?
What I tell you?
He's fuckin' that woman
from the real estate office.
I got him!
You get the woman!
[Ringing]
CARMEN: Hello.
- It's me.
- Mom.
Oh, ask me something else.
How are you? How are you?
Oh, he's out. He'll be back.
LENORE: You know,
I went to see
that doctor again
this afternoon.
I told him those pills
don't agree with me at all.
Hey, Mom,
I have to call you back.
BLACKBIRD:
You going hunting, miss?
I was looking
for your husband,
have a talk with him.
He's not home.
I know that.
I was wondering maybe
I'd come inside and wait.
We met before, remember?
At the real estate office.
You going to shoot me?
The police should be here
any minute.
Oh, you had time
to call them, huh?
I don't think
you're going to shoot me.
Hi.
Ohh!
All right!
It's your big day, honey!
It's a double feature!
Get out the cash tray,
lay it on the counter.
And some gum.
Make that bubblegum.
Do it!
Get out of there!
Get the hell
out of there!
Fuck!
Fuck.
Get up.
Are you Indian?
You look Indian.
You know, you should do
somethin' with your hair.
Use a shampoo
with conditioner in one.
Give it some body.
Look at me.
Are you sure
you're not Indian?
Oh, well, doesn't matter.
WAYNE: How many times
are you gonna ask me,
"Did I see him
shoot the girl?"
I thought she'd gotten
out of there!
How many times
are you gonna go
look at that bullet hole
in the tree?
My wife told you that she
wasn't tryin' to hit him,
and you guys act like
you don't believe her!
Not one of you guys
has said, "Nice goin',"
or that was brave thing
my wife did!
These maniacs
are tryin' to kill us,
and what are you
doin' about it?
Mr. Colson?
Mrs. Colson.
I'm Paul Scallen,
Federal Bureau of Investigation.
WAYNE: That's the same color
as the guy's car.
A big goddamn Cadillac
nobody can seem to find.
Oh, we found it
on Walpole Island.
Only there wasn't
a lot of paintwork left.
Mr. Colson, do you know
a Lionel Adam?
Yeah, sure.
Well, I'm afraid
I have some bad news.
Would you mind telling us who
the hell these assholes are now
and why would they want
to kill Lionel Adam?
SCALLEN:
We don't know for sure.
We think they were
trying to find you.
It seems you and your wife
had a good look at them.
WAYNE: So what?
All they were doin'
at that point
was shakin' down
a real estate business.
SCALLEN:
This one maybe, but...
this one's
got more of a history.
His name's Armand Degas.
He's known as The Blackbird.
He's a contract killer
for the Toronto Mafia.
Takes an awful lot of nerve
to stand up to a man like that.
What does the Toronto Mafia
have to do with us?
Last week,
the head of the family
was shot dead
in a Detroit hotel room,
along with a girl
who might have seen it happen.
We think it was an inside job.
And thanks to you,
we know that Degas
was in the area at the time.
So if we can, uh,
pick him up,
even if it's
just for extortion,
there's a chance that
he may want to cut a deal.
WAYNE: Wait.
You want us to testify
against a Mafia hitman?
He's gonna come
after you either way.
Without you, there's nothing
to say he was even here.
WAYNE:
So what do you suggest?
Well, your lives
are in danger,
so we figure you qualify
for federal protection
under the Witness
Security Program.
You want to move us
someplace else?
SCALLEN: Until we find them.
We'll provide you
with new identities,
temporary employment.
You won't need
to sell the house.
I'm sure we can make a deal
with this Nelson Davies,
have his company appear
to offer it for sale.
Yeah?
BLACKBIRD: It's me.
Why the fuck
are you callin' me here?
BLACKBIRD: I need a car.
A clean one with papers.
MAN: Word is,
you really upset the man.
He was fuckin' that girl
you blew away.
BLACKBIRD:
Can you arrange it or not?
You can't come here.
They got everyone
lookin' for you.
FBI AGENT: We'll transfer
your baggage overnight.
Replacement vehicles will be
waiting for you in the morning.
Your own will be held
until you're released
from the program.
WAYNE: Never hear about that,
do you?
People gettin'
out of witness protection?
Destination location
is Cape Girardeau.
That's about
another 2-hour drive
south down the Mississippi River.
Now, you'll be checking in here
under your new names.
You must be Pam Benkowski.
I'm your husband Matt.
FEMALE FBI AGENT:
It's best to stick
as close
to the truth as possible.
That way, you're less
likely to have trouble
with your invented histories.
How long you been married?
WAYNE: 15 years.
AGENT: Where'd you meet?
WAYNE: On a building site
in Saint Auburn.
June 4, 1991.
AGENT:
Who asked who out first?
CARMEN: I did.
How long after that
were you married?
A week.
How many children?
Almost one.
RICHIE: Well, if they moved,
how come all their furniture's
still here?
Hey, Bird.
What?
You gonna kill Donna, too?
I mean, you're goin'
to all this trouble
findin' witnesses,
and she's a witness.
What does that make you?
No, you need me.
Leave my fingerprints
everywhere.
Steal cars and shoot people,
do all your dirty work
for you.
[Phone ringing]
Who is it?
Uh, yes, ma'am,
I'm looking for Wayne Colson.
Who gave you my number?
Excuse me, ma'am.
That was a new fella
works here
I just asked to call you.
We been tryin'
to get ahold of Wayne,
and, uh, he gave us
this number before he left.
He gave you my number?
Well, as a matter of fact,
he gave it to the boss.
Boss gave it to me.
Only he isn't here right now
'cause it's so late,
but, uh, he said that
you'd know where he was.
Wayne, that is.
LENORE: I don't know
where they've gone.
Wayne and my daughter
never tell me anything.
RICHIE: See, 'cause I got this
check I'm tryin' to send him.
Yeah. Yes.
FBI AGENT: Mr. Benkowski.
Mrs. Benkowski.
Good morning. Welcome.
- Morning.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Shall we?
AGENT: If the neighbors ask,
you paid about $200,000 for it.
CARMEN: It looks more
like 150 to me.
# The best I can #
# But it's not good #
# Enough for you #
# You know I was
the kind who'd run #
# Anytime you'd call #
# I guess I was the only one #
# Who didn't mind at all #
# I'll be your dreamer #
# I'll be your fool #
# Oh, my darling #
# My whole life through #
# Doing the best #
# The best I can #
# But it's not good #
Sure ain't much privacy
around here.
# Enough for you... #
You want privacy,
you close the door.
But I don't think
that's what you want.
Well, I guess you're gonna do
whatever it is you want.
There's no way on earth
I can stop you.
There'll be a slight delay
in the divorce proceedings
while the couple hides out
from the killers.
Good night.
# Every time you kiss me #
# I'm still not certain
that you love me #
DONNA: This is Elvis Presley
Boulevard on a rainy day.
This is the Lisa Marie.
It's a jetliner he bought.
He named it
after his daughter.
Her and I have
the same birthday.
And I'll tell ya
somethin' else.
My life number is 9.
BLACKBIRD:
What's a life number?
Okay, well, you add up
your date of birth, right?
Um, like February's
the second month, so that's 2.
I was born on the first.
That's 1, so 2 and 1 is 3.
Then you add in the year
that you were born.
I'm not gonna tell you
when that was,
but my number
comes out to 9.
BLACKBIRD:
Even if you were born in 1900,
that'd still add up to 10.
Yeah, see, 10 counts as 1.
Donna, get dressed,
go buy some fuckin' beers.
Think he cares
about your queer photos?
- You're just jealous.
- Jealous of what?
You know what the difference
between me and Elvis is?
Yeah. You're ignorant.
No. I'm alive,
and he's dead.
Well, I got news for you.
After you die,
you think anybody's
gonna go and visit your grave?
Not even your mama,
if you had one.
But a hundred years from now,
people will still be going
to Graceland.
Donna,
you're so goddamn stupid.
Let me ask you
a question, Donna.
Would you rather
have Elvis sing to you
or fuck you?
I know what you think
I'm gonna say,
and you'll probably
call me a liar,
but I'd rather
have him sing to me.
Damn. You know what?
I believe her, though.
'cause Elvis
wasn't no con.
He wouldn't have been dirty
or smelly enough for Donna.
Hey, leave her alone.
Who, Donna?
Why don't you
shut the fuck up for a while?
If you ever talk to me
like that again...
Yeah?
What?
This is
Elvis' billiard room.
There's 750 yards of material...
Can I have a word... Armand?
What the fuck
is your problem?!
You are.
And from now on, you don't
leave my fucking sight.
Well, how about
when I go to the bathroom?
You wanna watch?
Or when I'm givin'
Donna a jump
and you're out there,
wishin' it was you.
Or do we keep pretendin' that
you're not tryin' to fuck her?
Hey, you listen to me.
Keep your big
fucking mouth shut,
and don't worry about it.
MAN: So you're a welder, huh?
WAYNE: You bet I am.
AWS certified.
Can you weld plates
watertight?
Well, I can weld a goddamn
building so it won't fall down.
MAN: I got a job you might
want to take a look at.
BLACKBIRD: Hey.
Maybe today she can't
tell us where they are.
But tomorrow, she might.
What job were
you and Wayne working on?
Well, we've been
on different ones.
Anyway, what I started
to tell you,
I don't see what difference
it makes who mails the check,
you or us, but the boss says
we have to do it.
Now, I told him you were
a nice lady to offer...
And I told you,
I don't have their address.
She never gave it to me.
The only thing I have
is their phone number.
You want that?
Oh. Well, you didn't
mention that, did you?
You have their number?
Not on the phone, I didn't.
I wasn't absolutely positive
whom I was speaking to.
That's how they find out
if you're home
so they can come in
and rape you.
I understand.
Can't be too careful.
You give him a check... hmm!
And you know
where he'll cash it, don't ya?
The nearest bar.
Oh!
What's wrong?
I should never bend
that far from the waist!
It's like somebody
stuck a knife in me.
Oh!
That's your sacroiliac.
Why don't you lay down
on the couch?
No, no, let's get you
down here on the carpet.
I'm gonna give you
a backrub.
I had a foster mom
one time named Jackie.
She was some kind of therapist.
She worked with cripples.
She showed me how.
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
Yes, ma'am.
Oh!
You're not gonna hurt me,
are you?
Oh! Ohh!
What the fuck
did you do?
Oh, God! Fuck!
I just gave her a backrub.
Jesus!
It's a Missouri code.
I did a bank there once.
[Ringing]
WAYNE, RECORDING:
Hi, it's Matt and Pam.
We're not here.
We'll call you back.
Hello.
Hello?
[Phone ringing]
RECORDING:
Hi, it's Matt and Pam.
We're not here.
We'll call you back.
WAYNE: Hey, it's me. I tried
calling you a couple times.
Wayne.
No, I'm fine.
What?
I'm losing you. What?
BLACKBIRD:
We gotta make a plan.
RICHIE:
That's my fucking phone!
You want to wait
till they trace the number?
That thing had all
my fuckin' numbers in it.
Why don't we go to Missouri?
- We will.
- Yeah? When?
When they stop looking
for us,
or when they think
we stopped looking for them.
So, Gerald,
this is the master bedroom.
I love how you guys
say "master bedroom."
Yes, we guys
like our guy words.
You're not from here.
That's right.
Where are you from?
Detroit way.
I know Detroit.
We, uh, didn't look
at the kitchen.
Are you following me?
Excuse me?
Mrs. Benkowski, hello.
How'd the viewing work out?
Well, you should know.
You were outside
this morning.
Hey, did you make
a sale with Gerald?
I know he's been
looking at a lot of places.
Do they know we're here?
Are they coming after us?
Listen, you come by
the office anytime.
It's always good to see you.
CARMEN: What if we're bait?
What are you talkin' about?
What if we're
being used as bait?
What if the FBI's just waiting
for those two freaks
to find us
so they can find them?
What if they
show up here, Wayne?
They'll get caught.
Oh. Before they kill us.
Sure.
Yeah, I vote for before.
I can't even begin
to pretend to do my job here.
I show a house,
I'm just waiting
for somebody
to pull a gun on me.
What's the choice?
I mean, I don't understand.
I could sit here
and go crazy.
I don't know.
Why don't you tell me?
Listen...
can we try something different?
Come down after work one night.
Meet some of the guys
and their wives.
You know, they're good people.
There's little places
along the river.
We could get something to eat.
Does nothing bother you?
Sure, yeah.
This bothers me.
You and me.
Not gangsters.
I need you to do
something for me.
Is that what you dragged me
out here to tell me?
You got some balls on you,
chief, I'll give you that.
I don't give a fuck
what you need.
Yes, you do.
That's why you come
when I called.
You don't want
the cops picking me up.
If for some reason
they start asking me,
was I in Detroit
when the old man was killed.
And how the fuck
they gonna connect me
to a half-breed
piece of shit
they dragged up
from the bottom of this lake?
The blue Cadillac
you gave me,
the one with the papers
in the glove compartment,
registered
to your pepperoni company.
Anything happen to me,
a friend gonna drive the car
to some precinct.
They gonna find
the piece I used
to whack the old man for you
wrapped in a letter...
from me about you.
Not a love letter.
This is what
you're gonna do for me.
There's a cemetery
in Port Huron.
My kid brother
is buried there.
He never had the kind
of funeral he deserved.
WAYNE: You can be walkin' around
on that skinny little beam,
and you've got clouds
around your head.
I mean, some days, you think
you see things so clear.
The place you live,
the store you shop in,
the church
you got married in.
I could see everything.
Everywhere I'd ever been
my whole life
from the top of a building.
MAN: So why the hell
did you quit and come here?
Job quit me, man.
Get to an age,
they start pullin' you down,
about one floor a year.
End up too near the ground.
I got my pride.
Too much maybe.
WAITRESS:
I've been watchin' you, honey,
and you should talk less
and drink more.
I think these poor folks
deserve another round there,
uh... Linda.
MAN: Oh, ho ho, yeah.
Hey, Pam, honey,
how did you, uh...
fall for a shy guy like Matt?
- His muscles.
- Ahh!
And the short shorts.
Ooh!
CARMEN: Nah, he was
a show-off, even back then.
I had to show off
to get her attention.
Every guy in town's
chasin' after her.
Not only is she gorgeous,
she's smart as a whip.
Don't exaggerate, Matthew.
Her mother's always sayin',
"Carmen, honey"...
because that's
what her mother called her
'cause she's a great singer.
She'd say, "Carmen, honey,
"you're a talented,
beautiful girl.
"Don't go wastin' your life
on an ironworker.
"You're gonna wake up
in 20 years,
and you're gonna realize,
he never deserved you."
15 years.
He is such a liar.
My mother adores him.
We got karaoke here
on Friday.
You gotta come.
- Yeah!
- Oh, no.
You wait.
She's a knockout.
Ah ha ha. I'm gonna
knock you out, Matt.
"I have been
watching you, honey.
You should talk less
and drink more."
Why is it that
I feel I know you best
when I hear you talking
with other people?
WAYNE: I felt good tonight.
I like this town.
Telling all your stories.
Hey, nothin'
I said tonight back there
wasn't the God's truth.
Hmm.
No.
Don't turn on the light.
You married?
No, sir, I'm on a break.
Live around here?
I can't tell you
where I live.
That's a government secret.
SCALLEN: We found them
last week.
Two bodies, probably shot,
driven to a remote location,
and burned in the car.
Nothing much left
to be identified.
The Indian has
a surviving brother.
He's doing life in Kingston
Correctional Facility.
We ran DNA tests,
and we checked them against his.
Match was positive.
What happens to us now?
Well,
after we close the case,
you can go back
to your life.
What if we
don't want to go back?
SCALLEN: That happens.
But what you're saying is,
if we wanted to, we could?
That also happens.
It's still busy.
Try her again.
I'm not your fuckin'
kid brother.
You can't order me around.
I know that, Richie.
I buried my kid brother.
So lighten up. We're dead.
If they dig around some more,
we're alive.
We just bought us
some more time, that's all.
Now try the old lady again.
WAYNE: She's, uh, packing,
Lenore. Let me go find her.
She says she'll call you
when she gets back to the house.
LENORE: You're not
coming together?
No. As a matter of fact,
I'm stayin' down here
for a while.
LENORE: What do you mean,
for a while?
Kind of a trial separation.
LENORE: I don't understand.
I'm not sure we do, either.
But that's where we're at.
LENORE: Have you been
fighting again?
No, no fighting.
LENORE:
You will not break up.
Lord knows
I prayed for it.
WAYNE: Okay, Mom,
appreciate it.
Well, she says
no way we'll break up.
"Lord knows I prayed for it.
It'll never happen."
Mississippi River Navigation
and Rules of Inland Waterways?
Homework.
Lot of laughs.
I'll wait for the movie.
Can we at least
give it a try...
now that we're safe?
Maybe Matt and Pam
can fix the things
Wayne and Carmen
never could.
Do you honestly believe that?
I honestly do.
Stay.
- No.
- Stay.
No.
Fight with me.
Don't say no.
CARMEN: It's not one thing.
It's not one day.
It's not a baby, or...
no baby.
It's years.
And I need time, Wayne.
Time to remember
what I cared for you,
and what you cared for me.
Okay, let's fix that.
I think we can fix that.
I think we started
to fix it right here.
[Phone ringing]
LENORE: Who is it?
Are you leaving?
Richie, too?
What did he tell you
about me?
You know how he is.
He brags about you a lot.
What I do for a living?
That's none
of my business, Armand.
I've enjoyed your company...
and I think
you're a nice person,
and I wish you all the best.
I forgot somethin'.
[Gunshot]
Please pick up.
[Phone ringing]
RECORDING:
Hi. It's Matt and Pam.
We're not here.
We'll call you back.
[Timer beeping]
RICHIE: Hungry?
Your mom told us
you'd be home by breakfast.
You could have driven
a little faster.
We're gettin' hungry.
Mmm! Now you got nice hair.
Why don't you scoot over?
I want to get somethin' here.
You want to fix
the Bird some lunch?
We brought our own food.
What do you want?
Just waiting
for your husband.
And then what?
What? You can't say it?
I know why you're here.
BLACKBIRD: The last time
you had the shotgun,
the 12-gauge, you wanted
to shoot me, didn't you?
But you couldn't.
Where is it?
In Missouri.
BLACKBIRD:
So your husband has it.
I hope so.
Why don't we
just shoot her now, Bird,
and take care
of the husband later?
Yeah? What if he calls her?
Don't answer the phone.
He'd think she went out
to get food
to fix him lunch.
He comes in.
"Hi, honey, I'm home." boom!
What's "Hot doe buck lure"?
Why don't you try some?
Maybe you'll attract a deer.
You makin'
the Bird some lunch?
He put in an order
for dessert yet?
I eat chicken every meal.
Know why?
No.
'Cause Wade Boggs ate
chicken before every game.
That's why they called him
"the chicken man."
Bird, do you know
who Wade Boggs is?
Ah, Bird doesn't know shit.
Yeah, I was gonna be
a major league ballplayer
until my deprived childhood
as an orphan
fucked up my chances,
so I became a bank robber
instead.
Hey, Carmen, I got an idea.
Why don't you
take your clothes off?
You don't have to take off
all your clothes.
You can leave on your panties
and your brassiere...
if you wear a brassiere.
Do you?
Oh, Bird, she don't wear one!
Well, you can just strip down
to your panties then,
be our little topless bunny,
serve us drinks.
Aah! God!
You're gonna have
to kick harder than that.
Come here!
RICHIE: I think you're gonna
feel a lot better
if you go in the bathroom
and take off your clothes...
and wash yourself.
BLACKBIRD: Hey!
Use that one.
LINDA: You need somewhere
to sleep off that hangover?
Give me five minutes.
Okay.
RICHIE: I said
I want you topless.
That's my husband's jacket.
Take it off.
Why don't we make a trade?
I'll take off the jacket...
you take off your top.
No. I like your outfit.
You look like
a little schoolgirl.
Go on. Hold that.
[Phone ringing]
Oh. Now you're gonna
answer the fucking phone?
Let it ring.
RECORDING: Hi.
We're not in right now,
so go ahead and leave a mess...
[Dial tone]
Jesus Christ, Bird,
you ever stop eatin'?
Aw. What's wrong
with our little bunny?
You scared? What?
There's no reason to be.
Ol' Wayne comes home,
just gonna have
a little talk with him.
Isn't that right, Bird?
Hey, Bird, you gonna ask
if anyone else wants some
'fore you finish it?
Man, what you gonna do
when Donna asks you to wear
one of them Elvis jumpsuits
for her?
I guess you could always wear
that pink one he had
after he swolled up like a pig.
I read about this guy once,
weighed 1,200 pounds.
Can you believe that?
For breakfast, he'd have
like two pounds of bacon,
a dozen eggs, some rolls.
Then for lunch,
he'd have four hamburgers,
four double cheeseburgers,
eight boxes of fries.
For dinner, three ham steaks,
six sweet potatoes,
six or seven regular potatoes,
some stuffing.
Carmen, can you imagine
this guy takin' a dump?
See, Donna,
that's the Bird's sweetheart.
When this is all done,
the Bird and Donna...
they're gonna
go down to Memphis,
hold hands,
look at all that Elvis shit.
Isn't that right, Bird?
Only trouble is,
Donna is probably fuckin' Elvis
as we speak.
You get one, Richie,
just like everybody else.
You know why I shot him?
He wasn't who I thought he was.
I had this kid brother.
We were in a hospital
one time on a job.
And when we were done,
there was this nurse
standing there.
She saw us do it.
My kid brother just stood there,
looking at her.
He looked at her too long.
Maybe he liked her face.
Anyway,
that's what killed him.
Go put some clothes on.
I have to go upstairs.
I'm not like Richie.
I'm not the same as him.
I know.
Aah!
You meet a woman.
You kid yourself
she sees you.
Sees who you really are
under all the shit.
Turns out, just another bitch
with the lip service.
You're wrong.
- I do see you.
- Shut up.
I panic. I panicked
when I saw the gun.
I... I panicked.
Shut up!
Where's your husband?
I don't know.
When's he get back?
Well, then you call him.
You call him, and
you tell him to get back here.
I'm tired of waiting.
I want to finish this.
No, please.
He's not coming back.
He's in Missouri.
He's not even
my husband anymore.
Don't you get it?
Don't you know anything
about real life?
Real life?
What the fuck is that?
Missouri, huh?
WAYNE: Carmen?
It's me!
Tried calling.
Honey?
You're gonna have to let me in.
I... I don't have a key.
CARMEN: Wayne, please go.
WAYNE: Okay, all right.
Just hear me out.
Look, I've had 400 miles,
15 years
to think about this, so...
say five's terrible, right?
That's what you said.
So let's go for six.
And then if we make it to six,
then we could try for seven.
'Cause... I really want
to make it to 10 for you.
Carmen, 'cause I get it now.
Carmen?
I understand.
So, uh, if you're
not gonna let me in,
then at least
let me get somethin'...
in the car.
A present. I left it.
Ooh!
Aah! Aah! God!
Aah!
BLACKBIRD: You gotta know what
you're doing when you go in.
You gotta have it
figured out.
Don't hang around.
Don't get interested.
It's empty.
Then you
don't make mistakes.
Subtitles by LeapinLar