Read this, puta.
Thanks.
Want a date, honey?
Money, money, money.
Check this out.
You want to stop?
No.
Tubes, my boy, what's up?
What?
What's taking so long?
It's gonna take a few minutes.
We ain't got a few minutes.
We got to get busy.
Why don't you do what you
got to do so we can get busy?
Do me a favor. Here.
Calm down. Relax.
I'm gonna show you
how to do this.
I'm gonna show you how
to test this. Like that.
Right. It's dope.
It's dope, Tito.
You ever get the feeling
you was being watched?
Damn.
You got any soda, man...
like some root beer
or something?
I hurt my leg playing ball.
I got these aspirins
I want to take.
Now, what the fuck is he...
Tell him to turn this shit off.
What kind of help you got?
Watching cartoons?
Tell my man to turn the tv
off and get me a soda.
And make sure it's cold.
I like my shit cold,
especially when I play ball.
You play ball, Tito?
You don't look
like you play no ball.
But nice gloves.
I like those.
Hey, Jump.
What's up?
It's copacetic.
Now maybe you satisfied.
No. Maybe now I want
to check out another one.
What the fuck I look like,
Joe Neckbone?
Trust ain't one
of my stronger qualities.
You know what I'm saying?
You fucking disrespect me.
I guarantee the shit.
To hell with testing.
Let's get to the large
plus ten percent.
Did he say ten percent?
Wait a minute, Tito.
We had a deal. What's up?
What ten percent
you talking about?
Transportation costs, amigo.
I got expenses.
Well, take the train...
if you got expenses
in transportation.
Why you want to be greedy?
You fuck the sucking greed.
That's our price.
No one else even talks to you
goddamn motherfucking coños.
Now take it or leave it.
Why you want to talk
to me like that?
Take it or leave it?
I take it.
'Cause I like you,
I'm gonna take it.
Pack the shit up.
You in power, Tito.
You the king.
Where's my soda?
What the fuck is this?
They're for
the bullet holes, puta.
Room service, motherfuckers!
There's somebody
here to see you.
What's in the cup?
Root beer.
You want some?
There's some things I don't do.
Welcome back home, Frank.
Check him out.
Congratulations, Frank.
Congratulations, man.
Them Colombian motherfuckers...
they took permanent vacation
in hell...
if you know what I mean.
Wow. I must have been
away too long...
because my feelings are dead.
I feel no remorse.
It's a terrible thing.
I heard being in jail makes
you feel like that.
I got a present for you.
Check it out.
They were King Tito's...
but he don't need them
where he is now.
I thought maybe you would
donate them...
to a clothing drive
or something.
Having a good time,
huh, Jump?
I been waiting years for this.
Emilio Zapa sends his regards.
You know how I love money.
Well, help yourself.
Is the meeting set with Dalesio?
Downtown.
You need to let me
bust a cap...
in that moonheaded
motherfucker's ass.
Word!
He's a fucking glitter boy.
He's looking
to get sprayed, laid...
played, and slayed.
Know what I'm saying?
I heard that.
You gonna come down, say hello?
You hobnob with them homos,
you want to.
I'm going downtown,
find me a girl...
get my knob polished.
Time for a real party.
Jim.
How come you never
came to see me?
Who wanted to see you in a cage?
Of course.
Later.
Champagne. Let's break out.
It's King Tito's.
King Tito's gloves.
It's a good thing he's dead
'cause I'd take that glove...
I'd wrap it right round his...
Sex.
And it's how much?
Wait for the paperback,
and you can get it.
It's too fucking much for me.
You should read that book, Joey.
Why?
Because I think you
might learn something.
What?
How to be good?
Joey, just don't say a word, OK?
Why not?
Because I don't want
you to say anything.
But we're going home, right?
I know. I'm tired already.
Where is he?
Welcome home, Frank.
Good to see you.
Nice to see you.
Thanks for everything.
To freedom.
Come on.
Bill, nice to see you.
Bill, Charlie, you know Frank.
How are you?
Good of you to come.
Judge, how are you?
Nice to see you.
Listen, I want to
introduce you to...
I'm gonna say hello
to your junior partner.
Hiya, Frank.
Good to see you.
You should
be more careful...
of the affairs
you attend, counselor.
One is known by
the company one keeps.
Ain't that right, Joey?
Pete, how are you?
Hey, Frank. Welcome home.
Hello, Frank.
Welcome back.
You know everybody here,
I think.
Pete, how's the family...
Brian, Dennis?
Better than when
you left town, Frank.
They're all working.
How about you?
Back from the dead.
Frank White. I've heard
a lot about you...
and it's all bad.
Don't believe everything that
Pete writes in the columns...
because... well...
I've been reformed.
A lot of people
will be happy to hear that.
Huh, Pete?
What can we expect from
the reformed Frank White?
I want to be mayor.
Thinks I'm kidding.
But first, I want
to talk to Arty Clay.
Why don't you relax?
We're supposed to be having
a good time here.
Tell him I got things
on my mind.
I want to
talk them over with him.
The guy's a fucking animal.
He ain't gonna meet with you.
Maybe you can do one
of his lieutenants at best.
Tell him...
Frank White wants to talk
business with him.
Just tell him
that all I want to know...
is where and when.
You know, counselor,
they did a wonderful job...
with this gentleman.
He's better than ever.
If you'll excuse me...
I'll see you people
in a little while...
if I'm still around.
Look at you.
What's the matter?
You're not glad to see me?
You belonged
where they put you.
Maybe this time you'll
stay out of trouble.
That depends on how
good my lawyers are.
I thought people like you...
didn't believe
in the legal process.
I thought people like me
were the legal process.
You know what?
You know what
I'd like to do to you?
I would like to take
you on the subway.
What can I do for you?
Tell Arty
I need to speak to him.
Wait here.
Sure.
There's some yarm out there
that wants to talk to you.
Ace is still the better.
Arty, you're still...
What's happening here?
You got aces?
Two hundred.
Two hundred?
I got to see your two.
All right. One shot.
Last ticket.
Johnny, give me
something good here.
Take it easy.
Arty. Gentlemen.
- Who goes?
- Arty.
I bet two hundred.
Go ahead.
I got a message
from Frank White.
He wants to sit down.
He wants to talk.
You tell him I don't
talk to nigger lovers.
Let's go. What's down?
He says he's got things
on his mind...
that he wants to discuss
with you...
and he wants to know where
and he wants to know when.
You tell him in fucking hell,
that's where.
He's gonna wish his lawyer...
left him fucking
the Sambos in the joint...
when I get through with him.
I was making money
off them Colombians.
That's right.
If that's what you want me
to tell him, I'll tell him.
It ain't clear enough?
You tell
that son of a bitch...
he made a big
mistake with me.
And you tell him
something else!
This is what
Arty Clay has to say.
You tell him personally
from me!
Stay outta here!
Come on, sit down.
Let's go.
Come on, you go.
I missed you.
Your watch and your wallet,
blood.
How about that?
Come by the Plaza Hotel.
I got work for you.
Ask for Frank White.
Come on.
It's up to me, right?
You guys are in trouble.
I bet two hundred.
Hurry up, will you?
I'm down a lot of money here.
Let's play cards.
I got your message, Arty.
You stupid son of a bitch.
You running games here?
I want to play.
Sure, Frank, play.
Bring your friends.
I want to play with Arty.
Come on.
Let's go, will you?
Jump deals.
Blackjack. House out.
You got some balls coming here.
Pick up the card.
Come on.
Pick it up.
From here on, nothing goes down
unless I'm involved...
no blackjack,
no dope deals, no nothing.
A nickel bag
gets sold in the park...
I want in.
You guys got fat while everybody
starved on the street.
It's my turn.
You think you're gonna
live long enough...
to spend that money,
you fucking hump?
If any of you...
are tired of
getting ripped off...
by guys like that...
You come with me.
I'm at the Plaza Hotel.
You're welcome.
You're all welcome!
To join!
Man or ghost,
I'll kill you again.
Ed.
Aiesha, how you doing?
I'm very upset about
what happened today.
I told you, Frank,
I did the best I could...
and you know that.
Edward.
I told you I tried
to make it work, Frank.
Hello, counselor.
How are you?
Alisha, how are you?
Aiesha.
The city councilman
was just explaining to me...
why that hospital
in the South Bronx...
didn't survive
the fiscal cut this afternoon.
I'm telling him
about how disappointed I am.
I was explaining to Frank...
that there simply wasn't
money in the budget...
to fund that facility.
In a city
of twelve million people...
I find that hard to believe.
I hoped we could do better.
I hoped so, too, Frank...
but there simply was
no money in the budget.
If you think it's so easy...
why don't you try
funding it yourself?
Maybe I will.
How about sixteen million
by the end of the quarter?
Tell your friends
they'll have the money.
Counselor, you're
this man's legal advisor.
Why don't you explain to him
the hard financial facts...
of running a municipality.
I know what this city needs...
and privileged districts...
shouldn't be the only ones
with hospitals.
Forget it, Frank.
I want that place kept open.
Forget it.
The city can't afford it
and neither can you.
The city doesn't know
where to look for the money.
Let me give you some
very expensive advice...
go someplace where
you can stay out of trouble.
I thought
that's what I pay you for.
Hello, Frank.
I want to talk to you.
I don't think so.
Come on. O'Neill can wait
for two old friends, can't he?
I'm not your friend.
Come on, Frank. We missed you
while you were away.
Thought about you, too.
I heard a rumor about you.
What's that?
I heard you got AIDS...
getting dicked
up your ass in prison.
That's what I heard.
I thought about you every time
I jerked off, dickhead.
Why don't we
just take this outside.
Next time, wear a tie.
Get Abe.
Here we go.
Excuse us, folks.
Excuse us. Easy, easy.
What the hell is this?
We're taking him in
for questioning.
On what grounds?
This is harassment, Bishop.
You're welcome to come along.
Even your client's
got a right to counsel.
Come on. Get out!
Look inside.
Let's go.
What's that?
You tell me.
I don't know.
This is the only chance
you get, White.
What's it gonna be?
Are you arresting me?
Oh, fuck. Here we go.
If so, do it.
If not, I got people
waiting for me.
Shut the fuck up, motherfucker!
Hey, Frank.
All right, that's it.
Come here, Frank.
Here, Frank, meet somebody.
Meet somebody, huh?
Piece of shit!
That's it!
I'll kill the motherfucker!
No, I'm gonna cap him.
Let me cap the mo...
Get in the fucking car!
This how you do things?
I know what you're up to, White.
Forget it.
I'm gonna make you and
your friends disappear...
long before that.
Welcome home, fuck face.
Gilley, get in the fucking car.
Last fucking time, you fuck.
We're onto your fucking ass.
Give your friends that message.
Ladies and gentlemen...
can I have
your attention, please?
The best man
has something to say.
First of all, I'd like
to thank Tommy Flanigan...
for being the only black male
at an Irish wedding.
Are you comfortable, Tom?
I'm from the South.
Are you comfortable?
Real comfortable.
All my buddies here,
all my brothers.
He's sweating.
Joe Mulligan,
father of the bride.
Come on up here, Joe.
Joe provided these
lovely decorations for us.
Where'd you get these, Joe,
an A.A. Meeting?
Not only that, he paid
for the whole thing.
The whole two hundred dollars.
Joe, by the way,
put your shotgun away.
The test came back negative.
Roy Bishop, do I detect
a little Afro Sheen...
on that unusually
wavy hair of yours?
Tip... Kathy...
to the finest couple...
I've ever had
the pleasure to know.
Join me, folks.
They're the only couple...
that's still together
in this neighborhood.
I wish you health, wealth...
happiness,
a lot of babies, no cops.
We don't need no more
degenerate donkeys...
running around with guns.
All bullshit aside...
and may I speak
for everybody...
we love you.
God bless.
Hear, hear.
Here's to youse.
How did I do?
I'm proud of you.
Hey, Father,
thank you for coming.
Let's get Father laid.
Give me a real drink.
Get Dennis
a drink over here.
Get the house a drink.
The bar's not open now.
You pay.
That's my wife!
It was a fucking joke!
Would you relax?
Virginia, come here.
Come here. Excuse me.
Tip, take a tip.
Gilley's after your wife.
It's pretty obvious, isn't it?
Hell, it's more than obvious.
He'll find the vampire marks
sunk into her neck.
Get outta here!
What's what, my friend?
How you doing?
What's what? Terrific.
Yeah? How come
you're not dancing?
I'm gonna leave that
to the father of the bride.
Are you sure you're gonna
make it through the night?
Aw, shit. You kidding?
I'm the one that
needs the honeymoon.
All they do is stay in bed
all fucking night.
Do me a favor.
Give this to the kids.
I got a million things to do.
Wish them my love.
You sure you won't come in?
Nah. I got
a million things to do.
I'll see you during the week.
You take it easy.
Take care, Pops.
You can tell your boyfriend
to forget about it.
He ain't got enough money.
Maybe he'll surprise you.
I don't like
his fucking surprises.
He's got a lot of nerve
even sending you here.
You could step
all over that shit...
and still get
a hundred twenty a gram.
And I got
two hundred twenty pounds of it.
Comes to fifteen mil,
street value.
And I want guarantees
nobody in this town can give.
Especially him.
Look, Larry, why don't you
set the terms?
I'll go back, and I'll tell
Frank.
If you two see eye to eye,
we'll make a deal.
If not, everybody goes
their own way still friends.
What do you say?
That cocksucker
ain't got no friends.
And before I even think...
of sitting across
some table with him...
he got to know one thing...
I ain't no fucking greaseball
named Arty Clay.
You got it.
And he pays for your cut.
Why don't you stick around?
I got "Frankenstein"
coming on next.
Stop fucking with my lady.
You know what I'm saying?
I told him, stop fucking
with my bitch.
And when he started
crying like a bitch...
he got fucked like a bitch.
You know what I'm saying?
We're gonna shoot the bitch!
We'll just shoot the bitch!
Hey, Joe. What you want?
Don't forget the hot sauce.
You want white meat, right?
- No dark meat!
- No problem.
Don't shoot me!
Can I help you?
Can you help me?
Yeah, you can start...
by giving me fifteen pieces
of chicken, motherfucker.
Mix it up. I want barbecue,
and I want crispy.
You getting this all down?
I want six pieces of corn...
and I want, uh... yeah,
give me eight spareribs...
and give me
twelve pieces of shrimp.
Some onion rings.
You want tartar sauce
or ketchup on those?
I want tartar sauce.
You got any potato salad?
No, we ain't got potato sal...
Get away from the games!
All right?
You ain't got no money.
Just get away from the games.
What the fuck
is the matter with you...
talking to them like that?
They ain't got no money.
Is that it?
Yeah, that's it.
Make sure you get my food,
get it now...
and don't be drooling on it.
And I better not get
none of that cat.
I want chicken.
Here you are.
Y'all go play the games.
No offense, ma'am...
but you make sure
they get what they want.
Go ahead.
Y'all go play them games. Hear?
What's happening
with the food?
What's up? I ain't got
all day, you know.
That'll be 56.70, total.
Did I say I was finished?
I want something to drink.
Maybe I want some birch beer.
You got birch beer?
No, we don't have
no birch beer.
You don't even know
what that shit is.
You got any root beer?
We ain't got no root beer,
either.
- How much is this?
- 56.90
56.90? Fuck you very much.
Hey, scumbag, guess what?
You're under fucking arrest.
Yeah, motherfucker?
How about that?
Police!
It's all over, Jimmy.
You're under arrest
for the murder of Miguel Mata...
Salvador Tito,
and Rafael Santodomingo.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Shut the fuck up.
What's this?
Did you use this on Mata?
Yeah, same one
I'm gonna use on you, punk.
Laugh now, motherfucker,
but for the rest of your life...
you gonna be somebody's bitch.
Some motherfucker named Bubba.
But you're
a motherfucking bro!
Don't you slap me,
motherfucker.
I'm gonna slap
the black off you.
Take the cuffs off,
you motherfucker!
I'm gonna finish
his ass off!
This is the happiest day
of my life. You know why?
'Cause we got a real,
live, talking witness.
I don't leave no witnesses!
Oh, yeah, motherfucker?
Well, you must be getting old.
I'll teach you
to fuck with my friend.
I'm gonna fuck you up!
Without private assistance...
everything we've seen
will close down.
I can't stress enough how much
your help could mean...
to the thousands of families...
that depend on us
for medical care.
Please, just look around.
Look, Larry...
the most anybody's
gonna give you for your stuff...
is thirty grand a key.
That's about
three million dollars...
on a bulk sale.
So whoever buys it's
gonna turn around...
cut it, bag it,
and sell it on the street...
for a hundred twenty,
a hundred fifty a gram.
That's a hundred fifty thousand
dollars a key...
five times what they paid you.
So now your quintal's worth
fifteen million dollars...
a markup of
eleven million something...
that you get no part of.
I know you don't
have the manpower...
to peddle
the uptown streets, but I do.
You put up the stuff,
I put up the guys to sell it.
I take the heat
and the risk...
if there is any.
We divide the difference...
setting aside something
for places like this.
What do you say?
If I was into
socialized medicine...
I would have stayed
in the Peking province.
I want cash for my goods.
How much?
Three million up front...
like you said...
with another half a mil
when you unload it.
That's a lot of money.
I got a lot of shit.
Make up your mind.
You know something, Frank?
This conversation
made me realize...
just how fucking crazy
you really are.
It's all set up.
I don't think you should
go down there alone.
I don't trust
that crazy Chinese guy.
Know what I mean?
It's Enrico Mata.
They got him recovering
in a hospital somewhere...
with a police guard
around him 24 hours.
He's agreed to testify
for them in court.
They got Jump cold
this time, Frank.
It's Murder-One.
Did Abe get them set bail?
A million dollars apiece.
So go sign him out.
Posting that kind
of money's gonna raise...
more problems
than it solves, Frank.
Also, I want you to get Abe...
to talk to some of
those friends of his...
see if they can't get
this cop transferred...
or retired or something.
I want him out of my way.
He's chief
investigating officer...
on a multiple homicide.
It's stupid
to even think about it.
Ask him...
before I blow Bishop's brains
all over his fucking wing tips.
Get some guys and pick him up.
You got it, Frank.
Hope you had a good time.
My old man's back.
That's right.
Captain Crunch
and that doughnut crew is here.
Yo, fellas, what's up?
Long time no see.
Bishop, we having
a party downtown.
Why don't you bring Howdy Doody
and the Chocolate Wonder?
I hear your mother's
gonna be there.
We having a real
good time down there.
You know what I'm sayin'...
Give me some.
Black man.
Some flowers for your witness.
Jimmy, we got business to do.
We got business to do.
Get some cheap ones.
And you can kiss my ass, too.
I'll see you downtown.
You'll be all right?
What?
Proud of yourself, counselor?
If you got a problem,
take it to the judge.
Come on! Let's go!