Have you seen Francis?
-No, not lately.
It has been a while, right?
The social worker asked you
to come by.
Shut up. I don앖 have the
right to anything.
There is mail for you.
Should I bring it?
You have been gone for 5 days.
Don앖 you want to live together anymore?
Because I go out late, I don앖
want to move yet. Stop whyning.
Did you come here to drink something,
we haven앖 talked in a while.
Have you got any money?
-Yes, I앏l buy. Where are we going?
Give up, I앏l play again.
You know that girl?
-Sure. A first class whore.
I believe that immediately.
Can앖 you introduce me to her?
Nadine, phone for you.
It압 Francis.
Don앖 stand there like that,
I앏l lose my concentration.
Will you be late tonight?
-I don앖 know. Stop whyning.
There압 nobody here.
It압 a week now.
Its ok.
Manu...
Manu, come please.
Where is Radouan?
-Come here.
Are you watching that junk
again?
I thought you wouldn앖 come to eat.
-Shut down that tv.
You are totally insane.
If you were a guy...
Go to the kitchen.
I want to finger myself here.
I have had enough of doing it in my room.
Where are the papers?
-In the basket.
Do you smoke nowadays?
-No, it압 for you.
A gift from King Radouan.
Do you deal like your brother, fucking Radouan?
-Relax.
I am relaxed.
But the whole neighbourhood is talking about it.
You are so scared that the cops
will arest you.
He압 not the type
to jump at everything.
Something happened between us.
I shouldn앖 have done
it immediately the first night.
I don앖 understand
why he doesn앖 call back.
I think he압 affraid of me.
A girl with character scares men.
They feel less virile.
They are all sissies, that압 what they are.
Manu, come please.
You haven앖 seen Radouan?
-No. We don앖 live together.
Tell that dick that he압 wanted.
When we find him, he압 dead.
What did he do wrong?
-When we find that dick, he압 dead.
it압 ok.
Don앖 talk like that
or you will die!
No jokes, we will come and
find you. Understand? Fuck off now.
Do you still have some stuff?
-Or did you smoke everything?
Bah, you really are hopeless.
Are we going to drink something?
Have you got any money?
-I just got my welfare.
Are you French enough
to get that?
I'm going to my brother's.
-I don앖 want to see him.
What are you still doing
with that damn junkie?
Can앖 you do anything
with your shitty life?
Mind your own business.
There are always problems with you.
You are a piece of shit.
Can you lend me 300 francs?
-Your are daring.
Work. You know what that is?
-There's no work in France.
Thanks.
Come, lets go.
-Did you get hit, Manu?
You saw that. So what?
-You should have hit back.
I wouldn't take something like that.
-I am prepared for anything.
We will buy some beer and
go for a stroll on the quay.
You want me to come?
Yes, that would be nice.
There are some things...
I need to talk to you about.
Maybe you can tell me what
I have to do.
I have an importane meeting
now...
...but I will ask what time the
last train leaves.
OK.
-You will give me the address?
Juvisy, H進el de la Gare.
You can앖 miss it.
They have seen your porn movies.
With all those nice details,
I think it압 gross.
You help everybody,
then you have to hear something like that.
If you didn앖 want to tell it,
you should have shut up.
I앇 rather have you know it.
-Well, I know it now.
I could care less.
Shit on them.
Bring them to me, I앏l make
them stand in a row and shit on them.
Give me a beer..
You want to be a rebel?
Shall I show you what
I do to rebels?
You haven앖 had enough yet?
Stay down.
Take her out of there.
Lets go!
Take off your pants.
Strip or I'll kill you.
Exchange?
Turn around. On your hands and knees.
Hurry.
Shut up.
It압 like I am fucking a zombie.
Move your ass a bit.
What do you think you have
between your legs, asshole?
I았e had enough. Bitch.
Manu. How could you?...
How could you let him take you like that?
How could you, Manu?
They can have done much worse.
Were still alive, right?
How can you say that?
How can you say that?!
Because I don앖 care about
their stupid dicks.
I have had more in me.
You wouldn앖 leave your car behind
with valuable stuff in it either.
I can앖 keep dicks out of my pussy,
there압 nothing valuable in there.
It압 only a dick and were only
girls. It will be alright.
Damnit.
I will make you come.
You are touching my whiskey without
asking and you didn앖 even put it back.
Be happy there압 still something in it.
It압 always the same.
With everything I say,
you give stupid answers.
If you want to live together,
there has to be dialog and respect.
And you can앖 cope with that.
You really don앖 have some stuff?
What압 up with you?
Don앖 you have enough of being down?
Will you give me a Jack?
-No.
Come on.
Here you go, little princess.
Damnit asshole.
Kill him.
Waste him.
Stop it. It압 a poor guy.
-mind your own business.
Fuckers. Don앖 you see he압
a poor guy?
Don앖 you see he압 whyning?
Is he your sweetheart?
Do we have to waste you too,
bitch?
Leave her alone. Understood?
I will only tell you once... ok?
You, come here.
-No. I don앖 want that. They will kill him.
Come here.
Hurry up,
Mother Teresa.
Your big friend Francis called.
What do you see in that dirty junk?
-What did he say?
Nothing. He was totally stoned.
And I don앖 want to see him anymore.
When did he call?
He will be here for a few days
and then he앏l squat for 3 weeks.
He makes a mess, eats everything
and spills coffee everywhere.
And he shouts at me too.
He압 whining because I threw his
stuff away...
...because when he doesn앖 have enough speed,
he wants to filter it twice
I don앖 want to see him again.
-Please, be quiet now.
Stop it please.
Youre a fucking idiot.
How did you get those bruises?
From dickheads like you.
They always like to hit me...
...otheriwse they don앖 feel alive.
Did you have a fight again?
Youre always stoned.
They didn앖 rape you, right?
You haven앖 been raped, right?!
Who?
-That guy is a real pain in the ass.
He압 my best friend,
shut your fucking mouth.
Your best friend?
And you are his best slave...
...and he doesn앖 give a shit about you.
Your best friend.
Who was it?
Who did it?
It doesn앖 even come to your
mind, to ask how I am doing.
You are so dumb you make me puke.
You don앖 look th磬 traumatized.
Damnit, you make me puke.
Slut..... Slut.
Good evening.
Can I have the number of Francis Godot압
room?
Number 26, second floor.
He only payed for 1 person.
I only come for the evening blowjob.
How is it going?
-I am without Subutex.
Basic stuff.
Can you make a nice prescription for me
with nice...
...handwriting.
The above right, three boxes of eight.
I know. I have done it so many times
I know it by heart.
Didn앖 be rude on the prescription.
That will cause suspicion.
Now is not the time to
whine to me about that.
There압 something I really can앖
forget. Do you remember No泄le?
You know how she rode her
bike over the border, full of acid.
I have to get her false papers,
but I can앖 get them.
I have to be at the Luxeuil station
buffet on the 13th at 12 o앆lock.
Where압 that?
-In the Vosges.
First class.
But I can앖 be there.
You have to give her the papers.
She압 driving across the border,
with the stuff, her acid.
You have to take care of it.
Now a days there are enough
people with problems.
I am going downstairs for a while and my...
Thank you.
It압 nice of you to come.
-That압 normal, isn앖 it?
Have you seen it...
...there압 pharmacy near the hotel.
You know how to choose good hotels.
I am asking you something.
At the moment there are no trains.
Insane.
This is going to be a long night.
Fuck, no trains till tomorrow
night.
You aren앖 very social...
Where are you going?
To Paris.
To Paris?
Can you drive a car?
-Yes.
If you can drive, I have a car.
And I want to go to Paris.
Will you wait for me in Paris?
-Not really.
That압 convenient.
That압 very convenient.
I am in a very shitty position.
I bet you'll say again that
youre having bad luck.
I want to see the sea. Take me there.
That압 what the car is for,
with gas to go back again.
Can I ask you something?
-What?
Have you done any porno movies?
Yes. How did you know?
Is your boyfriend a fan?
I don앖 have a boyfriend.
I'm crazy about it myself.
That압 one point for you.
God damn. I'm thirsty.
Stop please, I have to drink.
Further down the road is a gas
station - There's the sign.
Good news.
But you better not do something
to me.
I really won앖 do anything.
If you want, you can take the car
now and drive away.
I am going to eat. And you?
I don앖 know. Eat with you.
Funny how we met eachother,
isn' it?
No, it압 not funny at all.
It was now or never.
We can see it like that too.
-We can go on a journey.
With your 10,000 Francs?
-I don앖 want to go anywhere.
And I have to be in the Vosges
on the 13th.
I don앖 want to screw No梭le.
We can stay together till then.
Too bad for her.
-Damn, I am scared.
What a funny feeling.
It압 going pretty fast actually.
You were standing to close to me.
I could have shot off your arm.
Because of that experience were
getting better.
What did you think about it?
Immediately afterwards I felt bad.
Really bad.
I wanted to sit down and cry,
end of the world atmosphere.
But now...
...I feel very good.
I would almost feel like doing it...
Again, right?
Awkward.
We don앖 know if they are looking for us.
Don't forget that
cops are stupid by nature.
But they're also very diligent.
And we weren앖 very cautious either.
You have to be sharp.
From now on we have to drink a lot.
And catch some guys.
The more you fuck...
The less you think and
the better you sleep.
What would be fun...
...is if you do 69 with us.
Fuck off.
Did you see how that dick went down.
With his expensive suit. Hello... Boom.
The face he made.
-Stupid fuck.
Where are we going?
-How would I know.
Where luck takes us.
And we앏l let the "you can fuck off"
side of our souls go it압 own way
I have cut myself everywhere.
-It압 crazy like that.
You don앖 know anything, it압 cool.
We are far from the Vosges.
We have to be there at the 13th.
What do we have to do there?
It압 far away, it압 cold and ugly.
We have an appointment there
with No泄le, right?
Yes, I forgot.
I would advise you to use the Beretta 92f,
with the Pachmayr grip, totally stainless steel.
It압 one of my favouite guns.
It압 very virile.
I think it압 great.
You push the magazine deep
into the end...
...you pull the sledge back,
unbolt on the side.
And the gun is ready to fire.
Remember to push the magazine
into the end hard.
Pull the sledge and unbolt
on the side.
And if your husband....
And if his wife
likes to shoot dickheads?
We don앖 have the right answers
at the right time.
But we do have the right actions.
That압 a start.
And we aren앖 doing it that bad.
No. But those people are going to die.
The dialogs need to have some level.
Crucial to death.
Will we prepare some lines?
-Ofcourse not.
Then we wouldn앖 have any ethics.
Don앖 forget to buy some drinks.
Did you buy drinks?
-Yes.
As a kid I spilled my drinks on
purpose to get my mom mad.
She got sick of it.
Damn, I am getting anxious to fuck.
Thanks.
Youre not playing?
You want some coins?
You will bring me some luck.
Only your dick, nothing else.
-But that압 dumb. Safe sex.
Can앖 do that anymore.
I can앖 do this.
It압 against my principles.
You can앖 get it hard.
That압 boring.
I don앖 know what압 wrong.
Maybe if you do it with your
mouth for once...
You are lucky I have a female
concious, pal.
Bitch.
That압 filthy.
I don앖 get what압 so funny about that.
Damnit.
I chocked myself..
Bitches.
Filthy fucking whores.
I didn앖 say you could leave.
What we didn앖 like about you,
was your condom.
You have been revealed, pal.
Your a condom dick.
You can앖 just go around fucking
unknown girls.
Because you never know who
your dealing... pal
With killers of condom-dicks.
Yuck... Terror in the city.
-Is our picture included?
No one will recognize us
with that.
We are just two girls,
one big and one small.
Do you want to feel my balls
against your ass?
Fucking bastard.
Do you know the way to Biarritz?
No, I don앖 see the signs.
You앏l have to tell me the way.
Me? Are you crazy? Just drive.
I have to tell you.
Will you just leave me like that?
Hello. Can we get a room?
The best looking room.
-The best...
There압 no better room.
Are there drinks in the room?
-No, but we have drinks down here.
How much?
-For the best room? 800 Francs.
This is a nice Hotel. Very nice.
OK...
See you later maybe.
Don앖 you think it압 weird
that nothing is happening?
You always have strange thoughts
about "nothing happening".
That we are sitting in a hotel
doing nothing after all this.
Like everything is allowed.
Tactically, it압 not good to
think about things like that.
Right.
We have to remain mentally strong.
Why not start ruining your
Jack with Coke.
I do what I want.
Excuse me....
I am thisty.
You are thirsty? You want a beer?
Good evening.
One beer, please.
Where are you going?
To the room.
-I am going with you.
Thanks, bye.
Damnit.
Too bad for them.
Good evening.
-Gendarmerie.
Do you have your license and registration?
-Ofcourse
They should be in my purse.
Sorry.
I hope you are not leaving me?
I also know who you are.
For being on the run like this,
you don앖 look that scared.
That압 because of our shortage
of fantasy.
You are going too far.
Everyone is scared to die or
to end up in prison.
It압 not about that.
Nobody escapes from it.
I don앖 know, but on tv
they said you shot a man...
...and a woman without a reason.
Does it have a better morals
if we want money?
We don앖 have extenuating
circumstances.
If I would have met you on the bus,
I wouldn앖 have wondered that much.
That압 the ultimate trick.
Come, girl... Come on.
We are going to bed.
Are you coming?
Are we going to bed?
Good night, girls.
-See you tomorrow.
He reminds me very much
of my brother.
Reminds me of the house
we will get sometime.
Thank you.
You too?
Why don앖 you go passed the border?
Too silly. And what would we
do somewhere else?
I don앖 believe is somewhere else.
You can앖 just sit here without
doing anything. That can앖 be.
Yes it can.
You can앖 just wait
untill they catch you.
I am hesitating between jumping
from something or burning alive.
But to just sacrifice yourself
is too arrogant.
After our first meeting in Vosges
I vote for a jump without a cord.
It압 a miracle that were
still here.
I want to end it just as good
as it all started.
A joke has to have a good
point.
You will have to push me before
the jump. I앐 too affraid.
I don앖 get it.
Don앖 worry, I will push you.
We should write the press
a letter too.
"They jumped without a cord."
Or else they will just make up something.
-Yes, communication is important.
Concentrate.
I don앖 have all day.
Now I missed it.
Concentrate please.
Don앖 talk to me like that.
You think your brave?
What kind of guy is it?
-An asshole. I am glad you are paying him a visit.
Did he do something to you?
-Getting on my nerves.
I wouldn앖 gladly get
on your nerves.
And the volt is there.
The dick lives in a huge castle.
Good morning.
-Hello, sir.
We work for the inquiry firm Lpsos.
Would you be so kind to answer some
questions about culture-consumption?
Sure. Come in.
-Thank you.
There we go.
I am ready.
Then we can start immediately.
I don앖 have a tv,
but I have heard about you.
I had someone else in my mind though.
I wouldn앖 have expected
to meet you either.
I won앖 ask how you know me.
-That would be misplaced.
I don앖 know anyone like you.
You must be different than others.
What you do, is...
...extremely violent.
You must have suffered very much
to become violent like that.
I don앖 know what you went
through...
...and I don앖 know why
I trust you.
Open the safe, pal.
-You are an open book to me.
I would be glad to make a deal
with you.
Get out of the way, asshole.
Unbelievable what he was talking
about before he opened that damn safe.
You already look a lot worse,
fucker.
No, I won앖 kill you.
-Thank you.
Hey, sis...
...kill that son of a bitch.
Good evening.
Champagne, please.
-Later.
I will have a walk around
-Here.
Fuck off.
Keep your dirty hands off me!
This a fuck club here,
not a Mosque.
Act like a pig, dickhead.
Act like a pig!
Strip those pants.
Yes, they must have coffee.
And with a little luck,
we will get some bread too.
Then we can stay together.
This is not the moment to give up.
I can앖 use that.
Don앖 move!
Where is she?
-Back off, nothing to see here.
Don앖 move.
-Please move back.
Where압 your friend?
where is your damn friend?