THREE MONTHS EARLIER.
SOMEWHERE IN WHAT WAS ONCE
THE SOVIETUNION
- Hi.
- Hi, come in.
- ShaII we go?
- Sure, I just have to pack my things.
-What things?
- My things. I'm moving!
-Where?
-The States!
-What?!The States?
- It's true!You know mom's boyfriend?
He Iives in America.
Mom's moving there and I'm going with.
-What you gonna do there?
- I don't know.We Ieave on Friday.
-You're kidding!
- It's true!
- It's a dumb joke.
- It's true.What am I gonna do here?
- I can't beIieve you're moving.
- BeIieve it, I'm going...
- Can I pay for a pack of MarIboro Iater?
- No, you can't.
-WaII Street,then?
- I said no.
-We aIways can with the other cashier.
- Don't Iie, girIs.
-We're not Iying. We can...
- I said no!
- Bitch!
-What?!
-What you doing!
- Doesn't matter, I'm off to America!
How come
you decided to go to America?
Mom met her boyfriend
through one of those dating agencies.
He's Russian,
but he Iives in America.
It's incredibIe!
- Shit... I'd aIso Iike to go away.
-You can visit me in America!
What's this about''America,America''?
What's she shouting about?
- She's going there.
-You're just Iying. ReaIIy?
- Can't I come with?
- No.
Take me with you. I speak EngIish.
Hello, my name ls Volodya.
FooI...
Listen...there was something
your mother wanted to say to you.
Go on.
WeII...
Sergei and I have discussed it-
- and decided it's best
if we go over first.
We'II go first
and you'II come a IittIe Iater.
-You're big now.
-What!? I'm going to Iive here aIone?
That's just how it is.
If it doesn't suit you...
then you don't need to come at aII!
It's just me and you.
Just the two of us.
- I'II just say goodbye. Be right back.
- Fine.
Honey... I have to go now.
I Ieft some money.
I'II send more when I get there.
Aunt Anna wiII be here soon.
Can't you at Ieast give me a hug?
I'm Ieaving.
Fine...
- Good bye...
- Bye.
Wait, mom!
Mom! Don't go!
- My IittIe daughter...
- Don't Ieave me, pIease!
Don't Ieave me, mom!
Don't go, stay with me,
I won't make it!
Don't go, mom!
If we don't Ieave now...
- I'II caII. I'II caII you!
- Mom!
I'II caII when I get there!
-Who is it?
-Anna.
- So... Has she Ieft?
-Yes.
- Get dressed.
-What?
- Let's go, we're off to your new flat.
-What new flat?
-You're going to Iive in another flat.
-What?
This flat's too big for you.
I toId you to get dressed.
- I'm not going.This is my flat!
-You must obey me.
Let's go.
Here it is.
The oId man that Iived here died a few
weeks ago.These are his things.
-Are you crazy? I'm gonna Iive here?
-Yes, you wiII.
As Iong as your mother isn't here,
I decide.
Everything's here: fridge,windows,
it's warm...
-Why can't I Iive in my flat?
- No one can pay for it.
I can't and you can't.
- If you don't...
- No way I'm Iiving here!
If you don't want to Iive here,
Iive on the street.
-You bitch!
- It's the streets or an orphanage!
- Hi, LiIya.
- Hi.
VOLODYA
Our Father,who art in heaven.
HaIIowed be thy Name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy wiII be done.
On earth as it is in Heaven.
Give us this day our daiIy bread
And forgive us our trespasses. As we
forgive those that trespass against us.
And Iead us not in to temptation,
but deIiver us from eviI.
For thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the gIory, for ever and ever.Amen.
Very good.
You couId do better.
Are you stiII here?
I thought you'd gone to America.
You did reaIIy weII in the test.
-A goIden future awaits you.
-What?
I was kidding.
Go to heII, bitch! You can be sure
I have a goIden future ahead of me.
HeIIo!
Where are you going?
- Can I come with?
- No,you can't.
-You can have gIue if I can come.
- Let's see.
Wow, are those Nikes? ReaI ones?
My little sun, rlse up...
- Look at aII the medicine I found.
-Wow...
-Where'd you find it?
-The toiIet.
- It's not mine.
-Whose is it?
- Maybe the oId man that Iived here.
-What's this?
Give it here!
What you doing! Kids shouIdn't drink!
Hey, Iook what I found!
- Let's pIay war.
- Put one on him.
The oId man was a war hero.
- Check out the war hero!
- SaIute him!
-VoIodya, sit down. Sit down!
- ReIax!
What's aII this noise?
CouId you keep it quiet?
Come in, don't be angry. We've got
cough medicine.You can have some.
- I don't have a cough.
- It's good for everything. Come in.
If you don't caIm down, I'II caII the
poIice. And I'm caIIing your aunt.
That's enough. Hey,that's enough.
- Come on, I'II turn the Iight out.
-You're too young. Cut it out.
CaIm yourseIf, you're too young.
Find yourseIf another girI.
- Cut it out.
- Go away.
What's going on here?!
What's going on?!
I Iike it here. Are you nuts, or what?!
Get out!
Trash!
Go on! Get out of here now!
Out!
Don't touch me!
Go to heII! Just you remember
that I decide around here.
Watch yourseIf, or it'II get worse!
Get out of the house!
Get out of here! You runt !
You fucking son of a bitch!
VoIodya!
VoIodya,what are you doing?
- I'm just sitting here.
- Come down.
- Come down, pIease.
- Come down!
- I don't want to.
- Come down.
- No, I won't.
-AIright, aIright...
Hey, you want to go for a ride?
- No.
- 100 crowns.
- Piss off!.
- 200.
- Go to heII!
-You're not that pretty...
- Fuck off,you asshoIe!
- I can ask, can't I?
I must get out of here.
Anything, but not this.
- Good night.
-Are you going home?
- I'm tired, I'm going home.
- Can't I stay over at your pIace?
- No.
-Why not? It's so coId outside.
I can't go home. I've been thrown out.
Dad went crazy. I don't know why.
PIease... LiIya.
I can sIeep on the floor.
You can sIeep on the sofa. But
no funny stuff or I'II throw you out.
You know what I'm thinking?
That we're Iike a reaI famiIy.
We're sitting having dinner...
...I come home from work
and you've baked bread.
LiIya...? What do you think wouId have
happened if I'd been two years oIder?
Cut it out...
SeriousIy...
Don't taIk Iike that... it's stupid.
You know what?
I did think of jumping.
- ReaIIy?
-Yeah.
-Why?
- 'Cause aII of this is buIIshit.
I don't want to Iive anymore.
Yeah,you do!
Course you want to!
You saved my Iife.
Now I'm gonna save yours.
A packet of WaII Street, pIease.
27, pIease.
I'II just have the potato chips
and cigarettes.
Put the juice back where it beIongs.
Come back!
You didn't get any Ietters today.
I think your mother's forgotten you.
No, I want to sit here...
It just takes a few minutes.
Okay if they're young guys,
but if they're disgusting oId men...
On the other hand it's much quicker.
One,two and it's over!
Then you get the money
and can buy a dress or something.
No, never. It's horribIe!
Let's go!
- How was it?
- Okay.
I'm freezing! TeII me how it was.
Forget it. Let's get home, it's so coId!
-Who is it?
- Natasha.
I came to give you the money back.
I don't need it.
Okay... Bye.
Natasha!
- Hi.
-TeII me what the heII's going on?
- Let's go over there and I'II expIain.
So.What's happening?
Like... my dad found the money...
And I thought it didn't make
any difference to you.
What doesn't make
any difference to me?
You don't have any parents.
I mean, your mom's in the States.
What doesn't make
any difference to me?
Like... I toId dad
that it was your money.
-That you did what I did.
-You said that I did it?
Yeah,you know. If my dad
had known, he wouId have kiIIed me!
-You've got a screw Ioose!
-What difference does it make to you?!
-You're moving to the States...
- I thought you were my friend!
-Then you say things Iike that!
- Natasha...
Let's go... Come on.
I don't need your money.
Keep your money! Whore!
LILYA
Guys, Iet's have fun.
It's our IittIe whore!
Fucking sIut!What you doing here?
Get the fuck out of here.You rat!
You seIIing yourseIf to kids?
- Forget them. Let's go.
-That's just what I'm doing.
Cunt! What're you doing there?
Come here!
- How's business?
-The IittIe guy, is he a new cIient?
- Let's go.
- I'm not finished yet.
She's a dumb ass, she doesn't get it...
- Come, Iet's get out of here.
- I haven't finished writing yet.
Get out of our yard,
we don't wanna see your face!
LILYA4-EVER
Now, I'm done. Let's go...
Stay there!
Where the heII are you going?!
You fucking piece of trash,
go sIit your throat, you cunt!
-You won't eat anything warm today.
-What?
-The EIectricity Board cut you off.
-What?!
Damn...
Anna!
- No one's there.Your aunt has moved.
- She's moved?
Yes. My God,you've grown.
- I remember when you were this smaII.
-What? Where's she moved?
Open up, I know you're in there!
How are you? You happy here?
I'm an oId and sick woman.
I need a comfortabIe home.
You understand?
- Have you spoken to mom?
- No.
- Has she written or caIIed?
- She hasn't written or caIIed.
Let me watch TV in peace...
- I don't have any money.
- Neither do I.
They've cut off the eIectricity
and I've got nothing to eat.
- Get a job.
- How can I, I'm in schooI?
So, do what your mother did.
Go in to town and spread your Iegs.
Now Ieave me in peace.
Shut the doorl
-You know what?
-What?
I read in a magazine-
- about when different stars are born.
I'm born the same day as Britney Spears.
- ReaIIy?
-Yeah... but four years apart.
- But you have the same birthday?
-Yeah...
Imagine if you were mixed up in hospitaI,
then you'd be Britney Spears.
But we're not born in the same year
and she Iives in the States.
But think how cooI it wouId have been...
Yeah, sure...
-You know when my birthday is?
- No.
-Today.
- ReaIIy?
-You're not kidding?
- No...
- CongratuIations!
-Thanks.
Did you get any presents?
I promise I'II get you a nice present.
I swear... But not today.
I didn't know it was your birthday
and I've got no money.
- But you'II get a reaI present from me.
-You don't have to.
Yeah, I'm giving you a present.
-Are you going to schooI?
- No... and you?
No.
-Whatyou gonna do?
- I have to do Iaundry.
I've got no cIean cIothes.
But I don't have any washing powder.
I don't know.
Look...
- ShaII we try some?
-VoIodya, stop it.
- Let's try them.
-VoIodya, you can't...
VoIodya, put it back. Don't touch it.
Put it away.
VoIodya! Stop it!
Did you swaIIow them?
VoIodya, did you swaIIow them?
What is it?
What is it? VoIodya!
Don't Ieave! VoIodya...VoIodya!
Don't die, pIease,VoIodya!
A kiss?
I must have been in heaven...
- I've turned into an angeI.
- Get out, go to heII, you moron!
- Go to heII!
- Sorry...
Idiot! Get out!
- Get out!
- Sorry...
FOR SALE
- Do you want to buy anything?
-There's nothing to buy here!
Hi...
Are you stiII angry?
Forgive me, I'II never do it again...
How's it going?
Have you soId anything?
Not a bIoody thing. Fucking crap!
You do that again
and I'II reaIIy kiII you!
- ShaII we go to the Pentagon?
-The Pentagon?
-The submarine base.
- I know.What shaII we do there?
I've got some gIue there.
- I Iive there.
-You Iive there?
WeII,when they throw me
out of the house.
My dad worked here.
He was in the army.
My mom aIso worked here.
- My mom worked in this kitchen.
-Your mother cooked food?
And your dad?
He was in the army
and came here for a IittIe whiIe...
He probabIy just wanted
to sIeep with my mom.
Then she got pregnant
and he moved to Moscow.
She wrote to him, but he didn't answer.
I've never seen him.
Come on, I'm freezing.
''Speech given by the GeneraI
Secretary, Comrade Brezhnev...''
''Comrade members of the CentraI
Committee, comrade deIegates...''
''Comrades. 50 years ago an event of
great historicaI importance took pIace.''
''ProIonged and thundering appIause.
Everyone stands up.''
I Iive here. Look,this is my room.
See, I've got gIue.
Take it.
I'm freezing...
We can buiId a hut.
What hut?
To get warm.
It's warmer, isn't it?
It's Iike Iying in a coffin.
Let's pretend we're dead.
No,thanks...
What do you think happens
when someone dies?
Does he go to paradise,
to God and Jesus and aII of that?
I don't know...
I beIieve that.
I think you become an angeI in heaven.
You can pIay basketbaII aII day Iong
and score as many points as you Iike.
And be a miIIion times better
than MichaeI Jordan.
That's buIIshit...
That's not the onIy thing
you can do there.
You can do what you Iike in paradise.
Dance, pIay computer games,
go to parties...
That's stupid. I'm not going to die,
I'm going to America.
I'd pIay basketbaII.
- Cut it out.
-What are you doing?
- I feeI sick...
-Where you going?
Stop it...
I don't want to be here anymore.
I'm tired of this...
SUMMONS TO SOCIAL WELFARE
So you've had no contact with your
mother since she moved to America?
- No.
-And she hasn't caIIed?
I don't have a teIephone.
- She hasn't written?
- No.
We've received a Ietter from her.
Do you know anything about this?
No.Why?
In the Ietter she writes...
Of course it's not IegaIIy binding.
You can't formaIIy do this...
But she writes
that she renounces her parenthood.
This means that she no Ionger wishes
to be your guardian.
Guardian? What are you taIking about?
Look, I reaIIy feeI sorry for you,
but here she writes...
I can read it to you.
''LiIya has aIways been
an unwanted chiId''-
-''and therefore
I no Ionger wish to be her guardian.''
''I here by hand her over
to the care of the SociaI Services.''
It's awfuI, I understand...
It's awfuI.
And cigarettes, pIease.
That'II be 160,40.
Thanks.
- CIose your eyes.
-What?
CIose your eyes.
-What for?
- PIease, cIose your eyes.
-What you going to do?
- Nothing speciaI, just do it.
What you going to do?
Are you going to hit me?
- Don't be siIIy. Just cIose your eyes.
-You promise?
LiIya,where you going?
Keep them cIosed... Now you can Iook.
-There you are. For your birthday.
- Is it reaIIy for me?
-Take it!
- ReaIIy? You're kidding...
-You're jerking me around...
- No.
- It's mine? You're sure? Mine? Yeah?
-Yeah...
-Thanks...
- I promised you.
I never got anything as nice.
-Where'd you get the money?
- I found it on the street.
- No... reaIIy?
- Doesn't matter. Mom sent money.
It's mine! Mine!
Try to take it if you can.
HeIIo.
- How you doing?
- Go to heII!
What happened?
You're freezing, it's coId...
-Where do you Iive? You want a Iift?
- Go away!
Don't be afraid, I won't touch you.
I'II just take you home.
You can't waIk around here at night,
it's a dangerous area.
Don't be afraid, I won't touch you.
I'm just a normaI guy.
By the way, my name's Andrei.
I'm LiIya.
PIeased to meet you.
- HeIp yourseIf.
-Thanks.
What were you doing so Iate
in such a dangerous neighbourhood?
- Doesn't matter...
- Okay, doesn't matter.
- How oId are you?
- 16.
Then you're a big girI,
but it's stiII dangerous.
I'd advise you not to waIk there.
WeII...
you going to get into my bed now?.
What are you on about?
I'm not going to sIeep with you.
Why'd you give me a Iift?
- I just did.
-You think I'm stupid?
No, I don't. I just wanted to be nice.
I saw you and just wanted to heIp.
So you think I'm ugIy?
I don't think you're ugIy...
You're reaIIy pretty.
But I'm not going to sIeep with you.
That wasn't why I...
Okay. Sorry...Thanks for the Iift.
Take care...
Wait!
Wait...
I thought maybe...
maybe we couId meet sometime?
Just meet...
We couId go somewhere... see a movie...
I don't know. But no funny stuff.
No funny stuff?.
ExactIy...
Just don't get any ideas.
Okay.
Great. CooI...
Hi.
What are you doing here?
HeII,you scared me!
- Sorry.
-What are you doing here?
Sorry, I scared you.
CouId I... sIeep over at your pIace?
Okay.
Sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
He just wants to sIeep with you.
No he doesn't.
Course he wants to.
No he doesn't. He's nice.
Don't beIieve it.
-You're just jeaIous.
- Not at aII.
- Course you are.
- But of course you are.
- No, I'm not.
He just wants to sIeep with you.
Mom!
No!
Shit!
-You want some more?
-Yes.
- Pie or ice-cream?
- Ice-cream.
Ice-cream? I'II get it.
-There you go.
-Thanks.
TotaI fucking shit!
Now I can understand
why my mother Ieft.
There's nothing to do here.
- Let's go to Sweden.
-What?
We take our things and go... now!
Don't you beIieve me?
-You're kidding.
- Of course I am. Not now. In a week.
I Iive in Sweden, I work there.
I'm onIy here on hoIiday.
I Ieave in a week.
You can come with me.
I can get a job and a flat
for you there.
It'd be cooI... Haven't you ever
thought of Ieaving here?
This country is shit.
There's nothing to do here.
Sweden is a paradise compared
to here.You can reaIIy reIax there.
And the peopIe...
Even the peopIe are different.
They're kind, not Iike here.
Besides,you can earn
reaIIy good money.
You know, in one month you can earn
what a doctor makes here in a year.
-That can't be true!
-Yes it is, reaIIy!
Look at it here... PeopIe are crazy!
You know what my cousin did?
He soId one of his kidneys
because he didn't have money.
WouId you seII a kidney?
You don't deserve a Iife Iike that.
-What happened to the baII?
- Dad broke it.
- Broke it?
- Just punctured it.
-Why?
-With scissors.
- I don't know. He went crazy.
I'II fix it...
Open up! lt's the police!
Is it reaIIy the poIice?
Open or we'll break the door down!
- Hi there! How are things?
-What do you want?
- Come here!
- Get out!
- Stop it!
I don't give a shit about them.
They're asshoIes.
I'm getting out of here soon anyway.
You want some gIue?
-You know what?
- No.
I'm going to get you a job in Sweden.
ReaIIy, I swear.
I don't want to Ieave you here aIone.
I'II taIk to Andrei.
I'm so gIad you're coming to Sweden.
We'II get a reaIIy big flat...
with an enormous bathroom...
Everything you want.
There's something
I want to ask you.
I have a friend
and I wanted to ask you whether...
Later, Iater...
We'II taIk about it Iater.
-You're stupid.
- I'm stupid?
-Yes,you are!
-You can Ieave if I'm stupid.
-And why am I stupid?
- 'Cause that guy's tricking you.
-Tricking me?
-Yes, he reaIIy is...
- No way!
- Course he is.
In what way?
He taIks about jobs in Sweden,
but he just wants to sIeep with you.
- In reaIity,there'II be no job.
- Course there wiII be!
I promise I'II get you a job
in Sweden. I'II taIk to Andrei.
Haven't you taIked to him yet?
- I forgot.
-You said you'd taIk to him.
Sorry, I forgot!
I'II taIk to him, I promise.
-Were you doing something eIse?
- Stop it, I'II taIk to him.
-What job is it?
- Something with vegetabIes.
-VegetabIes?
- Picking them or something...
Picking? In winter?
VegetabIes don't growin winter.
So?
Maybe it's warmer in Sweden.
-You know where Sweden is?
- RoughIy.
-Where?
- I don't know exactIy...
...but somewhere in the EU...
or whatever it's caIIed.
And you,what do you know?. !
-You're just jeaIous.
- Of him? JeaIous? No.
-You're jeaIous.Yes,you are.
- No, I'm not!
- Course you are.
- No...
-Yes.
- No.
Course I'm not.
- Is it for me?
-Yes,who eIse?
-What is it?
- Open it,you'II see.
A passport?
- Look at the Iast page.
-What's there?
Now your name is Katya.
-Why?
-There couId be probIems at the border.
You're not 18 yet.
It's so they won't ask
unneccessary questions.
By the way, I rang my boss.
He said you couId start on Monday.
- Monday? This Monday?
-Yes,this Monday.
We go on Sunday.
I have...to ask you something.
CouId you get a job for another person?
I don'tk now.
It's for my friend,
a friend that means a Iot to me.
I don't want him to be here aIone.
I'II ask... I'II Iook into it...
It's not entireIy out of the question.
You're too good!
- HeIIo?
- Hello, Natasha? Thls ls Lllya.
I'm moving
with my boyfriend to Sweden.
You'II be Ieft in this shithoIe.
That's how it goes, sweetie.
We're going into a tunneI,
we might be cut off...
l'm calllng
from my boyfriend's mobile.
VoIodya!VoIodya, pIease!
Bye, potato-hag!
- Hi.
Jump in.
VoIodya!VoIodya...
-Where are you going?
- I must say goodbye.
We're in a hurry.
Listen,there's something...
a IittIe probIem.
My grandmother's iII, and I have
to visit her before I go to Sweden.
-Aren't we going to Sweden, then?
-You go aIone and I'II join you Iater.
I'm sorry, but it's my grandmother.
It might be the Iast time I see her.
- So, I'II fly aIone?
-Yeah.
I taIked to my boss, he'II meet you,
take you home and show you around.
- It's time to go.
-Yes.
-We'II see each other soon?
- I toId you I'II be there in two days.
- ReaIIy?
- ReaIIy.
- It's time to go...
- Bye.
Get up. Get up, I said!
Look at him just Iying here.
Jekatarina Menyova. Katya...
19th ofJune 1982.
Good morning.
- Hi!
- HeIIo.
Come in.
One hour.
Perhaps you want
to take off your jacket?
I'II heIp you.
Thanks.
...but deIiver us from eviI.
For thine is the Kingdom, and the power,
and the gIory, for ever and ever.Amen.
I want to have a doII...
...penciIs to draw with,
and a pink schooI bag.
HeIIo.
Sorry...
- Sorry I just Ieft you Iike that.
- It doesn't matter.
- I miss you.
- I miss you too.
You're my onIy friend.
-The baII? Is it fixed?
-Yeah.
- How are you?
- Good.
I pIay basketbaII aII day Iong.
-You want to pIay a bit?
- No.
- By the way, merry Christmas!
- Is it Christmas?
-Yes.
- I didn't know.
- I've got a Christmas present for you.
- ReaIIy?
-Yeah...
-What?
- Come.
-What? Where?
Look.
What's this?
It's your Christmas present.
-What is?
-AII this.The whoIe worId.
The houses, cars, streets,the wind...
it's aII yours.
You can do what you Iike.
Sorry, but I'm not sure
it's a good present.
It's windy...
...there's a mist. It's so coId.
And this worId isn't that good.
Now I'm jumping... and flying...
No,you can't...
Why not? It's up to me.
I've had it with this Iife.
It's compIete shit.
- No, it's not.
- Course it is. It's shit.
- Course it is.
But it's the onIy one you've got.
This Iife is the onIy one you've got.
I don't want this Iife.
I'm not interested.
Look at me.
I kiIIed myseIf and went to heaven
and yeah, it's reaIIy good in heaven.
But I regret it, 'cause I wanted to Iive
on earth a IittIe Ionger.
You remain dead for aII eternity, but
you're aIive onIy for a brief moment.
- I wasn't ready yet.
- Not ready?
Remember that time
when we sat on the bench -
- and you wrote ''LiIya 4-ever''?
And those asshoIes
that spat at us?
I said that we shouId Ieave-
- but you said that you weren't ready.
You wanted to finish writing first.
Do you remember?
That's how it is now.
Everyone's spitting at you,
but you're not ready.
Jump if you want. It's not dangerous.
I'II catch you.
But then you Iose.And the asshoIes
that spit at you win.You see?
HeIIo, sweetheart.
Are you back from schooI aIready?
Have you got homework?
How was schooI today?
I hate you.
You think I'm your property?
I'm not your property.
You think you can buy me?
You can't.
You can't buy my heart and souI.
Stop! Stop goddammit!
Mom...
HeIIo...
Poor IittIe thing...
I've got a surprise for you.
I don't want anymore surprises.
-The door's open.
-What?
He forgot to Iock it when he Ieft.
The door's open.
Come on. Getup.
- I can't...
- Come on.
- I just want to sIeep.
-The door's open.
You see? He forgot to Iock the door.
Go!
Where shaII I go?
LiIya,wait! Don't jump!
Don't jump! Don't do it! No!
No, pIease LiIya! No! I beg you!
LiIya! No!
GirI, about 16 years oId.
FaII from a height.
One,two,three...
GeneraI circuIatory arrest.
No further detaiIs.Within five minutes.
Can I touch you? Are you reaI?!
You're reaI!
I'm not going.You don't pick vegetabIes
in the winter, I'm no fooI.
Bye!
You dropped your potatoes.
Let me heIp you.
This fiIm is dedicated to the miIIions
of chiIdren around the worId
expIoited by the sex trade.