Mr. Burns, any comment
about your possible indictment?
I must get to the hospital .
My wife's ill .
I' m very sorry. Perhaps
you can empathize with the people. . .
. . .who have been wiped out
of their entire life savings.
-What about them?
-No comment.
-How many people you hurt?
You know how many. . .
. . .senior citizens over the age of 65--?
Mr. Burns may have had
no comment for KXBD. . .
. . . but he may be compelled to find
his voice for the district attorney.
Inquiries made by this reporter
prompted an investigation. . .
. . .into Ralph Burns and his role
in the Foothill Federal Bank scandal.
-We' re not using that.
-It's an exclusive.
-It's conjecture.
-It is not.
Let me have another crack at him .
Tell him to answer my questions.
-Why?
-You' re not a judge. We' re not a jury.
-You know him, right?
-Yes, I know him .
-You play golf with him .
-Occasionally.
His wife has cancer.
He's under pressure. Leave him alone.
Wait. Three questions.
No, no and no.
He's a sleaze.
He stole money.
He took the savings of senior citizens.
We say that the man has no comment
and we finish the piece.
We don't ambush him at his work.
I don't want to ambush him .
I just want to ask him one question.
You are relentless, you know that?!
You seem to forget
we cover the news. . .
. . .of this area
for the people of this area.
And we are not going anyplace.
Are we going anyplace, Max?
-If they wanted me back in New York. . . .
-They don't.
You better come to terms with that.
I did .
In the 1 1 months that I've been here,
you've gone from a 3 share to a 9.
Excuse me!
Excuse me, people!
Whose week was it to kiss Max Brackett's
ass for saving this station?!
The bank story might make you
look like network.
No, not here.
There's a line I won't cross.
-I' m not asking you to.
-Yes, you are.
I am not. I' m saying,
you move the line, you get the story.
You going out to the museum?
Yes, trying to get it on
at noon.
Mr. Brackett's taking that assignment.
The state has let off
some people down there.
It's a great story.
You'll relate to it.
-I must finish my edit.
-I'll do it. What are friends for?
You really are an asshole.
-What am l?
-A wonderful human being .
Why don't you go to the museum
with Mr. Brackett.
You could run tape while you' re there.
Maybe we'll use it tonight.
She's an intern!
Then you can be her mentor.
Teach her how to " move the line. "
I' m gay.
Mr. Brackett. . . .
Max.
Can I put a microphone on you?
We'll get the curator to tell us why the
museum is facing drastic budget cuts.
And then we'll find
a couple of locals to tell us. . .
. . .that without a museum,
the city's a dog kennel .
Then, as a brilliant career move,
you' re taking me to lunch.
-You have to answer.
-You' re done.
Is that the answer?
You did it wrong .
It's much better on the lapel .
Can you help me?
We' re looking for the curator.
I know you. TV, right?
-Right.
-You' re the TV guy.
You' re the museum guy.
No, I' m the guard .
-The museum has financial problems?
-Tell me about it.
There were 2 of us.
The other guy got laid off.
-Is that right?
-You never know who'll be next.
Stick around . Maybe we'll get you
to say that on camera.
Really?
Mrs. Banks' through there.
Right. We don't pay much.
More than I make here.
They' re not the Mohawks, Mr. Brackett.
The Miwoks are from northern California.
They have a very rich past.
We currently have on exhibition
the largest display of lndian baskets. . .
. . .ever assembled
by a museum of this size.
Some would say it's not responsible. . .
. . .to pour money
into a dying institution.
Then let's close down the libraries,
museums and symphonies.
If we do not learn from our past,
we will be. . .
. . . doomed to relive it.
Yes, Mort.
I see dinosaurs.
The fear of today is that the museum
might share the same fate.
That's right, Mort.
That is exactly the fear.
Very good . Thanks.
It's okay, Mort.
We' re clear.
Good .
You must've done this before.
Good heavens, no. I haven't.
I feel strongly about this museum .
My great-grandfather founded it.
Right. I thank you for your time
and wish you all the best.
Come on down from there.
In the next room we have a stuffed dodo.
Come and take a look.
Give me the mike.
Get some of this.
One's Cretaceous, the other's Jurassic.
I know .
Come on, let's go.
Why are they together?
Want to go outside and get B-roll?
Where's the bathroom?
I'll freshen up.
Get your cam ready.
I'll do a stand-up for tonight's news.
Sorry.
I' m standing in front of the museum . . .
. . .where the past collided
with the hardships of the present.
Actually, you' re standing at the urinal
at the museum and look who's here.
Your friend, dick.
A fine upstanding young man.
No, no longer young
and no longer upstanding .
Tell me, dick,
what's your comment on my situation?
Max, I think you should get packed.
I can't. I got screwed there.
That's more than you' re getting here.
And as long as we' re on the subject. . .
. . . I kind of have a little tickle. . .
. . .for that young camera girl
working for you.
Really?
She 's young enough to be my daughter.
I know it. She 's just right for me.
You shouldn't be here.
Mrs. Banks, you must listen to me.
I don't have to do any such thing .
-One minute.
-I told you, there's nothing I can do.
I'd take a reduction, okay?
Do you have a hearing problem?
No, no hearing problem .
This is completely out of my hands.
You' re wasting both of our times.
You must leave now . Now .
Get out of here!
Right now !
Now will you listen?
Will you listen?
Are you?
Are you going to listen to me?
You must be kidding .
No, I' m not.
All right, hold up. Hold up.
Now just stay there, okay?
And hush up.
And don't be scared of the gun.
I got to talk to her.
I need 5 minutes with you, that's all .
I hope you' re not pointing that at me.
Just be quiet.
Is this some kind of a joke?
Because it won't be so funny
when the police arrive.
Shut up!
Give me the keys.
Come on.
Damn.
This way.
Quietly.
I hope we get to see some shooting .
Van two, this is Laurie.
Will you accept a collect call
from Max Brackett?
Mr. Brack-- I mean, Max?
There's a man with a gun in here.
Where are you?
The museum .
Okay, I' m going to call the police.
Call Lou. We'll go live. The police
we'll call when it's their turn.
I think I should call--
We have some real news going on here.
Don't blow this.
Okay, I'll call Lou.
Lou, line 3.
It's Laurie. It's urgent.
It's Brackett again.
What do you got?
Gunman.
He's got a rifle and a canvas bag .
I' m guessing more firepower.
He's holding 2 adults and some kids.
Laurie, how soon
before you can power back up?
2 minutes.
That's too long .
Tell Dohlen to get ready to go live
with Max. He's got a hostage situation.
Max, Mort's going to throw it to you.
Listen to me.
There are kids involved here.
We don't want any grandstanding .
Don't worry.
We got good stuff here.
Keep the line open.
We' re live.
We now go to Max Brackett, who is
inside the Museum of Natural History. . .
. . .with a hostage situation.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can.
I am inside the men 's room. . . .
Mobilize every camera
and audio crew you can get.
Most of them are children.
Do you know what his motives are?
I don't. But I can tell you
that the gunman does seem agitated .
Can you escape?
Can you hear me?
Think about what you' re doing .
Can you hear me, Max?
Does Jen know you' re here?
I don't know how much longer I can--
-I want you to be calm .
-No, you be calm .
I got 2 things to tell you.
I' m not listening to you as long as
you' re holding that stupid gun.
Why should l? This is absurd .
Get that stupid thing away from me!
Oh, God !
- That was a shot, right?
-Cut the feed, now .
Someone was hit in front of the museum.
I didn 't get a good look at him.
What asshole pulled the plug?
We' re still live, Max.
You did it. You did it.
He's okay.
He could be dying .
-Listen to me.
-Want him to do that on camera?
They didn't pull the plug
when the Challenger blew up.
Our viewers don't need to see the blood .
We' re telling them what's happening .
Mort is.
We 've got live pictures
and you 're giving them radio.
He's right!
It's the story of your career.
In 24 hours, this turns into a gangbang .
There's 1 000 people with cameras here.
If you don't record it, they will .
-Please don 't blow this.
-Go.
Yeah, move.
We have reestablished our live hookup
to the museum . Max, are you there?
Yes, Mort, I am still here.
Sorry, the camera 's not responding.
Wait a minute, I see a figure. . .
. . .approaching the wounded man.
I can 't make him out.
Why are we on TV?
Oh, my God .
You' re bleeding .
Can you walk?
I don't know .
I just called the ambulance.
That's Laurie Callahan.
Max, how are the children?
These kids are very frightened.
They're terrified.
They' re together
in one corner of the lobby. . .
. . .with the curator
on the floor next to them .
The teacher is tending to them.
Trying to keep them calm.
Mort, the situation has shifted
dramatically. A man has been shot.
A line has been crossed.
We have a very dangerous situation here.
It reminds me. . .
. . .two years ago. . . .
Oh, God .
We' re live on the air.
Max Brackett, KXBD News.
Want to tell us why you' re here?
You don't? Okay.
-We lost him .
-What happened?
Can you hear me?
Max Brackett, are you there?
Max, are you there?
We 've lost contact momentarily with
Max Brackett, reporting from the museum.
This is not news, brothers and sisters.
Stories like this happen every day.
What we have here is news
for all time in the Word of God .
I want you people out of there!
Back up! There's an armed man inside!
This is dangerous!
Franklin, Johnson,
I want those people off the steps now !
What happened?
Can you tell me who shot you?
How do you feel?
Sir, can you tell us who shot you?
Are you all right?
One man? Two men?
There's the chief!
Chief Lemke, do you
have any plans yet?! Do you know--?!
Do you have a statement?
What are you going to do?
Our cameraperson has informed us. . .
. . . that the victim 's name
is Clifford Williams. . .
. . .a security guard at the museum.
Mom !
It's Dad .
Coming up. . .
. . .an unexpected role for pigeons here
in New York today at the United Nations.
We'll have that story and more. . .
. . .when we return.
We' re back in two.
I heard you talking
during the broadcast. What's up?
Hostage situation.
Who's feeding it?
It's our affiliate
in Madeline, California.
Guess who the reporter is?
-Who?
-Max Brackett.
I knew that bastard would pop up again
with something spectacular.
Absolutely.
Here's the tease you' re going to use
at the top of the hour.
I' m not sharing a broadcast with him .
He's a loose cannon.
Say, "The situation's still unfolding .
Tune in tonight for an update. "
I' m not saying that. I' m not
teasing a story I know nothing about.
I promise them a story
and it evaporates.
How does that make me look?
How does that make the network look?
It's from above.
We' re back in 30.
Goddamn foolishness just because
somebody thinks this is a good lead-in.
With Brackett, it won't evaporate.
Kevin. . .
. . .it's a guy getting shot. . .
. . . bunch of kids taken hostage.
It's good television.
And no other net has it.
The man can't be trusted .
I' m not broadcasting . . .
. . .with that crazy son of a bitch.
Remember what he did?
It was before the beginning of time.
5 and 4, 3. . . .
Call Madeline.
Find out how Brackett got there.
I want to know
what the hell he's doing there.
Now that the gunman has shown
a willingness to use firepower. . . .
It was an accident, moron.
-Boys!
-It's broken.
I just want my job back.
Now look at this.
Look at this!
I' m never going to get my job back now .
Everybody knows who I am,
where l--
Your fault. Everyone knows where I am
because of you.
Everyone knows you' re here
because you shot someone.
Shut up, newsboy.
You really did this
to get your job back?
What do you think?
That's for you.
If you make contact. . .
. . .tell them everyone is okay in here.
You'll buy yourself some time.
I'll tell them they better back off
because I will shoot someone.
This first one will be you.
I'll throw your body out the front door.
I wouldn't do that.
Why not?
That'll just make everybody jumpy. They
might do something we'll all regret.
Remember that hostage situation
in Torrance about 2 years ago?
Yeah, car dealership.
4 people died .
One was the gunman.
Shut up.
I was there.
I covered that story.
This is Chief Alvin Lemke.
Am I speaking to the man responsible
for this situation?
Yep, you are.
Could I have your name, please?
No.
How's that guy? Cliff?
ls he all right?
No, he's in the hospital !
May I have your name, please?
Listen. . .
. . .you must know I didn't mean
to shoot him . That was an accident.
That's good .
That's a good thing .
We will take that into account
if you give up now .
No.
-I don't think so.
-No, he's a killer.
I don't think I can do that.
What do you want?
What are your demands?
My what?
What do you want?
Hold on.
He said, "What are my demands?"
Tell him .
I don't have any.
I didn't plan on this.
I don't wish to appear hostile,
but you' re making my job difficult.
Tell them that you'll talk
when you' re good and ready.
And no bodies out the front door.
Right.
I want everybody to back off and I' m
going to talk when I' m good and ready.
Hello?
He hung up.
How was that?
Sounded good to me.
That was good .
Why don't you sit down?
Just sit down.
All right now . . .
. . .what's next?
You give up
or you get yourself some demands.
-Like what?
-Money.
-Ransom .
-No, I can't take money I didn't earn.
I want my job back.
No, you got to ask for a fast car,
or a Lear jet or a Greyhound bus.
You have to have a valid demand
or you'll make them nervous.
I came here to get my job back.
Why did you bring a gun?
-I want her to listen!
-Who?
Mrs. Banks!
Look. . .
. . . I can't go out there.
If I do, I'll be put in prison.
I can't take care of my family
in prison.
There's different ways of giving up.
What?
-Which way?
-Can I show you something?
Here.
No, that's dangerous.
You got another window in this place?
Now, listen.
Slowly.
-Have you ever been arrested?
-No.
That's very good .
American bald eagle.
I want you to look at this.
See those people?
Not the cops, not the news media.
I want you to look. Go on.
See?
The people.
-That's public opinion.
-I guess so.
That's a powerful force.
You got a problem right now .
Those people hate your guts.
You' re holding kids hostage
and that's a no-no.
At best, they think you' re nuts.
But I' m not.
I mean, not usually.
Jenny tells me I don't think.
Who's Jenny?
-My wife.
-And you' re--?
"Sam . "
I don't think you' re crazy.
You' re just an ordinary guy
who's popped his top.
But you must connect
with those people out there.
They know what it's like to lose their
job, or they know someone who has.
They'll understand
if you give them a chance.
The one thing you might want to do
before you give yourself up. . .
. . .is let those people know
what you' re about.
How?
If I put a camera on you right now
and I interview you. . .
. . .and you tell people what's going on,
I think they'll want to know .
Don't you?
No.
That's your jury pool out there.
All right.
Exchange the kids for the interview .
No.
You help them, they help you.
One.
One, that's it.
One's good .
No, I can't do that. I can't put
a hostage-taker on television.
I understand.
He's insisting
that I put him on right now .
"As a good faith gesture,
I will let one child go.
Once Mr. Brackett has put me on TV,
I will . . .
. . . I will consider
releasing the others. "
No, you let everybody go first.
Hold on.
-He said let everybody go first.
-He can't negotiate with your emotions.
Unacceptable!
Don't negotiate my emotions.
Hello Sheriff Lemke, Max Brackett.
I know the rules about these things--
Is he listening to us?
-No, sir, he's not.
-Is he pointing his weapon at you?
I can guarantee Mr. Baily's sincere. I
think that things'll become unstable. . .
. . .if you don 't grant him this.
Jesus!
I don't like this.
-I know you don't.
-Tell him I' m upset.
But this man is very upset, sir.
Things are very unpredictable here.
All right, look. . . .
Okay, but I want this over quickly,
understand?
Someone.
That's all you' re going to get.
They'll want to know what's in the bag .
Nothing .
May I look?
Oh, man!
My brother-in-law uses it
to clear stumps away on his farm .
Why'd you bring it?
Because I wanted
Mrs. Banks to believe I was serious.
The gun's not enough?
I wanted to impress her!
What are you going to do with it?
I just want to go home.
You don't need it anymore.
I'll take it.
Now, go. Now, just go.
How do I know you' re coming back?
Because you' re the best show in town.
Wait a minute.
Wait!
Come here.
I need to ask you something .
I need you to talk to my wife, okay?
Because when she finds out about this. . .
. . .she's going to be upset big-time.
The press will be all over her.
Oh, man!
That's okay. Want me to fix it
so I' m the only one who talks to her?
-Only me?
-Just you.
You got it.
You watch yourself.
Chief!
Stay here.
Mr. Brackett,
are the children all right?!
Go get your camera.
-How are the kids?
-The kids are fine.
What's the story?
The story is he has enough dynamite to
level the place, so don't piss him off.
Jesus!
Excuse me.
I' m Mr. Brackett's assistant.
Come here.
Don't get cocky.
You want to make your TV show,
then you cooperate with me.
You scratch my back. . . .
Notice all the cameras are on my back
and your face is on the channels.
When I go in front of the camera,
I'll say you' re in charge.
-May I go now?
-What's his name?
Sam Baily.
Please?
-You may go.
-You' re hitting a pressure point.
-I know I am .
-I got the parents right over here.
Can you tell us
what's going on in there?
I just want to say
that your children are fine.
We' re doing everything we can to resolve
the situation as soon as possible.
You won't believe this,
but your kids are playing inside.
When will it end?
The police don't have any control
so some news guy's running things?
I' m not running anything .
What would happen
if I decided to get my kid?
That wouldn't be a good idea.
That's right.
You'd put everyone's kids in danger.
Mister Mayor.
Cochran and I are doing everything to
make sure your kids are home for dinner.
Don't talk to the press.
Network orders. We' re going national .
What's going on?
Sorry, we've been promoted .
You 'll have to turn on the news
when I report it.
We go now to Max Brackett. . .
. . . for an exclusive report
on the situation in the museum.
It's good to see you safe.
This is a remarkable job you' re doing .
Thank you, Mort.
I was just. . . .
I'm just happy I was in a position
to help the children.
I'm optimistic that Mr. Baily--
Should we bring Broyles down from
San Francisco if this takes hold?
We can ask, but what for?
Brackett was born for this job.
Look at him .
He's a pig in shit.
Kevin, anyone ever feel him out
for anchor work?
That's an anchor?!
Look at him .
I wouldn't even
buy a new car from that guy.
He'd never sit behind a desk. He wanted
to be where the bullets were flying .
Then he got too hot to keep around
after your little incident.
Little incident?
Are we suffering from memory loss?
He did his two years in the sticks.
He learned his lesson.
He chilled .
Max, we understand you are going back
inside the museum.
Yes. Mr. Baily has agreed
to release one child.
What about that girl in the glasses?
-You' re asking me?
-I got to choose somebody.
-Do you have children?
-I have two.
-Could you bear saving just one?
-Quiet.
Let all of them go. That's how you'll
get people to sympathize with you.
Everybody's going to get to go home.
You just got to take turns.
I would like to say I stand by to offer
whatever help I can give, and hope. . .
. . .there will be a peaceful resolution,
without further violence.
Be careful, Max. . .
. . .and Godspeed.
Thank you. Godspeed .
-We' re clear.
-Mort has Shakespeare writing for him .
We were number one.
What happened with the guard?
What do you mean?
You left the camera
and went to help him .
He was hurt.
Why didn't you take the camera
if you' re going to be so humane?
Because I can't--
I can't hold a camera
and help someone at the same time.
By not having your camera. . .
. . .we lost footage
nobody else would have had .
You must decide whether you are
going to be part of a story. . .
. . .or record the story.
Max, it's Lou.
I want you with me
from the start to the end of the story.
Hi, Lou.
You having fun?
I send you out for some fluff and
you come back with a hostage situation.
I guess I' m just not
one of your fluffy kind of reporters.
He's an average guy. He's married .
He's got kids. He flipped .
And now he's the Terminator.
What does he want?
Wants his job back. Wants to be heard .
A little dignity.
And we' re stuck in the middle.
It's a good place to be.
If you 're uncomfortable with it. . .
. . .we don't have a contract.
-I can go to another channel .
- The network called.
Looks like
you' re back in the big saddle.
There's nothing like old friends.
Look at this jerk.
What a showboat!
Zoom in.
It's a military helicopter!
Which one gets to leave?
I was thinking of that girl
in the glasses.
Which one?
That one.
Let's give them two.
-No, I said one.
-You shot a black man.
Some people
are going to make an issue of that.
Show kindness to a black, it's harder
to play the race card against you.
You understand?
Two kids are being released !
Hurry up!
All right, what happened?
Did he treat you okay?!
Let them say something !
Right next to the man.
There she is.
Maybe I'll see my mom .
I hope I see my mom .
Look!
A bigger one.
I came in. I don't know,
I was twenty minutes late and . . . .
You see, the night before
we had a softball game. We won.
I had a double and a triple.
So we were happy. We had a party
and I had, I don't know . . .
. . .three beers,
something like that.
The next day I came into work
and Mrs. Banks told me to come in--
Leave out the part about the ball game,
and the drinks.
-Yeah, but we drank. I mean, I drank.
-Sure, but that's not why you got fired .
Let's not give them that impression.
Start from " Mrs. Banks. . . . "
Mrs. Banks-- See, she didn't ask me.
She tells you what to do, okay?
It's like those dinosaurs.
Her great-granddaddy made, I mean. . .
. . . he just put them there
and that's enough for her.
I have no clue
as to what you' re talking about.
-She does.
-We can leave out the dinosaurs.
Mrs. Banks said . . . .
"We have two security guards. . .
. . .we don't need them
because we must cut back on money.
We only need one. So Cliff,
who's been around here longer. . .
. . .and he, you know . . . . "
So I said, "All right, fine. I'll take
less money or I'll take less hours. "
She didn't listen.
Did it ever occur to you
that I might deal with problems. . .
. . . bigger than your personal economics?
That my job is running the museum,
not my employee's careers?
I came to you twice, you didn't see--
I couldn't at that moment.
Well, don't turn around .
You only want things your way.
Walk over there and make sure
the buffalo are grazing properly.
Bison.
I stand corrected .
Let me ask you something .
Is this the first time you came
to see her? Today? Mrs. Banks?
No. The second time.
The second time.
I want you to tell me what
you were feeling when she fired you.
-This will sound stupid but. . . .
-Go ahead .
You know that thing in a car
that measures miles?
-The meter.
-It goes back to zero.
That's what was going on in my mind .
I couldn't tell my wife.
You couldn't tell her you were fired?
Then I'd get dressed for work every day,
like a fool, and . . .
. . . I'd just go to some movie theater
and just spend the day. . .
. . .sitting, eating popcorn, thinking .
And today, when you came here,
what did you want?
I just wanted her to listen.
Did you want to hurt her?
Not really.
Why would you grab a gun and explosives
if you didn't want to hurt her?
I don't know .
You have to know .
Sam, this is critical .
When you grabbed that gun,
what went on in your head?
I thought about my babies.
That's a good point.
What about them?
You see, if I lose my job,
I lose my house and my benefits. . .
. . .and I can't take care of them
if I lose my benefits.
I' m in front of Sam Baily's house,
and I' m joined by his best friend . . .
. . .Travis Bartholomew .
That's right. I know Sam well .
We go fishing and stuff.
So, what's he like?
ls he weird or what?
Who is he?
Who is this guy?
You could say he 's pretty weird.
Does he have a temper?
Temper?
If we could talk to a few of them . . . .
Mr. Brackett said that
we were only to talk just to him .
He says it's better for Sam .
Dangerous, yeah.
Dangerous.
Whatever, you know?
You heard it
from the best friend of Sam Baily.
Thank you very much.
How could Sam do this to us?
How could he?
There appears to be activity
in the house. Let's get a statement.
They' re standing in my flowers!
That does it!
Would you get out of my flowers?
Do not stand in my flowers!
Has your husband been in contact
with you? Can we get a statement?
I' m here. Jackson is with the victim's
wife. I' m being completely blocked out.
-Ready?
-Anytime.
Roll .
Your husband was kept on at the museum .
The man who was let go, a white man,
came back and shot him .
Do you feel
race had anything to do with that?
Cliff and Sam were friends.
Sam didn't blame Cliff
for what happened .
At least, I don't think he did .
Christ, I' m going to hate this.
Chief, showtime.
Here we go.
It's about to start.
We take you now, live,
inside the Museum of Natural History. . .
. . . to meet the hostage-taker.
We now bring you an exclusive report.
Max Brackett is inside the siege.
Key in the graphic.
You are Sam Baily
and you 're a loving husband. . .
. . .and a devoted father of two.
You've got a mortgage,
car payments, medical bills. . .
. . .food bills, electricity bills,
gas bills, clothing bills. . .
. . .and, by the way. . .
. . .you' re fired .
I just want to say that I' m . . . .
I didn't mean to shoot that guy, Cliff.
That was an accident.
And . . . .
I used to complain about my paycheck.
And then when. . .
. . .when I didn't get it no more. . .
. . . I realized that was the last. . . .
That little piece of paper
was the only thing . . .
. . . holding my life together.
And . . . .
You know, when I seen. . .
. . . I seen
people out on the street living . . .
. . .and . . .
. . . I thought. . .
. . . they were maybe
like bums or like junkies.
And then one day. . .
. . .I seen this family live. . . .
I seen this family living in a box
and. . .
. . . I imagined my babies living
in that box and I couldn't stand it.
I went crazy.
And . . .
. . .about the gun. . . .
It's just a Remington gun.
It ain 't nothing, really.
It's just. . . .
I've seen on TV shows. . .
. . .where they flash a gun
and it gets them attention.
I thought
maybe if I brought the gun in. . .
. . .that Mrs. Banks,
who's my boss. . .
. . .she would . . .
. . .she would listen, you know,
for maybe just even five minutes.
You know, but. . .
. . . I don't know
if people listen to guys like me.
I'm just a guy that has a job, goes to
work everyday and people don 't listen.
We' re a good family.
We don't do drugs. . .
. . .and we don't cause trouble.
We go to church.
I go to church too,
with my family.
But I don't think anybody listens
to someone like me.
I don 't think anybody cares
about someone like us.
This guy shot a man in cold blood . . .
. . .and I feel like bringing him home
for Christmas dinner.
Let's run a nationwide poll
and see how this guy is playing .
I don't know if anybody's listening .
Are they?
Your name is Sam Baily. . .
. . .and the law is pushing in on you.
Because of one impulsive act, you' re
trapped in the fight of your life.
Your sole demand, Sam . . .
. . .is simple
to the point of absurdity. . .
. . .and yet dauntingly complex,
isn't it?
I just want the police to--
I just want everybody
to forget about it. . .
. . .and let me go home.
Yeah, right.
I feel so bad about what I did to Cliff.
He 's my friend.
I'm praying for him.
And I know when he feels better,
he 'll forgive me.
I' m sorry, Cliff.
The kids, you know, they' re fine.
They' re happy.
Look.
They' re okay.
Look, we' re on TV!
Kids, please sit down.
The kids,
they' re seeing themselves on TV.
Start over right now about the kids.
Talk about the kids.
I'd never hurt them .
I would never hurt them .
I got kids of my own.
I just don't have a job to take care
of them . I don't know how I will .
But ljust want to say I'm sorry.
I couldn 't be sorrier.
-That's my daddy.
-Phillip, come back here.
Come here.
Mommy wants to watch Daddy.
I just want to go home, okay?
Just. . . .
I want to go.
And that's my demand .
That's it, right there.
Hey, wait.
Sam, wait.
I hope I don't have to
go through that again.
We' re not finished yet.
You know why?
Because people watching this right now
are saying, "Yeah, right.
This guy's holding a gun
on a bunch of helpless kids--"
I ain't holding no gun
on no helpless kids! They' re okay.
They think you are.
And they think you should be shot. . .
. . .executed . . .
. . .strung up.
For the people who are saying this,
what do you have to say to them?
I hope you never go through this.
You say it to them .
I hope nobody ever has to go through
what I' m going through now, that's all .
Your name is Sam Baily. . .
. . .and you' re asking
for the most poignant ransom of all :
Forgiveness.
And while we all have it
in our hearts to give. . .
. . .we' re not the law .
Why'd you bring up that shotgun stuff?
Reporting exclusively for KXBD News,
I'm Max Brackett.
We' re clear.
I thought it was great.
-Why'd you bring up the shotgun?
-It was for your own benefit.
It didn't seem like it.
Believe me, it was important.
All right, now what?
Now what?
Now we wait.
Take a look out there.
Is anybody listening?
Is anybody listening
Careful .
See what I mean?
-What do you got?
-Baily's all over the place.
Television, radio, newspapers.
Take a look
at the front page of the Times.
Turn the radio up a little.
This guy has never broken a law
in his life. He is under pressure.
We can all understand,
and so I think we should let him walk.
The situation's a shame, isn't it?
Man takes children hostage. . . .
This is America.
It can make you crazy.
Hollander arrived the next morning and--
You'll see why Hollander
still hates Brackett's guts.
They were live.
What's it like out there?
It's basically a mess.
There 's a kind of a. . . .
The wreckage is spread over a wide area.
I don 't know how many acres.
-Any bodies?
- Yes, there are.
What condition are they in?
Condition?
-Condition?
- Were they mutilated?
See, we 're still looking for survivors
and we 're hoping. . . .
Were they--?
Did they suffer any trauma?
Were they broken up in any way?
They fell out of the sky.
Were there any body parts?
You 're asking me if I saw body parts?
You want me to report--?
I don 't mean to be grim. . . .
But I understand there were reports,
sharks in the area.
I didn 't see any sharks.
But don 't let the fact that the. . .
. . . family of the victims
are probably watching the show. . .
. . .I don 't want that to stop you.
- You 've had a tough night.
-No, I feel great.
This is the best story in the year
for me, and probably for you.
If you can see
all the vultures out there. . .
. . . that have flocked to the seashore
to see these collective body parts.
If you want a body part,
I'll get a gaff--
What do you want?
An arm or a leg?
You can have your pick.
That went out over the air?
Why don 't you have a seat?
All of it.
It'd be interesting
to see them together again.
I thought of that.
One here, one there.
It'd be good for 2 or 3 points.
At least.
I want to show you something .
It's going to be a tough sell .
Not for me.
Good morning .
-How are you?
-Just great.
59'%' of the American people are showing
compassion for an armed felon.
He asks for forgiveness
and everyone says, "Sure. "
This is a fascinating story.
What do we do?
We' re covering it, Kevin.
Brackett's interview was brilliant.
Unless you want to double-team it?
You and Brackett.
I' m not sharing my time with him .
I' m getting on a plane
and will cover the story from there.
It could be over by tomorrow .
No, Brackett won't let it be over.
This has the potential
to be a huge story.
We must jump all over this.
The guy's a poster child
for the disenfranchised . Why? How?
It's good television.
-No other net has it.
-It's a great story.
What about Brackett?
I'll take care of Brackett.
Special Agent Dobbins, FBI .
The situation is stable, sir.
We have televisions in Washington.
We know the situation.
Every time I scratch my ass,
it's on TV.
I'll drive.
Have the militias arrived yet?
No. At least I don't think so.
I was across the street all night.
How'd you do this?
We' re very sneaky.
-I guess.
-This way, sir.
What's the plan?
I' m under pressure to do something .
We don't move
until we get public opinion on our side.
People are beginning to like him .
Wire him, please.
That'll change.
They'll get bored or he'll do something
to make them turn on him .
By then we'll be in a position
to take him out.
Anything I should be afraid of saying?
Get in front of the cameras and say
we' re waiting as long as it takes.
We' re not about to play games
when kids are involved .
Good .
I got shots!
Must be his shotgun.
What's going on?
-What?
-Calm down.
The phone--
What was that?
What's that about?
Just forget it, all right?
Don't worry about it.
Don 't worry?
Was anyone hurt?
Nobody's been hurt.
It was just an accident.
The phone rang and the gun went off
and that was it.
You can't shoot and not expect me
to not storm the place.
You don't want that.
We had a deal, right?
Are you taping?
We kept up our end of the bargain.
Now it's time to end this.
What about my end of the bargain?
The demand?
Do we get to forget about all this?
Sam, I can't let you go.
You won't be allowed
to walk away from this.
The only option you have is to give up.
I' m going to make the options now .
You better come up with something else.
Take the shells out of the gun.
The plan didn't work, newsboy.
Did you hear me?
What are those?
In the Air Force, I did night duty
and didn't fall asleep once.
-Can I see them?
-It's just caffeine.
You don't want to lose control .
I' m sorry about that, okay?
I didn't mean to scare you kids, okay?
I' m not scared .
You guys sleep good?
-Not really.
-Sort of.
I guess.
Now I' m kind of hungry.
You' re hungry?
Sam, you got to let them go now .
Follow me!
Where' re you going?
Let's go, quickly.
Look at all the animals.
Now what's the magic word?
Open Sesame?
Good guess.
What do you want?
-Nice, huh?
-Whose side are you on, Mr. Brackett?
The good guys' .
Doesn't look that way.
Sam needs all the help he can get.
Oh, you' re so concerned about Sam?
Yes. You' re looking at the difference
between 1 and 1 0 years in prison.
Is that because this insanity
benefits your career?
I hope so.
It benefits yours as well .
What?
You' re running the most famous
little museum in the country.
You'll have dodos
and dinosaur bones up the wazoo.
You can have a lot.
You can have two.
T-shirts, right here.
Sam's T-shirts!
We' re providing Americans what they
were denied at Ruby Ridge and Waco:
Witnesses to the actions of the
so-called law enforcement establishment.
But you agree with the calling for
the peaceful surrender of Sam Baily?
Is that a trick question?
Of course we don 't approve
of his putting children in harm 's way.
-They' re here.
-I know that .
Keep an eye on them .
A family man
put out of work by racial quotas.
What do you plan on doing?
What's he trying to say?
They fired you. They kept Cliff.
You shot Cliff. He's black.
Some people might say
you' re prejudiced .
I must get on TV and say I ain't.
No way they'll let you
do another interview .
I'll give them 1 kid .
I'll give them 5 kids.
Bad idea.
We just did an interview . We built what
is probably a positive image of you.
Understand, the public's fickle.
They' re on a very short leash of
sympathy. We have a narrow opportunity.
Think of when you'll give up,
when you'll let the children go.
I can't have people saying bad things
about me on TV.
You want to go on and debate neo-Nazis?
Destroy everything?
People got to start saying good things
about me! My friends, my wife.
Okay, let's call her.
It's a good idea. Come on.
I can't talk to my wife.
Why not?
She's probably worried .
Oh, man!
She'll just yell .
You should talk to her.
You should talk to her
because you said you would before.
You go get her and tell her
to say good things about me on TV.
-When?
-And my friends too! Now !
Someone's coming out!
Chief.
Brackett's out.
How are the kids?
What's the condition of the kids?!
Are any more children
going to be released?!
Anybody injured?!
-Over here!
-Whose side are you on?!
-You better tell me he's coming out.
-He wants another story.
-What? Absolutely not.
-He'll give you 5 more kids.
He wants me to talk to his wife,
interview her and a few others.
You' re saying no to releasing 5 kids.
No, I want all the kids out here.
How about 5 kids and a teddy bear?
Don't get cute with me, Brackett.
I want him out here and arrested .
He's not ready to give up.
Prison terrifies him .
TV keeps him calm .
I'll interview his wife. . .
. . . with you standing there.
Pull the plug anytime you want.
You 're walking in and out.
You' re supposed to be a hostage.
Let him do it.
You can do it, but you
and Baily better not be playing games.
Son of a gun.
Who's the FBI guy?
Maybe I know him .
Do you know Sam Baily's making you
the most famous cop. . .
. . .in the United States of America?
On TV, with those sunglasses. . .
. . .you' re so sexy.
Mr. Williams is still unconscious
here in room 404.
Doctors are cautious
about the possibility of infection. . .
. . .caused by the bullet
still lodged in his abdomen.
What about Cliff Williams?
He cannot know that his attacker. . .
. . . became something of a folk hero. . .
. . . his words tapping into a nationwide
movement of discontent among the public.
What about Cliff Williams?
But what about Cliff
What about Cliff
Cliff was the one
with the shattered dream
Sam tries real hard .
And sometimes he screws things up
because he's. . . .
It's okay. Tell me,
what kind of a husband is Sam?
He's a good husband .
He's a good husband . . .
. . .as long as you--
You have to help to keep him . . .
. . . pointed in the right direction.
And, you know .
But I don't understand that.
That's not like him .
Tell me, Jenny, did you
make him lunches the last few days?
He makes his own.
So he's already been fired and yet
he kept making himself lunches. . .
. . . kept putting on his uniform
and kept pretending to go to work.
How do you feel about that?
About what?
That he was afraid
to tell you that he was fired?
Do you scare him?
I think that he didn't want to worry me.
Because he was scared?
Think that's a sign of a good marriage?
We had a good marriage.
We have a good marriage.
Did he tell you we didn't?
I' m sure you have a good marriage. But
it seems at times you treat him . . .
. . .Iike a child .
He is like a child sometimes.
And he likes calling himself
my third child .
It's a bad question.
I' m sorry, I didn't mean to--
Do you still love him?
Yes, I love my husband .
I love my husband very much!
He's the most gentle. . . .
He's the kindest man I've ever known!
The parents of the children. . . .
Grab her.
We'll put her on the line with Sam .
Jenny, we want you to talk to him .
You have to be very careful about that.
He's stressed .
There's no telling how he'll react.
This doesn't concern you.
He's very sensitive
about his wife.
Come with me.
Please don't do this now .
You asked the right question.
I just got that sick taste in my mouth.
So much for bubble gum .
That's too gross for me.
I' m Max's assistant.
I need to get through now .
What are you doing, Sam?
I guess I got myself in a jam, huh?
You've got to come out right now .
How' re the sprouts?
They're wondering where their father is,
that's how they are.
They want to put me in prison.
I don't want any more argument.
I want you to come out now.
Is that you on TV?
What?
Put away the gun and come out!
Get away from her!
Put Brackett on the phone!
Forget about Brackett!
Put the gun down. . . .
You tell them right now
I ain't going to prison!
-Put the gun down!
-Go home!
Go home, Jenny!
Jeez, I'm going to get him out myself.
I' m going to get him out myself!
Give me the horn.
Speak into here.
Hold the button down. Talk into here.
Listen, I'd think twice about this.
Please don't do this.
Listen to me!
You 've got to stop this nonsense.
- Think about our kids.
-Shut up!
They're waiting for you.
Please, come out.
Please, listen to me.
-Sam, please come out now.
-Shut up!
Do you hear me, Sam?
Please. . .
. . . come out now.
That is enough!
Stop it!
-Sam, stop!
-Hold your fire!
Sam, please,
that's enough now ! No!
-Stop it!
-This is on your head !
Get away!
Get away from the window !
They'll kill you!
-The lock.
-It's open!
Why'd you let her
say those things on TV?
You stand at the door,
they'll kill you.
-What is the problem?
-Why'd you let her say those things?
I didn't and that's not a good reason
to shoot over people's heads!
You said you'd talk to her alone.
It was the police chief's idea.
People were beginning to like you, then
you start shooting out the window . . .
. . .and your image is down the drain.
I just got crazy when I seen her on TV,
okay? All the people around her. . . .
What have I done?
Tell me you won't throw dynamite
out the window .
You know
I' m not going to do that.
I screwed up.
I' m going to go outside. . .
. . . I' m going to do damage control
and you'll be okay.
I'll send you to do interviews.
I'll give you the names. . .
. . .and the questions to ask.
Why can't you do it?
Because I need to be near Sam .
He's getting edgy.
And tell Lou to send over
the editing bay.
-I completely forgot.
-What's that?
The editing bay is here.
Kevin Hollander is coming here.
What?
I think the editing bay is here for him .
-He's going to try to freeze us out.
-Why?
Because he'd love to steal
a story from us.
Kevin Hollander?
You like him .
It's our story.
He wouldn't do that.
Go to work.
-Thank you.
-Listen, Laurie.
This is our story
and it's nobody else's.
I' m depending on you.
It's too early to celebrate. Go on.
Don't touch me.
I'll get arrested .
Would you say Sam Baily
is a religious man?
Yes. Sam is religious.
But when I say that
you should understand I mean proud . . .
. . .and he's kind .
Do you think Sam is a fun guy?
Fun?
Yeah, he's a real fun guy.
In what way?
Gullible.
You could always play jokes on him .
Is Sam Baily a violent man?
You see any fishermen throwing fits?
No.
He 's not a violent man.
He was not a remarkable student.
I'm sure you 'll find people
who 'll say we failed Sam Baily.
The system isn 't set up to provide
a safety net for men like him.
But the only person accountable
for this situation is Sam Baily.
A compassionate bastard .
We failed Sam Baily.
The system isn 't set up to provide
a safety net for men like him.
That's what I thought you said .
The parents won't speak to me.
I'm keeping a hole open for this.
They must speak to you.
The mother's crying and the father has
a stutter. They won't talk on camera.
You don 't get this,
don 't come back.
-Is that clear?
- Yes.
Good .
Mrs. Baily,
I' m really sorry to bother you. . .
. . . but I really am trying
to help your son.
I was wondering if he has a horse. . .
. . .or a dog .
I want to use it in the story.
I want to show the people that Sam can't
be that bad if he has a dog he loves.
Go, follow .
We've had him since Sam
got back from the Air Force.
Old Rex.
He's almost fifteen years old now .
We nearly lost him last year.
Sam was a wreck.
He stayed up with him all night. . .
. . . made sure he kept warm .
He's really a sweet boy.
He's confused but. . .
. . .all he's trying to do is get by.
Sam was a wreck.
That's the most important interview
of the whole case.
See that?
That's on the money.
You know what you did?
You got that sweet old woman
saying how Sam loves. . .
. . .that pathetic, mangy,
tick-ridden dog .
Who's here?
-Who's coming?
-I have no idea.
Max is over there.
See if we can get them
something to drink.
I'll get it.
I see a great underlying theme here.
Baily is tapping into something
the working class can relate to.
What's wrong?
Your numbers taking a dip?
Have a seat, Max.
Look, sit down.
Let's cut the crap.
You and I have had our problems
in the past.
But you want back on the network.
Yes, Kevin.
You' re talking to it.
If you can be a team player. . .
. . .this is your ticket back in.
When can I meet him?
The network wants him
to do a one-on-one with me.
He can't do a one-on-one. He's
in the middle of committing a crime.
-You've done okay.
-I spent the day and a night with him .
I think he'll talk to me.
I' m "the man America trusts for news. "
You really shouldn't let
a marketing slogan go to your head .
-Can I get some coffee?
-It'll be ready in 5 minutes.
Maybe you could both speak to him,
make it more comfortable for him .
You' re the one
who saved the guard .
No. Yes.
I mean, I helped .
I understand you' re doing
a new piece on Baily.
Yes, but it's Max's story.
-Thanks.
-I want to see it.
I mean, I want to see it now .
Sam Baily stands firm to his appeal
for clemency but the law says no.
So the waiting continues.
This is Max Brackett reporting.
That's a testimonial .
We don't judge people
before they go to trial .
We don't make them celebrities either.
He's committing a felony.
No, we' re just packaging what
people who knew Baily said about him .
I'll take care of the felonies
in the lead-in.
I own this story.
This story is the property of KXBD.
It's the network's.
I need to make some changes in this.
I want to see everything you shot.
When am I going to have
my meeting with Baily?
I need to prepare my one-on-one.
What?
Yeah. Yeah, I know .
I can't even guarantee he'll do it.
He'll jump at it.
They all do.
Fine.
-Excuse me.
-One second .
Why don't you play nice?
This could be very good for you.
Excuse me, Max.
-Coach Bob is arriving .
-What?
Coach Bob,
with the food for the kids.
I'll keep it in mind .
-What about the kids?
-The kids are okay.
I' m worried about Hollander.
Why don't you get him off my back?
I can't.
I can't wrestle 300-pound gorillas!
You guys got the pizza?
That's it?
We' re dying here!
You can't keep this all to yourself!
Go to hell, Max!
-You' re an asshole!
-What's going on?
Get them
to take those skins off, please.
I need you to come back down here
and take the skins off.
These kids get bored just visiting
a museum . Imagine being trapped in one.
Have a hamburger.
You guys knock it off!
Get down here! I got to talk to you!
That was awesome.
Everybody, come here!
Come here!
Everybody, quick!
I can 't see very well.
The rain 's heavy.
Where are we going?
Hey, Mr. Indian Man.
What's that?
You want me to tell them?
I'll tell them the story.
Get over there. He wants me
to tell you a story. Go ahead .
Sit down over there.
Now you kids,
you know the name of this lndian?
This guy's name is Big John. . .
. . .and he's a friend of mine.
Do you know what kind of lndian he is?
A Miwok lndian.
Do you know how to say " Miwok" ?
That's good .
The lndians used to own this country.
They owned it.
This was their home.
I think I found
one of their arrowheads once.
You did?
Hold on to it. If Big John finds out,
he'll come and get it.
The Miwok lndians. . .
. . .they lived off the land .
They had, like, you know . . . .
They had their own crops.
They hunted and built tepees
out of wood like this.
And, you know,
they had kids just like you.
Big John was the chief of them .
Do you know what a chief is?
The chief is the boss.
Right.
The chief is a good boss.
And a good boss knows
how to take care of his people!
He's too close to the kids.
The white man came along . . .
. . .and he wanted to take the land
away from the lndians.
And so he killed
all of Big John's people.
He killed his friends.
He killed his family.
He's got his rifle drawn on the kids.
That made Big John so sad, he stood
at the top of the valley, like this:
He looked down and saw everybody.
Everyone he loved was killed .
And he just started
to do an lndian dance. . .
. . .to bring them back to life.
But it didn't work.
And he was so sad his heart froze.
Is he still alive?
You bet he is.
Museum found him . . .
. . . he was like this.
And then when I started to work here
his hand was up here like this.
And every day I noticed it went
like this, came down like this.
Then I realized he was just
waving goodbye.
Let's go! Come on!
Pick him up!
Pick him up! Run!
Behind the buffalo!
I hope we get to see some more!
That was cool !
Chief, it's for you!
What the heck are you doing?
We got kids in here!
Sam, it wasn't us.
No, it wasn't us.
Some nutcase made it
through the perimeter.
He says it wasn't him .
Listen.
If this happens again,
I' m calling a parents' conference. . .
. . .and tell them you' re taking potshots
at their kids.
And I suggest that you tell
the FBI agent you' re standing with. . .
. . .that I said so.
One moment, please.
Anything else, Sam?
Thank you.
Shit!
Dobbins, you' re a jackoff.
Joke just gets funnier and funnier,
doesn 't it?
And up there in Madeline
we 've got this guy, Sam Baily. . .
. . . using the Steve Martin defense.
Leno just said my name.
Hasn 't been used in a few years.
Well, excuse me!
Please.
Jay Leno knows who I am .
Oh, man!
He's a nice man.
You met him?
I did a story on antique cars.
He collects them .
Who else you met?
Everyone from the Pope to Mel Gibson.
Mel Gibson?
What's he like?
I threw him softball questions.
He threw me softball answers.
He plays softball?
I play softball .
I'd get along good with him .
I bet your wife didn't know
she was getting a celebrity. . .
. . .when she said yes, did she?
No, I think she knew
exactly what she was getting .
35 years old and . . .
. . .the only job I could get
is guarding a museum at $8 an hour.
-How long you been doing it?
-And I can't even keep that.
5 years.
I was in the Air Force,
you know, but I left. . .
. . . because they wouldn't let me fly.
Why not?
No college.
Why didn't you go to college?
No money.
But. . . .
The results ain't in yet,
but it appears that I ain't too bright.
Guess what.
I didn't go either.
Get out.
I couldn't afford it.
Then how'd you get to be so smart?
The results aren't in yet. . .
. . . but rumor has it
I got by on my charm .
That's something
that you got a lot of:
Charm .
Charm . Personality.
I ain't got no personality.
Sure you do, otherwise people
wouldn't be responding to you.
Then I could do
one of those TV shows?
Why not?
You' re already famous.
Yeah, but. . .
. . . I' m famous in a bad way.
It doesn't make any difference on TV.
People know who you are.
Like them fishing shows.
I heard that you were a great fisherman.
I'd like to do a fishing show .
Fish all day on TV and you get to go. . .
. . .see the best spots.
All the new equipment.
I'd like that.
I'll tell you what. When this is over,
I'll recommend you to my station.
Nah. It's over for me.
Things are bad, but at least people
are sympathizing with you now .
Am I going to jail?
Best-case scenario. . .
. . .you'll do a little time. . .
. . .you'll get some probation.
Then. . . .
. . . "Sam Baily's Catfish Corner. "
Yeah, right.
Stranger things have happened .
I was up and I was down.
Now I' m up again,
thanks to you.
Who knows? You might be back in your
wife's arms sooner than you think.
They got too much light, them kids.
Back in my loving woman's arms again.
-You married?
-Been there.
You got kids?
1 out of 3.
What's that mean?
One kid, three wives.
My last wife didn't even wait. . .
. . .for me to leave.
She took off with the kid .
I couldn't leave my family.
You'd be surprised
what you can learn to live with.
You don't want to take those.
Sam, why don't you
get yourself some sleep?
Nothing's going to happen, I promise.
Can I go to the candy room?
We' re hungry.
Yeah. Go, go.
Well, Max,
they are suggesting that. . .
. . .if you have any control
over the situation. . .
. . .it wouldn't be a bad idea
if Baily surrendered in the evening .
Prime time?
Their Thursdays are particularly weak.
Oh, Jesus, Marty!
I know, Max. I know .
So let's forget about this.
They're asking--
Tell them this is my story
and Hollander is trying to steal it.
They know that.
They' re asking you
to let him have Baily.
In exchange,
they' re offering you your own show .
Magazine, 60 Minutes format. . .
. . .investigative, in-your-face. . . .
They say,
and it remains to be seen. . .
. . .you will have editorial freedom,
whatever that means.
But it will be national and they
are talking about real money.
Do I lock the deal down?
--but I know what it's like to be angry.
I understand what it's like
to not have a future.
T-shirts, right here!
Get your Sam T-shirts!
One size fits all !
What a circus!
They tried to cut a deal in the Foothill
Federal fraud last night.
With this nonsense, they didn't think
anybody'd notice.
Brackett was right.
Banker's a crook.
Laurie, I'd like to assign you to--
There's something you can help me with.
If Baily doesn't talk tonight,
I'll need a sidebar.
Do you think you could plug me in
out in the field?
I was planning to free you up
to work on the bank fraud .
People have lost their life savings.
Nobody's covering the story.
It's not the microphone.
You really must talk louder.
Could you please come. . . .
-Don't touch me.
-No one's allowed in.
I really must advise against this.
Your husband is just not strong enough.
Mrs. Williams. . .
. . . I saved your husband's life.
His first interview
should be with Kevin Hollander.
We really need the money.
3, 2. . . .
Cliff,
Sam Baily, the man who shot you. . .
. . .is pleading for forgiveness.
How do you feel about that?
I've known Sam for a long time.
I don 't think he meant to hurt me.
That's right, Cliff.
Doctor said it looks like I'll be okay.
I got no problem with him.
-See? You' re a very lucky man.
-How's that?
He just gave you his blessing .
Did Cliff get money to do that show?
Sure. It's a tabloid .
Big bucks. Show business.
How much?
I don't know . 1 0 grand .
1 0 grand?
If Cliff can get 1 0 grand,
I could get 50 grand .
I' m the whole deal .
I thought this wasn't about ransom .
This ain't about ransom .
About show business.
Left, right, left.
You shoot a guy, take kids hostage
and now you want money for it.
How do you think that'll look to people?
I don't care.
I got to make money for my family.
Maybe later you'll write a book,
we'll make a TV movie. . . .
I know people who might
help you with that. But not now .
I need to check out them shows to see
how much they pay. You go do that.
What?
No, it's just the kids playing around .
What is it?
Hollander wants to see you right away.
That's it? Fine.
What's up?
You want to make money on this,
you call the tabloids.
You don't need me for this.
I got Kevin Hollander out there.
We planned to do an important show
on you, but you do what you want.
Kevin Hollander?
He's here?
Listen,
Larry King wants to make you an offer.
A full hour tonight,
you and your boy.
-Talk to my agent.
-This is global .
The networks can't compete.
I have something else going for him .
Come here.
You know where to reach me.
What did Gottsegen want?
I'll give you 3 guesses.
The network wants you
to turn Baily over to me.
I' m doing a prime-time special .
You' re creative.
Maybe you could get him a variety show .
You little fuck, if you want back on
the network, turn Baily over to me now .
Don't screw this up for yourself, okay?
Sam belongs to the network, okay?
You hired her.
You taught her.
Oh, come on, Max.
How is this going to end?
I' m getting out of here.
Or what?
Because they' re not going to let you go.
Max Brackett said--
Max Brackett is not your friend, Sam .
If you had listened to me for 5 minutes,
that's all I wanted .
I wish I had listened to you.
But this is much bigger
than you and me now .
They' re forcing you
to do something drastic.
I don't want to scare you,
but they' re. . . .
They' re ready to kill you.
And Max Brackett
is not going to stop them .
You know what? You've been
so sweet to me, how can I say no?
You've got your show .
All right. That's smart.
-What?
-Congratulations.
Okay, just a sec.
You were right.
The polls have turned against him .
It's flipped .
59'%' positive down to 32'%' and sliding .
It's the kids' parents.
They' re all over television
and they' re just killing him .
I'll call you back.
Baily's polls. . . .
I want to make this as objective
and balanced as we can.
I want to see more stuff
on the guy in the hospital .
Somewhere,
somebody says he's dangerous.
I want to see that.
I want to see pieces
on the racists out there.
Why are they piling on this bandwagon,
cheering him on?
Start pulling that material .
Get back to me.
It's going to be great
working in New York together.
You' re not being objective.
You want to sink him .
We have a deal .
He's sunk. It's over.
It's another kind of story.
He's the same person.
You can't do this. He's an innocent.
-I'll put that angle in the story.
-Not an angle.
It's not an angle,
it's the truth.
-He shot a guard .
-It was an accident.
He didn't know the guard was there,
that the children would be there.
He's an out of work husband .
He's--
We' re all impressed with your humanity.
Really.
Where's yours?
You'll kill him .
Cut this stuff out. Get out of here.
Let's get back to business.
" Business" ?
Yeah.
Business.
Max, come here.
Let me give you a little advice.
Don't screw this up again.
You got a network deal here.
Don't blow it for some hick with a gun.
You know what?
I' m not going to let you destroy him .
Pal, if you don't deliver Baily to me. . .
. . .you'll be lucky to get a gig
giving the surfing report in Kansas.
Kansas is starting to sound
pretty good to me.
Getting harder to move the line?
It doesn't move.
You cross it.
-That's not what you said before.
-I know it now, Lou.
It's time, Sam .
What do you mean, it's time?
It's time to give up.
What are you talking about? You said
you'd set up an interview with that guy.
Hollander's getting ready to hurt you.
He'll make you look bad .
-I ain't afraid of him .
-Be afraid . Be very afraid .
I ain't afraid of anybody right now .
-I can take care of myself.
-No, you can't.
You told me that the people like me.
I also said the public's very fickle.
If you don't set it up with Hollander,
I will .
Fine.
Let's get someone else.
Is he as big as him?
Bigger.
And nicer.
Fine.
Set it up, newsboy.
Sam, I' m on your side.
After the interview . . .
. . .you and I will end it.
You lost the exclusive.
No, I didn't.
I did not lose it.
-Made us look preposterous.
-I didn't.
After announcing all day your one-on-one
with Baily, now you want to what?
Just look stupid?
You want the network to look witless?
-Jeremy, listen to me.
-No, you listen to me.
You' re done.
You' re coming home.
No, I am not coming back there.
I'm staying here.
It's Brackett's now .
I'll take care of Brackett. I won't let
anyone say I let the network down.
Nobody's going to say that.
-Do you got everything I need?
-Everything is here.
How are the kids, Sam?
You 've got a couple of your own,
don 't you?
I got 2.
Are they friends, by the way,
with any of these kids?
No. I mean,
they' re different ages.
Let's go to calls. Van Nuys,
California, you have a question?
What would you say to the people of the
former Soviet Union who are suffering. . .
. . .hardships greater than your own
in the United States?
I don't speak Russian.
Sam has a normal complement
of compassion.
Max Brackett, veteran newsman.
By the way, why are you here, Max?
I' m just here to help.
Sam wants me here, so I' m here.
Wichita, Kansas,
you 're on the air with Sam Baily.
Liberals are saying guys like you
show why we need more gun control laws.
I can't believe
they made us watch.
Everybody's got their own opinion
on that kind of thing .
To politicize this tragedy
is to go the wrong way.
Max, this is my show.
Please. Sam 's doing well.
You don 't have to answer.
I know this is your show,
but I'm here to help.
I hope your show
helps this difficult situation as well.
Lubbock, Texas, go ahead.
How long are you going to hold out?
-He just needs space.
-He was talking to me!
It's been very. . .
. . .stressful . . .
. . .for him .
I don't think you know
the seriousness of this.
Okay?
Something's going to happen here.
You want to elaborate on that, Sam?
No, that's all . That's it.
From Madeline. . .
. . .I understand we have the mother
of one of the hostages.
Are you there?
Yes, I am. Thank you, Larry.
And thank you. . .
. . . for giving me a worldwide audience.
Hey, it's my mom .
-Is it really?
-It's my mom .
This man has been pointing a gun
at my child for 3 days.
What about them?
Why do you deserve our sympathy after
what you 've done to those hostages?
I don't want no sympathy, all right?
I didn't mean for this to happen.
I' m not trying--
What're you trying to do?
I think I know what I want to say.
Go ahead .
I was just taking care of my own.
Every man in my situation
would take care of his own.
That's all I was doing .
You don 't feel guilt
for what's gone down?
I feel bad .
You know, I feel bad .
But I didn't mean to hurt anybody.
Quit.
You know, it ain't my fault.
Whose fault is it?
Who are you mad at?
I ain't mad at anybody.
I mean, maybe,
you know, Mrs. Banks. . .
. . .a little, that's all .
We don 't care about his excuses.
People like Max Brackett and the media
are turning him into some kind of hero.
We found this to be a good opportunity
to present all perspectives--
Since when do we need
all perspectives of a crime?
Please. . .
. . .just let my child go.
Let them all go.
Sam, response?
Just tell the lady I' m sorry, okay?
We 'll be right back.
We 're clear.
We 'll be back in 2 minutes.
-If you' re uncomfortable, don't answer.
-Don't tell me what to do!
-Don't answer my questions.
-You' re not obligated .
People want to hear from me
what's on my mind !
-You need help sometimes.
-You don't need to sit here.
Fine. I' m outside.
-I'll take care of this.
-You' re in the shithouse.
And don't leave the building !
Everybody knows about it if I get mad !
Sit down!
You' re erasing everything we built!
You've buried yourself!
Can I talk to that guy from Texas?
-You all set?
-Yes. It's all set.
I've got to talk to you.
She ought to have something
more upscale. More color.
New York is not happy you' re going on
without checking with them .
Brackett is a freelancer.
He's not with the network. Don't worry.
They need to know
what you' re planning on doing .
The other networks are leading
with Larry King .
Tomorrow they'll be leading
with my stuff.
Good evening
from Madeline, California. . .
. . .where the eyes of the nation. . .
. . . remain fixed on the events taking
place inside the museum behind me.
But the real story I've uncovered since
I arrived here is even more troubling.
Quiet!
I came to understand the unconventional
relationship between a reporter. . .
. . .and his subject,
and I began to worry.
And as I learned more about Sam Baily's
personality, I began to worry even more.
The testimonies on Mr. Baily
were not reassuring.
He 's really a sweet boy.
He 's confused,
but all he 's trying to do is get by.
Sometimes he screws things up
because he 's. . . .
You could say he 's pretty weird.
Does he have a temper?
I don't even know that guy.
-I've seen him have a temper.
-So you 'd call him dangerous.
Dangerous, yeah. Dangerous.
This confused and dangerous man. . .
. . .is being advised by the reporter
covering the story.
Things are breaking down in there.
Let's get ready to move.
In his effort to tell
a more compelling story. . .
. . . the reporter, Max Brackett,
may have increased the danger. . .
. . .in an already critical situation.
I had hoped my suspicions were wrong.
Sadly, they were right.
I can guarantee
Mr. Baily is sincere in his offer.
I think things 'll become increasingly
unstable if you don 't grant him this.
Two little girls were set free,
supposedly at the behest of Baily.
But tapes of conversations
tell a far different story.
-Let's give them 2.
-I said one.
You shot a black man. Some people
are going to make an issue of that.
Show kindness to a black kid, it's hard
to play the race card against you.
A story that places a colleague
in an unfavorable light. . .
. . .is not one any newsman wants to tell.
Yeah, Kevin's the best.
We had to improvise this
after Brackett sold us out.
Here he is.
The numbers are high.
There are children inside that building,
held hostage at gunpoint.
And inside that building
there is also the truth.
The facts of this story
are also held hostage, unfortunately. . .
. . .by Max Brackett.
And I'm sorry to say
they are all at great risk.
I'll be back with more
of our special report after this.
What did you do to me, newsboy?
I took a bad story
and made it good TV.
You' re still in better shape.
I' m screwed !
What you want to do now
is give up and let those kids go.
There's still people on my side.
You said you've seen these things
on TV before. Remember how they end?
The guy dies or he winds up in jail .
You ain't my friend .
Shoot.
You kill someone, you'll spend your life
in jail, or they'll fry you.
Please don't shoot him, Sam .
It's not over for you, Sam .
Will you get your act together?
You want to go home and be a daddy.
Hey, kids.
Guess what?
I got some good news for you.
This is Lawrence Dobbins of the FBl.
You 're going to free your hostages. . .
. . .Iay down your weapons. . .
. . .and surrender.
Now!
I wanted it to be my idea.
You have five minutes
to lay down your weapons. . .
. . .and surrender.
Ijust learned Cliff Williams
is experiencing cardiac problems.
Doctors are working feverishly
to revive him .
Wait,
I see Mrs. Williams coming out now .
Would you like to make a statement
about your husband's condition?
Would you like to make a statement?
Please!
I want people to see. . .
. . . what this is all about.
I want all the people. . .
. . . who 've been worrying
about Sam Baily's side. . .
. . . . to start thinking about my children.
Their father is dead!
My husband is dead.
Mount Trinity Hospital has just
announced the death of Cliff Williams.
The tragedy of this simple man
started. . .
. . . when Baily shot him because he tried
to help the children taken hostage.
After almost 3 days of the most unusual
hostage situation. . . .
Samuel Baily,
this is Lawrence Dobbins of the FBl.
You must free those hostages.
Lay down your weapon. . .
. . .and surrender. . .
. . .now!
Kids, come on.
Come on.
All right, go!
-See you, Sam .
-See you.
Good night, Sam .
I'll pray for you.
Good luck, Sam .
Thank you, Sam .
Look at all those lights.
You were great with the kids.
The court will remember that.
But I killed a man.
It was an accident.
I'll testify to it.
Nobody would believe you anymore?
That's a good point.
Would you like to talk to your wife?
Let me get her on the phone.
I heard about Cliff.
I killed him .
I didn't mean to kill him .
You still have our kids to think about.
-How are they doing?
- They miss you.
I miss you so much.
They want you home.
Jen, I can't come home.
I ain't no good anymore.
Honey. . .
. . .it's time that we get this over with.
I know .
You mad at me?
No, I' m not.
I love you.
I love you too.
This is Chief Lemke.
I'm asking you to come out now.
Oh, God !
Come on, Sam .
Let's get out of here.
You go first.
-You go first.
-Okay. Sure.
I'll get them to put their guns away and
then I'll come back and get you, okay?
What actor do you want
to play you in the TV movie?
How about that guy Mel Gibson?
Mel Gibson doesn't do television.
-Why not?
-You' re right. Why not?
Bad joke.
I'll explain it to you later.
Why? Television's good .
He's coming out now !
Unarmed !
Come away from the building !
No, I am not going to send him out. . .
. . .till I see you tell them
to put their guns away!
Step away from the door!
He's coming out!
What are you doing?
Sam, open up!
They' re going to let you come out!
We have a deal ! Come on!
Give me a few more seconds!
He is coming out! He's just
a little nervous! He's coming out!
We' re still rolling !
This is Oscar Harrington, live
on the scene in front of the museum .
There's been an explosion.
Debris is everywhere.
Somebody get the camera.
It looks like Max Brackett's alive.
Come on, I can walk.
Let me just go over there.
Stay with him .
I' m okay.
Get in there. Get as close as you can,
find out what he knows.
What were his last words?
I' m Max Brackett's assistant!
You'll go exclusive on this for me?
Sure. Where's Sam?
Sam? Sam is confetti .
No, don't wipe that.
How does that make you feel?
Where is he?
What did you say?
Sam's dead .
It's a bigger story now .
Don't wipe it.
It looks good .
Zoom in.
We killed him .
Could anybody have helped him?
-Did he say anything?
-Did he give you a message for his wife?
What are you feeling?
You don't understand !
We killed him !
We killed him .
You don't understand !
We killed him !
Subtitled By:
GELULA & CO. , INC.
You be calm, because I got two things
I want to tell you.
I' m not listening to you as long as
you' re holding that gun.
Get that stupid thing away!
That was a shot.
Right?
Will you listen now?
We' re in a hostage situation
at the Museum of Natural History. . .
. . .where our correspondent,
Max Brackett, is being held hostage.
Do you want to tell us
why you' re here?
You don't.
I don't think you' re crazy.
I know you' re not a terrorist.
I know you' re just an ordinary guy
who popped his top.
People don't listen
to guys like me.
You got to connect
with those people out there!
I want everybody to back off,
and I'll talk when I' m good and ready.
-How's that?
-Sounded good to me.
With a simple demand,
the madness started.
You have to ask for a Lear jet
or a fast car.
I just want my job back.
I don't want him understood .
I want him out here and arrested .
With a reporter's ambition,
the story grew.
Mobilize every camera
and audio crew you can get.
Big bucks. Show business.
With the media 's power,
it became a spectacle.
You know that Sam Baily
is making you famous?
I just want to go home, okay?
Is getting the story
the same as getting the truth?
Police don't have any control, so
some news guy's running things?
Is the news what we need to know. . .
. . . or what we want to hear?
How do I know
you' re coming back?
Because you' re the best show
in town, Sam .
It may be unethical.
I don't want to cross the line, Lou.
I just want to move it a little.
-It may be immoral.
- You know you 'll sink the guy.
I' m not sinking him .
He's sunk.
But it makes great television.
This insanity benefits your career.
Stop this nonsense!
Come out!
I hope it does.
No!
The world is watching. . .
In Madeline, California,
we've got this guy Sam Baily--
Jay Leno just said my name.
Why have you chosen to stay on
in this volatile situation?
. . .but is anybody listening?
I didn't mean for this to happen.
I' m not trying for this.
When I go in front of the camera,
I will say that you' re in charge.
Say thank you.
You' re manipulating it.
I' m not manipulating anything .
I' m controlling the story.
I' m just kind of this guy
that has a job, goes to work everyday.
I don't know if anyone cares,
if anyone's listening to me.
It's my daddy.