Did you talk to anyone? Look at me.
Talk to anybody, huh?
Did you see anybody?
Did you talk to anybody, huh?
Did you make a phone call?
Who did you talk to?
Got anything else to say?
I didn't think so.
- How long was he out of your sight?
- Maybe a couple of minutes.
Chico, I'm disappointed in you!
How could you do that?
Look, we can't go into that meeting.
If anyone was ever made, we were made.
You know what I say? We're going.
What are you? Are you crazy?
I mean, probably a hundred people
saw us chasing him.
Chico!
Since when did anybody ever accuse
me of being sane? We're going.
- All right? Come on. Come on.
- Jesus Christ.
You see anything strange?
Just the usual weirdness.
The deal's going down, man.
- Keep an eye out for me, huh?
- Right, Hatcher.
- Are you sure it's cool?
- It's very cool. Relax.
Good. Then let's go.
And next time, you're going to
introduce me to Salazar, aren't you?
- Yes, I promise.
- All right. Let's go.
- You got it.
- All right.
Well, here we are, gentlemen.
Right on time.
You see? I told you.
This guy, he's been a good customer.
- Did you bring the green?
- Of course. Got it right here.
- Half.
- Then what are you here for?
I'm here to do business. If you don't
like that, then I'll take off, all right?
You know something?
I do business for a long time.
You know why? 'Cause I'm careful.
- You can never be too careful, right?
- Careful is good with me, amigo.
- Careful never killed nobody.
- Is that right?
Stupid. Stupid kills, me entiendes?
- Okay, gringo, I think we can do business.
- Good. Then let's get it over with, all right?
What's the matter? Hey, how you doing?
You know, in our country, we love cops.
When we do a cop,
it's like a tremendous status symbol.
But an American cop
is like a gift from God.
My little friend here is gonna
open you up a little bit
so you can tell us where
the rest of the money is, huh?
- There is no more money.
- There's gotta be more money.
Hatcher, let's get the hell out of here!
Come on!
Cover me!
- All right. Clear.
- Let's go.
- Quickly.
- Okay.
Time to go, Hatch.
I knew that the only justice
that I could get
would be that that I made for myself,
not always by law.
Father, I just killed a woman.
I've lied, I've slept with informants,
I've taken drugs, I've falsified evidence.
I did whatever I had to do
to get the bad guys.
Then I realized something.
That I had become what I most despised.
- Do you have a family?
- Yes, Father.
Go to them and leave these things.
Try to find the gentle self inside you.
Allow this person to come back.
What are you gonna
retire to, Hatcher, huh?
You're up your neck in this life.
I got Bennett burning up
the phone lines every day.
I got the President going on television,
promising results, for Christ's sake.
This is not the time for you
to walk out on me. Not now.
- You can't...
- I've had enough.
Look,John.
There was nothing you could've done
to save Chico.
These things happen when you're in deep.
You know that.
Take a leave. With pay.
Hell, take a month. Take two.
You've felt burned out before this.
I need you, John, okay?
Pete, nothing we ever did
amounted to shit, and you know it.
- Who is it?
- Uncle John.
You're not my uncle.
My uncle John lives far away.
I am your uncle,
and you've grown up to be a big girl.
- You allergic to cats?
- Nope.
- Okay, then you can come in.
- Tracey, come on back...
Johnny? Johnny!
- I can't believe it. Oh, God!
- How's my little sister?
Boys, come and say hello
to your uncle John. Come on.
- Who's this?
- This is Ricky.
Ricky, how you doing? You look great.
You look good. Everything's all right?
- Yeah, everything's great.
- Hey, Uncle John.
- Hey, how you doing?
- All right. Welcome home.
- Where you been?
- I've been here, waiting for you.
You're home!
Let me look at you. You look great.
You look great.
Why, you look like Melissa now, huh?
- Twenty years younger.
- Thank you.
I accept all compliments
from handsome men.
Everything all right?
You sounded strange on the phone.
No. It's all right. I'm just a little tired.
Well, you've come
to the right place to rest.
Head up!
- Cool!
- Make you happy?
Hey, we have lots more
where that come from, you know.
Don't worry about it. Be happy.
- Ready?
- Break!
Let's go! Let's go!
Come up and play!
Play it again. One more time.
Harris, you're a failure! Tackling
ten yards down the field ain't shit!
Pardon my French. Get back in the huddle.
- Come on. Let's go!
- Coach?
Coach, put me in. Put me in.
I'll be damned. Trouble.
That's me.
And I heard you were shot dead
in the streets of Bangkok.
Well, I was in Bangkok. I was there.
But I didn't get shot,
if that's all right with you.
Hell, yeah!
- All right, Coach, we're ready.
- I'll be right back.
Hey, come on! Come on! Show this guy
you can play some ball.
You know, if you like that, you should
try some of this thing right here.
Send you right to heaven.
Make cloud nine look soft.
- Is that crack?
- That it is, man. You know, the real deal.
- The shit you hear about on the news.
- Hey, it's funny, you know,
how the man always tell lie about
certain things what make us happy.
But you don't want to try this.
It too tough.
Women, it make them want
to love all the time, you know?
- I'll try it.
- All the time.
Sure thing, pretty girl.
Go on, put it right up to your lips.
You ready?
- Break!
- Four laps then hit the showers.
Why, you were gone so long,
you missed my entire marriage.
- How was it?
- Cambodia was more fun.
I mean, I love giving away
all my possessions.
It makes me feel real spiritual.
- And probably poor, huh?
- And poor!
It's all right. Let's go.
Get in the car. Get in the car.
Tito Barco, we're glad you come
to show some respect.
Walk up.
- Check him clean.
- Cool.
Do your best, man.
You very funny, man.
Wait here for the man.
Forward.
You move into my territory.
What do you think I'm going to do?
The streets will be red with blood
and nobody makes money.
They don't even notice us.
We fit in. We look like them.
But you?
You go marching into the suburbs
with your rag-head soldiers
and we're front-page news.
The DEA will be crawling down
our throats long after you've gone.
Everybody want go heaven
but nobody want dead.
Afraid?
This is how it'll go.
You a work for I man now.
You a do the selling.
You a be the mule.
I supply the crack and the powder.
What's the split?
Twenty percent to you.
Give me some time to consider
your proposition.
I will give you an answer very soon.
I a wait and watch.
I and I see everything.
I and I be everywhere.
The santero told me that you are the
one with the most frightening power,
that you are the one I must seek.
This man is not only Abakué,
the leopard people.
This man is using the power of the spirits
to do very evil things.
Will you... Will you help me?
I hope to see you again.
Looks good.
Nice to be back. Your team looks great.
It looks good now. Last year one
of my best players OD'd on cocaine.
I remember when the worst problem
I had to worry about
was one of them knocking up some girl.
Not any more.
I think I remember this place.
Wasn't this the place where
all the ugly girls worked?
- Hey, Nurse! Got an emergency here!
- Call a doctor!
Listen, give me a beer,
and give my man here a double.
You know, I don't do
doubles on the first date.
Now, that's not what I heard.
- This is my boy Hatch.
- Hi, Hatch.
- They're going in.
- Okay.
- Some hormones in here.
- Yeah!
Looks like one of the locals
is doing some dealing.
- Supplementing his income.
- Leave it alone, man.
- Leave it alone.
- Leave it alone?
He's buying dope from the Jamaicans
and selling it to his friends.
Look, I've been all over the world
with this stuff and you know it.
It ain't just the Jamaicans. It's everybody
But that's the same guy
I saw down by the school today.
And every time I see something going
down, I see him. There he is.
Last month, my 13-year-old nephew died
in a crack house run by these guys.
- That cut it for me.
- I'm sorry.
Look, I've had it.
And now it seems
they're moving in down here.
I'm just waiting
to do something, you hear?
Let me tell you something.
There's nothing you can do about it
and there never was, all right?
Yeah, but you gotta try
to protect your own.
Or are you so burnt out
you can't relate to that?
No, I can relate to that.
Excuse me.
Blood and fire!
Yo!
Move out! Move out!
Come on! Call an ambulance!
Hey, boy, somebody about dead tonight.
Me not know you, no. But I promise you,
you is a dead man walking.
So what else is new?
- Give me some room here!
- Come on. Let's go.
Let's clear the area. Clear that area.
You're dead, boy, hear? Dead!
- Welcome home.
- Was that the suspect, Mr. Hatcher?
- Yeah, the first guy up there.
- All right, watch it, people.
Stay back behind the lines.
Like Los Angeles,
New York and Washington,
small-town America
now has blood in its streets
as a gang shootout in Lincoln Heights
tonight has left four dead.
Although less than one percent
of Jamaican immigrants are involved,
Jamaican gangs, known as posses,
are now dominating
the American drug trade
with more than 10,000 members
trafficking drugs in 20 states.
According to Justice Department officials,
they are as disciplined as they are violent.
Torture and maiming
are posse trademarks,
and posse gunmen are said to prefer
shooting their victims in public.
Sources estimate they have committed
1,400 murders in three and a half years.
Dale Harimoto, WXTV, Chicago.
- Stay back. Watch it.
- Sheriff O'Dwyer.
I'm Sheriff O'Dwyer. Who might you be?
Roselli, FBI, OC Task Force.
We're taking over here.
- By what authority?
- United States Government Code,
Title 18, Section 111.
Go get their statements. Keep the
looky-loos out of the crime scene.
- Yes, sir.
- You're excused, Sheriff.
Roselli, I won't forget this.
You and your agents so much as spit
on the deck around here
and I'll personally write the citation.
Hatcher.
Jesus Christ.
What the hell are you doing back here?
Thought I'd visit my mother, you know.
I'm retired now.
- Retired, huh? Well, that's cozy.
- Yeah.
So what the hell went down?
Gee, I don't know.
What does it look like, Roselli?
It's a shootout, Colombians,
what do you want me to say?
Yeah, figures. Probably Tito Barco's clan.
What would Tito Barco
be doing up this far?
Losing. The turf is spreading out, Hatcher.
The Jamaican posse is more organized
than these other players.
They got more guns, more balls.
Jimmy Fingers is giving them everything
from arms to legal protection.
Jimmy Fingers, Jimmy Fingers,
ex-casino man out of Atlantic City.
- Right.
- It's a piece of cake.
- You pop him, you got it.
- Hey,
why don't you help us out on this one?
-'Cause I'm out. You know I'm out.
- Hey, come on, Hatcher. It's in the blood.
If it's in the blood,
I'll get a transfusion, all right?
Pardon me, Lieutenant.
May I see you for a moment?
It seems the professor has found
something very interesting.
- Charles, how you doing?
- We'll see you around, Hatcher.
- The sign on the wall is Abakué.
- What, more of this voodoo bullshit?
Professor, you call the markings
on the wall voodoo bullshit?
Nope. Seen them in New York,
Los Angeles and now here.
Sal, this is no bullshit, man.
Those markings were put there
by a man named Screwface.
You know what it means when we say
a man face is screwed?
No.
Well, I pray you never
have to find that out.
Who's that?
It's John Hatcher. He was an undercover
troubleshooter for the DEA.
We worked together on one
a couple years ago.
Yes, I know him. Him coming in with us?
No, he thinks he's retired.
He still looks functional to me.
I have a message for you
from Tito.
Him say, meet him in hell!
What up, dread?
- Them let you out?
- Yes, man. No jail can hold me
when Jimmy Fingers is on my side.
Same.
Jimmy Fingers.
Give thanks for bringing out
my bredren. Same.
Bondsman knew he was gonna skip,
so I figured I'd throw him a little extra.
Hey, Monkey. Time for business.
- Yeah, let's take care of this.
- Come.
No, man. I just think you have
to take it one step at a time.
No time in here. Nobody.
You know what I'm saying?
- Me not joking, boy
- Yes, man, yes.
Hold on, hold on. Listen up, you see.
Our provider, the man of science, a come.
Dreadlocks, Monkey be with us again.
That no good?
And the magic be everywhere.
- The warriors.
- Yes, sir.
Conquerors.
- Respect.
- Respect...
The Almighty has given I and I his hand.
His rod of correction I hold.
Let no man here fear for his own life!
Them that wish I and I to be left
in poverty and squalor
will themselves be damned.
If a man commit a crime against you,
he must be paid back a thousand times!
Who you fear?
Him or me?
Let no man here steer from
the path I have prepared!
Them the streets out there
belong to you now!
- Take it.
- Irie.
- Take it!
Yeah!
- Go.
- Yes.
I still don't believe you, man.
If you don't see
the shit that's happening around us,
you're blind or you just don't want to see.
Maybe I've seen enough.
Listen, man, I don't think the world
wants to change anyway.
But things do change, man.
Let me tell you something. It's like
you see this big dam with a leak in it.
You plug it with your finger. Pretty
soon you see more holes, bigger ones.
You plug it with your other fingers,
you plug it with your toes,
you plug it with your tongue.
But the water keeps on gushing out.
That's the way it is.
Pretty soon, you quit or get killed.
Five days later they got some
shit-bird cherry to take your place.
They give him your shield
and you're forgotten about.
The way I look at it, you come home,
mind your own business,
watch your own yard.
And then, if trouble finds you,
you go after it and you bite its head off,
before it does the same thing to you. Huh?
Look, Hatch, you haven't
been here in a long time.
And I'm telling you, trouble is tapping
us both on the shoulder right now.
- And you don't want to turn around.
- I hope you're wrong.
- You look a little winded there, big guy.
- Give me a break. I'm on vacation.
Tracey has something to show you.
She's been waiting.
Get down!
Johnny!
They hurt my baby! No!
Tracey is in serious condition
and she's unstable.
There's pressure on the brain
that we'll have to relieve.
- What does that mean?
- Surgery. I can't give you a prognosis.
She's fighting for her life, and so are we.
Let me tell you something, Doc.
You treat this girl like
she's the President of the United States,
and money isn't a consideration.
- We treat all of our patients exactly...
- Let me tell you something.
Like the President
of the United States, okay?
Don't touch me, John. Don't touch me!
This is your fault. Do you understand?
This is your fault.
God damn you! God damn you!
This is your fault, and my baby...
My baby!
Jimmy, how you doing, man?
Hatcher, what the fuck are you doing here?
Why don't you guys take a hike?
Go find another trick, all right?
Let me tell you something.
You bailed out a Jamaican
street named Monkey the other day.
I want him.
This other piece of shit, Screwface?
Now I know you, you're a scumbag
and a puke. I don't mind that.
You give me what I need,
I'm gonna leave here a nice guy.
You don't, I'm gonna fuck you up.
You fucking know better than that,
Hatcher. You know where the fuck...
Come here. I just want to talk to you for
a minute. Come here, come here, look.
The mob throws you out of Atlantic City,
you come here, you're selling guns
to the Jamaicans, huh?
Fucking sell anything to anybody, Hatcher,
except you, man.
I won't sell you
the fucking sweat off my balls!
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
Watch it!
You're a fucking dead man, Hatcher!
You hear me?
- Yeah?
- I'm fucking Jimmy Fingers!
I'm a made fucking man!
God made men.
All right, I want to know
where Screwface is.
Screwface? Me don't know no Screwface.
Really? That's strange.
- Does that remind you?
- You just shoot me now, man!
I got a better idea.
You're gonna go for a ride with me.
And everybody's gonna see us together
and Screwface is gonna find out
what good buddies we are.
Come on.
Let's go! Let's go!
- All right, man. All right!
- Come on. Let's go!
Just, easy. I will take you.
Good. I want to get there
while I'm still young.
Screwface give me a thousand deaths
worse than you do.
- Yeah?
- Find him your fucking self!
Well?
One thought he was invincible,
the other thought he could fly.
- So?
- They were both wrong.
Go home. Stay behind the line.
I want to know the second
that call comes in, okay?
So?
Two men are dead. This one was
shot one time in the forehead.
The other one was forced
out the window up there.
Did you find the hookers
who were in there?
Sal, do you honestly believe that now
is the time for finding them hookers?
- Look, this job was done by a pro.
- Is that right?
That's right, and I'll bet my money
it was John Hatcher.
- Now find me something.
- Sal, I will find you something.
Look, he thinks he can do things his own
way, but I'll tell you something, he can't.
Stay close to home, Charles.
Do it, man. Do it.
Where Nesta?
Jimmy Fingers and Nesta
are not too good.
Nesta dead? Who do it?
The white boy Hatcher?
I want Hatcher dead!
I want his family dead!
And if you can't kill him,
I go kill him, and then I go kill you.
- What about protection for my family?
- They're assigned.
- Good.
- I should probably have them tailing you.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Where were you last night?
With a friend.
Stay retired.
Hello?
Hi. I'm John Hatcher.
I saw you the other night.
- Yes, at the Shamrock.
- Kind of need some help.
Hold on. I'll be right down.
The ideogram is an
African black magic symbol.
It was used by the Jamaican drug gang
the other night.
The FBI said I'd be getting photos today.
I'm not with the FBI, you know.
Well, the cow's tongue means
you've talked
or exposed them
and have been marked for death.
Where did you get these?
I got these at my family's house
this morning.
What about this black cross?
This may seem ridiculous to you, Hatcher,
but these people are for real.
Your family has been marked.
- Could I use your phone for a minute?
- Yeah, sure.
- Hello?
- Yeah, it's me. ls everything all right?
Yeah, Johnny, I'm fine.
I just got back from the hospital.
Mom's there with Tracey.
She's better. She's stable.
I just had to come home
and get some rest.
Listen. Go look out the window.
ls the guard still there?
Just a minute.
Yeah, the car's there,
but I don't see the guard.
Johnny? Johnny?
Oh, my God.
No! No! Somebody help me!
- No!No!
- Come on!
- What do you want?
- I want you.
What do you want?
Just leave me alone. Somebody's coming.
- You're making a big mistake.
- You're lying!
Stop the bloodclot crying.
- Everybody must dead.
- No.
No, no.
It's your turn.
My father.
I and I go take you to a place, you see,
far, far away.
You never been there before.
You go there now.
It's not your body me want, no.
It's your dreams.
No, you bastard!
I own you now.
- No!
- Now I have the power!
Help me! Help me! Johnny, help me!
He said... He said he'd be back.
He said he'd kill us both.
Somehow, I don't think
he's gonna get the chance.
I can't wait to nail this fucker.
This is gonna be fun.
Serious fun.
Time to have fun.
- What's happening, bredda?
- Irie, irie.
- You want some blow?
- Yeah, I want some blow.
Put your hands where I can see them
or I'm gonna blow your head off.
Cool, now. Keep a cool head, man.
- See them here?
- Right there. Right there.
Hatch!
Watch out!
Shit!
Take the right side! Take the right side!
I got it! I got it!
Shit!
Say, boy! I'm gonna kill
your little bloodclot!
You are a bloodclot!
You are a bumbaclot.
You go, raas.
- Help me, please!
- Back off, boy!
- Help me.
- Me say back off!
You didn't hear me say?
You want her dead?
Go ahead. Kill her.
I don't know her. I don't care about her.
I got you where I want you now.
You're just like a dog with no teeth.
You want to kill her, kill her.
I don't mind if you kill her, you know,
'cause I don't know her at all.
Yeah, bad boy. Me a carve you, now, boy.
Me a carve you. Me a carve you.
Me a carve blood...
Run, dread, run!
- What?
- Didn't you see it?
From a bloodclot? What run for?
A one white boy
against two bredda enough!
Let's kick this little bloodclot
batty-hole, you see?
I ready. You ready?
Get him!
Hold on. Hold on, now.
Tear you, raasclot!
You fuck with my family, you die.
- Now we're talking serious fun.
- Abso-fucking-lutely.
I've never met anyone
quite like you, Hatcher.
Let me tell you something.
Go down to any soup kitchen
and you're gonna find
a lot of guys just like me
Why a soup kitchen?
I'm just another unemployed guy,
you know.
I don't think there is
a lot of guys like you anywhere.
What's that supposed to mean?
I finally met a guy who's nice,
not married, gay,
or trying to find himself, and he's
trying very hard to get himself killed.
Well, I have some unfinished business,
you know?
And I was hoping that you'd maybe
give me some of your advice.
- What are you planning to do?
- I want to take out the posse.
Then destroy their system.
When Screwface kills, he wants everyone
to see he did it or know that he ordered it.
That way he's both feared and worshiped.
You'd have to kill him, so the posse
thinks you've taken his power.
That way they will believe
your magic is bigger.
Otherwise, they'll never stop
until you and your family are dead.
I want you to meet my sister.
Goddess of fire.
Come on, God damn it!
Yeah, well, this is what you ordered.
Do you want anything else?
Wires, surveillance?
- No. Just firearms this time.
- Okay, you got it.
- For you.
- Thank you.
- You still sober?
- Yeah, five years, man. One day at a time.
- Stay away from that Nembutal.
- You got it.
Hang on. Hang on.
Max, meet Charles. Charles, meet Max.
Man, I've been after Screwface
for five long years, you see?
I have followed him from Kingston to here.
- All around!
- You break my heart, man.
Your tactics are just making him
tougher to snatch up.
Him jump already, you know.
And it's only I who can guide you
to what it is you seek.
I don't know if that would be
a very wise career move for you.
Come on! Look close!
Who you think me work for, the DEA?
I'm a Jamaican cop, man,
and Screwface is my career!
Look, man, I don't really care
who you work for.
You got your reasons and I got mine.
Screwface has gone back to Jamaica.
You know, Charles,
sometimes three's not a crowd.
Way I look at it, we need each other.
Know what I mean?
Let's do it, man.
- How you doing?
- Okay.
Care package.
Uncle Sam's contribution?
Welfare for warfare, you know.
This is my silent partner.
A whisper in your ear from this girl goes
a long way, you know what I'm saying?
You guys didn't hear a thing, did you?
All right, you heard the slide
click a little, right?
Massive cool.
Forward, Jamaica.
These are the streets that breed
the Screwfaces of the world.
This is the first time I ever got the idea
it's not all sunshine and bikinis.
I owe you an apology, man,
because until today I thought
all Jamaicans were dope-dealing dreads.
No, man. Don't feel you have
to apologize for nothing, man.
Man, these streets are hard out here,
and some people make a bad choice,
that's all.
They say life is hard.
- What up, man?
- Nothing now.
What you doing all the way up here?
You're not having enough trouble
in Kingston, peace boy?
Back with country, boy. You do your duty?
Pay him.
This girl, she hang with Screwface
more time.
They always partying together.
Can usually find her at Cat Club.
Heebie-jeebie, wicked boy
your time has come
You don't live right
you will have no more fun
Jankrow a go nyam your supper soon, boy
Jankrow a go lead the children astray
Jankrow a go meet the retribution
Justice has finally find a way
Screwface, you know
that your time has come
You don't do right, you gonna dead tonight
So now a go take you down
the road to doom
And, jankrow, a go nyam
all your supper soon
Jankrow a go nyam your supper soon, boy
Jankrow a go lead the children astray
Jankrow a go meet the retribution
Justice has finally find the way
Are you worried
it's just a wolf in sheep's clothing
Trying to lead the children astray?
But don't you know our 'ope it brighten?
Take my hands, I will show you the way
Jankrow a go nyam your supper soon, boy
Jankrow a go lead the children astray
Jankrow a go meet the retribution
Justice has finally find a way
Screwface?
Road to doom.
Sounds like you know this guy
pretty well.
Yeah, I know him. I partied with him.
I don't care him sell the drugs.
It's part of doing business.
But my sister,
she lost a shipment, and him cut her dead.
And for that, somehow, someday,
him a go dust off.
Yeah, so why don't you just tell me
what I gotta know,
and I'll go do what I gotta do?
Screwface have two head and four eyes.
And that is the secret to his magic.
Look upon this madman.
Him dead and him don't even know it.
Get away from the window!
I got it! I got it! Don't worry. I got it!
Welcome to I island.
Fuck you.
You a woman?
Me know what you is.
You is a dog after a bone!
And you have no teeth!
Hold him!
Tie him down.
You was conceived in darkness.
But I going deliver you into the light.
I got him! I got him!
Get up!
I know you. You love the killing.
But you is an empty shell inside.
Fall out.
Charles, move out.
So, bred, tell me one more time.
Did you tell them exactly
what I told you to?
I told them exactly
what you told me to tell them. Yes.
And what did they say?
They said exactly what you said
they was going to say.
Is that right? And what was that?
"Business is business, man."
$10.
It ain't over yet.
Does this guy ever pay you on time?
So, who's the boss-man?
I man.
Thanks for taking this meeting, man. I got
a message for you. Screwface is dead.
You raasclot stupid.
Hey, anybody ever see this?
Screwface is dead!
Now you get the fuck out of town or die!
You must want me and my
bumbaclot posse to shoot you down, boy.
Dead and about to be buried.
The evil is demolished!
I'll give you guys till tomorrow or you die.
Don't even think about it.
- Magic man!
- Screwface no dead!
- Magic man back!
Screwface alive!
Judas!
The man is everywhere, man!
Everywhere.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Here, just take this.
I'm sorry, man.
Don't you let him get away.
I got you covered.
Come on! Come on!
Yeah, you bloodclot.
You kill me bredda.
Now you going wish you was dead.
Come on.
I hope they weren't triplets.
English