[###]
[ALARM WAILING]
How long does it
take to make a taco?
Two minutes. But it
takes 20 to convince
them I'm not lmmigration
to get the cook up
from the basement. Here.
Call it.
Ex-con.
No way.
What?
Wannabe cop.
He's got " police academy
reject" written all over him.
Hey, pal.
Hey, buddy.
Try "dude."
Hey, dude!
Hey, you did time in Chino, right?
No, Lompoc.
I told you, ex-con. It's
the only job those poor
bastards can get. Thank you.
DISPATCHER:
Thirteen-A-six-seven, you have a 4-59,
silent alarm at Centurion
Storage, Alvarado and Marathon.
A-six-seven, roger.
DISPATCHER:
Thirteen-A-six-seven,
cancel that, per alarm company.
Must've been a power glitch.
Want to take a peek anyway?
Why is it that on these nice,
quiet nights you get so restless?
I mean, this is a great opportunity
for us to connect, you know?
We can open up with one another
and really kind of talk. You need a hug?
CHARLIE:
Shut up.
[###]
HANK:
You called it.
A-six-seven, door open,
Centurion Storage,
Alameda and 22nd. Requesting backup.
DISPATCHER: Roger, A-six-seven.
Let's go.
DISPATCHER: Three-one en route.
[GRUNTS]
Hey, Charlie, you ever hear
of that word "stealth"?
CHARLIE:
Shut up.
At least they don't know we're
here. The element of surprise.
Ready?
Yeah, I'm ready.
Go.
Unbelievable.
Let's split up.
Okay.
[GUNSHOTS]
CHARLIE:
Hank!
A-six-seven, shots fired!
Shots fired! Officer needs help!
CHARLIE: Hank, taking fire, four to five
suspects on my side.
Hank!
Come in! Where you at?
CHARLIE:
I'm in the big room, off the office.
Hank!
I got you!
It's bulletproof! I'm coming in!
Charlie! Your six!
What?
Your six!
A-six-seven, my partner's down!
Request paramedics.
I have four suspects, armed!
My partner has been hit!
DISPATCHER: All units, all
units, all L.A. units.
Officer down. Officer down.
[###]
lmpressive shooting,
Montgomery.
You realize, though, that you
missed the target in the middle.
Who, the brother?
I wasn't shooting at him.
You mind telling me why not?
He don't look suspicious to me.
Look at him. One lone
brother, surrounded by
four white guys with guns.
The man is terrified.
What do you want him to do,
tap-dance?
It's all right, brother.
Okay? I got you.
Don't be afraid to call 911.
I keeps it clean, when Earl
Montgomery's on the scene.
What the problem is?
[BAGPIPES PLAYING
"AMAZING GRACE"]
On behalf of the citizens
of Los Angeles,
I present to you our nation's flag.
McDuff.
Sorry about Charlie, Hank.
He was a good man.
I want in on the investigation.
Hank, I think it's best to let
McDuff handle this in his own
way. It's a complicated situation.
What's so complicated about it?
My partner's dead and
I just want the son of a bitch
who pulled the trigger.
There was over $800,000 of stolen
computer chips in that storage room
and a police warrant to seize it.
The night before the raid,
somebody blew in there
and cleared it out.
Look, I don't care about any
goddamn computer chips. I just
want the guy who killed Charlie.
You're a uniform, not a
detective. Stick to your job.
Fine.
You interfere with an ongoing
investigation, you won't have a job.
Am I clear?
Yeah. Fine.
Hank, they're gonna find him.
Yeah.
When chasing a suspect,
the goal is simply to
maintain visual contact
until a backup force of
sufficient size can arrive
to assist in the arrest.
Time!
Nice job, Taylor.
Pshh.
[CHUCKLES]
Did you say something, Montgomery?
Well, you said, "Nice job, Taylor,"
and I just said, "Pshh."
You think you can do it better?
Let me think.
Check me out.
Hey, Taylor, you
think he ready?
I'll take this one.
It's all yours.
Show this boy how it's done.
[MIMICS POLICE SIREN]
So you the suspect, man?
What you do?
Doesn't matter.
Oh, so you could've robbed a bank,
mugged an old lady,
said something about my mama?
Just chase me, smartmouth.
Okay, Mr. White Bank Robber.
[MIMICS POLICE SIREN]
[###]
[CRASHING]
[SCREAMING]
You're insane!
And you're resisting arrest.
[LAUGHS]
Don't you run from me.
I'm insane? I'm insane when it
comes to old-lady muggers, huh?
You like robbing banks,
huh? You said something
about my mama?
And I heard you
call me "boy."
That's cowboy to you.
Time!
EARL:
I see how this works.
The system can't tolerate a black man
with my superior police skills.
I'm the future of law enforcement,
and it scares you
because you're gonna
be out of work, right?
Look, I remember when
the NBA was all white.
That's right. That's all right.
That's all right. I'm cool.
Because y'all losing somebody
good, though. I'm a virtual
one-man, kung-fu SWAT team.
[YELLS]
That's all right.
I got skills!
You bitches!
[###]
Hank.
You don't have to get out there so soon.
No, I'm better off.
Want somebody to ride with you?
Nope. It's okay.
[###]
Aww.
Need some help?
You asking me if I need some
help, or if I'm stealing this car?
Okay, fine.
Are you stealing this car?
Does it look like I'm
stealing this damn car?
Little bit.
Why? Because I'm black?
White man has
his hand in the car,
you probably give him a
Good Samaritan award, huh?
Figure he's just going around
turning off people's lights.
Yeah, all right, could I see your
license and registration, please.
I ain't showing you a
damn thing, you Nazi.
Excuse me?
Hey, man!
This here? This is my car.
Okay? Now I ain't done
nothing wrong.
Now, the way I see it,
you owe me an apology.
Wait, what did you just call me?
You ain't listening, baby.
We ain't got nothing to talk about.
Unless it starts
with you saying, "I'm sorry."
You're on dangerous
grounds here, bub.
I'd be very careful what
comes out of your mouth next.
You wanna hear what comes
out of my mouth next?
You're...
a...
fucking...
pig.
You're under arrest.
Oh, no.
I ain't under arrest. You're under
arrest. I'm arresting your ass.
Citizen's arrest. You're under
arrest for illegal false arrest.
Now get your hands up on
the car! And give me those cuffs.
Back off! I'm warning you.
You're warning me? Aha.
You have the right to
shut the hell up.
All right, that's it,
get up against the car!
Don't make me
add "resisting arrest"
to the charges.
Now! Up against the car!
Watch my car. I just had it detailed.
Settle down! Do you understand?
This is police brutality!
Okay? And you ain't
doing nothing but
compounding your problems.
I've had enough of your crap!
I'm telling you, man. Get off me.
Whoa!
What?
A big-ass bumblebee behind you!
You don't think I'm gonna
fall for that crap, do you?
I'm allergic to bees.
If I get stung,
I'm gonna seize up and die.
What? Just ignore him
and he won't touch you.
Yeah. All right.
Look! Right there.
I'm gonna...
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
EARL:
Help! He's trying to kill me!
Help! Help! He's trying to kill me!
Get down! I got him!
Don't kill me!
I got him!
[###]
He's trying to kill me!
REPORTER: You are seeing video,
MAN: Check this out.
tak en earlier today,
showing Los Angeles
police officer Hank Rafferty
brutally beating an
unidentified black male.
Police are withholding
the name of the victim,
but we have obtained
this photograph of the man,
tak en after the beating, his face
grotesquely bruised and swollen.
It was a bumblebee.
Officer Rafferty's vicious
beating of a black suspect
has spark ed a swift and angry
response from the black community.
Detective Frank McDuff
had this reaction:
I want to assure you that the police
department and the district attorney's
office are treating this very seriously.
I urge the people of this city
to please be patient and
trust us to do our jobs.
Clearly, this is an isolated incident.
[CHATTERING]
It was a bee.
Get the hell out of here.
Mr. Montgomery, this
is Detective McDuff,
Lieutenant Washington
and District Attorney
Robert Barton.
Morning.
Good morning. Call me.
I'm serious.
Giggler. All right.
Weren't you on TV last night?
Oh, snap, that is you.
What's up, man?
What happened to your face?
I was attacked by one of
your deranged officers.
What do you think happened?
No, I mean, what happened
to the swelling and the bruises?
Oh, that. That ain't nothing
but allergies. You know, bee sting.
Come again?
Y'all mind if I have a seat? Cool.
I mean, y'all gonna ask
a brother all these questions,
don't even offer me a seat.
What's happening?
All right, well, um...
While I was being slammed
into the car, having billy
clubs jammed into my neck,
that psychotic storm
trooper y'all call a cop
also allowed this big-ass
bumblebee to nearly
sting me to death.
You know what? I'm not
even sure that that bee
wasn't one of his own.
You know, like some
anti-Africanised attack bee
trained to hate black people.
But you know what? That's the
sort of thing y'all gonna uncover
in the course of your investigation,
so I ain't tripping.
Would you excuse us for just a moment?
Do your thing, man.
Thank you.
BARTON:
We can't put this guy on the stand.
He's unstable. Not to mention that he...
Yo.
Who's the Planet-of-the
Apes-looking lady in the dress?
That's my father.
Handsome man.
I don't believe this.
I don't either. I'm calling
off the prelim. This is crazy...
Hold it, hold it, look. Whether
you like this guy or not, Hank
Rafferty violated his rights,
and the people of this
city are not going to
look the other way.
We can't go through this again.
You drop the prosecution
and I guarantee you got a
riot on your hands.
Earl, do you work?
I mean, do you have a steady job?
Yes, I work.
I work in security, man.
Ah.
That's until I get back in the academy.
I see.
Speaking of which, you know what?
Y'all need to investigate them...
Mr. Montgomery,
all allergies aside, did Officer
Rafferty assault you or not?
How many times I gotta say it?
All right. Let's get
down to business.
Superior Court of the county
of Los Angeles is now in
session. Please be seated.
People of the state of
California versus Henry Rafferty.
Case number CV-34259.
Honourable Marsha Healy
presiding.
Okay. It's at this time that the
bee appeared. Right here.
There it is. It's coming in.
You can't...
You can't really see
it on the tape, but it's there.
Okay.
I'm swatting it with my stick.
There I am, stomping on it,
with the heel of my boot.
Kept missing it.
It's not a good angle.
So, Mr. Montgomery, are you
claiming there was no bumblebee
present at the time of the incident?
No, I'm not.
There was a bumblebee present, man.
Oh, good.
And there were birds chirping.
There were dogs barking.
Hell, for all I know, there was
a chipmunk in the bushes
humping a turtle.
You know, you gotta
be careful with them chipmunks.
They'll hump anything.
[GAVEL KNOCKING]
This is no laughing matter,
Mr. Montgomery.
Look, man, I came here for justice.
Okay, that man right there?
That man harassed and choked me.
He used excessive violence
way before there was or
was not a bumblebee, sir.
I know the score.
It's not the first time I been
pulled over for DWB.
DWB?
Driving While Black.
Move to strike!
Kiss my ass.
JUDGE:
Will the defendant please rise?
The jury has found you
guilty as charged.
You are hereby sentenced to serve
six months in a state penitentiary.
[###]
Murphy. Okay,
move along.
Keep it moving.
You must be that white cop,
huh? Beat up the black guy.
What makes you say that?
Them.
Oh, man.
Hey, ése.
Save your strength.
You're gonna need it.
PRISONER: You look cute, baby.
Get going.
Look, don't mess with me or I'll
throw your ass in solitary.
All right, let's go.
You're out of the hole.
Hey, how long have I been in here?
Three months.
MAN:
Congratulations.
You are the graduating class
of this third week of August.
Many people don't make it through
both days of intense training.
You are the elite.
Wherever you go, you'll be
part of this special fraternity.
You're equipped with everything
you'll need to do your job:
Flashlight.
Pepper spray.
And if things get really nasty...
a coin holster full of quarters,
so you can call the police.
Congratulations.
[###]
HANK:
What do you mean, you got nothing?
You had a crime scene,
physical evidence.
I gave you a goddamn tattoo.
Which was a ghost.
We couldn't find anything
on it in the database.
Look, these things
take time, Hank.
Oh, please...
Holy cow, check it out. Hank Rafferty,
a security guard.
Nobody throw their gum
on the ground, okay?
We'd get, like, a warning.
[###]
DISPATCHER: District 21 units,
additional on the ADW in progress.
Suspect, male white,
blue jack et, brown pants.
Male black, green shirt, brown pants.
Fled eastbound on foot.
Excuse me. You ever see that?
DISPATCHER: Four-59. Silent alarm,
A and L Beverages, 18th and Main.
Cancel that. Must have
been a power glitch.
Gotcha.
Where's security?
Freeze!
What are you doing?
The lights went out,
and I couldn't find a switch.
So I was filing in the dark.
That's why I called you here.
Lola,
filing in the dark is a
serious offence. You're
in a lot of trouble.
Get up against that wall.
What are you
gonna do to me?
I'm gonna search you. Make
sure you ain't carrying
any concealed weapons.
Ooh.
You finding anything?
Is this a thong?
What?
Is this a thong?!
Are you gonna
strip-search me?
No.
I'm gonna put on some music.
You gonna strip-search yourself.
[BARRY WHITE'S " CAN'T GET ENOUGH
OF YOUR LOVE BABE" PLAYS]
Whoa, whoa, slow it up
for me. Nice and easy. Yeah.
[GROWLS]
Can't get enough
of your love, babe!
MAN 1:
Yo, Cain, pass those two.
MAN 2: Get the motherboard.
MAN 3: Check those boxes, man.
MAN 4: Got it. Load them up.
Get them out of here.
MAN 1: Come on, guys,
we have to check the load.
Oh, yeah, Earl.
No. Don't call me Earl. Call me "officer."
Oh, okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Are you gonna give it to
me now, officer?
Hell, yeah.
I'm gonna incarcerate you.
[SQUEALS]
Yeah, you know my
style. I like it wild.
MAN 2: All right, pass it over here.
MAN 5: No, I got it.
Freeze!
Hands up!
What was that?
HANK:
I said, freeze!
You, behind there!
Wait here. Might get
a little dangerous.
You really playing this thing
out, aren't you, baby?
Talk to me about a hit six
months ago, Centurion Storage!
Go to hell.
We wondered where security was.
Drop the weapon.
You should have run when
you had the chance.
Now you got no chance.
[GUNSHOT]
MAN 1:
Over there! There he is! Get him!
[YELLS]
NASH:
Somebody shoot them!
Thanks.
No sweat.
What the hell are you doing here?
I work here! What the hell
are you doing here?
You little punk! I spent six months
in prison because of you!
Six months? That's all they
gave you, six months?
[GUNSHOTS]
Damn it, Earl! This
ain't turning me on!
What the hell is that?
Earl Junior.
Likes to hang out with Daddy.
Precious, ain't it?
NASH:
Get the goods! Load them up. Now!
Cover me!
Hey, man, you ain't my boss.
The way I see it, we work
for the same company.
Since I got seniority,
you cover me.
Okay, I cover you.
Go!
No! My car!
No, not my car!
Somebody shoot that monkey!
What did you call me?
Let's go, now!
NASH:
Get them in here!
Go, go, go!
Get out of my car!
Why? Because I'm a black man?
Look. This has nothing to
do with you. It's personal!
You damn right it's personal.
White boy back there
called me "monkey." Drive!
Get out, now!
Look, man.
I been waiting my whole
life for some shit like
this to go down. Okay?
Now, if you're gonna shoot
me, shoot me. Because that's the
only way I'm getting out this car.
They getting away, man!
Come on! Go!
Earl?
[###]
Man, this slow-ass,
damn Flintstone car, man.
We might as well be
peddling with our damn feet.
What the hell is wrong
with this piece of junk?
Gee, I don't know.
You know, I was gonna
take it in for a regular
scheduled maintenance,
but for the past six months
I've been in prison!
Hey, man, you should've
got more time.
Pushing me into cars and putting
me in satanic chokeholds.
You were resisting arrest!
I was authorized to use
any force necessar...
Hey, hey. Look, man.
We could go back and forth
on this all night long, man.
Fortunately, there are courts
to handle this matter.
And according to the courts,
you were assaulting
and battering me like
a hillbilly on his wife.
[HORN HONKS]
Yo, yo, yo!
Oh, shit. This is how I'm
gonna conceal the weapon.
Pull over! Pull over!
Get the van!
You pull over, buddy!
No, get the van!
Drop the gun!
The van!
Drop it!
Get the v... Oh.
Get...
Damn!
If I would've gotten out
with a wallet in my hand,
I'd have bullets all in my ass!
That's some bullshit, man.
Security guard,
huh, Hank?
That's a shame.
Hey, Washington, how you doing?
Better than you.
You okay, man?
You know how it is, my brother.
Just a little shaken up, that's all.
Let me see if
I got this figured out.
You get out of prison,
pissed with your life,
you decide to pay your buddy Earl
here a visit. Things get out of hand,
shots are fired, the police respond
just in time to catch Hank trying to get
away with you in his car, probably
holding you at gunpoint. Am I correct?
Amazing. You are
very, very good.
No, wait a second. This is crazy.
I wasn't out for revenge.
Shut the hell up! Just shut the hell up.
I'm tired of your goddamn lies.
You know, I got a restraining
order that says you can't get
within 100 feet of this guy, okay?
So I don't really give a
damn what you have to
say. All I need from you
is your testimony and his ass
goes back to prison. Tomorrow.
Nothing would make me
happier than to see this
man go back to prison.
Good.
For the heartache...
and the trauma.
One time he took the club
and he switched it around
with the handle sticking out,
and bop, right there.
Can you see that little cut
right there? Anyway...
What happens is, it makes
me start saying incoherent...
You know, I'm liable
to spurt that out. Just
incoherent shit. Bitch!
I apologize.
My doctor said that I'm not getting
the proper oxygen up through here.
They said pump it and breathe.
And it's sort of like that sneaker.
It's a weird exercise, but...
Anyway, nothing would
make me happier than
to see him go back to prison.
Wait a second here!
Get back, bitch!
Shut the hell up, Hank, and I mean it!
You... The violence.
Let me calm myself.
Unfortunately, certain details
of your story are slightly skewed.
What do you mean, skewed?
Hank...
did not come back for revenge.
Thank you.
He came back to apologize.
What?
You went there to apologize?
The man's talking to you.
Yep.
And you were saying?
I was...
saying I was sorry.
For what?
Beating you.
Yeah, my dog. That's what
I'm talking about, man.
Hank was right in the middle
of this very touching apology
when I discovered that my
warehouse was being robbed.
So Hank and I, we banded
together to apprehend
these outlaws.
And we would've
had them, had not your
boys come along.
Excuse me?
Deputy Droop-a-long.
Man, they stopped the wrong car.
You better watch your mouth.
What you gonna do?
Beat the hell out of me?
Probably blame it on a damn spider.
What you got?
The updated report.
We got a 4-59 at the warehouse,
but nothing on a van.
Coroner has two bodies.
DA says self-defence.
So we kick them loose.
The C and L warehouse on 18th?
Yeah.
Not a cop anymore, Hank,
so stop acting like one.
I'm all too happy to find
any reason to lock your
ass up. You understand?
Go find McDuff, tell him
I want to see him right away.
Oh, yeah, we also encountered
a naked girl upstairs,
handcuffed to a light fixture.
Oh, Lo... Lola.
Do you think you could
hook a brother up with
another restraining order?
Right there, because
I recognize them. Great.
All my stuff should
be in here too.
What's up?
Right.
I don't believe this.
Where's my bullets?
We don't return live ammunition.
Well, if you're gonna keep
the bullets, why don't you
just keep the gun.
All right.
Give me my gun, man.
Where's my car?
lmpound lot. Twenty blocks up,
seven blocks over.
You expect that man to walk...?
Y'all got a shuttle bus?
You know what?
You upset my partner.
I should set it off up in this...
But you got your boys.
Hank, you believe
his attitude, man?
Man, they probably gonna give
you your car back with no tires.
I like the way you
played it back there, Hank.
Yeah, not letting them in on
our case. That was smooth.
This is our bust, right, partner?
Get the hell away from me!
Hey, Hank! You know what?
Sooner or later, your
hostility is officially gonna
start affecting our work.
Now, look, man.
All you got to do is kind of...
What is you running for?
I'm trying to talk to you.
Look! I am trying
to remain calm,
because I know that if I hit you,
I will never see the light of day again.
Which right now seems almost
worth it. So don't push it!
You threatening me?
Yeah! Yeah, I'm threatening you!
Well, bring it on.
Bring it on, Hank.
I could have went pro.
I drop bombs on them,
drop bombs on them.
What? Here, slip, move, slide, duck.
Can't redial without a signal.
Oh, bang them out of there.
Hey, where you going, man?
Shut up!
MAN: Big Red Truck and Trailer.
Truck and trailer. Yeah, look,
you guys got a call...
yesterday, I think it was, regarding
a white van that you rented out.
We only rent big rigs.
Oh.
Yeah, well, maybe you can
help me out. I'm trying to
find a couple of my buddies.
I think they rented a truck
from you yesterday.
What name is it under?
No, I don't know their names.
Listen, pal, we get a lot of people here.
No...
You listen.
Give me the phone.
Where are you located?
Downtown, on Normandie.
South Central?
These were white folks.
Oh, they just left. They bought
extra insurance for Baja.
Heading to Mexico?
I guess.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
The way I see it, they got
a 20-minute head start.
They're probably
heading down the 405.
What are you doing?
Stop the car! National Security!
[HORN HONKS]
Stop the damn car!
National Security,
I'm commandeering this vehicle.
What did I do?
Oh, student driver, huh?
Well, lesson 12: Man with gun,
get your ass up out the car.
Go!
Okay, okay, don't shoot.
And do your homework!
What the problem is?
[###]
Hey, man, do I got to solve
this crime by myself?
Unbelievable.
Big, red truck. It's gonna
be easy to find.
It's probably gonna say
"Big Red" all along
the side of the truck
in big, red letters.
Hey, Hank, you know that file
back at Washington's office?
Well, I used my acute peripheral
vision to get a upside-down read.
Wanna know what I saw?
What?
On one of them papers,
it said, "CIA heist."
And?
That's all I saw, "CIA."
That's it?
Hey, look, man, I said I
got peripheral vision, not
X-ray vision, man. All right?
Now, apparently, we are
caught up in some real live,
complex-ass, espionage shit.
This is great, man, isn't it?
Me and you, man, we're
security guards out here
acting like real cops.
I was a real cop, Earl.
Well, you must've loved it, huh?
I can't believe you gave that up.
Yeah. There's Route 1.
No, just stay on the freeway,
it's a lot faster.
No, they wanna keep a low profile.
They're gonna go Route 1.
Stay on the freeway.
No, on the freeway, come on.
Hey, don't...
Don't!
Oh, shit!
Hey, come on!
Freeway traffic, man.
Stay on the freeway.
We're in the middle of the street.
What are you doing?!
Let go of the wheel!
Freeway!
What are you doing, Hank?!
Oh, shit!
[###]
[YELLING]
God! Are you okay?
Yeah.
Shit.
MAN: Hey!
HANK:
Sorry.
Looks like somebody was
right about the freeway.
What?
Look at that. You can't tell me
that ain't a big, red truck.
Yeah, yeah.
[###]
Gun under the seat.
Hank! Hank!
Hank!
Get off me!
Hey!
Shoot her, Hank.
Shoot this big bitch.
Hank's about to shoot you.
No, I ain't gonna shoot
anybody. Put him down...
in a minute or two. No hurry.
I don't like nobody
messing with my rig.
Don't be a pussy, Hank. Shoot her!
You oversized, big-boot,
thick-ass, Jerry Springer-reject ass...
Earl, come on. Let's go.
No, man.
Shaq here owes me an apology.
But then again,
what your name is?
Brittany.
Yeah?
Got a ring on every finger
except that lock down one, huh?
You like to wrestle? Because that's
my thing. I like to wrestle.
Earl. Earl, come on, let's go.
Why don't you give me your number?
And if you're nice, I'll show you
what a real big rig looks like.
Earl, come on!
I'll call you.
Let's go! The truck's leaving.
I'm with you. Hold on, hold on.
Come on!
[###]
Think these are our guys?
How the hell am I supposed to know?
No, wait. Wait. No.
Sorry.
Earl!
Earl, come on!
Come on, come on!
[SCREAMING]
HANK:
Swing around!
Oh, my knee!
Oh, shit.
Hey, come on!
Come on, come on.
You did that on purpose.
Look.
So that's why the cops
couldn't find the van.
Hey, do you know how
to hot-wire a car?
Oh, because I'm black,
I automatically know
how to hot-wire a car?
Do you know how or don't you?
Yeah.
But not because I'm black.
Do it then.
Move your leg, man. Close your legs.
Get in there.
See that?
All right, go, go, go.
Okay.
See how that sparked when one
of them bumped into each other?
That's because that red wire
is what gives off all that energy.
I don't care.
See how that's sparking there?
Got it?
How's that? What's that doing?
Earl, the windshield wipers are on.
Must be a '94.
I touched the wrong one.
How's that?
[CAR ALARM WAILING]
What's that?
What the hell?
Turn it off. Turn it off!
Oh, come on.
Somebody's back in that trailer.
Let's take a look.
[HORN HONKS]
Eddie, look out!
Shh.
Do it. Come on, come on, come on.
Yeah.
[CAR STARTS]
Go!
[###]
[SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
[BOAT WHISTLE BLOWS]
Oh, shit!
[GROANING]
Thanks, Hank.
That's the second time
in 20 minutes you landed
us in some shit.
Hey, you messing
with Earl and Hank!
What the problem is?
Now what the hell
is in these boxes?
Oh, Hank!
Oh, it stinks.
Ow!
Oh, damn!
Sorry.
Oh!
Damn, it looks like Christmas.
Except for these fish guts
and orange peels.
Please be guns. Please be guns.
What the hell is that?
This is a beer keg.
It doesn't make any sense.
It makes a lot of sense when
you put together all the pieces.
What pieces?
It's obvious.
The CIA, they're
smuggling alcohol
into the inner city in an
effort to further subjugate
the black man.
Hey, do you actually
believe the crap that
comes out of your mouth?
Oh, I'm never really sure
until I'm finished talking.
Think they all kegs?
Yeah. Nash. We got a problem.
Well, what we have
here appears to be
your average, garden-variety,
$22-deposit beer keg,
but it's way too light.
Must be light beer.
Yeah, way too light.
Couldn't be a pound and a half.
Let's take a peek inside, huh?
Yeah, she's empty all right.
You think maybe there's
a double wall? Something
stashed in between?
Happy to take a look.
Put on the glasses, boys,
or you will go blind.
This torch burns
at 4000 degrees Fahrenheit,
so let's slice open
this can of peaches.
Incredible.
She's cold as ice.
Oh.
Gorgeous.
Why don't you and
the keg get a room?
Gentlemen, what we have here
is an Area 51, high-tech,
aerospace alloy.
Weighs next to nothing,
disperses heat instantaneously,
and is resistant to almost
any force in man or nature.
Well, is it worth anything?
Yeah, millions!
Which is exactly why
I want you two to take this thing
and get the hell out of my shop.
Personally, I don't feel
like dying right now,
and this is exactly the kind
of shit people get killed over.
[###]
Thanks.
We'll stash the van here
until we find out what's what.
Whose garage is this?
This guy I know. It doesn't matter.
No, no. This ain't no guy garage.
There ain't a power tool in here.
Let's go.
Hank, this box up here
got your name on it.
This wouldn't happen to be
your girlfriend's house, would it?
Hey, Earl, could you do me a favour?
Could you stay out of my business?
Oh, well, lookie, lookie,
lookie. Looks like
somebody got dissed, huh?
All right,
let me guess, Hank.
Your girl left because you
beat the shit out of her.
No. Ironically, she left me
because I was convicted of beating
the shit out of somebody else.
Oh, me? Moi?
Man, go ahead with that, man.
Look, Hank, I'm just saying, man,
I suppose that's what your
attitude is all about? Huh?
Hanky ain't getting no loving.
Hey, man. I'll be happy
to go back in there
and straighten this
whole mess out for you.
No, thanks, I think you've done enough.
No, serious, Hank. I wanna do it, man.
Earl Montgomery is a
love-maker, not a love-taker.
Wait a second.
Let me get this straight.
You're telling me you'd go
in there and tell Denise
that I never harassed you,
and that I went to jail for no reason?
Absolutely.
But you and I both
know you got exactly
what you deserve.
Denise.
I hope they don't
think we're breaking in.
She's not home.
Damn. Denise got
one fine-looking maid.
Excuse me?
Earl...
that is Denise. Hey.
What do you want, Hank?
I only wanna talk.
Oh, you wanna talk?
Yeah.
Or you wanna lie? Because
there's a difference, you know.
I've always been honest with you.
Of course you were.
You just forgot to tell me
you were beating up black
men on your lunch hour.
Oh, snap. She's witty.
Yeah. She most definitely
got the upper hand.
Hey, yeah, could you be
quiet for a minute? Thanks.
Look, I told you...
Yeah, I know, the bumblebee did it.
Yeah.
You lied to me, Henry.
Lies, lies. Lies just compound lies.
You know? But you saying
the same thing. Do your thing.
I didn't beat anybody, okay?
And I can prove it.
This is the man that
I was accused of
assaulting. Okay, Earl.
Hi.
You got something you wanna say?
Oh, yeah.
She's black. You never
told me she was black.
Did I or did I
not assault you?
Oh, he beat the hell
out of me, ma'am.
What?
I'm not gonna lie to the sister.
No, you're... You son of a bitch!
I'm not gonna take this!
Hey! Get your hands
off him. Stop it. Get out.
Get out!
Get out! Just get out!
Henry, get out!
You too. Get out! Get!
But...
Get!
I think the violence
might kick off out there.
Get out.
Listen, man.
Wait. Why you all
salty at me, man?
Look, Hank, kill that
noise, man. Listen, it's
not my fault. Okay?
You told me she was white.
I did not.
Well, you didn't tell
me she was black, so
that's the same thing.
What difference does it make?
It makes a big difference.
Look, if I had lied and told her
that you didn't beat me up,
I'd be condoning
interracial relationships.
Which is something
I do not condone.
Okay, that's it. If you're not out
of my face in three seconds...
Whoa. Now, you don't wanna
be threatening your partner.
I am not your partner!
I had a partner! I would
have taken a bullet for him!
You, I'm having a hard
time not shooting!
All right, hold on! Now,
that's it. Now I'm upset.
If you try to leave, I'm gonna put
your ass under citizen's arrest.
Okay? And you and I both
know you are in direct violation
of a legal, binding
restraining order.
You have something in your teeth.
Where? Here, or here?
[###]
Now you can tell people I hit you.
Hi.
Hi, '78 Plymouth Volare, tan.
Can I have your driver's license?
Yep.
Are you kidding me?
I got something in my teeth?
I'll tell you what it was, Hank.
Trust. And now it's gone.
Earl, what do I have to do?
I just came to get back Earl Jr.
Okay, I don't go nowhere
without my baby.
So why don't you get your jalopy,
and we both go our separate ways.
Hey, that's my car right
over there. Do you think I
could just have the keys?
We're just trying to locate
your paperwork, sir.
Lookie, lookie, lookie.
What do we have here?
How you doing, Miss Dolly?
Fine.
Oh, yes, you are.
You got a pair of handcuffs
on you I can borrow?
You hitting on her?
Uh, yeah.
What was all that crap
about interracial couples?
Oh.
I am firmly and belligerently
against any interracial coupling
when the man is white.
Darling...
can I interest you
in a stick of gum?
You know, they say
five out of five dentists
recommend this shit.
Thanks.
Get your stuff out of my car
and get the hell out of here!
Miss Darling, what do I have
to do to get my car out of here?!
Would you please just be patient?
Patient.
[###]
Freeze!
On the ground, now!
Goddamn it. God.
[SIREN WAILS]
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I gave up!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
No, don't give up. Get in.
Hank, freeze!
[SIRENS WAILING]
Know what I'm doing?
Stealing a police car.
I'm saving your ass yet again,
despite the fact that you struck me
yet again.
Okay. Sorry. Thank you.
God!
Apology accepted.
Okay, we're even. Go, go, go!
Don't hit me no damn more.
Go, go, go!
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Car!
Forklift. Forklift, my side.
Forklift!
I got it!
Yep...
you got it.
Watch out!
Dead end! Dead end, dead end!
Hey!
I see it.
Come to think of it,
you hit me and
I didn't kill you?
I'm letting you live,
saving your ass.
Oh, I'm going straight to heaven.
Fence!
Chill, Hank. I'm blessed.
[HANK SCREAMS]
What'd you do this time, Hank?
I don't know. I'll find out.
You know, for a cop, you sure
get in a hell of a lot of trouble.
Yeah, yeah.
Turn here. Turn, turn, turn!
Hey, chopper.
Turn here, turn here!
Turn!
[HORN HONKS]
Always loved the
car wash, man.
White, foamy water over you.
Brushes waving in the breeze.
When you a kid in the ghetto,
that's like going to Hawaii.
They got an APB out on both of us.
Both of us? What the hell did I do?
We're both wanted for the shootout
on the Vincent Thomas Bridge.
Yeah, well, that's fair.
No, it doesn't make any sense.
How'd the cops know
we were on the bridge?
The only people who could have
ID'd us were the guys in the truck,
and they're not gonna call it in.
Maybe someone on the inside
put out a APB to locate us.
Now we're talking
about dirty cops.
What you doing?
Running the numbers on the van.
[BEEPING]
No, plates are phoney. Damn it!
Check the VIN.
What?
I thought they were all scratched off.
Not underneath.
I pulled it when
I was wiring the van.
DISPATCHER: All units, 5-0-3,
stolen police vehicle.
Bingo. Address. Okay.
Car wash at Venice and Crenshaw.
They tracked us.
Let's ditch the car!
[###]
We need a car.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, hey! Hey, hey!
Hey, could you pull over here?
God!
Use the badge.
What?
Stop! National Security!
I'm commandeering this vehicle!
Let me see that badge.
Please just step out of the car, ma'am.
Don't you raise your voice at me.
Get out of the damn car!
Didn't your mama
teach you any manners?
At least you could
ask me nicely.
You call this
commandeering a car?
You wanna shut the hell up?
Don't be using that language in my car.
Sorry.
Now, I got no problem
giving you boys a ride.
But I don't take kindly to
being told to get out of my car.
No, sir. I surely do not.
Warrant.
A warrant.
Look, they must've had a
warrant to raid the warehouse.
The dirty cop had to have access
to it to send his boys in first.
Same thing must've happened
at the storage place.
EARL: So who's the leak?
I don't know.
APB's go through
watch commander.
Washington? Ain't that
how it always is?
What?
You have absolutely nothing to go on,
and already you blaming
the black man.
I'm just throwing names out.
I'll tell you how to find a dirty cop.
Pick up the phone
and call the police station.
Don't really matter who answers.
What you gonna say?
Thanks.
Thank you.
Okay, you boys behave now.
No question.
Take care.
Think I should have
gotten her number?
Definitely. She's very nice.
I thought so too.
[###]
Is this the place?
Stay cool.
Can you pick this?
What? "Just because I'm
a black man... What?"
You were doing good.
But why you said like this:
What's all that? All black
people don't do that.
Look, man. Just let it flow...
Can you pick the lock or not?
Not without my tools.
Hey, hey. Come on.
This is great.
A real stakeout.
My whole life, man,
I wanted to be a cop.
Ever since I was a kid,
watching Quincy on TV.
Quincy was a
medical examiner.
Oh. I guess in the
projects we didn't
get real good reception.
[SIGHS]
Hey, man. This is boring.
How long we been here?
Coming up on 12 minutes.
Where the hell are these people?
Earl, this is a stakeout. We
could be sitting here for hours.
No wonder cops are so fat.
Shoot.
Hey, whatever
happened to Charlie?
If you don't mind, I'd just...
I'd rather not talk about it.
You sure?
Yeah.
You know, they shot him
right in front of me, man.
[###]
I couldn't do a
damn thing about it.
I'm sorry to hear
that, man. Who did it?
The guys we're looking for.
So that's why
this is personal.
Let me get this straight.
Your partner got killed,
you lost your job, you got thrown
in jail, your girlfriend walked,
and now you're a
security guard making
182 dollars a week?
Know what you are, Hank?
You're a black man.
Now, though, you gotta
think about it though, right?
Glad to see you laugh, man.
Now how long have we been here?
Oh, come on.
Coming up on 13 minutes.
I got to get something to eat, man.
[WHISTLING]
[###]
Earl.
Hey, Earl.
What are you doing?
No! Earl!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Earl, hey. Earl.
NASH:
We're always early.
He's always late.
Damn it!
[PHONE RINGING]
MAN 1: Call me back. They were
spotted at the police impound yard.
NASH:
Get down and get the goods.
Pain in the ass!
[HORN HONKS]
[GUN FIRES]
[GROANS]
[YELLS]
Are you okay?
Hell, no, I ain't okay,
man. I been shot!
Shit.
It's him!
How do you know?
Tattoo!
Son of a bitch!
Partner.
Go get him.
[YELLING]
EARL: Hank.
Yeah?
You get him?
No.
Come on.
I ain't gonna make it, Hank.
I'm cold, man. I'm cold all over.
I'm starting to see white light.
Damn. Even the light is white.
Come on. You got hit
in the leg, Sally. Let's go!
Don't bounce. Don't bounce!
You gotta help me a little.
You're bouncing!
Your other leg.
[KNOCKING]
Denise! Denise!
It's Hank. Hank.
I thought I told you. It's over.
I been shot!
You shot him now?
No.
What happened?
Look, it's a long story, but you
gotta trust us. We didn't do
anything wrong or illegal.
So then take him
to a hospital.
No, no! We can't, 'cause
the cops are looking for us.
What?
It's complicated!
Look, Denise, I understand
you're a nurse, right?
I'm bleeding out here.
Y'all can bicker later. Come on.
Please, please.
Let me come in?
All right.
Yeah, go.
Hey.
Sorry.
Take off your pants.
Huh?
Earl? You're not wearing
any underwear.
I don't like to wear drawers,
okay? Makes me feel constricted.
So does dying. Now,
hurry up, Hank! Come on!
I'll get you a towel.
Better make it a beach towel.
It's not that big.
It ain't small.
Thank you, Denise.
That was very sweet of you.
All right, I'm gonna
need you to keep
pressure on the wound.
Right. Okay, bend over the
chair and hike up the towel.
What? I'm not like that, man!
Do it!
Oh, oh. Well,
just say that, Hank.
I thought you was trying
to get a free ass shot.
Come on, Denise.
Now, tell me the truth.
Earl, there's no bullet in you.
It went through the bone,
out the other side?
It barely touched you.
It's a scratch.
Denise, you think I'm
gonna need stitches?
Yes.
I knew it.
Well, just...
Oh! Whoa. You know what?
What?
I'll let it heal naturally.
Oh...
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
[BEE BUZZING]
Oh, no!
It's just a bee.
No, no. Calm down!
A bumblebee! No!
Don't move. Don't move!
Death from above!
No! Swish it out.
Death from above, man.
[###]
Is it safe?
Not for you it ain't!
I can't believe your girl
can go off like that.
She hits harder than you do.
Yeah, this is it.
Marina Yacht Club.
This is where the
call came from.
How we gonna get in?
[###]
Split up.
WOMAN: I want the big fat one.
Oh, that looks interesting.
What is it?
I don't know, but it
smells like ass.
You recognize anyone?
Man, it's so damn white
in here, my pupils
haven't adjusted yet.
Hey. Hey, look.
That's him.
Son of a bitch.
What do you know?
It's the white guy.
A sad day in
Caucasian history.
[###]
Where the hell the two of you been?
Jimmy Buffet's in town. Come on.
You got five minutes.
It better be good.
Can I get a chip?
No.
You've got a leak,
and we know who it is.
Now can I get a chip?
No.
It's McDuff.
I assume you have some proof.
Yeah.
We been tracking them knuckleheads
who hit my warehouse.
The same guys who killed Charlie.
Led us right to McDuff.
That's all very interesting,
but do you have any actual evidence?
No.
No. But we got what he wants.
And what's that?
The goods from the CIA heist.
You got the CIA goods?
Wait a minute. It was really CIA?
Crupps International Aerospace.
What CIA did you think
I was talking about?
Would you tell him, please?
A year ago, over $7 million
in niobium-coated atomic alloy
was stolen out of Crupps.
And to smuggle it out of the
country, they had to melt it down
and recast it as beer kegs.
Feds tipped us off.
Our leak beat us to the punch.
That's right. McDuff. Offer to sell
him back his stuff. Oh, he'll bite.
If he's dirty.
Oh, he's dirty.
Now, give the man a chip.
I appreciate you trying
to get me a chip.
But thinking that I was
talking about the actual CIA...
HANK:
Yeah. I don't know
what I was thinking.
Hey, McDuff. It's your
buddies Hank and Earl.
What's up, Duff?
Look, we got something you want.
MCDUFF: I don't know what
you're talking about.
We're talking beer kegs, bitch!
You two are wanted felons.
Frank, save it. We know you're dirty.
Listen to me...
No, you listen to me.
Look, I don't know who
you're selling these things to.
I don't really care.
All we want is a piece of the
pie. Say, $1 million worth.
We're talking six zeros, chump.
So, what's your plan?
Meet us tomorrow morning, 7 a.m.
The old fort, Luna Point.
[###]
How'd you find this place?
I did a couple nights of
security watching some
construction equipment.
It's perfect for us, though.
How many boys Washington got?
Uh... I don't know.
I see five or so.
Shh.
I'm starting to feel all tingly and shit.
Yeah.
I thought I shot you once
already. You're a tough
little monkey, aren't you?
You into monkey jokes, huh?
Didn't your mama teach
you some manners when
you were humping her?
You bring the metal, Hank?
You bring the money, Frank?
We'll see about that
when I see the kegs.
You know what, let's just forget
about the money. I think we
already got what we came for.
[WHISTLES]
I don't think you'll find
them as helpful as you
thought they'd be.
You see, my men aren't actually
members of the L.A. SWAT team.
Where's Washington?
I don't know.
Excellent question.
Shit.
Oh, man.
The brother's in on it?
He must've grew up
in a white neighbourhood.
Gun. Scratch that.
He's a real brother, getting
messed over just like the rest of us.
Guns, gentlemen.
Look, l... No. Look!
Sorry. No, no. Look, look.
No, no, no, no! Go!
[###]
HANK:
Washington, get over here!
Get in! Get in! Get in!
HANK:
I know a way out!
There's a tunnel at the other end.
Down! Down!
What the hell happened?
I don't know. They grabbed
me after we talked.
HANK:
Take a right! Come on!
Get through the other end!
[YELLING]
HANK:
Earl!
Come on! The tunnel!
Go, go!
WASHINGTON:
Hank, come on!
[YELLING]
Earl.
What? Where's Hank?
I don't know.
Hank!
Hank! Shit. I gotta
go find him.
Okay, go ahead. My foot's busted up.
You gonna be okay?
I'll be fine. Go!
[###]
Damn it!
Earl!
[GRUNTS]
No!
Busted!
Son of a bitch.
[GUN FIRES]
[GROANING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Yeah!
[HORN HONKS]
Hey, Nash! Catch!
[SCREAMS]
Yeah!
Who's a monkey now? Monkey!
[YELLS]
Shit. Hank!
Hold on!
Whoops! Sorry!
Hank!
Hold on!
Good, good, good, good!
Whoa!
Yes!
Yeah!
You the man!
No, you are the man!
Okay, I am the man!
Yeah, yeah!
WOMAN: Six months ago,
these two men were lock ed
in a conflict that shook our city.
Today, they stand together as heroes.
Gentlemen, thank you for your
bravery and your selflessness.
Hank, welcome
back to the force.
Thanks.
Earl, welcome to the L.A.P.D.
You serious?
Congratulations, Earl.
Yeah. Thank you.
Whoo! Whoo!
Earl! That's enough.
Oh.
Whoo-whoo-whoo!
Hey, check it out, 10:00.
EARL:
Pull over.
Excuse me.
You wanna step away from the vehicle?
Hank. Please, man.
Let me show you how this type
of situation is properly handled.
Excuse me, Mr. Civilian,
who has rights.
Did you perhaps lock your keys
in your vehicle?
Yeah, I do it all the time.
They're right there in the visor.
Yeah, yeah. Right
there in the visor.
For my partner's
peace of mind,
would you please
tell us the numbers
on your license plate?
Sure, 2CQN654.
Is he right?
Yeah.
Allow me to assist you,
instead of beat you senseless,
like some cops would.
Thank you, officer.
You're very welcome.
You have a good day, all right?
I will. Thanks.
Hey, listen, man.
Not everyone's a
criminal. Remember that.
My car! No, wait!
That's my car!
Of course, it's always good
to have a backup plan.
Hey!
I give up!
Ma'am, you may
re-procure your vehicle.
[CAR ALARM WAILS]
WOMAN:
You idiot!
What the problem is?
[###]
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group