Live from WZIL, News 25 at noon starts now.
Colin Evans,
convicted of voluntary manslaughter
for one of the most brutal murders
in recent history,
is up for parole today.
Five years ago, Evans was one of
the most wanted men in state history,
having emerged as the prime suspect
in the disappearance of five young women.
Evans was eventually apprehended
for the crimes,
only to escape
and elude authorities for several months,
until the night he was arrested
for the fatal barroom brawl
that would lead
to his manslaughter conviction.
The evidence necessary to try Evans
for the abduction of
the five young women proved illusory.
The DA's office decided to settle for what
it knew it could prove in a court of law.
Hence, the lesser manslaughter conviction.
No mention of Evans
being the primary suspect
in the disappearance and
presumed death of the five young women
was ever made at his manslaughter trial.
But now, on a day
when one of the most feared men
in the annals of state history might walk
after having served
only five years in prison for manslaughter,
the five families are huddled together
outside the courthouse hoping and praying
that the man they believe to be
nothing more than a vicious animal,
is not set free.
I'm hoping you get a
fair shake today, Colin.
I prayed hard for it Sunday.
I appreciate that.
In my experience,
if you give a man a second chance,
usually, they rise to the occasion.
Well, except politicians.
I've never met one of them
ever learned from their mistakes.
What about you, Officer Reid?
Can I count on your support?
They pay me to guard
you, not to talk to you.
Don't mind him, Colin.
He's got woman troubles.
You know how that goes.
Yeah.
Colin Evans, currently serving 10 to
15 years for involuntary manslaughter.
Let the record show you've requested
to address the parole board
in lieu of your attorney. You may begin.
Thank you, sir.
I'm not going to stand here and lie to you,
because I'm not very good at that.
When I was sentenced, I was angry.
I told myself fights like this
get out of hand all the time.
Accidents happen and I could have
easily been the man that died that night.
But as time went by, I realized I was
wrong. I shouldn't have been angry.
I should have been ashamed.
A man had died, and there was
no way I could bring him back.
But I could make a change within myself.
And others, perhaps.
I started a teaching program,
teaching other prisoners to read and write.
And the warden saw this,
and they're talking about taking
my program statewide to other prisons.
I feel like that's an achievement.
I stand here right now as a changed,
humble man.
I've been in the prison correctional system
for five years now,
and that is exactly what I am, corrected.
Rehabilitated.
I just wanted you to give me a chance.
I won't let you down.
Thank you for your time.
Mr. Chairman, if I could
have just a moment?
Go ahead.
You see, I did my homework on this man.
And I can tell you with confidence
that he's actually quite a good liar.
That fight that got out of hand,
that was actually
Mr. Evans flying into a murderous rage
because of how
the victim was looking at his girlfriend.
And as a younger man,
there were other acts of violence,
frequently involving
the attentions of a woman.
Mr. Evans fits the criteria
of a malignant narcissist.
Charming, highly intelligent,
as you've witnessed,
but malignant narcissists
are compelled to prove their superiority.
Everything's a seduction,
and if they're rejected,
or things don't go their way,
they lose control.
Some other
more well-known malignant narcissists were
Jeffrey Dahmer, John Wayne Gacy...
Now, hold on.
No. Sir. Sir.
Mr. Evans, please, just sit down.
Please sit down, Mr. Evans.
I can tell you there's
violence in this man.
And his control over himself is slender.
I'll let my fellow board members
make up their own minds,
but there are five families outside
who are hoping and praying
that we do not set Colin Evans free.
Mr. Evans, as I'm sure you're aware,
to be granted parole
in the state of Tennessee,
it must be a unanimous vote.
We'll take this up again in five years,
as mandated.
Ladies and gentlemen, that convenes the state
of Tennessee parole hearing for today.
Madame Secretary,
you can turn off your recording devices.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you are free to go at this time.
I don't know what to say, Colin.
Why even waste your breath?
A little help. My nose is bleeding.
- Reid.
- He'll be fine.
Give him a tissue or something.
Here.
Shit!
- No, no, put the gun down!
- No!
Or you can watch him die
and I don't want that!
- No!
- You don't want that.
Put the gun down
and you both walk out of here!
Come on.
I just want to get out of here, that's all.
Colin, please.
You have my word.
Go on.
Come on.
Just put it down. Just put it down!
Yes, I'm still here.
Yeah. Ryan, honey, please don't do that.
Yeah, can you please tell me
how long ago my husband left?
Ryan, stop it.
Yeah. Javier, one second.
Yeah, well, if he checks in,
can you please have him call me?
Yeah. Thanks, Karen. Okay. Bye-bye.
What's up?
There's a storm coming.
Is everything gonna be okay out there?
I covered the concrete with plastic.
It will delay the dry-time a little,
but nothing to worry about...
Ryan, paint Mommy a picture.
Please, go make me a picture. Go ahead.
Come on. Go get your coloring book.
With the storm coming,
there's really not much we can do.
Hey, Javier. The house is looking great.
- It's getting there. Have a good weekend.
- You, too. Bye.
All right, let's go, guys. Load it up!
- Terry?
- Hey!
Hey!
- When are they going to be done?
- Last month.
Maybe I should remodel.
Who's got the prettiest goddaughter
in the whole world?
You!
- And who's Meg's best friend?
- Ryan.
- And who's Ryan's best friend?
- Meg.
- And what's all the rest?
- Bullshit!
Meg. Yeah, you're going to school
the first time she gets called
to the principal's office, not me.
What's he look like, and is he single?
You are a mess, but you look good.
Thanks. So do you.
Yeah, covered in spit-up
and carrying an extra
10 pounds, but thanks.
Do you know what I think? I think you're
not the reason you feel bad about yourself.
I think that Jeffrey should be making
you feel appreciated and he should...
Meg, Jeffrey makes me
feel appreciated, okay?
He appreciates me.
- I am just saying... Okay.
- Thanks for your concern.
Daddy! Daddy!
Hey, sweetheart.
- Jeffrey's home early.
- I forgot to tell you.
It's his dad's birthday, so,
he's taking him on a golf trip.
Okay. You know what?
We're going to have a girls' night.
- I'm going to get some wine.
- Great.
My girl needs a girls' night.
We're going to get drunk!
I can't wait.
Hey, Jeffrey.
Hey, Meg.
What are the two of you up to?
You know, just braiding each other's hair
and talking about the boys we like.
Meg stopped by on her run.
Which I should probably get back to,
so, I'll see you tonight?
Yes, I can't wait.
Jeffrey, you're a lucky man.
Yes, I am.
- See you later, Meg.
- Bye, honey.
- Hi.
- Hello, darling.
Damn, baby.
I was feeding your children.
Can you try not to act so grossed out?
I'm sorry. It's just this Hopkins case
is turning into a nightmare.
The judge rejected our plea today.
I am sorry to hear that.
That's life, right?
I saw that Meg sold
that house down by the school.
She must be making a killing.
Meg has quite the life.
Here we go. I'm home two minutes
and you're already being negative.
- All I said was that Meg had the life.
- And you don't?
Jeffrey, I...
Babe, just remember
it was your idea to be a full-time mom.
This is what you wanted, not me.
Yes, it is what I wanted, Jeffrey.
I hardly saw you all week
and I'm going to miss you.
I know. I'm sorry. Okay?
Let's get away. Okay? Just you and me.
Without the kids.
Somewhere for a couple of days.
We need it. It's been a long time.
Okay?
All right. We can do that.
I'm going to the store.
That way, you can spend
some time with the kids before you leave.
No, wait a minute. No, no.
I'm already running late
and I still got to pack.
Jeffrey. That's why
I asked you to be home early.
It's my dad's birthday.
I'm going to go pack.
You're not taking your big, warm coat?
It's going to be cold up there.
It's just two hours away. I'll be fine.
They say the storm is
going to be really bad.
Are you sure
you want to drive all the way there?
Is all this worrying
because you need me to stay?
Of course not. I know how important
this is for your father.
I better get going.
Tell your dad I said, "Happy birthday."
I will.
Make sure you use the alarm
when I'm gone, all right?
I know, I know,
but just use it for my peace of mind.
All right.
- Do you remember the code?
- Yes. I'll use it.
All right.
I'll miss you.
When I get back, we'll plan that trip.
Maybe, we'll go back to
that little place on the vineyard.
How does that sound?
Great.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Hey, it's Renée.
I hope you're having a great day.
Listen, we should catch up this weekend.
I have to tell you about
the horrible date I went on last week.
Anyway, give me a call and maybe
we can meet up for a movie or something?
Talk to you soon. Bye.
Honey, I'm home.
Colin...
I just want to talk.
You know, I wanted to tell you
that after what happened that night,
I don't blame you for pulling away from me.
You know, moving out here.
The point is,
I can't do anything about that now.
When I was in prison,
I thought a lot about you.
What do you want from me?
I just want you to forgive me.
Give me a chance.
I know someone that can make passports.
We can get two new names.
Travel, you know?
Go around the world, you and me,
like we talked about.
Maybe get married.
Would you come with me?
I'm going to need an answer, yes or no.
Yes.
Yes?
Do you still love me?
Yes.
Because I wrote you a lot of letters
and you ain't answer them.
But that's because I
didn't know what to say.
And there's no one else?
- No.
- That's right.
Because you still love me.
Right?
Is that him?
- Who?
- "Who?"
The guy I saw you talking to
at the coffee shop.
Nice looking fellow.
He and I are going to
have to have a chat later on.
He's my trainer. He wanted to
talk to me about his boyfriend.
His boyfriend?
Do you think I spent five years in prison
for you to come and lie to me now?
Where did you meet him?
You know, I found this on your bed.
"Didn't want to wake you,
"'cause you look so beautiful
when you sleep."
Colin...
- I tried to wait.
- No, you didn't.
I found these, too.
You didn't even read any of these.
Didn't read that one. Not one. Not one!
Hey!
Hey! No!
Here.
- Colin!
- You didn't give me a chance!
You murdered a man!
It's manslaughter in the eyes of the law.
It's very, very different.
And those girls? What about them?
Does he even know about me?
Who?
Do you love him? Do you love him?
- Leave me alone.
- Just tell me. Just tell me!
- Leave me alone!
- Just answer the question!
- What?
- Did you have sex in this bed?
You're just being ridiculous. It's stupid.
That's what's going on?
While I'm in jail, you're sitting here
having sex with this man. Is that right?
Why don't you just tell me the truth?
Why don't you just tell me?
Yes! Yes, Colin!
We do it right here, in this bed.
All the time! And it's great!
Is that what you want to hear?
Is that what I need to say
to get you to just leave me alone?
Just leave me alone.
I'm sorry.
That's okay.
- I just missed you.
- It's okay.
I missed you so much.
I...
I am done!
Shit. Okay.
Mr. Evans fits the criteria
of a malignant narcissist.
Some other more well-known
malignant narcissists were
Jeffrey Dahmer, John Wayne Gacy...
Cut those up.
Go ahead, cut it up and
put it on the plate.
That's very good. Big girl.
Okay, baby. Finish that up, okay?
I'll be right back.
Okay, Mommy.
You are so early.
Hello?
I'm sorry, I don't mean to bother you.
You were the only house with the lights on.
I just lost control of my car.
I skidded and wrecked it.
- Are you all right?
- I'm good. I just had a scratch.
Oh, my God.
I'm all right.
Do you think I could use your phone?
I don't even need to come in.
I'll stand right here.
You can hand the phone and shut the door.
Okay. I'll be right back.
All right, thank you.
Okay, baby.
I guess somebody needs to use the phone.
Okay, finish cutting that up, baby.
Put it on the plate,
and then come over here and eat,
because I want you in bed
at a decent hour tonight, okay?
- Okay.
- All right. I'll be right back.
Okay. Here.
- I'll get that for you.
- You don't have to worry about that.
That's all right.
I really can get that later.
You know,
the one time I forget my cell phone...
- Here.
- Thank you.
Oh, boy.
Do you live around here?
- Yeah, over on River Road.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Mommy!
- I'm feeding my daughter. I'm sorry.
- Go on.
Look, why don't you make the call
and I'll be right back?
- Go on. I'll be fine.
- Okay. All right.
Okay, Ryan.
Ryan. I need your help, baby.
I'm trying to help a neighbor.
You have to clean that up.
Lord.
Wait right... I'll be back, baby.
Yeah, it's going to need a tow.
It's totaled.
Hold on.
Is there anyone here
that can give me a ride to my car?
They want me to sign something
before they can tow me.
My husband's not home...
...yet, but he should be home soon.
You know what?
Why don't you have them
meet you here just in case he's late?
- Here?
- Yeah.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, it's fine.
Okay. Sir, is there any way the driver
can meet me here where I am right now?
Great.
- I'm at...
- 17 Creston Lane.
- 17...
- Creston...
- Creston.
- ...Lane.
Lane.
- All right.
- Okay.
He said he doesn't know how long it's going
to take because of the storm, but...
They're on their way. So, thank you again.
- Yeah, sure.
- I appreciate it.
- All right.
- Okay.
You know what?
- You can come in.
- I don't want to bother you.
No, it's no bother. Just come on.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
I can't leave you out in the rain
to bleed to death. It's fine.
- You're sure?
- I'm positive.
- Thank you.
- That cut's really bad.
No, it's not that bad.
Yeah, let me see if I
have something for that.
- Stay right there. I'll be right back.
- All right.
Okay.
- It's really nice of you...
- Okay, there's this.
...to look after a stranger
on your doorstep like this.
I mean, really, you don't have to do this.
Like I said, I couldn't leave you
out in the rain bleeding like that.
You can dry yourself off with that.
You can come over here.
This is all I have, so, hopefully,
I can patch you up.
It's a beautiful house you've got here.
Thanks.
- Let me get this for you. Thank you.
- Okay.
- Do you want me to take that for you?
- No, I'll just leave it here.
Okay.
Okay. Let's see.
Well, hello, little princess.
What's your name?
This is Ryan.
- I'm a superhero!
- Ryan, no hitting.
That's a mean right hook you have there.
Who taught you that, your daddy?
I'm so sorry. I don't know where
she's learning this from.
Ryan, do me a favor.
Go in the kitchen
and get Mommy a wet paper towel,
so I can clean up his boo-boo.
- She is so beautiful.
- Thank you.
Is that your only child?
No. Sam's in the nursery, sleeping.
You lucked out.
It can be quite the zoo
around here sometimes.
And trust me,
I don't turn down an opportunity to
have some adult interaction these days.
Thank you, baby.
Finish cleaning up your mess, okay?
All right, let's see here.
You must have thought I was your husband.
At the door?
Yeah, he'll be home shortly.
Yeah, you said.
So, I'm Colin.
- Terry.
- Terry?
Nice to meet you.
Okay. That should do it.
I don't think I'll put a Band-Aid on it.
It looks like it needs to breathe.
Okay, bugaboo. What about Spy Dogs?
- Spy Dogs!
- Yeah!
Bye-bye. Watch some Spy Dogs.
- Spy Dogs.
- Say, "Bye-bye."
Spy Dogs, Spy Dogs.
Get you good and sleepy.
Okay. God, that should keep her occupied.
You know what?
Why don't you come in here?
I'll see if I have a dry shirt for you.
You're soaking wet. Here.
- Thank you.
- Hopefully, the sizes are okay.
- Thanks so much.
- You're welcome.
So, your husband went to NYU?
We both did, actually.
We met in law school.
So, you're both lawyers?
Yeah. I was a prosecutor
at the DA's office.
- That's fascinating.
- It was.
Well, most of my cases
were violence against women.
They're easier to make.
Why is that?
Well, it's almost always
someone close to the victim.
- Husband, boyfriend.
- They beat them?
They kill them.
I worked in the homicide division.
I bet you were
a force to be reckoned with, though.
That's the nicest thing
anyone has said to me in a long time.
Come here.
There you go. Got it.
Give me your shirt. I can dry that for you.
Right. Okay.
It helped that the men made my job easy.
How come?
Unlike what you see on TV,
most killers aren't that smart or clever.
Actually, they're pretty pathetic.
- Pathetic?
- Yeah, they're weak.
Shit, that's going to wake Sam.
- Is everything all right?
- No. It's not working.
- It does this sometimes.
- Do you want me to take a look?
Do you mind?
Yeah, just grab that coat right there.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Alarm. Alarm.
- It's loud!
- Yes!
It says there's a valet button
underneath the steering wheel.
- Wait. I think I know where that is.
- You know where it is?
- That's not it.
- What now?
We need to do something else.
- What did you do?
- I have no idea.
That was bizarre.
I don't know. Maybe it was a fuse.
Something's gone wrong.
Let me lock this.
Do you want some hot tea?
- Sure.
- Okay.
Did you get lost?
No.
I'm just drying off.
- Is this your husband?
- Yeah.
Nice.
What about you? Are you married?
Girlfriend?
- Ex-fiancée.
- I'm sorry.
Yeah. It just happened.
Sugar? Fresh lemon?
She was cheating on me.
That's got to hurt.
The knowing is the tough part.
The act itself, well, that's going to
happen whether you know about it or not.
The only way to stop it is to know more.
So, you want to know who he was,
what he was wearing, what he was driving.
It sounds like torture.
No, it's worse. It's like getting
your heart ripped out of your chest.
Yeah, but at least you know.
Isn't that better?
No.
- We were going to get married.
- I can tell you, marriage is not all that.
- Do you still love him?
- Of course.
I guess I just miss my own fire.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
When we met, I was independent,
strong, and powerful.
I just think he sees me differently now.
He's just gone blind, that's all.
Because you're still beautiful, powerful,
fierce.
Yeah.
I'm going to go put Ryan to sleep.
- Can I use the restroom?
- It's this way.
- Night-night, bugaboo.
- Night-night.
Okay.
You scared me.
Is everything okay?
I couldn't find the sugar.
I offered you sugar.
Are you looking for your husband?
I feel silly.
He's not coming home.
He's not what?
The tow truck's here.
- Hey!
- Hey.
- Did you walk?
- It's just down the street. I'm fine.
Crazy lady, give me that coat.
- You're soaking...
- I know.
- Here. Give me the coat.
- Sorry.
Look, I meant to call you because I have...
- What?
- Hi.
Hi. And who are you?
I'm Colin.
That's why I wanted to call you.
Colin got into an accident and I was
the first house that he stumbled upon,
and he needed to use the phone.
So, he called a tow truck
and we're just waiting for the tow truck.
- We're waiting.
- You don't have your own cell phone?
I left it at home.
That cut's pretty nasty. Are you all right?
No, I'm good. Terry's
been looking after me.
- I'm sure she has.
- Stop it.
She's a good little nurse, isn't she?
Well, listen, I thought
we were going to have a girls' night,
but I suppose we can all share.
Yeah, sure. I'll get glasses.
- Meg.
- Meg. Colin.
- So you said.
- Right.
You know,
it's funny.
I thought I knew all the good
looking men in this town.
I bet you do.
Well, obviously not.
- Now, where do you live?
- River Road.
Hey, I just sold a house there.
- I'm a realtor.
- Really?
Yeah, 6267. It's an old Georgian.
It was a horrible shade of brown.
The new owners just painted.
Do you know the one?
Do you know the one that I'm talking about?
- The new owners just painted.
- Nope.
- No, I don't think I've seen that one.
- I know all the families on that street.
What's your address?
- Come on. What is it?
- My address?
Yeah, which house are you in?
Are you going to stalk me?
You should be so lucky.
Yeah, I think I should stalk you.
Now, seriously, where do you live?
I...
What happened?
Terry, are you okay? What happened?
God, that scared the hell out of me.
- Look at that.
- You got garbage bags?
- Duct tape? Garbage bags?
- What? Yeah, everything's in there.
Do you believe that?
That was such a freak accident.
No, I'm fine,
but that scared the shit out of me.
- Jeffrey's not going to be happy.
- No, he's not.
- It's just a broken branch. There you go.
- I need a drink.
Jeffrey's not going to like that.
- Colin, you're so handy.
- I've fixed a couple of windows before.
Stop it.
- Come on.
- This is for you.
Thank you.
- To Terry.
- Me?
A great friend, a great mom,
and a great wife...
Thank you.
- ...who Jeffrey doesn't deserve.
- Meg.
To Terry.
Cheers.
You were thirsty.
Come on, let's go in the living room.
Bring the bottle.
Come on. I'll give you some more.
Meg.
Exactly what I needed.
A definite step up from tea, huh?
- You guys were drinking tea?
- Yeah. It's cold out.
Terry, a man that looks like this
shows up on your doorstep,
and you offer him tea.
You would have plied him full of alcohol.
Yes. I would have.
Would you have taken advantage of me?
Where's your glass?
In every way possible.
Cheers.
Married women so quickly
forget what a sex drive is.
- Meg.
- Honey, I'm just kidding.
But I do think sex is
like going to the gym.
You should do it every day and never use
the same equipment two days in a row.
I guess you're not the settling-down type.
The term "settling down,"
it just seems redundant to me.
And marriage?
It's not really a goal for me
like it is for most women.
If I found the right guy,
but that's a big if.
The right guy has to make me laugh
and be smarter than me.
Do you think love follows all those rules?
You could get swept off your feet, right?
Absolutely. By an incredibly smart
and really funny guy.
How did you two meet?
- Where do we start?
- College BFFs.
Yeah, we've known each other
and we go so far back.
And don't let this one fool you.
I wasn't always the wild one of the pair.
It's true. It's shocking, right?
This one, the wild one.
It's surprising, right?
No, not really.
When...
When Meg...
When I told her
I was moving back to Georgia,
she insisted on being
our real estate agent.
And just happened to own a house
down the street from me.
Which Jeffrey loved.
I was talking to Colin about where he lived,
but he wouldn't tell me where he lived.
Yeah, well, I don't blame him.
Colin just broke up with his fiancée.
It's been really tough for him.
Did you two know each other before tonight?
- No.
- Yes.
Drink some more wine.
Oh, God.
A mother's work is never done.
You two behave yourselves.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
- Are you going to behave yourself?
- I don't know, Colin.
Behave yourself.
I will.
Where can I smoke without getting wet?
The garage should be good. It's just...
It's the door at the end of the hall.
Hey.
Can I get one of those?
Sure, there you go. You can have that one.
Thank you.
So, what's the deal?
What do you mean?
She's happily married.
Well, I guess,
that depends on how you define happily.
What does that mean?
It means you just never know
what's going on behind closed doors.
Is there something
going on between you two?
Is there?
Are you serious?
You two are having an affair?
I can't believe she didn't tell me.
You know, sometimes you like someone...
I don't... What?
You feel close to them.
But they don't feel the same way about you.
You know?
She hasn't told me because
she doesn't think we're very close anymore?
What are you saying?
You talked about this?
When I got here,
I didn't even know you were coming.
She didn't want you to find out.
Not this way.
I wrecked my car
and the first place I came was here.
Because I knew
Jeffrey wasn't going to be here.
Hey, Colin.
You're so full of shit.
- What?
- I said, "You're so full of shit."
Terry is my best friend.
I know everything about her,
and she knows everything about me.
So, there's no way she would ever
have an affair and not tell me.
It doesn't add up.
And, you know what else doesn't add up?
You don't add up.
And I'm going to find out
exactly what's going on.
Hey, Terry! Terry!
Hey!
- Where's Meg?
- She changed her mind.
About?
Staying.
- She left?
- Yeah.
Well, was she upset?
No. But I don't know her.
I'm going to call her.
So, you lied?
Excuse me?
About your husband. You lied.
So, where is he?
He went on a golf trip with his father.
- A golf trip?
- Yeah.
I'm going to get some water. Are
you thirsty? Do you want anything?
No.
Yeah, I'm going to call Meg
and the tow truck, see if they're coming.
Are you sure she wasn't
upset when she left?
Yeah.
But like I said, I don't know her.
Colin?
Up again? Here we go.
- Here we go.
- Put her down!
Hey, Mom.
- Do it again.
- Again? All right. Let's do it. Let's go.
And up! Touch the sky!
No, Ryan.
Ryan, baby, you have to go to bed, okay?
Please.
Ryan and I are just having some fun,
that's all. Aren't we, Ryan?
No. Ryan, come on, bugaboo.
It's past your bedtime, sweetie. Okay?
Please.
Terry, is there something wrong?
Did I do something wrong?
Go to bed, sweetheart, okay?
What is this?
Who gave you this? No. Give it to me.
Ryan and I are friends. I wanted her
to have something real special, that's all.
Keep it.
Baby, go to sleep, okay?
Mommy and her friend will be downstairs.
All right, sweetheart?
Okay, bugaboo.
Bye, Ryan.
I'll see you later, okay?
Kids.
They know, you know?
They have a real sense of
who's good, who's bad.
And your daughter, she has...
Okay.
Come on. Come on, get up.
Put the baby back down.
- Please.
- Put the baby back.
It's okay, baby. Just go back to sleep.
Everything's going to be okay, okay?
Don't you do anything stupid like
that again. Do you understand me?
- Yes.
- You do?
Come on. In the bathroom.
Let's go. Come on!
Go on.
In the bathroom.
- Get in.
- What?
Get in.
Stay right there.
Come on. Get out.
Turn the lights on.
- Are these your clothes?
- Yes.
- Right here?
- Yeah.
- Put those on.
- I'm fine.
Hey. Hey.
Put those clothes on.
I'm not going to tell you again.
Go on.
Turn around.
Stand up straight.
Please. Please.
Please, what?
You don't have to do this.
Don't flatter yourself.
Put your clothes on.
- Fuck you.
- What did you say?
- I said, "Fuck you."
- I would be real careful if I were you.
You're not going to kill me.
If you were going to kill me,
you would have done that already.
Maybe, this is some sick fantasy
you're playing out against your
ex-girlfriend. What was it, your fiancée?
Or your sick mother. I don't know.
I don't care.
Can we just move it along?
Because I'm really getting sick
and tired of your sadistic bullshit.
Terry, I would have thought
with all those brains you've got, DA,
you would have figured out
the game we're playing by now.
- This is a game?
- It's all a game.
Yeah, well, I don't play, asshole.
Well, we're just getting to the fun part.
Yeah, well, I'm sure the fun is long over.
Answer the phone.
Hello. Yes, there's an
intruder in my house.
There's a crazy man in my house.
He's trying to kill me. 17 Creston Lane.
Please hurry!
- Put that down!
- Okay. Okay.
Hey!
Hey! Hey, stop!
Please, Colin.
- I will shoot you!
- Okay.
- Do you understand?
- Yes! Okay.
- I will shoot you!
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
I called 911. The police are on their way.
It's over, Colin. Okay?
So, just leave, okay?
All you have to do is just leave.
Look. If you leave now,
you haven't hurt me,
you haven't hurt my family.
I don't have a reason to carry this on,
Colin, but you've got to go. Just go!
- Go get the kids.
- What do you mean?
You're absolutely right. We've got to go.
No. I will call the operator right now.
- Go get the kids.
- No, please. Please let...
- I'll go get them!
- No, I'll go! I'll get them.
I'll get them.
It's okay, baby. I know.
Go that way.
Don't stop. Keep moving.
Keep moving.
Come on, let's go.
- Mommy.
- Get up!
Come on, get in the car. Let's go.
- Are you going to tell me where we're going?
- Just keep straight.
You don't look so good.
You lost a lot of blood.
You need to get to a hospital.
I need you to shut up.
Just keep driving straight.
Just keep driving.
Don't even think about it.
You know, when the cops get to my house
and see signs of struggle,
your blood all over my kitchen,
and an empty house, they'll run my tags.
It's not too late.
If not a hospital,
I can take you somewhere, anywhere,
but you can't stay in this car because they'll
eventually spot my tags and pull me over.
I'm not going to warn you again.
I need you to shut the hell up.
Shit.
Shit. God damn it.
- What do you want me to do?
- Pull over.
Stay calm.
- What are you doing?
- Get off me.
- No, no. Please. No.
- Come on.
No.
It's just a little motivation
to keep your mouth shut.
I won't do anything, I promise.
Please put my baby back.
Just shut up!
I hope my APB hasn't crossed state lines.
Your what?
Just keep your mouth shut.
I ain't got nothing to lose.
You stand to lose it all.
I won't do anything, I promise.
- Please put him down.
- Just be smart.
License and registration, please.
- Mommy?
- Okay.
- Mommy.
- Everything's okay, baby.
Your baby needs to be in a car seat.
He was, he was,
but we took him out just as we stopped.
He was crying. He's gone to sleep now.
Mommy.
- What happened to your head?
- What now?
Your head. What happened to it?
I was fixing the windows in the storm,
but it fought back.
Mommy.
Right back.
- Is everything all right, Officer?
- Mommy, where is Daddy?
I want to go home.
Ma'am, could you step
out of the car, please?
- Is everything all right, ma'am?
- Yeah, everything's fine.
Were you trying to signal me
with your headlights back there?
You flashed your brights at me back there.
Ma'am.
No, I...
I was reaching for the radio
and my hand must have slipped
and hit the brights.
Honestly, it wouldn't be the first time.
I'm really sorry.
Who's the man in the car with you?
The man in the car?
Who is he?
Well, Officer,
it's kind of embarrassing.
My husband,
he's out of town.
And you must think I'm awful.
Look, lady, it's none of my business.
But you might do whatever
you're doing without the kids around.
- Do you know what I'm saying?
- Yes, Officer. I'm really sorry.
Are you sure everything's all right?
You keep looking back at the car.
Is there something you need to tell me?
I can't say anything right now.
All right, ma'am. Have a nice night.
Don't move.
Stay right there!
Get over here! Right here.
He could have been alive
if it wasn't for you.
It's your fault!
I tell you to do something, you do it.
Do you understand me?
- I will kill you. Do you understand me?
- Yes.
- Do you understand me?
- Yes!
Go on and get in the car. Get around there.
You're at my mercy. Do you understand me?
You are going to do exactly as you're told.
Get in the car. Let's go.
Why are you doing this?
You'll see.
Pull in here.
This house right here. Pull in.
There you go.
Pull straight in. And I want you
to back up on the side right here.
Back it up a little bit. That's right.
Keep going.
That's good.
Grab the kids, let's go.
Go on. Put the kids in here.
We're just going to have a
little sleepover, okay, baby?
- Listen.
- Come on.
I love you.
- Why are you doing this?
- Shut up. Go on.
Through the door right there. Come on.
I want you to go in that bathroom
over there. Find a first aid kit.
Patch me up. Come on.
- I don't know where a first aid kit is.
- Just keep looking.
There's something in there.
Terry, meet Alexis.
Alexis, Terry.
You should have seen the look on her face.
Life draining from her eyes.
And after all I did for her.
Come on, what have you got?
Give me the key.
- Give me the key. Come on!
- Okay.
Shit!
- Come here. Get on your knees.
- Why?
On your knees. Take your coat off.
Take your coat off.
There you go.
Put your hands behind your back. Now.
You stay right here.
I don't want you running around. Right
here. Stay right there. Legs out.
- Please don't.
- Shut up. Just shut up.
- Hello? Hello?
- Finally, babe.
I'm at the hotel. I've been here all night.
I left you, like, five messages.
Where are you?
- Jeffrey?
- Alexis.
Alexis?
"Didn't want to wake you,
'cause you looked so beautiful sleeping."
- 17...
- 17 Creston Lane.
- ...Creston.
- Lane.
Lane.
Oh, my God.
Alexis? I'm at the hotel.
She's dead, Jeffrey.
- Your goddamn girlfriend is dead.
- Terry.
- Call the police.
- Wait a minute.
Jeffrey, call the goddamn police.
You've reached 911 emergency response.
We are receiving
a high volume of calls in this area.
Ryan, baby. Come on.
Come on.
Shit!
Okay, Ryan.
I need you to stay right here, okay?
Be very quiet
and wait for Mommy to come back, okay?
- You bitch!
- Jeffrey called!
What?
Jeffrey called. He's on his way.
I know why you killed her.
The affair she was having with my husband.
- Where is he?
- This is about getting revenge with Jeffrey.
- Mommy.
Run, Ryan, run!
- Where are you going? Come here.
- Get off of me.
- Excuse me. What's your business?
- I'm sorry, sir. You can't go in there.
- That's my... Terry! Terry!
- Hold up.
Terry.
Baby, I'm sorry.
Listen to me.
It's not what you think.
It didn't mean anything to me.
Baby.
Terry, it didn't mean...
Great. That goes on the first level.
Thanks.
So, it looks like
you'll be right at home in there.
It's perfect.
If you have any questions,
you know how to reach me.
Everything is going to be great.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
Come on, Ryan.
- Are you taking them to the park?
- Yeah.
Great. I'll walk over
on my way to the court house.
Come on, baby.
How do you like the house, bugaboo?