[Thunder Rumbling]
[ Man ] Where you gonna be
10 years from now?
[ Man #2 ] Ten years from now,
where do I wanna be?
I wanna be...just living, man. Just living
comfortably with my wife, you know.
Just layin'back. Just chilling.
You know what I'm saying? Living.
Where do I thi nk I'll be
in 10 years?
I don't think I'll be seeing it, dog, for real,
man. I don't think my luck is that good.
- [ Cheering ]
- I hope it is, but if it ain't, so be it. I'm ready.
# [ Hip-hop ]
[ Biggie Rapping ] # Come on, hah, sicker
than your average poppa #
# Twist cabbage off instinct
Niggas don't think shit stink #
# Pink gators
my Detroit players #
- Puffy! Congratulations!
- # Timbs for my hooligans in Brooklyn #
# Dead right, ifthey head right
Biggie there every night #
# Poppa been smooth
since days of Underoos #
## [ Continues ]
Can't wait for the new al bum, man.
Congratulations.
- [ Camera Shutter Clicks ]
- Yeah!
Yo, Big, let's change the world.
[ Man ]
Let's roll. Let's roll,y'all.
[ Man #2 ]
You needa real man.
## [ Hip-hop On Car Stereo ]
## [ Man Rapping, Indistinct ]
- We back, baby. We back!
- No doubt.
We back on top, baby!
- Yo, what's up, ma?.
- What's up?.
[ Man ] You looking fine.
I'm going to have to getyournumber.
I don't know.
What's up with you?.
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Biggie Narrating] In the beginning...
God gave me a clean slate.
- [ Voices Overlapping, Echoing ]
- [ Baby Crying ]
But where I grew up,
I knew I couldn't stay clean.
Ifyou was a nice, ordinary kid...
you was an easy mark for the wannabe gangsters
and cutthroat girls in the schoolyard.
- You wanna check out this magazine?.
- Right on. Let's go.
Fab 5 Freddy. There we go.
Kurtis Blow, man!
He's the man! You know--
# Clap your hands, everybody
Ifyou got what it takes #
[ Together] # 'Cause I'm Kurtis Blow and I want
you to know that these are the breaks #
# Break it up, break it up
break it up ##
- There we go.
- Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
I know.
Y'all want our autograph?.
We gonna be in a magazine one day.
Chris Shy-ass
can't be in no magazine.
He's too fat, black and ugly.
[ Girls Laughing ]
At least there ain't
no train tracks in my mouth.
What do I tellyou?
Ifyoujustpayattention...
you study hard, always do your best
and lookwhat happens.
A hundred percent!
[ Chuckles ]
- I'm proud ofyou, Chrissy-poo.
- Don't call me that!
Oh, I forgot.
You're all grown-up now, huh?.
[Biggie Narrating] Mymoms was from
a small town inJamaica...
where theyleft
the doors unlocked at night.
But in our neighborhood, the only time
she let me offthe stoop...
was when she walked me
home from school.
[ Woman ] We've seen that 1 2, 1 3 times.
Don'tyou wanna see something different?
[ Biggie Narrating ]
This was Brooklyn. Do-or-die Bed-Stuy.
- And there was just some shit
Moms couldn't protect me from.
- [ Gasps ]
Voletta.
[ Chuckles ]
Christopher, say hello to your father.
You are still beautiful,
Voletta.
If that's what you came for
you can leave right now.
Sugar?.
A hundred dollars.
Is that all he's worth toyou?
Are you even planning on
being in his life?.
- Things are complicated.
- Things?.
I feel like
ifyou and I could just--
It was easy to lie
about yourwife.
Now, when it comes toyour child,
""things"are complicated.
Bye, Voletta.
Hey!
You forgot something.
[ Voletta ]
You're a real piece ofshit.
- [ Footsteps ]
- [ Door Opens ]
## [ Hip-hop ]
- [ DoorSlams ]
- [ Man ] What's up, y'all?.
This is Super Rocking
Mr. Magic holding it down.
- [ Man #2 ] This is DJ Marley Marl.
- Check it out, y'all.
It's all the waylive.
##[ Continues ]
It's time for bed, mister.
He ain't coming back, is he?.
No. I don't believe so.
Good. I'm glad.
Oh.
Come here.
- [ Exhales ]
- [ Sniffles ]
We're gonna be all right,
justyou and me.
- ## [ Hip-hop On Headphones ]
- #You ain't no pops to me #
#You just some nigga
sipping on tea #
# Moms don'twantyour money
so run and flee #
Flee--
# Back all hunched over
'causeyou gotta admit #
# I don't need you in my life
'causeyou ain't shit ##
- ## [ Continues ]
- [ Mumbling ]
[Laughing]
[ Chorus ]# Hey, ho
Hey, ho #
[Biggie Narrating]
Right then and there...
I decided to stop being
that little kid on the stoop.
[ Chorus ] # Hey, ho
Hey, ho #
I wanted to be like
them brothers on the block.
They didn't hold
their heads down for no one.
# Hey, ho
Hey, ho #
I knew life
was a fucked-up game...
and I knew D Roc was fucked up enough
to show me how to play.
- What's up, D Roc?.
- What up, big boy?.
- Your mama finally let you out the house?.
- Told you I would come.
- I ain't on lockdown like that.
- So you ready to be a big baller?.
What I gotta do?.
- ##[ Hip-hop ]
- ##[ Man Rapping]
Remember, just act like
you slapping the nigga five.
# Five, six
One, one, two, two, three #
# Four, four, five, six
One, two, three, four, five #
- The phone is ringing.
- [ Ringing ]
[ Biggie Narrating] Motherfuckers got
addicted to crack after they first hit...
but I got addicted to money
after my first sale.
By the time I was 1 7,,
I wasn't no ordinary kid. I was paid.
[ Voletta ] Christopher, you're not still
lying in that bed, are you?
No.
- [ Door Opens ]
- Christopher, what are you doing?
- ## [ Country On Radio ]
- You sayingyourprayers?
Prayi ng that God teaches you how to knock.
Please. Don't you mock your prayers.
You don't thinkJehovah
has a sense ofhumor?
He must have, if he made you.
[ Laughs ]
We always gotta listen
to this corny old country music?.
I happen to like this music.
They tell good stories.
So, who wereyou yappin'
on the phone with last night?.
-Jan.
- [ Clicks Tongue, Scoffs ]
It's perfectly normal
for a mother to feel jealous...
when her son cares about another female.
Oh, for crying out loud!
By the way, Ma--
- What?.
- How much does a garbage collector make?.
I think about 28,000 a year. Why?.
- No reason.
- Would you hurry up beforeyou
make us both late for class?.
- [Man ] Hey, Voletta.
Is that the new Watchtower?.
- Of course.
We gonna see you this weekend, right?.
# ""W" for Wallace
Rappers are demolished #
- ##[ Hip-hop ]
- # Wax 'em and buff'em like polish #
# Don't I look like the illest thing
you ever saw #
# Live with action
guaranteed raw #
##[ Continues ]
[ Muttering ]
# Rappers are demolished #
#Wax 'em and buff'em
like polish #
Shit!
[ Beeping ]
- [School Bell Rings ]
- You need to add 3X to the other side.
Now,you need to solve the problem forX.
Who wants to come up and do that?
- Come on up, Mr. Wallace.
- [ Students Laughing ]
7X equals 84...
then 1 2 equals X.
Impressive. You're actually
smarter than you look.
- [ Students ] Ooh!
- Mr. Webber.
- Yesterdayyou said
I was gonna end up a garbageman.
- That's right.
Ifyou keep cutting class,
that's exactlywhatyou'll become.
Well, I found out a teacher
makes 24,000 a year...
and a garbageman makes 28,000 a year.
I'm gonna make $4,000 more
than his dumb ass.
- [Students Laughing]
- All right. Get out.
Hey!. Get out ofmyclass.
[ Laughing ]
- [ Chattering]
- Thanks for meeting up.
You know you got it like that.
When my moms see that phone bill,
she gonna kill me.
We gotta chill with all that wild-ass phone sex.
[ Chuckles ]
Um--
I'm pregnant.
I-I went to the doctor
and everything.
We gonna have a baby.
- Damn.
- Damn?.
Is that it?. I was halfway hoping
you was gonna be happy.
But ifthis fucks upyourworld,
then I'm sorry.
Whoa, whoa.
Jan, hold up. Sit down, baby.
What you talking about?.
Sit down.
What's wrong with you?.
Ifyou're carrying my seed,
it means you are myworld.
- You're not sitting there thinking, ""Oh, fuck"?.
- No, I'm not.
- You know I gotyou.
- You got me?.
- No doubt.
- [ Chuckles ]
Come here.
[ Softly]
Oh, fuck.
- [ Chattering]
- [Horn Honks ]
- What up, D Roc?.
- Yo, what up, son?.
You okay?.
Yeah, I'm all right.
Let's get this money then.
[ Biggie Narrating]
Me and D Roc were like factoryworkers...
and Fulton Street
was the assemblyline.
[ Man ]
# Here we go #
[ Biggie Narrating ] But every now and then,
D Roc would say, ""Yo, can I get a rhyme?"
- [ No Audi ble Dialogue ]
- See, drug dealing was like my wife.
Rapping was just some chick on the side.
Before I knew it, word got out
about my skills and shit.
Then this kid named Primo
called me out.
Everyone was jocking him,
'cause he never lost a battle.
It was one thing to rhyme foryour boys,
but it was another to battle.
- ' Bout ti me you stopped runni ng.
- ' Bout time your ass stopped talking shit.
- [ Man ] Yeah. That's Chris.
- Come on, man.
Get out ofhere. Y'all got big--
This what y'all wanna see?. Huh?.
Y'all wanna see me and big boy?.
We got MC quest out here.
That's what-- MC Quest.
Come on, man. Y'all know
who the king ofFulton is.
Hey, deejay, play me something nice, man.
- ## [ Hip-hop ]
- [ Man #2 ] All right. Do it.
I 'm gonna get some barbecue chicken
when I'm done with big boy.
You sure you don't want
no barbecue chicken?.
# Now let me tell you a little story
about the P-P-Preem #
# Preem head bald
like Mr. Clean #
# And Preem be fresh
like Irish Spring #
# And 'round here
I'm raining and reigning king #
# Big Preem
Coming from the borough of Brooks #
# You sweet on the mike
soyourmike get took#
# Playa slowjam track
and I'll smoke that ass #
#Techno track
and I smoke that ass #
# You can't see me
It's likeyou blind#
# I callyou son 'causeyou mine
not 'causeyou shine ##
Man, get this fool out ofhere.
You can't be serious, man.
[ Man ]
Let's do it though, kid.
## [ Song Changes ]
[ Primo ]
Come on. Whatyou got, big boy?
# Bed-Stuy, Brooklyn where this rapper
was originated #
# Yourrhymes ain't shit
Yourflow's constipated#
# Many awaited the heavyset brother
from Fulton Street #
# Drop a rhyme to a funkybeat#
# Niggas wanna know
how I live the mack life #
# Making money
smoking mikes like crack pipes #
# Making loot
knocking boots on the regular #
# Pass the microphone
I'm the perfect competitor #
#Jewels and all that
The clothes is all that #
# Come step it to me
That's whereyou takeyour fall at #
# B.I.G.,just like mymurder #
# It's unheard of
I stay close to mine like Tina on Turner #
#Word to mother
I'm aboveya #
# And I loveya
'causeyou a sweet bitch #
# A crazy crab
that might make my dick itch #
# I flow looser than Luther
You have to get used to B.I.G. is the boss trooper #
# Like ice cream, I'll scoopya
I got it going on #
# Live with action
guaranteed raw #
# For all you bum-ass niggas ##
[ Crowd Cheering,Jeering ]
- Yo, that was hot.
- That's what I'm talking about.
[Man ]
Get him downtown.
[Man #2 ]
Primo. Who the hell is that?
- [ Door Closes ]
- [ Biggie, Softly] Word!
What's up, Mom Dukes?.
So I was by Fulton Records and I thought,
""What would make Slim happy??"'
So I bought you the corniest
country album I could find.
In the last month,
you have missed 20 days of school.
All right. Look.
I tried, Ma.
I missed a few days.
But I went back three weeks straight.
Then three people came to
my class on career day:.
a computer technician,
a store owner, a doctor...
- and they all looked like poor, broke-down niggas.
- You watch your mouth.
I can't see myself going to
school to end up like them...
'cause I got something to do right now.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?.
Jan's pregnant.
I'm gonna be a father.
[Siren, Distant]
[ Exhales ]
Please tell me thatyou are not that stupid.
Whywould you even say
something like that?.
Becauseyou are still a damn boy.
Is this whyyou think
I came to the States--
So I can spend all my days
taking care ofyou, feeding you?.
Cleaning up old plates of mashed potatoes
you leave underyour bed?.
- What?.
- You can't take care ofyourself.
- How areyou gonna take care of a baby?.
- What didyou do with it?
- Where's the plate?.
- I threw it in the trash. It was disgusting.
[ Scoffs, Mutters ]
It's mywork, man.
- What are you doing?.
- Those wasn't no damn mashed potatoes, all right?.
Look at me.
I said, ""Look at me."
Areyou telling me
what I thinkyou're telling me?.
Boy, you gonna end up like those
worthless bums you hang with.
- Don'tyou see that?.
- Bums don't have chains, and boys
don't have money. I'm a man.
You think that makes you a man?.
Get out.
- Ma.
- Get out.
- [ Exhales ]
- [ Door Slams ]
# The fuck is goin'on#
[Biggie Narrating]
I wasn't the man mymoms wanted me to be.
So fuck it. I was gonna be
the man I needed to be.
# When I die, fuck it
I wanna go to hell #
# 'Cause I'm a piece ofshit
It ain't hard to fuckin' tell #
# It don't make sense, goin' to heaven wit'
the goodie-goodies dressed in white #
# I like black Timbs
and black hoodies #
# God will probably have me
on some real strict shit #
- # No sleepin'all day #
- What up, baby?.
- What up, man?.
- Yo! What up, Chris?.
I 'm telling you, Lil' Cee,
the corner ain't no place foryou.
Yo, man. I'm just chilling.
That's all.
Yo, D!
Yo, D. Come here.
- Hell.
- Come here, man. Come here.
Does this look like a Lamaze class toyou?.
Hey, yo, Sandy, takeyour ass home.
- Come on!
- I got this.
#She don't even love me like she did
when I wasyounger #
# Suckin'on her chest
just to stop myfuckin'hunger #
# I wonderifl died
would tears come to her eyes #
# Forgive me for my disrespect
Forgive me for my lies #
-# My baby mother's eight months
Her little sister's two #
- Thanks, black man.
- # I swear to God, I wanna just slit my wrists #
- Yo, D!
- # And end this bullshit #
- Fuck you, man!
I love you too, Sandy.
Yo! You selling crack
to someone who's pregnant.
Fuck a pregnant bitch.
I ain't get in this game to be no social worker.
- #A worthless fuckin'buddha-head#
- [ Knocking]
[ Biggie Narrating] I got tired ofthat
nickel-and-dime shit, so I stepped up my game.
- # I feel like death is fuckin' callin'me #
- [ Door Bolt Clicks ]
- # Nah, you wouldn't understand#
- # Nigga, talk to me, please #
# You see, it's kinda like the crack did
to Pookie in New J ack ##
[ Biggie Narrating ]
I had fouryoung cats out on the streets.
Look atyou, man.
All grown up and shit.
Shut the fuck up and get back by the door.
[ Biggie Narrating ] I wasn't hanging with
my boys, wasn't messing with no chicks.
I was too busy counting paper.
- But I was moving too fucking fast and I slipped up.
- [ Chattering On Police Radio ]
- [ Phone Ri ngs ]
- [ Heart Beating ]
- [ Woman's Voice ]
You have a collect call from--
- [ Heartbeat Slows ]
[ Biggie's Voice ]
Christopher Wallace.
[ Woman's Voice ]
...an inmate at the Wake CountyJail.
- [ Cell DoorCloses ]
- Ma.
[ Voletta ]
Damn you, Christopher.
I fucked up.
I need your help.
No. You gotyourselfinto this mess.
You getyourself out.
I can't askyou to pray for me?.
I never stop praying foryou.
Butyou need to stop wasting God's time
and pray foryourself.
So it's like that?.
It is like that.
- Closeyour eyes, Christopher.
- [ Sniffles ]
Yea, though I walk through
the valley ofthe shadow of death--
[ Together]
I will fear no evil, for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
[Together] Thoupreparest a table before me
in the presence ofmine enemies.
- [ Cell Door Closes ]
- [ Biggie's Voice ] My cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy
will follow me all the days ofmy life.
[ Voletta's Voice ] You gotyourself
into this mess. You getyourselfout.
[ Biggie Narrating ] That was the first time
in my life I thought ifl was dead...
my fucking problems
would go away.
I started rhyming 'cause I was bored.
Plain and simple.
But then my frustrations turned into rhymes,
and those rhymes told my story.
- # The 23 rd Psal m was what
my moms had to offer #
- [ Voice Begins Echoing ]
# No collection plate
to make hard time feel softer #
# I know how it feels
to wake up fucked up #
# Pockets broke as hell
Another rock to sell #
# I got P-A -I-D
That's why my moms hates me #
# She was forced
to kick me out, no doubt #
# Then I figured out nicks
went for 20 down south #
[ Voletta's Voice ]
Christopher, it's a girl.
# I know how it feels
to wake up fucked up #
# Pockets broke as hell
Another rock to sell #
## [ Continues, Voices Overlapping ]
# Baby on the way
Mad bills to pay ##
[ Cell Door Closes ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Welcome home.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh.
- Where is she?.
- Oh. All right. All right.
[ Baby Crying]
[ Baby Fusses ]
Here. Let me take that.
Give me that.
- [ Chuckles ] T'yanna, say hello to your daddy.
- Let me see.
Come on.
- Here.
- [ Fussing ]
No, no, no, no. Like this.
[ Laughs ]
Hmm.
[ Crying ]
Oh.
What's wrong, Ma?.
She ain't that ugly.
[ Laughing ]
Chris!
Mmm.
- Hey, what's going on?.
- Chris?.
You be a great father.
No doubt. No doubt, Ma.
##[Hip-hop ]
[Man ]
Yo, what's up?
[Man #2 ]
Hey. Look who's back, man.
Oh, shoot! Yo, it's Chris, man.
What's up, Chris?.
- What you doing down here, man?.
- I'm chilling. I'm chilling.
Holding niggas down in here, man.
- You know he a pop now, right?.
- Word! Areyou a pop?.
- Yeah.
- Yo, whatyou got, a boy or girl?.
- Little girl.
- Wow. Thank God she look like her mother.
- You know Mister Cee right here.
- What's up, dog?. How areyou?.
Hey,yo, Big. I hopeyou remember
how to smoke one ofthese.
It's what I do, man.
Keep this out your hand.
That's for grown folks, man.
- [ Coughing ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Give me that shit.
- Hey, yo. Now thatyou out, whatyou gonna do?.
[Biggie Narrating] Having a daughter
made me want to be a different kind ofcat.
Got a little shorty I gotta support,
you know what I'm saying?.
[ Biggie Narrating] But not being able to
support her felt like a whole other kind of jail.
- Me and D Roc gonna hold it
down like we always did.
- Hell, yeah.
## [ Hip-hop ]
[ Voices Overlapping, Echoing]
Come on.
Come on. One, two. Yeah.
# The microphone murderer
mass mayhem maker #
# B.I.G. is on the mike
Call the undertaker #
# Make an appointment
and schedule an interview #
# Becauseyou know
what big man's about to do #
# 50 Grandon the Technic
with the right beat#
- # Brothers wanna hear the words #
- Hold up, hold up.
What'd you say at the beginning
ofyour rhyme?. B.I.G.?.
- Biggie Smalls.
- Biggie Smalls, huh?.
- Let's do it again, nigga.
- Hey, yo, son. Your shit got nice.
- For real.
- But,yo, ifyou gonna...
put it down like that,
we gotta record this shit.
- Nigga, don't be gassing me up.
- I'mjust saying.
I know motherfuckers
who know motherfuckers.
- Then pop a tape in, nigga.
- All right, yo.
Let's do this. Let's take it
from the top, Biggie Smalls.
# A whole lot of niggas
want Big to do a demo tape #
- #Yo, 50, what's this #
- ##[Hip-hop]
# Uh, the microphone murderer
mass mayhem maker #
# B.I.G. 's on the mike
Call the undertaker #
# Make an appointment
and schedule an interview #
# Because you know
what big man's about to do #
# 50 Grand on the Technics
with the right beat#
# Brothers wanna hear the word
the big man speak #
#The microphone a-ripping
The burner got the clip in #
# Slamming MC's
like Scottie Pippen #
# Sipping on Old Gold cold
'cause the rhymes were sold #
# Puffing on dime bags
andI've been told#
# Mywords are harder than a brick
Chinese arithmetic #
# A thick stick in my dick #
- # Makes me sick whenyou pick#
- That's it, right there.
#Yourweak rap rhymes, G
I'm kicking and pumping
It's tic-tac time, see #
#The B.I.G. moves swifter
than a ninja #
# Even on stickups
I'm the masked avenger #
# Keep my eyes open
and the case is closed #
# No eyewitnesses
No names are exposed #
# It's the heavyset one with the big gun
and the sweet tongue, taking down everyone #
# Coop like Michael Jackson
Kicks like BoJackson #
# Fuck like FreddyJackson
No need for action #
# My crew, ooh
No fronting, no faking moves #
# Hot into fucking
and even when we stick a move ##
[Man ]
He got sex appeal like LL?
[ Man #2 ]
Yeah, a little bigger than that.
What, like Heavy D?.
He a little darker than that.
- Yo, he look like Wesley Snipes?.
- He ain't Wesley.
- Okay?.
- Yo, bring him in. Bring him in.
Yes, bring him in, please.
This is Biggie Smalls.
You know Mister Cee and, um--
- D Roc. What up?.
- D Roc.
Uh, y'all have a seat.
So my boy said
thatyou was digging the tape.
[Biggie] I knowwhatyou did
forJodeci and MaryJ.
And I got rhymes for days,
know what I'm saying?.
What kind of story
you trying to tell?.
I guess I'm trying to tell a story about a average
nigga from Brooklyn. Know what I'm saying?.
- Nigga gotta figure out that life shit.
- You still hustling?.
Soyou don't get it twisted,
I'm not against making money.
My business is about the streets,
but my business ain't in the streets.
And I can't be building nothing around
no artist that can get locked up anyminute.
I'm saying, ifyou got real paper
coming my way, I'm out the game.
Don't chase the paper.
Chase the dream!
I started offas Andre Harrell's assistant.
Now I'm damn nearrunning this place.
Nigga, I'm hungry! You can throw me butt-naked
in thejungle, and I'll come out with a--
with a chi nchilla coat, a leopard hat
and 1 0 pounds heavier from eating them niggas.
With all due respect, Puff,
dreams ain't paying the bills, G.
His do.
Puffy, I don't know
about a chinchilla...
but ifyou throw me out to the jungle,
I'll have them motherfuckers dancing.
[All Laughing]
Maybe in the right hands,
I could be, like, one ofthe greatest.
Hmm.
- How old areyou?.
- Nineteen.
By the timeyou 21,
I'll makeyou into a millionaire.
We can change theworld, Biggie Smalls.
We can change this game.
Saying theWest Coast--
They got Snoop, they got Dre, they got Cube.
They killing it. The East Coast just waitin'
for somebody to fill that void.
The decision is yours.
You can be the average nigga
from Brooklyn...
oryou can rap about
the average nigga from Brooklyn.
You gotta let me know whether
it's the streets or the studio.
So you in?.
- ##[Salsa ]
- [ CarAlarm Beeping]
What's up, big mama?.
What'd you just call me?.
- ##[ Woman Singing In Spanish ]
- Big mama.
You looking damn good.
How's work today?.
Every dayyou ask me how I'm doing.
What's that about?.
- It's 'cause I care. Know what I'm saying?.
- Yeah, right.
Whateveryou say, big poppa.
You got a smart-ass mouth.
You gonna do something about it?.
I ain't think so.
Hold up.
You wanna get something to eat?.
[ Moans ]
Fuck. Oh, I like it.
Oh, shit, Big.
[ Moaning ] Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Oh, damn. I wantyou
to get on top ofme, Big.
- Mm-mmm.
- Oh.
Oh, it feels sogood, bigpoppa.
[ Grunts ]
Oh. Oh. Oh!
[ Panting ]
- You seein' anybody?.
- [ Laughs ]
Kind oflate to be asking.
[ Exhales ]
Well, I was seeing someone.
He kept thinkin'
we was in a Mike Tyson fight.
Ain't nobody gonna hurtyou no more.
I gotyou, all right?.
Oh, shit.
Wegot Puffout, huh?
Been out here waiting
fory'all asses.
What's up, man?.
- What's up, Big?.
- What's up?.
Andre said there only can be
one lion in the jungle.
The fuckyou talking 'bout?.
I got fired, Big.
So what about my deal?.
You really had my ass goin'.
Just didn't know
itwas all fucking bullshit.
Onlything I got lined up is some--
some college shows.
- It's gonna be a minute
before I get something real.
- [ Scoffs ]
Hey, Big.
Myfather died hustling on these streets
when I was twoyears old.
Ain't no future in this right here.
Just because we got knocked down,
don't mean we can't get back up.
What don't break a nigga
make a nigga.
I thought I hada record deal, and now
I can't even buyfuckin'diapers for T'yanna.
Gotta punch the clock and shit.
- I thought you told Puff
you gonna stop hustling, man.
- I thought I was.
[ Siren Blares ]
- Oh, shit.
- Shit!
- [ Tires Squealing ]
- [D Roc] Yo, toss that! Toss that!
- [ Brakes Squealing ]
- We got another one.
He's heading to Saint Mark's.
There's nowhere to go.
- [ CarDoors Open ]
- Let's do this the easyway, huh?.
- [ Pistols Cocking ]
- Show meyour hands.
Come on, show meyour hands.
You show meyourhands,
I'll put the piece away.
You know, when I was a kid...
you had a switchblade,
brass knuckles, you were a bad dude.
Now you got 1 3-year-olds
looking to shoot the big niggers...
on the corner so they could start
running shit themselves.
I mean, what the fuck
is the world coming to...
when a drug dealer can't
walk the streets at night?.
Tell me, Chris,
what doyou put on first?.
Your socks, yourjacket,
your piece?.
I ain't never saw
that gun before.
- So then it must beyours.
- Nah.
Okay, dumb fucks...
one ofyou is goin' down
for carrying an illegal firearm.
Whichever one it is,
I don't give a shit.
But there's no way that the two ofyou
are walkin' out ofhere.
I giveyou one minute.
- He just trying to make us sweat.
- Yo, we play hardball with him,
he's gonna dust it for prints.
- We'll cross that bridgewhen we get there.
- No, by then it'll be too late.
Look, y-you got priors.
You're looking at five or sixyears, easy.
Ifl plead guilty,
I get three and a day.
- No, D Roc. My gun, my bid.
- No, man. That's bullshit.
Look, this music shit
you got going on--
- It don't come around every fuckin' day.
- [ Clicks Tongue ]
When a motherfucker likeyou
make it, we all make it.
- What ifl don't make it?.
- Listen.
I told you
how to get into the drug game.
Now I'm telling you
how to get the fuck out.
You don't have a record deal?.
Then go out and get one.
Butyou're not going back
on the block.
Not whenyou got the skills
to do something...
and not if I take this bid
foryour ass.
So you're gonna make it.
[ Door Opens ]
So?.
I put my socks on first,
motherfucker.
Okay.
Go ahead. Take a walk.
- [ Handcuffs Unlocking]
- [ Door Opens ]
Big, what's going on?
You good?
Look, Mark,
I 'm gonna be for real about this shit.
This is my motherfucking life,
you feel me?. I got a kid.
I feel like
I'm stuck in the mud, yo.
Tell PuffI'm down
with chasing the dream.
Whatever he want me to do, I'm in.
But this shit gotta jump off now.
I'm gonna tell Puff.
Look, I gotyou.
[Woman ]
Puffwill be rightwith you.
[MonitorPops ]
##[Hip-hop]
#This is going out
to all the pimps and macks #
#Y'all know the flavor, Brooklyn style
You know how we do #
# Is it true
All I wanna do is screw #
# Drink brew with the crew
on the avenue #
# Ooh, I flip skins
like Mary Lou #
# So whatyou gonna do
when she'll come foryou, boo #
# I got girls that
look like Toni Braxton #
# And give me the skins
without aksin' #
#When I'm relaxin' on my back
and you know what time it is, oh #
# But ifit's red, man
I'll leaveyou alone #
# She can call me
on my cellular phone #
# And I'll mess around and pickyou up
takeyou to the crib, stickyou up #
# And put my Silk CD
and lickyou, ooh #
- Yeah, Big. You ready.
- # Hit the twat till your pops call the cops #
# And when I make bail, out ofjail
I'm-a wail on that tail #
# Because sex neverfails
This is going out to the pimps and macks #
- [ Cheering ]
- # This is forthe macks anddons ##
- What up, Howard University?.
- [ All ] What up?.
- Y'all ready for the next performer?.
- [ Cheering ]
All right, coming to you from do-or-die
Bed-Stuy, Biggie Smalls!
- [ Cheering Dies Down ]
- Also known as Notorious B.I.G.
- [ Woman ] Who is that?
- What's up, y'all?. How you feel, Big?.
...Business Instead ofGame.
I need y'all to get loud right now--
- Doyour thing, a'ight?.
- and give it up for Notorious B.I.G.!
[ Cheering]
- A-Yo!
- All right!
[Biggie Narrating] Puffmade a name
forhisselfwhen he went to Howard.
But myname
didn't mean shit to that crowd.
- Yo!
- [ Crowd ] All right!
Hey, Howard. I'm back.
Go get it, big man.
[ Biggie Narrating]
I wanted to do so fuckin'good.
I felt like I owed it to D Roc.
I felt like I owed it to myself.
- [ Pufffy] Welcome to B.I. G.
- [ Cheers, Scattered Boos ]
- Get the fuck out of here.
- Got you, Big. I got you.
- ## [ Hip-hop ]
- All right?.
Where my niggas at?.
- Don't stop. We won't stop.
- Let's go. Let's go.
Stop.
# I was a terror
since the public school era #
# Bathroom passes
cuttin' classes, squeezing asses #
# Smoking blunts was a daily routine since 1 3
A chubby nigga on the scene #
# I used to have the tre-deuce
and the deuce-deuce in my bubblegoose #
# Now I got the MAC in my knapsack
Lounging black #
#Smoking sacks up in acts
with sidekicks #
#With my sidekicks
rocking fly kicks #
# Honeys wanna chat
but all we wanna know #
# Is where the party at
And can I bring my gat #
- # It don't take nothing #
- What up, Pac?.
Vince. How's it going?.
Good to seeyou.
# Dumping out,just me and my crew
'Cause all we gonna do is #
# Bullshit and party
and bullshit and party #
# And bullshit and party #
- # And bullshit and party and bullshit #
- Nextverse.
# Honeys in the back
looking righteous #
# In a tight dress
I think I mightjust #
# Hit 'em with a little Biggie 1 01
how I tote guns #
- What up, Pac?.
- Hey, man.
- You hitting the stage tonight?.
- No. You know, I'm just here
for the recreational activities.
# Smoking, drinking
Got the hooker thinkin' #
# If money smell bad
then that nigga Biggie stinking #
# Niggas start to loke out
A kidgot choked out#
- # Blows were thrown
and a fucking fight broke out #
- [ Record Scratching ]
[ Crowd Shouting ]
[ Chuckling ]
Yeah.
- Yo, chill!
- [ Shouting Continues ]
# Can't we just all get along
So I can put hickeys on your
chest like Little Shawn #
# Getyou pissy drunk off of Dom Prignon
And it's on #
# And I'm gone
That's that party #
#Andbullshit andparty
and bullshit andparty#
# And bullshit and party
and bullshit and party #
- #Andbullshit andparty
and bullshit andparty##
- # Hey ##
- [ Crowd ] All right!
-[ Biggie Narrating] I saw
Tupac about 20 times in J uice.
Now here I was
walking into a party with him.
It was crazy. Females were ready
tojump out their clothes to get at him.
- Yo, man.
- And all the brothers gave him mad respect.
What's up, baby?.
When you starting out, that's the best time.
'Cause as soon as you get on top,
that's when the shit start.
[ Biggie Narrating]
I figured ifit was this good starting out...
then being as large as Pac
must be the shit.
[ Tupac ]
Catchyou later, Big.
You see that fine-ass girl over there?.
[ Sighs ]
Which one?.
Right over there.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Man ]# Before I flip a script
you know I must keepyou dozing#
# I nto the stage of the Buckshot Shorty
Son, pass the boom #
That's my joint.
# Never, ever, ever get played
Kill that #
# Bust a mad cap inyourback
'cause I'm all that#
# Straight from Crooklyn
Betterknown as Brooklyn
Elude the hook and#
- Nice voice.
- # The whole beat's took in #
- Keep going.
- Why?. So you can laugh?.
I ain't gonna laugh at you.
[ Chuckles ]
Least not to your face.
# My mental is criminal
Felony thought subliminal #
# Sinful
quick to trigger pull #
# Grab a pocketful of duckets
So what #
# Fuck it
Don't give a damn
Niggas know who I am #
# See, a bitch like me come
and doyou in your sleep #
#You wake up, shook up
Running scared in the streets #
# Known around town
as the bitch who gets down #
#Till they put me in a cell
or they put me in the ground ##
- That's tight.
- But?.
Dudes want to hear some sexiness
come out a chick's mouth...
not nogangsta shit.
#Yourwhole world changed when you #
Wait. Wait.
Loosen up.
Go on.
#Yourwhole world changed
when you heard me rap #
# Hand on your dick
while my ass you smack#
#Wanna take offmy panties
and put it in the hole #
# But this ain't cheap, nigga
Gots to pay a toll #
# Give a nigga head
and no, I never bite #
#Sexy-ass lyrics
you knowyou kind oflike #
# Mike in my hand
You better understand #
# Lil' Kim be the baddest bitch
in Brooklyn ##
Damn, shorty.
I'm loving that.
- Yeah?.
- Uh-huh.
- What elseyou love?.
- Mmm. I love it when you call me Big Poppa.
- [ Voletta ] I don't understand whatyou're doing.
- [ Biggie] I am being a man.
You're coming in here
all hours ofthe night.
-Jan's calling me.
- Me and Jan ain't even kicking it.
You breaking upwith your daughtertoo?.
You too busy hanging out to go see her.
I'm not hanging out.
I'm working.
And I'm starting to question
what this job really is.
Puff got it all lined up.
- What kind ofman, grown-ass man,
calls himself""Puffy"?.
- [ Snickers ]
That's just absolutely ridiculous.
- Puffy doesn't even have a job himself.
- It's not even like that.
- It's not like what?. It's not like what?.
-Jesus.
- What isn't it like, huh?.
- Excuse me, Ms. Wallace.
Ifl could just explain
why Chris has been late.
Please. I want to hear this.
Yes, ma'am. Uh--
Your son has something special.
And sometimes it's gonna mean late nights
and hard work, but I think it's gonna pay off.
Now, the minute I see him slacking,
I'll be the first to letyou know.
I been talking to Mark
about becoming my manager.
Good.
And ifyou're asking me to hold you
equally responsible, Mark-- believe me, I will.
Yes, ma'am.
- I need to have a word with Chris.
- Yes, ma'am.
[DoorOpens, Closes ]
[ Inhales, Clears Throat ]
My doctor found a lump in my chest.
What?.
My surgery is next week. They need to act
aggressively if I'm gonna have a chance.
""If'?.
- What is that supposed to mean?.
- I want to be up front with you, Christopher.
- No, Ma. No, I don't want to hear all that.
- No, listen.
- I need you to know something.
Christopher! Please!
- I don't want to hear this, Ma.
[DoorOpens, Closes ]
[Mark]
Listen,yo. I got these ideas in myhead.
Like, I've been thinking all night.
I-I can't get--Whoo!
L-Look, look, yo. I've been thinkin'
about my cousin Wayne. He's smart.
I been thinking about bringing him in
to help mewith the management.
I thinkyou'll dig him, Big.
- [Seat Belt Warning Chiming]
- Yo.
Big. Big.
Do you want to talk about it?.
- About what?.
- I mean, whatever's buggin' you, Big.
You haven't said shit
for the past couple days, man.
My moms has breast cancer.
Talkin' gonna fix that?.
[ Sighs, Clicks Tongue ]
[ Whispering ]
Shit.
No. I guess not.
I was only 1 5
when I lost my moms to cancer.
How'd you deal with shit?.
I ain't feel like talking.
[ Chuckles ]
Look, Big, I knowyou goin'
through hard times right now.
Butyou're gonna have to be
a soldier foryour moms.
You gonna have to be there
and support her, man.
I'm gonna pray foryour moms, Big.
[ Breathing Heavily]
- Some ofy'all wrote me off.
- [ Cheering ]
Maybe some ofy'all in this room.
- But what don't break a nigga will make a nigga!
- [Man] Yeah.
- To Bad Boy Records!
- [ All ] To Bad Boy!
[ All Affirming ]
[ Chattering ]
Yo, Puff, can I holler atyou
for a minute?.
Yeah, I wanna talk toyou.
- Yo, howyour moms?.
- Gettin' her strength back.
Shejustgot back from the hospital.
Look, Puff, man, this Bad Boyshit forreal?
Let me show you something.
Yo, I took this here to Clive Davis.
Big on Side One-- Biggie Smalls--
Side Two, Craig Mack.
B.I.G. Mack.
It's the B.I.G. Mack. Feel me?.
What the hell couldhe say?
Just open it.
Welcome to Bad Boy.
[ Groans ]
[ Biggie Narrating]
Doctors got all the cancer out ofher.
My moms was gonna live.
And me? I was finally
gonna change my life.
- # Love got to do #
- # When I 'm rippin' all through your whole crew #
# Strapped like bamboo
but I don't sling guns #
# I got bags offunk
and it's sellin'by the tons #
# Niggas wanna know
how I live the mack life #
# Making money
smoking mikes like crack pipes #
# It's type simple
andplain to maintain #
# Add a little funk to the brain
The funk, baby#
- # I live for the funk#
- # The funk, baby#
# I live for the funk, I'll die for the funk
I'll die for the funk#
- # I live for the funk, I'll die for the funk #
- Fuck around and be hard-core.
# I live for the funk
I'll die for the funk##
That's hot. That's hot.
I love it.
- This could be my first single.
- I want you to hear something.
##[ Stops ]
- ##[ Pop Funk]
- [ Man ]#Juicyfruit#
[ Woman ]
#Juicy#
[ Man ]
#Juicy #
- [ Woman ]# Yeah#
- [Man ]#Juicyfruit#
##[ Woman Vocalizing]
[ Laughing]
- # Candyrain
Comin'down #
- See what I'm saying?.
I'm trying to get niggas out their seat.
This going to be like soul music.
- If I spit this, niggas going to be laughing at me.
- [ Laughing ]
Ifyou spit this, niggas going to be
laughing atyou all the way to the bank, Big.
What's next?. You want me
to dance like MC Hammer?.
Look,yougive me
that street shit forSide B.
But ifl don't have something
I can play on the radio...
nobody'll everhear orbuyyouralbum.
You'll just be a broke-ass, mix-tape rapper.
Trust me, Big.
- [ Exhales ]
- Yo. Puff got a point.
And he's burning a lot ofmoney
in the studio.
- These niggas look like RickJames.
- [ Laughing ]
- Yo.
- I need some time, man.
You gotta do whatyou gotta do.
Yo, come back in, like, an hour or two.
We'll have something ready by then. Puff, I got this.
- All right.
- All day.
Yo, Cease.
I'm gonna need some Pepsi
and some more weed.
- All right, man.
- And some females. Tell them we having a party.
-About time, baby! I'll be right back.
-Let me hear that one more time.
- [Man ]#Juicyfruit#
- [ Woman ]#Juicy#
- [ Chattering, Laughing ]
- [Dice Rattling]
##[ Continues ]
What's up?. That's 500.
Game over, man. Now you mad.
You lost. Loser.
Hey, yo, Big.
Your baby mama on the phone.
Not right now, man.
All right, man. I gotyou.
# You're mysugarthing
Mychocolate star #
Look, Big, haveyou written
some lyrics downyet?
Gotta find some inspiration.
# Butyou're the only one #
# That gives me
good and plenty#
[ Moaning ]
## [ Continues ]
- [Zipper Opens ]
- Yeah?. Yeah?. How that feel?.
[ Mark] You ready to go in the studio, Big?
Puff's on his way over.
- Come on. Wake up. Pull that track up.
- We don't payyou to sleep.
# Live from Bedford-Stuyvesant
the livest one #
# Representing B.K. to the fullest
Gats I pull it #
[ Laughing ] # Bastards ducking
when Big be buckin' #
# Chickenheads be cluckin'
in my bathroom fuckin' #
# It ain't nothing ##
- [ Laughs ]
- Yo, uh, anytimeyou wanna stop playin'.
- Drop the drum.
- ##[Starts ]
# Uh #
# Itwas all a dream
I used to read Word Up magazine #
#Salt-N-Pepa and HeavyD
up in the limousine #
# Hanging pictures on mywall #
# Every Saturday, Rap Attack
Mr. Magic, Marley Marl #
# I let my tape rock
till my tape popped #
# Smoking weed and bamboo
sipping on Private Stock#
# Way back, when I had the red and black
lumberjack with the hat to match #
# Remember Rappin' Duke
Duh-ha, duh-ha #
# You neverthought that hip-hop
would take it this far #
# Now I'm in the limelight
'cause I rhyme tight #
- [ Puffy] That's that money, baby!
- That's fire. That's fire.
# Born sinner
The opposite ofa winner #
- Yo, he ain't write this down?.
- I don't even know.
I mean, I think.
Tell you the truth,
I'm a little fucked up right now.
# I'm blowin' up
likeyou thought I would #
- #Call the crib
Same numbers, same hood#
- Yeah, Big.
# It's all good
Uh #
#Andifyou don't know
nowyou know, nigga##
[ Biggie Narrating]
That shitjust clicked. Pufffygave it that gloss.
The way them snares
hitting them vocals dropped...
he took that track
from 1 00 percent to 200 percent.
They started saying we brought
the funk back to hip-hop.
All I know is,
I was doing what I always did.
[ Man ] Bad Boy Records is
taking over the rap game...
with Craig Mack
burning up the charts.
And now everybody's excited about
the Notorious B.I. G. 's debut album, Ready to Die.
[ Craig Mack ] #Just like uniblab
robotic kickin' flab #
# My flavor be the badder chitter-chatter
Madder than the Mad Hatter #
# I betyou my shit come out fatter
Got the data #
[ Biggie Narrating ] Ifthey didn't know
PuffDaddy and Biggie Smalls before...
they damn sure knew us now.
# The king is what I mean
I mean #
# My man, get a cup
and put some change inside your hand#
# Now hold up
Let's make this official #
# Everybody, let's agree
that M. C. 's need a tissue #
# The funk's my only issue
I betyour mama miss you #
- This is my man, right here.
- # And I bet the Mack take off
like an M.X. missile #
# No more ofyour whinin'
on the charts climbin'#
# As I make the funk
kickin' out harder than a diamond#
# And ifyou didn't know
who's rhymin'#
# I guess I'm gonna say Craig Mack
with perfect timin'#
# You won't be around
nextyear #
- # My rap's too severe, kickin'
mad flava in your ear #
- # Kick his ass #
# Here comes the brand-new
flava in your ear #
# Time for new flava
in your ear #
# I'm kickin'new flava
# Mack's the brand-new
flava in your ear #
# Craig Mack, 1, 000 degrees #
# You'll be on your knees
You'll be burnin', begging please #
# Brother, freeze #
# Deep-booted funk smoke that
leaves your brains booted #
# This bad M. C. with
stamina like BruceJenner #
# The winner
Tasting M. C. 's for dinner #
# You're crazy like that glue
to think thatyou could outdo my one-two #
- # That's sick like the flu #
- # Shake 'em down #
- How y'al I been?.
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
I wanna thank each
and every one ofy'all...
for helping us celebrate
the Ready to Die album. Thankyou.
- [ Cheering ]
- Hip-hop ain't never going to be the same...
because ofthis man right here,
Biggie Smalls!
The Notorious B.I.G.!
You got something to say?.
Brooklyn, we did it!
##[Song Changes ]
Takeyour crown. Takeyour crown.
Have a seat, Big. You're a Brooklyn king.
# Biggie Biggie Biggie Smalls
is the illest#
# Yeah
Biggie Biggie Biggie Smalls is the illest#
# Live from Bedford-Stuyvesant
The livest one #
- # Representing B.K. to
the fullest, gats I pull it #
- I t's a hot party.
# Bastards ducking
when Big be buckin'#
- # Chickenheads be cluckin'
in my bathroom fuckin'#
- B. K. al I day.
# It ain't nothing
They know Big be handlin'#
# With the MA C
in the Ack doorpanelin'#
# Bandagin' MCs
Oxygen they can't breathe #
# Mad tricks up the sleeve
Wear boxers so my dick can breathe ##
- What's up, homey?.
- What's up?.
Yeah. I'm-a be right back.
Hey, hold this.
Don't let them go nowhere.
- [ Biggie ] What's up, homey?
- Congratulations!
We doing it.
- You shining, baby. Congratulations!
- Get my man a bottle.
-[Tupac] No doubt. What's up?
- Yo, how well you know them cats?.
Oh, theyjust helping me
with this movie I'm doing. They cool.
Mmm. Watch the companyyou keep, man.
They got a rep.
So?. Nigga, you got a rep.
So what the fuckyou saying?.
Shit. I'm a bad boy!
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Man ] Yo, Pac, Big.
Can I getyou to say
a couple words for the camera?
Man, fuckyour camera! No, I'm fucking
with you. Come on. [ Laughing ]
Hey, yo, check it out, motherfucker!
I'm Tupac.
I'm chilling here with my homeboy
the Notorious B.I.G. on the scene.
We about to takey'all motherfuckers by storm.
Give them something, Big.
True, that. True, that.
You know, I'm chilling with my man Pac...
who schooled me
to the game and shit.
- Yeah, they know who it is.
- You know what I'm saying?.
Now we about to wreak havoc
on you motherfuckers, man.
You know what I'm saying?.
Chandon sippers.
- Know what I mean?. FrankWhite piece holders.
- Yeah!
- Rolex diamond. You know what it is, nigga.
- Get some. Get some.
We taking your money
and buying your bitches with your money.
- That's right, nigga. You'll see.
- Come get some, motherfucker!
Ifl ain't holdin' my dick,
I'm sleepin' and then you holdin' it, bitch!
- [ Camera ShutterClicks ]
- [Flash Unit Charges ]
I'm wearing this
to my first show coming up.
Whatyou think?.
That ain't bad.
Ain't bad?.
You must be going blind.
I'm trying to makeyou
the Marilyn Monroe ofhip-hop.
That ain't turning no heads.
- So I should lose the suspenders?.
- Keep the suspenders.
Lose the shirt.
- Like this?.
- Mmm.
Like that. Yeah.
- [ Camera Shutter Clicking]
- [ Pufffy] Faith, come on.
Get it going. That's good.
Move, Faith. Yeah, good.
Come on, y'all.
This ain't no funeral.
It ain't even a photo.
It's a mission statement.
Bad Boy ai n't here to be in the game.
Bad Boy here to take over the game.
Everybody, take 1 0 minutes.
[ Biggie Narrating]
Watching Faith, all I could think was, ""Damn!"
She was like some chick
fresh offa movie screen.
My baby. Thank you.
So, why a brother
gotta be left out in the cold?.
You done show everyone
up in here them pictures, except me.
[ Exhales ]
Look, uh, no offense.
I thinkyou're an incredible rapper
and I'm sureyou're a nice guy...
but I don't need all that right now.
All what?.
Whatyou saying?.
You don't need a brother
to makeyou smile?.
Sorry, but I'm not smiling.
Notyet.
All right, fine.
My daughter, Chyna.
- She's beautiful.
- Thankyou.
Just like her mother.
What wereyou doing before
you hooked up with Pufffy?
- Pharmaceuticals. You know how it is.
- Typical.
- [ Clicks Tongue ]
- [ Sighs ]
So, are you a bad guy trying to be good,
or a good guy trying to be bad?.
I'm someone trying to make it.
- How'd you start singing?.
- North Baptist Church choir.
- Typical.
- [ Laughs ]
I wrote a couple joints
for other artists and finally I got my shot.
I don't know what I'd be doing,
but I ain't think I'd be doing this.
When I was a little girl,
everybody told me singing was my destiny...
but I was secretly hoping to make a career
at doing the beat box.
No! Get out ofhere. I knowyou ain't
trying to sayyou know how to beat box.
- You trying to play me out?.
- Let me hear some old-school flavor.
- You gonna rhyme?.
- I'm going to tear it down.
- Shh.
- You shootin' jabs?.
- ## [ Imitating Beat Box ]
- ## [ Vocalizing ]
# Some call me Biggie
or B.I.G. #
# I'm just chilling
in the place to be #
# And I ain't trying to preach
orteach some knowledge #
# I'm just trying to call you
FEW-- Faith Evans Wallace ##
Ta-da!
- [ Laughs ]
- I likeyour laugh. It's sexy.
Why don'tyou let me do that?.
- Do what?.
- Makeyou laugh.
Can I be that man?.
#Oh, oh
Checkit out#
- [ Clamoring ]
- # To all the ladies in the place
with style andgrace #
# Allow me to lace
these lyrical#
Man, you're making all the big niggas
sexy again, brother. All right?.
Yo, Big. Thanks for representing for
the brothers hustling on the corners, man.
Your storytelling is the shit. For real.
I could picture everything you're rapping about.
- Shit is like a fucking movie.
- For real, man.
- Shit.
- What's up, Big?. Can you sign right here for me?.
Right there.
I do all this foryou, baby.
- [ All ] I loveyou, Big Poppa!
- I lovey'all, too.
[Biggie Narrating] We hadbeen
seeing each otherforthree weeks.
But I ain't wanna wait anotherminute.
I n prosperity and adversity.
Prosperity and adversity.
And, forsaking all others,
to always be faithful.
You know me about a month, Big.
Don't say it ifyou're not ready.
And, forsaking all others,
to always be true.
With the powervested in me,
I now pronounceyou husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
##[Hip-hop ]
#You got it goin' on #
##[ Continues ]
Let's get it.
Come on!
# Uh, wha wha #
#You got it goin' on
Wha wha #
- #I used to be scared ofthe dick#
- Is she for real?.
# Now I throw lips to the shit
Handle it like a real bitch #
# Heather Hunter,JanetJacme
Take it in the butt #
- #Yeah, yeah, what, I got-- #
- No! That's not theway I said do it.
Maybe I don't feel like doin' it
yourwack-ass way.
-Look, bitch, stop being so fucking difficult.
-Whoyou calling a bitch, nigga?.
You wasn't talking that shit when you was
eating my pussy the other night.
- Turn that shit off.
- ##[Stops ]
- Areyou out ofyour fucking mind?.
- Areyou out ofyours?.
- Since when doyou start treating me like a ho?
- She's mywife.
And what the fuck am I?.
Someone whose ass I took out
of the fucking department stores.
Ain't that what you wanted?.
You said, ""I got you."
- Shit.
- ""No one's gonna hurt you no more."
Look, this fucking recording studio
ain't big enough for all that personal shit.
What doyou see in her thatyou
don't see in me?. I want to know.
You're my fucking artist.
All right?.
That's all I am toyou, Big?.
Do the fucking song.
- [ Cheering]
- ## [ Hip-hop ]