- Are you okay?
- Yeah, go check on the car.
- Buddy, are you okay?
- Fine. Thanks for asking.
Now get your goddamn hands off me
and open the door.
My Ieg !
It's broken !
Come here.
You know the routine, oId man.
Hands behind your back. WaIk!
My Ieg ! My arm !
- Which is it, your arm or your Ieg?
- Your face.
- Come on, Iet's go.
- Take it easy.
Let 'em aII go. Do it!
Shit!
SteaI the car . . . Go to heII.
Let's go, come on.
I toId you I'd get you out.
BiIIy!
It shouId have been me in jaiI,
not you.
Do you forgive me?
- I forgive you, BiIIy.
- I'm gIad, man.
I couIdn't have that hanging over me
for the rest of my Iife.
BiIIy . . .
- You think that ought to hoId you?
- And some whisky.
I wouIdn't seII meat without whisky.
What are you doing up here?
- Hunting.
- In a suit?
- What kind of hunting?
- Pink fIamingos.
The police have rounded up
12 of the 18 escaped prisoners.
The six unaccounted for are to
be considered armed and dangerous.
You ever see
any pink fIamingos?
No, sir, never have . . .
and never wiII.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, sir.
How much?
- Do we have to go to bed?
- Yes.
Thanks for Ieaving me this mess.
And you didn't make your beds.
Mummy, can we get another dog?
We'II see, honey. Night-night.
- You too, paI.
- Goodnight, Mum.
SIeep weII.
- Who named God ''God''?
- God did.
God named God ''God''? Why didn't
he name himseIf Tom or CharIie?
Can I put some saIt on this?
It's okay.
It's okay, it's aII right.
- That's the dynamite again.
- Yes.
- It's okay. Eat your breakfast.
- Where's the saIt?
- It doesn't need any saIt.
- Come on, just a IittIe.
Did you move the saIt shaker?
I don't beIieve this.
E.T. took it. He did !
He was here. I heard him Iast night.
- E.T.'s make-beIieve, honey.
- He is not. He was here.
- Mookie, stop making things up.
- I'm not!
FROM YOUR BOY
I LOVE YOU, MOOKIE
WORLD'S GREATEST DAD
"WorId's greatest dad."
Sam, it's Billy. l wish l was there
to split all that money with you.
l guess if you're listening
to this, it's all yours now.
You deserve it for being in prison
all that time because of me.
l wonder where l'm headed.
Either way l've got a 50-50 chance
of meeting Elvis.
How did you like the suit?
Lay low and stay out of trouble.
Sam ... l'm glad l knew you.
Come in!
Come in, Lonnie.
I want you to meet Mr. Dunston.
- Lonnie PooIe.
- He'II be organizing security . . . .
. . . and surveying.
- Don't mind me.
- Mr. Dunston knows our situation.
- How are things with Mrs. Anderson?
- I think we'II work it out.
We need her parceI
and the Lewis pIace next to her.
It's 1 20 acres, right in the middIe
of the whoIe deveIopment.
What's your security training,
Mr. Dunston?
- CIeveIand PoIice Department.
- Why did you Ieave?
- Pick a card.
- Take it.
Go on, pick a card.
You got it? Put it back in the deck.
This Anderson woman,
are you fucking her?
None of your damn business!
Who is this guy?
I didn't mean anything by it.
I'm sorry.
- Was that your card?
- No.
I must be sIipping.
Lonnie, why don't you
go back to work?
Good to meet you. Sorry about that.
I'm not too optimistic
about our young friend's success.
Some of these Iandowners
can be hard nuts to crack.
Then we use a hammer.
- That was nice.
- It was.
- Has he come to see you again?
- I don't want to taIk about this.
They're bIasting at the Braemer's.
Turning the whoIe thing into a Iake.
Yeah, my whoIe house shakes.
So what?
These peopIe . . . when they want
something, they can pIay rough.
What are you saying to me?
I Iive here.
- They don't scare me.
- You're something, you know that?
- I'II see you.
- I won't give up my home.
E.T. , is that you?
How come you didn't
throw the baII back?
- Did you come from outer space?
- No.
How come you've got a gun?
Are you a bad guy?
No.
- You Iike boobs?
- Sometimes.
I think they're totaIIy gross.
My name's Mike, but everybody
caIIs me Mookie. What's your name?
Sam.
- See you tomorrow, Sam, okay?
- I may not be here tomorrow.
Don't you know how to start a fire?
You have to Iet the air get in
or it's not going to burn.
- Are you going to cook something?
- A steak.
Let me have it.
I'II cook it for you.
Mookie?
- Do you have to ruin everything?
- I can be here. Don't boss me.
This is my sister Bree. This is Sam.
I'm going to cook him a steak.
- My dad used to Iet me cook.
- You don't remember that.
- You were too IittIe. Mum said.
- I remember.
- Where's your dad now?
- Dead. He had a nurdism.
An aneurysm !
Don't you know anything?
- He's in the cemetery.
- He is not.
- Mookie? Bree?
- We've got to go. Bye, Sam.
- Don't teII anyone you saw me here.
- Why not?
- He doesn't want us to, aII right?
- I want to teII Mum.
- If you do, I'II say you smoke.
- I do not.
Mummy . . . What happened to him?
Get away!
Mum, who are these guys?
Stay down !
You're scaring my chiIdren !
- Get out of the truck!
- Leave them aIone.
Sam!
- Who the heII are you?
- The parking attendant.
Come on.
Stay here.
- Who are you?
- He's my friend. His name is Sam.
Are you just going to Iet him
stand there?
- What are you hunting?
- Dear . . . mostIy.
Dear is out of season.
- Yeah . . . and jack rabbit.
- We've got Iots of rabbits.
- There's no hunting on my property.
- I'm mostIy camping.
I don't aIIow camping, either.
- Who were those men?
- Come on, kids, up to bed.
- Can't we stay up a IittIe whiIe?
- No, Iet's go.
- We didn't say goodnight to Sam.
- Say goodnight and Iet's go.
I'II be right up.
- Where are you from?
- Quebec.
What do you do there?
- What difference does it make?
- It's an innocent question.
I'm a Iawyer.
- Where did you Iearn to fight?
- Law schooI.
- Who are those guys?
- Poachers, I suspect.
Thank you for the coffee.
Goodnight, ma'am.
Wait!
You can sIeep in my barn
for a night or two, if you want.
No, thanks.
- You can hunt here aII you want.
- You don't aIIow hunting.
- I changed my mind.
- You're afraid they'II be back?
- Forget it.
- Wait! How much?
How much for the barn?
- You don't have to pay me.
- Are you sure?
Out of the way!
Bree, I've toId you about that.
You know not to run in front
of the truck. It's not funny.
I'II be right back.
Hi. I thought
you might want to wear these.
- Who the heII are you?
- A friend of CIydie's.
- What's your name?
- Sam.
- Have you got some I . D.?
- Sure.
- Lonnie?
- I'm naked.
- It doesn't bother me. Who's this?
- What are you doing?
He's my cousin . . . from Quebec.
- He toId me he was your friend.
- My third cousin.
What's wrong? This is ridicuIous.
Put the gun down.
Sorry.
Can I taIk to you a second?
- Do you want some more?
- Yeah . . . thanks.
Can you pass the salt?
The oId bike in the barn . . .
I wouId Iike to buy it.
- How much wiII you pay for it?
- I don't know. 200?
- 300 . . . take it or Ieave it.
- I'II take it.
- Are you going to go away on it?
- I'II have to fix it first.
It's too broken to be fixed.
He's got a big penis.
- He does!
- He was in the pond washing.
He's got an average penis.
I saw it.
- AIready?
- That's enought about penises.
- Are you going to sIeep in her bed?
- That's enough.
No one's going to sIeep in my bed
except me.
Did you change your mind?
You want to heIp me?
It's a damn good offer.
No one eIse wouId offer you that.
I won't seII it to anyone eIse.
I don't want to seII it.
Mrs. Anderson,
I know your financiaI situation.
This might be indeIicate, but you
might not make your payments.
If you can't, the bank
wiII be forced to forecIose.
You bought into the bank.
They never used to do that.
It wiII take a month
to get the order to forecIose.
She'd get a Iawyer.
He wouId fiIe a writ.
That wouId deIay you months.
You wouId have to go to triaI.
If you don't want to seII it,
don't seII it.
- Forgive me . . . Who are you?
- My cousin Sam.
FrankIin HaIe.
I'm deIighted to meet you.
Thank you, Mrs. Anderson.
GentIemen, shaII we?
Astonishing, isn't it?
One IittIe woman in a wheat fieId,
and what is she doing?
She's fucking us up.
My proposed deveIopment
is one of the Iargest of its kind.
It represents a totaI investment
in your community of $1 biIIion.
What we're taIking about here
is naturaI beauty.
I must teII you,
this vaIIey of yours . . .
It's one of the most extraordinariIy
beautifuI pIaces I've ever seen.
My company wouId never dream
of desecrating such beauty.
But this town's Iand can be used
so much more efficientIy.
Everyone wouId benefit.
I'II guarantee you . . .
You aII shouId be ashamed !
SeIIing off your famiIy heritage.
BuiId your goIf course around me.
I'm not seIIing !
Let him speak.
He has the right to speak.
My dear sir, there's bound to be
opposition to a pIan Iike this.
But your eIected counciI peopIe
understand the wisdom of our ideas.
I don't care. I know about
the tactics you've been using.
- Nobody takes my Iand from me!
- It's okay, Tom.
- They can't make us seII.
- Are you sure about that, CIydie?
Let's go, honey.
Sam! Something's wrong! Wake up!
It's our neighbour's barn.
Wake up your mum.
Say to caII the fire department.
- Are you okay?
- My husband's in there.
- Stay back!
- PIease, heIp him !
Let me heIp.
Get that one.
The gas tanks! They're going to go!
Move back!
- God !
- The tanks are going to bIow.
Get back.
FLAMMABLE
Look, it's going to be aII right.
- Did you get burned?
- No. I was Iucky.
Sam, are you going to go home now?
- Are you going to stay?
- For a whiIe.
You're going home sometime,
aren't you?
I reaIIy don't remember my dad . . .
not Iike I say I do.
It's okay.
You did good
in discovering the fire.
- I wasn't scared.
- I know.
Goodnight.
I've been out here on my own
ever since my husband died.
I aIways thought I couId handIe
whatever came up.
Why am I teIIing you this?
I don't even know you.
Sam . . .
- Is that your reaI name?
- Yes.
Sometimes you just get tired.
I'II be okay tomorrow. Things
wiII be better in the morning.
- What's this stuff for?
- That's for the brakes.
- What about this?
- That's gasket seaIer.
- What kind of a car have you got?
- It's a motorcycIe.
- A what?
- A motorcycIe.
You're not from around here,
are you?
- Neither are you.
- That's right.
You're that Canadian guy who
puIIed Tom Lewis out of his barn.
- You're him.
- He saved aII the horses, too.
You did? Wow! That must
have reaIIy been something.
- What kind?
- What?
What kind of motorcycIe
are you working on?
A Triumph.
They don't make 'em
Iike that any more, do they?
No, they don't.
Let's go.
See you.
Good Iuck with the motorcycIe.
- CouId I Iearn to drive this thing?
- I can show you right now.
I don't reaIIy want to know.
Just as you know what you're doing.
- Don't get caught.
- I thought the Iaw was bought.
- He was paid, but I'm not sure.
- It's not for you to worry about.
- Who's worrying?
- Good.
- Is that your card?
- Yeah. How did you do that?
Magic.
- Mummy, is that your wedding?
- Yep.
Come on in.
Do you want some coffee?
Sam, that's my dad.
Come on, Iook at him.
- Why is Daddy carrying you?
- That's what the groom does.
He carries his wife off so they
can start their new Iife together.
- That's me!
- So IittIe.
I bet he was a good kisser.
Yes, he was.
It's very beautifuI here.
It's the vaIIey of the Moon.
That's what we caIIed it.
Can you smeII the vioIets?
There's no prettier smeII on earth
than the smeII of vioIets.
You're not used to aII this.
- You're not married, are you?
- I used to be.
A Iong time ago.
You miss your husband, don't you?
Yes . . . there are days
when I miss him very much.
WouId you Iike to sIeep
in my room tonight?
You're a very speciaI woman.
I'II see you tomorrow.
- It's Iate, Lonnie.
- No Iater than it usuaIIy is.
- What's the matter?
- I just don't feeI Iike it.
Are the kids up?
What's the matter?
- Are you upset about the barn?
- It's nothing to do with the barn.
Then what's it about?
You have to Iet me know!
She won't be growing much here now.
Son of a . . !
Strike three. You're out.
This is business, Mr. Dunston.
These things can be compIicated.
If I don't have her Iand by the end
of the week, I Iose my permits.
If I Iose my permits,
I'm out of business.
If you and your pissant army
can't persuade this woman to seII, -
- I may have to find
somebody who can.
- What did you find out about him?
- I know he's not her cousin.
Good, Lonnie.
I don't care who he isn't.
This asshoIe is reaIIy bothering me.
I'm going to go out there and
persuade him not to stick around.
Listen, as a personaI favour,
give me first crack at him.
ReaIIy?
Fine.
- CIydie's not here.
- I know that.
- I never saw your identification.
- I thought we'd been through this.
Put your hands up against
the barn door. Move!
Spread 'em !
- Are you arresting me?
- Maybe.
- What for?
- I haven't decided yet.
Why don't you just Ieave her aIone?
You're fucking it aII up!
For everybody's sake, just Ieave.
If you cared for her,
you wouId not be doing this.
Sam?
What happened?
Does this have anything to do
with what happened Iast night?
- Who did this to you?
- It was personaI.
Why do you do that?
Why don't you taIk to me?
Who are you?
- Do you want me to go?
- Yes!
No.
I don't know.
I don't know what I want.
And I don't know what I'm doing.
- Hi, honey, where's your sister?
- She's pIaying. Where's Sam?
- He's stiII asIeep.
- He's not in the barn.
- He stayed in my room.
- AII night?
- AII right! Can I go see him?
- Let him sIeep a few more hours.
A few more hours?
What did you do to him?
Does this IittIe girI beIong to you?
- Bree, what were you doing?
- He wanted to pIay with me.
He can puII a magic card
out from my ear.
- She was out running around.
- Do I know you?
Go inside.
Bye.
I'm surprised to see
that you're stiII here.
- No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
If I see you near her
or the chiIdren, I'II kiII you.
You seem Iike a smart feIIa.
The woman isn't worth it.
When push comes to shove, you won't
be deaIing with the sheriff . . .
You'II be deaIing with me.
I'II Iook forward to it.
Me, too.
- Au revoir.
- Yeah, for now.
The FBI just Ieft my office.
- What do you want?
- I know who you are.
I'II do everybody a favour.
Leave . . . do it right now.
- I won't be abIe to heIp you.
- What about CIydie and this pIace?
You're making it worse for her
than it was ever supposed to be.
If you care for her, you'II go.
Jesus!
I was a thief. There was a bank,
and a guard got shot.
- So you're a murderer.
- No.
A boy, BiIIy . . . I took him with me
on a coupIe of jobs.
The guard was going to shoot me.
BiIIy shot him, but I was taken.
Damn you ! You had no right
to come into our Iives!
- You have to go.
- You're going to Iose this pIace.
No, I am not.
I can take care of myseIf.
I was doing just fine
before you came here.
I've been aIone a Iong time.
So have I.
Clydie, l thought it might be
easier talking to you on tape.
But now l'm not so sure ...
This is exceIIent, Lonnie!
Why did you Iet him go? You'd be
famous now if you'd coIIared him.
Now isn't the perfect time to have
the pIace crawIing with state cops.
- Quite right.
- Lonnie, you're aIways thinking.
It shouIdn't be difficuIt to break
Mrs. Anderson's resistance now.
- I'II work on that right away.
- Thank you, Lonnie.
I don't care if he's Ieft town,
I stiII think he's dangerous.
Me, too.
I think we shouId take
personaI charge of the situation.
- Hey, Pete. What's new with you?
- Nothing.
HeIIo . . . Excuse me.
Does that bike parked out front
beIong to you?
- Did you restore it yourseIf?
- It just needed a IittIe work.
- Where are you from?
- Quebec.
- Did you drive it here from Canada?
- Yeah.
- You must be a good mechanic.
- Coffee?
Do you want anything to eat?
Today's speciaI is meatIoaf.
Or you can have
the rest of that guy's steak.
Mookie?
Clydie, l thought it might be
easier talking to you on tape ...
But now l'm not so sure.
l can never change what l did,
no matter how much l regret it.
Mookie will hear things about me.
Most of them won't be true.
Please say goodbye to him for me.
l never meant for anyone
to get hurt ... especially him.
Son of a bitch!
Get a chopper up here!
- What are you doing?
- Just Iocking up.
- We never Iock up.
- WeII, we're going to start.
Mummy, are you scared of something.
I'm just being cautious,
that's different from being scared.
CIydie.
Kentucky Avenue.
- Who has that?
- Nobody.
A six. Where am I?
- Run !
- Go get the kids.
What do you want?
Jack, use the stairs.
- Bree, upstairs.
- Open the door, kid.
- I'II go get some heIp.
- You'II faII.
I've done it before.
- Mum !
- Bree.
- The boy went out of the window.
- PIease, don't hurt my chiIdren.
CIydie?
- What's the matter?
- Lonnie!
Go find the other kid.
I'm over here, jerk.
Come on out, kid.
Come on, son.
I wouIdn't hurt you.
- Sam?
- Stay here.
I'm going to kiII
that IittIe son of a bitch.
No more threats. No more buIIshit.
You know what we're here for.
I'm not going to hurt her.
You stay in there, and no noise!
I'm sick of this town !
I want to go home.
Now, sign the fucking contract!
Here's a pen.
- I'm sorry it had to come to this.
- Right here.
- very good.
- Go to heII.
Get out now!
- This is my house!
- We can't Ieave before the fire.
- I can't take the risk.
- AI, if you wiII.
Watch her.
Where is he?
Get up!
Sam!
Leave him aIone.
- Sam.
- Are you okay?
Just stay behind me.
Au revoir, fucker!
- CIydie!
- Sam !
- Don't come any cIoser.
- Let her go.
Don't even think of it.
Throw the gun down !
Throw the gun down now!
Throw the gun down.
- Bree.
- Mum !
- Put your hands over your head.
- I own haIf this vaIIey.
- There's an escaped convict inside.
- Turn around and face the house.
Go! You can stiII get away.
Sam GiIIen ! The house is surrounded.
Come out with your hands up.
Why do they want you?
You didn't do anything wrong.
A Iong time ago, I did some things
I was not supposed to do.
- WiII they take you to jaiI?
- Yes.
- I don't want you to go.
- I've got to go.
Goodbye, Mookie.
Goodbye, Bree.
Are you coming back?
I'II find a way. Somehow I'II find
a way to come back to you.
No matter how Iong it takes,
we'II be here.
I know.
- I Iove you.
- I Iove you, too.
You saved a Iot of Iives here.
That ought to count for something.
Goodbye, my friend.
Goodbye, Sam.
Go.
You bastard !
Do you know who I am?
I know what you are.