Translation: Jacques Hooi
Synchronization: gligac & Sherpe
Yeah.
Shit.
Where is he?
Gotta go.
What's the latest?
Nothing, they say the first
24 hours (?)...
Did she understand?
It's not their fight.
Where are Tess and Isabel?
Any change?
He's in critical condition,
but he's still alive.
- You know, if he doesn't...
- Is Stan there?
- Yeah, he's been there an hour.
- Stan'll us what's going on.
(?) cardio(?) infarction.
He's endured an incredible shock
to his system.
- Can he recover?
- Yes.
Will he recover?
It helps if they have
something to live for.
Family.
Friends then.
Maybe that'll be enough.
Reuben, when it comes
to Willie Bank
you can't rely on contracts.
My lawyers say...
the ironclad.
Gimme some credit for
my business (?).
But you'll still think it's a good idea
neither does Rusty?
Well, I'm doing it.
It's done.
And you tell Rusty that
I won't have to pull jobs...
to keep my hotel
solvent.
Hey, Reuben...
You fellows are young.
You don't understand.
Did you know that the Inuit people...
put their elders out on a ice foe to die...
when they're too
old to hunt?
- Thanks.
- That's just a myth.
Well that ain't gonna happen to me.
I can still hunt.
This is it.
It's my chance.
I used to mean something in this town.
I would walk into a restaurant...
if it was full, they'd snap out
a new table for me...
like that.
Listen Reuben, if you're worried
about your place in history...
then let us get a street named after you...
or a boulevard.
We can talk about that
when I'm dead.
Danny, I appreciate you coming
this far to see me...
but I gotta do this.
Reuben!
- Partner!
- Reuben!
So good of you to come.
Of course. Of course. I get
more items for my punch list...
I got so much energy, I can...
hardly sleep from the excitement.
Where are you at on the visas for the chefs?
My man in Washington says...
they'll be stamped
by the time we open.
- No, no, no, not good enough.
- That's what I said.
That's good.
And the chandeliers?
My ex-wife's new brother-in-law...
You don't need the details.
It's done.
Half priced.
They're already at the warehouse.
And because I know it mattered to you...
I appeared before the
City Council.
The one-way street leading
away...
from the rear entrance, now...
leads toward the rear entrance.
All roads lead to the "Midas".
This is perfect.
Great views up here.
Where's the partner's desk gonna be?
No partner's desk.
- Two desks.
- No two desks, one desk.
One chairman's desk.
One.
The arrangement is changing.
Was changed.
As a matter of fact there is no arrangement.
Everybody said that you would
try to screw me.
But you've done it to everyone
of your partners.
But I defended you.
I said:
No, me and Willie Bank
been around long enough...
that we both shook Sinatra's hand.
And there's a code amongst guys
that shook Sinatra's hand.
Screw Sinatra's hand.
- Screw?
- You're deadweight.
Do you think I'm gonna carry you
and pay you at the same time?
Reuben...
you're out.
Never.
This is my (?).
Was. Was your (?).
- You signed it over to the corporation.
- For 50% interest.
Which I'm gonna ask you
to sign over to me.
For a small cash payment.
- I'm not signing that.
- Yes.
Get outta here.
I'm not signing that.
What are you gonna do?
Throw me of the roof?
No, I don't want to.
This is wrong. This is all wrong.
You're leaving me with nothing.
You know you're right.
And it's rude.
Here.
It's the first badge.
Just got made.
You changed the name.
I like it better.
Don't you?
Reuben...
he always was too
trusted.
Is Saul.
Is.
Of course.
He tried talking him out
of it next time.
Look,
Bank hurt Reuben...
I know how that makes
me feel.
- I know what that makes me wanna do.
- Well, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna get close to Bank
and I don't care if it gets messy.
I'll drive you...
and get him leaving his barber.
Good, then I'll inject him.
Yeah and I'll find a spot
to get rid of the body.
All valid ideas.
Great initiative.
But...
Even though Bank stepped
over the line...
we have to do what's best
for Reuben.
Which means
we offer Bank...
a "Billy Martin".
Wait a minute? And then what,
he goes for it? And that's it, he gets off?
- That's the rule.
- No, that's the rules...
for someone who understands the rules.
which Bank don't,
because he already broke them.
So he don't get the chance.
For Reuben...
I think we give him a chance.
I need answers before
I ask questions.
You get that?
Allright. Do it!
So...
some guys I take
seriously...
tell me you're a serious guy.
Right.
What I want...
what's most important to be is that Reuben
gets his share of the hotel restored.
I'm here to give you a chance
to do that.
You're gonna give me a chance?
Okay.
It's a Billy Martin?
I pass.
Last time I looked
and I look every morning...
it was my name listed as owner
on more valuable property...
in this state than anyone else
in history.
Which means you gotta
lot more to lose.
Well I don't lose.
People who bet on me
to lose, lose...
and they lose big.
You come at me
you better know...
I move quick
and when i do...
I slice...
like a goddamn hammer.
So you're not gonna make Rueben (?)?
If Reuben was too weak
or too stupid...
to see what was coming down...
then you know what?
He didn't belong here.
He's made the right choice:
roll over and die.
Let him be.
How long do I have to
wait for a conduit?
I don't want the labor pains
I just want the baby.
Six months later.
Well...
thanks for coming.
Thanks for the 100 Grant.
This takes longer than
a day though.
Gonna have to re-negociate.
That's fair.
I'd like some Sen Cha
or Genmaicha.
Green tea.
Yes, sir.
And don't burn it.
Pour it just before boiling point...
- not after.
- Green Tea. Si signore.
Graci.
Just us three?
- For now...
- Figured we talk to you first..
Good lord.
How stuck I am?
Stuck.
Stalled really.
Run it from me.
Don't leave anything out.
Give me the big picture.
- You wanna?
- It's all yours.
- Where shall we start?
- Start with the hotel.
Bank really put (?)
on this one.
Forget weekenders
and conventioneers.
He's built this place for the whales.
The (?)
of a Five Diamond Award.
The marble was handpicked in Italy...
and the chefs stolen from the highest
rated restaurants on the Michelin guidebook.
In the villas (?)
big players
the silverwear is
actually gold.
Bank's greatest strength
is also his weakness.
Ego.
He's been spending his days checking
and rechecking every inch of the property...
getting(?) ready for the grand
opening celebration.
It's a compulsion.
Bank's right-hand man
is a woman.
Abigail Sponder.
We're gonna have to let you go.
Turn in your uniform.
I only gained 4 pounds.
You can't.
Yeah, well your bodymass index
is not what it supossed to be.
- But miss Sponder...
- Oh no, babydoll,
it's your butt that's the problem.
You can't find a waitress
based on appearance, man.
That's just unconstitutional.
If they were waitresses.
Yeah, they're actually hired
as models who serve.
So that Bank can monitor their
physical appearance.
It's a cruel cruel practice.
So between Bank and Sponder
they got the place covered.
- When is opening night?
- July the 3th.
Got fireworks the stroke of midnight
the whole charade.
Are we going in now?
It's already open.
No, it's a soft opening.
To test the place
before the grand opening.
Yeah it's kinda like a out of town
preview...
on the (?) town.
Soft opening? Grand opening?
When they opened the Flamingo...
one day it was closed
the next day it was open.
End of story.
I know, I was there.
Well it's different now.
So when is opening night?
July the 3th.
Now the top casinos can clear
3 million dollars a day...
just on the floor.
Bank with his high level players...
and no limits is projecting 5.
Upon exchange for the loans
he had to give up...
six of the nine seats
on the board.
So he doesn't control his own company. And
a couple of the guys he brought in aren't friendly.
So he has to clear 500 million
in the first quarter...
or he gets dumped out of
his own hotel.
(?) Bank wants another
Five Diamond Award (?).
Every hotel I ever (?)...
has one: a Royal Review
Five Diamond Award.
The Cigarou Inn:
five diamonds.
The Peloponnesian Monte Carlo:
The Grand Saphir, Singapore:
cinco diamantes.
Atomano Crest, Tahiti...
I never not won one.
So, how are you gonne get the diamonds?
- We're not.
- We thought about it for a minute...
- Then we decided... It was...
- Impossible.
(?) (?) (?)
- Tell him about Debbie.
- Yeah, tell him about Debbie.
Debbie is a concierge at the Bank.
She's very ambitious.
In a good way...
for us.
As soon as I said the words:
general manager and a (?)...
she was in.
I put a cherry on top
to make sure.
We found out who'd be
reviewing the hotel.
We're gonna get to him
before Bank can.
I feel bad.
Like torture.
This is war, kid.
There's gonna be collateral damage.
Iar restul se va întâmpla
at the airport.
- No, he doesn't know that.
- So what?
He has to know why you won?
You enjoy it? Who says?
Alright so you go through that
for 10 milion?
No. I do it for eleven mille.
Now, we found out
Bank is tapped into
the federal fingerprint
database.
Highly illegal.
We came up with a way
to piggyback his system...
in between
firewall checks.
Very interesting stuff out there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, what else?
We're gonna get his whales.
How?
He talked to Denny Shields.
Denny Shields?
After he bragged about you guys
into (?) talking about how (?)?
We need him.
I should have kept my mouth shut.
And then I saw that guy walking around.
I didn't know who he was.
And I... Just some guy to me.
- And I guess I pissed him off.
- Denny, look...
you know what you gotta know who he was.
Just forget it. Let it go.
The other stuff I got taken
care of...
is all straight.
I got 18 whales,
I spoke to their handlers,
I spoke to their managers,
I spoke to their assistants.
Everyone of them is gonna (?).
We're gonna do it in two (?).
I'm gonna leave first
they're gonna follow.
- Okay.
But you gotta make sure they win
because these guys usually lose.
- And when they lose, they get (?).
- They're gonna win big.
- How big?
- 500.
- One million.
- That night, just the (?)?
No, it's a reverse
Big Store.
Right...
- Doesn't matter if we win...
- As long as the casino loses, yes...
That could actually work.
So you need to (?)...
Craps, Black Jack,
roulette, slots.
This polymer reacts to
ultrasonic pulses...
but it's not metallic, so the compasses
on the table won't detect it...
and it don't effect the way
(?) mark the dice.
Now this...
(?) lighter?
The dice are controlled from the
manufacturer all the way to the floor.
Which is why we went
all the way to the manufacturer.
Could the climat control be switched on?
The climat control? You're crazy.
Cred cã va trebui sã...
ªtii ceva?
E periculos.
Pune-þi înapoi masca.
Periculos, e cel de-al
doilea nume al meu.
That's not your problem.
So you're jammed on
Black Jack.
We've embedded Livingston in
the Shuffle Company.
Now the tap will stimulate your EKG
much in the same way a lie would.
But you have to step on it
during the control questions.
Your name, birth date, so on.
So those levels will match the stress level
with your false answers.
I got it.
How much is this gonna hurt?
If you're doing it right,
it should be pretty excruciating.
Is your birth date February 11, 1965?
Yes.
Are you wearing a white shirt?
Have you ever been involved in
the commission of a crime?
Oh, no.
Have you ever defrauded or attempted
to defraud the gaming industry?
No.
- Alex...
- Solid.
I love technology.
- I guess to look at you I'd swear
you would be evasive... - But?
the machine says you're clean.
I'm just a little nervous.
I really want this job.
You can relax now.
Welcome to Shuffle Royal.
The Shuffle Royal.
Well I doubt I've heard the last of that one.
So if Black Jack is
not your problem...
it must be slots.
Progressors(?) run of computer
chips now.
You're gonna have to program in a trapdoor.
I can probably find you
someone to do that.
Thanks Roman, we got somebody in
on the inside.
A great kid
named Eugene.
Who's got a little
too much downtime.
He's run up a nice little online gaming tap.
He won't be able to keep
it a secret much longer.
Now I have no...
Uh yeah, it's crazed.
How bad is it?
Uh, it's bad...
I-I owe 30.000 dollars.
- So it may as well be a 100.
- Alright.
Let's call it a 100.
Thanks Danny.
Eugene. My pleasure.
Now tell me how you're
gonna program that trapdoor.
So if that's not the problem,
it must be roulette.
(?) is in for a scanner
on the shoe...
wired to a microcomputer
somewhere on your person.
It figures the probability where
the wheels will end within 3 digits.
Yeah, we-we tried that.
No offense, the way he
was dressed, didn't help.
Not very subtle, this guy.
- So you're stuck on roulette?
- No.
We're going lo-fi we think we can
get some loaded balls in there.
Kidding?
How are you gonna deliver?
Two stages.
First we position a man of our own.
There's a gaming Expo the day
of the grand opening...
which Bank is committed to attend.
To show what a regular
guy he is.
Frank's suiting up as The Game.
The men who make the decisions
are very very hard to impress.
That's why I'm asking each and
every one of you to help me so...
by being the most classy, gentile...
ladies.
The image that we're looking for...
are tasteful elegance.
What exactly do you want us to do?
Raise your skirts up about 3 inches.
Second part.
We tie Frank to one of theirs.
A pit boss with sticky fingers.
How much for these?
Is Willie Bank know
you're stealing his gold flatware, Neil?
How do you know my name?
Well we know a lotta names.
Your wife, Mary...
your kids, Leanne and Dolly.
We know that you are
the pit boss at the casino.
You don't wanna...
- I mean, I don't...
- We don't wanna hurt you.
We wanna help you.
We wanna double your salary.
All in one night.
What do you need me to do?
Right now, nothing. Go home,
do your job.
And at the appropriate moment
somebody'll present himself to you.
- Enough said?
- Enough said.
Who is the shill at the Expo
to rope Bank?
- We're still looking.
- We'll find someone.
Make sure it's somebody
he really despises.
Back to macro.
What is your exit strategy?
The players won't be on the scam...
so they'll all think
it's their lucky night.
But you never get them out of
the door with all their winnings...
they'll dump it all back.
That's Vegas
and that's your problem.
Well the exit strategy is A problem...
it's not THE problem.
The problem is security.
We're drawing a blank.
It's a little spooky.
(?) aren't on the grey market,
the black market...
or any other market.
And all I keep hearing, is there's
never been a system like this.
Now I've found out where they designed it,
but I can't even get in the building.
I've blown all my buy money,
my bribe money...
4 of my best ideas and
I am nowhere.
But not only I'm nowhere,
I'm pretty sure I'm being followed.
Do you have anything?
Yeah, I think I have a name,
but I don't even know if it's right.
- They're calling it...
- The Greco.
The Greco Player Tracker.
They've put it in Vegas.
- Well I give you back the 100 Grant.
- Why?
Danny,
I like you.
And you, Rusty.
I mean you got style.
You're brillant, got loyalty.
You two are (?), but...
even they went off to blow.
You're analogue players
in a digital world.
You're done.
Believe me, I would love to
go up against Greco...
and crush him.
But it can't be beaten.
It can't be hacked...
and it can't be beaten.
Not even by you?
Oh with 18 months...
nothing else on my plate
no other jobs, no women or distractions...
maybe.
- You know everything about this thing.
- Everything.
Except where it was being
deployed.
The inventor is an old schoolmate of mine.
His name is Greco Montgomery
The pompous ass named
it after himself.
Greco?
Roman?
Yeah, you've obviously never served
time in a Britsh boarding school.
So what's so tough about this thing?
It's an artificial intelligence
security system.
He must be field-testing.
You mean it has a brain?
A hell of a brain.
It doesn't only think...
it reasons.
(?) every permutation in every weight
in every seat in the entire casino.
Hand by hand.
That's why this
security cameras
that measure pupil dilation.
And determine if a win
is legitimate or expected.
It gathers biofeedback...
player's hartrates,
body temperatures...
it measures on a second by
second basis...
whether the standard variations
of gaming(?) algorithm...
are holding...
or are being manipulated.
The data is analyzed in real-time...
in a field of exabytes.
Exabytes?
- You know what a terabyte is?
- Yeah. It's a...
- An exabyte is a million terabytes.
- Right.
MacGreco is housed
in an impregnable room.
Shock mounted...
temperature controlled and it locks down
if it even sensors it is under attack.
If it locks down, there wouldn't
even be able to get out of the room.
Couldn't we just shut it off?
You know, cut the wires?
That could work.
Better still you'd just kick
the plug out of the socket.
- Seriously.
- No, short of walking into that room...
with a bloody magnetron around your neck.
You know what a magnetron is?
Something that screws up the Greco.
Aha...
short of that.
I'm kinda shocked this is
where we are, because...
- This is a problem.
- That's what I said.
But if we could somehow...
No there is no if...
It can not be shut off.
I mean you'd need a real natural
disaster an actual act of God.
- But if we could...
- You can't.
- But if we did?
You could.
Don't flatter.
If we could, how long
would it take to reboot?
Because it's so sophisticated
3,5 minutes.
Would be enough.
Pick a natural disaster.
Get me a laptop.
Now the drill access is through
a sewer main of Paris Drive.
Grind along here into the
northwest corner of the hotel.
Here.
Probably about 6,00 Rpm
so you won't wake all the neighbors.
When it reaches the resident's frequency...
the building acts like a tuning fork.
To the people inside it will
feel like an earthquake.
That should knock out
the Greco.
And that's your exit strategy.
- Hey Bash?
- I'm up here.
- Hey!
- Here you go.
Hey, where the mags?
- Linus...
- I can't find those things.
I need them.
I can't leave.
- Why are you such a...
- I'm sorry...
ask somebody else.
- Ask Livingston.
- You're such a wowser.
Look, read this to Reuben.
I've done research. Positive
messages get through.
I can't say this.
No, no I'm saying it.
You're just a vessel.
Come on Basher, look,
why don't you take a break?
I'll watch all the equipment.
You'll go read it to him.
Shit.
You know we never digging
the tunnel...
they had teams of guys
monitoring this.
Yeah?
How many?
Teams.
That's a 5.6.
If you don't think a 5.6
is possible...
or even likely. Then quit frankly you don't know
much about the (?) senior report...
specifically the Saxon
and the Mohabi block.
I know what you're hoping
then it'll be just a blind trust(?)...
See that, that's Rusty.
He's doing an Irwin Allen.
See that?
He's not deaf, Linus.
- Why am I here?
- Close your hotel.
Permanently.
What?
We haven't even opened yet.
- What are all those people downstairs?
- Well, it's a soft open.
It's like an out of town preview...
What do you think? You just come in
here to tell me to close my hotel.
I'm not gonna close my hotel.
Sir, if you just let me come in with
my team and (?) here for a few days.
- No.
- I can proof what I'm saying.
No hey, there is no way we are exposing
our exclusive clientele to a bunch of...
Scientists?
We wouldn't want that, would we?
Let's just hope for the best, shall we.
That should be enough.
Take this.
It's a standard torsion seismograph.
If there is a foreshock
it will register...
and you just might have
time te evacuate.
I don't want this thing on my desk.
No sir, let me tell you what you don't want.
Your hotel on the cover of Time magazine...
in a twisted heap of steel and glass.
You and your customers are
underneath it. Headline reads:
Who's to blame?
That's what you don't want.
Okay...
Put an evacuation plan on paper.
Will do, sir.
Consider it done.
I do thank you for your time.
If you really wanna put yourself to
good use... Why don't you hit the tables?
I don't gamble, sir...
neither should you
not with people's lives.
I'll screen the meetings more careful
the next time. I'm sorry, Mr. Bank.
And now we have a camera
in Bank's office.
I see you, Reuben.
A letter from Basher.
Dear Reuben...
as the band said: two hearts
beat as one.
When men have been
in battle together...
they are bonded like the flower
and the soil and the sun...
and like the moon catches the light...
Reuben, I'm gonna go ahead on and leave this...
here.
I see you, pall.
So she says:
What did I do? What did I do?
I said:
What do I look like, a pancake eater?
- So you just left her down on the floor?
- Right on the floor.
- For how long?
- The next morning.
Good.
Yeah.
Thanks Debbie.
Pack your swimsuit.
I don't wanna see any slack
faces in front of the house.
- Only happy faces, no slack faces.
- Right.
Go!
- Go! Go!
- Right.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Mr. Shields, where are you going?
We got you (?) grand opening.
A friend of mine, a very serious man...
told me very seriously...
that'll be a good idea
if I left the hotel.
I'm taking his suggestion.
He can't be too serious...
if he knew what I got in store for you now.
Willie, I'm outta here.
Thank you.
- See you Willie.
- I really hate to see you go, man.
Let's go.
Bank here.
Confirmed?
Bine.
- Where?
- The gentleman in the Trilby, sir.
The what?
The Dr. Dolittle hat.
Why don't you just say that?
Okay.
- Excuse me... Mr.?
- Chubb.
Kensington Chubb.
How do you do, Mr. Chubb?
Would you like to follow me, I think
I might be able to move things along.
How very nice of you.
No, no, no, no, no!
Her Highness is a very
delicate animal.
It upsets her so everyone
but papa carries her about.
All's well, dear.
- Why don't you just follow me?
- How very considerate.
I do appreciate what
your're doing for me.
Oh, sorry.
- Why does he get to go...
- He's a V.I.P.
So what's that make me?
A V.U.P.?
A Very Unimportant Person?
I have a reservation.
De ce nu iei o pauzã?
Mã ocup eu de oaspete.
Hello sir, I'm sorry for the wait.
Welcome to the Bank.
Hello.
Kensington Chubb here.
Saul, it's me.
He's in his room. Blast him.
Got it.
Gloves and mask
don't take any chances.
Got it.
Hello, front desk.
Yeah, I'm in room 1706...
and there's some sort of
terrible smell in here.
It smells like...
Well but... I need, I need to move!
Certainly, sir.
I'll just see if we have anything available.
I'm sorry, sir. We are fully booked
for the grand opening gala...
but I'll let you know if anything ends up.
Enjoy your stay at the Bank.
- But...
- Goodbye.
- That I'm ready to see all available rooms.
- My way, mister. - Thank you.
Her highness is so very
sensitive to smells.
Get away.
If you keep on complaining...
they'll fire us, just for listening...
I just say that the working
conditions are bad.
Nobody can deny that.
Payment... little.
Working hours... long.
That's the way it is in Mexico.
Did you all forget about...
general Emiliano Zapata?
When they took the land
from the poor...
they believed it was
forever stolen.
But Zapata said to them:
it's better to die on your feet...
than to live on your knees.
And they fought.
Hello.
I'd like a table for one.
I hear your risotto is tremendous.
It is tremendous.
- The name on the reservation?
- (?).
I'm sorry, sir. I can't
accomodate you.
Those are reserved.
May I recommend one of
our other restaurants?
Ling Su, Cantonesian (?) cuisine.
Great.
Okay it's not a prop, for prop's sake.
No, the Brody can work.
What? Just you got the
greatest cover known to men?
Right? So you don't even have to
think about these things anymore.
Congratulations!
No, maybe you're getting soft.
No, I'm not gonna put Danny on...
or Rusty.
Just... Goodbye dad.
Okay.
I rerouted all the impulses
going to the main randomizer.
In Black Jack the best (?) is 21.
It's called Black Jack.
So the results should be 20's
and Black Jack...
to all the players...
with the dealer "bust".
Your call.
Do over. A do over.
Okay... I'll keep working.
- Good.
- Great.
Yes, I'll have the dumplings and
the Shataki mushroom (?)...
and a sparkling water.
Staff...
casino...
food...
room cleanliness.
At this point...
there's nothing I can do to help.
He said that he'd be...
Cum îi zice?
Ambulatory by now.
- Are you keeping his spirits (?).
- We're working on it.
Thanks Stan.
Oh no, that's way too much.
- No.
- It's not like I removed a bullet.
This side.
- Dr. Stan! - Hey Linus, how's it going?
- Great.
- We're dead.
- What are you talking about?
- The factory in Mexico is offline.
- Offline?
- What does that mean exactly?
- I couldn't get details.
It just shut down.
- You don't think that...
- Yeah, I do. - Oh boy.
So he says that they want their bread
and they want their roses too.
We better get down there
and straighten this out.
- He doesn't listen to me.
- You're going.
If we don't get this factory back online...
we have to dock this showboat.
What do you mean?
Just the whole operation...
Dude, I got the showboat metaphor.
Thank you, Linus.
I gotta get back.
What?
What do you mean "what"?
(?) little something for the effort, maybe.
We pull tips.
The other guys are gonna think I'm kiting.
- Come on. - You want it
to come out of my pocket, or something?
Yeah.
Take it easy.
What's the problem?
The Tricode Optimizers that be into
into the nipple sleeve receivers...
pulverated their lubricating
(?)...
up against tension against the sidewalls.
Aha...
Picture a knee but without any
cartilage, bone on bone.
Apar deformãri în densitatea aliajului.
Devine ca un magnet.
Inverseazã polaritatea.
Where does that put us?
Cattled.
Okay. The good news is
there's another B600 available.
The one that dug the Chunnel.
- I thought we had the one that dug the Chunnel.
- We did.
This one dug from
the French side.
The bad news is with timing this short
we're gonna have to buy this one.
- And it's expensive.
- How much do we have left?
If I tap the whole contingency
just over 10 million.
- How close does that get us?
- No.
How much is it?
- 30.
- 30?
- 6.
- 6?
36.
- Isn't there a way doing it without the drill?
- The drill is the exit strategy.
Well...
is there a way for us to raise money?
- I got everything I have in this already.
- So do I.
- Me too.
- We all do.
If anyone of us was lying up
on that bed Reuben wouldn't rest...
until he made it right.
I gotta go up there and tell him
that we failed...
and there's nothing we can do about it?
- So we're stopping?
- I'm not saying that. - So what then?
Scuzi, signori.
Mr. Reuben is talking.
He asks for Mr. Danny.
I hear cars pulling in...
I hear whispering conversations,
Linus crying.
Why don't you tell me what
everyone else seems to know?
Well the thing is...
Wait!
Hi.
Good to see you smiling again.
Can I talk to you guys for a second?
That's your idea?
Well, we've shaken all the trees,
we've looked under every rock...
we've searched every...
We talked to everybody
we can trust.
I know it's not a great idea,
but it is an idea...
and I think as long as we have one idea
we shouldn't give up.
I was really hoping to avoid
that this time.
Number one.
If any of you is trying to screw me...
he'll be dead.
And I'm gonna be looking in
on the operation...
just to make sure.
Number two.
I'll lend you this money
I am your senior partner.
Last money in, first money out.
And you will double my investment.
Double?
- Is that a "yes"?
- Double.
That monstrosity that Bank
calls a hotel...
casts a shadow over my pool.
Break him.
Break him in half.
The man has no taste...
and yet every time
he opens a hotel...
he wins a Royal Review Board...
Five Diamond Award.
Every time he wins the Five
Diamond Award, he celebrates by...
We know.
- By buying one for his wife.
- You mean five.
- One is five.
- Number three.
I want you to steal the diamonds.
- No, that's... - Can't be done.
- We don't have the manpower or time.
- (?)
- We get caught we go away for life.
We're not gonna risk that
so you can get his diamonds.
They're not for me.
I just want him to lose
what matters most to him.
Do what you want with them.
But you need to steal the diamonds...
or you find somebody else
to finance your drill.
The B600 drill.
So what's the deal with
these diamonds then?
They're out of Tiffany
they're 30 karat each.
(?) the award plaques...
On today's legitimate market they'd be worth...
250 million dollars.
Bank's already purchased the next one
in anticipation of winning the award.
The rest are kept in a secure glass
viewing boot at the top of the tower.
- And Benedict said we can keep?
- That's what he said.
Then why want these diamonds
on the agenda to begin with?
Because it can't be done.
This is why revenge jobs
don't work, Daniel.
You put yourself in a position, you know
you should walk away, but you can't.
This is how guys die
or go to jail.
Alright.
Does anybody wanna walk away?
- Saul?
- I say I was walking away.
Let's cut the son of a bitch.
Okay. Bank fired (?), (?), (?)
and 4 others, just so he could say
he designed the hotel himself.
What this means to us?
There's no set of unified plans.
- Routes?
- According to March 05 plans...
there's interior shafts with potential access to
the diamond viewing room. Here, here and here.
But the May 05 plans only show
shafts: here and here.
September 05 shows no shafts...
and December 06 plans are
the same as...
- How many sets of plans are there?
- That's ten.
Since we can't trust the accuracy
of these drawings...
based on my walking around...
these are the shafts we have to
clap an eyeball on.
Now there's still nowhere of knowing the
thickness of the floor underneath the diamonds.
Anything thicker than 5 inches
we have a problem.
Right.
This here is the elevator shaft...
which can be accessed through
a super high roller villa.
- Got it?
- Alright.
So who's gonna be our super high roller?
I'm so sorry to bring (?)...
Pepperidge, Lenny Pepperidge.
I'm Mr. Weng's communicator.
He'd like you to know that
he was waiting for 7 minutes.
We've received your 10 million
dollar cash deposit...
and I would like you to know
that what we normally do...
Mr. Weng won't take a line.
He's a man of extraordinary
discipline.
He's willing to risk 10 million,
not a dollar more.
Did you say Mr. Weng was in
real estate, Mr. Pepperidge?
That's right.
I only ask because his name...
doesn't come up on our
standard file database.
And Mr. Weng and I have worked
very hard to keep it that way.
Exactly what kind of real estate did
you say that Mr. Weng was involved?
Look he owns all the air
south of Beijing.
- The air?
- Put it to you this way...
try building something larger
than 3 stories...
in the Tianjin province...
see if his name comes up
in your database then.
How quickly can you transfer his money
from your cage to the cage at the Bellagio?
Now I don't think that's necessary...
at all Mr. Pepperidge, we've
reserved our largest villa for Mr. Weng.
Extension 765.
Hello Robert.
This is Abigail Sponder.
Your (?) introduced
us not too long ago...
at the gaming fraud seminar.
I remember you.
What can I do for you, Miss Sponder?
Well, you know... We're about
to open a new property...
and there are a couple of
characters here...
I'm not to sure about.
Why don't you give me their names
and I'll check them out.
Up you go.
- What do you mean you're not going?
- You gotta go.
Too fast?
You did the bullet train stunt
with all of Asia watching...
elevators aren't faster than that.
That was C.G.I.?
Adicã a fost o minciunã?
Jesus.
- Okay then.
- We're down again.
Well what about Reuben?
- Este fãrã inimã.
- It's just a living.
Am putea plãti pe cineva
sã-i citeascã.
Maybe he'll see his
next birthday.
- January?
- I don't think so.
Shit.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
And then what happened?
She said she liked surprises.
I don't think that's what she meant.
You think?
- So she put down the remote.
- And I put the towel back on.
Now, those (?)
- Relationships can be...
- Sure.
- But they're also...
- That's right.
I've gone through so many
blueprints...
I can taste the ink
on my fingers.
Yeah...
The only other access point is through
the main airconditiong (?).
- We gotta move that guard.
- We don't have anything on him.
Let's find something.
ªi sã ajungem la elicopter
(?), this used to be the dunes.
Reuben thought me to shoot craps
here when I was a kid.
Am jucat. Instrumentarul
nu este 66.
He straightened me out.
I was 20... 2.
First time I met Reuben...
he looked me off getting cheated
at an old dealer's game at the (?)...
and he bought me breakfast.
Sands was there... Desert Inn.
They built them a lot smaller back then.
They seemed pretty big.
The town has changed.
You know if I read
încã ceva despre
Vegas legend,
Terry Benedict...
I'm gonna have to buy
a magazine of my own.
And I haven't forgotten about that phone.
Ah, the gold model, the one
that retails for 10.000.
The double light Samsung.
Okay, that would be... Ungettable.
No, no... You call Teddy Sanders
of promotion.
I did that and he promised you...
the very first one as soon as
it comes of the line in September.
That's July for me.
What did you say about Samsung?
He said he used to bowl with
the owner of Samsung.
Well call Danny.
Oh and tell Danny I know the perfect guy
we can use for the roleplay at the Expo.