[thunder rumbling]
[thunder crashing]
[rain falling]
[thunder rumbling]
[thunder crashing]
[snaps fingers]
[doorbell buzzes]
- I KNEW YOU WOULD COME.
HE'S BEEN CALLING
FOR YOU, ANGELO.
- I CAME AS SOON
AS I COULD, AUNT ROSA.
HOW IS HE?
- YOU CAME JUST IN TIME.
- IT'S ALL
IN GOD'S HANDS NOW.
- EDUARDO, ANGELO IS HERE.
- PAPA, IT'S ANGELO.
- MY SON.
- PAPA, IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
- COME CLOSER.
CLOSER.
[slap]
YOU BUM!
[speaking Italian]
- PAPA, WHAT HAVE I DONE?
- GANGSTER!
YOU ROB, YOU STEAL,
YOU SHOOT PEOPLE!
YOU BRING SHAME
IN THE FAMILY.
[muttering in Italian]
- I'M SORRY, PA, BUT...
WHAT CAN I DO
TO MAKE PEACE WITH YOU?
- OH...
NOW YOU WANT TO MAKE PEACE
WITH YOUR PAPA.
YOU WANT-A ME DIE HAPPY.
- OF COURSE I DO, PAPA.
- SO NOW YOU WANT ME DIE!
[slap]
- PAPA, NO!
- ANGELO!
ANGELO!
MAKE ME ONE PROMISE.
- YOU NAME IT, ANYTHING.
IT'S DONE.
- SWEAR IN FRONT
OF YOUR FAMILY...
IN FRONT OF PADRE CLEMENTE,
IN FRONT OF JESUCRISTO...
IN FRONT OF THE MADONNA...
- WHAT?
- SWEAR YOU BECOME HONEST MAN.
GIVE UP THE SHAMEFUL LIFE.
- WELL, PAPA...
- PADRE, VIENI QUI.
- YES, I-M--I'M--I'M HERE.
WHAT?
- VIENI QUI!
[coughing]
PROMISE.
- ALL RIGHT, PAPA.
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT...
I'LL GO STRAIGHT.
I PROMISE.
- NOW...
I'M READY.
[slap]
THAT'S-A SO YOU WON'T FORGET.
[singing Largo al Factotum
from The Barber of Seville]
- ¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ PRESTO A BOTTEGA CHE
L'ALBA E GIA, PRESTO ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ AH, CHE BEL VIVERE,
CHE BEL PIACERE ¶
¶ CHE BEL PIACERE ¶
¶ PER UN BARBIERE ¶
¶ DI QUALITA,
DI QUALITA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ AH, BRAVO FIGARO,
BRAVO, BRAVISSIMO, BRAVO ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ FORTUNATISSIMO
PER VERITA, BRAVO ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ FORTUNATISSIMO PER VERITA ¶
¶ FORTUNATISSIMO
PER VERITA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA
LA LA LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ TUTTI MI CHIEDONO,
TUTTI MI VOGLIONO ¶
¶ DONNE, RAGAZZI
VECCHI, FANCIULLE ¶
¶ QUA LA PARRUCCA,
PRESTO LA BARBA ¶
¶ QUA LA SANGUIGNA,
PRESTO IL BIGLIETTO ¶
¶ TUTTI MI CHIEDONO,
TUTTI MI VOGLIONO ¶
¶ QUA LA PARRUCCA,
PRESTO LA BARBA ¶
¶ PRESTO IL BIGLIETTO ¶
¶ FIGARO, FIGARO ¶
¶ FIGARO, FIGARO, FIGARO ¶
¶ FIGARO ¶
¶ AHIME, AHIME,
CHE FURIA, AHIME ¶
¶ CHE FOLLA,
UNO ALLA VOLTA, PER CARITA ¶
¶ PER CARITA, PER CARITA ¶
¶ UNO ALLA VOLTA,
UNO ALLA VOLTA ¶
PER CARITA ¶
¶ FIGARO, SON QUA ¶
¶ EHI, FIGARO, SON QUA ¶
¶ FIGARO QUA, FIGARO LA,
FIGARO QUA, FIGARO LA ¶
¶ FIGARO SU, FIGARO GIU,
FIGARO SU, FIGARO GIU ¶
¶ PRONTO PRONTISSIMO
SON COME IL FULMINE ¶
¶ SONO IL FACTOTUM
DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ DELLA CITTA, DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ DELLA CITTA,
DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ AH, BRAVO, FIGARO,
BRAVO, BRAVISSIMO ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA,
A TE FORTUNA ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA
NON MANCHERA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA LA LA LA LA ¶
LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA,
A TE FORTUNA ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA
NON MACHERA ¶
¶ SONO IL FACTOTUM
DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ DELLA ¶
¶ CITTA ¶
- BRAVO!
[cheers and applause]
[car horn honks]
[bicycle bell ringing]
[clock bell tolling]
[big band music]
- READ 'EM AND WEEP.
- FULL HOUSE.
- OH, JESUS!
I THOUGHT YOU WAS BLUFFIN'.
- LOWER THAT!
YOU'LL WAKE THE BOSS.
[lowers volume]
ALL RIGHT, YOUS MUGS,
CASINO'S CLOSED.
ACE, GET STARTED
ON THOSE MELON BALLS.
- YEAH, YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
- SHAKE A LEG.
TODAY'S THE BOSS' BIG DAY.
REMEMBER?
- YEAH.
THE DAY SNAPS PROVOLONE
GOES STRAIGHT.
- THE WHOLE THING
AIN'T KOSHER.
WHOEVER HEARD
OF A BANKER NAMED SNAPS?
- BUYIN' INTO A BANK?
THAT'S NOT SNAPS.
IT'S GOTTA BE A DODGE.
- IT'S NO DODGE.
THOSE BANKERS'LL BE HERE
TO CINCH THE DEAL AT NOON.
- OH, JEEZ!
I GOTTA CHECK MY MUFFINS.
- YOU SURE THIS INFO'S
THE MCCOY, FIVE SPOT?
- OH, I-I-IT'S THE MCCOY,
MR. VENDETTI,
AND IT--AND IT'S BIG.
AND IT'S GONNA HAPPEN
T-T-T-T-T-TODAY.
- I KNEW IT.
HE'S HOOKIN' UP
WITH O'BANION'S MOB.
- HOLD STILL, HONEY!
- O'BANION!
Y-Y-YEAH, THAT--THAT--
THAT'S GOTTA BE IT.
I'M--I'M--I'M PRETTY S-S-SURE
I HEARD THAT NAME, O'BA-BA-BA--
- WHAT DOES THIS STOOLIE KNOW?
- LOOK,
I'M A PAID INFORMANT!
TH--THAT'S--
THAT'S AN HONORABLE PROFESSION.
UH, CAN I HAVE MY, UH,
FIVE SPOT NOW, MR. VENDETTI?
- [chuckles]
GIVE HIM A 20.
- OH, UH...
- IT'S A RETAINER.
LET ME KNOW
IF YOU HEAR ANYTHING.
- [whispering]
I TELL THE TRUTH...
TH--THA--THANK YOU,
M-M-MR. VENDETTI.
THANK YOU.
- I TOLD YOU THINGS
WERE TOO QUIET.
PROVOLONE
WAS JUST LAYIN' LOW.
- SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO
ABOUT SNAPS?
- WE'RE GONNA OBSERVE
THE 11TH COMMANDMENT.
"DO UNTO OTHERS
BEFORE THEY DO UNTO YOU."
- I FINISHED YOUR NAILS.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
I CAN DO, HUH?
- WE'D HAVE MORE EXCITEMENT
STAKIN' OUT GRANT'S TOMB.
- THANK GOD THIS DETAIL
ENDS TODAY.
- OOH, TOOMEY'S SORE AS HELL.
HE'S BEEN ACHIN' TO GET
SOMETHING ON SNAPS FOR YEARS.
- SO HE'S SORE.
WHAT'S HE WANT FROM US?
I MEAN, THE GUY HASN'T SO MUCH
AS SPIT ON THE SIDEWALK
IN THREE WEEKS.
[telephone ringing]
both: TOOMEY.
I GOT IT LAST TIME.
- HIYA, TOOMEY.
- I SUPPOSE
YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME
THAT YOU GOT NOTHIN' AGAIN
ON OUR BOY ACROSS THE STREET.
- SO SUE ME, TOOMEY.
- WELL, LOOK ALIVE
OVER THERE!
I HEAR HE MAY BE TYIN' UP WITH
THE O'BANION MOB FROM CHICAGO.
- WHY DON'T YOU JUST GIVE UP
THE GHOST, TOOMEY?
I MEAN, MAYBE THE EGG'S
GONE STRAIGHT.
- LOOK, I KNOW THIS GUY.
AND I'M TELLIN' YA, A LEOPARD
DON'T CHANGE HIS STRIPES.
- YOU MEAN SPOTS.
- I MEAN SNAPS!
NOW, AS SOON AS SOMETHIN'
HAPPENS DOWN THERE--
I DON'T CARE WHAT--
YOU CALL ME.
GET IT?
- GOT IT.
- SAY, TAKE A GANDER.
[doorbell ringing]
- I'M COMIN', I'M COMIN'.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
IF IT ISN'T LITTLE ANTHONY...
AND HIIMPERIAL.
[vacuum humming]
- I'VE GOTTA SEE MR. PROVOLONE.
- WHAT?
HEY!
SHUT THAT THING OFF!
- I SAID I GOTTA SEE
MR. PROVOLONE RIGHT AWAY.
- I DON'T REMEMBER SEEIN' YOU
IN MY APPOINTMENT BOOK, ANTHONY.
NOPE.
NOW, I GOT THE FINUCCI BROTHERS
AT 9:30...
DR. POOLE AT 10:30,
FATHER CLEMENTE AT 11:00,
AND THE BANKERS AT NOON.
BUT I DON'T SEE NO MEETIN'
WITH HIS ACCOUNTANT!
- LOOK, ALDO,
DON'T SCREW AROUND WITH ME.
THIS IS URGENT.
- THE BOSS DON'T GET UP
BEFORE 9:00 A.M.
EVEN THE FEDS KNOW THAT.
- I'LL TAKE THE HEAT.
- YOU'LL TAKE THE HEAT?
I'M THE ONE
THAT'S GOTTA WAKE HIM.
- TELL HIM IT'S A MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH.
- OKAY, OKAY.
BUT HE AIN'T GONNA LIKE THIS.
WAIT IN THE LIVING ROOM.
HOW DO YOU LIKE
THE CRUST ON THAT MUG?
THROWS OFF
MY WHOLE ITINERARY.
- [laughing]
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOIN'?
- I GOTTA WAKE HIM.
- HE DOESN'T WANNA BE
DISRUPTED.
HE NEEDS HIS BEAUTY SLEEP
FOR THOSE BANKERS.
- IT'S URGENT.
KEEP ME COVERED.
- THIS BETTER BE GOOD.
- I WARNED HIM, BOSS.
- ANTHONY TOLD ME IT WAS
LIFE AND DEATH, BOSS.
- YOU MUGS STOP CALLIN' ME BOSS.
IT AIN'T RESCTABLE!
both: SORRY, BOSS.
- WELL, LITTLE ANTHONY,
PROBATION AND WALL STREET
LAY ANOTHER EGG--WHAT?
- CAN I TALK TO YOU ALONE,
MR. PROVOLONE?
- WE ARE ALONE.
ALDO, BREAKFAST.
- HALF A GRAPEFRUIT?
- SECTIONED,
NIX THE CHERRY IN THE MIDDLE.
- FRENCH TOAST?
- LIGHT BROWN.
- BACON?
- TRIM THE FAT.
- COFFEE?
- NO CREAM.
- TWO LUMPS?
- [snaps fingers] GO.
- ON ITS WAY, SNAPS.
- UH, IT'S "MR. PROVOLONE" NOW.
AND IF YOU CALL ME THAT
IN FRONT OF THE BANKERS,
YOU'RE GONNA GUM UP THE WORKS.
- YES, MR. PROVOLONE.
- AND I'LL EAT IN THE YARD--
I MEAN ATRIUM.
- YES, MR. PROVOLONE.
WHATEVER YOU SAY, MR. PROVOLONE.
- YOU KNOW WHAT
"ATRIUM" MEANS, ANTHONY?
- NO, SIR.
- IT'S A COURTYARD OFTTIMES
SURROUNDED BY COLUMNS.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT, SIR.
- PARK IT, ANTHONY.
I LEARN
A NEW WORD EVERY DAY.
YOU SHOULD EXPAND
YOUR VOCABULARY, ANTHONY,
AND YOU WOULDN'T
JUST BE A BOOKKEEPER.
- ACCOUNTANT, SIR.
- MY WORD FOR TODAY IS...
EXPEDITIOUS.
"TO BE EFFICIENT AND SPEEDY."
ALL RIGHT, ANTHONY,
LET'S BE EXPEDITIOUS.
WHAT'S SO IMPORTANT
YOU GOT ME UP AT 8:00?
- WELL, MR. PROVOLONE,
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
I'VE COME TO ASK YOU
FOR A RAISE.
- [chuckles]
MAYBE MY HEARING
AIN'T 20/20 NO MORE.
WHAT DID HE JUST ASK ME?
- HE ASKED YOU FOR A RAISE.
- THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
- WHEN YOU HEAR WHY--
- YOU BELIEVE
THIS GUY'S MOXIE?
- HE'S GOT CHUTZPAH, BOSS.
- DON'T CALL ME BOSS.
- SORRY, BOSS.
- I KNOW THIS WASN'T
THE BEST DAY, SIR.
- YOU'RE TELLING ME?
IF EVERYTHING GOES WELL TODAY--
- KNOCK ON WOOD.
- I'LL BE A BOARD OF DIRECTOR.
- I KNOW THAT.
AND--AND I WOULDN'T
BOTHER YOU,
BUT LOVE MAKES US DO
STRANGE THINGS.
- WHAT'S LOVE GOT TO DO
WITH THE PRICE OF BEER?
- BREAKFAST IS "SOIVED."
- "SERVED," YOU PALOOKA.
I'M SIGNING YOU UP FOR ELOCUTION
LESSONS WITH DR. POOLE.
IF I GOTTA DO IT,
YOU GOTTA DO IT.
- ALL OF A SUDDEN,
HE'S THE DUKE OF ELLINGTON.
DON'T FORGET, YOU GOT A MEETIN'
WITH THE FINUCCI BROTHERS
AT 9:30.
- YEAH, YEAH.
COME ON, KID.
I WANNA SIT ON MY ATRIUM.
NOT BAD FOR A KID
FROM THE SLUMS.
MY WIFE PICKS ALL THIS OUT.
SHE'S GOT AN EYE.
[snaps fingers]
SO WHO IS THE DAME
THAT'S GOT ME UP AT 8:43?
- EXCUSE ME, SIR?
- YOU SAID YOU WERE IN LOVE.
I ASSUME IT'S A DAME.
- OH, SHE'S A WONDERFUL GIRL
FROM A FINE, WEALTHY FAMILY.
AND I'M GONNA PROPOSE TO HER
THIS MORNING.
- AH, AIN'T LOVE GRAND?
WELL, YOU GOT MY BLESSING.
CONGRATULATIONS TO YOU
AND YOUR NEW BRIDE.
- BUT I CAN'T MARRY HER,
NOT UNLESS I CAN GIVE HER
THE KIND OF LIFE
THAT HER PARENTS DID.
- WELL, DUMP HER.
SHE SOUNDS LIKE A GOLD DIGGER.
- OH, NO, NO, SIR.
SHE'S JUST THE OPPOSITE--
VERY KIND AND SWEET,
DOWN-TO-EARTH.
- WELL, I CAN SEE
THIS DAME'S GOT YOU
WRAPPED AROUND
HER LITTLE FINGER, HUH?
OKAY, HOW MUCH YOU MAKIN'?
- 400 A MONTH.
- HOW MUCH YOU WANNA
TO BE MAKIN'?
- 1,400 A MONTH.
YOU CAN TAKE A FEW MINUTES
TO THINK IT OVER.
- I HAVE THOUGHT IT OVER.
GET THE HELL OFF MY ATRIUM!
IF BIG ANTHONY
WERE ALIVE TO HEAR THIS...
- ON THE GRAVE OF MY FATHER,
I NEVER WANTED TO UPSET YOU.
BUT YOU HAVE NO IDEA
HOW TOUGH IT IS
FOR TWO YOUNG PEOPLE
STARTING OUT THESE DAYS...
AS I WAS SAYING LAST NIGHT
TO MR. LIPINSKY.
- LIPINSKY?
- YES.
MR. MYRON LIPINSKY.
- LUCKY LIPINSKY THE GANGSTER?
HOW CAN YOU ASSOCIATE
WITH SUCH A LOWLIFE?
- HE'S LOOKING
FOR A NEW ACCOUNTANT.
HIS LAST ONE DIED
IN HIS SLEEP.
- OH, YOU DON'T THINK THAT BUM
WOULD SHOOT HIM
WHILE HE WAS AWAKE, DO YOU?
THE CHEAP HOOD.
- HE'S NOT THAT CHEAP, SIR.
MR. LIPINSKY IS WILLING
TO PAY ME THE 1,400 A MONTH.
- OH, BACKSTABBING WEASEL.
HE'D LOVE TO GET HIS MEAT HOOKS
INTO ONE OF MY BOYS.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL PAY...
1,200.
- OH, MR. PROVOLONE,
I AM TOUCHED
BY YOUR FAITH IN ME.
- I SHOULD HAVE HAD THIS MUG
IN COLLECTIONS.
HE'S NOT AN ACCOUNTANT.
HE'S A SHAKEDOWN ARTIST.
- NOW, I CAN COUNT
ON THIS 1,200 A MONTH?
- YEAH, YOU GOT IT.
GO.
GO PROPOSE.
- MR. PROVOLONE,
IT IS MY HONOR
TO ASK FOR YOUR DAUGHTER'S HAND
IN MATRIMONY.
- [spits]
PARDON ME?
- YES.
YOUR DAUGHTER
IS THE ONE I LOVE.
- MY DAUGHTER?
HOW DO YOU KNOW MY DAUGHTER?
- [choking]
WE MET AT CLUB 33.
- IN A SPEAKEASY?
- IT'S A VERY RESPECTABLE
SPEAKEASY.
- COULDN'T EVEN PICK ONE
THAT BOUGHT MY BEER!
- BOSS, BOSS,
GET A HOLD OF YOURSELF.
LET ME TAKE CARE OF HIM.
- ARE YOU STILL PACKIN'?
FORK IT OVER.
FORK!
WE'RE NOT
IN THAT BUSINESS ANYMORE.
AT NOON,
WE BECOME BANKERS.
- CAN I GET UP NOW,
MR. PROVOLONE?
[coughing]
- SORRY I LOST MY TEMPER.
- [normal voice]
NO PROBLEM.
IT IS
WITH THE GREATEST HUMILITY
THAT I ASK TO MARRY
YOUR DAUGHTER.
- ON A LOUSY 1,200 A MONTH?
SHE DESERVES BETTER!
- YES, SHE DESERVES A HUSBAND
WHO MAKES 1,400.
- SHE'LL GET ONE,
AND IT WON'T BE YOU.
[belches]
CONNIE,
BRING ME A BRIOSCHI.
- THAT'S ALDO'S JOB.
- WELL, THEN GET ALDO TO DO IT.
- YES, BOSS.
- DON'T CALL ME BOSS.
- SORRY, BOSS.
- AND AS FOR YOU,
YOU THINK I'M GONNA LET YOU
MARRY MY DAUGHTER FOR HER MONEY?
- OH, MR. PROVOLONE...
I DON'T LOVE YOUR DAUGHTER
FOR HER MONEY,
AND I CAN PROVE IT.
- YEAH?
HOW?
- WHEN I MARRY HER,
I PLAN TO GIVE HER
MY ENTIRE FORTUNE.
- HOW MUCH CAN A GOOMBAH
LIKE YOU HAVE?
- $48,642.30.
- HOW DID YOU SAVE 50 GRAND
ON 400 A MONTH?
- I STOLE IT FROM YOU.
- YOU WHAT?
YOU WALK INTO MY HOUSE
AND TELL ME
YOU STOLE 50 Gs FROM ME?
- THIS GINK!
YOU WANT I SHOULD BUMP HIM?
- GIVE ME THAT GAT, ALDO.
YOU KNOW WHAT I TOLD YOU.
YOU'RE A BUTLER NOW.
"BUTTLE"!
- THAT PIECE HAS BEEN
IN THE FAMILY FOR YEARS!
- QUIT SQUAWKIN'.
NOW, I'M WAITIN'
FOR AN EXPLANATION.
- MAYBE I SHOULD START
FROM THE BEGINNING.
- JUST START
FROM WHERE YOU STOLE MY MONEY.
- WHEN I FIRST TOOK OVER
AS YOUR ACCOUNTANT,
YOUR BOOKS WERE A MESS.
- THEY DON'T SOUND LIKE
THEY'RE IN NO GREAT SHAPE NOW.
DAMN IT.
DOUBLE NEGATIVE.
- YOUR OVERHEAD WAS HIGH,
AND YOUR NET PROFITS WERE LOW.
I CHANGED ALL THAT.
- AND I SENT YOU A FRUIT BASKET
FOR CHRISTMAS, DIDN'T I?
- I TOOK ALL THE PROFITS
FROM YOUR PROTECTION RACKETS
AND USED THEM TO UPGRADE
YOUR BOOTLEGGING OPERATION.
NOW, THAT ALLOWED ME
TO CUT THE COSTS
ON YOUR BEER
A DIME A BOTTLE.
- SURE, YOU WERE FATTENING ME UP
FOR THE KILL.
- THEN A STRANGE THING
HAPPENED.
I MADE
A SLIGHT CLERICAL ERROR.
- WAS THAT THE ONE
THAT COST ME $50,000?
- DON'T GET AHEAD OF THE STORY.
- WELL, EXCUSE ME!
- IT WAS A SIMPLE MISTAKE
IN ADDITION.
ON THE BOOKS, I ACCIDENTALLY
LOWERED YOUR COSTS BY A NICKEL
INSTEAD OF A DIME.
NOW, WHEN I REALIZED
MY MISTAKE,
I WENT TO SPEAK
TO YOU ABOUT IT.
- I DON'T REMEMBER THAT.
- YOU WERE IN CHICAGO.
IT WAS ST. VALENTINE'S DAY.
- OH, YEAH.
[laughing]
- [laughing]
- ZIP IT.
- I REMEMBER IT WAS
ST. VALENTINE'S DAY
BECAUSE THAT'S THE DAY
I MET YOUR DAUGHTER.
- IN VENDETTI'S SPEAKEASY.
I'LL KILL HER.
- IT WAS LOVE
AT FIRST SIGHT.
AND THAT'S WHEN I TURNED
THAT 5-CENT ERROR
INTO THE KEY TO MY HAPPINESS.
I HID IT ON THE BOOKS
AND BEEFED UP PETTY CASH.
AND I KNEW THAT A BIG MAN
LIKE ANGELO PROVOLONE
WOULDN'T BEGRUDGE HIS FUTURE
SON-IN-LAW A NICKEL,
WHICH I PLAN TO GIVE
TO YOUR DAUGHTER ANYWAY.
- OH, THIS GUY IS BEAUTIFUL.
HE FLATTERS YOU TO YOUR FACE
WHILE HE STICKS A KNIFE
IN YOUR BACK.
- I'M NOT PROUD OF WHAT
I'VE DONE, MR. PROVOLONE.
BUT I'D DO IT
ALL OVER AGAIN
TO CAPTURE
YOUR DAUGHTER'S HEART.
- YOU REALLY LOVE HER
THAT MUCH, HUH?
- OH, YES, SIR.
- DOES SHE KNOW
ABOUT THIS STUFF
YOU'VE BEEN DOING HERE?
- NO, SIR.
- DOES SHE LOVE YOU?
- OH, YES.
I'M SURE OF THAT.
IN FACT,
SHE'S EVEN GIVEN ME PROOF.
- PROOF?
WHAT PROOF?
- ALDO!
- WHAT ARE YOU
CALLIN' HIM FOR?
- I THINK YOU'RE GONNA NEED
SOME MORE BICARBONATE.
- WHY?
- NOW, KEEP IN MIND,
MR. PROVOLONE,
THIS IS 1931.
WE'RE ALL SOPHISTICATED ADULTS
HERE, RIGHT?
- THIS DOESN'T BODE WELL.
- YOUR DAUGHTER AND I
ARE LOVERS.
- WHAT?
MY DAUGHTER?
POP THIS GUY!
- WAIT, BOSS.
WE CAN'T HAVE A STIFF IN
THE HOUSE WITH COMPANY COMIN'.
- HE'S RIGHT.
IT AIN'T PROPER.
- THE LAST THING I EVER
WANTED TO DO WAS UPSET YOU.
- WHY SHOULD I BE UPSET?
YOU WAKE ME UP IN THE MORNING
AND TELL ME
YOU'RE STEALING MY MONEY
AND SLEEPING WITH MY DAUGHTER!
YOU GUYS SEE ANYTHING
TO BE UPSET ABOUT?
YOU'RE LUCKY
YOU DIDN'T UPSET ME TODAY.
IF YOU DIDN'T UPSET ME
LIKE THIS YESTERDAY,
YOU'D BE WEARING
A CEMENT KIMONO!
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO GIVE ME
YOUR ANSWER RIGHT NOW.
- GOOD!
'CAUSE I WANT TO TALK
TO MY SWEET LITTLE GIRL FIRST,
ANTHONY.
- YOU TWO HAVE A PLEASANT
FATHER-DAUGHTER CHAT.
I'LL TAKE A WALK
AROUND THE BLOCK,
AND YOU CAN GIVE ME YOUR ANSWER
WHEN YOU GET BACK, DAD.
- DON'T YOU CALL ME DAD.
- SAY, BOSS...
- AND DON'T YOU CALL ME BOSS.
- SORRY, BOSS.
- LET ME SHOW YOU THE DOOR.
THERE'S THE DOOR!
- HE'S LEAVIN' THE HOUSE.
MAKE A NOTE.
[crooner scatting
to Sweet Georgia Brown]
- CAN I SPEAK TO YOU A MINUTE,
MR. PROVOLONE?
- NO.
[crooner scatting]
¶ ¶
[doorknob rattles]
LISA!
LISA?
- ¶ SINCE SHE CAME,
WHY, IT'S A SHAME ¶
- LISA!
- ¶ OTHERS SHE CAN'T GET ¶
¶ MUST BE SOMEONE... ¶
- LISA!
- ¶ GEORGIA CLAIMED HER,
GEORGIA NAMED HER ¶
¶ SWEET GEORGIA ¶
[knock at door]
- LISA, I'M WAITING!
- ¶ THEY CALL HER
SWEET MISS GEORGIA BROWN ¶
[record scratches]
- LISA!
LISA!
SO NOW YOU'RE LOCKING
YOUR DOOR?
- A GIRL NEEDS
HER PRIVACY, DADDY.
I'M A GROWN WOMAN NOW.
- SO I HEARD.
- WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- DON'T BE COY WITH ME!
I KNOW ALL
ABOUT YOUR BOYFRIEND,
OR SHOULD I SAY LOVER?
- YOU KNOW?
- YES.
AND YOU'VE BROUGHT NOTHING
BUT SHAME TO THIS FAMILY.
INDECENTE.
- DADDY, YOU HAVE TO REALIZE
I'M NOT A LITTLE GIRL ANYMORE.
LOOK.
- PUT THAT AWAY!
I'M YOUR FATHER!
- SAY, HOW'D YOU FIND OUT
ABOUT US, ANYWAY?
- THE MUG WAS JUST HERE ASKIN'
ME FOR YOUR HAND IN MARRIAGE.
- OH!
[crying]
- WHAT ARE YOU CRYIN' FOR?
- BECAUSE I'M SO HAPPY.
I THOUGHT
HE LEFT ME FOR GOOD.
- YOU SHOULD BE SO LUCKY.
- DON'T SAY THAT ABOUT THE MAN
I'M GONNA MARRY.
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA MARRY
THAT MONKEY.
YOU'RE GONNA MARRY THE MAN
I PICKED OUT FOR YOU--
BRUCE UNDERWOOD III.
- [whining] I DON'T WANNA MARRY
BRUCE UNDERWOOD.
HE'S A SNOB,
AND HE'S GOT PIMPLES.
- A COUPLE OF DATES WITH YOU,
AND THAT'LL CLEAR UP.
- GO AHEAD, INSULT ME.
- YOUR MOTHER AND I SEND YOU
TO THE FINEST CATHOLIC SCHOOLS,
AND LOOK AT YOU--
A DISGRACE.
YOU LOOK LIKE YOU JUST STEPPED
OFF THE RUNWAY AT MINSKY'S.
- I'M A MODERN '30s WOMAN.
- IT'S THE MUSIC
YOU KIDS LISTEN TO TODAY--
BING CROSBY, CAB CALLOWAY!
DON'T THINK
I HAVEN'T HEARD THE LYRICS
TO MINNIE THE MOOCHER.
- OH, I AM SO STIFLED
IN THIS HOUSE.
I WANNA SWIM
THE ENGLISH CHANNEL.
I WANNA GO SHOPPING IN PARIS.
I WANNA LAY ON THE BEACH
IN HONOLULU.
- DO WHATEVER YOU WANT.
JUST DON'T LEAVE THIS ROOM.
- AAH!
[fake crying]
- THE FINUCCIS IS HERE.
- CONNIE, WATCH THIS DOOR.
SHE'S NOT GOIN' NOWHERE.
FINUCCIS.
[snaps fingers]
both:
BUON GIORNO, SIGNORE PROVOLONE.
- IS THAT MY SUIT?
- IT'S NOT JUST A SUIT.
IT'S A FINUCCI.
- TOOK YOU LONG ENOUGH.
- YOU WANT IT FAST,
OR YOU WANT IT GOOD?
WE NO RUSH.
YOU NO RUSH MICHELANGELO.
YOU NO RUSH LEONARDO.
- YOU NO RUSH A FINUCCI.
- GUIDO, THAT'S MY SPEECH.
- WHO SAY IT'S YOUR SPEECH?
[arguing in Italian]
- ENOUGH!
[both chuckle]
[snaps fingers]
MOVE IT INTO THE LIBRARY.
- STAIRS.
UNO, DUE...
- OH,
LOOK AT ALL OF THE BOOKS.
I NEVER SEE SO MANY.
- YEAH, YEAH.
READING'S MY PASSION.
- SIGNORE PROVOLONE,
THIS IS OUR LAST HOUSE CALL,
UH, BECAUSE NOW WE FAMOUS.
- FAMOUS?
- OH, SURE.
ONE OF OUR SUITS, SHE MAKE A BIG
SPREAD IN HERALD TRIBUNE.
SHOW HIM THE PICTURE.
- NICE PIECE OF WORK.
SUIT LOOKS GOOD TOO.
- GRAZIE.
HIS WIDOW, SHE WANT
A NEW SUIT TO BURY HIM.
I SAY, WHEN HE PAY
FOR THE FIRST, HE GET ANOTHER.
NICE COLOR, HUH?
FEEL THIS.
THIS NICE...
LIKE A BABY'S BEHIND.
- MMM.
WELL, LET'S SEE IF IT FITS.
I GOT TILL NOON
TO LOOK LIKE A BANKER.
- OH, WE MAKE-A YOU
LOOK LIKE A BANKER.
TAKE OFF YOUR PANTS.
- FOUR MILLION UNEMPLOYED.
IT'S ENOUGH TO BREAK YOUR HEART,
ISN'T IT, GENTLEMEN?
- YES.
WE COULD BE FORCED TO LOWER
OUR INTEREST RATES ONCE AGAIN.
- DAMN SHAME.
- ONE CAN'T EVEN WALK
FROM THE OFFICE TO THE CLUB
WITHOUT BEING PESTERED
BY SOME HOMELESS BEGGAR.
EXCUSE ME.
I MEANT "FORGOTTEN MAN."
- DRASTIC TIMES
CALL FOR DRASTIC MEASURES,
WHICH BRINGS ME TO OUR
PRESENT MEETING, GENTLEMEN.
- PLEASE.
MY STOMACH.
- WHITNEY, I WISH YOU'D
BE A LITTLE MORE RECEPTIVE--
- ARE WE IN SUCH DIRE STRAITS
THAT WE WANT THE NAME
ANGELO "SNAPS" PROVOLONE
ON OUR LETTERHEAD?
- HIS NAME WON'T BE
ON OUR LETTERHEAD.
BUT HIS MONEY
WILL BE IN OUR VAULTS.
- BUT, GENTLEMEN,
BRINGING A...
GANGSTER ON THE BOARD?
- EX-GANGSTER...
OR AS I PREFER TO THINK OF HIM,
A ROBBER BARON...
LIKE J.P. MORGAN
OR JOHN D. ROCKEFELLER.
- AT LEAST THEY DIDN'T HAVE
A MIDDLE NAME IN QUOTES.
- LET ME HANDLE
MR. PROVOLONE.
- WELL, I MAY HAVE TO TAKE
THIS GREASEBALL'S MONEY,
BUT I DON'T HAVE TO LIKE IT.
- [sniffling] OH, NORA,
I HAVE SO MANY DREAMS.
I WANNA RIDE ON A ZEPPELIN,
ATTEND A RUDY VALLEE SHOW.
I WANNA GO TO AN OPIUM TENT
IN CHINATOWN.
- YOU'LL BE DOIN'
ALL THESE THINGS, LISA.
- NO!
- YOU'LL SEE.
- MY LIFE IS OVER.
MARRYING MY BOYFRIEND
WAS MY LAST CHANCE
TO GET OUT OF THIS PRISON.
- WELL, AS PRISONS GO,
IT'S NOT SO BAD.
YOU KNOW...
I WENT TO THIS PLAY ONCE.
- YOU WENT TO A PLAY?
WHAT DID YOU WEAR?
- NEVER MIND.
THERE WAS A SCENE
WHERE A GIRL
MADE HER PARENTS THINK
SHE WAS PREGNANT,
AND THEY WERE FORCED TO LET HER
MARRY HER BOYFRIEND.
- BUT IF I TOLD DADDY
I WAS PREGNANT,
HE'D KILL ME.
- EITHER WAY,
YOU'D GET OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
- I GIVE YOU A NICE BANKER TIE
TO GO WITH THE BANKER SUIT.
PICK ONE.
- TOO LOUD, TOO QUIET,
TOO STRIPED, TOO PLAID...
[snaps fingers]
BINGO.
- MR. PROVOLONE!
- WHAT IS IT?
I'M IN THE MIDDLE
OF A FITTIN' HERE.
- MR. PROVOLONE,
YOUR DAUGHTER WANTS TO SEE YA.
- WHAT, AGAIN?
- SHE SAYS IT'S A MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH.
- NOW WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- DADDY, DEAR...
THERE'S SOMETHING
I'VE GOTTA TELL YOU
THAT'S GONNA GIVE YOU
QUITE A SHOCK.
DADDY...
I'VE DECIDED TO GO AWAY
TO A CONVENT.
- NOW YOU WANNA BE A NUN.
WELL, YOU'RE A LITTLE LATE.
- NO, DADDY.
CONVENTS ARE ALSO WHERE UNWED
MOTHERS GO TO HAVE THEIR BABIES.
- WHAT?
- YOU ALL RIGHT, BOSS?
- I THOUGHT I TOOK THIS ROD
AWAY FROM YOU.
- IT'S MY SPARE,
FOR EMERGENCIES.
- [snaps fingers]
GIVE IT TO ME.
EVERYTHING.
[ticking]
IS THAT IT?
IT'S LIKE DISARMING GERMANY.
NOW, GET OUTTA HERE!
I SHOULD USE THIS ON MYSELF
AFTER WHAT YOU'VE DONE TO ME
AND YOUR MOTHER.
THE SHAME OF IT!
- I'M SORRY, DADDY.
I'LL START PACKING
TO GO TO THE CONVENT.
- YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO ANY CONVENT!
YOU'RE GONNA MARRY THIS BUM
JUST AS SOON
AS I GET MY HANDS ON HIM.
- OH, DADDY,
YOU CHANGED YOUR MIND!
- WHAT CHOICE HAVE I GOT,
YOU TRAMP?
AND AFTER THE WEDDING,
YOU'LL MOVE INTO A NICE
GROUND-FLOOR APARTMENT.
- WHY A GROUND-FLOOR
APARTMENT?
- 'CAUSE AFTER
I BREAK HIS LEGS,
HE'S NOT GONNA MAKE IT
UP ANY STEPS.
- INTERESTING.
- THERE'S A DAME
AT THE DOOR.
- CAN'T YOU SEE I'M BUSY?
BRUSH HER OFF.
- I CAN'T.
- WHY NOT?
- BECAUSE THE DAME SAYS--
- I KNOW.
IT'S A MATTER OF LIFE
AND DEATH.
[speaking Italian]
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU, MISS...
- THERESA.
- CAN WE SPEAK PRIVATELY?
- YEAH, SURE.
WHY DON'T YOU COME UP
TO MY OFFICE?
IF DEMPSEY GOT THE WORKOUT
I'M GETTING,
HE WOULDN'T HAVE LOST
HIS LAST FIGHT.
[Connie laughing]
- MR. PROVOLONE,
I'VE DONE A STUPID THING.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- I'VE FALLEN IN LOVE
WITH A MAN
NAMED ANTHONY ROSSANO.
- YOU'RE RIGHT,
THAT'S A STUPID THING.
HE'S ALREADY SPOKEN FOR.
- BY WHO?
- BY ME.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- ANTHONY JUST ASKED
TO MARRY MY DAUGHTER.
- HE WAS HERE ALREADY?
- YES. BUT YOU'RE YOUNG.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
YOU'RE ATTRACTIVE.
THE BREAD LINES
ARE FULL OF ELIGIBLE YOUNG MEN.
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME...
- NO, YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND,
MR. PROVOLONE.
I LIED TO ANTHONY.
I TOLD HIM
THAT I WAS YOUR DAUGHTER.
- YOU DID WHAT?
- HE THINKS
YOU'RE MY FATHER.
SO, YOU SEE, WHEN HE ASKED
FOR PERMISSION TO MARRY,
IT WAS ME HE WANTED.
- THAT MEANS HE NEVER EVEN
MET MY DAUGHTER.
THAT'S WONDERFUL!
NO, WAIT.
THAT'S TERRIBLE.
IF HE NEVER MET HER,
THEN WHO'S THE FATHER?
LISTEN, OF ALL THE GUYS IN
THE WORLD, WHY DID YOU PICK ME?
- BECAUSE I WANTED
ANTHONY TO THINK
THAT I CAME
FROM A WEALTHY FAMILY.
AFTER ALL,
HE MAKES 1,400 A MONTH.
- IT'S 1,200 A MONTH!
- WHEN HE ASKED MY NAME,
I HAD JUST SEEN YOUR PICTURE
IN THE DAILY NEWS.
SO I TOLD HIM
I WAS THERESA PROVOLONE.
- THAT MAKES SENSE.
- I DIDN'T FIND OUT
UNTIL LATER
THAT YOU WERE A GANGST--
I MEAN,
THAT YOU WERE WHO YOU WERE.
- THEN WHY DIDN'T YOU
TELL HIM THE TRUTH?
- BECAUSE HE LIKED THE IDEA
THAT I WAS YOUR DAUGHTER.
I JUST FOUND OUT
THAT HE WORKED FOR YOU.
- IT'S MORE LIKE HE WORKS
FOR HIMSELF.
- SO YOU SEE, MR. PROVOLONE,
I DON'T WANT ANTHONY TO FIND OUT
THE TRUTH FROM ANYONE ELSE.
- YEAH, IF HE DOES,
I'M OUT 50,000 CLAMS.
THINK, THINK, THINK.
[snapping fingers]
ALL RIGHT, I GOT IT!
NOW, I WON'T TELL HIM
YOU'RE NOT MY DAUGHTER,
BUT YOU GOTTA DO
SOMETHING FOR ME.
- OH, ANYTHING,
MR. PROVOLONE.
- DON'T LEAVE THIS ROOM
UNTIL I SETTLE A SMALL MATTER
WITH MR. ROSSANO.
- I'LL WAIT RIGHT HERE.
I PROMISE.
- CONNIE, KEEP YOUR EYE
ON MY OFFICE
AND MAKE SURE MY DAUGHTER
DON'T GO NOWHERE, HUH?
- HOW'D SHE GET IN THERE?
I'VE BEEN WATCHIN' THIS DOOR
THE WHOLE TIME.
- NOT LISA.
THERESA!
- YOU GOT TWO DAUGHTERS?
- ALL RIGHT, IN THE THIRD,
I WANT $40 ACROSS THE BOARD
ON HIGH HAT.
THAT'S RIGHT,
$40 WORTH OF PARSLEY.
WE'RE RUNNING A LITTLE LOW
ON GARNISH.
- ALDO, THAT KID ANTHONY?
- HE LEFT.
- I KNOW HE LEFT.
GET HIM BACK HERE.
HE SAID HE WAS TAKIN' A WALK
AROUND THE BLOCK.
- I CAN'T.
I'M SMOKIN' A SALMON.
- PUT IT OUT, GET ANTHONY,
AND STASH HIM SOMEWHERE...
BUT NOT IN MY OFFICE.
- LOOK AT YOU, SNAPS.
ONE DAY OF BEIN' HONEST,
AND YOU'RE FALLIN' APART.
FORGET ABOUT THE PROMISE
TO YOUR OLD MAN.
- A PROMISE IS A PROMISE.
- MR. PROVOLONE!
CAN I SPEAK TO YA NOW?
- NOT NOW!
FINUCCIS!
- ANGELO!
- AS YOU WERE.
- SOFIA, HONEY.
YOU'RE THE FIRST PERSON
I'VE WANTED TO SEE TODAY.
BELLA.
- THIS IS THE LAST TIME,
ABSOLUTELY THE LAST TIME
I DRIVE WITH THAT
CRAZY CHAUFFEUR OF YOURS!
- JOHNNY ELBOWS?
- HE DROPPED ME OFF AT MASS
AND STAYED OUT FRONT
WITH THE MOTOR RUNNING!
- AH, IT'S A FORCE OF HABIT.
- YOU HAD TO FIRE OSCAR!
HE WAS A REAL CHAUFFEUR!
- FORGET ABOUT OSCAR.
WE GOT MORE IMPORTANT THINGS
TO TALK ABOUT.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER?
JESUS, MARY, AND JOSEPH!
MY BABY!
MY LITTLE BABY.
[Lisa sobbing]
- YOUR FATHER JUST TOLD ME.
- MAMA.
I'M SORRY, MAMA.
- OH, IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT.
- IT'S HIS FAULT!
- MY FAULT?
- YES!
YOU SUFFOCATED HER!
- YOU KEPT ME PRISONER UP HERE
LIKE RAPUNZEL!
- WELL, YOU CERTAINLY
AIN'T SNOW WHITE!
- LOOK AT THE EXAMPLE
YOU'VE SET.
FILLING THE HOUSE WITH THUGS,
GOONS, AND HIT MEN!
- ALL RIGHT, WELL, SOMETIMES
I HAD TO BRING
MY WORK HOME WITH ME.
- WHO DID THIS THING TO YOU?
TELL MAMA.
- DADDY KNOWS.
HE MET WITH HIM THIS MORNING.
- WELL, WHO IS IT?
- BETTER YOU HEAR IT
FROM YOUR OWN DAUGHTER'S LIPS.
- IT'S OSCAR.
both:
THE CHAUFFEUR!
[car horn blows]
- WHY YOU ACTIN' SO SURPRISED?
YOU KNEW.
- OF COURSE I KNEW!
I JUST HAD NO IDEA.
[doorbell rings]
BE RIGHT BACK.
- THERE YOU ARE.
I FOUND HIM.
- [snaps fingers]
WE GOTTA TALK.
- ANGELO, WE'VE GOTTA TALK.
OH, I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE BUSY.
- YOU MUST BE MRS. PROVOLONE.
WHAT AN HONOR.
- SOFIA, LITTLE ANTHONY,
MY ACCOUNTANT.
- AND FUTURE SON-IN-LAW.
I'VE JUST ASKED PERMISSION
TO MARRY YOUR DAUGHTER.
LISA?
- NO, DEAR, NOT LISA,
THE OTHER ONE.
- WHAT OTHER ONE?
- YOU KNOW,
THE OTHER ONE.
THE OTHER ONE THAT'S NOT LISA.
WHY DON'T YOU GO CHECK
ON THE GIRLS, DEAR?
- I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU HAD TWO DAUGHTERS.
- YEAH, THIS HOUSE
IS FULL OF SURPRISES TODAY.
LOOK, ANTHONY, I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU NOTICED,
BUT MY WIFE
WAS A LITTLE COOL TO YOU.
- I DID NOTICE.
IS THERE ANYTHING WRONG?
- YEAH, SHE THINKS
YOU'RE A FORTUNE HUNTER.
- OH, NO!
NOTHING COULD BE FURTHER
FROM THE TRUTH!
HOW CAN I CONVINCE YOUR WIFE
OF MY GOOD INTENTIONS?
- EASY. YOU KNOW
THAT 50 Gs YOU CHISELED FROM ME?
- AND PLAN TO GIVE TO YOUR
DAUGHTER AFTER WE'RE MARRIED.
- WELL, GIVE IT TO HER
BEFORE YOU'RE MARRIED.
[snaps fingers]
WRITE OUT A CHECK.
THAT WAY, MY WIFE WILL KNOW
YOU'RE NOT MARRYING LISA
JUST FOR HER MONEY.
- THERESA.
- YEAH, YEAH.
I'M ALWAYS GETTIN'
THESE TWO KIDS MIXED UP.
HERE, SIT DOWN.
- THERE'S A LITTLE PROBLEM.
- NO INK?
- I DIDN'T WANT
TO PUT THE MONEY IN A BANK.
YOU KNOW WHAT KIND OF SHAPE
THEY'RE IN THESE DAYS.
I CONVERTED IT
TO PRECIOUS STONES--
DIAMONDS, EMERALDS,
THAT KIND OF THING.
- THAT'S THE PERFECT
WEDDING GIFT.
YOU KNOW HOW WOMEN
LOVE JEWELS.
- I'LL GO GET IT RIGHT NOW.
- ANTHONY, IF YOU WANT,
I COULD HAVE ONE OF MY BOYS
ESCORT YOU.
AFTER ALL,
THAT'S A LOT OF ICE.
- OH, NO, NO, DON'T BOTHER.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK, DAD.
- I'LL BE WAITIN', SON.
YOU MISERABLE LITTLE PUNK.
ALDO,
WHERE'S THAT CHAUFFEUR?
- JOHNNY'S OUT
WAXIN' THE CADDY.
- NOT THAT LUG,
THE OTHER ONE--OSCAR.
- YOU FIRED HIM.
- I KNOW I FIRED HIM.
WHERE DOES HE LIVE?
- HOW SHOULD I KNOW
WHERE OSCAR LIVES?
- I KNOW WHERE HE LIVES.
- YEAH? WHERE?
- SOUTH SIDE.
- ALL RIGHT.
YOU TAKE A RIDE OUT THERE
WITH JOHNNY ELBOWS AND GRAB HIM!
- ONLY HE DON'T LIVE THERE
NO MORE.
- WHERE DOES HE LIVE NOW?
- HE JOINED THE ARMY
FOR A SIX-YEAR HITCH,
AND THEY SHIPPED HIM ABROAD.
- IT SEEMS HE WAS IN LOVE
WITH SOME SKIRT,
NEVER TOLD US WHO,
BUT THEY BROKE UP
BECAUSE HER FATHER
WAS A REAL PAIN IN THE ASS.
- OH, IS THAT SO?
- OH, YEAH.
AS MUCH AS HE LOVED HER,
HE COULDN'T BEAR HAVIN'
THIS CREEP AS A FATHER-IN-LAW.
- DON'T YOU EVER SHUT UP?
- WHAT'D I SAY?
- I HAVE GOT TO TALK TO YOU,
MR. PROVOLONE.
- LATER!
- MR. PROVOLONE,
I'M LEAVIN' YOU
TO GO TO THE UNDERWOODS.
- UNDERWOODS!
YOU'RE GOIN' TO WORK
FOR BRUCE?
- I'M MARRYIN' BRUCE.
- YOU'RE MARRYIN' BRUCE?
I FOUND HIM FIRST!
I MEAN FOR MY DAUGHTER.
- WE MET THE DAY
HE CALLED ON LISA.
OH...
IT WAS LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT.
- CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU'RE FIRED!
- YOU CAN'T FIRE ME.
I QUIT!
- TRY GETTIN' A REFERENCE
OUT OF ME, SISTER!
GREAT. MY MAID
GETS A MILLIONAIRE,
MY DAUGHTER
GETS A CHAUFFEUR.
- BETTER TELL TOOMEY
TO HIGHTAIL IT OVER HERE.
- YOU GOT IT TOO TIGHT!
EH, I MAKE IT MORE LOOSE.
- SHUT UP-A YOU FACE,
MUSSOLINI.
- COME ON, YOU GUYS.
I'M RUNNIN' OUT OF TIME.
- ANGELO.
CAN I TALK TO YOU ALONE?
- NEVER MIND THEM.
THEY ONLY HEAR IN ITALIAN.
- I JUST CAME
FROM LISA'S BEDROOM.
- YOU AND EVERYBODY ELSE.
- ANGELO,
OUR DAUGHTER IS DISGRACED
BEFORE THE EYES OF GOD.
YOU HAVE TO FIND OSCAR!
- OSCAR'S BEEN SCRATCHED.
HE JUMPED THE COUNTRY.
- BUT THE BABY NEEDS A FATHER!
- THE BABY'S GOT A FATHER.
WHAT WE NEED IS A HUSBAND.
- A HUSBAND, A HUSBAND--
WHERE WILL WE FIND A HUSBAND?
- NO LOOK AT US.
WE ALREADY MARRIED.
- SI, WE MARRIED REAL GOOD.
- I GOT TEN BAMBINOS.
HE GOT EIGHT.
- YOU NO GOT TEN BAMBINOS.
- I GOT TEN BAMBINOS.
- NO. WHO?
- I GOT ANNA MARIA.
I GOT SALVATORE.
I GOT FABRIZIO.
I GOT ANTONIO.
I GOT MARIO.
I GOT BIG LUIGI.
I GOT LITTLE LUIGI.
I GOT LUIGI JR.
I GOT GUISEPPE.
AND I GOT FIGARO.
- FIGARO NO YOURS.
FIGARO COME FROM THE MILKMAN.
- [laughing]
HE MAKE A JOKE.
- DID I ASK
FOR THE FINUCCI ROLL CALL?
both: SCUSI.
- YOU'RE SCUSED.
- WHAT ABOUT THAT BOY
WHO WAS HERE BEFORE?
DIDN'T HE WANT TO MARRY
OUR DAUGHTER?
- YEAH, BUT NOT LISA,
THE OTHER ONE.
- WHAT OTHER ONE?
- THE OTHER ONE
THAT'S NOT LISA!
- WE DON'T HAVE A DAUGHTER
- SOFIA, YOU THINK
I DON'T KNOW THAT?
- I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
BUT IF YOU LOVE ME,
IF YOU EVER LOVED ME,
YOU'LL FIND MY LITTLE GIRL
A HUSBAND!
- [sighs]
[car horns honking]
- HE'S BACK AGAIN,
FOR THE THIRD TIME,
AND NOW HE'S GOT
A LITTLE BLACK BAG.
- BREAK OUT THE JAVA
AND THE SINKERS, BOYS.
I THINK I'LL STICK AROUND.
[overlapping chatter]
- MAKE SURE THE STRIPES
LOOK STRAIGHT AS AN ARROW.
- HERE HE IS,
BACK BY POPULAR REQUEST.
- [snaps fingers]
FINUCCIS, OUT.
[Finuccis whispering]
- SHH, SHH, SHH.
[both arguing]
- SO, MR. PROVOLONE,
DO I HAVE PERMISSION
TO MARRY YOUR DAUGHTER NOW?
- MY SON.
- OH, MR. PROVOLONE,
YOU'VE MADE ME SO HAPPY.
- WHERE ARE YOU GOIN'?
- TO TELL THERESA
THE WONDERFUL NEWS.
- NOT SO FAST.
I'VE GOT SOME WONDERFUL NEWS
FOR YOU.
- WHAT COULD BE MORE WONDERFUL
THAN MARRYING YOUR DAUGHTER?
- HAVIN' HER BABY.
- THERESA'S PREGNANT?
- THERESA'S PREGNANT!
WHO'S THERESA?
- MY DAUGHTER, YOU SAP!
- I'VE GOTTA SEE HER.
- LIFE--
YOU KNOW, LIFE'S A FUNNY THING.
YOU'RE HERE ONE MINUTE...
[snaps fingers] GONE THE NEXT.
- AIN'T THAT THE TRUTH?
- NOW, YOU TAKE
LOUIE "THE LUG" MCGURK.
HE DIED TRAGICALLY AT 25.
- I'M 25.
WHAT HAPPENED?
- SOMEBODY
STEPPED ON HIS FINGERS.
- AND THAT KILLED HIM?
- HE WAS HANGIN'
FROM A WINDOW LEDGE
AT THE EDISON HOTEL AT THE TIME.
- THE POINT IS, SON,
THE LUG DIDN'T PLAN AHEAD,
AND THE GOVERNMENT
GOT EVERYTHING.
- POOR GUY.
- POOR WIDOW, MRS. "THE LUG."
NOW SHE'S SELLING APPLES.
MAKES YOU THINK.
- SURE DOES.
- NOW, WHAT IF SOMETHIN'
WERE TO HAPPEN TO YOU?
WHERE WOULD THAT LEAVE
MY DAUGHTER?
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
FIRST THING TOMORROW,
I'LL GET A LAWYER
AND PUT IT IN WRITING.
- SON, WE'RE FAMILY NOW.
WE DON'T NEED ANY LAWYERS.
HERE, JUST WRITE WHAT I SAY.
"I, ANTHONY ROSSANO"...
- WAIT A MINUTE,
WAIT A MINUTE.
I JUST THOUGHT OF SOMETHING.
- YOU'RE THINKIN'
WHEN YOU OUGHTA BE WRITIN'.
- IF SOMETHING
WAS TO HAPPEN TO ME,
HOW DO I KNOW YOU'LL GIVE
THESE JEWELS TO YOUR DAUGHTER?
- FAIR ENOUGH.
I'LL SIGN A STATEMENT TOO.
YOU SIGN YOURS FIRST,
AND THEN I'LL SIGN MINE.
- WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER NOW?
- MAYBE WE SHOULD SIGN
THEM TOGETHER.
- ALDO, YOU BE A WITNESS.
- AH, COME ON, SNAPS,
YOU KNOW THE RULE.
NEVER WITNESS NOTHIN'.
YOU LIVE LONGER.
- JUST DO IT.
ALL RIGHT, ON THREE.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
- "I, ANTHONY ROSSANO"...
- "I, SNAPS PROVOLONE"...
- "HEREBY DECLARE"...
- "AGREE TO GIVE $50,000"...
- "I AM THE FATHER"...
- "TO MY DAUGHTER
UPON HER MARRIAGE"...
- "OF MISS PROVOLONE'S CHILD."
- "TO ANTHONY ROSSANO."
- THERE.
- SIGN IT.
- YOU SIGN TOO.
- ALDO, YOU'RE THE WITNESS.
WITNESS!
- LOUIE "THE LUG"
WAS A WITNESS.
LOOK WHAT IT GOT HIM.
- QUIT SQUAWKIN'.
GIVE ME YOURS.
- YOU GIVE ME YOURS.
- ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL DO IT TOGETHER.
- GOOD.
VERY GOOD.
NOW FOR THE FUN PART.
I BELIEVE
YOU TWO KNOW EACH OTHER.
ALL RIGHT, CONNIE,
NEVER MIND ABOUT HER NOW.
GO BACK TO WATCHING
MY OTHER DAUGHTER.
[snaps fingers]
FINUCCIS!
- I HAVE SOMETHING TO TELL YOU.
- I KNOW WHAT IT IS.
- YOU DO?
- SIT DOWN, SWEETHEART.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE STANDING
IN YOUR CONDITION.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- YOU'RE HAVING A BABY.
YOUR FATHER TOLD ME.
- I AM NOT HAVING A BABY.
AND HE'S NOT MY FATHER.
- WHAT?
- MR. PROVOLONE--
HE'S NOT MY FATHER.
- DOES HE KNOW
THAT HE'S NOT YOUR FATHER?
- OF COURSE HE KNOWS
HE'S NOT MY FATHER.
WHAT KIND OF A QUESTION
IS THAT?
- THEN HE KNOWS
YOU'RE NOT HIS DAUGHTER?
- YES.
I LIED TO YOU, ANTHONY.
I'M SORRY.
- THAT SON OF A BITCH.
- WHAT'S WRONG?
- HE CONNED ME OUT OF HIS MONEY.
- ANTHONY, I ONLY DID IT
BECAUSE I LOVE YOU.
I WAS AFRAID I'D LOSE YOU.
- I'VE GOTTA GET IT BACK.
- GET WHAT BACK?
- THE MONEY, OF COURSE!
- YOU SEEM MORE INTERESTED
IN THIS MONEY
THAN YOU ARE IN ME.
- NO, NO, NO. IT--PLEASE.
I'VE JUST GOTTA THINK.
- I'M GLAD I FOUND OUT
WHAT YOU'RE REALLY LIKE
BEFORE IT WAS TOO LATE!
- [talking under breath]
[door slams]
- THERESA, COME BACK.
THERESA!
- THANK GOD I'M NOT PREGNANT!
- WHAT HAVE YOU TWO BEEN DOIN'
UP THERE?
- GET OUT OF MY WAY.
- WHY, I OUGHTA--
- GET OUTTA HERE!
- THERESA!
THERESA, COME BACK!
- THERE'S TOO MUCH ACTIVITY.
SNAPS IS UP TO SOMETHIN'.
- IT'S TOO QUIET.
PROVOLONE
IS UP TO SOMETHING.
- BRAVO.
THIS SUIT, SHE A WORK OF ART.
- OF COURSE.
SHE'S A FINUCCI.
- AH, YOU FINUCCI'D ME
PRETTY GOOD ON THIS ONE--
150 BUCKS.
[chuckles]
I'LL JUST WRITE YOU BOYS OUT
A CHECK.
- I DEMAND TO SPEAK WITH YOU,
MR. PROVOLONE.
- FINUCCIS...
[snaps fingers] OUT!
[muttering to themselves]
- AH!
HA HA.
- SO WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU, KID?
- I GUESS YOU'RE PRETTY PLEASED
WITH YOURSELF.
- MY FATHER
WOULD HAVE BEEN PROUD.
I GOT MY MONEY BACK,
AND NOBODY GOT SHOT.
- NOT SO FAST.
I'VE BEEN TRICKED.
- I WOULDN'T DO THAT
IF I WERE YOU.
- YOU FORGET, MR. PROVOLONE,
YOU'RE GOING STRAIGHT TODAY.
- YOU'RE RIGHT,
I AM GOING STRAIGHT TODAY...
BUT THEY'RE NOT.
- AND WHO ARE THEY?
- YOU DON'T RECOGNIZE
THE FINUCCIS? SICILIANS.
THE MOST VICIOUS CONTRACT
KILLERS IN THE COUNTRY.
- THEY DON'T LOOK
THAT VICIOUS TO ME.
- [speaking Italian]
[arguing in Italian]
- DON'T LET THAT FOOL YOU.
ONE WORD FROM ME,
AND IT'S...KRRR...KRRR!
HMM?
BUT, ANTHONY, IF IT'S THE JEWELS
YOU WANT, YOU CAN HAVE 'EM.
JUST KEEP YOUR PART OF THE
BARGAIN AND MARRY MY DAUGHTER.
- THE REAL ONE?
- OF COURSE THE REAL ONE!
LISA PROVOLONE.
- BUT I'VE NEVER EVEN MET HER!
- NOT ACCORDING TO THIS.
IT'LL HOLD UP IN ANY COURT.
- GIVE ME THAT!
- THIS DOCUMENT SAYS
THAT YOU ARE THE FATHER
OF MY DAUGHTER'S BABY.
- OH, NOW YOU'RE TELLING ME
THAT YOUR REAL DAUGHTER
IS PREGNANT?
- YOU GOT A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
- I AM NOT MARRYING LISA.
I AM MARRYING THERESA!
- ANTHONY, ANTHONY,
LITTLE ANTHONY...
WE ARE TALKIN'
ABOUT MY BABY'S BABY.
- FORGET IT!
- FINE!
FINUCCIS!
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
CALL OFF YOUR DOGS.
- FINUCCIS, SIT!
WISE DECISION.
NOW, WAIT HERE.
I'LL GET YOUR FIANCEE.
IT'S ABOUT TIME
YOU TWO KIDS MET.
[plays notes]
[playing bluesy music]
¶ ¶
[tempo increases]
[strikes off-chord]
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- OH...
SCUSI.
COULD YOU TELL SIGNORE PROVOLONE
WE IN A HURRY?
WE GOTTA DO
ANOTHER GUY 11:00.
- YOU DO MORE THAN ONE A DAY?
- OH, SOMETIME WE DO SIX,
EIGHT A DAY.
- IT'S A CUTTHROAT BUSINESS,
AND IF WE GET BACKED UP,
WE GOTTA WORK WEEKENDS.
- AND WE NO LIKE THAT.
- NO, WE FAMILY MEN.
- YOU TREAT IT LIKE
IT'S A NORMAL BUSINESS.
- [clicking tongue]
TO US...IT'S ART.
SHOW HIM THE PICTURE.
- WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THIS?
- YOU GUYS DID THIS?
- WHO ELSE?
THAT'S A FINUCCI.
OH, WE GET PLENTY BUSINESS
FROM THIS PICTURE, HUH?
- MAYBE SOMEDAY
WE DO YOU TOO, HUH?
AND WHEN WE
GET THROUGH WITH YOU,
NOBODY GONNA RECOGNIZE YOU.
CHE COSA C'E?
YOU LOOK A LITTLE PALE.
- YOU OKAY?
- NOW, THIS GUY'S WILLING
TO MARRY YOU, SO BE NICE.
- BUT I WANT OSCAR!
- I WANT HIM MORE THAN YOU DO,
BUT HE'S ON THE LAM,
AND ANTHONY'S
TAKING THE RAP FOR HIM.
- THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHATEVER HAPPENED TO LOVE?
WHATEVER HAPPENED TO ROMANCE?
- WHATEVER HAPPENED TO WAITING
UNTIL THE WEDDING NIGHT?
- ANGELO, PLEASE!
NOT IN FRONT OF THE HELP.
- TRUST ME, HE'S NO HELP.
CONNIE, GO WRAP YOUR TEETH
AROUND SOME LUNCH.
GIRLS...
LISA, THIS IS YOUR
HUSBAND-TO-BE, ANTHONY ROSSANO.
LISA.
- HELLO.
- HELLO, LISA.
- YOU SEE THAT?
YOU'RE HITTIN' IT OFF ALREADY.
- SOMETIMES ARRANGED MARRIAGES
WORK OUT THE BEST.
- MM.
- OSCAR WAS CUTER.
- WHO'S OSCAR?
- THE CHAUFFEUR.
- YOU MEAN SHE'S HAVING
THE CHAUFFEUR'S BABY?
- WHY DON'T YOU JUST PHONE IT IN
TO WALTER WINCHELL?
- ANGELO, LET'S LEAVE
THE TWO LOVEBIRDS ALONE.
- GOOD IDEA.
YOU TWO GET TO KNOW
ALL ABOUT EACH OTHER,
BUT, LISA, MAKE IT QUICK.
I GOT PEOPLE COMIN' AT NOON.
- [snaps fingers]
- THAT'S THE BEST HUSBAND
YOU COULD FIND?
- HE PASSED THE PHYSICAL.
HE'S BREATHIN'.
[snaps fingers]
FINUCCIS.
- SO YOU'RE PREGNANT
WITH OSCAR'S BABY?
- WOULD I BE MARRYING YOU
IF I WASN'T?
- YOU DON'T WANNA MARRY ME.
I'M IN LOVE WITH SOMEONE ELSE.
- SO AM I.
- THEN WHY ARE WE
GOING THROUGH WITH THIS?
- BECAUSE I'D DO ANYTHING
TO GET OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
- THAT MAKES TWO OF US.
- I WANNA--I WANNA GO
ON AN AFRICAN SAFARI.
I WANNA RUN WITH THE BULLS
IN SPAIN.
I WANNA GO TO THE TOP
OF THE EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
- AND WHERE AM I
DURING ALL THIS--
BABYSITTING OSCAR'S KID?
- YOU ALWAYS THIS NASTY?
- YES!
GET USED TO IT!
- [gasps]
I'M MARRYING A BRUTE.
I NEVER WANNA SEE
YOUR FACE AGAIN--
UNTIL THE WEDDING!
- THAT'S FINE WITH ME!
AND SEPARATE HONEYMOONS!
- FINE!
- SEE YOU IN CHURCH!
- HMPH!
[doorbell rings]
- IT'S PROBABLY JUDGE CRATER.
OH, HI, DR. POOLE.
COME ON IN.
THE BOSS BEEN EXPECTING YOU.
- [chuckling]
ALDO, DO YOU REALIZE
WHAT YOU JUST DID?
- WHAT?
- YOU USED THE PAST PARTICIPLE
WITHOUT A MODIFIER.
- I DID?
WHAT'S THE RAP ON THAT?
COOL YOUR HEELS, DOC.
HE'LL BE RIGHT WITH YOU.
- MARVELOUS.
ALDO IS A TREASURE TROVE
OF LINGUISTIC ANOMALIES.
- I "HOID" THAT.
- MIDDLESEX.
- WHAT?
- YOU'RE FROM MIDDLESEX COUNTY
IN NEW JERSEY.
AM I RIGHT?
- YEAH.
NEW BRUNSWICK.
- I KNEW IT.
YOU SEE,
THE NEW JERSEY ACCENT
BECOMES INCREASINGLY NASAL
THE FURTHER SOUTH ONE GOES.
- THAT'S
AN AMAZING TALENT, DOCTOR.
HAVE YOU EVER THOUGHT
OF WORKING CARNIVALS?
- YOUNG MAN,
I'VE MADE A SERIOUS STUDY
OF THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE.
IN MY TRAVELS, I'VE UNCOVERED
2,700 SUBDIALECTS
IN THE UNITED STATES ALONE.
NOW, YOU TAKE THE ATTENUATED
VOWELS OF THE EAST TEXANS--
- ALL THAT TRAVEL MUST CUT
INTO YOUR HOME LIFE, DOCTOR.
- WELL, I DON'T SPEND
AS MUCH TIME WITH MOTHER
AS I WLD LIKE.
BUT SHE'S GOT THE CATS.
- A BRILLIANT SCHOLAR
LIKE YOURSELF IS STILL SINGLE?
- OH, WORK
HAS ALWAYS COME FIRST.
THIS WEEKEND
I'M OFF TO APPALACHIA
TO STUDY
REGIONAL COLLOQUIALISMS
AMONG THE COAL-MINING
COMMUNITY.
- WOULD YOU EXCUSE ME
A MINUTE, DOCTOR?
YOU'LL BE HERE FOR A WHILE,
WON'T YOU?
- OH, YES.
I'LL BE GIVING MR. PROVOLONE
HIS ELOCUTION LESSON.
- GOOD NEWS--WE DON'T HAVE
TO MARRY EACH OTHER.
I FOUND SOMEONE ELSE.
- WHO?
- SOMEONE WHO'S HANDSOME
AND INTELLIGENT
AND WORSHIPS THE GROUND
YOU WALK UPON...DR. POOLE.
- [laughing]
DR. POOLE.
SAY, WHAT'S THE GAG?
HE'S OLD ENOUGH
TO BE MY FATHER.
- MORE IMPORTANTLY, HE'S OLD
ENOUGH TO BE YOUR BABY'S FATHER.
- WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
HE WANTS TO MARRY ME?
- BECAUSE HE LOVES YOU
PASSIONATELY.
HE JUST TOLD ME.
- BUT HE'S NEVER SAID
ANYTHING.
- IRONIC, ISN'T IT?
A MAN WHOSE LIFE
IS DEVOTED TO WORDS,
AND HE CAN'T PUT TOGETHER
THE THREE MOST IMPORTANT ONES.
- THAT'S SO TOUCHING.
- I KNEW YOU'D SEE IT MY WAY.
STAY RIGHT HERE.
- FINUCCIS IN, FINUCCIS OUT,
FINUCCIS IN.
HE GIVE ME AGITA.
- LISA...
ANTHONY'S TRYING TO TELL ME
THAT NOW YOU'RE IN LOVE
WITH DR. POOLE.
- YES, I AM.
- YOU SEE?
WHAT?
- OH, DADDY, YES.
HE'S SO SWEET, SO INTELLIGENT,
SO CULTURED...
NOT LIKE
SOME OTHER FELLAS I KNOW.
- WELL, PUT POOLE
OUT OF YOUR MIND.
YOU'RE MARRYING ANTHONY.
- BUT I LOVE THORNTON!
- OH, SO NOW IT'S THORNTON?
- [sobbing]
- OH, STOP THAT BAWLIN',
WILL YA?
- HE'S THE ONLY SENSITIVE MAN
I'VE EVER MET.
- WHAT ARE YOU SAYIN'?
I'M NOT SENSITIVE?
- [braying sobs]
- ALL RIGHT, LISA.
LISA, STOP--WILL YOU STOP--
[snaps fingers]
- [squeaky inhale, stops crying]
- IF IT'S POOLE YOU WANT,
IT'S POOLE YOU'LL GET,
BUT, LISA, YOU GOT TO CROSS
THE FINISH LINE ON THIS ONE.
HE'S YOUR THIRD FIANCE TODAY,
AND IT'S NOT EVEN LUNCH YET!
- LOOK, MR. PROVOLONE,
NOW THAT SHE HAS A HUSBAND,
CAN I HAVE BACK
THE STATEMENT I SIGNED?
- FORGET ABOUT IT.
I'M KEEPING YOU ON THE BENCH
IN CASE THIS GUY
DOESN'T COME THROUGH.
GOOD MORNIN', DOC.
- NOW, NOW, MR. PROVOLONE.
WHERE ARE THOSE Gs?
- IN HERE.
- NO, NO.
YOU'RE NOT ENUNCIATING.
"GOOD MORNING, DR. POOLE."
- OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
DON'T YOU HAVE
SOMETHIN' TO DO?
- YES, I DO,
AS A MATTER OF FACT.
GOOD-BYE, MR. PROVOLONE.
GOOD-BYE, DR. POOLE.
- [snaps fingers]
- NOW, LOOK,
THAT GUY'S LEAVIN' AGAIN.
- AND HERE COMES A PRIEST.
- ENTER AT YOUR
OWN RISK, FATHER.
- ALDO, HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
AT MASS LATELY.
- OH, REALLY, FATHER?
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHY.
- NOW, REMEMBER,
MR. PROVOLONE,
SPEECH IS MAN'S
MOST IMPORTANT TOOL
FOR THE CONVEYANCE
OF THOUGHT.
- YEAH, DOC, BUT WHEN
AM I GONNA START SOUNDIN'
LIKE A BANKER?
- AFTER ME...
[rolling Rs] ROUND THE ROUGH
AND RUGGED ROCKS,
THE RAGGED RASCAL RUDELY RAN.
- ROUND THE ROUGH
AND RUGGED ROCKS,
THE RAGGED RA--
- ROUND THE ROUGH
AND RUGGED ROCKS.
THE RAGGED...
- ROUND
THE ROUGH AND RASCAL,
THE RAGGED--
AW, LOOK, DOC,
I JUST CAN'T DO IT.
I'LL NEVER LEARN
TO SPEAK GOOD.
- DO NOT DESPAIR,
MR. PROVOLONE.
LET'S TRY A NEW LINE
OF ATTACK, SHALL WE?
AFTER ME...
ROCCO THE RUM RUNNER RUBBED OUT
RICO THE RAT WITH HIS ROSCOE
FOR ROBBING
HIS RUM-RUNNING RECEIPTS.
CAN YOU SAY THAT?
- ROCCO THE RUM RUNNER
RUBBED OUT RICO THE RAT
WITH HIS ROSCOE
FOR ROBBIN'
HIS RUM-RUNNIN' RECEIPTS!
- YOU DID IT!
- SURE.
YOU FINALLY COME UP
WITH SOMETHIN' THAT MADE SENSE.
- EXCUSE ME, MR. PROVOLONE.
I'LL BE GOIN' NOW,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
- SO WHAT'S KEEPIN' YA?
- WELL...
THERE'S THE LITTLE MATTER
OF A WEEK'S PAY
YOU'LL BE OWIN' ME.
- SHE SHOULD PAY ME
FOR INTRODUCING HER
TO BRUCE UNDERWOOD.
- I'M GLAD I'LL NO LONGER BE
WORKIN' IN THIS HOUSE.
FROM NOW ON, I'LL BE HAVIN'
SERVANTS OF ME OWN.
- YOU'LL FIND OUT
WHAT A PICNIC THAT IS!
- SHOCKING INSOLENCE.
I WOULD'VE TERMINATED HER
IMMEDIATELY.
- I CAN'T DO THAT ANYMORE.
THE BEST I COULD DO
IS FIRE HER.
LISTEN, DOC,
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT A LITTLE DIFFICULTY
MY DAUGHTER'S HAVIN'.
- REALLY?
SHE SEEMS TO HAVE
SUCH NICELY ROUNDED DIPHTHONGS.
- THAT'S WHAT GOT HER
INTO THIS JAM.
YOU SEE, MY DAUGHTER'S
TURNING 18,
AND SHE WANTS TO GET MARRIED.
- WELL, SHE'S CHARMING.
WHO'S THE LUCKY MAN?
- YOU ARE, DOC.
- WELL, I'M FLAT--
WHAT?
- YOU'RE NOT MARRIED
OR ANYTHING, ARE YOU?
- WELL, NO, OF COURSE NOT.
- AND HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT KIDS?
- CHILDREN?
WELL, I LOVE--
- THEN IT'S SETTLED!
- SETTLED?
BUT I HARDLY KNOW THE GIRL.
- LET ME SWEETEN THE POT.
NOW, THERE MUST BE SOMETHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU,
SOME...
DREAM THAT YOU GOT.
- WELL,
NOW THAT YOU MENTION IT,
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO TAKE
MOTHER TO BADEN-BADEN.
THERE'S A DOCTOR THERE
WHO'S DOING SIMPLY MIRACULOUS
THINGS WITH GALLBLADDERS.
- [snaps fingers]
HER GALLBLADDER'S
ON THE NEXT BOAT.
ANYTHING ELSE?
- UM, WELL...
THEN THERE'S THE THORNTON POOLE
SCHOOL OF LINGUISTICS.
- I CAN SEE IT FROM HERE.
DEAL, DOC?
- UH, I-I DON'T KNOW.
EVENTS ARE MOVING SO FAST.
- HERE.
THIS IS THE CLINCHER.
- GOD.
WHAT'S THIS?
- YOUR MOTHER'S GALLBLADDER,
THE LINGUISTICS SCHOOL,
ALL YOUR DREAMS.
LOOK!
- I'M A LITTLE CONFUSED.
- I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
NORA!
- WHERE TO, LADY?
- REGENCY GARDENS.
- NORA!
NORA!
NOR...
RA!
- NOW PROVOLONE'S COMIN' OUT
WITH A BLACK BAG.
- WHAT DO YOU THINK'S IN IT?
- BAG MONEY.
WHAT ELSE?
THAT DOES IT.
I'M CALLIN' FOR THE WARRANT.
- DAMN.
SON OF A...
GUN, GOSH ALMIGHTY.
CHEESE AND CRACKERS!
- SO SORRY TO KEEP YOU WAITING,
FATHER CLEMENTE.
ANGELO, YOU REMEMBER
FATHER CLEMENTE?
- MORNIN', FATHER.
AND THANKS AGAIN FOR THE SWELL
JOB YOU DID ON PAPA'S FUNERAL.
- I KNOW HE'D BE PROUD THAT YOU
KEPT YOUR PROMISE TO HIM.
- THE FATHER IS HERE TO COLLECT
FOR THE BUILDING FUND.
- OH, BY THE WAY,
CONGRATULATIONS
ON YOUR DAUGHTER MARRYING
BRUCE UNDERWOOD.
- UH, I'M AFRAID THERE'S BEEN
A CHANGE, FATHER.
SHE'S NOW MARRYING A NICE
ITALIAN BOY, ANTHONY ROSSANO.
- THAT'S ALL FOR THE BETTER.
NOTHING LIKE
A BIG ITALIAN WEDDING.
ANTHONY ROSSANO!
- WELL, FORGET ANTHONY.
SHE'S NOT MARRYING HIM ANYMORE.
- WHAT?
- W-WELL, THAT'S A SHAME.
BUT SHE'S YOUNG.
SOMEDAY SHE'LL FIND
THE RIGHT ONE.
- SHE'S FOUND THE RIGHT ONE.
- WHO?
- DR. POOLE!
- DR. POOLE?
- HELLO!
- GET BACK IN THE ROOM!
- LOOKS LIKE
A NICE YOUNG MAN.
- WHY IS SHE MARRYING DR. POOLE?
SHE BARELY KNOWS HIM.
- SHE BARELY KNEW
THE CHAUFFEUR TOO.
- DON'T DRAG OUT OSCAR
IN FRONT OF THE FATHER!
- WHO'S OSCAR?
- WHY ISN'T SHE
MARRYING ANTHONY?
- BECAUSE ANTHONY'S
MARRYING THERESA.
- WHO'S THERESA?
- LOOK,
IT'S REALLY VERY SIMPLE,
BUT I AIN'T GOT TIME
TO EXPLAIN IT.
I GOT TO CALL NORA.
- WHO'S NORA?
- OUR MAID.
- EX-MAID!
- NOW YOU FIRED THE MAID?
- NO, SHE QUIT TO MARRY
BRUCE UNDERWOOD!
- WHEN DID THAT HAPPEN?
- I DON'T KNOW!
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN MY VEST
AND MY PANTS.
- WHAT?
- THIS IS ALL VERY CONFUSING.
- WELL, FATHER,
IT'S ONE
OF THEM MYSTERIES IN LIFE
YOU JUST GOTTA ACCEPT
ON FAITH.
I GOTTA RUN.
- FATHER, WHY DON'T YOU
GO INTO THE KITCHEN
AND HAVE A CUP OF TEA
WHILE I CLEAR THIS MATTER UP?
- SORRY TO BOTHER YOU, BRUCE.
NORA TOOK THE WRONG BAG.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
YES. WOULD YOU MIND
SENDING YOUR MAN AROUND
AND BRING THE BAG BACK?
YEAH, IT'S SNAPS PROVOLONE.
WHO THE HELL YOU THINK IT IS?
- WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU COULDN'T MAKE IT
ON THE OUTSIDE?
- I CAME TO RETURN
THIS SUITCASE
AND COLLECT ME OWN.
- IS THIS IT?
- YES.
I REALIZED THAT ONE WASN'T MINE
WHEN I TRIED TO OPEN IT.
- GO ON. BEAT IT.
WE GOT BANKERS COMIN',
AND WE DON'T NEED
NO RIFFRAFF AROUND HERE.
- SUGAR?
- OH, NO.
THANK YOU.
WHO TOLD YOU
I WAS IN LOVE WITH YOU?
- ANTHONY.
- BUT I THOUGHT
YOU WERE IN LOVE WITH ME.
- WHO TOLD YOU THAT?
- YOUR FATHER.
- OH.
AND DID HE TELL YOU
I WAS PREGNANT?
- NO, HE DIDN--
YOU'RE PREGNANT?
- NO. I JUST TOLD HIM THAT
SO I COULD MARRY OSCAR.
- WHO'S OSCAR?
- OUR EX-CHAUFFEUR.
YOU SEE, I'D DO ANYTHING
TO GET OUT OF THIS HOUSE!
- OH, I DO KNOW
HOW YOU FEEL.
- [laughs] OF COURSE.
YOU'VE MET MY FATHER.
- OH, NO.
I WAS THINKING OF MY MOTHER.
SHE CAN BE SO...
POSSESSIVE.
- THEN YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M GOING THROUGH, DR. POOLE?
- THORNTON.
Y-YES, I DO.
LISA...
AT THE RISK
OF BEING FORWARD...
- YES, THORNTON?
- YOUR DICTION
IS SURPRISINGLY GOOD,
CONSIDERING YOUR GENEALOGY.
- THAT'S THE SWEETEST THING
ANYBODY'S EVER SAID TO ME...
THORNTON.
[both giggling]
[doorbell rings]
- THAT MUST BE THE CHAUFFEUR
TO PICK UP THE UNDERWEAR.
THERE IT IS.
[snaps fingers]
I GOT IT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'
BACK HERE?
- WHAT'S HE DOIN'
BACK THERE?
- I SEE YOU'VE
STILL GOT THE JEWELS.
- YEAH, SURE.
YEAH, SURE.
I WOULDN'T LET THESE BABIES
OUT OF MY SIGHT.
- THIS MORNING
I HAD EVERYTHING--
THE JEWELS, THERESA.
NOW I HAVE NOTHING.
- WELL, DON'T TAKE IT
TOO HARD.
- I CAN'T EVEN CALL HER,
BECAUSE SHE NEVER TOLD ME
HER REAL NAME OR ADDRESS.
- CONSIDER YOURSELF LUCKY.
- I'LL MAKE YOU
A DEAL, MR. P.
- WHAT KIND OF DEAL?
- WELL, I'VE BECOME ATTACHED
TO THOSE JEWELS.
THEY REMIND ME OF THERESA.
I'D LIKE TO BUY THEM BACK
FROM YOU FOR $50,000.
- NOW, WHERE'D YOU COME UP
WITH ANOTHER 50,000 SMACKERS?
- I STOLE IT FROM YOU.
- CONNIE!
[quick footsteps]
- WHAT IS IT, BOSS?
YOU TOOK MY GAT.
- NOW YOU'RE TRYIN'
TO TELL ME
YOU STOLE ANOTHER 50,000 CLAMS
SINCE THE LAST TIME I SAW YOU?
- REMEMBER THAT DUMMY
CORPORATION I SET UP FOR YOU
TO HIDE
YOUR PROTECTION INCOME?
- YEAH.
- REMEMBER WHO YOU MADE
TREASURER AS A BEARD?
- YOU DIDN'T.
- I JUST WROTE OUT A CHECK
TO MYSELF.
AS TREASURER,
THE BANK ASKED ME NO QUESTIONS.
- ONLY A RAT WOULD STEAL
ANOTHER GUY'S EXTORTION MONEY.
- HERE'S MY OFFER.
YOU GIVE ME BACK THE JEWELS
THAT ARE RIGHTFULLY MINE,
AND I'LL GIVE YOU BACK
THE MONEY, WHICH ISN'T.
- ALL RIGHT.
I GUESS YOU OUTSMARTED ME.
YOU GIVE ME THAT MONEY,
AND I'LL GIVE YOU THESE JEWELS.
- IT'S OUT IN THE CAR.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
AND I WANT THAT DOCUMENT BACK
THAT I SIGNED TOO.
- NO PROBLEM.
GOT IT RIGHT HERE.
I GOT HIM.
THIS TIME I GOT HIM.
- ANOTHER DROP...
IN BROAD DAYLIGHT!
- GIVE ME THE BAG.
- LET'S EXCHANGE THEM
AT THE SAME TIME.
GOOD IDEA.
- THAT'S IT.
I'M CALLIN' THE GENTLEMEN
OF THE PRESS.
I WANT 'EM TO SEE ME
MAKE THIS PINCH.
- EVERYTHING OKAY, BOSS?
- WHY DON'T YOU MAKE SOME NOISE
WHEN YOU WALK?
- ANGELO.
COME UP TO YOUR OFFICE.
WE HAVE TO TALK.
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
CONNIE!
- YEAH, BOSS?
- WILL YOU STOP EATIN'
AND LISTEN UP?
TAKE THIS BAG AND BRING IT
INTO THE LIBRARY.
AND NO MATTER WHAT YOU DO,
DON'T TAKE YOUR EYES OFF
THIS BAG EVEN FOR A SECOND.
GET ME?
- YEAH, BOSS.
- I JUST CALLED
THE MAID SERVICE,
AND THEY'RE SENDING
SOMEONE OVER.
- YOU GOT ME UP HERE
FOR THAT?
- ANGELO, NOBODY
WANTS TO WORK FOR YOU.
NOW, I WANT YOU TO BE NICER
TO THIS WOMAN
THAN YOU WERE TO NORA.
- NORA?
SHE'S MARRYING
INTO THE UNDERWOOD FORTUNE.
I OUGHTA GET A COMMISSION.
[Thornton and Lisa giggling]
- HEY, TOOMEY.
- THIS TIME IT'S A CHAUFFEUR.
HE'S GOT BAGMEN
ALL OVER THE CITY.
- WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU, GENERAL?
- MR. UNDERWOOD SENT ME
TO RETURN
MR. PROVOLONE'S SUITCASE.
- THANKS.
- UND...
I'M HERE TO COLLECT
MISS NORA'S SUITCASE.
- OH, RIGHT.
I THINK HE PUT IT
IN THE LIBRARY.
PARK IT IN HERE, FRITZ.
SITTEN SIE.
HERE YOU GO.
GIVE MY REGARDS
TO THE KAISER.
- I PROMISE
I'LL BE NICE TO THE HELP.
- I'M GOING TO DRESS
FOR LUNCH.
- I LOVE TALKING
TO YOU, THORNTON.
YOU'RE SO DEEP-DISH.
- LISA, I'LL BE LEAVING
NEXT MONTH ON THE ILE DE FRANCE
FOR A LINGUISTICS SYMPOSIUM
IN BRUSSELS.
- BRUSSELS?
THE ONE IN EUROPE?
- YES.
- DO SEND ME A POSTCARD.
YOU CAN ADDRESS IT HERE,
IN CARE OF MY GILDED CAGE.
- I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'D CONSIDER--
WELL, I MEAN TO SAY...
I-I-I CAN'T ASK.
- COME ON.
SPILL IT.
- I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU WOULD ACCOMPANY ME.
- WILL I?
- DR. POOLE!
[snaps fingers]
GET IN HERE. WE GOTTA TALK.
- PLEASE FORGIVE ME.
- OKAY, DOC, SIT DOWN.
NOW, WHERE WERE WE?
OH, YEAH.
I MADE YOU AN OFFER EARLIER
TO MARRY MY DAUGHTER.
- YES.
IN EXCHANGE FOR A BAG
OF WOMEN'S UNDERWEAR.
- NIX THE UNDERWEAR.
IT NEVER HAPPENED.
NOW, THE OFFER STILL STANDS.
AND ANYBODY'LL TELL YOU
THAT SNAPS PROVOLONE'S WORD
IS HIS BOND.
- THAT'S RIGHT, DOC.
EVEN IN THE OLD DAYS,
HE WAS KNOWN
AS AN HONEST CROOK.
- THAT'S AN OXYMORON.
- GEE, DOC, YOU SHOULDN'T
OUGHTA SAID THAT.
- LEAVE CONNIE ALONE.
HE DOES THE BEST HE CAN.
- I'M SORRY.
- OKAY, DOC,
HERE'S THE DEAL.
MARRY MY DAUGHTER,
AND YOU CAN USE
ALL THE DOUGH IN THIS BAG TO
START YOUR LINGUISTICS SCHOOL.
MOST MEN SPEND
THEIR WHOLE LIVES
TRYIN' TO GET THEIR HANDS
ON WHAT'S IN HERE.
- MM. THAT'S RIGHT,
MR. PROVOLONE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN SO MUCH MONEY.
[chuckles]
LOOK...
HERE'S MONEY, AND...
[clears throat]
AND HERE'S MORE MONEY.
AND--OH!
LOOK...
HERE'S A LOVELY NEW $20 BILL.
- DR. POOLE,
WOULD YOU BE SO KIND
AS TO STEP INTO THE GARDEN
WHILE I HAVE A CONFERENCE
WITH MY ASSOCIATE?
[door opens, closes]
PLEASE...
CORRECT ME IF I AM WRONG,
BUT DID I
OR DID I NOT TELL YOU
TO KEEP AN EYE
ON THIS PARTICULAR BAG?
- I DID.
I WATCHED THE BAG OF UNDERWEAR
THE WHOLE TIME.
- IT WASN'T UNDERWEAR
WHEN I LEFT!
IT WAS 50 GRAND IN CASH!
POOLE WAS RIGHT.
YOU ARE AN OX AND A MORON!
- HOW DID 50 GRAND
CHANGE INTO UNDERWEAR?
- THAT'S WHAT
I'M ASKIN' YOU!
- MAYBE IT WAS A MIRACLE,
YOU KNOW,
LIKE THE LOAVES
AND THE FISHES?
- LISA, COME WITH ME.
LET'S GET
OUT OF THIS MADHOUSE.
- WHATEVER YOU SAY, BABY.
- "BABY"!
- SNAPS, ARE YOU SURE
THERE WAS CASH IN THAT BAG?
- YEAH.
LITTLE ANTHONY STOLE IT.
- IF LITTLE ANTHONY STOLE IT,
THEN HE'S GOT IT.
- NO, YOU BLOCKHEAD.
HE STOLE IT,
THEN HE GAVE IT BACK TO ME.
- WHY'D HE GIVE IT BACK TO YOU?
- TO BUY BACK THE JEWELS.
- WHAT JEWELS?
- THE JEWELS HE STOLE FROM ME.
- HE STOLE JEWELS
FROM YOU TOO?
- YEAH, SO HE COULD
MARRY MY DAUGHTER.
- LISA.
- NOT LISA, THERESA.
- HOW COME NOBODY'S NEVER MET
THIS DAUGHTER THERESA?
- BECAUSE SHE'S NOT
MY DAUGHTER, CAPISCE?
- YEAH, YOUR DAUGHTER'S
NOT YOUR DAUGHTER,
AND THE CASH THAT USED TO BE
THE JEWELS IS NOW UNDERWEAR.
- NOW YOU GOT IT!
- I GOT IT!
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT!
- I'M BACK.
- QUELLE SURPRISE.
TAKE A SEAT.
THE NURSE'LL CALL YOUR NUMBER.
THE SKIRT IS BACK.
- WHAT SKIRT?
NORA?
- NO.
THE OTHER ONE--THERESA.
- YOU REMEMBER, BOSS, THE ONE
THAT'S NOT YOUR DAUGHTER.
- KEEP HER ON ICE.
I'M LOOKIN' FOR SOMETHIN'.
- WHAT?
- A BAG JUST LIKE THIS ONE.
- AH, DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
I GAVE IT BACK
TO UNDERWOOD'S CHAUFFEUR.
- YOU DID WHAT?
- IT WAS SITTIN' HERE
IN THE LIBRARY BEFORE,
SO I SWITCHED
THE BAGS FOR YA.
- AND WHERE WAS EINSTEIN?
- WAS CONNIE IN HERE?
CONNIE, WAS YOU IN HERE?
I DIDN'T SEE HIM.
- WHY DON'T YOU GO STAND OVER
THERE NEXT TO YOUR GIRLFRIEND?
AH...MUSH!
UNDERWEAR.
UNDERWEAR? UND--
UNDERWOOD.
UNDERWOOD. UNDERWOOD.
- MR. PROVOLONE
WILL SEE YOU IN THE LIBRARY.
CONNIE?
- COME ON.
- AND NOW HE'S BACK AGAIN
FOR ANOTHER DROP.
AND YOU KNUCKLEHEADS THOUGHT
THAT SNAPS WAS GOIN' STRAIGHT.
[doorbell rings]
[rings]
- OH, THAT'S OKAY.
I'LL GET IT!
[rings]
WELL, WELL,
THE MAN WHO STARTED IT ALL.
- LOOK, UNDERWOOD,
YOUR CHAUFFEUR
SNATCHED THE WRONG BAG!
WELL, DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT,
AND PRONTO!
NOW, WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
- CAN WE TALK IN PRIVATE?
- CONNIE, AM-SCRAY.
- CAN'T I STICK AROUND, BOSS?
EVERY TIME I LEAVE,
I FALL BEHIND.
- ALL RIGHT,
STAY, BUT SHUT UP.
- MR. PROVOLONE,
I'M DESPERATE.
I'VE DONE A STUPID THING.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
YOU ALREADY TOLD ME.
- NO, I MEAN,
I WALKED OUT ON ANTHONY,
THE ONLY MAN I'VE EVER LOVED.
- HONEY...
[snaps fingers]
THAT'S THE FIRST SMART MOVE
YOU'VE MADE.
- I LOOKED FOR HIM EVERYWHERE.
I TRIED HIS APARTMENT,
AND HE WASN'T THERE.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE
I CAN FIND HIM?
- NO.
BUT WHEREVER HE IS,
HE'S PROBABLY STEALING
ANOTHER 50 Gs FROM ME.
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I HAVE ANOTHER APPOINTMENT.
I MAY HAVE AN IDEA
WHERE HE IS.
- WHERE?
- CLOSER THAN I THOUGHT.
NOW, I WANT YOU TO STAY IN HERE
AND DON'T COME OUT.
YOU OWE ME THIS, SISTER.
- I THOUGHT
SHE WAS YOUR DAUGHTER.
- SHUT UP.
WELL, LITTLE ANTHONY,
THOUGHT YOU COULD PULL
A FAST ONE ON ME, HUH?
- YOU MUST'VE FORGOTTEN,
MR. PROVOLONE.
I GAVE YOU THE CASH IN EXCHANGE
FOR THOSE JEWELS.
- YEAH? BUT YOU WERE
SUPPOSED TO GET THE UNDERWEAR.
- WHAT UNDERWEAR?
- I KNOW.
THE MAID'S UNDERWEAR.
- CONNIE, PLEASE.
BINGO.
AND I'M NOT GIVIN' YOU
ANOTHER BAG IN RETURN.
I'M ONTO THAT RACKET.
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT,
BUT YOU CAN HAVE THE JEWELS.
- DO YOU BELIEVE THE COJONES
ON THIS GUY?
HE'S JUST GIVING ME BACK
MY OWN DOUGH.
HERE, CONNIE,
WATCH THIS.
LOOK WHO I'M TALKIN' TO.
SO YOU'RE JUST GIVIN' ME BACK
MY OWN ROCKS, HUH?
- YES. I'VE REALIZED THAT
ALL THE JEWELS IN THE WORLD
ARE WORTHLESS TO ME NOW--
NOW THAT I'VE LOST THERESA.
- THIS GUY'S A POET.
- AND IF YOU EVER HEAR
FROM HER AGAIN,
PLEASE TELL HER
THAT I STILL LOVE HER
AND THAT I'M SORRY I HURT HER.
- THERESA'S IN THE LIBRARY.
- SHE'S HERE?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
AND SHE'S CRAZY ABOUT YOU.
- ANTHONY, I AM SO SORRY.
- NO, NO, NO.
THIS WHOLE THING WAS MY FAULT.
- [sighs]
- I'LL GET IT.
MAYBE THAT'S THE UNDERWOOD
CHAUFFEUR WITH MY DOUGH.
- HE'LL GET IT.
- HELLO.
I WAS SENT
BY THE EMPLOYMENT AGENCY.
- I DON'T MEAN
TO SEEM DISCOURTEOUS,
BUT I GOT ANOTHER APPOINTMENT
COMIN' UP.
SIT DOWN, HONEY.
- I'LL TRY NOT TO KEEP YOU,
MR. PROVOLONE.
HERE'S MY REFERENCES.
I DO LIGHT HOUSEKEEPING,
SOME COOKING--
- YOU DON'T, BY ANY CHANCE,
ANSWER FRONT DOORS, DO YA?
- [snaps fingers]
WELL, ALL THIS LOOKS
PRETTY GOOD, ROXANNE.
SO HOW LONG YOU BEEN A MAID?
- MY FIRST JOB WAS FOR A MAN
NAMED JAMES BONOMO.
- "JUMPIN'" JIMMY BONOMO?
HEY, ALDO, SHE WORKED
FOR JUMPIN' JIMMY.
YOU REMEMBER HIM--
NERVOUS LITTLE GUY.
- SURE, SURE.
I REMEMBER HIM.
BIGHEARTED, SWEET GUY.
GIVE YOU THE SHIRT OFF HIS BACK.
WHEN DID HE DIE?
- LET'S SEE, UH...
GOT THE CHAIR IN '27.
- I DON'T BELIEVE THIS.
I WAS A DRIVER
FOR JUMPIN' JIMMY.
THAT WAS MY FIRST JOB
IN THE RACKETS--
I MEAN, INDUSTRY.
- THAT'S RIGHT, SNAPS.
- NO.
ROXY?
- THEN YOU REMEMBER ME?
- REMEMBER YOU?
HOW COULD I FORGET?
YOU WERE MY FIRST.
I MEAN, WE WERE--
HOW DO YOU LIKE THAT?
WHAT A SMALL WORLD!
JEEZ, I HAD A REAL THING
FOR HER.
BUT...
YOU JUST DISAPPEARED ON ME.
HOW COME?
- WELL, I-I DIDN'T THINK
I WAS WORKING
IN THE BEST ATMOSPHERE
TO RAISE MY BABY.
- YOU HAD A BABY?
- SHE'S A BIG GIRL NOW.
IN FACT, UH,
SHE'LL BE GETTING MARRIED SOON.
- AH, I'M SO HAPPY
FOR YOU, ROXANNE.
SAY, WHO'S THE LUCKY GUY?
- OH, HE'S A VERY
SUCCESSFUL ACCOUNTANT.
HE MAKES 1,400 A MONTH.
- WOW.
THAT'S A LOT OF DOUGH.
WAIT A MINUTE.
SAY, HIS NAME
WOULDN'T HAPPEN TO BE
LITTLE ANTHONY ROSSANO,
WOULD IT?
- YOU KNOW HIM?
- KNOW HIM?
SOMETIMES I THINK I DON'T KNOW
ANYBODY ELSE BUT HIM!
WAIT. THEN YOU GOTTA BE
THERESA'S MOTHER.
- YOU KNOW THERESA TOO?
- [laughs] WELL, I SHOULD.
AFTER ALL, SHE'S MY DAUGHTER.
[both snickering]
- THEN YOU'VE KNOWN
ALL ALONG.
- KNOWN WHAT?
- THAT YOU AND I...
THAT WE...
- DON'T YOU GET IT, BOSS?
SHE HAD YOUR KID.
THERESA
REALLY IS YOUR DAUGHTER.
[laughing]
I'M GETTIN' GOOD AT THIS.
- NO, NO, IT CAN'T BE.
- YOU SEEM SURPRISED.
- WELL, NOTHIN' THIS MORNIN'
WOULD SURPRISE ME EXCEPT THIS.
- BUT YOU SAID YOU KNEW
THAT SHE WAS YOUR DAUGHTER.
- I KNEW SHE SAID
SHE WAS MY DAUGHTER,
BUT I DIDN'T THINK
I WAS HER FATHER.
- I SHOULD'VE TOLD YOU...
BUT I LOST TOUCH
WHEN I WAS SENT TO THE CONVENT.
- [sniffles]
- COME ON, COME ON.
IT'S OKAY.
- THIS DAY HAS BEEN
AN EMOTIONAL ROLLER COASTER.
- MY FATHER SENT ME TO THE NUNS
TO HAVE THERESA.
HE SAID I BROUGHT SHAME
TO THE FAMILY.
- WHAT A BLOCKHEAD
HE MUST'VE BEEN.
- I DIDN'T WANNA COME
ON THIS INTERVIEW, BECAUSE...
I WAS AFRAID
THAT YOU'D BE ANGRY.
- OH, NO, ROXY.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
JUST DON'T CRY, PLEASE?
[Roxy and Connie crying]
- ANGELO!
WHO IS THIS WOMAN?
- THE NEW MAID.
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE
THAT FRIENDLY WITH THE HELP.
WHY IS SHE CRYING?
- SHE'S JUST HAPPY
TO BE WORKING FOR US.
- THAT'LL CHANGE.
- WHEW.
COME ON.
THERE'S SOMEBODY
I WANT YOU TO MEET.
- WHO'S HERE?
- OUR DAUGHTER.
- THERESA'S HERE?
BUT WHY?
- IT ALL STARTED AROUND 8:30.
- WILL YA SHUT UP?
AL, GET THERESA.
- THERESA!
- DO YOU SEE WHAT I GOTTA PUT UP
WITH AROUND HERE?
- MAMA?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I CAME TO SEE YOUR FATHER.
- FATHER?
- IT'S TIME
YOU KNEW THE TRUTH.
YOU'RE THE DAUGHTER
OF SNAPS PROVOLONE.
- MR. PROVOLONE?
OH, MAMA!
- THEN I REALLY CAN
CALL YOU "DAD."
- YOU DO,
I'LL MOP THE FLOOR WITH YOU.
- LISTEN, EVERYBODY!
WE HAVE
AN ANNOUNCEMENT TO MAKE!
- WHAT IS IT, LISA?
- THORNTON AND I
ARE GETTING MARRIED.
- ALDO...
[snaps fingers]
GET OUT A COUPLE BOTTLES
OF CHAMPAGNE.
WE'RE GONNA CELEBRATE!
- MY BABY!
- MY GIRLS!
- CONGRATULATIONS, DOC.
WILL THERE BE
A HONEYMOON FOLLOWING?
- WATCH IT THERE, CONNIE.
YOU'VE GOT
A DANGLING PARTICIPLE.
- HUH?
OH.
- LET'S JUST GET THIS
OVER WITH.
I HAVE TO GET BACK TO THE OFFICE
AND TURN DOWN A LOAN.
[car horn blows]
- ARE YOU SURE
ABOUT THIS ONE, LIEUTENANT?
- HEY, TOOMEY...
YOU BETTER GET OVER HERE.
- HERE COME THE BIG BOYS.
IT'S THE O'BANION GANG,
ALL RIGHT.
- WELL, OBVIOUSLY,
THEY'RE EXPECTING US.
- THIS TURNED OUT TO BE
A WONDERFUL DAY AFTER ALL.
BOTH MY GIRLS
ARE GETTING MARRIED.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN "BOTH"?
- SOFIA, MY WIFE,
MEET THERESA, MY DAUGHTER.
- YOUR DAUGHTER?
- I JUST FOUND OUT MYSELF.
- ME TOO.
- IF SHE'S YOUR DAUGHTER,
WHO'S HER MOTHER?
- I AM.
- YOU HAD A CHILD
WITH THE NEW MAID?
- PARDON ME.
HAVE WE COME AT A BAD TIME?
- NO, GENTLEMEN.
COME IN.
- HERE'S THE BUBBLY, BOSS.
- ALDO, I'M SHOCKED!
YOU KNOW LIQUOR'S
AGAINST THE LAW!
DIDN'T YOU EVER HEAR
OF PROHIBITION?
- HEARD OF IT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK
PAID FOR THIS HOUSE?
- IX-NAY THE OOZE-BAY.
ANKERS-BAY.
- OH, WE JUST KEEP THIS
IN THE HOUSE
FOR YACHT CHRISTENINGS.
- IT'S SO DIFFICULT
TO FIND GOOD HELP
THESE DAYS.
- NOW, IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I GOT SOME BUSINESS TO CONDUCT
WITH THESE GENTLEMEN.
[telephone rings]
- YEAH?
- I HAVE A COLLECT CALL
FROM MR. FIVE SPOT CHARLIE.
WILL YOU ACCEPT
THE NICKEL CHARGE?
- YEAH.
PUT HIM ON.
[clang]
- HELLO.
M-M-M-MR. VEND-D-DETTI?
- WHAT DO YOU GOT FOR ME,
FIVE SPOT?
- WELL, I-I-I-IT'S HAPPENING,
MR. VE--VENDETTI,
J-JUST LIKE WE THOUGHT.
FOUR T-T-T-TOUGH CUSTOMERS
JUST WENT INTO
S-S-S-S-S-S-S-SNAP'S PLACE.
- THANKS, FIVE SPOT. THERE'S
A "C" NOTE IN IT FOR YOU.
- A-A-A "C" NOTE?
GEE, TH--TH--THANKS.
THAN, MR.--
- THAT CINCHES IT.
HE'S HOOKIN' UP
WITH O'BANION.
OKAY, WE'RE MOVIN' ON PROVOLONE.
WE'RE MOVIN' NOW!
- A "C" NOTE.
- ORDER OUT FOR PIZZA.
WE'LL BE BACK IN AN HOUR.
- WAIT TILL YOU SEE
YOUR OFFICE DOWNTOWN.
- MMM.
YOU'LL HAVE A SECRETARY,
A TELEPHONE,
BEAUTIFUL VIEW OF THE HARBOR.
- AND A KEY
TO THE EXECUTIVE LOUNGE.
- BUT NOT A VOTE ON THE BOARD.
- WHAT?
LET ME SEE THAT.
- WELL...
WE THOUGHT YOU MIGHT SERVE
IN MORE OF AN ADVISORY CAPACITY.
- JUST UNTIL YOU LEARN
THE ROPES, THAT IS.
- AS SORT OF A SILENT PARTNER.
- CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG,
BUT I THINK FOR THE DOUGH
THAT I AM PUTTING IN,
I DESERVE A VOTE.
- AND WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
GENTLEMEN,
MAY I CALL YOUR ATTENTION
TO ADDENDUM "B"?
- OH, THAT?
THAT SIMPLY ABSOLVES THE BANK
OF ANY LIABILITY.
- YES.
SHOULD MR. PROVOLONE...
- SHOULD MR. PROVOLONE WHAT?
- INCUR ANY...
LEGAL DIFFICULTIES.
- LET'S NOT BEAT
AROUND THE BUSH.
WE ALL KNOW WHAT KIND
OF BACKGROUND HE COMES FROM.
- ANTHONY, IT SOUNDS LIKE
THEY DON'T TRUST ME.
- NOT ACCORDING TO THIS.
- NO, MR. PROVOLONE...
THESE CLAUSES ARE AS MUCH
FOR YOUR PROTECTION AS OURS.
NOW, IF YOU JUST SIGN THIS...
PLEASE?
- ALL RIGHT!
GRAB SOME SKY, HOODS,
AND HOLD IT!
DRILL THE FIRST RAT
THAT MAKES A MOVE.
- LIEUTENANT,
WHAT A PLEASANT SURPRISE.
- I'LL BET.
- I WAS JUST SAYIN' TO SOFIA
THIS MORNING
THAT WE GOTTA HAVE THE TOOMEYS
OVER FOR TEA.
[chuckles]
- YOU DON'T REALLY THINK WE'RE
IN BUSINESS WITH THESE PEOPLE,
DO YOU, OFFICER?
- WE'RE ONLY HERE
BECAUSE HE THREATENED US.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
HE THREATENED
TO PUT THE ARM ON US.
- SAVE YOUR BREATH, FINGERS.
FINGERS FRISCHETTI,
O'BANION'S TRIGGERMAN.
- IT'S A PRIVILEGE TO WATCH
YOUR MIND WORK, TOOMEY.
- THANK YOU.
AND THIS, GENTLEMEN,
IS THE INFAMOUS
SID "THE SHIV" SAPERSTEIN.
- I BEG YOUR PARDON?
- HEY, SID, SAY, "CHEESE."
- YOU BETTER TAKE A LOOK
AT THESE, LIEUTENANT.
- AH, "UNIVERSITY CLUB.
"HARVARD ALUMNI CLUB.
REPUBLICAN
NATIONAL COMMITTEE"?
WAIT A MINUTE.
"THE CITY COMMERCE
BOARD OF DIRECTORS.
"CITY TRADE ASSOCIATION
"THE STATE FINANCIAL
ADVISORY BOARD.
"COMMITTEE TO REELECT
HERBERT HOOVER.
EASTSIDE ATHLETIC CLUB."
AND TWO TICKETS
TO THE POLICEMEN'S BALL.
EITHER YOU GUYS ARE LEGIT,
OR THIS IS THE GREATEST JOB
OF FORGERY I EVER SEEN.
- I HOPE
YOU'RE SATISFIED, OFFICER.
- GEE, TOOMEY,
HE HAD ME CONVINCED
HE WAS FINGERS FRISCHETTI.
- IT DON'T ADD UP.
WHY WOULD SNAPS PROVOLONE
BE MEETIN' WITH FOUR BANKERS?
- MAYBE I WAS SLUMMIN'.
- CLAM IT, SNAPS.
I GOT IT!
THE BAG!
FAN OUT, BOYS.
FIND THAT LITTLE BLACK BAG,
THE ONE THAT'S BEEN COMIN' IN
AND OUT OF THIS HOUSE ALL DAY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
SNAPS--NERVOUS?
[whistling]
- LIEUTENANT, FOUND IT.
- JUST AS I FIGURED...
IT SEEMS THAT
OUR FRIEND SNAPS HERE
HAS BEEN LAUNDERING
MOB MONEY THROUGH THEIR BANK,
AND HERE'S YOUR PROOF.
GET YOUR CAMERAS READY, BOYS.
BOY, IS THIS GONNA MAKE ME
LOOK GOOD DOWNTOWN.
[chortling]
GET OUT OF MY WAY!
- WELL, BOYS, HE GOT
THE "LAUNDRY" PART RIGHT.
[laughter]
I HATE TO SAY,
"I TOLD YOU SO,"
BUT THAT'S WHAT WE GET
FOR GOING INTO BUSINESS
WITH A CROOK!
- I'M A CROOK?
YOU COME INTO MY HOUSE
WITH YOUR FINE PRINT
AND ADDENDUMS
AND TRY TO CON ME
OUT OF MY DOUGH?
JEEZ, I'M USED TO DEALING
WITH MOBSTERS,
BOOTLEGGERS, AND GUNSELS,
BUT YOU BANKERS...
YOU'RE SCARY.
- I HAVE NEVER BEEN SO INSULTED
IN ALL MY LIFE.
- WAIT.
YOU'RE YOUNG YET.
- IT ALL CAME OUT IN THE WASH,
DIDN'T IT, TOOMEY?
- YEAH, I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU COLLECTED LADIES' UNDERWEAR.
- DON'T WORRY, TOOMEY.
MAYBE THEY'LL GIVE YOU A JOB
AS A BANK GUARD.
[laughter]
- YEAH, YEAH.
SHOVE OFF, YOU BUMS.
WE HIT 'EM FAST AND HARD,
AND NOBODY GETS OUT ALIVE.
- STEP ON IT, DUGAN.
[commotion, shouting]
- YOU ALL RIGHT, LIEUTENANT?
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
OUT OF THE WAY.
WELL, WELL...
MR. VENDETTI.
- HIYA, TOOMEY.
- ALL RIGHT, BOYS,
TAKE 'EM IN.
- ANTHONY, I LIKE THE WAY YOU
HANDLED YOURSELF IN HERE TODAY.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
- AND I'M MAKING YOU
CHIEF FINANCIAL OFFICER
OF PROVOLONE ENTERPRISES, INC.
- SIR...
DAD, WHAT AN HONOR!
- SO ARE WE BACK IN BUSINESS,
MR. PROVOLONE?
- YOU CAN FORGET THAT
"MR. PROVOLONE" STUFF.
FROM NOW ON, CALL ME BOSS.
all: YES, BOSS!
- SORRY, POP.
I DID THE BEST I COULD.
- DO YOU, LISA AND THERESA,
TAKE THORNTON AND ANTHONY
TO BE YOUR
LAWFULLY WEDDED HUSBANDS?
- I DO.
- IF ANYONE AMONG YOU
HAS REASONS TO DOUBT
THAT THESE UNIONS
SHOULD TAKE PLACE,
LET HIM SPEAK NOW
OR FOREVER HOLD HIS PEACE.
women:
OH!
- STOP!
- WHO ARE YOU?
- I'M OSCAR.
- GET RID OF HIM,
EXPEDITIOUSLY.
- YOU GOT IT.
[shuffling footsteps]
- NO, WAIT!
- GRAB HIS FEET.
- THEN I NOW PRONOUNCE YOU
MAN AND WIFE.
YOU MAY KISS THE BRIDES.
[majestic music]
¶ ¶
[Largo al Factotum]
- ¶ LARGO AL FACTOTUM
DELLA CITTA, LARGO ¶
- ¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ PRESTO A BOTTEGA CHE
L'ALBA E GIA, PRESTO ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ AH, CHE BEL VIVERE,
CHE BEL PIACERE ¶
¶ CHE BEL PIACERE ¶
¶ PER UN BARBIERE ¶
¶ DI QUALITA
DI QUALITA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ AH, BRAVO FIGARO,
BRAVO, BRAVISSIMO, BRAVO ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ FORTUNATISSIMO
PER VERITA, BRAVO ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA...LA! ¶
¶ FORTUNATISSIMO PER VERITA ¶
¶ FORTUNATISSIMO
PER VERITA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA,
LA LA LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ PRONTO A FAR TUTTO,
LA NOTTE E IL GIORNO ¶
¶ SEMPRE D'INTORNO
IN GIRO STA ¶
¶ MIGLIOR CUCCAGNA
PER UN BARBIERE ¶
¶ VITA PIU NOBILE,
NO, NON SI DA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA LA LA LA LA ¶
LA LA LA LA! ¶
¶ ¶
¶ RASORI E PETTINI
LANCETTE E FORBICI ¶
¶ AL MIO COMANDO
TUTTO QUI STA ¶
¶ LANCETTE E FORBICI
RASORI E PETTINI ¶
¶ AL MIO COMANDO
TUTTO QUI STA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ V'E LA RISORSA ¶
¶ POI, DEL MESTIERE ¶
¶ COLLA DONNETTA ¶
¶ COL CAVALIERE ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ LA LA LA! ¶
¶ CHE BEL VIVERE,
CHE BEL PIACERE ¶
¶ CHE BEL PIACERE ¶
¶ PER UN BARBIERE ¶
¶ DI QUALITA, DI QUALITA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ TUTTI MI CHIEDONO,
TUTTI MI VOGLIONO ¶
¶ DONNE, RAGAZZI
VECCHI, FANCIULLE ¶
¶ QUA LA PARRUCCA,
PRESTO LA BARBA ¶
¶ QUA LA SANGUIGNA,
PRESTO IL BIGLIETTO ¶
¶ TUTTI MI CHIEDONO,
TUTTI MI VOGLIONO ¶
¶ QUA LA PARRUCCA,
PRESTO LA BARBA ¶
¶ PRESTO IL BIGLIETTO ¶
¶ FIGARO, FIGARO ¶
¶ FIGARO, FIGARO, FIGARO,
FIGARO, FIGARO, FIGARO ¶
¶ FIGARO ¶
¶ AHIME, AHIME,
CHE FURIA, AHIME ¶
¶ CHE FOLLA,
UNO ALLA VOLTA, PER CARITA ¶
¶ PER CARITA, PER CARITA ¶
¶ UNO ALLA VOLTA,
UNO ALLA VOLTA ¶
PER CARITA ¶
¶ FIGARO, SON QUA ¶
¶ EHI, FIGARO, SON QUA ¶
¶ FIGARO QUA, FIGARO LA,
FIGARO QUA, FIGARO LA ¶
¶ FIGARO SU, FIGARO GIU,
FIGARO SU, FIGARO GIU ¶
¶ PRONTO PRONTISSIMO
SON COME IL FULMINE ¶
¶ SONO IL FACTOTUM
DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ DELLA CITTA, DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ DELLA CITTA,
DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ AH, BRAVO, FIGARO,
BRAVO, BRAVISSIMO ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA,
A TE FORTUNA ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA
NON MANCHERA ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA LA LA LA LA ¶
LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA,
A TE FORTUNA ¶
¶ A TE FORTUNA
NON MACHERA ¶
¶ SONO IL FACTOTUM
DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ DELLA CITTA ¶
¶ ¶
¶ DELLA ¶
¶ CITTA ¶