Keller: Our father,
who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For the kingdom, the power,
and the glory are yours,
now and forever.
Amen.
[ Animal chitters ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Man: Looking at mostly
cloudy skies
and with lows
in the upper 20s.
There will likely be some
refreeze on some of the roads.
So, slick spots are possible
tonight in isolated lo-
[ radio clicks off ]
You know
the most important thing
your granddad
ever taught me?
Hmm?
Be ready.
Hurricane, flood,
whatever it ends up being.
No more food gets delivered
to the grocery store,
gas stations dry up.
People just turn
on each other, and, uh...
All of a sudden,
all that stands between you
and being dead is you.
I'm proud of you, son.
It was a nice shot.
[ Mid-tempo gospel music plays ]
♪ Put your hand in the hand of
the man who stilled the water ♪
♪ put your hand in the hand
of the man who calmed the sea ♪
♪ take a look at yourself
♪ and you can look
at others differently ♪
[ Dog barking ]
♪ By putting your hand
in the hand ♪
♪ of the man from galilee
♪ every time I look at the holy
book, I want to tremble ♪
♪ and then I read
about the part ♪
♪ where a carpenter
cleared the temple... ♪
[ Grace clears throat ]
Hey, come on, hon.
[ Humming ]
Wait, wait, wait.
I forgot something.
Hold on a second, Anna!
Keller: Ralph,
you have the venison?
Ralph: Yup.
I forgot the pie.
[ Screen door bangs shut ]
[ Humming ]
[ Door handle clicks ]
Are we taking the truck?
We're going up the street,
you dope.
Come on.
Grace: Hey, wait
for your mother, please.
Give me a ride.
Here.
[ Straining ]
Oh, you're gettin' heavy.
Ralph: Um, Danny's dad said
he'd sell me their old car.
I got half of what I need saved
from the summer.
I thought maybe you'd --
forget it.
I can barely get
enough carpentry work
to keep up
with the mortgage.
Well, why don't you
rent out grandpa's
old apartment house?
Like I keep telling your mother,
it's an old building,
and it'll cost a fortune
to fix it up.
[ Grunts ]
[ Coughs ]
[ Doorbell ringing ]
Grace: Okay, okay.
Nancy: They're here!
[ Classical music plays ]
Grace: Hello.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Keller: Anna,
wait until we're invited.
Oh, for God's sake, Keller.
Get the hell in here.
Aah!
[ Children gasp ]
[ Laughs ]
Keller,
you got the deer you shot?
This one's Ralph's.
Well, you killed it,
you take it into the kitchen.
All right.
Thank you.
Mwah.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Keller: There he is.
Franklin: Thank you.
Happy t-day.
All right.
Joy. Joy, three times.
Joy, get your dolls
off the table.
Y'all missing the game.
Keller: Anna! Anna!
Eliza: Hi. How are you?
Hey.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Anna, come here.
We wait until we're invited.
You understand?
[ Chopping ]
Nancy:
You're in charge of this.
Us veterinarians make
lousy butchers.
[ Chuckles ] No problem.
Can I go outside
with joy?
Uh, convince your brother
to go with you, and you can.
All right.
And wear a hat, please.
You're just
getting over a cold.
Joy, you wear a hat, too.
Eliza: Did you feel bad
for that deer
when you shot it?
Ralph: Do you feel bad for cows
when you go into McDonald's?
That's --
that's what my dad says.
And the deer,
if they have too many babies,
then the babies
starve anyway.
You gotta keep
the population down.
Right.
Your dad say that, too?
Anna: Pull harder.
Hey, hey!
Get away from that thing!
Let me see that.
Come on, let's go.
No.
I said let's go!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Stop. You can't just take
somebody's stuff like that.
No! Let's go!
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
[ Grunts ]
Wait. Shh.
You hear that?
[ Gospel music playing faintly
inside camper ]
Somebody's in there.
All right, I don't feel like
getting yelled at.
Let's go.
Not on Thanksgiving, okay?
[ Chatter ]
[ Gospel music continues ]
Franklin: Now the school board's
telling me
there's no money for new
marching-band uniforms.
These kids are wearin'
the same uniforms
they had when we went there,
and they were old then.
[ Chuckling ] I mean,
marchin' right out of 1979.
Why isn't he
speaking to me?
He doesn't speak.
Cutie pie.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my gosh!
He's fast, too.
He's so quick.
Is that a slide?
Thank you, all. Thank you, all.
Got a surprise.
Ohh.
And I am taking requests.
Yes!
No.
[ Laughter ]
[ Chuckles ]
You gotta listen out for it,
'cause this is not easy.
Mom. Mommy, can I take joy
to our house?
Why?
My red whistle.
She's gonna help me look for it.
Oh, my sweetheart, I think
that red whistle is long gone.
What whistle?
The emergency whistle
daddy gave me.
I lost it...
...133 days ago.
Franklin: Well, if you want
to find a whistle,
you have to whistle for it.
So we'll do "jingle bells"
to find it.
[ Whistling "jingle bells" ]
♪ Jingle bells, Batman smells,
Robin laid an egg ♪
♪ the Batmobile lost its wheels,
and joker got away -- hey! ♪
Yay! Okay! Okay!
You can go, all right?
Just make sure eliza and Ralph
go with you, please.
Keller:
No looking in the basement.
I won't.
Y'all eardrums
are just startin' to grow.
I don't want
to damage them yet.
But I am taking requests
from you, Keller.
From me?
Your day, your request.
Oh. Uh, the piano.
No.
[ Laughter ]
No, no, no.
So all set?
Wait, listen,
he used to love --
he used to dress
like Springsteen.
Really?
I still love Springsteen.
Grace: "The river,"
"Jersey girl."
Well, I ain't white,
and I like him too much
[laughs] And I'm too drunk
to cover the boss.
Thank you.
Honey?
What else?
Nothing comes to mind.
Nothing.
Oh, I know.
What?
He actually loves
"the star-spangled banner."
I know.
Sings it in the shower.
I do not.
Yes, you do!
Franklin: I got you.
[ Plays sour notes to the tune
of "star-spangled banner" ]
[ "Star-spangled banner"
continues off-key ]
[ "Spongebob squarepants" theme
playing on television ]
Where are your sisters?
I can't find them.
You, uh, you go to the house
with them?
No. What are you
talking about?
Earlier?
No.
What? They were supposed to come
down earlier and get you.
They didn't come get you?
No. We haven't seen them
since we ate.
It's all right.
All right.
They're probably
at our house.
[ Dog barks in distance ]
[ Door opens ]
Keller: Anna? Joy?
[ Door closes ]
Anna?
Girls?
Girls?!
Who put these dishes
in here?
Get outta here.
They weren't outside.
It's starting to rain.
Did you check
over by Maria's swing?
Yeah.
Well, they're gettin' whupped
when they get here.
Sorry, grace.
I whup kids.
So they weren't
there either?
[ Door closes ]
They must be at home.
Keller:
Are they here?
No. They're not here.
They weren't there?
No, they're not
at our house.
No, they're not there.
I checked the entire house.
They're not here.
The -- the --
the rv.
What rv?
Dad, there was this rv,
and they were playing on it.
We thought there was
someone inside.
Where?
Where was it? Show me.
You wait here.
I'm gonna gonna over
the house again.
Franklin: Relax. Relax.
[ Door opens ]
Keller: Go that way.
I'll meet you on the other side.
Anna?!
Joy!
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Roger, you seen my daughter
walk by here?
No. Is there a problem?
Anna?
Here!
Dad, it was parked
right here.
Anna? Anna?
[ Knock on door ]
Hello, hello!
Did you see 'em?
No!
Hello!
I couldn't find 'em!
Were you messing around
in this house?
No.
I told you not to come here.
We weren't.
They were just on the rv,
and we got them off of it.
Tell me everything you remember
about that rv.
Everything.
A-a ladder on the back.
Police, police.
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Happy Thanksgiving.
Thanks.
Hey, you have any of those,
um, fortune-cookie things?
My boss told me cops don't like
fortune cookies.
What year were you born?
Are you a dragon or a snake
or a horse?
I'm a monkey.
Oh, you're a monkey.
You're very intelligent.
[ Chuckles ]
You have an ability
to influence people.
Think maybe you could
influence your boss
to lower the check
a little bit?
[ Chuckles ]
No. I cannot.
My boss is a rooster.
Silly, selfish,
and eccentric.
That's...
[ Cellphone vibrates ]
Woman:
All units, all units,
an rv was reported
matching the description.
The vehicle is parked
at a rest stop off of route 46,
northbound, past exit 17.
Any available units?
Man:
This is 12-12 responding.
Man #2:
10-80 responding.
This is 13-40.
I'm five minutes out.
I'll meet
the responding units.
Man:
12-12 standing by.
Man #2:
10-80 standing by.
13-40. I'm on scene.
Be advised, we're moving in.
[ Engine revving ]
Whoa! Hey, don't move!
Hey!
Whoa, whoa, watch out!
Hey, don't shoot!
Don't shoot!
[ Glass shatters ]
All right, Sloan,
take the right!
Officer: Clear!
Clear!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
I got this.
Gimme that.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Hey.
I see you in there.
Show me both your hands
right now.
Hey, I see you in there!
Show me your hands!
Both hands right now!
That's it.
Slow. Slow. Slow!
Slow. Slowly. Both hands.
Both fuckin' hands!
Walk! Walk!
Hey!
Walk!
Get up! Get up!
Get up!
Show me those girls!
Show me where you put
those girls, huh?
Where are those girls?
Where are those girls?!
Hey, give me the flashlight.
Sir.
Show me where those girls --
they in the woods?
You put them in the woods?
Where did you put
those girls?
You hear me?!
What the fuck
is this guy on?
He's high on something.
Put this fucking guy
in the car.
Get him in the car.
Put him in the fucking car!
Walk!
Let's go.
Hey, call psp, tell 'em
to send their scent dogs.
And seal off the whole area.
The entrance, all of it.
Right.
You, come with me.
No, they weren't playing
on your rv?
No.
[ Sighs ]
Okay, take a look
at 'em again.
Don't recognize
these girls?
I didn't see them.
May I sit down?
What do you do in the rv?
Answer my question.
Sleep there.
You sleep in there?
You were sleeping
out there?
In the day?
Why was the rv
parked outside the house?
Hmm.
I went for a drive?
You went for a drive?
You weren't driving.
I know for a fact those girls
were playing outside your rv.
You weren't driving.
It was parked.
Was it a special day?
Were you planning on taking
two little girls?
No.
Have you done that before?
Did you ask them
to come inside?
No.
You ask them to come
inside the rv and then
you take them away?
No.
Did you put
those girls somewhere?
May I sit down?
Come on.
Did you put
those girls somewhere?
Please don't touch me.
I know you put
those girls somewhere.
You hide 'em?
No.
How did you hide 'em?
Do you tie 'em up?
Mnh-mnh.
Mnh-mnh-mnh.
Huh? Hey. Hey. Hey.
Look, I know you're a good guy,
all right?
I know you're a decent guy.
I'm not tryin' to tell you
you're doing anything bad.
I'm just tryin' to get the right
answers out of you, okay?
The real ones.
That's all I want.
Where do you usually park
your rv, Alex?
My aunt's house.
Your aunt's house?
She lets me park it
in the backyard.
The grass don't grow
back there anyway.
Holly:
It was my husband's.
For sale, if you want it.
No, thanks.
Well, would you tell me
what you're doin'
on my property then?
I'm just glad
to know where he is.
He's always home
before dark, and...
I just don't understand.
That boy has never been
in trouble,
not a day in his life.
Uh, in the summertime,
he sleeps out
in the camper some, but...
This time of year, he sleeps
in here on the sofa bed.
That -- that's my husband.
We had a fight,
jeez, five years ago.
Walked out,
didn't come back.
Alex loved him
like a father.
Where are
Alex's real parents?
My husband's brother
and his girlfriend,
they died in a car accident
when Alex was about 6.
Sorry to hear that.
[ Drawer slides open ]
He doesn't have much.
What have you got?
Well, this thing's clean.
I mean, it's filthy as shit,
but we didn't find anything.
We didn't find any, uh, wool
fibers, anything like that?
The girls could be wearing
some wool gloves or wool hat.
No cotton fibers?
Well, if he was just usin'
this thing to transport 'em,
I might buy that.
But if there had been
a struggle,
I would have
found something.
I'd start lookin' in the woods
by the rest stop.
Yeah.
Half the uniformed cops
in the state
are doin' that right now.
When you're done
with this thing,
can you send a crew
over to the aunt's house?
[ Police radio chatter ]
Anna!
Anna?!
[ Engine shuts off ]
[ Door opens ]
Franklin: Thanks for comin'.
Franklin birch.
My wife's in here.
Honey?
Her name's Nancy.
Detective loki is --
honey?
These photos are better than
the ones my husband gave you.
You can see her eyes
more clearly.
[ Sighs ]
[ Water running ]
[ Water stops ]
Grace: So, did we pass?
I'm sorry,
what did you say?
The poly thing.
The lie detector we took
this morning.
Did we pass?
Oh, yeah, yeah. Sorry.
Yes, we appreciate
your cooperation.
It's embarrassing, all the --
all this fuss.
Everyone's gonna think
we're crazy
when those two come out of
hiding, wherever they are.
Do you have some reason
to believe they ran away?
No.
They're happy.
They must have run away.
I think
they must have run away.
Right?
Um, your police captain
told me
that you've solved every case
that you've ever been assigned.
Is that right?
[ Sobs ] Sorry.
I am so sorry.
Do you -- do you have
children, detective?
I'm gonna find
your daughter.
We believe that
they came back here
after they left you
at the birches' yesterday.
They were looking
for Anna's red whistle.
Right.
I read your statement.
I'm detective loki.
I'm heading up
the investigation
into your daughter's
disappearance.
Please sit down.
Uh, uh, m-my son
already told you
that the guy was inside the rv
just watchin' 'em, right?
We haven't found any physical
evidence inside the rv.
Or his aunt's house
where he lives.
Nothing?
Alex Jones unfortunately
has the I.Q. Of a 10-year-old.
There is no way that someone
with the I.Q. Of a 10-year-old
could abduct two girls
in broad daylight and then...
Somehow make
them disappear.
Uh, well,
how can he drive an rv?
If he can't answer
a question...
Well, he has a legal
Pennsylvania license.
And he ran, right?
They said he tried to run away.
Why --
why...Why would he run?
I've just spent 10 hours
questioning this boy. Okay?
I hear what you're saying.
Uh...Did -- did you give him
a lie detector?
You gave us a lie detector.
Did you give him one?
Sir, I understand what you're
asking me. Yes, we did.
We gave him a lie detector,
and there is no way of --
[ scoffs ]
A lie detector
doesn't work
if you don't understand
the questions.
Well, maybe he wasn't
on his own.
How could he drive an rv
if he has an I.Q.
Of a 10-year-old?
Hey, we're considering
all possibilities.
I don't think you are
considering all possibilities.
I-I hear what you're saying.
Sir -- sir --
you listen to me.
Just shut the fuck up
for a fucking second!
[ Grace cries softly ]
This is what I'm gonna
need you to do for me.
I need you to calm down.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please listen to me
for a second.
Mr. Dover, I understand this is
an incredibly hard time.
But I have every uniformed
police officer in this state
looking for Anna.
I don't understand
what any of this means.
They said he ran.
They said
he tried to get away.
I don't understand why
he would try to run away.
We're considering all
possibilities, Mr. Dover.
I hear what you're saying.
I'm not crossing anybody
off my list.
Just...Let me do my job.
[ Cellphone vibrates ]
Hey!
Detective!
Oh, shit.
Hey!
He stays in custody until
my daughter's found, right?
Right?
We have
a 48-hour hold on him
that ends tomorrow
unless we bring charges.
Well, charge him with something.
Charge him.
Mr. Dover,
I understand what you're --
detective, detective,
two little girls
have got to be worth
whatever little rule
you've got to break to keep
that asshole in custody.
Now, I know you can't
promise me anything.
I understand that.
But I'm asking you
to be 100% sure.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
O'Malley: So you're positive
he's innocent,
but you want to keep
holding him?
Anna Dover's father was
on my ass this morning.
I-I get it. I understand.
But it's not gonna happen.
I was asking
for one more day.
Fuck you.
No, no.
You find his daughter,
he'll forgive you.
You don't,
he's gonna hate you anyway.
So what's next?
I'm knockin' on doors
all night.
Yeah, well, you're comin' up
on 24 hours missing,
and you have exactly shit.
No, I've got nine
level-three sex offenders
living within a 10-mile radius
of Fairmont circle.
So if you don't mind...
Then go.
Yeah.
Go.
[ Door opens, closes ]
It's right here.
Man: Look, I-I'm staying
straight, okay?
Well, hey, look.
Look, I know you're --
you like yourself
some German porn, huh?
Look, I was...
[ Doorbell ringing ]
[ Sighs ]
Father! Open up!
It's the police!
[ Doorbell ringing ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Door slams ]
[ Dramatic music playing
on television ]
[ Snoring ]
Father!
[ Snoring continues ]
Father.
You mind if I take
a look around?
[ Scoffs ]
Fuckin' drunk.
[ Grunting ]
What the fuck?
Whoa.
Fuck.
Aye. Fuck.
[ Sighs ]
Oh! [ Sobbing ]
Please, God! God!
What's the name of your buddy
down there, huh?
What's the name, huh?
I don't know his name.
You don't know his name?
Hey, you know what?
I spent six years in huntington
boys' home, father.
You know the huntington
boys' home, right? Huh?
Hurting a fuck like you'd
be a real treat for me.
Why don't you tell me
his fuckin' name?
[ Crying ]
He didn't tell me his name.
He came to me
for confession.
He said he'd killed 16 children.
He bragged about it.
I convinced him
to come back here.
He said he'd kill more.
16 children, huh?
Let's go, you fucking
chicken-hawk!
[ Dogs barking ]
[ Cellphone rings ]
Hey.
Grace:
They're letting him go.
What?
The man.
The police said they're
letting him go today.
O-okay.
I'll take care of it.
Ralph: Dad?
Keep searching.
Where are you goin'?!
[ Barking continues ]
[ Indistinct conversation ]
Holly: He wants you
to write your whole name.
That's good.
Mm-hmm. Good job.
Now you give it
to the man.
[ Keys jingle ]
All right. Come on.
I don't want you minding
these people out here.
Don't talk to them. You've got
nothing to say to them. Come on.
[ Reporters shouting
indistinctly ]
Woman: Come on, Alex.
You took those kids, didn't you?
Sir --
I just want to talk.
He's a free man,
I'm a free man!
Hey! Tell me what you did
with them!
Tell me!
They didn't cry
until I left them.
What did you say?
What did you say?!
Whoa, no, no!
Loki:
Fuckin' get off him!
God! Get up!
Get him down!
Move back!
Please, just let us go.
Thanks for nothing.
We're fine. Thank you.
Now, I know your dad was a guard
at graterford.
And I've got a daughter
of my own,
so we're gonna pretend
this never happened.
And as for Alex Jones,
he has orders not to leave
the commonwealth.
What?
Sir, I need you to go home.
All right?
I need you to go home
to your family.
What about what I just
fucking told you?
Why aren't you sending someone
out to go arrest this guy?
Tell detective loki
what you just told me,
and he'll definitely
look into it.
Go ahead.
That asshole you promised me
you'd keep in custody, right?
And you didn't.
And right now when I grabbed him
in the parking lot,
he said right
to my fucking face,
"they didn't cry
until I left them."
Right to my fucking face.
He -- he said that to you
in the parking lot just now?
Right now, yeah.
What did I just say?
In the parking lot.
Before you grabbed me
off him.
Did anyone else hear it
besides you?
I don't know.
It was quiet.
He -- he said it to me.
He wanted me to know.
Are you sure he said that?
What?
Are you sure
that's what he said?
Jesus Christ, you think
I'm makin' this up?
No.
Why would I make this up?
Hey, hey, hey, whoa, whoa.
No, think about it.
Why would I make this up?
I'm not saying that to you.
I'm just asking you
a couple questions.
I will talk to him.
No, don't talk to him!
Mr. Dover --
arrest him!
What did I
fuckin' tell you?
What'd I tell you?
One more day.
Loki: You sure you didn't say
anything to Mr. Dover
in the parking lot today?
Anything he could have
misinterpreted or...?
I was right there.
They didn't say anything
to each other.
Man just attacked the boy.
Nothing like "get away from me"
or "help" or...
Anything like that?
No.
Can I speak to Alex alone
for a minute?
It's all right, sweetie.
I'll be right
in the next room.
[ Groans ]
You love your aunt,
don't you, Alex?
Yes.
You know if you know something
you're not telling us
that she could go to jail
for a very long time.
Do you want that for her?
After everything
she's done for you?
No.
[ Crow caws ]
Mr. Dover,
this is detective loki.
Have you arrested him?
Yeah, look, I just came
from Alex Jones,
and he said he didn't say
anything to you
in the parking lot.
I pushed him pretty hard,
and he didn't budge.
So, look, we can't waste
any more time on this guy.
All right?
You're gonna have to trust me.
I'll let you know if I have
anything new, all right,
for the --
fuckin' "a."
[ Scoffs ]
[ Grace sobbing ]
[ Crying ] The zipper
on her coat was broken,
and I told her
it didn't matter
'cause we were just gonna go
right down the street.
No, no.
Why hasn't she come home?
It's been three days.
Why can't you
make her come home?
I don't understand.
It's been too long.
Please make her come home.
Please make her...
How many of these?
I don't know!
It's okay.
It's all right.
Just take one.
Here.
No.
I just want to sleep.
I just want to go to sleep.
You...
You made me feel so safe.
You told us that you could
protect us from everything.
Oh, God...
I'm gonna go out
and help the police.
Just keep an eye
on your mother.
Your sister needs us
to be brave for her.
Be brave for her.
Be a grown-up for me, okay?
Can you do that?
I know you're scared.
Look at me. Come here.
It's gonna be okay.
Man: The former is a reason
why we should be very patient.
The latter why we should be
very penitent
when we are afflicted.
[ Engine turns over ]
He reminds him
that trouble and affliction
are what we have all reason
to expect in this world.
Man is brought into trouble,
not as man,
but as sinful man,
who was in transgression.
Man born in sin and therefore
born to trouble.
[ Engine revs, tires screech ]
[ Engine shuts off ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Car alarm chimes ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Door creaks ]
[ Dog whimpering ]
[ Whimpering stops ]
Alex: Come on.
Come on, Tucker.
♪ Jingle bells, Batman smells
♪ Robin laid an egg
♪ the Batmobile
lost its wheels ♪
♪ joker got away, hey
♪ jingle bells, Batman smells,
Robin laid an egg ♪
[ Gun cocks ]
♪ Jingle bells, Batman smells
♪ Robin laid an egg
♪ the Batmobile --
Keller: Alex.
♪ Lost its wheel...
That song.
Where did you hear
those words?
Hmm?
[ Truck horn honks ]
[ Door closes ]
Did you bring a change
of clothes like I told you?
Yeah.
You gonna tell me why?
It's better
if I just show you.
Show me what?
[ Engine shuts off ]
Didn't you used
to live here?
Mm-hmm.
Close the door.
Lock it.
[ Door closes, locks ]
Wow.
[ Sighs ]
Oh, my God.
What -- what did you do?
Keller, what the hell...?
I heard him singing
the same song
they were singing
on Thanksgiving.
Swear to God, Franklin.
The same fucking song.
And I told you what he said
in the parking lot.
Then we take him
to the police --
no, no, no.
The police won't do shit.
He'll just clam up and act crazy
like he did last time.
Someone has
to make him talk.
Someone.
Shit, man.
This -- this ain't right.
I mean,
what if you're wrong?
I'm not wrong.
But what if you are?
What if you only heard
what you wanted to hear?
What if...
Man, I want my daughter back
as much as you do,
but it ain't right.
Franklin!
We hurt him until he talks,
or they're gonna die.
This ain't --
no! No!
We hurt him until he talks
or they're gonna die.
That's the choice.
That's the choice
you have to make.
I've made my choice.
I know what I heard.
He's not a person anymore.
No, he stopped being a person
when he took our daughters.
I need your help.
This is your last chance.
I know you're scared.
And I know
you wanna go home.
And I don't --
I don't want to hurt you.
I don't.
I'm gonna take
the tape off,
and I want you to tell me
where they are.
[ Tape rips ]
Alex: Mnh!
Hey. Come on.
[ Sniffs ]
Alex:
Did you see my glasses?
What?
I can't see.
If you're not gonna talk, Alex,
I'm gonna have to hurt you.
[ Faintly, distorted ]
Tell me where they are.
Where are they?
[ Muffled thud ]
Tell me where they are!
Loki: Yeah, I'm out here
at a house on Fairmont circle,
the house the rv
was parked in front of.
It's only been on the market
a couple of months.
I'm gonna track the owners down,
see if they know anything.
You got any new info
on that corpse
we found in
the priest's basement?
O'Malley: No DNA, dental,
or fingerprint matches.
Nothing.
Priest is sticking
to the story, too.
[ Sighs ] All right.
[ Computer keys clacking ]
Mrs. milland: Same person
who took him took those girls.
I'm sure of it.
Wearing out the tape,
I guess.
I watch it every day
after breakfast.
It's the only video
I have of him.
[ Sighs ]
It was before your time.
26 years ago, August 19th.
I took a nap
in the afternoon,
and when I woke up,
Barry was gone.
No one could ever tell me
what happened to him.
He was playing
in the front yard,
just a few feet from where they
say that rv was parked.
What do you think
that means?
I'm more interested
in what you think that means.
I don't think
we'll ever know.
It's just like Barry.
No one took them.
Nothing happened.
They're just gone.
[ Indistinct conversation ]
How you doin', father?
I'm...I'm --
gettin' better.
So detective chemelinski
tells me
that you have
some specifics
about the crime you claim
that guy committed.
The abductor.
He was...
Waging a war against God.
[ Chuckles ]
Great.
That's great.
I thought you said
he had something specific.
[ Stammers ]
Tell him
how he took the kids.
He said...
...he took them in daylight.
Sometimes...
More than one child
at a time.
He said that?
Yeah.
Did he say he was
with anybody?
He did it alone?
He...
He said he had a family.
[ Sighs ]
That's it?
All right.
Informative.
Keller: You said they cried
when you left them.
Look at me.
You said they cried
when you left them!
Now tell me!
Where is she?
Hmm? Hmm?
Tell me where they are!
Just tell me.
Just tell me and I'll stop.
I'll stop as soon
as you tell me.
Just...
Just tell me
where they are.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Why won't you tell me?
Huh?
Why won't you just
fuckin' tell us?
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Sighs ]
He knows.
I can see it in his eyes.
He fucking knows.
I know you know!
Why aren't you
fucking telling me?!
Why?!
Fine.
Get him up.
Get him up. Get up.
Get up. Get up.
Get up!
[ Whimpering ]
You gonna make me
use this?
You gonna tell us?
If you don't,
I'm gonna use this.
Fine.
You're doing this
to yourself.
Just tell us.
Tell me.
Tell me!
Tell me! Tell me!
Where's my daughter?!
Where's...My...
Daughter?!
[ Panting ]
Female newscaster:
Four days have passed
since Anna Dover and joy birch
were last seen
by their families.
The two girls, aged 6 and 7,
are believed to have been
playing on this street
when they disappeared
without a trace.
As you can see,
despite the cold,
a lot of people have turned out
tonight to show their support.
Police are asking that anyone
with any information
on the girls' whereabouts...
[ Voice breaking ]
Where have you been?
I was searching for her
in the woods.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Moans lightly ]
I'm okay. I'm okay.
[ Groans ]
Franklin.
Franklin, what is it?
I just need a minute.
[ Sobs ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Quiet chatter ]
[ Hurried footsteps ]
[ Dog barking ]
[ Barking continues ]
[ Branch snaps ]
What the fuck?
Hey! Get offa me!
[ Barking continues ]
Hey! Hey!
[ Panting ]
Okay.
Male newscaster: And this is
who police are saying
is a person of interest
in the investigation
of the two missing girls.
Now, this unidentified man,
who was last seen at last
night's candlelight vigil,
fled on foot when
the investigating detective
attempted to question him.
Police caution the public
not to approach this man,
but to call police immediately
if they do see him.
[ Car horn honks ]
Female newscaster:
Thanks, John, for that update.
And now for the weather.
We should expect heavy rain
into the weekend and --
[ Sighs shakily ]
[ Engine shuts off ]
Look, Keller, I mean,
just think about it.
Why would the police
be lookin' for this man
if they didn't think that he did
it in the first place?
They did it together.
They know each other.
Listen, I fuckin' told you,
all right?
Jones looked me in the eye
and he said,
"they only cried
when I left them."
He left 'em with someone,
and he knows where this guy is.
Holly Jones' dog got hit
on southward street.
Apparently Alex Jones
took the dog for a walk
the night before last --
they never came home.
And his aunt didn't want
to tell us about the dog
when we called her about it
this morning.
She said that she thought
it would get him into trouble
or some shit.
I thought you said you would
keep him under surveillance.
Yeah, and I thought you said
the guy was innocent.
And I thought the guy from last
night you said was our guy.
Look, I don't have money
in the budget
for watching
innocent people.
You said to me that you'd put
him under surveillance.
What do you want me to say?
You gonna keep your word?
You could have just given me
a call, because I would have
been there all night. I would
have stayed up all night.
I would know
where he was now.
I need to know
where everybody is.
All right, point made.
All right? Point made.
If you can be clear with me,
then I'll be clear with you.
I need to know
where everybody is.
If you're gonna do something
different, please tell me.
Loki:
Tell me about your rv.
What do you do in your rv?
It's where I go...
To be alone.
[ Video fast-forwarding ]
What music do you listen to
in your rv when you're alone?
Radio, tape...
[ Video fast-forwarding ]
The rv was parked over
on Fairmont circle?
No.
Is my aunt coming?
[ Stammers]
[ Video fast-forwarding ]
Have you seen
these girls?
No.
Take a look at 'em.
You seen these girls?
No.
Did you participate
in any way
in the abduction
of those girls?
No.
Loki! You got a call.
[ Sighs ]
All right.
Jill: I called as soon as I saw
the sketch on TV.
He comes in here
every week almost
and buys kids' clothes,
but he's always buying stuff
in different sizes.
Caught him messing around
with the mannequins once.
What did he pay with?
Cash.
All right, you give me a call
if you hear anything.
Okay.
It's been five days.
Maybe five days since they had
a drink of water.
This could be the last night
that matters.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Look, I'll call you after Nancy
goes to sleep, all right?
I promise.
[ Door closes ]
[ Indistinct, muffled talking ]
Where have you been
all this time?
[ Knock on door ]
What the hell
were you thinking?
You tell anyone?
Did you?
[ Sighs ]
I wanna see him.
Oh...
Please help me.
Could you help me find
my little girl?
[ Cries ]
Got a picture.
See?
This my baby.
You see her?
Her name is joy.
And, um...
[ Voice breaking ]
This is...
A stuffed animal
we got her when she was 2
because she's afraid
to sleep by herself.
Please...
Tell me where my little girl is.
Please tell me
where my little girl...
I know
you're gonna tell me.
I know.
Help me.
[ Voice breaking ]
Keller: Franklin, did you close
the door to the --
[ screams ]
Nancy!
[ Glass shatters ]
What the fuck you doin'?
[ Alex shrieking ]
God damn it!
Damn!
Let it go!
[ Glass shard shatters ]
You untied him?
Huh?
[ Keller breathing heavily ]
That was close.
[ Glass shard clangs lightly ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Saw whirring ]
[ Whirring slows, stops ]
[ Microwave beeping ]
[ Knock on door ]
What is it?
What happened?
Get Franklin.
I need to show you something.
Did he say anything new?
He will soon.
You'll see.
[ Sighs ]
No light gets in.
There's barely enough room
to sit down inside.
Shower still works,
but we control it
from out here.
And I rigged the water heater
so it either comes out scalding
or freezing.
And, uh, you talk to him
through this.
It's to remind us...
In case we start
feeling sorry for him.
My God.
I can't hurt him any more
without killing him,
so this is the only way.
Have you lost your mind,
Keller?
Do you have a better idea,
Franklin?
Do you?
Go ahead.
Let him out, if you want.
I'm not gonna stop you.
If that's what you really want,
you go ahead.
You think someone's
lookin' out for our girls
the way you're lookin' out
for him?
[ Voice breaking ]
I hope.
It's been five days now, man.
We're runnin' out of time.
You don't even know
it's him.
Yeah, I do.
No, you don't.
I do.
I know you. You don't.
Look,
I want my baby back...
As much as you miss Anna.
And despite
what you think about me,
I would die
for my daughter.
But this ain't right.
This has to stop.
Well, then,
you better get to work.
You can start
with that wall there.
Franklin.
Stop.
[ Crunching ]
Franklin...
[ Voice breaking ]
Think of joy.
[ Sighs ]
[ Hammer thuds ]
I need to get out
of this place, Ralph.
Everything in this house just
makes me want to throw up.
Your dad's building?
There is no way I'm staying
in that crackhouse.
It's disgusting.
Yeah, okay.
[ Keys jingle ]
We're not gonna help Keller,
but we won't stop him, either.
Let him do
what he needs to.
[ Seatbelt disconnects ]
We don't know
about it anymore.
[ Door closes downstairs ]
Eliza?
[ Footsteps approaching ]
[ Knock on door ]
Excuse me.
Eliza?
Eliza, open the door!
Is she in there?
Honey?
Get out of the way!
Yeah, fuck you both!
Next time you plan
on leaving me here alone,
maybe you could try at least
telling me where you're going!
[ Door slams ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Object taps ]
[ Gasps ]
Ralph?
Anna?
[ Window opens ]
[ Gasps lightly ]
Mom?
[ Wind whistling ]
[ Gasps ]
Mom?
Anna.
Anna was here.
Mom,
it's freezing in here.
Mom! Hey, mom, mom, mom,
please sit down.
Stop. Calm down.
I'm gonna close the window.
Grace:
And she wasn't here.
And then I heard a sound
from my room,
and I...I came in
and the window was open.
And -- and it wasn't
open before.
And then -- and then Ralph,
he -- he came in...
And he looked
and -- and, um...
And then...
Then I don't know.
Aren't you gonna
write this down?
[ Exhales lightly ]
The basement.
I didn't check the basement.
We need to check the basement.
I-I'll show you.
I'll show you.
The kids know they're not
allowed down here.
They're not supposed
to come down here,
but I-I don't know.
My husband likes to be prepared
for emergencies.
Where is your husband,
Mrs. Dover?
I was gonna ask you.
He's been out searching
with the police for Anna.
Which you should be doing
right now.
Does he always stay out
this late?
Yes, he stays out this late
when he's looking
for my daughter,
since my daughter
has been gone -- yes!
Shit.
[ Engine turns over ]
[ Truck horn honking ]
[ Honking continues ]
Hey, go aro--
go around.
[ Truck horn honks ]
Fuck.
Come on, Mr. Dover.
Shit.
Why are you following me?
Get in the car.
[ Car door opens ]
[ Car door closes ]
Why are you following me?
Where did you go just now?
I parked at a liquor store.
I have a bottle of liquor.
You're the shit-hot detective.
Work it out.
I actually meant
before that.
[ Sighs ]
You were walking
in the opposite direction
across the parking lot.
Towards campello street.
Yeah, well...
I haven't had a drink
in nine-and-a-half years.
I figured if I walked around
the parking lot for a while,
by the time they opened,
I'd stop wanting it that bad.
And then -- then I saw you.
Sorta helped me
make up my mind.
There's a bag of lye in your
basement that's half-empty.
Your wife thinks
you've been helpin' us...
But we both know
that's not true.
I used the lye to bury our dog
last year.
And "helping the cops"
sounds better
than "I've been driving
aimlessly in my truck
'cause I don't know
what the fuck else to do."
Is that what you were doing
last Saturday night?
Probably.
Am I a suspect?
No, I'm only asking --
I'm only asking 'cause
you assaulted a man
who's now missing.
I heard about that.
What happened to him?
Thought you had him
under surveillance.
I'm -- I'm gonna assume
you're asking me because
you have no idea.
Well, I didn't think it was
something I could get away with.
It's not.
Yeah, well, it couldn't be
that he skipped town
'cause the asshole is guilty.
Couldn't be that, right?
'Cause that would mean
it would be your fault,
right? [ Sniffs ]
Mr. Dover?
What?
You need to take care
of yourself and your wife.
That's the best thing
you can do right now.
That little girl is gonna need
you when she comes home.
Kids gone for more
than a week
have half as good a chance
of being found,
and after a month,
almost none are.
Not alive. All right?
So forgive me for doing
everything I can --
you know what?
It hasn't been a fucking week.
You're right.
It's day fucking six!
Day six!
[ Voice breaking ] And every day
she's wondering why
I'm not there
to fucking rescue her!
All right.
Do you understand that?!
Me! Not you!
Not you! But me!
Every day!
All right.
So forgive me for not going home
to have a good night's rest!
Now, why don't you look
for my fucking daughter
rather than fighting --
hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey.
Don't follow me.
Hey, hey.
Mr. Dover. Mr. Dover.
You don't think I'm gonna let
you get behind the wheel
after you've been drinkin',
do you?
I'm gonna walk.
You look for my daughter.
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Anna: Daddy.
Daddy.
Look, daddy, we found it.
Anna...Where was it?
[ Whistle blows]
[ Gasps ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Computer keys clacking ]
[ Light chatter ]
[ Water spraying ]
[ Alex screaming ]
[ Screaming continues ]
[ Water stops ]
[ Alex whimpering ]
[ Faintly ] I'm not Alex.
I'm not Alex.
What -- what are you saying?
What? What?
I'm...Not...Alex.
Wait a minute.
You're not Alex? What?
I'm not Alex.
Just a second.
I don't understand.
Just -- just talk to me.
I waited, and he never came.
Come on.
No more riddles.
Just fuckin' tell me.
I'll let you go home
to your aunt
if you tell me
where they are.
[ Panting ]
I just wanted to play.
Don't make me
do this again.
And he never came.
Don't make me do it.
[ Quietly]
He never came.
I just wanted to --
why are you
making me do this?
Help me, God.
[ Sighs ]
Relying on your almighty power
and infinite mercies
and promises,
I hope to obtain pardon
for my sins.
[ Sighs ]
[ Car alarm chimes ]
Fuck me.
No -- no noise.
You shut up.
You make any noise,
I'm gonna turn on that tap.
[ Wood creaks ]
Hey, rise and shine.
I'm not gonna find
two girls here, am I?
Fuck you.
What about Alex Jones?
What about him?
I came here to drink.
I don't want to drink
in front of my wife.
Look...My father left me
this building, all right?
You mind giving me a tour?
Why didn't you tell me
about this place?
I didn't think
it mattered.
Everything matters.
It's all pretty much
like this.
I'm gonna renovate soon.
Yeah.
Not as organized
as your basement, huh?
What's up with all
the survivor gear in there?
Pray for the best,
prepare for the worst.
Guess we agree there,
yeah?
Come on, hurry up.
[ Cellphone rings ]
Shit.
Hello?
The guy that you were looking
for was just here.
He saw me watching him
and ran.
You get a plate?
Yeah.
Go home, Mr. Dover.
[ Knock on door ]
Hi.
Mornin'.
Why'd you run away from me
the other night, man?
I've never
seen you before.
You sure you have
the right house?
You doin' some shopping
at the value mall lately?
Yeah.
[ Clears throat ]
Why? Is it a crime
to shop there?
I can't afford to buy suits
from Brooks brothers.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughing ]
Yeah, I know.
You bought
children's clothes.
Did I?
Must've been in a hurry.
Mm-hmm.
Do -- do you
have children?
[ Softly ] No.
I don't...
Have...
Have anything --
come on! Christ!
[ Whimpering ]
Give me your fucking hand.
[ Whimpers ]
Hey.
If you move, I'll put a bullet
through your fuckin' head.
[ Insects buzzing ]
This is 13-40.
I need additional unit
for search.
437 Carrol street.
Possible kidnapping victims
on the premises.
[ Buzzing continues ]
[ Door creaks ]
[ Grunts ]
Anna? Fuckin'...
Anna? Joy?
Fuck.
[ Metal clangs ]
[ Crowbar clangs ]
[ Snakes hiss ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
Ah! Fuck.
[ Snakes hissing ]
Ah.
Ah. Fuck.
[ Siren wailing in distance ]
So we've taken photographs
of some of the clothing
we found
in the suspect's house.
[ Chatter in distance ]
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Nancy sobs ]
[ Sobbing ]
Loki: Mr. Dover.
Mr. Dover,
is your wife here?
She's not coming.
Well, if you can't make
a positive I.D.
On any
of these photographs
I'm gonna need her to come in
and take a look at them.
Have a seat.
[ Clears throat ]
So he confessed?
He said he killed them?
We were hoping
he was lying, but...
We haven't even found any
bodies, Mr. Dover, but...
...the birches
positively identified
two pieces of clothing.
I'm gonna need you --
I'm gonna need you to tell me
if you recognize anything.
[ Sighs ]
No.
Uh...
I'm not sure.
I don't know.
Okay.
No.
[ Voice breaking ] No.
That...That's her...
That's her sock.
You...
You wasted time.
You wasted time
following me.
[ Exhales sharply ]
You let this happen.
[ Clock ticking ]
Don't talk to them.
Eliza told me
they're dead.
Is it true?
No.
She said they found
their bloody clothes --
don't you tell
your mother that.
Don't you dare
tell your mother that.
You understand me?
Now, I need you
to listen to me.
I need you to stay around
the house for a couple of days,
and you make sure she does not
watch the news,
and when the paper comes,
you just throw it
the fuck away -- listen to me!
We do not give up
on your sister!
We do not!
I'm gonna find her.
I'm gonna bring her home.
We do not give up.
You're gonna bring her home?
She's dead.
You can't do anything.
You've been leavin' me and mom
here while you --
you've been goin' out
and getting fuckin' drunk!
You think
I can't smell it on you?!
Shut...Up!
[ Clatter ]
How long has this Bob Taylor
been workin' on this map?
Three-and-a-half hours.
And you think this is gonna lead
you to the bodies?
'Cause I sure
as shit don't.
Do me a favor, captain.
Go fuck yourself.
We weren't getting anywhere
questioning him.
That looks more like a maze
than a map.
He's got a thing
for mazes.
I'm goin' home.
Call me if somethin' happens.
[ Sighs deeply ]
[ Door closes ]
[ Humming shakily ]
[ Humming continues ]
Give me that card, Johnny.
The key card.
[ Door buzzes ]
All right,
it's done now.
Tell me
what you're drawing.
You said
you were drawing a map.
That looks like
a fucking puzzle.
You tell me
what you're drawing.
[ Hums ]
Tell me
what you're drawing.
I can't!
Yes, you can!
Oh, shit!
Shit!
Yes, you can!
Take him! Come on!
Yes, he can!
Oh, shit!
Gun! Gun! Gun!
Bob, don't!
Put the gun down!
Bob. Bob.
Bob, Bob, Bob, Bob, Bob, no!
No, no, no!
Fuck.
Go call a fuckin' r.A.!
Keller:
Our father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread,
and forgive us
our trespasses...
As we --
[ breathing heavily ]
As we for--
[ exhales sharply ]
[ Indistinct conversation ]
He explain this
before he ate the bullet?
I'm sorry.
Fuck you're sorry.
Save it
for the girls' parents.
[ Sighs ]
I don't know
what to do, Alex.
what to do anymore.
And what's completely fucked up
about all this
is I know
you know where they are.
I think we're done.
[ Sighs ]
[ Hoarsely ]
They're in the maze.
That's where
you'll find them.
What?
What did you say?
In the maze.
What -- what -- maze?
Where is it?
Where is the maze?
Where do I find it?
Alex?
Alex, Alex, listen to me.
I'm gonna get you
out of here, okay?
Just tell me
where the maze is.
That's it.
Just tell me, man.
[ Weakly ]
Where is the maze?
Come on, tell me.
Just tell me
where the maze is, okay?
Come on,
don't fuck with me.
Don't fuck with me now.
Tell me, God damn it!
Tell me where they are!
Tell me! Tell me!
Tell me!
[ Breathing heavily ]
Something's gonna
get to you, man.
Something's
gonna get to you!
[ Pounding ]
Something's
gonna get to you!
[ Pounding stops ]
[ Knocking ]
Holly:
Just a minute!
Can I help you?
Morning, ma'am.
Um...
I'm Keller Dover.
Uh, my little girl was abducted
with a friend.
What do you want?
Uh...
I-I guess I haven't thought this
through too good, huh?
I...
I've been thinkin' a lot about
what happened to your nephew.
And I know I scared him
the other day at the police
station, and -- and...
What I'm tryin' to say is
I kind of feel responsible
for him running away.
You wanna come on in?
Yeah.
My husband and I were...
Very devout at one time.
Spent our summers
driving around
in that camper
with our son...
Handin' out pamphlets...
Spreadin' the good word.
After our son died
of cancer...
We started seein' things
differently.
Adopting Alex helped...
But we never got over it.
I'm sorry.
You look very tired.
Yeah, I don't sleep much.
I, uh...
I keep dreaming
about being lost in a maze.
I'm sorry.
[ Chuckles lightly ]
Alex never talks
very much, so...
When people come over here,
I hardly know what to say.
He doesn't talk much?
Well, he talks, you know.
"Good morning," "good night" --
that sort of thing.
Hard to get too much more
than that out of him.
He had an accident
when he was little.
After that, he started
choosing his words
a little too carefully.
What, uh, what kind
of accident did he...
Oh.
My husband kept snakes.
It wasn't that bad
what happened,
but Alex had a fear
of them and...
That's not
my favorite memory.
I'm sorry. It's none --
none of my business.
Oh, it's...
Can I get you a cup of tea,
Mr. Dover?
Oh.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I thought you had known
about that already.
I say it's better
this way.
You know,
that awful man,
he would have spent years
on death row
just watchin' TV
and gettin' fat.
[ Liquid pours ]
Well, least I don't have to
worry about losing you to psp.
When forensics is finished
with the guy's place,
we're gonna deploy
the cadaver dogs.
Look, kid, we can't always
save the day.
All right?
We're just cops, janitors.
So you lost this one,
all right?
Look, you want fulfillment,
you need to find a girl,
you know, start a family,
have some kids.
Let it go.
[ Toy clatters ]
[ Cellphone rings ]
Right.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Yeah?
Hey, it's rich.
We found somethin'.
Guys, let us have a look.
Two kid-sized
department store mannequins,
with their heads caved in.
I just talked
to our lab guys,
and they told me that all
the blood that we sampled
from the plastic containers --
pig's blood.
All right, you guys,
let's get this covered up.
It's supposed to snow soon.
Hurry up, okay?
It's like
he's play-acting.
I mean, case in point.
Except for the few items I.D.'D
by the dovers and the birches,
all the kids' clothes
that we found
still had the tags
on them.
And that maze book
that we found, he made it.
Photocopies,
pictures from this book
that we found
in the attic.
Ex-f.B.I. Agent
wrote that.
"Finding
the invisible man."
Yeah, it's about a theoretical
suspect that he believed
was responsible for a bunch
of child abductions.
It's totally discredited,
I guess,
but I read some of it.
Taylor -- Taylor was abducted
when he was a kid.
He ran away
after three weeks.
And the captor drugged him
on some sort of
lsd/ketamine cocktail.
He never remembered.
They never caught the guy.
Okay, so...
He read the book
and decided he was taken
by the invisible man.
Now he's doing
his best imitation, right?
Yeah, he was doing
his best imitation.
He killed himself
last night.
How did he do that?
I thought he was in custody.
Hey.
Taylor drew this.
It's a map to the bodies.
And we found the same design
on a pendant
that we pulled off that corpse
the other day.
There's a connection.
Okay?
The connection is that it's
the last maze in the book.
I did it. It's unsolvable.
There's no way out.
Your corpse is another wannabe
who read the book.
What are you saying
to me, rich?
What are you saying to me?
What are you saying?
That -- that --
that this guy is a fake?
You're saying
that the girls --
the girls are still
out there somewhere?
How did Bob Taylor
get those clothes?
How did -- how did --
how did the parents...
Positively I.D.
Those clothes?!
That I can't reconcile.
You can't reconcile that?
Just keep knockin' on doors,
look in the windows.
Hey, why is that there?
Bag that.
Man:
Will do, sir. Right away.
[ Door closes ]
[ Dog barking in distance ]
[ Telephone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
Yes?
Um, yeah. This is she.
What?
Oh, my God!
Uh, wait. Is she...?
Ralph! Keller!
[ Engine shuts off ]
[ Screen door bangs shut ]
Keller! We need to go
to the hospital!
They found joy,
but not Anna!
What?
They didn't find Anna!
Maybe she'll know where Anna is!
Please, we have to go!
Keller!
Eliza's not picking up.
You should text her.
Nancy: Yeah.
[ Chatter ]
Nobody gets
beyond this point.
Don't touch me.
Miss!
Wait a minute --
it's okay.
Grace: Nancy.
Grace.
They'll find Anna.
I know they will.
Nancy:
Grace: I know.
How is she?
Keller: Is she awake?
Joy, were you far
from our street?
How far from the street
were you, joy?
Joy?
You can't be
doing this now.
How long did it take you
to get there?
Just let me ask a question!
Please.
Keller!
The detective will be back
in just a minute.
You need to wait.
She's been drugged.
Grace: Joy.
Sweetheart...
Just let us know
she's alive, okay?
Can you just
nod your head, baby?
Just nod your head?
Baby?
Can you give us a nod?
Can you nod your head
for us, please? Joy?
Keller: Joy?
[ Ominous music plays ]
[ Horn blares ]
You were there.
What?
I was -- I was where?
[ Crying ]
It put tape on our mouths.
Franklin: Shhh.
It's okay.
It's okay, baby.
It's okay. It's okay.
Mommy and daddy
are here now, okay?
You're all right.
Grace: Excuse me.
You're all right now.
I said nobody's allowed
in that room but her family.
Hey! Where you goin'?
Keller?
Hey!
Where's he goin'?
I don't know.
Hey!
Call downstairs.
Don't let him go.
Hey! Hey!
Block off the exits.
Hey!
[ Engine revs ]
Stop that car!
Get his truck!
Stop it! Hey!
Hey!
[ Horn blares ]
[ Tires screech ]
I've got you, you fucker.
I know where you're goin'.
[ Tires screech ]
[ Car alarm chimes ]
[ Alex screaming ]
[ Thumping in distance ]
[ Screaming continues ]
[ Screaming and thumping
continue ]
[ Alex wails ]
[ Knock on door ]
Hello again.
Hey. I was hoping you'd, uh,
you'd let me do some penance.
For what?
For scaring you the other day
at the, uh, the police station.
You already apologized
for that.
I know. I was -- you know,
I thought maybe you, uh...
You could use some, uh, help
around the --
you know, I noticed your door
here needs fixing,
so I brought my tools
and, uh...
Oh.
I see.
I burned myself.
Feel a little icky today.
But I'm glad you want
to talk some more.
No need to make excuses.
You come on in
and make me a cup of tea.
Come on in.
I don't want to have
to hurt you.
I know they were here.
Put your hands on your head
and turn around.
Do it.
I'm just gonna go.
Don't touch that bag.
Put your hands
on your head.
Come over here
to this counter.
Come on!
Top drawer.
Open it.
Mm-hmm.
Put them on.
You don't know me,
Mr. Dover.
But believe me when I tell you,
I won't let you go.
You don't have to
drink all of it.
About a third should do
for a man your size.
Something to make you
more manageable.
Forget it.
Drink it, Mr. Dover,
or I'll kill you right here
in my kitchen
and bring
your daughter in here
and have her scrub your brains
off the floor --
where is she?
[ Gun cocks ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
Drink.
Just let me see her.
You want to see her?
Yes!
That's your ticket to
your daughter right there.
[ Cap unscrews, clatters ]
A little more, Mr. Dover.
[ Sighs ]
Little more.
Good, isn't it?
That's my darlin'
husband's recipe.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Now go on out back.
Let me see her.
[ Cellphone ringing ]
[ Inhales sharply ]
Take it out
of your pocket.
Put it in the sink.
Put it in the disposal.
[ Ringing continues ]
[ Ringing stops ]
Put your car keys
on the table.
[ Gagging ]
Put your car keys
on the table.
That's right.
Over to the trans am
over there.
The car over there.
Come on, move it.
Get over there.
The look on your face.
My husband used to have
the very same look...
Till we took Alex.
He was the first kid
we ever took.
His name was Jimmy.
Or Barry.
Can't remember.
Doubt he can, either.
So many names.
Forgot all about
Bobby Taylor
till I read about him
in the paper.
Get in the driver's seat.
Open the door
and get in the car.
[ Car door creaks ]
Making children disappear
is the war we wage with God.
Makes people
lose their faith.
Turns them into demons
like you.
Had to slow down since
my husband disappeared.
But I do what I can.
Start the car.
[ Ignition turns,
engine grinds ]
Keep tryin'.
[ Engine whines, turns over ]
[ Engine sputtering ]
Back up. Slowly.
Come on. Back up.
Come on.
Stop.
Turn it off.
Turn it off!
[ Engine shuts off ]
Get out.
Think you should know.
Alex never laid a hand
on those girls.
Just wanted to take 'em
for a ride in the camper.
I was the one who decided
they should stay.
Take a look.
Maybe your daughter's
under there.
You never know.
Anna.
Anna!
Anna?
Anna. Anna!
[ Echoing ] Anna!
Anna?!
I had the girls down there
when the police
came pokin' around.
Should have
left 'em down there.
I was so lonely
without Alex.
[ Panting ]
Now get in there.
What?
Get in.
[ Breathing heavily ]
You want me to get in there,
you're gonna have to shoot me.
I'm not gonna get in there
just 'cause you asked.
God! Oh! God!
[ Groaning ]
Go on.
Get in there.
[ Groaning ]
That's right.
[ Shouts ]
[ Groaning ]
Ah!
Make yourself
a tourniquet.
Just might last 24 hours.
I'd love for you
to still be alive
when I dump your daughter's body
down there.
[ Groaning ]
[ Cover sliding ]
Wait!
No, wait, wait, wait!
[ Cover slides into place ]
No.
[ Engine sputters, turns over ]
[ Engine turns over ]
Hey.
I need you to go over
to holly Jones'.
She needs to be notified.
No. I need to find Dover.
Come on. You're done with Dover,
okay? Please?
You want me to go
to holly Jones'?
I want you to go to holly Jones'
and notify her, please.
Oh, God.
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Breathing raggedly ]
[ Moaning softly ]
Almighty God...
Protect my girl.
[ Engine shuts off ]
[ Car alarm chimes ]
[ Dog barks in distance ]
[ Door creaks ]
Mrs. Jones?
[ Creak ]
[ Light creaking ]
Show me your hands
right now.
Don't move and show me
your fuckin' hands right now.
Stop! Right now!
Show me
your fuckin' hands.
Do not move
and show me your hands.
Make sure they cremate me.
I sure as hell don't want
to be buried in some box.
Both hands! Right now!
Right now!
Fuck!
[ Breathing heavily ]
Anna.
Oh, my God.
[ Engine revs ]
Oh, God.
Anna.
[ Engine revs ]
[ Tires screech, horn blares ]
[ Moaning ]
Oh, shit.
[ Horn honks ]
[ Horn blares, tires screech ]
[ Horn blares ]
Come on. Come on.
Anna. Anna. Come on.
[ Tires screech ]
Stay with me, Anna.
Anna, stay with me, huh?
Stay with me, Anna!
[ Tires screech ]
It's all right!
Come on!
Go, move, move, move, move!
[ Tires screech ]
Don't die, don't die.
[ Engine revs ]
[ Tires screech ]
[ Horns blare, tires screech ]
It's okay, it's okay.
Honey. You're okay.
Hey.
Hey! Help!
Help! Help!
Help!
[ Chatter ]
Uh, detective loki?
I hope
we're not intruding.
No.
She's doing real good.
She's gonna be up and around
in a few days,
aren't you, buddy?
She just wanted to come and say
thank you and hi to her hero.
[ Scoffs lightly ]
Hello.
Uh, would you mind
giving me a minute?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Say goodbye, joy.
Bye.
I'll be out in a minute.
All right?
Say goodbye, Anna.
She found her whistle?
Uh, no.
She keeps insisting that
joy helped her find it
on Thanksgiving
before they were taken.
But I think
she's just confused.
I got her a new one.
[ Exhales sharply ]
He hasn't contacted me.
I know you don't...
I know you probably don't
believe that, but he hasn't.
I-I believe you.
Do you think
you're gonna find him?
[ Sighs ]
Yeah.
And he'll go to jail.
Probably.
Anyway...
Thank you for everything.
[ Sighing ] Oh, God.
[ Cries ]
I miss him.
He...He did what he had to do
to find Anna,
and I thank God for that.
[ Sniffles ]
He's a good man.
Bye.
[ Soulful vocalizing
on sound system ]
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Blows ]
That's it.
Let's pack it up.
[ Turns sound system off ]
You all done for the night?
Yeah, the ground's
frozen solid.
It's gonna take weeks to
excavate the entire property.
Just found some dead snakes
and shit.
Pray for the best,
prepare for the worst, yeah?
Night.
Shut her down.
[ Indistinct talking ]
[ Lights whir down ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Whistle chirps faintly ]
[ Scoffs lightly ]
[ Somber music playing ]