Reputed crime boss Gaetano Chezere...
Once again avoided prison
when a mistrial was declared
today in his 8-week-long RICO prosecution.
Allegedly responsible for over 200 murders,
Chezere has yet to spend one day behind bars.
Mr Eugene Gordlock, a witness that repeatedly
asked to be recused from the case
was gunned down just a few hours earlier.
Punisher - War Zone
left all alone in a city outraged
by today's developments
No concrete evidence of tampering,
and with Mr Gordlock now dead...
Do I fix your
make up for you?
Come on.
You know so, the captain should have
sent me out here with 30 or 40 men
to raze this bloody get out of jail party.
Instead I'm stuck here with you.
He might come out tonight.
As a matter of fact I'm
pretty sure he's going to show up.
And what are you going to do?
I'm going to bring him in.
You know, you kill me so.
Let's just say you can make this happen.
Why would you?
He does to those bastard what
me and you can only fantasize about
Hey, keep your nose clean.
-Yeah, sure thing pops.
Hey, Okay now, I was just, uh...
Take it easy in there, ok?
Nicky
What am I going to do?
Give the old guy a heart attack?
Go on, beat it.
- Give me una minuto.
You handled the witness situation...
... perfectly.
No sweat, Uncle G.
You look great?
The hell I do.
I shit in a bag for Christ's sake.
Hey, it saves you a
trip to the can, right?
You came to discuss a private matter.
Down at the docks!
-Right yeah, Cristu Bulat.
I hear he's a sick fucker...
...fresh off the boat.
Cristu's bringing in a shipment.
Needs a safe port.
I've arranged for my custom's guy
Simmons to be on that night...
The union boys will be there to unload
Our cut's 10 mil.
We won't break a sweat.
10 mil. What's Cristu's shipment?
-I don't know.
Some kind of biological package.
-Biological package!
I fucking knew it!
Probably going up to
the rag heads in Queens.
Cristu's guaranteed it's leaving the city.
We don't touch that kind that shit!
In case your memory is going along with
the rest of your bodily functions...
... you might like to remember,
I'm the top earner around here.
I'm not stupid.
- Stupido.
You're as shithouse crazy as your brother,...
...Loony Bin Jimmy.
I should have had the
both of you locked away!
One more word about my brother,
I swear to Christ I'll....
You know what,
you make one move you greasy fuck!
Hey, let's just all calm down here, ok.
I put on a big spread out here,
So come on boys.
Eat up!
I'm not fucking eating with that
shit bag. You understand?
Pittzy, pour me a drink!
Vaffanculo!
What the fuck?
Let's go!
Alright, let's split up.
Shouldn't we wait for back up?
Police! Freeze!
Listen, Billy Russoti is getting away.
The silver Rover.
Might want to head out to the docks first.
Shit! That hurt!
What happen to you?
Your Punisher. He disarmed me, held me at gunpoint
then he stole my damn ride.
And where the hell were you, huh?
I know he would come.
Let me get your statement.
Come on, Cesare, tell me everything.
How'd it go down? Huh?
-muffled-
Oh well. Maybe it's a blessing in disguise.
It's time for me to take over
anyway, thanks to the Punisher!
I won't even get my fucking hands dirty.
There's your problem.
What the fuck he doing here?
-Relax!
I asked him to come.
My man. How are you doing?
Who the fuck are these fanooks?
These are a couple of my colleagues.
They are very very...
...gifted deliverymen.
No mountain too high. No river...
...too deep.
Alright, alright...enough!
Pittsy, get me some money.
Time to go to work.
Running a little low, boss.
We just picked up 200K from
the Luciano Construction site.
I had to launder it
through the Pussy Cat lounge
Like you told me, remember?
Well bring it back tomorrow.
- You got it boss.
Here. That's 20 rolls of hundreds.
That's a grand each, all counted.
Head for the port. Do your monkey thing.
Get over the security fence. Hand out the money.
Hey, where the fuck you going?
Will it be alright if
I took the roof instead of the door?
Whatever.
You're a fucking saint.
Hey, what's the matter?
Fuck!
What the fuck with that?
Agent down! Repeat, agent down! Fuck!
I'll check it out boss.
Pop!
-No, I'l take care of it.
You get the guards!
Pittsy!
Fuck!
Fuck you Castle!
Come on, Frank!
Fuck you, Frank!
Fuck you Castle you fuckin...
Pittsy! Pittsy!
There he is!
FBl, drop your weapons!
Oh shit! Shit!
You two, up the stairs.
The rest, behind me.
Don't move!
FBI
Put your weapons down!
We got a live one!
Billy the Beaut!
Not anymore, eh?
Wait a minute.
The Lord is compassion and love.
Slow to anger and rich in mercy.
He does not treat us according to our sin,
nor repay us according to our faults
As parents have compassion on their children
The Lord had pity of those here.
For he know of what we are made.
He remembers that we are dust
And for us, our days are like grass.
We flower like a flower in a field.
The wind blows and we are gone,
and our place never sees us again.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
-Thank you.
Who compromised Donatelli?
Calm down Budiansky.
It wasn't anybody's fault.
None of us could have foreseen Frank Castle
opening up hunting season on La Cosa Nostra.
Come on!
Look, Donatelli sent us a message.
He said something big is going to happen.
He asked for Homeland Security. We've
been running 24 hours surveillance on Russoti.
And just as we were about to find
out what the fuck is happening,
Donatelli got shot
believe me!
No one's more pissed off about it than I am!
How is it we are not all over Frank Castle?
Because we have real National Security
threat, and the last time I checked
that tops trying to stop some
crazed vigilante.
Go!
Hey.
- Hey.
I'm going to get this guy Angie.
I promise you.
I heard the Bureau
was sending a baby sitter.
A liaison.
-Thirty years on the force.
I still don't know what that word means.
We have a certain way of doing
things around here, Special Agent Budiansky.
Like letting mass murderers run free?
4 years, this Punisher
has been wreaking havoc.
And you haven't once caught a break.
I'm always deep in shit
around here as you can plainly see.
Your buddies from the Bureau told me
the city is under some kind of terror threat
New Yorkers are a bit sensitive
about that if you know what I mean.
I've got all my men trying to find out what
your late colleague came across when he went under.
Maybe if you Feds allowed us lowly cops
in on your undercover operations once in a while
all of this could have been avoided.
With all due respect, Captain,...
that, is bullshit!
What if it had been your man lying there, huh?
in a pool of his own blood?
You crispy crème mother fuckers
would be beating down every door in the city
Captain. Captain, You know what?
The Punisher task force could
use an extra man.
Room 12,
The basement.
Ah, Agent Budiansky?
Did I get that right?
Captain told me you were coming in.
Welcome to the Punisher task force.
I'm Detective Martin Soap.
Pleasure.
Make yourself at home.
-You have a degree in behavioral psychology
Surprised?
That's okay, most people are.
So, what do you actually do here?
Here?
- Uh huh.
This is ground zero.
I shadowed his every step for the last five years.
I've documented every murder that fit his profile.
I've collected intelligence on all known associates.
Take the look at this.
Six years ago,
Frank Castle was a
Special Forces instructor
And a simple family man. One day
he takes his wife and kids for a picnic
And by chance or fate,
depending on which you believe in,
they witnessed a mob execution.
When they were discovered.
Castle survived.
Since then, he's been taking down
one crime family after another.
I'm really close, Budiansky
The only thing getting
in my way is some bad luck.
But I have a feeling
that's about to change.
You know, I've
been waiting for someone like you.
Take a look at some of the case files.
Get the lay of land. I'll get us a pie
from Melanos. Best pizza in the city
With drawer?
-What?
The alleged Punisher murders.
All of them.
What do you want, Micro?
You ever heard of Jahadiblogger.com?
I'm posing as a one-arm Wahabi warrior
who took a crap in a cave next to bin Laden.
I think I can score you a couple of rocket launchers.
What do you want?
I haven't seen you in a while.
I brought you some treats.
It's gun show season in Virginia
No background checks, no problems.
That's too much Frank.
Call it a retirement package.
Look I know this thing with the Fed is eating you
up inside but that doesn't mean that you pack up your tent.
We all make the mistakes Frank.
You are fighting a war...
against the assholes who slip through
the raindrops. Who get away with it.
In any war there is collateral damage.
You know that.
Collateral damage?
I killed an agent in the field.
One of the good guys.
He had a family.
You didn't know.
I fucked up Micro.
Now please, just leave me alone.
Where the fuck is Nicky?
He didn't make it.
-Nicky was a fucking rat.
For the Feds.
What about my money?
We already went
to his place and tore it apart.
No sign of the safety deposit key or nothing.
Does he got any next of kin?
Somebody to carry
on the family name?
Yeah. Paper said something
about a wife and a little girl.
Good. Let's look there.
- You got it.
Hey, Buck! Where you been?
Am I glad to see you.
- Hi Billy.
You should have seen those
fucking brashules at the clinic.
They must have bought their
fucking degrees off of the internet.
How the heck did you end up at a free clinic?
Insurance said I missed a payment.
Can you fucking believe that?
Yeah, before we do this,
I need you to understand.
The severity of your injuries
when you arrived here.
Statistically speaking you
shouldn't have been able to survive this.
Well that's why I'm here, Doc.
I have the best plastic surgeon
in all of New York.
Your facial muscles, tendons,
bone structure, everything - it was destroyed.
There wasn't a single
square inch of skin
left intact.
Just take it off already.
Ok, let's do this.
Now I need you to sit
forward a little bit.
Alright.
Ok!
Polymers
strategically placed alloy plates,
And just a little bit of horse hide.
A little what?
I need to talk to my doctor alone.
Yeah, of course, Billy.
What the fuck's the matter with you?
You can't fuckin' control yourself?
You know how sensitive
he is about his looks.
Sorry Pops, it's just that I've never
seen anything so...  -Just shut the fuck up!
You ok boss?
Much better, thanks.
I'll be in the car.
No more distractions.
We need to focus on my goals.
One.
We need to get my money back.
Two. We gonna get rid of Frank Castle.
Well...
He took out like 30 of us. I mean-
How are we gonna kill him
before he'll kill us?
My brother will take care of that.
Loony Bin Jim?
-Shut the fuck up.
His name is James.
Not Loony Bin Jim.
Not LBJ, James.
-I'm sorry.
It was a good idea Really, It is.
Don't mind him.
He doesn't think before he talks.
Just like his mother.
Sorry about that Billy.
Billy is dead.
From now on, you call me Jigsaw.
How are we doing today,
Loony Bin Jim?
Yummy yummy.
So good.
What?
Doctor Basner. Open up.
Yes, doctor.
Billy?
Is that you?
It is.
You look fantastic, brother.
Ink, cut these off. Now.
Pittsy, go open the doors of every other cell.
Lead everybody out at the front door.
Sure thing, Billy... Jigsaw.
I'll take care of this guy.
Oh no brother. Fatso is mine.
Of course.
I'm gonna get my apple sauce back.
Did you know...
Kidneys in apple sauce are
a delicacy in Sweden?
Did you know that? Yes.
Yummy yummy yummy,
in my tummy tummy tummy.
What do ya say boss?
Stuff might come in handy.
What for?
Well, in case he starts,
you know, not feeling so good.
He's doing just great.
You're in my light.
For the next time someone
gets in your light.
Stay the fuck away from my little girl.
Mom! That's a bad word.
-Go inside, Grace.
You're messing with the wrong family
on the wrong day, asshole.
You... You are...
What are you doing here?
What makes you think you can come here?
You scared the girl.
-Shut up.
Just shut your mouth.
I'm sorry.
-I said shut up.
What's this?
Something to help out.
-No.
No, you don't get to do that.
You don't get to shoot my husband
in cold blood...
and did stuff with the ATM.
It's for your daughter.
This is what you deserve.
What you did to Nicky.
Who punishes you?
He taught you how to shoot.
Good agent keeps his family safe.
He couldn't always be here.
Took the out to the range.
Showed you what to do.
This... is where you do it.
Squeeze.
Don't pull.
I can't find my red pen.
Mom? I need it.
Take it.
Is this it boss?
- Yeah.
Nice brother.
Is it yours?
Not yet.
Ol' Cesare used to
rent it to screw hookers
Let's go inside before I freeze
my fucking balls off.
What's the matter, Billy?
Just when I think I'm Ok
I see my reflection somewhere and ...
I look horrible.
What has he done to me?
Oh no... don't cry, brother.
Everything is gonna be alright.
I promise you two things.
One, I will find Castle and
I will kill him.
Slowly and painfully.
And two, you will never ever have to
look at your reflection again,
as long as you're with me.
- Speaking in Russian -
You're not in Transylvania anymore Cristu.
We don't talk vampire.
It's Russian,...
My men is concerned.
If Punisher can do this to your face,
what might he do to our deal?
The tongue stretches further than
most people think.
Ask your man how he's gonna talk
that shit,
when I pull it from his mouth.
Or you'll what?
Enough!
The Punisher is not a problem.
The docks are mine.
My looks have nothing to do with this.
Everybody.
From local security to international
customs is in my pocket.
Quite frankly. This job doesn't get done
without me.
What do you think?
It seems he is right.
We do not need monster.
Shit!
Stop!
My most sincere apologies.
My father always say never insult
your host.
Sounds like a reasonable man.
You don't know my father.
Three days.
It has to be 12 million.
We agreed on 10.
- We both know ...
that this biological shit you're
bringing in isn't leaving the city.
You're selling it to the ragheads
in Queens.
The ports been crawling with suits
from Homeland.
It's going to take a lot of payola
to keep it quiet.
I always knew you'd be a good boss, Billy
Thanks brother.
Latin kings.
Let him go, Frank.
You know this piece of shit?
Ex piece of shit.
-Yeah.
He's a regular choir boy.
Fuck you, cracker.
-Language!
It's a genius racket.
You know how the cops are
always running those guns buy backs?
Except they never work.
Because what banger
is gonna trust a cop, right?
Well, these drive by whack jobs,
they just love Carlos here.
They get one look at that lnk,
and they know he's for real.
We get the guns of the streets to you
Never once seen a banger that could quit.
Too fucking stupid.
He's straight, Frank.
Hey ma! Frank's here.
He says eat up.
How is she doing?
Yeah well...
As long as she's got her cooking shows,
she's good.
It's the only thing she notices.
But hey that's something, right?
Listen. I-
I just came around to tell you I'm
going out of town for a while.
Out of town?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I never thought of the Punisher, you know
taking a long weekend.
I'm not planning on coming back.
So I take it things didn't go so well
at the Donatelli home.
Are you aware that Billy Russoti survived?
I heard.
Let the cops take care of him.
You and I know they got nothing on him.
Their hands are tied.
This is where the Punisher comes in.
This is why I believe in you.
Why I've supported you all these years.
You want me to tell you when
something happens to...
Mrs. Donatelli and her daughter?
Because that's what's gonna happen.
You don't think he's gonna go
for revenge?
It's not a question of if.
it's just a matter of when.
Pull a couple of Berettas.
-For what?
3, 2, 1
Russoti is the last one.
Then I'm done.
For your own lips to God's ears.
You know where I can find him.
I don't have a fix on him.
You wiped out all of his associates
that are known to me.
I saw him with some new guys.
The leader was black.
Dreadlocks.
Doing some kind of acrobatic
stuff over the roofs.
That's Maginty and his
Urban Freeflow Gang.
He's a mean motherfucker.
He's on a constant meth high.
Well come on.
You want to find this guy or not?
You boys play nice.
I've been looking for you.
Agent Budiansky. Take a load off.
I need to go see Castle.
Where do I find him?
-Brats, you know.
He just left.
Wait...
You know what I like to do.
I like to sit in my car and listen
to the CB Radio and follow the crime.
I might just run into him.
It's never worked for me
in five years now.
But I'm not the luckiest guy
on the planet, you know.
Let's get through the back door.
Maginty and his boys are planning to hit
a convenience store of 45th and 2nd.
Suspects are armed and dangerous.
I repeat.
Let's do this.
Really?
Just drive the car.
Come on! Run!
Oh fuck!
Please
Don't kill me.
Russoti, where is he?
Yeah Jigsaw, I was just with him.
He was suppose to give us some
dope for a job.
But it turns out...
He don't have any anymore.
He forgot. He botched it.
He be a bastard.
So you wanna go see him,
you need to tell him this,
Wee bitch. Take it back.
So tell him, for something,
Mr. Punisher, sir.
So when did Donatelli
go undercover?
We were partners in narcotics.
Unfortunately,
most of the blow we confiscated.
ended up in my nose.
Internal Affairs tried to
get Nicky to rat me out.
He wouldn't.
So, they sent him undercover.
He's dead because of me.
So you still skiing the old Alps?
No. That's in the past.
Holy shit!
I'm getting out.
You meet me on the other side.
Boo.
Hello, Mrs. Donatelli.
Or will you be calling
yourself 'miss' from now on.
What do you want from us?
I'm looking for my money.
Which your rat of a husband
stole from me.
But we don't have it. I swear to God.
How about you, sweet cheeks?
Would you also like to swear
on an imaginary friend?
Make sure they don't move.
I'll look for the money.
-Come here kid.
Freeze, asshole.
You're under arrest.
Stay out of my way.
Listen to me.
Russoti is headed to the Donatelli house.
He's probably already there.
You have to let me go.
You have the right to shut the fuck up.
Good evening, officers.
Is everything Ok in there?
No. Everything is not Ok.
Follow me.
Officer.
No you don't!
Well...
This day was about to come sooner
or later, wasn't it?
Have you heard back from the patrol car?
So...
I tried it a couple times.
There was no answer.
Listen.
We gotta get out of here before
more pigs arrive.
Where is my fuckin' money?
My husband has a safe upstairs
in the bedroom.
I don't know if it's there but
I can give you the combination.
10-12-1965
Oh how cute.
Is that your dead husband's birthday?
Let me out here.
Get him to the station.
-You bet.
Let me out.
You know, Frank.
Throwing your tip now and then
is one thing.
Password to the crime database, sure,
but letting you go, so-
Fine.
How you doing?
19.
What was that?
Go check it out.
What the fuck you waiting for? Christmas?
Now.
Now, you sit down.
I'm calling this in.
Put your hands behind your back.
Goddamnit you asshole!
Where do you think you're going?
Hands up!
I repeat,
Request immediate back up.
Don't worry. I'm here.
Give me your fucking gun.
Stay right where you fucking are.
We did it, Budiansky, huh?
You mind explaining it to me...
how a handcuffed criminal escapes custody
the back of your locked car?
The Castle is a slippery one.
You'll be safe here.
We can manage on our own.
Just until we know Russoti's
been arrested.
Grace.
Grace, you listen, honey.
She's smart.
Go ahead. Open it.
It... belonged to my daughter.
Here.
Wow!
Put that down, honey.
This was... Lisa's favorite toy.
She got so angry when her little
brother used to hide it from her.
Does she care if I play with it?
No.
You gonna fry for killing
two of my officers, Billy.
I want a lawyer.
- Oh, you'll get your fucking lawyer.
No lawyer's going to get
you out of this one.
Lousy piece of shit.
Agent Miller.
What are you doing here?
Russoti.
What's he gotta do with the Bureau?
The case Donatelli was
working on.
He says he got some intel to
make a deal for.
Anyone know where he is right now?
They just brought him
into the observation room.
Good.
Yeah.
Captain Ross. Agent Miller with the Bureau.
I believe you've been informed
I'll be taking over this.
This perp killed two of my officers.
And terrorized a widow and child
of one of your agents.
You keep that in mind, Miller.
You're lucky I came to you with this.
But then I'm a patriot just like you.
I shit red white and blue.
The reason you came to me is
because you got caught.
So don't insult my intelligence, Ok?
You tell me what you know.
If it's any good,
I'll recommend life without parole.
This deal is going down tonight?
I know when and I know where.
So you're gonna give me and my brother
the immunity and the money.
Or you're gonna have to explain
to Wolf fucking Blitzer...
why you had a lead on the thing
that killed half of the fucking city,
and you didn't do
a goddamn thing about it.
I'll be right back.
Oh and Miller.
Just that one other little thing.
Wow!
Happy?
Shit! You bastard.
You're fucking dead men.
My father will kill you.
Hear me?
My father will serve your head
on a fucking silver platter!
Agent Miller.
It's agreed.
The other conditions of our agreement?
Clear the area.
I hope to God he finds you,
and you get what you deserve.
How long was l-
A long time.
You should eat.
Yuck!
-Grace.
What is it?
Egg and cheese MREs.
That's all I have.
What's an MRE?
Meal. Ready to eat.
Military food.
It's great for people who can't cook.
Look, Grace.
This is gonna come with chuckles.
It's the best one I got.
Not exactly a balanced breakfast.
Out of practice.
Not one more step.
Where's Micro?
His mother isn't feeling well.
He didn't want to leave her.
Damn it.
I need to talk to him.
This is Carlos.
He's... a friend of mine.
He's gonna hang while I
take care of some things.
Hi Carlos. I'm Grace.
Hey little darling.
We're gonna be homies, right?
Yeah. we're gonna be tight.
This all will be over soon.
Then you can go.
Don't go.
I need you alert.
Don't make me regret this.
That was fun.
Now let's go kill Castle and
his miserable whore.
No, not yet.
We're gonna have ourselves
a little fun with this.
Next time he has to face us
and a fucking army.
Where do we get the army from?
Just like Uncle Sam, bro.
We recruit in troubled neighborhoods.
Offer a hundred grand towards
a college education they'll never get.
Promise nobody ever has to
go to Iraq.
Just as long as I get to kill Castle.
Don't worry brother. You will.
Just making damn sure this time
he don't come back breathing.
Hold it.
Hello sportsfans.
How are you today my friend?
Run! Get out of here!
Hey! I axed you a question.
- Run!
You don't answer.
Guess I'll have to ask it again.
Here I come.
Good.
Bring them upstairs.
Meet me back down here.
I'll see if we can talk a few
poor bastards into signing up.
Where are they?
I shout. I swear I shout.
Goddamnit! Don't die on me.
I'm bleeding out.
I seen this shit before.
Shut up kid. You're gonna be fine.
It hurts real bad.
Hurts real bad, Frank.
Don't let me die like this, man.
Not like this.
See you in hell.
I see you anywhere near hell,
I'll kick your ass out.
I haven't seen you in ages, Frank.
Whatever it is, it must be pretty bad.
Maybe I'm just here to see an old friend, Mike.
Yeah right. I haven't seen you since-
The funeral. I know.
I've been reading about you.
You've been a long way from
the seminary, my friend.
I don't even remember
that as part of my life.
Why do you do this?
Somebody has to punish the corrupt.
For in the same way you judge others,
you will be judged.
And with the measure you use,
it will be measured to you.
Matthew. 72.
I'm Ok with that.
God be with you, Frank.
Sometimes I'd like to get
my hands on God.
Interesting choice for a meeting place.
Didn't take you for a religious man,
Castle.
Yeah well. An eye for an eye.
If I remember right, they are
not called the Ten Suggestions.
Russoti's got Angela and Grace.
How?-
Doesn't matter.
Or maybe if you put her in protective
custody like you should've...
we wouldn't be having this conversation.
They'd be dead.
The law can't touch them, Castle.
Total immunity.
Unless you got a video tape of
Russoti taking them.
Can't even give him a parking ticket.
It's a fucked up system you're
sworn to protect.
I never said it was perfect.
He wants me in
exchange for them.
I need you to secure the trade.
Ok.
But I'm doing this by the book.
What book do you think
they're going by huh?
I took an oath, Castle.
There are laws.
-No official police procedure.
You wanna come along?
Leave your badge at home.
I have to think about it.
The clock's ticking.
Gentlemen. Gentlemen.
Relax.
We're looking for a few good man.
And we'd like to offer you
the opportunity...
to be all that you can be.
Now we've all suffered loss,
at the hands of the Punisher.
And because we don't look like
everybody else,
and because we don't act like
nobody does a goddamn thing about it.
Well I say, he ain't the only one who can
take the war into his own hands.
So if you're as sick of this
cocksucker as I am,
raise your armies.
You'll be well paid.
You'll be well armed.
And at the end of it, the Punisher
will be dead.
Agent Budiansky.
Just in time for happy hour.
You need to come with me.
Where to?
Your partner, Frank Castle.
He needs help.
Partner is a little bit
of an exaggeration.
How did you know?
Usually unless you've arrested Houdini.
A handcuffed criminal does
not escape that easily.
You know you're not as stupid as you-
I didn't say that.
Who are we looking for?
Cristu's father.
I don't think this is a good idea.
What?
We're looking for Tiberiu,
Cristu father.
Why?
If I were to Tiberiu,
I'd probably wanna find the man who was
responsible for sending my son to prison,
for the rest of his life.
And how would you do that?
I tell him when and where to find him.
What do you want from me?
I don't like him.
I want him taken care of.
No worries my friend.
Here they are.
Oh boy!
Take it easy James.
He'll be here.
You get it.
- Fuck that, you get it!
I'll get it.
What you looking for?
I'm here to see the Jigsaw.
- You out of luck. No Jigsaw here.
I'm here, for the Punisher party.
Who is the old man?
That's Critu's father.
Old country genocidal maniac.
Figured he'd stir up a shitstorm for us.
Cops will be all over this place
once the fireworks start.
I wouldn't worry about that,
I called in a explosives permit.
Consruction. Said we'd be
blasting dynamite all night
So, what's the plan?
I going in to get them.
You call that a plan.
It's all I've made.
Well I'm going with you.
I never took the time
to think about where I was headed.
I'm far down that road.
You're not going there.
Thanks Frank.
You know he's going to take it
out on me when he wakes up.
You don't hear gunfire for
longer than 5 minutes
Then the girls are not here.
Set him loose.
It's time.
James, be careful.
Oh for fuck sake!
You won't be replacing that
son of yours any time soon.
Blood in the urine. Early
indicator of kidney failure.
You should be seeing
double right about now.
That would be a torn meniscus.
James!
Gun!
Welcome! Welcome! Welcome!
Please help us!
-Shut the fuck up!
C'mon Castle, don't be shy.
Throw down your gun!
Die you bastard.
-No, James
That's no way to punish the Punisher.
Nice shooter!
Catch! Let's play a game.
What do you say?
You got one round left in there.
You shoot one of these two
I'll let the other one go free.
What do you say, Frank?
Who's it to be,
your fat friend right here?
Or that nice little piece
of jailbait over there?
Burn in hell!
-Ok
Then they both die.
Frank!
She's a kid. Shoot me.
Ok, fuck it, kill her first!
-No!
Stop!
He's made a decision.
Not looking too good for you, fatso
You have to three, Castle!
One
Two
You won't feel a thing my friend.
God!
Frank!
Get out!
Fuck you!
Let me put you out of my misery!
This is just the beginning!
You ok?
Where is Castle?
-Still inside
And Micro?
Frank!
Are you ok?
You better get out of here.
Come on, Frank, I'll buy you a drink.
Wait! Wait!
My husband Nicky, we talked about you.
Argued about you.
He said you were one of the good guys.
You know buddy?
Maybe it's time to quit now, huh?
I mean, you must get tired of this, right?
I think you got all the criminals in town.
If there are any left
at least consider rehabilitation.
I mean contrary to popular
belief, people can change.
I guess what I'm saying is, I'm
just personally not a fan of the death penalty.
Frank?
Where did he go?
Hey, give me your fucking
wallet motherfucker!
You're kidding right?
Do I look like I'm fucking kidding?
Frank!
- Give me your wallet!
Frank?
Do you wanna die?
For the last time, give me your wallet!
Oh God. Now I've got
brains splattered all over me.