LOS ANGELES, 1999.
Subtitle by D3xt3r
www.addic7ed.com
You're getting roving in by
Senor Rapist here huh?
Having a good day?
- Yeah.
I'll break it down for you,
all you really need to know is...
On this whole, sear brown skin..
A Mexican man hates a Honduran,
Just like a Guatemalan hates a Salvadoran.
They're really not all the same.
No matter what you think.
Everybody's dealing dope.
Twenty-four Seven.
Like opening a supermarket.
Everybody got a wood-stick for LAPD.
Typical onion head banger.
Maybe a mexican, you know?
Tucson or Fuego..
and all the shit that eldoras..
something important, what little barn
or cooler can Uncle Juanito comes from.
How many fucking cayotes,
dirty little hamster bred with--
turning 'em up to promise land.
What about the scandal?
Scandal is bullshit.
Two dickhead cops got involved
in some fuck off..
ratted out the entire sweet division,
to save their wretched own asses.
D.A's office is running scared;
Afraid to file..
afraid not to exonerate en fucking mass...
Now you got a lot of hopped up
'riding-the-king' wannabe,
beaner wrecking whoopty do,
with their own 'get out of jail' free card,
and pile of county cash.
This used to be a glorious soldier's department.
Now, it's...
..you.
What's funny?
Private Hatcher here's enquiring
about the scandal of the century.
You didn't touch your fries?
- What?
No, I had a couple of them,
but i got a cholesterol thing,
What.. you want 'em?
No, you want them.
Finish it.
I can't...i don't eat french fries.
- Well then, you shouldn't order it.
Finish this fries.
Dave hates wasting food.
You never see him eating nothing but...
he hates wasting food.
Hey, if you keep going
the way you're going..
you're gonna start looking like
one of 'em crackheads.
Munch, munch! Cowgirl..c'mon.
Very attractive crackhead, mind you.
You want one?
- No, no..no. You're doing good.
I'd stay healthy.
Finish those fucking fries,
if you wanna make probation.
Okay?
- Yes, sir.
Your dad, ever discipline you?
Huh?
No, sir.
I never met my father.
Never met him...Why?
- He wasn't around.
General!
Eat up.
You aim for the shortest wet-back..
You watch him skedaddle,
Pull out the dice in shit small liquor cans.
And hit your siren in farewell.
Let's see what we've got.
You'll get the hang of it.
Aren't you worried?
- About?
You getting 128.
Okay, this is the most important thing
I've told you so far.
Everything you learned at the Academy..
Bullshit.
Illegal is just a shit bird.
Just some military occupation kit.
Emergency law.
Alright, let's have some fun.
What went on here?
Caught him boosting Ephederine.
Toprol Alcohol.
What happened?
He hit you?
- Yeah.
You hit him?
Tough guy...
Step outside, will you?
- Outside?
- Yeah, outside.
Can you step out too?
I don't know, Sir.
Now!
And shut that door behind you.
Now, you're cooking crank,
out of somebody's
garage..Now,
I don't know where that garage is.
But you do.
- I don't know shit.
- You do. Yes, you do.
Okay, so now..you have
petty theft..assault..
You have at least four prior
upto violation mandatory bullet..Compadre.
You give me that address,
it all goes away.
What's the address?
Tell me where it is..
C'mon now.
That's you man.
What?
- Meth lab.
Fourty One, eight Shay Chavez.
That's it..No explaination Dave?
Hey, Dave..listen.
Yeah?
Circuit Court appeals for
Illegal search and seizure, give me a precedent.
Cuthbert VS Engleside County, Virginia.
1966...look it up.
You have all those cases memorized?
- Even if I don't,
I'd make it up.
Hey, ladies.
Dave.
Hey, babe.
Dinner is at six thirty.
I'll be there.
Daddy!
Hey!
How's my girls?
- Great.
Yeah?
No Hello, Helen?
Hey, Date rape.
Don't call me that.
What's up, monkey?
- Helen has a question.
Maybe, You have a question.
- Uhm, We both have a question.
Helen's studying genetics in school;
and since our moms are sisters
and you're our dad...
We were just wondering,
If we're inbred.
It's not funny!
No, sorry...
Sorry.
No. I married your moms consecutively,
Not, concurrently.
Which makes you and Helen,
first cousins and sisters..Half.
...It's all..
perfectly legal and genetically
upto insurance's
industries standards.
You're not gonna turn into Mongoloids,
anytime soon.
If that's what you're asking.
You're not inbred.
You know what you are?
You are Native.
Marla, where's the olives?
There's no olives.
I'm sorry, I don't know.
I think we're out.
I'll look, but i think
we are out.
Why do you let her put that
thing on the wall?
Helen's poster?
- Yeah, that little cloth.
It's amazing!
She's been working really hard on it.
She's been working on that thing
for three weeks.
It's amazing, is it?
- It's..it's quite something.
- It is amazing.
I think it should be at the museum.
That's what I think.
Don't you tell your mother,
you learned that from me.
May I sleep with you, tonight?
I have sketching to do.
Please.
No? So, that's not a 'no'..Is it?
- That would be a nice way to say, NO.
What about after, your sketching?
- No.
Helen?
I'm curious about that artwork,
you have on the wall there.
What it mean?
What's it mean?
- What's it mean?
- Yeah, what is that?
What does that mean, that collage?
It's like, little bits of paper.
You cut them out and you like..
glue 'em together...
and like, make another picture -
Okay, so you have..like a man's head..
and a woman's heel..
digging into his head and..
stepping on his mouth and..
- It's art. Dave..it's art.
Naked woman and blood flowing
from her vagina. You have...
You have the C word prominently displayed.
- You have eyes. That's great!
What's the problem?
What is the problem?
Margereth, do you like..
Do you like her collage?
What is it?
Yeah, I agree.
It just need more color.
More color.
Honey?
- Mmmhmm.
How's your spagetti?
- It's good.
Yeah?
That's good.
How is yours?
- It's very good. Thank you.
You should try some.
Oh, I'm fine. Thank you.
Do your wanna cover later?
- I have a boyfriend.
Cheat on him.
- Like you cheat on your taxes?
I don't cheat on my taxes.
You can't...
cheat on something, you never commited to.
Alright.
I'm gonna go take a walk,
look for smilers.
Come on, we're just setting out something to eat.
He wouldn't be like this,
if you guys weren't so hard on him.
If only we have that option.
Well, it's the truth.
It's always something.
It's not the truth..
- okay.
But he's too hard on him,
but still..
Yeah, Dave Brown. Just..
It's too plain a name for somebody like me.
- What? You don't have a moniker?
You don't have a moniker,
like something...
your 'cop buddies' call you?
Yeah, my brother's on the...
Shamberdoor Sheriffs.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
I got a little..
I got a thing for Cops.
Are you sure, you don't
have a thing for your brother?
What? No!
NO!
That was...very, very impressive.
No, thank you. I don't smoke.
You don't smoke?
- No, I don't need it.
So, that wasn't as impressive as a..
- No, it was still very impressive trick.
Waiter: No smoking in here, Sir.
Jesus Christ!
You used to let me smoke in here.
Poor little rose.
That's for you.
- Woww!
I didn't get you anything.
I'm sure, you'll think of something.
So, come on, tell me.
What's your moniker?
What's it matter?
It matters. It tells everything
i need to know about you.
Maybe a little bit more...
Oh, come on. Don't be shy.
What? Is it..uh is it?
uh..Rough House Dave?
Yeah?
- I like that.
or uh...Bang Bang Brown?
Date Rape Dave.
Why is that?
Rumour from when I worked Hollywood sex,
That I can't comfirm it, nor I won't deny it.
So, tell me.
Maybe, I killed a bad guy.
Maybe, I didn't.
By the way,
he got what he paid for,
And he'll never hurt another woman,
ever again.
Oh.
Is that your foot?
Uhhh, yeah.
Oh, stop. Stop, stop.
Okay.
Good, go again.
Oh, well.
Hey, what's your fucking problem?
TV: Brown was video taped.
Severely, beating a motorist named..
Shaundel Palmry.
In what civil rights group are calling
'Old School LAPD brutality',
revisited..
revised and regurgitated.
Local activists have launched
a new attacks on the LAPD
for it's culture of racialist conduct.
While, Officer Brown remains
on limited duty,
awaiting, possible disciplinary action
and pending civil lawsuit.
Bill Blago:
The Shaundel gate matter,
is in the early stages of investigation.
As opposed to the rampart scandal,
Which we should know as a
long standing..
highly complex and
multi-faceted issue,
of great social import.
That's Bill B for you.
He got..
Highly complex and multi-faceted
and great social import...
into one sentence and
he didn't say a damn thing.
I'll say this though,
The citizens of this great city
are sick and tired in the old ways of doing business..
They want action, not...
How's your day?
- Good, You?
Pretty good.
- Is someone still mad at me?
I don't know.
What are we watching?
Uhmm.
Hey, did you do your homework?
No.
- Great idea.
How about we make this
a homework free day?
Not that you'll tell your mom.
And I'll just watch television?
Okay.
Alright, what do you wanna watch?
Is this good?
Yeah.
Okay.
Date rape!
Thanks for making us look good, Dave.
- You're the man!
What's the word, Chief?
Close the door.
So, what would you like me to say, Al?
I'll..I'll say whatever I need to.
Have you thought about retirement?
Ahh, No.
In fact...uhm...
If you force me to retired filed on me,
I'll plead not guilty,
take it to trial and represent myself.
I'll be playing to mentally,
deficient jury,
So, I'll loose.
Though, I'll work
Vietnam for all it's worth.
I'll have PTSD, DDT, TNT...
Ageing orange and the creeping
chinese crud before it's over..
Not to mention,
twenty-four years on the job.
I'll draw a fine and a suspended sentence.
Court T.V will broadcast the whole thing,
I'll have my own show on Fox News
inside one week...
You'll be my first guest.
- So, you have thought about it?
I don't intend to retire,
Miss Confrey.
- Alright.
You know,
Rampart has become..
a shit storm of such
epic proportions.
Legally and financially.
We have..
bullshit police brutality complains,
bullshit felony evidence plans...
Wrong door-fuck ups,
we have them all!
I have a ton of testimonies,
solicited and unsolicited;
that is, ambiguous... if not..
downright indecipherable.
County is going bankrupt,
paying lawsuit money.
The D.A's office and LAPD
are hemorrhaging prestige..
and a great many hardened criminals
are out on the street,
Way before, they should be.
And now..Dave,
We have you to deal with.
and we can't afford you.
So, how do we solve the problem
like Dave Brown? You tell me.
I was under attack.
I went after the suspect.
End of story.
A tape doesn't show everything,
they never do.
I had to neutralize him.
- The tape showed you...
brutally beating a man,
almost to dead.
I think, on his part
it was an assault with a deadly weapon.
- You think, he drove
into you on purpose?
It was an assault
with a deadly weapon.
Okay, I got out of the car-
- It was an accident.
I intended to help the gentleman.
He opened the door into me
and he started running.
A lot of cops would've shot him
and got a medal.
I took it easy on him
and now I'm here before you.
- I don't think, what we saw
was taking it easy on any one.
Correct me,
if I am wrong, Cal.
But nine out of ten cops..
would've shot him, right there.
- Do you admit that
you over reacted?
You seem to have
everything under control here.
And uh, I do appreciate
the opportunity...
Just remember,
which side you are on.
You are wearing a court room suit
and you have litigator eyes.
You here for me?
- Nope.
Dave.
- Linda.
Gordy!
Isn't that game on?
- I can't find the clicker.
Tell me you are not a lawyer?
- Okay, I'm not a lawyer.
Are you selling something...Art?
Insurance..Pharmaceuticals?
- How about real estate?
Great.
- That's good.
- Yeah! I'm in from Phoenix..
My 87 years old hausband and..
he's taking six hour nap.
I'm taking a five hour walk...
How's that work for you?
- Oh, perfect.
I'm looking to refinance.
That's good.
Gordy?
Anyway,
thank you for talking to me.
Yeah, well...
I figure,
I'll be safe. Everybody's..
watching your every move.
- Now they're watching you.
Maybe, I like being watched.
- I am watching you.
You're the most beautiful woman
I've ever seen.
In this bar.
What're you doing?
- I gotta go.
Sneaking out of me?
You don't have to go.
- I gotta go.
Come here,
give me that purse.
- I gotta go.
You don't have to go anywhere.
No, you don't.
Okay,
I gotta go.
You have to stay.
You're too famous for me,
all of a sudden?
It's all..
deliberate provocation!
They predicted your response..
and you fell for it!
- Who are they?
They?
They don't like you.
- Why me?
B'cos they don't like you.
Look, what do I know?
Maybe, it's a coincidence...
the camera was there.
- Look? If this is the...
gang faux..
I don't mind.
generic..
criminal scum..
Bogus-lawsuits settlement scum,
Press Scum?
I can deal with scum.
But, this is Rampart..LAPD..
some fucking girly politician,
setting me up, as a shit magnet.
To take the heat off..the fucking scandal.
I gotta go deep into this.
Look kid..
What can I do?
I am just,
'a law abiding retiree',
enjoying his golden years.
- Fuck you!
with the Micky Cohen routine, old man.
You got your fingers in more
department..
twat than,
any active cop i know.
Now,
Milk your contacts.
I got cash left,
from the Harris job.
Thanks, for that.
By the way.
You could, just stop.
Beating people up.
This isn't your father's
LAPD, you know.
I know...
It's more fun than
a barrel of monkies.
It is a barrel of monkies!
I'll get through it.
I always do.
You know, when you
first came into the department?
It wasn't certain whether or not,
you're the dumbest rookie ever..
Or the most bull-headed?
I'm still debating it.
- That's what my old man said about you.
'The most bull-headed man'
He's ever made.
I should've filed murder one on you,
for that Date Rape, shooting!
- I would've booked him on..
elevent counts, of rape...
sodomy one...
penetration of with a four...
- Gentlemen..can we talk about
the present circumstances..
and not go back
to the ancient past?
I'd say, your punishment..
breached legal status..
as well as as moral code.
- 'The law must  acknowledge
and occationally accomodate the..
extraordinary vacisitudes of Justice.'
Judge D.T Eagleton, 1946.
I don't know that quote.
How could you..
You went to County State.
- Gentlemen...
- Well, at least..
I passed the bar.
Knock it off!
- Barely..I'm told.
Hence, politics.
Should I break out
the millk and cookies here?
Can we actually talk about...
the possibility of you
holding a press conference together,
Addressing what's happened with
Mr.Parmaly..
Issuign an apology...
and moving on?
It would help
if I've done something wrong.
- Oh, you've done nothing wrong?
Someone, planted
a camera in my way.
Maybe, it's you.
Maybe, it's someone smart...
Definitely, smarter than me.
Because, I don't stop...
to see, if there's a photographer
nearby..while I do the people's dirty work.
- So, you can't...
see yourself taking any responsibility,
that moves us beyond this?
- No. Because the only thing..
that's wrong here. Is that,
a camera caught him
doing police work.
Is this a fucking joke to you?
You think, its funny?
- What is funny and peculiar to me,
is how this office spends, all it's time..
going after decent cops.
Did you do it?
- Do what?
Without admitting, guilt or complicity.
Did you actually,
killed that rapist?
- Alleged rapist?
Did you do it?
- I don't live in the past.
Is that a 'Yes'?
Let me re-phrase..
If you were to have done it.
Could you tell me why?
- So, women would love me.
I don't think,
the could be the reason.
It's too lame.
- I'm curious,
Why you're so curious.
Let's talk about it this weekend,
give me a call.
Brown..I have your number.
- I bet, you do.
What did you do to the captain?
What?
Come on, let's get
back to homework, honey.
Anything you wanna say to me?
What?
As in, why am i
still collecting paycheck?
Shaundel skipped town.
His nerves are shot.
That civil lawsuit is still going forward.
Someone upstairs,
is pulling strings for you.
Close the door.
Brown: I'm LAPD,
and I wanna stay LAPD.
That's the most important
thing for me.
- Why?
Why, what?
I'm just asking.
Why's staying a Cop,
the most important thing?
Becuase, I am a Hard-charging dutyful,
motherfucker..and I want to
explicate the LAPD
somewhat..hyperbolized, misdeed -
with true 'panache'
regarless of my alleged transgressions.
Capisce ?
In other words,
I have nowhere else to go.
So, If i get canned by the department,
I swear to God...
I'll study for the bar, this time.
And work as your Token passes.
- Well..
We'll need a retainer,
That's standard.
Have you seen my pick?
No.
Are you still mad at me?
Yeah.
Why? What did I do?
Whatever.
You didn't even finished it.
I just quit.
Right.
Hey!
You remember, when we used
to make up songs together?
You know,
like that one...
I want you.
And, You want me...
We..
We're always meant to be.
You are me..
and I am you,
And we're meant to see it through.
- Nooo.
- You have to remember that!
I have no idea,
What you are talking about.
- Let's take a walk!
Come on.
- No, I'm busy.
How long have you been standing there?
You are me.
I am you...
Get out.
Get out, Dave.
Yeah?
Hah!
Hey!
Back in town?
Yeah, it was fun.
What do you mean,
the truth?
Dave: So, you were lying
about everything?
Dave, we were playing
with each other.
Come on!
I liked the way you moved. Okay?
That was it.
Like a John Wayne thing.
Or something...
I don't know.
And I like to suck cock.
So, sue me.
Seemed like a fine idea,
at the time. Didn't it?
And you were asking for it. Dave..
You were asking for it,
'Tell me, you're not a lawyer.'
I did.
There's something you're
not telling me.
What? That I hate the scum,
that i represent?
Okay, I told you.
And, when I was at the D.A's office?
At least, I got
to see this guys go down.
That's not it.
Dave?
I helped, Criminals go free!
With County's cash
in their fucking pockets.
B'cos, LAPD fucks up!
And, eight times out of ten.
They are right back,
at Rampart again.
- You're giving me a closing statement.
You came looking for me.
No, I didn't!
- What is it that you're not telling me?
You are either lying to me
or you're withholding.
This is what I do.
The guy that you killed.
The guy...
the date rape guy.
Look I'm the Defense Attorney, Okay?
And I'm not supposed to...
But, I respect..
What you did.
I'm sorry.
Don't proof I killed anyone.
I have daughters.
I'm sorry.
Can I sleep with you, tonight?
Yes.
Nice surprise!
Hello.
Is she any good?
She was.
I gotta talk to you.
Can it wait?
Nope.
I'm kinda busy right now.
We gotta put the houses in the market.
You gotta start thinking
about finding another place to live, okay?
No.
That's not okay.
You gotta do it,
this isn't working.
You can't do that.
Everybody living on top of each other,
like this...
You know it isn't working,
as well as I do.
We gotta...
- Don't do that.
- We gotta go our own ways!
You can't make the decisions
for us, anymore.
You'll get a lot of scope.
That's not acceptable.
I gotta keep everybody together.
- I know.
- All this is gonna blow over.
I promise you.
I know.
You've been trying to keep us
together, for a long time.
But we gotta know
it won't let.
You gotta let us go.
- Don't say that.
- You gotta let us go.
I'll never let you go.
I'm never letting you go.
They all know, someone like me
is more dangerous on the winess stand,
then on the streets.
- Right?
- The way I see it, you gave 'em only one option.
Top brass is gonna try
to bury the beating in the scandal.
And keep you as the side-show.
Keep the press guessing,
while they investigate this into oblivion.
Just, stick to the assault with
a deathly weapon routine,
and they won't touch you.
- Well, I hope you're right.
Meanwhile, I'm hemorrhaging cash.
I know that twich.
Okay.
There's gonna be
a high stakes card game.
At the Crystal Market,
tonight.
You didn't hear it from me, Buddy.
Thanks Hart.
You..you don't know...
How much this means to me.
I was gonna..
I was gonna mention it before.
But..
I wanna shape your realities.
I hate to see you bled
dry like that.
How're you doing?
Are you okay?
- I am fine.
You are hanging in there.
- Hanging in there.
- You are hanging in there.
You're keeping it in a gold one.
I'm in on this one.
Twenty on that one.
Shut the fuck up!
Don't even look up.
Look the fuck down!
Fuck!
What the..fuck!
I've got kids man...please.
Take off your mask!
Alright, alright man!
Please, don't fucking shoot me, man!
Please, don't shoot me.
- Get some money out of there.
- What'd I do it man?
Put it in your fucking pocket.
Hurry up!
God Damn It!!!
Go!
GO!
Reporter: We're right outside,
Officer's Dave Brown.
Brown's involved in a high stake
card game robbery...
That's the part that gets me
the most upset, Mom.
When you keep saying sorry.
- I know.
I'm sorry.
I am sorry!
Why do you feel bad?
You didn't do anything!
What did you do?
- That's the point.
I didn't do anything, you know?
I'm sorry about the reporters.
Do you have cancer?
Hmm?
Cos, if you don't..
I'm done!
We are done.
He fired at me, three times.
I returned fire, in self defence.
It was self-defence.
I swear to God!
You need rest.
You need to eat.
I didn't know about the card games.
I swear.
You need to set up shops,
someplace else.
Right now.
I talked to Barb.
Subtitle by D3xt3r
Big Jim?
Hookers that work the bar, weekends.
Your call or I notify
Central Night Watch or I don't.
- You can't keep doing this, Dave.
Just a scotch, a room...
and a wake-up call.
- And loose my job?
At least, you'll be on the outside.
Your Bun boy, honked a Vice Cop
with a pink pair last night.
He's got a parole hold..
So, no bail.
Lorazepam and pinot bar up
and it all goes away.
We are taking a look
at your teams report.
It's a pretty extensive package.
- Not germaine to the issue, Sir.
I'd like the event to be judged, Ad-hoc.
Empirical knowledge often distorts,
the content of the act under scrutiny, Sir.
You are not making this easy.
And you are not making friends, here.
- I have all the friends
I need, at this stage of my life, Sir.
Describe the events that led up
to your use of deathly force, Officer Brown.
You are alive..
And an individual named..
Jose Lancha Masias is dead.
How did that occur?
At approximately, 23-50 hours
I was parked in the South-East Corner
of the viewing street on Echo Park Avenue.
A man approached my patrol car
and stated that, he thought he had seen,
a suspicious man in the adjacent alley.
The alley in question was
just to the West of my location.
At this time, I observed,
an unknown suspect with a gun...
chasing another man,
who appeared to be unarmed.
I identified myself, verbally.
And began, chasing the man
with the gun.
Get off past me.
Who tipped you to the game?
- You know,
I can't give you that, Dave.
You got a tip..
I improvised.
There's a man dead.
How do you feel about that?
The streets were cleaner already.
LAPD is back in town.
And it's called, Dave Brown.
Where's your gratitude?
Glad I could help.
I need to know.
Forget it, I can't.
I don't play games..
I don't name, names!
SHhh.
Shhh, yourself!
God Damn it.
That's the way I handle it,
Do you understand?
- Yeah, that's a good motto.
What are the odds?
They go, when I go.
Same night...
To take that game down.
What're the odds?
You 'handled it' Dave.
Hooray!
- I could've got killed myself!
You didn't.
- Huhh..I don't know
how much more of this shit, I can take.
Jesus Christ!
- Where the hell were you?
I left you six messages.
I'm not your fucking girlfriend,
My battery died.
- I nearly got killed myself,
the other night.
While you were out,
looking for a bone to chew on.
Where the hell were you?
Fuck You!
You're insane, Dave.
You are insane.
- Well, guess what? Lyn,
It takes one to know one.
I want the truth.
You came after me,
that night.
Yeah, of course I fucking did.
You're the man of my dreams, right?
Who the hell are you working for?
You watch too much television.
I told you,
I am on your side!
I'm not working
for anyone or anybody!
- You're paranoid, Dave.
- You are breaking my heart, linda.
Yeah?
You broke into my fucking house!
I located your security flaw.
- Oh, fuck you!
- Your pool gate was open.
Should I leave?
- Mmmhm.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I am a mess.
Will you sleep with me?
Just tonight?
No.
You drink too much.
- Really?
You're great in the sack, Linda.
But, you're lying to be liked.
- Is that right?
That's right.
Yeah, well... guess what?
It takes one, to know one.
You are a bitch,
you know that?
- Mmmhmm.
General!
Get over here, now.
How're you doing?
I'm okay, how are you?
I'm good.
How are you?
Didn't we just go through this?
Good.
Hey?
Look at me.
Look me right in the eye.
Have you seen anything, unusual lately?
- NO.
Anything around the Chrystal Market?
No, I said no.
I didn't see shit.
Sure?
Yeah.
Are you positive?
Not a damn thing.
Thanks.
Yeah, take two.
Look, what happened to your head?
Watch that beard.
I don't wanna see you,
go up in smoke.
This dick head cops,
throw flashlights on me...
Fuck!
Don't do that!
Keeping the streets safe.
I'm not hurting anybody.
I don't sell no more,
don't smoke no more.
No big deal.
I'm nobody, nobody..Im nothing.
You got fucking niggers,
swinging golf balls up and down this streets.
They all talk,
gabby gabby, gabbygaby.
They wanna crack my head open.
Asshole, Cop.
Give me a sip.
Here.
Call this lawyer,
Sue the LAPD.
Linda.
Is she hot?
Linda Fentress?
She's blond all over.
- Fuck...yeah!
Why..your thing still working?
No.
Not really.
My stock(?)Nanny's the best pussy.
You don't have any brothers?
Huh?
You're my brother.
Keep it.
Brother.
Hey!
- Can I help you?
Let me get a...
Six shrimps.
You fucking with me?
- What?
I'm listening.
What are you..I.A?
- Man, i'm just sitting here,
trying to get my shrimp.
Is that what you're gonna say,
the next time I spot you?
- Here we go.
Here we go.
Kyle Timkins, DIA investigator.
You said both robbers escaped,
That's kinda hard to believe.
Also, there's a big gap.
Between the time..
the neighbours said they heard the shots..
and you reported the incident.
Also...
It's kinda strange..that
you'd be in that location, without your radio.
Why is the robbery unit on this?
When both robbers
did indeed escaped?
- Well, your recent misconduct..
Perceived, misconduct.
- Perceived misconduct.
Brings into question,
your mental state,
on the night of the incident.
That's why, I am here.
Oh, listen...Jack?
- No, I'm Kyle.
Listen, Jack.
You got this assignment,
because...
I am controversial and your ancestors
were restored from Africa.
You got this assignment,
to cover the department on perceived...
racial bias.
Pertaining to Shaudel J.Parmley
and other shit-faced scum.
You're mad as hell..
and you want me to know it.
While you're playing 'Gumshoe'..
bear in mind,
that i'm not a racist.
The fact is,
I hate all people.
Equally.
And if it helps...
I've slept with
some of your people.
Now, you wanna be mad at someone?
Try, J.Edgar Hoover.
He was a racist.
Or the founding fathers.
All slave owners.
Me?
I'm just doing my job.
- All that may be true.
But, we're not here talking about me.
We are here talking about you.
Okay?
Oh, Officer Hoover?
I got another question.
Why are you still
with the department?
After all this shit that's going on.
The Mayor..The D.A -
The Chief of Police...
Why do they still have you around?
It must be cos,
I'm innocent.
Nice to meet you, Kyle.
Y'all see, you know..
that I didn't wanna be no gangbanger,
walking down the street.
Pull downed by their dogs.
Hey, Boss?
Boss.
Dave?
Stayed up well late, last night?
How are you feeling?
Just waiting to piss all these protestor.
You know,
you are being watched?
What do you mean?
There he goes.
I am glad, you found me.
- It wasn't hard.
I just wanted to see for myself.
Mom said you are deeper
in this shit.
Those are my words, not hers.
People keep telling me that.
- Well, maybe..it's true then.
You took a cab, right?
Tell me, you didn't take a bus
all the way out here...
in the God damn jungle.
- It's the barrio, Dad.
It's not a fucking jungle.
- Yes, I took the bus.
- I told you a thousand times, babe...
I don't want you taking...
Don't call me Babe!
It's disgusting.
How's uh...
How is school?
- It sucks.
Full of uh..
Candy Ass, Future Fags
and Dykes like me.
Those are your word.
Not mine.
I never said that.
How's it going, at home?
What've they done to you?
She's angry.
She said, it's something everyday,
Brown daughter has to go through.
You are a dinosaur, Date Rape.
You're a Classic Racist.
A Bigot.
A Sexist.
A Womeniser,
A Chauvinist...
A Misentroph.
Homophobic, clearly or maybe,
you just don't like yourself.
How long did it take you
to rehearse that?
Well, say something.
Don't touch me. Say something.
Well, I'll drive you home.
No. I don't wanna go home.
Thriving in an open house,
I don't wanna be around those heidious people.
I wanna be at Joe's.
Joe Joseph or Joe Jones?
I'll jsut take the bus!
Helen?
I'm kidding!
Yeah?
Your phone is tapped.
Don't say a word.
Jesus, the shits
i have to take care of because of you.
You are just like your father, Dave.
You're think,
you are smarter than you are.
Every shooting
testimony contains, Inconsistencies.
Otherwise, you wouldn't have a job.
No man, whoever
shoots and kills another man,
is entirely coached in,
in the moment.
No plans survives contact,
with the enemy.
- Did you learn that,
with the first man you killed?
I learned that serving my country,
as a non electic pop up target.
In an often misunderstood crusade
for liberty and justice...
turned puppet show for politicians,
known as the Vietnam War.
Let's fast forward to the present.
Why are you looking to hang me?
Why me?
I know you're setting me up.
Blood was gutted in for me.
Answer my question,
of all the truly rotten cops out there...
Why, why are you
after the one guy who gets it?
The one cop who gets it?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Let me remind you,
that several years ago..
You killed an alledged
serial Date rapist, premeditatively?
Did you know that,
he had a wife and three small children?
She had a nervous breakdown after his death,
and ended up in an insane asylum,
where she spend nine years,
until she cut her wrist.
With a disposable razor blade.
The kids were raised, by the way..
in foster homes.
Two of them have alleged that,
they were...
sexually abused
by their foster fathers.
So, please..
don't come in here.
Whining!
Took a lot of nerve.
Up this time.
Something to make it hard!
Watch it, man.
I feel like....
Dave, what are you doing here?
Listen,
My lawyers...
are burning throuh my money and,
uh..we're gonna have to tighten our belts.
We..we're gonna have
a trial date soon. So,
What were...
What are you even doing here, Dave?
I came to talk to you about this.
You don't live here anymore. You can't just walk
in the house like, you still live here.
Oh, for God's sake.
You know what I think?
I think, you're a dirty cop
from day one.
You're a dirty cop,
with a dirty mind and you dirtied...
all of us, by default.
I think..you think,
you can just ride this out!
Thinking you can go back to
your fucking...
Tough guy..
law and order bullshit!
It's over, Dave.
It's over!
You know what happened to you?
- Just let him go.
Just let him go.
Just let him get out.
Selfish man, Dave!
- It's not worth it. Just let him go.
You're a bad hausband.
You're a bad father..
you're bad lay.
And all this...all this man,
keeping the family together, bullshit.
It only fucks the girls up, forever.
Forever.
You don't know what...
one thing about your girls...
You're a fraud.
You gotta go.
Okay.
I'm..I'm thirsty.
I bet you are.
Come on, just give me a pull.
just give me a pull.
Get your fucking hand,
out of the car.
Come on, you're by bro...
Come on.
Just a sip.
a sip...
Give me a smoke.
I want a cigerette.
Give me a cigerette.
No.
- Yeah, C'mon..give me a drink.
Sober up.
Linda is a good woman,
she's taking really good care of me.
I'm gonna take all your
asshole friends, Down!
Can you spot me a fiver?
I don't feel so hot.
Sell your wheelchair.
Fuck you, White skin.
I got robbed.
I need a blanket.
Five bucks, please.
Do I look like,
Santa Claus to you?
No, you don't look like Santa Claus,
You're my brother...
Us, guys stick together.
Don't leave a man behind.
- I'm not your brother, okay?
- Yes, you are.
I'll pay you back.
When, Linda and I make a killing.
Stop saying her name!
- Linda.
You stop saying her name, okay?
Say her name one more time..
- You don't get it.
- I will, hurt you.
- You don't fucking get it.
We're gonna be rich as shit.
I'm gonna go around the world.
Round the world...round the world.
I'm gonna tell my story.
And they're gonna fucking pay me.
I'm gonna be on talk shows,
I'm gonna have a suit.
What did you tell her?
I told her everything.
Tell me, exactly..
what you've told her.
I told her my plan,
about...
We're gonna get a big house, together.
Somewhere, in Northern California.
On a lot of property...
Where anybody can come.
Who needs a place, Has a place.
Where you can shower..
Where you can hang out.
Or where you can just get your head right.
All my friends are gonna be there...
So, you should definitely come.
And Linda would make us eggs.
What about the Crystal Market?
Yeah.
I told her everything.
Everything?
Everything.
Come on, give me a drink.
Get the fuck out of here!
What the hell are you doing?
Why? You afraid of something?
Come inside, Dave.
C'mon, it's raining.
Yeah, I can see that.
I'm already in,
what does it matter?
What are you doing?
General, told you.
Who?
He saw me shoot that man,
in Crystal Market.
And dropped a piece on him.
Baby, I don't wanna hear this.
Come on, it's raining. Come inside.
He got rough up by the LAPD.
That's all.
You're gonna believe him,
over me?
Get in,
get in the pool.
I'm not getting in the fucking pool.
No..no.
If you're on my side,
get in the fucking pool.
No, you've gone crazy.
I'm going in.
Get in the fucking pool.
You make the next move.
Don't fucking touch me.
- Get off.
- If you're on my side, get in the pool.
Come in.
You think,
you can take me down?
I don't need you.
I don't need anyone!
I'm just a fucking cop.
I'm a fucking soldier.
I'm dispensible.
There're lot of other
cocks to suck.
You are heartless, Linda.
You played me.
I hate you!
I fucking hate you!
Are you even listening, you bitch?
Get in the fucking pool!
Kyle: Discrepencies...and inconsistencies.
- Jesus.
Dave, I got six card players.
All of them claiming...
that it was a 'no weapons' game.
Four of them heard the shots.
All of them claimed,
it was two sets of three pops.
All at the same clip.
Which indicates...
You fired your weapon, first.
Right?
Now, i traced the gun...
Right back to this station.
Right here.
Ballistic, showed that
the gun was involved...
in another,
officer shooting.
Alright?
So, I'm sweating
...? to gun..
Cos not only can I prove...
that his shooting was dirty...
I can prove..
that your shooting was dirty.
Just like i can prove...
YOU dirty!
I got two eye witnesses.
That saw your ass,
outside of that crystal market.
Right before, you jump off.
So, go home and pack a bag.
Make sure there's a wet suit in there.
Cos, I'm sending your ass
up the river.
Oh, come on baby.
I've been up the river, motherfucker.
When you were still
sucking on your mother's tits.
My mother died,
when i was born.
You racist, son of a bitch!
You save that grand wizard shit,
for the jury.
I need you to help me
put a leash on Kyle Timkins.
Help you?
That's all I do is help.
I'm not the help.
Crystal Market.
Again, with the market.
No. Still... with the market.
You're covering for someone,
who's trying to bury me.
Now..
I'm not sure I understand
the rules, okay?
The rules...change.
The Laws change..the peoples change.
They're accomodate,
they adapt.
But, not you?
Why is that?
Explain to me, exactly...
what happened at the Chrystal Market?
I gotta get away from you.
I got a business to protect,
contacts...
I don't know you.
I don't know...
Put that away.
- Why me, Harv?
Why me?
Stop whining.
Why you?
Why me?
Why anybody!
You set me up!
You...set yourself up, Dave.
Give me the gun.
Call an ambulance.
Hey!
Come in.
What was that noise?
- It's uh..the lock.
Come on.
Come in.
Get out of the hallway.
Please.
Come on.
Hey..
What a surprise.
Do you wanna give it to him?
I thought you wanted to?
No.
These are for you.
Thank you.
How are you?
Good.
Yeah?
So, tell me...uhh..
What you've been upto?
Nothing, we just came
by to drop off those clothes.
You found me!
How did you do that?
There's a caller I.D.
What?
Caller ID??
You called the house, from here.
That's...
that's good police work.
Yeah, it was really hard.
So?
Here you are.
Come on in.
Don't be afraid.
You wanna sit?
No.
Can I get you a soda?
No. I'm good.
Yeah?
You don't want anything?
Noo..I'm good.
You look beautiful.
Both of you.
Your face looks red.
Too much sun.
It means, he's been drinking.
Haven't you?
What?
You've been drinking.
Uh, just a..
yeah, little bit.
Okay...wow.
Do you want to go.
Yeah.
Let's go.
We're gonna go.
Okay, you wanna then,
talk a little bit?
No. It's fine.
Hey?
I know why you came.
It's to drop off your clothes.
- Come on.
- You wanna know, if it's true.
Every bad thing,
you've heard about me.
You want me to give you,
some kind of way out, so it doesn't...
hurt so much?
There's no way out.
Every single thing,
you've heard and more...
It's all true.
It can never...
change.
But...uhhh
I want you to know.
I never, I never...
Hurt any good people.
What about us?
No. That..that's...
that's not what i mean, Helen.
I don't understand,
what did you mean.
Have I hurt you?
I didn't mean to.
We gotta go okay?
Hey, come on.
Hey, come here.
Hey.
What're you doing?
I love you, monkey.
You know that, right?
I'm gonna get you a soda, okay?
No..I ...
Will you come back?
Monkey. Come back
to the room...huh?
This is Officer David D.Brown,
of the Los Angeles Police Department.
This statement is made
of my own free will.
During my twenty four year,
police career...I employed..
brutal and coersive methods, at whim.
and...
created racial anymous...
With reckless disregard,
for the law that I was sworn..
to uphold as a police officer.
On April, 15th..1987
I murdered a business client of mine.
Carl Joseph Heunick.
As rationalised the act,
as a morally sound, expression of street justice.
Against the man,
who i knew to be a serial date rapist.
I was legally sane
at the time i commited the act.
Over the years,
I've killed many men.
Bad guys,
all of them.
And if there are one or two exceptions..
I can only assume,
they ended on the wrong end of my gun,
To satisfy some..karmic breach.
This statement is proferred lucidly,
i'm not in the state of duress.
Okay.
I'll give you this tape,
if you cut me a deal.
- I don't want your tape.
What?
- That's not the confession i want.
Is that the fucking Crystal Market case?
You're a fucking idiot!
- Next time i see you?
I'm putting cuffs on you.
Are you out of your mind?
Timkins?
Take what you got.
Which is a good case.
- It's the wrong confession!
Take the fucking tape.
You fucking idiot.
Take this fucking tape!
You're a fucking idiot, Timkins!
Fucking idiot!
Really?
Where are you going?
What?
Subtitle by D3xt3r
www.addic7ed.com