(KIDS LAUGHING)
(CHATTING)
- (GIRL SCREAMING)
- Where's Emma? Emma?!
Emma! Emma!
Emma, where are you, honey? Emma?
Emma?
- Oh God. Oh my God.
- (CRYING)
Are you okay? Oh God.
Okay. Okay.
Oh, thank God.
EMMA: I saw a scary man.
- (BIRD CAWING)
- (CARS HONKING)
Neither fate nor society put
Francis Mulligan in the house
of Gloria Mitchell
on the night of the 15th.
Neither fate nor society
told him to tie her up,
shove a gun in her face
and steal her belongings.
That was his choice.
The defense would have you
walk in his client's shoes.
Well, I have.
I'm from Riverdale.
It's a craphole.
(CHUCKLES)
Nobody's saying it's not, but...
that's where I'm from.
It's not who I am.
He is not the victim here.
So if you are gonna put
yourself in anyone's shoes...
put yourself...
in Gloria Mitchell's.
Thank you.
JUDGE: The jury will now adjourn
to deliberate a verdict.
(POUNDS)
Nice close.
Straight to your top five.
- You like that?
- Yeah, I did.
"Not who I am." That was very cute.
- I gotta go.
- Mitch, the jury only just left.
Guilty, five years,
parole after two.
- How do you know that?
- One, the judge is soft
on the educationally-challenged
and nobody got shot.
And two?
I don't lose.
Well, that part's true.
- That's why I hate you.
- See you tonight.
(GARAGE DOOR SQUEAKING)
- (GROANS)
- Look up. Look up.
- (PHONE CAMERA CLICKING)
- Please. (CHUCKLES)
- One more.
- No. Absolutely not.
- Look at those tiny little hands.
- I know.
(BABY FUSSES)
- (GROANS)
- I can't believe her. Looks so perfect.
She's so peaceful.
Thank you.
We're lucky.
I'm sorry I have to go
to this work thing tonight.
I wish I could stay here with you.
(TRAIN RATTLING)
(MUFFLED MUSIC PLAYING)
- MAN: Help me.
- MAN #2: Careful, it's slippery.
MAN: Guys. Tomorrow, thank you.
- (SIGHS)
- MAN: Good night, boys.
(MITCH COUGHING)
I fucking hate Tequila!
MAN: Everybody hates Tequila.
That's the idea.
Well, I...
I didn't know what to get
- the man who has everything, so...
- (MAN LAUGHS)
He's got a career,
a beautiful little baby...
- Oh, my little baby.
- ...a sexy wife.
- Careful.
- And then it hits me...
I'm gonna get the man
a Tequila hangover.
So, Mitch, tomorrow morning, you are
gonna wake up complete, my friend.
That's right.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- I helped.
Complete.
You okay getting home?
Yeah. Gonna get a...
- gonna get a cab.
- All right.
- (CELLPHONE RINGS)
- Oh.
- Hello?
- WOMAN'S VOICE: This is a collect call
from an inmate
at Concord penitentiary.
- To accept this call, press 1.
- (GROANS)
- MAN #2: Everything okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Ugh. See you tomorrow.
Listen, when you throw up
in the middle of the night,
- aim away from your baby.
- Yeah, I will.
- Aim away from the baby.
- MITCH: Away from the baby.
MITCH: I promise.
MAN #2:
Don't puke on your child, Mitch.
- I won't puke on my child.
- MAN: Until tomorrow.
MITCH: Tomorrow.
MAN: Don't be late!
(LINE RINGS)
MAN: Inner-City taxi.
- Hey!
- (KEYS JINGLE)
- (ALARM CHIRPS, HONKS)
- Inner-City taxi. Hello?
Can I help you guys?
What the fuck?
Oh, fuck it.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(MAN SPEAKING ON RADIO)
(SIREN BLARES)
(SIREN BLARING)
(MOUTHING)
(SIREN FADES)
- (THUDS)
- Fuck.
Fuck.
What the fuck?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh no.
Oh fuck. Oh fuck.
(GAGS)
Oh, I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Oh fuck. I'm so sorry.
- Oh shit.
- (MUTTERS)
Hey, I'll get an ambulance.
Oh fuck.
(GRUNTS)
Take this.
- (GROANING)
- It's okay. I'm gonna get help.
I'm gonna get an ambulance,
all right? Hold in there.
(METAL CLICKS)
(MOANING)
Okay. Okay.
Hey. Two minutes. I promise.
- Don't leave me.
- Just gonna call an ambulance.
I'll be back in two minutes.
(GRUNTS, PANTING)
(CLICKS)
WOMAN:
911, what's your emergency?
I need an ambulance.
A guy's been hit by a car.
- What's the location, sir?
- Uh, Keeler.
- Keeler and 26th.
- What's your name, sir?
Please just hurry.
Hurry, he's hurt real bad.
- Sir.
- (CLATTERS)
- (GROANS)
- The ambulance is coming.
- Don't leave me.
- I have to go. I can't stay.
I can't stay. You'll be fine.
I promise. I promise. I'm sorry.
- Please. No.
- I have to go.
- Please.
- Please. Please.
Fuck. Fuck.
An ambulance is coming, okay?
- (TRAIN CLATTERING)
- Okay?
(TIRES SCREECH)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLICKS, SQUEAKING)
- (GEAR SHIFT CLICKS)
- (ENGINE STOPS)
(GARAGE DOOR CLOSING)
(SHOWER RUNNING)
(SIGHS)
(SIGHING)
Don't leave me, please.
- There's daddy. Hey, lover.
- Hey.
What on earth are you doing up?
- I didn't sleep great.
- Hangover?
- (CHUCKLES) Yeah.
- (BABY FUSSING)
How are you?
Well, apparently they wake up every
two hours and they demand food.
- Who knew?
- Can I help?
Yes, you could fix the garage doors.
They're driving me crazy.
Just gonna grab some diapers.
WOMAN ON TV: ...blamed a ride
home when she got into...
MAN: ...in the third period,
they mounted...
MAN #2: ...remind everybody
that no matter what the weather,
the winter festival is happening...
WOMAN: just be careful out there, folks.
The weather is...
- WIFE: Mitch.
- Uh-huh.
WIFE: Something you wanna tell me?
What?
About last night?
(TV CLICKS OFF)
- What?
- And the car?
Rach...
uh...
And why it's parked in the garage?
Did you drive home?
Yeah.
- You promised to take a cab.
- I know.
No, I mean... What, are you crazy?
'Cause if you get a D.U.I.,
then you can kiss
the D.A.'s office goodbye.
I know. I know, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have.
I won't do it again.
Mitch, I am serious.
You're a father now, okay?
You can't afford to take chances.
I know. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
See?
Look, even Ella agrees.
Ella?
Are you sure?
Mm-hmm. Don't change the topic.
I don't know what I'd do
if I lost you guys.
Mmm. Here, let me take her.
You go to bed.
(SIGHS)
Go get some rest.
- There you go. Thanks.
- (TRUCK APPROACHES)
Just an hour.
(ELLA AND MITCH SIGH)
- (BRAKES SQUEAK)
- Shh shh shh.
(WHIRRING)
(TRASH CAN THUMPS)
(KEYS JINGLING)
(GARAGE DOOR RATTLING, SQUEAKING OPEN)
(CAR ALARM CHIRPS)
- (CLEARS THROAT) Hey.
- You okay?
Yeah.
Could you call around
the local hospitals and clinics?
I'm trying to track down
a young man who was involved
in a hit-and-run accident
last night around midnight.
- What case is it connected to?
- Just let me know what you find.
(PLASTIC CUP RUSTLES)
(GROANS)
(RADIO CHATTER)
- MAN: Yeah.
- WOMAN: Over there.
MAN: Thanks.
- Morning, officers.
- Good morning.
- Good. This way.
- Thanks.
REPORTER: I'm down here in front
of the police department
with the story of the tragic
death of this local young man.
What started out as a routine
traffic stop last night
has turned into a gruesome
murder investigation
when police officers
stopped this van
parked behind me
in the police impound
for nothing more than
a burnt-out taillight.
When they saw blood dripping
from the rear door,
they demanded
the driver open the van
and it was then they discovered
the body of Cecil Ackerman,
a 24-year-old parolee
from Naperville.
Please don't.
The driver claims he found Ackerman
dying in the road
from an apparent hit-and-run
and was merely trying
to get him to the hospital.
This is Jeff Franklin,
reporting live from the scene.
Hey, counselor.
- (BUZZES)
- Thanks.
(CHATTERING)
WOMAN: Yeah?
- Detective Kanon?
- Yeah.
How many "T"s in "committed"?
- Two.
- Fucking paperwork.
(SIGHS)
You got here fast.
Yeah.
You said you were interested
in the Ackerman murder?
- Yes, I am.
- (PAPER RUSTLES)
D.A. assigned just you?
Well, it's just
a provisional inquiry.
Walk with me.
Suspect's name is Clinton Davis.
55; Car mechanic;
couple of assault charges,
nothing he did time for;
no relatives;
Wife and daughter were murdered
in a home invasion
a few years back.
Priest was in here already,
saying what a good guy he is,
how he'd never hurt a fly,
- et cetera.
- They said on the news
that he found Cecil
Ackerman in the road.
Yeah, we've been there.
No broken car parts,
no blood that we could see.
Yeah, but the snow
thawed overnight, so...
we've got Ackerman's blood and
hair all over Davis's clothes.
We've got the bloody tools and the
plastic sheets in the back of his van.
We've got enough to charge him.
You guys need to decide
if it's enough to convict.
- He looks terrified.
- He should be.
He's staring down 20 to life
for this one alone.
This one?
I ran some keywords
through the database.
It flagged a string
of unsolved homicides.
You think this guy's
a serial killer?
You don't even know
that he killed this guy.
Tell your boss we'll send him
everything we got.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
- (KNOCKS)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Mitch.
- I have a request, sir.
Thanks. Hey.
Mitch Brockden, D.A.'s office.
My associate Stuart Wilson.
Terry Roberts, public
defender's office.
There you go.
Mr. Davis, we're going
to ask you a few questions
about the night of the 4th.
If you can answer
as accurately as possible...
You're gonna be my prosecutor?
Uh, if this goes to trial,
then yes, I am.
I didn't do anything. I'm innocent.
Then you've got nothing
to worry about.
Okay, Mr. Davis,
let's start with you
telling us where you were
earlier that evening.
Left work, went to group,
went for a drive.
Group?
Yeah, I help out at
some support groups.
- And the drive?
- Just something I do.
It's not against the law, right?
I mean, don't you ever go out
and drive around at night?
Due respect, I think
that's beside the point.
I don't like to spend
too much time at home.
It brings back memories...
My wife and child.
Uh, yes.
I heard what happened
to your family.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Emanuel fryer.
Gunned down the next night
attacking someone else's family.
MAN:
What do we know about the victim?
STUART: Cecil Ackerman...
registered sex offender;
two counts of child sex
abuse; Did two years inside;
was only out
on parole three months.
So a real loss to society.
So far there's no connection
between him and Davis.
- What about the murder weapon?
- Weapons.
The coroner couldn't be exact,
but he suggested these
wounds could be consistent
with the type of tools
and machine parts
found in the back of Davis's van.
- Could be?
- Well, they also found
significant amounts of oil
and grit in the wounds,
which corroborates Davis's
hit-and-run story.
True, but the Vic's
D.N.A. And blood were
all over Davis's clothes,
inside his van.
Which could've got there when he
lifted Ackerman into his van.
Yeah, or when he murdered him.
Davis has two counts
- of aggravated assault.
- At a time when his family
had just been murdered
in a home invasion.
He hasn't had so much
as a parking ticket since.
What's bothering you, Mitch?
I don't see motive.
- (KNOCKS)
- (DOOR OPENS)
Just got this audio file.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Here's the transcript.
It was a 911 call.
Somebody called in an accident
20 minutes
before Davis was picked up.
By the time the ambulance
arrived at the location,
there was no one there.
MAN: Okay, thank you.
Is there any way
we can find the caller?
- No, he used a payphone.
- How do you know that?
If he used his cell, it would
have his name, phone records.
MAN: Okay, 911 call's
potentially damaging,
but it's not conclusive.
And if we can't find the caller,
defense probably can't either.
Could be anyone in Chicago.
Mitch, where were you that evening?
(LAUGHS)
- No, Mitch couldn't
string a sentence together
- that night, right, Mitch?
- (CHUCKLES)
- Yeah, thanks, Stu.
- If it was a hit-and-run,
all it takes is
for the guy who hit him
to come forward and confess,
and we're dead in the water.
STUART: What's the likelihood
of anybody doing that, huh?
Bottom line: Do we have
enough for a conviction?
Davis was found with a
dead man in his van.
We have a ton of physical evidence.
No alibi, a documented
history of violence
and his public defender's
still in diapers.
Mitch will eat him for breakfast.
Charge him, murder one.
MITCH:
You examined the body, doctor.
In your professional... opinion,
what was the cause of death?
Blunt force trauma to the skull.
And what caused that trauma?
The back of the skull
was badly crushed,
so it's hard to narrow
it down to any one item,
but some of the marks
seemed consistent
with a hammer found
in the suspect's van.
And the interior was covered
in grease and motor oil,
so any type of violent
struggle in that environment
could've also caused those wounds
and left that trace evidence.
You said, "seemed consistent."
That's correct.
Your report talks of abrasions
and impact wounds with grease
and motor oil in them.
Now the defense I'm sure
is gonna argue that...
those wounds indicate
that a car ran over Cecil Ackerman
as per the defendant's testimony
and that the rest is just...
a misinterpretation
of the evidence.
No more questions, your honor.
OPERATOR: 911, what's your emergency?
(MITCH PANTING)
I need an ambulance.
- A guy's been hit by a car.
- What's the location, sir?
Uh, Keeler. Keeler and 26th.
OPERATOR: What's your name, sir?
MITCH: Please just hurry.
- Hurry, he's hurt real bad.
- OPERATOR: Sir.
It's your witness, Mr. Brockden.
Doctor, the jury will be unfamiliar
with your field of expertise,
so I'll ask
quite a simple question.
Just how accurate
is forensic linguistics?
- Extremely.
- But it's not perfect?
Perfection doesn't happen
in science.
Okay. On a sliding scale
of one to 10 then...
you may want to object, counselor.
The witness's field
is not on trial here.
I'll withdraw
the question, your honor.
You stated earlier that you believe
the caller to be genuine?
By this I assume you mean
he was reporting a real accident.
Correct.
And you can tell this just by...
hearing his voice?
It's more complicated
than that, but yes.
What else can you tell
us about the caller?
Hard to be certain
from the quality of the tape.
Sounded like a white male...
possibly in his 30s...
from the South of Chicago,
but he's tried hard
to soften the accent,
not unlike yourself, counselor.
Now you're from where, Riverdale?
When you say it's hard
to tell for certain...
that the tape is unclear,
that it seems to be
a white male...
WOMAN: The underlying ethnicity
is hard to fully hide
from trained ears.
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
- Yes, it's a good recording.
- Uh-huh.
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
- Okay, thank you.
- Thank you too.
- Hey.
- Staff meeting starts in five.
Someone named Jimmy called,
wouldn't leave a last name.
Said to tell you he's out
and wants to see you.
Left a contact number. Do you want
me to get him on the phone for you?
No no no, thank you.
(INHALES)
Smell that?
That's the smell of freedom.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, so I called
your house the other day,
you know, looking for ya.
Your wife...
she doesn't know
who I am, does she?
You've been gone a
long time, Jimmy.
How do you not tell her about
your own fucking brother?
Step-brother.
And let's face it,
legally not even that.
- You wanna play like that.
- Don't be fucking cute with me, Jimmy.
I was working at that warehouse
to pay my way through law
school when you fucking hit it!
I could've been done as
a fucking accessory. Huh?
- Bye-bye, career.
- Yeah, I know. I was fucking stupid.
(CHUCKLES)
Fuck, Mitch.
I mean, Jesus, I was doing
a lot of drugs back then.
I was selfish.
I've had a lot of fucking time
to think about my life,
think about who I was.
Okay?
Now I let you down.
But I will not let you down again.
Look...
I met Rachel when I was graduating.
She processed my application
to the D.A.'s office.
Seeing as my ma never
officially married your dad...
yeah, you figured
why mention us, right?
Jimmy, it was best
for me not to have ties
- to a criminal past, you know?
- (SNORTS)
Once I'd lied on the forms,
- I couldn't tell...
- Yeah, I get it.
I understand.
- God.
- I'm not that kid anymore.
Riverdale, it's...
It was another life.
Well, lucky you.
I only got the one.
Hey.
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
- (BEEPS)
- Hello?
Hey, Mr. Brockden. It's Kanon.
Detective Kanon.
What can I do for you?
Just checking in.
We lost a point or two
on that forensic linguist.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know. It's, umm...
it's almost impossible to make
Davis the caller, so...
Right.
It's kinda late, detective.
Is there something you need?
No, just wanted to know
that you're ready for tomorrow.
(LINE CLICKS)
- What was that?
- What?
You're recording this?
Why would I be recording this?
(CHUCKLES) They say
that cops are paranoid.
See you in court.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
She's asleep. Hey.
Hey.
(FRIDGE OPENS)
- You smell like milk.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Ella was sick on me, again.
- (FRIDGE CLOSES)
- (GLASS CLATTERS)
- Nice.
Mitch. Hey.
Look at me.
Mitch.
What is it?
Is there something
you're not telling me?
Yes.
What?
Can't you just...
Tell me?
I love you.
(CHUCKLES)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
I love you too.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
BAILIFF: All rise.
Be seated.
Before session begins, your honor,
I would like to approach the bench.
I will not tolerate
tardiness, Mr. Roberts.
I'm sorry, your honor,
but there has been
an important development.
Defense would like to
call a new witness.
Objection, your honor.
The prosecution wasn't informed of this.
TERRY: Defense was unaware of their
identity until late last night.
What is the relevance
of this witness, Mr. Roberts?
He's the man who made the 911 call.
- PEOPLE: What? What?
- Order!
- (GAVEL BANGS)
- JUDGE: Order.
- Your honor...
- I'm inclined to allow it, Mr. Brockden.
Yes, I understand that,
but if you could just...
- Mr. Brockden!
- TERRY: Dr. Brown's lab
ran a voice analysis overnight
and we got a viable match.
How soon can defense
present this witness?
Right away, your honor.
He's been in the courtroom
- this entire trial.
- MITCH: Your honor, please!
- Can I just please say some...
- (GAVEL BANGS)
Enough!
Call your witness.
The defense calls...
- Jimmy Logan to the stand.
- MAN: What?
(MURMURING)
REPORTER:
In a surprise twist of events,
a witness came forward today
and ended the prosecution's case
against Clinton Davis.
The witness saw the victim,
Cecil Ackerman,
mowed down by a hit-and-run driver
in a red S.U.V.
And left on the road to die.
He then called 911.
(REPORTERS CHATTER)
TERRY: It seems that Clinton Davis
was not the only
good samaritan in this trial.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Mr. Davis?
I just wanted
to wish you all the best.
Yeah, it's like you said...
if I was innocent,
everything would work out.
Yes, I did.
So what happens now?
- You go back to your life.
- No no no,
I mean with
the hit-and-run driver,
the one the witness saw.
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
Maybe he'll turn himself in.
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
- (HUMPHS)
Would you?
(DISTANT SIREN)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MAN: I fucking love you,
you fucking bitch!
- Whore!
- Stop it!
- I'll fucking kill you!
- WOMAN: No! Leave me alone!
- Don't do this to me, you fucking bitch!
I fucking love you!
- GUARD: Hey!
- Fucking let me go!
I fucking love you!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(TRAFFIC SOUNDS)
(CHATTERING)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
REPORTER: The mutilated body
of Pedro Gonzales
was found early this morning on
the bank of the Chicago river.
According to a source
at the coroner's office,
the back of his skull
was badly crushed,
possibly by a hammer.
His family says the last time
anybody saw him alive
was at the north mall on Saturday.
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
KANON'S VOICE: I ran some keywords
through the database.
It flagged a string
of unsolved homicides.
(ENGINE STOPS)
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
(RATTLES)
(SNIFFS)
(CLICKS)
(PANICKED BREATHING)
(SIREN APPROACHING)
(THUDS)
(CLICKS)
I can't stay here. Shit!
(TIRES SCREECH)
Oh fuck. No. No.
MITCH:
I looked at the autopsy results.
The wounds on Ackerman were similar
to those found on Gonzales.
Ackerman was
a hit-and-run, remember?
The wounds were inconclusive.
You yourself pointed
that out at the trial.
Inconclusive, exactly.
What if it was both?
What if Ackerman ran
into the path of a car
because he was trying
to get away from Davis
who was in the process
of torturing him?
It explains why the
forensics was so confusing.
Anything else?
Thanks for coming by.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(TRAFFIC SOUNDS)
(VAN STARTS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE STOPS)
(CHATTERING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FAINT CHATTERING)
Hey.
Oh fuck.
(MUTTERS)
Shit. Fuck.
(CLICKS, SQUEAKING)
(ELLA CRYING)
- (GASPS)
- (CRYING STOPS)
(ELLA FUSSING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(CAR ALARM BEEPS)
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Yes sir...
Oh shit.
(DRAWER OPENS, CLOSES)
(COMPUTER RATTLES)
(KEYBOARD CLICKING)
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
(PRINTER WHIRRING)
(BEEPING)
- (KEYBOARD CLICKING)
- (KEYS JINGLING)
(BEEPS)
(BEEPS, WHIRRS)
(PHONE RINGING)
- Yeah, hello.
- CLINTON: You get my photograph?
- What do you want?
- Stop following me.
I know what you did.
And yet the cops
haven't come a'calling.
- (TOOL WHIRRING)
- Why you think that is, Mitch?
If you knew I was the driver,
why didn't you
just turn me in, huh?
I didn't want to play my ace
in the police station.
I needed to go to court.
I had to get a jury of my peers
to see your card, find me innocent.
You wanted double jeopardy.
Bingo. A free pass.
- But you didn't expose me.
- There was no need.
I could see you were having
a crisis of conscience.
- Is this a fucking game to you?
- Far from it.
I won't let you get away with this.
Yeah, you will,
or I will ruin you.
Besides, who's gonna
protect Rachel and Ella
when you get locked up
for hit-and-run, hmm?
What did you say?
Family is
a precious thing, Mitch.
It's our job as men
to protect 'em.
- Davis.
- (CLICKS)
(TRAFFIC SOUNDS)
(KNOCKS)
Hey. Shut the door.
Is that Ackerman?
And the guy from the news.
Have to work out
what links all these men.
How he's picking
his victims and why.
How who's picking them?
Clinton Davis.
What?
These are the unsolved homicides
that Kanon thinks
match Davis's M.O.
Davis's M.O.?
(CHUCKLES)
Dav... Davis was innocent.
Hit-and-run, Mitch.
911 caller proved it.
Yeah, I wish it were that simple.
(SCOFFS)
What the hell is going on?
What the hell
is going on, Mitch?
First you blow the Davis case,
almost get yourself disbarred
and now what?
You're trying to prove
that this guy is the
goddamn Boston strangler?
Stu, if I could
explain this, I would.
With what pathologists
think were tools.
The first took place eight months
after Davis's family was
tortured with similar tools.
You see, I think he picked 'em.
I think he picked all of them,
but what the fuck
do they all have in common?
Well, Ackerman was
a child molester.
None of the others were.
Well, they do all have
criminal records.
So you think this behavior started
- with the death of his family, right?
- Yes, I do.
So remind me...
what happened there?
A man broke into their home
and systematically tortured
and butchered
his wife and child...
using similar tools to the
ones that killed these guys.
The guy made Davis watch
the whole goddamn thing.
Then he slit his throat
and left him for dead.
It was a miracle he survived.
(KEYBOARD CLICKS)
The guy's name was Emanuel Fryer...
career criminal;
gunned down the following night
during another home invasion;
recently paroled; Blah blah blah.
- Broken home...
- Oh shit.
What?
Gonzales, recently paroled.
Fryer, recently paroled.
Ackerman was recently...
all these men are
recently fucking paroled.
Stu, you are a goddamn genius!
Shit. I love you. I love you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Okay, so you're saying
that the only reason
Ackerman was in the street
was because Davis was chasing him.
- Uh-huh.
- And then after you left,
- Davis finished the job?
- (WHISPERING) Exactly.
If I could just
get proof, you know?
Davis can't be retried
for Ackerman,
but if I can
get evidence that he...
he killed those other guys,
I can cut us both a deal.
What you said under oath,
what I did...
WOMAN: You all right there?
...What I did, it just goes away.
Mitch, I'm on parole.
I get busted breaking
into some guy's fucking house...
come on, I don't want you breaking in.
I'll break in.
I just need for you to tail him,
let me know when he's coming back.
Ah, it's just a little
aiding and abetting then.
Eh.
Forget it, Mitch.
Let it go. I'm done.
- (BELL JINGLES)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
That fucker really break
into your house?
Yes.
While we were sleeping.
(TAPS FINGERS)
All right,
he's gonna know your ride.
Can you rent me
a clean set of wheels?
Of course.
Thanks, Jimmy.
You know what? I mean that.
I may be an asshole,
but I'm still your brother.
(CHUCKLES)
(ENGINE STOPS)
MAN: See you later, Davis.
All right, guys. See you later.
Have a good evening.
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
(DOG BARKING)
(TOOL CLANGS)
- (ENGINE STARTS)
- (VAN DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(VAN ENGINE STARTS)
(GEAR SHIFT CLICKS)
(KEYS JINGLE)
(CELLPHONE BUZZING)
- (BEEPS)
- Yo, Jimmy.
Got anything
tying him to the victims?
No. Not yet.
Looks like he eats and sleeps
here, but that's about it.
The rest of the time
he spends in self-help groups.
You know, sometimes he
goes to two a night.
Oh fuck.
That's it.
That's how he picks his victims.
The guy that killed
his family was a parolee.
They're all parolee meetings.
Nobody notices
the guy making coffee.
He just hangs around
like a fly on the wall,
listening for the guy who feels
worried about re-offending.
Yeah, I've been to those meetings.
- The room's full of guys like that.
- Exactly.
(FLOORBOARD THUDS, CREAKS)
Fuck me.
He kept their parolee cards.
- (HORN BLASTS)
- Jimmy, what's that?
Uh, we're near the cement works.
Must be coffee break or something.
You know, that's pretty close.
Is he coming back?
I don't know. He went
into some old warehouse
and came out carrying something.
I lost him.
- Looked like some old tools or something.
- Get the fuck outta there.
Jimmy? Jimmy!
Jimmy, can you hear me?
Jimmy? Jimmy, are you there?
I'm coming, Jimmy.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Jimmy!
(JIMMY SCREAMS)
- Jimmy!
- Aah! Fuck! (GRUNTS)
(YELLS, GRUNTING)
- (JIMMY YELLS)
- Jimmy!
- JIMMY: Mitch!
JIMMY: Help me!
- (MITCH PANTING)
- You gotta help me, Mitch!
- Help... Mitch.
- (RUNNING FOOTSTEPS)
MITCH: Yo, Jimmy!
JIMMY: Oh, please help me!
- Jimmy!
- Mitch!
(GASPS) Mitch!
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- (GASPING BREATHS)
Oh Jimmy.
OPERATOR:
911, what is your emergency?
(WEAKLY) Help me.
Help me, please.
He's trying to kill me.
- (PANTS) Hurry.
- OPERATOR: Sir?
Sir, who is trying to kill you?
Sir? Sir, are you there?
Sir?
Hello? Yeah, I need an ambulance.
(COUGHS WEAKLY)
Can you hear... can you hear me?
- Hello?
- (COUGHS, GROANS)
Yeah, I need an ambulance.
- (BEEPS)
- Fuck! Fuck!
(SIRENS BLARING)
- Stay with me. I'm gonna move you, okay?
- (GRUNTS)
- Okay?
- Okay.
Okay okay, come on.
(GRUNTING)
- (SCREAMS)
- Come on, stay with me!
- Come on!
- (GRUNTS)
Let's go, men.
Hey!
- Hey, he needs an ambulance.
- COP: Set him down now!
- Oh fuck.
- COP #2: Put him down!
- Do it!
- Put him down now!
- Now! Down! Down!
- Fuck.
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
Oh fuck.
COP #3: Go!
- He needs an ambulance!
- COP: Cool it!
Jimmy. Oh God,
get him a fucking ambulance!
(COUGHING)
Jimmy, hang in there.
Hang in there, brother.
- Hang in there, brother.
- ...can and will be used against you...
- COP: Calm down.
- Hang in there.
You have the right to an attorney.
We've got an injured white male.
(GATE BUZZES, CLANGS)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (FOOTSTEPS)
- How's Jimmy?
- KANON: He's in a coma...
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- ...but the doctors are hopeful.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
So you wanna tell me what
your relationship is to him?
Yeah, we're, um...
(CLEARS THROAT)
step-brothers.
Our parents just never married.
That's why he'd lie
for you in court.
Exactly.
So why turn on him now?
What?
Was he blackmailing you?
What are you talking about?
I didn't do this.
Clinton Davis did this.
- KANON: Using your hammer?
- Yes.
He broke into my house,
he stole my tools.
Did you report that?
- No.
It's only your prints
on the hammer.
Jesus Christ.
I made the 911 call,
for Christ's sakes.
Why would I do that
if I was guilty?
I really don't know, Mitch.
But you did it before.
OPERATOR:
911, what's your emergency?
MITCH: I need an ambulance.
A guy's been hit by a car.
OPERATOR: What's the location, sir?
MITCH: Uh, Keeler.
- That's you, right?
- Yes yes yes, it's me.
I hit Ackerman with
my car and I left.
It was wrong.
I know that, but I was scared.
I'd been drinking.
It was an accident.
We found this...
in the bottom of your toolbox.
It has Ackerman's
blood all over it.
Well, Davis must've put it there.
I dropped my cards when
I was helping Ackerman.
- I must've missed one.
- All of this...
- leads directly to you.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
All right, listen, okay?
If I killed Ackerman,
why didn't I crucify Davis in
court when I had the chance, hmm?
He was the perfect scapegoat.
(SIGHS)
Okay, there's a bag.
- There's a bag?
- Yes.
Davis kept the I.D.S
of all his victims.
He's targeting violent parolees
that he thinks will re-offend,
like the man that
killed his family.
- Where's this bag?
- In his house.
How do you know this?
- I broke in.
- You broke in?
(CHUCKLES)
You broke into his fucking house?
Seriously, Mitch...
How do I know
you didn't put it there?
You know, I don't think I should
answer any more questions
till I have a lawyer present.
You know, I think
that's a really good idea.
- (KNOCKS)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (GATE BUZZES, CLANGS)
(DISTANT SIREN)
You've got a call...
Stuart Wilson from the D.A.'s office.
(CLICKS)
Stu, where the fuck have you been?
CLINTON: I'm sorry, Mitch.
This is the only way
they'd let me talk to you.
Now you listen to me,
you fucking son of a bitch.
I will find you, I will come for
you and I will take your life.
- You hear me, Davis?
- Oh, listen to you.
Where was all that backbone
when you hit Ackerman, huh?
If you'd showed it then,
you would've waited for the
ambulance and he'd be alive.
Course, he'd still be free
- to go around hurting small children...
- (KIDS LAUGHING)
- (THUDS)
- ...which he was about
to do when I took him.
You do know that, right?
If you'd let well enough alone,
we never would've come
to this place, Mitch.
What do you want?
You could've ruined my life
or ruined yours,
but yet you found a third option.
One that helped us both.
There is no fucking
third option here.
Yeah, there is.
What if another murder happened
with the same M.O.
While they have you
in custody, hmm?
Go a long way towards
shedding light on your innocence
or even throw a reasonable
doubt on your guilt.
MITCH: What are you...
what are you talking about,
- another murder?
- The problem is
you don't know my pain
or my emptiness.
But now you're going
to know what it is to be me.
(GARAGE DOOR SQUEAKING)
Davis?
Davis, what...?
Where are you, Davis? Huh?
I have to go now, Mitch.
- Davis!
- (CLICKS RAPIDLY)
Hey! Is the line cut? Hey!
I need a line.
I need an outside line.
- Davis is going to kill my wife!
- Stop!
- Hey!
- He's gonna kill my fucking wife.
(YELLS)
(HONKS)
(CAR APPROACHES)
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
- Mrs. Brockden?
- Yes.
I'm Detective Kanon.
I hate to bother you
at this ungodly hour,
but I'd like to ask you
- some questions about your husband...
- (ELLA CRYING)
...if it's all right with you.
No, not at all. Of co... I'm...
just one minute.
MAN ON RADIO:
Suspect is approximately 5'5"...
(VOICE DISTORTS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
You know, I've been
calling all day and I...
I hope you don't mind.
Hey, officer.
Just finished up with a client.
Can you tell me what
you've arrested my husband for?
- Murder.
- What?!
That... I mean,
that's insane. Mitch...
I know.
I know it... it's crazy.
And I personally don't
believe he's guilty at all,
but I just need to ask you
some questions to clear...
(COUGHS) Could you get me
a glass of water, please?
Um, yeah, sure.
Good night, counselor.
Drive safe.
- (CAR HONKS)
- (TIRES SCREECH)
- There you go. (SIGHS)
- (ELLA CRYING)
Look, I just don't understand.
If you know that he didn't do it,
then why are you still holding him?
Some of the other detectives are
having a problem with his story.
But like I said,
once we have our conversation,
I'm sure we can clear that all up.
(ENGINE REVS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- He got a phone call and he went crazy.
- Who called?
Wilson or something
from the D.A.'s office.
He was ranting about
making another call,
said someone was gonna
kill his wife. Davis.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(FAUCET RUNNING)
(CAR ALARM CHIRPS)
What the hell's going on in here?
- Did you just call Mitch?
- No.
Get a unit over to
Brockden's house now.
(SCREAMS)
(WHIMPERING)
(YELPS)
Rachel! Rach!
Oh, somebody! Somebody help me!
(GRUNTS)
- Get up.
- No! Why are you doing this?
- No!
Please, don't kill me.
- No.
- Don't hurt her!
Mitch. Mitch.
- (GULPS LOUDLY)
- Toss the gun over here.
Do it.
Now, Rachel,
I want you to bend down
take that gun by the barrel
and pass it to me.
Whatever you're thinking of
doing, Clinton, don't do it.
Well, it looks like
you just fucked up
our reasonable doubt here, Mitch.
What happened to your
family was terrible.
Doing this, it's...
it's not gonna change that.
I was protecting other
people's families.
Who's gonna protect
yours now, Mitch?
You?
(DISTANT SIREN)
You understand now? Do you get it?
Yeah, I get it.
I get that you watched
your wife and child
tortured to death
and you did nothing.
I get that you're a fucking coward.
You froze.
You cared more about saving yourself
than your own flesh and blood.
- RACHEL: Mitch, please don't.
- You think if you take out
- as many parolees as possible...
- RACHEL: Shut up.
...you'll make what happened
to your family go away.
- Please.
- You know, if you were a man...
a real man,
you would've died first.
I thought I was dead.
I was hog-tied with my throat cut,
but I wasn't so lucky.
I had to watch my loved ones die.
You're not tied up though, Mitch.
So what are you gonna do, huh?
Are you willing to die first?
Yes.
Yes, I am.
We'll see about that.
- (GRUNTS)
- Oh! Mitch! No!
You need to understand,
to see someone you love
bleed to death
in front of your eyes.
(CRYING)
Please. Please don't.
- Please don't.
- Begging won't help, Rachel.
My wife begged.
It's a waste of time.
- Now...
- No! No!
Now you're gonna see
what it's like to be me.
RACHEL: Please!
To feel my emptiness,
my pain.
I'm gonna give you something
I never had, Mitch.
(GROANING)
Prove you can do better than I did.
- Please.
- Go ahead.
(GRUNTS)
- Save... your family.
- (CRYING)
Mitch, no!
- (GUNSHOT)
- (RACHEL YELPS)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Mitch!
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
Can I help you with anything?
Oh, you're hysterical.
Rach!
Rach, he's here.
Give me Ella,
then you can say hello.
- Yeah, I got her.
- RACHEL: I know.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
- This is my wife Rachel.
- JIMMY: Hey.
- (CLEARS THROAT)
- This is my brother Jimmy.
- Hello, Jimmy.
- Wow, hi.
- How are you?
- Better than I look.
- (ALL LAUGH)
- And this...
- Oh Jesus.
- This is your niece...
Ella.
Oh my God. Hi, Ella.
Ella, that's your Uncle Jimmy.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, Ella.
Oh my God.
Oh, Mitch.
You named her after your ma.
Wow.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Well, I don't know about you guys,
- but I am freezing.
- MITCH: Yeah.
- Jimmy, wanna come in?
- Yeah, all right. Definitely.
- You okay with her?
- This is terrifying.
How do you do this?
(CHATTERING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)