So he wants to cut it off, just like that?
- He doesn't think you can handle it.
- The arrangements have been concluded.
I gave them my word
because he gave me his word.
- So you tell me why.
- Hey, you know why.
You're not strong any more.
You lost control.
Now, you tell him this:
nothing has changed.
We've had a few setbacks.
That's to be expected in any business.
But I am still in charge,
and I am still strong.
Make no mistake.
You tell him he had better keep his word.
Tell him the 25th, as agreed.
I’ll send him a sign, a little demonstration,
to prove that I’m still strong.
- Good afternoon, Mr Douvier.
- Good afternoon, Simone.
- Any calls?
- On your desk.
- What's this ''Dr Herb called''?
- Your yearly checkup. Tuesday at 4.30.
- Is New York gonna call back?
- Mm-hm. Between five and six.
- Everybody else here?
- Yes, in the boardroom.
Well, l don't think
we should keep them waiting any longer.
- Will l see you tonight?
- Of course, Miss Legree.
Gentlemen, we have a problem.
The Gannet transaction is in jeopardy
because New York feels l no longer
have the power to control the situation.
So l have sent word
that l will give them
a demonstration, a sign,
to show that l am still in control.
That France is still a viable territory.
What I want from you are suggestions.
- I have an idea.
- All right.
Would you ask your secretary
to bring in the morning paper?
- Bring in the morning paper, please.
- Right away, sir.
Who's the most important man in France?
Present company excluded, of course.
Thank you, Miss Legree.
The president, I suppose.
No, for our purpose. A man New York
knows better than the president of France.
A man with which our entire
world organisation is familiar,
and would like nothing better
than to see him out of the way.
Who?
Who has given us nothing but trouble
for the past ten years?
Who has survived
16 assassination attempts,
including two by his own boss?
Clouseau.
You want to impress New York?
Eliminate Clouseau.
We'll have every cop in France
down on our necks.
Not if we do it smart.
There is a rumour
that he is really a complete imbecile.
- I’ve heard that.
- Yet he continues to survive.
I have it on good authority
that he is anything but an imbecile.
That he only plays the fool.
In any case, it is too dangerous.
Can you do it smart?
Yes.
Then do it.
( tenor sings on scratchy record)
Balls?
Inspector Clouseau!
My dear Chief Inspector Clouseau!
How we have missed you!
Your disguise is ready for the final fitting.
I think you'll be very pleased.
Cunny! Quick, quick!
Inspector Clouseau is here!
- You have some very interesting noses...
- l will model them for you!
Get on with it, get on with it!
l will bring you one right away.
There were some on the left there.
Ah, the final fitting.
I call this one ''Wino and Roses''.
Magnificent.
Even though l say so myself,
this is no small feat.
Now you can work the Left Bank
and Montmartre with anonymity.
Yes, the old anonymity ploy.
That's it! That's it!
You can do it, Inspector!
- Chief Inspector.
- You can walk, Chief Inspector!
You can walk!
Yes! Yes!
You are a genius, Balls!
l can! l can walk!
Thank heavens
For little girls
They keep on getting smaller every day
Thank heavens
For little girls
They grow down in a most pecu...
Yes?
A special delivery.
Thank you.
I’m sorry, I’m a little short.
Forget it.
(car engine starts)
(car speeds off)
Special delivery. A beum.
Were you expecting one?
A beum?!
Aaaaagh!
(phone)
Yes?
What?!
- Right.
- What's the matter?
The bomb destroyed half the block,
and Clouseau survived.
I am certain, sir,
that the beum was intended for me.
- Beum?
- What?
- You said ''beum''.
- Yes, yes.
Fortunately Professor Balls took refuge
behind a shipment of inflatable goitres
which cushioned the explosion.
- Inflatable goitres?
- Yes. His Valentine's Day collection.
(coughs)
- It's amazing that you survived.
- Yes, sir.
I must apprehend this mad beumer
before he does any more of the damage.
- Or she.
- Or she?
A man dressed as a woman.
Four armed robberies in three weeks.
Two victims were assaulted,
and grappled with the robber.
Both victims said the robber
was much too strong to be a woman.
Three years ago, we sent to prison
a man named Claude Russo.
Russo committed robberies
disguised as a woman.
Well, sir, l must be off
to apprehend this... this mad beumer now.
Remember, it just could be Russo.
Yes. It just could be Russo, yes.
- Yes, l just said that.
- Yes, I know that. Yes, sir.
Well, sir, until we meet again,
and the case is solved.
Au revoir, Hercule.
Fire!
(alarm bell)
You may not have seen these gentlemen
before, but they have worked for you.
And needless to say,
they are specialists, the best in France.
And you expect them
to take care of Clouseau?
Oh, no. They've been contracted
to eliminate Mr Chong.
Who the hell is Mr Chong?
Mr Chong?
Mr Chong was recommended
by Hong Kong.
Gentlemen, fulfil your contract.
(click)
(sneezes)
Why don't you get out of those wet
clothes? You could catch pneumonia.
Yes, I know that.
I will do as soon as I get home,
provided that idiot Cato
does not attack me first.
- Why don't you just tell him not to?
- Believe me, it's not that easy.
l have given him instructions to attack me
wherever and whenever possible,
and it has now become a matter of pride
with him to try to outsmart me.
l guarantee that at this very minute,
his fiendish little yellow brain
is plotting some new ambush.
(sneezes)
- Gesundheit.
- Yes, I know that, I know that.
Cato?
Cato?!
(plays discordant notes)
Pay attention!
This is your employer speaking!
I am cancelling
the attack orders for tonight!
You understand?
I know that I told you to show no mercy,
and to attack, and to pay
no attention to what I say!
But tonight...
(karate yell)
But tonight,
I am ordering you to pay attention!
You will not attack, Cato!
(blows bugle)
Shut up that row!
I am trying to save my life, madam!
Obviously the little yellow swine
is not paying attention.
(feeble karate yell)
Aaagh-ha!
(sawing)
(imitates sawing)
It’s a very substantial building.
We're doing a great deal to it.
I’m sure you'll find it
very peaceful, and quite delightful.
(Cato yells)
A-ha! Ha-ha!
(cone)
Swine!
Chief Inspector Clouseau's residence.
- (Douvier) Clouseau?
- One moment, please.
For you.
(woman shrieks)
What on earth is going on?
Excuse me, madame and messieurs.
- I beg your pardon. I am so sorry.
- It’s still for you, Inspector.
Chief Inspector.
Pardon me, I am needed on the telephone.
Hello? This is Chief Inspector Clouseau
speaking on the phone.
Now listen to me carefully, Clouseau.
lf you wanna catch the French
Connection meet me tonight at 11 o'clock,
in the Bois de Boulogne,
near the Grande Cascade.
- And come alone.
- (click)
That's so obvious.
He's bound to think it's a trap.
Yes, or it's so obvious that
he's bound to think it can't be a trap.
It’s so obvious, it's bound to be a trap.
That is why you will never be
a great detective, Cato.
It’s so obvious,
it could not possibly be a trap.
Now, Cato, warm up the Silver Hornet.
Cato, l very much suspect that
the Hornet is overdue for a service.
So if you don't mind,
I’ll use your car tonight.
(sounds horn)
He's driving a white Peugeot.
Licence number is...
By any chance,
are you going to Fontainebleau?
- Well, l...
- Wonderful!
How lucky can a girl get?
You're an absolute darling.
- It’s green.
- It is?
The traffic light.
Oh!
Generally speaking, it's dangerous for a
beautiful girl like you to hitchhike at night.
That's because, generally speaking,
beautiful girls like me don't carry guns.
Yes, yes.
Are you saying that you carry a gun?
Mm-hm. I’ve got it in here somewhere.
It’s not very big.
- Watch it. It might go off.
- Only if you don't do exactly what I say.
Listen, Miss, uh...
- Russo.
- Russo?
(male voice) But you can call me Claude.
- ''Claude''?
- Pull off the road.
The old ''pull off the road'' ploy, eh?
Yes. Then we will see how you do with
the old ''take off all your clothes'' ploy.
lf you don't want to freeze to death,
you'd better put on the dress.
- Never!
- Suit yourself.
But the dress is an original Dior,
and you've got sensational legs.
(blows kiss)
(whistles)
(phone)
(man) Merde!
Yes?
Oh... Good. Thank you.
- Why don't you take it off the hook?
- Won't be necessary, my dear.
The great Inspector Clouseau
will not be bothering us any more.
Hello, boys!
Oh! Am I glad to see you!
And we are certainly glad to see you.
Hey, hey, hey!
Wait a moment! Wait a moment!
I am Chief Inspector Clouseau
of the Sûreté!
- And I am Officer Bardot.
- ''Bardot''?
But you can call me Brigitte.
Brigitte! You are making
an understandable mistake.
Don't let my legs fool you.
I’m really a man.
(solemn drum roll)
(man) The palace flag
is lowered to half-mast.
The president has declared
a day of national mourning.
Only a few hours ago, the great detective
stood in this very courtyard,
and was decorated by the president
for outstanding service to his country.
According to the coroner's report,
Chief Inspector Clouseau
was probably dead
before his car hit the telephone pole
and burst into flames.
The president called me
at six o'clock this morning.
A dozen countries have offered
the services of their finest detectives,
but the president made it painfully clear
that this must be solved
by Frenchmen, and quickly.
- Or we can all hand in our resignations.
- l spoke with Dr Laprone at the hospital.
He assures me
that Dreyfus is completely cured.
It’s amazing.
I’ve seen some lunatics in my time, but
they were all pikers compared to Dreyfus.
- He was like a wild animal!
- Didn't he actually bite you?
Oh, yes. On the leg.
l had to take rabies shots, just in case.
The doctor swears
his recovery is complete.
He said that in the last 12 hours,
Dreyfus has literally become a new man.
Thank God for that, because we need him.
lf anyone knows about Clouseau
and who might have murdered him,
that man is former
Chief Inspector Charles Dreyfus.
Isn't it fantastic, Doctor?
Reinstated at my former rank,
with no loss of pay or social benefits.
Yes. It could actually be called
a psychic rebirth.
I’m in your debt.
l shall be eternally grateful.
l only helped. l led the way.
But in the final analysis,
it was your victory, Charles.
Our victory, Paul. (laughs)
But only at the expense of another.
Huh? Oh, Clouseau, you mean.
It could be said that he died
so that you might live.
- l wish l could feel sorry.
- You feel no guilt?
None.
To be honest,
when l first heard he was dead,
there were a few moments
when l was actually convinced
l was in a state of grace. (laughs)
- Is that wrong?
- It isn't a matter of right or wrong.
Look, l hated him.
He literally drove me
out of my mind, as you know.
Isn’t it natural that
l should feel happiness, even joy,
at the thought of him being dead,
out of the way, and gone for ever?
Natural, yes. But there is a danger
that such feelings might promote guilt.
Clouseau would come back
and haunt you.
- I have no guilt.
- Not now.
Not ever. Clouseau is gone,
and I am free, for ever.
- Now, have a cigar.
- Thank you, Charles.
I’ve made the arrangements
for your release.
The Sûreté is sending a car
for you to be picked up at 5.30.
Remember,
you're on probation for 12 months.
lf you have any problems,
call on me immediately.
Thank you, Paul.
Officer, you are making
a most serious mistake.
Release me immediately,
or l will personally see to it
you are transferred to Martinique,
and spend the rest of your career
writing traffic citations
and checking parking meters.
The man who was killed in that car,
my car - uh, Cato's car - was not me.
He was wearing my clothes.
These are his clothes.
I am Chief Inspector Jacques Clouseau.
Miss or Mrs?
You fool! The president himself,
when he decorated me, said:
''Clouseau, you are a man of courage.''
He called me
the greatest detective in all of France!
You charlatan! Impostor!
All right. Calm down, Mr Poirot.
- Poirot?
- Yes!
Yes, but you can call me Hercule.
And l am the greatest detective
in all of France,
the greatest in all the world.
(blows raspberry)
That man is obviously crazy.
Uh-uh. We do not use
that word round here.
Oh? What do you
normally use round here?
- Now, now.
- He is very ''now, now'', l can tell you that.
Court order.
l shall need your signature
on the transfer document.
90 days' comprehensive - thank you -
psychiatric examination.
Hey!
Peekaboo?
Your car's at the entrance, Inspector.
Goodbye, Chief Inspector Dreyfus.
- Good evening, Chief Inspector Dreyfus.
- (gruffly) Good evening, François.
It’s good to have you back on the job,
Chief Inspector.
Is it true that you will take charge
of the Clouseau investigation?
- Yes, yes.
- You must feel torn.
On the one hand, it is your duty to send
the guilty parties to the guillotine.
On the other hand... (laughs)
I am sure you'd rather
congratulate them, eh?
Can you imagine?
A state funeral for that idiot?
The president. Dignitaries from
all over the world will be coming.
Why, there's a rumour
the Pope might even show up.
The Peup?
- ''Peup''?
- What?
You said ''Peup''.
- Do you have a cold?
- Oh, yes. Yes, I have.
I have the cold in the chest, you know.
You sound terrible.
Do you want me to send you a doctor?
No, no. It’s much better than it sounds.
Anyway, I want to go directly
to the Clouseau apartments
to commence the search for the clues.
Yes, sir.
- Is this the Clouseau residence?
- Yes.
This is also the residence
of the Clouseau manservant, Cato Fong?
Yes.
Then be so good as to tell him that l wish
to have speaks with him, would you?
And who should l say
''wish to have speaks'' with Mr Fong?
Tell him it is an old friend.
Mr Fong has many old friends.
Listen, you.
Tell him it is Chief Inspector... Clouseau.
Why didn't you say so in the first place?
Please come in.
Good evening.
- And congratulations.
- What?
You are our first Caucasian,
and that entitles you
to a 10º/% discount until midnight.
- Who are you?
- Mrs Wu. But you can call me Madam.
(doorbell)
- Yes?
- Inspector Clouseau.
Oh! Please come in.
- Madam.
- Welcome.
- Good evening.
- Please, make yourself at home.
That man just called himself
Inspector Clouseau.
It was Mr Fong's idea, but personally,
I think we should have a better password.
Password?!
Madam, l demand to know
exactly what is going on in here.
Well, just about anything
your little heart desires.
But first, why don't you relax?
Give Benson your hat and your coat,
have a drink, get to know the girls.
And then, when you are up to it,
you can choose from a wide variety
of exciting little diversions.
But I see that
you already have a preference.
Allow me to introduce
Tanya, the Lotus Eater.
What else does she do?
l warn you, Tanya the Easter Lotus,
I am opposed to the women's libs.
Man is the master,
and women's place is in the home.
- (whip swishes)
- Ooh! Ow!
And another round-eye bites the dust.
- (whip)
- Aagh! Aaaow!
Cato!
Aaagh! Ooh!
Take your hands off me, you oriental fool!
You are under arrest!
- Anything you say will be taken down...
- Arrest?!
You have the right to remain silent,
but let me tell you this:
I am not your ordinary,
run-of-the-mill transvestite.
- Say no more!
- What was that talk about arresting us?
- He was just kidding, weren't you, boss?
- Boss?
l used to work for him.
He used to be a cop.
- A cop?!
- Tell them you were kidding, boss.
Yes, he is right.
l was just kidding.
Cross my heart and...
hope to meet you again sometime.
And you, Madam.
And you, too. You two
should be ashamed of yourselves.
And you! I want to talk to you, Cato!
- Here. Come in here. Listen now.
- Please, boss!
l thought you were dead!
So, as a tribute to my memory, you
open up this... Chinese nooky factory!
l had to do something to keep busy.
Besides, a first-rate joint like this
can make as much as
three, four hundred thousand a year!
- Is that net?
- No, gross.
But even so, a smart operator
can clear a coupla hundred grand,
and that ain't exactly chicken feed.
No.
No, and ten years on Devil's Island
ain't exactly the chicken's feed either,
my greedy little yellow pimp.
Ow!
I’ll have to close up anyway,
now that you're alive.
Yes. Yes, normally that is
precisely what you would have to do.
But these are not normal times, Cato.
- Someone has just tried to kill me.
- That's normal.
Ah, but this time
that someone thinks he has succeeded.
Except for you and me,
the whole world believes that I am dead.
And in this case, death has its advantages.
No one will know it is me
as I glide... (coughs)
through the underworld like a shadow.
- Good evening, Commissioner.
- Charles! (laughs)
I, uh...
Thank you.
I’m sorry to be late, but as you must have
heard, a lunatic was hiding in my closet.
Yes. Russo.
Russo?
Russo...
- Ah!
- You remember?
Why wouldn't I?
It was only three years ago.
Of course. Claude Russo.
Alias Claudine Russo.
Armed robbery, dressed as a woman.
But he got five years.
He was released on parole
three months ago.
So it could have been Russo.
He's clever.
- Clever enough to fool François?
- Huh!
l like François, but fooling him
no longer constitutes an act of more
than average cleverness, shall we say?
l always thought
he was rather a good policeman.
When he was my assistant, he was a very
good policeman, with a bright future.
- But then he was assigned to Clouseau.
- Oh, now, now, Charles.
- All that's in the past.
- Yes, of course.
Tomorrow morning,
when they plant him six feet deep
and shovel in the dirt... (laughs)
l shall be truly free.
And unless he's figured out
a way to come back from the dead,
nothing anyone does or says about him
will ever make any difference again.
- Shall we do some work?
- That reminds me.
- What is it?
- The chief wants you to give the eulogy.
- The what?
- The tribute.
- Me?!
- You knew him intimately.
l hated him intimately.
But you're the expert who's
going to track down his murderers.
I’m the expert who
would love to kiss his murderers!
The PR people loved the angle.
It’s sacrilege! l won't do it.
Politics.
No. I’m a good Catholic.
- So's the chief's wife.
- I don't care.
What's she got to do with it?
She wrote the speech.
Ladies and gentlemen,
honoured guests,
dear friends. (clears throat)
We are gathered here to say... goodbye
to a, uh...
a great man.
(stifles laugh)
(coughs)
Not only was he a model police officer,
a brilliant detective,
admired and respected
by his fellow officers,
and all those
who were fortunate enough...
enough...
enough to know him.
He was, above all else,
a modest man.
His kind will not pass this way again,
and our loss is surely...
heaven's gain.
Present arms!
Fire!
- Get rid of that woman.
- We'll talk about it later.
I want your answer now,
or I sue for divorce.
- I’m warning you, Therese.
- What will you do? Have me killed?
(priest prays in Latin)
Gentlemen... you will be relieved to know
that our friend in New York was very
impressed by our little demonstration.
It was a good idea, Guy.
- The Gannet transaction is on again.
- The same delivery date?
- Unless there's something l don't know.
- l spoke to Hong Kong.
- They say the Gannet's right on schedule.
- Good.
That means this time next week we can
declare ourselves a very healthy dividend,
letting our international colleagues know
the French Connection's back in business.
I’ll be at the farm, and I do not want to be
contacted except in extreme emergency.
Meeting adjourned.
Guy?
- Stick around, will you? l might need you.
- Right.
Miss Legree, would you
come in here for a moment, please?
Well, now, what's wrong with you?
- We have to stop seeing each other.
- Your wife?
- Mm-hm.
- That witch. OK, how long this time?
- I’m afraid this time permanently.
- Permanently?
- Permanently? Permanently?!
- She gave me an ultimatum.
- You're saying you have no choice?
- I haven't.
- You have too. Get rid of her!
- My own wife?
- Get rid of her! Why can't you?
- She's got enough evidence to ruin me.
If anything happens to her, her attorney
will give it to the authorities!
- Then get rid of the authorities!
- Who do you think I am?
- Get rid of her attorney!
- Get rid of her attorney?!
- I couldn't afford the scandal.
- Scandal? I’ll show you scandal.
It’s not that I love her. You know I don't.
I just need her respectability.
- Permanently?
- Yes.
You mean six years together,
just washed up, just over with?
- I’m afraid so. I’m sorry.
- That's just wonderful.
And you obviously
can't go on being my secretary.
I have deposited a substantial amount
of money in your bank account...
I don't want your money!
I don't know what I want.
But I’ll think of something!
(muttering)
- Leaving early, Miss Legree?
- Later than you think, Mr Algo.
Something you want me to do?
Not unless she decides to be indiscreet.
If you have to, just be sure
you make it look like an accident.
(Clouseau) Ahoy! Lower the kipper!
Hello there in the fog!
Don't worry.
It’s only an old salty Swedish sea dog
out there from the salty seas, you know.
- (dog barks)
- Pumping the air in the parrot in.
Naughty bird afraid of the fog.
Swine leg!
Hello, Inspector.
Chief Inspector.
I’m working under the covers.
No one must suspect a thing.
(speaks mock Swedish)
What do you have of special interest
to my secret investigations?
There's something big
going down at Le Club Foot.
Le Club Foot? Remarkable.
Keep your...
(mutters in mock Swedish)
Keep your eyes and ears peeled
and keep in constant contact.
I am extremely grateful
for this excellent piece of information.
Thar she blows!
Once again, l thank you
for this most useful tip,
and if there is anything
I can ever do to repay you...
Now that you mention it, Chief Inspector...
Oh...
You mean the line in the hand?
All the dark strangers coming.
(mock Swedish)
Sixteen chests on the dead man's rum
Yo ho ho and a bottle of the chest
Drink to the devils
and down with the rums
Aaargh!
(splash)
Gimme some more.
Yeah, gimme some more.
All right!
Whoo! Come on!
Yeah! It’s started!
Move 'em out
If you mess around with women, boy,
you'll wanna fix the trimmin'
Move 'em out
Better listen to me, cousin...
She's coming in now.
Move 'em out
Move 'em out, move 'em out
- Whoo! Bonsoir, Vic.
- How you doin', Simone?
Mr Toledo, Mr Vancouver.
- Vic, you can show us to my usual table.
- How about something nearer the floor?
No, thank you. I want my usual table.
- Is something wrong?
- It is Mr Douvier's table, ain't it, love?
No, love, but if you're worried about Mr
Douvier, why don't you give him a call?
- l wouldn't want you to get in trouble.
- He ain't my boss.
Then why do you pay him
all that money every month?
- That ain't cool, baby.
- You ain't seen nothin' yet. Come on.
Listen to me, cousin,
I’ve got stories by the dozen
Move 'em out
Move 'em out, move 'em out
- Where are we going?
- We don't want to be obvious.
We'll make our entrance through the back
way in disguise, as l told you, you fool.
(rings bell)
- (clattering)
- (cat yowls)
( funk)
Get up here. Get up here!
- It’s a bakery.
- I know that. I know that.
Come on.
At least you're not yellow any more.
This time I’m going to
stand on your shoulders.
What good would that do?
Because I’m taller than you are, you fool.
- Oh, yeah.
- Make a cradle.
Get rid of that.
I can't reach it.
You'll have to find something to stand on.
Argh! Aaargh!
Whoo!
Yes!
All right! Let me see ya, baby! Come on!
Do it, baby!
(shrieks)
Wait! Let me go!
- (Cato) Can you reach it?
- Yes.
Merde!
- Hey! Are you OK?
- No!
You know something? You're terrific.
You're terrific! You saved my life!
Come on with me now.
I wanna save your life.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Oh, God.
Come on, before the killers see us.
- What killers?
- I’ll tell you at my apartment.
- What apartment?
- My apartment.
Oh! My God!
Mine too.
I’m soaked to the skin.
Yes. Yes, l have received
considerable soak also.
You'd better get out of those wet clothes
before you catch pneumonia.
What shall l do with my coat?
I don't want to spoil your...
Just put it down anywhere.
Put it on the floor. That's fine.
Help yourself. I’m gonna change.
I’ll bring you a robe.
I’m gonna put on some music.
- You know, it's strange.
- What?
I say it's strange.
Yes, I know. And l said ''What?''
- Oh, you mean ''What is strange?''
- Yes.
Yes, yes.
It’s strange that l have
never yet set foot in this building,
but I have the distinct impression
that I have been here before.
Déjà vu. I have it all the time.
- Oh. The old déjà vu. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- You OK?
- Yes.
Ah! That feels good.
That won't do you much good
if you don't take your pants off.
- What?
- You gotta take your pants off.
Look at me. Look, I’m shaking like a leaf.
I can't stop shaking. I don't know...
Oh, I know what it is.
I’m just not used to being killed.
That's my first time, you know?
I know. But listen.
When you have been killed as many times
as I have, you get used to it, believe me.
- Really?
- Yes. Oh, yes, yes. Yes indeed.
I’ll put this here, keep it nice and warm.
- Cheers.
- Oh. This is for you.
- Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
- Then this must be yours.
- Thank you. Cheers.
Cheers.
Yes. Anyway... you have nothing to fear.
- Yes, I have.
- No, you don't.
- I have.
- No. You see,
I am an officer of the Ieu.
- The Ieu?
- What?
You said you were an officer of the Ieu?
That is correct. Yes, yes.
I am a chief inspector of the Sûreté.
What?
You doubt me.
No, I don't doubt you.
- Why should l doubt you?
- That's right.
lf you say so, l don't.
Who were those two men
who tried to kill you?
- Killers.
- Killers? How do you know?
- I know because I worked for Douvier.
- Douvier? I know that name.
Everyone in France knows it.
He's a millionaire businessman.
Of course. Douvier the millionaire
businessman. l knew l knew it.
But how many people do you think know
that Douvier the millionaire businessman
is also Douvier the French Connection?
Hm? How many?
Well, I suppose his mother, for one.
Why do you suppose
he wanted to have me killed?
Elementary. He wanted you dead.
Oh!
It’s nothing. Just a slight singe.
- I’m sorry about your robe.
- Oh, that's all right.
Tell me about this Douvier.
I was his mistress and
his private secretary for two years.
I know enough about Philippe to
send him to prison for his whole life.
You keep talking about this Douvier.
But Philippe... Who is Philippe?
- Philippe Douvier.
- His son?
Whose son? He has no son.
- His brother, then.
- His name's Fred.
- Then it has to be his father.
- He's dead.
Now we're getting somewhere.
Who killed him?
- He died of natural causes.
- Then who is this Philippe?!
I wanna see some identification.
Right now.
- What?
- Now. I wanna see some identification.
lf you're not a policeman then l shouldn't
be telling you any of these things.
- Can you keep a secret?
- I don't know. That depends.
Then brace yourself
for what l am about to tell you.
I am none other...
than Chief Inspector Jacques Clouseau.
No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
- No, you're not.
- I am.
- You're not.
- You're not. You are not!
Look.
Yes, you are.
Oh, my God.
I admit it's not
a very good photograph, but...
But l saw your funeral on television.
Yes. Even the Peup was there, you know.
- Cheers.
But if you're not dead, who's dead?
A wandering transvestite took my car
and stole my clothes at gunpoint.
I have been working under the covers
tracking the killer.
- The killer's Douvier.
- What?
He wanted to impress the Godfather.
You mean Douvier killed a wandering
transvestite just to impress his godfather?
- Yes!
- (rattling)
- The man's unthinkable!
- (whispers) The door.
- What's wrong with it?
- l saw the knob turn.
(gunshots)
Oh, hurry!
- I wonder whose apartment this is.
- I don't know.
- The other one's probably in my room.
- How do you know there's another one?
Philippe's assassins travel in pairs.
It’s a company rule.
Do you know
what the Gannet transaction is?
- What is that?
- It’s a code name
for a 50-million-franc heroin sale.
50 million francs?!
Philippe's going to Hong Kong
on Tuesday to meet the American buyer.
- Hong Kong?
- I don't know how it fits in,
but the Gannet's a boat.
(karate yell)
What are you doing?
Now l know why this place
looked so familiar.
Chief Inspector Dreyfus lives here.
I think he has received a faint.
Wake up, Chief Inspector. Wake up.
Chief Inspector!
Hello? Are you in there, Chief Inspector?
Hello?
There's no reply.
It’s no use. I think we will
have to go to Hong Kong without him.
- ''We''?
- Yes.
- You, l and Cato, who will translate for us.
- Not me. I am not going to Hong Kong.
- Douvier would shoot me on sight.
- Not if he doesn't recognise you.
- And he won't.
- Why not?
We will leave that up to the great Balls.
''The great balls''?
At your service! Please forgive
the condition of my establishment,
but as the inspector knows -
the chief inspector knows...
- Auguste!
- Argh!
- I’m so sorry. I beg your pardon.
- But as the chief inspector knows,
- we were bombed.
- It sounds like you still are.
Almost all my collection
was either destroyed or damaged.
Starting Monday, I have to have a fire sale.
You could call it
''The Great Balls of Fire Sale''.
A catchy suggestion!
(blows) Cunny!
(grunting)
l can't tell you how good it is
to see that you are still alive.
It has been my privilege to serve
the good inspector - the chief inspector -
for all these many years.
Thirteen, to be precise.
And his reported demise
was a real blow to me.
Something's coming.
Yes! Yes, Cunny! You are not dreaming.
Our friend, our customer, is alive!
Hello, Cunny.
Now, how can l serve you?
- Well...
- Through wind and mud, snow and hail,
whether long or short, dark or pale.
Remember that when duty calls,
you've got Balls.
(clap of thunder)
- l gotta sit down.
- Yes, of course. Cunny! Quick!
Please, please! Come along.
That's right. There you are. Sit.
- Come, come, come. Sit, sit, sit.
- You're not serious?
There has been no time
to get new furniture.
Since the blast,
he's much more comfortable. Please, sit.
As a matter of fact,
I’ve been sleeping on him.
Chief Inspector?
I am leaving for Hong Kong
first thing in the morning.
Hong Kong?
Do you think you could pick me up
some cheap coolie hats?
My dear Auguste,
I need your best Hong Kong disguise.
Also, l will need something
extra special in the Godfather line.
Doctor, please. You must help me.
Is Clouseau real,
or am I going mad again?
- What do you think?
- What do I think? What can l think?
lf that nincompoop is really alive,
and the things l heard are true,
he'll probably be decorated for rounding
up the biggest drug ring in France,
and I’ll be a laughing stock.
That sounds reasonable.
What are you going to do?
What choice do I have?
I either commit myself and come back
to be locked up in here, or...
I go to Hong Kong.
- Listen, I don't think I can do this.
- Of course you can.
Just think yellow and follow me.
Mr and Mrs... Lo Kee.
- (clattering)
- (man) You stupid clumsy oaf!
What the hell do you think you're doing?
You've ruined my suit!
Why the hell don't you
look where you're going?!
I am Mr Algo. When Mr Scallini arrives,
have me paged in the bar.
Certainly, Mr Algo.
Who is gonna pay for my suit?
See that man that was right there? That's
Guy Algo, Philippe's right-hand man.
This Scallini must be
Mr Big from New York.
Listen. We'll go up to the room.
You stay here ten minutes,
then tell Mr, um...
- Algo.
- Right. Yes, Algo. Yes.
..Mr You-Know-Who has arrived,
and bring him to the room.
- Mr You-Know-Who?
- l will be Mr You-Know-Who. Get it?
Right. Come, Ming Loy.
You got a reservation for Scallini.
Page Mr Algo in the bar.
Tell him Mr Scallini's here.
- What do you think you're doing?
- Mr Scallini in lobby.
Cochon.
No, no. Fongu.
Hey, you heard what l said to him?
Dumb Frenchman! ''Cochon''.
That means ''pig''.
I tell Mr Scallini you're here.
- Listen, boss!
- It’s not boss. It’s me.
- Where is he?
- Getting into his Godfather disguise.
Algo's in the next room.
Scallini's down the hall in the Tang suite.
- We rode up in the same elevator.
- Maybe l can reach him before Philippe.
- What will you do?
- I’m not sure. Keep your eye on Algo.
(spills drink)
- Ice?
- Please.
- Soda?
- Yes.
I hope it's not too strong.
I’m sure it will be fine.
Heh-heh-heh! Ha-ha-ha-ho!
Hey! Mamma mia! Ho-ho!
Spaghettini to Al Pacino!
Heh-heh! Ho-ho!
Carlo and me have got a little business
to talk over. We won't be long.
Have another drink. Ho-ho-ho!
Viva Zapata! Ha-ha-ha!
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
(knocking)
(mouths)
- Hello, Mr Marchione.
- Hey.
- Come on in.
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Can l get you a drink?
- Oh, no. Nothing, thank you.
- It’s, uh... Simone.
- Oh, you really have a good memory.
Well, I never forget a pretty face.
Hey, boss. This is Simone.
- That's Douvier's personal...
- Secretary. How do you do, Mr Scallini?
We never met before.
lf we meet before, you call me Julio.
- That's a nice hand.
- Thank you. That's only the right one.
- You type too?
- 100 words a minute.
l may faint.
Mr Douvier is running a little late. lf you
like, I’ll keep you company till he arrives.
lf l like? Does my mother cook spaghetti?
To the Gannet transaction.
Shall l tell Douvier we're on our way?
(choking)
Don't forget the money.
(coughs and splutters)
What?
Throat?
Back?
Choking!
You want me to hit you on the back?
(karate yell)
Aaagh!
We're on our way.
- Mr Douvier will meet us in the lobby.
- Great, great.
- Is that it?
- Yep. Ha-ha-ha!
- 50 million francs and no bodyguard?
- Listen, buddy.
l take care of my body, my body takes
care of me. Know what I’m drivin' at?
- I’ll buy you some cigarettes, huh?
- Smoke a few.
When Douvier shows,
I’ll meet you in the lobby.
(fart)
Hey! Be right with you.
What the hell is going on here?
Lee Kee Shipyard.
- Where'd he go?
- I think they went to Lee Kee Shipyard.
Aaaargh!
(yells in Chinese)
See this? l can tell by your heart line
that you're very passionate.
- See how long this is?
- Keep watchin'. It’s gonna get longer.
(phone)
- Hello?
- Lee Kee Shipyard. Douvier.
It was Douvier.
And the doorman heard him tell the driver
to go to the Lee Kee Shipyard.
Somethin' is cacuzza around here.
Your boss and a couple of boys
just left the hotel.
- Really? I wonder why they did that.
- You got me. Why don't we go ask him?
Yes. OK. Yes, I understand.
OK. Yes.
Douvier left the hotel about
five minutes ago. He was with two men.
He told the driver
to go to the Lee Kee Shipyard.
I’m sure it was that nincompoop!
- I’m sure Mr Douvier won't be gone long.
- Well, we'll see.
It doesn't make much sense
if you leave and he comes back.
Stop worrying.
You'll give yourself wrinkles.
- What about this Lee Kee Shipyard?
- Perfectly legitimate, as far as l know.
They build a line
of expensive power cruisers.
Maybe Mr Douvier
is just buying himself a yacht.
- Lee Kee Shipyard?
- That's what the come si chiama said.
Come si chiama. Lee Kee.
Come on! Move it!
Come on!
(sounds horn)
(driver sounds horn)
(horn)
(siren)
Aaaargh!
Mr Chow, our Far Eastern representative.
Mr Scallini.
- It is an honour to meet you.
- You remember Mr Algo, of course.
Shall we go? After you launch the boat,
we'll go to the office
and sign the ownership papers.
- Everything legal and above board.
- Above the board, yes. Good.
- Where is it? You know...
- Well, l understood you were told.
No, l was told, but checking, you know...
- In the keel.
- Oh, the old keel ploy.
All you have to do is sail
around the Caribbean for a while,
haul her out of the water, take the
midsection out of the keel, and voilà.
40 kilos of the finest merchandise
your experts have ever tested.
I tell ya, it better had be
the best merchandise,
cos my experts
certainly have tested some.
- We have faith in our merchandise.
- That's good enough for me.
- Now, would you like to launch her?
- l would be delighted, you know.
(coughs and sneezes)
September. A good month for the vintage.
Well...
Congratulations!
Aaaargh!
He must be a cop! Get him! Get him!
Hey, boss!
Look out, you Oriental idiot!
What are you doing?!
(Marchione) Jesus Christ!
- It’s me!
- I know!
Wait!
(gunshot)
- (gunshot)
- Hey! Cancel the artillery!
(gunshots)
I don't care! I don't care!
Get out of my way!
- Hey, Al! Where are ya?
- How do I know?
Well, wherever you are,
this is Chief Inspector Clouseau,
and I am warning you
that if you are not careful,
I will arrest you all in the name of the Ieu!
You and your bright ideas.
Let me get my hands on you.
(Dreyfus) Clouseau?
Yes?
- Are you wounded?
- No!
Fortunately l was saved by the darkness.
So what we need is more light.
Look what you did to my shoes!
Oh, I’ll kill you!
Hello, Philippe.
Simone!
- What are you doing here?
- Waiting for the firecrackers to go off.
- What firecrackers?
- The ones l just stuck in your pants.
(bang)
(drum tattoo)
( rousing march)
- Hello! I’m so sorry I’m late.
- i was a little worried.
I had some rather important
police business to attend to.
- And everything's all right?
- Absolutely fine.
Allow me to let you in the car.
- Please.
- It’s beautiful.
It’s rather neat, isn't it?
I call it the Silver Hornet.
Yes... Service, service.
It’s a little overdue
for a service, unfortunately.
Perhaps it's better to leave that there.
- It’s a beautiful night. Why don't we walk?
- What an excellent idea.
- I’m sorry about that.
- That's quite all right.
- You look ravishing tonight.
- Yes, I know that.
- You know that?
- Yes.
- Yes, l knew that you knew that.
- You did? l knew you knew l knew that.
What made you decide
to become a detective?
Well, it's not something
one decides every day of the week.
But in my case, it began
when my great-aunt was kidnapped
and held for ransom by
an unlicensed Armenian phrenologist.
An Armenian phrenologist?
Yes. You know, a man
who reads the beumps on your head.
- The beumps?
- What?
- You said ''beumps''?
- Yes, yes.
- Have you ever had your beumps read?
- I don't think so.
I would guess that your beumps
would make excellent reading.
Would you mind
if I read your beumps someday?
Subtitles ripped and worked by:
frp