People also wondered
What is a rocker?
It's not battery and drugs.
Oh, no.
It is much more than that, buddy.
We have a good life.
Some love the money.
Some drugs.
Other sex, glamor, the struggle.
But it is always a rocker
different.
Why?
Because a real
rocker wants love.
Downloaded via
http:/links. dogoo. us
My name is Archie, of Archivel.
I work for Lenny.
Let me give you an example that
Lenny's world is magical.
Two years ago, this property costing
1 million pounds.
Today: 5 million.
How did this happen?
attracting an opportunity for tax
foreign investment
London, my friend, is rapidly
becoming the financial capital
and the cultural world.
London is another world.
All the world struggle to get out alive.
I can not teach you how despellejar
cat,
but I can tell you many things
about the money that makes the difference.
As he said, going in one direction.
You need a lawyer.
We need a lawyer.
Good business.
These are the work permits,
cost 10.
First we have to take the radish
by the leaves. The same agent before.
I will tell you to develop the planes.
Thank you, counsel.
Do you have plans, you take
the attorney and got the runner.
I need your help, Daddy called.
We have to move fast and try
the ground.
We have to move fast and make
a little more.
It is always safer to invest in property,
but we must know how to do it,
because it is not easy money.
Because of the criminal record of these
types, it accomplishes what the bank can not
It is so called Mr. Lenny el
Wizard of money laundering and
false transfer of properties
London.
No. I am disappointed, guys.
Give me your hands.
And then it does
its transformation from black
magic. There are big problems.
Sorry, guys, do not get the plans.
That was an unpleasant surprise because
Lenny never happens to that.
You can not get the planes.
It is everything we do.
You can not get both?
What jodieron.
What do you mean by that can not
get the damn planes?
They owe me.
I get the building and you lose
your part.
And yet I am being magnanimous.
Find.
We had to find Lenny before
to end the month.
because the way he had. Carlile
to earn a living was very uncomfortable.
You have to find it.
What I do not know is that Lenny controls
counsel, judges and all.
Not cocheriza no work permit
until Lenny did not "move".
And as does the building, wants
your permission.
Hi, lawyer?
Yes.
Yes
I heard who got the money.
Yes, he was very generous, Lenny.
Sure. Now it resolves the plane.
Already done.
Good.
What is the problem, Archie?
That was a bit strong.
I mean, I come from the same
place than you and you seem more violent.
In the same place that I? ¿Quieres
sound a damn immigrant?
I do not download. They need a
bit of fear or will be against me.
I have to teach them a lesson,
Did not it?
Here is an example of how it operates Lenny.
Today is the big day for Lenny.
There is a great opportunity, a new
Russian billionaire wants contacts
Lenny buildings.
He wants permission to work for
a property.
Lenny took the step to the front, insurance
take the deal with Russian.
Nice to see you.
Take a seat.
Excuse the rush, but I have a day
busy.
Sit down.
I can see that we are very similar.
We want things done.
How much is going to cost me?
First let me clarify exactly
how you can benefit
this business.
Without me, I would have to wait 5
to 10 years to get permission to work.
Second, the British Law
A minute.
How much?
7 million euros.
I hope to have the assurance that I
awarded in 6 months and without bureaucracy.
Deal, it as fact.
A drink?
This painting is very nice, Yuri.
This painting has brought me just Luckily,
Lenny.
It is my painting of good luck.
He likes?
take it for a while. You may be
given luck.
Oh, no, could not.
Do not refuse, I insist. Take it
to their home and when I returned
I have given the license.
I thought you were drinking vodka.
The whiskey is the new vodka.
Did not with me?
Do not drink.
Health.
Are you okay?
You're a little red.
Give me some water.
He tried to poison the very bloody.
Leave it, give me the bottle.
Okay, Lenny.
That man is a billionaire.
Well, let me tell you something.
We have a great opportunity here.
What is it? ¿Dónde is the famous
smile of Archie?
I do not want to see you suffer. Are crazy
by change.
They do not respect the old school.
Oh, my God, there is no school like
old and I'm the damn director.
That's why he came to me. ¿Entendiste?
Yes, I understood.
You're sure of what to paint?
It's the best. Not so welcome to lose,
they need it now.
I want this to Cusack.
Call the accountant and tell him to wipe
money.
If you want to understand Yuri contacts
Lenny, you have to do
with cash and for that
you need your personal accountant,
the very talented creative financial
Stella.
Always get the accounts? Why
looking for you in this pitiful that fat
sweating like crazy.
You, my love, you're a good
peculiar.
Come on, you look better smiling.
I do not feel like smiling.
My accountant of 30 years met
at a gay lawyer.
In the midst of our case.
The greatest conveniences become
inconvenience.
Yes, here it is.
This is it.
You're sure he is not gay?
But what the Russian did not know was that
his accountant grew weary of life secure,
emotion and seeks nothing in places
appropriate.
Welcome to SPIL.
This is the home of organized crime.
So if you get 5
¿entiendes, Bob? Do not save anything.
What are you talking about?
Bertie had drugs.
I was smoking throughout.
Okay, guys.
What to do?
Are vagueando as ever?
Fuck you.
But in the world of crime, always
there are coincidences.
And the men who need it are the
same as Lenny has at his command.
Who is the girl?
You know the girl who manages
accounts?
Ah, yes, of the accounts safe.
Well, he wants to do a job.
Normally it would reject, but I think
I'm not in a position to do so.
I am inside.
At home had these, but for fishing.
From where I come to you that they call
human ingenuity.
Are what they call art where
next?
You do know how to entertain.
He also knows how to get there late.
Please do not arrive late.
I have a job that may interest you.
Say?
There are two accounts of 7 million euros
we must protect.
The details are here.
¿Algo more?
Yes. I do not want me to be retaliation.
You can strikeouts an eye.
Only one eye punches, nothing more.
So do not release, only
poncho an eye.
Cute shoes.
Thank you.
You can buy a few equals in a
couple of days.
The rock star, Johnny Quit, is
disappeared.
It is believed that he died yesterday at
the fall of a yacht that possibly belong to
A prominent tycoon fashion.
Sorry, I do not know what to say.
Yes, I bet it took a few.
Do not mention it again another time.
ZDE agreement, Arch?
Tell the lawyer who ceases to
fuck with the damn ball and that.
Okay, great, lawyer.
He has learned the lesson well.
Ashley Cougar.
Go to talk with Lenny.
You know Jackie?
No, Archie. Please do not say anything.
Do not worry, Ash, is very good
friend of mine.
Y is a member.
Hey, sweet talk ¿quieres
a while with the lawyer?
Only if a case "weak".
What you mean by that?
We do not pay much attention.
Ven.
Here you go, plans.
When you're on board with Lenny, he
likes big move.
You want a cigar?
I would love to.
Love at first row
with a new car on the road.
The skill lies in knowing Lenny
when hit low.
Bonita fosforera.
Costa 8 billion and paid.
You know what?
Tell me, Lenny.
Everything lies in the details.
There's also a good business there.
Look at Lenny, plays with everything.
Only paid 100 pounds by the fosforera
and makes the lawyer want to do.
I do not forget that.
First, what is most important.
The best thing about Lenny is that whenever
goes one step further.
You leave that.
Now you only need a lawyer
a few hours on the track,
so what
We stay in touch.
I am calling for the morning.
And then, the shot from the left.
Cuídalo, Jackie.
Lenny, you forgot your fosforera.
I would not say it is mine.
Have your name.
"Advocate"
Nothing is to prevent Lenny make the
big business in Russian.
I knew that he would like the fosforera.
It was a nice touch, do not they?
Yes, Jackie is a good girl. Dale
another drink.
Yes.
You're quite right.
I am not going to give his preferred
painting if I would not want to do business.
Yes, I removed the pedestal and put him in
the wall.
Yes, it seems Archie, painting
Archie
Archie, I have stolen.
What? Hello?
I said I stole.
Yes, I do not know when.
The painting, which gave me Yuri.
Okay.
Archie, this is not good. It is his painting
preferred.
His painting of luck.
Yes, robbed.
Come here and to bring the troops.
Yes.
Oh, shit.
It is in cases like this that what
Lenny gets to want what you want
Lenny gets mad and
Archie comes to the rescue.
Where was, Lenny?
Let's stop throwing stones.
Archie, abofetéalo, Mandal back
to school because he did not resist this.
Resolve this. Recover the painting.
Bring me a body.
Because I'm going to bed.
Ban, if you ask a question so
mierdera like that again,
Danny is going to slap you.
I am sorry, Archie. I just wanted to take
initiative.
Danny, abofetéalo.
With the right, Danny. As it should be.
No, no and no. Do it as it should, with
the back of his right hand.
Leave it already, Archie.
Abofetéalo.
Oh, damn.
Pay attention.
Learn how to slap well, nobody te
resist.
The whole world will open as a source
full of words.
There is no need for excessive violence.
transport you back to your childhood.
The past is in your hands.
Look, I think that again is in
the school.
He did not go to school, Archie.
You want me to also slapped you?
Well, if the slaps are not working,
what you pay cut or,
but keep the receipt.
Let's go find the painting.
Hello.
Put luggage in the car, lock
the door and leave.
I listened.
Leave the keys, dense round, look
at the head and smile.
Well, Are a robbery?
Yes, it is a robbery.
Move.
Thank you.
That was easy.
As I thought about it.
Yes.
Yes, well.
How it started this?
You have to remove the emergency.
Now get out.
Any electrician was able to do a
four years.
Welcome to the new Bourish, sir. Wantoo.
Here I also have something for you,
Mrs. Baxter.
What elegant!
If this seems heavy, imagine if
what counts.
It seems that did not need as many eyes
strikeouts.
I would have liked, but from the point
professional standpoint,
I do not seem natural.
Until next time.
Maybe.
This place has been waiting for
4 years.
The area covers all this and become
in one of my permanent residences.
Excuse me, sir.
What is it?
stolen at the counters.
We lost 7 million.
They know who we are?
It's not like in the old continent.
There are only out cowboys and Indians.
We do not have time to game.
There are people waiting.
Pick up to the counter
and looking for more money.
Victor, Victor.
Let there be no problems this time.
Hey, Archie.
Speak, Lord.
I have pasta for Lenny.
¿Todo?
Yes and the thing is hot
so you better come and get it before
I burn.
I'm going to SPIL.
Wait, I got another call.
¿Lenny? Archie, the Russian
did not come with the money.
Do not worry, the lawyer may
wait. I have good news.
It is your pasta.
Everything?
This is what I said.
Where the removed?
No idea, I do not want to know.
Listen, all we have
to do is get the permit.
Yes, sure to succeed.
Listen, I got another call.
Hello.
All my people are waiting, Lenny.
I can not fail.
Who said you would? It is only a
backlog, a lawyer.
Well, call me soon.
Yes, of course.
Look at Tanks.
Hey, Arch.
¿Quieres some tickets?
No, I'm looking for Tanks
You know you do not like to see.
Look at that street.
Tanks owns the tickets for the
organization west of London.
He knows most of the street themselves
street.
Tanks world is fortified
disguised as information.
Hello.
What do you do?
I need to talk.
You must be in trouble.
Enter.
I love this.
Look at that picture.
The sound is exquisite.
Sorry, Archie, ¿quieres tickets?
I do not want tickets.
I am looking for
a painting, a classical painting.
We took her home for Lenny.
I am going to leave a breakthrough.
We have only a couple of hours before
it is known.
Yes?
Here it is.
For years there had been an informer
very well hidden.
And our boy from the grass stalks.
Well, tell me.
What's new on the streets?
Please, Frank. Again, no.
Sorry, partner, you're not so
important.
But what the situation is getting worse
everybody knows that
the dirty rat
lurking and waiting time of the attack.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Beautiful hat, beautiful.
What the hell you?
Gentlemen, was angry.
I have to apologize for the flaws
my sister.
It has extremely long arms and a
neck scandalously short.
This is why we wear a coat
Versache.
This is fashion.
I're interrupting.
Whatever. Christmas is always
around the corner.
Whenever you're in the same stupidity.
Leave the sillies, tell us the price
and then leave.
Hold on now, gentlemen.
Lord, we have many good things
tonight.
Journals very, very rich.
The drogatas, as would any
drogata, are not trustworthy.
The reality does not belong to them.
Not because I do not believe
him, but because they are drugged.
Satisfied?
A huge rock in the middle of the road
can not seem peculiar
a regular drogata.
The film is set in the
darkness.
In the dark of Siberia.
And we could all be there,
to the menacing wolf.
Hey, Arch
Come here, son.
You two, lárguense.
My legal paperwork
mysteriously disappeared
Hola
I see you brought your dog with you
That's very unkind
You might want to be careful
Bite
Really?
I am afraid that is fairly quiet
I do not know why
So it's best
How well
Let ¿Dónde is?
You can not smell it?
No, I can not
Look at that, we could be a team
Did not you like that?
By the way
This is yours. Buy a
new pair of shoes or something
Yes?
Did not you bloody friendly?
Good evening, dear
They say they are only two days
On the day you buy and you sell
Well, I agree with my
Vegas that sounds correct
What you gonna do?
Beauty is a cruel mistress
I remember that phrase
Whatever
We worship more?
No thanks
You know I like you
I like the way you are
Always thinking about business
Very competent
That Did not pay me?
Tell me about your husband
My husband is a lawyer
I heard it is very good at what he does
Maybe I can get
a job. Dime
What to do for fun?
I am offending in any way?
Like you said I am a professional
And you are my employer and
so long as
Why be offended?
You see, Hector?
That's what I'm talking
This is what I like about this place
They understand the hierarchy
You do your job, I do mine
And we all get along
We are talking about business again
We have bigger problems
To make the story short
I need 7 million euros
lost in the books
Look, I'm the best at what I do
I can certainly get
a portion of that money but
I can not even hide
7 billion of taxes
But if you're so good
Diablo. Let me think
There are always options
Thanks
Come on, boy
Rejoice
Why not tomorrow night?
That's OK tomorrow night?
So tonight it is time to have fun
And we have a feast
planned for you, my partner
We must relax tensions
We have the most sexy twins
Probably escorts
most expensive in history
They have the night off from the Russians
and the Greeks only by us
OK, I see that you do not encourage
There is not
grateful, it's just that
What? What is it?
I do not understand
Come on, Bobby. That is not fair
I do not understand anything coming from you
Okay
Bob, you're my best man
This is not what I have always wanted
I refer to this
Yes?
Bloody bastard!
Look, you have offered
all as friends!
I told you not understand
What? Did not understand that you're a damn?
I could not wait to kill him
That you are
Goddamn!
In other words, which I did cagara
in the fucking pants!
I should have kept his mouth shut!
Yes, of course you should!
O have gone without bother with this!
You're just a kid, you do not know
Shit
I am so sorry
Sorry
No, I'm sorry
No, I am hell! Zest right?
I spent
And it was a damn surprise, Bob
By God!
Okay
Okay. Everything is fine
I feel like an idiot
I do not know what I was thinking
It is normal that I do not think
as you call it
You know there are not many like you
Probably you'll love
God!
What exactly?
want to do?
¿Quieres a drink?
No thanks
I do not at this time
Everything is very sophisticated
Details Scandinavian
English mixed with details
Nice touch
Look at that
How?
Century 19, of Amsterdam, master Bence
Is that true?
You know
I am not the man who look like
Go
You know why they call me Tank, no?
I guess because they're dirty
Think. Tank
Nothing comes out of the tank. Nothing
Apart from that, I have
a few questions
For this reason I came to see you
I think there's new news
Yes?
OK!
Let me tell you. You
take a few sips
I and a cup of tea
Their fate hangs by a thread
I do not have much time to lose
After that, I'm going to
make a question
Just one question
I get a name
And if the name
correctly, the sending home
with their wives and nothing happened here
If the name is wrong
will be food for fish
Are Americans
These fish are hungry bastards
Like most things
U.S. are dazzling
but still are implacable
Muéstrales
Okay, we are. Enjoy
These fish were Americans
introduced here in the 20s
A gift should I add
It seems being
fun and did not want to go
You spent 50 years
They began to feed on other fish
The exterminated
After started eating each other
That suggests greed
It is blind
We do not know when to stop
That's why I am here
To continue to give war. Danny!
Do not let down so long
Sure. Already had enough. One name
The singer of the group. The Quittakers
It's covered in blood Did not?
How a dead man
can send to a party?
No, not dead. I know it is not dead
because it is celebrating with a few girls
It's as obsessed
Oh, please
Do not mess with me!
Please, you would never
I do not know, never lie to him,
never in life!
Let me go
I think
Double Identity
t you dare get in this
You know I think you have
an excellent staff
But it might be true
I thought you had died
as a cockroach!
That junkie has had
more funerals than anyone
and I say that the next
World War, nor will damage
Find this moron
used to be their manager
as it was called
Greek and Meny
Robert and Mickey
Yeah, whatever
Go see what you can find
Take care!
You're not listening to what I say
It is exactly
I need the damn dry ice!
My show does not work without it
Wait a second
If you'd asked me yesterday your dry ice
You have achieved the
more dry ice in the world
but I did not ask for dry ice
I asked two Johnny
Walker, Black Label
Y 4 girls
You Did not get those?
You did
I confess, but Mickey
You are the manager
I am the rock
You have the hat ¿por
what we did not get anything from it?
My hat is deep and full of magic
I have rabbits, handkerchiefs and
girls taking black label
I have cigarette machines,
all, until Marines
And yet the head gets more
Yes?
But there are no dry ice!
I understood
But tomorrow get dry ice
¿Viste this?
What?
The extraordinary Johnny
Quint fell off the boat
They say it is missing,
possibly dead
Our Johnny?
How many rock stars
there under the name Johnny Quint?
What is the single fell out of bed
Not as dead as
to get those shoes
Well?
I look as happy as a worm
Jill What Johnny is as dead?
If you are dead, this is
the third time this year
The rockers like him never die
They continue to cause pain to live
15 years before
Now listen to me, boy
Listen
I never lied to you, no
I'm your real father
You are a rejected
A mistake
A stone on the road
I never told by your mother
but is no longer with us
so we are just you and me
And the following week
go back to school
The most expensive school of
this country, I must add
And then you you will be taken to a tour
And in the meantime
show a little gratitude
low and the damn music!
Go on, John.
I can not, Pete.
It hurts a lot.
Do not give your notes get well.
Do not understand.
Why not?
Because you are a pig street.
What you need is good education.
It's what you need.
But your dad does not give a shit,
Did not it?
So are you in the game, the game
your pathetic father.
Leave it, John. What is this, time
sermon?
Come on, Peter.
I am the sponsor.
Do not be surprised if you start a
regret.
But first let's drink.
My dad forced me to see "Benance"
every Sunday after church.
That is what they call ruin a
a son.
All those silly fools cowboys
with their weapons.
Everything was not bad, his songs also
I did laugh.
But now answer something.
Have you ever got with you?
You know, ZTE touched inappropriately?
If you slept with me, do you want
to say.
In psychology, there is
a technical term for this situation.
Yes?
Tricolatus monstrous.
Your father was monstrous.
Hey, that's my drink.
Go to masturbarte.
Stop telling Peter.
You want to fight?
Te I will love you and your friends.
Do not look like a pirate?
Well, goodbye, piérdanse, lárguense.
Way to go. Everything is in the eye.
Drug addicts are crap.
Hello.
I tried to stop him, but
Can not stop.
I think he wants
I just want to talk.
Sorry, Mickey.
no.
Do not worry, June.
Why do not you go to lunch something?
Come on, come together.
I am sorry to interrupt.
I call Lineshee?
Leeshee, Laishee Leeshee.
appetite and exotic, like you, June.
Thank you.
We can help you?
Have a group called the Quit
ickers? We had.
And there are a singer named Johnny Quit.
There were.
I would like to see Mr. Quit.
I too would like,
there will be a bit difficult because
as newspapers,
the only songs that Mr. Quit
sing, hymns will be heavenly.
Echaría a tear a tear for
all the fools who read the newspaper
and believe this lie.
You saw the body?
I saw broken, broken,
with the language in the jaw,
swinging as a yacht
true rocker?
No, Did not it? And nobody saw it.
Why is not dead.
It is alive and kicking somewhere
painting and has a very important
it does not belong to him.
Excuse me, What does that have to do
with us?
Who bought the painting?
One name.
Johnny, Johnny Quit.
It is the singer of the group
Quit the Lickers.
How can a dead ve
bought a painting?
Not dead, not dead, I know that
it is not because I bought it.
Son of a bitch. Bájenlo of there before
shoot him.
Please do not kill me, I will make what
want.
I do not know where he is.
We can talk?
Your kid is not dead, Did not it?
Do not you dare to call him "my boy. "
You know this maniac, is the
stepson of Boris.
He wants to be close to the art, Did not it?
No one dies damn cockroach.
That damn junkie has seen many deaths
and there are those who do not find it.
I'm telling you, the next war
world bear his name.
Go see if you can find the idiot
who was his manager
that is called Cleanfield Ricky
They call him Mickey.
Yeah, whatever.
Find the idiot.
No, you're not listening to what I say.
I need drugs.
Wait a second.
If you'd asked me yesterday
yesterday, you would have
the best in the world, but I do not
ask no dry ice.
I asked for two boxes of Jonnhy Walker,
black label.
And you get those, Did not it?
Yes, you did, I confess.
But Mickey, you're the manager.
I am the rock.
You got your hat, why not get
a little inside?
My hat is deep and is filled
magic.
I have rabbits, scarves and other tricks.
I have smoke machines, bubble,
everything.
And the hat is even deeper.
Well, there is no fucking drugs
Agreed.
I understand.
So tenlo morning.
I am a little echarme drug.
read this?
What?
The extraordinary Johnny Quit fell
a yacht, is missing
is believed to be dead.
Our Johnny?
How many rock stars calls
Johnny Quit know, Mickey?
The only thing that I think could fall es
spoon to prepare their drugs.
Not dead. Is no better than those
shoes you wear.
You must be living a happier
oyster in the collar of a fisherman.
June, ¿crees that John is dead?
If you are dead, as would be the third time.
The rockers never die like that.
I am going to give problems.
Fifteen years before
Listen child, listen to me.
Let me married to your mother, do not
mean that I am your father true.
You're an outcast, an evil fairy in the
mirror that I inherited from your mother.
But it is not, we are alone you and me and
next week go back to school.
The most expensive school
in the country, as well.
Meanwhile, it shows a little
gratitude and not get that goddamn music.
Go on, John.
It hurts a lot.
Do not give your notes get well.
Do not understand.
Why not?
Because you are a pig street.
What you need is good education.
It's what you need.
But your dad does not give a shit,
Did not it?
So are you in the game, the game
your pathetic father.
Leave it, John. What is this, time
sermon?
Come on, Peter.
I am the sponsor.
Do not be surprised if you start a
regret.
But first, I need a drink.
My dad forced me to see "Benance"
every Sunday after church.
That is what they call ruin a
a son.
All those silly fools cowboys
with their weapons.
Everything was not bad, his songs also
I did laugh.
But now answer something.
Have you ever got with you?
You know, ZTE touched inappropriately?
If you slept with me, do you want
to say.
In psychology there
a technical term for this situation.
Yes?
Tricolatus monstrous.
Your father was monstrous.
Hey, that's my drink.
Go to masturbarte.
Stop telling Peter.
¿Quieres fight?
Te I will love you and your friends.
Do not look like a pirate?
Well, goodbye, piérdanse, lárguense.
Way to go. Everything is in the eye.
Drug addicts are crap.
Hello.
I tried to stop him, but
Can not stop.
I think he wants
I just want to talk.
Sorry, Mickey.
Do not worry, June.
Why do not you go to lunch something?
Come on, come together.
I am sorry to interrupt.
I call Lineshee?
Leeshee, Laishee Leeshee.
appetite and exotic, like June.
Thank you.
We can help you?
Have a group called the Quit
Lickers? We had.
And there are a singer named Johnny Quit?
Had.
I would like to see Mr. Quit.
I too would like,
there will be a bit difficult because
as newspapers,
the only songs that Mr. Quit
sing, hymns will be heavenly.
Echaría a tear a tear for
all the fools who read the newspaper
and believe this lie.
You saw the body?
I saw broken, broken,
with the language in the jaw,
swinging as a yacht
true rocker?
No, Did not it? And nobody saw it.
Why is not dead.
It is alive and kicking somewhere
painting and has a very important
it does not belong to him.
Excuse me, What does that have to do
with us?
They have business licenses in
the jurisdictions that I control.
So if you want to be in the game,
do what I say.
I know what they are thinking now. I see
that there is not much you do not know.
Take it easy, kid.
You are going to instruct?
You who think we are?
Gangsters?
That's not my style.
Hágannos a favor before the
cold.
I lost everything.
There was very compassionate not go to his
funeral, Zeh?
All were, except you.
The only person who did not want Lenny
see there was you.
What to say?
What the hell do you mean?
Leave him, we all know how much you wanted
to Bob.
What do you mean exactly
"Bob wanted to"?
Leave it, is stuffed with paperwork,
the case is closed.
It was assumed that
A call for you.
Someone lost the paperwork and today
want two.
Pretty slick.
Yes, but do remember the next time
exactly what it says Lenny.
Understood?
Yes.
Good.
How do I get this number?
Can I get any number,
working with numbers, ¿recuerdas?
One point for the initiative and two if I
tell what you're thinking.
There are a party tonight.
There is no problem
the wisky not resolved.
I suppose you ask
by those here.
assumed that you wanted to check
that everything was in order.
I was surprised that no
came a point in time.
But I accept that you must have
your own business.
I understand, and neither wanted to
put things ugly.
Which brings me to my
next point.
Since my box the fate
is not hung on the wall
things we have been
so well.
I am not saying that is for you, poker
We have not even finished the business.
But what I need there.
Yes.
Hey, you think that is causing
some problems.
Shut up, Archie.
He spent something?
Nothing, just wants her damn box of luck.
Your table? It is curious that
You had to have seen his eyes.
You do not know what I'm annoyed.
It does not interest me what you want.
That fucking bastard can expect
what they want. If I run this goddamn
If I vuleves to talk like that,
you cut the tongue!
I am the boss of this city.
Understand? I!
And do not talk that when he
lifts everything becomes a finger.
Because I wanted to cut.
Understand, Archie, is not it?
Yes, I understand, yes.
Look at that.
The daddy of Charley Quiz.
As left
control?
For anyone who knows?
I wish someone knew he was your father.
What if he'd signed
'd known?
I know something. Better we give something
to this man.
Anything, something that can be
call shred of evidence,
If you want to find Johnny,
have to go see Cookain.
Who are you?
My name Cookain.
Must be with the others.
No, we are alone.
Well, you better come.
This will be difficult.
Game, women, everything.
It will be a hot night.
I think you'll find something
you like it.
Excuse me, guys.
Well, who is the man?
I guess you need your er.
You might want to do something
around.
What are you doing ray, stupid?
Nothing bad, he had no plans
for tonight.
And I did not want to stay
locked.
I thought we could celebrate.
You mind?
Sure! What happened is
between you and me.
Well, and it only happened because
were gonna go to jail.
If you tell someone what
step, to anyone
Good evening, gentlemen.
Good.
They want something to drink?
Sure.
Remember.
Hello.
A drink?
Bailamos?
You're a dancer?
What if I am a dancer?
Look and will know.
My father was a dancer.
Coming into the blood.
Want to try?
Sure, I want to dance.
Hi, I feel a little
competition.
No, it is my party.
I was told to take
care, you were dangerous.
I'm dangerous.
Maintain the job.
Steady, I sucrase
of way.
The same time,
the same place,
the same money,
Is your friend?
Well, no.
It's a spectacle.
How is security?
Same as before?
Except that they are not
counters mine.
Some heavy
Apart from that, everything is
the same.
I want to go back?
Oh, yeah?
I am a criminal lawyer, and
I am also in good terms with everyone.
And that includes the party?
You have a infirmante.
How is it called?
You have to pay for a secret.
That's not very nice,
right?
What is it?
But remember, I'm dangerous.
I want to know
's show.
See that man sitting
on the couch?
Arvier Queen, no?
It is very optimistic. We can
do a favor.
Damn, that want that?
It's a great lawyer.
Perhaps you know the informant.
Y might be interested.
I go back to work?
Same as before.
Oi you have a secret.
You seem to have more than one.
I want to talk to you.
If you tell me who is the informant
We can talk about what you
want.
I think I should go to
verify.
Wait, you wanted to hear
take all this into a big party.
I understand, Cookain.
If you are an informant, you will have
their statements, questions.
That's a lot more
valuable.
How wise of these
other things?
What?
I hear.
I give and next week
dire you all about it.
What I need is
paperwork.
Look.
Whoever that Russian?
Okay.
What is it?
Call Archie. Tell him
we have a problem.
How?
What would cost us if we close
tonight?
Eleven thousand three hundred
All right, fine.
Go up and see that
happening.
What do think?
What do you think?
We try to enter.
Get in line.
Sign and costs money.
I know that costs money.
Lord Archie, could not close.
We have a concert.
I know.
We have a man on stage.
Find them. I understand, but
the club has to remain open.
you hear that?
Get in the row,
fools.
Look, but do not touch.
I gave, and you are a man
dead.
I have to leave the club
open.
There are 400 people
here.
Leave this garbage. Look
as I am here.
finish here.
No way.
Oh, no.
What happens now you rays?
Sort this out, you and me.
I have to earn my
money.
Look at this, man. Outside
there is a fucking revolution.
Rays. If we want to keep
the license we have to look at Cookain.
We are together in the car, the
still, the wrecked, and they
remove the money. Everything
is going to leave well.
Bob is our driver, and
I do not want to Bob here.
What? Paul is our driver.
No driver are not complete.
What happened between you and him?
There's something about Bob that I think
you should know.
What? That is a bird?
How wise that?
Come on, everybody knows that it is
Suavecito. Only you ignore it.
That does not count here. Only
behaves as it should do so.
In which Ray talking about?
Let him go.
This is crazy.
I do not see what the problem is.
Last night should have been
last night. What consoles,
that's what friends do.
well done. Not
talk over the matter.
What do you mean? Do not tell him
to heads?
But you did?
Looks like you love
It is enough, right?
That ray is going on here?
I believe?
You're gay?
No!
I'm not gay, understand?
I just wonder if I wanted
to dance, is all.
And if you want to dance?
I think there is something that
should know about Bob.
When your mother was wrong,
I was the whole arrangement.
Because I did not, was not
his best friend, was Bob.
Bob was the one who will assure
take care of that.
And Bob did the best we
could to bring her back.
Let me tell you something.
If I bring her and that the UDIERE
price was that Bob is gay,
What would think.
Not you, but I think
it would be worthwhile.
I told them, that
have that face?
There were so funny
last week.
I need to talk to
Cookain.
Come with me.
We need to know who is
Johnny Queen.
It might be the first to
noticed,
Come on, you know that sae
who killed Johnny.
Come on, Cookain, who has been
here in the last 5 years.
God.
Have the courage to go
sauna Johnny?
is an unpleasant place.
Be there and die. I
eu sound is not pretty.
It seems like that quisera
tell?
It's a terrible sound to hear a
man drowning in his own bathroom.
Burn your body.
I've been there, I've
done that.
The eyes are here, and
the other does not.
Imagine all that in
a non-smoking cafe.
It is about protecting
others.
What did this man is
what we call clouds.
And if you have some brain
is not carrying
to be here for weeks.
Veran, Johnny, the addict,
now is the drug.
worth more dead than
alive.
Understand that good.
Mr Queen is not more
us.
He made a trip, but let me
a message.
If the dead return, will be
the first to know.
Victor brought me. And this?
Remains of a grenade.
I am one of those.
Mira.
Wait a minute.
How many of those Hermoso
got?
Many, there's one here
wire
Mine is worse.
Show.
From the streets of Grozny.
I bring the table in two
days. I have it saved for
you. He was in a place
sure.
And then Artie loses
table.
Do not try to be funny but
I want to know if there is any
chance of getting the money.
Where is Ray?
It seems that not impresinaste.
There is something wrong with
this immigrant. Do not trust him.
There is something strange. Not as
I know, but something happens.
I can smell it.
Lenny was the only one who knew.
They were transporting
money
The brain has no
nor the courage for that.
It's a fighter, not very
powerful but it is.
Ona after can be conincidencia,
but two?
And the picture, your picture
the fate?
I think you are taking
by silly.
Fixes a reunion.
Oh, God, you're a disaster.
There you go.
No such right?
It's a rhetorical question, no?
A bottle of water, please,
and an absorbent.
You do not want you to know that
happened?
I know what happened.
You go to eat?
I see it sorted.
You got here late.
Take a few precautions.
Sure.
It was your job, no?
What are these facts
guys?
Do not you realize.
Darme account?
No, I realized that
had weapons?
What were dangerous criminals
war with weapons?
Damn!
you know something? I will leave this
dirty clothes here under the table
for you.
Damn!
Watch out!
damn it!
Get out of here!
this is still alive!
Come on.
Wait, damn!
Goodbye, dear.
You are too dangerous
for me.
Need help?
No, I'm fine.
She is the great
leagues, right?
I hope that we will not
bother.
I'm not interested if
very difficult.
We were going to deliver,
this was the deal.
Hey, counselor.
Counselor!
before taking off?
Show me your phone!
You should not be here.
I am where I want to
because this is my city, not yours.
Despite what you and your
buddy immigrant might think.
And what happens?
Come here.
I can not do it. You're
too many mistakes.
You're almost not going
this city.
I was told that I do not
give permission to build.
Do not leave me with that.
Miro by my window and I see 20 mil
buildings that could not be
to build.
No. I gave you a deadline for the
construction of these buildings?
No, darling. It was some time ago,
too long ago.
Whenever you have imported the
money, counselor, always.
So you do what you have to do.
This time I can not. Do not understand?
Do not treat you happen
so goddamn piece of garbage.
O ahogaré you on your shit.
I feel, right?
Do not think there's a price to
pay for all these
gifts?
cars, travel,
tennis courts, swimming pools?
I am the master of that.
And now my mood is fragile
and can have serious consequences.
So you do it!
Pedro, come back here.
Where are you going to think
that table?
You know that the requested. I have
to deliver it.
The streets are revolts
looking for this box.
No. I've asked.
Do not deliver.
You know that.
No, why?
Meet me in the park
in two minutes.
Tendre that table in a
couple of days.
You can trust me.
It's a small favor and may
be sure that I will.
Nole like to annoy his
enemies, no?
You can not walk well
all the time.
Nobody understands it, no
works well.
It's because I want what
I had.
We do not want us
bother.
Victor, please, come
with us.
You see this package
Geeny Kin above the piano?
Yes.
Everything You Need to Know
of life is there.
And we're going to do?
Every time I'm on the verge
to pay,
something dishonest going on.
will not know anything about that,
right?
It is not just about your
personality.
There are also allusions
to greatness
The dome, refers to the
stature of the Kings
that is a divine signal.
You suggested that the cigars are
your true and loyal friends.
And this is a lie.
Sorry, these are trying to
say something?
No deal, I'm saying
something.
Your other personality is trying
to call your attention to another point
the discussion.
Writings in black and white represent
I amuerte signal.
Because in truth they are trying
to kill you.
And that's the truth.
I think I forgot to talk,
damn rude.
I think you forgot where you are,
bloody immigrant!
Beauty is one of the
way that attracts you to death.
And I'm addicted to it.
This and my land is my show,
I turn this city
It starts sweet and ends
bitter.
And start bitter
and sweet.
I gotta go. I have a reunion
with the counselor, your counselor.
This is your ninth hole.
It's a long way to
get to your car.
get there at dawn, in time
devolvemrme to my table in luck.
I want him back, you hear me?
Yes, yes.
I need to change.
I can not go out like that.
That's why you and I
let drugs.
And that's why no
I can repay that table.
Now, please ask.
You are very special, sr Johnny Quid.
Tell me you, Brody.
Drink something.
And who wrong with the paperwork?
I'm busy tonight.
On Monday, all right.
Letting roles in the
reception, to your name.
You can pick it.
Well, then you vere
on Monday.
You got guts.
That damn you'll
slap.
Well, let's pick up the
people and your boyfriend.
And let me in the Rina. I am going
to sleep.
Can I go?
To bring people to my
place I have to say yes.
John, are good.
Just what you need.
Do not bother, I am a
good friend.
You know, I can help.
Sure, if your I
allows.
Come on, John, you know.
We are your fans. Te
continue.
RockanRolla '
Get out! Get your stuff
and larguense.
What is this?
Sitting? They are fools?
It is a demonstration of
Where the hell have found
to these addicts?
Come with me now.
It's the last time I let you
bring fools well.
Next time, these alone.
Sorry, I just thought I
would like some company.
I'm dead. Sounds like you?
Which means that the dead not
they like the company.
Let's get him out.
Yes, I will tell you that they leave.
Yes, and not to bring back
addicts sucks.
Get him out now.
Fortunately you do not follow.
Pete, where is the box?
Since we arrived. That is what will we do?
Show our treasure to friends.
Gentlemen, we are going to enter the
wonderful world of the paintings.
Come on, let it.
One moment, sir. There is something
you should know this table.
Tell me soon enough.
It is a very unusual box and
expensive, Lord.
Really?
Come on, I do not like the theater.
Good evening, gentlemen.
My pleasure.
Tell me, I am a bit rushed.
I'm in the hospital.
Want your table.
But I have not been able to achieve this.
Well, then acabalo.
Who is?
When you leave, I want
the table.
Well, Cookain.
Tell me.
I'm me.
Who is me?
Who do you want?
You.
Well, come on then.
Come on, what these ends
doing and come here for.
Are you of the time
we've been here.
Who the hell is Sidney Cho?
Sidney Cho is an alias,
idiot.
Never use the real one.
Look, call me later, I
busy, all right?
Okay.
where I learned the word
alias?
Look, all dressed.
I gotta go.
I suppose you have a lot of things that
do during the week.
I call you later.
I have something for you.
assumed that you would like, so
you like the pictures.
You like it?
You have an excellent taste.
What happened?
I broke my leg in
four locations.
That damn left me lame
for life.
And you want to do?
Well, you can not pay.
I'm very badly hurt.
I will do it for you, do not worry.
I think I can do it
better.
Someone is stealing the money of
the Russians.
Who?
You know, and you do not like it.
I'm not playing, Archie. Whoever
Mambo Bob and another.
And we call,
Johnny?
Sorry, no Johnny
this.
But it Pipa, said that
those in trouble, guys.
Well, this quiequiera
speaking you give this message to Johnny.
Tell him that his dad and his crew
gangsters to visit us.
We closed several clubs, and
us close more unless the
sr Quid return with him.
Why do so to speak
Pipa?
They are worse than I thought.
Come back, Johnny, go back
home.
Johnny can come back quietly,
but may have some problems
with Pipa.
Now if you excuse me talk
Pete with anything else.
Disculpennos a moment.
Always come back a bit
afternoon, right?
He wants to go down the stairs
or by the elevator, sr Coke?
Artie, come here.
You've been bebieno.
No, sir Coke.
Think before you drink before
I'm crazy.
Archie, some guys
want company.
Yes, it is pronoto.
Wait.
Who is it?
Hey, we are.
Come.
Looks like we have visitors,
vere hopes that they want.
Wait, I entered another call.
God, this job!
Archie, you have a kid.
Or what's left of him.
You might want to do the
role of pope at a later time.
Yuri, I do not like, nor
trust her.
Your what?
Yes, sorry. But even so
I do not like.
It does not interest me what you like,
I'm in charge.
But your last girl we cost
20 million.
Nobody knows how much we cost
this.
Victor chooses.
Can I come?
Excuse me come by surprise,
but I have something for you.
A token of my appreciation.
For this is?
Please do not insult you.
But I like more than what
you think. And not just want your services.
It's just a sample of
As you appreciate it.
I wanted to ask you something
personally.
you marry me?
Well, I think it needs to
a couple of days.
To think about it.
Yes, of course.
What happens, I'm busy.
A very pretty picture.
Since when have you got?
years ago. You like it?
Beauty is a lady
cold, right?
Victor, please, come
with us.
Give me my gloves.
Spot. As
in the old days.
What about today? A mayhem?
Another issue?
You will not greet Johnny?
Do not play, Johnny.
Lights a little upset.
Still working?
Do not you feel good to be a lawyer.
What do you, John?
Mirense, guys. How scary.
This is what makes 4 years of absence.
And worry so much about the money makes
a man who becomes murky.
I have no idea that goes through your
head, thinking that these dirt.
Fifteen years earlier.
Hi, Archie.
Hey, Johnny, look!
What these big!
Come into the courtyard, the guys
are there.
I can not, come on.
Raise your hands!
Give me that, go to the car.
Here you have kids, for
who have never seen anything.
Dress as we find you,
and without many problems.
The handsome Bob, Mambo,
Morty,
I bet you already have a
squad formed.
I can see them doing their job,
destroying people's lives.
Shut up and will not hurt.
Dress, is the famous Archie stupid.
Shut up, or tematare myself,
damn stupid.
Do not remember, Archie? Since
I'm dead!
Sal.
Take him.
Daddy!
Good wheels!
Excuse porlo of the
table.
I needed the money for
some things.
Had you been more generous,
nothing would have happened.
I wanted to get clean when the soul
back to see us.
What are you, boy?
If you are not a poison?
Your father could not look at you.
Not for pleasure and I was jodio
I leave my pick
lospedazos.
But I was not enough
to you.
I had to put in your mouth
a bunch of pills.
And your mother all that he was staying
a hot bath and a cold knife.
Why? Because you are a poison,
Johnny.
That's why.
What can I say? I am an addict,
I like the crack.
you should never have put your
money in that school.
Archie, get him out of here.
I will, but let it
watch the wheels.
It's a reunion!
I love meetings.
Look at them. Mambo, the handsome
Bob, all the old faces.
And everything was going so well.
Except for Archie.
But ruined the day.
I was going to tell a story
on you, Daddy.
I was going to tell you as your
Quiet, quiet.
Give me that.
I was not one of your best
shot, right?
If you wanted to kill debian
being announced earlier.
As six inches above.
Come here.
Get rid of him, understand?
Get rid of him!
You do not know cuantosproblemas
've caused.
But you should know that kills
slowly, if not you tell me where
Archie, in my jacket.
Look what I got.
Who says?
Do not want to know what they
said.
If I think of the law,
can not be very flexible.
Because every time someone
viola, in front of judges.
A secret letter.
We need the collaboration and
efficiency of an informant.
And if that informant offered
adequate information,
then it will be Magic
released.
The removal of jail free
charges.
And it comes with a very good
alibi.
If you help us find these people,
can help you.
And you can turn into a bloody
guardian angel for the underworld.
Trust us.
They have evidence of many
things that were
in a bilingual
containing a statement secret.
Your statement is in the
road.
Of course I use many
things.
An angel like you, Johnny.
If you do not you go to jail.
I've seen these charges to end
men for 20 years.
Who is this Sydney Cho?
Nothing to do with you.
Why not Alexander?
I like Sydney.
What is wrong?
Sounds like the name of an actor.
It's free to go, sr
Sidney Cho.
I lay a trap,
Archie.
You're a damned dirty
Sydney.
In truth, you are.
Quitenle that. Get him out.
I need your help, partner.
Nothing will happen if we
together.
because we will load the
body.
This is a very
heavy.
Within two minutes, I
could lead to the bridges.
Danny there thrown Trigger,
three times to be sure.
They should not have
killed, friends.
There will be witnesses.
After you pull the body.
use 6 gallons of oil
to hide.
I can imagine letting
what follows.
But then the Danny
kill, porqeu knows that you know.
So, shoot.
Quick, give me the gun.
Hurry, hurry.
Quick, before they continue
thinking.
We need help.
Get on your hands.
We must go, not Johnny?
We made a deal.
Knights, ending up with.
Malcolm, 10 years.
Look at this paper, here this
the place and time.
Give him 15 years to Freisa Nesch.
Six years ago he wanted
finish with you, damn.
As a kid is ready, give him
three years.
The Jimaguas, 14 years.
Archie, is as loyal as
a dog.
this is becoming a bit
ambitious.
4 years for Archie.
Then I come.
Archie 4 long years.
There is no spring
winter.
There is no life without death.
And there is no drug that has not gone to
stop to the lungs of the young Johnny.
Goodbye, sir Sidney Cho.
It seems you were quite right,
Johnny.
You feel better.
I was until I saw you.
Still, I'm clean.
Only these are cursed.
Well, finally here.
Welcome home.
Give us your money, Arch.
You can do better.
Johnny came out of prison.
What, you gonna give me coffee?
Goodbye, cruel world.
A small gift from Arch,
Johnny, for your wall.
Do you count this
stories.
That must have been expensive.
Actually it cost much
to the Russians.
You are going to return to the music?
I wanted to relax a little.
You are going to come with me?
I think you should be careful.
Because SERE like you, man.
I will make Rock and Roll of truth.
Johnny, Archie and the clan
wild again in
The real Rock and Roll