I've done terrible things
in my life.
Things for which I can
never be forgiven.
I betrayed friends,
turned my back on the ones
closest to me.
Gabriela!
I've always known that my sins
would eventually
catch up to me.
No sin goes unpunished
in this life.
Your life doesn't flash before
your eyes when you're dying.
That's bullshit.
It's your regrets that haunt
you in your final moments.
Everything you failed to be.
Everyone you let down.
Run!
Everything you'd go back
and change
if only you had more time.
Look who's up.
Sleeping beauty.
You were fartin' in your sleep
again, you know that, conlon?
How would I know that, dickhead?
I was sleepin'.
More like dead to the world.
Danny in yet?
In the office.
Uh-oh, here he goes.
Oh, he's fucked.
Here he goes.
And he's chasin' her
around the house
with his thing all night.
Finally she goes,
"How is titty-fucking me
gonna make my tits
any bigger?"
Boyfriend says,
"hey, baby, it beats me,
but it worked on your ass."
All right, there you go.
Merry Christmas.
I appreciate that,
Danny. Thank you.
All right, get outta here.
Shit, shower and shave time
for me.
Hot date tonight?
Little grab-ass
under the mistletoe?
I wish.
- I'm introducin' my father to some
new business partners. - Oh, yeah?
Been workin' on it
for about nine months
and finally he agrees
to hear me out.
Hey, well, he's a busy man,
your father.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, no shit.
- All right. See ya later, fellas.
- All right, see ya.
- Hey, guys.
- What's up, Jimmy? How you doin'?
Christ! Can I get one moment
to myself?
Hey, Danny.
Hey.
What-what do you want?
Uh, I talked to your father
this mornin'
and, uh, the-the heater
blew over at my place.
He, uh, told me to ask you
about a loan.
- A loan?
- Yeah.
Or a handout?
Naw, it's-it's just a loan.
Why he keeps you around,
I got no idea.
All right.
How much do you need?
Uh...About eight hundred.
I don't know what "about
eight hundred" means, Jimmy.
Give me a number.
Eight hundred?
Eight hundred.
- All right.
- Thanks, Danny.
Oh...Jee- you know...
Mccauley, he- the son
of a bitch canceled on me.
I need a Santa for a Christmas
party this afternoon.
Santa claus?
Yeah.
Aw, jeez, Danny, I-
you'll be great.
Find someone else, huh?
I gotta get home.
Yeah.
I'll get somebody else.
You freeze
your little nuts off.
Come on, Danny.
Hm?
You see that?
You see that switch?
- I switch, and then I get out.
- Yeah.
And then you're out.
- You control him with the jab.
- Yeah.
- All right?
- Right. - Put the phone down.
Watch me with your own eyes.
Okay?
What the fuck, man?
Oh, shit! Yo!
Yo, look at his face.
Sorry, man.
Get the fuck outta here.
You started it.
Aw, walk of shame.
Yo, Mike, you knocked him
the fuck out.
Hey, what'd I tell you
about talkin' like that?
My bust.
- See how I kept my elbows tight?
- Yeah, I saw 'em.
You gotta be careful
fighting garrity.
He's gonna wanna push you
against the ropes.
Just give him one-a these.
Knock his shit-talkin' mouth
right out.
Sorry. It slipped.
Go ahead, legs.
Gonna find out real soon
how fast it can all slip away.
Relax, Mike.
I was just messing around.
That's your problem. You got
all the talent in the world
and all you wanna do is mess around.
I'm told that you're a man
of influence, Mr. Maguire,
and that nothing moves in or out
of this borough
without your approval.
And my employers are, uh,
looking for a partner
to help bring our product
into the city.
We use our contacts
in the union, pop.
Three bins a month,
dockworkers know which bins
are comin' in
and all they gotta do
is make sure
they pass through
without inspection.
What exactly
is your product?
Heroin.
99% pure.
The very best in the world.
And my son told you
I'd be interested in this?
Very interested.
The business has changed,
Mr. grezda.
Twenty years ago,
I made a living
the same way we all did.
Couple big scores a year,
but mostly I was a grinder.
Now, you want to lay down
on a few ballgames,
you came to me.
You want to open up
a butcher shop
and the bank said "fuck you"
on a loan, you came to me.
You know what that butcher shop
is today?
Mm, no.
An applebee's.
Why are you
telling me this?
Because I've had to adapt
to the times.
I am a legitimate
businessman now.
I know
your business, Mr. Maguire.
That's why I'm here.
You're wasting your time.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hey, hey.
Wait!
Come on, now. Pop, just listen
to what he has to say.
You haven't heard
the offer yet.
Two million dollars
up front.
After that,
you'll receive 20%
of all the product you allow
to pass safely through the port.
The answer's no.
Take the night
to think it over.
Once you've considered it
more carefully,
you'll realize the mistake
you are making.
How do you think I survived
in this business for 35 years?
Everyone I came up with
is either dead
or locked up in federal prison
waitin' to be buried.
I don't make mistakes.
It's Christmas time.
My friends are here
to celebrate with me.
Get the fuck
outta my house.
Take this shit with ya.
Guys. My old man. I don't even
know what just happened.
We paid you to guarantee
your father's support.
Just let me talk to him,
all right?
I'll get it all figured out.
I'll be stopping by
your house tonight...
To pick up our money.
You know what happens
if you don't have it.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, guys.
Fucking garbage.
I hate Albanians.
What the fuck was that?
Did you even listen
to what he had to say?
That's not our business,
Danny.
Shut your mouth.
I'm talkin' to my father.
What's the problem, Danny?
The problem is,
all I ever hear outta your mouth
is when am I gonna pull
my weight?
And now I bring you
a piece of business...
A good piece of business-
and you're mad because I let it
walk out the door.
- Yeah. - When I was younger, somebody
made me the same proposal.
- Mm. - I made so much money bringing
cocaine into the city,
I had to rent a storage unit
to store all the cash.
The problem was, everybody
got hooked on the shit.
I watched my friends rot away
in front of me
until I couldn't recognize
them anymore.
I had to kill people I loved
because I couldn't trust them.
Not enough money in the world
to pull me back in.
Pop, I made promises
to these people.
I can't just walk away.
- You made a mess.
- Mm.
It's time somebody other than me
cleaned it up.
One, two...
Three...Four...Five...
Lily, what are you doin'
in here?
- ...six, seven, eight...
- Shh! I'm hiding from catelyn.
...nine...Ten.
- Is she in here?
- Is who in here?
She's over there.
I see you.
It doesn't count!
You have to tag me!
- I said I see you.
- Doesn't count unless you tag her.
- Hey. - It doesn't count
unless you tag her.
You didn't touch her.
- Tag!
- You got tagged.
Didn't I tell you girls
to get ready?
We're going to
your uncle Ricky's house.
Go on.
Get your butts in that room.
- I thought you were off tonight.
- I was.
Till somebody broke her wrist
fallin' off-a the jungle gym.
So you're not comin' to Ricky's
for dinner?
I can pay the hospital bill
or go to Ricky's for dinner.
- What do you want me to do?
- I want you to do what you promised.
And you said Friday-
don't tell me what I said.
I know what I said.
Fine. I don't want you there anyway
if you're gonna act
like an asshole.
Hey! Come on.
Hey.
Mnh. Mnh.
Come on.
- I'm sorry.
- You better be.
- What're you working on?
- It's for the baby.
Show him what our lives
were like
before he came along.
You like it?
I'm sorry.
I forgot to take it out.
No, it's all right.
There.
Now I won't have to see him
for another five years.
We want Santa!
Jimmy?
Kids are waitin' for you.
Yeah, I know.
I'm comin'.
- And a bitty baby and a Barbie
power wheels car and a... - Uh-huh.
- ...nintendo three-d-s.
- Yeah.
And a hello kitty
backpack...
Merry Christmas.
There you go.
But I wasn't finished.
I'll read this on the way back
to the north pole.
Okay?
There you go.
Whose idea was it to get Jimmy
to do this thing?
Okay.
Who's next, huh?
Ha ha.
This little girl.
What's your name, sweetie?
Kristen.
Mommy?
Santa smells funny.
You think mommy wants to sit
on Santa's other knee?
I think mommy's
a little too big.
Oh, Santa can make lotsa room
on here.
That's my wife, Jimmy.
Frank.
It's Christmas.
Gimme a call...
If you wanna break
the Irish curse.
I'm skinny, but I'm long.
Okay...Let's see
what Santa brought you
this year, kristie.
Aah!
Shit!
Ah, fuck!
Fucking kids!
Jesus Christ!
- Where is he going?
- Santa'll be right back, kids.
I didn't get to read
my list.
- Get in there!
- Oh. Oh.
Jesus, guy, come on.
It's Christmas.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh, god.
Hey, pat.
When you get done in there,
get him a meal...
And some water.
Come on, pat,
gimme a drink.
You remember what that's from,
don't you?
Hm? Must have been, what,
the summer of '71?
Point pleasant.
'70.
We enlisted that fall.
That's right.
I was in that bed
with Jenny Blake.
You were in this one with,
uh...Uh, you know,
what was that redhead's name?
- Maureen Galvin.
- Yeah.
All of a sudden,
from downstairs,
my father's voice booms out:
"Who the hell's
been drinking my scotch?"
And Jenny, she jumped off me
so fast- bam!
She smacked her head
right on that thing,
knocked herself out.
You get enough to eat?
Yeah, yeah.
Got plenty left over,
you wanna take some home.
No.
I'm fine.
Rosie mad at me?
She'll get over it.
Gimme a cigarette,
will ya?
She'll think the smell's
coming from you.
You wanna tell me
what's goin' on?
Come on, Jimmy.
You look like
a goddamn castaway.
I can't sleep no more,
Shawn.
I keep seeing their faces
in my dreams.
Whose faces?
All of 'em.
Terry Burke.
Vince amato.
Ernie Hayes.
It was different then,
Jimmy.
We did what we did
because we had to.
Billy, too.
I see Billy a lot.
I got no one left in my life
because of the things I done.
I chased everyone away.
Look at me.
What do I always tell you?
Wherever we're going,
when we cross that line,
we're going together.
Me and you.
Hm?
Yeah.
Uh, excuse me, buddy, where
the hell are you taking us?
There's, uh, construction
on the Manhattan bridge.
Traffic's a mess over there,
so I'm tryin' to save you
a little time.
Or make yourself
a little more money, huh?
Trust me, okay?
I lived here my whole life.
Just one hour away
from another chapter
in a historic rivalry
that is the New Jersey devils
and the New York rangers
at Madison square garden
in New York.
It is a crucial game
in the eastern conference
standings for both teams.
Look who it is.
You wanna join us?
I'm expecting someone.
Bullshit, Jimmy.
You don't got any friends.
Detective torres,
meet Jimmy conlon.
Jimmy and I spent a lot
of quality time together
back when he was killing people
for Shawn Maguire.
Nice to meet you, Jimmy.
We had a name for him
on homicide task force.
Jimmy the gravedigger.
What happened
to the other guy?
- That ginzo?
- Tornetta.
- Yeah. The ginzo.
- He retired.
I guess he got tired of workin'
with a d.A.
On Maguire's payroll.
Tired of watching murderers
like you walk free.
Maybe you should have taken
a bite outta that pie, Harding.
You still wouldn't be wearing
suits like that.
Oh, you're breaking my heart.
You don't like my suits.
What's the number, Jim?
What's the number?
Tornetta had you
at sixteen.
I always thought it was more.
I made a list once.
- All the names.
- How'd that work out?
Seventeen.
You see, tornetta,
he didn't have Ernest Hayes.
But that was yours.
Doesn't ring a bell.
Sorry.
I get a letter from his widow,
every year, handwritten,
asking me if I got
any new information.
25 years later,
she's still lookin' for closure.
I got stacks
of those letters...
Crowdin' my fuckin' desk.
That get
under your skin at all?
Why don't you
whisper it to me.
What's the number, Jim?
What's the number?
Tell your partner they don't
serve chimichangas in here.
You know
when the nightmares...
When they get so bad
you can't look at yourself
in the mirror no more,
you give me a call.
Let's go.
Suddenly I lost my appetite.
Getting set to go here
in Madison square garden,
and we are now
less than an hour to go
until the puck drops.
Get the door.
Hey, guy.
Hey, there the boys are!
Hey, hey.
Whoa, whoa.
Whoa. Whoa.
Whoa, be gentle, now.
Be gentle.
You're grabbing
the real weapon there, baby.
- Hey!
- Hey, Danny!
My boy!
Whoa!
What do you think?
Nice apartment.
Come on in.
Sit down.
So, Danny...
Huh?
Where's our money?
You're a businessman.
I like that about you.
All right.
You heard him.
Get him his money.
In New York City,
which means we're less
than twenty minutes to go
till the opening face-off
between the New York rangers...
Jesus Christ.
Hey, legs!
Come here.
The atmosphere
could not be more electric.
What'd I tell you about riding
around these streets alone?
I don't gotta answer
your questions.
You're not my dad, Mike.
Oh, so that's how it is
between us now.
Yeah.
That's how it is.
Your mom know
you're out here?
What if I called her?
Let her know you're out here
on your own? Mm-hm.
Oh! We have some serious weapons
here, huh?
Oh! That's loaded!
That's loaded!
Look. I'll go home
if you give me a ride.
I can't give you a ride.
I'm with a client right now.
Come on, Mike.
Just let me sit inside.
I ain't never been
in a limo before.
Look. I won't break anything.
I promise.
All right.
- If I let you inside, you'll
go home straight after? - Yes!
- You go home straight after?
- Promise. Straight after.
All right.
Caught him.
Ohh.
It's all there.
Count it.
Boh!
Do you find this funny,
Danny?
Think about what you can do
with all that money!
You can put up a luxury
high-rise on park place.
...so excited at what
they can do in the playoffs...
♪ some Remy Martin
and some good-ass cigars ♪
Oh, dang,
this is my song, Mike.
♪ Ayo, late night, candlelight ♪
♪ fiend with diesel
in his needle ♪
♪ queensbridge leader,
no equal ♪
Danny.
♪ Like a record, baby ♪
Do you have any idea
what we gonna do to you?
Ah, no.
♪ All I know is that to me ♪
♪ you look like
you're lots of fun ♪
♪ To pop thousand dollar bottles
of scotch ♪
♪ smoke pot and heal
the people ♪
♪ Baby, right round,
round, round ♪♪
♪ count how many bad honeys
I slut, it's a high- ♪
Look, I'm, uh...
I'm sorry about
what I said earlier.
I was upset with myself,
not with you.
It's all right. I was just worried
you weren't gonna come back.
I'm not going anywhere.
♪ Panties start drippin'
the ways of carlito ♪
♪ Blaze, torpedo ♪
♪ cigars drop rolls ♪
♪ freaks, women nice size
I ride like porsches, thick ♪
Yo, Mike.
Mike, check this out.
Shit. Get down!
Get outta the car.
D- Danny.
It's Mike.
Get out of the car.
Get out!
- Fuck.
- Move. Move. Move.
Ow!
Shit.
I found this in his jacket.
What do we do?
Move! Yo, I think you
should call your dad.
...live and we are ready for
the opening face-off center ice
at Madison square garden
in New York.
Off the face, New Jersey
in control, henrique.
Henrique gives it
to jaromir jágr,
and he gets the puck all the
way down near the goal line.
Sends it in front and it's
cleared out by lundqvist.
Nash on the wing,
dumps it into the corner.
Hey, Shawn.
Listen, uh,
sorry again about-
now it's zuccarello,
swooping in to get the puck.
What?
Michael?
My Michael?
Yeah. Yeah. Sure.
Gabby?
Gabby? Catelyn?
Lily?
Tell Danny to stay put
until I hear from Jimmy.
What about the Albanians?
It won't be long
before they realize
grezda's not around.
They'll come after Danny.
What are you
thinking about?
The exact moment
my son went wrong.
Hello?
Hey, Ricky.
It's me.
Put-put-put Gabby
on the phone.
Okay.
Hold on a second.
Michael?
Hey. Listen.
I need you and the girls to stay at
Ricky's until I call you back, okay?
- What? Why do we have to stay here?
- Gabby?
No! Tell me what's going on, Michael!
- Gabby? Goddamn it!
- Why are you yelling at me?
Wa-uh-I don't wanna yell,
but it's the only way
I can get through to you!
Hello?
- Can I come in?
- What are you doing here?
I got a call from Shawn.
You talk
to the police yet?
Talk to the police
about what?
We both know why I'm here,
Michael.
Now, let's figure this out
so no one else gets hurt.
You stay out of my house,
you understand me?
What are you gonna do
with that thing?
Huh?
So, what, they sent you
to keep me quiet?
Shawn would, uh...Well,
he'd appreciate your support.
You mean he'd appreciate me
keeping my mouth shut.
Yeah.
Who were they?
I don't know.
Whatever Danny did,
I'm sure he had a reason for it.
You always had a reason?
Or were you just...
Following marchin' orders?
Let's just get through
the night, huh?
After that, you can go back
to hating me all you want.
Yeah.
Yeah, I get it.
I get it! All right.
Yeah.
No, I'm not goin' nowhere.
Oh, that's the house here.
342856th drive.
That's it.
Are you sure
you wanna do this?
I mean, your old man told us
to stay put.
He wants me
to clean up my mess.
That's exactly what
I'm gonna do.
Well, I think we should wait
for Jimmy to get here.
Maybe you shouldn't think
so much.
You don't smoke in my house.
The place looks nice.
I haven't been here since-
since mom's funeral.
It was nice of you
to show up.
Well, I heard there was
free booze.
It's funny to you.
Just trying to be-
yeah.
Five years
and it takes Shawn Maguire
for you to come see me.
You never wanted me
to come see you.
Because you're trash.
And I don't want trash
around my family.
They shoulda locked you up
a long time ago.
Made you pay
for the things you did.
Just because
I'm not behind bars
doesn't mean I'm not paying
for what I did, Michael.
So, what happens now?
I'll go see Shawn.
Let him know we talked.
I'm sure he'll wanna show
his appreciation.
A little money he could set
aside for the girls.
Catelyn and Lily.
- What's that?
- My daughters' names.
Catelyn grace conlon
and Lily Margaret conlon.
I know what their names are.
Do they know mine?
They don't got a reason
to know yours.
You're not a part
of their lives.
It's bad enough
you were part of mine.
Goodbye, Michael.
Goodbye, Jimmy.
Oh, shit.
Call an ambulance.
What are you just
standing there for?
- Call an ambulance!
- You're wasting your time.
Hello.
Yeah.
It's-it's me.
How'd it go with Michael?
Hello?
I just killed your boy,
Shawn.
I just killed Danny.
I had to.
He was gonna shoot Michael.
Are you sure he's dead?
Yeah. I'm sure.
Who is it, honey?
You know how
this has to end.
Yeah, I know.
For Michael, too.
Yeah.
Hey, Shawn.
Hm?
Wherever we're going,
when we cross that line...
We're going together.
Right?
What are you doing?
I'm calling the cops.
You don't wanna do that.
Trust me.
Get out of my house.
Get out of my house!
Get out!
911, what's your emergency?
This is Michael conlon.
342856th drive.
A- a man's been...
Shot and killed here.
In self-defense.
Did you shoot the victim?
No.
My father did.
Oh, no.
Report of a shooting
at 342856th drive.
All area units respond.
Over.
- You Michael conlon?
- Yes, sir.
Officers randle
and colston.
Come on in.
I- I don't know
where to start, uh...
I work as a limousine driver,
and, uh, earlier today
I picked up a reservation.
Uh, two gentlemen
at the gramercy park hotel.
And, uh...And th-the-they wanted
me to take them to ridgewood.
Lift your arms for me,
please.
Lace your fingers together
behind your head.
Turn around, please.
Yes, sir.
What the he-?
What the hell?
- I'm trying to explain to you.
- You feel that?
Say another word and I'll blow
your fuckin' teeth out your ear.
Officer, I'm tryin'
to fuckin' explain to you.
I'm not-I'm not
hiding anything.
I'm...I'm trying to explain
to you.
Officer...You're making a
fuckin' mistake here, officer.
- Get in.
- I'm trying to tell you-
Six-double-0-five
at 343856th drive.
That als unit en route?
Ten-four,
six-double-0 five.
Westbound on 32nd.
All right. Let 'em know there's a
deceased white male in the kitchen.
Neighbors saw an armed suspect
flee the building
just before we arrived.
Wait, what the hell
are you talkin' about?
- White male, black sweatpants, black
hoodie. - What the hell you doin', man?
- Approximately 6'3".
- Hey!
- Suspect is armed.
- He's lying!
- I'm in the car! - Officer colston and
I have secured the perimeter.
We're gonna take a drive around
to see if we can locate him.
Hey!
Let me outta here!
Ten-four, six-double-0 five.
Where you takin' me?
Hey, that's frank.
He wants us to follow him.
Get outta here!
Watch out! Watch out!
Watch out!
He's still comin'.
Shit!
He's comin' back.
This fuckin' guy won't quit.
Watch it! Watch it!
Watch it!
Whoa-whoa whoa-whoa!
Get back! Get back!
Get back!
Mike.
Mike!
My god.
Cover your face!
Give me your hands.
- You okay?
- No! I'm not okay.
Come on!
Let's move!
Come on.
don't do it, son!
We gotta move.
Come on!
What the fuck?!
Hey!
Protect yourself.
Hey, asshole!
Slow down.
Come on, let's go!
Move, move, move!
You owe me $2.50,
dickhead.
- Back off, pal. - I'm not gonna
back off! You stole my fare.
I'm not gonna say it again.
- Are you kidding?!
- Get lost!
I'm not gonna get lost.
You should at least apologize
or somethin'.
Look,
I'll give ya the money.
Whoa-whoa! Whoa!
Take it easy, man.
Jesus Christ.
Forget about it.
It's just $2.50.
Hey, frank.
Your wife
called me earlier.
Yeah?
What'd she say?
She wants to take me up
on my offer.
- Is that right?
- And I gotta tell ya.
I've never seen a woman
swallow twelve inches
the way she does.
South entrance clear.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are being held momentarily
by train traffic ahead of us.
Stand clear of
the closing doors, please.
Jimmy.
Maria.
Rose is asleep.
don't wake her
till the mornin'.
Load the bodies from Danny's
into Michael's limousine.
Dump the car where the cops
can find it.
Make sure everything points
to Michael.
I know.
It's my fault.
Every shitty little thing in
your life is my fault, right?
I'm turning myself in.
Not yet, you're not.
Shawn's gonna come after you,
Michael.
And if he can't get to you,
he's gonna go after your family.
Right now you've gotta worry
about staying alive.
And I'm the best chance
you've got.
I know how this works.
I want people at his house.
Right now, Shawn's got everyone
meeting at the Abbey.
And from there, they're gonna
start pulling your life apart.
Friends, family,
coworkers.
Go!
Anyone that can connect them
to you.
And the cops?
They've got their own
motivation.
You know what they do
to cop killers?
They don't like to leave it
in a jury's hands.
Hey, Paul. Yeah.
I got what you need.
Got it.
Let's go.
Woodhaven, queens.
There's gotta be
a few good cops.
Someone'll listen.
The good cops won't listen
to you 'cause you're my son.
25 years, I've been
chasing this son of a bitch.
This has gotta end tonight.
And those two bodies
from Danny's place,
Shawn will make sure
they point back to you.
This is fourteen-eighty two.
We got a one-eight-seven
in the suspect vehicle.
They just found two bodies
inside of Mike conlon's limousine.
Albanians.
Part of a gang that operates
out of Brooklyn.
Right now, we're the most
wanted men in this city.
Michael, listen to me.
One night.
That's all I'm asking.
Listen to your father
for one night.
If I can't figure this out
by the morning,
I'll walk myself
into the precinct
and tell 'em I blew
those two officers away.
One night. Then you never
have to see me again.
One night.
This way.
- Gimme your lace.
- What?
Your shoelace.
Come on.
What're you doin'?
Where's your family?
My brother-in law's.
I want ya to drive there.
Make sure they're safe.
don't move until you hear
from me.
Wow.
Where're you gonna go?
I'm gonna talk to Shawn.
See if we can fix this thing.
Hey.
Stay off the main streets.
Yeah?
I'm so sorry, Mr. Maguire.
I'm so sorry
for all of this.
He was my best friend.
I shoulda done something.
Look at me.
Did he suffer?
- Danny?
- Did my boy suffer?
He just kind of went down.
It was real quick.
Thank you.
It's okay. Come here.
It's okay.
Sorry,
I didn't want him to die.
Did anybody see
who killed the cop?
Witness couldn't identify
the shooter.
Conlon and the son were both
seen pulling their weapons.
They couldn't get to Michael.
I know.
Jimmy called.
He wants to meet
in the old neighborhood.
You need to see this.
A city-wide manhunt
is underway tonight
as police search
for two suspects
identified as James conlon
and his son, Michael conlon,
who they say took the lives
of two police officers
during a deadly chase
on Jamaica Avenue earlier.
We're also getting
reports tonight
the two could be linked
to a double homicide.
Two bodies were discovered
inside a limousine
believed to have been driven
by Michael conlon.
What do you got?
Just got off
with the dispatcher.
Last contact she had
with the patrol car
was at 342856th drive.
Officers responded to a report
of a shooting
at Michael conlon's house.
Do you wanna guess
who the victim is?
Danny Maguire.
Michael conlon
told the officers
his father was the one
who killed him.
- Harding.
- Evening, detective.
This is Jimmy conlon.
You got some fuckin' nerve.
You better be on a plane
to shangri-la.
I tried.
Flight was full.
I got fifteen witnesses that say
you ran a cop car
off-a Jamaica Avenue
killin' an officer, while
your son killed his partner.
I killed that cop.
Not Michael.
Bullshit.
If your son's
anything like you,
he was probably laughing
when he pulled the trigger.
I need your help.
I am the last person
on this earth
that you should be
asking help from.
You're the only cop
I can trust.
And what's in it for me?
I'll turn myself in,
confess to killing those cops,
if you agree to help Michael.
I'll die in a prison cell.
That's what
you always wanted...
Right, Harding?
You're gonna die in
a prison cell anyway, conlon.
There's no way out
this time.
And I'm pretty sure
that I can find a witness
that says your boy did it.
Tell me what you want.
Names.
All of them.
Every life you took.
Every family you ruined.
If you give me that...
Maybe, fuckin' maybe,
I'll listen to your son.
Not yet.
I need to take care
of a few things.
Turn yourself in.
You drink coffee, Harding?
Yeah.
Six cups a day
for the last thirty years.
Put in a little extra sugar.
It's gonna be a long night.
- Gabby?
- What happened to your face?
- Where are the girls?
- They're asleep upstairs.
Hurry up
and go pack their stuff.
Why do you have a gun?
Look, Michael, whatever you're
going through, there's a way out.
- Mike. - Look, Michael,
we get- - sit down, Ricky.
They said you killed two cops.
It's all over the news.
Tell me you didn't do it.
I picked up
two clients today,
took 'em
to Danny Maguire's house.
And he killed 'em,
he shot 'em both,
and then he tried to kill me,
too, 'cause I saw him do it.
- Did you call the cops?
- It's-it's not that simple.
What do you mean
it's not that simple?
Look, I grew up around
this stuff.
I know what these people
are capable of.
And now they're
comin' after us.
You gotta take the girls
and go.
I'm calling the cops.
Baby. Baby, baby. Baby.
I'm gonna fix this.
But you gotta trust me.
Okay.
- You gotta tell 'em you haven't seen
us. - Do I have to?
They're not gonna
just go away, Ricky.
Open the goddamn door!
Can I help you?
Okay. Come-come here, sweetie.
Come here.
Where we going, daddy?
We're gonna play
hide-and-seek.
Where do you think
you're goin'?!
Be real quiet, okay?
Uncle Ricky's gonna try
to find us.
Can I help you find something
in my house?
Who was here for dinner?
Just some work friends.
You always serve your friends
chicken nuggets?
We're on a budget.
Where's your friend?
I know your sister called.
What are you,
stalking me?
- What did she want?
- She was cooking dinner.
She...Asked about a recipe.
A recipe?
Chicken nuggets?
I'm calling the cops.
Call 'em now.
Yeah?
Okay. I got it.
Tommy!
We gotta go!
Be quiet.
Shh!
They just left.
It doesn't count!
You have to tag me!
Driver...
Pull over.
Turn off the lights.
Anyone gives you shit,
your transmission blew
and you're waitin'
for a backup.
Hey.
You want a drink?
Nah.
don't make me drink alone.
Miss, get him a scotch,
will you?
On the rocks.
So I heard you, uh,
left frank face-down
in the subway.
Frank was an asshole.
Frank had fifteen years
and thirty pounds on ya.
I thought he woulda
worn you down.
So did I.
Gomez shoots...
Close game.
Coming up
on two minutes to go...
It's gotta be fifteen years
since I've been in here.
The place looks different.
All the old places
look different now.
Me, Richie Ryan,
Mickey featherstone
would meet every Saturday night
for drinks.
Sit in that back booth,
back there.
Yeah, I used to bring Danny here
when he was a boy.
Special occasions.
His first communion,
I ordered him a lobster.
Waitress brings it out.
Big as this table.
Beautiful, too.
He takes a look at it,
and he says,
"do you have
any chicken fingers?"
Thanks.
How's Rosie?
Hell of a thing to know
you're never gonna make the
woman you love happy again.
I'm here asking
for my son's life, Shawn.
I pulled the trigger.
I killed Danny.
You wanna send someone for me,
tell me when.
I'll keep the door open,
I'll put my gun on the table.
Michael, he's a good kid.
He's got a family.
He don't deserve this.
Michael was not gonna talk.
If Danny hadn't shown up-
you think I sent him there?
I told him to stay put.
He wouldn't listen.
He was into some bad shit,
Shawn.
don't talk to me
about my son.
I'm gonna do what I have to do
to protect Michael.
If that means I gotta talk
to someone...
Talk to someone?
Cops. John Harding.
The things I know.
Things that mattered
twenty years ago?
What, you think the feds
are parked outside,
listenin'
to this conversation?
Huh?
Take a look out there.
Nobody gives a shit
about what you know anymore.
about you.
You die tomorrow, you'd rot away
alone in your bedroom
until the stench gets so bad
the neighbors got no choice
but to call the cops.
Wouldn't be any point
in having a funeral
because no one would come.
He shoots!
Forty seconds to go.
Kick save by lundqvist.
I'm the only one
ever cared about you.
And all of that ended
an hour ago
when you killed my son.
I'm comin' after your boy
with everything I got.
I won't let you take him,
Shawn.
You got no choice.
And when it's done,
and it will be done,
you and I are gonna meet
back here at this restaurant,
at this same table that I used
to share with my boy,
and I'm gonna look you
in the eyes,
just like you're looking me
in the eyes right now,
and I'm gonna see
how empty they are
without your son
in the world.
Same thing I saw
in my wife's eyes.
Same thing you're seein'
in my eyes.
And when I see that...
Then I'll let you die.
...shoots just wide.
Lundqvist couldn't get
his stick on it.
And it just missed.
Two, one...
And it is over at the garden.
The rangers win it 3-2.
Thanks for the drink.
What a night for the rangers
here at Madison square garden.
Where do you think
you're going?
Devils suck!
Go back to Jersey!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy.
I left my wallet in my seat.
I'm leaving town tomorrow.
- I'm screwed without it. Please.
- All right.
Take this guy down
to his seat.
- Thanks, pal.
- All right.
Whoa, easy, fellas. Game's
over. No re-entry. Sorry.
Go back to Jersey!
- Sir!
- I got it! Thank you!
Hey, hey!
- What'd he say?
- You need to get your family out.
Remember the cabin I used
to bring you to
when you were a boy?
Up by north-south shore?
- Take the throughway all the
way up to Haines falls. - Yeah.
You'll be safe there.
Stay here.
Yeah,
that's, uh...That's Danny.
That's my son.
Who's that man, daddy?
It's nobody, honey.
Let's get in the car.
All right,
you know where you're going?
I'll find it.
Hey, babe.
Look at me.
It's gonna be okay.
Go.
What're you doing?
Get in the car.
If I run now,
I'll never stop running.
Michael.
You have to leave the city.
There's this kid I train
down at the boxing gym.
He was with me in the car
at Danny's house.
He saw everything.
Can you keep me alive
long enough to get to him?
I'll drive.
Get me price.
So you keep in touch with your
mom's side of the family?
What, you're the big
family supporter now?
Listen,
I came home a few times.
Your mom and I tried
to work things out.
The only time
you ever came home
was when you needed a place
to lay low.
And I'd find a gun hidden
in every room in the house.
And I'd be scared to death that
you'd end up like cousin Billy.
This is price.
I got a job for you.
Two people.
I'll double your quote.
But it's gotta be done
by the morning.
They killed two cops
and a couple of squarehead
gangsters in queens.
The whole city's
huntin' 'em down.
I need you
to get there first.
And what are their names?
Michael and Jimmy conlon.
You're fuckin' with me,
right?
You want the job or not?
Conlon? I'll kill that
motherfucker for free.
Just make sure
his son dies first.
Your next one,
is it a...A boy or a girl?
A boy.
Boy?
Got a name picked out?
Yeah.
You like what you do,
driving a limo around?
Sure. I do cartwheels on my way
out the door every night.
That bad, huh?
Since when do you give a shit
if I'm happy?
This is for your own sake,
right?
I say I'm happy,
that life turned out all right
and then you don't feel
so guilty about leaving.
- That's right.
- Yeah.
So, are you?
I'd be happier if I were
still fightin', but...
I used to watch your fights.
That's fuckin' bullshit.
Over on church street.
I'd stand in the tunnel.
I was there when you lost
to Ramirez.
You didn't have
the killer instinct
to make a top-class fighter,
Mike.
I got fucked by the judges.
The judges didn't fuck you.
You were ahead at the end
of the fourth,
and you stopped
using your jab.
You could've made the rankings
if you'd-a used that jab more.
That's life.
It don't offer any do-overs.
Believe me, I know.
Otherwise, I woulda put in
for one a long time ago.
You've got a lot of anger
in you.
Wouldn't you?
With you as a father?
Because I left?
You got it backwards.
The things I did,
the things I seen...
It becomes who you are.
You can't just go home
and scrub it off.
The only way I could protect you
was to walk away.
Forget about you
and your mom.
I wanted a better life for you
than the one I chose for myself.
That's it.
I'm sorry, Michael.
Hey. You know this kid called
legs? You know where he lives?
Building three.
Which apartment?
What do I look like,
Google maps?
Thanks.
His name's Curtis banks.
You know,
h- his mom works as a nurse.
No, sorry.
Yeah?
I'm lookin' for legs.
Yeah. Me too.
Preferably spread.
Hello?
911.
What's your emergency?
Yes. The bad guys
that was on the TV?
They're outside the door.
Just hold the line.
All units respond
to a code one.
Positive I.D. On the
I-278 shooting suspects.
648 park Avenue, Marcy houses,
building three.
Hi. I'm-I'm lookin' for this kid
called Curtis banks?
Legs?
Open the door, please.
He not ready.
No, you not ready.
Terrell is gettin'
his ass beat.
Boy, you see!
Yo, go get the door.
Hurry up.
Yeah?
I'm lookin' for this kid
named legs, or Curtis.
- Who are you?
- It doesn't matter who we are.
Do you know him or not?
Sorry, but my mom told me not to
talk to creepy-ass old men.
Hey. You.
I seen you before.
Down at the boxing gym.
You know legs, right?
Yeah, that's my brother.
Is he okay?
I need to get ahold of him.
It's really important.
He's not answering his phone.
Where would he go?
I don't know.
Well, think.
I need you to tell
your brother...
That Mike needs his help.
It's really important.
All right.
Let's go!
We gotta get out of here.
It's a big building.
We've got some time.
Let's wait.
We're looking for a white male,
in his thirties...
Anybody in there?
Police.
Open the door, please.
This is the police.
Let's go.
Everybody out.
Come on, folks.
Let's go.
Police! We need to evacuate
the building.
Everybody out!
Come on.
Let's go, let's go.
Come on, guys.
Let's go.
Copy that. I'm covering
the southeast door-
sir!
You can't be back here.
You don't understand.
My mom lives in this building.
- I'm sorry.
- She's having chest pains.
There's two fugitives hiding inside.
I'm not allowed to let anyone in.
Could you check on her
for me?
What's her apartment number?
317.
I have the keys right here.
Two tactical units
are heading inside now.
And you're sure
conlon's in there?
Why do you think I saved you
a front-row seat?
Police, open up!
Police.
Open up the door!
It's the police!
Go, go, go.
Open up! Police!
Hey!
Shit.
What's goin' on?
Now's our chance.
Let's move.
Fools are in there!
He's got a gun!
Yo, get back!
Get back! Move!
Freeze!
Targets are on
the twelfth floor,
headin' down
the west stairwell.
Repeat, twelfth floor.
Let's go!
Let's clear 'em out!
Shots fired
in the west stairwell.
Two officers down!
Holy shit!
Attention.
An emergency has been
reported in this building.
Do not use elevators.
Please leave the building.
We gotta get everybody
outta this building now!
This is some bullshit.
Stop pushing me, man.
Aw, shit.
Easy does it.
Okay.
Move!
Do not use elevators.
Shit!
He's got a gun!
Please leave the building,
utilizing...
...fire exit stairway.
You ever wanna see your family
again, leave.
- Leave now. - Who was that?
- He's a professional killer.
He won't stop
until we're all dead.
...fire exit stairway.
An emergency has...
- Go, Mike. Go!
- ...been reported in this building.
Please leave the building
utilizing the nearest...
- Price!
- ...exit or the fire exit.
Come on, you fucker!
Please do not use elevators.
Do not use elevators.
Come on, price!
You dumb fuck!
...elevators.
Attention...
Do not use elevators.
Repeat,
Repeat, Do not-
don't do it, Michael.
don't do it!
- don't fuckin' move!
- Let's go!
Police! Freeze!
On the ground!
All right, we're comin' down.
Conlon!
Stay there, conlon!
Goddamn it, conlon!
Conlon!
Stay back.
- Come on.
- Hey!
Jesus, conlon.
Come back up. Come on.
I'll give you a hand.
They're inside
on the ground floor!
I want them in custody.
Easy. Easy.
Get on the ground!
Put your hands up!
Suspects heading north
toward the rail yard.
We have the area surrounded!
Fuck!
Oh!
Get on the ground!
Freeze!
Get down on the ground!
don't fuckin' move!
Hold it right there!
Eyes on the suspects.
Headed to the east quadrant!
I lost visual.
Conlon, it's Harding.
It's over.
Do ya hear me?
You gotta surrender.
That's it.
We're comin' in.
He's not in here.
Is he fuckin' here?!
You can't ever pull that
trigger. You understand me?
You pull that trigger,
you're no better than I am.
We get everybody to go back
to the edge of the perimeter,
and we work our way back in.
We'll go to
your uncle Eddie's house.
Come on.
- Hey, uncle Eddie.
- Michael.
Just pull the sleeve.
I got it.
don't wipe off the tattoo.
Thanks.
There you go.
What the hell happened
to you?
We were jumped.
Over on,
uh...Bedford Avenue.
One of 'em had a knife
this long.
Hm.
Took my wallet, too.
Oh.
Where's mom?
Is she asleep?
Mom is in
the hospital again.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
What you got yourself
into now, Jimmy?
It's been all over TV.
All night long.
Showin' your picture.
Cops come here.
Asking me,
have I seen you?
Do I know where you guys are,
both of yous?
So, what's going on?
I'll need your car.
Mike and I need to lay low
for a while.
It wasn't enough that you ruined
your own fuckin' life?
Now you're gonna bring Michael
into this?
I'm not bringing Michael
into anything.
I'm trying to get him out.
Who you running from
this time, huh?
Shawn Maguire.
I killed his son.
I killed Danny.
Get the fuck out of my house! Hey, hey.
Get the fuck out of here!
It's not his fault
this time.
He's trying to get me
out of this.
No, he's not trying to get you
out of this, Michael.
He's not.
He's only loyal to one person.
He's gonna turn you over
to Shawn.
I'm his son. He's not gonna turn
me over to Shawn.
He killed his own cousin
for Shawn Maguire.
What the fuck
you talkin' about?
I'm talking about
your cousin Billy.
N- n-no.
R- Roy demeo's guys killed Billy.
Everybody knows that.
For god's sake, Jimmy.
Tell your son the truth.
Billy had problems.
Yeah. Sure.
He couldn't quite
quit the dope.
Billy used to follow Jimmy
and Shawn around everywhere.
He thought they were some kind
of goddamn heroes.
And then the night
he got pinched,
the d.A. Wanted him
to rat out Shawn.
Otherwise, they were gonna
lock him up for ten years.
And he's just a kid,
and he's scared to death.
And he was gonna talk.
But Jimmy, he wasn't gonna
let that happen.
Were you, Jimmy?
I had to tell the boy.
He can't trust you.
Mike!
Wait!
Michael. Wait.
Michael!
Here.
Whose side are you gonna choose
this time, Jimmy?
E.R.
Yeah, Cheryl's off tonight.
Yes.
How can I help you?
Ma.
Mm.
We heard from price?
Not yet.
Is it done?
Not yet, Shawn.
I'm giving you
one more chance
to walk away from this.
You're giving me
one more chance?
That's right. As long as
you're comin' after Michael,
I'm comin' after you.
Walk away, Shawn.
Walk away to what, Jimmy?
Huh?
Ain't got nothing left
to walk back to anymore.
This is between you and me.
Leave my son out of it.
Fuck you.
Then we do like
you always said.
We cross
that line together.
Right now.
Tell everyone to get ready.
Jimmy's comin'.
I'll take another, Terry.
All right.
One sec.
Hey, Terry.
♪ An old man said to me,
"won't see another one" ♪
You fuckin'-
♪ I turned my face away ♪
♪ And dreamed about you ♪
♪ got on a lucky one ♪
♪ I've got a feeling ♪
Drop it.
♪ This year's for me and you ♪
Open the door.
Come on. Move.
♪ I love you, baby ♪
♪ when all our dreams
come true ♪
♪ it was Christmas Eve, babe ♪
♪ in the drunk tank ♪
♪ an old man said to me,
"won't see another one" ♪
♪ and then he sang a song ♪
♪ the rare old mountain dew ♪
♪ I turned my face away ♪
♪ and dreamed about you ♪
♪ got on a lucky one ♪
Been a long night,
huh, Jimmy?
Yeah.
Growin' up, all we wanted
was to be like those guys
we saw walkin' down to their
social clubs on tenth Avenue.
Now look at us.
I never wanted
to be like those guys.
All I wanted was
to be like you, Shawn.
I'm sorry, Jimmy.
Shawn. Stop.
Come on, Shawn.
Ji...
We got a walk-in.
Young kid.
Says he's got information
about Mike conlon.
Get down!
Why didn't you bring this
to me earlier?
I thought they killed Mike
and maybe they were
comin' after me.
My little brother found me
at my friend's place
and told me that Mike came by
the apartment
and said he was in trouble.
So...That's why I'm here.
And tell me
how you know Mike again?
Trains me down at the gym
on fourth ave.
They, uh...They got a program
for kids who don't got dads.
He's my mentor.
All right. Sit tight.
I'll be right back.
Call ballistics. Tell 'em to
check Danny Maguire's gun.
See if it matches the bullets
- in the Albanians the patrol
found earlier. - All right. Got it.
Call for you, Harding.
Line two.
Tell 'em I left
for the night.
It's Michael conlon.
Says he wants
to turn himself in.
Michael.
I won the first round, so...
You won the first round?
Green!
Catching up to me.
- I can go in.
- I need orange, red, green.
You lose!
I'm getting over here.
What the fuck
are you doin' here?
Cops are on their way.
I'd get the hell out of here,
if I were you.
I'm too old to run.
Where the hell
would I go anyway?
It's over, Michael.
You and your family don't have
to worry about Shawn no more.
When the cops get here,
I'll tell them everything
they wanna hear.
That you...Didn't have any part
in all this.
You mi-you mind
if I wait inside?
The girls
are still in there.
Yeah. Right.
It's nice
to finally meet you.
I'm Gabriela.
Hi.
Nice to meet you, too,
Gabriela.
Why don't we go inside.
- Babe.
- Let's go inside.
Okay.
Girls?
Girls.
This is your grandfather.
Hi. My name's catelyn.
Well, hi, catelyn.
I'm Jimmy.
Nice to meet ya.
You're a pretty girl.
Why were you standing
by my house earlier?
Uh...
I was waitin' on your dad.
- Did you get all wet?
- Oh, just a little.
Wanna say hi
to your grandfather?
Could we go feed
the ducks now, mommy?
Come on.
Let's go put your coats on.
- Okay, Lily, you got the bread?
- Yep.
- You're gonna hold on to it?
- Got it!
You have to give some
to your sister, too, okay?
No, I won't eat it.
Let's go.
- I'm gonna go and keep 'em busy.
- Okay. All right.
I don't want the girls to be
here when the cops come around.
Yeah. Yeah,
they shouldn't see that.
Goodbye, Michael.
Duckie.
Remember to walk
really slowly, okay?
You don't want
to scare them.
You okay?
Mm.
Roll...
I gotta go back up there.
- It's for me.
- Okay.
I'll be right back.
Get the girls out of here.
Come on, let's go.
Stay quiet, honey.
Stay quiet.
Oh, god.
Where's daddy?
I'm scared.
Shh!
It's okay, honey.
You have to be quiet-quiet.
Gabriela, ruuuuun!
You should have killed me
when you had the chance.
Dad?
Mike!
Put that gun down!
I'm-I'm-I'm innocent!
- I know.
- I didn't do anything!
I know.
I need you to put the gun down.
Get on the outside, legs.
Get on the outside.
Get off the ropes, legs.
Get off the ropes.
There you go.
Roll to the left.
Get outta there.
Check him with a jab.
There you go.
Quick feet.
Yes!
Two! Three!
- He's done.
- Four!
Five! It's over!
That's what I'm talking about.
Beautiful!
Now get in the middle.
You're gonna get
a big, big sugar rush.
Here. Take the nose.
Put that there, like this.
- There you go. Hey.
- Daddy!
- What's that supposed to be, Cate?
- Frosty the snowman, duh.
Duh!
What about you, sweetheart?
Rudolph the reindeer.
Aw. He's so pretty I might have
to take a bite.
No, daddy!
It's mine!
Okay,
I won't do anything.
I gotta go get ready
for work.
don't take all of them.