Sometimes things happen in life
that turn everybody silent.
So silent that nobody dares
to talk about it any more.
To no one. Not even themselves.
Not in their own head, not aloud,
not a fucking word.
Because everything has been lingering.
There deep in those fields, year after year.
But out of the blue it is all back.
Just like that, from one day to another.
It may be ever so long ago, there is always
someone who digs it up again.
Whatever you do, and whatever you think,
one thing you can be sure of:
you're always fucked.
Now, tomorrow, next week and next
year, until the end of time.
Fucked.
What did I hear, man?
You don't want to sell us
your cows any more?
That's a little late, huh.
You have no say in that any more.
You do what we tell you.
You use our products
when we say so.
You bring your animals to my uncle
Mate, you're lucky that your father
used to know my father.
When I get home ...
I want to hear that you have
called Uncle Eddy.
Do you understand that?
You sell your bulls only to him
and at his price.
Marc. Léon.
Which one is it?
- That white one.
Yes, open it.
Yes, that's ok.
Put that one in my trunk
and the rest in the truck. And quickly.
Come on, guys,
the rest in the truck.
Diederik, call me.
De Kuyper Marc...
can't answer your call.
Hey, grandma.
Grandma is going to get you.
Come inside with grandma.
Hi, Jacky.
Hi, bro.
New wheels?
- Not bad, huh?
They look expensive.
- No.
A bargain.
How much?
- Six hundred.
Where did you get them?
- At David's.
David?
- David, David, that Walloon from Waremme.
Everything all right, mate?
- Yes, yes.
What happened?
- Football, huh
Why is he wearing a suit?
It looks chic, right.
I can pay it, eh. Voilà.
That's it, androstenedione?
It disappears completely
half an hour after you've injected it.
No trace, nothing.
Animals fattened up in eight weeks
instead of ten, and ten percent more fat.
Making big money.
- That's good.
Even in the Hormonic States of America
they don't know that.
Say, that Uncle Eddy ...
- He will come to here.
Yes, I'll call you back later. See you, huh.
Here, see.
- Eddy.
Are you going to the moon or what?
- Eddy, everything all right?
Stieve. Jacky.
The slaughterhouse is once again packed.
Sam wants to propose something to you.
- Tell it.
A former business partner of mine
from West-Flanders told me ...
that a client of his, Marc De Kuyper,
is looking for a new supply channel.
But I can't deal with it alone,
so I'm looking for support.
What do these people from West Flanders
suddenly see in us?
Limburg is far away.
Just West Flanders isn't right either.
Jackie, what do you think?
- We can always go and talk.
Let me know when, Sam.
That's okay.
And?
Go ahead, those Walloons don't
understand a thing we say.
Not simple, Richter. Daems shot back.
I had to put five bullets in it.
Where are the toilets?
- There in the corner.
Say are those the original wheels?
- We have stolen it like that.
Those are the original wheels.
Right, David?
David? That we stole it like that.
- Yes, yes, we have stolen it that way.
That's the rest: 1,500 euros.
Listen well, friends. This car
must disappear. No hassle.
Dis-Ap-Pear.
Yes, yes, I understand.
Disappear.
Let's go, we're gone.
Chef?. You forgot your box.
- No. That's a gift. From my boss.
Christian?
- What is that crap?
A steak?
- Christian?
What?
A hole.
- They can lick my arse.
Here, it's a bullet hole. Here.
- What?
That's a bullet hole.
You're right. That's a bullet hole.
- Yes, I'm right. That's ...
a bullet hole.
Top detective and hormone hunter
Gilbert Daems ...
was found murdered last night.
Daems was slain by
several bullets.
His car was cornered
by a stranger near his home.
Jacky?
- Yes?
Where are you?
- Here.
Phone for you. Get off that ladder.
What is it?
- It's Uncle Eddy.
Yes.
- Quick, turn on the TV.
On the news.
Well, now there is talk of
Daems himself shooting back.
No trace of the perpetrators,
but everyone agrees ...
they must be sought
amongst the hormone Mafia.
David? David?
- I'm here.
Daems, that's him. I know it for sure.
They have killed a cop.
How do you know?
You think it's the first time
I've worked for these Flemish butchers?
I didn't know that.
- You never know anything.
Mafia. Supporters of 't Vlaams Gezang.
All fascists.
Let them be damned, those dirty Flemings.
How can you know for sure?
- Don't you get anything?
The night of the murder
two Flemings arrive here ...
in a car with a bullet hole.
Even if I'm wrong, no risks.
Certainly not for those Flemish bastards.
Watch your steak.
What are we going to do?
- What we are going to do?
We're going to dump that car. We have
nothing to do with their affairs.
Let it disappear? My ass.
Ikske seen nothing, Ikske done nothing.
- Ikske what?
Don't bother. It's Flemish.
You know?
We dump that car in their town
and wash our hands of innocence.
Wait, wait, wait.
They are going to find that car.
Think about it, that's the idea.
A car found, nothing special.
Nobody will think of a murder.
We have a problem.
- What problem?
The tires.
- What tires?
The original tires.
Ah yes, shit.
- Yeah, shit.
You just have to think about it, eh?
When they find out that
it's not the original tires...
I say it:
We should dump it into the canal.
That can't hurt.
- That can't hurt. Are you crazy?
Driving 30 km and risking someone
seeing us dump the car into the canal.
We're going to get them back.
See, with a little effort ...
- What?
Your steak burns.
You'll see.
The front does not match the back.
This is a disaster, huh, kid.
Look, look, he's there.
- Marc.
He's there. You see it well, huh.
Hello.
- Marc.
See that? He's still not getting away.
You help me with a Limburg connection.
Limburg ...
You can sit at the table, but mouth shut.
Look carefully, listen carefully.
See that?
That isn't right again, eh.
Guys see him jump.
There you have it.
Who is it?
- Sam Raymond, a veterinarian ...
and a contact of him from Limburg.
What's his name again?
- Jacky. Jacky Vanmarsenille.
Jacky?
Vanmarsenille?
Marc, are you OK?
- Yes, everything OK.
Jacky Vanmarsenille. Leon.
Sam Raymond.
- Diederik.
Let's go eat.
Yes, Limburg ...
I've been there many times.
Chaussée d'amour, surely?
Chaussée d'amour. Do you know that?
Chaussée d'amour, you know that?
Hearsay.
- He will be familiar with it.
It's fun there, man. That's one
whorehouse next to the other.
Everyone drives thirty there.
No speed cameras there, I bet.
A stake in your pants, yeah.
What is the matter with him?
- I don't know.
Hold on.
Some-thing's not right.
You should not worry so much.
I'll take care of it. Just hurry up.
I'll call you later, okay?
My brother.
You go look.
Come on, mate, go take a look.
Jack.
I do not know you.
You know what bothers me?
They have destroyed that Daems.
Nobody makes a problem of that.
We can no longer work
like we should.
True or not?
Maybe they keep an eye on us.
You, me, here, now.
What then?
Nobody keeps an eye on me.
I keep an eye on you.
Then we can talk.
I swear, I actually thought
for a moment it would go wrong.
But then ... beautifully played, Jacky.
"I keep an eye on you."
We should celebrate this.
I know how we will celebrate this.
Drop me off at home first.
- You can really be a spoilsport.
Allee, hup.
Jacky, come on.
Come on.
What's the problem, kid? I'll pay.
Hey, it is along here, huh.
- Yes ...
I will tell you in a moment where it is.
Allee.
Okay, okay. Just go, partner.
I will do yours also.
But at your expense.
Run, Jacky, run. Run.
You can run well.
Did you watch Merlina yesterday?
Go on.
Jean, I'm coming.
Allee, Stieve.
They're going to teach me how to inject.
- Cool.
Stieve, be careful with those syringes.
Hi, pretty boy.
Come here, you.
Why did God invent hot water?
Bah, that tastes like coffee.
- Go give your brother some help.
Are they getting injected again?
- Yes, we must strengthen them.
Right, Renaat?
- Yes, yes, certainly.
What's in those bottles, is called DES.
Diethylstilbestrol.
DES?
- DES, yes.
Growth hormone, eh.
Because everything in the body,
is regulated by various substances.
And hormones are the most important.
Sometimes we have to give nature
a helping hand.
Like methanol, in the mopeds.
- Well done, lad.
Try to pay attention to the syringes.
Jean? From now on always use new ones.
To avoid infections.
Inject it in the arse or between the hooves.
Gendarmes.
What are those gendarmes doing here?
- Wait a little.
Come.
I'll be back soon. Be good.
Don't touch anything.
Yes.
What are they doing out here?
Getting products for the animals.
I don't know.
At a truck company?
Methanol, methadone, hormones ...
All the same, sure.
Look at that.
I fancy her.
- Your French isn't good enough.
Oh, Jacky, I love you.
I have big boobs. Oh, yes ...
Hey. You're laughing with my sister?
- We don't speak good French.
Laughing with my sister?
Do you want to fuck her?
Bruno, let it go.
- Want to fuck my sister?
Bruno, stop it.
Want to fuck?
- What is that?
Have sex.
You know what that is, sex?
So.
- Enough. Stop it.
What are you laughing at? Laughing at me?
Looking for a fight?
Want to fuck? Wait.
- Stop it.
Shut up.
5,000 francs, and you can fuck Lucia.
- Let me go.
Want to fuck?
- You're hurting me.
Shut up. Fuck him.
How much do you give to fuck her?
Do you want to come into my sister?
It is your contact.
If that Italian doesn't pay ...
Listen ...
- You are going to listen.
No money, no merchandise.
Clear? Do not play with my balls.
Bruno, have you done what
I asked you?
Then go.
Another one who plays with my balls.
Jacky. What did I say:
don't touch anything. Allee, come.
In the car.
Just pay attention, those chicks.
Tits, their rules
and god knows what else. Already, eh.
And then?
And then we ... We have to wait
until we can shoot, eh.
Shoot?
We must wait, that's all.
Let's go one more time. The last.
We have been so many times already.
The eleventh time she won't be there either.
I'll buy you an ice cream. With four scoops.
And whipped cream?
Diederik?
Yes, Jacky.
Where were you now?
- I had to pee.
It does not matter. I have seen something.
Come see. Duck.
What did you see?
Come, come.
Come on.
Let me go, you're crazy.
- Bitch, behave.
Who wants a new one?
Want a new one? Here.
And you?
- Me too.
What are they doing?
- I don't know.
Are those sex magazines?
- I think so.
Turn around.
Look there. Don't look, huh.
Hey, don't look.
Watch him go.
Invasion of the enemy. Attack.
I'll beat you up.
I've got one of those little bastards.
You're a little bastard,
I got you.
And we're going to fuck you over.
Grab his arm.
And pick up a stone also.
Asshole. We will crush your balls.
Grab his leg. Give me a stone.
I'm going to knock your balls.
Asshole. Asshole.
(Literal translation Ballsack. Ballsack.)
You're crazy.
Shit.
- I didn't think he would do it.
Asshole.
Hi, Rikkie.
Well? Are you hiding?
Let's go fuck.
- Are you crazy?
Crazy? No, I'm horny.
Come to the hotel. Or do you want
Mustafa of cell 12 in your ass later on?
Does it have to be like this every time?
- We're lovers and lovers fuck.
OK, what was that at the Hippodrome?
Just a meeting.
- Jacky Vanmarsenille.
Sam Raymond. At the Hippodrome.
With De Kuyper.
Do you think we don't know
Vanmarsenille?
That has nothing to do with Daems.
Every day brings more evidence ...
that at the least De Kuyper is
the instigator of the murder.
But of those clues suspiciously
few come from you.
I'm waiting. Jacky Vanmarsenille.
- I don't know those men.
They come from fucking Limburg.
Coincidence or what?
- Yes. Coincidence.
Coincidence does not exist, Maes.
Coincidence is for dumb guys.
Stupidities, those exist.
Coincidence is used by dumb guys
if they don't know what else to say.
He just came for business. That's what
he came for. Business. That's it.
Meat, meat, meat. That's all.
That's what we are working on. So, yes,
no coincidence, if you look at it like that.
Okay, listen up.
That order has to come from your corner.
Diederik.
You're going to help us ...
otherwise it is accessory to murder.
You don't think ...
I can't believe it.
Can we trust you, Diederik?
Trust?
You'll have to, right?
- I'm not supposed to share this with an informant.
But they have seen a BMW drive away
shortly after the murder.
Such a big one, 5-series.
Can you help us, Diederik?
I'll see what I can do.
Antony, wait.
Would you ... Would you sometime ...
want to have something to drink with me?
I mean, if all this is over?
The sooner this here is resolved,
the better, Diederik.
Okay. Okay, then.
A BMW 5. I'm going to check.
I promise.
And? Are you ready?
- Almost.
Move away, so I can see something.
- Wait.
Make room.
Nice work,
no more bullet hole in sight.
David, what have you done?
- Got them back.
What tires did you give then?
- To Stieve? None.
We'll give him new ones.
New ones? Did you win the lottery or something?
Who will pay for those?
We'll give him back the old ones
and when we got rid of that car ...
we'll search for others.
On those tires are traces of
the murder location.
Do you think you're a cop?
They'll never look at Vanmarsenille.
It's better to spread everything.
- OK, we'll spread everything.
Stieve.
What now?
- Where are your tires?
David came to get them back.
- What do you mean, get back?
Something about a manufacturing defect.
He'll bring others.
David-David?
- Yes, yes ...
That guy only sells manufacturing defects.
Didn't you get spare tires?
- No, you can see that.
Stieve, buy your tires in a
tire shop.
I only have two hands.
I have put the men to work.
Say something to David
instead of always chewing on me.
Those were chic tires.
Call me back later. Yes, see you later.
How was the horse race?
- Good.
Were you able to arrange something?
- It looks like that, yes.
All the better then.
- Something is not right.
What's wrong?
- De Kuyper ...
Wait, one minute. Wait.
Hold on. My phone's ringing just now.
Yes. Yes, that's about the raffle.
You were supposed to do that, eh.
The most important now is, Irene ...
that he can develop
secondary sexual characteristics.
What is that?
- The male sex characteristics.
get a beard, have more body here,
stronger muscles, a deeper voice ...
penis development for erections.
He has to become a man.
And ejaculations.
It is possible he'll 'be able'.
But then you definitely will have to
treat him with testosterone, otherwise ...
That will be it, that they'll
shoot up my little guy with that.
But Jacky has no testicles any more.
So in his teenage years we'll have to ...
give him the necessary extra testosterone
so that he can develop sufficiently.
You must do that,
otherwise he'll never be a man.
Ask it now.
- Yes ... You ask it.
Irene, go on. We are adults.
Ask what you want to ask.
Will he be gay now?
Diederik is the only one
who can testify against that ass-hole.
No, no. Jean, listen to me.
If Diederik testifies against
Schepers' son ...
Schepers snaps his fingers
and we are done. You and me too.
Would you like to start world war three
against such a Mafia figure?
I don't want to go to jail, Jean.
Schepers knows much too much about us.
The prison, that's what awaits us.
And then Jackie will be all by himself as well.
Do you know who the real criminal is here?
You, coward.
Jacky, come.
I wasn't allowed to talk by my dad.
Get lost. If you can't do anything,
go to hell.
It is Okay, kid.
Diederik. Why are you here? Huh?
Well?
There he goes. Ask him
whether it was an accident.
Wait. It wasn't an accident.
Stay here, eh, Jacky.
Hey.
Remember me?
- What?
Come on. You know that boy?
- I don't understand you.
You know him, eh?
Come look what you've done.
On your knees. On your knees.
- Let me go.
Look what you did.
Stop it, you.
What's the matter? Huh?
I'll kill him.
- You do nothing.
Don't you see that he's disturbed.
It was an accident.
An accident?
- Yes, it was an accident.
Get out of here. Go away.
Away.
Good day, sir. Can I help you?
- Good day.
Aftershave, please.
- Certainly. Do you have a favourite brand?
No.
- Then we'll try a few.
Follow me?
So. This is something special,
a hint of iris, slightly powdery.
This is seen typically in
women's fragrances.
Otherwise we have this,
our most masculine fragrance.
The slight smell of wood.
It's a classic. Very popular.
And this is my personal favourite.
Sporty, slightly lemony,
fresh, young ... For the active man.
It's hard to choose, eh.
I know what we're going to do.
I'll give you some samples, all right.
You try them at home at ease.
It is important to feel good,
not only smell good.
If you have chosen,
you'll simply return.
I'll take this.
- A cologne.
Why not?
- For my mom.
Of course. What a spoiled mama.
Follow me to the checkout?
Voilà. 28 euros, sir.
- Here you are.
Thank you.
There.
Do you already have a loyalty card?
No.
- May I have your details?
Jacky.
Vanmarsenille.
Steenweg, Heers.
- Heers?
The other side of the linguistic border?
My mother lives near there.
I will keep them, right? Well.
So, good day, sir. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
It's off.
- What are you saying?
Why?
- Just so. Some thing's not right.
Okay, De Kuyper has a reputation ...
but you said it yourself:
We need him.
This is an opportunity.
De Kuyper has a fucked up head.
He scores his own shit.
Be inconspicuous, that's what we need now.
Wait until they've got Daems' killer
and see who remains. True or not?
We're fine.
We do not fuck this up by working
with a circus monkey from the polders.
You seriously blow this up. You act
like De Kuyper whacked him.
Call it off.
- Call it off?
Come on, eh, stay calm. Let's
just get something to drink later.
What did you spray yourself with?
Sam Raymond.
11:37.
Leaves the Vanmarsenille farm.
Antony.
- Hey, man.
I already thought, Eva is not here,
it must be something special.
Not everything has to be according to the book.
- That's what I think also.
We're not by the book either, huh.
I'll get straight to the point, Rikkie.
I'd like to see you again, but afterwards.
We need to separate business from ...
- From personal? Of course, man. Shoot.
Sit down.
You hold back things from us.
- I? Not at all.
No bullshit. I am warning you, don't.
I mean it. I am a cop,
I figure things out, that's my nature.
I get you. I feel you. I smell you.
And I sense that something is not right.
At that time Jacky's dad informed
against your dad to the court.
At that time, few resources
and little political interest.
And suddenly Dad Vanmarsenille comes
with a case, ideal for press and morality.
Vanmarsenille free from persecution,
your dad into jail.
And yet they were good friends.
And now that Jacky suddenly pops up
in your entourage.
Diederik, this feels wrong.
- Jacky has nothing to do with this.
We knew each other, 20 years ago.
When we were little, shit has happened
with Jacky and me, heavy shit.
Pedophilia or what?
- No, man.
Look, what his dad did,
I would have done as well.
Set your father up?
- My father?
My father is a coward.
Was a coward.
He made me keep quiet.
And then himself.
I gotta go.
- Me too.
An appointment with your primary suspect.
Diederik, give us that one thing.
Do it for yourself.
And for us.
The zoo had to close because of GAIA ...
and I as a veterinarian
had to kill those animals.
Instead of bringing them to the
meat plant, I sold them.
Restaurants.
That month, all Congolese from
Matonge in Brussels ate monkeys ...
from the zoo in Limburg.
And snakes and all that shit.
Dinner's ready. Pork Roast,
croquettes and vegetables.
And, Richter? What do you do for a living?
Ask and I deliver it.
My product is called networking.
Very important. Very important.
That's also more or less the reason
why we are here together.
Some networks
can sometimes break down.
Especially the pharmaceutical,
if you know what I mean.
The court found hormones in my meat
which led to Pharmakin.
What did Pharmakin do? Drop us.
I need not draw it all out,
a deal with the cops.
They said:
We make sure that he gets caught.
What can you do in such a case?
Dare to be faster than them. Harder.
- Ensure that they are afraid of you.
So they no longer rattle with my balls.
They will know by now,
we're not to be trifled with.
Anyway ...
We will now be more concerned
with the smaller supply channels.
Small is beautiful, as we say here.
We need to fill the hole.
No other way.
And you will be our new supplier.
Diederik, you're gonna help him.
And Richter provides the contacts.
What? Isn't it okay?
Yes, yes, of course.
I did not expect it, that's all.
I drive back to Limburg tonight.
Why don't you come with me?
Then you can see the Vanmarsenilles again.
If we have to develop a network anyway.
I think that's a good idea of Sam.
The Vanmarsenilles.
That's good.
Excuse me, sir.
You must wear a shirt.
I don't have a shirt.
- Patrick.
Hello, friend.
- Good day.
Do you know anyone here?
- No. And you?
I am the owner.
You're a Fleming? First time here?
I love Flemings.
Business sense, ambitious, correct.
I like it like that.
But here, everyone has to wear a shirt
We sell them here for fifteen euros.
Thirteen euros.
- Fifteen euros, friend.
Okay.
Two vodka. Twenty euros.
What?
- Twenty euros.
Two champagne.
Two.
Shit, guys. I'm drunk.
I need to take a leak.
Yes, hello? God damn, anyway.
No, I'll call you back. Yes.
Buddy, come along.
I think we have a problem.
Richter, come along.
Let it stand. Come on.
How is possible that car was found?
Nothing was to be left of it.
How can the cops find it
along the side of the road?
Marc, listen. I clearly said
that the car had to disappear.
Who was responsible?
- Two garage owners from Liege.
From Liege? From fucking Liege? Goddamn.
What's wrong with West-Flanders?
Who is this guy
that's staring at you the whole time?
It is a customer. Stop it.
- A customer?
Have you seen how he looks at you?
Not normal.
I don't know.
- Don't you like him?
He is too ... I don't know ... too bulky.
- Muscular?
Bitch, you don't have to marry him, huh.
Go for it. It will do you good.
Hello.
Everything okay? Everything okay?
- Yes.
You come here often?
- First time.
For me too.
My girlfriend dragged me along
because she is in love with the boss.
That negro?
- We here say 'black'.
Have you applied that perfume sample?
It suits you.
Come to the store if you want to buy it.
We are open tomorrow.
And what do you do for work?
- Meat.
Then you must do many barbecues.
What? Where is there a barbecue?
And when? Too bad, I can't come.
Vincent and his jokes ...
- Lucia, what are you standing here?
Can't you see ...
- Come dance.
I'll show you a great African dance.
- Vincent, no ...
Come on, beautiful.
See you later, mate.
My dear, good boy. Oh, God ...
Look, our circus monkey is also present.
Where were you today?
Hey, I'm talking to you. Where were you?
He has been drinking again.
Look. He has been drinking again.
Come, sit down somewhere. It's okay.
Go sit down somewhere. There in the corner.
Look here, you drunk.
I've brought someone.
What say you, Jacky?
Call it quits? Diederik here
guarantees us trust.
Come on.
Are you negotiating with De Kuyper
behind my back?
It's ... No ... No.
I mean ...
It's more like a surprise.
To show that everything is okay.
What did I tell you?
I told you that the deal
with De Kuyper was cancelled.
You know what it is with you?
You have nothing. You have no balls.
Want to know how it is?
Come on, Jack.
- What do you want?
You'll never know how it is.
Both. You have to do both.
Ah, mister Vanmarsenille.
How are you? Everything alright?
Nice weather today, eh.
Good day,
you are Steve's brother?
It's annoying.
We only have the old tires.
The new ones are coming, they are ordered.
Just a little more patience, they're coming.
My brother has already paid?
- Yes.
So he has paid for tires
which he already had?
You circus monkey.
No, no. Please.
- Shut up.
I'll never do it again.
Why are you cheating us?
- I will not do it again.
What have we done?
I will not do it again.
He always talks too fast.
- It's all about the tires, eh?
What about it?
- A special brand.
I'll give you a special brand.
Jacky. What is going on here?
What are you doing?
That's not normal any-more.
I told you:
Buy your tires at a tire shop.
True or not?
Don't you want to take a shower?
Bunch of Flemish assholes.
Get lost.
You're sick.
- Come on, Christian.
All that for a set of tires?
Have you seen what state they were in?
You never answer. For years I try.
And yet you treat me just like shit.
You know what I've done for you?
I was always there for you.
With your thirtieth birthday ...
I went to remove posters when they
wanted to celebrate your ox party.
Yes. And I am the fat neck ...
because I tell people never to say
klootzak (ballsack/asshole) when you're around.
Shut your mouth.
- Hit me.
I am the only one you got left.
Don't you forget it.
Stieve ...
Stieve.
Don't you forget it.
Here, Sustanon. Good stuff,
no derivative from Poland or Russia.
How much for you? 250 mg?
Intramuscular injection, eh. Okay?
Testoviron. You had asked for it?
- No, you didn't.
No? Mestanolone, very aggressive, huh.
I also have derivatives, such as DHT.
No BHV, eh.
- No, no ...
Okay, Mestanolone, ten to thirty mg
per day, thirty mg maximum.
And absolutely no alcohol. Otherwise,
your liver breaks down within a week.
We don't know each other.
I'd rather say it.
And that?
- That?
That Methyltestosterone. Do you know it?
That's what we call high caliber.
Bazooka. Very, very dangerous.
I don't give that to everyone.
I take a risk here.
Long ago, Bruno.
Should we call your sister?
Lucia here. Leave a message ...
- Want to leave a message?
You know why I'm here?
You know it? Because I'm getting something.
You know what I'm getting?
A memory.
That face you have never drawn before.
Say, Mom,
I think I've seen him.
That boy. His father came to show him,
twenty years ago or so.
I have to constantly think of him.
It's him. I'm sure.
Did he come to threaten you?
- No, Mom.
Because ... it was an accident, eh ...
- Yes, yes, Mom.
We know that,
those accidents of Bruno.
Therese, there's still gin?
- I come.
Diederik, for you too?
- Yes.
That case in Limburg, I'm pulling out.
There's too much shit in the air.
Diederik, you speak French?
- A little.
Go to Liege. There are two garage owners
who rattle my balls.
Say Richter sent you.
Not me, Richter.
Can't Richter go himself?
When they open their mouths
about Richter and his car ...
he'll grind them into the meat.
What's up.
If you dare open your mouth once ...
In French, boy.
Eva, Diederik here.
There's something going on.
I have to intimidate two guys.
A certain David and Christian.
I think that they ...
know more about that BMW of yours.
Eve, the results are in.
of that BMW.
Ah, Eva. Come inside.
The lab has found a bullet from Daems
in that BMW.
Impact number four is just
inside that BMW.
The bullet hole has been filled with polyester.
Inside the car body,
two fingerprints.
David Filippini. Convicted for
receiving stolen goods.
Nephew of Christian Filippini,
ditto plus assault and robbery.
Those guys have been seen at Vanmarsenille.
The SIE is on its way to arrest them.
- A message from my informant. Just a sec.
Eva, Diederik here.
There's something going on.
I need to intimidate two guys.
A certain David and Christian.
Oh, fuck.
You are the garage owners?
David and Christian?
Who wants to know?
- Richter.
Damn.
- I got a message from him.
If you say one word about that BMW,
he'll make sausages from your nuts.
What?
- And where?
Tripe, damn.
Shit, shit, shit.
Lucia, stupid goat.
Hello.
- What are you doing here?
A friend.
She'll have to wait.
Why did you come here?
Oh, but what does she want? You know her.
Daphne. She was with me in the club.
Did you stay long?
- No.
Again.
I should call her back. It looks
urgent, must be something with the store.
Yes, Daphne. What is it?
- That guy in the disco ...
Who? Vincent? That womaniser?
Yes. Did he sleep with you that night?
- I don't dive into bed with just anyone.
Wait. He's in a coma.
He was beaten up like an animal.
He will remain a plant.
If he ever wakes up.
Hello? Lucia? Hello?
Everything okay?
Yes, yes. But I got to go.
An urgent case. I have to go there.
I will come for that perfume.
- Yes. Okay.
See you then.
Hello, Peter.
Sit down. Come on.
Nobody can see you.
Antony stays with you.
Shit, I am fed up with you.
I'm sick of all you Flemings.
Bunch of assholes.
I didn't do anything.
But I did not kill him, huh.
It's David.
He introduced me to that Fleming.
I want you to steal a car for me.
Christian is my cousin, a cool guy,
but he has those friends who ...
Do not worry, Flemish friend.
Letting cars disappear is our business.
He would never get rid of that car.
He wanted to sell the parts.
The next day Christian appears
with a Bayerische Motoren Werke ...
a BMW 5.
- It's over.
Stolen ...
- In Liege.
No, David has stolen that BMW
in Namur.
Richter came back with a bastard
from 't Vlaams Gezang.
A butcher, with a Bruges scarf.
I did not say anything,
but I was wondering:
David, how do you know those Flemish
bastards?
My Flemish friends.
What are you doing with those people,
I wondered.
Suddenly, five hours later that
Flemish legionnaire was back there.
He dumps the car in the garage
and what do I see? The bullet hole.
I think they have ...
- Killed someone.
The hormone hunter.
Which tires?
- Christian wanted to sell them.
Ah, those tires.
I knew that one of the Vanmarsenille
brothers drove a BMW ...
So I thought, why not him?
I know him reasonably well.
He passes by when he goes to the whores.
I have changed the tires and put the old
tires on Richters BMW.
The next day I hear the news
on the radio.
So I drive straight to the Vanmarsenilles
to retrieve the tires.
That's where it went wrong.
Especially ... Especially for Christian.
My mobile.
You want to know where those tires are?
Richter and those other Flemish
assholes work for Jacky Vanmarsenille.
That guy is sick,
got a head like a bull.
The tires? Those of the murder?
Well, they are with him.
This is Richter's address.
De Kuyper and Leon are with that woman.
Diederik.
- Eva.
Those Vanmarsenilles? They have nothing,
and I mean nothing, to do with it?
I've never seen Sam with De Kuyper,
let alone Jacky. That were just ...
Stop whining, Diederik.
I don't want to demonize him just
because he happens ...
Coincidence? You know how I feel about coincidence.
It is what it is. Okay?
You go home and mention nothing to
De Kuyper about your arrest.
Message conveyed.
Basta.
All I want ...
is that you go over this list again.
Who do you remember?
What?
- Nothing.
Nothing?
- Lucia.
Someone that I was in school with,
was called that name.
Lucia?
Send him away.
- Diederik. Come on.
Go home, Diederik.
What? There's no one to see us.
When it's done.
- When it's done ...
Yes, when it's done, Diederik.
Lucia Schepers?
According to surveillance it's nothing.
- No risks. We tap this girl.
Fuck you, Antony. Fuck you.
What's for dinner?
- Roast chicken with apricots.
With cocktail sauce?
- Yes.
Shouldn't Dad eat?
- Just let him sit down a little longer.
Is that intentional?
Diederik just arrived at the Bullhead.
What? Diederik? At Vanmarsenille?
Anyone else check the transponder?
- Just now he was riding to the coast.
Diederik, goddamn, pick up.
Jean.
Jean?
Jacky, there's someone with Dad. Do you know him?
Does he come for you?
Stay here.
What are you doing here?
Jack.
What do you want?
Jack, listen.
Make sure your family are gone from here.
Why?
Nine out of ten that the POSA will be here
within a few hours,.
I don't understand.
- The cops.
Special whatever squadron.
- What are you saying?
I'm an informant with the cops.
I said you had nothing to do with it.
What?
- Jacky, stop it.
- They're going to pick up everyone.
De Kuyper, Sam, you.
According to the cops you have something to do
with the murder of Daems.
I know you have
nothing to do with it.
Pure coincidence. But if you want your family ...
Okay, Mom. Go to Stieve and take pa with you.
Tell Stieve he should not come.
What about the animals?
- Get away.
Yes, but ...
You stay here.
I gotta go.
- You stay here.
De Kuyper will know that I talked.
- No way.
Sure they'll come tonight?
- Not one hundred percent.
I hope tonight.
I'll be gone from all this misery.
Yes, yes ...
You must help me.
Anything else?
All my life.
Known nothing else than beasts.
I've always felt like those bulls.
I never knew what it was
to protect someone.
Calves, a flock,
like a wife, children.
Really have to protect.
As it should, because it is your nature.
I don't have what should have been my nature.
You're not gay?
I? Are you crazy?
Where is your car?
Diederik Vanmarsenille leaves.
He is alone.
When will the intervention team be here?
What's in there?
Vitamins.
Yes?
Why, Diederik away again?
Yes? Liege?
Fuck.
It is here that you have to be?
- Yes.
And who lives here?
Lucia or what?
- How do you know?
I did not expect anything else
from such a guy.
Come on, go.
Then go. Go get that girl.
Yes?
- It's Jacky.
Jacky? You surprise me.
It's a bad time, I have visitors.
Can you come back tomorrow?
Okay? Until tomorrow. Bye, bye.
- Lucia.
Hello, police?
There's a guy at my door
and I think he wants to get inside.
Yes, I'm afraid.
His name is Jacky.
Jacky Vanmarsenille.
Chef?
There was a distress call received
for the local police in Liege.
From Lucia Schepers.
Jacky?
Jacky, I can't let you in.
I am not alone.
- Five minutes, Lucia.
Why don't you just go home?
We see each other tomorrow, okay?
Then you can tell me everything. Good?
Who is with you?
Don't do that now, Lucia.
Don't do that.
Okay, don't trash my door.
I'll open the door. Okay?
Yes.
What is it, Lucia?
You are alone?
Are you afraid of me?
- Afraid? But no.
You come here at nine o'clock in the
evening, you almost trash my door.
No, of course I'm not afraid.
Why did you come to my house?
Because I am a woman.
Because I'm stupid.
Okay. You know what we do?
I go get something to drink.
We calm down.
Then you go home and tomorrow
We see each other again. Okay?
Stay where you are and don't break anything.
Yes, I called the police.
I realise it,
I know what you did.
You are ...
You're all animals.
So. Now you know.
He attacked me.
I did not do anything.
I'm not an animal.
I understand nothing of what you say.
If you leave now,
you can still get away.
The bathroom.
There.
We're too late.
Police.
Mister Vanmarsenille, come out.
Come out.
Hands up. Are you alone?
Forward. Hurry. Come on, come on.