(THUMPING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
WESTON: I'm going to
talk to Parker about my promotion today.
In the worst-case scenario
you're two weeks ahead of me,
you get a gorgeous little
apartment in the Marais.
What if I don't want
to live in the Marais?
(SHOWER RUNNING)
WESTON: We could live
somewhere else, then.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
We could go to Detroit.
Detroit?
Yeah, you could
meet my mom and dad.
You can meet my sister.
She owns a bakery,
and she will
make you fat.
(LAUGHS)
I have six hours before I have
to go back to the hospital.
You want to go
back into bed with me?
WESTON: I do.
(BEEPS)
But I got back-to-back
meetings all morning.
Too bad for you.
WESTON: Yeah, I know.
But I got to get in.
There's probably
already 25 people
lined up outside
the door, waiting.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I love when
you speak French.
(KEYS BEEPING)
(DIALING)
(RINGING TONE)
OPERATOR: Satcom check.
Echo Nine Three
Victor Echo Two.
LANDLORD: Ops Center.
WESTON: This is safe house 7-R.
We're open for business.
Confirmed.
Any reservations?
Nothing in
the registry.
Walk-ins?
Not expected.
Reconfirm in three hours.
Understood.
(DIALING)
(RINGING TONE)
BARLOW: Matt?
Your cell, really?
(CHUCKLING) Relax, I've got
an encryption packet.
You know me,
I never relax.
Watch the cholesterol,
old man.
You sound like Miriam.
So, what's new
in Cape Town?
WESTON ON PHONE:
Nothing, nothing.
I updated my Surveillance Target Analysis.
It's complete now.
Yeah, that's an exit report.
It's not due until you leave.
Exactly. Exactly.
And when is that?
How long has it been?
Twelve months.
Well, talk to me
in another four.
David, I'm dying here.
What's happening
with the post in Paris?
One slot,
37 applicants.
Every one of them with more
field experience than you.
How am I supposed to
get more experience?
I'm staring at
four walls all day.
I got passed up on Rome,
then Berlin.
You said yourself,
my evaluation was excellent.
Just put it in
front of Whitford.
I know he'll see that I'm
ready to go, I'm all in.
Matt, I know
this has been hard,
but it's the way
the system works.
Look, I'll talk to Whitford about Paris,
but I can’t promise anything.
(SIGHS)
Look, I've got to go.
Don't worry,
I'm looking after you, okay?
Yeah, I know,
I know, I know.
(DISCONNECTS CALL)
(CAR DOOROPENS)
FROST ON PHONE:
This is not a negotiation.
It's 10 million.
You'll get the file,
and if the money
is not in the account
by 3:00 p.m.,
I'll take it
to another buyer.
MAN ON PHONE: How do we know that
you won't do that anyway?
You don't.
(DISCONNECTS CALL)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Here you are, sir.
FROST:
Alec, how are you?
Petrus, 1972.
You look good.
- I do, don't I?
- (BOTH CHUCKLING)
So, how are things
at Ml6?
The usual. Same bureaucratic
bullshit and appalling remuneration.
Life of a government man.
Mmm-hmm.
So...
WADE: The original file.
Dates,
transactions, names.
A bargain
at triple the price.
Take a look.
Hmm.
(SIGHS)
I've been waiting
a long time for this.
WADE: Tobin...
What's in that box
is going to make
the world
a smaller place for you,
for both of us.
I got your account.
You get your cut
24 hours after transaction.
Some of our old bosses
aren't going to be happy
these files are out
in the open.
Do I make you nervous?
- Always.
- Good.
(BEEPS)
(METALLIC CLINK)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You want her?
(GUN FIRES)
(GRUNTS)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
WADE:
Please, listen to me.
I had nothing to do
with this.
FROST: Stop.
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
Let's go.
(ENGINE STARTS)
WADE: Tobin, you have
to believe me.
I knew nothing
about any of that.
FROST: Did you know if
anybody was following you?
No, I don't think
anybody was following me.
I swear on my life,
Tobin, I had absolutely...
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- (GRUNTS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CARALARM BLARING)
(HORN HONKING)
(HORN BLARING)
Slow down.
(CROWD CHANTING)
(HORN HONKING)
We're going by foot.
Head towards the square.
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
(GUN FIRING)
(PEOPLE PANICKING)
MAN: Move! Move! Move!
(SIRENS WAILING)
We're heading west.
Holland Street.
Move, move.
Excuse me, sir.
Thank you.
My name is Tobin Frost.
(PHONE RINGING)
Linklater.
When?
Lock down the consulate.
Get me a team in the Situation
Room in five minutes.
I want everything we got
on Tobin Frost.
ASSISTANT: Yes, ma'am.
- Is it him?
- Yep.
Whitford know?
LINKLATER:
I'm on my way there now.
GUARD: Sir, place your finger in
there until I tell you to stop.
(BEEPS)
Thank you.
(KEYS CLATTERING)
So how long has he been
playing in your backyard?
We're working to get you
that answer right now.
Meaning you don't know.
No, meaning,
we're looking into it.
The guy goes rogue,
he spends nine years
selling out the Agency
to all takers.
To Russia, China, Iran,
you name it.
The guy is just not
going to prance
into an American consulate
without good reason.
(BEEPS)
WHITFORD:
All right, listen up.
Everybody off the phone.
Tobin Frost has
just waltzed his way
into a U.S. Consulate
in Cape Town, South Africa.
Now this man,
without question,
is one of the most notorious
traders that we've got.
Errington, call up
his background profile.
ERRINGTON: Tobin Frost was
recruited into the Agency in 1984.
He tested off the charts in aptitude
for psychological field work.
His first assignment was in
Lebanon, in January, 1985.
Three months later,
he captured and flipped
a high-ranking
Hezbollah leader.
Over the next
several years,
Frost successfully questioned and recruited
many high-value individuals.
He became known as an expert
manipulator of human assets,
and he literally rewrote
Agency interrogation protocols.
LINKLATER: Frost served
in many active theaters,
including Libya
from 1995 to 1998,
Jordan, 1998 to 2000.
During his tenure
in Jordan,
Frost was suspected of leaking
information to Mossad,
but nothing
was confirmed.
Ten years ago, Frost went off
the reservation completely.
He currently
has no allegiances
and is wanted for espionage
on four continents.
His last known sighting
is Hamburg, Germany, in 2011.
You know, Harlan, we should
interrogate Frost now.
Sweat him for
everything he's got.
Once he's stateside,
we have fewer options.
I have an interrogator in Yemen,
can be there in eight hours.
I already have a team in Jo'burg
that can be there in two.
We'll take Frost to the safe
house, interrogate him there.
My people are fully
capable of handling this.
This is Tobin Frost.
We'll go with Jo'burg.
Okay.
(BALL BOUNCING)
You must turn around.
Help. Help.
(PHONE RINGING)
Accident.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
Housekeeping.
LANDLORD ON PHONE: We have
a last-minute reservation.
ETA for check-in?
Sometime tonight.
Freeark Insurance.
Got it.
(DIALING)
(RINGING TONE)
ANAON PHONE: Hello.
- Hey.
Hey, where are you?
WESTON: Parker just handed me
his oversight papers to finish
and his daughter Chloe's got the
measles, can you believe that?
How long are you
going to be out for?
I don't know.
Okay. Well, look,
I'm gonna dive into this,
and then hopefully I can
meet up with you later, okay?
Yeah, that sounds good.
Hey, hey...
I love you.
I love you, too.
- Bye.
RICHARDS: Extraction team
is in the air, sir.
They should be on the
ground within the hour.
I want that team in and out
of the city in less than 12 hours.
We're not even
supposed to have
a presence in Cape Town.
RICHARDS: Yes, sir.
WHITFORD: Any communications about Frost's
whereabouts are strictly need-to-know.
Sir, the extraction team is
en route to the consulate now.
Who's reaching out
to 7-R?
Richards, ma'am.
I want
the housekeeper briefed.
High-priority target is coming
in. I want the house quiet.
Under no circumstances
should there be
any communication
until the team has left.
Yes, ma'am.
(BEEPING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(INTERCOM CHIMING)
Yeah?
Do you have a room?
- Account?
- Daniel Kiefer.
Freeark Insurance.
K-I-E-F-E-R.
Kiefer. Freeark Insurance.
LANDLORD ON PHONE:
You are ago.
You're good to go.
- Hi, I'm Weston.
- Guest room?
It's right around the
corner. Two rights and a left.
All the way back.
That's Tobin Frost.
KIEFER: Stay with him.
Let's go download our gear.
POPE: Yes, sir.
Linen closet?
Down the hall. Just
right at the end, there.
Kill all the surveillance
cameras in this room.
(OVERSPEAKERS)
My name is Daniel Kiefer.
We were at
The Farm together.
Technically,
you were a year ahead.
I'm here to make you
aware of your rights.
You're being held under
a National Security Directive,
which means you have none,
but you know that.
Six-hundreds.
The towels,
you need six-hundreds.
Those are 350,
375-gram weight.
You're gonna
need six-hundreds.
KIEFER: I want to know
the reasons for you being in Cape Town.
I want you to name your
resources, contacts, assets,
everybody you've
done business with,
traded intel with,
sold secrets to,
in the nine years since
you betrayed your country.
Absolutely.
Anything you want, Daniel.
KIEFER: Khalid Sheikh Mohammed
lasted 20 seconds.
They had six-hundreds.
Is this legal?
KIEFER: Bring him down.
(MUFFLED YELLING)
(SIGHS)
Bring him up.
(GASPING)
How long was that?
(FROST COUGHS)
All right,
take him down.
(FROST GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
Bring him up!
(GASPING)
(SPITS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Get me a knife.
(POWERSHUTS DOWN)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Miller?
Get in there
with Frost.
Sir, all the security cameras
are down.
- Reboot. I want to see what's out there.
POPE: Copy that.
KIEFER: Let's go, boys!
MILLER: Go! Go! Go!
Let's go, move!
Velez, take this corner.
Ericksson,
get the back elevator.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Pope, what do you got?
POPE: Sir, I see approximately 12
heavily armed men in perimeter two.
KIEFER: Okay, gents!
Work fore to aft.
Two-by-twos.
Perimeter two.
KIEFER: Greer?
GREER: Sir!
KIEFER: Ericksson?
ERICKSSON: Yes, sir.
KIEFER: Velez?
Velez?
I'm good!
Let's go, fellas.
(EXPLOSION)
GREER: Incoming!
KIEFER: Grenade!
(GREERGRUNTING)
(GUN FIRING)
(GROANING)
Greer!
KIEFER: Step-slide!
Start walking back!
Velez!
Three-round bursts!
(FIRING CONTINUES)
Velez, where's Greer?
He's over there, sir.
Go, son.
This ain't a test.
This is the real thing.
What are you
gonna do?
You don't want
to try me.
KIEFER: Magazine!
VELEZ: Let's go.
- (GUN FIRING)
- (SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Velez, stay there!
Listen to me,
stay there!
Son of a bitch!
Miller!
Hey! Get in here!
Hey, hey. Take these.
Go watch him.
(PANTING)
Hey, they're here for me,
but they want me alive.
You, they'll kill.
(SNIFFLES)
You got one
in the chamber?
(BULLET CLINKING)
It's okay.
I remember my first
posting. Rio de Janeiro.
A house like this.
Beautiful women.
Not one single visitor, but
I remember rule number one.
You are responsible
for your houseguest.
I'm your houseguest.
The clock is ticking.
They gave you the keys.
Do your duty, son.
Shut up. Let me think.
You want to be the guy
that lost Tobin Frost?
Tick-tock,
tick-tock, tick-tock.
(KEYS BEEPING)
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Where's Frost?
(GUN FIRING)
(PANTING)
We're leaving.
Where is he?
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Stay here, stay here!
Wait! Don't move!
Hey, hey, hey!
(HORN BLARING)
(SPEAKING AFRIKAANS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
WESTON: Go!
Get in the trunk.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah, get in.
- The trunk?
- Get in the trunk now!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SHOUTS IN FRUSTRATION)
No!
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(RINGING TONE)
OPERATOR: Ops Center.
Echo Three
Victor Echo Nine.
Go ahead.
This is Weston. 7-R's
been hit. Everyone's dead.
I need you to repeat that, please.
Say again.
Kiefer, his team,
everyone, they're all dead.
Stand by.
Transferring.
- (PHONE RINGING)
- It's the house.
- Linklater.
- (ON PHONE)This is Weston.
The safe house
has been breached.
What's your location?
WESTON: I'm eastbound
on Albert Road.
I’m just
passing Woodstock.
(GRUNTING)
I want eyes on this.
Real-time sat feed.
LINKLATER: And what's
the location of the guest?
WESTON: We escaped.
LINKLATER: Clarify.
Do you have the guest?
Yes, we escaped!
Look, I can make it
to the consulate.
There's no chance
for SDR,
I think I might have
picked up a tail.
We can't have a gun battle
in front of the consulate.
Diplomatic catastrophe.
Where's that
satellite feed?
Denied by National Recon.
War theater use only.
Buy us some time.
Do not go
to the consulate.
Follow protocol
Alpha Zero.
Secure the guest
and stay off the grid.
Reconnect at 1800 hours.
I repeat, stay off the grid.
Copy, copy, copy.
(HORN BLARING)
- (THUD)
- (BRAKES SCREECHING)
(GUN FIRING)
(HORN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
All right, Cape Town police
have responded to the house.
- Confirmed.
LINKLATER: I want the site secured.
RICHARDS:
I'm hearing nine dead.
FEMALE ANALYST:
Initiating damage control.
MALE ANALYST: I'm on it.
Reaching out to NIA now.
The locals are going to
have that house locked off.
Check all the traffic cameras,
police reports...
Find out why Frost wanted
to go in that consulate to begin with
and who in the hell else
might be after him.
We need to get Weston and
Frost out of South Africa.
Now, do we have any tactical
teams? Anything in play?
Yeah, I have assets in
Egypt, but they're in deep.
If I pull them out, that would
compromise two years' worth of work.
I can scramble a team
from Europe or Asia,
but it's going to
take at least 18 hours.
At this point,
Weston is all we got.
I need to find out who this
Matt Weston is, right now.
FEMALE ANALYST:
Matthew James Weston.
Born 02-24-82 to
Terry and Madeline Weston
in Port Washington,
New York.
An assault arrest,
one month after
both parents and
a younger sister
were killed in
a traffic accident
in which his
father's blood-alcohol
was twice
the legal limit.
Yale, degree in Economics,
recruited out of Yale law.
High marks in analytics
and linguistics at The Farm.
Excellent in
tradecraft skills.
His girlfriend, Ana Moreau,
is a French national.
He reported them
as having "close and continuing contact."
She's a second year resident
in the oncology department at Groote Schuur.
WESTON: Get in that car.
FEMALE ANALYST: She accepted a
position with Hôtel-Dieu Hospital
in Paris,
starts in two weeks.
No known political
affiliations. She's clean.
I want you to post a car
outside their apartment.
Use back channels.
And get NSA to cross-check their telephone
records and their e-mails, please.
Yes, ma'am.
FROST: You know, it would be
easier if I knew where we were going.
You just drive, all right?
Just drive, middle lane.
All right.
Hey, what are you doing?
Middle lane.
Just drive around.
FROST: All right.
I'm driving.
(SNIFFLES)
Nice to know who you're
talking to. What's your name?
You crushed my windpipe.
Well, you locked me
in the trunk.
Come on, you're not NOC. You're
here under your real name.
What is it?
Weston, Matt.
All right.
How long you been
a safe house keeper?
Twelve months.
Happy birthday.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Cape Town,
that's low-level detail.
You should have been
out of here by now.
Maybe I requested
the assignment.
(FROST CHUCKLES)
Or maybe Langley doesn't
trust you with anything else.
So, what's your plan?
Oh, let me guess.
Follow protocol.
Protocol states that
if your house is crashed,
you do an SDR to make sure
no one's following you.
Activate your GPS in your
Go-Bag, select another safe house.
You think I'm going to
let you just take me in?
I think you need
to shut up.
(FROST CHUCKLES)
I think you need to consider how your
house was attacked in the first place.
Have you done that, Matt?
They followed Kiefer. They
followed him from the consulate,
and that's how they
found the safe house.
Come on, you don't really
believe that, do you?
How did they know I was near
the consulate in the first place?
Hmm.
But I like this, you know.
You and me, figuring shit out.
Like the Hardy Boys.
(LAUGHS)
That house was
a secure location.
Whoever crashed it
didn't stop by a gas station and ask for
directions to the nearest safe house.
They were invited.
Someone told them, Matthew.
Think about it.
Someone you know.
So you better ask yourself,
can you trust your landlord?
Go ahead, you're not
going to get in my head.
I already am
in your head.
They're going to
isolate you, Matt.
They're going to be real
nice to you at first.
They're going to put their arm
around you and tell you things like,
"You did a decent job, son.
We'll take it from here."
That's when you know
you're screwed.
Forget about me. They're
going to focus on you.
They're going to try and make
a connection between you and I.
So that if this
all goes wrong,
they'll have something
to fall back on
in their little
Senate hearings.
I'm not your
only enemy tonight.
WHITFORD:
So, it's someone in-house.
It's the only way this
thing could've happened.
We were
completely buttoned up.
I want a list of everyone
who knew about this.
Backgrounds, affiliations,
particularly any
connections with Frost.
Every movement right
up until this operation.
Your extraction team, how
long had they been together?
My team had been
together six months. Why?
Well, I’m just trying to
get my head around this.
That will do, thank you.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(DOORCLOSES)
(DIALING)
(RINGING TONE)
ANAON PHONE: Hello.
- Hey.
Baby, where are you?
I'm all right.
I'm okay.
I'm sorry I didn’t call you back,
I saw your missed calls.
You must be worried sick.
Is everything okay?
WESTON: I'm good.
I'm good. Listen.
This sounds so crazy.
We had some threats against
the clinic last night,
so Parker and I,
we stayed all night
trying to get to
the bottom of it.
And I'm sorry that I didn’t call you back.
I should have, right away.
I was so worried.
I know.
Can you do me a favor? Can you go
over to the window for a second?
Why?
Can you just take a quick look
out the window?
I want you to see if
there's anyone out there.
Are there any cars
that don't belong?
Anyone hanging
around out front?
There's a police car.
What's going on?
I'm sorry about this.
I know this is a lot,
but we felt like
it would be best
if we didn't go home
as a precaution,
and I agree with him.
I know there’s nothing to worry
about, but I agree with him.
I think you should just go to Dena's
for a little while,
just for a few hours,
and I'll call you in a little bit.
And we'll
get together, okay?
Okay, I'll go.
Okay. I love you.
I'll talk to you soon, all right?
Don’t worry. Okay, bye.
(WATER RUNNING)
She know what you do
for a living?
The girl on the phone.
It was a girl, wasn't it?
Maybe it was a guy,
I don't know.
I don’t judge.
You can't expect to have a real
relationship in our line of work, Matthew.
Don't worry. She's
not going to leave you.
See, what happens is, you
try to protect her with lies,
and then it starts
to add up.
At the safe house you said that
they'd kill me to get to you.
After a while,
even the truth...
- Why?
- ...starts to sound like a lie.
You have something. You got
something that they want. What is it?
Is she a local?
Don't worry about her.
What is it?
Oh, it is a girl.
You'll keep covering your
tracks, she'll keep believing.
Because she wants to,
because she needs to.
That's why we exist, you
and me, that's our job.
To take advantage of that.
People's desire
to believe.
To trust.
She's not going to
leave you, Matthew.
You're going
to leave her.
I'm not you.
MALE ANALYST: Correct,
sir. We verified it.
(PHONE RINGING)
That is your boy.
You take it.
MALE ANALYST:
Everybody, stand by.
Matty, it's me.
How are you holding up?
I'm all right.
Matt, we can't get another
team in for at least 12 hours.
Sorry.
We've cleared a new safe
house for you outside the city.
There's a Go-Bag located
at locker number 256, Green
Point Stadium Metrorail station.
The combination
is 2-5-1-22.
2-5-1-22.
Now, the bag's
got a GPS in it.
It'll direct you
to the safe house.
But you got to be careful,
it's an active location.
So, approach
with caution.
Matt?
Do you know how
they found Frost?
Do you know who
led them to us?
We're working on that.
We're counting
on you, Matt.
Get Frost to that safe house and
you can write your own ticket.
I will.
WESTON: Left at the light.
To the stadium?
Yeah.
(HORNS BLOWING)
(SPECTATORS CHEERING)
WESTON: Hey, scarf.
How much for a scarf?
VENDOR: Only fifty rand.
WESTON: Thanks.
Cuff your hands
together.
- Together?
- Yeah.
Out.
FROST: Are you sure you don't
want to just walk away from this?
Can't do that.
Yes, you can.
You should.
Move. Go.
Across the street.
(ALL CHEERING)
Going to the game.
I like games.
Metrorail,
straight ahead.
Straight ahead.
Right over there.
(BEEPING)
Let's go.
(SPECTATORS CHEERING)
Help! Help! He's trying to kidnap me!
WESTON: Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
He's trying to
kidnap me! Help!
He's got a gun!
(SPEAKING AFRIKAANS)
He's got a gun! He's
got a gun right there!
I'm undercover.
I'm undercover!
Calm down, sir.
Everybody, calm down!
(FROST CONTINUES YELLING)
(PEOPLE PANICKING)
Get down! Get down!
All right! Okay!
(SPEAKING AFRIKAANS)
OFFICER:
Get him up. Get up.
FROST: Ow, ow, ow!
I'm an American citizen. I don't
know what he wanted from me.
OFFICER: Just calm down.
(YELLING IN AFRIKAANS)
(SPEAKING AFRIKAANS)
Hey, hey, hey. I'm a police
officer. I'm from America.
I arrested this man.
His name is Tobin Frost.
Where did you take him?
He's in the infirmary.
There, there!
Is that it?
Top left, second screen from the
top! Look, look, the infirmary.
Right. Go back.
Third-tier infirmary,
now! Move!
Third-tier infirmary.
Go, now!
Do you see?
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)