Help! Help!
Hey. How are you?
Happy holidays.
You're good.
Thank you, sir.
Is that you, angel?
Yeah, it's me.
What brought you back this way?
I just... I couldn't
stay away from you.
Oh, stop. I'm gonna
see them upstairs.
Ray Kasten. She's expecting me.
Go right ahead.
Look who's back.
Could you ask Jessica Cobb
to come in, please? Mm-hmm.
Like a rash.
Wow. Thirteen years.
Two promotions.
Still an asshole.
Three promotions.
Thanks for keeping track.
What can I say? I'm a fan.
You mind?
Good luck.
- Am I late?
- Just a bit.
It's good to see you, ray.
Well, it's...
I see your filing system
hasn't changed much.
The wheels of justice turn
slowly, but they do turn.
And look at you.
Up on the fifth floor.
We will do whatever
is necessary to protect America.
But make no mistake. The resolve
of our great nation is being...
Fax went down again.
Hello, al-fawid.
Now be a good little terrorist
and just hand over some yellow-cake
uranium in broad daylight,
and we're all set.
Amen.
Erectile dysfunction hotline.
How can I direct your call?
Not at all. Have a good day.
Attaboy, bumpy. Give 'em hell.
You really are a moron, bumpy.
You know that?
Siefert, you keep
throwing that term around,
but I'm not sure you know
what it actually means.
It's a medical term. Did you know that?
Is that right?
It means someone with an
IQ between 50 and 69.
An imbecile is someone
with an IQ between 49 and 20.
And an idiot, which I think is the word you're
looking for, is someone who scores below 19.
Hmm. What do you call
someone who's dumber than that?
Lieutenant. Lieutenant.
Where you going?
I'm wanted in photo.
Chin up. Shoulders back.
Pakistani Taliban
are increasingly upping
their fight to cross the border.
This is one of their recent propaganda
videos shot in Afghanistan.
In a barbaric act, they murder a
man they claim is an Afghan spy
working for NATO.
Hi.
Hello.
Um, I'm, uh, ray.
Ray Kasten.
Claire. Claire Sloan.
Okay. It's nice to meet you.
Yes. Nice to meet you.
I guess we're the, uh,
new kids at school, huh?
Yep. Today is picture day.
Yeah.
That must be why I suddenly feel
like my mom picked out my outfit.
Oh.
- Have a great day.
- Thanks.
- You're bureau?
- Yeah. Field office, lower Manhattan.
I was transferred here to sit on
a mosque with the Da's office.
You?
I just got to the Da's
office, from Philly.
I'm second chair
of the homicide unit.
Well, that's a pretty stiff rank to
come in with. You must be a star.
No. Hardly.
Is this a temporary
assignment for you?
I don't know.
I guess that kinda depends
on the guys in the mosque.
Counselor?
Oh. Yes. Thank you.
Well, it was nice to meet you.
Yes.
Uh, Claire, yeah?
Yes. I'm ray. I
said that, right?
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Kasten. Ray Kasten.
Uh, ray Kasten, yeah.
FBI.
- Have a seat.
- Thanks.
Give me one second. I just
want to adjust this light.
Yes. A picture's forever, right?
Ray Kasten.
So, how are you liking
Los Angeles?
I'm still just
finding my way around.
Okay, now your right collar, please?
Great.
Smile.
District attorney. My goodness.
It's lawyering.
Same as before, only more of it.
You wanna sit down?
And from here, where? Mayor?
No.
No more campaigns for a while.
I'm here, I'm happy.
Oh, you thinking of
governor already? Wow!
Well, I wanted to be head of security for the
Mets, but the position was already filled.
And, um, how's Ellis?
Fine. Yeah. The same... busy.
Any kids? Kids? No.
No, never the right time.
What about you?
Oh, no. Same.
Mind if I close the door?
- Ray?
- Jess.
Jesus! How are you?
How are you?
I'm good. I'm good. You?
Oh, I'm... I'm fine. I'm f...
I was just congratulating cl...
Well, you made
chief investigator, right?
So I'm...
I'm looking at royalty here.
You still living in Moorpark?
Yes.
It's quiet out there.
I like the quiet.
You still bureau?
No. No, I went private sector.
Badge kinda
lost its charm for me.
I'll let you two...
No, no, no. Stay.
Please.
This is about you.
I found him, Jess.
I found Marzin.
All right. Here you go.
Thank you.
Psst.
You could just ask
her out, you know.
Who said I wanted
to ask her out?
Christ.
An unrequited office romance.
The cliché of it doesn't bother you?
Jess.
Uh, have a little respect.
She's engaged.
You know? This is...
It's inappropriate.
The beauty from Harvard law and the blue-collar
fed from the wrong side of Brooklyn.
So sad. Don't be a dick, Jess.
Thank you, ray.
A sexist would've
called me something else.
Why? You're such a dick.
- Up. Let's go.
- Where's the fire?
LAPD just found an unidentified
female body in a garage dumpster.
So, what's that
got to do with us?
Garage is next door
to our mosque, al-Ankara.
This is not good... mosque
turning into a crime scene.
Now al-fawid's gonna shut
everything down and go to ground.
Think positive, ray.
Maybe al-fawid did the murder.
We could arrest him without him
having to blow something up first.
I'll talk to my snitch. He knows
everything going on in that mosque.
Siefert, when are you gonna cough
that guy's name up already?
My curiosity is killing me.
Sorry, Cobb.
Golden rule of counterterrorism.
Remember?
Siefert, bumpy;
Protect the snitch.
Four months after
the events of 9/11,
la's high rises and hospitals
remain unprepared
to respond
to a terrorist attack,
according to a study released
today by the rand corporation.
One of the biggest concerns...
communication between first responders...
Intelligence officials
are increasingly concerned
about the level of chatter
they're picking up.
Senior administration members telling us
this could mean terror cells in the us
are about to become operational.
Terrorists may be planning another
attack on a major us city.
The department of homeland security raised
the terror threat level to red today
in response to what's
being called, quote,
"credible intelligence of
an impending domestic attack."
Whoa! Dai's at a crime scene.
Things a little slow today, guys?
No subpoenas to serve?
You really are an idiot, Fierro.
Medically.
Impressive, huh? He was homicide
before he joined the bureau.
Be the ball, ray.
No purse, no ID.
Body appears to have been
bleached inside and out.
Take notes, fellas.
This is evidence collection.
Custodian reports seeing a
young man, possibly Arab,
leaving the scene about 10:30,
carrying his belongings.
Looked to be homeless. Was
he running or walking?
Didn't say. You mean,
you didn't ask.
I didn't do the interview.
Just 'cause they're Muslims
doesn't mean they're terrorists.
Wouldn't wanna stereotype
anybody, would we?
No, of course not.
G-give her some room.
They aren't even
spelling things right in here.
He's got a theory.
What is it?
It's Carolyn.
What?
I-it's Carolyn.
It's your daughter.
No!
No! Jess, Jess, Jess!
No! My girl!
No! No!
Please! No!
Help me! Help me!
Oh, my god!
Oh, sweet girl.
It's my baby!
Where... is he?
He's on parole.
Just did 10 years.
Tracy. Armed robbery.
Under the name...
Clay Beckwith.
How did you find him?
Inmate photos hacked online.
696,000 Caucasian males
in the us prison system.
You can cycle through the
entire population in a year
if you look at 1,906
faces every night.
- So that's what I did.
- For a year?
For 13 years.
Started the day I left here.
The, uh... the nose is
different, and the eyes.
Yeah. Must've had surgery.
Makes sense, given what he did.
And contact lenses.
But the ages sync up.
Beckwith's 33,
Marzin 20 when we lost him.
What do you want?
Reopen it.
I'm without portfolio now. I can't
exactly contact the guy's po.
Jess?
Surveillance video shows a gray Van
entering this garage at 10:27,
leaving 20 minutes later.
Same Van that was reported
stolen three days ago.
She have any errands in the
neighborhood or appointments?
I don't know. Where are we?
We're at the mosque.
Oh.
Would she take her car?
She didn't tell me what
she was... doing this morning
because she always told me
about her morning
at lunchtime.
Jess?
I thought if I ever found him, it
would just be me and him in an alley.
This is...
I don't think I have the stomach
to watch him walk away again.
This is Claire's shop now.
- Nobody torches it this time.
- Right. Easy.
Except the police would have to run point, and
we never did have an actual case against him.
- Well, maybe he confesses.
- Would you?
Maybe we could go about this
a little less officially.
I could call
the parole officer...
No, no, no. If we did this,
you couldn't be involved.
You know that.
- They're here.
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Should I tell them you'll be late?
- Be along in a minute, yeah.
- Good to see you, ray.
- Hey, Jess.
You can leave it open.
So, this is how
you waltz back in here?
I know.
Look at him.
Same guy.
We've had about 20 Marzin
sightings since you left.
All of them have been false alarms, and
Jess dies a little bit every time.
Claire, look at him.
You'd just be reopening a case.
For review. Under the radar.
That's all we'd be doing. Yeah.
Let's pretend that
that's all we'd be doing.
Claire, I have to...
I have to leave. I have
to leave in two weeks.
I gotta be back after the first.
Please help me do this.
It's everything.
Um, if you leave
your number at the desk,
I'll call you later.
Okay.
You know...
You always did belong here.
So did you.
Kasten, call your office.
It's urgent.
Someone stole second base.
It's December, shithead.
I finished her room.
It's all packed.
Where will you go?
Someplace quiet.
Outside the city.
Just not here.
Homicide hasn't found
anything yet, have they?
They will.
- What are we hearing from the mosque?
- A lot of praying.
Not much else.
Did you find his Van?
No.
We found her car.
Where?
Outside a bakery.
- Was it broken into?
- No.
It's just...
We're talking about...
It's just impossible.
We're talking about Carolyn.
Um...
There's a lot of...
Stuff in the...
In the garage to pack.
She made some beautiful
things, didn't she?
Yeah.
Yeah, she did.
Who is this?
You ever see him
before that day?
I don't remember
seeing him on that day.
This is the office picnic, right?
Yeah.
She ever mention him to you?
Why would she?
Mind if I take this?
Sure.
Why?
I've seen this guy before.
Hey, bumpy. Hey.
Somebody here needs some help.
I always knew you'd be back.
- Great to see you, bump.
- You too.
Nothing like Christmas
in Los Angeles, huh?
Sleighs, snow-covered streets.
Are you up for a little field work?
Ray needs a few doors opened.
- Which ones?
- Old ones.
Guess I always knew
he'd be back too.
I'm not sure
how much use I'll be.
- I've been an indoor pet for a while now.
- I'll take my chances.
We ask anybody else,
red flags will go up.
Well, that's flattering.
Okay.
This time it sticks, right?
Thanks, bumpy.
That never got better?
- What?
- Your limp.
What limp?
Hey, bump. Yeah?
Who's this guy?
Who, the guy in blue? Yeah.
This is the office picnic, right?
Yeah.
Okay. Who's that? I don't know.
You didn't see him there? Yeah,
but I don't know who he is.
Hey, who's this guy?
No idea.
Dave. Yeah?
Who's this guy? You're
standing right by him.
Sorry.
He's standing right by you.
I don't know him.
Rupert. This guy.
You know him? Mm-mmm. No.
Hey, Siefert!
Siefert. Office picnic. This guy. He's
staring at Carolyn Cobb. Who is he?
What, are you
working homicide now?
You know the guy or not?
No.
Okay.
Okay, so a guy shows up at the office
picnic, except nobody saw him.
Half of you were there.
Nobody knows who he is.
Is that right?
This guy.
No? No.
Okay.
Let's do it this way.
I've seen this guy before, bump.
Hey.
Can I give you some
unsolicited advice,
one cop to another?
You're kinda
crossing a line here.
You're using ct software
on a rape-murder case.
Things like that get noticed.
So I should, what,
ignore the lead? No.
You give the lead to the guys that are actually
investigating the case over at homicide.
You were brought here
to fight terrorism.
Well, her body was found next
to the hottest mosque in la.
What makes you think
I'm not fighting terrorism?
I'm just trying to spare you an
ass-kicking. Spare yourself.
Okay? Spare myself.
Right.
Goddamn it, I knew
I'd seen that guy before!
He's from the mosque!
God, I hope you're wrong
about this.
The idea that it could've been
someone connected to this office?
I don't think
I could live with that.
Who's the lead on this at LAPD?
Um, a detective named Guerrero.
Has he seen these? No.
No, I thought it might reflect badly on
the office, the guy being at the picnic,
so I wanted to show them
to you first.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
All right.
Leave all this with me.
Get back to your ct work.
I'll get this Guerrero
up to speed.
I can take care of that.
No, no, no.
Nothing should ever come before
your terrorism cases. Ever.
It's not a problem for me, sir,
to put out a field report.
I can explain things to him.
You know, one vato to another.
Well, the thing is, sir, because it's
Jess, I wanna bird-dog this one.
They teach you some version of "yes,
sir" at the bureau, don't they?
Yes, sir.
So?
Be careful in there. He's slick.
And unless I'm very wrong,
he's about to ask you to lunch.
Mean a lot to me if you said no.
How's Jess?
Did you find anything yet?
I did.
Aban Ghazala, the guy seen
running from the garage?
He'd been living down there.
Just confessed.
- Where is he?
- County.
Well, well, well. Our new star.
Come on in, Claire.
It's almost lunchtime.
Are you hungry?
Hey.
I wasn't here today, okay? We're
trying to assess him as a ct source.
We gotta keep it quiet.
Understood.
"C" block, stand by.
Ghazala?
You really are a dumb son of a bitch,
Siefert! Is that how cases get buried?
You find the nearest Muslim
and you ring him up?
You're protecting someone, Siefert,
and you're gonna tell me who it is!
Who are you protecting?
Just let me up!
Let me up, ray. Come on.
Jesus god.
I was just trying to
point you away from someone.
That guy in that stupid
picture of yours...
I can't have you questioning
him at the moment.
Why is that? Who is he?
- My snitch.
- Huh?
My guy in the al-Ankara mosque.
Th-the guy staring at Carolyn
Cobb is your snitch?
- I don't think he's your doer, Kasten.
- Introduce us. I'll ask him.
'Cause he is this close to
giving us a whole sleeper cell!
You don't spook a guy like that.
- What the hell you bring him to the picnic for?
- He's a wannabe.
The guy's got some fantasy
of being a cop someday.
So I brought him to the picnic, I let him feel
like a big shot. Anything to keep him happy.
Well, it worked. He found
his true love there.
You don't know that.
I do know you tricked a phony confession
out of a guy who didn't do it!
My guy shuts down,
everybody loses!
A couple more buildings
come down maybe.
So I redirected things a bit.
Sorry.
He got a name?
You want me to send Jess
in here to ask you?
Anzor Marzin.
Street name's pac-man.
Where is he?
Where is he? Hey, I don't know.
Okay?
Maybe you can find him.
Okay.
When's the last time
you seen him?
Ten days.
Carolyn Cobb was killed 10 days ago.
What's that, a coincidence?
Detective on the case, Guerrero,
he know about all this?
Of course he does.
Guy understands the ugly truth.
Meaning what?
Meaning, someone
hands us good names,
his love life doesn't matter.
Jesus Christ!
All right.
All right, start writing.
Address.
His address, his girlfriend's
address, something useful.
Couldn't just let it go, huh?
A stripper, huh? Mm-hmm.
Well, that is exciting.
But she's not coming out.
She's coming out. Yeah, right.
And then Marzin's gonna pull
up in a stolen gray Van
with Carolyn's DNA under his
nails, and everybody wins.
You can forget about the Van.
We're not gonna find it.
You know what I like
about you, ray?
We're not even pretending
to do this right.
Meet the detective who's
actually in charge? Screw that.
We're not just crossing the
line, we're burying it.
I don't need to know Guerrero
to know Guerrero.
I've seen guys
eat a case before.
I'm gonna go water that
bush over there, okay?
Swimming pools and movie stars.
Come on, moose.
Nice stealth.
Well, if you had evidence on this asshole,
we could warrant him like professionals.
Hey, bump.
Get the door, will ya?
All right, check upstairs.
I'll watch the door.
Did you find... Jesus!
Shit. You scared the hell out of me.
I scared you?
What the hell are you sneaking up
on me for? Sorry. Did I wake you?
There's nothing upstairs.
Anything down here?
I don't know. Maybe.
Wow, this guy can really draw.
Shit!
What are you bitching about?
I gave you a cookie.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Get up there. I'm trying.
Move that trash can.
Damn it!
Ouch! That is a bad bite.
He looked rabid to me. Probably gonna die.
We need to get back in there.
Why, to see
how the comic book turns out?
Yeah, obviously.
Yeah, I guess
that would be huge. Epic.
Probably a lot
of clues in there.
You didn't take it, bump.
Pork rinds look pretty good. You couldn't
have taken it. Nobody'd be that stupid.
Yeah, well, how about a Twinkie?
You hungry? You want a Twinkie?
Bump?
Ohh.
Happy birthday! Dipshit.
What? She's not gonna miss it. She tells him
someone was there, he never comes back!
What's your brilliant idea? Leave it
on the bed? At least now we have it.
Do me a favor, okay?
Let me run point on this.
I'll put an extra dollar in
your paycheck, I swear to god.
Suit yourself.
All right, let me have it.
Thought you didn't want it.
Bump, give me...
Bumpy, give me the...
Give me the...
Well, it looks like
you won another convert.
Po took one look at those
pictures, said, "yep, same guy."
What else he say?
Said he knows him as Beckwith.
Never heard him called Marzin
or pac-man or anything else.
Beckwith checked in two weeks after
release, then skipped two weeks ago.
I asked if he had any hobbies,
you know, like drawing,
or if he ever talked
about baseball.
No and no.
But he does seem to like horses.
The racing kind.
Talks about them all the time.
In an unhealthy kind of way,
according to the po.
He has sort of a fixation.
Uh, said, "if I had the time to do
it, I'd look for him at the track."
Horses might be the only thing he
likes as much as stealing cars."
Hey.
Your table, as I recall.
He skipped parole, didn't he?
Your Beckwith.
Wasn't much of a surprise.
Why?
And the po
doesn't recall Beckwith
having a particular talent
for drawing, does he?
His name's Marzin. Not Beckwith.
This why you called me here?
Just trying to Gauge
the value of your leads.
Thank you. But they're my leads.
And she was my kid.
Jess.
It's not gonna be
like last time.
We find the guy, he goes down.
You shouldn't make promises like that.
I can make that promise.
You know, everybody's asking
me, since you're back,
"who is this guy?
What is it with his obsession
with your daughter?"
And I say, "well, he's a friend.
He's a badge."
They say, "yeah? Then where's
he been the last 13 years?"
I was supposed to meet Carolyn
in that bakery the day she...
She was gonna have a...
A party for your birthday.
I told her I'd meet her there
and pay for the cake.
Last minute I begged off,
after she'd
already gotten there.
I had...
I had some case work to file.
Two hours later, we found her.
That's where I've been
the last 13 years.
What happened to Siefert's face?
Hell if I know.
I was hoping for a
better answer than that.
Well, I don't spend that much time
thinking about Siefert's face.
Assaulting an officer?
Where the hell
were you and bumpy yesterday?
You do that in court? You
spin your chain like that?
- I do it when I'm anxious. You're making me anxious.
- Oh, yeah? Why is that?
Because I caught the case.
Ghazala.
Morales put me on it.
Of course he did.
That son of a bitch.
You're being taken, Claire.
Ghazala's not your guy.
You're gonna have to explain that.
There's a snitch.
He's working al-Ankara mosque.
His name's Marzin.
He's also a person of
interest on Carolyn Cobb.
And everybody's running around, trying
to blow this thing up. He's the doer!
Siefert squeezes a phony confession out of
Ghazala and the snitch stays untouched.
'Cause he's working ct for us.
Now he turns up as the
rapist-murderer of a cop's kid?
No. No, can't be the guy.
Morales has assured me that this
case has the highest priority.
Yeah. And Guantánamo's
a club med resort.
Hey, Jess.
- What you got there?
- Oh, it's nothing.
It's not for you.
That's not what I hear.
- Sorry.
- Is he the guy?
He's a guy.
That's all we know.
Anything in there indicate a
predilection for violence?
It's a comic book.
They're all violent.
- Can I see it?
- Jess, you shouldn't be here.
Anything you touch
is inadmissible.
- Can I see it?
- No.
Ray.
You have to be honest.
That's the only rule.
- 'Cause she's good at this.
- All right. Okay.
The truth and nothing but the truth.
Wow. I'm ready.
Fear not. This is beautiful, by the way.
Thank you.
You're welcome. It's beautiful.
Okay. So, are you looking
for a professional type?
Struggling actress type?
A what?
Nurturing schoolteacher type?
I'm... I'm willing to
cast a wide net, so...
- Very wise. Very wise.
- Thank you.
Uh, how about tall?
Short? Other?
No preference? There's no
preference, as long as she's smart.
- How smart?
- Preferably Harvard-educated.
Oh. Okay.
From Philly. Hmm.
- Who's a prosecutor.
- I see.
Named Claire.
That might narrow the field a bit.
That's very good. Very good.
What can I say?
What can you say?
You look a little quiet
all of a sudden.
Claire.
I think you should know
that I can't rein her in.
She's not gonna stop
till she finds this guy.
You never saw Jess and her kid.
They were inseparable.
Yeah.
I can imagine.
I know it's messy.
I mean, working ct.
But we gotta find this guy
before Jess does. Okay?
I'll work it at night,
under the radar.
Morales doesn't have to know.
I can't tell you what to do
with your free time.
My legal advice would be,
find that Van.
Thank you.
Good night.
Uh, let me walk you to your car.
You don't have to do that. No,
I'd like to, if you don't mind.
Something about garages lately.
So, when's the big day? Hmm?
Oh. Um, sometime next year.
Congratulations. Oh.
What's he do?
He manages a hedge fund
in Philly.
His name is Ellis.
So, what, is he...
He moving here?
That's the plan.
Is that a hard thing to do, to manage a hedge
fund in Philly when you're living in la?
Might be.
But he's pretty clever.
I bet he is.
Ellis is a pretty clever name.
And love conquers all, right?
That's me.
See you tomorrow.
Jess is lucky to have you, ray.
You're a good friend.
She'd do the same for me.
She'd do more.
God, this guy could be anywhere.
All right,
I want to see the stables.
What the hell for?
That's where the horses are.
I love you, baby boy.
Ain't you?
Look at you.
Bump.
I'll be damned.
You like that?
All right then. Shh.
Hey.
Hey, buddy.
Nice work on the face, pac-man.
I like it.
And you are?
You don't remember me?
Let's talk.
Call it in!
Ray.
Where did he get you?
I had him, bump.
That was Marzin.
It's okay. This is Luis.
He says the guy is here
all the time boosting cars.
The guy got a name?
I-I don't talk to him.
I don't like the way
he looks at the horses.
You got a cell phone, Luis?
Huh?
Give it to me.
The guy comes in again,
text 911 to this number
and I'll be here.
Bump, will ya? Yeah.
I got it.
It's him, all right.
Oh, yeah.
Son of a bitch.
Thanks, Luis.
- Hi.
- Oh!
Um...
I was waiting for... I'm sorry.
Oh. No.
It's fine. Is there
anything I can...
Well, I was just gonna see if you wanted
me to walk you to your car again.
Oh.
I wasn't ready to leave yet.
Neither was I.
- Something making you nervous?
- Oh, this.
It's a... It's a silly habit.
It's kind of endearing,
if you ask me.
Then it's yours.
Well, you need it
more than I do anyway.
- Is that right?
- Mm-hmm.
You sure you can live without it? I know
how you heady types tend to obsess.
That's right.
Obsessing is awful.
Hope it never happens to you.
Let me, uh...
I-I...
I like the one on
page 90, by the way.
I mean, I don't know,
but I think you...
You'd break hearts
in that dress.
That's sweet.
Yeah, really sweet, ray.
Come with me.
Uh, would you excuse us, Claire?
Please tell me
I've been misinformed.
Please tell me no one from this office
broke into the home of a stripper
to steal a comic book
in some half-assed attempt at making
a case against a prime ct asset.
There's a case to be made, sir. -With
a picture from a picnic as evidence.
And no participation from the
actual cop investigating the case.
This how you do things
in New York? Hmm?
No warrant. You just
surveil whomever you wish.
My sense was that your enthusiasm
for the target was low, sir.
I'll tell you what's lower...
My "enthusiasm" for
witnessing another 9/11.
Jesus Christ.
Everybody knows those
assholes want to hit la next!
Half the families in my neighborhood
are buying duct tape and Hazmat suits!
You don't even have a
case against this guy!
You don't have his Van.
You don't have shit!
If I did, would you file?
No, I'd let a
rapist-murderer go free!
Jess is a friend of mine.
You'd charge him,
politics aside?
And while you're doing this, how
many ct leads are going unpursued?
How many hurdles are you placing between
Marzin and his ultimate use to us,
which is intel on the mosque?
If I had evidence on him tying him
to Carolyn Cobb, you'd charge him?
Of course!
- I have your word on that?
- Did I just stutter?
And by the way,
Harvard law doesn't date
community college.
Stop hitting on my new hire.
You're embarrassing yourself.
You were always beautiful,
but so ambitious.
I prefer "determined."
Political.
Collegial.
Oblivious.
I think you like looking
back more than I do.
I don't have the time for it.
Okay. Let's look forward.
Okay, let's.
- I think you should go back to New York.
- Why?
Because I don't like where this is going, and I
can't justify it for a case that isn't there.
Oh, it's there. I got two broken
ribs from a shovel says it's there.
That was Marzin.
- I need two more men.
- What?
Bumpy's on one leg, and truth is
I don't move like I used to.
Come on, ray. You move
exactly like you used to.
They don't have to be big men.
Get out.
I mean it. Go home.
I can't.
9/11 was just the beginning.
Protect your home, please.
Protect your family.
Bin laden, Saddam Hussein...
They have Anthrax now.
Bump. What is it? You said
you had a lead on Marzin.
We do. "We"?
Come here.
- Hey, Jess.
- I hate the death penalty.
Oh, yeah? Why's that?
Death would be too good
for this guy.
A big meal and
a... shot and a nap.
Let him rot in jail,
live a life full of nothing.
Uh-huh.
- What we doing here, guys?
- Waiting for him.
He's been here? He will be.
Bumpy and I figured it out.
Jess, you come within a mile of
this guy, we never make a case.
He can quit his job,
he can change his name,
he can dump his car,
but I will still find him.
'Cause there's one thing
you can't change,
and it's right here.
Are you drunk?
The justifier by pac-man Marzin.
Page one, first character...
A monster hunter
named Alston Sherry.
Bumpy? Alston.
Could that be Walter Alston,
the winningest manager
in the history of the Dodgers?
He won four world series titles,
three of 'em here in la.
And Sherry. Larry Sherry?
The MVP of the '59 world series.
That's the first championship
here in la.
Not that it matters, but he had two
wins and two saves in that series.
Page two.
Alston's partner,
named bulldog O'Malley.
- Bump?
- Walter O'Malley?
The owner who brought the
Dodgers to la from Brooklyn.
- Man was a Saint.
- You seeing a pattern here, ray?
How about "bulldog," huh?
Orel "bulldog" Hershiser?
Star of the last dodger team that won
a series, '88? Before we sucked.
So, why are we here, bumpy?
'Cause this is the place
where ex-Dodgers hang out.
And all the crazies know it.
And by the way, the monster that
O'Malley and Sherry are chasing
is orange and black.
You know, the colors worn
by that, uh, team up north.
Think I'd have noticed that
a little sooner.
Don't beat yourself up, bump.
Think blue.
See?
Passions... are like maps.
Take me, for example.
Carolyn is...
Was...
The thing that made me me.
Nothing will ever change that.
Take you. The way you keep
thinking about Claire.
It's a lost cause.
But you don't give up.
Passion always wins.
So I will be here
every night from now on.
He'll come here.
Kind of a long shot.
Crazy. I know.
Sort of like building
a whole case
around a picture
from an office picnic.
But you look at enough faces,
you're bound to find
the one you're looking for.
Eventually, right?
So, when's the next game?
This capacity crowd
coming to life now
as the Dodgers have
gotten off the mat.
Onlinger checks the runner,
rocks and deals.
Way outside. Ball four.
And that fast, manager Dave
Mcdaniels out of the dugout,
on his way to the mound.
We'll see if he's bringing
a hook with him.
The 2002 met bullpen has not
been particularly impressive.
Yo, buddy, sit down!
Sit down!
- I'm looking for my uncle.
- Yeah, and I'm trying to watch the game.
You know, after 10 nights of this,
I'm ready to learn something.
Bump.
Ten rows up, seven guys in.
- Yeah. Yeah, maybe.
- Okay.
Now batting, number 11,
shortstop Drew Sagano.
Excuse me.
The Dodgers sending
the go-ahead run to the plate.
Sir. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hey, Marzin! Hey! Hey!
Sorry.
Down in front.
Let's go. Come on, move!
Onlinger ready to go back to
work now, checking the runners.
Bump! With me!
Delivers. Belted.
Out of the way!
Bump! Check down there!
Hey, Kennedy, shield the exits!
Over there!
Long trek back out to the mound.
Suddenly, on the wrong side
of a one-run game,
history repeating itself...
- What the hell, bro!
- Jesus.
The crowd refusing to sit
until Sagano emerges
to take a curtain call.
Aah! God!
Move!
I got the suspect. Hey!
Stop! Marzin, stop!
Marzin!
Goddamn it!
You okay?
- Get him!
- Suspect is...
Hey!
Hold it right there!
Get out of the way!
You got him? Yeah.
Stay where you are.
Son of a bitch!
The Dodgers, nine games back and
left for dead just 30 days ago,
can see daylight now.
Just a half a game back
in the west,
with a 6-5 lead
in the bottom of the eighth.
Quite a night.
What are you trying to do,
get yourself suspended,
sent back to New York?
We didn't know the guy would run.
It was a baseball game.
We were just there to ask him a
couple of questions, but then he ran!
Don't do that to me. Don't talk
to me like you talk to Morales.
I know what you
were there to do.
- What were we supposed to do, let him go?
- Yes.
We don't have anything on him.
I want him released.
You don't wanna
question him first? No!
I want him advised of his rights
and released before morales...
Morales will file
if I can make a case.
And Marzin already knows his rights.
He's here voluntarily.
He'll confess! I just
gotta work him a little.
Meaning waterboarding?
No, meaning conversation.
Five minutes. If you don't
think he's the doer, he walks.
Claire.
Claire, come on.
We can't just let him go.
What are you doing? I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm begging you.
I just wanna remind you
that you're here
of your own volition.
You're free to go at any time.
"Volition."
That's a great word.
I think I'm gonna use that
someday, when I'm a cop.
You understand your rights.
Yeah.
Is this about the mosque?
No.
This is about Carolyn Cobb.
Who?
Carolyn Cobb.
Mmm.
I never met her.
I don't remember this picture.
Where is this?
It's the office picnic.
You were the guest of Reggie
Siefert, your rabbi in here,
your godfather.
Oh, yeah, yeah. I came for the
picnic for 10 minute, maybe.
Music was shit.
That... is that a Glock 9?
That's standard issue, right?
Why did you run from us?
You serious?
I'm ratting on the sickest
sleeper cell in la.
I get spotted chatting with
two cops, I'm a dead man.
Wait.
Are you the guys
who took my comic book?
Yeah, fuckhead.
I'm the guy that took
your comic book.
Carolyn Cobb.
I think you raped her
and killed her, pac-man.
Hmm.
Yeah, that would be smart
'cause I don't have enough
heat on me as it is, do I?
So...
I think you met her
at the picnic,
convinced yourself that she
was interested in you,
and then maybe after a couple
of days following her around,
you went up to her,
declared your undying love,
and when she told you
to piss off,
you raped her and killed her and
dumped her body in the trash,
doused in bleach.
- Bleach?
- Where'd you hide the Van?
I'm... I'm trying to do good.
Pretty girl. Okay, you
should be thanking me.
I'm not even saying I'm blaming
you for taking the shot.
Excuse me. Yeah.
You need to walk away. He has
a lawyer in the building.
- He hasn't made any calls.
- He has friends here, remember?
Look, I just need
a few more minutes.
No, that won't be necessary.
Mr. Marzin has been a very
good friend to this office.
I thought I made that
clear to you.
May I see the file, please?
Hmm.
Mr. Marzin.
You're free to go. We're sorry
if we've inconvenienced you.
This is not your doer.
How do you know?
Read the file. Carolyn Cobb,
5'7", 130 pounds, an athlete.
"The damage to the right parietal
bone and left mandible of the victim
indicated that the attacker was of
extraordinary physical strength."
You see? We're looking
for a brute, not a kid.
You can't overpower a girl like that with
two noodles for arms. It's laughable.
And then, of course,
there's the bleach.
A clear sign of premeditation.
Your killer knew enough to douse the
victim thoroughly inside and out
so as to destroy
all the DNA evidence.
Now, that takes smarts.
It takes strategic thinking.
What is your level
of education, Mr. Marzin?
What is it, high school?
Less than that?
We're looking for an intellect.
This one likes to sit in his room
and draw comic books with monsters
and maybe Jack off
to the posters on his wall.
Which brings me to the final
piece of exculpatory evidence.
Which means, Mr. Marzin,
evidence which proves
your innocence of the charge.
"Examination of
the decedent's vaginal walls
indicate injuries
at a depth of nine inches."
We're looking for someone
with a hammer,
not a peanut.
- You have no idea what he...
- Women always know.
Men carry themselves one way,
boys another.
Don't they?
Don't they, Mr. Marzin?
And that right there.
Trying to look down my blouse.
That's something a boy would do.
So you run along, little one.
You run along.
We're sorry for the mix-up.
"Peanut."
Is that what you said,
you cocky bitch?
Gosh. How impressive.
Am I swooning?
Go home, loser.
Draw yourself
some more monsters.
- You want some of this, bitch?
- We're done here.
- You want what she got?
- What?
Here's what she got!
You don't touch her!
Son of a... you don't touch her!
I'll kill you!
Ray! Ray!
- Goddamn it!
- Ray! Ray, enough!
Ray! Ray. It's okay.
Get off! Ray!
It's okay. Ray!
Ray! It's okay.
He said it!
You okay? We got him.
Lock him up.
Oh, god. You okay? You okay?
You're letting him go,
aren't you?
You think I'm stupid, sir?
That's two questions. Which one
do you want me to answer first?
- Hello, Claire.
- You and I had an understanding!
Yes, that you would bring me a case.
But you don't have one.
Just this half-assed
confession from Marzin,
who claims it was beaten
out of him.
- And he's got the injuries to prove it!
- He attacked Claire!
You want me to trade a whole
mosque full of potential arrests
for a comic book and a
picture from a picnic?
Put me in the goddamn mosque! I'll
get you more names than he will!
If that'll get you
out of my office.
You looked me right in the eye.
You told me you'd prosecute.
I also told you nothing comes before our
efforts in counterterrorism. Nothing!
Now, you drop this right now or I'm sending
you back to the bureau! You understand me?
That boy is officially
untouchable!
Untouchable?
He's guilty.
Welcome to the war.
There's a time to shut up, Claire, and
there's a time to tell your boss the truth.
When he's being a horse's ass,
that's when you tell him the truth!
You really turned him around in there.
You just knocked him flat.
But it's your case!
We don't have a case!
You wanna tell Jess that,
or should I?
Son of a bitch! Ray. Ray.
Come on. Come on.
Jess.
Cover your ears.
- What?
- You don't wanna hear this.
Let's kill him.
Let's kill him. Let's do it
now, before we lose him again.
We just do it
and that's it. He goes.
Nobody will miss him.
We'll make the case on the mosque
without him, and Carolyn gets to rest.
And then what?
What would a few bullets get me?
A lifetime in jail.
So he dies
without ever serving a day,
and I spend the next 50 years
envying him.
Does that sound
like justice to you?
You're both working for a liar.
That's the trouble
with you, ray.
You think that matters.
So, then... Would 26 be too old?
Yes. Who's the guy?
- Would 25?
- Who's the guy?
He's a student like me.
How old is this...
Twenty-one... ish.
That's clever.
You start me at 26, so that 21,
which is really 22,
sounds reasonable.
I admire that.
Thank you.
But I'm still not gonna say yes.
Mom!
What? He already asked me out.
But it would mean missing
your office picnic.
This just gets worse and worse.
I want you to be there.
I only have three
more months with you,
and then you're
2,000 miles away,
and it's dorm life
and frat parties,
and I'll seem boring
by comparison.
Come, please.
Come.
I think I have to quit.
You wanna bet on whether I get
called back to New York tomorrow?
Claire.
Yeah?
If I am...
A Van's just been found
wrecked on grand street.
Driver fled.
Inside smells like bleach.
He tried to move it.
He tried to move it!
Give me the keys. I'll drive!
We find anything in there
that ID's Marzin,
we might actually have him.
Maybe you won't have to go.
Oh.
Oh, god.
Welcome to the war.
You think Morales did this?
Of course he did.
He had to.
Ray.
Claire, I'm sorry.
I don't know. I've been
with the Mets 10 years now.
It's the same thing every
season... our pitching's weak.
Our best guy went down
with an elbow injury.
They had this great kid
coming up, but he...
Well, they decided to trade
him for a left fielder, so...
Well, that's the thing
about trades, huh?
Everybody has to
give up something.
Well, I can tell you where we
are with Marzin, if you want.
Tell me why
you're not married anymore.
Why don't you tell me
why you still are?
Ellis and I
understand each other.
You?
Well, she was, um...
She was great, actually.
She was kind of a Saint.
There was just one thing about her
that neither one of us could fix.
What was that?
She wasn't you.
Well, you always were
a little slow.
Oh, yeah? Mm-hmm.
How's that? Why didn't you
ask me to come with you?
And give up second chair?
No, not you.
Like I said, slow.
What is that?
Oh, it's just, um...
Just the office, back home.
Baseball emergency?
Yeah, they, uh... they put in
this new surveillance system.
It's giving everybody fits. I gotta
get to the laptop in the hotel.
You're really not gonna
tell me where you're going?
You know what?
Truth is, it's probably better I
didn't ask you to come with me.
This way, I got to spend
the next 13 years
pretending that you might
have actually said yes.
And I did.
Good night.
Would you be careful?
Be careful, okay?
Hey. The Mercedes.
- Where the hell are you?
- I got him, bump.
He's in a Benz. We're heading
over the fourth street bridge.
He made you yet? No.
Looks like he's gonna take
a right on Anderson.
Okay. I'm on my way.
Under the radar, right?
What, I'm gonna start respecting
protocol now? Break my perfect record?
Let me look around
and see who I can scare up.
Okay.
Brick building,
corner of Anderson and Mateo.
I'm betting it's a chop shop.
Hey, don't do anything
till I get there.
You wind up dead,
I get a demerit.
Hey, man. Hey, yo.
Let's get it in!
Ain't no thing!
Ain't no thing, dog!
Hey. Asshole.
Why you following me?
He's a cop. He's gotta be a cop.
No badge. He's in a rented car.
So why's he following you then?
Nice.
I said, why are you
following me, man?
Pac-man, you still
don't remember me?
I'm pac-man.
I'm in a video game.
Who the hell is pac-man?
You have to answer for Carolyn Cobb.
You have to answer...
- yo, can we lose this guy already?
- Yeah, get rid of him. Do it.
I don't know who he is.
Come on. Come on.
I know it was you.
- Freeze! Freeze!
- Raise your hands! Get 'em up!
- Hands up! Nobody do anything stupid!
- Let me see your hands!
- Get on the ground!
- Drop it!
- Get down!
- Drop the gun now. Drop it!
Put it on the ground.
That's it. Slide it over here.
Bump, you got him? Yeah.
Reggie! Reg, talk to me!
- Reggie!
- Don't move!
- Reggie, talk to me!
- I got it, bump. I got it.
Come here, buddy.
Reggie. Reggie.
Stay with me, buddy.
Come on. Eyes on me, buddy.
Reggie. Reggie. Come on, buddy.
Eyes on me, buddy.
Shots fired.
I have an officer down.
We are at 516 Anderson street
in a warehouse.
I repeat, officer down.
Come on, buddy.
- Jess.
- Copy that.
Officer down,
516 Anderson street.
Look. It's him.
It's Marzin.
You see?
Goddamn it!
How's he doing, bumpy?
He's dead.
I told you I'd get him.
Congratulations.
You don't think he's Marzin?
No, I don't think he's Marzin.
I think we just sent a
15-year guy home in a box
for five grand theft autos
and a parole violation.
You saw his face? Up close?
Yes, I saw his face.
Did you look at Siefert's face?
'Cause he's dead.
Well, he had to answer
for Carolyn too.
Don't you ever, ever
say her name again!
So, what now?
You fly home? It's done?
I don't know. Part of it maybe.
I know I should forget it.
It was another lifetime.
Except it wasn't.
We blew it, didn't we?
Didn't we?
Sure. Move him in.
He's been living here for
the last 12 years anyway.
I'm going to bed.
I told you he understood me.
Jess?
Would, uh, you like
any coffee or...
No. No.
Have a seat, please.
My guys are doing a
widows-and-orphans for Siefert.
Might not be a bad idea
for you to contribute.
Yeah.
Of course.
I forgot he was married.
Divorced.
Two kids in high school.
Well, that's on me.
No.
It's on me.
I could have stopped all this.
That's...
That's why you're here.
I want to thank you both for
staying with this like you have,
but it has to stop now,
before anybody else gets hurt.
I couldn't live with that. Jess,
this is the guy. This is Marzin.
- He's not the guy.
- I know you don't wanna get invested all over again.
It's not Marzin.
I know it.
How?
'Cause Marzin's been dead
for 13 years.
I killed him.
What?
I killed him about a
month after you left.
He's buried out in the yard.
You understand you're speaking
to an officer of the court?
I do. Jess.
Before you say another word, you
need to get yourself a lawyer.
It's okay. I'll be fine with whatever
you decide to do about it, okay?
I would've left him alone.
I want you to know that.
When they torched that Van...
I knew, if Morales
could do that,
he would never let us
bring this guy in.
It just...
It had to be me.
I owed my daughter that.
Truth is,
he wasn't that hard to find.
Eventually, he did come to that
bar, like I always said he would.
Passion always wins.
Right?
It's the weirdest thing, when
you're on your way to do something,
but you're not sure you're
actually gonna go through with it.
Like reading a book, only you are the
person that you're reading about.
And then you...
You watch yourself do it.
Nobody missed him. You were
right about that, ray.
We made our case
on al-Ankara without him.
Got our convictions,
and everybody walked away happy.
So forget about this Beckwith.
He's a creep,
but he's not our creep.
Just let it go, okay?
Reliving it, wondering
if you could've stopped it.
That's no way to live.
- You're telling me...
- Sorry.
But it's done.
- Claire, I'm fine with whatever you...
- I need a second. All right?
Give me a second.
Jess.
Was this better?
What do you think?
I think you look
a million years old.
I always thought
if this one was over,
it would feel like it was over.
Maybe it's been over
a long time.
We just...
Never knew it.
I'm gonna go and check on her.
What do I say?
I don't know.
Good night.
Just let it go, okay?
Reliving it, wondering
if you could've stopped it...
That's where I've been
the last 13 years.
That's no way to live.
Don't you ever, ever
say her name again!
It's quiet out there.
I like the quiet.
Carolyn is...
Was the thing
that made me me.
What would a few bullets get me?
Maybe we could go about this
a little less officially.
I owed my daughter that.
I don't think I have the stomach
to watch him walk away again.
That sound like justice to you?
I hate the death penalty.
Let him rot in jail,
live a life full of nothing.
Please.
Can... can you ask her
to talk to me?
Life sentence, right?
For you too.
Ray?