How ya doin'?
That's for you.
- You sure you're up for this?
- Yeah.
- So, see you tonight, right?
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
- So I'll see you tonight.
- OK.
- (man) What happened to you?
- (man #2) What does it look like?
I don't know.
I had this pit bull, right?
Joe. Joe the dog.
I go to feed the fuck, right?
I put his bowl down, he goes nuts.
Bites my fucking thumb off.
19 stitches.
I'm in the hospital three days.
I get out. I get my gun.
I go to him "You like to bite things?"
Bite this." I put the gun in his mouth.
Bam! I blow him
all over the apartment.
- Ever see a dog explode?
- They're here.
This neighbourhood's a real shit hole.
I don't know why you had to meet here.
We'll do the next meeting at
Tavern on the Green, all right?
- How you doin', Noonan?
- I'm cold. Let's get this over with.
- Fine. Let's see the stuff.
- Show 'em.
- Let's see the money.
- We'll take this at a little discount.
- I knew this shit was gonna happen.
- This is fucking bullshit.
What are you gonna do?
Are you gonna shoot me?
- I'll shoot him.
- Don't point that at me.
We'll walk away. This is bullshit.
Give me the bag.
I want to shoot you.
Shoot him.
I'll take this and get the fuck...
Did you hear what I said?
I said give me the fucking bag.
Don't be a fool.
Give me the bag. You want to die?
- Shut up.
- Want me to shoot him?
- I don't give a fuck.
- I'll shoot you now.
Give me the fucking bag!
- Let's go.
- Want to fucking get shot?
Give me that fucking bag!
- Jesus Christ...
- What happened back there?
- What?
- Nothing, right?
I don't... No! No!
- Do you know me?
- No, I don't know ya!
All right, put me
in a subway station. Go!
(? "White City" by the Pogues)
He's wearing a silk suit.
He's got crocodile shoes.
I said "I don't care what fucking shoes
you wear. You're still a crack dealer."
The guy says "I didn't know
I was in your neighbourhood, man."
Like his balls were in his throat.
"Don't go to pieces" I tell him.
Then he gets the joke.
- Who the fuck is this?
- What do you want?
- Whatever you're having.
- Fuck you.
Trying to hurt my feelings?
Won't introduce me to your friends?
- Terry?
- That took you fucking long enough.
Terry Noonan. Terry.
- Terry Noonan.
- Hey, motherfucker.
You fuckin'... Come here, come here.
Where you fuckin' been, man? Oh, man.
(man yells)
- It's great to fucking see ya.
- Hey.
This is my best fucking friend.
See, I love this fucking guy.
Where you been, fucking Mars?
You're looking good.
I gotta take my lord here for a stroll.
- I gotta talk to you.
- Wanna go somewhere?
- Yeah.
- OK.
Hey, catch you guys later, all right?
Give me this, give me this.
You're a fucking prick. (laughs)
Where'd our fucking neighbourhood go?
I don't even recognise the place.
A bunch of yuppie condos.
They could've left ten blocks for the Irish.
They don't even want to call it
Hell's Kitchen no more.
Renamed it Clinton.
Sounds like a fucking steamboat.
These guys you dropped.
- The guy you were with, this...
- My partner? DeMarco.
DeMarco? Can you trust him?
He might as well have done it himself,
Jack. Who's he gonna tell?
Who's he gonna tell?
Anybody he fucking wants.
Terry, this guy, this DeMarco,
he gets into a little trouble
with the cops, right?
He'd trade everything he knows
about you for a slice of pizza.
Wake up.
Would you ask Mikey
if he'd throw me something?
Mikey met with a little accident.
So did Flynn.
Frankie's running the show now.
- Frankie's the boss?
- My big brother is the boss.
- Frank's the boss?
- Yeah.
He's trying to put this deal together
with the Italians. This guy Borelli.
- Joe Borelli?
- You heard of him?
We're like that.
- Hey, you want another beer?
- I'd love one.
Cheers.
Is your sister still around?
No, Kate moved way the fuck uptown.
- You wouldn't recognise her.
- Yeah?
Terry.
Check this out.
- What the fuck is that?
- It's...
It's Frankie's idea.
You got your favourite gun, right?
He got tired of tossing away
a perfectly good piece after every job.
You take your hands,
and you take your gun.
You put the prints on the gun,
you stash it.
The cops find the gun.
They're lookin' for a dead man.
- This is somebody's hands?!
- Yeah.
- What are you touching 'em for?!
- Terry, meet Flynn.
Don't fuck with me.
No, don't fuck with me.
- (Jack laughs hysterically)
- Don't! Don't! You're gonna get... Fuck!
- That's somebody's hands!
- Are you scared?
- Get the fuck...!
- All right, hands up.
- Put 'em back.
- They're in. They're in.
- They're in. All right?
- You're a sick pup.
- I know.
- You're a very sick pup.
What's this? Come here.
Sweet.
See this gun I got here?
I love this fucking gun.
- I usually shoot straight when I'm drunk.
- You mean you were aiming?
Thank God you're back. I was feeling like
the last fucking Irishman in the Kitchen.
Terry, you've been away
too long. You gotta wake up.
Never do business with a greaser.
The cops get him, they got an eyewitness.
And an eyewitness puts you away.
Unless it's around here.
The cops can't do shit around here.
Now, me and Frankie took
this union guy out last year.
Went up to him on the street,
popped his button.
There must've been 50 witnesses.
Cops were all over the Kitchen
asking questions.
This one asshole raised his hand.
Cops found his head spinning
inside a washer- dryer over on 47th.
Haven't heard from the cops in a year.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Jackie, where the hell were you?
- Kate.
I waited for you. You said you'd come by.
- When?
- You don't remember?
- At my apartment.
- You shouldn't have moved so far away.
She moved all the fucking way
uptown. Who can get there?
Oh, right. You get above the 50s,
you get disoriented.
Hello, Kathleen.
- Well.
- It's Terry Noonan. He showed up.
- Look what the cat dragged in.
- How are you?
I thought you were...
Where did we think he was?
Nobody knew.
So, you got nostalgic for mayhem?
Yeah, he just appeared.
It's like angels were flying by,
so they dropped him off.
- What?
- What do you mean, what?
You've got this look. What's this look?
Trying to remember how I feel about you.
- That hard?
- Yeah, right.
- I think I'm pissed.
- Yeah, you guys were, you know.
Young. Very young.
She cried a lot when you went away.
My poor little sister.
She cried every night, praying
to the rosary you'd come back.
- You broke her heart, Terry.
- You're an asshole, Jackie.
- What did I do?
- I gotta go.
Stay. Have some coffee.
- You just got here.
- I gotta go to work.
Come on. I never see you.
Just for a minute.
- Terry asked about you.
- What did he want to know?
She works up at the Regent Hotel.
Ashtray in the lobby
costs more than my car.
It's a supernatural event for her
to come down here amongst us.
So, what was it I forgot?
You said it would be no trouble
doing that favour I asked you.
My car got hit by a cab.
I used up all my money to pay for it.
- I have nothing to live on till payday.
- I can loan you right now.
She likes our money,
but not the way we get it.
Why don't you keep it?
Keep your money.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said that.
Sometimes my feelings get hurt too,
you know? The way you snub us.
Take the money, Kathleen.
- Come on, take it.
- All right. Thank you, Jackie.
You're welcome.
So, Terry.
- You just passin' through?
- No. He's coming home.
We're trying to work something out.
If you get above the 40s,
maybe you'll run into me.
It could happen. Right?
- Be up to the angels, I guess.
- (Jackie) Them fucks.
- Well, nice to see you... I guess.
- Same.
My mother-in-law's got
a foot thing I gotta pay for.
- She's got a foot thing.
- She's in the hospital.
It isn't up to me, all right?
Hey, Stevie! I got a surprise for you!
Don't bother me. I'm negotiatin'.
- Hey, negotiator!
- I don't believe this!
Terry fuckin' Noonan!
- Where the fuck have you been?
- Fuck, look at you.
Scary Terry. What the fuck is this?
- You go to the seminary? You don't write.
- He's bigger than me now.
- It's been a long time.
- Ten years.
- 12 years.
- We're doin' business.
Hey, Stevie. 300 bucks here, Stevie.
It ain't even gonna cut it.
- Where'd you find these two idiots?
- They come lookin' for me.
They take my money. I work
my ass off for it and they take it.
Listen. This punk owes
Jimmy Cavello eight grand.
Cavello's got cuff links
cost more than that.
Eight grand buys Jimmy
a Broadway ticket. Let's talk business.
They're out of spumone,
you blame the waiter?
What do we have, another mick
to contend with? What's going on?
- You heard what I said.
- Where you fuckin' been?
The last guinea around here was
Columbus. He only lasted a week.
Are you some kind of fuckin' asshole,
or just taking lessons?
Hey, I'll kill you!
(cries out)
You want to fuck with me?
You want to do that?!
What do you want to do, asshole?
Play it out? Let's straighten this out here.
Tommy! Tommy, it's over!
It's over, man!
Cocksucker. Who do you think
you're fuckin' with, eh?
You'll be hearing from
Jimmy Cavello, Stevie.
Hope that was your favourite gun.
I hope you loved that gun.
You don't know who you fucked with!
You motherfucker.
Fuck 'em.
- You fuckin' guys.
- You got it all?
You're better than the cavalry.
You saved me from the guineas.
- They was gonna burn you at the stake.
- I'm glad you're back. I missed you.
We'll take this town apart
on St Patty's Day.
Stevie, there's a horse runnin'
called Old Friend Arrives.
No shit. Look at this.
You saved my ass,
now you'll win me money.
I love ya. I gotta go.
OTB opens in ten minutes.
- Hey, today's my lucky day.
- See ya later.
Luckiest day he ever had,
his dog got run over.
- Is he fucked up or is he fucked up?
- I wouldn't let him operate on me.
You'd have to be dead two years first.
I'm gonna call Frankie
about taking you on.
We'll probably have to
go to Jersey to see him.
Jersey? Frankie lives in Jersey?
Yeah. What's the fuckin' world coming to?
I want to have kids. I just gotta
find the right broad, like Frankie did.
She'd let me fuck around on weekends,
and make pancakes before Sunday Mass.
- Like Irene, maybe.
- Who's Irene?
I spend one night with her, my eyes
are crossed for days. I walk into walls.
- I'd like to meet her.
- She's mine.
- Uncle Jackie!
- Hey.
Hey, hey. Lola, come here.
Look what the fuckin' cat dragged in.
Nice to see you, Terry.
You remember Maureen?
- How you doin'?
- Come on inside. We should talk.
- I'm Pat.
- How you doin'?
Play with the kids, OK, Jackie?
Teach 'em how to kneel or something.
(Jackie) You want to see my gun, hm?
Before you began exploiting these
pathetic skanks' addictive personalities,
- Where were you?
- A lot of different places.
Tell me about one.
- Texas.
- No shit?
I did my bit with the Corps.
Worked an oiI rig for a while.
Spent a couple of years driving
heavy machinery in Oklahoma.
Even rode a jackhammer in Milwaukee.
You picked some very odd fuckin' places.
- No time in the slam, huh?
- No.
You're lucky.
I gotta say, when you was a kid,
I never took you for a shooter.
You weren't somebody I'd expect to drop
two guys, like I hear you did in the Bronx.
I'll do a good job for you. Take me on.
We'll see.
You wouldn't regret it.
- What do I have to do?
- It's gonna be a hoot, man.
Check him out, Pat.
Find this DeMarco guy
Jackie says is the hit.
If things check out,
relocate DeMarco in a dumpster.
Noonan's with us, I don't want the cops to
look at us for drug bullshit from the Bronx.
This is how me and Frankie deal with
guys tearing apart the neighbourhood.
Easier than sending a telegram.
Don't cost as much.
These guys get rich evicting
the real people who live here.
They kick out the Irish
to build yuppie nests.
Yuppies gotta be thicker
than the rats and the roaches.
Assholes can't live without their dogs.
Got dog shit all over the sidewalk.
It never used to be that way.
Used to be, you dropped a cone,
you could pick it up and finish it.
People wander the streets homeless
cos of these assholes.
- So we're like Robin Hood here.
- Yeah. And I'm Friar Fuck.
- What the fuck you doin'?
- 100-yard dash.
- 100-yard dash?
- Yeah.
Are you fuckin' crazy?
You'll blow up the whole place.
I'll only do it if you really want to, Terry.
All right. All right, you fuckin' asshole.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
OK.
One.
Two.
Three!
(exuberant yells)
Neighbourhood, one! Yuppies, zero!
(whooping)
Come on.
(honking horn)
(? "Trip Through Your Wires" by U2)
Bartender. Guinness.
I want you to meet Irene, man.
- Irene.
- Pleased to meet ya, Terry Noonan.
What you two boys been doin'?
Playing with matches?
- Tell you later, OK?
- You can tell me all night.
It's a long story.
What you gonna do?
- Maybe I'll come back.
- Yeah, the hell you will. (laughs)
Jackie, what the fuck are you doin'?
- Get the fuck off me!
- Rock 'n' roll!
- Look what you did.
- (Jackie) See you later, Terry.
- Have a good flight.
- Thank you very much.
Hi.
You mind I'm here?
No. No, but it's busy.
What possessed you?
Listen, I have a break in an hour.
- Meet you here?
- Sure.
- Or outside?
- Here's OK.
- Outside's better.
- OK.
I love your uniform.
Is this your dinner break?
You wanna go eat?
Yeah, we could.
I'm not hungry, really.
Frankie's kids are cute.
His wife looks great next to him in court.
They're some Laura Ashley
suburban mutation.
He commutes,
she drives a station wagon.
So what are we doin'?
I wanted to see you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Where's Jackie? Did he stand you up?
He ran into Irene.
What a slut.
So how come you don't have a boyfriend?
I do have a boyfriend. He's out of town.
I met him at the hotel. He travels a lot.
I'm lying. I recently broke up.
- I'm divorced.
- Divorced? Really?
Any kids? I hope not.
Six months ago. Yeah, no kids.
- Let's go dancing.
- Don't you want dinner?
- Don't you have to go back?
- I got somebody.
I called the girl who works the other shift.
I begged her. We can do that.
You want to go dancing with me?
Come on, Terry. No one forgets
their first love. You know that.
Just the slow ones?
Just the slow ones.
? Well, you tell us that we're wrong
? You tell us not to sing our song
? Nothing we can say will make you see
? You got a heart of stone
you can never feel
? You say: oh, I'm not afraid,
it can't happen to me
- Yeah?
- DeMarco. Buick's out front.
- Point him out.
- You gotta be kidding me, man.
In the corner. At the table.
Just wanted change.
I understand you knew a Terry Noonan.
Get out of my face. I don't know no one.
- What's this?
- We're gonna go for a little walk.
- What are you, a cop?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
- I don't know no one.
- Come on.
- I don't!
(pounding on door)
- Yeah?
- Hey, Terry. Terry, it's me, Jackie.
Frankie wants us on the job.
Now? It's two in the morning, man.
This is one of Frankie's peak hours.
- How are you, Mr Raferty?
- I'm fine, Stevie.
I got you five cases of Bushmills.
Nobody drinks it, Flannery.
It costs too much.
I'm selling it cheap. 900 bucks for
all five cases. I'm doing you a favour.
Mikey McDonnell ran
the same scam on me for 500.
Might be the reason
Mikey didn't leave nothing in his will.
(men chuckling)
I ain't paying for any
goddamn Bushmills I don't need.
Jackie, check out the bar.
- See what this gentleman needs.
- Sure thing, Frank.
Stevie, what are you doing
with these bums?
Stevie, are you gonna let
this dickhead insult us like that?
Looks like they're low. Bar got crowded
tomorrow, it'd go dry in an hour.
(men chuckle)
Ain't givin' you a fuckin' cent, Flannery.
What are you doing?
It's like beating up your grandfather.
- Shut the fuck up.
- You shut the fuck up.
- Don't tell me to shut up.
- Fuck you. You shut the fuck up.
- I won't tell you again! Shut up!
- The man's 50 years old!
- Shut up!
- You shut up!
- Fuck you!
- Stevie, shut up!
- You ain't my fuckin' father!
- Hey, Stevie!
Hey, Pat! Fuck you! Shut up!
- I want your opinion, I'll dial your asshole.
- Nicholson's the asshole.
What the fuck is goin' on here?!
- Terry! Get outta here!
- What's the matter, tough guy?
Get outta here!
Pat, you do what I'm telling you!
The bunch of you,
get the fuck outta here!
Get outta here!
I want the balance in two days, Raferty,
or you can scratch your name
out of the Yellow Pages.
- What the fuck were you doin'?
- He hit Stevie.
I know he hit him. He was supposed to.
He acted like an asshole.
Why do we have to
beat the shit out of an old man?
To scare him, you clown.
He was scared. He was already scared.
We're trying to intimidate this dickhead.
Then we're in a self-inflicted brawl
acting like a bunch of cowboys.
The one thing Borelli don't want!
He'll piss on us if he thinks
we lost our manners.
Frankie, I was fuckin' proud of ya.
Acting like yourself for a change,
jumping in there. Not like a greaseball.
You check with Borelli before you shit.
I don't know who you are half the time.
- Fuck you.
- I'm sorry if I love you.
- You're my brother.
- You're a curse.
- I've taken care of you my whole life.
- You were doin' a good job of it, too.
You fuck me up again,
the whip comes down.
- You got that? You understand me?
- Yeah.
(knocking)
- Who is it?
- Terry.
What's the matter?
Terry, what is it?
Now, Frankie, if we're gonna work
together, I got a little problem.
Somehow I got to solve it.
Is it something I could
help you with, Mr Borelli?
Stevie McGuire.
Lives in your neighbourhood.
- You know him?
- Yeah, I know him.
It's true. He runs some errands for me.
It's also true he owes
Jimmy here eight grand.
Now, eight grand's not a lot of money.
I got guys out there owe me 80.
Except I know I'm gonna
get it back from them.
It's really not the eight grand
that's got Jimmy and me upset here.
It's this McGuire kid's attitude.
Jimmy here goes asking for our money,
and this McGuire kid, he spills
a drink on Jimmy's new cashmere.
Did it deliberately.
This is what Jimmy tells me.
Now Jimmy can't get the stain out.
He's been to six fucking cleaners,
and the best they could do was fade it.
This kid just doesn't have
any respect for Jimmy here.
And if he's got no respect for Jimmy,
he's got no respect for me.
Frankie, the most important thing
in doing business is good manners.
And I really don't think it would be proper
for us to have to go into your
neighbourhood to solve our problem.
Understand?
Frankie, don't make a mess.
You kids from the Westside.
(Stevie) I'm not a connoisseur,
but I know my wine.
I know my way around if I'm at a table.
Not just by the names.
- How you doin', Stevie?
- Hi, Pat.
- We gotta talk.
- Not tonight, Pat, all right?
I'm right in the middle of
telling her my life story.
Yeah, well, it won't take long. I promise.
I gotta step outside. I'll be right back.
Cindy, right? Sandy. I'm sorry.
What's goin' on, Pat?
The eight grand you owe Jimmy Cavello.
Should have quit at two.
Cavello? What have you
got to do with Cavello?
How you doin', Stevie?
You won't cut me over eight grand
don't even belong to you.
It ain't my habit to cut people up.
I've been working on the eight grand.
I've been chipping away at it. Let me
make a phone call. I'll check on it.
You should've made it yesterday,
Stevie. Rent's overdue.
Frankie, it's me, all right?
We grew up together. We're friends.
Don't give me that bullshit.
My friends don't owe money.
You fuck! Fuck you, Frankie,
you motherfucker!
(Frankie) Fuck you. You son of a bitch!
Get the fuck off me!
- Give me the knife. Got the knife?
- Yeah. Here.
You shouldn't have fuckin' said that,
Stevie. I was gonna let Pat do this.
Pat's the expert.
Me, I'm just an amateur.
You did better than
you thought you would.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
(phone rings)
(Kathleen on machine) Hi. Please
leave a message after the beep.
(Jackie) Where the fuck are you?
Terry. Kathleen. Stevie's dead.
- Stevie's fuckin' dead.
- Jack? Jack, where are you?
(siren)
Aw, look what they fuckin' did!
- Kate.
- Hello, Frankie.
- What are you doin'?
- Frankie! Frank!
You see this, man?!
- You see this?
- What are you doin' here, Kathleen?
Oh, Jesus! They cut his throat, the fucks!
- You shouldn't have brought Kathleen.
- I want to go.
- Kathleen, I'd like to buy you breakfast.
- I gotta go.
Whoever did it, the fucker doesn't
get his cappuccino in the morning.
And I do it. I fuckin' whack him out!
- Don't you jump to conclusions.
- Hey! Hey, Terry!
I'll be right back.
- What did Frankie say?
- Stevie never hurt nobody.
I hurt people. Frankie hurts people.
Stevie borrowed money, that's all.
Who'd kill him over fuckin' money?!
You act surprised? Are you serious?
This surprises you?
Every time you turn around
somebody's dead.
- What?
- How many wakes did we go to as kids
because somebody forgot to pay money?
Every time we turn around
somebody's dead, huh? Bullshit!
Hey! See?
Stevie never hurt nobody!
Fuck you!
You'll hunt him down. You three
will conduct an investigation
untiI you find somebody
who maybe did this.
I'm glad I saw this. I was forgetting
how you are, how you think.
- It's crazy of me to be near any of you.
- Let me straighten it out.
I shouldn't be seeing you.
Can we stop? Let's just stop.
- Don't do this.
- I'm not gonna get caught... No!
I won't get caught in this any more.
I'm not falling back.
What about me? Huh?
What about me? Hold on.
- Let's go.
- No, hold on!
Here.
What about me?
All right, fuck it. I'll call you.
I'll fuckin' call.
- Let's go. I gotta go somewhere.
- Where?
Remember Mickey Cassidy? His sister
didn't wear panties to dance class?
He's dead too. He was
dumb enough to become a cop.
I gotta go to the funeral.
It's over in Queens.
- I can't stand driving in Queens.
- You want me to drive?
No. Then I'd have to look out the window.
(? "Amazing Grace" on bagpipes)
Ain't gonna be like this when we go.
Probably paste shamrocks on our
foreheads, drop us next to an expressway.
And two years later,
build a fuckin' mall on top of us.
People walking all over us
to get a fuckin' milkshake.
I'm feeling squirrelly, man.
All this fuckin' marching music.
I want a drink.
- What do you want?
- Heineken.
Two Heineken.
Cassidy's old man.
Better go pay my respects. You coming?
Go ahead.
A couple of Buds.
I'm Jackie Flannery. I knew Mickey.
Ain't smart, marching in a parade.
You're supposed to be dead.
If DeMarco were here,
he'd think he was seeing ghosts.
DeMarco is a ghost.
Somebody left him in a dumpster
in his favourite neighbourhood.
Call me.
I gotta get outta here.
I feel like I'm on Mars.
I feel surrounded.
- The guineas did Stevie, didn't they?
- Stevie owed everybody.
- (Jackie stifles sob)
- Hey.
- All right. You ready?
- Yeah.
This Stevie McGuire they found floating
in the East River, he's part of this?
- (Terry) Cavello did it.
- Could Flannery have been involved?
He didn't hit one of his own
for no reason.
- Money's always a reason.
- He didn't owe Frankie money.
As a favour, to impress Borelli.
Stevie ain't wrapped in a ribbon,
but Borelli's sense of
self- importance is soothed
that this goofball ain't
walking the streets no more.
You gotta get me outta this.
I'm gonna get caught up in this shit.
- What?
- I don't know what I'm doing here.
- You're a cop.
- These guys are my pals.
You smell like a distillery. You drink
too much. How much are you drinking?
Just listen to me.
Please fuckin' listen to me.
- You gotta get me outta this.
- I gotta get you outta this?
- You're talking like my grandma.
- Fuck!
I'm drinking too much. You're right.
Jackie's my friend. My best fuckin' friend.
I thought I could walk in
and do this, but I can't.
- It'll get outta control.
- It's a bullshit attack of feelings.
Just surgically remove the fuckers.
Get on with putting these
scumbags off the street.
You think I went to Boston to be a cop
cos I hated Boston crooks so much?
No, to get away. To get as far away as
I could so that this could never happen.
I'd never be in such circumstances
where I'd have to arrest my own friends!
These animals are your friends?
Hey, what do you know about it?
I don't know you.
Where are you from?
Poughkeepsie? White Plains?
- Stop drinking, Noonan.
- That's what I'm saying, you fuckin' idiot!
That's all they do is drink.
I'm Irish muscle in these circumstances.
We drink, we shoot people,
and I'll get caught in it.
I'm warning you,
I gotta go back to Boston.
You're talking like an asshole.
I'll run the fuck away,
where none of you can find me.
Jesus Christ, I thought you
Kitchen guys were tough guys.
We're not tough, Nick!
- Just crazy.
- You ain't either.
You're a fuckin' crybaby.
Oh, God.
You gotta get something on Flannery.
Hey. Come on.
You gotta see something
we can accuse him of.
You can get on the witness stand and say
"Him. Fuck him. Put him away."
It ain't gonna work.
Borelli and Flannery make that deal,
people will drop dead all over the city.
If that happens, Noonan,
the blood's on your hands.
It's a difficult situation.
We're here, they're there in their world.
Looks like Borelli's
gonna let us in. Now this.
- How'd you find out?
- People saw him take Stevie to the car.
Cavello was there. They all drove away.
- They think they can do this to us.
- I know that.
They don't respect us.
Cavello's head has gotta roll.
Yes, but first we're gonna show some
maturity. Can you show me maturity?
- I'm talking about the neighbourhood.
- I'm talking about I am your boss.
Borelli says nobody gets hit.
We don't have his permission.
The neighbourhood's disappearing
in a tide of yuppies and dog shit.
Borelli's our ticket
so we can retire to Phoenix.
Cavello keeps gettin' up in the morning
till I say different. You got that?
Or you want me to put it
in writing on your forehead?
Jack?
You listening to me, Jackie?
- (lrene) Stop it!
- Terry, Terry, wait. Hold it.
Jackie, stop it!
He wasn't doin' nothing!
Hey, whoa, Jack. Jackie!
You fuckin' maniac! Fuckin' maniac!
(lrene) You're crazy, you know that?
It's all right. Let him go.
- You OK, huh?
- You all right?
Broads, huh?
They put a wire around your dick
and lead you around like Dodo the dog.
You gotta marry 'em to forget 'em.
Don't worry about Jackie.
Sit down. Sit down a minute, Terry.
I want to talk to you.
So, you like Kate, huh?
- You've been seeing her.
- Yeah.
You gotta trust me on this one.
It's a crime, but she holds people
like you and me in nothin' but contempt.
You heard of ice queens? My sister Kate
has moved a Frigidaire inside herself.
I'm just tryin' to let you
learn from my experience.
If she thinks I'm shit,
what will she make of you?
Don't you think we ought to
be worried about Jackie?
Yeah, you're right. Keep an eye on Jackie.
Keep him out of trouble.
I'm countin' on you, Terry.
Pat.
- Something wrong?
- I don't know.
When you're not too busy,
keep an eye on Noonan for me.
Love to.
(buzzer)
- Who is it?
- Kate, it's Terry.
I'm sorry I'm here,
but Jackie's disappeared.
I looked everywhere. I can't find him.
You got any idea where he might be?
Jack.
I'd offer you a beer, Kate,
except I drank all of it.
You know...
we'd come here...
But not now.
I thought about Stevie
as hard as I could.
I hope that he's praying.
I should've known to look for you here.
Do you remember Stevie used to
come here... and hide with us?
Nobody'd ever think we'd come in here
without a nun dragging us in by the ear.
Like Father whatshisface.
Remember him?
He had too much spit, so he foamed
at the mouth when he gave the sermon.
(Kate) We were kids.
(Terry) It's peaceful here, right.
Look at all the saints.
There's St Anthony and St Francis.
Who's that one over there?
Hey.
(bottle rolls)
Let's go see St Anthony.
Maybe he wants a drink.
(Terry) Jackie!
I don't think he wants a drink, Jack.
No.
- He's a teetotaller.
- (drops bottle)
I'm sorry.
(sobs)
- Jackie.
- Jack, come on.
I'm gonna make Stevie a saint.
I'm gonna make Stevie a saint!
(whispers) I'm gonna make Stevie a saint.
I'm gonna make Stevie a saint.
(Jackie sobs)
- Come on. What...?
- You want some?
No, I don't want some.
Terry, stop it! What are you doin'?!
What are you doin'? Terry, stop it!
(Terry sobs)
What are you doin'?
- Come here.
- I'm a cop!
I'm a cop. I'm a fuckin' Judas cop!
- Terry...
- I gotta go.
- What are you sayin'?
- I don't know.
What are you talking about?
What the fuck are you talking about?
(? "Street Fighting Man"
by the Rolling Stones)
Uh-uh.
- What's wrong? Your stomach upset?
- It's hard to get up in the morning.
It's like pulling my socks over my shoes.
- Yeah?
- Like I'm in this fuckin' fog.
Terry, you're missing the point here.
I can't remember shit.
That's the way I like it.
Only hint of a problem is,
I need a little Maalox.
But I can buy Maalox.
- You always were tougher than me.
- I always thought I was just crazier.