Corrections made by Darkon11.
With the help of submerge.delarue-berlin.de
Looks like she's dragged in a real crowd.
Sure does. Looks like
it's going to be a full house tonight.
What do you say
we run in and check out the show?
- How are we doing? All set?
- Big crowd, huh?
Yeah, and not one of them
has got a pot to piss in.
I let myself get talked into this benefit.
I could be making real money tonight.
Let's get this thing started.
(cheering)
(announcer) And now, back home again,
the one, the only Ellen Aim!
I love you, Ellen.
# Lying in your bed on a Saturday night
sweating buckets and it's not even hot
# But your brain has got the message
and it's sending it out
# To every nerve
and every muscle you've got
# You've got so many dreams
that you don't know where to put them
# So you'd better turn a few of 'em loose
# Your body's got a feeling
that it's starting to rust
# You'd better rev it up and put it to use
# And I don't know how I ever thought
that I could make it all alone
# When you only make it better
and it better be tonight
# I'll be there for you tonight
# Even if you don't have anywhere to go
you go down on the pedal, ready to roll
# And your speed is all you'll ever need
All you'll ever need to know
# Darlin', darlin', you and me,
we're going nowhere slowly
# And we gotta get away from the past
# There's nothing wrong
with going nowhere, baby
# But we should be going nowhere fast
It's so much better going nowhere fast
# Stalking in the shadows
by the light of the moon
# It's like a prison and the night is a cell
# Going anywhere
has gotta be heaven tonight
# Cos staying here has gotta be hell
# Dying in the city
like a fire on the water
# Let's go running on the back of the wind
# There's gotta be some action
on the face of the earth
# And I gotta see your face once again
# I don't know where I ever got
the bright idea that I was cool
# So alone and independent
but I'm depending on you now
# And you'll always be the only thing
that I just can't be without
# And I'm out for you tonight
I'm coming out for you tonight
# Even if you don't have anywhere to go
# You go down on the pedal
and you're ready to roll
# And your speed is all you'll ever need
All you'll ever need to know
# Darlin', darlin', you and me,
we're going nowhere slowly
# And we gotta get away from the past
# There's nothing wrong
with going nowhere, baby
# But we should be going nowhere fast
# Everybody's going nowhere slowly
# They're only fighting
for the chance to be last
# There's nothing wrong
with going nowhere, baby
# But we should be going nowhere fast
# Godspeed! Godspeed!
# Godspeed! Speed us away!
- # Godspeed! Speed us away!
- # We're going nowhere fast
- # Godspeed!
- # Going nowhere fast
# Godspeed! Speed us away!
# We're going nowhere fast
- # Godspeed!
- # Going nowhere fast
- # I'm going nowhere fast
# Godspeed! Speed us away!
(cheering)
Now!
What the hell are you doing?
What are you guys doing?
Hey, we don't want no trouble.
Put me down! No!
Put me down! You bastards, put me down!
No! No! Let me go!
Put me down!
(screaming)
Help me!
(siren)
Get him!
- Goddamn son-of-a-bitches.
- Hang a 180.
What's with that guy?
- Watch out.
- These guys are gonna pay.
Someone save me!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
- Can I help you?
- Coffee.
- Cream and sugar?
- Just black.
(wolf whistle)
You know how to come through a door.
What are you trying to prove?
We just came down from King's Park
looking for a good time.
You guys already missed
all the excitement. The party's over.
The Roadmasters are hungry,
and when they're hungry,
they eat.
The Bombers
have brought this act through.
- All you're doing is looking like punks.
- Is that right?
We're just gonna
have to mess the place up.
(china and glass smash)
And after we mess your place up,
maybe we'll mess you up.
You got a problem with this, pretty boy?
Try it again, punk.
Come on.
Go on, go home.
- What do you think of my new car?
- Looks great.
Sell it and buy me a new window.
Tom, come on, slow down.
Reva, there is no point stealing a car
and not wringing it out.
- When are you going to grow up?
- Why should I? This is more fun.
Let me give you some news. The
Bombers and this guy Raven Shaddock,
they stole Ellen Aim.
- How the hell did that happen?
- (police siren)
- Oh, shit.
- Goddamn cops.
OK, what do you think this is? We don't
go for that speeding here. Your licence.
Sorry, officer, I must've left it at home.
Tom Cody, it's been a couple of years
since I've had any trouble out of you.
Ed, I came home to visit my big sister.
You won't have any trouble.
Glad to hear it. We don't need somebody
coming here to give us a hard time.
Come on, Ed, he just got back.
Give him a break.
Yeah, I'll give him a break.
Get out of here, Cody.
Any more driving like that
and I'll give you a ticket.
Asshole.
Who the hell does that guy think he is?
He's always been a real badass.
I busted him a couple of years ago.
He had a pistol
in the glove compartment of his car.
Real punk, huh?
He belongs in jail
with all the other delinquents.
Sure I'm not going to be
cramping your style with any guy?
Not tonight. I bring one in now and then
but there's nothing steady.
- I never find the right one.
- I ain't much luck in that department.
Look, Tom, you were close with Ellen.
She wasn't like those tramps you ran with.
- Reva, it didn't work out, OK?
- Somebody figured how to make it work.
- She's been living with a guy, Billy Fish.
- Who?
He's done some rock joints in the Battery.
Started managing her.
Yeah, she was always interested
in going someplace.
Tom!
- She's not just your old girlfriend.
- What do you want?
You know.
You want me to rescue an old girlfriend
shacked up with another guy? Thanks.
- Tequila.
- Hey, Tom! Tom Cody!
A long time, pal.
How's your hammer hanging?
- How's it going, Clyde?
- Not so hot.
I got beat up trying to save your old girl.
I could have used a little help.
You should have been there, Tom.
It would've been like the old days.
We'd have kicked ass.
Hey, bartender, do you want to shoot
the shit or get me another drink?
Hey, would you get a load of this honey?
She thinks she owns the place.
I'm just trying to get myself a drink, pal.
Well, maybe you've
already had enough, babe.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- Do I look like it?
Maybe you ought to pay up. You've
been driving up a tab here all night.
- We're not big on credit.
- Are you saying I can't pay?
Yeah, let's see the colour of your money.
- There, happy.
- Yeah, but now I don't like your face.
You know, everywhere I go,
there's always an asshole.
- Hey, have you got any preferences?
- I've always been a tequila man.
Let's get out of here.
My name's McCoy. I'm a soldier. At least,
I was up until a year ago. I ran out of wars.
- Yeah, what's your spec?
- Motor pool, nothing fancy.
- If it's got wheels, I can drive it and fix it.
- That's funny. I just got out.
- Been R & R ever since.
- Yeah, how did you like the army?
I liked shooting the guns,
but I didn't win no medal.
Hey!
- Is that your car?
- Yeah.
- Nice.
- I know. I just picked it up.
Hey, Cody. That's your name, right? Cody.
- Yeah.
- You got a spare bed?
You want a quick tumble, huh?
You may have a rough time with this one
and I don't wanna hurt your feelings.
You're not my type.
Yeah, I guess it figures.
I ain't had much luck with women lately.
Yeah, you'll live. Something tells me
that getting girls ain't your problem.
- Maybe some other time.
- I doubt it, but anything's possible.
Hey, look.
About the spare bed. I'm just passing
through. I don't know anybody.
I'm between jobs and last time I heard,
hotels cost money.
Get in.
My sister's got the bedroom. I've got
the spare. That puts you on the couch.
- Thanks, man, I appreciate it.
- Yeah, no sweat.
There you go, McCoy.
I'll see you in the morning.
- Hey, you always walk around packed?
- I told you, I'm a soldier.
Well, don't go pointing
that thing at me. I wouldn't like it.
I don't go pointing it
unless I'm gonna use it.
Yeah, right.
# Take a look at my eyes
# No' you can't hide the truth
# You don't get by on pride
# lt'll run over you
# But since you let me down
I'm hard to be around
# I don't know what I'm gonna do
lt'll never be you
# Never be you
(knocking)
OK, you got it. I'm gonna go and get her.
But I ain't doing it for nothing.
Tell this Mr Billy Fish to meet me
at the diner tomorrow at 12.00.
Me and him
are going to talk some business.
And there's a girl I picked up
sleeping on the couch.
- Give her some coffee in the morning.
- How come she's in the front room?
Why don't you go ask her?
Hey, Pete!
Hey, I really needed a place to stay.
Thanks for the sofa.
Oh, that's OK. You're the first girl
Tom ever brought home that used it.
Sometimes it helps a guy out
if you don't make it so easy.
He could use a little help in that direction.
He ought to meet a few more like you.
Fella came through here
a couple of months ago.
Tapped out, had to part
with this outfit after a card game.
Real unhappy about it too
because it's all custom stuff.
Tom wasn't going for being
number two to her music.
So he took off. He was crazy about Ellen.
He's the kind that doesn't like to admit it.
Sure, I know the type.
Some people who never talk about their
feelings got 'em deeper than anybody.
Others never talk
about them cos they ain't got any.
- What's your story?
- Me? Just looking for work.
- You must be Billy Fish.
- Yeah.
So what gives? Make it fast,
my time is valuable.
You want Ellen Aim back.
I'm gonna get her.
- You and what army?
- I can see you two will get along just fine.
- I want ten grand.
- Easy, all you gotta do is earn it.
I'll earn it, and you're gonna help. Reva
told me you used to live in the Battery.
I started out there. It's the shits. I wouldn't
go back to that dump if you paid me.
You're goin'. I need somebody
who knows their way around.
I don't think so. It's not my scene.
If you want your meal ticket back,
get in the car, otherwise the deal is off.
Cody, you sound pretty dumb,
but nobody's that dumb.
I'm the one paying you. That means
you go get her and bring her back to me.
You smart guys always figure you can
hire a bum like me to do your dirty work.
- Well, not this time.
- Can you really get her back?
You got a better volunteer?
All right, I'll go.
She's real important to me.
The Battery is gonna be
nothing but trouble.
Yeah? Well, I'm getting paid for it.
Right, Fish?
- That's right, Cody.
- Cut me in, I'll back you up.
- I don't think so.
- We're not taking no skirt along.
- Look, I don't think you can handle it, OK?
- What do I gotta do?
People don't have written references
for this work.
You should know that, Cody.
I need the job. I'm plenty good enough
and I ain't gonna let you down.
Listen, skirt, let me make it simple
for you. Take a hike.
All right, I'll cut you in
for ten per cent but get this.
You're working for me. I tell you to do
something, you do it, no more, no less.
And if you start dragging your ass,
I'm sending you home.
- I got it.
- What is this? Get serious.
I'm not paying you to take
some sweetie-pie along for company.
You drive.
Don't worry about it. They always hire
bums like me for jobs like this.
I'll take you to where the Bombers
hang out, but I'm not taking any risks.
I'm not paying you to add thrills to my life.
You've got a big mouth.
Butch, I buy and sell people
more valuable than you every day.
It's hard to figure out what's more
pathetic, the way you talk or dress.
Let me tell you. These clothes
are worth more than you make in a year.
I can see working with you two
is gonna be a real dream.
If they've got her anywhere, it's Torchie's.
It's a knockdown joint, no class.
I used to book bands in there. It's in
the middle of a big factory. It's the shits.
You'll love it, McCoy. Just your style.
OK, Cody, what's the plan?
How do you figure to handle these guys?
Kill Bombers and we'll be in worse shape
than we're already in.
I don't have to kill anybody. Motorcycles
don't run when you shoot holes in them.
Some neighbourhood. Everything's dead.
What a place to come to.
Keep going straight
then turn left under the bridge.
- What, are you giving the orders now?
- I know my way around, remember?
I'll take care of the orders. Get under
the bridge, pull over and kill the lights.
# Well, one bad stud moved
in my neighbourhood
# He's big and, man,
I know he ain't no good
# He don't wear no hat,
and, Lord, he don't wear no shoes
# He just hangs on the corner
singing old country blues
# Well, one bad stud
# One bad stud
One bad stud
# I said, one, one, one, one
# If he likes your baby,
you can kiss your baby goodbye
# Cos the girls all love him
like a schoolboy loves his pie
# He loves his whiskey,
he loves his rock'n'rye
# Yes, he loves his whiskey,
# You know it takes ten bottles
to make that fool get high
# Well, one bad stud...
You're making things
real hard on yourself.
You act nice, you and me fall in love
for a week or two, and then I let you go.
Nobody gets hurt.
You see? I ain't such a bad guy.
I just get excited around pretty girls.
# Well, one bad stud
# One bad stud
One bad stud
# I said, one, one, one, one
(music climaxes)
From now on, any mistakes
and I'm making you walk home.
- Walk around here? I'd get killed.
- You got it. What about you, McCoy?
Are we gonna do it
or are we gonna talk about it?
All right.
The main drag is around here somewhere.
- What the hell's that?
- I guess you don't know who I am.
Things have got funny around here.
All kinds of strangers
sneaking through the alleys.
What the hell are we talking
to this creep for? Let's get outta here.
My gosh, you're scared.
What's even funnier, you're afraid of me.
Trying to get away from you.
We've got business.
Oh, you're dumb. And you're short.
- Real short.
- (she laughs)
- You're after that girl, aren't you?
- What makes you say that?
You're down a back alley
at night with a bunch of guns.
You here to give the Battery
a coat of paint?
- Where are they keeping her?
- Torchie's.
- Don't tell 'em I told you, though.
- Pay him.
- Yeah, pay me.
- I'm not gonna pay this jerk.
Shithead, give him some of your money
or I'll give him some of your money.
Don't call me shithead.
You've gotta keep moving forward.
That's the point of things. I appreciate it.
You could buy some soap.
I don't need this guy to tell me she's
at Torchie's. I said she was at Torchie's.
I am a shithead.
OK, Fish, head back to the car.
I want you in that doorway in 15 minutes.
- And I mean 15 minutes.
- They'll notice me in a second there.
I'll give them other things to worry about.
What about her?
She was supposed to drive.
Get moving. You better be ready
when we get there.
- Do you trust him or are you desperate?
- Take the front entrance. I'll go topside.
If you can work your way upstairs, fine.
If not, I'll handle it.
Just what I always wanted to do, Cody.
Take on the Bombers.
Hey, baby!
(shouting)
# I've been around the world
And every man bleeds the same
# But when the lights are dim
You never know who's to blame
# I don't want no scars to show
I don't want no one to know
# So I'll be killing time in the blue shadows
# No other place for me to go
# No other place for dying slow
# So I'll be killing time in the blue shadows
# I've been around the world
I'll take credit for the things I've done
# But when the lights are dim
I'm not the only guilty one
# I don't want no scars to show
I don't want no one to know
# So I'll be killing time in the blue shadows
Hey! Hey! How are you doing, babe?
Come around here much?
- Only for some action.
- You're talking to the right guy.
- Says who?
- Says me.
- I like a guy that's got confidence.
- All right.
# I've been around the world
And every story ends the same
(whistle)
# I don't want no scars to show
I don't want no one to know
# So I'll be killing time in the blue shadows
That way's the card game. We're going
down here. We've got a party to go to.
# No other place for dying slow
Check it out, baby. This is the party room.
How do you like it, huh?
Had a lot of good times here
so let's party, huh?
Hey, killer.
- Can I take my jacket off first?
- You can take off whatever you want.
All right... Now listen to me, buddy.
There is just one thing I want you to do.
- That is to keep quiet.
- Come on, babe, is this thing loaded?
We'll play a game you Bombers will like.
It's called Lights Out.
# No place for me to go
No other place for dying slow
# So I'll be killing time
# Just killing time
# So I'll be killing time in the blue shadows
Knock, knock.
(commotion)
Go ahead and take that money, sweetie.
You better pray you get out of the Battery.
- I don't think she's after the money.
- (distant gunshot)
Get out of here!
Poker's a real interesting game
when you've got all the best cards.
Next time, right in your nuts, pal.
Guys, it's been a slice.
- Who are you?
- I'm a big fan.
Come on. Let's go.
Who is that guy?
What the hell's going on here?
Move it, move it!
- Which way?
- Follow me.
Jesus, am I glad to see you?
I thought you were gone forever.
- This is no time to check out the sights.
- I'm gonna run these guys.
- I'm staying with you.
- Stay in the car.
Stay with your boyfriend.
McCoy, meet me at Grand St underpass.
If we don't see you, Cody, have a nice life.
Can't you drive this car any faster? I don't
want any Bombers sneaking up on us.
- Where's Grand St? I never heard of it.
- Turn it off, Fish, you sound pathetic.
Well...
Looks like I finally ran into someone
that likes to play as rough as I do.
- Yeah, this must be your lucky night.
- I'm lucky?
I guess maybe I am.
You're dumb, real dumb,
if you think you can pull this off.
I think you're forgetting something.
I got the gun.
I can get guns, smart guy, lots of 'em.
- Now, why don't you tell me your name?
- Tom Cody. Pleased to meet ya.
I'll be coming for her.
And I'll be coming for you too.
Sure you will, and I'll be waitin'.
A couple of minutes
and then we get out of here.
- What are you talking about?
- Saving our ass. We've a lot to live for.
He got me.
I'm not going back without him.
Don't worry, he's getting paid
a lot of money to look after Raven.
- What money?
- Do you think it's for love?
You think he's doing this cos he's a fan?
He's getting paid. He takes his chances.
Hey, too bad, Billy.
Looks like Ellen's old flame
decided to show up.
OK, we're on the move.
- What is this old flame stuff?
- Ellen used to go with Cody.
Real hot'n'heavy from what I heard.
Know what I mean?
- Is she kidding?
- Let's not get into it now, OK, Billy?
Hard news, huh, shorty?
Cody, we've had our differences
but it looks like we've got it made now.
We just zoom along here
then we're home and dry.
I got news for you. It ain't that simple.
We've got to bury the car.
- Bury the car? What?
- He means "get rid of it", stupid.
Get rid of the car? What's wrong with it?
Is this what I'm paying you for,
these brilliant ideas?
Why don't we hand ourselves
over to Raven and ask him to shoot us?
You two go ahead.
I want to talk alone with Tom for a minute.
What are you talking about?
What are you going with him for?
I don't like the way this looks. I'm paying
the bills. How about some respect?
- What do you want to talk about?
- I've got a lot to say.
No, you don't. You have nothing
to say to me. Go talk to your boyfriend.
What was I supposed to do? I had work.
Things were starting to happen for me.
- Yeah, so bye-bye, Tom, right?
- You took off and joined the army.
Forget all this. It's history.
From now on, I'm just like you.
I do what I'm good at. I do it for money.
- Is that why you came and got me?
- Right. Billy Fish is paying me ten grand.
- I can't believe you'd do that.
- You'd better get used to the idea.
- Wonder what they're talking about.
- Who says they're talking?
- Cute.
- It's just a joke. You know what I mean?
How big a thing do you think they had?
- From what I hear, it was real major.
- Well, she's with me now.
Right, against a big, tough, good-looking
guy like you, Cody don't stand a chance.
- I hope you two straightened things out.
- Yeah, we got a lot straightened out.
- It was a real eye-opener.
- I think I hurt your girlfriend's feelings.
What does he mean? What did he say?
Did he say anything about me? Tell me.
# I'm tired
# I'm thirsty
# I'm wild-eyed
# In my misery
# Timeless
# In your finery
# A high price
# For your luxury, yeah
# Sorcerer
# Who is the master?
# Man and woman on a star stream
# In the middle of a snow dream
# Sorcerer
# Show me the high life
# Come over
# Let me put you on ice
# I'm tired
# When I need you badly
# Wild-eyed
# In the middle of a dream
# Timeless
Hey, hi, you guys.
Where are you guys going?
- We're nobody, going nowhere.
- Nobody goes nowhere.
Knock it off, we're not interested
in conversation, OK, moron?
I know you.
I love your stuff so much. I really do.
Look, if you love me so much,
go away and leave us alone.
No, look, I'm your biggest fan.
Let me go with you.
And I tell you, you gotta get off the street.
The cops know the guys that
hit the Battery are coming through here.
Shit. We've gotta get a new set of wheels.
Great, we just got rid of the old wheels.
Wonderful leadership, Cody.
What's the matter with you?
Are you looking to get run over?
- Me and my friends need a lift.
- So what? This ain't no muni bus.
- We need a lift real bad.
- Look.
Let me make it real clear. Nobody tells me
where to take my bus. You dig?
We're very flexible. We'll take you where
you want to go. You just say the word.
You folks just hop right in.
Make yourselves at home.
I'm driving.
Bird, what the hell are you doing?
Get off this bus. Oh, man.
Hey, how are you guys doing? Don't
worry, we're not gonna hurt you none.
That's great. Oh, I'm glad to hear that.
We're the Sorels. I'm Bird.
These are my associates. This is Lester.
My man BJ. And that's Reggie.
- Aren't you Ellen Aim?
- That's right. It's Ellen Aim.
Hey, Ellen, do you guys need an opener?
We're good.
- We are.
- We can't seem to get anything going.
I handle the management and the
booking. Shut up and leave Ellen alone.
- What did he say?
- I know how tough it can be.
- Baby, you don't even begin to know.
- What did I tell you guys? Cool it.
Hey!
If you've got any chance
of missing the cops, it's through here.
- Yeah, so what are our chances?
- Horrible.
- And terrible.
- That's just great.
Look, we don't want to mess
with Ardmore cops.
They busted me and threw my ass right
in jail because I wouldn't pay 'em off.
- What did they bust you for?
- Disturbing the peace.
- They said I got out of line in some bar.
- Great. I love a girl with class.
- This is great.
- You want to help change this tyre?
Changing flat tyres isn't
exactly my line of work, dear.
If that's the case,
then why don't you shut up?
(mocking grumble)
I wish I could write songs. I just can't
figure out how to do it right, like you do it.
I can't figure out how you work out
the rhymes and the melodies.
Somebody else writes the songs.
Billy buys or steals them. I can't write.
- I always thought those were your songs.
- I just sing 'em.
Yeah, but when you sing 'em, you make
it yours. That's the way it is, right?
I guess so. Who knows?
The famous Sorels sure put
a lot of money into that bus.
I didn't know you had a thing with Ellen.
You better get some smarts.
Adjust to the fact you're out of the picture.
You see, I do things for her,
things a guy like you could never do.
Things that matter in the real world.
You know, the only trouble with kicking
the shit out of you is it would be too easy.
Keep your hands off the suit, buddy.
Come on, hurry the hell up
with that flat tyre. Let's get going.
# Ten, nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four, three, two, one
# Remember when you didn't love me
# Now all the time you're thinking of me
# If life is great, you're all I'm living for
# This is my countdown to love
# Oh, this is my countdown to love
# You are the one love in my life
# I know you feel that way too
# Oh, what a thrill
when I'm holding you near
# All of my wild dreams come true
# Forever more you'll be my lover
# Because for me
there'll never be another
# Together forever
we'll be as one
- (laughs) Pretty good, you guys.
- # This is my countdown to love
- Cody.
Ellen, Baby Doll, get down in the back.
Fish, McCoy, we work for the Sorels.
- Fish, you're the manager.
- I'm way ahead of you, Cody.
I'll handle this. I'll talk us through.
Hey, guys, how's it going?
I'm the bus driver here for the Sorels.
We're on our way to a gig
at an after-hours joint.
- The Sorels, the singers. You know 'em?
- No, never heard of 'em.
- You know what's going on here?
- All I know is we're running real late.
Babe, some outfit broke into the Battery
and burned it down.
- Really?
- Knock off the crap, will ya?
Anybody that goes into the Battery and
does some damage deserves a medal.
- Let me tell you how we look at it.
- Cut the shit, OK?
You guys have got a big job to do.
Now, let us through or do you want
to come to a financial arrangement?
- What do you think, Harry?
- What we've got here is a model citizen.
I knew you guys talked my language.
Keep it coming.
- Just take a big bite.
- That's right.
- There's some integrity left in the force!
- You are too anxious to buy us off.
- Spade musicians and a wad of money.
- (all) Spade?
All right, everybody off the bus.
All right. Now, this is
how we're going to play it.
You're going to walk off this bus
like there's nothing wrong. Get me?
- All right, down on the ground.
- Do it now!
- All right. OK.
- Get on with it.
Don't worry about it, fellas.
We'll be out of your face in no time.
Some of you have got cute little asses.
A shame to blow them off.
- Get down.
- Holy shit.
- (wild cheering)
- All right.
Come on, man, let's get outta here.
Let's go.
(shouting)
- Go! Go!
- (shouting)
Shut the hell up! McCoy, pull down
a back alley. We need to dump the bus.
First he dumps the car and now the bus.
Code 99. Code 99.
Blockade across on Ardmore.
- Over here.
- Suspects armed and dangerous.
Repeat, armed and dangerous.
Broke blockade.
Heading north on Ardmore.
Cannot pursue. Do you copy?
Goddamn it, this is the blockade
at Ardmore. Come back to me.
Whoa!
(sirens)
- Move over.
- Faster.
- We had $1,000 in that bus.
- I lost my clothes. The luggage is gone.
- All the sheet music is gone.
- This is great.
- On our way to the Richmond. No bus.
- You shouldn't have stopped.
I...
He ain't a real social kind of guy, is he?
Really?
Gee, I think he's a real sweetheart.
Cut him some slack. He was there for you.
Yeah, he earned his money.
You've got a funny way of sayin' thanks
when someone saves your ass.
Why don't you go and sit with your pal
Billy? I guess he's more your kind of guy.
Yeah, I think maybe I will.
Don't worry, babe.
Everything is going to be OK from now on.
We're gonna be great.
Reva, Ellen Aim is back. Tom is with her.
- Is he OK?
- He looked all right to me.
Chief.
Tom.
Aw, Reva, cut it out. We made it.
Everybody's in one piece.
What about that, Ellen? You OK?
- Yeah, I'm all right, I guess.
- She's tired. She's been roughed up.
I'm gonna take her back to the hotel
so she can get some rest.
This started because of a gig
in this shithole.
I should have stayed
the hell away from this dump.
- Is that the way you feel about it, Ellen?
- I just want to get away from here.
- Get back on the road.
- Now you're talking, kiddo.
Come on, let's get outta here.
I hate you for taking money
to come and get me.
That's tellin' him, Ellen.
(cheering)
I guess she doesn't like you much.
She doesn't seem thankful.
- One thing about you, you catch on quick.
- That's right and I get the job done.
Good. Because I think it's just starting.
(motorcycle)
- What does he want to talk about?
- Tom Cody.
I want Tom Cody.
I want to nail his head to the sidewalk
under the marquee that says "Ellen Aim".
And just to prove to you
I'm gonna be a nice guy,
I'm coming in with just two of my men.
After I take care of Cody,
there'll be no more trouble.
Do your job, man. Keep the peace.
Hey, Cody, I need a drink.
Let's get outta here.
Maybe I can pick a fight
with that bartender.
No, not this time.
Hey, McCoy, look,
I'll get you your money later, OK?
Is that all you've got to say?
Yeah, that's all.
What else do you wanna hear?
- Look, I did real good back there.
- So what? I'm all out of medals.
Besides, you're getting paid.
You know, Reva. Ellen Aim was right
about one thing. Your brother's a jerk.
What's your problem?
Feeling sorry for yourself?
- Don't start on me, Reva.
- She tells you it doesn't mean a thing.
The worst part
is she runs off with Billy Fish.
I didn't ask you to go out and get Ellen
Aim because she looks great on stage.
- What the hell do you care about, then?
- About you.
And this town. If you're gonna fight,
you're supposed to fight for something.
You and Billy Fish are the same.
You're both selfish. All you worry about...
- Hi, Ed.
- I came to talk to your brother.
Come on outside.
Raven says he has to face you alone
right here in the Richmond.
I'm ordering you to get out of town, Tom.
I want you on a train tonight.
If Raven comes in here to face you,
I'll be waiting for him with a lot of guns.
I'm throwing his ass in jail.
I am not gonna sit around and watch
two maniacs play out
some little game about personal honour.
I want you gone.
If you're in town tomorrow,
I'm throwing your ass in jail
right next to Raven.
Look, you did real good
rescuing her, Tom. You surprised me.
I didn't think you had it in you. Surprise
me again. Do something else real good.
Be on that train tonight.
- (knocking)
- Yeah, come in.
Hey, I'll get it. Who is it?
Oh...
- What the hell are you still doing here?
- I'll see you guys later, all right?
I've been expecting you.
I know what you want. Ten grand.
I'm as good as my word. I pay on time.
You play rough, but you do a good job.
You should do a little more work for me.
Then you'll realise I'm the one with
the brains here and you'll treat me nicer.
Nobody had a hold on me the way you
did. I would have done anything for you.
A long time ago, I would have thought
you were worth it. Not any more, babe.
Where do you get off talking to her
like that? She's way out of your league.
This is the grand I promised McCoy.
You can keep the rest.
You know what's wrong with that guy?
He's stupid.
- Sorry, Billy.
- What? Where are you goin'?
Tom! Tom, wait! Tom!
Wait!
What was I supposed to do? I hadn't heard
from you in two years, not even a letter.
What did I do that was so wrong?
You gotta go away. You've fought
enough fights. Let this one go.
- With both of us gone...
- What do you mean, both of us?
I want to go with you.
We could be together.
- You'd really come along with me?
- In two seconds I would.
Please?
Well...
- If it isn't my old pal Tom Cody.
- How's it going?
Great till you got here.
I've been talking things over with Clyde.
- Remember, he and I used to be close.
- Hey, Tom, tequila, right?
There's what I owe you.
You did real good back there.
I couldn't have got her out without you.
Maybe I rode you a little harder
than I should have.
Don't get sentimental on me.
I wouldn't know how to handle it.
Hey, I got a problem with Ellen
I gotta talk to you about.
I understand about these kind of things.
I was actually in love once myself.
- Didn't work out.
- You make bad picks?
He was the worst.
Lied to me all the time. Cheated on me.
- If I run into him, I'll give him your best.
- That was before I was a soldier.
- You're real crazy about Ellen, aren't you?
- I don't know. I guess I am.
Nothing wrong with it,
nothing to be embarrassed about.
I ain't embarrassed. Ellen and I are going
in different directions. Nobody's fault.
Maybe you're right. You don't look
like no backup singer to me.
Look, I need your help tonight.
I gotta do something I don't want to do.
- Come on.
- Tom? This is not the Bayside.
There is something I gotta take care of.
Get as far from here as you can.
Run until the Bayside. Hang out there.
Sure, tough guy.
- When does this train take off?
- We don't.
Lady, I gotta get moving. It's important.
You ain't gonna get there on this train.
Hey!
- Maybe you better think about it.
- The Bombers have gone crazy.
They're doing everything they can
to seal off the Richmond.
Let's go.
What the hell are you doing here, Clyde?
I told everybody to get off the streets.
Yeah, but I wanna see
Raven run from up close.
Just stay out of the way.
- Well?
- Real simple.
There's no showdown. Tom Cody
ain't here and neither is the girl.
- I don't get it.
- Get off your bike, Raven.
I ain't too crazy about jails, Chief.
I got a better idea for you.
(sounds horn)
Holy shit!
They're coming! They're here!
I told your friend Cody
I could get a lot of guns.
Get out of my way. What the hell?
What is this? You think you can ride into
any town and kidnap anybody you want?
Get the hell outta town
and leave these people alone.
- Sorry I'm late.
- I got something special in mind.
I brought them along just for you.
Well, my plan went to shit.
Let's see how you do.
Kick his ass.
(approaching voices)
Come on, kill 'em!
Nice, huh?
(cheering)
Kill him!
Drop him!
Tom!
(cheering)
(wild cheering)
Let's get outta here!
# No more timing
each tear that falls from my eyes
# I'm not hiding the remedy
to cure this old heart of mine
# I can dream about you
if I can't hold you tonight
# I can dream about you...
You know something, Waldo?
- We're gonna be rich.
- Yeah, long live rock'n'roll.
# I can dream about you
if I can't hold you tonight
You know how to hold me just right
# Moving sidewalks
I don't see under my feet
Great, huh? My new discovery.
I'll take them right up the ladder.
Yeah, they oughtta make you
a lot of money, Fish.
Don't worry. I won't stand in your way
with Ellen. I know how it is between you.
There's one thing we both know.
She needs you more than she needs me.
- Yeah, she needs me but she loves you.
- She'll get over it.
- She's used to me being unreliable.
- Is that what I'm supposed to tell her?
You're OK with words.
You'll make her feel better than I could.
Take it easy, Cody. Thanks.
I'll take it wherever I can get it.
# Climbing up from the pain in my heart
cos it's you that I need
(cheering)
# I can dream
Everybody!
# Yes, I can dream
# I don't understand it
I can't keep my mind off loving you
# Not even for a minute
# Oh, now, baby
# I'm caught up in the magic I see in you
There's one thing to do...
I guess you're just gonna cut out, huh?
- Yeah, you know me.
- Yeah, you're the guy with the right hook.
Is that it? Is that all you have left to say?
Look, I know you're gonna be
goin' places with your singing.
I'm not the kind of guy that will carry
any guitars around for you.
But if you ever need me
for something, I'll be there.
# I can dream about you
# I'm gonna press my lips
against you and hold you to me
# I can dream about you
# You know you've got me spellbound
What else can it be?
# I can dream
# Dreaming about you...
(music ends' cheering)
# I've got a dream about an angel
on the beach
# And the perfect waves
are starting to come
# His hair is flying out in ribbons of gold
and his touch has got the power to stun
# I've got a dream
about an angel in the forest
# Enchanted by the edge of a lake
# His body's flowing in the jewels alive
and the earth below is starting to shake
# But I don't see any angels in the city
I don't hear any holy choirs sing
# And if I can't get an angel I can still get
a boy and a boy'd be the next best thing
# The next best thing to an angel
# A boy'd be the next best thing
# I've got a dream about a boy in a castle
and he's dancing like the cat on the stairs
# He's got the fire of a prince in his eyes
and the thunder of a drum in his ears
# I've got a dream about a boy on a star
lookin' down upon the rim of the world
# He's there all alone
and dreamin' of someone like me
# I'm not an angel but at least I'm a girl
# I've got a dream when the darkness is
over, we'll be lyin' in the rays of the sun
# But it's only a dream
and tonight is for real
# You'll never know what it means but
you'll know how it feels, it's gonna be over
# Before you know it's begun
# It's all we really got tonight
# Stop your cryin', hold on tonight
Before you know it, it's gone tonight
# Tonight is what it means to be young
Tonight is what it means to be young
# Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the restless
and the brokenhearted
# Let the rebels begin
Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the desperate
and the brokenhearted
# Let the rebels begin
# Tonight is what it means to be young
Before you know it, it's gone
# Say a prayer in the darkness
for the magic to come
# No matter what it seems
Tonight is what it means to be young
# Tonight is what it means to be young
Before you know it, it's gone
# I've got a dream when the darkness is
over, we'll be lyin' in the rays of the sun
# But it's only a dream
and tonight is for real
# You'll never know what it means
But you'll know how it feels
# It's gonna be over
before you know it's begun
# It's all we really got tonight
# Stop your cryin', hold on tonight
Before you know it, it's gone tonight
# Tonight is what it means to be young
Tonight is what it means to be young
# Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the restless
and the brokenhearted
# Let the rebels begin
Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the restless
and the brokenhearted
# Say a prayer in the darkness
for the magic to come
# Cos no matter what it seems
Tonight is what it means to be young
# Tonight is what it means to be young...
Hey, Cody,
how do you like my new wheels?
I found it in the middle of the street.
Somebody dumped it. Finders keepers.
- Maybe you need some company, huh?
- I don't mind if you tag along.
I guess this is my big chance, huh?
Cool down, big guy.
I already told you. You're not my type.
# Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the desperate
and the brokenhearted
# The things they say
and then the things they do
# Nothing's gonna stop us
if our aim is true
# The things they say
and then the things they do
# Nothing's gonna stop us
if our aim is true
# The things they say
and then the things they do
# Nothing's gonna stop us
if our aim is true
# Let the rebels begin
Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the restless
and the brokenhearted
# Let the rebels begin
Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the desperate
and the brokenhearted
# Let the rebels begin
Let the fire be started
# We're dancing for the restless
and the brokenhearted...
# Talking about stealing the show
No one would know
when they're all letting go
# Take a look at the witch, see the twitch
in her eye, tell me what did she feel
# Is this the way of the world, to take
a boy and a girl, show them lying is real?
# Then I see the edge, I look, I fall
# And I get deeper and deeper
# The more I see, the more I fall, there's
no place to hide, I better take the call
# I get deeper and deeper
# Is it the smell of the oil, the sweat
and the toil that makes living unreal?
# Was it the man in the suit, the man
with a flute, tell me, what did he steal?
# Is it beginning to break?
Can you see the mistake? Nowhere to go
# Was it a fool and his blood in the wrong
neighbourhood, what price does he pay?
# Then I see the edge, I look, I fall
# I get deeper and deeper
# The more I see, the more I fall
No place to hide, I better take the call
# I get deeper and deeper
# I see the edge, I look, I fall
# No place to hide, I better take the call