(LIGHTER CLINKS OPEN)
KEVIN: If you like stories about
chance and coincidence and fate...
...then here's one
you've never heard.
(LIGHTER CLINKS OPEN)
Boy meets girl...
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Girl almost kills boy by running
a red light at rush hour.
Boy is T-boned at
over 60 miles per hour...
Oh, my God! Are you all right?
Uh-huh.
...and survives
with barely a scratch.
Are you drunk?
Not anymore.
Is that cocaine on your nose?
Between the bottle
and the sports book,
boy had lost his way
in the City of Angels.
Until he found one.
The one he's been
looking for his entire life.
I'm sorry,
I didn't see the light.
Well, don't go towards it now.
Boy falls in love in that second,
and knows his luck
is about to change.
(THUDS)
CANDICE: (MOANING) Baby, cum.
Cum, baby, cum on me.
(MOANING)
What a difference a year makes...
(BOTH GROANING)
...off
the bottle and the blow,
high on life itself.
And about to put a ring
on this girl's finger.
- That felt good, baby.
- Oh, my God, so good.
- Are you happy?
- Yeah, I'm so happy.
I'm breaking up with you.
Yeah.
I've met someone, right?
And... And I fell really hard for him
and I didn't expect it to happen,
but now that it has, I just feel like I
can't ignore my feelings any longer.
Candice,
I just came.
I know.
I know and so did I.
(GROANS)
Are you shitting me?
I wanted you to feel euphoric.
It didn't work!
And after that,
everything pretty
much went to shit.
What a difference
another fucking year makes.
She'd dumped me for the starting
quarterback of the Cleveland Browns.
His signing bonus
was 4.5 million,
my last check was for 816...
...dollars.
And I still sit here
like an asshole
and wonder if I could've done
something different?
She devastated me.
She knocked my dick in the dirt.
She took my steam.
My mojo...
And I gotta get it back
because this is killing me!
I mean,
what the fuck am I doing?
Fuck!
I came to LA to be an actor.
Uh, hi, I'm Kevin Briyzowski.
MAN: Next.
What's up, I'm Kevin Brizow.
WOMAN: Next.
I'm Kai Bravo.
And now, I drive a limo.
And, shocker, I hate it.
I hate the hours...
I hate the clients...
And, fuck me, I hate my life.
I gotta get my shit together.
I know I do.
My life is nearly half over and I have
exactly jack shit to show for it.
No money...
(MAN SHOUTING FURIOUSLY
OVER CELL PHONE)
No power...
...and no women.
And in this town, I am fucking positive
that's the order they come in.
Better men would've blown
their heads off by now.
Men like Karl with a "K."
Hi, I'm Karl...
That's how he
introduced himself.
...with a "K."
Karl with a "K" was legendary.
Karl with a "K" lived to serve.
Karl with a "K" was the
industry gold standard.
Do you like dry two olive Bombay
martinis with a shot of Chambord?
Karl with a "K" knows you do.
- Loose.
- Yeah.
- See that?
- Okay. Okay.
- Just, no tension.
- I see it now.
- Costa Rica...
- Aruba.
Karl with a "K" was trim,
worldly and well-traveled.
You know, I actually did an
Ironman Triathlon in Panama.
Wow.
To Karl with a "K"...
All right, Norman, I think I got
everything out of the bathroom.
...it was about the client.
Quick question.
Is that a severed penis?
Always about the client.
Yes, sir.
Some chilled Veuve Clicquot for
the returning honeymooners.
Karl with a "K" was quite simply the
personification of total client satisfaction.
- What about her?
- She's dead.
But, uh, I got you a blueberry muffin.
It's on the seat.
Oh! You're the greatest, Karl.
I am sure his sterling reputation
thrilled Karl with a "K" to no end...
Wow.
(RETCHING)
You guys look so happy.
- (SCREAMING)
- (HORN HONKING)
...right up until the day
he sucked on a .38 snub nose.
It would mark the only time
in nearly 20 years
that someone else
would clean his limo.
Jesus, they buried
him in one of those.
I heard later that Karl
had come to LA to be an actor.
But I cannot go out like that.
I don't even believe in fate,
only in the destiny
that you make for yourself.
The only reason I am in this hole
is because I couldn't stop digging.
But that has to change.
Starting today,
this fucking minute,
I am putting
the goddamn shovel down.
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
KEVIN: Yes, indeed.
What's up, babe?
What's with these guys?
Naseem wants you
front and center, homie.
He taking heads?
Not yet, but whatever fears
you have are totally founded.
(SIGHS) Oh, no.
- Oh, come on.
- What?
- Jesus.
- What? What are you doing?
Look at you.
- You're a disaster.
- Okay.
I can't...
Who gains weight in their neck?
Sexy people.
Smartass.
You look like a slob.
And you look like desert camo.
That's what I'm going for.
Wait, you just disappeared in that chair.
I can only see your head.
You're funny.
You think I'm gonna get axed?
Since you seem to actively
want to lose this job?
- Yeah.
- I don't know, maybe...
Maybe losing my job is like...
Is like part of some plan.
(CHUCKLES) Wait. This is coming
from the guy who doesn't even want
to acknowledge that shit
actually happens for a reason.
You're talking about fate,
I don't believe in that.
And yet, you're a fatalist.
(SCOFFS) Not even close.
I'm sorry. Sorry, it was easy.
- Easy.
- You really think so?
(IN DEEP VOICE) Yes, indeed.
- Hi.
- (IN NORMAL VOICE) Hi.
- Hey.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Someone is calling you.
- Again?
- Get out of here.
Go get yourself fired.
Shit.
(CHUCKLES)
Are you firing me, Naseem?
You have a past, eh, Stretch?
Lots of drugs, alcohol, gambling.
You were addicted, yes?
I was addicted, yes. Severely.
Uh, but I haven't placed a bet, uh, taken
a drink or done a drug in over a year.
Oh, right.
Do you believe
you owe something?
Uh, to the people
I gambled against?
Uh, yes.
About $6,000 to be exact.
$6,000?
Well, it was 12,
so I cut it in half.
Do you believe that
you owe me something?
Well, you have given me
a ton of breaks, so...
'Cause I need the old you now.
The part of you
powered by pure need, hmm?
These other companies
like this cockfuckers
Cossack trying to
steal our clients.
So I need every driver to work
as hard as they've ever worked,
for if these Cossack sons of whores
take over, I'm out of business.
And you are out of luck.
This is do,
or this is die.
Yes, indeed.
KEVIN: Yes, indeed.
It's funny.
that Naseem was gonna cap my ass
this morning and send me packing.
Huh, I guess things
are looking up already.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey.
Oh, shit.
Whoo!
- Look at this motherfucker.
- Iggy.
I know you've been getting my calls.
You're fuckin' ignoring 'em.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Before you say anything else,
you need to know that I'm
totally powerless against this.
- Okay, this is not good.
- This is not good at all.
Carlos has sold the farm.
It's new ownership.
No books.
So, the six grand you owe...
I'm gonna need it
by midnight tonight.
- Fuck me!
- Exactly.
- You're serious?
- I'm colon cancer.
I pay every month on time!
- I know.
- Well, do they know?
They do and they
don't give a shit!
I got a better shot at
shitting out a full
grown female giraffe
than coming up with six grand
by midnight tonight!
- Can I talk to the new owners?
- Can you speak Cantonese?
- All right, so if I can't get the cash?
- What do you think, Kevin?
I've been chasing
you all around town.
When you call me Kevin
I really start to flip out.
Yeah,
you should get freaked out,
because I'm gonna have to leave
a lot more than bruises behind.
Don't make me
come looking for you.
KEVIN: Uh, babe, I'm sorry but
I'm running really fucking late.
CHARLIE: Tell me
you're messing with me, dude.
KEVIN: Uh, I got hung
up with an old friend.
CHARLIE: What is wrong with you?
This is a first run of the day.
KEVIN: Charlie...
CHARLIE: First one!
KEVIN: Charlie, relax. I'll handle it.
Now, who am I pickin' up?
(WRISTWATCH TICKING)
(TICKING STOPS)
Has anyone ever referred to you
as a punk-ass motherfucker?
Uh, not to my recollection.
You're
a punk-ass motherfucker.
Who's an hour late.
Um, I'm really sorry.
Come on, son.
If you're gonna patronize me, at
least put your fucking back into it.
You don't have any
respect for the Hoff.
Am I right?
You think I never held a knife?
That I'm unfamiliar
with the taste of blood?
That I took a shitty, sub-par
show about lifeguards,
and turned it into the highest-rated
syndicated hit in television history
because I got fuckin' lucky?
I once forcibly sodomized a Viet
Cong colonel with a stick grenade
because he placed an ancestral curse
on me while I was interrogating him.
And I don't even
believe in ancestral curses,
but that's how
fucking deep I roll.
If Karl with a "K" represented
the light of the limo industry,
then its black hole,
its darkest dungeon
came in the form of a nameless,
ageless Eastern European immigrant
known simply as, "The Jovi."
He lorded over
his company Cossack
with an iron fist and a
white-maned hair metal band wig
that looked like Dog the Bounty Hunter
had been dropped into a deep fryer.
I don't care how it sounds.
That hair scared
the living shit out of me.
This blow-dried, death shroud that encased
The Jovi in permanent, perpetual shadow
made him seem indestructible.
(INAUDIBLE)
Fuck!
What the fuck, dude?
Naseem's going nuts!
What happened to Hasselhoff?
The Jovi got him?
Did you not get Naseem's
speech to the troops today?
I did, I did.
This is the fifth client we've lost
to The Jovi in the last month.
He picked off Andy Cohen last week
and he got Seacrest yesterday.
Flew him to Vegas personally.
What? Jovi's a fucking pilot?
Naseem thinks he's monitoring
our dispatch calls.
I mean, I... I don't know.
Oh, is that why those guys
were in the office today?
Yep.
They wired us up so we can
eavesdrop on The Jovi.
(CHUCKLES) So we're
stealing his clients too?
Tit for tat.
I want in.
Jovi jacked Hasselhoff,
and I want to steal The Jovi's
next client, whoever it is.
And not to mention, babe,
but I need the cash, badly.
(SIGHS)
I'm way too good to you.
I'll keep my eye out for a big
fish and let Naseem know.
It might buy you
a stay of execution.
- I'll call you back.
- Yes, indeed.
- (CELL PHONE BEEPS)
- Here you go.
Here it is.
That is called
"take-charge shit," son!
(IMITATING) "That is called
'take-charge shit, ' son!
"Yes, indeed. Yes, indeed.
"Hi, my name is Stretch,
"aka Billy Big
Balls With Bad Ideas."
(SNICKERING)
KEVIN: Karl would appear
to me occasionally
when I was
exhausted or otherwise beat.
I thought you hated this job?
Doesn't mean I can
afford to lose it.
Wearing a mustache
that he said he grew in hell.
Just drink.
You're so boring.
Do some blow.
- Anything...
- I need you to leave me alone.
I'm not here, dicksmoke!
I'm a figment.
I'm your fragile, fagotty mind!
Fracturing from lack of sleep,
anxiety, weakness...
Failure.
(LAUGHS)
I knew it was in my head, but lately,
he was showing up more and more.
You know, right before I blew my head off,
I rolled the gun barrel in powdered sugar.
It was between that and cake batter.
Which way are you leaning?
I couldn't kill myself.
You are killing yourself,
fuckwit!
(GROANS)
All right,
so that was just dumb luck.
Iggy tracking me down,
making me late for Hasselhoff.
I gotta stay positive.
I'm pretty sure
karma owes me one now.
Fuck me!
(MUMBLES) No, no, no.
(CHUCKLES)
MAN: You fucker!
You fucker! You fucker!
Holy shit!
(PANTING)
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
- KEVIN: Yes, indeed.
Yo, we got an ASAP in Cossack. You
still wanna steal Jovi's clients?
Babe, I just saw a gun fight.
My ears are still ringing.
Was it in the Valley?
- Yeah.
- Shocker.
- Are you all right? -Oh yeah, I'm good.
Woke me up.
Limo, not so much.
Took a little damage.
What kind of damage?
Uh, bullets of
the bullet-hole variety.
You're fucking with me.
Really?
Yeah, whatever. Who cares?
Gives it a little character.
So, are we gonna boost The
Jovi's client list or what?
Yup. Ray Liotta, Sony in Culver
City going to Santa Monica Airport.
And Liotta's
a personal client, bitches!
All right, fuck The Jovi
and his horrible head of hair.
- Oh, sick!
- (LAUGHS)
- (CRINGES)
- (LAUGHING) You love it.
- I owe you, babe.
- All right, I'm hanging up.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(MESSAGE TONE)
(KEVIN READING)
WOMAN:
We'll need you back at 7 a.m.
No! No, no, no,
no, no. Just push the call!
I'm not gonna land
and go straight to set.
It's stupid. Come on, Monica.
- That's not my name. -(STAMMERING) Marcy!
I knew that.
Why are you so
angry all the time?
- You always seem so angry. What's wrong?
- You want me to tell you?
- Is it me?
- No.
Oh, well then I
don't give a shit.
- KEVIN: Mr. Liotta.
- I'm just being honest.
Hi, I'm Kevin. I'm your driver.
Can I take your bags?
Wait, wait, wait. Where's what's-his-name?
My guy? That Jovi?
Well, he couldn't
make it today, sir.
Uh, he's traveling with another client.
My car's right down there.
What, do you work for him?
I work for a rival company, sir.
My company called when he couldn't
make the pick-up personally.
He's driving David
Hasselhoff right now.
Who?
From TV? Baywatch?
Knight Rider?
Remember back in the '80s? That, uh...
That car that talked?
No, I don't remember
a fucking car that talked.
(SCOFFS) Car that talked.
What movies has he been in?
Uh, well, not one that
I can think of offhand.
Wait a second, I'm getting
tossed for a TV actor
who hasn't been in one movie
that you can remember?
Honestly, sir, it, uh...
It's really shocking to me that
you're being treated this way.
You're not an actor, are you?
- Actually...
- 'Cause that last line...
About being really shocked,
I didn't buy it for a second.
(LAUGHS) Not a second.
That's all we need is another wannabe
Denzel driving a fucking limo.
Come on, come on, come on,
it's hot, it's hot, it's hot.
Watch your legs.
- (CAR DOOR SLAMS)
- Dick.
RAY: (MUFFLED)
Fucking unbelievable!
What? What? What, Marcy?
You've been fucking calling me
since I left the fucking set!
What could be so
fucking important?
What?
Fuck me! Gosh, damn it!
All right, you know what? I'm
gonna give it to the driver,
he'll get it back, okay?
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
- Everything all right?
- Will you do me a favor?
- Take this back to Sony.
- Mmm.
Give it to that little dyke
Marcy with the red hair, okay?
Can you do that for me?
Look, there's blanks in that
gun so don't be an asshole.
Absolutely.
- I'll have it to them within the hour.
- RAY: Thanks.
Wow. That's very kind of you.
Hey.
And that Jovi...
You made yourself a new enemy today.
Be careful.
KEVIN: Yeah, well, The Jovi's just
going to have to take a number.
Right now I'm a bit preoccupied
with the six large I need
to come up with for Iggy.
Liotta's $200 tip, while
generous, isn't going to save me
- from a pair of shattered kneecaps.
- (MESSAGE TONE)
(READING)
(MESSAGE TONE)
I know what you're thinking.
It's stupid of me to be lavishing
attention on my love life
the same day that a very agitated
member of the Mexican mafia
has promised to break things
I don't want broken.
And there's always the chance that this
"Pinkminx" isn't actually a woman,
there was just
something about the...
Pink. Huh.
Well, if that's stupid, then
this is just plain old reckless.
The one addiction
I haven't been able to shake.
Her.
Let's not call it stalking.
I know I'm not getting her back,
there was just never any closure.
On some cellular level
that still torments me.
Could you be
a bigger chump right now?
Not really, no.
(SOBBING)
"She left me,
the loser limo driver,
"for a millionaire athlete.
"And I never saw it coming."
Seriously, pal, did that shocker
really sneak up on you?
Yeah, it did.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yes, indeed.
I got you a booking.
- The great white whale
has surfaced... -Oh.
...and his name
is Roger Karos.
Heard of him?
- If he's cash rich, I don't care.
- Huge.
Billionaire.
He used to be Karl's regular and he
sorta still thinks Karl's alive.
Uh, come on. I can be Karl.
From what I heard,
this dude's pretty nuts,
but I've also heard of him tipping
thousands just for an airport run, so...
- All right, where?
- I've got coordinates.
You... You got what?
Coordinates. GPS.
He doesn't want to disclose the
location, I don't know what that means.
Oh, and he wants to be met
with a weird list of goodies.
You have to get that
before you go and pick him up.
I'll text it to you.
Oh, God damn it!
(STAMMERING) I forgot, I gotta take
this stuff over to Sony for Liotta.
You do that and
this booking goes poof.
- Come on. -All right,
all right, all right.
I'll figure something out.
KEVIN: Charlie comes
through in the clutch,
a crazy billionaire
who can paint my pockets.
The only thing missing now
is the crazy billionaire.
These are the coordinates,
X marks the spot.
I'm here. Where is this guy?
- (LOUD THUDDING)
- Shit!
(METAL CREAKING)
What the fuck?
(GROANS)
Oh, shit!
Uh...
Mr. Karos?
(GROANS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Oh, you're not Karl.
- I'm Kevin.
- Who the fuck is Kevin?
That's me,
uh, Stretch, if you'd prefer.
What I prefer is Karl.
Okay. Um, Karl...
Uh, passed away
a little while ago.
So I'm here.
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
- Those are the things I asked for?
- Yeah.
- Scotch?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Caulking gun?
- Butt plugs, plural?
- (INHALES) Mmm-hmm.
What'd he die of? Karl?
He took his own life,
unfortunately.
(SNICKERING)
Fuck him.
I need a driver and a confidant,
a bagman and a protector.
- I'm in.
- Walk with me.
You got any religious hang-ups?
You a godhead?
Uh, nope.
Uh, tomorrow I will be a brand
new face in a brand new place,
so I've got a marathon in mind.
First stop,
my tailor Enzo.
That suit looks like
death taking a shit.
How far is Beverly Hills?
Uh, 45 minutes,
depending on which...
KEVIN: Okay, so this Karos
is a total freak show.
So what? It's Hollywood.
A town that specializes
in the sick and deranged.
As long as he's got the cash,
I can take all the weird...
Holy shit!
Boris. The Jovi's
brother and head henchman.
I once saw him body slam
a 300-pound bouncer
onto the hood of a VW Cabriolet.
He had plates in his head.
Hello, buddy.
He had murdered
men with his hands.
He knows about Liotta.
He knows what I did.
- Fuck it.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yes, indeed.
What's wrong?
You sound weird, is it him?
He skydived in, naked.
(CHUCKLES) No way,
completely naked?
Mmm-hmm, bare-assed,
except for a pair of sneakers
and about 60 pounds
of Rick Rubin's beard.
If you're
feelin' funky about it,
we'll just lay him off on The Jovi.
It's not worth it.
No, I can't explain it.
I mean, as oddball as he is,
I get the sense that, like,
my meeting him is a...
If you say fated...
Let me finish.
Not fated, lucky.
- Luck, fate, I mean, it's semantics.
- Do me a favor.
Go online,
get me a bio, all right?
I got a feeling this guy's
about to skip town for good
and bleed a boatload
of cash on his way out.
- It's a big gamble.
- From a former gambler.
I know odds.
He's sitting on my $6,000.
- Long shot.
- Sure thing.
(CHUCKLES) I'm going
on the Internet now.
All right. Call me back.
KAROS: No, I've got a vehicle, I'll ring
you with the time and a place later.
(SIGHS) Later.
(BLOWS KISS)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(SNORTING)
(GROANS)
What kind of man
are you, Stretch?
Are you one of those
Habitat-for-Humanity,
eco-friendly, all-veggie
douchebags
devoted to crippled
kids and the elderly?
(INHALES)
Or are you a money,
power, pussy,
Holy Trinity type?
I don't know.
Haven't really...
You see, me, I am about
simple, succinct pleasures.
Cocaine is my first
and longest-standing love,
but I would be equally lost
without good Scotch whiskey...
(INHALES)
...and sadomasochism.
I want you to try something
when you have a free moment.
You just make a fist,
and hit yourself in the face
as hard as you can.
I swear to God, you will
find it so fucking freeing.
It is like...
It is like stepping off a cliff.
- (GROANS)
- Holy shit!
- There it is.
- You okay back there?
That metallic taste,
it's tremendous!
It's living!
Hey,
can I ask you, what do you...
What do you get out of
punching yourself in the face?
(GROANS)
(BONES CRACKING)
Clarity.
The comfort in knowing
I can take that punch.
What do you make weekly,
this line of work?
Don't know, depends.
25-30 an hour.
- Plus tips.
- Take home, total?
Not enough.
- To get by.
- No.
- Or to pay down $6,000 in gambling debt...
- (SNIFFING)
...that you just
found out was due in full.
You're a gambler?
I have a, uh... I had...
A gambling addiction.
That just means you lost
a lot more than you won.
And if you don't pay,
what happens then?
Broken bones?
Bullet in the head?
That, uh,
that could be a coin toss.
Are you a fire starter, Stretch?
Am I what?
Oh, it takes almost no imagination,
sounds exactly like what it is.
Are you a fire starter?
Yeah, sure. Yeah, I guess.
No, say it in stride.
(ENUNCIATING) "I
am a fire starter."
I am a fire starter.
Good.
So am I.
Now, we're on fire!
Holy shit!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GROANING)
Jesus Christ.
(COUGHING)
Goddamn!
What is wrong with you?
God damn it.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Fine.
- Did you say firefighter?
- (LAUGHING)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Do my bidding tonight,
Stretch, and maybe...
Maybe I'd dig down deep and make
that $6,000 worth of headache...
...disappear.
You game?
Yes, indeed.
(OPERA MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Thank you.
So, where we headed tonight?
Have you heard of
the Midnight Shadow?
- Social club.
- KEVIN: I have heard.
What have you heard?
(KEVIN STAMMERING)
(STAMMERING) Gentlemen, I
have everything I need.
Uh, give me 10 minutes.
KAROS: Eight minutes, Enzo.
KEVIN: You want my coat?
ENZO: No, no, no. Ciao, ciao.
- No, no. No, no. No, no. -Ciao, ciao.
Ciao, ciao. Choo-choo train.
KEVIN:
Um, in a nutshell, um...
You can pay to see a coked-out snow
leopard sexually assaulted in one room
and, uh, participate in an
all-amputee-orgy in the next?
Oh, drugs, sexual depravity,
animal cruelty.
I mean to me that's
just a slow night, but...
- (LAUGHS) That's very good!
- (KEVIN LAUGHING)
That's very quick, Stretch.
I like that.
(SIGHS)
I like so very few people.
I'm wondering how you endeared
yourself to me so fast.
(WHISPERING) I think fate
brought us together.
I don't believe
in fate, destiny...
To me life's nothing but timing.
I like that!
Life is nothing but timing.
Yeah.
I'm going to steal that one.
Okay.
- (LAUGHS)
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Uh...
- (SNORING)
You okay?
Mr. Karos?
I think I just fell asleep.
I think so, too.
That's very soft, by the way.
- You bought it.
- Is that alpaca?
I don't think so.
You look sharp.
Sit tight.
Have some company joining us.
(DIALING)
- (PHONE RINGING)
- (SIGHS)
Finally.
- Yo.
- Hey, talk to me.
I have someone
named Marcy from Sony
on the line who's in
complete hysterics.
Oh, shit, yes. That's the stuff
I was telling you about.
The prop gun that
Liotta wanted me to return.
She said that she and the prop master
can't leave set because you, my friend,
have a registered firearm that
could be used to commit a crime.
Well, tell her forget it.
It's not gonna happen.
I got a client. Speaking of
which, did you find out anything?
First of all, I just want to say I'm
sorry from the bottom of my heart
he's about to be indicted
on major money laundering.
- What?
- Yeah.
I mean, these
investment pyramid schemes,
some shady Nigerian holding
company he was involved with...
Wait, where are you
seeing this stuff?
On the LA Times website.
Well, what am I
supposed to do about it?
Kick him the fuck out!
Kick him out...
I can't kick him out.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Here they are.
I'm shameless in
that I pay for pussy,
but this is
world class.
This is a level of appreciation
one reserves for great art,
or fine wine or...
Ah, whatever.
Oh...
The one in the middle there,
the things she can do
with her mouth and throat,
will have you thinking one of her
ancestors fucked a python at some point.
- (DOOR LOCKS CLICK)
- Yep.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Wow.
(SIGHS)
Benedict Canyon,
10,000 block, entry fee.
- (LIGHTER CLICKS)
- (MESSAGE TONE)
(KEVIN READING)
(SCOFFS)
(KEYPAD CLICKING)
(MESSAGE TONE)
(KEVIN READING)
- (KAROS MOANING)
- (LOUD BANGING)
(GURGLING)
(WOMAN GIGGLING)
(KAROS MOANING)
KARL: Jesus!
You know there's a reason they
call Karos "Captain Fisty."
KAROS: All right. You, uh...
(LIQUID SQUISHING)
(WOMAN MOANING)
Ew.
KEVIN: The Midnight Shadows Social Club
didn't have a single fixed address.
It was a horrible,
hedonistic little road show,
that would pop up at a new and
unsuspecting location each time.
Rumor had it they once desecrated the
Right Field Pavilion at Dodger Stadium,
but because it was
the first inning...
(BUZZES)
...nobody was
there to witness it.
Midnight Shadow.
- Uh, Mr. Karos...
- No name.
(SING-SONG) Entry fee.
There you go. (SIGHS)
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
(DINGS)
It's all here.
I'm leaving now. Bye-bye.
KEVIN:
This ought to be interesting.
- There we go.
- (WOMEN GIGGLING)
I'm not sure, but...
I think someone just
got pregnant in there.
(CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY)
Ovulating. (CHUCKLES)
- Uh-oh.
- Whatever.
Tell your mom I said hi.
Mr. Karos?
He had a disco ball...
- I didn't see you get out of the car.
- Nor did I.
(SIGHS)
Are you completely flipped out?
I drove Charlie
Sheen for six weeks.
Who's he?
- Doesn't matter.
We're out of blow and these
bitches are aardvarks.
KEVIN: Okay. KAROS: Bring back
as much as you can carry.
- Okay.
- All right.
(SIGHS) The Xavier Club,
Hollywood, you ask for Laurant.
He's a Frenchman.
He has a briefcase.
You bring it back to me,
no matter what.
Under no circumstances
do you fail in this endeavor,
or our entire night is
null and void, understood?
Understood.
This is on a countdown.
It's set up for 99 minutes which is
exactly how long I'll be inside.
You come back before it runs out.
Not a minute more.
There's a lot of
money in this, Stretch.
Maybe $6,000.
(CHUCKLES)
Tell me to have fun.
- Enjoy yourself over there.
- (SWORD SWOOSHES)
There's no joy in there.
- (EXCLAIMING)
- Uh-oh.
- Hey, babe.
- NASEEM: Hey, cockfucker.
- Uh, Naseem...
- Bring the limo back.
- You're fired.
- What?
Fired? I got us Liotta.
Liotta says he
wants to kill you!
You don't return a registered
weapon after he paid you to?
What the fuck?
Bring the limo back
or I swear to God,
the cops are sitting right in front of
me, I'm gonna tell him you stole it.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Wait, Naseem, listen,
I am with a client, Mr. Karos.
No! I told you,
this is do, or this is die,
and you're fucking dead!
You're dead! Dead! Dead...
- I gotta go.
- (CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Hello?
Motherfucker hung up on me.
Charlie!
Right there.
Hey, can I park
here for a few minutes?
Fuck, no. Are you kidding?
(SIGHS) Can I park it
here for a few minutes?
Stay as long as you want.
KEVIN: Just long enough
to pick up a briefcase.
(SIGHS)
- Because I'm all in now.
- (MESSAGE TONE)
(KEVIN READING)
Huh.
(TICKING)
Get the briefcase.
Get it.
I once auditioned for
a role on CSI: Miami,
but didn't get it because the
casting director felt I didn't,
as she put it,
"Own the space."
Excuse me. Thank you.
I'm, uh, looking for
a man named Laurant.
Not seeing that name.
Oh, there he is.
- Elevator inside.
- Thank you.
- He's up in VIP.
- Hold that.
KEVIN: I don't think I understood what
they meant until this very moment.
- Because the truth of the matter is...
- (ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
...I ain't getting a sniff of that
briefcase without heeding those words.
- (RADIO STATIC)
- Yeah, it's not Karos...
You can do this.
- Own the space. Own the space.
- (LIGHTER CLINKING)
- Own the space.
- KARL: Billy Big Balls,
becomes Geisha Bitch Boy.
Running errands for a mad man.
- Shut up. -You're not
getting that money.
And then Ignacio is gonna break every
part of you that can be broken.
Who, but an absolute asshole
would bank on a $6,000 tip?
- (ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
- Fuck you.
- "Laurent"?
- (IN FRENCH ACCENT) Laurant.
- La... What?
- La...
...rant.
- Mr. Karos sent me.
- Mmm-hmm.
You have something for me?
I have something
for Monsieur Karos.
Well, I'm here in his place.
Mmm.
To pick up a briefcase and
return to him in 78 minutes.
- Is he timing you?
- He is.
And why would he be timing you?
Well, you'd have to ask him.
Would I have to ask him
about my ledgers as well?
This was supposed
to be an exchange.
Wasn't that explained to you?
Ledger for briefcase.
- Ledger... -Oh, so let
me get this straight.
It was ledgers for briefcase?
Where is Monsieur Karos now?
I really couldn't tell you.
I'm certain you could.
Look around you.
Mon vieil ami,he has put you into
very bad spot with very bad people.
KEVIN: Own the space.
Yeah, all right, listen.
"Laurent."
- (GUN CLICKS)
- Easy.
You want an LAPD Tactical Team on
your ass in the next 10 seconds?
Huh?
Then keep fucking with me!
You see it?
I'll get you your ledgers,
you have my word.
But right now, you're gonna
give me that goddamn briefcase,
or I'm gonna turn this VIP
room into a goddamn pig roast
with more cops
than you can count.
When the smoke clears,
and you're in LA County,
hip-deep in hardened cons
who wanna double park
their dicks in your hind hole,
you're gonna be wishing
you had this moment back.
Wishing that you had taken the
word of a heavily decorated,
veteran police officer,
instead of trying to play tough
guy in your tennis whites.
So come on, Crayola,
you wanna color or what?
75 minutes.
I'll get you your ledgers.
You have my word,
and I'm a man of my word.
I see a lot of eyeballs.
You better put them
on a fucking dimmer
before I put cases
on all of you bitches!
Make a lane. Make a lane.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(GRUNTING) Who
the fuck was that guy?
(LAUGHING) Yay! I can't
believe I just did that.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Where the fuck is Karos?
That was awesome!
- Right?
- Yeah.
Tonight,
get this guy or he's gone.
I'm not gonna lie to you,
- I'm pretty impressed.
- (SIGHS)
Non-extradition country ghost!
Don't get cocky.
The agreement was
ledgers in the hand,
him in person. This is 10
months of undercover work,
six months of Rosetta Stone
learning fucking French.
I hate the fucking French!
- Fuck!
- Hey, relax. We'll get him.
Get a hold of the justice
lawyers downstairs,
tell them to sit tight, do not
let them book flights home.
Order them room service.
Call the LAPD, run deep
background on this asshole.
'Cause I need to find out everything
known and unknown about this shithead!
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(CLUB MUSIC PLAYING)
KEVIN: Oh, shit.
Candice.
Fuck.
Fuck!
Whatever you do,
don't follow her.
Ah, you're following her.
The chances of seeing her tonight
have gotta be fucking astronomical.
Right, you need to
turn around and leave.
Do you not recall those wicked little
left hooks to the heart she threw,
that knocked your ass flat
for an entire fucking year?
All you are doing
is chasing more punishment.
(ALL CHEERING)
KEVIN: Seriously,
what are you doing?
Club soda.
KEVIN: All right. Great, okay.
Well, you're here,
what's the play, hotshot?
You guys, I'm just gonna be right back.
I'm gonna get more.
KEVIN: Right. Here she comes.
- Say something cool.
- Oh, my God.
- Kevin.
- What?
- Hey!
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Good.
- Yeah.
- You?
Yeah, um, it's...
Yeah, good, it's my...
- It's... -Ah, bachelorette
party I'm gonna guess.
- Yeah.
- Good. Um...
Great suit.
You look... You look good.
You look better.
Congratulations, too.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- You mean it? -Of course, of course.
I'm so happy for you.
- Happy?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- You bet.
Are you...
Are you meeting someone or...
I'm actually here on business,
unfortunately.
A client, right?
Someone you're driving?
No, no, no.
I'm not really,
uh, driving anymore, Candice.
I'm being driven.
Hmm.
Uh, could I get a vodka juice, please?
Thank you.
What do you mean?
Are you carrying a gun?
I seriously can't talk about it.
(SNIFFS)
It's better that I go.
Subject arrived
in a stretch limo.
There's bullet holes in the side panel.
They look recent.
And a check on the license plate
says the limo reported as stolen.
Tag that limo! This asshole
will lead us straight to Karos,
but you're gonna put
rotating parallels on him.
No straight tails
because if he's a cop,
he's gonna sniff 'em out.
- Copy that.
- (DEVICE BEEPING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
- So?
- Yeah?
- What's in there?
- Oh, can't say.
- Is it money?
- Hmm.
You're not mixed up
in anything illegal, are you?
(SIGHS)
Candice.
Thank you.
- (MOANS)
- Thank you.
You have no idea what
your leaving did for me.
And by breaking up with me you
gave me the greatest gift ever.
The life that I always wanted,
I now have.
- (ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
- There we go.
You just seem so together.
You know, I don't know.
You look... You look better
than I've ever seen you.
- Ready for your car, sir?
- Yeah.
So, listen,
um, we're gonna go out
if maybe you wanna
see one another later.
Candice, you need to enjoy
your last night of freedom.
I need you to go upstairs now, okay?
All right?
Suspect is in front of the club
conversing with an unknown female.
You're gonna make
a beautiful bride
and a wonderful, wonderful wife.
Bye.
Twenty bucks if you
drive me out of here.
Make it 40 and I'll do it.
(WHISPERS) Fucker.
Just get
the door for me, please?
- There you go.
- Oh.
Oh, blowing a kiss, huh?
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Bro, who the fuck was that?
An ex or something?
(SIGHS IN RELIEF) No, dude.
That was the ex.
What? Did she dump your ass?
She destroyed me.
- Well, payback's a bitch. Am I right?
- Yes, it is. You are right.
How long have you
been planning that stunt?
I didn't.
It just... It just happened.
She look like that
when you went out with her?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- That bitch is fucking fine.
- Thank you.
- She have those tits when you dated her?
- Uh, yeah.
Those things look natural,
were they?
Okay, see, the principle of a payback
is that you get to enjoy it.
And I'm not being able
to do that right now.
- You know what I'd like to enjoy?
Those tits. -I gotcha. I gotcha.
Ever do that thing where you
put your dick between them?
- (STUTTERING)
- (ENGINE DYING)
Uh-oh.
What'd you just do?
Fuck. Your limo
just lost power, man.
- Did you just do that? -Oh, now
this NavStar light's blinking.
- What?
- That's probably bad news.
Oh, fuck!
(PHONE RINGING)
- Stretch?
- What? Hey...
Did they just use the NavStar
system to disable the limo?
(WHISPERING) Yes, they did.
- God damn it.
- I'm outta here, bro.
- Good luck!
- Where you going?
Hold on, Charlie.
I'll call you back! Wait!
- Stretch!
- Hey, man, where you going?
Bro, this car is dead.
- Can you help me push, please? -No,
it's not going anywhere. Oh, hey! Look!
Shit! Come on! Come on!
Get back on the wheel
and please help me push.
- Take the tow truck! -I can't
take the tow truck, all right?
I got a client!
Shut the fuck up!
Hey! Hey! Be nice to me!
- Hey! I'm being nice to you!
- I'm helping you!
- You're doing a great job!
Thank you! Thank you for
that positive feedback.
- I could do with less sarcasm.
- You're doing wonderful. Fantastic.
- We should go out sometime.
- Really? Do you mean that?
- No!
- Because a bunch of my buddies
just got married
- Oh, shit. It's fucking power steering.
- KEVIN: Just push and shut up!
Come on, come on. Here we go.
(GROANS)
You just got it on the curb
and in a red-zone.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
- Come on! Just push it a
little further. -What?
Just get it a little further.
We're in the red-zone.
There is no further.
You're up on the curb now.
Come on, man! I'm a...
Just help me push
it a little further.
You're definitely
gonna get towed right here.
Fine, fine, fine, fine. Here.
- Pleasure doing business
with you, man. -Yeah.
Eat your own dick! Suck it!
KEVIN: If I lose this
limo now, it's game over.
I'm done. My fate is sealed.
Oh, God. (PANTING)
Come on, start!
Start. Come on, start!
Holy shit. The Jovi.
(LAUGHS MOCKINGLY)
I don't know about you, hoss,
but I don't like
where this is headed.
- (CAR BEEPING)
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
FEMALE VOICE: The vehicle you are
occupying has been reported stolen.
The engine functions
have been disabled.
Come on! Damn it!
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
KEVIN: Whether that fate is a
wrath-of-God-like beating from Boris there,
or just wasting away in a life
I never intended to live,
it's got me cornered now.
God, he's really big.
KEVIN: (SIGHS)
Maybe all this was inevitable.
Facing this now.
Figuring it out on the fly.
Life doesn't allow you to rehearse.
You just have to...
...live and learn.
God damn it.
That has to mean something.
What do I want it to mean?
And what the hell
do I do with it?
(GROANS)
That's what I'm talking about!
You know, that really works.
OPERATOR:
This is the NavStar operator.
Ma'am, this is Detective
Raymond Liotta of the LAPD.
I am occupying the stolen
vehicle and I am pinned down
in a gun battle with the
armed suspects who stole...
Ma'am! You have got to
start this car for me!
Oh, God, Bill!
Are you dead?
Oh, man, I think he's dead.
Bill! Bill!
Are you hit? You're hit!
Oh, my God! Ma'am, he's hit!
Officer, what is going on?
Oh, my partner's been gun shot.
There's so much blood everywhere!
- Oh, my God. -They keep
firing at us, ma'am!
They keep firing! Start
this car for me, please!
Come on, Billy!
Oh, God! I'm outta ammo.
Bill, we're gonna die.
I'm so sorry! I tried!
I did everything I could!
(ENGINE STARTING)
We're good! We're good. We gotta go to
the hospital now. Thank you so much!
Get it! Get it! Get it!
Motherfucker!
That's what I'm talking about!
Fuck CSI!
Well, you just might get
- your SAG card after all, princess.
- (EXCLAIMS)
Hey, suspect was involved
in a shots-fired incident
up in Hollywood Boulevard.
- When?
- Just now!
Unless he's killing people
in the street,
we don't touch him until
he has Karos in tow.
- Holy shit.
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- How's the hunt?
- Iggy, I'm so close.
How close?
I'm staring at hundreds of
thousands of dollars as we speak.
Andale.Well, shave six Gs off that shit.
I'll meet you in 30.
Yeah, wish it were that easy.
Mira Stretch. If $6,000 isn't
delivered to me by 12:01 AM
you're gonna see some shit
up close you'll never forget.
Because you won't be able to.
Oh, fuck.
(RHYTHMIC TAPPING ON WINDOW)
Stop.
Ay, what up, player?
Trying to get this fine
set of dimes up Sunset.
- My boys gots a table and
the goose is loose. -Ah!
- Grab a cab, yeezy. I'm busy.
- Hey, dude!
- You don't recognize me?
- No.
I'm ACB, man!
I was on Idol!
Nigga, Cee Lo Green be all up in my shit
trying to get me signed to his label, dog.
These girlies are my backup singers.
Come here, girls!
Wanna hear something?
Little bit of sample do?
- No. -All right, dude,
this is from my new album,
Bitches and Tits.
This is the single It's Raining Tits.
You ready?
Oh, my God.
♪ We be getting all
romantic, watching Titantic
♪ -You roll up on me quick
- Let me suck your dick
♪ You can suck my dick
♪ Baby
Wow.
- That's really terrible.
- Come on, dude!
I just sang for
my supper, homie.
It's like a 10-minute ride, dude. Let
me Jigga-Jay-Z this motherfucker.
- Fifty bucks per block.
- Damn, nigga!
Why you gotta do me
like this in a public place?
Because you're a giant bag.
That's why. Look at you.
Has your father stopped crying?
Three-hundy. Best I can do.
And the coke.
- What coke? -Those three
chicken heads wouldn't get
within spitting distance of you
unless you got some yay. Now, gimme.
- I like you.
- I don't like you.
- You got Facebook, dude?
- Fuck off.
All right. Let's ride, ladies.
Suspect is engaged with
an unidentified white male,
who's accompanied
by three females.
Stay put! That sounds like Karos.
We're en route right now.
- Come on, girls! It's shower time, baby!
- (GIRLS SQUEALING)
(SINGING ALONG TO MUSIC)
Pop bottles on the J-Lo!
Hey, chill out back there.
ACB:
Them vocals is golden, dude.
It's gonna be a platinum
record for real, homie.
- (HISSING SOUND)
- Is that spray paint?
- Stretch?
- Put the spray paint away.
Put the spray paint away.
Ah, fuck!
Stretch!
- All right.
- You are going to jail.
The police put out
a warrant for your arrest.
Wait.
Where... Where's the limo?
- Driving down Sunset with me.
- It's running?
- How?
- My friends at NavStar.
(CHUCKLING)
Stretch!
You are a wanted felon.
Are you fucking delusional?
Listen, I'm gonna finish this
night with Karos,
collect my fee and
then hit restart.
Love, life, career, all of it.
All this weirdness that
I got sucked into tonight,
it rebuilt my mojo!
Do you not get
what's going on here?
Come on. Not only do I get it,
I'm getting the better of it.
I am beating a game that kicks
my ass on a regular basis.
Remember how you
said I was a fatalist
that couldn't function unless everything
around me was turning to shit?
Well, guess what? That is
happening, and I am thriving.
Do you understand that?
It's like the worse it gets,
the better I am.
It's like I'm five steps ahead.
(SING-SONG) You can
suck my dick, baby!
- (LAUGHING)
- Fuck!
Sunset and Cahuenga, right now!
Karos just stole the limo.
The driver's outside removing the
license plates, and he just took off!
(PANTING)
Oh, shit.
Hey, man. Excuse me.
You see some punk Kanye West
wannabe white boy
come through here
with a shitty mohawk?
All right. Um...
I'm gonna need your car.
Oh, you mean, like, the
police commandeer your car?
- Yeah.
- No.
Unless you're really Officer...
Ray Liotta.
(SIGHS)
You thought the badge was
a slam dunk, didn't you?
I did... I did though. I really did.
Why wouldn't I?
Hey, the delivery was good, man.
Man, I appreciate it.
Thank you.
It was solid.
I was impressed.
- Thank you. Got something
going for me. -Hey!
So, how many times you're
gonna tell this story, huh?
Shithead limo driver
impersonating a cop.
It's classic, man. I'm gonna get
a lot of mileage out of this.
- Yeah, I don't blame you.
- I mean, you'd do the same.
Oh, in a second.
Are you kidding me?
And if that's the case, we
might as well give the story
- the ending it deserves, right?
- Hey, why not?
Now, give me your fucking car before
I put a bullet in your liver!
Gun!
- Oh, shit!
- Yeah!
Get that motherfucker!
Oh, shit!
You better run, white boy!
So what's the plan, Stretch!
Successfully outrunning
black men over flat surfaces?
Oh, God!
BODYGUARD 1: Where'd he go?
Okay, crank it.
- Oh.
- Are you all right?
- No.
- Time's up, white boy!
Sweet Jesus! Coloreds!
BODYGUARD 1:
He got hit by a car!
BODYGUARD 2:
That's what you get!
- God damn it! Stop running! -Bring
that motherfucker back over here!
(LAUGHING)
That is fascinating. I mean, the
way that you told that story.
WOMAN: That's not...
HADACK: They got the limo.
Karos wasn't inside.
Some dumb ass kid boosted it.
He's got a bunch of fucking coked
up club girls in the back.
- LAURENT: Did they recover the case?
- They have not located it yet.
You get that limo towed to the nearest
impound yard and stripped to the chassis,
and find that fucking driver!
(PANTING)
- (GIRLS ARGUING)
- (ACB CRYING)
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
(READING)
Oh, doll, I would love to
text you back right now,
but I got bigger problems.
Fuck me!
You gotta get the limo back.
Think.
Think, God damn it.
LAURENT: Hey, Bubba,
get the CHP on the line
and tell them to close the Eastbound
lane to the 101 and the 134.
I want sawhorses
and spike strips.
KEVIN: Slow is smooth,
smooth is fast.
Slow is smooth, smooth is fast.
Slow is smooth,
smooth is faster. Shit!
Shit!
Fuck you!
(THUD)
(STRAINING)
Oh, shi...
You're gonna die out here, dickhead.
(LAUGHING)
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
KEVIN: Oh, my. Fuck me!
You gotta be shitting me.
Of course.
When did they
have time to do this?
GIRLS: (SING-SONG)
You can suck my dick, baby!
- Jesus. -I love what they've
done with the place.
I can't take it back to
Karos looking like this.
Bro,
not to point out the obvious,
you're still attached to a
tow-truck on the fucking freeway.
Oh...
Fuck you, motherfucker!
Shit!
Hey, buddy, you like that?
(CHUCKLING)
Here we go again!
Damn it!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Come on, start, God damn it!
- (ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Come on, come on,
come on, come on. Start!
Come on!
(YELLING)
Come on, I am begging you!
Shit!
- (LAUGHING)
- Fuck me! Come on!
- Turn on!
- Hello, baby.
I am begging you right now.
We have rape party, huh?
(GRUNTS)
We're not gonna
have a rape party.
Little baby pussy.
(ENGINE STARTING)
There you go!
- Bye-bye!
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
Uh-oh.
Buddy!
Okay.
(HORNS HONKING)
The limo was retaken.
It was what?
Fuck!
The tow truck driver tried to stop him.
The fucking cop got away!
This cop is obviously on
a schedule with Karos.
We got to get to him fast
or Karos is gone.
I want everybody
pulled out right now.
LAPD, Sheriff's Department, CHP.
You make 'em task
force loan-outs.
Get a chopper up there, too.
Next time Karos shows his face, we
take the whole fucking thing down.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
VOICEMAIL: Hey, it's Stretch.
You know what to do.
(BEEP)
Come on, Karos.
Where are you, man?
Let's go.
MECHANICAL VOICE: Delinquents,
take your mark.
(RACETRACK SIREN BLARING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(UNDER BREATH) What the fuck?
(DOGS BARKING)
- (MAN SCREAMING)
- Oh, shit!
(MAN WHOOPING)
- You're late.
- I'm not late.
Did this limo get
squat-fucked by Satan?
Hmm.
Along with your wardrobe?
What in the patron
saint of shit happened?
Couple of twists and turns.
Few complications.
Did you get the briefcase?
- Laurent mentioned some ledgers.
- Did you get the briefcase?
- I got the briefcase.
- (SIGHS)
Yes, I gave my word that I would
return with those ledgers.
Where's the fucking briefcase?
Under your seat.
(GASPS)
Oh, you're a Magic Mike.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
I'm here.
No, no, no, no. Public. I said public,
I want public. That's not public.
You do it out in the open, then it's you
and I to the air strip and no one else.
There's a place called Kite on Ivar.
Meet me there in 20.
(SIGHS) My balls are itchy.
Did you get my blow?
Oh, sweet mama.
- No, I'm good. -I wasn't
gonna give it to you anyway.
(SNORTING)
What's the problem?
You get a thumb in
the ass that I missed?
- Pretty rough night, Rog.
- Mmm-hmm.
I'm not sure even
the clothes or the car
paint
an accurate enough portrait
of the fucking hell that I
have gone through for you.
Oh, wait a minute.
You mean you did something
other than drive
a limo while dying slowly?
You went out and risked something, you
learned something. You felt something!
Is that what I did? For shame!
You owe me an explanation, Roger,
at the very fucking least.
All right.
The ledgers
contain hard financials,
i.e., illegal activity of everyone
I've ever done business with.
And I've done business with some
bad guys that I am now selling out
to save myself.
- Laurent bought the ledgers?
- No, he's a blackmailer.
He paid 300k.
You could get 10 times that.
- So, then, why don't you hang onto them?
- I'm short selling them
to purchase a very expensive plane
ticket out of here tonight,
one which gets me somewhere
I cannot be extradited.
And the gentleman I'm buying the
flight from has a fleet of jets.
He's willing to run the risk,
provided he gets the ledgers.
- What about Laurent?
- He's a fucking idiot.
And since I just got done explaining to you
that I did business with some bad guys
- and then beat them, that
would make me... -Worse.
Better!
Opposite of a fucking idiot food
chain, pal. So, fuck Laurent!
And your word, none of
which means bupkis to me.
- (SIGHS)
- What does is "finish line."
I'm gonna change.
Muscles.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- (BEEP)
- (EXHALES)
You missed the fucking deadline, Kevin.
Where's my money?
Kite, on Ivar. Twenty minutes.
Stay close.
Okay.
Oh, no.
Hello, buddy!
- (GROANING)
- (LAUGHING)
Now, you are my victim, huh?
Stretch, it looks like our
journey has come to an end.
- You've been a wonderful driver.
- What?
Where are you going?
And now, I'm going to fuck you up, dick!
(LAUGHING)
- (GUN COCKING)
- Chill, drago. Let him go.
He owes me six grand, so, before you
fuck him up, I need to collect.
Trucha.
Mr. Karos!
Wait. Will you just...
I need to, uh, settle a bill.
Would you mind
letting me go there?
(GRUNTING)
Have a rape party with them.
(PANTING) All that's
left is the, the tip.
The gratuity.
Let me know...
(SNICKERS)
You were late
getting back to me.
(UNDER BREATH) No.
And to quote you,
"Life is nothing but timing."
Told you I was
gonna steal that one.
Like I've stolen
everything else before.
But that's not the reason you're
getting fucked, I was just having fun.
Truth is, you were always gonna get
fucked, pal, because you are a beta male!
And I grind guys like you
down to make my bread.
Promise of six grand was all it
took to fit you for strings.
Now, who but an absolute asshole
would bank on a $6,000 tip?
Sound familiar?
I said that first.
Take comfort in this.
You got beat by the best.
By a bona fide,
true, blue-blooded
bad guy.
I eat, sleep, fuck, earn,
ergo, I survive.
And when this whole marble
has finally melted down
and the roaches are running what
remains, I will be crowned their king!
Because I am
a fire starter, Stretch.
(SLOWLY) And you are
not!
(CHUCKLES)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
KEVIN: Cops.
Drop the fucking gun!
KEVIN: Feds.
That's Karos.
KEVIN: Fuck.
You're a fucking fed?
That's right,
I'm a fucking fed, asshole!
Drop the briefcase, turn around,
put your hands on your head.
How about that?
KEVIN: Stretch,
you're going to jail.
(COCKING GUN) Do it!
KEVIN: After all this?
After this fucking night?
You lost, you let a
lying-piece-of-shit crook play you.
And now,
you're going down with him.
Gun.
Gun!
Holy shit!
You have to do something.
Your whole life has led to
this night, this very moment.
Do something.
You have got to do something.
Own the space.
Own it!
He couldn't have been
more wrong about me.
I am a fire starter.
And now we're on fire.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Iggy!
Here's your six grand!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
LAURENT: You're under arrest!
Get up! Get the fuck up!
You got balls, Stretch!
Big balls!
Argh!
Yeah! That's more like it.
(PANTING)
(EXHALES)
Hi, uh, coffee, please. Black.
(SIGHS) Sorry, babe.
(MAN TALKING ON WALKIE-TALKIE)
(DOOR OPENS)
(SIGHS)
I knew you weren't French.
I'm about as
French as you are LAPD.
Speaking of...
Told you I'd get
those ledgers for you.
Yeah, but what you didn't tell me is you
were gonna throw away my $300,000 to do it.
I thought Karos was gonna shoot.
Somebody would've returned fire, then
somebody else might've gotten killed.
I didn't know Karos
was a, was an FBI target.
I thought he was just some rich flake
that I could make a big tip off of.
(SIGHING)
(GROANING)
I don't know how it
sort of snowballed on me.
Just one thing led
to another and...
Look at me.
It doesn't take much
to go from good to bad.
Smallest, dumbest little
twist of fate sometimes.
I didn't believe in that,
"fate," before last night.
My friend, everything
happens for a reason.
Has to be that way.
It'd be too
depressing otherwise.
So, am I going to jail then?
If you are, I'm not
taking you. You taking him?
- Nah.
Karos is locked up,
hopefully, for life.
I'm gonna go home and see if
my wife still recognizes me.
You're out of a job.
You have warrants outstanding, and
you're probably gonna be the target
of multiple lawsuits. So, I'd say you're
swimming in your fair share of shit.
Pretty much.
You're on your own now, pal.
Good luck.
You should do it professionally.
What?
Acting. You should do it professionally
'cause you're good, man.
I mean, you're really good. I totally
believed everything you were doing.
- Really?
- Yeah!
Thank you.
If I'm you, next time I'm sitting
in a limo, I'm in the backseat.
Thank you.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
(TYPING MESSAGE)
(SIGHS)
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXHALES)
KEVIN: If you like stories about
chance and coincidence and fate,
then here's one
you've never heard.
Boy meets girl...
Girl is the one he's been
looking for his entire life.
Yes, indeed.
MAN 1: Go. And set.
MAN 2: Two cameras, A mark.
- And action.
- Action.
Action!
Those are
the things I asked for?
Yeah.
- Scotch?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Caulking gun?
- Cheese puff?
- Mmm-hmm.
One?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- Wilford Brimley's office, please?
- (MAN LAUGHING)
She just looks so
ridiculously happy, doesn't she?
Not to rub salt in the wound,
but I hear the groom-to-be has
(SHOUTING)
a gorilla-sized cock
and a tongue like an octopus.
(LAUGHS)
B mark, action!
(HUMMING)
(LAUGHING)
- (LAUGHING) -J. Edgar Hoover.
Do you know who he is?
- I do.
- (LIGHTER CLINKS OPEN)
He's Leonardo Di Caprio.
- Not the same person.
- Yep.
- No, he played him in a movie.
- Arnie Hanger. (LAUGHS)
Oh, I thought you'd get that.
B mark.
- Scotch? Tracksuit?
- Mmm-hmm.
Caulking gun? Cheese Fritos?
- Cold vanilla milk?
- Mmm-hmm.
Raven's blood.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Could you be...
- Fuck!
- (MAN LAUGHING)
It's on fire, it's on fire.
(LAUGHING)
I thought you were gonna
shit the bed for sure.
- And I don't take cocaine.
- (SNORTING)
- MAN: Your mistake.
- My fucking mistake.
MAN: Sound coming from
the rear of the limo, and Ed.
Jesus!
I knew Karos like to fist.
But it sounds like he's footing, right?
(CHUCKLES)
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'm trying... I'm trying to get that
visual out of my head. (LAUGHS)
Great. It's fine.
Get it all out now.
(MAN LAUGHING)
- Raven's blood, falcon hair.
- Falcon hair?
MAN: (LAUGHING) Here we go.
Bring me Wilford
Brimley's mustache.
- Oh shit!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
Wilford,
Wilford, give me your treat.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I'll lick you sour
or lick you sweet.
(LAUGHING)
That's amazing.
MAN: Oh, man!
(LAUGHING) Do it again.
(LAUGHTER)
- Arnie Hanger?
- (LAUGHS)
- All right, you got it.
- Arnie. I got it, I got it.
(GROANS) Okay.
- No, they're not the same person.
- Yes, they are. Do you know...
- No, you got it. Come on.
- I got it.
- They're... -Do you know
who Arnie Hanger is?
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
- You got it.
This is the best thing.
MAN: Still rolling, guys.
He just saved
the whole movie right there.
Scotch?
- Weedos?
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
MAN: What the hell are weedos?
It's like a 10-minute ride, dude. Let
me Jigga Jay-Z this motherfucker.
- Fifty bucks per block.
- That's like 10 blocks, dude.
(MOCKINGLY) Come on, you're about to
sign a big recording contract, boy.
(SPUTTERING)
(LAUGHING)
The first one was better.
You're gonna see some shit up
close you've never seen before.
'Cause you won't be able to.
MAN: Won't be able to see it?
- Fuck! Motherfucker!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- What's up, baby? Yeah, yeah!
- (GIRLS SQUEALING)
Oh! Ow, it burns!
Put rotating parallels on his ass
because straight tails... (MUMBLING)
MAN: And action.
(LAUGHING) Cut.
- What a dick.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
(SIGHS) We should probably
find our marks at this point.
MAN: Or not. (CHUCKLES)
- (PANTING)
- MAN: Where's Leon?
What are you doing, Leon?
Arnie Hanger is his lover.
(LAUGHS)
You're gonna need some tampons.
(ALL LAUGHING)
- Fuck!
- No, we're good, we're good.
See?
Wilford Brimley. (LAUGHING)
MAN: You got him. Wilford
Brimley, the sun is going down.
There we go.
- (LAUGHTER)
- MAN: Cut!
- Cut!
- (LAUGHING)
And we're a hit.