(SIREN WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
FIRE FIGHTER 1 : Watch
the wall on the left!
FIRE FIGHTER 2:
I need a line!
(FIRE FIGHTERS
CONTINUE CHATTERING)
DARREN: I found her!
I found her!
I need some help
down here!
I need it now!
Anybody hear me?
Get down here now!
Come on!
(GIRL CRYING)
Shepherd! Burr!
I got her!
I can't move!
Come down here now!
Hold on.
They'll be here.
Move!
We heard a voice.
DARREN: Help me!
I can't breathe!
Help me! Help me out!
Help me move her!
Bring up the Skycam.
Pan it left.
DIRECTOR: Show me
what God sees.
Okay, Camera 2,
show me the stands.
3, give me the ice.
MAN: Okay, graphic is up.
Put Game 7 on preset.
How many technicians
will be inside the arena?
We got 1 2 cameramen,
six support. That's 1 8.
HALLMARK: I want to limit
their access.
SPOTA: It is.
Technicians and announcers
are the only ones cleared.
Hey, Spota, let us in.
Work don't stop just 'cause
the Vice President's
coming, you know, babe.
Must be Republicans.
Having everybody check in
through one gate like this
is a real pain in the butt.
It's only one night.
Yeah, but it's the last game
of the Stanley Cup
and having
the Vice President here
turns a headache
into a concussion.
I didn't even
vote for this guy.
HALLMARK: That's what makes
what you're doing
such a special gesture.
RADIO ANNOUNCER: Hello,
Pittsburgh, and here we are.
The seventh game
of the Stanley Cup finals.
Penguins and Hawks.
Penguins in a
come-from-behind victory
to shut down the Hawks.
Shit.
Sorry, but my dog's missing.
We're out here
looking for him.
Is it bad?
What? You think
this might be good?
Let me see your license.
Oh, sure.
Move.
We are going to
steal your car.
Don't get killed
over it, huh?
It's the last game,
we've got a couple
of minutes to go.
Just 1 5 seconds to go
before it comes
down into the ice.
He skates up to off center.
He knocks down one defender.
He knocks down another one.
He's skating like a madman,
around the ice.
He gets to the blue
line. He shoots.
(EXCLAIMING)
And he scores!
Scratch my back
with a hack...
Yes!
Dad!
Hey.
That's a fancy new stick.
Michael gave it to me.
Hi.
How are you, Darren?
Darren, what are you
doing here?
You can't stay.
We're just getting
ready to leave.
It's his birthday.
And you've got him
all day tomorrow.
I just got these.
I thought
the kids might wanna...
We're all going
out to dinner.
Looks like those
might be Penguin tickets.
They are.
TYLER: It's
the seventh game.
Vice President's
gonna be there.
Daddy! Daddy!
Hey, that's my hat!
I can wear it.
Mom said I could.
KATHI: I did?
You know what
that means?
DARREN: Not a clue.
It means "I love you."
I love you, too.
She's practicing to be deaf,
but that's still my hat.
I'll get you
a new one at the game.
Darren, you can't
just show up here
and take them without
talking to me first.
Besides, you
only have two tickets.
I'm working at the arena.
You're back to work, Dad?
Your dad's a fire
inspector at the game.
It's very important work.
EMILY: Are you
a fireman again, Daddy?
Kind of, yeah.
Kathi tells me
it's only temporary.
He was trying to
save a little girl...
Are we going to the game?
Don't do this again.
I mean it.
It's not fair to
the kids or me.
I promise.
(BELL DINGS)
Excuse me.
This is Andrew,
he's the head chef.
Nobody goes in that elevator,
and I mean nobody.
Even if they have proper ID,
unless this man
says it's okay.
If he doesn't know them,
they don't get
in that elevator.
After you finish serving
the Vice President's party,
this kitchen is closed,
and everyone goes home.
Have I made myself clear?
Abundantly.
That's how I like it.
Mrs. Ferrara?
Yes?
Let's just
stroll into your house
Iike I'm your
favorite nephew.
Ackerman, Akers.
Come on, Mac.
Mr. McCord, make sure
the building
doesn't burn down.
Go on through, Mr. Mac.
And who's this beauty?
This is my daughter, Emily,
and my son, Tyler.
EMILY: Want a stamp?
Love a stamp.
MAN: Can you guys play
after we get in?
Hey, hold your horses.
I'm getting a stamp, here.
I'll never wash
this hand again.
See you later, Mr. Mac.
Okay.
Joan.
Hi, Darren.
Are you working tonight?
Yeah, after I take
Tyler into the locker room.
Could you give
Emily a look at Icey?
Icey always loves company.
Come on, Emily,
I'm gonna show you
where Icey is, okay?
Icey. Big deal.
Some fat guy in
a ratty penguin suit.
That blonde
you're staring at,
she's the fat guy.
What's he doing?
Shaping the blade.
They're like horseshoes.
You get them hot enough,
you can bend them.
You recognize him?
TYLER: Yeah. Luc Robitaille.
He waved at me.
You see that, Dad?
Luc Robitaille waved at me.
Come on, I'll introduce you.
He won't bite.
Luc, this is Tyler McCord
and his father, Darren.
Hi, Tyler, how are you?
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CHUCKLES)
Dad, what
did he say?
He thinks they're
gonna win.
That's Brad Tolliver!
Dad, he doesn't
have a rocking chair.
A what?
My Dad said you
should be sitting
in a rocking chair,
instead of on the ice.
Oh, is that so?
You play hockey, Tyler?
No, but my dad played.
He was a goalie.
A little semi-pro in Canada.
It was a long time ago.
Come by some afternoon.
I'll show you
the difference between
the game you played
and the one I play.
I can see the difference.
I got this one, man.
MAN: All clear?
Yes.
Did you boys have fun?
Luc Robitaille talked to me,
and we saw Brad
Tolliver close up.
Your friends are gonna
be so jealous of you.
I wanna go with Icey.
So does Tyler.
Icey has to hit
the stands, guys.
I'll see you later, okay?
Bye.
Andrew, this is
Emily and Tyler.
Pleasure.
Be right back.
Come here.
I want to show you something.
Whoa! Cool!
That's why you
won't hear anybody
complain about my cooking.
At least not to my face.
DARREN: You got a burned-out
light bulb.
ANDREW: Could you change it?
I've got my hands full.
Sure.
Is that what Daddy does,
change light bulbs?
No, Emily.
He's just helping out.
Firemen don't do
that kind of stuff.
What kind of stuff?
Nothing.
When are we
gonna sit down?
(CROWD CHEERING)
MAN ON RADIO: Erequent Elyer
is in and on his way
to the locker room.
Keep him moving.
I think here, tonight,
the Penguin fans
are really anxious to
see for the first time
the Penguins
kicking the Stanley Cup...
Do you have any cookies?
You force your way
in here with a gun
and now I have to feed you?
You don't have to.
But I still have the gun.
I think I have
some Fig Newtons.
Hey!
Caution.
Caution keeps you safe.
I keep my machine gun
in with the produce.
Okay, Veep's coming in.
Let's get decent!
Christ, Jefferson,
it's a locker room.
Duckerman, why don't
you put on a jock?
Well, at least you're
covering the right head.
MAN: Don't worry. Let's go.
All right, guys,
I'm privileged to introduce
Vice President Daniel Bender.
He's a big hockey fan
and he'd like to say
a few words.
"A few words."
There's an optimist.
(HOCKEY PLAYERS LAUGHING)
I want to wish you all
the best of luck and...
Are you Democrats
or Republicans?
Neither, sir. Canadians.
(ALL LAUGH)
Well, in that case,
good luck.
And I hope to toast
your championship
after the game.
Sir, are you going
to say the same thing
to the Blackhawks?
Of course.
Nice outfit, Duckerman.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN ON TV: Two nights ago
in Chicago
with the Blackhawks
on the brink of elimination...
It's time!
I want you to
pick up the phone
and dial 555-1 793.
That's my
husband's work number.
It certainly is.
When you get him
on the line,
say only what's
written on this.
(PHONE RINGING)
Kitchen. Yeah. Hold on.
Andrew, it's your wife.
Hello?
Andy...
We have your wife.
Eollow her instructions.
(CLEARS THROAT)
"They will not hurt me,
"if you do as they say.
"If you give any indication
that something is wrong,
"they will kill me.
"When you go to the...
"Vice President's box,
"you will take two
new assistants with you,
escorted by
"two security men.
Get them into the box.
"That's all you need to do.
"That's all you
need to know."
Who are these men?
How will I know them?
In 30 seconds,
you'll know.
I swear this.
If you hurt my wife, I'll...
You'll what?
Burn my toast?
(LAUGHING)
(DIAL TONE)
MAN: Mr. Ferrara?
Yes?
Are these men yours?
Yes. They're mine.
ANNOUNCER ON PA: Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
The National
Hockey League presents
Game 7 of
the Stanley Cup finals.
The Chicago Blackhawks
and the Pittsburgh Penguins.
As we get ready
for the final game
of the Stanley Cup finals,
you can feel
the electricity in the air,
it sends a chill
up your spine, Paul.
One of these clubs
is going to skate
with Lord Stanley's cup
here at Civic
Arena ice tonight.
PA UL: Listen
to the crowd, Mike.
They're going crazy.
Here's to a great game.
Great if we win,
not so great if we lose.
(ALL LAUGH ING)
We are ready.
SECURITY GUARD: Thank you,
everybody. You may leave now.
Mr. Ferrara will
close up your stations.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
MAN ON PA:...singing of our
National Anthem.
(SINGING STAR-SPANGLED BANNER)
Who the hell are you?
(GUN FIRING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
I love that part.
Well, gotta go.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(SINGING ENDS)
PAUL: This place is
going crazy right now.
You know,
you could not beg, borrow
or steal a ticket
outside this building
before the game tonight.
If you were packing heat,
you couldn 't get in here.
PA UL: Eddie Belfour starts
in goal for Chicago.
Amazingly,
Brad Tolliver will play
for the Penguins even though
he can hardly walk today
much less skate
with a fever of 1 04.
Here we go.
Game 7 of
the Stanley Cup finals.
And the Chicago Blackhawks
control the opening face-off.
They're working up
into Pittsburgh territory,
putting pressure on
the Penguins early.
Graham, slap shot!
Tolliver makes the save.
Please,
he needs a doctor.
(ALL SCREAM)
WOMAN : No!
Not anymore. Go ahead.
Dead heroes get
the best funerals.
(GUNSHOT)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Thanks for your help, Andrew.
His wife's recently deceased.
He would have been
lonely without her.
I hope that clarifies
the urgency of this mission.
Only your best behavior's
gonna be good enough.
That agent's name
was Eddie Caline.
He has a 5-year-old boy,
a 3-year-old little girl,
and his wife's pregnant.
I'll send a card.
What do you want?
What do I want?
World peace,
an end to bigotry
and no more mini-malls.
What am I gonna get?
And I am gonna get it.
That, boys and girls,
is really hot.
What is your objective?
My objective?
(SHUDDERS)
I get funny all over
when you talk like that.
I know just what
you're thinking.
Evaluate the situation,
calculate potential losses
and take appropriate action.
Let me do that for you.
The situation is hopeless.
The losses would
be unacceptable.
So the appropriate action
is for you to do nothing
and keep your
fucking mouth shut.
What kind of lunatic
are you?
(LAUGHS)
The best kind.
You can keep calling me names
if it makes you feel better.
Throw me your
earpiece and your mic.
MIKE: Robitaille with
a center pass.
That's just gonna miss.
We are still
scoreless in Game 7,
Period Number 1,
the Hawks and Pens.
Watch Lohman.
He's got eyes in
the back of his head.
They must be closed.
Oh, gross!
I have some work to do.
I'll be back
before the period ends.
You two,
stay right here.
I'll go, too,
so you'll have company.
Thanks, sweetheart,
but you stay with Tyler.
Now you won't be
by yourself.
Thank you.
I mean it.
Don't leave your seats.
Oh! In case you want
a soda.
Don't get out of
your seats to get it.
We get the idea, Dad.
Hey, what's that?
Nothing.
What's Daddy gotta do?
Probably change
more light bulbs.
I thought you
said firemen don't do
that kind of stuff.
Dad's not really
a fireman anymore, Emily.
MIKE: A steal by Stevens.
He walks into
the Chicago end.
Slap shot!
He shoots and scores!
Kevin Stevens
gives the Penguins
the opening goal.
(CROWD CH EERING)
Get in the fast lane,
Grandma.
The bingo game
is ready to roll.
CROWD: Hey!
MIKE: He doesn't know whether
to cry or wind his watch.
CROWD: Hey!
MIKE: The Penguins
have scored.
CROWD: Hey!
MIKE: That one came
off Steve Smith,
the Chicago defenseman,
and finds the net.
MAN ON PA:... Pittsburgh goal,
his 1 1th in the play-offs,
scored by Number 25,
Kevin Stevens!
MIKE: Eace-off
at center ice.
Naslund of
the Penguins controls.
He jumps into
the Chicago end with
the Penguins
leading 1-0 in Game 7.
PAUL: Mike,
closer than we expected,
the hitting here,
early in the game,
has been ferocious.
If the smoke bothers anyone,
you can speak up.
There's no reason
to kill anyone else.
Nobody's a threat to you.
(SCOFFS)
You know, I voted for you.
I really did.
It's your sincerity
and your compassion.
You happen to be wrong.
There may be a reason
to kill someone else.
There's bound
to be resistance
to my "objective."
(WOMAN SOBBING)
So I can only assure you
I won't kill any more people
than it takes to convince
everyone of my sincerity.
Will you make that
cow stop moaning?
What's that?
An invitation
to the White House.
Open it and read it.
(SOBBING)
Don't, don't, don't.
Out loud.
It's nothing but
a bunch of numbers.
And they wonder why
this economy's so fucked up.
Those are the numbers
of 1 3 bank accounts
in five US banks
that belong to three
different countries
that our government
has frozen for
a variety of reasons.
They represent
a total deposit of
$1,700,000,000.
Christ,
it runs in the family.
During the course
of this game,
all that money is
going to be released
and transferred to
banks of my choice.
That's impossible.
At least
one-third of the money
must be moved
during each of
the three periods
of the game.
If, at the first
period's end,
the deposits are behind,
one of you will die.
If we're still lagging
at the end
of the second period,
two of you will die.
At the end of
the third period
everyone in this
building will die.
You have no idea
of the complexity...
I had an idea.
I had this idea,
and we are gonna
make it work or
we're gonna die trying.
You will call the President,
and on flash
precedence priority,
he will call
the Secretary of State
and Secretary
of the Treasury.
Then banks will be notified
and the money
will begin to move.
Or it won't.
And if it doesn't,
when the game ends,
everyone in this box
and in this arena will die
by explosion, fire and panic.
Enough bombs
have been planted
in this building
to stop all
the clocks in the hemisphere.
You'll die with us.
Could be.
I don't think anyone
with manicured fingernails,
wearing a $1 0,000 wristwatch
is planning on
blowing himself up.
$1 5,000 wristwatch.
I'm not sure if I like you.
When I make up my mind,
you'll be the first to know.
You're out of your mind.
Me?
Ha!
I'm not one paying
some Neanderthal $40 million
to skate up and down
a slab of ice.
Call the White House.
FOSS: You need the number?
MIKE: Left wing pass
down to Steve Smith...
I've got every agent
converging on the arena.
We'll all get the support
we need from local PD.
The FBI won't be necessary.
He's our asset.
We lost him,
we'll get him back.
Tell the President
I'll keep him fully informed
until the Vice
President's out.
Yes, sir, absolutely.
There'll be a total
media blackout on this.
We'll inform all news outlets
of how serious this is.
Yes, sir, absolutely.
The place is sealed off.
No one can go in or out.
And...
We messed up a few times
since I've been an agent,
but how the fuck did we lose
the Vice President?
(SIRENS WAILING)
MIKE: Right side,
Weinrich fires.
Down the left side,
Graham shoots!
...Penguins
trying to get it out...
The sound in this building
is absolutely deafening.
Shot right on,
picked up by Dubinsky.
PAUL: Players are just
playing their guts out,
right now.
MIKE: I'll tell you something,
it's so loud, right now
I can hardly
hear myself think.
You don 't have
to think, Mike.
This is hockey.
MIKE: Well, the Hawks'
pressure now,
under two minutes to go.
Graham moves
against Tolliver.
Eires and scores!
The Chicago Blackhawks
have tied this
game as Dirk Graham
nailed it home,
his fourth of the play-offs.
And the Penguins and Hawks
are tied at one in Game 7.
MAN ON PA: The Chicago goal,
his fourth of the play-offs...
They haven't moved a dime.
You know, I don't
think they believe you.
They're gonna sacrifice
a life to test my will.
(SCOFFS)
I'm truly disappointed.
Nobody does
anything these days
because it's right.
They only do it
if you make them.
Would you like to
vote on who gets
the distinction
of demonstrating my resolve?
You're not giving
them enough time.
I told you it couldn't
be done that quickly.
FOSS: Watch how much
they accomplish
during the next period.
Now...
(SOBBING)
FOSS: Would you all agree
that the mayor's wife's
been most annoying?
MIKE:...again trying
to make a move.
The Hawks attacking
the Penguin territory.
An Orangeade.
Coke or Sprite.
Sprite.
No, Coke.
Are you sure this time?
MAN ON PA: One minute
remaining in the first period.
"Sprite.
No, Coke. No, Sprite."
Shut up!
You're lucky
Daddy's not here!
Why, is there a light bulb
that needs changing?
You take that back!
Daddy's a fireman!
He's too scared
to be a fireman.
He is not!
Is too.
I hate you.
Hey, Emily!
Dad said to stay here!
MIKE: Cruising back into
the right corner,
it'll be Steve Smith.
Smith back out around.
He suddenly lost the puck
and Robitaille
heads back down
into Chicago territory.
Doesn't look too good.
(SOBBING)
MIKE: Graham comes
down the slot.
He's stopped by Tolliver...
Hey, Joan, going out
to entertain the Veep?
Hmm.
Are you okay?
He can't push it in.
He had a chance...
(HORN BLARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
MAN ON PA: Eirst period,
shots on goal, Chicago, 12,
Pittsburgh, eight.
Icey!
(SCREAMING)
Say anything and
I'll kill your mother.
MAN ON PA: The official
Stanley Cup album
is on sale now at
the Arena Concourse area.
Be sure to pick
up your copy now...
Where's Emily?
She went to the bathroom.
I told you two
not to move.
What did you do?
Nothing.
She hit me and...
You soaked her.
Don't move. If
the building is falling down
around you, you don't move!
Emily!
(SOBBING)
It's a young wine.
Frisky.
It's almost impetuous,
wouldn't you say?
I can't think of any
punishment as severe
as the one you deserve.
(CHUCKLES)
They didn't listen to me
and someone died.
Call the President.
Tell him how much
fun we're having.
I'm sorry.
You're not cleared.
What? The owner
just called me.
I'm Icey,
the team mascot.
We're here to see
the Vice President.
Who's this?
The owner's niece.
Randy, we got
clearance on a Mr. Icey?
Randy?
Randy.
Mr. Icey's a woman,
jerk-off.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
DARREN: Emily!
(SECURITY GUARD GROANS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUN CLICKS)
Fuck it.
You owe me
a Mother's Day card.
(WHIMPERING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(FOSS LAUGHS)
What is this,
a day-care center?
She saw me off a guy.
FOSS: Then you off her.
I tried.
If you touch her,
you lose me as a hostage
because you'll
have to shoot me...
Mr. Vice President.
Shut up.
He's campaigning.
FOSS: Who are you here with?
My daddy, and he's a boss.
And he's very brave
and he's not afraid.
And he's gonna
come looking for me,
and you'll be sorry.
I'm already sorry.
What do you mean,
he's a boss?
He's a head fireman.
He makes sure
everybody's safe here
and there's no fire.
Who is this boss?
He must be
a fire marshal.
When we have
special events...
Yeah. Go downstairs
and see if there's
a nervous father
Iooking for his daughter.
What is your name?
Emily.
Emily what?
McCord.
And your father's name?
It's McCord, too.
Would you like it if I filled
your little
mouth with spiders?
What's his whole name?
Darren Francis Thomas McCord.
Thank you.
Let's find out who he is.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Joan,
I was trying to catch up
with you and Emily.
She wasn't supposed
to leave her seat.
I'm Carla.
Joan had to go home sick.
But you were with
my daughter, Emily.
Yeah, she was lost.
So I took her up
to the owner's box.
Come on. We'll go get her.
(SLICER WHIRRING)
(GRUNTS)
(CARLA SCREAMING IN PAIN)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
MIKE: Second period
action about to begin.
The Penguins and
Hawks tied at 1.
Penguins
control the face-off.
Erancis deals it up
to the Chicago end.
Jagr will chase it down.
He coughed it up
to Steve Smith
from the Hawks.
The pass is out.
The Penguins...
You've got to get the cops.
My daughter's missing,
and someone just
tried to kill me.
Show me where
this happened.
(PHONE RINGING)
May I help you?
This is Matthew Hallmark,
Secret Service.
Put the Vice President on.
Hallmark?
(LAUGHS)
Well, I see they care enough
to send their very best.
I never heard
that one before.
Say hello.
This is Vice
President Bender...
EOSS: Now you talk to me.
Who are you?
Is that necessary?
Yes.
I'm a disillusioned
patriot
with a yen to fulfill
my personal ambitions.
All right.
How many are dead?
Counting Secret Service?
Uh...
Oh, by the way,
why do you guys tell everybody
you're Secret Service agents?
If it's supposed
to be a secret,
don't tell anyone.
How many are dead?
One civilian,
but the room is
full of candidates.
Don't kill anyone else,
you hear me?
FOSS: You were told
the parameters.
Full transfer of funds
by the end of this game.
No attempt to storm this box,
no attempt to
clear the arena.
No helicopters
or police vehicles
encroach on
the stadium grounds.
Your demands and
timetable are unrealistic.
Oh, I'm a positive thinker,
Matty.
We know you've already
checked on these accounts,
so the wheels are turning.
By the way,
don't make any transfers
to the Bentley-owned banks.
Shocking as it may be,
they're CIA fronts.
You were with one
of our agencies.
You're wasting some of that
unrealistic timetable.
(DIAL TONE)
Did he sound like he'd do it?
Kill the Vice
President and everybody?
It sounds like he
knows way too much.
MIKE: Chelios, right side
of the wing, wide open,
going to the net.
Tolliver! A great save there
from right in
front on Dubinsky.
And back come
the Pittsburgh Penguins.
Hawgood's got a man,
Robitaille,
but he can 't
connect on the pass.
So, where's this
seven-foot penguin?
She was there.
I wanna go up to
the owner's box.
There's a VIP
in the box stand,
and you don't have clearance.
Neither does my daughter.
Who knows if that's
where she is?
Let's page her over
the public address.
Maybe she's just lost.
Oh, I made this up?
The penguin had a gun.
We'll page it, too.
You said her name
was Carla, didn't you?
I always do things
like that.
You didn't say
her name, did you?
No.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
What the fuck is going on?
Fuck you.
And fuck your kid.
(SCREAMS)
Where is she?
I don't know.
Is she up in
the owner's box?
Maybe.
Maybe she went
out to dinner.
(SCREAMS)
In a minute,
that ear will come off.
All right!
All right! We took the box.
We got people everywhere.
The whole joint's
rigged with bombs.
We could bring
the whole building down.
What are you, terrorists?
I'm no fucking terrorist.
I'm a professional.
How do I get in the box?
You don't.
Not if you want to
see that kid alive.
(SCREAMS)
MIKE: The game's tied at 1.
Chicago puts
the pressure on the Penguins.
In the Pittsburgh zone.
Here's Shantz around the net.
He knocks it in.
Chicago has taken the lead
against the Penguins.
Jeff Shantz, the goal scorer.
PAUL: This crowd's unhappy,
Mike, but you gotta give
the Hawks credit...
MIKE ON TV: Joe Murphy helping
the play, the Chicago
center iceman...
(CHA TTERING CONTINUES)
Joan.
... to Murphy.
Murphy backhanded it
off the right wing boards,
and ahead it goes,
into Chicago ice.
Cam Russell wearing Number 8
in a bright red
Chicago uniform.
Eor Chicago, every step,
every rush is so important.
9 1 1, emergency services,
Officer Lyons speaking.
My name is Darren McCord.
I'm calling you from
the Civic Arena 555- 1 923.
This is not a crank call.
The Vice President
is being held hostage
in the owner's box.
And they've got
my daughter, too.
This is Sergeant Kurtz.
Where in the building
are you calling from?
Where?
The executive offices.
Stay there for 90 seconds
and keep the line clear.
MIKE: The Hawks got
a man wide open.
He's a step
behind the defense.
Here he comes in on goal.
His shot.
Diving to make the save.
(PHONE RINGS)
Yeah?
McCord?
Hallmark, Secret Service.
What's your situation?
Lousy.
How long have you
known what's going on?
Assume we don't.
Someone is holding
the owner's box
and everybody in it,
including my kid.
What else?
Did you have agents
posted at a private elevator?
Two.
Notify their families.
Have you had any contact
with the aggressors?
I killed two.
Is that contact?
Look, one of them
told me
they're going to bring
this whole building down.
What are you
gonna do about it?
We're still
evaluating the situation.
There's no situation!
They want money, a lot of it.
Give it to them.
If you fuck around
and something
happens to my kid...
We're considering
every possible response.
If you're not
gonna pay, say so.
I'll get my daughter.
Do not try any
kind of rescue.
Do you understand me?
You will jeopardize
the Vice President
and everyone
else in the arena.
Believe me, we know
what the hell we're doing.
(SIGHS)
Our agents are
entering the arena.
You stay where you are.
We're gonna do
this by the numbers.
(SCREAMING)
What number was that, three?
What I said still goes.
Don't do one damn thing.
They've turned
this whole place
into one big bomb.
Do you understand?
We have a couple
of bomb squads.
They don't do us
any good out there.
I'll find the bombs myself.
McCord, you can't
do anything alone!
I'm not alone.
(DIAL TONE)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(IMITATES EXPLOSION)
Watching them operate doesn't
give one much hope, does it?
I'm comfortable
with whatever strategy
they deem appropriate.
Strategy? Shit.
They fucked up!
Two men
should've been stationed
in that kitchen,
one with a clean
geometrical line of fire
to every square
inch of the room.
And everybody and everything
going into that elevator
should've been
searched squat and flat.
And no covered tray
should've been allowed
up here without inspection.
How long were
you in the Service?
I still am.
FOSS: This is my vacation.
Counterfeit section.
Money's good.
You just can't spend it.
(PENCIL SCRATCHING)
MAN 1 ON RADIO: We have
confirmation. 1,000 meters.
MAN 2: 1,000 meters.
Roger.
500 meters and closing.
Tango Alpha,
going to start
deployment here.
Sierra Papa deploying.
Deploy one.
Deploying two.
What's your rate
of deployment there?
Roger.
300 feet.
300 feet. Copy.
200 feet.
Break off!
MAN : Man down!
(CLAMORI NG)
(PHON E RINGS)
This is Hallmark.
FOSS: I said no
vehicles on the grounds,
no helicopters in the air,
and no agents
in the building.
What part of that
did you not understand?
Three cars are
closing in on the building
that missile came from.
Ground the other choppers.
I don't want to
take this guy alive.
MIKE: Penguins slip it back
behind the Chicago goal.
Cullen with a play.
Sandstrom on it,
but he shoots and scores!
Tomas Sandstrom
and the Penguins
have tied it at 2.
Scratch my back
with a hacksaw!
MAN ON PA: The Pittsburgh
goal, fourth of the play-offs,
scored by Number 1 7,
Tomas Sandstrom!
The cavalry's coming.
FOSS: Custer was in
the cavalry. Let them come.
MAN 1 ON RADIO: Command.
MAN 2: Access acquired.
Roger, we copy that.
Second team going.
Now.
Motorola MX 360,
encryption and
frequency-hopping capability.
Right out of
the company store.
You talk, we listen.
Four at
the east side entrance.
We got a light blazer,
maybe a tan
windbreaker with
a black baseball cap.
A dark yet
tasteful windbreaker and
(CHUCKLING) a Penguin jacket
and dark pants.
We pay these
idiots to protect you,
and they're trying
to get you killed.
As a taxpayer, I don't think
you're getting
our money's worth.
If those guys want
to see a hockey game so much,
maybe we should
put them on ice.
HALLMARK: We're giving it five
minutes. If they don't report,
we're moving in.
I don't think
there are many options.
That's the President's
choice, but I think
it's the wrong one.
Unless I get an order,
I'm getting those guys out.
Sir.
What?
I think you
ought to see this.
OFFICER: Stay back!
(CHATTERING ON RADIO)
Jesus Christ.
Get them out of here.
MIKE: Penguins gun out
of their own end
at the center ice.
They work it
down the right wing.
Murphy got it and
he gave it away.
Here's Mullen.
It goes wide off
the glove of Eddie Belfour.
John Cullen going
behind the Chicago net.
This guy could prove
to be a pain in the ass.
He has heroic tendencies.
Don't get so worked up.
They'll win.
MIKE: We've got four minutes
left in Period Number 2.
MIKE: Sutter is centering it
into the Chicago zone.
Cullen passes
to Larry Murphy.
Murphy backhanded it
off the right wing boards.
To the net area,
Jagr backhands to
keep the play alive.
No, don't!
Don't do it!
This place is
ready to explode.
The last seconds of play.
(PHONE RINGING)
Don't!
You just killed
two useful
members of society.
No! It's being done!
MIKE: Time's ticking
down here.
Maybe you'll do
better in the third period.
They're moving some.
They're way behind.
I said one-third at
the end of the first period,
one-third at the end
of the second period.
I don't see anything
even close to that.
(HORN BLARING)
No!
MAN ON PA: Second period
shots on goal,
Chicago, seven, Pittsburgh...
The mayor has decided not
to run for re-election.
Now, for my second selection,
I think...
No, please!
They're moving more.
But it's not that much.
Listen to me, God damn it!
You're getting it!
Kids, don't try this at home.
(GASPS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Yeah
I have a message
for the board.
You haven't heard
a guy named Bell who
invented the phone?
Come on,
it's been dead all day.
Which one
controls the billboard?
I can't let you do that.
I can't let you...
I'm having a real bad day.
(CHATTERING ON RADIO)
You're assuming
his detonators
are radio-controlled,
we could get someone inside
with equipment to
jam all frequencies.
Damn!
C-4. I hope he's wrong.
Not likely.
Arson investigator,
lots of commendations.
The problem is...
Is what, sir?
He was taken off-line.
He's a head case.
Shit.
MIKE: And here we go,
final period of
the Stanley Cup finals!
And the Chicago Blackhawks
control the opening face-off.
They'll work it up
into Pittsburgh territory,
putting pressure on
the Penguins early.
AG ENT: Sir, I have
strong reservations
about you going alone.
HALLMARK: You've got
a bloody nose.
There's no way
to deploy any number
of men and get close.
Nobody else
under my authority
is coming out there dead.
How are you gonna get
from here to there, sir?
Walk! One solitary
man shouldn't trigger
a deadly response.
If it does, tell my ex-wife
her gravy train
went off the tracks.
This is the most powerful
plastic explosive
in the world.
Don't be too quick
to pull the trigger.
Save it.
I placed some of that stuff.
No detonator, no "ka-boom."
Everybody's an expert.
Bye-bye.
(SCREAMS)
This is the most powerful
plastic explosive
in the world.
Do you believe me
about the explosives?
Afraid not.
You're McCord.
I'm Hallmark.
Have any ID?
I didn't kill you.
That's for doing
your job half-assed,
and putting my
daughter's life in danger.
And the Vice President's.
How'd you happen
to come down here?
I saw these two
and I followed them.
Part of my job is
recognizing who's out
of place and who isn't.
They didn't seem
interested in hockey.
How'd you kill that guy?
Magic.
I think there's
more setups like this.
You know where
they are?
I made some educated guesses.
These are the points I'd pop
if I wanted to
bring this place down.
Looks like you
marked 1 5 or 20.
And I'm just hitting
the places that would cause
the most structural damage.
Third period started.
We've got
less than 20 minutes
and we're guessing.
Let's hope
I know what I'm doing.
Listen. My son is here, too.
If I can't get back to him,
he's sitting in D-1 0.
I'll be there.
Thanks.
Where are the rest
of your men?
Erom the Chicago end,
McEachern centers.
Belfour made the stop.
Straka with a quick shot.
Just missed the far post...
Now they're moving it.
Yeah, but where?
Check the codes.
$400 million to
Banco Bilbao Vizcaya, Madrid.
That's one
of the counter banks.
And $300 million
to Banco Popular,
Virgin Islands.
You know, these
transfers are being tracked,
no matter what happens here,
you'll never get
your hands on the money.
Not all of it.
The money will be transferred
again to 1 2 more banks.
I have arrangements with
the presidents of two.
So once it's transferred,
it's transferred
again and again,
all in a matter of minutes.
With each stop,
cash is
siphoned and rerouted,
some converted to
foreign currency,
some to
negotiable instruments.
Thanks to the incredibly vast
and complicated
world of banking
that our CIA uses
to such advantage,
about $500
million will be lost,
absorbed by the system.
And the other $1,200,000,000
is just a diversion.
I only wanted enough to
pay off my American Express.
You wouldn't be so generous
with that information
if you weren't planning
to kill everyone here.
I wonder who gets
the Cup if I blow up
the building
before the game is over.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
Not on the phone.
You know they've got
the frequency by now.
Don't go away.
MIKE: Taken away,
and McEachern hustling
down the right side.
Coming to the Chicago end.
Moves in towards the net.
A backhand shot, off target.
McCord's
disarming your bombs.
Is he guessing?
He's a pretty good
guesser.
Is he alone?
Yeah.
Why didn't you kill him?
'Cause two of your goons
started firing at us.
He ran off.
It was all I could do
to keep from getting
my own ass shot off.
I want him.
I would've had him if you
had a little more
control over your men.
The only problem my men had
is they didn't hit what
they were shooting at.
Look, I was there, too.
Nice.
I got the next best
thing to the fireman.
He's got a little
boy here in the arena.
I know where he's sitting.
Bring him to me.
I always wanted a son.
MIKE: Greg Smyth
against Robitaille.
Quick shot, save made!
Rebound.
Where's the puck?
Bounces free.
Hawgood trying to tee it up.
And stopped by Tolliver.
Tyler?
Yeah?
Pretty exciting game, huh?
How come you know my name?
Your dad and I are friends.
He asked me to
come and get you.
He and your sister
got invited to sit
in the owner's box,
way up there.
Come on,
they got big soft chairs
and plenty to eat.
My dad told me to stay here,
even if
the building fell down.
Well if it did come down,
up there is
where you'd wanna be.
Come on.
I'm gonna stay here.
I'm gonna be embarrassed
going back without you.
Do you know my mom?
No, but your dad's
invited me over
for dinner tomorrow night.
My mom and dad
don't live together.
He didn't mention that.
He just said
bring you upstairs.
Now don't you think,
you should do
what you're told?
I am.
Look,
I need you to come with me.
I'm with the Secret Service.
Come with me now.
Come on! Down in front!
I'll scream.
I told you,
I'm with the Secret Service.
And I'm a little kid.
Hey, fella,
I didn't pay to watch you!
Down in front!
MIKE: Steve Smith
finds the lane.
He'll skate ahead.
Coming to the Penguin line.
How many did you get?
Four, so far.
Is that all?
Christ, I'm just one guy.
How many did you get?
Just one.
You are all alone,
aren't you?
You must be real proud.
I'm gonna be real rich.
Now, very slowly,
I mean very slowly,
pull your hands
out of your pockets.
What are you
gonna do, drown me?
No.
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(PHONE RINGS)
Yeah?
DARREN: Hallmark's dead.
Who's this?
Tom Castillo, Secret Service.
Tom Castillo.
How you doing, Tom?
I hope you were
gentle with Hallmark.
How many hostages
besides the Vice President,
are still alive?
Oh, now, that's
a personal question, Tom.
Ever been
involved in an AOP, Tom?
I didn't call
for conversation.
How many are still alive?
You'd probably
think I was lying,
no matter what I
told you, so...
I'm gonna let you talk
to a little friend of mine.
Hello?
Emily.
Don't let him know it's me.
I'll get you out.
I'll take you home,
I promise.
Look around and tell me
how many people are there.
1 2.
Well, now, wasn't that sweet?
She included me, Tom.
Now, you tell me
what an AOP is,
or I'm gonna shoot
this cute little pumpkin.
Listen to me. Listen good.
If you touch her,
you look at her cross-eyed,
you lose.
(LAUGHING) How do you
figure that, fireman?
Okay, here's the game
and here are the rules.
You've got hostages
and you've got your bombs,
so you can get your money.
I'm gonna try to stop you,
but I don't want
anyone to get hurt.
You stop me, you win.
I get your bombs, I win.
That's the game
we're gonna play,
you piece of shit.
Now, if you touch her,
the game's off.
Then I'll come after you.
You'll have to kill me
in front of everybody
in this arena.
There will be panic.
The Secret Service, SWAT,
the fucking navy will
have to come in here.
Then you don't
get your money.
You lose, pal.
Well, that's not bad
for a civil servant.
Oh, by the way,
in the Secret Service,
AOP is
an "assault on principle."
In this case,
our esteemed Vice President.
I don't give a shit.
Ooh, now, Tom, come on.
If we're gonna play,
you got to play nice.
So you go run
your little ass off.
I know where the bombs are,
so I know where you're going.
Then come and get me.
Would you like
a glass of wine
or a cigarette?
It's customary to
offer these minor vices
to someone before they die.
I'm not afraid of you.
Sure you are.
I'm the scariest
person you've ever seen.
You're the meanest.
Am I, now?
How do you
suppose I got that way?
Maybe when you were born
you had something
wrong with your brain.
Don't you know any
little boys like me?
If there were
any at my school,
they'd get expelled.
I can assure you
there are one or two.
I'm gonna kill your daddy.
What do you think about that?
He promised
he'd take me home.
He always does what he says.
So do I.
(LAUGHS)
MIKE: We're in the third
period of this dramatic game.
The Penguins on the rush.
Tamer brings it in.
He puts it in!
Ron Erancis!
Oh, buy Sam a drink
and get his dog one, too!
Chicago desperately
trying to get back
into this game.
Sutter cuts in
around the net,
fires and scores!
Chicago does
get the third goal!
PA UL: I tell you,
Mike, I don 't think
Tolliver looks like
himself right now.
I guess we shouldn 't
be surprised.
He had a 1 04-degree
temperature earlier today.
Right now,
he looks like he's struggling
in that goal for the Penguin.
Yo, Ref.
Right now,
he's calling for the referee.
Looks like he might
wanna go to the bench.
MIKE: Tolliver is
gonna head that way.
Backup for
the Penguins is Ken Wregget.
What's the matter?
Coach,
I really feel like shit.
I don't think I can goal.
Go to the locker room.
Wregget!
Get in there.
PLAYER: Let's go, Kenny.
MAN ON PA: Now in goal
for Pittsburgh, Number 31,
Ken Wregget.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hey, fireman,
where are you?
You don't call,
you don't write.
I'm not far away.
How many have you found?
How many what?
I could detonate
all 1 0 right now.
Go ahead. Then you lose.
(BANGING)
Nervous stomach, fireman?
He's at number seven.
Get somebody there.
Roberts cannot get it out.
Chelios in deep.
A shot off the stick!
Section B. Now.
Chelios guns it
ahead to Bernie Nicholls.
Here he comes! Look out!
He shoots and scores!
Bernie Nicholls
carried it into
the Penguins inn,
coming right down the slot.
He wrapped a heavy slap shot.
MIKE: An old-fashioned
shoot-out here
at the Stanley
Cup competition.
Up the alley,
now to center circle.
Lines it up to the Penguins...
Murphy plays to the board...
He'll beat
the puck out of there.
Leroux shakes his stick
because he wanted
that puck right there.
Mike, they're making
some noise down here
in the corner
and I'm not really
sure why.
I don 't believe this.
Brad Tolliver is actually
coming back into the game,
right now.
MIKE: This is unbelievable.
This is a guy that once
finished a game
with a broken ankle.
Takes a lot of guts
to come back in at this
point with
Chicago leading 4-3.
They're on
the verge of winning
their first
Stanley Cup since 1 960.
Now he's just
sitting on the bench.
Feeling better?
Then get the fuck in there.
MIKE: And here he comes.
MAN ON PA: Now back in goal
for Pittsburgh,
Number 35, Brad Tolliver,
replacing Number 31,
Ken Wregget.
PAUL: This is amazing.
I don't know what he did
when he went to
the locker room,
if he just recharged
his battery or what.
But this is the guy
who was really sick
and he's gonna go back in
and try to finish the game.
I wonder if he
can he can make
the big saves to keep
the Penguins from
within striking distance.
One thing we do know,
he's got all summer
long to get better.
There's Tolliver,
with the crowd here
at the Civic Arena,
Iiterally crazy
on their feet.
Penguins looking
for a lift here
to try and get
back into this game.
Here we go!
Chicago will control
the face-off and
they'll dump it quickly
towards the Penguin end.
DARREN : Stay down there.
Oh, Christ.
... and they drive it back
into Pittsburgh territory.
And Chicago took the puck...
... sweeps in,
they're trying
to get some Hawks
and get the puck back,
and they do just that
as they scramble now
and deliver up
the right side.
PA UL: The Hawks are still
on the offense
and Tolliver's not challenging
the shooters at all.
He hasn 't challenged
much all night.
Oh, shit.
Move out!
God damn it, move out!
He's gonna come out.
He'll challenge.
Tolliver hits his
head on the ice,
and he's hurt,
but play continues.
The puck gets free.
The Penguins
have command of it.
And the Penguins
still trail by only one.
Tolliver hit his head so hard
that his kids
will be born dizzy.
This is Chicago
on the attack.
(GRU NTS)
What a save
by Brad Tolliver!
That has to be
the save of the year!
He ought to get five-to-ten
for robbing the Hawks on that
to keep the Penguins
within a goal.
What's amazing to me, Paul,
the fact that he's been sick.
He didn 't challenge much
in this game tonight.
Now all of a sudden,
he comes up with
the save of the year.
No question about it,
that is his
biggest save ever.
Tolliver makes
a little move out,
in front of the net.
What's he doing?
He just slammed Dubinsky!
T olliver,
what the fuck are you doing?
He gave him a right cross
and knocked him down.
He's gonna get
a game misconduct and a fine.
He's put his
team shorthanded.
The Penguins now,
are really in the hole.
I don't believe this.
PAUL: This has been
a strange night for Tolliver.
I don 't know what
he's up to, Mike.
T olliver,
that's a $1,000 fine!
Get out of there!
Who the hell are you?
What the hell...
Ysebaert on the rebound.
He'll turn and shoot.
Less than three
minutes to go.
MIKE: He'll have
to find the puck. And he does.
Off with the puck he goes!
Penguins center.
Nobody around.
Chicago has it
back again
with two minutes to go
in third-period action.
On the move. The Blackhawks
stopped by
the Penguins' line.
The Penguins,
right now, desperately
trying to get back and tie.
And the Chicago Blackhawks
hold on to a 4-3 lead.
Penguins have to
look for a big gun
to try and
topple Chicago again.
Just moments away,
they're gonna pack up
the Stanley Cup and
take it to Chicago.
Intercepted by Chicago!
Big check on John
Cullen of the Penguins
and the play continues.
Jagr going for the net,
Naslund shoots,
and he's stopped by Belfour.
1 : 35 to go,
here in the third period.
That's all that remains
for Chicago to
win the Stanley Cup.
The Penguins
need to rally now
to get back and tie the game.
Penguins reach
in the corner.
Drop it.
(GU N CLICKS)
Larmer drills one!
Nice stop!
He gave more moves than
Mae West on that one!
MAN ON PA: One minute
remaining in the third period.
MIKE: And the Penguins
trailing by a goal.
Chicago still
putting pressure on.
Just 40 seconds remaining now.
The Penguins need
a goal desperately.
Remember,
they're short-handed.
30 seconds left.
Chicago's looking
for the parade
down Michigan Avenue.
They feel they've
got the Stanley Cup.
Time again, ticking down.
The Penguins
running out of it.
Penguins right now,
going back
for every
possible thing they have.
Can the Chicago
Blackhawks take it away?
They'll drive it to center
with 1 4 seconds to go.
The Penguins
don 't have much time!
Now,
the puck's run by Erancis,
ahead to Robitaille.
Not much time to go.
Luc Robitaille...
We've got eight
seconds left!
Seconds to go...
(HORN BLARING)
Stop the press!
The Penguins
have tied the game.
We're going to
sudden death overtime!
You would have to be
here to believe it!
Lucky Luc has
scored for the Penguins
with under a second to go!
I don 't believe it!
This series has
been incredible!
Lucky Luc has done it again
for the Penguins!
Sudden death?
Sudden death.
Paul, the Penguins
would not give up
despite the odds.
Belfour tried everything
in his power to stop them.
The Penguins are absolutely
out of their minds.
The Penguins have forced
sudden death overtime.
It'll mean, the team
that scores first
in the next period
will win the Stanley Cup!
MAN ON PA: Pittsburgh goal,
his 1 4th in the play-offs,
scored by...
Life's just
a shitbox of ironies, huh?
We still got money to move.
I hope it's not mine.
Everybody's got
a little more time.
I'd hate to see
them waste it.
Wouldn't you?
You can throw away
all the clocks, Mike,
because the next
goal is going to win
the Stanley Cup.
That's what sudden
death is all about.
MIKE: Penguins control
the draw, drop it
into the Chicago end.
Jagr will carry it in.
Both net-minders
coming up tough here.
McEachern has it again!
(GRU NTS)
(SCREAMING)
Breaking quickly!
Got a man! Move!
Bang! I'm immortal.
Jagr will carry it in,
right behind the net
but he's checked.
Holy shit!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
EMILY: Daddy!
Daddy!
How many did
you find, fireman?
I didn't move, Dad.
I didn't move.
Not even when things blew up.
I'm sorry.
You're McCord, right?
I'm Agent Saccio.
Better off not moving
until this settles down.
The Vice President
wants very much
to meet you.
He's very grateful.
Daddy, that's the man.
That's the man, Daddy.
That's him.
Daddy!
Stay with him.
Emily!
Daddy!
(WHIMPERING)
(EMILY SCREAMS)
(EMILY SCREAMING)
No!
(SCREAMS)
Daddy!
(LAUGHS)
I'm not gonna kill you!
I'd rather you spent
the rest of your life
remembering you couldn't save
your little girl.
Daddy!
(LAUGHS)
(SCREAMING)
(CHATTERING ON RADIO)
You should've seen my dad.
EMILY: My daddy's a fireman.