I'm a good person
I'm a hard worker
My older sister is
the only family I have
To put me through
art school
she gave up college
and got a job at a factory
But then she fell seriously
ill and had to quit
So I gave up art school
and got a job
But recently
I made a decision
I'm not sure whether
to tell my sister or not
I'm hesitating even
as I write this letter
If I decide to do it
I'll be listening to the
broadcast with my sister
I can't speak with my mouth
I'm deaf and dumb
Please read this letter to my
sister for me, since I can't
Sis, you're listening?
You told me if you die
you want to be buried by
the river where
we used to play
All right
I'll do that
But that'll be in
40 or 50 years' time
I'm going to save you
Really, I swear
Actually, I registered to
donate my kidney today
I know you
said not to that you'd rather die
that you'd rather die
than be a burden
But you know I never
do what I'm told
Not A type
if the blood types
don't match
then we can't do
a transplant
You haven't had test
since school, have you?
If you can't pay
take her home for now
Until we find
a suitable donor
just keep coming
in for dialysis
ok?
It's type B, B
Our new house
is an old house
The estate thought
it'd be OK for I'm deaf
If sister can't sleep
then neither can I
Aw, fucking great!
I heard that
this happened
in Australia
A man...
thought he had
two heads
Two heads?
Yeah, two
And
he kept getting
headaches
With two heads
he had headaches
all the time
So you know
what he did?
He shot
one of his heads
The left
or the right?
Aren't you
going to lunch?
Come on
let's go
eat something
You've only
got 10 million won?
Well, first of all
give us your kidney
then we'll do it
You give us
yours and we'll
get you one
for your sister
For 10 million won
Got it?
Understand me?
Your blood type's B
right?
21 days later
Congratulations
Finding a donor
this fast is
simply a miracle
The surgery's in a week
so have her
admitted in 5 days
You said you had
10 million won, right?
So all your
problems are solved
Isn't it great?
You idiot
you stupid fuck!
That money would've
saved your sister
Why not?
not the time to
be thinking that way
There's a saying
Is a boiled pig afraid
of boiling water?
Besides
What are you going to do?
You've only got a week
You know how long
it'll take to find
another donor?
Is that her?
She's cute
Must be a friend
That's the bastard
who fired you?
That car's worth
10 years of your salary
That's why we
need a revolution
So sick people will
get free treatment
The time must come
when you can get any
damned organ you need!
The bad image
they get is cause
kids keep getting killed
But we're different
Give us money, we'll
return the kid pronto
I'm afraid
She won't want to go home
She'll be playing
with us all the time
Won't have
to go to school
What? What?
It's summer vacation
But think about it from
parents' point of view
They'll be so happy
to see her again
They'll love her more
and the family will be closer
we'll ask for
exactly 26 million won
How conscientious is
that right?
That money's nothing
to them
but for us it's a
matter of life and death
Movement of capital
maximizes the value of money
it's not a crime
don't you think?
There are
good kidnappings
and bad kidnappings
Good kidnapping enlists
the parents' cooperation
If they call the
police, the kid dies
The parents pay up
and the kid gets returned
Then nobody finds
out about it
People think all
kidnappings are bad
Daddy!
What?
Can I go play
at Yoosun's house?
No
Then will you buy me a
cell phone like Yoosun's?
Why do you buy
her stuff like that?
Have consideration
for your neighbors
Peng!
President Park!
Sir
please help me!
My wife ran off and
my kids are starving
In six years I never
missed a day of work
You know the percentage
of faulty goods was 0.008%
0.008%
Peng
what are you doing?
I explained it
to you already
Your employee?
I gave away my youth
to Ilshin Electronics
-Are you OK?
-Daddy!
It's not going to work
Why?
Look at him
I was fired by the kid's father
I'll be the first
person the police call in
Then what do we do?
Defeat the communists
the way for Korea is victory
Let's go for Freedom
Down
Defeat the communists
the way for
Korea is victory
By the way
how come Daddy's
friend is so poor?
Huh?
We spent a lot of
money because I'm sick
What hospital is
your mother in?
She doesn't know
about the car accident
Daddy was too busy
so they got divorced
so
That's why
he left me with you
Mine?
Don't cry
Stop it!
Please
Stop
He wants to trade
it for your doll
Daddy loves Yoosun
Yoosun loves Daddy, too
Sis
More than anything
I'm jealous of girls with
mommys to braid their hair
Then come see
me sometime
Really?
Call me anytime
I'm all alone
so I get bored
He never said why he
missed work so often?
Then he never went off
for special training?
Yes, last week from
Monday to Wednesday
She's washing
Give it!
I'm watching cartoons
Is anybody
out there?
Somebody help me
Go away!
Ryu
Ryu!
Ryu Ryu Ryu
Ryu
The water's deep there
it's far over my head
Later I realized why
I thought the water was deep
When I was a kid
it was up over my head
Have you ever done
anything to provoke anyone?
Please think again
I always thought
I lived
an honest life
But think
Excuse me, what is
your net worth?
I'm a high school
graduate
and I started as
an electrical engineer
My wife left me when
the economy crashed
But why
I don't understand
Why didn't you
call the police?
I thought lots of
kids returned safely
If I do what
they tell me
Sir, I checked
it looks like they
used this phone number
they didn't answer
so we can't locate them
It's this number
right?
My wife gave it to
her before she left
Just a second
Yeah
I'm working
So an operation will
take care of it?
Where would I get
10 million won?
am I supposed to do?
At least kid wasn't
kidnapped and killed
We're lucky
you know
Cause we don't
have any money
Saw
Lift up
One, Two, Three
Saw
Lung was
Swollen badly
It looks like a
woman's handwriting
Do you recognize it?
Yoosun
Why didn't you give
me swimming lessons?
I put this house
for sale
and I sold
the company, too
That's all
the money I have
there's nothing
special about it
A brother and
sister lived here
They don't know
where they moved to
I'll look into it
Let's go
Nothing more
to see here
You asked if
I ever provoked anyone?
Are you the father?
-Well, actually
-I am
How is he?
If I were a very
optimistic doctor
I'd tell you
there was hope
this is my guess
When did you know
we'd become like this?
The moment
our eyes met
You're like an ant
An ant?
They say
ants are psychic
They predict
earthquakes and floods
Baek Hyun-jin's "Affection"
requested by a man who
signed Ryu of Doksan-dong
Any of you remember
this guy?
He was deaf
He sent a letter
saying his sister was sick
Oh, no
She passed away
He says, "I'm the
one who killed her"
"My life has no
meaning now."
You shouldn't
say that
Would she want to
see you like this?
Don't forget she's
watching you from above
I know
you can't hear me
but me and our
listening audience
are praying for you
Be strong
To help you out
I'll send you a new
Kimchi refrigerator
It hasn't an address
so if anyone listening to
broadcast knows him
please let him know
We're waiting for such
touching stories from you
If there's a story
you want to tell
send me a letter
Our address is Seoul
Yeongdungpo Yeouido...
I kept them cause the
pictures were pretty
I cried so much
while reading them
But
is he
really a kidnapper?
Don't send him a gift
You haven't sent it?
Two, three
He's mentally
disabled
not stupid
President Park
this is Choi
the results are out
and we checked the car
Yes
I know that place
I'll see you
there at 2:00
Yes, I'm calling
about the sticker
Yeah the kidney
transplant
Yes
She wouldn't have
lived long anyway
I searched hospitals
and found her file
They managed to get a
kidney from someone
but apparently they
didn't have money
President Park
What I really
want to ask is
What are you going to do
to when you find them?
Kill them
Dismantle
the conglomerates!
Drive out
U.S. Army!
Destroy
the new liberalism
that ruins the lives
of the people!
Destroy
the new liberalism
I understand
I'll wire you the money
tomorrow and then call you back
Destroy
the conglomerates!
Drive out
U.S. Army
Are you going far?
Hell, yeah
Shit, you said
I could go first!
It's in an artery
Chulseung
Don't take it out!
Mom
The noodles were all
soggy last time
Yeah, hurry
Huh?
Where is the bastard?
Fuck you
Where?
Tell me
you bitch!
Fuck
Next time, don't
order just one dish
Mister
Yoosun
We didn't kill
her on purpose
I'm sorry
we made a mistake
But I have something
to tell you
I'm not just any
ordinary person
If anything
happens to me
my organization
is a terrorist group
They'll kill you
100%
For sure
I gave them
your picture
If you want to live
just leave me
This is
for your sake
honest
And
I'm sorry
100%
She sat next to
the deaf kid
so
she's deaf, too?
No
how come she went
to same school?
So
what I mean is
she got expelled
when was find out
she wasn't deaf
She went to college
and was a left wing activist
sneaked onto a boat once
trying to reach N-Korea
And?
She got caught
by some fishermen
caught her in a net
while she was swimming
She's part of the RAA
What?
I mean, she was
Go to Intelligence
and bring a few of them
The problem is
She was the only
member of RAA
Make way please
excuse me
Excuse me
we're
coming through
I'm sorry
you can't ride here
Its C-3
They found some of
Cha Youngmi's flyers
at a crime scene
What scene?
Three people
were murdered
yes
The organ dealers
are dead!
But
their sides
are cut open
You know
He took
the kidneys!
President Park
he seems like
a real psycho
Killed three people
He isn't human
Give this up now
I'll return
all your money
I know
you're a good guy
But you know
why I have to
kill you?
Understand?
Huh?
you know?
-Hello?
-yeh, Inchon Hospital
is there
boy's father?
He died
just now at 12:20
The mortuary's
on floor B2
You've got
the wrong number
What?
Mister
If anything
happens to me
my organization
is a terrorist group
They'll kill you
100%
For sure
I gave them
your picture