Mr Cicci, from the year 1942
to the present time,
you were an employee
of the Genco Olive Oil Company?
That's right.
But in actuality you were a member
of the Corleone crime organisation.
No, we called it
the Corleone family, Senator.
What was your position?
At first, like everybody else,
I was a soldier.
- What is that?
- A button, you know, Senator.
No, I don't know. Tell me.
When the boss says "push a button" on
a guy, I push a button. See, Senator?
Mr Questadt.
You mean you kill people?
You kill people at the...
behest of your superiors.
Yeah, that's right.
And the head of your family
is Michael Corleone?
Yeah, Counsellor. Michael Corleone.
Did you ever get such an order
directly from Michael Corleone?
No, I never talked to him.
Mr Cicci, could you amplify
your answer a bit?
- Do what?
- Could you expand on your answer?
I'm particularly interested in knowing,
was there always a buffer involved?
Someone in between you
and your superiors who gave the order.
Right, a buffer.
The family had a lot of buffers!
You may find this very amusing, but
the members of this committee do not.
Tell me something, Ma.
What did Papa think...
deep in his heart?
He was being strong...
Strong for his family.
But by being strong for his family...
...could he...
...Iose it?
You're thinking about your wife...
about the baby you lost.
But you and your wife can
always have another baby.
No, I meant...Iose his family.
But you can never lose your family.
Times are changing.
It's my pleasure.
I don't want money.
Take it as a gift.
If there's something I can do for you,
you come, we talk.
Signora Colombo, why did you
come to see me?
Your wife told me to ask
if you could help me.
She's in bad trouble.
Her neighbors complained to the
landlord about her dog.
He told her to get rid of the animal.
But her little boy loves that dog.
So she hid it.
When the landlord found out, he
got mad and told her to leave.
Now she can't stay even if she
gets rid of it.
I'm so ashamed!
He said he'd get the police to
throw us out on the street.
I'm sorry, but...
I could give you a couple dollars
to help you move.
I can't move!
I want you to talk to him!
Tell him I want to stay here!
What's your landlord's name?
His name is Signor Roberto.
He lives on Fourth Street, near here.
They break the windows,
they dirty the floors...
A real pig-sty, eh?
My name is vito Corleone.
Signora Colombo is a friend of my wife.
She says she's been evicted
for no good reason.
She's a poor widow, she has nobody
to take care of her.
She has no relatives, no money.
All she has is this neighborhood.
I already rented the place
to another family.
I told her that I'd talk to you.
That you're a reasonable man.
She got rid of the animal that
caused all the trouble.
So let her stay.
Impossible.
Are you Sicilian?
No, I'm Calabrese.
We're practically paesani,
do me this favor.
I already rented it!
I'll look like an idiot.
Besides, the new tenants
pay more rent.
How much more a month?
Five bucks.
Here's six months increase in advance.
But don't tell her about it.
She's very proud.
Come see me in another six months.
Of course, the dog stays. Right?
The dog stays.
Who the hell are you
to come give me orders?
Watch out or I'll kick your Sicilian ass
right into the street!
Do me this favor.
I won't forget it.
Ask your friends in the
neighborhood about me.
They'll tell you I know how
to return a favor.
What a character!
That landlord is here... Roberto,
the one who owns those ratholes.
He's been asking all around
the neighborhood about you.
I hope I'm not disturbing you,
Don vito.
What can I do for you, Don Roberto?
What a misunderstanding! Holy Mary!
Of course Signora Colombo can stay!
I'm giving back the money you gave me.
Un, due, three, four, five, six, tutt'!
Because after all, Don vito,
money isn't everything.
Can I sit down?
Your kindness to that widow
made me ashamed of myself.
The rent stays like before!
I'll even lower it.
I'll lower it $5.
I'll lower it $1 0!
Can I offer you some coffee?
I'm late for an appointment! I can't
this time! Ask me another time!
You'll have to excuse me for now.
I wish I could stay longer!
Just call me and I'll be here!
He won't be back. He'll hide out
in the Bronx!
- vito, what do you think?
- We'll make a big business!
Would you speak up, please?
New York City.
- Are you the son of vito Corleone?
- Yes, I am.
- Where was he born?
- Corleone, Sicily.
Did he at times use an alias that was
known in certain circles as Godfather?
Godfather is a term used by his friends.
One of affection and respect.
Mr Chairman, I would like to verify
the witness' statement.
For years many of my constituents
have been of ltalian descent.
I've come to know them well.
They have honoured me
with their support and their friendship.
I can proudly say that some of my
very best friends are ltalian-Americans.
However, Mr Chairman, unfortunately
I have to leave these proceedings,
in order to preside over a very important
meeting of my own committee.
Before I leave, I do want to say this,
that these hearings on the Mafia
are in no way whatsoever
a slur upon the great ltalian people.
I can state from my own knowledge
and experience
that ltalian-Americans are among
the most loyal, most law-abiding,
patriotic, hard-working
American citizens in this land.
It would be a shame, Mr Chairman,
if we allowed a few rotten apples
to give a bad name to the whole barrel.
Because from the time of Christopher
Columbus to the time of Enrico Fermi,
to the present day,
Italian-Americans have been pioneers
in building and defending our nation.
They are the salt of the earth, and
one of the backbones of this country.
I'm sure we all agree
with our esteemed colleague.
Mr Corleone, you have been advised
as to your legal rights.
We have testimony from
a previous witness, one Willi Cicci.
He stated that you are head of the most
powerful Mafia family in the country.
- Are you?
- No, I'm not.
He testified that you are personally
responsible
for the murder of a New York
police captain in 1 947,
and with him a man
named virgil Sollozzo.
- Do you deny this?
- Yes, I do.
Is it true that in the year 1 950
you devised the murder of the heads
of the "Five Families" in New York,
to assume and consolidate
your nefarious power?
- It's a complete falsehood.
- Mr Questadt.
Is it true you have a controlling interest
in three major hotels in Las vegas?
No, it's not true. I own some stock in
some of the hotels there, but very little.
I also have stock in lBM and lT&T.
Do you have any control over gambling
and narcotics in New York State?
No, I do not.
Senator, my client would like to
read a statement.
Mr Chairman, I think this statement
is totally out of order at this time.
Sir, my client has answered this
committee's questions with sincerity.
He hasn't taken the Fifth Amendment,
so this statement should be heard!
No, I'll allow Mr Corleone to read
his statement. I'll put it in the record.
In the hopes of clearing
my family name,
to give my children their share
of the American way of life
without a blemish on their name
and background,
I have appeared before this committee
and given it all my cooperation.
I consider it a great personal dishonour
to have to deny that I am a criminal.
I wish to have the following noted
for the record:
That I served my country faithfully
in World War Two
and was awarded the Navy Cross
for actions in defence of my country.
That I have never been arrested
or indicted for any crime.
That no proof linking me to any
criminal conspiracy,
whether it is called Mafia
or Cosa Nostra or any other name,
has ever been made public.
I have not taken refuge behind the Fifth
Amendment, although I may do so.
I challenge this committee to produce
any witness or evidence against me,
and if they do not, I hope they will have
the decency to clear my name
with the same publicity
with which they have besmirched it.
I'm sure we're impressed. Particularly
with your love for our country.
We'll be in recess until 1 0 a.m. Monday,
when we will produce a witness who'll
corroborate the charges against you.
At which time you may very well
be subject to indictment for perjury.
I remind you that you're still
under subpoena. Adjourned!
Ten-to-one shot, you said.
He would take the Fifth, and I'd lose.
You sound like my bookie.
I owe that monkey my life.
- Well, just get a good night's sleep.
- Yeah.
You've got a big day tomorrow.
I've got you a new suit,
new shirt, new tie.
I'll shave you myself in the morning.
You'll look respectable for 50 million
of your fellow Americans.
Tomorrow... My life won't be worth
a nickel after tomorrow.
Come on! I saw this 1 9 times.
You've got a great home here,
for the rest of your life.
Nobody gets near you,
you're not going anywhere.
That's great. Beautiful.
Some deal I made.
You'll live like a king. You'll be a hero.
You'll live better here
than most people outside.
Some deal!
Alive. Pentangeli is alive.
- How did they get their hands on him?
- Roth. He engineered it, Michael.
When Frankie went to make a deal with
the Rosato brothers they tried to kill him.
He thought you double-crossed him.
Our people with the detectives
said he was half dead, scared,
and shouted that you'd turned on him.
They already had him on possession,
bookmaking, murder one and more.
The FBl has him airtight. He's on
an army base, 24 hour guards.
We can't get to him. You've opened
yourself to five counts of perjury.
What about Fredo?
What does he know?
He says he doesn't know anything,
and I believe him.
Roth, he... played this one beautifully.
I'm going to talk to Fredo.
I haven't got a lot to say, Mike.
We have time.
I was kept pretty much in the dark.
I didn't know all that much.
What about now? Is there anything
you can help me out with?
Anything you can tell me now?
They've got Pentangeli.
I didn't know it was going to be
a hit, Mike.
I swear to God I didn't know.
Johnny Ola bumped into me
in Beverly Hills.
He said that he wanted to talk.
He said that you and Roth
were in on a big deal together.
And that there was something in it
for me if I could help him out.
He said that you were being tough
on the negotiations,
but if they could get a little help
and close the deal fast...
...it would be good for the family.
And you believed that story?
You believed that?
He said there was something in it
for me, on my own!
- I've always taken care of you, Fredo.
- Taken care of me?!
You're my kid brother!
You take care of me?
Did you ever think about that?
Did you ever once think about that?
"Send Fredo off to do this,
send Fredo off to do that!"
"Let Fredo take care of some
Mickey Mouse nightclub somewhere."
"Let Fredo fetch somebody at the airport!"
I'm your older brother,
but was stepped over!
- It's the way Pop wanted it.
- It's not the way I wanted it!
I can handle things, I'm smart!
Not like everybody says.
Like dumb. I'm smart
and I want respect!
Is there anything you can tell me about
this investigation? Anything more?
The senate lawyer, Questadt...
He belongs to Roth.
Fredo...
...you're nothing to me now.
Not a brother, not a friend.
I don't want to know you,
or what you do.
I don't want to see you at the hotels.
I don't want you near my house.
When you see our mother, I want to
know in advance, so I won't be there.
You understand?
Mikey.
I don't want anything to happen to him
while my mother's alive.
There's more people
than at a ballgame in here.
- Hey, there's Willi Cicci!
- Frankie Five-Angels...
This committee will come to order!
- State your name, please.
- Frank Pentangeli.
- Where were you born?
- Pontenegro, it's outside of Palermo.
Where do you live now?
I live in an army barracks
with the FBl guys.
We have here a witness
that will further testify
to Michael Corleone's rule of a criminal
empire that controls all gambling.
This witness has had no buffer between
himself and Michael Corleone.
He can corroborate enough charges
for us to recommend a charge
of perjury against Michael Corleone.
- Senator.
- Thank you, Chairman.
Mr Pentangeli...
Mr Pentangeli. Were you a member
of the Corleone family?
Did you serve under Caporegime,
Peter Clemenza,
and under vito Corleone,
also known as the Godfather?
I never knew any Godfather.
I have my own family.
Mr Pentangeli, you...
You are contradicting
your own sworn statement.
I ask you again, sir, here and now
under oath,
were you at any time a member of a crime
organisation led by Michael Corleone?
I don't know nothing about that!
I was in the olive oil business
with his father,
but that was a long time ago.
We have a sworn affidavit.
Your sworn affidavit, that you murdered
on the orders of Michael Corleone.
Do you deny this confession, and do
you realise what will happen if you do?
The FBl guys promised me a deal,
so I made up a lot of stuff about
Michael Corleone, just to please them.
But it was all lies. Everything!
They kept saying,
"Michael Corleone did this"
and "Michael Corleone did that".
So I said, "Yeah, sure. Why not?"
Mr Corleone, would you kindly identify
the gentleman sitting to your left?
I can answer that.
His name is vincenzo Pentangeli.
- Is he related to the witness?
- He is, I believe, his brother.
- Will he come forward and be sworn?
- He doesn't understand English.
He came at his own expense
to aid his brother.
He's not under subpoena
and has an impeccable reputation.
- He knows nothing about this?
- To my knowledge, nothing.
I'm going to find out what happened!
This committee is now adjourned.
- The witness is excused.
- Senator!
Senator! This committee
owes an apology!
This committee owes an apology.
Apology, Senator!
- Michael, excuse me.
- Hello, darling.
The children are outside. We're going.
What do you mean?
We're leaving tomorrow.
Rocco?
I'll be in my room, Mike.
Michael, I'm not going back to Nevada.
I brought the children
to say goodbye to you.
I'm very happy for you.
I always knew you were too smart
to let any of them beat you.
- Why don't you sit down?
- No, I'm not going to stay long.
There are some things
I'd like to talk to you about.
Things that have been on my mind,
changes I want to make.
I think it's too late for changes, Michael.
- I wasn't going to say anything...
- What do you mean, "too late"?
What really happened with Pentangeli?
- His brother came and helped him.
- I didn't even know he had a brother.
Where is he now?
He's on a plane, back to Sicily.
All he had to do was show his face.
It was between the brothers, Kay.
I had nothing to do with it.
Don't tell me you're going.
Not you, not the kids. No.
You're my wife and my children.
I love you and won't allow it.
You say you love me,
but talk about allowing me to leave!
Things between men and women
will not change.
You've become blind!
Look what's happened to us.
- Look what's happened to our son!
- Nothing's happened to him. He's fine!
- Anthony is not fine!
- I don't want to hear about it.
- Anthony is...
- I don't want to hear about it!
Over!
At this moment
I feel no love for you at all.
I never thought that would ever happen,
but it has.
Kay...
We're leaving tomorrow.
Why don't you take the kids
back to their room?
- Michael, you haven't heard me.
- Kay, what do you want from me?
Do you expect me to let you go,
to let you take my children from me?
Don't you know me? Don't you know
that that's an impossibility?
That I'd use all my power
to keep that from happening?
Don't you know that?
Kay...
In time, you'll feel differently.
You'll be glad I stopped you now.
I know that.
I know you blame me
for losing the baby.
Yes.
I know what that meant to you.
I'll make it up to you, Kay.
I swear I'll make it up to you. I'll...
I'm going to change.
I'll change. I've learned that I have
the strength to change.
Then you'll forget about
this miscarriage...
...and we'll have another child.
And we'll go on, you and l.
- We'll go on.
- Oh, Michael!
Michael, you are blind.
It wasn't a miscarriage.
It was an abortion.
An abortion, Michael.
Just like our marriage is an abortion.
Something that's unholy and evil!
I didn't want your son, Michael!
I wouldn't bring another one
of your sons into this world!
It was an abortion, Michael.
It was a son - and I had it killed
because this must all end!
I know now that it's over. I knew it then.
There would be no way, Michael,
no way you could ever forgive me.
Not with this Sicilian thing
that's been going on for 2,000...
- You won't take my children.
- I will.
- You won't take my children!
- They're my children too.
Fredo, give this to Grandmother.
Don Ciccio, it's Tommasino.
Allow me the honor of
introducing someone.
My partner in America, in New York.
His name is vito Corleone.
We'll send him olive oil from here.
To his company in America.
They're olive oil importers, Don Ciccio.
We'd like your blessing, and your
permission to start work.
Where is this young man
from New York?
Have him come closer.
I can't see him so good.
My respects, Don Ciccio.
Give me your blessing.
Bless you!
What's your name?
You took the name of this town!
And what's your father's name?
His name was...Antonio Andolini.
Louder, I don't hear so good.
My father's name was
Antonio Andolini...
...and this is for you!
Michael, say goodbye.
Hi, Al.
Can I speak with you
for a second, Tom?
Tom, where's Mike?
Waiting for you to leave.
- Can I talk with him?
- Sorry, Fredo. No chance.
- Can I see him?
- He's in the boathouse.
Michael, it's Connie.
Michael...
I'd like to stay close to home now,
if it's all right.
Is Kay coming?
No.
Fredo's in the house with Mama.
He asked for you
and Tom said you wouldn't see him.
That's right.
Kids, why don't you go outside
for a while?
Please, I want to talk to you.
Michael, I hated you for so many years.
I think I did things to myself,
to hurt myself, so that you'd know...
...that I could hurt you.
You were just being strong for all of us,
the way Papa was.
And I forgive you.
Can't you forgive Fredo?
He's so sweet,
and helpless without you.
You need me.
I want to take care of you now.
Connie...
Tom, sit down.
Our friend and business partner,
Hyman Roth, is in the news.
- Did you hear about it?
- I hear that he's in lsrael.
The High Court in lsrael
turned down his request to live there.
His passport's been invalidated,
except to return here.
He landed in Buenos Aires yesterday.
He offered them a million dollars
if they'd let him live there.
- They turned him down.
- He's going to try Panama.
Panama won't take him.
Not for a million, not for ten million.
His condition is reported as terminal.
He's only got six months left.
He's had the same heart attack
for 20 years.
- That plane goes to Miami.
- That's right. That's where I want it met.
Impossible. They'll turn him over to the
lnternal Revenue, Customs and FBl.
It's not impossible.
Nothing's impossible.
- There's no way we can get to him!
- Tom, you surprise me.
If anything in this life is certain...
...if history has taught us anything...
...it's that you can kill anyone.
- Rocco?
- Difficult. Not impossible.
Good.
Why did you ask me if something
was wrong when I came in?
I thought you were going to tell me that
you're moving your family to vegas...
...and that you'd been offered the vice
Presidency of the Houstan hotels there.
- I thought you'd tell me that.
- Must I tell you every offer I turn down?
- Let's do business.
- All right.
Just consider this, Michael.
Just consider it.
Roth and the Rosatos are on the run.
Are they worth it, are we strong enough?
Is it worth it? You've won.
Do you want to wipe everybody out?
I don't feel I have to wipe everybody
out, Tom. Just my enemies, that's all.
Are you with me in these things,
or what?
Because if not, you can take your wife,
your family and your mistress,
and move them all to Las vegas.
Why do you hurt me, Michael? I've
always been loyal to you. What is this?
So...you're staying?
Yes, I'm staying.
What do you want me to do?
Hey, Anthony...
How would you like it if I taught you
how to catch the really big fish?
- Would you like that?
- Okay.
You know, when I was your age...
... I went out fishing with all my brothers
and my father. Everybody.
I was the only one that caught a fish.
Nobody else could catch one.
Do you know how I did it?
Every time I put the line in the water
I said a Hail Mary
and every time I said a Hail Mary,
I caught a fish.
Do you believe that? It's true.
That's the secret.
- Do you want to try it out on the lake?
- Okay.
What else have you got?
Everything will be okay.
- Did my brother go back?
- Yeah, don't worry.
He's ten times tougher than me,
my brother. He's old-fashioned.
He didn't want dinner,
just wanted to go home.
That's my brother! Nothing could get
him away from that two-mule town.
He could have been big here.
He could have had his own family.
Tom...
...what do I do now?
Frankie...
You were always interested
in politics and history.
I remember you talking about Hitler
back in '33.
Yeah, I still read a lot.
I get good stuff in there.
You were around the old-timers, who
built the organisation of the families,
basing them on the old Roman legions,
with "regimes", "capos" and "soldiers".
- And it worked.
- Yeah, it worked.
Those were the great old days,
you know.
We was like the Roman Empire.
The Corleone family
was like the Roman Empire.
Yeah...
...it was once.
Frankie...
When a plot against the Emperor failed...
...the plotters were always
given a chance...
...to let their families keep their fortunes.
Right?
Only the rich guys.
The little guys got knocked off and all
their estates went to the Emperors.
Unless they went home and killed
themselves, then nothing happened.
And their families were taken care of.
That was a good break, a nice deal.
Yeah.
They went home...
...and sat in a hot bath...
...opened up their veins...
...and bled to death.
And sometimes they had a little party
before they did it.
Don't worry about anything,
Frankie Five-Angels.
Thanks, Tom. Thanks.
- See you, Tom.
- Addio, Frankie.
Kay... You have to go.
- So pretty...
- Kay, please hurry. He's coming.
Anthony... Kiss Mama goodbye.
Anthony, kiss your mother goodbye!
Anthony, say goodbye to Mama.
Anthony... I love you, Anthony.
Kay, please.
All right.
Mary, come here.
Anthony...
Anthony, please. Kiss me once.
Easy.
Anthony! Anthony!
- He's here, we're going fishing.
- No!
Michael wants to take him to Reno now.
Shit!
Okay, kid, you have to go to Reno
with your pop.
- I'll take you fishing tomorrow, okay?
- Okay.
Hey, Anthony...
Listen, I'll catch one for you in secret.
Let's go.
- Mr Roth, I must take you into custody.
- I understand.
What's your reaction
to the lsraeli High Court ruling?
I'm a retired investor on a pension.
I went to lsrael to live there as a Jew,
in the twilight of my life.
Hey, Frankie! Come on out,
let's play some Hearts.
Frankie!
Is it true you're worth
over 300 million dollars?
I'm a retired investor,
living on a pension.
I came home to vote
in the presidential election,
because they wouldn't give me
an absentee ballot.
Jesus Christ.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women.
Blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners.
Hey! Everybody, pay attention.
This is my friend Carlo Rizzi.
- You know my brother Fredo.
- Sure.
This is my stepbrother Tom,
and that's his girl Theresa.
This cute little thing is my sister Connie.
- Say hello to Carlo. He's good-looking?
- Yes.
The droopy thing is Mike.
We call him Joe College.
Sit down. Talk to each other.
Hey, Mr Einstein...
- The cake.
- Sally, get in here!
- I was scared.
- Come on.
- Where's your father?
- Christmas shopping.
Let's see that thing.
That's nice!
- Should I put the candles on now?
- Yeah. You help her, Carlo.
- What is that? Rum?
- Yeah.
Don't touch the antipasto
until Pop sees it.
He's not ugly...
What do you think of the nerve of those
Japs? Bombing us on Pop's birthday.
They didn't know it was Pop's birthday.
Not surprising after the oil embargo.
They've got no right dropping bombs!
Are you a Jap-lover?
- 30,000 enlisted this morning.
- Bunch of saps...
- Why are they saps?
- Let's not talk about the war.
You talk to Carlo.
Only saps risk their lives for strangers.
- That's Pop talking.
- You're right, that's Pop talking!
- They risk their lives for their country.
- Country isn't your blood.
- I don't feel that way.
- Then quit college and join the army!
I did.
I've enlisted in the Marines.
- Why didn't you come to us?
- What do you mean?
- Pop managed to get you a deferment.
- I didn't ask for it.
I didn't want it.
Come on! Knock it off!
- Punk!
- Sonny, sit down.
Mommy, Daddy's fighting again!
Go and show Carlo the tree.
Nice.
Break your father's heart
on his birthday.
That's swell, Mike. Congratulations.
Don't encourage him!
Get me a drink. Go on!
You don't understand.
Your father has plans for you.
Many times he and I have talked
about your future.
You've talked to my father
about my future?
- My future.
- Mikey, he has high hopes for you.
- I have my own plans for my future.
- Did you go to college to get stupid?
He's here!
Come on.
Stupid!
Surprise!
For he's a jolly good fellow
That nobody can deny
Nobody can deny...