# See them
tumbling down #
# Pledging their love
to the ground #
Narrator: A way out west
there was this fella,
fella I want
to tell you about,
fella by the name
of Jeff Lebowski,
at least that
was the handle
That his loving parents
gave him.
But he never had
much use for it himself.
This Lebowski,
he called himself The Dude.
Now Dude, that's a name
no one would self-apply
where I come from.
But then, there was
a lot about The Dude
that didn't make a whole
lot of sense to me,
and a lot about
where he lived, likewise.
# Along with the
tumbling tumbleweed #
Narrator: But then again,
maybe that's why I found the
place so dern interesting.
They call Los Angeles
The City of Angels.
I didn't find it
to be that exactly.
But I値l allow there
are some nice folks there.
'Course I can't
say I seen London,
And I never
been to France,
And I ain't never seen no
queen in her damned undies
as the fella says.
But I値l tell you what,
after seeing Los Angeles
And this a-here story
I'm about to unfold,
Well, I guess
I seen somethin'
every bit as stupefyin'
as you'd see in any
of those other places,
and in English, too.
So I can die
with a smile on my face
without feeling like
the good Lord gypped me.
Now this here story
I'm about to unfold
took place back
in the early nineties,
just about the time of
our conflict with Saddam
and the Iraqis.
I only mention it 'cause
sometimes there's a man,
I won't say a hero,
'Cause what's a hero?
But sometimes
there's a man,
and I知 talking
about The Dude here,
sometimes there's a man,
well,
he's the man
for his time and place.
He fits right in there,
and that's The Dude,
in Los Angeles.
And even if
he's a lazy man,
and The Dude was
most certainly that,
quite possibly the laziest
in Los Angeles county,
which would place him
high in the running
for laziest worldwide.
But sometimes
there's a man,
sometimes...
There's a man.
Wow, lost my train
of thought here.
But--ah, hell.
I done introduced
him enough.
George Bush: All for
a collective action.
This will not stand.
This will not stand,
this aggression
against Kuwait.
# Here on the range
I belong #
# Drifting along
with the tumbling #
# Tumbleweed #
Aah!
Where's the money,
Lebowski?
I want that money,
Lebowski.
Bunny says you're
good for it.
Where's the money,
Lebowski?
Where's the fucking
money, shithead?!
Well, it's, uh, ohh,
Uh,
It's down there somewhere.
let me take another look.
Don't fuck with us!
Your wife owes money
to Jackie Treehorn,
That means you own
money to Jackie Treehorn.
Ever thus to
deadbeats, Lebowski.
No, no, don't do that--
Not on the rug, man.
See?
See what happens,
Lebowski?
You see what happens?
Nobody calls me
Lebowski.
You got the wrong guy.
I'm The Dude, man.
Your name's
Lebowski, Lebowski.
Your wife is Bunny.
My--my wife--
my wife Bunny?
Do you see a wedding
ring on my finger?
Does this place look
like I知 fucking married?
The toilet seat's up,
man.
What the fuck
is this?
Obviously,
you're not a golfer.
Woo?
Yeah?
Isn't this guy supposed
to be a millionaire?
Woo: Fuck!
Yeah, what do you think?
He looks like
a fucking loser.
Hey, at least
I'm housebroken.
Fucking time wasted.
Thanks a lot,
asshole.
# La la la la
la la la la la #
# La la la la #
# La la la #
# La la la la
la la la la la #
# The man in me will do #
# Nearly any task #
# And as for compensation #
# There's a little
he would ask #
# Take a woman like you #
# To get through #
# To the man in me #
# The storm clouds
are raging #
# All around my door #
# I think to myself #
# I might not
take it anymore #
# Take a woman
like your kind #
# To find the man in me #
# But, oh #
# What a wonderful feeling #
# Just to know
that you are near #
# That sets
my heart a-reelin' #
# From my toes #
# Up to my ears #
# The man in me
will hide sometimes #
# To keep from being seen #
# But that's just because #
# He doesn't want to
turn into some machine #
# Take a woman like you #
# To get through #
# To the man in me #
Whoo!
I'm throwing
rocks tonight.
Mark it, Dude.
This was a valued rug.
Ahem. This was a...
Yeah, man, it really
tied the room together.
So this was
a valued, uh--
What tied the room
together, Dude?
My rug.
Were you listening to
The Dude's story, Donny?
What?
Were you listening
to The Dude's story?
I was bowling.
So you have no frame
of reference here, Donny.
You're like a child
who wanders in
in the middle of a movie--
Walter, what's
the point, man?
There's no reason--
here's my point, Dude--
There's no fucking reason--
Yeah, Walter,
what's your point?
Huh?
Walter, what
is the point--
Look, we all know
who is at fault here.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Huh? No, what
the fuck are you--
I'm not--
We're talking about unchecked
aggression here, Dude.
What the fuck is
he talking about?
My rug.
Forget it, Donny.
you're out of your element.
Walter, the chinaman
who peed on my rug,
I can't go
give him a bill.
So what the fuck
are you talking about?
What the fuck
The chinaman is not
the issue here, Dude.
I'm talking about drawing
a line in the sand, Dude.
Across this line,
you do not--
Also, Dude, chinaman is not
the preferred nomenclature.
Asian-american,
please.
Walter, this isn't a guy
who built the railroads here,
this is a guy--
What the fuck
are you talking--
Walter,
he peed on my rug.
He peed on
The Dude's rug.
Donny, you're
out of your element.
Dude, the chinaman
is not the issue here.
So, who--who--
Jeff Lebowski.
The other
Jeffrey Lebowski,
the millionaire.
That's fucking
interesting, man.
interesting.
Plus, he has
the wealth, obviously,
and the resources,
uh, so that
there's no reason--
there's no
fucking reason
why his wife
should go out
and owe money
all over town,
and then they come
and they pee on
your fucking rug!
Am I wrong? No.
Am I wrong?
Yeah, but--
Ok, then. Ahem.
That rug really tied
the room together,
Did it not?
Fuckin' a!
And this guy
peed on it.
Donny, please.
You know, this
is the fucking guy--
I could find this
fucking Lebowski guy.
His name is Lebowski?
That's your name, Dude.
This is the guy
who should compensate me
for the fucking rug.
His wife goes out
and owes money
all over town,
and they pee on my rug?
They pee on
your fucking rug.
my fucking rug.
Walter: That's right, Dude.
They peed on
your fucking rug.
This is the study.
As you can see,
the various commendations...
"Jeffrey Lebowski."
Honorary degrees,
etcetera.
Hmm, very impressive.
Oh, please feel free
to inspect them.
Hmm? Oh, no, I知
not really that--
Oh, please, please.
That is the key to
the city of Pasadena,
Which Mr. Lebowski
received 2 years ago
In recognition of
his various civic, uh...
Oh, that's
the Los Angeles
Chamber of Commerce
Business Achiever Award,
which is given--
oh, not necessarily
given every year.
Hey, is this, uh,
is this him with Nancy?
Yes, indeed,
that is Mr. Lebowski
with the first lady, yes.
it was taken when--
That's, uh, Lebowski
on the left there?
Yeah, of course.
Mr. Lebowski on the left--
so he's a cripple--
Uh, you know,
a--a handicapped guy?
Mr. Lebowski
is disabled, yes.
Uh, this picture
was taken
when Mrs. Reagan was
first lady of the nation,
Yes, yes.
Not of California.
Pope John.
Uh, in fact, he met
privately with the President,
though unfortunately,
There wasn't enough time
for a photo opportunity.
Oh, Nancy痴 pretty good.
Oh, wonderful woman.
we're very happy--
these are, uh...
oh, those are Mr. Lebowski's
children, so to speak.
Different mothers, huh?
Racially, pretty cool.
Ha ha ha ha.
They're not literally
his children.
They're the little
Lebowski Urban Achievers,
Inner-city children
of promise
but without
the necessary means for--
necessary means for
a higher education.
So Mr. Lebowski
is committed
to sending all
of them to college.
Excuse me.
Thank you. Thank you.
Far out.
Think he's got room
for one more?
One, uh...
Oh. Ha ha ha.
You never
went to college.
Please,
don't touch that.
Yeah, no, I did,
but, you know,
I spent most
of my time, um,
occupying various
administration buildings,
uh, smoking a lot
of thai stick,
breaking into
the R.O.T.C.,
and bowling.
to tell you
the truth, Brandt,
I don't remember
most of it.
Oh.
Hmm.
Ok, sir, you're a Lebowski,
I'm a Lebowski,
That's terrific.
But I知 very busy,
as I imagine you are.
What can I
do for you, sir?
Uh, well, sir,
it's, uh,
this rug I have.
It really tied
the room together. Uh--
You told Brandt on
the phone, he told me.
Where do I fit in?
Well, uh, they were--
They were looking
for you, these 2 guys.
Uh--
I値l say it again.
You told Brandt on
the phone, he told me.
I know what happened.
Yes? Yes?
Oh, so you know that
They were trying
to piss on your rug?
Did I urinate
on your rug?
You mean, did you
personally come
and pee on my rug?
Hello! Do you
speak English, son?
Parla usted ingles?
I値l ask you again.
Did I urinate on your rug?
No, like I said,
Woo peed on my rug.
I just want to
understand this, sir.
Every time a rug
is micturated upon
In this fair city, I have
to compensate the person--
Come on, man,
I'm not trying
io scam anybody here.
Uh, you know,
I--I was just--
You were just
looking for a handout
like every other...
Are you employed,
Mr. Lebowski?
Uh, wait, let me--
let me explain
something to you.
I am not Mr. Lebowski.
You're Mr. Lebowski.
I'm The Dude. So that's
what you call me,
You know, uh, that
or, uh, his Dudeness,
Or, uh, Duder, or, you
know, uh, el Duderino,
If you're not into
the whole brevity thing.
Are you employed, sir?
Employed?
Ha ha.
You don't go out
looking for a job
dressed like that,
do you, on a weekday?
Is this a--
what day is this?
Well, I do work, sir.
So if you don't mind--
No, I do mind.
Uh, The Dude minds.
This will not stand,
you know.
This aggression
will not stand, man.
I mean, your wife owes--
My wife is not
the issue here!
I hope that
someday my wife
will learn to live
on her allowance,
which is ample,
but if she does not,
that is her problem,
not mine,
just as the rug
is your problem,
just as every bum's
lot in life
is his own
responsibility,
regardless of who
he chooses to blame.
I didn't blame anyone
for the loss of my legs.
Some chinaman took them
from me in Korea.
But I went out
and achieved anyway.
Ha ha ha.
I cannot solve
your problems, sir,
only you can.
Oh, fuck it.
Yes, that's your answer.
That's your answer
to everything.
Tattoo it
on your forehead.
Your revolution is
over, Mr. Lebowski!
Condolences!
The bums lost!
My advice to you is to do
what your parents did!
Get a job, sir!
The bums will always lose!
Do you hear me,
Lebowski?!
The bums
will always lose!
How was your meeting,
Mr. Lebowski?
Ok. The old man told me to
take any rug in the house.
Well, enjoy,
and perhaps we'll see you
again sometime, Dude.
Yeah, sure, uh, if I知
in the neighborhood,
You know, and, uh...
I need to use the John.
Blow on them.
Huh?
Go ahead, blow.
You want me to blow
on your, uh, toes?
Uh-huh. Ha ha ha.
I can't blow that far.
Are you sure
he won't mind?
He really doesn't
care about anything.
He's a nihilist.
Oh, and that
must be exhausting.
You're not blowing.
Our guest has to be getting
along, Mrs. Lebowski.
Oh, you're Bunny.
I値l suck your cock
for $1,000.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Wonderful woman.
We're all--we're all
very fond of her.
Very free-spirited.
Brandt can't watch,
though,
Or he has
to pay 100.
Ha ha ha.
that's marvelous.
Uh, I知 just gonna
go find a cash machine.
Whoo! Ha ha!
Slamming them
tonight.
You guys are
dead in the water.
Walter: All right!
Way to go, Donny!
If you will it,
it is no dream.
You're fucking
20 minutes late, man.
What the fuck is that?
Theodore Herzel.
Huh?
The state of Israel.
If you will it, Dude,
It is no dream.
What the fuck you
talking about, man?
The carrier. What's
in the fucking carrier?
Hmm?
Oh, Cynthia痴 dog.
I think
it's a Pomeranian.
I can't leave him
home alone
or he eats
the furniture.
I'm watching it
while Cynthia
and Marty Ackerman
are in Hawaii.
You brought a fucking
Pomeranian bowling?
What do you mean,
"brought it bowling"?
I didn't rent it shoes,
I'm not buying it
a fucking beer,
he's not taking
your fucking turn, Dude.
Man, if my
fucking ex-wife
asked me to take care
of her fucking dog
while she and her boyfriend
went to Honolulu,
I'd tell her to
go fuck herself.
Why can't she board it?
First of all, Dude,
you don't have an ex.
Secondly, this is
a fucking show dog
with fucking papers.
You can't board it.
It gets upset.
Its hair falls out.
Walter--
The fucking dog
has fucking papers.
Over the line!
Huh?
I'm sorry, Smokey,
you were over the line.
That's a foul.
Bullshit.
Mark it 8, Dude.
Uh, excuse me, mark it
zero. Next frame.
Bullshit, Walter.
Mark it 8, Dude.
Smokey, this is not
'nam, this is bowling.
There are rules.
Hey, Walter, come on,
it's just--
Hey, man, it's Smokey.
So his toe slipped
over a little.
You know, it's
just a game, man.
This is a league game.
This determines
who enters
the next round-robin.
Am I wrong?
Smokey: Yeah,
but I wasn't--
Am I wrong?
Yeah,
but I wasn't over.
Give me
the marker, Dude.
I'm marking an 8.
Smokey, my friend,
You're entering
a world of pain.
Walter, man.
You mark
that frame an 8,
You're entering
a world of pain.
I'm not--
A world of pain.
Look, Dude,
this is your partner.
Has the whole world
gone crazy?!
Am I the only one
around here
who gives a shit
about the rules?!
Mark it zero!
They're calling
the cops, man.
Put the piece away.
Mark it zero!
Walter, put
the piece away.
Walter--
You think I知
fucking around here?
Mark it zero!
All right,
it's fucking zero.
You happy,
you crazy fuck?
It's a league game,
Smoke.
You can't do that, man.
These guys, you know,
they're like me.
They're pacifists.
Smokey was a
conscientious objector.
You know, Dude,
I, myself,
dabbled in pacifism
at one point,
not in 'nam,
of course.
And you know he's got
emotional problems, man.
You mean,
beyond pacifism?
He's fragile,
Very fragile.
Huh. I did not know that.
Well,
it's all water
under the bridge,
and we do enter
the next round-robin.
Am I wrong?
No, you're not wrong.
You're not wrong,
Walter,
you're just an asshole!
Ok, then.
We play Quintana
and O達rien next week.
They should be pushovers.
Man, will you just--
Just take it easy,
man.
You know, that's your
answer for everything, Dude.
And let me
point out something.
Pacifism is not--look
at our current situation
with that
camelfucker in Iraq.
Pacifism is not something
to hide behind.
Just take it easy, man.
I'm perfectly calm, Dude.
Yeah, waving
the fucking gun around?
Calmer than you are.
Will you
just take it easy?
Calmer than you are.
Dude, this is Smokey.
Look, I don't want to
be a hard-on about this,
and I know it
wasn't your fault,
but I just thought
it was fair to tell you
that Gilbert and I will be
submitting this to the league
and asking them to
set aside the round,
I don't know,
maybe forfeit it to us.
So, like I say, just thought,
you know, fair warning.
Tell Walter. I'm sorry.
Mr. Lebowski, this
is Brandt at, uh,
well, at
Mr. Lebowski's office.
Please call us as
soon as it's convenient.
Mr. Lebowski,
this is Bill Selliger
of the Southern Cal
Bowling League,
and I just got
uh, an informal report
that a member of your team,
a Walter Sobchak,
drew a firearm
during league play.
If this is true,
of course,
it contravenes a number
of the league's bylaws
and also article 27
of the league--
Man: Dude.
Hey, Monty.
Dude, I--I finally got--
I got the, uh,
the venue I wanted.
I'm performing
my dance quintet,
you know, my cycle,
at Crane Jackson's
fountain street theater
on Tuesday night,
and, well, I壇
love it if you came
and gave me notes.
I値l be there, man.
Uh...
Dude, uh,
tomorrow's
already the 10th.
Far out.
Oh. Oh, all right, ok.
Just, uh, just slip
the rent under my door.
Bill Selliger:
...serious infraction
and examine your standing.
Thank you.
Mr. Lebowski,
Brandt again.
Please do call us as
soon as you get in,
and I値l
send a limo.
I hope you're not
avoiding this call
because of the rug--
Ha ha ha--
Which, I assure you,
is not a problem.
We need your help,
and, uh...
Well, we'd very much
like to see you.
Thank you.
it's Brandt.
We've had some
terrible news.
Mr. Lebowski's in seclusion
in the west wing.
Mr. Lebowski.
Funny...
I can look back
on a life of achievement,
challenges met,
competitors bested,
obstacles overcome.
I've accomplished more
than most men
and without the use
of my legs.
What...
What makes a man,
Mr. Lebowski?
Dude.
Huh?
Uh, I--I
don't know, sir.
Is it being prepared
to do the right thing?
Whatever the cost?
Isn't that what
makes a man?
Mmm, sure, that
and a pair of testicles.
You're joking.
But...
Perhaps you're right.
You mind
if I do a "j"?
Bunny...
Excuse me?
Bunny Lebowski,
She is the light
of my life.
Are you surprised
at my tears, sir?
Fuckin' a.
Strong men also cry.
I received this fax
this morning.
As you can see,
it is a ransom note.
"We have Bunnie."
Written by men who
are unable to achieve
on a level field
of play.
"Gather one million dollars
in unmarked,
non-consecutive twenties."
Weaklings.
"Await instructions."
Bums!
"No funny stuff."
Bummer.
Huh?
This is a bummer,
man.
That's, uh,
that's a bummer.
Brandt will fill you in
on the details.
Mr. Lebowski
is prepared to make
a generous offer to you
to act as courier
once we get instructions
for the money.
Why me, man?
He believes the culprits
might be the very people
who, uh...
soiled your rug,
and you're in
a unique position
to confirm
or disconfirm
that suspicion.
He thinks the
carpet pissers did this?
Well, Dude,
we just don't know.
Fucking Quintana.
That creep
can roll, man.
Yeah, but he's
a pervert, Dude.
Yeah.
No. He's a sex offender
with a record.
He did 6 months at chino
for exposing himself
to an 8-year-old.
When he
moved to Hollywood,
hHe had to go
door-to-door
to tell everyone
he was a pederast.
Donny: What's
a pederast, Walter?
Shut the fuck up,
Donny.
So...
How much
they give you?
20 grand, man.
And, of course, I still
get to keep the rug.
Just for making
the hand-off?
Yeah. They gave, uh,
Dude a beeper.
Now, so whenever
these guys call--
What if it's
during a game?
Oh, I told them if it
was during league play...
What's during
league play?
Life does not
stop and start
at your convenience,
you miserable
piece of shit.
I figure, uh...
What's wrong
with Walter, Dude?
I figure
it's easy money.
It's all
pretty harmless.
She probably
kidnapped herself.
Huh?
What do you mean, Dude?
Rug pee-ers
did not do this.
Look at it.
A young trophy wife
marries this guy
for his money.
She figures he isn't
giving her enough.
You know, she owes money
all over town.
That fuckin'...
Bitch.
It's all goddamn
fake, man.
It's like Lenin said.
You look for the person
who will benefit,
and, uh, uh,
you know...
I am the walrus?
You know,
you'll, uh, uh...
You know what
I'm trying to say.
I am the walrus.
That fuckin' bitch!
Oh, yeah.
I am the walrus.
Shut the fuck up,
Donny!
V.I. Lenin. Vladimir
Ilyich Ulyanov!
What the fuck
is he talking about?
Fucking exactly
what happened.
That makes me
fucking sick.
What do you care,
Walter?
Those rich fucks.
This whole
fuckin' thing.
I did not watch
my buddies die
facedown in the mud
so that this
fucking strumpet,
This fucking whore--
I don't see any connection
to Vietnam, man.
Well, there's
a literal connection.
No, Walter, face it,
there isn't any connection.
Your roll.
Have it your way,
but my point is--
Your roll.
My point is--
Quintana: Are you ready
to be fucked, man?
I see you roll your way
into the semis.
Dios mio, man.
Liam and me, we're
gonna fuck you up.
Yeah?
Well...you know,
that's just like, uh...
Your opinion, man.
Let me tell you
something, pendejo,
you pull any
crazy shit with us,
you flash a piece out
on the lanes,
I値l take it away from you
and stick it up your ass
and pull
The fuckin' trigger
till it goes click.
Jesus.
You said it, man.
Nobody fucks
with the Jesus.
8-year-olds, Dude.
# La-la la-la-la-la
la la la #
# La-la-la-la
# La la
la-la-la-la-la #
# La la la la #
# La la la #
# La-la-la-la
la la la la la-la #
# The man in me will do #
# Nearly any task #
# And as for compensation #
# There's little
he will ask #
# Aah! #
# Take a woman
like you #
# To get through #
# To the man in me #
# The storm clouds
are raging #
# All around my door #
# I think to myself #
# I might not take it
anymore #
# Take a woman
like your kind #
# To find #
# The man in me #
# But oh-ohh #
# What a wonderful feeling #
# Just to know
that you are near... #
Ohh, man.
Ohh!
Ohh...
They called about
80 minutes ago.
They want you
to take the money,
drive north on the 405.
They will call you
on the portable phone
with instructions
n about 40 minutes.
One person only. They
were very clear on that,
Or I壇 go with you.
One person only.
What happened to your jaw?
Oh, nothin',
you know.
Here's the money.
And the phone.
Please, Dude, follow whatever
instructions they give.
All right.
Her life is in your hands.
Oh, man,
don't say that.
Mr. Lebowski asked me
to repeat that.
Her life is in your hands.
Oh, shit, man.
Her life is in
your hands, Dude.
Report back to us
as soon as it's done.
Where the fuck
are you goin', man?
Take the ringer.
I値l drive.
What? The what?
The ringer.
The ringer,
Dude.
Have they
Called yet? What the--
What the hell is this?
My dirty undies,
Dude.
Laundry.
The whites.
Walter, I知 sure
there's a reason
you brought
your dirty undies, man.
That's right, Dude.
The weight.
The ringer
cannot look empty.
Walter, what the fuck
are you thinking, man?
You're right, Dude.
I got to thinking.
I got to thinking
why should we settle
for a measly fuckin'
20 grand--
We? What the fuck we?
You said you just wanted
to come along.
My point, Dude, is
why should we
settle for 20 grand
when we can keep
the entire million?
Am I wrong?
Yes, you're wrong.
This isn't
a fuckin' game, man.
Oh, but it is a game.
You said so yourself.
She kidnapped herself.
I said I thought--
Dude here.
Man, German accent:
Who is this?
Dude the bagman, man.
Where do you want us to go?
Us?
Shit!
Yeah, you know,
me and the driver.
I'm not handling the money,
driving the car,
and talking on the phone
all by my--
Shut the fuck up!
Dude, are you
fuckin' this up?
Who is that?
That is the driver.
I told you--
Shit!
What the fuck's
goin' on?
Walter! What the fuck
is goin' on?
He hung up, man!
You fucked it up!
Her life was
in our hands, man.
Easy, Dude.
We're screwed now.
We don't get shit.
They're gonna kill her.
We're fucked, Walter.
Nothing is fucked,
Dude.
Come on, you're
being very un-Dude.
They'll call back.
Look,
she kidnapped--
You see? Nothing's
fucked here, Dude.
Nothing is fucked.
They're a bunch of
fuckin' amateurs!
Hey, Walter, will you
just shut the fuck up?
Don't say peep while I知
doin' business here, man.
Ok, Dude,
have it your way.
But they're amateurs.
Fuck.
Dude.
Ok, we proceed.
But only if there's
no funny stuff.
Yeah, yeah.
So no funny stuff, ok?
Just tell me where the fuck
you want us to go.
That was the sign, man.
So all we gotta do
is get her back,
No one's in a position
to complain,
And we keep
the baksheesh.
Yeah, terrific, Walter,
but you haven't told me how
we're gonna get her back.
Where is she?
That's the simple part,
Dude.
We make the hand-off,
I grab one of 'em,
beat it out of him.
Huh?
Yeah. That's
a great plan.
Walter, that's
fucking ingenious,
If I understand it
correctly.
It's a Swiss
fuckin' watch.
That's right, Dude.
The beauty of this
is its simplicity.
Once a plan
gets too complex,
everything
can go wrong.
If there's one thing I
learned in 'nam, it's--
Dude.
You're coming
to a wooden bridge.
When you cross
the bridge,
you throw the bag
from the left window
of the moving car.
You're being watched.
Fuck!
What'd he say?
Where's the hand-off?
There is no fuckin'
hand-off, man.
At the wooden bridge, we throw
the money out of the car.
Huh?
We throw the money
out of the moving car.
No, we can't
do that, Dude.
That fucks up
our plan.
Well, call 'em up and
explain it to them, Walter.
Your plan
is so fuckin' simple
I'm sure they'll
fuckin' understand it.
That's the beauty of it.
Wooden bridge, huh?
I'm throwin' the money,
Walter.
We're not fuckin'
around, man.
Ok, Dude,
bridge is comin' up.
Give me the ringer,
chop-chop.
Fuck that, Walter.
I love ya,
but sooner or later you're
gonna have to face the fact
you're a goddamn moron.
Ok, Dude.
No time to argue.
Hey, man.
The bridge.
Hey, Walter! Hey!
Walter, hey!
There goes the ringer!
What the fuck?!
Here, Dude, your wheel.
At 15 mph, I roll out.
I double back, grab one,
and beat it out of him.
The Uzi.
Uzi?!
You didn't think I was
rolling out of here naked?
W-Walter, please--
15, Dude. This is it.
Let's take that hill!
Whoo-hoo-oo.
Aah...aah.
We have it!
We...have it!
Aw, fuck it, Dude.
Let's go bowling.
Ah.
Etz chaim he, Dude,
as the ex used to say.
What the fuck is that
supposed to mean?
What the fuck are we
gonna tell Lebowski?
Huh?
Oh, him. Uh...
Well, uh, what exactly
is the problem?
The problem is--
What do you mean,
What's the--
There was no...
We--we didn't, uh...
They're gonna kill
that poor woman, man.
What the fuck are you
talking about?
The poor woman--
that poor slut
kidnapped herself.
Come on, Dude,
you said so yourself.
Man, I said I thought
she kidnapped herself.
You're the one who's
so fuckin' certain.
That's right, Dude.
100% certain.
They posted the next round
for the tournament.
Donny, shut the fuck--
when do we play?
This Saturday.
Quintana and--
Saturday? Well, they
have to reschedule.
Walter, what am I
gonna tell Lebowski?
I told that fuck down
at the league office--
Who's in charge Walter--
of scheduling?
Burkhalter.
I told that kraut
a fuckin' thousand times
I don't roll
on Shabbos.
He already Walter--
posted it.
Well, he can fuckin'
unpost it!
Who gives a shit?!
They're gonna kill
that poor woman, man.
What am I gonna tell
Lebowski?
Come on, Dude,
eventually she'll get tired
of her little game
and, you know,
wander on back.
How come you don't roll
on Saturday, Walter?
I'm Shomer Shabbos.
What's that, Walter?
Yeah,
and in the meantime,
What do I tell
Lebowski?
Saturday, Donny,
is Shabbos,
The jewish day of rest.
That means I don't work,
I don't drive a car,
I don't fuckin' ride in a car,
I don't handle money,
I don't turn on the oven,
and I sure as shit
don't fucking roll!
Sheesh.
Shomer Shabbos!
Walter,
How am I gonna--
Shomer fucking Shabbos.
Oh, fuck! That's it!
I'm outta here.
Oh, come on, Dude.
Dude! Dude!
Look, you just tell him--
Tell him we made the drop,
and everything went,
you know...
Oh, yeah,
how'd it go?
Went all right. Dude's car
got a little dinged up.
Walter, we didn't make
the fuckin' hand-off, man.
They didn't get
the fuckin' money!
And they're gonna--
they're gonna--
They're gonna kill
that poor woman.
that poor woman
Hey, Walter, if you
can't ride in a car,
how do you get around
on shammos?
Really, Dude,
you surprise me.
They're not gonna kill shit,
they're not gonna do shit.
What can they do to her?
They're a bunch
of fuckin' amateurs,
And meanwhile,
look at the bottom line.
Who's sittin' on
a million fucking dollars?
Am I wrong? Walter--
Who's got a fuckin' million
fuckin' dollars
sitting in the trunk
of our car?
Our car, Walter?
And what do they got?
My dirty undies.
My fuckin' whites.
Say, Dude.
Where is your car?
Who's got your
undies, Walter?
Where's your car, Dude?
You don't know,
Walter?
It was parked
in a handicap zone.
Perhaps they towed it.
You fuckin' know
it's been stolen.
Well, certainly that's
a possibility, Dude.
Oh, fuck it.
Donny:
Where you goin', Dude?
I'm goin' home, Donny.
Phone's ringing, Dude.
Thank you, Donny.
Uh...
Yeah, uh...
Green.
Some, uh, brown or...
Rust coloration.
And was there anything
of value in the car?
Oh. Uh, yeah.
Uh...a tape deck,
some Creedence tapes,
and there was a, uh...
Uh, my briefcase.
In the briefcase?
Uh, uh, papers.
You know, um,
just papers.
Uh, you know,
uh, my papers.
Business papers.
And what do you do,
Sir?
I'm unemployed.
My rug was
also stolen.
Your rug was in the car?
No, here.
Separate incidents?
Answering machine:
The Dude is not in.
Do you find them much,
these stolen cars?
Sometimes.
Wouldn't hold out much hope
for the tape deck, though.
Or the Creedence.
Well, what about, uh...
The briefcase?
Woman: Mr. Lebowski,
I'd like to see you.
Call when you get home,
and I値l send a car for you.
My name is Maude Lebowski.
I'm the one
who took your rug.
Whoa.
Guess we can close
the file on that one.
Huh.
Woman: El Franco,
ay`dame abajo.
I値l be with you
in a moment, Mr. Lebowski.
Does the female form make you
uncomfortable, Mr. Lebowski?
Uh, is that what this
is a picture of?
In a sense, yes.
My art has been commended
as being strongly vaginal,
which bothers some men.
The word itself makes
some men uncomfortable.
Vagina.
Oh, yeah?
Yes, they don't like hearing it
and find it difficult to say,
whereas without
batting an eye,
a man will refer to
his dick or his rod
Or his... Johnson.
Johnson?
All right, Mr. Lebowski.
Let's get down to cases.
My father told me he agreed
to let you have the rug,
but as it was a gift
from me to my late mother,
it was not his to give.
Now--
Your face.
As for this kidnapping...
Huh?
Yes, I know all about it,
And I know that
you acted as courier.
Let me tell you something.
The whole thing stinks
to high heaven.
Yeah...
Right, but let me
explain something
About the rug.
Do you like sex,
Mr. Lebowski?
Excuse me?
Sex. The physical act
of love. Coitus.
Do you like it?
I was talking
about my rug.
You're not interested
in sex?
You mean coitus?
I like it, too.
It's a male myth
about feminists
That we hate sex.
It can be a natural,
zesty enterprise.
However, there
are some people--
It is called satyriasis in men,
nymphomania in women--
who engage in it compulsively
and without joy.
Oh, no.
Oh, yes, Mr. Lebowski.
These unfortunate souls
cannot love
in the true sense
of the word.
Our mutual acquaintance
Bunny is one of these.
Listen, Maude,
um, I知 sorry if your
stepmother is a nympho,
but, you know,
I don't see what this
has to do with, uh...
Do you have any Kahlua?
Take a look
at this, sir.
Hmm?
Oh, I know that guy.
He's a nihilist.
Hi.
Hello. Meine dispatcher says
there's something wrong
mitt deine kable.
Yeah, come on in.
I'm not really sure
exactly what's really
wrong with the cable.
Zat's why they sent me.
I am an expert.
The TV痴 in here.
You recognize her,
of course.
Bunny: Oh, that's
my friend Shari.
She just came over
to use the shower.
The story
is ludicrous.
Meine nommen is Karl.
Ich bin expert.
You must be here
to fix the cable.
Maude: Lord, you can imagine
where it goes from here.
He fixes the cable?
Don't be fatuous,
Jeffrey.
Little matter to me
that this woman chose
to pursue a career
in pornography
nor that she has been
"banging" Jackie Treehorn,
to use the parlance
of our times,
however,
I am one of the 2 trustees
of the Lebowski Foundation,
the other being my father.
The Foundation takes
youngsters from watts and--
Shit, yeah,
the achievers.
Little Lebowski
urban achievers, yes,
and proud we are
of all of them,
I asked my father about
his withdrawal of $1 million
from the Foundation account,
and he told me
about this abduction.
But I tell you,
it is preposterous.
This compulsive fornicator
is taking my father
for the proverbial ride.
Yeah, but my--
I'm getting to your rug.
My father and I
don't get along.
He doesn't approve
of my lifestyle,
and, needless to say,
I don't approve of his.
However, I hardly wish to make
my father's embezzlement
a police matter,
so I知 proposing that you
try to recover the money
from the people
you delivered it to.
Well, uh,
I could do that.
If you successfully do so,
I will compensate you
to the tune of 10%
of the recovered sum.
A hundred...
Thousand. Yes.
Bones or clams
Or whatever you call them.
Yeah, but--but, uh...
What about my, uh...
Your rug, yes.
well, with that money
you can buy
any number of rugs
That don't have
sentimental value for me.
And I am sorry about
that crack on the jaw.
Oh, th-that's fine.
That doesn't even, uh...
Here's the name and number
of a doctor
who will look at it
for you.
You will receive no bill.
He's a good man,
and thorough.
Th-that's thoughtful,
But--
Please see him, Jeffrey.
He's a good man,
and thorough.
Oh, well...
All right.
So he says, "My wife's
a pain in the ass.
She's always bustin'
my friggin' agates.
My daughter's married
to a real loser bastard,
and I got a rash
so bad on my ass
I can't even sit down.
But you know me, I can't
complain."
Ah, fuckin' a, man.
I got a rash, man.
Fuckin' a.
I gotta tell you,
Tone, man,
Earlier in the day, I was
really feeling shitty, man.
Really down
in the dumps.
Lost a little money...
Hey, you know what?
forget about it, huh?
Forget about it.
Yeah, fuck it, man.
I can't be worried
about that shit.
Life goes on, man.
Home, sweet home,
Mr. L.
Tony: Hey, yo. Look.
Who's your friend
in the Volkswagen?
Huh?
Yeah, he followed us
here.
When did he start foll--
Aah!
What the fuck?!
In the limo, you son
of a bitch. No arguing.
Hey, careful, man.
there's a beverage here.
Hey!
Start talking
and talk fast,
you lousy bum.
We've been frantically
trying to reach you, Dude.
Where's my goddamn
money, you bum?!
W-well, we...
I--I--I...
They did not
receive the money,
you nitwit!
They did not receive
the money!
Her life
was in your hands!
This is our concern,
Dude.
No, man,
nothing is fucked here.
Nothing is fucked?!
No, man.
The goddamn plane
Has crashed
into the mountain!
Look, man, come on.
Who are you gonna believe,
those guys or, uh...
We dropped off
the damn money.
We?!
I.
The royal we.
You know, the editorial.
I dropped off the money
exactly as per--
Look. Man, I致e got certain
information, all right?
Certain things have
come to light, and...
You know, has it
ever occurred to you
that instead of, uh,
you know, running around,
uh, blaming me, given the
nature of all this new shit,
th-th-this could be
a lot more, uh...
Uh, uh, uh, complex?
I mean, it might not be
just such a simple, uh,
You know?
What in God's
holy name
Are you blathering
about?
Well, I値l tell you what
I'm blathering about.
I've got information, man.
New shit has come to light.
And--and, shit, man...
She kidnapped herself.
Well, sure, man.
Look at it. You know,
a young trophy wife--
In the parlance
of our times, you know--
She, uh, uh, uh, owes
money all over town,
Including to known
pornographers.
And that's cool.
that-that's cool.
I'm saying,
she needs money, man.
And--and, you know,
of course they're gonna say
they didn't get it,
uh, uh, because
she wants more, man.
She's gotta feed the monkey.
I mean, uh...
Hasn't that ever occurred
to you, man?
Sir?
No, Mr. Lebowski,
it had not occurred
to me.
That had not occurred
to us, Dude.
Well, ok, you know,
you guys aren't privy
to all the new shit, so...
Uh, you know. But...
Hey, that's what you--
that's what you pay me for.
Speaking of which,
do you think that you could, uh,
give me my 20,000 in cash?
My concern is--and I gotta
check with my accountant--
but this might bump me
into a higher tax, uh--
Brandt...
Give him
the envelope.
Oh, well, if you've already
got the check made out,
Th-that's cool.
We received this
this morning.
Since you have
failed to achieve,
even in the modest task
which was your charge,
since you have
stolen my money,
since you have unrepentantly
betrayed my trust...
I have no choice
but to tell these bums to do
whatever is necessary
to recover their money
from you, Jeffrey Lebowski.
And with Brandt
as my witness,
I will tell you this:
Any further harm
visited upon Bunny
will be visited tenfold
upon your head.
By god, sir, I will not
abide another toe.
# I hear the cottonwoods
whisperin' above #
That wasn't her toe, Dude.
Whose toe was it,
Walter?
How the fuck should I know?
I do know that nothing
about it indicates--
Man, the nail
polish, Walter.
Fine, Dude.
As if it's impossible
to get some nail polish,
Apply it
To someone else's toe.
Someone else's--
Where the fuck
are they gonna get--
You want a toe?
I can get you a toe.
Believe me,
there are ways, Dude.
You don't wanna know
about it, believe me.
Hell, I can get you a toe
by 3:00 this afternoon,
with nail polish.
These fuckin' amateurs.
Walter--
They send us a toe,
we're supposed to shit
ourselves with fear.
Jesus Christ. Walter--
Now, the point is--
They're gonna kill her,
Walter,
And then they're gonna
kill me.
Dude...
That's...
That's just the stress
talking, man.
Now so far we have
what appears to me
To be a series of
victimless crimes.
What about the toe?
Forget about
the fucking toe!
Excuse me, sir,
Could you please
keep your voices down?
This is a family restaurant.
Oh, please, dear.
For your information,
the supreme court
has roundly rejected
prior restraint!
Walter, this is not
a first amendment thing.
If you don't calm down,
I'm gonna have to ask you
to leave.
Lady, I got buddies who
died face down in the muck
so you and I could enjoy
this family restaurant!
All right,
I'm outta here.
Hey, Dude,
don't go away, man.
Come on, this affects
all of us, man.
Our basic freedoms!
I'm stayin'.
I'm finishing my coffee.
Enjoying my coffee.
Answering machine:
The Dude is not in.
Leave a message
after the beep.
Thanks, man.
Mr. Lebowski, this is
duty officer Rolvaag
of the LAPD.
We've recovered
your automobile.
It can be claimed at the
North Hollywood auto circus
there on Victory.
Far out, man.
Far fucking out!
H-hey!
This is a private
residence, man.
Ah, nice marmot.
Aah!
Aaaahhh!
Ve vant the money,
Lebowski.
Aah!
You think
ve are kidding
Or making with
the funny stuff?
There are things
you haven't dreamed of,
Lebowski.
Ja. Ve believe
in nothing.
He believes in nothing,
Lebowski, nothing.
and tomorrow
ve come back
and ve cut off
your chonson.
Excuse me?
I said we'll cut off
Your Johnson!
Just think about that,
Lebowski.
Ja, your viggly penis,
Ja, and maybe we stomp on it
and sqoosh it, Lebowski.
Man: It was discovered
last night in Van Nuys
lodged against
an abutment.
Oh, man, lodged where?
You're lucky she
didn't get chopped,
Mr. Lebowski.
Oh, man!
Must've been
a joyride situation.
They abandoned
the vehicle
once they hit
the retaining wall.
Oh, my
fucking briefcase!
Man, it's not here.
Shit!
Yeah, I saw that
on the report. Sorry.
You gotta get in
on the other side.
The side-view was
found on the road
by the car.
You're lucky they left
the tape deck, though,
And the Creedence.
Aw, Jesus!
What's that smell, man?
Probably a vagrant
slept in the car
or maybe just used it
as a toilet and moved on.
Hey, man...
Are you gonna find
these guys or, you know,
I mean, you got any
promising, uh, leads or...
Leads?
Yeah. Sure.
I値l just check
with the boys
down at
the crime lab.
They, uh, got
4 more detectives
Working on the case.
They got us
working in shifts.
Ha ha ha!
Leads.
My only hope is that
the big Lebowski kills me
Before the Germans
can cut my dick off.
Now, that is just
ridiculous, Dude.
No one's going to
cut your dick off.
Thank you, Walter.
Not if I have anything
to say about it.
Thank you, Walter.
That makes me feel
very secure.
Dude.
That makes me feel
very warm inside.
Now, Dude.
This whole
fuckin' thing.
I could be sitting here
with just pee stains
on my rug.
Yeah.
But, no, man,
I gotta, you know.
Fucking Germans.
Nothing changes.
Fucking Nazis.
They were Nazis, Dude?
Oh, come on, Donny.
They were threatening
castration.
Are we gonna
split hairs here?
No.
Am I wrong?
Well, he--he--
They were
nihilists, man.
Huh?
They kept saying
they believed in nothing.
Nihilists.
Fuck me.
I mean,
say what you want
about the tenets
of national
Socialism, Dude.
At least
it's an ethos.
And also,
let's not forget--
Let痴 not forget,
Dude--
That keeping
wildlife, um,
an amphibious rodent
for, um, you know,
domestic...
Within the city...
That ain't legal
either.
What are you,
a fucking park ranger now?
No, I知
just trying--
Who gives a shit
about the fucking marmot?
We are sympathizing
here, Dude.
Fuck sympathy.
I don't need your
fucking sympathy, man.
I need my
fucking Johnson.
What do you need
that for, Dude?
You have got to
buck up, man!
You cannot drag
this negative energy
Into the tournament.
Fuck the tournament.
Fuck you, Walter.
Fuck the tournament?
Ok, Dude. I can see
you don't want to be
cheered up here.
Come on, Donny.
Let's go get us
a lane.
Another Caucasian, Gary.
Right, Dude.
Friends like these,
huh, Gary?
That's right, Dude.
Do you have
A good sarsaparilla?
Bartender:
Sioux city sarsaparilla?
Yeah. That痴 a good one.
How you doin'
there, Dude?
Not too good, man.
One of those days, huh?
Yeah.
Well...
A wiser fella than myself
once said,
"Sometimes you eat
the bar and--"
Much obliged.
"And sometimes
the bar, well...
He eats you."
Hmm. That some kind
of eastern thing?
Far from it.
I like your style,
Dude.
Hmm. Well...
I dig your style, too,
man.
You got
a whole cowboy thing going.
Thankie.
There's just one thing,
Dude.
And what's that?
Do you have to use
so many cuss words?
What the fuck
are you talking about?
Ok, Dude,
Have it your way.
Take her easy, Dude.
Yeah. Thanks, man.
Call for you, Dude.
Hello?
Maude: Jeffrey, you have
not gone to the doctor.
Uh, oh, yeah.
no--no, I haven't yet.
Uh--
I'd like to see you
immediately.
Oh?
So you're Lebowski.
Yeah.
Maude has told me
all about you.
She'll be back
in a minute. Sit down.
Do you want a drink?
Yeah, sure.
White Russian.
The bar's over there.
So what do you do,
Lebowski?
Who the fuck are you,
man?
Just a friend
of Maudie's.
Yeah, the friend
with the cleft asshole?
What do you do?
Oh, nothing much.
Maude: Hello, Jeffrey.
Hello.
Yeah, how are you?
Um...
Listen, Maude,
I got to, uh...
Tender my resignation
or whatever,
Because, uh...it
looks like your mother
really was kidnapped
after all.
She most certainly
was not.
Hey, man, why
don't you fucking...
Listen occasionally?
You might
learn something.
Now, I got--
Please don't call her
my mother.
She's most definitely
the perpetrator
and not the victim.
I'm telling you, I got
pretty definitive evidence--
From who?
From the main guy--
Oolie.
Oolie Coco?
Her co-star in
the beaver picture?
Beaver?
you mean vagina--
I mean,
you know the guy?
I might have introduced them
for all I know.
Do you remember Oolie?
Hmm.
He's a musician. Used
to have a group--Autobahn.
Look in my LP's.
They released one album
in the late seventies.
Their music is sort of
a--ugh--technopop.
So he's pretending to be
the abductor?
Well, yeah.
Look, Jeffrey, you don't
really kidnap someone
you're acquainted with.
The whole idea
is that the hostage can't
be able to identify you
after you've let them go.
I know that.
What the fuck
is with this guy?
Who is he?
Knox Harrington.
The video artist.
So Oolie
has the money?
Well...
Uh, no, not exactly.
Uh...
This is a very
complicated case, Maude.
A lot of ins,
a lot of outs,
a lot of what-have-yous,
and, uh,
a lot of, uh, strands
to keep in my head, man.
A lot of strands
in old Duder's head.
Hello?
If Oolie doesn't have it,
then who does?
Ha ha ha ha! It's Sandra,
about the Bearnali.
Uh, look,
I have to take this.
Do you still have
that doctor's number?
Oh. No, really. It's
not even bruised anymore.
Oh, please, Jeffrey,
I don't want
to be responsible
For any delayed
after-effects.
After-effects?
Maude: See, see.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Could you slide
your shorts down,
Mr. Lebowski, please?
Hmm?
No. No, man.
She hit me right here.
I understand.
Could you slide
your shorts down, please?
# Just got home
from Illinois #
# Lock the front door,
oh, boy #
# Got to sit down,
take a rest on the porch #
# Imagination sets in #
# Pretty soon I知 singin' #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
# There's a giant
doing cartwheels #
# A statue
wearin' high heels #
# Look at all
the happy creatures #
# Dancin' on the lawn #
# A dinosaur Victrola #
# Listenin' to Buck Owens #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
Ow! Ooh! Ooh!
# Tambourines and elephants
are playing in the band #
# Wondrous apparition #
# Provided by magician #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
# Tambourines
and elephants #
# Are playing in the band #
# Won't you take a ride
on the flyin' spoon? #
# Doo doo doo #
# Bother me tomorrow #
# Today I値l buy
no sorrows #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
He lives
in north Hollywood,
on Radford, near
the in-n-out burger.
The in-n-out burger's
on Camrose.
Near
the in-n-out burger.
Those are good burgers,
Walter.
Shut the fuck up,
Donny.
The kid is in
ninth grade, Dude,
And his father is--
Are you ready for this?
His father is
Arthur Digby Sellers.
Who the fuck is that?
Huh?
Who the fuck is
Arthur Digby Sellers?
Ever heard of a little show
called branded, Dude?
Yes, I know--
All but one man died
there at bitter creek?
I know the fucking show,
Walter. So what?
Fucking Arthur Digby Sellers
wrote 156 episodes, Dude.
Huh.
The bulk
of the series.
Oh.
Not exactly
a lightweight.
No.
And yet his son
is a fucking dunce.
Heh.
Anyway, we'll go there
after the what-have-you,
we'll brace the kid,
should be a pushover.
We'll be near
the in-n-out burger.
Shut the fuck up,
Donny!
We'll go out there,
we'll brace the kid,
He should be a pushover.
We'll get that fucking
$1 million back--
If he hasn't spent it
already.
A million fucking clams.
And yes, we'll be near
the, uh...
In-n-out.
Hey, shh! Shh!
Some burgers,
some beers,
a few laughs.
Our fucking troubles
are over, Dude.
Oh, fuck me, man!
That kid's already spent
all the money, man!
New 'vette?
Hardly, Dude.
I'd say he still has
960, $970,000 left,
depending on the options.
Wait in the car, Donny.
Woman: Yes?
Pilar?
My name
is Walter Sobchak.
This is my associate
Jeffrey Lebowski.
Um, we came to talk
about little Larry.
May we come in?
Pilar: Yes, yes.
Thank you.
That's him, Dude.
And a good day to you,
Sir!
Uh, sit down, please.
Larry, sweetie,
that man is here!
Is he...
Does he still write?
Oh, no, no.
He has health problems.
Uh-huh.
Uh, sir, I just
want to say, uh...
That we're both,
on a personal level...
Really enormous fans.
Branded, especially
the early episodes,
was truly a source
of inspiration--
Pilar:
Sweetie, sit down!
Uh, this man
is the police.
Oh, no, ma'am,
we didn't want
to give the impression
that we were police
exactly.
We're hoping
it won't be necessary
to call the police.
But that's up
to little Larry here.
Isn't it, Larry?
Is this your homework,
Larry?
Look, man--
Dude, please.
Is this your homework,
Larry?
Just ask him
about the car, man.
Is this yours, Larry?
Is this your homework,
Larry?
Is that your car
out front?
Is this your homework,
Larry?
We know it's
his fucking homework!
Where's the fucking money,
you little brat?
Look, Larry...
Have you ever heard
of Vietnam?
You're entering
a world of pain, son.
we know that this is
your homework.
We know that you stole
the car.
And the fucking money!
And the fucking money.
And we know that this
is your homework.
We're gonna cut
your dick off, Larry.
You're killing
your father, Larry.
All right.
This is pointless.
Ok?
It's time for plan "b."
You might want to watch out
that front window, Larry.
Son, this is what happens
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass!
Little language problem
here.
The little prick's
stonewalling me.
Walter!
What--what are you doing,
man?
What are you doing?
Here you go, Larry.
You see what happens?
You see what happens,
Larry?
You see what happens?
This is what happens
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass, Larry!
This is what happens,
Larry!
You see what happens,
Larry?
You see what happens
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass?
This is what happens.
You see what happens,
Larry?
Do you see what happens,
Larry,
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass?
This is what happens,
Larry!
Man: No!
This is what happens,
Larry!
This is what happens
when you fuck a stranger--
What the fuck
are you doing, man?!
Stop it!
I just bought
that fucking car last week!
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
I'm gonna
fuckin' kill you!
I just bought
the fucking car last week!
I値l kill your
fucking car, man!
No! No! Hey! Hey!
That's not his--hey!
God damn it!
No! Oh, no!
Man: Fuck you!
You like that?
Fuck you!
I kill your fucking car!
I accept your apology.
No. I just--I just
Want to handle it
by myself from now on.
No, no, no.
That has nothing
to do with it.
Yes, the car made it home.
You're calling me at home.
No, Walter,
it did not look like...
Larry was about to crack.
Well,
that's your perception.
You know, Walter,
you're right.
There is
an unspoken message here.
It's fuck you!
Leave me the fuck alone!
Yeah, I値l be at practice.
Pin your diapers on,
Lebowski.
Jackie Treehorn
wants to see you.
Jackie Treehorn knows
which Lebowski you are.
Jackie Treehorn wants to see
the deadbeat Lebowski.
You're not dealing
with morons here.
Hello, Dude.
Thanks for coming.
I'm Jackie Treehorn.
This is quite a pad
you got here, man.
Completely unspoiled.
What's your drink, Dude?
White Russian.
Thanks.
How's the smut business,
Jackie?
I wouldn't know,
Dude.
I deal in publishing,
entertainment,
political advocacy.
Oh. Which one's
Logjamming?
Yes, regrettably,
it's true.
Standards have fallen
in adult entertainment.
It's video, Dude.
Now that we're competing
with those amateurs,
We can't afford to invest
in little extras, like story,
production value,
feelings.
You know, people forget
that the brain is
the biggest erogenous zone.
On you maybe.
Of course, you have to take
the good with the bad.
New technology permits us
to do very exciting things
In interactive
erotic software.
Wave of the future,
Dude.
100% electronic.
Hmm. Well...
I still jerk off
manually.
Of course you do.
I can see you're anxious
for me to get to the point.
Well, here it is, Dude.
Where's Bunny?
Well, I thought you
might know that, man.
Why would I?
She only ran off
to get away from that
rather sizable debt to me.
No. She didn't run off.
She's been, um--
I've heard that kidnapping
story, so save it.
I know you're mixed up
in all this, Dude,
And I don't care what you're
trying to get from the husband.
That's your business.
All I知 saying is...
I want mine.
Yeah, right, man.
I mean, there are
a lot of, um,
Facets to this, a lot
of interested parties.
Excuse me.
Yeah?
Oh, yeah.
Where's that?
All right.
Excuse me.
Oh.
Forgive me.
No problemo, man.
So, uh...
If I, uh, can find
your money...
Uh, what's in it
for The Dude?
Well, of course,
there's that to discuss.
Uh, refill?
Yeah. The pope
shit in the woods?
10% finder's fee.
That all right?
Mmm. Ok.
Done, Jackie.
Yeah. I dig the way
you do business, man.
Your money
is being held
By a kid named
Larry Sellers.
He lives
in north Hollywood,
On Radford, uh...
By the
in-n-out burger.
A fuckin' brat,
but I知 sure your goons
Can get it off him.
I mean, he's 15.
Flunking social studies.
So, if you could just,
uh...
Write me a check for my
10% of half a million...
5 grand...
I値l go out and mingle--
You mix a hell
of a Caucasian, Jackie.
A 15-year-old kid.
Is this
some sort of a joke?
No, no joke.
No funny stuff, Jackie.
the kid's got it.
Hi, fellas.
The kid just wanted
a car.
All The Dude ever wanted
was his rug back.
I'm not greedy.
It would really...
Tie the room together.
The stranger:
Darkness washed over The Dude.
Darker than
a black steer's took us
On a moonless prairie night.
There was no bottom.
# Yeah, yeah #
# Oh, yeah #
# What condition
my condition was in #
# I woke up this morning
with the sun down #
# Shinin' in him #
# I found my mind
in a brown paper bag #
# But then #
# I tripped on a cloud
and fell 8 miles high #
# I tore my mind
on a jagged sky #
# I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# Yeah, yeah, oh, yeah #
# What condition
my condition was in #
# I pushed my soul
in a deep dark hole #
# And then
I followed it in #
# I watched myself
crawlin' out #
# As I was crawlin' in #
# I got up so tight #
# I couldn't unwind #
# I saw so much #
# I broke my mind #
# I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# Yeah, yeah, oh, yeah #
# What condition
my condition was in #
# Someone
painted echoes on #
# In big black letters #
# On the dead inside #
# I kept my foot
on the gas #
# As I left the road #
# Blew out my mind #
# 8 miles out of Memphis,
and I got no spare #
# 8 miles straightened up
downtown somewhere #
# I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# I said,
I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# Yeah #
# Oh, yeah #
Ah...
But the charge was true
and they say
he ran away
branded!
Is this your only I.D.?
I know my rights,
man.
You don't know shit,
Lebowski.
I want
a fucking lawyer, man.
I want...
Bill Kunstler, man.
Or Ron Coobie.
Mr. Treehorn tells us
that he had to eject you
from his garden party,
that you were drunk
and abusive.
Mr. Treehorn treats objects
like women, man.
Mr. Treehorn draws
a lot of water in this town.
You don't draw shit,
Lebowski.
Now we got a nice quiet
little beach community here,
and I aim to keep it
nice and quiet.
So let me
make something plain.
I don't like you
sucking around,
bothering our citizens,
Lebowski.
I don't like
your jerk-off name,
your jerk-off face,
I don't like
your jerk-off behavior,
And I don't like you...
Jerk-off.
Do I make myself clear?
I'm sorry.
I wasn't listening.
Ow!
Fucking fascist!
Aah!
Stay out of Malibu,
Lebowski!
Ow!
Stay out of Malibu,
deadbeat!
Keep your ugly fucking
gold-bricking ass
out of
my beach community.
# I want to sleep with you
in the desert tonight #
# With a billion stars
all around #
Jesus...
Man, could you
change the channel?
Fuck you, man!
if you don't like my music,
get your own fucking cab!
I had a really rough--
I値l pull over
and kiss your ass out.
Man, come on,
I had a rough night,
And I hate
the fucking eagles, man.
Out of my fucking cab!
Out! Get--
Hey...
Man!
Man, hey!
# Devil-may-care #
# And I知 the devil
with love to spare #
# So viva, Las Vegas #
# Viva, Las Vegas #
Oh...
Jesus.
Jeffrey.
Maude?
Love me.
Uh, that's my robe.
Maude: Tell me about
yourself, Jeffrey.
Well, not much
to tell.
I, um, I was one
of the authors
of the port Huron
Statement.
The original
Port Huron Statement.
Uh-huh.
Not the compromised
second draft.
Uh, and then I, uh,
you ever hear
of the Seattle 7?
Mmm.
That was me.
And, um,
the 6 other guys.
Um, and then
a music business briefly.
Oh?
Yeah, a roadie
for Metallica.
Oh.
Speed of sound tour.
Mm-hmm.
Bunch of assholes.
Uh, and then,
you know,
A little of this,
a little of that.
My career's slowed down
a little lately.
What do you do
for recreation?
Oh, the usual.
Bowl, drive around.
The occasional
acid flashback.
What happened
to your house?
Oh, Jackie Treehorn
trashed the place.
He thought I had
your father's money.
He got me out of the way
while he looked for it.
Cocktail?
No, thanks.
It's not my
father's money.
It's the
Foundation's.
Why did he think
you have it?
And who does?
Oh, Larry Sellers,
this high school kid.
Real fucking brat.
You know, this is a very
complicated case, Maude.
Lotta ins, lotta outs.
You know, fortunately,
I'm adhering to
a pretty strict, uh,
drug regiment to keep
my mind, you know,
Uh, limber, you know.
Very fucking close
to your father's money.
I keep telling you it's
the Foundation's money.
Father doesn't have any.
What are you talking about?
he's fucking loaded.
No, no, the wealth
was all mother's.
No, he runs stuff, uh--
We did let him run one
of the companies briefly,
But he didn't do
very well at it.
No, he's, you know.
No, he helps administer
the charities now,
and I give him
a reasonable allowance.
He has no money
of his own.
I know how he likes
to present himself.
Father's weakness
is vanity.
Hence, the slut.
Uh, do you think he, uh--
What is that, yoga?
It increases the chances
of conception.
Increases?
Well, yes.
What did you think
this was all about?
Fun and games?
I want a child.
Ok, yeah, ok,
but let me--
Ahem, let me explain
something about The Dude.
Uh, look, Jeffrey,
I don't want
a partner.
In fact, I don't
want the father
to be someone
I have to see socially
or who'll have
any interest
in raising
the child himself.
Oh, so that doctor--
Exactly. Now, what
happened to your face?
Did Jackie Treehorn
Do that as well?
No, uh, it was the chief
of police of Malibu.
A real reactionary.
So, your father...
Oh, yeah, I get it.
Yeah, yeah.
What?
Oh, man, my thinking
about this case
had become very uptight.
Yeah, your father.
Jeffrey, what are
you talking about?
Jeffrey!
Walter, if you're there,
pick up the fucking phone,
man, come on, Walter.
Pick it up, man,
this is an emergency.
Come on, enough--Dude?
Yeah, listen, Walter,
I'm at my place.
I need you to come
pick me up.
I can't drive, Dude,
It's Erev Shabbos.
What?
Erev Shabbos.
I can't drive.
Man!
I'm not even supposed
to pick up the phone
unless it's
an emergency.
This is
a fucking emergency.
I understand. That's why
I picked up the phone.
Walter, you fuck,
we gotta go
to Pasadena, man.
Come pick me up or I知 off
the fucking bowling team.
Get out of that
fucking car, man.
fucking car!
Get the fuck out
of the car, man.
Get out of
the fucking--
Who the fuck
are you, man?
Easy, man.
Relax, man.
No physical harm
intended.
Who the fuck
are you?
Why are you
following me around?
Come on, fuckhead.
Relax, man.
I'm a brother Seamus.
Brother Seamus?
Like an Irish monk?
What the fuck are you
talking about?
My name is Da Fino.
I'm a private snoop,
like you, man.
What?
A dick, man.
And let me tell you
something. I dig your work.
Playing one side
against the other.
In bed with everybody.
Fabulous stuff, man.
I'm not--fuck it, man.
Just stay away from
my fucking lady friend.
Hey, hey, I知 not messing
with your special lady.
She's not
my special lady.
She's my fucking
lady friend.
I'm just helping
her conceive, man.
Hey, man, I知 not--
Who are you
working for?
Lebowski?
Jackie Treehorn?
The Knutsens.
The--who the fuck
are the Knutsens?
The Knutsen's. It's
a wandering daughter job.
Bunny Lebowski, man.
Her real name
is Fawn Knutsen.
Her parents want her back.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Crazy, huh? Ran away
about a year ago.
The Knutsens told me
I should show her this
when I found her.
It's the family farm.
It's outside of
Moorhead, Minnesota.
They think it'll
make her homesick.
Oh, boy.
How are you gonna
keep 'em
down on the farm
once they've seen
Karl Hungus?
She's been
kidnapped, Da Fino.
Oh, man.
Oh, I don't know.
maybe not,
But she's definitely
not around.
Hey, maybe you and me
could pool our resources.
Trade information.
Professional courtesy.
Compeers, you know
what I mean?
Yeah, yeah, I get it.
Fuck off, Da Fino.
And stay away
from my special--
From my fucking
lady friend, man.
Ze lingonberry
pancakes.
Lingonberry pancakes.
Sree pigs in blanket.
Dieter: Huh?
She has lingonberry
pancakes.
I mean we totally
fucked it up, man.
We fucked up his payoff,
we got the kidnappers
all pissed off,
And Lebowski, you know,
he yelled at me a lot,
But he didn't
do anything, huh?
Well, sometimes
it's a cathartic--
No, no, I知 saying if
he knows I知 a fuck-up,
why does he
leave me in charge
Of getting his wife back?
Because he doesn't fucking
want her back, man.
He's had enough.
He no longer digs her.
It's all a show.
Ok, but then, why
doesn't he give a shit
About his million bucks?
I mean, he knows we never
handed off his briefcase,
but he never asked
for it back.
The million bucks was
never in the briefcase.
The briefcase was
fucking empty, man.
The asshole was hoping
that they would kill her.
You threw out a ringer
for a ringer.
Ok, but how does
this all add up
To an emergency?
Huh?
I'm saying I see what
you're getting at, Dude,
He kept the money.
My point is, ahem,
here we are,
it's Shabbos,
the Sabbath, which
I'm allowed to break
only if it's a matter
of life or death.
Will you come off it,
Walter?
You're not even
fucking Jewish, man.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
You're fucking
Polish-catholic.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
I converted when
I married Cynthia.
Come on, Dude.
Yeah, yeah.
You know this.
And 5 fucking years ago,
you were divorced.
So what are saying?
When you get divorced,
You turn in
your library card?
You get a new license?
You stop being Jewish?
This is
the driveway, huh?
I'm Jewish as
fucking Tevye.
Man, you know,
it's all a part
of your sick
Cynthia thing.
Man, taking care
of her fucking dog.
Going to her
fucking synagogue.
You're living in
the fucking past.
3,000 years of
beautiful tradition
from Moses
to Sandy Koufax,
you're goddamn right
I'm living in
the fucking past!
I--Jesus.
What the hell
happened?
# Viva Las Vegas #
Ah!
Where was she, man?
Visiting friends of hers
in palm springs.
She just picked up
and left.
Never bothered
to tell us.
Well, I guess the fucking
nihilist knew where she was.
Jesus, Dude, she never
even kidnapped herself.
Who is this gentleman,
Dude?
Who am I? I'm
a fucking veteran.
He shouldn't go
in there, Dude.
He's very angry.
Hello, man.
So, she's back,
no thanks to you.
Where's the fucking
money, Lebowski?
A million bucks
from fucking needy
Little urban
achievers!
You are scum, man!
Who the hell is he?
Who am I? Who am I?
I'm the guy
that's gonna kick
Your phony goldbricking
ass! That's who I am.
Man, we know the briefcase
was fucking empty.
We know you kept the million
bucks for yourself.
You have your story,
I have mine.
I say I entrusted
the money to you,
And you stole it.
As if we would ever
dream of taking
your bullshit
money!
You thought that Bunny
had been kidnapped,
and you were
fucking glad, man.
You could use it as an excuse
to make some money disappear.
All you needed was a sap
to pin it on.
You just met me.
You--human paraquat!
You figured, oh,
here's a loser, you know.
A deadbeat.
somebody the square community
Won't give a shit about.
Well, aren't you?
Well, yeah, but--
Get out, both of you.
Look at that
fucking phony, Dude.
Pretending to be a
fucking millionaire.
Out of this house now,
you bums!
Let me tell you
something else.
I've seen a lot of
spinals, Dude,
And this guy's
a fake.
A fucking
goldbricker.
Stay away from me,
mister!
This guy
fucking walks.
I've never been
more certain
of anything
in my life.
You stay away from me!
Walter, for Christ痴 sake,
man, he's a cripple.
Come on, come on.
Get away from me!
Aah!
Put him down, man!
Yeah, I値l put
him down, Dude!
Rauss! Achtung, baby!
Come on, man, help me
put him back in his chair.
Sure, you'll see
some tank battles.
But fighting in desert
is very different
from fighting
in canopy jungle.
I mean 'nam was
a foot soldier's war.
Whereas, this thing
should, uh, you know,
should be
a piece of cake.
I mean, I had
an M16, Jacko.
Not an Abrams
fucking tank.
Me and Charlie,
eyeball to eyeball.
Yeah.
That's fuckin' combat.
The man in the
black pajamas, Dude.
Worthy fuckin'
adversary.
Who's in
pajamas, Walter?
Shut the fuck up,
Donny.
Whereas, what we
have here...
Lots of fig-eaters wearing
towels on their heads,
trying to find reverse
on a soviet tank.
This--this is not
a worthy--
Hey!
What's this
day of rest shit?
What's this bullshit!
I don't fuckin' care!
It don't matter
to Jesus.
But you not
fooling me, man.
You might fool the fucks
in the league office,
but you don't
fool Jesus.
It's bush league
psyche-out stuff.
Laughable, man. Ha ha!
I would have fucked you
in the ass Saturday.
I値l fuck you in the ass
Next Wednesday instead.
Whoo! You got a date
Wednesday, baby.
He's cracking.
The whole concept of Asia.
I mean, many learned men
have disputed this,
but in the 14th century.
the rabahm, he--
Well, they
finally did it.
They killed
my fucking car.
We want some money,
Lebowski.
Ja, otherwise,
we kill the girl.
Ja, it seems
you have forgotten
Our little deal,
Lebowski.
You don't have the
fucking girl, dipshit.
We know you never did.
Are these the Nazis,
Walter?
No, Donny, these men
are nihilists.
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
Vee don't care. Vee
still want the money,
Lebowski, or
we'll fuck you up.
Fuck you.
Fuck the 3 of yous.
No, without a hostage,
there is no ransom.
That's what ransom is.
Those are the fucking rules.
His girlfriend
gave up her toe.
She zought we'd be
getting $1 million.
It's not fair.
Fair? Who's the fucking
nihilist around here?
You bunch of
fucking crybabies.
Cool it, Walter.
Hey, look, pal,
There never was
any money.
The big Lebowski gave
me an empty briefcase,
So take it up
with him, man.
Yeah, and I would like
my undies back.
Are these guys gonna
hurt us, Walter?
No, Donny, these
men are cowards.
Ok, so we take ze
money you haf on you
And we calls it
even.
Fuck you.
Hey, no, come on,
Walter, come on.
We're ending this
thing cheap, man.
No, what's mine is mine.
Oh, come on, Walter.
Dieter:
No funny stuff.
All right,
all right, I got,
Uh, 4 bucks,
almost 5.
I got $18.
Walter: What's
mine is mine.
We fuck you up, man.
We takes the money.
Come and get it.
Dieter: We fuck you up.
Show me what
you got, nihilist.
I fuck you.
Walter, come on,
he's got a sword.
Fucking dipshit with
a 9-toed woman.
Fuck you!
I fuck you up!
Take it easy, man.
Here's the $4.00.
I got a fucking ball, man.
Aah!
Anti-semite!
I fuck you in ze ass.
I fuck you
in ze ass.
I fuck you!
We got a man down, Dude.
God, they shot him,
man.
No, Dude.
They shot Donny?
There weren't
any shots fired.
Huh?
It's a heart attack.
Call the medics, Dude.
I'd go myself, but I知
pumping blood. Might pass out.
Rest easy, good buddy,
you're doing fine.
We got help
choppering in.
Hello, gentlemen.
You are the bereaved?
Yeah, man.
Francis Donnelly.
Pleased to meet you.
Jeff Lebowski.
Walter Sobchak.
The Dude, actually,
is, uh--
Excuse me?
Oh, nothing.
Yes, I understand you're
taking away the remains.
Yeah.
We have the urn.
I assume this is
credit card.
Yeah.
Walter: Ahem.
What's this?
That's for the urn.
Don't need it. We're
Scattering the ashes.
Yes, so we
Were informed.
However, we must,
Of course,
Transmit the remains
To you in a receptacle.
This is $180.
It is our most modestly
priced receptacle.
Can we just, uh--$180?
They range up to 3,000.
Uh, we're, uh, ahem!
Can't we just
rent it from you?
Sir, this is a mortuary,
not a rental house.
We're scattering
the fucking ashes!
Look, just because
we're bereaved,
Doesn't
make us saps!
Sir, please,
lower your voices.
Man, don't you have,
you know,
Something else we could
put him in, you know?
That is our most modestly
priced receptacle.
God damn it!
Is there a Ralph痴
around here?
Donny was
a good bowler
And a good man.
He was one of us.
He was a man who loved
the outdoors and bowling.
And as a surfer,
he explored the beaches
of Southern California,
from La Jolla
to Leo Carrillo
and up to Pismo.
He died--he died as so
many men of his generation,
Before his time.
In your wisdom, Lord,
you took him.
As you took so many bright,
flowering young men
at Khe Sanh, at Lan Doc,
and Hill 364.
These young men
gave their lives.
So did Donny.
Donny who loved bowling.
And so, Theodore
Donald Karabatsos,
in accordance with
what we think
your dying wishes
might well have been,
We commit your final
mortal remains
To the bosom
of the pacific ocean,
which you loved so well.
Good night, sweet prince.
Shit.
Oh, shit, Dude,
I'm sorry.
God damn wind.
God damn it, Walter.
You fucking asshole!
Dude, I知 sorry.
Everything's a fucking
travesty with you, man.
I'm sorry.
It was an accident.
What was that shit
About Vietnam?
What the fuck
does anything
have to do
with Vietnam?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Dude, I知 sorry.
Fuckin'...
Fuck, Walter.
Come on, Dude.
Hey, fuck it, man.
Let's go bowling.
And when you're
sitting there
in your silk
upholstered chair
talkin' to some rich folks
that you know
well, I hope
you don't see me
in my ragged company
Aw, that you know
I could never be alone
2 oat sodas, Gary.
Good luck tomorrow.
Yeah, thanks, man.
I'm sorry to hear
about Donny.
Oh, well, yeah,
you know,
Sometimes you
eat the bar,
And sometimes,
you know--
Hey, man!
Howdy doo, Dude.
I wondered if I壇
see you again.
I wouldn't
miss the semis?
How have things
been going?
Oh, you know,
strikes and gutters,
ups and downs.
Sure. I gotcha.
Yeah. Thanks, Gary.
Well, take care, man.
Gotta get back.
Sure. Take it
easy, Dude.
Oh, yeah.
I know that you will.
Yeah, well,
The Dude abides.
I don't know about you,
but I take comfort in that.
It's good knowing he's
out there, The Dude.
Takin' her easy
for all us sinners.
Shoosh. I sure hope
he makes the finals.
Well, that about does her.
Wraps her all up.
Things seemed to have
worked out pretty good
for The Dude and Walter.
And it was
a pretty good story,
Don't you think?
Made me laugh
to beat the band.
Parts, anyway.
I didn't like
seeing Donny go.
But then
I happen to know
That there's a little
Lebowski on the way.
I guess that's how the
whole darn human comedy
keeps perpetuating itself
down through
the generations.
westward in the wagons,
and across the sands
of time until we--
Oh, look at me.
I'm ramblin' again.
Well, I hope you folks
enjoyed yourselves.
Catch ya later
on down the trail.
Say, friend,
you got any more
of that good
Sarsaparilla?