It wasn't easy...
...when Nick's father died,
raising a teenager alone.
But, with a boy like Nick,
well, he is... now...
...everything a mother could want.
We've been through some hard times.
We've carried each other.
Now I look to the future,
and I know there's nothing
that we can't do together.
Thank you.
Go on, open it.
Turn it over.
"To Nick, from Mother.
Make me proud."
So, to us.
To us, all.
Cheers.
Around the table.
You look pale.
How would you know?
Are you taking the Valerian Root
I got you?
- Mom...
- Finals are next week.
Mom?
What?
Have you... thought about it?
- About what?
- The writer's course?
- London?
- I don't need to think about it.
You know how I feel.
Why do we keep bringing this up?
What is that?
Irony?
What's up, dude?
You got it?
Thanks, man.
You just saved my ass.
Pleasure doing business with you.
You want to know what it says?
When am I going to speak French?
Hey, caught you.
Are you coming to
Ava's party tomorrow?
I can't. I'm busy.
Busy? School's almost out.
Whatever.
Come on.
- What's he got?
- Nothing.
Not a dime.
Unbelievable.
Nic gum.
And a pack.
You wearing the patch, too?
Kind of a mixed message, Pete.
Like the fact that you
accepted merchandise from me...
...and still haven't
paid for it.
I'll get your money, please!
Got money for this crap,
but not for me?
No, please!
I'll get your money! Please!
Don't be such a baby.
It's just a scratch.
See you soon.
"She sits up and cries
A sigh
Long thighs
Gotta fly
Love you, baby
A lie
Why?"
Jimmy, you wrote that?
Yes, ma'am.
OK, then. Thanks.
Nicholas, let's see
if you can top that.
Please.
It still needs some work.
It always needs work, get used to it.
"Day burns down to night
Burns the edge of my soul
In the night
I break into sparks of suns
And become fire's end
The dust of bones
Night knifes my breath
Swallows whole my tongue
Turn back reverse return
In the night I see the real
Concealed in the day's bright lie
Eyes stitched shut
White teeth smile
Sleep walks
And talks and feet mark time..."
OK, I know it's party week,
but it's finals, too.
Hey.
Hey. Don't look at me like that.
I needed a new phone.
So go buy one at RadioShack.
Are you serious?
You know my dad.
- He gives me no cash.
- You gotta stand up for yourself, man.
Don't let them push you
around like that.
That's easy for you to say,
because when you talk, people listen.
When I talk, you listen.
That's about it.
I can't, man. OK? I can't.
Hey, Nick, come on.
Dude, stop it, stop.
Come on, Nick.
Damn it.
OK...
How much does
my friend owe you?
Is that enough?
Disappear, asshole.
You are so broken.
What are you looking at?
No. Nothing. I'm just...
...more of a Grover guy, that's all.
You're so polite.
The whole "golden boy" thing, right?
Except it's not really you.
I mean, I know you sell essays.
You're no better than me.
You're right.
I'm a total hypocrite.
Anybody want to explain?
She...
...finds me irresistible.
All right. Newton, I'm not gonna
suspend you. I know the game.
Just go home today,
be back here tomorrow.
Try decaf.
What are you doing, Nick?
Wasting your time on
a lost soul like Annie Newton?
She has no future.
You do.
Don't let us down.
Can I leave now?
Hey, Annie.
Where's dinner?
Hey, Victor. Are you hungry?
See?
Get your bony ass out of this chair
right now and make him something to eat.
You can't talk to me like that.
I just did.
- Just gonna leave?
- What do you want? I got night shift.
Say something to her.
It's a little food. You got
nothing else to do all day.
You wanna fight, then?
Is that what you want to do?
- Yeah.
- You wanna get into this now?
Discipline your kids, for God's sake.
You don't tell me what to do.
Take some responsibility
for your kids.
Why won't you talk to her?
My main responsibility...
Annie, you going out tonight?
Annie? Annie!
You're leaving?
Later. I'll be back.
I'll be back.
Hey.
It's from Seb and Tash.
They need those...
translations by tomorrow morning.
Yeah, they're done.
- So, you got beat up by a girl.
- Yeah, I don't want to talk about it.
Yeah, don't want to talk about it, huh?
So, are we gonna go to Ava's
party tomorrow night?
Party.
I'm not gonna be here
tomorrow night.
Ticket and baggage information.
- London?
- Yeah.
The Royal Academy
writer's program.
Really?
No, you're graduating next week,
you can't go.
- I have enough credits to graduate.
- Oh, my God.
London?
- London?
- Yeah.
- Wait, does your mom know?
- No.
But she will, when I'm gone.
She just... she won't get it.
You know, she doesn't get it.
- Yeah.
- There's no other way.
Do you remember
when my dad died?
The first thing that
she said to me was,
"Don't worry about it, Nick.
This won't change a thing for you."
You know, I'm like, 13, right.
All I wanna do is cry.
She's thinking about my future?
She's always had it mapped out.
You know, I stay here,
I might as well retire and die.
I mean, my dad
didn't even get to retire.
He was 46 when he got sick.
I'm not gonna let her do that to me.
Hey, baby girl.
You ready?
Always.
Hey...
Hey! Don't even
think about it, all right?
They're still inside, that's why
they haven't cleared the window.
Hey... hey, what the hell
are you doing?
No, no. Annie, no!
Goddamn it, Annie!
Goddamn it.
Whoo!
Yeah, nice work, Annie.
Jesus Christ.
You just invited the cops
to a fuckin' auto theft!
Fuckin' retard!
You always expect me
to just stand around?
You're getting more
and more out of control.
- What time is it?
- Go back to sleep.
- Leave the bag. I'll take care of it.
- Sure you will.
You gonna shop it around at school?
It's not like cell phones.
What, I can't make
a little money on the side?
What for? College?
I'll figure it out.
Leave the bag.
- What are you gonna do, Marcus?
- Leave the bag, Annie.
Nothing.
Nothing?
Hey, I'm talking to you.
Don't walk away from me
when I'm talking to you!
Nothing?
Nothing.
Police Department.
Can I help you?
Marcus? Marcus!
- Marcus.
- They found the stuff. I got busted.
- What did you tell them?
- Nothing. You think I'm an idiot?
Police Department.
How may I direct your call?
I'm out on OR. I got
a court date in a couple weeks.
- Any idea how they found out?
- Yeah. An idea.
I'll take care of it myself.
- Hey, Nick?
- Yeah?
- I wanna leave, too, man.
- Why?
Why? Why?
'Cause I'd be the foreigner.
I'd be American, I have the accent.
What are you gonna do in London?
I'll be a cricket star.
You know, those dudes with mallets?
- I think that's polo.
- I'd be a polo star.
You didn't have money to afford a cell
phone, how are you gonna get a ticket?
- You have a passport?
- No.
I need someone to write to, man.
OK. All right. Good luck.
I love you, man.
I love you, too.
Take care of yourself, man.
- Don't look back, baby.
- Don't look back.
The airline called.
Your flight's been changed.
- I can explain, Mom.
- Can you?
Can you, really?
- I tried to talk to you.
- Why bother?
You've had this ticket for weeks.
You were planning to go
no matter what I said.
My God, Nicholas.
You were just going to leave
tonight without saying a word?
I feel like I've been living
in this house with a stranger.
I swear I didn't do it, OK?
You were watching me.
It wasn't me.
You were watching me
by the lockers.
- I didn't do it.
- Then who did?
I don't know, I swear,
I don't know!
Please stop!
No, no!
- Get back here.
- No! No! Don't!
How's your hand, Pete?
How's your hand, Pete!
Huh?
OK!
I'll tell you, OK?
I'll tell you!
Thought you were
too busy to come.
You wanna go to London?
Seriously.
Flight leaves in two hours.
Then we'd better hurry up.
What would she think of us right now?
Your mom.
Hmm?
Wow.
That's a nice watch.
So why are you still wearing
that beat up, old thing?
My dad gave it to me.
Wouldn't he want you
to have a better watch?
It was my dad's.
What are you doing?
Have a good time.
Hey, where you off to?
Come on, man.
You gonna fight back?
I can't watch this.
Please, tell them to stop.
- Shut up.
- Please, tell them to stop.
Please, tell them to stop.
Think you're so smart?
Gonna cry? Why don't you cry?
Come on, you little baby.
Look at me!
Get the hell up!
Come on, man. Fight back.
Get off.
No.
- How do you like that?
- Stop it!
Do you feel good about yourself now?
Now that you turned me in, huh?
I didn't know... You were
supposed to be on a plane, Nick!
He can't hear you, idiot.
You're so damn perfect.
Annie, Annie.
That's enough. Look at him.
- Stop. Just stop.
- Get off of me!
- Who's the broken one, now?
- You are.
It's still you.
Come on, come on.
Still you.
- What'd you say?
- Still you.
What'd you...?
Oh, jeez.
- He's not breathing.
- Aw, man!
What the hell, Annie!
What did you do that for?
- What did you do? What did you do?
- Shut up. Shut up!
- What did you do?
- I am not going to jail for this!
- Oh!
- Now we have to pick him up.
- I'm not picking him up.
- Pick him up!
Just keep moving.
We gotta get further into the woods.
- We know, we got it!
- Just come.
Just keep moving.
Come on, get in here.
Open up.
- Open up!
- Oh, Christ.
What the hell
happened to you?
I killed him.
What did you say?
- I killed him.
- Killed who?
Nicholas Powell,
the kid who sold me out.
It got all screwed up.
What am I gonna do?
Why the hell did you
come here, Annie?
Jesus Christ!
You know I'm on parole, Annie!
Why'd you come here?
I need an alibi, Marcus.
What did I say to you, huh?
You're way out of control.
You should've listened to me.
Now get out.
Get out!
Don't touch that.
Stolen.
Stolen...
...stolen, stolen, stolen.
Stolen, stolen...
...stolen!
I knew I could count on you.
Guess you didn't
use the ticket, huh?
I don't even know
where he went.
See, they return.
Ah, see the tentative movements
and the slow feet
Trouble in the pace
and the uncertain wavering
Anyone?
Come on, guys.
We did this poem three days ago.
- Ezra Pound?
- No one?
Hello?
- It's Ezra Pound, The Return.
- No one?
Ezra Pound. You guys
are killing me.
OK. Discussion.
Poems we heard in last class.
- Jimmy.
- Nick Powell's poem.
I mean, I didn't get it.
How does sleep talk?
- It's a metaphor.
- It doesn't even rhyme.
- What's your problem?
- It's pretentious.
Nick's always trying
to make himself important.
I think Powell
has serious issues.
- Whatever, it sucked.
- I liked it.
Is this a game?
You guys playing a game?
Think this is funny?
Hello!
Anybody?
Hello! Hello!
Hello? Hello!
Can anybody hear me?
Hey, guys. Guys.
Let's talk about this when Nick
gets back to class, shall we?
Come on, Mom, answer the phone.
Answer the phone.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I just had to use the phone.
Hello?
Nicholas Powell?
No, he must be in class right now,
Mrs. Powell.
Yeah, just a minute.
I'll have someone go check if he's here.
Hold on, please.
I'm sorry, detective, what was that?
- Mom... can you hear me?
- He left the house last night at 7:00.
He's never stayed out
all night without calling me.
I just...
I have a bad feeling about this.
Mom!
Hello!
You saw me.
You were at the window
and you saw me.
I need your help. Can you help me?
I know you can see me.
You'll never be seen again.
They... can't hear you anymore.
They can't touch you.
You don't exist.
No.
No. No.
Hello, hello!
- Hello?
- Oh, thank God.
Is that better?
Can you hear me?
I said 18 year old, white male,
name's Nicholas Powell.
Possible missing persons case.
What are you looking for, detective?
My son is missing
and you're in here.
What exactly are you doing?
Looking for anything to help find Nick.
I mean, I could fill out a report,
give it 24 hours, but...
That's not what I do...
Not when a kid's involved.
I don't know.
You know if Nick used drugs
or sold them?
No. Of course not.
What can you tell me about him?
He's very well liked.
He's bright. He's very bright.
He's very bright.
I mean, who is he, really?
As a person?
You have my number
if there's anything.
Detective?
I found a plane ticket...
for London.
- Did you call the airline?
- He missed the flight.
He wasn't on it.
I wouldn't worry too much,
Mrs. Powell.
He's only been gone the one night.
No. Something is wrong.
He... he wouldn't.
I know him.
You didn't know
about the plane ticket.
Mom. I'm dead.
We need to get a search party up here.
- Comb these woods.
- Yeah, I spoke with the principal.
Nick had a run in yesterday
with a girl at school.
Sorry. Newton.
Annie Newton.
Something I should know?
Jack.
We're here to talk to Annie.
She's on the roof.
Some history there?
He used to be a cop.
What happened?
It's a long story.
I knew Annie when
she was just a baby.
She liked my ties.
Hey, kiddo. What's up?
What do you want now?
Nice. You know,
you asked me to marry you once.
Another lifetime.
I guess so.
What did you do last night, Annie?
- I don't remember.
- She was busy cracking my skull.
Happen to run into Nicholas Powell?
- Who?
- Why not ask her why she killed me.
- We know you had a problem with him.
- Do I know you?
Someone called to
turn you in yesterday.
You knew that.
Think it was Nicholas?
- What?
- I was with my boyfriend, Marcus.
- Marcus know this?
- Ask him.
They found something by the woods.
Putting together a search party, so...
So... I have
some homework to do.
You'll have to excuse me.
- I'll let you get to it.
- Mm-hmm.
No more questions?
You bought that?
I can't believe this.
You killed me because you thought
I called the police on you?
- Was she a sweet baby?
- Everybody has a story.
You bitch!
Be careful, you'll break it.
- Why can't I fly it on the roof?
- Because it's not safe.
- Don't pretend you're a human being.
- Come on, please.
I'll take you to the park
sometime. The one by the bluffs?
- When?
- Sometime.
- I'm just a little busy right now.
- Hey, Annie.
- What's gonna happen to you?
- Nothing to worry about, little man.
Hey, Pete. There's a search party
in the woods. I want you there.
I don't care.
Oh, my God, this is a nightmare.
Shit!
Go slowly, keep together,
pay attention.
If you find something,
call one of the officers.
Try not to disturb the area.
OK. Let's get to it.
Set your radios
on channel three.
- Tell them to go south.
- Nicholas!
Nick!
Nicholas!
Nick Powell!
Nick!
Can you hear us?
Day burns down to night
Burns the edge of my soul
In the night
I break into sparks of suns
And become fire's end
The dust of bones
In the night I see the real
Concealed in the day's bright lie
Eyes stitched shut
White teeth smile
Sleep walks
And talks
Oh, jeez.
I'm alive.
Shit. I'm alive.
Nick Powell!
Nick!
- Nick!
- Here! I'm right here!
Hey, I'm over here!
Here I am, right here.
Come here, boy.
Good boy.
Come here, come here, buddy.
This way, come here.
Good boy!
- Good boy!
- Hey, wait. You see me, don't you?
Come here.
- Good boy, come here. Good boy.
- Nicholas!
"To Nicholas, From Mother."
Got something here!
Good boy, you can see me, yeah!
No, no! Wrong way!
- That way! I think he's onto something.
- No! Wait, don't go!
Nick!
Nicholas!
Pete.
Why was Annie calling you?
They'll find him.
It just takes some time,
you know? I mean, I...
...I was literally right there
when they found the watch.
You were right there
and they didn't find the body.
Nobody knows but us, so?
What are you so afraid of?
I can't take this.
I'm going to the police.
You go to the police,
you go to jail.
No.
I won't. It was you.
You were right there
and you didn't do a thing.
You're in as deep as we are.
Pete, I'm still alive out there.
Pete...
Pete!
They know you did it
and they'll keep coming back.
Don't think you can run, Annie,
'cause they'll get you.
Hey, Annie.
I have to go away
for a little while.
Are you gonna go away
and never come back, like Mom?
Go on, Annie, tell him.
Here.
- I want you to keep this for me.
- I don't want it.
- It was Mom's
- I know.
You need it more than I do.
- You're pretty great.
- Yeah, I know.
Come here, little man.
Do you know what I want
more than anything?
Don't be like me.
I ruin everything I touch.
OK?
One day, if I'm lucky, maybe
I'll get to do one good thing.
Make you proud of me.
How'd you get in here?
Everybody's out there looking for you.
You listening to me?
- I want you out of here.
- No problem. I'm gone.
Just know...
...if anything happens to Victor...
...I will come back here,
and I will kill you.
Whatever you've done,
I want no part of it.
So, your mom's gone,
your dad married somebody else,
you all hate each other,
does that give you an excuse?
Does that make it OK?
Well, you know what?
Don't think about blaming
anyone but yourself.
Annie, this is your fault!
Goddamn it, Annie!
I'm still alive!
Tell them where my body is!
Oh, that's right!
You can't hear me.
You can't hear me, Annie.
Burnaby Police are not offering
any information at this point.
We do know forensics
are on the scene.
However, night has fallen
and with rain in the city...
What's our time frame
if he's out there alive?
It depends on his injuries.
I'd say two, three days, tops.
All right.
- Nice shop.
- We're closed, man.
- You only work on the old cars?
- No.
What about you work on, say, an '03?
Sure thing, man. Come back tomorrow,
I'll sort you out, all right?
Hey, I know you.
You're Marcus Bohem.
You go out with
Annie Newton, right?
Yeah, that's right.
You seen her lately?
No. Well, I see her sometimes.
Hmm. Open relationship.
- You see her on Tuesday night?
- Yeah, I was with her.
- School night.
- Yeah.
Because Monday night she got busted
for a smash-and-grab at a jewelry store.
You know, and they
took a car the same time.
And so, you weren't
with her that night?
- I don't know anything about that.
- Good. That's good.
No, but she phoned you
from the police station.
Right, but I wasn't with
her that night, you see?
OK.
How long has it been?
Hmm.
I've been on parole eight
months with a clean record.
- You can check with my PO.
- I already did.
OK.
You see Annie, you tell her
I want to talk to her.
About a missing person at her school.
Know anything about it?
No.
2003 Mercedes S500.
Car that got stolen.
Keep an eye out for me.
Yeah, well, let's see where he takes us.
Don't worry about it, Mom.
This won't change
a thing for you.
You got everything
all under control, right?
You always had your...
your fingers in everything.
You know, fingering
through this house.
Me, my room.
Don't! Don't feel a thing, Mom!
You don't want to ruin your
face, your pretty face!
I'm out there in the mud!
I'm dying, Mom,
and you're sitting here
with your briefs and your
herbal tea and your books!
I wish you could
see me right now, Mom!
So you know how sick I am of you!
I am sick of you
and your perfect world!
I am sick of you 'cause
it's not perfect, you hear me?
Oh, Nicky. Oh!
Shut up, Pete.
Did you know you were
being followed by the police?
Who are you?
Did you know that you were
being followed by the police?
- No.
- Well, you are.
- You're coming with me.
- Where are we going?
You wonder why I'm angry.
Stomping through the forest in the
middle of the night, freezing cold,
in the mud, with my good boots on.
Get up, come on.
'Cause you guys are sloppy,
you don't think.
I gotta clean up your mess
or it's gonna be on me.
- You weren't there.
- Doesn't matter.
Any of you go down, you'll
take me with you, I know it.
I can't let you do that.
Where you going?
He's in there.
Jesus.
Get over here, man.
Why me?
Why not Matty?
Or Dean?
Why you?
Because you're weak.
Now get over here.
Lift it up, man. Let's go.
Oh, Jesus, man.
What did you do, man?
... and make your entire body over
exactly the way you want it,
all in as little as six weeks.
Mrs. Egan? Detective Tunney.
Come in.
I'm sorry to bother you at this hour,
but is your son Peter home?
What's this about?
We believe your son is involved
in the disappearance of Nicholas Powell.
- That's ridiculous.
- They were friends.
If we could just
ask him a few questions.
He's downstairs right now.
Come on.
We know that was Nick's money, Pete.
- I watched you break into his house.
- You followed him?
We believe he's involved
in the disappearance.
Ridiculous. They're good friends.
I understand. That's why if Pete knows
anything we thought he'd wanna help.
You're better
than you think you are, Pete.
Don't be such a coward.
Tell 'em what you know.
This is the report.
It's what you expected.
Forensics came back.
The DNAs match for Nick Powell.
Hey, look, my son's not under arrest,
and we've cooperated
more than we had to.
It's getting late. Peter has school
tomorrow. So if there's nothing else.
Let's go.
Where's Annie Newton?
God damn it! Say something, Pete!
Peter? Peter?
Let's go.
Talk to you soon, Pete.
Annie, it's me.
We gotta meet. It's Matty.
He says he's going to the cops.
- Where are you?
- I got him at the bridge.
Keep him there,
I'll be right over.
She's coming.
All right.
You guys did the right thing.
- Man, what're you gonna do?
- What am I gonna do?
What do you think I'm gonna do?
She's out of control, man.
- I need you to do something for me.
- Look, you gotta leave me alone.
Dean and Matty are up to something,
meet them at the bridge.
No. I can't take
this anymore, OK?
You wanna go missing, too?
Hey, hey hey!
Wake up!
Please, pay attention!
Oh, my God.
Go, go, go, go!
Come on, fly! Fly!
Thank you.
What the hell are you
doing here? Where's Annie?
- She says you have to talk to me.
- What? Oh, shit.
Hey, baby girl.
This is not right.
Go home.
We've gotta get out of here.
- There's a tail on him.
- There's just no loyalty these days.
Shut your mouth. You need
to learn to shut your mouth.
Or someone's gonna shut it for you.
And who would that be, Marcus? You?
Marcus, the cops.
- Annie!
- Drop the gun, Annie.
- Drop it now!
- Put the gun down.
Hold your fire.
Put the gun down!
Annie, stop!
Annie! Annie!
Nice.
Come on, Annie, where's
Nicholas? Just give it up.
They'll catch you, Annie!
Never!
She heard me.
She heard me!
You heard me!
- Baby girl, where'd you get this?
- It was Marcus's.
- One fifty.
- It's worth ten times that.
It's worth twenty times that.
But, word is, you're in trouble
and I'm in business, so...
One fifty.
- Two hundred.
- I just need a roof right now.
Go on, disappear.
Yeah, this is where
I wanna be right now.
I'm sorry.
I saw your face that night, Annie.
And I think right then, you
would've traded places with me.
You know, sometimes
I wish my mom was dead.
Instead of my dad.
I always did what she wanted.
You know, and I never even argued.
You know, maybe if I was a little more
like you, we both wouldn't be here.
I'm sorry.
Annie.
I know you can hear me.
Just tell them
where my body is.
We go live on the scene with
the latest developments in this case.
The search is on tonight
for suspect Annie Newton
in the case of missing Mckinley high
school honor student Nicholas Powell.
The 18-year-old is considered
armed and dangerous.
Newton evaded capture
earlier in the day...
I'm not gonna give up on you, Annie.
I'm not giving up on you.
What about Victor?
Is he gonna end up
just like you, Annie?
Stop the bus.
I'm dying, Annie.
I don't have much time left
and you're the only one
that can save my life.
How messed up is that?
Annie!
I'm right here, Annie.
Right here.
Annie.
Clear this stuff out of the way.
Come on, quit fooling around.
Let's go.
Why are we here, Annie?
There's no time.
There you are.
I remember you.
You were always so scrubbed.
You were in Miss Vogel's class?
- She was such a bitch.
That was fourth of July weekend.
Thirteen years old.
That's the last thing
I ever did with my dad.
My mom used to take me there.
Come on. Hurry, Annie. Come on.
Come on.
No. No.
Pete. Pete was here.
Annie. Annie, somebody
was here to move my body.
Who moved my body?
Think, Annie. Think.
It's there, it's right there.
Come on, Annie.
It's right there.
Hang on, Nick.
You're doing a great job,
decorating committee.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
As you all know...
As most of... No...
As most of you probably know,
this week has been a tough one.
- Where's Nick?
- Don't know what you're talking about.
- Don't start, Pete. Just tell her.
- Answer me!
Answer me!
You know what's really screwed
up about this whole thing?
- Nick didn't do it.
- What the hell are you saying?
Nick didn't turn you in.
- You're lying.
- No, I lied.
I thought he left town,
I lied to save my ass.
- You're lying.
- You know what?
- I didn't do it, either.
- What are you talking about?
You killed Nick for nothing.
- Nothing.
- You're lying.
- Jesus, man.
- Then don't believe me.
- Where's the body?
- Where'd you put the body?
I know you couldn't do it alone.
Who helped you?
Marcus.
Marcus?
- Marcus.
- What's going on here?
Little cozy, don't you think?
Miss me, baby boy?
- Get out. I said get out.
- What?
Where you gonna shoot me?
Outside a cop shop, baby girl?
If you want.
Or, you can drive.
OK, I'll drive.
Pete, what are you doing, man?
Keep walking.
I didn't say stop.
- You're not doing this.
- On your knees.
On your knees!
All right.
Pete, no! Pete!
What are you doing, Pete?
You don't need to do this,
I'm still alive!
God, you're my last chance!
Pete, please!
Trust me, this isn't the answer!
If you die, I die, Pete!
Pete, please!
This is not the way out!
It was you.
You called the police on me.
Nick was innocent,
I hurt him for nothing.
Yeah, well, that was your choice,
wasn't it?
Yeah, so is this.
Jesus Christ.
Pete, wake up!
Stay with me, come on!
Nick?
This is really weird.
Pete, where'd you move my body to?
- Pete, please.
- Where'd you move the body?
What does it matter, Annie?
- He's dead.
- No, he isn't!
I saw him,
I looked into his eyes.
- He's not dead!
- How do you know?
- I just know, OK?
- Come on, Pete.
- I screwed things up.
- I know. I know, Pete...
- You're the only friend I had.
- I know, where's my body?
For the last time, where is he?
Where'd you move the body?
In the ruins by the dam.
I'm so sorry, Nick.
- Peter!
- I'm so sorry, please.
- Peter?
- Nick?
You want the body?
You'd better hurry, baby.
- That water's gonna wash him away.
- Have a nice life.
Hey, Annie?
- Larson.
- You don't have to look for me anymore.
- Annie?
- I can tell you where Nick is.
He's still alive. I just need
you to do one thing for me.
I left something for my brother.
It's in my locker at school.
Make sure he gets it, please.
I'll take care of it.
Nick's at the Broward Dam.
- OK.
- What is it?
- The dam gates open in 15 minutes.
- So, what are you saying?
Anything downstream of it
will be flooded out.
- How much time we got?
- We don't.
Help me!
Help!
Somebody help me! Help!
We don't have minutes.
We have to cut the flow. Now!
Save me!
Help!
Help me!
Keep looking.
I want you to look everywhere.
There! There he is!
- Come on.
- Let's go! See if he's alive.
He's alive, I got a pulse.
- No response? Got it.
- Gotta get some fluids in him now.
Get him up there
as quick as we can.
Nick.
- Got it.
- C-collar on.
- You get the rhythm?
- Very slight.
Mrs. Powell? This is
Detective Tunney. We found Nick.
He's alive.
- We need to get bags in him.
- Shut down.
- I've got no IV access on that side.
- Damn it.
I got no pulse.
He's in V-Tach,
charge the paddles.
Clear!
- Charge 300.
- Charging.
Clear.
- Charge to 360.
- Charging.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm just tired.
I'm gonna have to ask
you to step out of the car.
No. I have to be somewhere.
Ma'am! Ma'am!
Teenage male found down
rescued from the base of a dam,
unconscious...
Nicholas?
- Let me be with my son.
- The team will do everything we can.
- He needs me, he needs me.
- We will do everything we can.
Now, please.
Get out of the car,
put your hands on your head.
Annie, I need you.
- I need you, Annie.
- Turn off the engine.
Get out of the car,
hands on your head now!
And what was the status
when we found him?
Annie.
This way.
I just got word a nurse spotted a girl
matching Annie's description.
Stop! Stop.
What?
Nothing.
OK, go.
Hurry.
I'm right here.
I'm in here.
You have some nerve.
No, Mom. No.
I just need to talk to him.
Talk? He can't talk,
thanks to you.
- You should hate me.
- Hate you? Yes.
I do. I hate you.
- Excuse me.
- Don't.
Please, don't.
I can't ask you to forgive me.
Stop it, Mom, stop it!
It's OK, she loves you.
What did you say?
Tell her that I'm here.
- I don't know how to say this, but...
- Just tell her.
He's here.
- Nick.
- Don't.
Don't you talk about my son.
You have to make her listen to you.
You have to make her listen.
I can feel him here.
Everywhere.
I can even hear him.
I know what he wants.
I don't believe you.
Tell her that she was in my room.
You were in his room.
After I disappeared.
- After he was gone.
- What are you doing?
You read one of my poems,
for the first time.
I was there, Mom.
I watched you.
I read it with you.
And you couldn't even finish it.
You were hurting too much,
and I see that now.
I never understood what you were
going through after Dad died.
How Ionely you felt.
But, I'm still here, Mom.
And you have to believe that.
I'm here.
What do you want?
I need to see him,
just for a minute.
- No.
- I can help him.
- Please.
I don't know why,
but, I'm supposed to be here.
I can bring him back.
I'm so sorry, Nick.
I didn't see you before.
I didn't know you.
I wish I could take it all back.
Nick.
Annie.
Please.
Don't go.
Annie. I'm here.
I'm right here.
Nick.
Annie.
I see you.
Nick...
I wanted to do one good thing.
You did, Annie.
You did.
You saved me.
I like your plane.
- What is it?
- Dragonfly 220.
Yeah.
Should you be
out here alone?
- Where are your parents?
- They don't know I'm here.
- My sister was supposed to bring me.
- But she didn't?
She died.
Think we should send her a message?
How?
What should we say?
It's your message.
Hey, Annie...
Hey, Annie.
- That's it.
- That's it?