Let's get down!
Let's hear you scream!
Wait!
What?
This...
No, later.
No, I want to smoke.
I want to smoke!
Fine. Smoke!
Smoke all night.
Be still. Do not turn around.
Do not turn around. You'll not be hurt.
- Bonjour, Nick.
- Bonjour, Madame.
- Voilá. Bonne journée.
- Bonne journée á vous.
Albert. Ca va?
- Ca va.
- Boss, hi!
- Jean-Claude.
- So, the trip was good?
Trés bien.
- How we doing?
- Great. Many reservations for tonight.
- Good. How many covers last night?
- Over 1 50.
- Good.
- The bar was steady.
- How was the music?
- Great band!
Good, good...
Albert...
Scotch on the rocks. A little water.
- Yeah, sure.
- Merci!
Attention, mes enfants!
- C'est grand-pére. J'arrive.
- Monsieur Max, comment vas-tu?
- Oú est Nicky?
- Juste en haut.
Max!
Voilá! Back from Bermuda.
Good trip?
Not as interesting as yours, I'm sure.
My God. Let me get a look at you.
You look like shit! What's your secret?
- Jean-Claude, set up number two.
- Yeah, sure.
J'ai une grande soif
et j'ai besoin d'un peu de glace.
Tout de suite.
- Merci.
- Give us a little room.
Et voilá. A votre santé, Monsieur Max.
Bermuda.
Ah, God!
Well...
- It was pretty tight out there.
- Good. It'll keep you sharp.
I got a minor development.
- We lost the buyer.
- What do you mean?
She's in a brass casket, 6 feet under
ground never to be heard from again.
I fronted 20,000 in expenses.
I'm due that plus two-fifty for my end.
You think I won't take care of you
and cover your expenses?
It's not about expenses, I want
the money. Find another buyer.
Of course! But shit happens!
It'll drag on. You gotta be patient.
Wait a minute!
How about this?
Four big ones in your hand...
- $4 million in your mit.
- $4 million?
More than you ever dreamed of.
More than we ever did together!
- $4 million... What are you into?
- Well, I spotted an exceptional item.
It was European antiquity...
Elegant and in the hands of this dumb
prick that didn't know what he had.
And unfortunately it's become
detained in transit a little...
You don't wanna know where?
- It depends.
- Depends on what?
It depends on
what you're gonna tell me.
It's in the Montreal Customs House.
- No. No way.
- Oh, yeah.
- Forget it.
- Wait a minute.
I got a guy...
...he gives you the whole layout,
handles security, everything.
You used to tell me:
"Steal outside the country, in the States,
in Europe, but live in Montreal."
I said a lot of dumb things
in my day, didn't l?
Let's just find another buyer for this,
OK? I gotta open the place.
OK, but I'm not finished
talking about this.
- Jean-Claude, Albert! Come on!
- You're making a large error here.
Not bad.
- Yeah?
- Ijust landed. I got the delivery.
- You got the bag?
- Yeah, right here.
- Where's Johnny?
- He got it in lstanbul, through the neck!
- Jesus. He was a good kid.
- Yeah. Good and dead.
- You want to talk or see what I got?
- How can I be sure you're OK?
- I suppose I could fuck you.
- That would work!
Hey... You OK?
Yeah...great.
- How was your trip?
- I dunno...
Cities!
They are all starting to look the same.
They really are.
And the pasta in Rome
is not as good as yours.
And the ass-pinchers! They used
to look so charmingly European!
Not as good as me?
Common!
It must be what it is about you I like,
because you are definitely not common.
- What if I were...?
- Were what?
...a little more common, you know,
and around more?
- How much more?
- Like all-the-time more?
If I was just a jazz club owner and not
that other thing. How'd you feel?
Are you saying
what I think you're saying?
I think that's what I'm saying.
Hey, baby, you know I'd never ask you
to change anything for me. Right?
I know that. I'm just asking
how would you feel about that?
I dunno...
I suppose I'd have to give it
some serious thought.
Then you'd better start giving it
Thank you.
I'll see you when I see you?
See you when I see you.
- Madame...
- Alors!
- Voilá. Bonne journée.
- Merci.
Excuse me. Can you help me, please?
C-Can you help me?
- Place Norman?
- Yes. Yes.
Go to the corner, make a right,
go two blocks...
- Two blocks, then a left...
- Again, please.
Two blocks on the corner,
two blocks this way, one block left.
- And you're there.
- OK, thank you.
Thank you, Nick.
What? What did you say?
I said, "Thank you, Nick."
I'm Max's guy in the Customs House.
We should talk.
OK, bye-bye. Thank you.
Thank you. Bye!
- Where's Max?
- He's in the sun room.
- Max...
- Nicolai, Nicolai.
Have you lost your fucking mind?!
My mind? Yes, years ago. Why?
- What did you tell this kid?
- Who?
Your inside guy with the retard act.
He was in front of my house,
he knew who I was.
He must have followed me
to the club and seen you.
Tell him next time
he'll wind up in the hospital.
Wait a minute. You think
I'd set you up with a jerk-off heister?
You gotta admit
the kid did a good show.
I don't give a shit.
Don't expose me like that.
You've got it pre-wired,
turn the key...
I'm not interested.
You'll never get another chance.
What's the matter with you?
- Why are you pushing this?
- Four million balls, that's why!
He's pushing it
'cause we're running out of time.
I'm saying if I'm gonna work
with a partner we gotta start now.
- What are you doing in my house?
- All I'm saying...
- What the fuck does this kid know?
- I've been on this for 3 weeks.
I gotta know if you're the guy
Max says you are.
- I gotta go.
- Nick! Nick! Wait!
- Nicky!
- Hey! I didn't come 500 miles to...
- Jack Teller, nice to meet you.
- You don't know where your dick is!
We decided
you'd sit tight until I called. Right?
I thought I could help.
You said he was in.
Don't be so creative.
Get the fuck outta my house!
When you get
your shit together, call me!
Unbelievable!
Jesus! Take it easy!
Listen close... Leave town tonight,
don't come back.
I see you again, I break your knees.
I see you around Nick, I'll kill you.
It's a dangerous game you're playing.
Are we clear?
Yeah, we're clear.
How did it go?
Not as planned.
- What do you want?
- Some respect from you for starters!
I mean, what are you thinking?
I'm on a job here.
If you just don't want
to come in on it, say no.
Don't send some fucking third-rate
Rent-a-Thug. Do it like a professional!
Hello...?
Yeah... OK.
He's right here. Don't worry.
Go home. I'll call you later.
All right? That's OK.
OK.
I didn't come here
to cause any trouble. All right? I didn't.
Coming up to you on the street,
that was a stupid move.
Sorry. Why don't we just call it even?
I just want to say one thing to you
and then I'll go away if you want.
I have been casing this place
for a couple of weeks, now.
It's a little bit complicated,
but it's a very doable job.
I can handle the system in there
if someone else can break into this box.
I don't know you. You don't know me.
It's not the best way to do things, but...
I am very good at what I do.
And I take it very, very seriously.
Check it out with Max.
If you are the guy
that he says you are, then...
...we should check this out, take
a look at it. That's all I'm saying.
This is a very big pay-off
for very acceptable risks.
Go take a look at it for yourself.
I like your place.
You got good taste.
Jesus! It's nice and dark in here!
Fucking everything!
- Hey! Nick!
- Max!
Jesus!
Why don't you jump for some lights?
Every time I come in here,
I have to play hide-and-seek!
How are you?
Now, you gotta tell me the...
...the magic word.
All right. I'm going to do it.
Good, good. Jesus! Sweetheart!
You're a sweetheart!
Bravo! You're making sense.
But because of the risk involved
my end's gotta be $6 million.
Operator? I gotta nut down here
that just said $6 million.
No. Send paramedics.
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
Six fucking million?!
What happened to four?
No. It's my backyard.
I'm not going to go like that.
If you want me to do this,
pay me right.
I always pay you right.
You think you pay me right,
but I know.
It's not always right. I need this for this.
I like your style.
Yeah, well, OK, I understand.
That's what I have to do.
I want to pay off the mortgage.
I want to own this place,
free and clear.
I live the way I want.
Because after this, no more jobs.
I'm quitting.
How many times you told me that?
I'll believe that
when the pigs eat my brother.
- Right?
- I'm done. No more.
Well, OK. I hope she's worth it.
It's Numb Nuts.
Nice house. Nice club.
You must be really good.
I don't want to have to do this
but raise your arms.
Be my guest.
He's all right.
OK?
Is this a social call?
What are we doing?
I will explore this with you. But I run
this operation down to the last detail.
If you have a problem with that,
we can go home right now.
- Is there a problem with that?
- That's fine.
Tell me everything you know,
then I'll design the plan.
If I smell something about the job
or you I don't like, I walk away.
If you're not living up to your end of it,
or if you hold out on me
in any way, I walk. Understood?
That's fine.
Tell me what you want to know.
- First of all, what are we looking for?
- Know what a sceptre is?
It's...something that a king holds.
Right there.
It was made in 1 661 in France
for a special coronation...
for a girl queen.
- It's priceless.
- Not to us, it's not.
- What about the specific location?
- I can give you the whole building.
I got floor plans. I've been clocking
security patterns for over three weeks.
All right. Paint me a picture.
OK. He fixed me up with the job.
- Not me...Brian, the guy on the street.
- I remember.
Is he traceable?
Phone number, address?
No, it's totally tight. It's a charity case,
a favour. He doesn't exist on paper.
He just shows up as assistant janitor,
midnight to 8 a.m.
The security's basic.
At night theyjust lock it down.
They bar the groundfloor windows.
You can only enter by the truck court.
Thank you, Albert. Thank you.
Manpower's very light. One guy sitting
outside, keeping an eye on things.
Inside, everyone's got to come in
through a standard metal-detector.
It's a little tricky bringing things in,
but I think I've figured it out.
The guards know me,
nobody looks too close.
- OK, thank you.
- All right.
Once I'm inside,
I can go anywhere I want.
Everything gets run
from this one central console.
They got fixed video systems
in the elevators and hallways,
a couple ofmagnetic doors,
all very basic.
Lots of overtime! Not so much now.
The headjanitor's this old guy, Danny.
He loves Brian. Loves him!
I got this guy wrapped
around my finger.
He'd do anything for me.
Most of the time he's got me working
with him. Low level shit, helping out.
But I can get away from him,
I've lots ofreasons.
I've sketched half the place already.
Copied keys.
I can get you access to any room.
Where's the sceptre?
Well, you see...that's the kink.
Now get this!
It was arranged
to be brought into the country
inside the leg of an antique piano!
And it was so simple...
and then they impounded it!
Can you guess why?
Fucking bugs!
The whole shipment
was contaminated with termites.
Asian longhorned beetles!
We got fucked by bugs!
They burrow into the wood,
into the shipment crates.
So they delivered most of the goods,
but the piano's wooden,
so they impounded it.
They put the whole thing in quarantine
in a medium-security lock-up.
They're scary things, and they can't
send them back to France.
So they decide to burn everything.
Now...l'll tell you,
I don't know which fucking leg it's in.
But I was tempted
tojust grab 'em all and run!
I dunno if the thing's
going to melt or what.
I mean, I was dying!
So I had to improvise a little bit.
Laurent! I saw something in the fire.
- It's burning...
- No, look, look!
I saw...something...in the piano.
In the piano, look!
I saw something!
Everybody's freaking out.
Nobody knows what to do.
They don't see this kind of excitement.
So they get this supervisor outta bed.
He takes one look, he doesn't know
what it is, but he knows it's worth a lot.
He tells them, till it's sorted out,
to put it in a box in the basement,
and that's what they do.
- It's not a toy.
- I want to see. Can I see?
- No. Come on, let's go.
- OK. Bye-bye.
The basement is the most secure
lock-up in Eastern Canada.
It was a bomb shelter
during the Cold War.
They put all their important stuff in here,
State's evidence, narcotics, weapons.
That sceptre is somewhere in the safe.
The thing is, there's no cameras.
I'd have seen them on the monitors.
So if we put you inside,
you can work on it all night.
We'll need pictures of the safe
or a model number.
Then we'll need plans, infrastructure,
maps, blueprints, anything.
That's all for now.
Give me two days.
We just got to find a way
into that basement.
- You gonna let it go or stay pissed?
- Kiss my ass.
- We're about set up here. You ready?
- Hold on.
- Want to give me a mark?
- Not yet. Not yet.
- How are you doing?
- Stay off the air till I call.
Three-three, two-six.
Two-nine, three-two.
I repeat: 33, 26, 29, 32.
Copy that. Three-three, two-six,
two-nine, three-two.
Make a right.
Proceed east about 20 yards.
You should see the next opening.
I'm at a wall here, a cinder-block wall,
where you told me I have to go.
You're sure?
It's a straight shot on here.
It's not my imagination!
Wanna come see for yourself?
Right. OK, hold on.
Give me a second.
- Can you read me?
- Make a left, 20 feet.
You'll run into a parallel tunnel,
make a right, back on course.
Take the tunnel 150 yards west.
- You'll reach a T-junction.
- About 300 yards.
- Came to the end, made a right.
- Head northeast. Northeast.
One second, hold on.
- You with me?
- Going west. Going west. All right.
Right. Go 40 yards east,
then make a left turn.
Left turn...then make a right.
It'll be 500 yards to go.
OK, straight ahead, 20 feet,
you'll be under the room.
The tunnel will continue,
but look up and
you'll see the access ladder.
I'm at a shaft. I'm going to climb up.
What are you doing?
Still climbing.
This looks like it.
I'm done.
Who the hell is this?
There's a utility crew at the entrance.
You'll have to find another way out.
Where are you?
At De La Montagne and Ottawa.
- Repeat: De La Montagne, Ottawa.
- Got it. We're on our way.
This should be it, right there.
OK, we're just trying to find you.
There. He's right over there.
OK, you're all clear.
Coming out.
Officer! Pardonnez-moi.
- Je suis...perdu.
- Oui.
J'ai besoin de...
Comment s'appelle...?
- Rue Bonsecours.
- Rue Bonsecours?
Deux routes par lá,
puis tournez á gauche.
Merci. Bonsoir.
Hello!
Anybody home?
Hey! Champagne! Nice touch.
- Nice dress.
- You like?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
So...you asked me a question
a couple of days ago.
And you gave it
some serious thought?
Actually I forgot the question!
Here's my answer.
- You're not holding up your glass.
- Sorry.
My father was a lawyer,
a very smart man, and he always said,
"A deal is good if it leaves both parties
feeling as if they gave up something."
Is an answer coming soon,
'cause the glass is getting heavy?
OK...
I will change my life.
I will move here.
I will love you.
And believe that
this is the best decision I've made.
But I will not move here if it means...
...l have to talk to you through glass.
I won't spend my nights worrying.
So...
If you can promise me as of now
that you're through,
then we can drink to making changes.
- I said you could drink now.
- I know.
I wanna do all that.
I just have to tell you
that I'm doing one more thing...
...and that's it.
Everything you said is great, perfect.
I just have one more thing I have to do.
I don't believe you asked me when
you knew you couldn't follow through!
- I'm following through. It's my last...
- Sure!
- I promise you, it is my last one.
- Then quit. Quit now.
- What's 'one last one' mean?
- We don't need anything.
I didn't need anything before,
and I don't need anything now.
What I wanted was to be with you.
What I didn't need
was this painful bullshit!
My life wasn't perfect before,
but at least we were clear.
- You gotta give me some...
- Shh! No.
See you when I see you.
Hey! What are you doing?
Somebody put fingerprints
on my window.
- You don't need to do it.
- I like a clean window.
It's all right.
We missed you last night.
- Feeling better?
- Yes, thank you.
- Sure?
- I'm OK.
- Take your time.
- OK, bye-bye!
Bye-bye!
That's your safe.
Traeger standing jeweller's safe.
This year's model.
If it's new, it'll be tough
getting the schematics.
I've got all this year's books, yeah.
What else?
OK. The system's lronclad Security,
a big commercial industrial outfit,
handling a lot
of the government buildings.
This building's old,
the lines are easy to find.
I can cut in three or four different places
and let you in.
But I gotta have the pass codes.
They don't keep them in here.
They'll be at lronclad.
- I dunno know what to do.
- OK...
You're calling someone now?
- Who is this?
- Me. Turn down the music.
Hey, Nick. I am fucked up.
My mother's totally out of control.
Listen carefully.
- Ironclad Security.
- Big outfit.
I need pass codes
for the Customs House.
Man, my concentration's shot,
I haven't slept in a month. Wait...
- What Customs House?
- Montreal.
You're not pissing in our own pool?
You said you'd never do a job
in Montreal!
- I know. Can you do it?
- Steven!
Who are you talking to?
I'm having a civil fucking conversation
with a friend, Mother!
- Are you OK?
- She is a ghoul!
- Now, tell me exactly what you want.
- One second.
I'll put someone on
to tell you what we need.
Just tell him what you need.
I need disarm and reset master codes
for the system.
I need individual sector bypass codes
to shut down one zone without lighting
off the whole board. OK?
Yes.
- You got that?
- Got it.
I'm gonna need this in 48 hours.
I'll double your last price.
Dude, give me a Kaypro 64 and
a live dial tone and I can do anything!
Now you are going to die!
This is someone you work with?
And you're giving me a hard time!
Thursday, 8.07 a.m.
Hi, got your message.
I got to cover for a sick stewardess
on a New York run.
We have to talk when I come through
in a couple of days. Bye.
End ofmessages.
Just lock it.
You work here?
No. Here.
Come on.
Come on, come on!
Want some coffee?
Yeah, yeah...
Is this what we're dealing with?
Page 720.
Where can I get one of these?
You gotta know the right people.
Traeger floor safe... Here it is.
"Solid steel body."
"Filled door with aluminium
and cobalt."
"Half inch hard plate."
"Double dial."
You'll need 2-3 hours
to drill through that.
- You can't drill this.
- Why not?
'Cause this is a newer model
with these glass packs.
See the glass pack, here?
See that? Drill through that, the glass
breaks and the bolts spring into place.
They're locked.
Not even with a bulldozer!
What do you have in mind?
I don't know, but if somebody built it,
somebody can unbuild it.
When I shut it down, this light'll go off,
but it won't register in the booth.
- Is that your box?
- That's it.
That's a fucking monster.
It's three times the size of this.
See that over there?
See it better over here.
That's an active infrared post.
That wasn't on the system specs.
That's some independent loop
set up in the cage.
I'll take care of it.
Yeah?
All right...just calm down. OK?
I'll be over in a few minutes.
I gotta do something. I'll drop you off.
My mom's only out for half an hour.
- What's the emergency?
- I was cruising lronclad's server...
...at the COBOL level, when someone
hacked back into my machines!
For 3 minutes I was fully exposed!
Now, I have to firewall
my whole operation from scratch.
- Can you just tell me that in English?
- Sorry...
I was just about to pull up those codes
when I hit a guy on the other end.
- What's on the other end?
- Ironclad's computers.
I guess he's some
low-level administrator, so...
...we switch to a private chat room,
and he sends me this...
Can you believe that? He comes
into my world and calls me an asshole!
And the bypass codes?
I type "How much?"
He says, "For the codes?"
I say, "You guessed it."
He says, "Fuck you!"
I say, "No, fuck you!" and he says,
"Fuck you!" I say, "Fuck you!" and...
Steven... Can you get me
the bypass codes?
The guy wants fifty thou'
in exchange for the codes.
- 50,000...?
- Yes.
Get the account.
I'll wire the money, he'll deliver to you.
Negative. No transfers.
He wants cash,
and he wants to do it in person.
- Anything else?
- No.
You set it up.
Stay, I'll let myself out.
When this whole score's done,
I'll brute this creep with all I got!
This fuck won't be able
to hide in Bolivia!
Jesus! Look at all these people!
Who sets up a meeting
in a public park?
- You see him?
- Still looking.
Got him. They brought back-up.
OK, I got him.
How you doing? Good to see you.
Shake my hand. That's right.
- You my guy?
- Yeah.
Who's this?
- Cousin.
- Cousin?
OK. See the guy back there
reading the paper, the big one?
That's my cousin. OK?
So we've all got family here,
which is nice, yeah?
I'll give you that. Take a look inside,
make sure you're happy.
Don't take that out!
Don't give me orders,
I get orders all day.
You can't count money in public.
That's why you don't set a meeting
in a park...for future reference.
Just flip through it in the bag.
- Set to go. You ready?
- What the fuck are you doing?
Give me the numbers,
and I'll read them into a mike
to get them checked out.
Think I was going
to write it down on a napkin?
- Ready.
- OK, you're on.
First set...
3-1 -7.
- 3-1 -7.
- Got it. 3- 1-7.
Steven...
...3-1 -7.
Confirm 3- 1-7.
It'll just be a second.
You guys maternal cousins or what?
- First numbers are clean.
- They're clean.
Tell the hack at the other end
if he tries to get in again, I'll fry him.
Worry about next time next time.
Let's finish before people start looking.
Give me the second set.
- 9-4-6.
9-4-6. I repeat: 9-4-6.
9-4-6.
- Take it easy. Have a smoke.
- I don't smoke.
I don't smoke, either, so good for us.
- You guys local? You live around here?
- Why so many fucking questions?
- They're good.
- Second set is good.
What's the third one?
5-8-3-9.
5-8-3-9, got it.
5-8...
...3-9.
- This is taking too long. I'm losing it!
- Shut up, Eric!
They have to verify the numbers.
It takes time.
Relax, Eric.
- Help! It's amateur hour here!
- Fuck you!
- What are you doing?
- One of them has a gun.
- How's it going?
- I'm working it, man!
- Steven, want some lunch?
- I'm on the phone, bitch!
- All right?
- Fine. Nobody move.
Eric, look in my hand right now.
If you take that, I'll take this out...
Be a big fucking mess.
Put it away, Eric.
What were you thinking?
Put it away. Take a deep breath.
Just put it in your back pocket.
Put it away.
- They're all good.
- Last set confirmed.
Last set confirmed.
Let's get out of here.
- Next time don't bring a gun.
- Listen...
I thought I might need one,
and I did...
Don't bring a gun.
Jesus...Christ!
I called, they said
you hadn't checked in yet. No...
So what time are you getting in?
Come on, don't stay at a hotel.
Just come over to my place.
I'll cook...
Yeah...
I was just saying come to my place,
I'll cook something, we'll talk, OK?
- This is good.
- Yeah.
When you gotta be there?
I'll go in a couple of hours.
I'm OK, fine.
Listen, tell me something...
All the years you've been doing this,
what's the biggest gamble you ever
took on a job, the biggest long shot?
I don't take long shots.
I know you're careful. I'm careful, too.
That's not what I mean.
When you were starting out,
you must've done something
a little wild, I'm just curious...
I never took long shots.
I'm gonna say something to you.
You're smart, you're talented,
but it's nothing
if you don't make the right choices.
Many talented people
never see the light of day.
Lastly, it takes discipline,
'cause this whole game is a long shot.
If you don't have the discipline to avoid
the gambles, the stupid moves,
then, my friend, one day
you will go down, it's inevitable.
You want my advice?
List everything you want now,
then spend the next 25 years
getting it...slowly...piece by piece.
I see what you're saying.
But still...you got all this already.
And you're still working with a partner,
in your own city on a job that's
more complicated than you thought.
So you're still taking
a shot at something.
I gotta go.
See you tomorrow.
Maintenance comes in by 6 a.m.
I gotta be in the hole by 5.30.
As soon as the guards leave,
you gotta tell me.
I'm more worried about how
you're going to break that safe...
...in half an hour, you know?
- Is that even possible?
- It's just physics.
- How long will it take?
- 1 2-1 5 minutes, tops.
1 5 minutes tops?
OK... OK...
If you're on the box by five, the prize
is in the bag by 5.1 5. No problem.
5.1 5-5.30 I'm in the hole,
you reset the system...
Perfect. I'll pack up my shit...
- We can go to Max's...
- We're not gonna meet back here.
- I'll meet you at Max's, then?
- No...
You finish your shift.
Max does his thing.
He pays us off,
we never meet again.
Forget it. I'll come with you
to deliver to Max.
- I'm telling you.
- No.
I've done this down to the last detail,
don't sideline me
when it's time to collect.
Listen to me, listen to me.
Do anything out of the ordinary,
you'll get made. Understand?
Be smart. Finish out your shift.
- You're the boss.
- OK.
Steven got these from a supplier.
Totally untraceable.
People are saying Max is in trouble
with Teddy Salida,
and he's pulling off a big job
to get rid of him.
That's what they say?
Maybe you should
walk away from this one.
Max?
Max!
What are you doing?
Jesus Christ!
You scared the shit out of me.
What the hell
are you doing down here?
Did you involve Teddy Salida in this?
- Teddy Salida?
- Yeah.
Why would you say that?
I see these guys outside.
They look like they might be with him.
How much you into him for?
$4 million.
You think they gave all this to me?
And a house in Bermuda?
What's the matter with you?
What's he know?
- About what?
- About what we're doing.
Nothing, I told him I'd found
something that would go for eight,
and we'd split the profits, that's all.
What are you actually
selling the sceptre for, Max?
$30 million.
Jesus! Max, what were you thinking?
Same thing you were thinking:
"How do we get out of all this bullshit?"
The chance came, I took it.
- It's gonna work out fine.
- No, it's not.
- What do you mean?
- It's a mess.
Wait a minute.
Wait a fucking minute!
This is absolutely clean, Nick.
What are you worried about?
It's my ass on the line, not yours.
I'm not gambling with my life
to hand my money to Teddy Salida.
You think you won't get
your fucking money?
Two things: one is you're gonna get
every fucking red cent.
- And yeah, Teddy knows a little.
- He knows?
- He knows a little!
- So you lied!
Lies! Shit happens, man!
Christ Almighty!
I lied for you and I lied for me.
To get you to suit up as always!
Max...
- I'm sorry, but I'm not going to do it.
- Nick...
It's a tiny door. Open it. Take the shit.
Close the door. We're out.
There's too much bullshit around!
What's that?
The buyer.
Simple.
Call him when you get the sceptre.
He'll meet you 30 miles up
the St Lawrence, a little town called...
...St Croix.
Give him the sceptre, take the cash.
Take your cut, wire me the rest.
I'll give Teddy his and...you're clean.
It's too risky. I can't.
You don't know what you're doing.
You know how long we go back?
25 years.
I'm gonna tell you something.
For the first time in my life,
I'm scared.
I don't know why it is. I was never
scared before, but I am now.
And you're right about Teddy.
He'll blow me away if he can.
If I don't get him his money, he...
Hey! Don't...
Don't let me slide on this one.
I can't afford it, man.
I can't... I can't scrap it out any more.
I gotta have some slack.
All right. OK.
- I hope you're not fucking me up.
- Nick... Hey, Nick!
Nicky...
I'm going down to check the power.
- How much more equipment you got?
- Here you go.
- Sorry, sorry!
- OK, Brian, come on in.
What's all the commotion?
- Just beefing things up downstairs.
- A few cameras.
- Like we'll lose it!
- Lose what?
That thing we found in the piano leg,
it turns out it's a French treasure.
- It's called a sceptre.
- Some expert got a look...
...now we're getting calls
from central office.
Hey, it's me.
We got a problem...
They got a camera
over the main door covering that.
They got a camera here
across the middle.
And they got one special
just on the box.
It sees this entire cage.
This camera is how high from the floor
and how low from the ceiling?
Probably 1 0-1 2 feet off the floor,
4 feet from the ceiling.
I think we're fucked.
So...
When I'm here...
...cut the feed when I'm here,
then restore it.
When I'm ready here,
cut it again and I'll work here.
I don't know about that.
They'll move it soon.
We'll not get another chance.
We gotta go now
or we don't go at all.
Hi, Doug!
- Hi, Henri.
- Hi, Brian.
- OK. Thank you.
- No problem.
- Hi, Danny.
- Hello, Brian.
Look at you. What fancy new shoes.
- Yeah. My mom got those for me.
- Your mom got you those!
- I think you got a girl.
- No girl, you're a stinker!
You and your new shoes can give me
a hand waxing the cafeteria floor.
- OK.
- You hit the garbage.
- I'll meet you there in 1 5 minutes.
- 1 5? OK.
OK. I'll get the garbage, Danny. OK.
Bye-bye, André.
- You look good with those shoes.
- Yeah, thanks, I know.
- Watch your step, Brian.
- I will, thank you.
OK? OK, Danny.
- Guess what time it is.
- I don't know.
Yes, you do, it's lunchtime.
I tell you what, let's carry on
and finish the other side.
What? No! Why?
Then we can go
and grab some pancakes.
It won't take long. Throw a little extra
thinner in the mix, it'll go like butter.
- Danny, I am sorry.
- It's OK, I'll mop it up.
- I will get some more.
- You don't need it...
All right. You know where?
The groundfloor.
Below the closet.
Set to go. Set to go.
Are you there? I'm on my mark.
- Are you there?
- We're running late.
There was a snag.
I'm already set up. Give me a second.
I just got to punch in these codes.
Just sit tight.
I got it.
Hang on, one more beat.
It's clear.
I'm inside the first cage.
Repeat: inside the first cage.
You're all clear.
I'm set. Kill it.
On my mark...
Hey!
Go!
I'm here.
There we go.
Perfect. Tell me
when you're in second position.
- How are you doing down there?
- Almost there.
Do you know where Brian is?
No idea.
- I'm ready.
- I need a second here, hold on.
I'm all set. Cut the cameras.
Got to go.
What's up? What's up?
I got company. I got company.
Hang on one second.
Sit tight. I'll be back.
Jack, where are you?
Jack?
Jack, come in. Jack!
Jack, are you there?
- I'm pulling out.
- I'm back.
- It's too late. I'm pulling out.
- No, it's not.
Get ready to go.
On my mark...
Go, go, go!
What's wrong with these?
Hey, stop banging on it.
Check the connection.
You see something?
I don't know.
Call them. Call lronclad.
- And look like idiots?
- I don't care. Call them!
Maybe it's the equipment
down in the basement.
OK. Thanks.
Someone'll be here in a few minutes.
Brian?
Where are you, kid?
Make a move, make a sound
and you're dead. Understand me?
Turn around.
- Brian...?
- Shh! Be quiet.
Danny...
Danny... I wish
you'd not come down here.
Get over there. Turn around.
Come on, let's go.
Turn around. Walk over there.
Open the door.
Open it.
Get inside.
Look at me.
I don't want to hurt you.
But if you try to open that fucking door,
I will do it. Understand?
Stay in there and be quiet.
Everything'll be fine.
I don't want to wait.
You and Tommy go
into the basement now.
Come on, André, I'm watching this.
Laurent, please.
Tommy, get Philippe, we're gonna
be checking out the basement again.
Hold it right there!
- Are you crazy?
- Put it down.
- Come on.
- Take it off and put it down!
- Don't do this.
- Put it on the fucking floor!
Don't fucking argue with me.
Take it off and put it down!
I can't. I can't.
The next one's in your knee.
Don't fuck around.
We can work out the details later.
I am leaving with that sceptre.
Now take it off
and hand it over right now!
Put it down.
Slowly.
Now step back. Back up.
- Take off your mask.
- What?
Take it off!
I don't have time to play games.
Throw it over there.
Step in the middle.
Step in the middle!
That's right.
We wouldn't be here if you'd
shown me some respect. Just a little.
Stupid move.
We all come out ahead.
What are you doing...?
"A long shot."
Know what I think of your advice?
That's you trying to make me take
a sucker's share on a score I set up!
You think I'm stupid, that I don't see
what you and Max are doing?
What is he giving you?
$5-$6 million?
Tell me that's not true.
See, that doesn't work for me.
I appreciate your help, but...
...you should've made me a partner.
Now I got to take a shot.
Just sit tight. Everything will be fine.
You got a choice:
head for that tunnel...
...or smile for that camera.
- André, what's happening?
- The basement!
We're being robbed!
Go outside, wait for the police!
- Let's go!
- Go! Go!
Ici! lci!
He's in the tunnel!
What do you see?
Find him!
Come on! Come on!
- André? André?
- Shit!
- Is there a fire?
- It's OK.
- Where's Danny?
- Just get out!
Just wait outside!
- My radio...?
- Just wait outside!
OK. Bye-bye!
Wait, Brian.
- Have you seen Brian?
- He's OK. He's outside.
It's him!
The bus to Albany, New York
leaves in five...
- Yeah?
- You make it?
Fuck you!
I'm just checking if you got out OK.
I knew you'd give them the slip.
I'm almost home, too.
- You sure?
- Whatever you're thinking of doing...
...just forget it, OK?
This is over. Deal with it.
You don't know
where you're going and I do.
You don't know shit!
I'm 5 minutes from being
so far gone you can't imagine!
- You got nothing!
- You know what I got! I beat you!
Yeah? What have you got?
What have you got?
You know what I've got.
Tell me, Jack... When did you start
thinking you were better than me?
You still there, Ace?
OK. Nicely done...nicely done.
- Let's talk about this.
- How did you put it, "Deal with it"?
I don't think so. I can burn you.
We work this out
or I will take you down.
Yeah? How?
My shop, my tools, they're gone!
I'm just a tax-paying jazz club owner.
You? Every cop's looking for you now.
Ifl were you, I'd quit making threats
and hit the road.
Nice working with you, Ace!
"OK. Bye-bye!"
...Montreal was stunned by the daring
robbery of the Customs House.
A priceless sceptre was stolen.
A Senior nightjanitor identified
this man as the prime suspect.
He was spotted
leaving the scene after the robbery.
He's now the focus of a manhunt.
A second suspect
vanished without a trace.
Police have no solid leads...