Subtitles By:   Aymondo
So..
What’re you gonna do...
for me?
We’re gonna be straight that I’ve had it..
What do you say to the fact that..
I’m gonna die!
I’m gonna miss you.
Fuck that.
I won’t know about that.
I need to know...
What’s your worth..
When I leave you nothing!
who wants the world at their feet?
it’s confusing isn’t it?
I’m gonna do the best I can..
you can go knowing that..Ok?
you’re me now...if you’ll have it.
10,000..
Player wins.
20,000
40,000
Player wins.
Again..
Again
Double it...make it 80,000
Come on, Mr. Lee
covers a lot more than that buddy..
you must be new...double it.
80,000
I hope you paid your rent homes?!
I don’t pay rent homes.
What’s up man..you got a problem?
Issue of some kind?
Yeah I don’t like your fuckin’ hat..
I think you kinda wanted me to have an
issue so I thought of that one.
I’ll see you..
outside my friend.
Oh, we all gotta go outside sometime brother..
this place is just a dream..
you a gambler?
Not like you.
You wanna fuck around..or you
wanna cut cards on my last 500?
I’ll put tend grand against your 500
I haven’t got ten grand..that’s an unequal bet.
It’s uhm, unequal general situation.
Well, fuck, you’ll get it then.
That’s funny you know!
I thought you wanted my business card!
Congratulations
I know you...
I think you’re the kind of guy that likes to lose
Life’s a losing proposition right?
You might as well get it over with.
Need a stake?
You like staking losers?
I know how you guys..
stake people.
Then you know everything.
Your luck is no good tonight.
Oh, that depends..
you give me another 10,000 credit
You came in with 10,000 in cash..
you didn’t give it to me.
Well, this is a gambling establishment
Have I ever not payed you?
Eventually a debt gets too big to pay.
You owe me 240,000 dollars..
and I want it in seven days.
Stake me 50 grand.
At 20 points.
Give him 50 grand.
You make sure my man over here has your..
your digits and so forth.
I feel better about your hat.
Hehe..this mother fucker..
There’s 40,
I’m gonna keep back 10 OK?
You can exact the whole 50 against my vig..
but this is a gambling establishment,
I came to play.
Just one blue 10,000 marker please.
No,no..
don’t look at anyone, syou look at me just do it.
21.
A satisfied customer.
Let’s play the two.
20,000 dollars!
He doesn’t want you to look at him..
just keep dealing the cards.
40,000 dollars.
I’m good.
Take it.
Player wins.
Don’t look at him..
there’s no limit..
He wants to fuck or fight and
I’m not interested in either..
please, just deal the cards.
-It’s for your protection.
-For my protection?
Fuck my protection all right, you don’t come
here for fuckin protection from yourself..
you come here for the fuckin opposite
and here I am so please..
deal the cards..
thank you.
80,000 dollars.
Player wins.
No more bets.
You got me feeling lucky
I’m putting everything on black.
Red’s been comin’ up all night!
You want me to pay you now?
-Is that want you want me to do?
-No.
Why not?
Maybe I enjoy watching the show.
What about ripping me off outside if I win?
Not in that business brother.
Everything on black.
No more bets.
19 Red.
Float me some spending money.
That’s at 20 points too.
The first public notice...
that was ever made of Shakespeare...
was from a grub street writer..
Robert Greene..
who called him an upstart crow..
beautified..
with our feathers.
In the book...
in the book..
under that title on the board.
Is the beautified feathers thing..
because Greene knew that
Shakespeare was the Earl of
Oxford?
Absolutely..
not..
not even close..
the Earle of Oxford published poetry..Ok?
and it wasn’t any good..
I mean had Oxford been able
to get a play put on..
he would’ve broken..
a leg to do it.
I mean..can you think of any human being..
that would, for any reason..
not put his name oh Hamlet?!
The Oxfordian thing...
the anti-Strafordian thing..
what pisses people off..about Shakespeare..
what lies behind every controversy,
about Shakespeare..
is rage..
rage..
over the nature..
and unequal..
distribution...of talent..
rage..that genius appears..
where it appears..
for no material reason at all..
desiring a thing..
can not make you have it..
now the trouble with writing...
if I may bring it up here
in the English department..
is we all do a little of it..
from time to time..
writing.
And some of us..start to think...
delusionally..
maybe with a little time..
a little peace..
a little money in the bank,
if you get that room of your own...
you think: well, shit..
I might be a writer too..
I mean we accept genius..
in sports..as something we cannot do..
but it’s no more likely that you
could be a writer that..
that you could be..
what? An Olympic..
pole Vaulter?
Because what you have to be..
before you try to be a pole vaulter...
hello!
Is a paul vaulter..no?!
Yeah.
You are one.
A pole vaulter?
A novelist.
No I’m not..
for me to be novelist..I would have
to make a deal with myself..
that it was OK being a mediocrity..
in a profession that died commercially
in the last Century..
All right, people do that. I’m not one of them
If you take away nothing else away from my class..
from this experience..let it be this..
if you’re not a genius..
don’t bother...all right?
The world needs plenty of electricians
and a lot of them are happy.
I’ll be fucked if I’ll be a mid-list novelist..
getting good reviews from the people I give
good reviews to.
Let’s have a look at Dexter.
Dexter..
An ordinary looking..
young man..with a what? size 40 jacket..
regular features and...
decent dentition..
is the second ranked collegiate tennis player..
in the United States of America..
who did that come about Dexter?
you come from..a tennis family?
I mean uh...
I started playing 5 years ago in high school..
cause the tennis guys had the best weed.
After you started tennis..
how long was it before you were
better than everybody?
before I was better than everybody
or before I knew it?
What happened when you noticed you
were naturally better than everybody?
I got interested in the game..
That’s an IQ break-point brother..
right there..
do you remember Machiavelli?
that would’ve been
in September.
Man...I can remember September.
All right...
Is it the game brother?
Or the money?
Ha..? Virtu or fama?
Fame or virtue? What’re you after?
don’t go modest on me..
what do you want?
Both.
You got ambitious, yeah?
I realized...
as I learned about the game
that I was in reach of..
In reach of?
In reach...of..
Highest level?
Highest level...yeah.
Highest level..
but it’s still a gamble isn’t it?
Look, I’m a literature teacher..
I can’t write well enough to bother..
or I just don’t bother..which ever..
which ever it is, there’ll be no
apotheosis around here..
there’ll be no ‘vae, puto deus fio’
around here..
that’s what the Emperor Vespasian
said on his death bed..
Dear me,
I think I’m becoming a God.
But you know who does write
at the highest level?
When most of us..and even I..
even I, write barely adequately..
do you know who it is?
in this room, who is it?
don’t give me that look..
no, no, no, no...
it isn’t the one who talks the most..
you’re an NPR host..tops..OK?
The literary person in here..
is Ms. Phillips..
she’s the least obstreperous in this room..
the quietest..
and the only one...
who can have a real career...at letters.
Some of you, can have one perceptually..
only she..
can have one in reality.
she’s better at writing..
than our U.S presently amateur number..
two is at tennis.
yet she chooses to hide..
or just blend in with the rest of you..
why?
Why is that Ms. Phillips?
Being in the middle is the safest place to be.
Where do you come from?
Ohio!
Ohio..
parents are geniuses by any chance?
Filthy rich?
No.
Well, your dad wasn’t the Earl of Oxford, was he?
No..
No?
How old were you when you read?
I was two.
Two? Well that’s early, that’s prodigious..
any advantages? Literary home life?
What was your father?
Well..he worked in a factory.
Your mother?
I..don’t..
-What was..?
-She was an alcoholic..
she was insane.
If it wasn’t your dad..
I don’t see how this is pertinent.
No money...
no advantages..no peer of the realm..
you’re not the
Earl of Oxford are you?
No?
So why are you better
than the rest of us?
No you look at me..
you are better than the rest of us..
if no one told you yet..that you’re a
genius and an artist..
let me be the first..
Ok, I don’t know if you can say that...
cause I think it’s subjective man
I mean we all have something to offer.
Bullshit...
genius is magical not material..
if you don’t have the magic, no
amount of wishing will make it so..
Ms. Phillips..
if you plan to continue to come to my class..
you sit in the front were you belong..
or don’t bother showing up.
Have a nice day.
May I have a word?
More words..?
The athletic department has asked how...
a certain person is doing..
You mean the certain person
who can not stay off his phone?
I mean you do realize that this..
certain person cannot write at a high school level..
never mind a collegial one..
but that doesn’t matter thought right?
I mean come on
half the entenured faculty would be
flogged to death for idiocy..
in any grammar school in
any previous Century so..
why would it matter?
Why do you care about that?
If..you don’t care about anything?
You’re probably right.
I’ll never beat you Mr. Dexter...
but if you ever give me a point
I cannot fire you.
Good luck in the finals.
Thank you ma'am.
Why do you need the money?
If you’re escaping for a purpose,
maybe I’d buy it.
Going on as I am is the only thing I’ve got.
That’s sophistical...
it’s beneath you...
I think you would agree that...
modification...
is possible.
Do you?
I know you’re in real trouble..
I know this is all connected to
your grand father’s death..
but you’re not narcissistic enough to..
put on a show..nor are you an adolescent..
and I think it goes without saying
that you’r far from stupid..
you’re my son..
but you have to understand..
I’ve said good bye before..
to people I love.
Yeah whatever did happen to dad?
I’ve done it many, many times...
I don’t want to know the nature of your problem..
I just want you to not have it anymore..
I’m not giving you anymore.
-You Jim Bennett?
-Yeah.
Get in.
Big Ernie.
You’re not that big.
Not talking about my jacket brother.
You know with all due respect I’m
not interested in you Johnson..so..
Sure you are..
it has been so since the Greeks.
I gotta tell you..I can’t argue with that I guess.
A friend of mine says that you are a teacher.
I’m a social professor.
The amount of cash you want...
is more than I am
ordinarily disposed to loan out..
unless, say, you’re a medium size country..
with the ability..
to raise taxes under the
threat of military force..
or..
a Euro trash coke head who has a father..
that could be squeezed
after the little prick’s..
micro-budget sci-fi film
doesn’t get picked up at Sundance..
are you following me?
You have family that could be squeezed?
I’m saying that rhetorically.
Let’s deal with this as gentlemen who
understand each other please?
No..
I need for us to treat each other like
we’re not gentlemen..
and that we’re very, very stupid.
OK..
there’s no family, there’s never any family.
What do you make..a 100?
150 a year? 200 before taxes?
What’s wrong with you? you got brain damage?
Some fundamental disability?
200 is a monk..
and you, a monk..
owe that Korean son of a bitch...
that prince of fuckin’ darkness,
that much already..
and then another fifty, excluding the vig..
to Neville Baraka..
who will kill you because when..
you cut cards..
he got the king of spades, and you laughed at him.
You’re pretty well informed.
You borrowed fifty K from a very dangerous man..
after he already was going to kill you.
Yes I did.
Birth, education, intelligence, talent, looks..
family money..
has all this been some real comprehensive fuckin’
burden for you?
I see two problems..
One..
the world at his feet, in this town..
and he’s a fuckin’ monk because
apparently..Fuck it.
Two..
he wants to dance with the devil..
for some unspecified reason therefore..
owes money to Korean murderers..
and talks about a schwarzer’s hat..
in a place where he can get killed..
and they merely drop your
body up the Angeles Crest..
Three, he wants to borrow a quarter of
a million dollars..
to pay off debts which he will, in fact,
not pay off..
because, to go back to point two...
he’s suicidal.
Just let me know
what you can do for me all right?
If I help you consolidate those debts
even at a lesser load..
do you think I would be anyone
you wanna fuck up the ass?
am I likelier to be fucked up the ass?
Less likely I imagine.
Listen to me, listen to me..
I’m not your doctor..
I’m not your cognitive therapist..
but let me be your uncle..
you have to pay 10 percent a week.
I know what I have to do.
Where are you gonna get my money?
-I'll get the money.
How much you want?
I’m 260,000 dollars all in.
When's the last time you had money in your hand..
to pay a debt..and payed it?
Don’t fuck with me..
this will be your first time when you pay.
Am I right?
That’s right.
We’re not done..
I need something from you..
What? Collateral?
No..I need you to tell me..
I need this money because
I’m a scumbag gambler..
I’m a scumbag gambler
who is  drowning in his own shit...
that’s the kind of man I am Frank..
and I want you..to loan me..
a dying suicidal asshole..
a lot of money.
That’s too much to remember to repeat it.
I’ll make it simple for you..
you want this money..tell me I am not a man.
Say it..
say I am not a man.
Yes..?
Did you mean what you said?
About me having talent?
Is there something you don’t get about A++
see me?
Then you never see me..
Yeah well,
I don’t wanna see you.
Because I’ve seen you in your other life?
No..
No it isn’t that.
Oh.
Do you know why I’m in trouble here?
Because I tell the truth..
It’s what I do..
Do want me to split the atoms..
succumb to velocity and tell you the truth..?
Physiology doesn’t lie..
everything else does..
everybody else does..
physiology doesn’t.
It’s post intellectual..
And what are you trying to say to me?
I’m not in any position to say anything.
Try.
Why should I try?
Because what you said before.
I need you to leave..
Right now..this is not happening..
I’m serious go..you have to go.
I want you to sign this.
Absolutely fuckin’ not
I want you..to fuckin’ sign it.
Look, I’m not being dramatic ok?
But that was somebody else.
You are being dramatic.
which is fine because the novel is basically OK..
but that’s what you are..a dramatist.
did you write this because you believed in it...
or because you thought that’s
what people wanted?
Well, what do you propose we move on to?
When was..
the last time that somebody told
you that you’re a genius?
We’re not having this conversation.
I wanna go to a restaurant.
There’s a whole bunch of things
I don’t do anymore..
and that’s...kind of up there.
Guy with no money speaking,
how may I direct your call?
I’m reading your book.
not bad.
Ah..If you wanna get into..
producing, there’s only about a hundred grand
against it in Warner Brothers..
good script..I know the guy who did.
It’s a Indie at best.
Yeah...yeah that’s what they thought.
I heard you went to little Franky for some money..
he wouldn’t loan it to you.
Well you heard wrong, because he did try
to loan it to me and I didn't take it.
You didn’t like the terms?
No, the terms weren’t acceptable.
But you’re into me..
and I ain’t Fannie May..ain’t no bail outs.
Oh yeah, then why did you loan me the money?
A gamble between two players who like to play...
me and you.
Double header?
Let me give you a bit of advice here.
What’s that?
You owe somebody money..you don’t fuck around..
I want the money by Monday...
I’ll take that car of yours..
consider it collateral.
In the Stranger..
Camus' protagonist fires five shots..
the sixth shot of the revolver..
he is reserving symbolically for himself...
noticing that, originally..
is why I’m here now...
Lamar...
Lamar..
you’re taking notes?
or you’re texting?
You have anything you wanna add?
What do you think?
All right...well..
maybe the dude had a hammer..
on an empty chamber or something..
or a weird French piece that only took five!
No, my idea works better if he has a full six.
I don’t understand suicide.
Well that’s because you’re happy.
You got a BMW, M1..
how are you unhappy?
Do I look happy?
I’m not happy.
You know why?
Because I’m teaching the modern novel..
to a class room full of students..
who don’t give a fuck..
you know..
we really should’ve gone for American realism..
I mean let’s have more fuckin’ realism..
I mean shouldn’t I be teaching you things?
No, I should..
I mean I know all you’re here for..
is a sufficiency..
of English credits but Jesus...if I'm here..
I ought to be doing better...right?
I could stand here..
stark naked..
and I could yell as loud as I want..
and nobody cares.
When you leave here today, call your parents..
and tell them you apologize..
for wasting their time..
and more importantly wasting their money..
sitting in this classroom learning absolutely..
nothing.
let’s start fresh, lets clean
the slate right now..
Let me introduce myself..
my name is James Bennett..
I’m here pretending to teach..
and you’ve been here pretending to learn..
this is what I want you to do...
write down..
that he saves the sixth shot
symbolically for himself...
you’re not gonna find a reference anywhere..ok?
because I am the only one who
thought of it all right..
It’s in a monograph somewhere...
that got me into this situation..
where I can’t..so I pretend to teach..
and you pretend to learn..
Lamar...!
the fucking...phone.
you stay after...everybody else...just go.
go...go.
What do I have to do?
What do I do? Get ten guys...
some weapons..take out a life insurance policy ..
trying to put that phone up your ass?
Because I will.
I need you to pay attention..
Is that too much to ask for? Huh?
You come into this class, and you pay
attention for a fuckin’ hour..
You know..they expect me
to pass you regardless..
regardless..they want me to give
you a passing grade..
so you can keep going out there..
and bouncing that basketball around..
I need you to put the phone down..for a second.
You’re not the only one loosing his shit..
I was gonna talk to you anyway...
cause I can’t talk to anybody over there..
cause all they’re gonna say
is what keeps me in line..
for what they want me to be...
which is Lamar, but..I don’t wanna be Lamar..
I done all that..
I just wanna be another fuckin’ dude,
in the Universe..
and do more than just being Lamar.
Yeah, I know all about it.
But the fuckin’ coach don’t know about it..
There's more than being Lamar..
I stick with this shit man I’d go out of my mind...
probably be one of those brothers
that talks to himself..
in like third person and shit...talk about how..
Lamar is at ease with his celebrity..
they got me in a box where they want me..
Trapped by talent...imagine that.
You know man...in here..
it’s all existential situations and shit..
no matter what you start talking about..
you come around to be free or not to be free...
how to be yourself..or nothing at all.
Is that what I talk about, all or nothing?
I never heard talking about anything else..
but to be or not to be...
and I’ve had four classes with you.
Maybe you got me.
I need to go pro.
I don’t think you’re
gonna have any trouble Lamar.
I don’t mean later, I mean now..I need to go pro..
I all ready got a knee.
nobody knows about it cause I don’t
say anything...
but I already got a knee...
see I’m not gonna sit here and tell you that...
my mom needs an operation...
or my little sister has Spina Bifida...
but I am gonna tell you that I got a knee...
I got a knee...
I’m a junior...
and whenever I tell somebody I don’t wanna
play college ball my senior year..
nobody listens to me...
it’s like I’m talking Chinese on
another fuckin’ planet...
and then the coach tells me..
I don’t have the market value I would have...
if I don’t play on my senior year..
but what he doesn’t know is that
I got a fuckin’ knee...
You have it looked at it
away from the department?
Yeah.
Did you have money on the game?
Why would I have money on the game?
He’s a student of mine...
that’s unethical all right..
I would not bet on a student of mine..
you think I would do something like that?
I would never do anything like that..OK?
What kind of a person do you think I am?
Do I have money on the game?!
Is he good at English?
No, he’s not.
How bad is this trouble you’re in?
I’m always in trouble.
No, I mean...
do you still need money?
No.
Truthfully?
Truthfully.
I never know when to believe you anymore..
perhaps I should believe...the gangster who..
phoned my home...
what’s that?
What I owe.
Jesus...how is this possible?
Same as your marriage..I lost.
No, marriage is in the real world..
it’s not a game of chance.
Now you’re talking crazy.
What will they do to you if you don’t pay?
Break every bone on my body...
Go after the family...
I can’t help doing this...
I don’t believe this is a disease..
Well I just had a considerable
conversation about character...
and there’s gonna be a moment
when I want something again...
when I won’t allow myself to be
seen i this condition..
but it’s not now..
and it’s not up to you...
or anything you..or anybody else fuckin’ says ok?
Are you degraded enough ..
to come with your mother to the bank?
In cases like this, I have to ask...
is everything ok?
Nothing is ok..
when someone needs
that amount of money in cash...
but it’s my money..and it’s none of
your goddamn business.
Are you a relation?
This is my son.
Either you can’t see the uncanny resemblance..
or you’re implying
she’s under duress or something.
Should I be?
Look dear...
it’s my money...and there’s plenty of it...
and don’t even start to tell me that all..
this bullshit is for my protection..
because that is understood...
now you have the withdrawal slip...
here..is my I.D...
there are sufficient funds...
my family has been with this bank...
since my father in law started it...
now what I want...
is 260,000 dollars...
in cash.
Are you sure you want that in cash?
Cash.....cash.
I’m sorry. I’m gonna ask for..
What?
For a second piece of identification...
it’s for your own protection.
This is the last of it...
if I ever have to hear
about your problems again...
I will never see you again..do you understand?
I need you to..
fuckin’ understand that...
am I embarrassing you?
You wanna just take the money?
You wanna just take the money and go?
Even if I say goodbye...
and consider it..
cheap to be rid of you?
Yeah, I wanna take the money and go.
Hey.
If I have to pull you into an
inappropriate relationship..
to get you out of your job..I’m ready to go.
So am I.
If I told you that I’m not a gambler...?
what if you saw me with a needle in my arm..
and I told you that I’m not a junkie?
I saw you be a professor
and I know you’re not one of those.
It’s good to come out here...
it’s good.
I come out here because it makes feel alive.
No..no..no, not good enough...
there is something else...
I don’t know quite what it is...
I know a lot, but I don’t fuckin’ know that..
I always sat on a blanket
in the middle of nowhere..
with nothing around me,
with infinite possibilities..
and it’s bullshit, and I’m sick of it.
You are the perfect example
of how a person can start off..
with no problems what so ever...
and then go out of their way to
make sure they have all of them.
There’s no relative degree of suffering..
what, you want me to talk about my problems?
I don’t like people with problems..
or the fuckin’ vanity to bring them up...
that’s where I’m from...
I’m like my mother...
you know...
whether I’m like my father or not..
I couldn’t tell you because
she got rid of him when I was little...
And you don’t think that you need..
to talk to anybody?
No...
I need a lot of things...
I gotta wipe myself out first...
I need to have no past,
if I get to nothing I could start over.
Oh..
echo...
you wanna help me start over?
There is something wrong with everybody here...
they should be in the hospital.
Yeah, that’s right..but they’re not..
All right? the Man wants you to be in the hospital..
these people are fucking Americans...
making a major stand for freedom.
Well..assisted autonomy, but...
this is the inside of my soul kid...
this is what I got.
Waw.
Well, at least I’m gonna get rid of my mother.
This table right here...come on.
All right, that’s 10,000.
How far are you going man?
As far as it goes, buddy.
I’d go as far as that seat on the other..
side of you man.
Save it for the old lady, cowboy.
That’s 500 dollars, sir.
Yes it is. Are you a dealer or an
investment councilor?
Double.
We gambling or what?
-Just draw..give me the three.
-You kiddin' me?
Wow..!
Who are you? Houdini?
Pulled that one out of your ass!
Pulls a three on an eight....unbelievable.
Give me another 10,000.
All right at 10,000.
Give me the bag.
That’s 500 dollars, sir.
It’s not 500 dollars...
1000 dollars...
another 500 dollars...
2000 dollars...
deal the cards please.
2000 placed.
Everything?
You wanna hear something really fuckin’ crazy?
There was this student...
just the other day...who said my problem...
if one’s nature is a problem...
rather than just..fuckin’ problematic...
right? Is I see things in terms
of victory or death...
and not just victory, but total victory.
It’s true.
I always have.
mine is either victory or don’t bother.
The only thing we’re doing is the impossible.
Right? everything else is fucking gray...
when you’re borne as
a man with nerves of a soldier..
the apprehension of an angel still lifts a phrase...
but there’s no fuckin’ use for it..here?
Where is the use for it?
You’re set to be a philosopher, or a king..
or fuckin’ Shakespeare...
and this is all they give you? This?!
Twenty-odd years of School,
with all the instruction on how to be ordinary...
or they fuckin’ kill you, and they’ll fuckin’ will...
and then it’s a career...
which is not the same thing as existence, so..
I want unlimited things, I want everything..
I want a real fuckin’ love...a real fuckin’ house...
a real fuckin’ thing to do, everyday...
and I just...
I’d just rather die if I don’t get it.
Did I just say that out loud?
Hey Jim..you stopped answering your phone.
I told you the time frame.
The fuck do I care about your time frame.
So you don’t die.
Everybody dies.
Aren’t you afraid of dying for
something other than natural causes?
I gotta take whatever is coming,
because I don’t have the money.
Your grand father pops
and you don’t have any money?
My grand father
thought I was a character builder..so.
Not even I’ll have it?
You just say no?
You give the Korean any of his?
No.
You know Lamar Allen?
Don’t fuck with me.
He’s a student of mine.
What’s this got to do with anything?
You know, what this got to do with everything.
How much you know Lamar?
Hey Jim..pick up.
Jim!
I called that number for Lamar,
and it wasn’t the number..
Now Jim, I need Lamar..
and I know where you live...
tick tock mother fucker.
Human weakness
is not something I discourage...
How could I?
I run gambling establishments...
I loan money...
I’ve not been in debt for many years, but..
I still remember the feeling...
What’s that?
To be obligated...
unbalanced in one’s thoughts..
insecure, unclean..
I think you wanna hurt yourself..
but make others do it for you...
I’m not gonna tell you
I’ll get the money all right?
Because I don’t know
if I can and I wouldn’t insult you.
it Doesn’t make any difference...
I mean I have no position....right?
You expected your money and I don’t have it..
Here we are..what the fuck do you wanna do?
How am I to collect?
Loan me another hundred thousand.
That’s how I got in, it’s the only way I’ll get out.
Not so bad..
not so bad..
perfectly good watch..
why do you want sell it?
Well either I don’t
need to know what time it is..
or I need money..what do you care?
Well, I need to know if it is...
No, what you need to do
is just come up with an offer or not.
We have so many..
of these here.
It’s an Omega..!
It’s worth more than six thousand brand new..
and when you have it...
no one will know that it isn’t brand new.
Your are insulting me why?
I’m insulting you?
Why, why are you insulting me?
You know, we’re not gonna fuck around..
No,no, don’t even talk to me anymore..
I want you to understand
that when I say what I want for it...
I’m giving you the figure
that I would take for it, you understand me?
No, no, no look at me...
I will say the price now..
and you will either say yes or no..
do you understand?
It is impossible...
impossible to say yes or..
All right.
Wait..wait wait..
It is a good watch..
I am good man you are good man..
No, I told you not to say anything but
yes or no you’re wasting my time
I’m willing to listening to your price..ok?
You can’t counter it...
when I say my figure...that’s the figure..
and you either say yes or no, you got it?
How can I say yes or no if I am not hearing..
the price?
You’r not getting it...
-I’m getting it.
-You're not getting it.
No, no, no..
-I am getting it.
-You're not getting it.
You need to understand fully that what I say...
it’s  not an opening figure..
You can say yes or no..
you can not say a lower figure and
expect to meet me at some point in the middle..
do you under fuckin stand
Please....please..
we are mour..yes? amour..ok?
Calm..calm..
Yes...I understand..what is your price?
Three thousand...five hundred dollars.
One thousand..
twelve hundred
Go fuck yourself I don’t give a shit.
Wow..no need for this..what?
where are you going?
What are you doing?
Wait one second..please...please
-I can’t help myself.
-Yes you can...try.
Two thousand..?
Why..it’s good price.
I give you check...it’s no problem.
Jim..!
Man you gave me the wrong number on Lamar..
you know what else I know?
What’s that?
You think all Koreans are Koreans and shit...
they don’t communicate with the
American Negro..
I heard you asked Mr. Lee
to stick you out of your situation..
and to give you enough to
have a shot at the title..
of being the world’s stupidest ass hole.
Give me Mr. Lee’s money.
He didn’t front me any.
Fuck you.
Well, your information is wrong.
How am I gonna get my money Jim?
What if I told you I quit my job, and I’m
gonna write a novel?
Really?
What did the first one make?
With the advance and royalties..
17,000 dollars all in.
Fuck me..
For one of the
better reviewed first novels of 2007?
I think I’ll make other arrangements..
I mean, the culture apparently did..
so let’s talk cash first, other business later.
What about your family?
Got all I could get.
Can I get the money from them?
If I send you to Mexico? You know..
Oh my god I don’t know what happened to him..
get my friend Valerio to mail them your dick.
My family didn’t make their money
because they pay up easily.
Apparently that’s genetic..
I tell you boy, genetics..
cruel mother fuckin’ mistress.
What if I lit a cigar and put it out
in your eyeball..
would you give me the money then?
Do I look like a magician?
You must’ve thought you..
was magic occasionally...
or else you wouldn’t be in the
Africa membership club..
owing me sixty grand.
I’m gonna need the equity on your house Jim..
We paper it right as a sale...
but then I gotta take over the
goddamn mortgage...
find some fucking vice-president
of animation to rent it to..
and I don’t fuckin’ wanna do that shit.
But you gotta make the turnip bleed from
what ever hole it’s got, right?
Now your grand father..I respect him..
he’s a business man..
but Lamar who you gave me the
wrong number for...
Lamar is a good kid all right?
He doesn’t need any of this shit.
You’re gonna tell me you made
a mistake with the number?
Why would I tell you I made a mistake?
I gave you a fake one, I made it up.
Ok..
Well see, my man Mr. Jones here is gonna
give you the real one.
That is the last time that you lie to me my friend..
Lamar don’t need your help..
every man’s gotta go it alone Jim..
and Lamar is gotta make his own
choices, so let him make it.
Now I’m not gonna call him..
that would really confuse the issue.
But you’re gonna get me Lamar...
and it will be more than an introduction...
In fact, I don’t even want an introduction...
Lamar is gonna do exactly what
I want him to do..
without ever seeing my face..
I need him before the game tomorrow at home..
now they’re running 8 point on Michigan...
you can tell Lamar he
can win if he wants, but no more than seven.
but you get him for tomorrow...
cause if not...
I’m gonna kill that pretty little blond girl...
show you the pictures and then kill you next.
Hey, what’s happening man?
Oh man, makin’it do with the do..
Yes sir..haha..no doubt.
What happened to your face?
Whatever happened had already happened
it won’t happen again.
So you’re starting to make promises now?
That’s not happening.
You don’t get it.
What’s going on?
I’m getting out of here as fast as I can..
and as everybody and their fuckin’ Aunt
is eyeballing me right now..
it might be better if you’re not chasing
along as if you were my wife.
Jesus Christ!
Gotta tell you the truth all right?
That’s all I got.
No..
No...
You can’t talk to people like that.
Really? Who says? Huh?
Who says?
I do.
I want you to stop looking concerned ok?
I want you to shake my hand..
you the kind of fuckin’ man I am..
don’t lie to yourself...I don’t
What happened?
Nothing happened...
you’re not getting it ok?
just..
if I come to your door, then I’ll have made it..
everything will start to be all right
if I don’t come then I didn’t fuckin’ make it...
and what you do with the dead
is you bury them, that’s it.
You really hate yourself that much?
Hold out your hand and say good bye.
Please.
It’s really fuckin’ easy to be passionate
about...
Robert fuckin’ Greene.
What happened to your face man?
A little while ago you came to me for
advice about turning pro..
I know it’s about your knee..
I know you have a feeling you have to
put money in the bank, so..
I was wondering if you’d like
to make a hundred and fifty grand in two hours.
Depends on what you have in mind.
Throwing a game...
you can’t win tomorrow by more than 7 points.
That’s not throwing the game..
that’s winning by less than 8...
who want’s me to do it?
What they got on you?
It doesn’t matter.
Man, they fucked you up...
they didn’t need to fuck you up.
No, I needed it...
and they’ll fuck you up if you need it too,
you gotta deliver.
I’m asking because I know you need it,
it’s up to you, it’s your call
I do this that get you out of trouble?
No.
Hey...
Where do a teacher like you get
that kind of money?
Well, they fuckin’ weren’t supposed to,
were they? That was the point.
Sit down.
You drink?
I don’t remember if you drink..
Of course there’s drink...and drink..
I drink..
but I haven’t been drunk since
Reagan was President..
I got a DUI and in jail..
I actually..fell down, and pissed my..
pants..
you don’t need to do that twice..
I tell you this so you know everybody’s
been there.
Everybody’s been there.
Once..
if you’re there twice..
having been there once, I can’t help you
you know..
I listen to the drunks..
and it’s like you’re listening to a fairy story..
about a fight with a fuckin’ monster..
when the actual title to the story is:
I Can't Handle My Liquor by Mr. Cry Baby.
Amen.
I don’t know maybe they gotta a problem..
but fuck’em if they do, cause I don’t..
which leads me to ask...
are you pulling this shit just now? or forever?
I mean..
do you have a problem..
wa wa wa like some little fuckin’ girl..wa wa wa
or some Somali who can’t process that
there’s no food where they live?
or are you just fucked up temporarily cause
you’re temporarily fuckin’ stupid?
Are you long business
or short business?
What’s the difference?
I need to know if you got the fuckin’ brains
to walk when it’s time to walk...
people don’t you know?
Ball players who can’t play any more..
ass holes trying to maintain a standard of
living not possible any more..
a lot of those around.
I’ve seen you be half a million dollars up.
I’ve been up two and a half million dollars.
What do you got on you?
Nothing.
What did you put away?
You get up two and a half million dollars..
any ass hole in the world..
knows what to do..
you get a house with a twenty five year roof..
an indestructible...
Jap economy shitbox..
you put the rest into the system at 3 to 5
percent to pay your taxes and that's
your base, get me?
That’s your fortress of fuckin’ solitude..
that puts you, for the rest of your life,
at a level...of fuck you.
Somebody wants you to do something? Fuck you.
Boss pisses you off..fuck you.
Own your house..
have a couple of bucks in the bank..
don’t drink.
That’s all I have to say to anybody
at any social level..
did your grand father take risks?
Yes.
I guarantee
he did it from position of fuck you.
A wise man’s life...
is based around fuck you..
the Unites States of America is based
on fuck you..
You’re a king..you have an Army...
greatest Navy in the history of the world?
Fuck you, blow me.
We’ll fuck it up ourselves..
which..
we have done. Beautiful fuck you position
lost forever..
King George the third looks like a fuckin’
birthday present.
This is the grand son of the..
seventeenth richest man in California...
Does he drink?
What he wants...is money..
cause he doesn’t know when to say that's it..
I’m two million ahead, fuck it, fuck you...
I have a car and a house and a family...
and it’s all payed for...fuck you.
I mean even I did that..of course it was
out by Pearblossom.
I’ll have a beer just like anybody else,
thank you.
What kind?
Any kind.
I got 37 beers, don’t fuckin’ put it on me.
But he did put it on you miss.
You still owe large two places you shouldn’t..
why do you want door number three?
How else do I get out?
Time payments, sell your sperm, sell your ass,
how the fuck should I know?
I am of the universe,
and you know what it’s worth.
It’s worth plenty.
If I give you this money...
and you don’t pay me back..
there are no rules..
you never get to say fuck you to anybody ever.
You will get me not just what
you owe me from your family...
you will get me their accounts..
so I can have them vacuumed from Russia..
you jump off a bridge..
you can doing it knowing I
will kill your entire blood line..
Do you understand the
gravity of your situation?
I understand.
You get up..you get out..
260 as requested.
What’s this?
With this much money..what’s a car?
What do you wanna be able to say to me?
Fuck you.
You have my money?
I don’t have any money.
I want you to stake me.
Stake me and I’ll get your money.
Why did you see Frank?
I didn’t..
fucking stake me.
Please..tell me you hit your wife
harder than that you fuckin’ pussy.
You’re gonna give a hundred and fifty..
fuckin’ thousand
What can I do with you?
Stake me.
Fuckin’ stake me.
That’s my boy there Lamar.
That’s your boy?
That’s the kid I’m talking about right there..
he know what he gotta do..
All right, all right now, all right..
Hang on, hang on, this shit ain’t right..
What is he doing?
Man he better stop performing and less scoring.
I don’t get it? Ain’t that your man?
Yeah if he don’t handle his business,
I’m gonna handle him.
Yeah that's better..that's better.
That’s more like, that’s what I’m taking about.
That’s all right, get in Lamar.
Still in that bench Lamar.
And a foul..take it to the house mother fucker.
Yeah, Ok, we good, we good.
There you go.
Stay on the bench Lamar...
stay on that fuckin’ bench Lamar
stay on the fuckin’ bench.
Oh, come on..
what did this mother fucker just do?
Damn!
Oh, come on!
He’s fuckin’ up like that he
knows what he’s got to be doing..
Yeah, say that to your man, he’s scoring.
Yeah, too damn much.
Oh come on man, that’s some bullshit!
I told him less than eight.
Yes sir...
Yes sir..
our boy delivered...
you delivered...
you know how rare that is?
A man delivers?
So we’re square?
You’re gonna stop threatening the girl?
How about I tell you..
you get to keep your job with the University...
forever..
just as long as you keep teaching English 101
to a whole lot of tall brothers.
Or I tell you to kill me.
Have a drink...
Don’t want one.
Thank you sweetheart.
I see the Koreans fucked your face up!
Yes they did.
And you just move on
to the next phase of bullshit..
You know?
The only trouble is with the game today?
What’s that?
Someone also bet an
eight-point spread in Vegas..
for a whole lot of fuckin’ money..
you wouldn’t happen to
know who did that would you?
No idea.
You ain’t tipped nobody?
No.
What’s your life’s plan Jim?
Make part of it never seeing me again.
I don’t need you no more brother.
I know that.
Think I want you out there..
knowing that? Knowing this?
I’m going to tell that I’m not going to..
do you the discourtesy of
assuming what your thinking..
but I know you’ll do the right thing.
Why is that?
It’s the whole amount..and points.
Where did you get that?
-I borrowed it from Frank.
-The fuck you did
-Ask him.
-I will.
And you will find out that I did.
You know Jim, everybody is ready to be bent..
Some ready to be straight..
personally I’m ready to be..
straight...
I’m gonna get my self a avocado farm...
or a winery..
do what I gotta do, you know?
Not a huge fan of low company.
A man can transform his shit Jim.
You know, I’ve never
done anything like this before..
I mean I didn’t think I was gonna
make it out there alive..you know.
Open it...
take out fifty grand, it’s yours.
Man, I’m gonna have my fuckin’..
picture on a Wheaties box
within months dude.
Well, suite yourself.
What was the point of me going to Vegas?
Obviously it wasn’t to earn fifty grand.
time to get away from me Dexter...
Far away.
I got your money..
but I’m not coming there, you gotta meet me..
Korea town, you the place right?
Everybody knows the place...
whether or not I want you around that place..
with my money in your
hand is another fuckin’ story.
Well that’s the only place I’ll meet you.
You have all my money plus everything.
Yeah, I have all your money..
but I don’t have everything...
you gotta meet me there.
What do you do when
you’re in the fuck you position?
Well we’v had that discussion and
I understand your point...
but you gotta meet me there.
If there’s a list of places were nobody gets ripped off..
I believe that’s at the top.
You have my money?
Yes.
Then you must come outside.
No...
I owe him too.
You’re gonna play?
It’s the only way I can pay you both...
you can’t take the money off..
me here and neither can he.
Red or Black, all or nothing, all
the money down that’s all I’ll do..
move.
Take a very..
sizable bet?
That is what this room is for.
What the fuck are you doing?
All on black.
I was playing for Mr. Lee
and for that gentleman over there.
I’m not actually a gambler.
Key is in the car.
You don’t need a ride?
No I’ll walk, I feel like walking.
What do you got on you?
Not a fuckin’ cent.
That’s not a fuck you position.
Yes it is.
Here's your hundred...
turns out to us a little extra, cream on top..
on me.
Fuck you.
Good boy.