The
CONTRACT
You and the new, Davis?
No, no, and like this. I am it
the person that will help you.
I hope you are better
that the other.
What and what did it happen?
- He didn't tolerate the "heat."
- Well, I am "the fire" proof.
You have problems
of self-discipline?
Bobby Fisher would be proud
of this movement.
Now you don't have as fleeing, friend.
Then, where this the great boss.
- Him this to arrive.
Have calm.
-That and a good way to be deaf.
What and what did say?
This to win?
- I never lose.
Everything well, we will begin with this.
And a contract in two steps
Everything that you/they need to know this oh.
Everything memorizes.
It ties tomorrow of guile.
Then the ficheiro destroys the hard disk.
Excellent.
You and Davis.
I didn't think that he/she knew that I was here.
- I knew.
Some thing no this well.
- I don't see...
...any escape strategy.
- The operation was planeada to the detail.
I am happy that he/she has trust,
but if he/she has to miscarry... or if we fail the objective.
- We won't fail
Do you have the intention of failing?
Me not. But I cannot guarantee
that the others don't fail.
I can.
We will travel for companies
aerial different.
The passports and the passages
they are with Turner.
First class?
- Tourist.
Apposed that is going in the 1..
- Yes, but am I the boss, does he/she remember?
Well and everything.
Ahhh, I don't believe.
Some problem?
he/she picked me, checkmate.
Good play!
We are going Matty,
Maintain the head lowers!
And quite so.
Ei, Two!
We will talk, it seats you.
What has to say in
your defense?
Anything, father, what wants
what do I say?
He/she begins with...
Excuses.
To ask excuse to who?
- To your companions of it equips, to me.
You have luck of you remove yourself
just with 3 days of suspension
- Luck!
Yes, luck.
Father, I don't understand this whole cry.
Nowadays everyone smokes herb.
Don't come me with shit
Do I seem you some idiot?
You know that don't matter
with the one that the others do, you are my son.
I know about the one that and,
and on your mother.
Or that.
Chris, I will only speak...
- Ok, will already finish with this.
Does he/she tell me, everything the one what I make this wandered, ok?
Chris, I am only to try to say...
- Then for of trying to help me.
And for of using that stupid bracelet,
as if it was to do some difference
You cannot make anything.
Why do pretend that you can make something?
You are not able to.
Everything was not well, father.
When she was sick said
that was everything well and no, no...
he/she was not.
Sr. Hammond?
Of a peep in this.
I have better pictures of the
that these, Mr. Hammond.
Do you know him/it what this means?
- Did my wife hire him?
Naturally, you know.
Who do you know and my father?
- Therefore and that are to speak with itself.
I calculated that maybe were able to
to do a better one negotiates.
How much and what will this cost me?
- Well...
Will we arrive late the school?
He/she throws the ball that I still win you.
- Do you win me?
He/she hears, I thought that
we could make something together.
Something what like to do?
He/she polices took me to her everything, father.
Haul of that, well, you know...
And that such to camp.
Do you like to camp?
-Is it later? You like.
What and what do find?
I don't think are to speak to her serialize.
Then, what makes in the life, Mr. Ellwood?
I sell equipments informaticos.
Outlying
They are not the computers.
Plus the things than they accompany them.
You know, cables, softwares. Systems
of storage of data, things like this.
I am afraid not to be of his/her interest.
- No, and fascinating.
Here this, Mr. Ellwood.
The light bill this included.
The income and he/she pays in the 1° day of the month.
Very well, thank you.
- You can use the garage.
He/she has a lock electronica.
The garbage Mondays and Thursdays...
- Thank you very much.
The first phase was executed.
- Without problems?
Correcto.
- Fortunately.
We are going to the second phase.
Don't speak anything to her.
She wanted to give me number him/it of the
call of her.
I told him/her, it excuses me dear.
I have a great girlfriend.
She sat down there.
Did he/she see this?
Car accident?
- Correcto.
Does he/she have more some?
- No. The second was a pile of ashes.
Him this stable one.
- Did he say something even so?
No, him this out of itself.
- Right.
-Call the safety.
How and what if this to feel?
My name and Wainwright.
Ed Wainwright, Boss of it Polices.
Go there,
the man came directamente upward of me.
Yes, I am the sure that yes.
No and that.
The weapon?
We did vary researches.
I tried to enter in contact
with somebody close, of Robert Ellwood.
He/she seems that he doesn't have anybody
And he died when he/she was 3 years old.
We examined ourselves their fingerprints,
Mr. Carden.
You this classified, as one
missing soldier has many years.
But you no longer this disappeared,
Mr. Carden.
You know, they don't appear a lot of people
of his/her type in our small city.
You know, frankly, Frank,
I cannot think about anything, though...
Ei, frankly, Frank,
this and a game of words.
No, and a pun,
no a game.
Yes, in every case...
then, and Frank...
...What and what this to do here?
- When and what will come for my cause?
I will put two men here
during the whole night.
Only for itself, Mr. Carden.
Very open eyes. I will be back of guile.
- Right.
That ray and he/she happened that is not able to
to wait an hour and a half.
It polices her/it in the northwest of the state.
It picked this man in a car accident.
And better than this is good.
I examined the fingerprints
of him, in the bases of data.
I found a such of Major
Frank Carden in the military files.
Frank Carden?
- Does he/she know him/it?
- No.
He/she served in the service of information
missing in combat in 1974.
I suppose that he/she didn't die in the accident.
- No, no, this in the hospital.
Somebody called the Department
of National security.
In FBI all are animated with this.
The another negotiate are already behind us.
This subjects and a hot potato.
- Do I serialize her?
He/she seems that nowadays all want
to tie the alarm system.
Everything well, find out when he arrives.
- With certainty.
It ties soon.
Yes.
- Miles.
What did happen he/she? And him?
- Yes, without you doubt and Carden.
An agent of FBI ended now
of telling me this.
I don't want this to go far away.
- No, gentleman.
He/she had not escaped us from the hand gentleman,
I am on top of the subject.
How and what does that know?
- He tied me.
- Did he/she tie him/her?
How and what did he get to do that?
- He/she asks him/her later.
- We will have to improvise.
- Ok, rule 1: we won't go back to have saved him/it.
Him this hurt, he will be like this...
He would make the same thing
regarding us.
He/she doesn't know him/it that this to say!
-The old let to be hit, problem of him.
Frank this in the command.
We are us with him there is a long time.
Yes, all less you.
-Some time heard to talk about loyalty?
Yes, I read once on that in a book.
Me I am not paid to save him/her the tail.
He/she had not received anything...
Unless it saves him/her the tail.
He/she knows that bill out of the parents
Only Frank has access to her.
Without Frank, any money.
That argument appeals
to my emotional side.
Local celebrities and Vip's
they are to do a lobby
for us to have dinner with the president.
after his/her speech in the university...
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Another announce, we were informed on
famous Lydel Hammond Jr,
It was involved in an accident
of running over and escape
out of the city
Will we make really this?
No, I propose that drink the coffee
and that go back to the bed.
Lydel Hammond Jr and son of the
lonely billionaire
It is waited that Lydell Senior
knife a rare appearance publishes
for his/her son's funeral
inside of few days.
And same Hammond of the name of the street, no and?
- Yes.
And of the stadium.
The contributo of Lydel Hammond Senior,
to the current administration.
It caused some recently confusion
after yours alleged support the hard accoes and violence
against the doctors and scientists
involved in the study of cells estaminais
Excuse me for the handcuffs, Frank...
rules, you know.
Clear, we cannot be too careful
yes?
Then the one what and what does make here, Frank?
And a beautiful part of the parents.
I like scenery.
Then of a good peep.
It can be her finishes time that sees her.
Does he/she equip him/it lost?
- Yes.
Again?
Again.
You know, we appeared and we tried,
and that and the most important. Certain, Chris?
He/she never worried about yours
capacity lack of
No, that doesn't worry me.
This ready one?
- Yes, ok.
Is he/she sure that we didn't need map?
Father, I know the area.
- Certain, certain, right.
Yes, but and exactamente same to alcohol and the beer.
- Yes, this and good argument.
Then and later?
I don't also want him to drink.
And legal in several states.
- But and illegal here.
But it could be.
- It is true but no and
Then never you did try?
I didn't say that.
I tried but I didn't like.
I didn't like the way as the people are.
They seem stupid.
The herb makes to seem stupid
and it reduces you QI.
Then you smoked more than I.
- Very funny.
I don't like that.
But than and that don't like
more exactamente?
I don't like to read
while I watch a film.
You become used to.
For you and easy.
You speak Spanish.
No so well,
I stopped reading the legends.
He/she admits, you don't simply want
to see a film in foreign language.
Yes, I, simply only want to see.
If you want to read, I buy a book.
Do Christ, help him/it?
Ei, you this to block the highway.
go!
He/she will sand you!
You are the sure that there is no alternative
for us to receive the money?
You and Davis go down.
Royko, liberates you of this.
I thought that these old bridges
they were built
over deep channels and you are worth.
You have been watching many films in TV.
Yes. Do you remember the "Crocodilo Dundee?"
There was an elephant
and he crossed...
Chris.
- What?
Come.
Help me!
I picked him/it!
I picked him/it.
I am polices federal.
My prisoner...
The keys...
it keeps an eye out for him.
My weapon.
He/she calls the service of the emergency.
Don't let to flee him.
Mister?
And a waste of time.
Does Carden have nine lives, did you know?
Can you point that thing for another place?
Chris.
Chris!
He/she already diffuses in your telephone
and league for the emergencies.
Be oh, gentleman.
Don't approach, don't approach.
He/she doesn't have net.
We will accompany this man ties the main street
there the telephone will work.
And what will do.
- Listen, it will be more intelligent if he/she lets to leave.
If it tries to take me,
both will die.
How?
-My men are me to proceed.
Former-members of the armed forks,
They will arrive here quickly.
Hear.
- Be far. Be far!
Let to leave.
Be here during one hour
and later go home.
And the best choice.
And the only choice.
Father, he is right.
Let to go him.
We have ourselves the weapon.
He won't make anything. He/she lets to go him.
He/she lets to think me.
Which his/her name, boy?
- Chris.
This well, Chris.
Let to leave.
You seem to be a good man.
Which his/her name?
Him and Ray.
- Ray.
You one don't want to see involved in this.
This goes for they haul of his/her capacity.
He/she said a wrong thing.
- What?
Now he will make that.
We will arise ties the main street.
Chris, you are behind me.
You, you had been my front
the whole road.
Good, we go.
Let us go.
Go.
Oh, My God.
Despachador...
Candidate disappeared.
- We will arrange other.
No and probable that he works alone.
- Of where and what did remove that idea?
We will eat lunch.
He/she tries to discover something.
Chris, gives me the telephone.
Continue to walk.
Fabulous.
I told you, and the end.
Carden still this sat down in the car...
...under it longs for.
Maybe.
Maybe?
Maybe not.
Three people were here.
One of them and woman,
maybe it is a child.
Balls, I hate mountaineering.
Father, we are close,
the parking and already there.
Chris, is going the front.
They have an I radiate and he/she asks them
to call her it polices.
Simply tell them that happened.
- That no and a good idea.
I didn't ask his/her opinion. Go.
He/she is going the front.
A car was misled the river close to
approximately to 800 meters of here.
That sounds badly.
- The current brought him/it, maybe have somebody inside.
If they help me, we will there be able to go.
And only the one measures in kilometers the jusante of here.
Did you communicate this?
- Yes, I communicated.
Chris?
Father!
- Father, they killed him/it!
They killed him/it, in the parking.
They killed him/it!
Chris, breathes bottom.
What did happen he/she?
Where and what him this now?
- They left.
Certainly they are close give.
- No this nobody here.
Wait, they must arrive oh.
And better.
Are you the sure of that?
It could be anybody, a couple of...
...homosexuals, lovers of the nature...
In the river? They are them.
I told him/her that this goes for there
of his/her capacity.
Well, he/she lets to think me.
We go there upward...
Are they their friends?
Well...
We are leaving in that direccao.
We go, in front.
Father, where and are we to go?
- We go for here.
Fast!
Faster.
They never arrived at the airport.
- Yes, that and what was me informed.
Do you think were them?
It could be.
And unlikely that have stopped
to eat and to drink.
What and what did make with them?
Where and what this Carden?
- He didn't arrive here.
He/she said that were three in the road.
- Yes, they were
They must have left the highway.
They must have seen us.
Concadin
he/she found some thing.
They went over there.
-He bring longs for, no and an explorer.
They were really here.
Didn't you see them?
Leave me alone, Davis.
-Balls, because and that he/she doesn't open the eyes.
We have ourselves a problem.
- Remain silent!
The driver of the carrinha communicated the accident,
We will have company.
This done the asneirada,
we should begin to walk
We have ourselves the day of payment to arrive.
- Yes.
They won't be very far.
We are going behind them.
Get rid of the carrinha.
- I make him/it.
Because?
I like to drive.
Does so much do?
Go.
Does it think will see him/it again?
- And who cares except we come him?
His greed will put upon to the rest.
I suppose that that means that
does he only want money, right?
Right. Let us go.
Faster, Chris.
In front.
Move.
And you, Davis?
- Yes, they walk the search of Carden.
Can you speak?
- Get rid of Carden.
What?
- Yes, he has to die, he/she noticed.
Can you make this?
- And possible, but no and easy.
Half million?
- How much?
You heard, half million.
Now he/she called me the attention.
Everything well.
Chris, this doesn't seem good.
Do you already know where go?
- Yes.
Of there part the navigation competition.
Is he/she the sure?
- Yes.
La has highways, restaurants,
"fastfood", coffee, something like that?
He/she has a road cuts near fire.
- Yes?
Yes, I arrived there first, before all.
- I serialize her
Hear, leave me here
and go straight ahead.
They will find me
and you will already have missing person.
No!
Father, you know what happened
in the parking?
They followed us and later...
- Yes, I know.
For our safety, you had been connosco.
Move.
How and what do you call her in any way?
- Carden, my name and Frank Carden.
I am really penitent
of having acquaintance.
Still no...
not yet.
We have a corpse, boss here.
And Danfield.
Done drown?
Drowned, they gave him/her a shot,
the legs broken choice.
I have a bad premonition that
his/her son this lost, Ray.
We are not lost.
We have to return.
Father, I didn't get lost.
We can go down ourselves of here.
Chris, we are not able to us, this and impossible.
- Father, really.
Don't discuss with me, Chris!
- Really, father, hear...
...Hear me at least once.
- Aggressive boy, Ray.
A road exists, you don't know him/it.
Me yes, right?
We are leaving in the trip.
Here this. And exactamente here.
Did he/she make this in the rain?
- No, but it was easy.
Once we begin
there are rifts in the rocks the feet and hands.
Well but it was tied to a rope.
And did he/she have an instructor, right?
Yes, but I am right that
we are capable to do this.
If he/she has the desire to die,
I know in a less painful way, Ray.
We will try.
I am not able to with these handcuffs.
If he/she tries to do some thing,
I will be behind...
And interest for God that I push you of the cliff.
What and what you and, does one police?
- I already went, now not.
I am physical education teacher.
- It should be a hard school.
Slowly, Chris, slowly!
Chris, this everything well?
- Yes.
I am well.
See, there in low!
Didn't they return?
No, or else we had seen them.
They went down.
I don't see as.
Right. I help him/it, I help him/it.
Is there a grotto there?
Ok.
This ready one?
We go, we Go, we Go.
Chris!
- Father! Father!
Hold him/it!
-Pull me.
- What was this?
- I think I heard some thing.
Search a rift.
I hold you.
He/she calms, Calm.
Let us go.
Hold him/it, Chris, hold him/it.
He already caught you.
Ok.
Do Chris, help me? Fast!
Stop! They can stop!
Release my father.
Feel the weapon.
No.
Any track of Gardner?
No, only of the two agents.
A still this inside.
Yes. Well, thank you.
Who and that such of Gardner?
Everything that I know and that him and a lot
important for the people of the capital.
Does he/she think him and a terrorist?
- No, I doubt.
He seems a normal person.
Yes, but those types also
they seem normal, as well as us.
To me, maybe,
but no as normal as you.
I will tell him/her a thing.
- What?
If we take advantage istos,
our pictures will appear in the newspapers.
An enlarged plan of the car.
It is then pass for a closed plan.
I am back
Where and what are you, clowns?
40.083 east.
25.55 west.
Ok.
He/she has to carry well
I won't return them to remove again.
I cannot blame myself of
to have tried this.
You have a lot of fork for an old one.
Training soldierly.
Which and does yours recount?
Because and what do they want him/it?
They picked me to smoke at a restaurant.
They consider that a lot a thing
it would be nowadays, he/she knows.
Who are the people behind us?
Friends.
They are not their friends.
Then you and a physical education teacher?
Yes.
It is also trains basebol and basket in the Winter.
- Truth?
I adore basebol.
Then, what did you make exactamente, gentleman?
Honestly.
I am an exterminator.
Exterminator? How? Termites?
No totally.
I am contracted to eliminate...
We called this of...
...To eliminate obstacles to the progress.
Obstacles to the progress.
Then and simply a mercenary?
Who doesn't import he/she exterminates?
Without limits.
I still didn't find none.
Him this to speak to her serializes, no and, father?
- No, him this to say nonsenses.
I picked him/it to lie.
I don't know...
He avoided that I fell.
It was simply a reflex.
No and I need to be sentimental with that.
I won't be sentimental with that.
I think I know than and capable.
A stop for a picnic.
No, we lost their track.
Is he/she the sure that you/they passed for here?
Without he/she doubts that I am sure.
Tomorrow all police them of the state
they will be here.
He/she polices federal and that treta.
They will roll all of the stones to meet.
Which and the problem, Royko?
Do you want to give up?
I don't know, I don't know.
Johnson?
I think tomorrow of guile encounter the tracks.
All know ourselves what wants to do.
I think should continue.
We go find them.
That and a change, Davis.
What does happen he/she?
Delicious and extensive money.
And that.
We will give him/her an opportunity.
Of picking the track tomorrow.
Who and Wayne Write?
- I am me.
Chuck Robbins, polices federal.
- How does it go?
Gordon Jennings.
- Gwen Miles of Washington, DC.
Gwen Miles.
Does he/she already have some thing for us?
my boys found tracks.
- What species of tracks?
Three people that left the river.
Where Stanfield was found.
Carden?
- Possibly.
And the other ones two.
I forgot about my crystal ball.
- Thank you, sergeant.
Gentlemen, the place of the crime and of FBI.
Thank you.
What? - If and this what the one wants?
- This and what wants.
The federal ones will treat of the search.
Then only they leave us the work of
go look for coffee.
It will be fabulous if you got some.
Double express, without sugar.
Two.
FBI.
Don't that say loud?
Or else they will be to think that are an idiot.
Chris, wakes up. Chris?
Let to sleep him.
What time is it, six of the guile?
We have to go.
I am with cramps.
- I am sad with this, Frank.
Did he/she drink the coffee of the guile?
What does think this about Hilton?
I told him/her that he/she doesn't make sense to return here.
They turned off the track.
Would not he/she find them?
- Maybe not.
Jesus, if it was not the picnic,
they would be already in our hands.
Because and what do find that?
- Because I would not lose them.
Can I shoot in him?
- Not yet.
Ei, Davis, no there is none
competition here.
You would not have any hypothesis.
Balls. They slept here.
They went down of here.
Carden can be
anywhere.
It also ties to be dead.
Don't have illusions in relation to Frank Carden.
- Why not?
They don't pretend to be always correctos.
- What does have that?
Don't you know him/it, yes?
Personal files of him.
- And?
The Service of Military Information protects him/it.
I eat like this, a murderer...
- He didn't give pizzas.
Without expressed.
Sugar.
Milk.
Repugnant?
- Repugnant.
Donuts?
- No.
Thank you.
Pardon.
- Come La.
What does the one know and more deplorable in this everything?
- What?
Clue Costa Leste,
the coffee no this good one and only sugar.
Then, why and what the carden this here?
The President of the United States
Woodburn arrives tomorrow.
He/she thinks the President and the objective.
- Maybe.
Because not?
Good, then they want to kill the President.
-These to play?
He/she continues, Chris.
They will return, don't worry.
They didn't count with that.
- Because not?
My men already notice his/her mistake.
They should not be very far away from us.
One of them and a professional explorer
he/she trained the aborigenes of Australia.
Frank.
- Do you know these native ones?
Frank, remain silent.
Do you play chess in one moment of these?
- I have to win this.
Women's game.
Finally we agreed
with some thing, Davis.
We leave.
- He/she calms, we go pick us them.
A thing and right. Frank will find
the means for delaying.
Is there how long and teacher?
- There are no many years.
It should be good in that.
- More or less, I find.
This and truth, Chris?
He thinks that yes, him and very demanding.
- We will stop.
Wait for a little.
Water.
Do you want?
- Yes.
Did his/her wife die from cancer?
Yes.
Two years ago.
I feel a lot.
Do I serialize her? And difficult to believe in that.
I don't know because.
Because?
Because of my profession?
Maybe.
Chris.
Receive medals for the
does my work, believe in that?
Now?
- No, now with the politically correcto.
And better to have a smaller profile.
The heroes are old-fashioned.
This to say that and a spy?
You and a soldier to work for CIA,
no and that?
In the past, now not.
- No.
For who he/she does work?
I sincerely don't know, Ray.
Special groups, people with a calendar,
people that have money for such.
And to you he/she doesn't worry about anything, right?
In the course of time you will understand that.
...some subjects are very complicated.
Naturally.
- The one that and certain, which and wrong.
However, you simply
he/she tries to do his/her work.
And you make the best than it can,
as well as everyone.
Ok, and best go walking.
And very late for me to change.
What and what can I make?
I don't know, Frank.
We are going ahead.
In front.
- Broker of safe?
I don't care, Frank.
Maybe study again and obtain him/it
my diploma.
Ei, what and what these to do?
I grew and I saw...
- Can we get more helicopters?
I already made the request. No and like this so simple,
Mr. Jennings.
Here no and Washington DC.
This and the state of Washington.
That and even truth.
I don't believe in anything of that.
In every case we don't have to do anything with that.
He/she didn't also have to do anything
connosco 24 hours ago.
I said that should have gone to Sao Francisco.
To visit your mother?
What and what did he make?
I don't know, but something ran badly.
And it comes men behind us for this road.
More is worth to go in that direccao.
- You go where wants.
And us through where want.
And when we come polices her will do complaint.
I don't want to see me involved in this.
We go, Sam.
I think this and a mistake.
He didn't say that those men
they would come on that side.
How will we know if that and truth?
How will we know that no and?
We are us here. One exists is worth or something like that.
When they arrive there, they will be been hit.
Maybe exist a bridge.
- In agreement with this map, not.
Who has Carden,
he/she also knows the area, very well.
Or else we had already picked them.
We have to think in something fast,
or else we lost them.
Then, what suggests?
Whose was the idea of go camp?
Do you think me planeei to find these crazy ones?
To excite still more the trip?
If we were in Sao Francisco
we would have coffee of the guile in the bed,
Tennis the afternoon, several cocktails
Yes, and much more...
A lot of plates of the sea.
- Yes.
And wine.
Boss?
Yes, continue.
We have here some thing.
- Yes, what and?
Excuse, alarm false, they are two mountaineers
that are to do a walk.
He/she seems that one of them this hurt.
- Will it verify and does he/she tell me some thing, ok?
Understood.
This certain friend, be calm.
I help you here...
Helicopter 4, this hearing?
Marty, these hearing me?
Marty, speech!
Helicopter 4, Marty in the he/she listens?
Marty, these to hear me?
You are not going me to say now that
don't you know how to fly with this thing?
No, I don't know.
Already enter in the helicopter.
The best road?
The road no chosen.
Does he/she like to walk, Ray?
Yes.
I am also surprised, I don't think to be his/her style.
Yes, and one of my favorite ones.
I choose the less known highway.
And this makes all the difference.
Many roads, Frank exist,
and you seem to find the wrong ones
This and the right moment to discuss poetry?
What ray and this?
This was created by an old glacier.
It was what was me dictated in the it finishes time.
This calls her "the brunettes."
- Porreiro.
Stones that deteriorated in the era of the ice were.
Him this certain, they are "brunet", this and the word.
If I don't do this, do they kill me, no and?
There is a great chance.
I think that yes.
I cannot make this with the handcuffs.
And necessary to have balance.
Ok.
But you can the for in front.
Father.
- Yes.
I only want to say that feel a lot.
I went me that offered the trip to camp.
Yes, but it was because I acted
in a stupid way...
The situation could be worse.
- Do you find?
Actually, not.
Carden, stop!
Chris, if he moves,
I want that point his leg and shoot.
- Only one moment.
I don't want to kill the bastard.
I only want to delay him/her the speed.
I think this thing this very destroyed.
Can you help?
- No, I won't destroy properties publish.
Almighty God!
- I am a broker.
I can lose my license.
- He/she goes, it helps him/it!
Let us go.
Ok. What?
You will do this side and me
I will do here in low.
Yes, totally free. You this ready one?
Chris, this everything well? - Yes.
A...
Two...
Down.
I don't need to help.
I am the bad of the ribbon.
Two... Three!
Push.
We picked them.
Ei, Ei!
Here, light this.
What? - Watch him.
Here! Come here!
Come here! Us, here!
To the front, fast!
Here we are us!
- Come here!
Pick the man with the weapon.
- Don't fail.
Elderly good-bye.
He/she thinks of the to stabilize this thing.
I am trying, but the air in the group upward.
Chris, goes for you hoist them.
Bow!
We will leave of here immediately.
We have to continue!
You this well?
I don't have a good angle to shoot of here.
I solve this.
Find a place to leave me.
I picked him/it
- Good work!
I hate amateurs.
Jesus.
- I thought that he had eliminated him/it.
Where and what him this?
The nut broke the back rotor.
We will leave of here.
Let us go!
He/she is not able to place him/it.
I don't get control him/it.
Where did he/she learn how to fly?
In Disneylandia?
What was that he/she said?
- Oh, My God!
Already remove that of here.
The mother's Filho!
Father.
One moment, and Duffin?
We have to return for taking.
We are not able to.
I saw them in the helicopter.
We are not able to leave him/it to us there.
It is impossible help him/it now,
and this can seem insensitive but...
...you two didn't seem to be happy.
Chris.
Come.
That incredible talent of destroying everything, Frank.
Lift that ass.
Walk!
The scouring pad and it stretches out are him to arrive.
I take this.
Here this.
- I don't want more coffee, he/she discovered some thing.
Nobody in the city heard some thing.
I have some information.
And on the helicopter that disappeared and the pilot.
He fell.
- Yes?
But no this there nobody and
we don't also see bodies.
And possible to cover with earth to verify?
He said that no there is where to cover with earth.
And a difficult place, Sr. Jennings.
Now that we lost him/it, we needed Clark.
I order personal,
but this will take some time.
That to the rhythm of the field, boss?
Balls, excuse me, Mr. Jennings.
He/she knows, the personnel of the forests and an awkward mouthful.
-Caracas.
Do see?
- Does he/she have a telephone?
Yes, and where slept before we will row.
Let us go.
Ok.
The line this without sign.
- What?
Chris, you said that there was a telephone.
- He/she has a telephone...
I feel a lot, but he/she didn't know that was not
to work in this station.
OK.
For bed. - What?
- We go, Frank!
Are you new in this?
Where are the boats, Chris?
- They are not there!
I feel a lot, father
still no and time.
What will make now, Ray?
- I don't have idea none.
For me it arrives.
I need to rest.
I thought this it was good.
After all an amateur put an end to him.
Without he/she doubts, he only had luck.
Even in a dark rift
he would find squirrels.
If we don't find Carden it ties tomorrow,
we will lose the contract.
What and what was you sent? An e-mail?
- Maybe something so good.
See this, we are to arrive at the end.
Be with this.
What?
- Me... Ray?
For God's sake!
- Ray!
What do you think he/she did?
- What does think this and a game?
He/she thinks and a rodeo
and what you and a national hero?
You and a teacher, for God's sake!
Open the eyes!
Chris, speak to his/her father.
Try do him/it to understand.
Maybe he hears him/it.
Do you think like this?
- Yes.
Funny, I never thought
that he heard me.
Do hear, what and what do you want?
What do I convince him free her/it him?
Yes, something like that.
Yes, but what had avoided yours
friends of to come here and to kill us.
No, that won't happen.
He/she has my word.
It has been very effective stop her/it them
it ties Frank now.
Balls.
- What did go now he/she?
Inside of this thing he/she only has classic music.
I knew that some thing was not well with him.
Are you the sure of the one what this to do?
- Shut up and continue to walk.
Did he/she know that this and funny?
Home we were more or less separate.
His idea of we camp was that
we were together one of the other.
I dislike to camp.
He knew about this.
The forests are beautiful, but me...
...I don't simply want to sleep in them.
I want a service of rooms.
- Right.
Mini-bar.
- Yes.
What and what do you make?
Do you know, in the real world?
I produce commercial announcements for TV.
- That and excellent.
Did you already meet some advertising one?
- No.
They are of the worst.
- Yes?
I don't make the low idealizes
of as it uses this thing, Ray.
No there is a lot what to speak.
Simply appear and pull the trigger.
Ray.
Ray!
They will wait for the darkness,
I will make him/her mine finishes offer.
Remove me the handcuffs.
And let to break before the fire to begin.
Practice in him.
This very darkness, boss.
Continue a little more and later return.
- It can have faith.
Did you and his/her father camp frequently?
No, nor for that.
I think us...
we are to create bows
Don't say anything else...
Maybe be wrong.
- No, they are there.
Ei, wait for my sign.
Chris. Ei, Chris.
We only want Carden!
Frank, everything well?
Yes, I am well.
Feel Carden and we left them alone.
Last hypothesis.
Surrender Carden.
You this alone one, Ray.
The choice and yours.
Think about his/her son, in his/her wife.
You don't need to prove anything,
you already made this.
I am convinced.
Be careful, son.
No!
Roy!
Royko, Royko!
Quiet.
- Balls.
Bow.
Chris? Chris!
Father!
Father! Father!
Place the weapon!
Place her
I take the boy, Ray.
- Father.
If he/she wants to return her see him/it alive, don't come behind me.
- Father!
I am to leave!
- Father.
Hear, if you ask help,
to scream or to try to flee...
Do I break you the neck, did he/she understand?
- Yes.
Don't think that I am a good person.
No, he/she hears. This will have to be like this.
If the White House interferes,
you will be involved in this...
He/she already said that I treat of this.
I was informed that the President
he/she had not changed their plans.
They don't want to change anything.
We have to use ours
resources for protecting.
But, Carden had tried to execute
with firmness his/her purpose.
But he lost previously
all his/her team.
He has the contract, it had tried to accomplish him/it.
Him and a person that he/she acts like this.
- How and what does that know?
We already worked with him in the past.
And on the boy?
- What boy?
The boy that he took with him.
Chris... or something like that.
Our main objectivo and to protect the president.
- Sr. Yen, Ray Iene.
Ray Iene, his/her son was taken as hostage.
- Naturally.
What and what this to do to find my son?
Sr. Yen, we are us his/her son's search,
we are to do the possible ones.
There is his possibility to die.
I know him/it as and difficult for itself.
This everything in order?
Everything well?
You know, Ray,
we will make everything to be within our reach.
But most of my personnel was moved away
because of the President in Woodburn.
But after this...
I don't believe that you have failed.
I want Carden to disappear.
I don't want him to go back to Washington.
I don't want him to speak to anybody.
- I understood.
It is if the son is alive,
knife with that seems that Carden has him/it dead.
The boy's father and Ray Reene.
Only God knows what Carden told him/her.
Him no and a professional?
He didn't tell him/her anything.
We cannot take risks.
Everything turns off.
Davis, be not disappointed.
Ei, what does it seem?
I only ask that, because for the sound
I think sexy
Apposed that has a great tail
I don't believe that have gone back to Washington.
With Miles and impossible to know.
Seemingly she thinks he/she made everything that was able to.
No and everyday that the President
he/she visits this part of the parents.
And somebody that is somebody of here
he/she will be present here today.
And possible that the President receives criticize...
for the reductions done by his/her administration
in the budget of the education
We will see him work with this in the interview colectiva.
Now with you, Bob.
Thank you, Diana.
It is now announce them places.
Lydel senior Hammond, the lonely billionaire...
he/she had attended his/her son's funeral, later...
and their comments regarding the researches
you inform of the government...
he/she became, second spokesperson of the White House,
an obstacle to the progress.
His/her son Hammond Jr
he/she died in the week passed in a tragic one...
car accident, far away from house.
Yes, lieutenant Evens.
Certain, only feel one minute.
I will be seen the encounter.
Excuse me, only one minute.
- Yes, what and what if this to pass?
Ray Iene this in the telephone.
- Yes?
He says that the President no and the objective.
He wants to speak with you.
He doesn't simply believe,
this tired and concerned.
He/she tells him/her that am not.
The President no and the objective?
Jesus!
Ray, I don't get to find him/it.
I later call of turn.
Carden!
You don't leave a man
to do his/her work, yes?
Where and what this Chris?
- I am busy.
I have the work to conclude, later we spoke.
- Where and what this my son?
Filho of the...
Who was?
- Did anybody shoot?
In me?
- No, in me.
Was it her polices?
- I believe that he/she was my friend.
His/her friend?
He actually sold her.
Be with the head in low.
Jesus said: "I am the resurrection and the life."
"That that to believe in me had lived, same to die."
"And that that to continue alive believing
in me... ...he/she had never died."
Smart?
I had the perfect curriculum
it ties today.
Where this my son, Frank?
I know that didn't hurt him/it.
Do you think that?
- Yes.
Where this my son?
Chris!
Good, I will count ties three.
This everything well?
- I am well.
This here a drought.
He put TV in the economy channel.
Certain, right.
Gwen, without caffeine with milk.
Do excuse me, this and yours?
The purpose, if there is something with Ray Reene...
...or with his/her son...
I came behind itself.
It can count with that!
The hero in this amazing case and Ed Dwayner.
Boss of it Polices and local inhabitant.
How and what did you know where Chris was?
Well, I am not authorized
to expose my informant.
But after so many years in that
you and the responsible,
It creates contacts in the city and it wins the trust...
of the community's inhabitants.
Did I hear to speak in a possible promotion, this and correcto?
Well, yes, leaning in running for office in the
municipal election next year.
Congratulations.
Here you have.
- Thank you.
Everything well?
- Yes, and you?
Thank you for the invitation.
- With certainty.
Barbecue...
...and the close than want to be of the field.
Support that declaration.
He just invited you because he/she doesn't know how to cook.
You cannot speak about that, and a family secret.
Good, I thought that could be
for a different reason.
I will look for you a plate, he/she waits for a little.
- Thank you.
WKGB 104. These are them announce of 14 o'clock.
The death of the billionaire Lydel Hammond was communicated...
in a tragic accident of cruise in the holiday in the island Wypee.
Coincidentally, his/her son Lydel Jr had an accident...
two weeks ago behind.
Lydel was seen as a controversial illustration
His opinions, on many subjects
they were consider extreme...