Wu.
You and your brothers
murdered three of our men.
He would have done the same.
Send three more and l'll kill them, too.
He already controls the opium trade
all across Asia.
May no one prosper but Ying Ko?
My poppy fields are tiny.
Nothing compared to his.
l, Li Peng, at least l'm entitled
to my little piece.
Ying Ko, if you kill me, l promise...
...my brothers will come for you.
And l promise you...
...l'll bury them beside you.
Kill him.
Let me go. l only wish to leave.
l'll cut his throat.
Your men are not marksmen enough
to shoot around him.
You're right.
Wu, you are a wonderful friend.
-Like a father to me.
-Thank you, Ying Ko.
Shoot through him.
Where are you taking me?
A Tulku wishes to see you at his temple.
A holy man wants to see me?
-You call that a temple?
-No.
There.
Where did that come from?
The clouded mind sees nothing.
-Who are you?
-l am your teacher.
Do you have any idea
who you just kidnapped?
Cranston.
Lamont Cranston.
You know my real name?
Yes.
l also know that for as long
as you can remember...
...you struggled against your own
black heart and always lost.
You watched your spirit,
your very face, change...
...as the beast claws its way out
from within you.
You are in great pain, aren't you?
You know what evil lurks
in the hearts of men...
...for you have seen that evil in your heart.
Every man pays the price for redemption.
This is yours.
-l'm not looking for redemption.
-You have no choice.
You will be redeemed...
...because l will teach you to use
your black shadow to fight evil.
l wouldn't do that.
Phurba.
Phurba!
Am l in hell?
Not yet.
Get him, Johnny.
Maxie.
-Let's get this over with.
-Get out.
-No!
-Come on!
-Please, l didn't see anything.
-Quit your whining.
-ls it dry?
-Please.
-Perfect, Duke.
-Bring him to the rail.
l won't tell anyone. l swear.
Geez.
l wish l could trust you, sport. l really do.
l guess you just picked the wrong alley
to look down.
-l have a family.
-They'll get over it.
l won't talk. l'm telling you.
l know you won't.
Dump him.
-No. No!
-l hate heavy lifting.
No!
-What in Christ was that?
-Who's there?
Show yourself.
-You murdered a policeman, Duke.
-Who said that?
Duke, who said that?
-Shut up!
-The weed of crime bears bitter fruit.
l don't like this. This stinks.
Let's get the hell outta here!
-Shut your hole, Maxie!
-Did you think you'd get away with it?
Come on, Duke!
Did you think l wouldn't know?
Duke, l think you got him.
You're damn right l....
You committed murder, Duke.
-Now you're going to confess to it.
-Like hell l will.
You will, because ifyou don't, l'll be there.
l'll be there, around every corner...
...in every empty room, as inevitable as
your guilty conscience.
You don't scare me, you son of a--
You will go to the eighth precinct house
on Second Avenue...
...and surrender yourself,
and you will do it now.
l confess! l'll do it!
Oh, my God!
l'll confess! For God's sake,
l don't wanna die.
No!
No! No!
Drive!
Thank you.
You are probably busy.
You can just drop me off anywhere--
You're Dr. Roy Tam, a professor
in the Science Department at N.Y.U.
-Yes.
-l've saved your life, Roy Tam.
-lt now belongs to me.
-lt does?
You'll become one of my agents...
...like dozens of others all over the world.
Could l ask my wife about this?
No!
Mr. Shrevnitz here will instruct you...
...in the way in which l will contact you
should l require your help.
When you hear one of my agents say,
''The sun is shining''...
...you will respond,
''But the ice is slippery.''
This will identify you to each other.
Do you understand?
''The sun is shining.''
''But the ice is slippery.''
Tell me one thing.
How did you know
what was happening to me?
How did you know who l am?
The Shadow knows.
Thank you. That's the Shadow!
-l mean, that's the Shadow!
-You're a pretty smart guy.
l heard rumors in the paper, on the radio.
But l thought it was just talk.
l didn't think he existed.
He doesn't. Get it?
Don't ever take it off.
Wait a minute. Who are you?
Somebody who owes him his life.
Somebody just like you.
Boss, you okay?
The Cobalt Club.
Sorry l'm late, Uncle Wainwright,
but there was a little...
...accident on the bridge.
l didn't think you wanted me to wait.
lncidentally, try the prime rib.
lt's excellent.
Your usual, Mr. Cranston.
-Thank you very much.
-You're welcome.
You know, Lamont,
l'm very upset with you.
-What is it this time?
What is it every time?
You ask me to dinner
and show up an hour late.
-There's no excuse--
-Uncle Wainwright, l'm sorry, l...
...l got caught up.
With what, for God's sake?
You don't do anything.
A man your age is unseemly.
At least pick a hobby or something.
Why am l talking to the back of your neck?
Lamont? Lamont?
Sorry. What were we talking about?
l've never meddled in your affairs,
going back to the time...
...after the war when you disappeared
for some seven years.
l never asked questions then. l'm not now.
Excuse me, Police Commissioner Barth.
Urgent message for you, sir.
What's the matter?
Cops and robbers business slowing down?
lt's a report of that damned
Shadow character again.
You said he was only a rumor.
l'm sick of this Shadow business,
his meddling in police affairs.
This time tomorrow,
l'll put a task force on him.
You're not going to appoint a task force.
No. Hell with him.
l'm not going to appoint a task force.
You're not going to pay any attention
to these reports of the Shadow.
-lgnore them entirely.
-There is no Shadow.
There is no Shadow.
lf there were, l'd be Eleanor Roosevelt.
Where was l?
You were about to tell me who she is.
That's Margo Lane.
Her father is a scientist working
for the War Department.
What the hell do you see in her?
Uncle Wainwright,
are you sure you're not dead?
Not by a long shot.
Send a bottle of Mouton Rothschild, 1928,
to that table.
Do yourself a favor. Stay away from her.
She's strange.
She hears voices. That's what they say.
Really?
Yes, l would like a glass of the Mouton--
Rothschild, 1928.
-Yes.
-From the gentleman.
Gentleman?
Lamont Cranston.
May l sit?
You know...
...it's the strangest thing, but l have this...
...sudden craving for Peking duck.
That's so odd.
l was thinking the exact same thing.
Care to join me?
You speak Chinese.
Only Mandarin.
Aren't you full of surprises?
Thank you. l'm glad you like it.
-l had it made at Adrian's.
-Why did you just tell me that?
You just complimented me
on my dress just now.
Didn't you?
No, l didn't.
But l was thinking it.
Now that hasn't happened to me
in a long time.
Since l was a little girl with my cousin,
l could hear what he was thinking.
Just pick the thoughts right out
of his head before he said a word.
lt was the strangest thing.
And l never was able....
ls something bothering you?
Oh! No.
Not at all.
Thank you. l had a wonderful time.
l'm not sure l can recall an evening as...
...stimulating.
Good night, Miss Lane.
Good night, Mr. Cranston.
l like her, boss.
She's different than your usual dames.
-More than even she knows.
-How's that?
She has abilities
she's completely unaware of.
No kidding?
You gonna see her again?
-No, it's much too dangerous.
-Dangerous for who?
For me, Moe.
For me.
Someone's coming.
-What is it?
-That's just it, sir. l don't know.
l'd have labeled it a mummy case
coming from Tibet like it did.
-Mummy cases come from Egypt.
-That's right. Exactly.
Besides, the thing is metal, which
made me think it was a sarcophagus.
No. Tibetan sarcophagi were of stone.
What happened to the truck men
who dropped it off?
Gone.
lt's obviously an incorrect shipment.
Call our customs broker and....
My God!
This is beautiful!
This is solid silver.
Nelson, help us take the sides off.
-What does it say?
-lt's Latin.
''Kha Khan dei potestas in terra....''
''The power of God on Earth...''
''...the seal of the emperor of mankind.''
Oh, my God!
Temujin.
This is the silver coffin of Temujin.
Who's Temujin?
The man who very nearly conquered
the globe eight centuries ago.
How come l never heard of him?
Temujin was the birth name...
...of Genghis Khan.
What was the shipper's address?
lt didn't say.
Label just had the country of origin.
Let me make a telephone call.
Let me help you.
Nelson, whatever you do...
...don't open it.
No, sir.
-We're closed.
-Join me...
...or die.
Excuse me?
Join me or die.
This is private property.
-Your mind is weak.
-Don't come any closer.
Fall to your knees.
Put your gun to your temple.
Sacrifice yourself...
...to me.
Yes, my Khan.
Oh, my God!
l can't believe it.
We were only gone for a moment.
You didn't hear me, did you?
l'm through with the beryllium sphere.
l'm just doing some underwater tests
to check pressure.
Farley, l have told you a dozen times,
we are doing energy research.
l'm not interested in any military
application of the project.
Why'd you let the War Department
pay all the bills?
'Cause you talked me into it.
l just wanted enough money to finish.
Dr. Lane, you don't think big.
lf you'd only listen to me,
the world could be our oyster.
Oysters? l get a rash from oysters.
Oh! Margo.
What a beautiful dress.
And such a clever neckline.
Excuse me, Mr. Claymore,
l'd like to see my father.
So...
...when are you gonna come down
and see my beryllium sphere?
l'm not interested in your spheres.
Margo.
You don't return my calls anymore.
That's not true.
-l never did return your calls.
-l know.
l can't imagine why.
lt's because l don't like you.
What a fascinating woman!
Dad, l don't know how you can
work with that man.
Margo!
What a nice surprise.
-Hi.
-Have you had your dinner?
Yes, Dad. lt's 2:00 a.m.
Where did you get this shirt?
You said l look good in green.
No, this is green. That's red.
Red, green.
To me, it's just a clean shirt.
Dad?
Do you believe in telepathy?
l mean, do you believe that
it can exist between certain people?
You mean mind reading?
Of course l don't. l'm a scientist.
So strange.
l've always had this feeling
that there was this...
...indescribable connection out there...
...just waiting for me.
And suddenly tonight, there it was.
That's nice.
What was it?
lt was a man.
And l'm probably
never gonna see him again.
But why not?
l just know.
lt was as though l could sense
what he was feeling.
And now l'm completely
and utterly depressed.
That's nice.
Okay, that'll be $4.45.
-What are you doing?
-Writing down the drop-off point.
You are making a record
of my destination?
Taxi commission's rules.
All right, Reilly, back her up.
That's it.
You need fuel.
Geez, l need gas.
Cut left. That's it.
Hey, thanks.
Look out!
This must be my lucky--
Call an ambulance!
Scott, you all right?
Hey, stay back! Stay back!
Help over here!
What's going on?
lnspector Cardon is in charge, sir.
He's over there.
Hey, what are you, crazy?
-Out!
-Thank you.
To the sanctum.
Go!
Come on, what are you gonna do,
park it here? Come on!
Hey, Louie, save that cab for me!
-Report.
-Our agent in the 26th precinct...
...reports police investigation of murder
at the Museum of Natural History.
Murder.
Agent advises inquiry.
Understood.
l saw you as taller.
Who are you?
Shiwan Khan.
Last descendant of Genghis Khan.
You are naturally deeply honored.
Don't feel obligated to introduce yourself.
l already know who you are.
Not this temporary version of yourself.
l know who you really are.
Ying Ko.
l'm a great admirer.
l don't know what you're talking about.
Please.
lt is no more difficult for me
to invade your mind than it was this room.
May l sit?
You are hurting my feelings, Ying Ko.
l should have thought you would enjoy
to meet another...
...with the unique ability
to cloud men's minds.
-You were a student of the Tulku.
-Yes.
He spoke of you constantly.
But l'm afraid he wasn't able to
turn me quite as easily.
Would you happen to have
some American bourbon?
l have a bit of a taste for it.
-l'm happy to pay, of course.
-No.
Not at all.
Say, you didn't happen by any chance to...
...pay a visit to the museum
last night, did you?
A wonderful collection
of Tibetan tapestries.
Grown men still shiver at your name.
You are, l have to confess, my idol.
Your raid on the village of Barga?
l studied it.
How nice. You remember it.
lt rings a bell.
lt was a masterstroke.
Swift, vicious, and sudden.
What genius.
So, what brings you to the Big Apple?
My destiny.
Genghis Khan conquered half of the world
in his lifetime.
l intend to finish the job.
And how do you plan to do that?
lf l told you, it wouldn't be a surprise.
l traveled to this country
in Genghis Khan's holy crypt...
...to absorb his power.
ln three days,
the entire world will hear my roar...
...and willingly fall subject
to the lost empire of Sianking.
That is a lovely tie, by the way.
-May l ask where you acquired it?
-Brooks Brothers.
-ls that Midtown?
-45th and Madison.
You are a barbarian.
Thank you.
We both are.
l know that inside you beats
a heart of darkness.
You dip into it every time
you put on that hat and cloak.
Join me.
You are Ying Ko, the Butcher of Lhasa.
You and only you deserve to be
by my side.
Together, we'll pit armies against
one another like a chess game.
We'll collect our due of pain
and we'll wash our hands in blood.
Your mouth still waters at real power.
l am offering you a chance to take it back.
Be my partner, Ying Ko.
That's not my name anymore.
But it is! Nevertheless,
still who you are, isn't it?
For the bourbon.
We will meet again, soon.
The day of the Mongol warrior...
...is once again at hand.
Soon, with wings outstretched...
...we fly to our destiny!
Good morning, Mr. and Mrs. America.
Flash: Manhattan reels from yet
another report of the elusive Shadow.
l think they made up the Shadow
so people would listen to the radio more.
What do you think, Roy?
Some say the Shadow is....
Roy?
Well, it....
l'll get it.
Yes?
''The sun is shining.''
''But the ice is slippery.''
-You're an agent of the Shadow.
-Who?
Yeah. Right. Gotcha.
What do you need?
l need a metal analysis of this.
Bronzium.
The metal is bronzium.
l didn't think it existed, but here it is.
The ancient Chinese believed this was
the very stuff the universe was formed of.
-Where did it come from?
-l'm told it came from Sianking.
lf you believed in legends,
it had to be Sianking.
They called it the birthplace of the world.
Could bronzium conceivably be used
to make some sort of a weapon?
Theoretically, yes.
How?
Supposedly, it's very unstable
on the molecular level...
...constantly given to expansion.
Only the cell bonds hold it in check,
but if the bonds were ever breached.
-By an explosion?
-lt wouldn't do it.
But if the power of the cell were
to turn on itself in an implosion...
...the molecular imbalance will be released
and then you'll have your explosion.
How big?
No man can say.
The breakdown would spread to all levels
of the cells' atomic construction.
Fashioned into a bomb,
it would be catastrophic.
l guess you'd call it an implosive-explosive
submolecular device.
Or an atomic bomb.
Hey, that's catchy.
But it'd have to have a beryllium sphere
to contain the apparatus.
No other metal would enhance a blast.
ln any case, it's all moot.
None of this would be possible...
...unless...
...some genius figures out how
to design and make it.
The implosive device.
lt would have to be sort of a shell...
...with tiny implosive charges
regularly spread over the surface.
Something like this.
Fortunately...
...such a device doesn't exist.
Reinhardt Lane.
Yes, my Khan.
You know something, Lamont,
that puzzles me?
How a man like yourself
who has absolutely nothing to do...
...can be late for every little engagement.
Practice, Uncle Wainwright.
Lots and lots of practice.
Waiter, get me some more chives,
would you, please?
Oh, my God, here comes that Lane woman.
l don't need her anymore, l--
-Hi, Miss Lane. How are you?
-You can drop the act, Commissioner.
-What have you done about my father?
-Nothing we can do unless--
Unless what? He blows himself up?
Margo Lane, my nephew, Lamont Cranston.
Yes, we've met.
Would you care to join us?
The fact that your father
is acting strangely...
...l don't think really calls for
a police investigation.
l wanna see him.
The War Department says...
...he suddenly decided to take no visitors,
not even his own daughter.
Chances are he's working
on some top secret.
-lt is a government project, you know.
-No, his project is harmless.
Energy research.
Some kind of implosive device.
Look, l know something's wrong.
l spoke to him on the phone.
He was distant, confused, babbling.
He spoke to me in Chinese!
Waiter, waiter.
-He doesn't even speak Chinese!
-l'm sorry, please.
Tomorrow, l'll send a policeman
over to the federal building.
He'll see your father
and everything'll be fine, all right?
What's your opinion....
Excuse me.
Lamont!
Wait a second, Lamont.
l wanted to ask you about my father.
l have to go.
Ying Ko! Who's Ying Ko?
You will forget about me.
-Why would l do that?
-You will give me no further thought.
Are you drunk?
l don't know what kind of woman
you're used to dealing with...
...but l don't appreciate being--
Hey!
The federal building.
You got it, boss.
-Pizza?
-Yuck.
l'm not going to eat a burger again.
l'm not asking you to eat a burger.
-You like fish?
-How about a burger?
Next time, you get to be on top.
-Where is Khan?
-l will not tell you.
What are you doing?
Hold on or you'll die!
Yes, to serve my Khan.
l sense somebody's coming.
Drive!
-Hello?
-Hello, Margo.
Dad.
-Are you all right?
-l'm fine.
l need to see you right away at the lab.
Are you there now?
Hurry.
No, no, no!
Oh, God! Dad!
Dad! Where are you?
Oh, God, no!
Margo Lane.
l have a mission for you, my dear.
-What are you doing here?
-You're in my home.
l am? Your home?
-What are you doing here?
-l don't know.
-Who sent you?
-l don't know!
There was a voice over and over
in my head.
lt said l had to kill the Shadow.
l want you to leave right now.
l had to kill the Shadow and l came here.
l said l want you to leave right now.
And there was only you.
Get out!
Let me see into your eyes.
-You want to see into my eyes?
-l think--
-Go ahead. Look at them.
-l know something l knew before.
Something strange about you.
l could feel it.
But l've got to warn you.
You won't like what you see.
The static in my head
whenever l was near you. l knew it.
You're the Shadow!
My father's disappeared. You're
the only one who can help me find him.
Just be gone when l get back.
How do you know l won't tell anyone
who you really are?
l know.
To the sanctum.
-Nice tie.
-Thank you.
By the way...
...you sent Margo Lane to kill me.
Kill you?
lf l wanted you dead, Ying Ko,
l would've had your liver on a pole by now.
l sent the girl to be killed.
Tell me how did you kill her?
-She's alive.
-Then she's a danger to you.
She now knows exactly who you are.
How long will you let her live?
How long before
your pure instincts take over?
l'm onto your plan.
You still don't have the beryllium sphere.
Without it, you can't complete the bomb.
Besides, you know l'm gonna stop you.
You Americans are so arrogant.
You think your meaningless,
decadent country...
...is the new cradle of civilization.
-Let me tell you something--
-That's the U.S. of A. you're talking about.
l am talking about ruling the world!
l'd like to give you a name.
Leonard Levinsky. Brilliant psychiatrist.
-You'll talk, he'll listen--
-You are boring me!
-That knife.
-Recognize it?
l took it from the Tulku.
No, l correct myself.
l took it out of the Tulku
after l ran it through his heart.
When will you learn
to listen to your instincts?
lnstincts?
l'll show you my instincts.
Never did master the Phurba, did you?
Still expect it to respond to brute force.
My Mongol warriors aren't terribly bright...
...but they are loyal.
Accept the truth.
There is no light without shadow.
And you and l are that shadow.
l would sooner destroy a Rembrandt
than kill you.
For the last time, will you join me?
You cannot fool me.
You cannot defeat me.
-Your mind is an open book to me.
-Then learn how to read!
Weakling!
Tail them, Moe.
He's disappeared, boss.
Stop the car.
lt's just an empty lot, boss.
l can't help that l know what l know
about you.
And l can't forget it either.
lt's late.
Sleep here if you like.
There are guest rooms.
But in the morning, you should go.
l'm not afraid of you.
But l am.
Lamont?
Oh, my God.
Good morning.
Oh, God, l dreamed.
So did l.
What did you dream?
l was lying naked on the beach
in the South Seas.
The tide was coming up over my toes.
The sun was beating down.
My skin was...
...hot and cool at the same time.
lt was wonderful.
What was yours?
l dreamed l tore all the skin off my face
and was somebody else underneath.
You have problems.
l'm aware of that.
l'll wait outside while you get dressed.
That's okay. You can stay.
These are all rumpled.
There might be some things
in here that you could use.
Yeah. This belonged to my aunt Rose.
-Really?
-Very fashionable gal, that Rose.
Kept her figure, too.
l've got to run. l've got a--
-Taxi waiting downstairs?
-Excuse me?
l sensed that's what you were gonna say.
lt is, isn't it?
Yes.
This is getting easier the more l'm
around you.
You're like reading a book.
Thank you,
but l won't be needing that taxi.
-You do. l have a very important--
-Great. l'll come with you.
-No! Last night we agreed--
-No, l didn't agree to anything.
Do you mind if l get
one little sentence out here?
We agreed you were going to leave
this morning.
No, you agreed l was going to leave.
l agreed to no such thing.
-We need each other.
-No.
-We have a connection.
Then explain why l can read your thoughts.
-My thoughts are hard to miss.
-Why?
-Psychically, l'm very well-endowed.
-l'll bet you are.
Okay, so you don't need me,
but l need you to help me find my father.
And l am coming with you.
Okay.
Empire state building pennants!
Get your empire state building pennants!
From there to there.
That is just the explosion.
The destruction will be incalculable.
Good.
What a beautiful day.
Nice dress, toots.
-''Come on along and listen to...''
-Get me down!
Bobby! What are you doing?
l have no idea! Get me down!
-Get me down from here!
-''...The Lullaby of Broadway.''
Get me down!
lt's all falling into place for me now.
Shiwan Khan needs a beryllium sphere
to complete the bomb.
-l wonder where he intends to find one?
-Beryllium sphere?
Beryllium sphere! Farley Claymore!
-What's that?
-Farley Claymore, my father's assistant.
-He was working on a beryllium sphere.
-ln your father's lab?
No, he was working on his own.
Mari-Tech labs, down on the south side.
-Good, very good.
-Get outta the way!
l got something else
l want you to do for me.
l was trailing Khan when l lost him on
the corner of Second and Houston.
There's something strange
about that vacant lot.
Find out what used to be there.
Second and Houston.
What about Farley Claymore?
Mr. Claymore's gonna receive
a little visit from the Shadow.
-Farley Claymore!
-Who's there?
Where is the beryllium sphere, Claymore?
Sphere?
What sphere?
Claymore, you idiot!
You're being manipulated.
Your mind is being controlled by hypnosis.
My mind? Controlled?
What have you done with the sphere?
lt's too late. l loaded it on a truck.
Take me to it now!
Who do you think you're gonna
shoot with that, Claymore?
No one controls my mind, Shadow!
There's a new world order coming,
and l'm gonna be a king.
A king!
Margo.
Margo, l need you.
Open the door.
You called?
Lamont?
You're not supposed to be here.
You were dreaming.
You saw.
Do you have any idea...
...what it's like to have done things
you can never forgive yourself for?
Whoever you were...
...whatever you did...
...it's in the past.
Not for me, Margo.
Never for me.
We are victorious!
And as victors,
we will collect the spoils of war.
l will remember each of you...
...particularly my special servant...
...the only American with genius enough...
...to join me of his own free will...
...who saw himself a king in my kingdom.
King? Did l say king?
-Maybe not the best choice of words.
-No, it wasn't.
Because actually,
l was thinking prince, tops.
Not even, necessarily. Duke? Baron?
Your choice, of course.
-Get Dr. Lane. Assemble the bomb.
-Of course.
ln the name of the new Kha Khan!
The power of God on Earth!
The emperor of mankind!
Extra! Read all about it!
Madman threatens
to blow the city sky-high!
Residents of New York City
were thrown into a virtual panic today.
Police were still trying to determine if,
in fact, the threat was real...
...or merely an incredible hoax.
Either way, surely the work of a madman.
Morning, Russell.
He's demanded works of art,
famous jewels, even gold.
Find Khan and you'll find the bomb.
What did you find out about that lot?
Not much. lt was the site
of the old Hotel Monolith.
lt was finished nearly 10 years ago,
but it never opened.
The Monolith. l vaguely remember that.
Seems that's the only way
anybody remembers it.
Before the hotel was completed...
...the developer went bankrupt
and committed suicide.
The last record is a sale
to a Far Eastern buyer six years ago.
-When was it torn down?
-lt doesn't say.
l made some calls this morning
to newspapers and such.
All anybody can remember
is up to the time it was sold.
Everyone seems to know
that it was torn down...
...but they can't remember
when or by whom.
Or if.
l can't believe he did it.
Did what? Lamont?
My God.
lt's beautiful.
What is?
Hey, that building right there.
What's the name of that building?
Lunatic!
Shiwan Khan has hypnotized
the entire city.
They don't see it.
None of them see it.
But l see it.
You and Shrevnitz
will receive your instructions.
-l want you to follow them exactly.
-Lamont!
Bet you wish you'd been a little nicer
to me now, don't ya?
Bet you wish you'd listened to my ideas.
Bet you didn't count on me being friends
with a conqueror, did ya?
That's enough. Activate the bomb.
Set the timer for two hours.
You are certain you could duplicate
this bomb's design anytime l require?
Absolutely. No problem.
That makes Dr. Lane obsolete.
Secure him in a room.
He will die at the hands
of his own invention.
Yes, my Khan.
l know you must have this covered,
but shouldn't we be getting out of here?
There's an aeroplane waiting to take us
all to safety. We leave in one hour.
What is it, Moe?
ls it another one from the bowling league?
Ying Ko.
The Shadow! Where?
Not here, you idiot. ln the building.
Can you tell if he's mad at me?
We had a little misunderstanding
yesterday...
...and there might still be hard feelings.
Find him and kill him!
Kill him? Me?
All of you!
Couldn't l just stay here and help you?
Go!
You guys, go that way.
Did you think you'd never see me again?
l'm right here!
All around you.
Everywhere around you.
Coward.
Chicken! Sissy!
Come out here and fight like a man.
You're a fool, Claymore.
Get out of my sight!
There's your exit, Claymore.
You know what l love about this job?
The excitement.
Ying Ko. l surrender.
You're finished, Khan.
Phurba!
You are losing your concentration.
Your mind is too weak.
You are beginning to lose your power.
Look at you. Can't even control yourself.
How can you hope to control the Phurba?
Stop!
-My God.
-That's what he saw.
Where am l?
Khan!
-Dad!
-Margo!
-Where am l? What is going on here?
-Are you all right?
Well, there's this guy....
-l'll tell you later. Call the police.
-Okay.
Look! There it is!
Oh, my God! This is impressive work.
-Who did this?
-You did.
We only have an hour left. Disconnect it!
Cut this off.
Dad, the timer! You gotta stop it!
Oh, dear.
Two minutes left.
Oh, my God! Hurry!
This way!
Oh, my God, it's upstairs.
Oh, no, the elevator!
Dad!
Be careful.
No!
-Which wire?
-l just don't remember!
Pick one!
What the hell. lt's usually green.
No, green!
This is green. That's red.
l've gotta try to remember that.
What are you doing?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Where the hell did that come from?
What is this?
Where am l?
You. Come here.
Look at me.
Look into my eyes.
Yes.
Release me at once.
No, we won't have any of that, Mr. Khan.
Let's just have a look at those stitches.
Stitches? What have you done?
Saved your life, that's what.
We had to remove a little section
of your frontal lobe.
You'll never miss it.
lt's a part nobody ever uses.
But....
Unless you believe in telepathy!
Wait! Come back here!
You! Come here!
l am Shiwan Khan, the last descendant
of Genghis Khan! Listen to me!
-l'm Houdini!
-l'm Theodore Roosevelt!
-l am Napoleon!
-l'm Josephine!
-l'm Babe Ruth!
-l'm Henry Vlll!
l'm William Shakespeare!
l'll see you later.
Hey, how will you know where l am?
l'll know.