(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(BIRDS CALLING)
(PANTING)
MAN: Starling!
Starling !
Crawford wants
to see you in
his office.
Thank you, sir.
Clarice.
Hey.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
...so there shouldn't be
any problem if you could...
You looking for Crawford?
Yes, sir.
He should be back
in a couple minutes.
Why don't you wait
in his office?
Okay.
And I think they
were over in Flushing...
Starling,
Clarice M. Good morning.
Good morning,
Mr. Crawford.
Sorry to pull you
off of the course
at such short notice.
Your instructors tell me
you're doing well.
Top quarter of your class.
I hope so. They haven't
posted any grades yet.
A job's come up,
and I thought about you.
Not a job, really.
More of
an interesting errand.
Sit down.
Yes, sir.
I remember you from
my seminar at UVA.
You grilled me pretty
hard, as I recall,
on the Bureau's
civil rights record
in the Hoover years.
I gave you an "A."
A-minus, sir.
Let's see. Double major,
psych and criminology.
Graduated magna.
Summer internships at
the Reitzinger Clinic.
It says here
when you graduate,
you want to come
to work for me in
Behavioral Science.
Yes, very much, sir.
Very much.
We're interviewing all
the serial killers
now in custody
for a psycho-behavioral
profile.
It could be a real help
in unsolved cases.
Most of them have been
happy to talk to us.
Do you spook easily,
Starling?
Not yet, sir.
See, the one we want most,
refuses to cooperate.
I want you to go after him
again today in the asylum.
And who's the subject?
The psychiatrist
Hannibal Lecter.
Hannibal the Cannibal.
I don't expect him
to talk to you,
but I have to be able
to say we tried.
So if he won't cooperate,
I want just
straight reporting.
How's he look?
How's his cell look?
Is he sketching, drawing?
If he is,
what's he sketching?
Here's a dossier
on Lecter.
A copy of our questionnaire
and a special ID for you.
Have your memo on my desk
by 0800 Wednesday.
Okay.
Excuse me, sir,
but why the urgency?
Lecter's been in prison
for so many years now.
Is there some
connection between him
and Buffalo Bill maybe?
I wish there were.
I want your full
attention, Starling.
Yes, sir.
Be very careful
with Hannibal Lecter.
Dr. Chilton at the asylum
will go over
all the physical procedures
used with him.
Do not deviate from them
for any reason whatsoever,
and you're to tell him
nothing personal, Starling.
Believe me, you don't
want Hannibal Lecter
inside your head.
Just do your job,
but never forget
what he is.
And what is that?
CHILTON: Oh, he's a monster.
A pure psychopath.
So rare to capture one alive.
From a research
point of view,
Lecter is our most
prized asset.
Well.
You know, we get a lot
of detectives here,
but I must say,
I can't ever remember
one as attractive.
Will you be in
Baltimore overnight?
Because this can be quite
a fun town if you have
the right guide.
Well, I'm sure this
is a great town,
Dr. Chilton,
but, uh, my instructions
are to talk to Dr. Lecter
and report back
this afternoon.
I see.
Let's make this quick, then.
We've tried to study him,
of course,
but he's much too
sophisticated for
the standard tests.
Oh, my,
does he hate us!
He thinks
I'm his nemesis.
Crawford's very clever,
isn't he? Using you.
CLARICE: What do
you mean, sir?
A pretty young woman
to turn him on.
I don't believe Lecter's
even seen a woman
in eight years.
And, oh, are you
ever his taste.
So to speak.
I graduated from
UVA, Doctor.
It is not a charm school.
Good. Then you
should be able to
remember the rules.
(MAN SHOUTING)
Do not touch
the glass.
Do not approach
You pass him nothing
but soft paper.
No pencils or pens.
No staples or paper
clips on his paper.
Use the sliding food
carrier. No exceptions.
If he attempts to
pass you anything,
do not accept it.
Do you understand me?
Yes, I understand, sir.
(BUZZER BUZZING)
I'm going to show you
why we insist on
such precautions.
On the afternoon
of July 8, 1981,
he complained
of chest pains
and was taken to
the dispensary.
His mouthpiece
and restraints were
removed for an EKG.
When the nurse
leaned over him,
he did this to her.
The doctors managed
to reset her jaw,
more or less,
save one of her eyes.
His pulse never
got above 85,
even when he
ate her tongue.
I keep him in here.
Dr. Chilton.
If Lecter feels
that you're his enemy,
then, uh, well,
maybe we'll have
more luck
if I go in by myself.
What do you think?
(BEEPING)
You might have
suggested this
in my office
and saved me the time.
Yes, sir, but then I...
I would have missed
the pleasure of
your company, sir.
When she's finished,
bring her out.
Hi. I'm Barney.
He told you, don't
get near the glass?
Yes, he did.
Clarice Starling.
Mmm-hmm. Nice to
meet you, Clarice.
You can hang your coat
up here if you like.
Thank you. I will.
He's past the others.
The last cell.
You keep to the right.
I put out
a chair for you.
Oh, yes.
That's very good.
Thank you.
I'll be watching.
You'll do fine.
INMATE: Hi.
I can smell your cunt.
Good morning.
Dr. Lecter, my name
is Clarice Starling.
May I speak with you?
You're one of
Jack Crawford's,
aren't you?
I am, yes, sir.
May I see your
credentials?
Certainly.
Closer, please.
Closer.
That expires in one week.
You're not real FBI, are you?
I'm still in training
at the Academy.
Jack Crawford
sent a trainee to me?
Yes. I'm a student.
I'm here to learn
from you.
Maybe you can decide
for yourself
whether or not I'm
qualified enough
to do that.
Mmm.
That is rather
slippery of you,
Agent Starling.
Sit, please.
Now, then. Tell me,
what did Miggs say to you?
Multiple Miggs
in the next cell.
He hissed at you.
What did he say?
He said, "l can
smell your cunt."
I see.
I myself cannot.
(INHALING)
You use Evyan skin cream.
And sometimes you
wear L'Air du Temps,
but not today.
Did you do all these
drawings, Doctor?
Ah !
That is the Duomo,
seen from the Belvedere.
You know Florence?
All that detail
just from memory,
sir?
Memory, Agent Starling,
is what I have instead
of a view.
Well,
perhaps you'd care
to lend us your view on
this questionnaire, sir.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
You were doing fine.
You had been courteous
and receptive to courtesy.
You had established trust
with the embarrassing
truth about Miggs.
And now this ham-handed
segue into your
questionnaire.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
It won't do.
I'm only asking you to
look at this, Doctor.
Either you will
or you won't.
Yeah.
Jack Crawford must
be very busy indeed,
if he is recruiting help
from the student body.
Busy hunting that new one,
Buffalo Bill.
What a naughty boy he is.
Do you know why he's
called Buffalo Bill?
Please tell me.
The newspapers
won't say.
Well, it started as a bad joke
in Kansas City Homicide.
They said, "This one likes
to skin his humps."
Why do you think
he removes their skins,
Agent Starling?
Enthrall me with your acumen.
It excites him.
Most serial killers keep
some sort of trophies
from their victims.
I didn't.
No.
No, you ate yours.
You send that through now.
Hmm.
Oh, Agent Starling,
you think you can dissect me
with this blunt, little tool?
No.
l... I thought that
your knowledge...
You're so ambitious,
aren't you?
You know what you
look like to me
with your good bag
and your cheap shoes?
You look like a rube.
A well-scrubbed, hustling
rube with a little taste.
Good nutrition has given
you some length of bone,
but you're not more
than one generation
from poor white trash,
are you, Agent Starling?
And that accent you've tried
so desperately to shed,
pure West Virginia.
(IN SOUTHERN ACCENT)
What does your father do?
Is he a coal miner?
Does he stink of the lamp?
And, oh, how quickly
the boys found you.
All those tedious,
sticky fumblings in
the back seats of cars,
while you could only
dream of getting out,
getting anywhere,
getting all the
way to the FBI.
You see a lot, Doctor.
But are you strong
enough to point
that high-powered
perception at yourself?
What about it?
Why don't you...
Why don't you look at
yourself and write
down what you see?
Maybe you're afraid to.
(THUDDING)
A census-taker once
tried to test me.
I ate his liver
with some fava beans,
and a nice Chianti.
(HISSING)
You fly back to school now,
little Starling.
Fly, fly, fly.
(MIGGS MOANING)
MIGGS: I bit my wrist
so I could die.
Look at the blood !
Gotcha!
Miggs! You stupid fuck!
Hannibal the Cannibal !
Agent Starling !
Come back!
I would not have had
that happen to you.
Discourtesy is
unspeakably ugly to me.
Then do this
test for me.
No, but I will
make you happy.
I'll give you a chance
for what you love most.
And what is that, Doctor?
Advancement, of course.
Now listen carefully.
Look deep within yourself,
Clarice Starling.
Go seek out Miss Mofet,
an old patient of mine.
M-o-f-e-t. Go now.
Doctor.
I don't think Miggs
could manage again
quite so soon,
even though
he is crazy.
Go now!
(INMATES SCREAMING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Hey, Bill.
Hey.
Daddy!
Hey, Clarice.
How are you?
Did you get any
bad guys today, Daddy?
No, angel,
they all got away.
Aw, shoot.
(DOG BARKING)
(CLARICE SOBBING)
FBI ! Hands up!
Don't move!
Turn around !
Hands behind your back!
Thumbs up.
(SIREN WAILING)
You're dead, Starling.
Johnson, good job.
Good entry. Good commands.
Starling, where's
your danger area?
In the corner, sir.
Did you check the corner?
No, sir.
That's the reason
you're dead.
3109.
Breaking doors or windows
to enter or exit.
Rule 404...
(PHONE RINGING)
Clarice, phone.
It's the guru.
Crawford?
Yeah.
Thanks, Ardelia.
Starling?
CLARICE: Sir?
Miggs is dead.
Dead? How?
The orderly heard Lecter
whispering to him
all afternoon,
and Miggs crying.
They found him
at bed check.
He'd swallowed
his own tongue.
Starling?
Yeah, I'm...
I'm still here, sir.
I just... I don't know
how to feel about this.
You don't have to feel
any way about it.
Lecter did it
to amuse himself.
Look, I know it
got ugly today,
but you mentioned
a name at the end.
Mofet.
Any follow-up on her?
Uh, well, Lecter
altered or destroyed
most of his
patients' histories
prior to capture,
so there's no record
of anyone named Mofet.
But, uh, I thought
the "yourself" reference
was, uh, too hokey
for Lecter,
so I figured,
he's from Baltimore,
and I looked
in the phone book,
and there's a
"Your Self Storage" facility,
right outside of
downtown Baltimore, sir.
Unit 31 was leased
for 10 years,
prepaid in full.
The contract
is in the name of
a Miss Hester Mofet.
So nobody's been
in here since 1980?
Not to my knowledge.
Privacy is a great concern
to my customers.
(GRUNTING)
Yes, I won't disturb
anything. I promise.
I'll be out of here
before you know it.
Yes, actually, you can.
(DOOR BANGING)
It's stuck.
We could return tomorrow
with my son.
What about him?
I would ask my
driver to help you,
but he detests
physical labor.
Great.
You just stay here.
I'll be back in
one minute.
(METALLIC CLANKING)
(GRUNTING)
It's stuck.
Hand me that
flashlight, sir.
(METALLIC CLATTERING)
Oh.
Um...
If this door
should fall down
(CHUCKLES)
or anything else, uh,
this is the number
for our Baltimore
field office.
Now, they know
that you're with me.
You call them
if anything
should happen.
Yes, Miss Starling.
(TROUSER FABRIC RIPPING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(THUDDING)
They're waiting for you.
Watch yourself.
Thank you.
CLARICE: Hester Mofet.
It's an anagram,
isn't it, Doctor?
Hester Mofet,
"The rest of me."
"Miss The Rest Of Me,"
meaning that you rented
that garage?
Thank you.
Your bleeding has stopped.
How did you...
It's nothing.
It's just a scratch.
Dr. Lecter, whose head
is in that bottle?
Why don't you ask me
about Buffalo Bill?
Why, do you know
something about him?
I might, if I saw
the case file.
You could get that for me.
Why don't we talk
about Miss Mofet?
You wanted me to find him.
His real name is
Benjamin Raspail.
A former patient of mine,
whose romantic attachments
ran to, shall we say,
the exotic.
I did not kill him,
I assure you.
Merely tucked him away
very much as I found him,
after he'd missed
three appointments.
If you didn't kill him,
then who did, sir?
Who can say?
Best thing for him, really.
His therapy was going nowhere.
His dress, uh, makeup...
Raspail was a transvestite?
In life? Oh, no.
Garden variety
manic-depressive.
Tedious. Very tedious.
And I just think of him
as a kind of experiment,
a fledgling killer's
first effort at
transformation.
How did you feel
when you saw him,
Clarice?
Scared at first, then,
exhilarated.
Jack Crawford is helping
your career, isn't he?
Apparently, he likes you,
and you like him, too.
I never thought about it.
Do you think Jack Crawford
wants you sexually?
True, he is much older,
but do you think he
visualizes scenarios,
exchanges,
fucking you?
That doesn't interest me,
Doctor.
Frankly, it's...
It's the sort of thing
that Miggs would say.
Not anymore.
Thank you, Barney.
(INDISTINCT)
CLARICE: What happened
to your drawings?
Punishment, you see,
for Miggs.
Just like that
gospel program.
When you leave,
they'll turn the
volume way up.
Dr. Chilton does enjoy
his petty torments.
What did you mean
by transformation,
Doctor?
I've been in this room for
eight years now, Clarice.
I know they will
never, ever let me
out while I'm alive.
What I want is a view.
I want a window where I can
see a tree, or even water.
I want to be in
a federal institution
far away from Dr. Chilton.
What did you mean
by fledgling killer?
Are you saying that
he's killed again?
I'm offering you
a psychological profile
on Buffalo Bill,
based on the case evidence.
I'll help you catch him,
Clarice.
You know who he is,
don't you?
Tell me who decapitated
your patient, Doctor.
All good things
to those who wait.
I've waited, Clarice,
but how long can you
and old Jackie boy wait?
Our little Billy must
already be searching
for that next
special lady.
After all it was
a great big world
With lots of places
to run to
(SINGING) Yeah, and
if she had to die
Trying she
Had one little promise
she was gonna keep
Oh, yes
All right
Take it easy, baby
Make it last all night
She was an American girl
(BEEPING)
(CAT MEOWING)
Hey, little cheeper.
I'll be right there.
MAN: Oh, shoot.
Goddamn it.
Perfect! Jesus.
Can I help you with that?
Would you?
Sure.
Thank you.
That's all right.
You look kind
of handicapped.
Yeah.
I got it this far.
I just can't get it
up in the truck.
Here. Just grab this.
Okay.
Good. Just set it down.
That's good.
Uh, get in the truck.
I want to push it
all the way up.
I really appreciate
this. Thank you.
All right.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Just go all
the way back.
Okay. Is this good?
Yeah, that's good.
That's great.
Okay.
Say, are you
about a size 14?
Sorry?
(GIRL GROANING)
MAN: Good.
(GIRL WHIMPERING)
Oh, good. Good.
MAN: Hold !
(GRUNTING)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Starling !
Outside. Let's go.
Cindy, in the ring
for Starling. Let's go!
(SIRENS BLARING)
FBI ! Hold it!
Hold it right there!
Saddle up.
Pack your field gear.
You're moving out.
You're going with Crawford.
Where?
Found a girl's body
down in West Virginia.
Been in the water
about a week.
Looks like a
Buffalo Bill-type
situation.
(AIRPLANE ENGINE WHIRRING)
CRAWFORD: He keeps them
alive for three days.
We don't know why.
There's no evidence of rape
or physical abuse
prior to death.
All the mutilation
you see there is
postmortem.
Okay, three days.
Then he shoots them,
skins them, and dumps them.
Each body in
a different river.
The water leaves us
no trace evidence
of any kind.
That's Fredrica Bimmel,
the first one.
Her body was the only one
he took the trouble
to weight down,
so actually, she was
the third girl found.
After her, he got lazy.
Okay. Let's see.
Circles where the girls
were abducted,
arrows where their
bodies were found.
This new one today
washed up here.
Elk River, West Virginia.
Look at him, Starling.
Tell me what you see.
Well, he's a white male.
Serial killers tend to hunt
within their
own ethnic groups.
He's not a drifter.
He's got his own
house somewhere,
not an apartment.
Why?
What he does with
them takes privacy.
He's in his 30s or 40s.
He's got real
physical strength,
combined with an older man's,
uh, self-control.
He's cautious, precise.
And he's never impulsive.
He'll never stop.
Why not?
He's got a real taste
for it now.
He's getting better
at his work.
Not bad, Starling.
Questions?
Yes, sir.
You haven't mentioned anything
about the information
contained in my report
or Dr. Lecter's offer, sir.
I'm considering it.
That's why you sent me
in there, isn't it?
To get his help on
Buffalo Bill, sir?
Well, if that was the
case, then I just...
I just wish I was
in on it. That's all.
If I had sent you in there
with an actual agenda,
Lecter would have
known it instantly.
He would have
toyed with you,
then turned to stone.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Excuse me.
Sheriff Perkins,
these are the FBI people.
Sheriff Perkins.
Jack Crawford, FBI.
Special Agent Terry,
Agent Starling.
We appreciate being invited
to your jurisdiction.
I didn't call you.
That was somebody from
the State Attorney's office.
We'll extend you
every courtesy,
but right now...
Sheriff, this type
of sex crime has
certain aspects.
I'd just as soon
discuss in private.
You know what I mean?
(ORGAN PLAYING)
PERKINS: Oscar, fetch
Dr. Akin from the chapel.
Yes, sir.
Starling,
we're back here.
Tell Lamar to come on
when he's finished
playing his music.
Yeah. We'll be
sending in a minute.
Is this working?
I need a six-way linkup.
Chicago, Detroit...
What? What?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Excuse me!
Excuse me, gentlemen.
You officers and gentlemen,
listen here now.
There's things
we need to do for her.
I know that you all
brought her this far
and that her folks would
thank you if they could
for your kindness
and your sensitivity.
And now, please,
go on now and let
us take care of her.
Go on, now.
Thank you.
(OFFICER CHATTERING
ON POLICE RADIO)
Thank you.
CRAWFORD: Okay, good.
Yeah, that's right.
West Virginia. Elk River.
Stand by for transmission.
(BEEPING)
Ray.
CRAWFORD: Doctor, Lamar,
let's take a look at her.
Oh, Jesus.
Okay, Starling.
Bill.
Star-shaped
contact entrance wound
over the, uh, sternum.
Uh, muzzle stamp at the top.
DR. AKIN: Wrongful death.
"Wrongful death."
She'll have to go to
the state pathologist
at Claxton.
Well, I better get
back to that service.
Lamar will help you.
Lord Almighty.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
CRAWFORD: What else
do you see, Starling?
Well, she's not local.
Her ears are pierced
three times, and
there's, uh...
Glitter nail polish.
It looks like town to me.
Two of her fingernails
are broken off,
and there's, uh, there's
dirt or grit under them.
It looks like
she's tried to claw
her way through something.
Ray, get pictures
of her teeth.
We'll fax them through
Missing Persons.
RAY: Right.
Let's do another.
She's got something
in her throat.
When a body comes
out of the water,
lots of times there's,
like, leaves and things
in the mouth.
What is that,
some kind of seedpod?
No, sir.
That's a bug cocoon.
There's no way that
could get way down
in there like that.
Not unless somebody
shoved it in there.
She'll be easier to print
when we turn her over.
Lamar, will you give
me a hand with this?
LAMAR: Yes, sir, I will.
Oh, Jack. What do
you make of these?
Different configuration
than the other victims.
Get close-ups.
Victim's skin removed
this time in two large
diamond-shaped sections
above the buttocks.
Stellate exit wound level
with the second or the
third thoracic vertebrae
approximately six inches
from the right shoulder blade.
CRAWFORD: Starling?
When I told
that sheriff
we shouldn't talk
in front of a woman,
that really burned you,
didn't it?
It was just smoke,
Starling.
I had to get rid of him.
It matters,
Mr. Crawford.
Cops look at you
to see how to act.
It matters.
Point taken.
Ligature marks found
around the wrists,
not around the ankles.
This would indicate that
the skinning was postmortem.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
RODEN: Time, Pilch.
My move.
PILCHER: No fair.
You lured him
with produce.
Tough noogies.
Still my turn.
Nice and slow, baby.
If the beetle
moves one of your men,
does that still count?
Of course it counts.
How do you play?
Agent Starling?
RODEN: Where the heck
did this come from?
It's practically mush.
It was found behind
the soft palate of
a murder victim.
The body was in
the Elk River,
West Virginia.
It's Buffalo Bill, isn't it?
I'm afraid I can't tell you
any more about that.
PILCHER: We heard about it
on the radio.
You mean this is like a clue
from a real murder case?
Cool !
Just ignore him.
He's not a Ph. D.
A Sphingid. Ceratomia,
maybe.
Boy, he's a big sucker.
Okay.
Let's check morphology.
Uh-huh.
What do you do when
you're not detecting,
Agent Starling?
I try to be a student,
Dr. Pilcher.
You ever go out
for cheeseburgers
and beer?
The amusing house wine?
Are you hitting on me,
Doctor?
Yes.
RODEN: Got you.
What do you got, Roden?
Agent Starling,
meet Mr. Acherontia styx.
Weird.
Better known to his friends
as the Death's Head Moth.
And where does
it come from?
That's what's strange.
They only live in Asia.
Asia?
In this country,
they'd have to be
specially raised
from imported eggs.
Somebody grew this guy,
fed him honey and nightshade,
kept him warm.
Somebody loved him.
(INSECTS BUZZING)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
(CATHERINE MUMBLING)
CATHERINE: Where are you?
Let me out of here!
(CATHERINE SCREAMING)
(HUMMING)
(BARKS)
Please don't leave!
Talk to me, please!
Why won't you answer me?
Please!
Good morning.
I'm Donna Ferucchi.
I'm Gene Cassel with sports.
And I'm Tim Langhorn.
Our top story
for this morning.
Catherine Martin,
the 25-year-old daughter
of Senator Ruth Martin,
listed first as
a missing person,
is now believed to
have been kidnapped
by the serial killer
known only as Buffalo Bill.
Memphis police
sources indicate
that the missing
girl's blouse
has been identified,
sliced up the back
in what has become
a kind of grim,
all-too-familiar
calling card.
Young Catherine Martin,
as we've said,
is the only daughter
of U.S. Senator Ruth Martin,
the Republican junior senator
from Tennessee.
And while her kidnapping
is not, at this point,
considered to be
politically motivated,
nevertheless, it has
stirred the government
to its highest levels.
Reached for a comment
on the ski slopes
of Stowe, Vermont,
the president
himself said to be,
and I quote,
"Intensely concerned."
Just moments ago,
Senator Martin
taped this dramatic
personal plea.
Excuse me.
MARTIN: I'm speaking now
to the person who is
holding my daughter.
Catherine is very
gentle and kind.
Talk to her, and you'll see.
You have the power.
You are in charge.
I know you can feel
love and compassion.
You have a wonderful chance
to show the whole world
that you can be merciful
as well as strong,
that you're big enough
to treat Catherine
better than the world
has treated you.
You have that power.
Please.
My daughter is Catherine.
ARDELIA: Boy, that's smart.
Release her unharmed.
Jesus, that's really smart.
MAN: She keeps
repeating the name.
If he sees
Catherine as a person
and not just an object,
it's harder to tear her up.
Please.
Release my little girl.
What you're doing,
Miss Starling,
is coming into my hospital
to conduct an interview
and refusing to share
information with me
for the third time.
Sir, I told you,
this is just
a routine follow-up
on the Raspail case.
He is my patient.
I have rights.
I understand that, sir.
Look, I am not
just some turnkey,
Miss Starling.
This is the number for
the U.S. Attorney's
office.
Please, either you
discuss this with him,
or you let me do my job.
Do you understand?
CLARICE: If your profile
helps us catch Buffalo Bill
in time to save
Catherine Martin,
the senator
promises you
a transfer
to the V.A. Hospital
at Oneida Park, New York,
with a view of
the woods nearby.
Maximum security
still applies,
of course.
You'd have reasonable
access to books.
Best of all, though.
One week of the year,
you get to leave
the hospital and
go here.
Plum Island.
Every day of that week
you may walk on the beach,
you may swim in the ocean
for up to one hour,
under SWAT team surveillance,
of course.
And there you have it.
A copy of the
Buffalo Bill
case file.
A copy of the
senator's offer.
This offer is
non-negotiable
and final.
If Catherine Martin dies,
you get nothing.
(THUDDING)
"Plum Island
Animal Disease
Research Center."
Sounds charming.
That's only part
of the island.
There's a very,
very nice beach.
Terns nest there.
There's beautiful...
Terns? Hmm.
If I help you, Clarice,
it will be "turns"
with us, too.
Quid pro quo.
I tell you things,
you tell me things.
Not about this case,
though. About yourself.
Quid pro quo. Yes or no?
Yes or no, Clarice?
Poor little Catherine
is waiting.
Go, Doctor.
What is your worst
memory of childhood?
The death of my father.
Tell me about it.
And don't lie,
or I'll know.
He was a town marshal,
and one night
he surprised
two burglars
coming out of the back
of a drugstore.
They shot him.
Was he killed outright?
No. He was very strong.
He lasted more than a month.
My mother died
when I was very young,
so my father had become
the whole world to me,
and when he left me,
I had nothing.
I was ten years old.
You're very frank, Clarice.
I think it would
be quite something to
know you in private life.
Quid pro quo, Doctor.
So tell me about
Miss West Virginia.
Was she a large girl?
Yes.
Big through the hips? Roomy?
They all were.
What else?
She had an object
deliberately inserted
into her throat.
Now, that hasn't
been made public yet.
We don't know
what it means.
Was it a butterfly?
Yes. A moth.
Just like the one we found
in Benjamin Raspail's head
an hour ago.
Why does he place
them there, Doctor?
The significance
of the moth is change.
Caterpillar into
chrysalis or pupa,
and from thence into beauty.
Our Billy wants
to change, too.
There's no correlation
in literature
between transsexualism
and violence.
Transsexuals
are very passive...
Clever girl.
You're so close to the way
you're gonna catch him.
Do you realize that?
No. Tell me why.
After your father's murder,
you were orphaned.
What happened next?
I don't imagine
the answer is on those
second-rate shoes, Clarice.
I went to live
with my mother's cousin
and her husband in Montana.
They had a ranch.
Was it a cattle ranch?
Sheep and horses.
How long did you live there?
Two months.
Why so briefly?
I ran away.
Why, Clarice?
Did the rancher make
you perform fellatio?
Did he sodomize you?
No. He was a very decent man.
Quid pro quo, Doctor.
Billy is not
a real transsexual.
But he thinks he is.
He tries to be.
He's tried to be
a lot of things, I expect.
And you said that
I was very close
to the way
we would catch him.
What did you mean, Doctor?
There are three major centers
for transsexual surgery.
Johns Hopkins,
the University of Minnesota,
and Columbus Medical Center.
I wouldn't be surprised
if Billy had applied
for sex reassignment
at one or all of them
and been rejected.
On what basis
would they reject him?
LECTER: Look for severe
childhood disturbances
associated with violence.
Our Billy wasn't born
a criminal, Clarice.
He was made one through
years of systematic abuse.
Billy hates his own
identity, you see,
and he thinks that
makes him a transsexual.
But his pathology
is a thousand times
more savage
and more terrifying.
It rubs the lotion
on its skin.
It does this
whenever it's told.
Mister, my family
will pay cash.
Whatever ransom
you're asking for,
they'll pay it.
It rubs the lotion
on its skin,
or else it gets
the hose again.
Yes, she will, Precious.
She will get the hose.
(SOBBING) Okay, okay, okay.
Okay. I'm there.
Okay.
Mister, if you let me go,
I won't... I won't
press charges.
I promise.
See, my mom is a real
important woman.
I guess you
already know that.
Now it places the
lotion in the basket.
Please! Please!
I want to go home.
I want to go home, please!
Please, I want to...
It places the lotion
in the basket.
I want to see my mommy!
Please.
I want to see
my mother again.
I want to... I want
to see my mommy.
Put the fucking lotion
in the basket!
(PRECIOUS BARKING)
(CATHERINE SCREAMING)
(SHOUTING)
You still think
you're gonna walk
on some beach
and see the birdies?
(LAUGHING) No,
I don't think so.
I called Senator Ruth Martin.
She never heard
of any deal with you.
They scammed you,
Hannibal.
Stand outside
and shut the door.
Barney.
There never was a deal
with Senator Martin,
but there is now.
I designed it.
Of course,
I worked in a few conditions
for my own benefit as well.
Identify Buffalo Bill
by name
and if the girl
is found in time,
Senator Martin will
have you transferred
to Brushy Mountain
State Prison in Tennessee.
Answer me, Hannibal.
You answer me now,
or by God,
you'll never
leave this cell.
Who is Buffalo Bill?
His first name is Louis.
I'll tell the rest to
the Senator herself,
but only in Tennessee,
and I have a few
conditions of my own.
Clean him up and
get him ready to go.
DIRECTOR ON PHONE: Jack,
Hannibal Lecter is being
transferred to Memphis.
Transferred?
Did you have a trainee
make some sort of
phony offer to Lecter
in the Senator's name?
Yeah. I rolled the
dice. I had to.
Well, she's mad
as hell, Jack.
Paul Krendler's
over here from Justice.
She's asking him to
take over in Memphis.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Welcome to Memphis,
Dr. Lecter.
I'm Lieutenant Boyle.
This is Sergeant Patrick.
Now, we're gonna treat you
as good as you treat us.
You be a gentleman,
you gonna get three
hots and a cot.
Sir. If you sign
right here,
we'll have us
a legal transfer.
Where is it?
Here, sir. Use mine.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Senator Martin,
Dr. Hannibal Lecter.
Dr. Lecter,
I brought an affidavit
guaranteeing your
new rights.
You'll want to read it
before I sign.
I won't waste your time
or Catherine's time
bargaining for
petty privileges.
Clarice Starling
and that awful
Jack Crawford
have wasted far too
much time already.
I only pray they haven't
doomed the poor girl.
Let me help you now
and I will trust you
when it is all over.
You have my word. Paul?
Buffalo Bill's real name
is Louis Friend.
I met him just once.
He was referred to me
in April or May, 1980,
by my patient
Benjamin Raspail.
They were lovers, you see.
But Raspail had become
very frightened.
Apparently, Louis had
murdered a transient
and done things
with her skin.
We need his address and
a physical description.
Tell me, Senator.
Did you nurse
Catherine yourself?
What?
Did you breast-feed her?
Now, wait a minute!
Yes, I did.
Toughened your nipples,
didn't it?
You son of a bitch !
Amputate a man's leg,
and he can still
feel it tickling.
Tell me, Mom,
when your little
girl is on the slab,
where will it tickle you?
Take this thing
back to Baltimore.
Five-foot-ten, strongly built,
about 180 pounds.
Hair, blond.
Eyes, pale blue.
He'd be about 35 now.
He said he lived
in Philadelphia,
but may have lied.
That's all I can
remember, Mom.
But if I think of any more,
I will let you know.
Oh, and, Senator,
just one more thing.
Love your suit.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
CHILTON: I tell you
now that in a meeting
earlier this evening
with Senator Ruth Martin,
Dr. Lecter agreed to assist
in the investigation
of trying to find the abductor
of Catherine Martin,
Buffalo Bill.
How do you fit in, sir?
Well, it's only through
my own unique insight
into Lecter's mind
that this breakthrough
was possible.
And Buffalo Bill's
real name...
Buffalo Bill's real name
is now a matter of record
with the proper authorities.
Can you give us
any more information?
My name is
Dr. Frederick Chilton.
How do you spell that?
C-H...
Are you with
Dr. Chilton's group?
Oh, well, I just saw
him outside, sir.
Access to Lecter
is strictly limited.
We've been getting
death threats.
I understand, sir.
Log in. Check your weapon.
KRENDLER: Well, I can't take
all the credit for myself.
Senator Martin,
the Justice Department,
the people at the FBI,
the folks at the
Baltimore State Hospital.
And now for the hard part,
apprehending the suspect.
Excuse me, folks,
I'm gonna have
to catch a flight.
(PHONE RINGING)
Command desk.
Officer Jacobs.
OFFICER: Is it true
what they're saying?
Huh?
He's some kind of vampire?
They don't have
a name for what he is.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
You do know the rules,
ma'am?
Yes, Lieutenant Boyle.
I've questioned him before.
Go ahead.
Good evening, Clarice.
I thought you might like
your drawings back, Doctor.
Just until you get your view.
How very thoughtful.
Or did Jack Crawford send
you for one last wheedle
before you're both
booted off the case?
No. I came
because I wanted to.
People will say
we're in love.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Anthrax Island.
That was an especially
nice touch, Clarice.
Yours?
Yes.
Yeah ! That was good.
Pity about poor Catherine,
though.
Tick-tock, tick-tock,
tick-tock, tick-tock.
Your anagrams are
showing, Doctor.
Louis Friend?
Iron sulfide,
also known as Fool's Gold.
Oh, Clarice.
Your problem
is you need to get
more fun out of life.
You were telling me the truth
back in Baltimore, sir.
Please continue now.
Well, I have read
the case files, have you?
Everything you need
to find him
is right there
in those pages.
Then tell me how.
First principles, Clarice.
Simplicity.
Read Marcus Aurelius.
Of each particular thing,
ask what is it in itself?
What is its nature?
What does he do,
this man you seek?
He kills women.
No! That is incidental.
What is the first
and principal thing
he does?
What needs does
he serve by killing?
Anger.
Um, social acceptance
and, uh,
sexual frustrations...
No! He covets.
That is his nature.
And how do we begin
to covet, Clarice?
Do we seek out
things to covet?
Make an effort to answer now.
No. We just...
No. We begin by coveting
what we see every day.
Don't you feel eyes moving
over your body, Clarice?
And don't your eyes
seek out the things
you want?
All right. Yes. Now
please tell me how.
No. It is your turn
to tell me, Clarice.
You don't have any more
vacations to sell.
Why did you leave that ranch?
Doctor, we don't
have any more time
for any of this now.
But we don't reckon
time the same way,
do we, Clarice?
This is all the time
you'll ever have.
Later. Now, please,
listen to me. We've
only got five...
No! I will listen now.
After your father's murder,
you were orphaned.
You were ten years old.
You went to live with cousins
on a sheep and horse ranch
in Montana.
And?
And one morning,
I just ran away.
Not "just", Clarice.
What set you off?
You started at what time?
Early. Still dark.
Then something woke you,
didn't it?
Was it a dream? What was it?
I heard a strange noise.
What was it?
It was screaming.
Some kind of screaming,
like a child's voice.
What did you do?
I went downstairs, outside.
I crept up into the barn.
I was so scared
to look inside,
but I had to.
And what did you see,
Clarice?
What did you see?
Lambs. They were screaming.
They were slaughtering
the spring lambs?
And they were screaming.
And you ran away?
No.
First I tried to free them.
l...
I opened
the gate to their pen,
but they wouldn't run.
They just stood there,
confused.
They wouldn't run.
But you could and you did,
didn't you?
Yes. I took one lamb,
and I ran away as
fast as I could.
Where were you going,
Clarice?
I don't know.
I didn't have any food,
any water,
and it was very cold,
very cold.
I thought...
I thought if I could
save just one, but,
he was so heavy.
He was so heavy.
I didn't get more
than a few miles
when the sheriff's car
picked me up.
The rancher was so angry,
he sent me to live at
the Lutheran orphanage
in Bozeman.
I never saw the ranch again.
What became of your lamb,
Clarice?
They killed him.
You still wake up
sometimes, don't you?
Wake up in the dark
and hear the screaming
of the lambs.
Yes.
And you think if you
save poor Catherine,
you could make them stop,
don't you?
You think if Catherine lives,
you won't wake up in
the dark ever again
to that awful
screaming of the lambs.
I don't know. I don't know.
Thank you, Clarice.
Thank you.
Tell me his name, Doctor.
Dr. Chilton, I presume.
I think you know each other.
Okay.
We found her.
Let's go!
It's your turn, Doctor.
Out.
Tell me his name.
Sorry, ma'am,
I've got orders.
I have to put you
on a plane.
Come on now.
Brave Clarice.
You will let me know when
those lambs stop screaming,
won't you?
Tell me his name, Doctor!
Clarice!
Your case file.
Goodbye, Clarice.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(CLASSICAL PIANO MUSIC
PLAYING ON RECORDER)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Ready when you are, Doc.
Just another minute, please.
The son of a bitch
demanded a second dinner.
Lamb chops, extra rare.
Wonder what he wants
for breakfast.
Some damn thing
from the zoo?
(PEMBRY CHUCKLING)
Good evening, gentlemen.
Okay, Doc.
Grab some floor.
Same drill as before,
please.
Mmm-hmm.
Ready when you are,
Sergeant Pembry.
PEMBRY: Okay.
BOYLE: Hand me that,
would you?
Thanks.
LECTER: Mind the
drawings, please.
Thank you.
Jimmy, watch it!
He's got me!
(SCREAMING)
Jesus Christ!
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(PIANO MUSIC RESUMES)
(PEMBRY GRUNTING)
Ready when you are,
Sergeant Pembry.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
TATE: What is this shit?
Did somebody go up on five?
No. Nobody went up.
Call Pembry. Ask him...
(GUN FIRING)
CP, shots fired on five.
Repeat.
Shots fired on five.
Sergeant Tate.
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON RADIO)
TATE: Holy shit.
What the hell? Bitch !
Shut up.
Bobby, get the vest.
Right, Sarge.
TATE: Brady, Howard...
Look!
It stopped.
Seal off a 10 block radius.
Get me the SWAT team
and an ambulance
double-quick.
We're going up.
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON RADIO)
TATE: Pembry!
Boyle!
Oh, God !
Go.
Clear!
OFFICER: Clear!
Command post,
two officers down.
OFFICER 1: Clear!
OFFICER 2: Clear!
Lecter's gone, Sarge.
The prisoner is missing.
Boyle's gun is gone,
Sergeant.
Repeat. Lecter is
missing and armed.
He stripped the bed.
Might be making a rope.
Check all windows.
Where the fuck
is my ambulance?
He's alive.
Sergeant Tate, he's alive!
Get ahold of
him where you can
feel his hands, son.
Talk to him.
What do I say?
It's Jim Pembry!
Now talk to him,
damn it!
Lecter is missing
and armed.
Pembry. Pembry,
can you hear me?
He took Boyle's gun.
Pembry got off one round.
There's a chance
Lecter was hit.
Keep breathing in and out.
That's it.
You're doing a good job.
You look real good there.
Yeah, you look...
You look real good.
(SIRENS WAILING)
You ready?
Let's go.
Let's do it.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Looking good, Pembry.
You're gonna make it.
You're just fine.
You're doing all right.
That's right.
Okay, I need that IV now.
Lactated ringers.
Can we get the strap?
Where's the fucking oxygen?
Looking good, buddy.
That's right.
TATE: Bob!
Stay with me.
Stay with me here.
We're losing him.
Downstairs. Take him !
And up!
Elevator!
Out of the way!
OFFICER ON RADIO:
CP to Tate.
Roger, Lieutenant.
Tate here.
(BEEPING)
I'm on the elevator
bringing Pembry down.
He seems to be hanging on.
Top three floors secured.
Main stairwell secured.
We think he's on two.
Tate, are you still with me?
We're pretty sure
he's somewhere
on two, sir.
That's all for now. Over.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
He's on the roof
of the elevator.
Okay, guys.
I see him.
There's a gun by his hand.
He's not moving.
One warning.
We need him alive.
JOHNNY: Got him.
Lecter.
Put your hands
on your head.
One in the leg.
(GUN CLICKING)
No movement.
Johnny, hold your fire.
We're coming into the car.
We're opening the hatch.
Watch his hands.
If there's any fire,
it'll come from us.
Affirm.
JOHNNY: Got it.
(SIREN WAILING)
Memphis General,
this is Medical Unit 26.
We're inbound
with a 50-year-old
male police officer
with severe
facial lacerations.
Weapon unknown.
We've got grand mal
seizure activity,
but he's postictal now.
WOMAN: Copy that.
Vital signs are good.
Pressure is 130 over 90.
90?
Yeah, that's right. 90.
Pulse, 84.
We've got him on
lactated ringers
running.
And the patient
is on 10 liters...
ARDELIA: They found
the ambulance
in a parking garage
at Memphis Airport.
The crew was dead.
He killed a tourist, too.
Got his clothes, cash.
By now he could be anywhere.
He won't come after me.
Oh, really?
No, he won't.
I can't explain it.
He... He would
consider that rude.
It's over. She's dead.
It's not your fault
it worked out like this.
The thing is that,
Lecter said everything
we need to catch him with
is right here in these
pages, only I can't...
Dr. Lecter said
a lot of things.
He's here, Ardelia.
(SNIFFING)
Is this Lecter's
handwriting?
"Clarice, doesn't this
random scattering of sites
"seem desperately random?
"Like the elaboration
of a bad liar.
"Ta, Hannibal Lecter."
Desperately random?
What does he mean?
Not random at all maybe.
Like there's
some pattern here.
Yeah, but there
is no pattern,
or the computers
would have nailed it.
They're even found
in random order.
Random because
of the one girl.
The one he weighted down.
Fredrica Bimmel...
Right.
From Belvedere, Ohio.
First girl taken,
third body found.
Why?
Well, she didn't drift.
He weighted her down.
What did Lecter say
about the first
principles?
Simplicity.
What does this guy do?
He covets.
How do we first
start to covet?
We covet what we see...
Every day.
Hot damn, Clarice.
He knew her.
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(SQUEAKING)
Mr. Bimmel?
That's me.
Hello.
I'm Clarice Starling.
I'm with the FBI.
CLARICE: I sure appreciate
you letting me
take a look around,
Mr. Bimmel.
I don't know nothing new
to tell you.
Police been back here
so many times already.
Fredrica went into
Chicago on the bus
to see about a job.
She left the
interview okay.
She never come home.
Her bedroom's
how she left it.
Upstairs. Door to the left.
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
(CAT MEOWING)
CLARICE: He's making himself
a woman suit, Mr. Crawford,
out of real women.
And he can sew, this guy.
He's very skilled.
He's a tailor or
a dressmaker or...
CRAWFORD: Starling.
That's why
they're all so big.
He has to keep them alive
so he can
starve them a while,
so he can loosen
their skin and take...
Starling.
Starling. Starling,
we know who he is
and where he is.
We're on our way right now.
CLARICE: Where?
Calumet City,
edge of Chicago.
Be on the ground
in 45 minutes with HRT.
Oh, that's great news, sir,
but how...
Johns Hopkins came up
with some names.
We fed him into
"Known Offenders."
Subject's name is Jamie Gumb,
AKA John Grant.
Lecter's
description is accurate.
He just lied about the name.
Listen to this.
Customs had some
paper on him.
They stopped a carton
two years ago at LAX.
Live caterpillars
from Surinam.
The addressee
was a Jame Gumb.
Well, Chicago's only
400 miles from here.
I'll be there in...
No, no, no, Starling.
There's not enough time.
We want him for murder,
not kidnapping.
I need you to link him
to the Bimmel girl
before he's indicted.
See what you can
dredge up in Belvedere.
Yes, sir. You bet.
I'll do my best.
Starling, we wouldn't
have found him without you.
Nobody's gonna forget that.
Least of all me.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Crawford.
Mr. Crawford?
CATHERINE: Thanks for
the scraps, asshole.
I got a better idea.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GOODBYE HORSES
PLAYING ON RECORDER)
Okay, Precious.
Time for a little treat.
(GROWLING)
Precious!
(WHISTLING)
Come on, girl !
Come on, Precious.
Come on, Precious!
I see you rise
But it always falls
Come on, Precious!
I got a yummy,
yummy snack for you.
Come on. Come and get it.
He said
All things pass
into the night
Precious!
Are you up there,
you little shit?
Come and get it, pretty girl.
I must disagree
Oh, no, sir
I must say
Precious.
Please come. Come on.
You told me
I've seen it all before
(CRYING) Come on...
I've seen
my hopes and dreams
Are lying on the ground
I've seen the sky
Just begin to fall
Would you fuck me?
CATHERINE: Come on.
Take that bone. Come on.
Come on. Come. Come on.
I'd fuck me.
Come on.
(YELPING)
I'd fuck me hard.
I'd fuck me so hard.
No.
Goodbye horses
I'm flying over you
(SINGING) I'm flying,
flying, flying over you
(SIRENS WAILING)
Is that a good job,
FBI agent?
You get to travel
around and stuff?
I mean, better
places than this?
Sometimes you do.
Freddie was so happy
for me when I got
this job at the bank.
Toaster giveaways
and Barry Manilow
on the speakers all day.
She thought
it was such hot shit.
What did she know? Big dummy.
Stacy, did Fredrica
ever mention a man
named Jamie Gumb
or a Jame Gumb?
How about John Grant?
No.
Oh, would she have
had a friend that you
didn't know about, or...
No way. If she had a guy,
I'd have known, believe me.
Sewing was her life.
Did you two
ever work together?
Oh, sure.
Me and Pam Malavesi used
to help her do alterations
for old Mrs. Lippman.
Can you give me
Mrs. Lippman's address?
I need to talk to her.
(INSECTS BUZZING)
So powerful. So beautiful.
(PRECIOUS YELPING)
Precious!
CATHERINE: Down here,
you sack of shit!
Put her in that bucket.
No! You get me a telephone
and lower it down here. Now!
Poolie-poo. Precious.
Darling heart,
are you all right?
She's in a lot of pain,
mister.
She needs a vet.
She broke her leg
on the way down.
I know it.
She's been licking...
Hey, don't you hurt my dog !
Don't you make me
hurt your dog !
Oh, you don't know
what pain is!
Get me a live telephone line
down here or the dog's dead !
Damn fuck.
CATHERINE: Get me
that telephone!
I'm gonna do it, mister!
I'll snap her neck off.
I swear to God !
You little fuck.
(RINGING)
CATHERINE: Down here!
Down here!
Help!
Okay, I'm coming.
We're going in.
Good afternoon.
Sorry to bother you.
I'm... I'm looking for
Mrs. Lippman's family.
FBI ! Everybody down !
Everybody down, now!
No. The Lippmans
don't live here anymore.
No. Excuse me, sir.
I really need
to speak with you.
Clear!
(STUTTERING)
What's the problem,
Officer?
Well, I'm investigating
the death of Fredrica Bimmel.
There's no one here, Jack.
Clarice.
Your name is?
Oh, Jack Gordon.
Mr. Gordon. Good. Um...
Well, Fredrica used to
work for Mrs. Lippman.
Did you know her?
No. Uh-uh.
Oh, wait.
Was she a great,
big fat person?
Yes. She was
a big girl, sir.
Yeah, I...
I may have...
No, I read about her
in the newspaper.
Um...
Mrs. Lippman had a son.
Maybe he could help you.
I got his card
in here someplace.
Do you want to come in
while I look for it?
May l?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Are you close to
catching somebody,
you think?
Yes. We may be.
Did you
take over this place
after Mrs. Lippman died?
Is that right?
Yeah. I bought
this house, uh,
two years ago.
Did she leave any records,
any business records,
tax forms,
list of employees?
No. Nothing like
that at all.
Say, has the FBI
learned something?
The police around here
don't seem to have
the first clue.
I mean, have you got, like,
a description, fingerprints,
anything like that?
No.
No, we don't.
Yeah. Here's that number.
Very good, Mr. Gordon.
May I use your phone, please?
Sure you can use my phone.
Freeze!
Put your hands
over your head !
And turn around !
Spread your legs!
Put your hands in the back!
Thumbs up!
Freeze!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PRECIOUS BARKING)
CATHERINE: Hey!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
CATHERINE: Hello!
Are you there?
I'm down here!
(PRECIOUS BARKING)
Catherine Martin?
CATHERINE: Yes!
FBI ! You're safe!
Safe, shit!
Get me out of here!
(GRUNTS)
You're all right, Catherine.
Where is he?
How the fuck should I know?
Just get me out of here!
Catherine,
you've got to be quiet.
Now shut that dog up!
Just get me out of here!
Oh, my God.
Catherine, I'm going
to get you out of there,
but right now,
you listen to me.
I've got to leave this room.
I'll be right back.
No! Don't you leave me here,
you fucking bitch !
No! Don't you
leave me here!
This guy's fucking crazy!
Please!
I've got to get
out of here!
Catherine, the other officers
will be here any minute now!
Wait!
Don't go! Please!
CLARICE: Quiet!
Oh, God !
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON RADIO)
You okay?
Gunpowder.
It's nothing. I'm okay.
Agent Starling, how did
you track Buffalo Bill
to this address?
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
Clarice M. Starling.
Congratulations.
Ernest W. Stevens.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Special Agent Starling.
Oh, Special Agent Mapp.
Phone call.
Thank you.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Starling.
Pilch, could you
take our picture?
Sure.
Look, I just wanted
to say congratulations.
And I'm not much good
at this kind of thing,
so I'm gonna
duck out of here.
Okay, sure.
Thank you, Mr. Crawford.
Your father would have
been proud today.
Don't forget your phone call.
Starling.
Well, Clarice, have the
lambs stopped screaming?
Dr. Lecter.
Don't bother with a trace.
I won't be on long enough.
Where are you, Dr. Lecter?
I have no plans
to call on you,
Clarice.
The world's more
interesting with
you in it.
So you take care now
to extend me the
same courtesy.
You know I can't
make that promise.
I do wish
we could chat longer,
but I'm having
an old friend
for dinner.
Bye.
Dr. Lecter...
Dr. Lecter.
Hey, what?
Oh, excuse me. I'm sorry.
Is the security system
all set up?
We have the
big-shot security.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(MAN SINGING)