Two large Bushmills please, darling.
Do you want another drink?
I'll buy you.
What's happening ?
- Get in.
- Alright
- Inside.
Harold will be well pleased.
- When is he back?
- Today.
Highly confidential.
I need them tomorrow,
for a counsel meeting.
No sweat, I'll get them photo-copied.
And the Americans?
- I'll reckon they're coming.
- Good.
- About the nosh: on the corporation?
- Of course, counsellor.
- See you, Jeff.
- See you.
Wait a minute!
These are plans, he needs them
back by this afternoon.
Good old George.
- Everything alright while I was away?
- Yeah.
The new casino has gone through.
- No problems?
- No, everything's alright.
Did anyone guess where I was?
Alan reckoned a health farm.
One or two rumours about New York.
- But nobody guessed?
- No.
Should have left 10 minutes ago,
I'm late for church.
I hate being late for church.
There you are.
Bye bye, have a nice Easter.
God rot your soul.
Oh Christ Harold she's always with us
when she goes to church.
She's got really religious in her
old age, hasn't she?
Church 3 times a day, it's Good Friday.
Have a Bloody Mary.
She thinks Paula is an angel
and I'm the devil in disguise.
Ah well, me and Paula have only been divorced
for 10 years, give her a chance to get used to it.
Cheers.
- Have you organised everything?
- Yes, it's coming along.
Charlie should be landing about now.
Here.
- Maybe we should have gone to the airport to meet him.
- Nah, play it cool.
When the governor of Coca-Cola drops in to London
the Queen don't go dashing off to Heathrow, does she?
- Queen?
- Well you know what I mean.
All plated up, right?
He went to school with princess Ann,
played hockey with her, all that.
- It's lacrosse at Benenden, hockey's frightfully vulgar.
- Yes, yes plenty of, yeah.
The Yanks love snobbery.
They really feel they've arrived in England
if the upper classes treat them like shit.
- Gives them a sense of history.
We'd better check how the chef's progressing.
That geezer don't half know about grub.
The smells that have been coming up from the galley
all morning have been driving me potty.
You lay off the vodka.
- It's going well?
- Madam, look at this.
These blue plates with these
white plates, it's ridiculous.
Now that's a right horrible ponce.
The polly's French isn't he?
It's really splendid.
We thank you very much.
Very nice.
These French geezers really know their stuff, eh?
- Are they new?
- Bought 'em yesterday, 20 quid a piece.
I bet Harold was reluctant
to take the labels off, eh?
He broke two of them demonstrating
their exquisite delicacy.
He doesn't know his own strength.
Have you sorted out Immigration for the Yank?
- Yeah Parky's dealt with that.
- Then you may go and have a drink on deck.
Hello, are you alright?
Having a good time?
Enjoy yourselves.
Counsellors.
Excuse me I won't keep him.
Those plans came in very handy
my son, much obliged.
No sweat, Harold.
- The license on the casino,
did that go through alright, no problems?
- A slight problem.
- How's that?
- Counsellor Taylor seems to think you're a gangster.
- What's the SP on the American?
- Just pump him full of information, everything you've got.
- Instant planning permission, all that sort of chat?
- Yeah.
The Yanks think we're a cock handed corner shop over here.
Exhume the fishes, right?
I'll tell him I quickly mind an enterprise that should appeal?
Parky, you're not drinking?
Harold you know I only drink when I'm on duty.
- How's business, alright?
- A drizzle of complaints.
You get a lot of that in your game, eh?
Hello, Dave.
- How are you, last time I saw you, you had spots.
- Thanks very much.
Even I notice the coppers are getting younger now.
- He's a detective sergeant now Harold.
- Is he?
Celebration, come here.
Champagne my son.
Here's to you.
Nice seeing real friends doing well.
Here's to real friends.
Hi George.
Jeff.
Won't be a minute.
Keep your eyes on the boy's behaviour, will you?
I don't want any of 'em acting like delinquents.
No chance, they know it's important.
I told 'em to put their wedding suits on.
I think you're gonna like Charlie.
So what's the plan?
A cocktail here so we can clog the marina,
then off down river so they can see
the scope of the whole project.
- Have you fixed the moorings?
- It's all under control.
Another thing...
Harris has got a lot of talking to do
this afternoon...
...can you keep him off the booze?
Top him off with Perrier water or something.
Harold, he's here.
You two pipe him aboard and I'll be up, right?
I can't believe you.
- The kid from New Yersey, eh?
- The boy from Stepney.
Charlie, have some champagne.
You should be the captain of this boat,
great timing.
Listen I wanna propose a toast.
- Hands across the ocean, right?
- To the future.
To the future here.
Harold, I don't think you met Tony,
when you were over there?
- Tony?
- My lawyer.
- Mr. Shand, Tony.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Charlie, Tony would you like to come and meet some people now?
- Good.
They're important, but they're nice. Come on.
Keep your eye on that Tony.
He never said he was gonna bring anybody.
They always come in two's, like the bailiffs.
Means they mean business.
Hola.
Hi.
"Happy are those who are called to His supper"
"Lord I am not worthy to receive You"
"but only say the word and I shall be healed."
My God!
Ladies and gentlemen.
I'm not a politician.
I'm a businessman with a sense of history.
And I'm also a Londoner,
and today is a day of great historical
significance for London.
Our country is not an island anymore.
We're a leading European state.
And I believe that this is the decade,
in which London will become Europe's capital.
Having cleared away the outdated,
we've got mile after mile and
acre after acre of land,
for our future prosperity.
No other city in the world...
has got right in its centre,
such an opportunity...
for profitable progress.
So it's important that the right people...
mastermind the new London.
Proven people, with nerve,
knowledge and expertise.
That, ladies and gentlemen,
is why you are all here today.
All trusted friends.
and why Charlie and Tony are here today,
our American friends,
to endorse the global nature of this venture.
Let's hear it ladies and gentlemen.
Hands across the ocean.
There used to be 80 or 90 ships in here at one time.
They used to queue up to get in...
all the way up to Galleon's Reach
right down to Tilbury.
Used to be the greatest docks in
the world at one time, this.
Things change Harold, don't get nostalgic.
Look to the future.
You realise you're 35 minutes away from Europe?
Great potential.
I live in a new country,
and I respect the past, but always
keep my eye on the future.
Don't touch, I'll take care of that.
You've got to go to sleep Charlie,
we've got a tight schedule.
I want you to meet my property lawyers, the best...
and then there's an accountant who
specialises in gambling tax.
This isn't a horse race,
don't rush me Harold.
Then there's someone you've got to meet.
Harold I said don't rush me,
I hate tight schedules.
I've got everything covered that I
have to cover, but in my own time.
We're just docking now, it will be
nice and quiet if you want to sleep.
Come on Harold, let's leave Charlie
alone for a while.
Bad luck putting the hat on the bed.
Relax, he'll be alright.
Yeah, poor old sod is tired.
Look out for the boys in blue.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What?
Right.
This is...
diabolical.
What is it?
Blown up, he's dead.
Eric is dead, a car bomb.
My mother's alright, she's suffering from shock,
she's in the London Hospital.
I don't understand.
You need a million dollar computer
to understand this.
Who'd do such a thing, it's outrageous.
Outside a church...
you don't go crucifying people outside
a church on Good Friday.
- What's the matter Harold?
- Eric's been blown up.
- A bomb?
- Yeah in the Rolls.
- I don't believe it, when?
- Just now.
Mother's in hospital suffering from shock,
I'm not surprised.
She went to church to say her prayers,
not to get blown up.
- But why?
- Someone tried to discredit you in front of...
The Yanks?
No, nobody knew, did they?
- Well they mustn't find out.
- They're sleeping.
Right, I want everybody in the corporation
working on this, fast!
And I want Colin here.
Where is he? He should have been here.
Where is he?
- He went swimming.
- Swimming?
He should have been here.
Right, I want everyone working.
Razors, you round them all up
and get them moving, fast.
Right, keep them on their toes because
I want this settled, tonight.
And you'd better see your mother.
Yeah.
Listen, if anyone hears anything, anything at all,
I'll be at the Mayfair casino, right?
It's the work of a maniac.
I'll have his carcass dripping blood by midnight.
More bad news...
...Colin.
- Colin?
- Yeah.
He's dead.
I did my national service with Colin
We did 6 months in the glasshouse together.
Two kids of 18, 6 months. They put us right
through it the bastards.
Salisbury Plain manoeuvres.
Used to hump this bleedin' great wireless about.
One window, snow, blizzards,
freezing the bollocks off the ponies.
I got lost.
In them days you stayed lost,
until they nicked you for being AWOL.
And Colin, on a 24 hour pass,
he came out looking for me on his own.
It's lucky he found me or I
would've froze to death.
Yeah.
Colin never hurt a fly...
...well only when it was necessary.
It was always clean, never anything
malicious about Colin.
- Why size him up?
- On my grief.
Sorry, H.
Me and Colin was very close.
I've known him since we was at school.
What's going on?
They try and blow up me mum,
wipe out me best mate...
What are they trying to do?
Put the frighteners on me, wind me up, what?
Harold,
I've kept it all incognito, they're gonna
collect the body in an ice cream van.
There's a lot of dignity in that, isn't there?
Going out like a raspberry ripple.
They're gonna store the body in the
freezer down the abattoir
Alright, granddad.
Thanks for the cool.
- Did anyone see anything?
- Not what happened,
the pool attendant found him but
I told her it was a haemorrhage.
- Good lad.
- Better close the bars, Harold.
No, open up, let 'em enjoy the holiday.
If you hear anything, anything at all,
you give me a bell.
Come on.
- Thank Christ you're here.
- Any news?
Colin's murdered.
- Colin's what?
- Dead.
- Where?
- In the swimming pool.
- Drowned
- Don't be stupid, he did life saving.
What does it all mean, a bomb in here and...
- A what?
- There's a bomb in the casino.
You'd better show us.
I wonder how it got disconnected?
Well the wire must have come loose
when Lou opened it.
Stroke of luck though, innit?
Last night...
...where there any peculiarities?
No, the usual crowd, regular punters,
nothing really.
But no strangers?
A few Arabs, it was a good night,
nothing unusual.
Nothing unusual he says!?
Eric's been blown to smithereens,
Colin's been carved up,
and I've got a bomb in me casino,
and you say nothing unusual?
- Well you know what I mean Harold.
Parky meeting King George V dock now.
He's put out a story the bomb in the car
was a gas leak, it will buy us some time.
Nice one, come here.
There was nothing unusual when I was
in New York, was there?
No, nothing at all.
- Nothing alien
- No.
How much did we pay Parky last year, 20 grand?
- More.
- Right.
Then he can start earning his bloody money.
Who's having a go at me?
Can you think of anybody who might have
an old score to settle, or something?
Who's big enough to take you on?
Well there was a few.
Like who?
Nah, they're all dead.
Let's walk.
We can't have bombs going off Harold,
we can't have corpses,
I had to stick my neck right out to keep
this out of the forensic blokes' hands.
- Did you come up with anything?
- Nothing, I thought you were gonna tell me.
- What, no whispers?
- Nothing, not a thing.
Look at this place.
You know I once caught the pocks
of some Indonesian bird here,
I was just a bobby on the beat then.
So this is where they're gonna build
the 1988 Olympic stadium?
Can you imagine nig-nogs doing the
long jump along these quays?
Stick a rocket up their arsehole,
they'll jump alright.
- I want action on this, Parky.
- The Yanks are clean, we've checked them out.
You got to go down to a third division messenger
to even come up with a sniff of villainy with that lot.
How about Tottenham?
They can't even nick car batteries
without getting electrocuted.
Some of the Clancy mob are out.
This is too accomplished for them.
Besides no one's had their teeth pulled out.
The spades?
Do they overlap?
I've never dealt in narcotics.
I don't know, don't know where
they're after do I?
I'll check it out.
I'm sorry about Colin.
I'll put him on the missing persons list,
that should hold it off for a while.
- Just as well, the commissioner will be poking around.
- Well stall him.
We should have sorted this out
by this afternoon, I'm hoping.
We're looking forward to this this deal
of yours Harold, with the Yanks,
the legitimisation of your corporation.
But we don't like fuss. Calm exteriors.
For 10 years there's been no aggro and it's all been
down to you Harold, you've had it under control.
Now do yourself a favour and get this lot under control
before the heavy mob is on you like a ton of horse shit.
Give us that case.
Get that checked out, will you.
- What is it?
- It's the bomb from the casino.
- Are you riding around with a bleedin' bomb?
- It's alright, it's been disconnected.
- I'll get the bomb people to have a look at it.
- No Parky, get it checked out privately, right?
- Cheers.
I want the name of your top grass.
No way, Harold
- I'll get more out of him than you can.
- That's true.
You do realise how this deal is gonna
be worth in 1988, do you?
Billions.
I'll cut in you in for a percentage
for the name of your grass.
- He trusts me Harold.
- I trust ta.
- I've known him a lot of years.
- Then you should remember his name, shouldn't you?
- If I give it to you...
- No ifs, Parky.
A percentage?
Erroll.
- Erroll the Ponce from Brixton?
- Yeah..
Can't trust nobody, did you hear all that?
Brixton.
Which one's Erroll's house?
Never heard of him, man.
Razors, teach him some respect.
Fucking hell!
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
I don't like people looking up
my nose when I'm talking to them
He could have killed me.
The way it's been going today I'll
probably get you cut price funeral.
Now Erroll's house, which one is it?
Number 33.
This used to be a nice street, this.
Decent families, no scum.
The beauty and the beast - blow his head off.
Are you in training or are you doing this for pleasure?
- We had a party last night.
- Booze, bins and pox.
Harold, get them to take that metal out of my ear.
No, I'm disgusted. Shoot him, let's put some muck
on the ceiling.
Please! What do you want?
Have you seen anything of my Eric flying
past your window about 2 hours ago?
What are you talking about?
Come on, downstairs. Down to the kitchen.
Put some deodorant on, I'm heavily into personal protection.
Filth.
Is there no decency in this disgusting world?
Here, while it's with us,
give yourself another prick.
Tell him what your name is.
Razors.
Otherwise known as Clapham Junction.
Or as the youth of today call him:
The Human Spirograph.
65 inches of stitching.
- Now you're gonna feel what it's like boy.
- He was a very popular fellow.
Harold, what do you want?
I have it from a very reliable source,
that you know what's what,
and you have ears and I wanna
know what you've heard.
Look am I supposed to know something?
Razors.
- What do you know about Colin?
- What about Colin?
I don't know nothing about Colin.
Look Harold, I've been here all night.
Look what's up?
Someone's been playing Guy Fawkes with
my Rolls, that's what's up mate.
What about Eric?
- Eric?
- You heard.
Well he doesn't like Colin.
I mean, queers get right up his hooter, you know?
After what happened this morning
you'd have to find his hooter to get up it.
Is something up with him then?
Well, let's put it this way:
apart from his arsehole being about 50 yards
away from his brains,
and the choirboys playing "'unt the thimble"
with the rest of him, he ain't too happy.
Well I haven't heard anything.
Well use your scarce ears.
Listen Erroll, the only decent grass
is the grass that grasses to me, right?
Harold, if I knew something...
Colin's been stabbed.
Well his boyfriend used to come here to score,
but he never said nothing so I know nothing.
Well a lot of people come here to score
but we sell very good shit.
Like you?
- Who's got it in for me?
- I don't know!.
Cut him.
I still can't hear anything.
I don't fucking know.
- Minded your car, mister.
- You should've asked for the money first.
I could've slashed your tires.
Here you are, don't get drunk.
Little acorns.
Little acorns grow..
Exactly, that's how I started.
- Didn't we all?
- Not Jeff.
Busy getting himself an education, weren't ya?
- Different generation, that's all.
- Billiard halls was my game.
Remember old Sammy?
I tore up 2 of his tables in a week,
he used to pay me not to play.
What do you think?
You told the yanks you control it here,
if they're sticking that many millions in it,
they wanna test if you DO control it.
No it's way off the mark.
They might check books and finances but they aren't going
to wipe out my firm, are they? I don't want anarchy.
These people deserve something better than this.
Not dog shit on the doorstep.
So nothing?
- Not a word, or no one's heard.
- No one's heard nothing?
That just ain't natural.
It's like one of them silent, deadly farts.
No clue, and then pow, you go cross-eyed.
- We've asked all the usual.
- Well maybe it's about time you asked the unusual, innit?
Like who?
- All the chaps are out asking, H.
- Well you've given up?
- Where are they?
- Down the casino.
Well get them of their arses and
make them start again, right?
Go on, what are you waiting for?
- Have you heard from Parky?
- Not yet.
Eugene will phone the minute he checks in.
Razors is back with the car.
Dinner at the pub.
Oh Christ.
Well you got to entertain 'em a bit, haven't ya?
- Are you refreshed?
- You bet, I'm ready for your tightest schedule.
Like you said Charlie, it's not a horse race, relax.
Sorry to hear the news Harold.
Victoria was just telling us about it.
Yes, well she hasn't been well for a long time,
hasn't she? Poor mother.
Don't worry, she'll be alright.
She's a fire, you know.
- I had to spend some time with her, you understand.
- That's nice.
Shall we go, dinner?
It's my favourite pub Charlie,
you're gonna love it, I'll tell ya.
I bought this pub about 2 years ago Charlie
the brewery turned it into slum, it's got real
old London character,
- you'll love it.
- That's nice
- I'm taking the counsellor in the Merc.
- Oh God help me have you seen him drive?
You can always walk, sunshine.
Let me out.
Stay back, stay back.
It might still be dangerous, stay back.
- Are you alright, Pete?
- I'm alright.
- What about your customers?
- I don't know I think they're alright.
It blew up there, there was no one up there.
Jesus.
If we've been 5 minutes earlier...
Yeah.
What the hell's going on?
- Keep it on the sofa.
- Alright.
- What is it, what is it?
- You gotta help Pete, right?
Occupy 'em.
Anything that's necessary
just buy me some time, right?
- Yeah I'll take them to Justine's.
- Terrific.
Get Razors to book a table.
- It was the gas.
- Gas?
This natural gas causes dangerous leaks sometimes.
Harold wants us to go onto a restaurant,
while he's dealing with it.
He'll join us later.
Jeff, stay with Harold will you, I'll drive.
How did he get in here in the first place?
Do you know how many people come up here
during the night?
And nobody spotted nothing, nothing at all?
Nothing happened tonight mate.
Mind you, a couple of days ago two guys came up,
they wanted protection..
I thought they were comedians, they had
big heads, sunglasses,
I thought the agency send them down for cabaret.
Protection, on my boozer?
he actually made threats?
I told 'em to piss off, I took no notice of 'em.
- Much obliged.
- I'm sorry mate, you know...
Didn't wanna worry you, sorry.
Razors, come here.
Get on the trumpet. I want all the corporation...
at the Mayfair Casino in half an hour.
I want them all there, I don't want any excuses.
I'm gonna nail these bastards, right?
- Who are they?
- Well we're gonna find out, aren't we?
It's getting dark, people get frightened
in the dark, they talk, don't they?
Hello Parky,
I'm afraid the business got a little bit burned.
What did these comedians look like?
I don't know H., I've never seen them before,
they just looked like any other micks, heavy micks.
- Micks?
- Yeah, you know, Irish.
Quite hard looking Paddies.
I'd never dream they'd do this, I'm sorry.
Harold.
Irish he said, Irish.
This is Special Branch Harold,
it ain't normal villainy.
- It's indecently abnormal, that was meant for me.
- It's serious.
Listen.
Check out all the micks in the
heavy mob working on my manor.
- I want names and addresses, right?
- Will you listen to what I'm trying to tell you.
- This very serious.
- Oh leave off.
It's just villains trying to
frighten their way into a few quid.
Harold, we're talking about bombs,
two bleedin'bombs.
- Did you get that one checked out by the way?
- Still waiting for the report.
Well get a fucking move on it.
Harold, if those boys are Irish it's a different game,
- now those boys don't know the rules.
- Names and addresses of the micks, right?
Two or three micks have been very busy,
covering a lot of ground here since yesterday,
and not one of you lot has turned up with a thing.
It's impossible no one knows nothing.
Someone, somewhere, knows...
and we're gonna find him..
I want a top capture from every manor,
and I don't want no punters.
This is personal, I want the man who knows...
Right. Who fancies what?
Well me and Chris will take Soho, we're gonna see
Maltese Charlie,
a couple of drinks and he'll talk.
Use that, it's cheaper.
Remember, the license is in the post.
Well, I only use it to get the pigeons
off the caravan roof, don't I?
I don't want want none of you playing
Roy Rogers on this lot, right?
As soon as you finish with 'em,
you give 'em back to Razors.
How about the Finsbury Park hill billies?
- I like the singsong but who do you fancy for a lullaby?
- Well Chopper's in the boob.
Harry and Pinchers?
- Why not?
They're like Siamese twins them two.
Pick 'em up together, the split 'em apart,
we'll interfere with their telepathy, right?
Has anybody seen the major lately?
I heard he's a sick man, bedridden.
It will make a nice change for him, a night out, eh?
Right, arm up and get going.
And use the butcher's truck, right?
Me and Razors will take the trip
to the Elephant and Castle.
- Where do we meet?
- Two hours from now at the abattoir
And remember: scare the shit out of 'em but don't
damage 'em, I want 'em conscious and talkative.
And lads,
try and be discrete, eh?
I think we'd employ your talents better
if you went to help Victoria with the Yanks.
- Are you sure?
- Oh yeah.
Do you reckon...
Colin was jealous of you?
Come again?
Well I was trying to ease him out,
you know how potty he could go.
So?
Well is Colin the reason for all this?
You know how bitchy queers get
when their looks start fading...
I don't know, he wasn't my type.
- How do you stay so cool?
- I'm on the winning side.
Yeah.
- Help Vicky out, right?
- Yeah.
- I want you at the abattoir by midnight, right?
- Alright.
Thank you.
If I knew Mr. Shand wanted this table tonight...
Well there was a change of plan.
You can say that again.
Would you care for a drink before you order?
Charlie?
- Yeah, bourbon on the rocks.
- I'll have the same, please.
A screwdriver, lots of vodka.
A San Pellegrino for me, please.
I think we should skip the flambé cooking,
considering the gas situation in London.
That sort of thing doesn't happen twice in one day.
You should level with us.
We're not just a pair of jerks out of college you know.
No, absolutely not.
Two bombs, that affects everyone.
Let's order, shall we?
Soupe de jour and the chef's special.
I'll have my usual.
No soup, hors d'oeuvres and the special.
I'll have the same.
So Charlie, how did you know about the bombs?
It's our business to know these things.
A bottle of champagne, very cold.
Harold has got bad problems.
- But he's dealing with them right now.
- He's been dealing with them all day.
- He's very thorough.
- I like your loyalty.
I'm being frank.
Victoria, unless you tell us what Harold's bad
problems are and how he's dealing with them...
...I'm gonna tell you what we're gonna do...
Tony and me we're gonna leave the table,
check out of the Savoy,
grab the first plane home...
there will be no deal.
It's not a good idea to bullshit us, Victoria.
Cheers.
Well?
A car was blown up,
then a bomb was found at the Mayfair Casino,
it hadn't detonated.
- One of our men was found dead in a swimming pool.
- Yeah, he was stabbed.
I'm giving Charlie all the essential details.
Well I think that is an essential detail.
An auto, casino, a stabbing, a bar blown up...
- What is this, a gang war?
- No, no question.
Then what?
Isn't it obvious Charlie?
This deal is very big, someone is envious.
Harold and I have no doubt that by tomorrow
the problem will be settled.
- You sound very confident.
- I am.
Tony, you're the lawyer, tell me what you're thinking?
I think we can afford to give you 24 hours to resolve
your problems before we make a final decision.
OK Victoria, I'll give you until tomorrow.
But just one more foul up and
we're on our way back home.
That goes without saying.
- Nothing personal Victoria, but business is business.
- I understand.
Harold what are you doing on this side of the river?
- Hi, Billy.
- Scotch?
- Sorry to hear about your mother.
The car blew up, that's what I heard.
- Have you got a spot of bother?
- No.
The music's loud here, innit?
- I'll get him to turn it down a bit.
- No, listen, Billy.
I've got a little bit of business I want to
drop you all by, can we talk in the other bar?
- Right.
- Nice one.
Jimmy,  bring the drinks around the back.
Everybody's American, ombrero,
- If there's anything going, put me in.
- Well there's plenty of money for everybody,
- I just need the right people you know what I mean?
- Well I'm your man...
Alternate car Billy or I'll blow your spine off.
It's not a shooter is it Harold?
Don't be silly Billy, would I come
hunting for you with me fingers?
If you're looking to make an investment,
you've come to the right place.
It's all gonna happen, with or without Harold.
My hotels are gonna be there!
Will you get us a cab to the Savoy?
I'll show you the plans tomorrow.
Magnificent.
Pie in the sky hotels, if you know what I mean,
something to be proud of.
Yes I think it's time we all went home, don't you?
No, Victoria, Charlie understands, right?
We're two of a kind me and him.
We had to claw our way out from the gutter.
We're self-made men, right Charles?
I don't think Mr. Restivo is as familiar
with the gutter as you assume.
If you don't watch your fucking step counsellor,
you'll be right back in it.
Come on Vicky, don't be like that.
I'll tell you what...
...we'll have some more brandy's at the bar
and I'll tell you all about my plans, Charlie.
Don't be hostile, Vicky.
- Jeff.
- Hello Jeff.
Charlie.
Tony.
- everything alright?
- You tell me...
I've put our American friends
in the picture about today, Jeff.
Then you'll understand why Harold couldn't make it.
It's all under control.
I'm sure Harold Shand can find a way out of this one.
Meantime, I'm going to take a piss.
Stay right where you are folks.
- That guy's a loud-mouth
- I don't like drunks.
Do you trust him?
Harold can handle him.
A city counsellor is a very wise investment at the moment.
- We'll talk out that tomorrow. Good night Victoria.
- Good night.
Good night.
- Thanks for the dinner.
- Good night, Charlie.
Good night.
Oh Christ am I pleased to see you.
That bloody Harris is a liability.
Any news yet?
No, not yet.
Where have the Yanks gone?
I've just bought some more brandy's.
Go home , Harris. Go home.
Don't look down your nose at me Victoria, makes you go cross-eyed.
You can't even see that I'm not the real bastard, he is.
Aren't you?
I'll get you a cab home, counsellor.
I'll talk to you later.
OK,
bastard.
God, I don't think I've ever been
so pleased to see anyone in my life.
It's been hard night.
You did a good job.
Without the help of counsellor Harris.
He fancies you, you know...
...then a lot of people do.
Must be my sparkling personality.
I'll see you to your door, just in case.
Thanks.
If you miss it, it's unlucky.
It won't move unless you press the button, you know.
It's not moving.
It's temperamental, I'll do it.
I hate lifts.
Gets really claustrophobic in here with a lot of people.
Depends on the people.
I wanna lick every inch of you.
Saved by the bell. Good night.
Bastard.
It's a long time since I went to a funeral.
That's a strange thing. Did Jeff tell you
about the funeral the day you got back?
A funeral every half hour down the East India Dock Road.
A woman got out of the funeral car and gobbed at him.
- Eh?
- I didn't see it properly, H.
I didn't crack on.
You're gonna love this here.
You will gonna love this.
Shut up all of ya!
For more than ten years there's been peace
everyone to his own patch.
We've all had it sweet.
I've done every single one of you
favours in the past
I've put money in all your pockets,
I've treated you lot  well, even when you was out of order, right?
even when you was out of order, right?
Well now there's been an eruption.
It's like fuckin' Belfast on a bad night.
One of my closest friends is lying out there in the freezer.
And believe me, all of you...
...nobody goes home until I find out who done it, and why.
Harold believe me, if I knew I'd say.
the last thing I want is any trouble.
- Everything's going too well for us.
- You lying bastard.
Look things have never been so good between
South London and East End.
You bastard.
Get him out of here.
Bastard.
Jeff, you behave yourself!
Right lads, it's your decision.
Frostbite or verbals, one of them two, right?
- What's the matter with you?
- Listen.
Listen.
If you kill him, we've got a gang war on our hands, right?
We already have. They're walking all over you.
That's 'cause we ain't got no lead!
Parky. About time.
- Well?
- You've got to drop it Harold,
it's not that lot.
- I've had the bomb checked.
- And?
It's the same sort of device the IRA use.
This is Special Branch now, Harold.
I'm turning it over to them.
What do the Irish got to do with me,
it's just a bunch of hoods trying to muscle in.
For Christ sake Harold, they're not just gangsters.
They run half of Londonderry on terror,
could be London next.
- No, I run London.
- Not now Harold, they're taking it away from you.
It's Special Branch now and I'm getting out.
Remember who pays your wages Parky,
you ain't going nowhere.
Now tell me something worthwhile
There was a robbery at counsellor Harris'
demolition yard, explosives.
We pulled in the security guard, Flynn.
We grilled him for hours,
but he just wouldn't crack, he was too scared.
Alan, check out this geezer Flynn, bring him in.
Harold you can't do that!
Don't you ever tell me what I can or can't do.
Bent law can be tolerated for as long as they're
lubricating, but you have become definitely parched.
If I was you, I'd run for cover and close the hatch,
cause you're gonna wind up on one of
those meat hooks, my son.
Right, let 'em go, they don't know nothing.
Jeff, clean 'em up and get them off and
give them a grand each expenses, just keep 'em sweeped.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna go home, I need some time to think.
Alan, first thing in the morning that
security geezer, right?
Razors, come on son.
Dave, do as he says, put 'em in a bubble bath.
- Eh?
- You heard.
Let's go lads.
How did it go with Charlie?
Well I stopped him going home.
- Going home?
- Yeah they were going home, they're not stupid.
They knew it was a bomb,
and now they now the rest.
- How?
- I told them.
- You did what?
- I told them everything, Harold.
I had to.
Victoria,
listen sweetheart,
I'm setting up the biggest deal in Europe,
with the hardest organization since Hitler
stuck as swastika on his jockstrap.
I've been through incredible lengths
all day to keep it incognito,
and now you, over a sherry,
calmly told the whole story.
I had to tell them everything
or the deal would have finished.
Howard, your trouble is you just
don't understand their psychology.
Bollocks you smart ass prat.
I can't talk to you.
I'm going to bed, good night.
Come here I'm talking to you!
Don't treat me like one of your thugs.
What's happening to me?
I'm sorry.
For 10 years it's been calm, no trouble.
And now this.
Listen I wouldn't hurt you for the world, come here.
I'm sorry.
I'm so scared Harold.
I don't want to die,
don't let them kill us.
Alright.
It's alright.
It will be alright, believe me.
What is it, boy?
For Christ sake,
Help me..
Sherry.
I'm sorry, H.
It's alright Alan it's not your fault,
you weren't to blame.
There's some fresh coffee in the kitchen,
go make yourself some breakfast.
Ta.
So someone got to him before you could.
How did they know?
- Or was it a coincidence?
- That's stretching it a bit, innit?
That means it's someone close to home.
You know last night in the restaurant
I had a funny feeling.
Harris being really strange.
he said something to Jeff,
just as we were leaving.
He said that I got it all wrong,
that Jeff was the real bastard.
Why should he say that?
Razors.
That funeral you were talking about...
something about a bird gobbing in Jeff's face.
That's right.
Find that woman, I wanna talk to her.
Well get her name and address off the undertakers.
How do I know, I wasn't there, was I?
Look it up in the Yellow pages there can't be
that many undertakers in the area.
Right. And as soon as you've found her,
come and pick me up.
Right. I'll see you. Ta.
Mrs. Benson?
You're a bastard, Harold Shand.
A vicious bastard.
You left him to die in a stinking ditch,
and didn't have the decency to...
- When did he die?
- Ten days ago, you should know.
Where?
Belfast.
Belfast?
- What was he doing there?
- That Jeff Hughes sent him.
- What?
- He was hired.
The blond one, that Colin, always asked him
to do the chauffeuring on the long runs.
- A chauffeur?
- A mini cab.
Your husband drove Colin...
and he got topped in Belfast?
Yes, left there.
I was left with all the arrangements,
to bring the body back here...
and not so much as a penny for me and the kids.
And Jeff Hughes hired him?
Yes.
- And that bastard hasn't payed me any compensation.
- Alright, alright.
You'll get some compensation,
the corporation will look after you.
- Is there anything you need?
- I'll need a 100 quid a week.
Alright.
Anything else you want?
I just want him back.
Get him a decent stone, send me the bill.
- Drink?
- Yeah.
- Do you ever worry about your liver?
- No, we're just good friends.
My mum used to have a go at my old man about
his boozing and he always used to say:
"If you drink less than your doctor, you're alright."
It's hot in here, shall we go on deck?
Hot?
Are you hot?
This will cool you down.
What did you want to talk about?
Shouldn't we be well...
with what's going on...
Everything's alright.
Alright?
I'm using the word the way you use it.
What?
Alright?
I remember vividly when you met me at
Heathrow of the plane form New York...
I said how's things been,
and you said "Alright".
- I'm not with you.
- Aren't ya?
Top that?
Quite frankly, I'm a bit flabbergasted...
you forgot to mention this carry on
in Belfast while I've been away.
Ah, that.
Yeah, that.
What about this mini cab driver, Phil Benson?
He's...
Well he was a friend of Colin's.
He got killed.
It's a long story.
- I know I should've told you, but...
- Well tell me now.
What the bloody hell was Colin doing
with a Lime'ouse mini cab driver in Belfast?
Colin can't drive.
Ah, that makes sense.
Second question: Belfast, what was he doing there?
I know Colin fancied soldiers,
but that's taking his buggery a bit far, innit?
- He had to make a delivery.
- A delivery of what?
Come on I'm curious...
what Chieftain tanks, bars of
chocolate, Fiesta Durex's, what?
- Money.
- Well ain't they got any banks out there?
Well what money, what for and who to?
He was delivering for Harris.
He had a problem.
He was being leant on to deliver,
deliver money I mean to Belfast.
Leant on by who?
He's got a 100 micks on his labour force,
he's without business without them.
He was being leant on to organise a delivery.
He asked me.
So you got my Colin to deliver for Harris money to Belfast?
Yeah.
Well that is irregular.
I don't approve of my men delivering funds for the IRA.
He had no choice, he has to do what they ask,
otherwise his buildings don't get built.
That's why he never has a strain, that's why we use Harris.
Jesus Christ!
Of all the faces here you could have used,
of all of them...
you have to pick Colin for a job like that?
So he took a dip, yeah?
Yeah, he stupidly helped himself.
How much?
- 5.000.
- What?
You mean all this anarchy is for 5 poxy grand?
And three of their top men where wiped out,
The night Colin delivered.
So they put 2 and 2 together and come up
with the answer, didn't they?
'cause Colin's my man, it's down to me.
I'm the one that's grassed them up aren't I?
This is all revenge.
Yeah.
Revenge.
I'll fucking show them.
That security guard, he could
give us a clue, couldn't he?
- Did he say anything?
- Nah not much when Alan got to him.
No?
Alan found him dying,
he'd been nailed to the floor.
- When was this then?
- It must have been just after you saw him and before Alan saw him.
Otherwise you would've  noticed, wouldn't you?
I mean a geezer nailed to the floor,
a man of your education would definitely
have spotted that, wouldn't he?
Traitor! Fucking Judas!
I didn't do nothing.
Maybe you didn't nail the geezer, but it's
down to you all the same, isn't it?
- It had nothing to do with me.
- Don't lie to me boy,
I can smell your lies and all,
I can smell your greed, ambition,
a disgusting like betrayal.
Why Jeff?
Why?
He threatened to kill me, I was scared.
- You put the finger on me, didn't you?
- No I didn't. It was Harris.
For micks, prick hard micks,
red-neck terrorist scum.
Blame me, blame Colin.
Revenge?
It's me who's gonna take revenge.
I'll crush them like beetles.
- Never.
- You watch, I'm gonna annihilate them.
- You can't wipe them out.
- You just watch me.
Kill 10, 20 bring out the tanks
and the flame-throwers,
They pour back. It's like an army of ants.
Work with them.
- It's my manor!
- Jesus Christ.
The British Army has been diving a battle
shit-frying at them from all angles,
- and you're not impressed?
- Shut up.
They can take over here any time they want.
- Just shut up.
- You wont'stop them.
To them you're nothing, nothing,
a shit on their shoes.
Jeff. He was with Harris.
They sold me out.
I'm gonna kill him.
Razors!
- Razors!
- Harold!
Take it easy.
- Calm down..
- Give me the gun.
You've got Harris, right?
You've got him.
Now you use him. You use him to stop
this bloody havoc, right?
- Counsellor Harris' office please.
- I'll show you the way.
- Thank you.
- He's on the second floor.
- A friend of yours, sir?
- Yes a very old friend, yeah.
Nice fellow isn't he?
And a hard worker.
Has been on all that bloody phone all afternoon.
- He has done a lot for the Irish community around here, hasn't he?
- So they tell me.
You know it's 3 weeks since they turned
over the pages of the Book of Remembrance,
there's a work to rule.
I said to the Union bloke, I said it's
a good job they didn't work to rule in 1418
in the trenches in France.
- Is this it?
- Are you gonna need me to show you the way down again?
- No, I think I can manage, thanks a lot.
Harold.
How unexpected.
Harold call it off!
You can't do it.
You can't deal with these people.
For Christ sake, they're not interested in money.
They're political, they're fanatics!
Come on, George.
Come in.
O'Flaherty, Harold Shand.
There's 60 grand here.
- To make sure there's no more hard feelings.
- Gonna have to wait and see the boss about that.
Where is he?
He's out there. Last race.
He'll be back in a minute.
This is Mr. Shand.
He's brought the money and he wants an answer.
- How much is that?
- 60 grand, it's in the case.
You'd better count it.
If you don't mind, I will.
You wait here, I'll got and get them,
I won't be a minute
Mr. Restivo?
Where's Charlie?
Everything's alright.
All the troubles are over.
What did he say?
Sorry, Harold.
But I'm glad you dropped in to say
goodbye, that's real nice.
- What are you leaving?
- Yeah.
- You're not going back to New York?
- Next flight out.
Come on, Charlie
I know we've had a few problems, we've only
been here a couple of days.
Yeah a couple of days that turned out to be
another St. Valentines Massacre.
But that settled it, once and for all.
Yes, I'd like a porter to suite 513 please,
and we'd like a cab right away.
Thank you.
You two can't wait to get out of here, can you?
I always react like that to bombs blowing up, mass murders...
It's a hang-up of mine.
It's coming to something when the Mafia
can't handle a little problem, innit?
A little problem?
Tony did you hear what he said?
A little problem...
This is like a bad night in Vietnam
But it's over, I've pulled the plug on 'em.
We do not deal with gangsters, period.
This country is a worse risk than Cuba was.
It's a banana republic.
You're a mess.
Ciao, Harold.
Bon voyage then.
I'll tell you something...
I'm glad I found out in time just what a partnership
with a pair of wankers like you would've been.
A sleeping partner's one thing,
but you're in a fucking coma!
No wonder you got an energy crisis
your side of the water!
But us British, we're used to a bit more
vitality, imagination,
touch of the Dunkirk spirit, know what I mean?
The days when Yanks could come over 'ere...
and buy up Nelson's Column...
an 'arley street surgeon and a couple'a Windmill
Girls are definitely over!
- Now look...
- Shut up you long streak of paralysed piss.
What I’m looking for is someone who can contribute
to what England has given to the world:
culture, sophistication, genius. A little bit more
than an 'ot dog, know what I mean?
We’re in the Common Market now, a
and my new deal is with Europe,
I’m going into partnership with a German
organisation. Yeah! The Krauts!
they've got ambition, know-how,
and they don’t lose their bottle.
Look at you...
The Mafia?
I've shit 'em.
Hey hold up, where's Victoria?