One, two.
One, two, three.
Let's go, let's go, let's go,
let's go, let's go!
-Watch out, it's hot.
-Thank you, honey.
Leave it right there.
-No, no, no.
-Come on.
-Wait for Leo.
-Get out of here, Bernard.
-We're waiting for your cousin.
-I'm hungry.
He's real good-looking.
You're going to like him.
I am? You think so?
I know so.
I know these things.
I'm blessed with a gift.
Careful, it's hot!
-I got it.
-Val, this all looks wonderful.
Let's try and make a
little more room.
What about your husband?
ls he coming?
Frank can't come.
I meant to tell you.
He's going to meet Leo
tomorrow at the interview.
Okay.
Well...
at least Bernard's eating.
Hey, sweetie.
-Hod you doing?
-Good.
Eric, you know Belvee? Belva.
Belva. Nice.
-Hey.
I told her about your cousin Leo.
I want her to meet him.
Oh, yeah?
Hey, everybody!
-He's here.
-Hey!
Hey, Ma.
You good?
Yeah, I'm good.
-You look terrific.
-Thanks. You too.
-I'm so glad you're home.
-Me too.
Hey, Leo!
Leo the lion!
We all came to see you!
How you doing?
-I'm all right.
-I love you, man.
-Welcome home.
-Thanks.
-It's good to see you.
-You too.
How you doing?
-Welcome home.
-What's up, Dante?
-You look great.
-What's up, Todd?
-What's up, Leo?
-Neil.
You guys look like
you're doing good.
Don't worry. It'll come
your way soon.
I want you to meet Belva.
-Belva, this is Leo.
-Hi.
-Belva's a dancer.
We've got so much food.
-Everybody, let's eat.
-Just dig in.
Help yourselves.
Mr. Handler.
Where can we go
over a few things?
In the bedroom.
Come on.
My records show you
were released...
-at 4:00 this afternoon.
-That's right.
You're supposed to make
an arrival report.
Nobody told me.
I thought I had 24 hours.
Okay...
in the future you're re requested
to report with diligence.
Your profile says you
had some problems.
That you served 1 6
months for auto theft.
Your parole status...
has you on intensive supervision.
I'll have access to your bank
records, w-2s, pay stubs.
To keep track of your cash flow.
What about employment?
Know what you're gonna do?
I think I got something.
What's that?
My aunt's new husband has a
business. He's very important.
I'm interviewing with him tomorrow.
A couple of my friends have
been working for him.
What about your counseling?
I don't want to cause no problems.
I just want to be a productive
person again in society.
What do you think? He looks
good? He looks good.
I never knew him from before.
That's the point.
I have nothing to go by.
Hey.
-Everything okay?
-Yeah.
How come you're not out there?
Willie's talking with everybody
and I wanted...
to get away for a second.
-You and him still okay?
-Yeah.
We're thinking of settling down...
but he's so busy with
work right now.
I was sorry to hear
about your father.
He was a good man.
-We should go back out.
-Erica.
You like your new father?
He's all right.
Did you get my letters?
They must've forgot to
switch the fuse box.
There you are.
-Hi, Ma.
-Looks like a blackout.
Yeah.
Why don't you let
your cousin be?
See if they need something.
Excuse me. Aunt Kitty?
Yeah?
I wanted to thank you
and your husband for
the meeting tomorrow.
I'd do anything for your mother.
She's not doing too well.
You should know that.
Her heart is getting weaker.
-Here he is!
-Leo!
Hey, Leo.
What's up, buddy?
-You all right?
-Yeah, cool.
-Did you get a beer?
-I'm all right.
Me and the guys really
appreciate what you did.
-Don't say nothing to the cops.
-I'd never fold on you.
I want you to come...
work with us. When you
see Frank, tell him that.
-All right.
-Good.
-Come have a beer.
-You've had enough for everybody.
No.
We're going to the club this
weekend, like we used to.
-That sounds excellent.
-Be good.
-Leo, what's going on?
-You don't say hi?
You look good.
Excuse me, everyone.
Everyone!
I'm very happy to
have you all here.
And...
the last few years have been...
sometimes not so easy.
But that's all over now.
And so, from now on...
we'll have nothing
but good times.
That's all I wanted to say.
-Hear, hear.
-Absolutely.
Thanks.
Let's have some coffee,
if I can find the pot.
Ma...
I wanted to say that I'm sorry..
for everything.
Don't worry about it.
Go be with your friends.
Have a good time.
What's up, Todd?
-Leo, sit down.
-How you doing?
Bye, Denise.
My best to your mother.
Send him in, Denise.
Leo.
Nice to finally meet you.
-Nice to me you too.
-Sorry you had to wait.
-Sit down.
-Thanks.
So, uh...
how's your mother?
She's okay. She's trying.
She's battling.
We had nice conversations
about you.
She's a wonderful woman.
Supporting you by herself...
took a lot of guts.
I know.
I'll do everything I can
to make it up to her.
My wife and I tried to
help her out but...
she won't take it.
I admire that. The last 2 years
have been hard on her.
You got yourself in trouble.
-Stole a couple of cars...
-Yeah.
You did a little time, though.
I know it's tough in there,
but...
the business world ain't
much different.
You got to have eyes in the
back of your fucking head.
So, you know what
we do here?
If it's on a train or N.Y. subway,
we make or fix it.
Couplers, brakes, transformers,
everything.
-Got experience with that stuff?
-I could learn.
Learn... good.
There's training programs
out there for machinists.
I could make a call.
I need to support me and
my mother right now.
How long would a program take?
Good machinist?
Couple of years.
But you get a good union
job when you're through.
Four, five hundred a week.
And...
I could help you along
till you graduate.
What about Willie?
He didn't go to school.
Maybe I could work with him.
That's not a good idea for you.
What does he do?
He deals with suppliers mostly.
I really think you should
look into a program.
I'd have to think about that.
All right.
Why don't your mother
and you come over...
Saturday night for dinner?
The whole family will be there.
It'll be nice.
Okay.
Leo.
Thanks for coming,
and look...
you're a nephew now
and I'd like to help you.
-Ricky!
-Willie, what's up?
This is my friend, Leo.
Leo, Ricky.
-We studied together.
-Cool.
Thanks for Russell.
I like the system...
he put in for me.
I like the way it sounds.
-I told you, he's the best.
-You did.
-What do you want?
-Give me 2 Millers...
Jim Bean and rum and Coke.
Put it on my tab.
Willie, I don't know what
the fuck I'm gonna do.
About what?
Frank?
Yeah.
You don't have to go back to
school. He tried that shit on me.
I convinced him.
Let me work with the suits.
How did you do that?
He let me hang out and
I earned their respect.
You're throwing money around.
What do you do for this guy?
Come with me tomorrow
and see for yourself.
If you like it,
we'll talk to Frank.
I'm just asking. I can't
get into any trouble.
You won't get into trouble.
I won't let you.
Frank's a great man.
We got a real chance with him.
My mother spent her fuckin'
life on handouts and shit.
Now I got fucking money.
The sky's the limit.
You was always good with people.
I'm not too good with words.
You're my best friend.
I'll look out for you,
get you in.
I hoe it works out.
I'd like that a lot.
-I want to work with you.
-Great, next week.
What do you think about Belva?
She's good from far,
but far from good.
-Your cousin's beautiful!
-Yeah, she is.
Leo! Come on, dance!
Come on!
Come on! Dance!
Raise yourhands.
Empty your pockets.
Okay, you're all right.
Go ahead.
-Thanks, Glenn.
-All right, Willie.
You got a lot of
fuckin' security here.
-Is it all right coming with you?
-Yeah, you're fine.
They all know me here.
-What is this place?
-This is Borough Hall.
The train businesses
live and die here.
Today we're aftercontracts
worth $14 million.
It'll be a fuckin' fight.
All ourrivals are here.
Our main competition...
is the Weltech Corporation.
It's run by Manny Sequiera
and Hector Gallardo.
A minority company so they're
guaranteed 10% ofthe business.
Frank says Sequiera paid off2
councilmen to get that deal.
Paul Lazarides works
right underFrank.
He makes ourpresentations
to the TransitAuthority.
The head ofthe Authority
is AI Granada.
I keep him happy so he'll keep
sending the work our way.
I look okay?
I don't want to call attention.
You look great.
Let's go in.
We now come up
on order 4-2-3-9-9...
regarding the replacement
of rectifiers...
on the Queens and Bronx lines.
After careful review...
weighing price and
performance ratings...
the committee has decided...
to award the contract to the
Electric Rail Corp. of Maspeth.
Make a note of that.
Next, order 4-6-9-6-4.
For 230 couplers,
all for the subway...
-Mr. Supervisor, please.
-Hector, let me finish.
-It's part of our guarantee.
-I'm sorry. You're wrong.
We get the rectifiers is the deal.
Hector, let me finish, please.
They know it.
The deal for minority
quotas is 10%.
Which 10% is up to us.
If it were up to me,
Weltech wouldn't get anything.
Your failure rate is
through the roof!
-Because of them.
-Let me finish.
They're trying to put us
out and you're a part of it.
We want to make a protest
with the inspector general.
There have been several
investigations...
into the allegations
made by Weltech.
And we have been repeatedly
cleared of any wrongdoing.
They know this.
But they persist with these
outrageous accusations.
And I think they owe
us an apology.
-I owe you an apology?
-Yes.
-Let's get on.
-Asshole!
-Gonna give me the finger?
-Yeah, that's right.
I'll kick you right into
the middle of next week.
-Let's go, old man.
-What do you think I'm doing?
Running some sort of 3-ring
circus? Come on.
Gutierrez.
I don't know what you mean.
Why not work for us instead
of those "cabrones"?
Don't waste my time.
Let's go.
Who's this?
That's Leo.
You'll get to know him.
I'm not in a mood to
make new friends.
All right.
-Who's that?
-Frank's nephew.
Did he do time?
Yeah, just a little bit.
He's a good kid.
Got the money?
Say hello to your uncle for me.
-See you, Willie.
-Take it easy.
What the fuck was that?
Nothing. He's just...
very worried about wires.
Or he's got a thing for me.
It seems pretty fucking weird.
He get a cut of everything?
Don't worry about it.
He's a city official.
It's the way the system works.
But here's the good part.
This is for you.
Pretty good?
A little pocket change.
You've saved up a lot.
I spend it all on your cousin.
We got a few more things
to do this week.
Next week I'll take you
into the tunnels.
-That sounds good.
-All right.
Let's go do it.
In this business, favors are
more important than threats.
It's about making people
feel wanted and liked...
to feel appreciated.
Find out what they like,
and make it happen.
They want to go to a
ball game ora show...
get them the tickets.
They want something for
their wife orgirlfriend...
get them a nice fur.
Sometimes all the want
is some expensive wine.
Ifthey want cash...
there's always plenty.
Ifyou take care ofthem...
this business takes care ofyou.
Just don't spread it
all in one place.
Leo, are you ready?
We got to go soon.
Ma.
I got you something.
You don't have to get me anything.
I wanted to.
-I thought you needed it.
-Leo, you can't.
Every dollar is saved,
you know that.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Come on, Frank is
sending a car for us.
All right.
I'm going to change...
real quick.
That's it.
That's their house.
Bernard, get the door.
Mom, I'm already sitting down.
-Sorry we're late.
-Here they are.
You're not late.
The food just got here.
-Good.
-Come in, sit down.
Sit over there?
-Yeah?
-Sit over here, Leo.
-Good.
-Hi, Bernard.
-Nice house.
-Thanks. Glad you like it.
We're doing work on it.
I'm building a family room.
Those assholes wake us
every morning.
-Is that absolutely necessary?
-Don't start.
-Ma, could I have some lo mein?
-Frank...
this looks delicious.
-They got great food.
-It's a little rich sometimes.
This is Bernie's dish.
Give it to him.
Pass the rice when you're finished?
-Thanks, Mom.
-Thanks.
Leo...
did you tell your mother
what we talked about?
-What was that?
-I told him he should look into...
some training program
as a machinist.
That sounds fantastic.
I went with Willie and am
thinking of working with him.
Yeah, I know.
I want to talk to you about that.
That sounds good.
Two of them working together.
I don't understand. I thought
we had this conversation.
I'm not comfortable
taking your money.
Money?
We've been through this.
Nobody's giving us any money.
-Why can't they work together?
-Erica.
It's all right.
Leo, I hope everything
works out for you...
and you'll be around.
Maybe you'll learn something.
I really hope so.
Good.
Okay. Good.
Clean plate club, okay?
Got the hot mustard there?
Got to have the hot mustard.
It's all here.
Erica.
What?
-I want to show you something.
-What?
What is it?
Open it.
Oh, Willie.
We'll tell everyone this week.
I want to make this right.
I love you.
Where we going?
To the Sunnyside Yards.
The guys are there waiting for us.
There's someone
I want you to meet.
What are we going to do there?
We take out our competitor's
trains.
Short their stuff, makes
sure it don't work.
They get his as unreliable,
we get the jobs.
Tonight it's Weltech's trains.
The guys we had the run-in
with at Borough Hall.
Stand back and watch tonight.
Everything'll be all right.
-Boys, what's going on?
-What's up, Dante?
-What's going on?
-Hey, Todd.
Hey, Leo.
Raymond, that's Leo.
-How you doing?
Good.
He's coming with me
to make a drop.
You ever in Local
One or Three?
No.
We don't deal with construction.
I don't know nothing about that.
You're here because your
friends clear you.
We're going down.
Leo, stay here.
-Make sure nobody comes down.
-Okay, I'll hang right here.
Got you those Knicks tickets.
This if for you.
I don't want it.
Get your guys off the tracks.
What?
You're out.
Weltech come last week and
put 2 K right here.
And they got the muscle
to back it up.
You know how this works.
You get a better offer,
you come back at us.
Not anymore.
Electric Rail's going under,
and Weltech matches any offer.
Get them off the track, I got
the cops coming down here.
Keep going!
Come on, Elliot.
You wouldn't do this to me.
What are you doing?
Jump!
Willie!
Will
What are you doing?
-Nothing.
-What do you mean nothing?
You a troublemaker?
I ought to crack your fuckin' head.
Turn that off.
-What you gonna do?
-Turn that...
fuckin' thing off.
I'm talking to you.
You got some ID?
Don't fucking do it.
Put your hands up.
Turn around.
-You motherfucker!
-I didn't do nothing!
You want to run? I ought to
break you down, motherfucker.
-Hello?
-Mrs. Handler.
Is Leo there?
I'm here, Ma, you can hang up.
Leo
-I didn't mean to do it.
-Willie, what happened?
-You said everything'd be okay.
-I know..
Everything got fucked up.
Did anyone see you?
What didyou do?
A cop come down and beat
me on my fucking head.
-You okay?
-Yeah, but the cop...
All right, we can'tpanic.
I'll talk to Frank, he'll
know what to do.
Don't worry, Leo.
The borough can't afford
an investigation.
The fucking politicians are in
on it. You understand?
I understand.
Willie?
Hey.
I didn't know you
were here tonight.
I had to get out of
the fucking house.
Who's that?
-Who is it?
-Raymond.
What the fuck happened?
I can't talk now.
Get the guys.
We'll meet back at the
office tonight. All right?
Is that blood?
It's nothing.
I cut myself.
Go on.
-Who was that?
-Someone from work.
-Now?
-Don't worry. Go back to sleep.
Hello?
Hold on.
-Who is it?
-I don't know.
-Yeah?
-You had trouble this morning?
-Who is this?
-The yardmasteris dead.
And that cop may
not make it either.
Hector, is that you?
You come forward.
Weltech has very good lawyers.
Don't call here again.
What does everybody want?
I'm sorry, it's so crazy.
I didn't know you'd be there.
I can't wait till we get married.
I'll tell my mother...
and we'll get married.
We going to have a
whole family.
-What's the matter?
-Nothing.
I'm tired.
You got a meeting.
We already got enough
problems with the minorities.
Conglomerates defense lose
contracts, they're back in trains.
We understand, but there's
nothing we can do now.
I'm getting squeezed
from all sides.
You got conglomerates taking
the work from the top.
Minorities get the bottom work.
I'm squeezed in the middle.
Frank, take it easy.
-Wait till after the election.
-Why after?
After this election,
the next election.
Be patient, Frank.
You listen to me.
You got to kill those minority
quotas or I'm out of business.
It's that simple.
It's too hot for us right now.
This...
killing in the yards.
Where's that going to go?
-You know anything, Frank?
-No. But if it were...
one of my guys,
I'd kill them.
That cop's still alive, Frank.
He's in a coma.
If he pulls through...
and it turns out to be the
business, hell will break loose.
The cops'll be all over us.
No way we could control it.
Can't do anything for me
and the quotas?
-Times are changing.
-Who is it?
-It's me.
-Hey, Willie.
What do you need?
I want to talk to you.
I'm very busy right now.
It's no big deal.
I can take care of it.
All right.
Good.
I'm telling you my company's
in serious trouble.
A Metropolitan Community
Transit workeris dead...
and a cop is in a coma
aftera pre-dawn attack...
at the Sunnyside Yards
in Queens.
OfficerRifkin responded to
an alarm call at the yards...
just after 1:00 this morning.
10 minutes later, backup units
discovered OfficerRifkin...
face down and unconscious.
The body ofyardmasterElliot
Gorwitz was also found...
bled to death from a
single stab wound.
Gorwitz had worked for
the M.C. T. for 14 years.
Queens borough presidentArthur
Mydanick was shocked...
and saddened by the incident.
Ofcourse I was very upset
over this.
We won't stand for these attacks.
Finding the assailants is
at the top ofouragenda.
OfficerRifkin remains in
critical condition...
andpolice are still without
a suspect.
I need milk.
-I'll get it, Aunt Val.
-Thanks, honey.
-You still go to Waldbaum's?
-Yeah, sometimes.
-Loe, is that for you?
-Yeah, I got it, Ma.
What's going on?
We got to talk.
The guys are downstairs.
-Let me get my jacket.
-Willie!
We're having cake.
Come in.
Thank you, Mrs. Handler.
I can't right now.
Erica's here.
-Won't you come in?
-Come on in.
I didn't know you were here.
Yep.
Hi.
-Hi, Mrs. Olchin.
-You look handsome tonight.
Thank you.
-Excuse me, I got to run.
-No, Willie, come here.
-Hey, baby...
-Come here.
Ma.
Willie and me...
talked about getting married.
-When did this happen?
-We talked...
Iast night.
What about school?
I'm still going to finish.
That a very big step.
Don't you think we should...
discuss it?
Will, is that them?
Yeah.
No, thanks.
I really got to go.
I didn't know we were
going to get into this.
I think we should discuss it.
Will, they're waiting.
Sorry.
Let's go.
Hey, Leo.
I got a call from Weltech.
That guy Hector.
They heard about what happened.
The want to offer me protection
if I talk to their lawyers.
They'd do anything
to get Frank.
Don't you fucking
turn on me, Willie.
Of course not.
I hung up on the fucking guy.
I'm just saying...
we got to stay tight here.
Listen to what the guys say.
Just listen to what
they have to say.
We're in a very tough
situation.
-What's p, Todd?
-What's going on?
Get in the back.
That cop you hit?
He's a fucking problem.
Ifhe wakes up,
we're all in trouble.
We don't know whatyou'd
do to stay out ofjail.
-I wouldn't fuck you.
-Yeah...
but you get caught
now, and it's life.
Will, you know I
wouldn't do that.
What happened? I thought
you'd talk to Frank.
Frank's got no pull
with the police.
He's on the 4th floor at
Booth Memorial.
4 beds to a room.
Todd's friend's an orderly,
he works night shift.
He'll get you in.
They got one officer
in front of the ward.
He's on an 8-hour shift.
Wait till he takes a leak...
then go inside.
The guy's a fucking cop.
Nobody wants this, Leo.
It's the only thing we can do.
I don't know if I could.
You think about it.
The only thing that
cop saw was you.
If you can't take care of this,
we got to take care of it.
We're not going after that
cop, you understand?
You guys wait here.
Todd's gonna talk to this guy.
Come on.
Leo...
if anything happens...
if anything goes wrong...
you run.
And get the fuck out of the city.
I'll look in on your mother.
I feel like I'm gonna fucking die.
Come on, man.
My break's almost over.
Don't you fucking back out.
Well, now.
How are we feeling?
I called your family, Jerry.
They're coming.
You were out cold for a while.
Get some rest.
You deserve some rest.
-What happened?
-Motherfucker ran away!
Your friend is fucking dead,
Willie! You hear me?
-What's wrong?
-He didn't come home last night...
from work.
-What happened?
-I don't know.
He missed his parole meeting.
They called for him.
Said he's in violation.
He's in violation.
All right, sit down.
Calm down.
Yeah, but what if...?
What if something happens?
-Val, listen to me.
-Yeah.
You're my sister. I love you
and can't let this kill you.
You hear me?
Okay, gentlemen, right in here.
All the way down the tracks.
Take your pictures of our circuit
in the train signal boxes.
Build them to the specs.
Preference will be given
to minority companies...
for a portion of contracts.
-Think about what I said.
-Get off me.
You want to help out?
I wouldn't bother with
a bid on this one.
What are you talking about?
Word from the inspector general.
The cop that was hit
came up with a suspect.
It's your nephew.
I'm sorry to have to tell you.
-You'll get caught.
-Shut the fuck up.
You'll be the first to go.
Come on!
Knock it off! Settle down!
What's the matter with you?
Why didn'tyou tell me?
We were going to handle
it on our own.
You fucking idiot!
This could be devastating.
The borough connects us,
we're out of business.
-We could all go to jail.
-I shouldn't have let him go.
Accident waiting to happen.
It's going to be all right.
Leo's gone.
Nobody knows he was
working for us.
They won't stop investigating.
You think there's a statue
of limits for murder?
Who killed the yardmaster?
Was it Leo?
I understand.
Trying to protect your friend.
We have to distance ourselves
from your nephew.
Say he never worked here.
I'll make sure the accountants
didn't file any W-2s.
I'll also put out a statement.
"We're all saddened by
the turn of events." Etc.
None of that's going to hold.
It's going to lead back to us.
We got to talk to this cop.
See what it takes for him
to remember differently.
Tonight's the president's party.
I'll talk to Seymour...
see if it's something
we could pursue.
I thought I could help.
I thought I was gonna help him.
I'm sorry.
-Are you waiting for them?
-We're always waiting.
Hello?
-Hey, Bernie.
-Hey.
How you doing?
-What? We ready?
-We'll be right down.
Right down?
What's the problem?
-Is Willie downstairs?
- Yeah.
Well?
They're thinking of
getting married.
I don't want to talk
about it with him.
He's not my father.
Your mother looks very upset.
Don't you think you
should discuss it?
Could you get the fuck out?
-Hey!
-It's all right.
You do what you want to do.
You want to upset your
mother? Go ahead.
You want to run into this
without thinking about it?
You do that.
But get ready.
Get ready.
Thank you.
Sweetie?
Harriet, how are you?
Let's wish Arthur a happy birthday.
-You wanna come?
-I've said enough.
Probably.
There he is.
-Hey, Manny.
-Hey.
-Good to see you.
-How are you?
Good.
Arthur.
I don't think he heard you.
They got some nice
roast beef over there.
You guys sit down.
I'll join you in a minute.
All right.
I try to say hello to Art, he
gives me the cold shoulder.
-He can't be seen with you.
-He embarrassed me.
You know how much money
I gave to his campaign?
Wait till things calm down.
What do you know
about this cop?
The one that's giving
us the hassle.
They say he's pretty sure
about his suspect.
-How sure?
-I don't know.
What are you trying to say?
I thought maybe we...
could create a little
fund for him.
He was hit in the head and...
maybe don't remember so good.
-I'll do a little digging.
-Good. You do that.
We want to help him out.
And before this investigation
gets out of hand.
Come on!
-Don't move!
-Warrant service, ma'am.
-Where's your son. Is he here?
-No. What are you doing?
We got a warrant for his arrest.
Ma'am?
You all right?
He's not here. Please!
Over here, Joe.
Ma'am.
Looks like chest pains.
Toss it all out! Come on!
Check it for weapons!
She's having problems.
Call paramedics.
OfficerRifkin will soon
be on his way home.
Rifkin, who was injured
in an attack at the...
Sunnyside Rail Yards of
Queens has recovered.
He has given police
theirfirst lead in their...
search forhis assailant
and killerof...
an M.C. T. yardmaster.
Afterreviewing police
mug books...
Rifkin identified...
24-year-old ex-convict Leo
Handleras his assailant.
Although police believe he
may have fled the state...
they are asking anyone
with information to...
contact them immediately.
Coming up, "Where were you
when the lights went out?"
-Hello?
-It's me, Will.
Leo.
Where are you?
You okay?
They're blaming me for
things I didn't do.
That ain't right.
I can't go nowhere.
-I can talk to nobody.
-I'm worry, l...
There's nothing I can do
right now.
-When can I come back?
-Leo...
you got to stay away
fora little longer.
How's my mother?
Her phone's probably tapped.
Didyou see her?
Willie?
Yeah, I did.
Is she okay?
-She'll be all right.
-What's wrong?
No, nothing.
The family's with her
and she's okay.
I can hear it in your
fucking voice.
No, listen.
Leo, listen, calm down.
I can't talk right now.
But...
call me back in
a couple ofweeks.
And...
Frank's trying tow work
everything out.
Leo?
You there?
Yeah, all right.
Is your mother up there?
What are you doing here?
Want to get caught?
-Police were here.
-I know.
I've been watching them.
I'll go around the back.
Let me in.
Go ahead.
I need to see her.
Ma.
Ma, you up?
How you feeling?
I just come to see you.
Ma.
I know I'm not the son you wanted.
And I promised myself...
I'd do whatever I could
to fit in.
What happened before,
I know I did wrong.
But I didn't do what
they're saying I did.
I know I'll...
never be able to redeem myself.
I just wanted you to know...
it wasn't me, Mom.
I just wanted to see
how she was doing.
Leo.
Was Willie with you?
At the yards?
It wasn't him, was it?
You've got to be strong now.
I know you guys had plans.
We got to find a way
through this.
We're going to get through this.
Come on.
Thanks for looking after her.
Yeah.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Get the doctor to see her.
Mr. Olchin, sorry to
interrupt your meeting.
-I'm Detective Tommasino.
-How you doing?
-Detective Bulette.
-What can I do for you?
Look at this. I want to
ask you a few questions.
-Yeah.
-Do you know his whereabouts?
I only met him a couple
of times.
Wife says he's a troubled kid.
He's not in your employ?
Oh, no.
Your secretary said
he came to see you.
He was looking for a job,
but I didn't have anything.
Will you contact us if you
gain any information?
Sure, absolutely.
-Thank you for your time.
-Thank you.
Thanks.
Seymour, what'd you find out?
They'll be a hearing on
thatyardmaster who got killed.
Something else, Frank.
I talked to the division
captain last night.
He says there's no way.
The cop is straight. No
chance he'll go under the table.
Can't Mydanick help us
out here?
Help?
The kid's a murderer.
What'd the cops say to you?
What do you think?
They're looking for him.
Maybe you should get him
before they do.
-What?
-Make sure he doesn't turn up.
What are we talking about?
What do you think I am?
I'm saying this is
real priority for...
the borough president right now.
He doesn't want us to
end up like Donnie Manes.
Yeah, well...
you'll have to think
of something else.
I can't do nothing like that.
Fucking kid is in
my family.
Make sure he don't turn up.
-Anything we can do, Dr.?
-I have her on Digoxin.
-So we'll watch.
-I need your number.
Take care.
Hi, Mrs. Olchin.
Hey, sweetheart.
Your brother said
you'd be here.
-I've been calling all day.
-Ma.
I'll go inside.
Where you been?
I been here.
I know that.
How come you didn't call me back?
There's a lot going on now.
Your mother got a problem with me?
I don't know. No.
I saw how she looked when
you said we'd get married.
You should go.
No, I want to talk to you.
I don't have anything to say.
Erica?
Is this because of what
happened with Leo?
'Cause...
-I'm going back inside.
-Wait, I want to talk to you.
Erica, listen. Erica!
I got a hearing coming
up with the city.
I'd be nice if you came
with me for support.
Okay.
How's your sister?
What's the matter, honey?
I saw Leo tonight,
outside the apartment.
You saw Leo tonight.
He's going to get all
of us into trouble.
You said he wasn't coming back.
I was there tonight.
-He was there?
-Yeah, he was there.
We've got to deal with
it right now.
What do you want me to do?
My wife is...
very upset.
Erica's been spending a lot
of time there with Leo.
She doesn't like them
being together...
because of what happened
between them.
What do you mean?
You don't know?
She caught them together
when they were 1 5.
I never knew.
I found some letters
from him to her but...
I never thought that...
I wish...
there was some way
to take care of this.
What are you doing here?
Willie?
I just came to see my mother.
To see your mother?
You're not supposed
to be here.
He went to the roof to
see if it was safe.
Shut up.
Why'd you come back?
You fucked everything up.
Willie, what the fuck?
What the fuck are you doing?
What the fuck's wrong with you?
Let me go.
You fucking...
Come on.
-Come on, Will.
-Fucker!
-Come on!
-Motherfucker!
You motherfucker!
It's over, Will. No more.
You fucked me, Will!
You fucked me.
Frank?
Jesus, what happened to you?
Your mother see you like that?
I know I haven't always given
you as much respect as I should.
I haven't give you a chance to
be a father to me and my brother.
And I'm sorry.
I know what that means to you,
how hard you've tried.
But I hope you can
forgive me.
It's been hard for me too.
I loved my father very much.
We were very close as a family.
That's why I'm asking you now.
Leo needs your help.
He wants to see you.
I told him you would.
Please.
Where is he?
I could take you.
Go out to the car.
Leo?
Yeah, over here.
You been causing me
a lot of difficulty.
Police been coming to see me.
I need you to help me.
What is it I can do?
I really don't know.
Talk to people you know.
I didn't kill anybody.
Do you know who did?
I...
wish I could help you.
I really do.
But I got to protect
what I've built.
For my family.
Because that's all I got left.
Leo.
Take care of yourself.
I can't stay. Too many
people know I'm here.
They're all against me.
I know.
I'm sorry it was always
just the two of us.
Always having to deal
with everything ourselves.
I never needed nobody
else anyway.
You never had...
someone to look up to.
I used to look at those
business people...
going to the city.
I always hoped you
could be one of them.
You'd look good in
one of those suits.
Yeah, but...
who knows what they do.
I love you, Ma.
Don't lose faith.
I'll stay a little longer tonight.
Okay.
I'm going to be good.
I'll get the rest of my things.
Ma.
I got to take you to
the neighbor's now.
Tell Willie I know he sent you.
Tell him to start looking
over his fuckin' back.
Hey!
Look at me.
I could get every one
of you fucking guys.
I could. I'm going to.
Don't. Don't.
Please!
Get up!
-Get the fuck out of here!
-Did you do it?
Go!
Hundreds ofcity residents are
expected at a public hearing...
to discuss charges of
corruption andpayoffs...
in the consumer
rail industry.
Mydanick called the meeting
amid criticism...
his office isn't doing enough
to resolve this scandal.
It may lead to the indictment
oflocalpoliticians...
and rail executives.
The controversy was sparked
last month when...
Elliot Gorwitz was killed...
and officer Gerald Rifkin
was injured...
in the attack at the
Sunnyside Yards.
There's been protests
including a demonstration...
in Manhattan that
turned violent.
29 people were arrested for
assault and disorderly conduct.
Meanwhile, police are
looking forLeo Handler...
the only suspect in
the Gorwitz murder.
Frank is very concerned, Willie.
I just talked to him.
He asked me to find out
how it went.
We had a little...
problem...
but we'll go back again.
You got this under control?
What...what time's the hearing?
I don't know if you'll be coming.
-Why not?
-Frank and l...
discussed it. We don't think it's
a good idea for you to come.
Because of the investigation.
Frank doesn't think I should?
You know how it is.
Yeah.
He also wanted me
to tell you that he...
doesn't want you
calling the house.
And you got the
house keys, right?
Yeah.
He wants them back.
Okay?
Well, I don't have them
on me right now.
That's all right.
Drop them off as soon as you can.
He's a little worried
about security.
See you later, Willie.
-Hello. Weltech.
-Hector Gallardo, please.
Just a minute, please.
-Hello?
-Hector, it's Willie Gutierrez.
You're too late.
The purpose is to let things
air, give people a voice...
and announce our investigation.
Any more quotes you'll get
later. Hold that for me.
Seymour.
-Hi, Frank.
-How you been?
-Fine.
-Good.
Move one over.
-You speak to Willie?
-Yeah.
He's still taking care
of the problem.
You won't have to worry.
I told him to keep his distance.
Where's Sequiera?
I haven't seen him.
He and the Weltech people want
to make a big entrance.
That's enough, thank you.
Thank you.
Frank, turn around.
My God, what's he doing here?
He is willing to turn himself
in after these proceedings.
You have my assurances.
Tell the borough we
need to talk now.
And I want Mydanick. Make sure
he understands I want him.
Let's make this quick.
We got a new problem out there.
What do you mean "we"?
He's your nephew.
You're on your own, Frank.
You throwing me to the wolves?
I got records and copies of
every check that went to you...
that bought your fuckin
house in Sands Point.
So let's not play games.
What are you talking about?
There was a murder.
A man lost his life.
You can't bargain
with a man's life.
And this man over here...
has been wrongly accused
of the crime.
Okay, all right, look.
Why are you telling me this?
You're talking about my nephew.
I'm going to do everything
I can to help. So now...
think we can agree on something
that would make everybody happy?
I don't know, Frank.
Your nephew...
has a lot to say about your
conducts in business.
Everybody out there has
a right to hear it.
Manny, come on.
What good is that going to do?
Can't we resolve this nice?
I don't think you understand.
We have been kept down by this
man and his people a long time.
It's about time for a little
retribution. Don't you think so?
Hello?
What are you doing here?
Came to drop off the keys.
-Thought you'd be at the hearing.
-I was at school.
If you're looking for Leo,
I don't know where he is.
I'm not looking for Leo.
I know where he is.
Artie, Seymour said you
wanted to see me.
Yeah, come in, Sal.
This is Deputy Chief Disipio
from Police Plaza.
-How do you do?
We got a problem.
We're hoping you can help.
Anything for you, Artie.
Well, we all think...
your Officer Rifkin out
there's a little confused.
-Is that right?
-Yeah, that's right.
This young man here...
is not your guy.
Look, Sal...
we understand the suffering
Rifkin has been through.
We're willing to compensate
him for it.
We'd present you with
the remuneration and...
you could distribute it...
however you see fit.
So...
-you've been wrongly accused?
-Yes, I have.
I can help with that murder.
I know who did it.
Oh, yeah?
You'd be willing
to testify to that?
Yes, I will.
I would definitely.
I think we might be...
able to solve a lot
of your problems.
Rifkin is supposed to
be by-the-book.
He can be a hard-ass...
but he can get carried away
with the nightstick.
And you and I know he won't
want that to come out.
Manny...
it's really up to you now.
I just want 20%
Of all the contracts.
Yeah.
That's fair.
I guess that's fair.
Leo was smart.
He did what I should have done.
It's a little late for that now.
I'm sure you'll be okay.
Yeah?
-Everyone's trying to cut me out.
-I can't help.
Erica, wait.
Erica, wait!
Willie, stop!
I love you, Erica.
I'm so sorry.
Don't run away from me, please.
You're all I have now.
I love you so much.
Where you going?
Come here.
You going to see fucking Leo?
You know how sick that is?
How fucking sick?
No!
Just leave me alone!
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Deputy Chief Disipio
and honored members...
of our police force.
I want you all to know...
that I have demanded an
internal investigation...
unprecedented in scope and rigor.
I know things can divide us here
in this borough and community...
but your showing up tonight
indicates confidence in our system.
Our internal investigation,
which will be aired next week...
will show the claims
of concerned citizens...
as well as some of our media...
are totally unfounded.
Our investigation concludes...
the suspect we have been
following for some time...
should be cleared of all charges.
Ladies and gentlemen, please.
Excuse me, sir?
We have a report of an alarm.
Can I see your license,
registration and insurance, please?
Sir?
Get out of the car.
Get out of the car!
-Go call for backup.
-You got it.
What were you doing in there?
Got anything on you?
Ourreport, which will be
made public next week...
will show we have a great deal
of violence in our subways.
We've made an unfailing
commitment to...
our transportation system.
We cannot let...
violence tearat the fabric
ofourgreat city.
Ourhearts go out to the
family ofMr. Gorwitz.
Mr. Gorwitz's murder
is a true tragedy.
We have show time and again
that we can come together.
As I look around the
room this evening...
-I see that we...
-Mr. and Mrs. Olchin?
-Could you come with us, please?
-What's the matter?
It's about your daughter.
I'm very sorry.
She was found in your house.
She was deceased.
I'm very sorry.
I'm very sorry, ma'am.
Mom!
Ladies and gentlemen,
just take your seats, please.
Ladies and gentlemen, please.
Leo.
Look...
I just want to tell you...
you got nothing to
worry about because...
I got friends.
And they can protect us.
I heard rumors people
people for the Attorney...
General's office want
to talk to you...
but you can't lose your head.
Just stick with us.
And in the future...
whatever you need...
You coming back inside?
Your mother needs you.
Come on.
I am not an importantperson.
Mypurpose today is to
shed some light on...
my experience in
a corrupt system.
I know I have made my own
mistakes through time...
but I have paid my debts
to society.
I hope today to re-enter
the community...
as a productive citizen.
That is all I want.
That is all I ever wanted.
Thank you.
We thank you for
your courageousness...
in coming forward this morning.
I will now ask you...
to read into the record, the
names of those individuals...
who you contend are key
members of this conspiracy.
Mr. Arthur C. Mydanick.
Mr. Seymour Korman.
Mr. Frank H. Olchin.
Mr. Paul Lazarides.
And Mr. Willie Gutierrez.
I would like to finish...
by saying that as a product
of my street environment...
I am aware of the code of
silence I have just violated.
But many lives have been
destroyed by this system...
and I believe that
in years to come...
my testimony will be
viewed for what it is...
and that I will not have to
look back on this day...
with any regret.
Thank you.
Ripped by Apophis!