August, 1962
was a stormy time for France.
Many people felt that
President Charles De Gaulle...
...had betrayed the country
by giving independence to Algeria.
Extremists, mostly from the army...
...swore to kill him in revenge.
They banded together
in an underground movement...
...and called themselves the OAS.
The Minister's meeting is over!
They're very late.
The time elapsed from the first
to the lastshot was seven seconds.
In all, more than 140 shots were fired.
Several bullets pierced the President's car.
One came within an inch of his head.
But, as if by a miracle,
neither he nor anyone else was hurt.
Six months later:
Most of the conspirators
have been caught and tried.
Their leader, Colonel Bastien-Thiry,
has been sentenced to death.
At the last moment, his lawyer
tries one more time for a stay of execution.
The appeal for clemency
has been turned down.
There is nothing more one can do.
I am sorry.
There is no need.
For heaven's sake,
don't you realize you're going to be shot?
You don't understand.
No French soldier is going to raise
his rifle against me.
Fire!
Here is the 8:00 news for today,
March 11, 1963.
An hour ago, in the courtyard
of the Fort d'Ivry, outside Paris...
...Lieutenant Colonel Bastien-Thiry
was executed by firing squad...
...for leading the attempt on the life
of General De Gaulle last August.
The OAS now seems
completely demoralized...
...by the splendid performance
of our national security forces.
Already it is known that
the new chief of operations of the OAS...
...Colonel Mark Rodin, a former
paratroop commanderin Algeria...
...is on the run
and hiding somewhere in Austria.
Today's execution must surely mean
that the OAS is finished...
...once and for all.
What are the finances like, René?
No wonder our people are giving up.
They've lost faith.
We've failed them every single time.
We won't fail again!
What can we do? We're paralyzed.
Every cop in France knows us.
informants are all around us.
We must find an outsider. A foreigner.
-A foreigner? Why?
-A contract killer.
One that hasn't worked in France,
so he won't have a police record.
-He can come and go as he pleases.
-That sort of person costs money.
Yes.
I'll find the right man.
We'd better meet again
in three months, in Vienna.
In the pension you both know:
Pension Kleist. June 15.
It's a limited market.
I've compiled 11 dossiers
over three months.
Only those four men
seemed anywhere near right.
Now that you've read the files,
what do you think?
-One Englishman did all these jobs?
-I don't believe it.
-It's true.
-He did that fellow in the Congo?
And Trujillo?
-Yes.
-That's our man then, isn'tit?
I should say so.
I'm glad you agree on the final choice.
-Because he'll be here any moment.
-What?
He's arriving this afternoon from London.
Wolenski.
A normal precaution, you understand.
Come in.
We are not terrorists, you understand.
We are patriots.
Our duty is to the soldiers
who died fighting in Algeria...
...and the 3 million French citizens
who live there.
You want to get rid of him?
Speaking as a professional,
do you think it's possible?
It's possible.
The point is getting away with it.
As a professional,
it's an important consideration.
In principle, you'd say it could be done?
Yes. With enough time and planning.
It would be more difficult
than most targets.
Why more?
Because De Gaulle has
the best security in the world.
Their information is first-class.
You see, gentlemen,
not only have your own efforts failed...
...but you've queered the pitch for others.
-How dare you suggest..
-You can't afford to be emotional.
It's why you've made so many mistakes.
-If we decided to employ a professional--
-You have to employ a professional.
Your organization is
so riddled with informers...
...that nothing you decide
is a secret for long.
The job would have to be done
by an outsider.
The only question is
by whom and for how much?
Will you do it?
-Yes.
-How much?
Understand, this is a once-in-a-lifetime job.
-They can never work again.
-How much?
-Half a million, in cash.
-What?
Half in advance and half on completion.
-Half a million francs?
-Dollars.
Are you mad?
Considering you'd get France in return,
I thought it a reasonable price.
But if you can't manage it,
there's nothing more to be said.
We accept.
How many people know about this?
-Just the four of us.
-Let's keep it that way.
This job depends on absolute secrecy.
No notes must be kept.
If any of you is captured, I shall call it off.
I suggest you stay in a safe place under
guard until the work is done. Agreed?
Agreed.
The planning will be mine.
No one else will get the details
and you won't hear from me again.
Here's the name and account number
of my bank in Switzerland.
When they tell me the first $250,000
has been deposited, I'll move...
...provided I'm ready.
But I'll not be hurried in any way.
Agreed.
All I want from you is
a phone number in Paris...
...that I can call
about changes in De Gaulle's plans.
The contact mustn't know
who I am or what this is about.
Send me the number by mail.
How do you expect us
to find the money so soon?
Use your network to rob some banks.
One last thing.
What code name will you use?
Why not "The Jackal"?
Why not?
There's nothing more you want from us.
You'll be working completely alone.
Not completely.
One will have the cooperation of De Gaulle.
He won't listen to his security service
and stay out of the public eye.
A pleasant journey home, Mr. Jackal.
960,000 francs? This has got to stop!
You're the Chief of Action Service.
You've had 3 weeks to find out
if the OAS is involved...
-...and if they are, what are they up to?
-It is the OAS, General.
But the ones we've caught are small fry.
They've been ordered to do it,
but they don't know why.
The Minister's been after me again.
We've questioned all known OAS people.
They know nothing.
-What about the informers?
-Nothing.
But we found out this morning
that Rodin and the other two are in Rome.
They arrived on June 18.
They've taken the two top floors
in Hotel Garibaldi.
-You're watching them, of course?
-Twenty-four hours a day.
'Morning. Birth certificate, please.
Paul Oliver Duggan.
Born in the parish of Sambourne Fishley,
April 3, 1929.
Fill in the form.
You'll find the 1929's up those stairs...
-...and left at the first gallery.
-Right. Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
Excuse me, please.
How many krone to the pound?
The official parity rate is 19.34.
Hello. Two bottles of hairpin, please.
One in chestnut brown and one in gray.
I've only got Clairol, dear.
That's fine. And also a tin of solvent.
-lt is here.
-ls it?
Hello?
Yes.
Hello, Zurich?
Mr. Kola, this is he.
That's right. Account Number 50664.
The money's been deposited.
How much?
Alitalia announces the departure
of Flight 127 to Genova.
Now boarding at Gate 5.
The Hotel Garibaldi is owned
by a Frenchman with OAS sympathies.
Extra Action Service staff have been sent
from Paris to Rome...
...to keep watching them around-the-clock.
Rodin, Montclair and Casson
live at the top floor alone.
On the next floor down
are the bodyguards...
...ex-paratroopers or foreign legionnaires.
-How many?
-Eight.
-They're afraid of being kidnapped.
-I know Rodin. He's not a man to be afraid.
The lift doors on the top floor
are welded together...
...and everything goes through
the bodyguards.
Not one of them has set a foot
outside the hotel for five weeks.
The only contact
with the outside world is one man:
-Adjutant Wolenski.
-Tell me about him.
Bersie, run the film, please.
This is Wolenski.
He goes to the post office
every morning and afternoon.
See that?
You'll have to cut his hand off
to get the mail away from him.
He always waits until the collection van
arrives before he posts any letters.
Then he goes to pick up the mail.
All their mail comes to general delivery
and is addressed in the name of Partrier.
Wolenski, of course,
can identify himself as such.
Colonel Rolland here.
I want everything you've got
in the archives on a foreign legionnaire.
His name is Viktor Wolenski.
If the OAS is planning something big,
their agents must be working on it now.
You must find out who they are
and where they make contact.
I let myself in.
l'll make us some coffee.
Denise.
I ask you to get rid of these.
It's for your own safety.
I'll do it tonight.
Maybe I should do it for you now.
They know all about your fiancé.
I have an assignment for you
that sounds very important.
It's not very pleasant.
Go on.
They want you to get involved
with an official of the Élysée Palace...
...someone fairly close to De Gaulle.
It might be dangerous.
It's certainly distasteful.
Who is this official?
I'll show him to you in a week or so.
Good afternoon.
Yes, please come in.
You think you can do it?
Certainly.
I can take an existing gun,
make the modifications.
It must be very light in weight,
and it must have a short barrel.
A short barrel. That's a pity.
Lastly, there must be a silencer
and a telescopic sight.
Over what range will you fire?
I'm not sure yet,
but probably not more than 400 feet.
-Will the gentleman be moving?
-Stationary.
Will you go for a head shot
or a chest shot?
Probably head.
What about the chances of a second shot?
I might get the chance, but I doubt it.
In any event, I'll need a silencer to escape.
In that case,
you better have explosive bullets.
-I can prepare a handful for you.
-Glycerin or mercury?
Mercury, I think.
It's much cleaner.
-More Campari?
-No, thank you.
It seems then...
...the gun must be carried past customs
without arousing suspicion.
Recognize that?
The whole thing should be made
of hollow aluminium tubes...
...which screw together. The top one...
...holds the rifle strut. The one below,
the bolt with the breech inside it.
The shoulder rest of the rifle
doubles for both purposes...
-...without changing in any way.
-That's excellent.
The last two sections house
the telescopic sight and silencer.
Here.
It's very remarkable. It's so simple.
I shall need the gun in about two weeks.
If you could meet me here...
...August 13, you could try out
the gun and discuss last minute details.
Very well. August 13.
Now the question of your fee.
I have to ask a fee of 1,000 pounds
for this kind of a job...
...you see and, say...
...another 100 or 200 pounds
for the raw materials.
Done.
I'll pay you half the fee now
and the rest on delivery.
What do you think? Marvelous?
I knew you didn't come to Genova
for a driver's license.
Anyone in London could've done that.
Problem is I won't have time
to play around with makeup.
-I'm not much good at it anyway.
-Forget about makeup.
The important thing is the skin.
It must look gray and tired.
We used a trick in the army to fake illness
and get out of fatigue duty.
-Can you get hold of some cordite?
-I suppose so.
You swallow a couple
of small pieces of cordite.
It'll make you feel sick
and turn the skin a gray color.
After about an hour...
...you'll feel all right again,
but your skin looks gray much longer.
I'll try it.
What about the French documents?
French identity card's all right.
The other one,
I don't think I've seen what they look like...
...let alone copy it.
I'll get a colleague in France to pick
a pocket so I can make a duplicate.
Give me more time, more money.
How much more?
Five hundred.
Three hundred pounds?
-Half now, half on delivery.
-When will I hear from you?
I'll be returning to Genova on August 14.
Be in the same place
where we met tonight at 6:00.
Must be a big job you've got.
There are certain things
I wish to make clear.
When you've finished,
I want the negatives...
...and all the prints
of the photographs you've taken.
You will also forget the name Duggan...
...and the name on the French
documents you're going to produce.
Is that understood?
Taking it easy? I wish I had your job.
All my tenants are on holiday.
What time is it?
-Half past 5:00.
-I must hurry.
-Good-bye.
That's him. See?
In the light coat.
He's the official at the Élysée Palace.
He'll pack his wife and children off
to the Loire Valley for the holiday.
You haven't got much time.
I need Wolenski.
Arrange to get him across the border.
What? Never mind the Italian government.
Once you have him inside France,
bring him to Paris immediately.
You're being very foolish, Viktor.
You know yourself,
they always talk in the end.
You've seen it with your own two eyes
in lndochina.
And in Algeria, of course.
Tell us what they're waiting for
in that hotel!
What are they planning?
Who have they been meeting with?
Nobody? Not a soul?
Then where were they
before they went to Rome?
Tell us, Viktor.
Go back a bit.
Hold it. Stop.
Question:
Rome, Viktor. Why did they go to Rome?
-No answer.
-Check.
Question: why are they in Rome?
-Answer: secret.
-Check.
Question: where did they stay
in Vienna, Viktor?
-No answer.
-Check.
Was it the house?
I am asking you, was it a house?
Answer:
Kleist.
Go on.
Question: who is Kleist?
What does he do?
What did they do to the bastard?
I can't understand a word.
-Put it on the speakers.
-Where from?
"Who is Kleist?" That bit.
Eho is Kleist? Ehat does he do?
Jack? Jackie?
-That wouldn't be Jackie? Would it?
-Jackie?
That's not possible.
Go back, and this time turn up the sound.
Heel, Rex!
Rex, come here!
Are you all right?
I think so.
-Do you want me to call for an ambulance?
-No.
Are you sure?
I'll survive.
There. See?
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
-Sorry to drag you away, Colonel.
-Nonsense.
The tape is on your machine
in case you want to refer back...
-...and here is the transcript.
-Yes.
Jackal.
I thought Wolenski used it
as a swear word...
...but it doesn't sound like him.
Fair.
Excuse me, Colonel. The foreigner...
...could it be a fair foreigner? A blonde?
Is Kleist the foreigner?
Colonel, it's 4:30.
The plot described above constitutes,
in my view...
...the most dangerous single conception
that the terrorists...
...could possibly have devised...
...to endanger the life
of President De Gaulle.
If the plot exists as described...
...and if a foreign-born assassin,
whose code name may be "Jackal"...
...has, in fact, been engaged
for this attempt on the life..
-Sorry.
-On the life of the President...
...it is my duty to inform you,
Minister, that in my opinion...
...we face a national emergency.
New paragraph.
The above report is top secret
and intended for your eyes only.
Written at 0800 hours...
...August 14, 1963.
Address to the Minister of the Interior.
Have the dispatch riderstand by...
...and forget everything you've heard.
Well?
If what Rolland says is true...
...the whole network of our agents
inside the OAS is no good to us.
The President must be told.
I'll ask for an interview.
Get me the Élysée Palace.
Minister. One moment, sir.
The Minister of the lnterior.
There you are.
It's all there.
The Duggan driving license
and French identity card were easy but...
...that third card was a big headache.
It's nicely dog-eared, isn't it?
-Have you forgotten something?
-Sorry?
The original driving license.
The one I said I wanted back.
I thought we might have a chat about that.
The fact is,
the original driving license is not here.
But don't worry.
It's put away in a very safe place.
Nobody can get at it but me.
-What do you want?
-I'm coming to that.
What I propose is simply a little trade.
I give you the original driving license...
...and all those negatives I took of you...
...for a certain sum of money.
-How much?
-A thousand pounds.
Isn't it worth that
to get those documents back?
Yes, I suppose so.
An English gentleman can always
be trusted to see sense.
I can find the first 500 by noon tomorrow,
but we don't meet here.
There's nothing wrong with this place.
It's very quiet and private.
There's everything wrong with this place.
Forget about that. Nobody comes here
unless they're invited by me.
One has to be very discreet,
you know, in my little sideline.
I asked for aluminium.
I tried the aluminium but it just did bend...
...like tissue paper.
I had to use stainless steel.
But it's all right. It looks the same.
Where can I practice?
There's the Montemorro Forest.
You could be there and back in a day.
-Excuse me.
-I won't need the case.
Silencer, please.
Strut.
And the sniper scope.
Here.
Trigger.
Trigger, please.
-Beautiful piece of work.
-I know.
-It's really excellent.
-Yes.
These are for practice.
I took out six of them...
...to convert to explosive tips.
Let me have one.
-Good evening, gentlemen.
-Good evening.
Please sit down.
I trust that you've all read
Colonel Rolland's report?
I delivered a copy
to the President this afternoon.
Unhappily, in the interest
of the dignity of France...
...he feels obliged to impose
enormous limitations on us.
He refuses to alter in any way...
...the summer schedule
of his public appearances.
Good heavens.
The search for this Jackal
will be conducted in absolute secrecy.
Needless to say,
you are all sworn to total silence...
...and won't discuss this matter
outside this room.
But Minister--
But it's impossible!
The President was absolutely adamant.
What extra security precautions
do we take, Minister?
None.
General Colbert. Any success in Vienna?
Inquiries were made by our agents
at the Pension Kleist.
They showed photographs of Rodin,
Montclair and Casson to the desk clerk.
Some money changed hands.
He stated that he recognized them.
They had arrived on June 14.
Were there any visitors?
One man the next afternoon.
He left half an hour later.
The only description the clerk could give
was the man was well-groomed...
...in his early thirties and had fair hair.
Surely a better description can be found.
From whom?
Rodin, for instance.
I hardly think he'd accept an invitation
from any of our departments, Colonel.
Commissioner Berthier, any suggestions?
We're in trouble on this one.
Our agents inside the OAS
can't pin him down...
...since not even the OAS know who he is.
Action Service can't destroy him.
They don't know who to destroy.
Surveillance can't get him at the border,
they don't know what he looks like.
The gendarmes, all 48,000 of them,
can't pursue him.
They don't know who to pursue.
The police can't arrest him.
We don't know who to arrest.
Without a name,
all other proposals are meaningless.
The first task, then, is to find it.
With a name, we get a passport and a face.
With a face, we get an arrest.
But to find his name,
and to do it in secret...
...is a job of pure detective work.
Commissioner,
who is the best detective on the force?
The best detective...
...is my own deputy commissioner,
Claude Lebel.
Claude!
Berthier wants to see you.
-What? Now?
-He's sent a car.
Don't be back later than 9:00.
Commissioner Lebel.
Good evening.
Remember, you have full powers
in this investigation...
...and the resources of every department
represented here entirely at your disposal.
My instructions are simply:
no publicity and do not fail.
Keep your copy of the report.
Any questions?
No, Minister.
In that case, I'll not detain you.
Thank you, Commissioner.
Collect the reports
and put them in my private safe.
-Yes, Minister.
-Good night.
-Thank you.
You'll have to drop whatever you're doing.
Clear the desk completely.
-You want a new office?
-No.
From now on, it's headquarters for this job,
nothing else.
The Minister said
he wants a progress report by you...
...every evening from now on.
-Here. 10:00 sharp.
-Oh, God.
I know.
You've just got to find him
before he gets to De Gaulle.
-I wonder if he has a timetable.
-I'm sure he has.
The trouble is, only he knows it.
He might go for a hit tomorrow
or maybe not for a month.
You've got to work flat out
until you locate him.
After that, we can have Action Service
do the rest, the thugs.
Obviously, you've got to have
a heavy mug for a thing like this.
Anyway, just go and find this Jackal,
will you?
What?
-I'll need help.
-Who?
Young Caron, and he'll have to be told.
-I'll have to get clearance.
-All I want is Caron. That's all.
You know, sir, what they'll do to you
if you don't catch him in time.
I've been given a job,
so we'll just have to do it.
But no crime has been committed yet.
Where are we supposed to start looking
for the criminal?
We start by recognizing that,
after De Gaulle...
...we are the two most
powerful people in France.
Now make notes.
Get my secretary transferred
until further notice.
You will be my secretary
and assistant rolled into one.
I want a camp bed in here
with linen and all the usual...
...including something to wash in
and shaving things.
Also, get a percolator and lots of coffee.
-Right, sir.
-Get onto the switchboard.
I want a good telephonist,
the best they've got.
I need ten outside lines
open around-the-clock.
If there's any nonsense,
refer them to Berthier.
This job gets top priority at all times.
Do you want anything
from them immediately?
A person-to-person link to the heads...
...of the homicide divisions
of the following countries:
Holland, Belgium, Italy, West Germany...
...and South Africa.
The FBl in the United States...
...and Scotland Yard's
Special Branch in Britain.
-How many is that?
-Seven.
Get the head man at home or in the office.
Ask them to take a call from me
tomorrow morning...
...and see that there's no one listening in.
In the meantime,
I'm going down to General Records...
...to check if this Jackal
has ever operated inside France.
Sir, how do you know the Jackal
comes from any of these countries?
I don't.
But he must be on file somewhere.
-Sorry I'm late, darling.
-What kept you so long?
-There was a long meeting.
-I've been waiting for hours.
Yes, I'm sorry about the hour, but....
Yes, Washington, I know it's 7:00 there.
It's midnight here.
What?
Could you call him at the club, please?
I didn't go out.
I just sat waiting for you to call.
It was impossible. There was a crisis on.
Crisis? What crisis?
Never mind.
-What crisis?
-It was nothing.
What crisis?
Mr. Mallinson.
I'm sorry to disturb you, sir.
It's Paris calling, Inspector Caron.
I don't wish to sound rude,
but wouldn't it be better...
...if routine inquiries could be conducted
through proper channels?
Preferably when we're all awake?
I'm sorry, Mr. Mallinson. It is very urgent.
Commissioner Lebel didn't wish
to make a formal request.
He was hoping
that you'd cooperate with us unofficially.
All right.
I'll take the Commissioner's call at 8:30.
Fine. Good night.
What's left of it.
-Who was that?
-The old boy network.
Yes?
-Denise.
-Valmy here.
They found out about the Jackal.
All I found in Central Records was that
in the 10 last years there've only been...
...four contract killers in France.
We've got three. The fourth is
serving time in Africa somewhere.
So, our man must be from abroad.
Surely he's come to someone's attention
somewhere.
-Who do I speak to first?
-Scotland Yard...
...Special Branch.
Assistant Commissioner Mallinson.
There's no name.
Nothing to go on, l'm afraid.
It's pretty irregular,
all this unofficial secrecy, isn't it?
Makes my task difficult.
Yes, I know.
I've never heard of a political killer
in this country.
-It's not our style, is it?
-No, it's more your department...
-...so, I'll leave it in your hands.
-Yes--
And try to get it out of the way
by tomorrow.
I'm understaffed as it is.
Yes, sir.
What's the cost?
Give me the Foreign Office,
would you, please, luv?
Extension 905.
Hello, Barrie?
Brian Thomas.
Could you meet me in an hour
at the usual place?
We've been plowing through the files
till we're cross-eyed.
None of them fits the description.
But before we drop it, I had a thought.
If this contract killer
did all his work abroad...
...he'd be quite respectable
in England, right?
So?
Your people operate abroad. I thought
you might have tabs on a bloke like that.
I'll have a look.
Brian, call for you.
Thomas.
Yes, that's right.
Is this some sort of bloody joke?
What, now?
Personally?
Yes, I'll--
-The Prime Minister?
-The Prime Minister, sir.
He said, "lf there's the remotest chance
of De Gaulle's life being threatened...
...by a person of these islands,
then it is to be stopped."
He's given me full powers and top priority.
-Is this some kind of joke?
-Of course not, sir.
I've got to drop whatever I'm doing.
I shall need six of your best men
straight away.
Where's the notification for this?
Where's the proper authority?
Yes!
Yes, sir. Of course, sir.
Nothing more than taproom gossip,
I'm afraid.
Do you remember Trujillo?
You mean the dictator
of some republic in South America?
Yes, Dominica. He was killed in 1961.
We got word that an Englishman
may have been mixed up in it.
Just an unconfirmed report, mind you.
-Did he have a name?
-Charles Harold Calthrop.
He was the Caribbean rep
for a small armaments firm.
According to the rumor,
he was a fantastic shot.
He disappeared after the assassination.
Nobody knows where he went.
Calthrop.
-Is that all there is to go on?
-Afraid so.
Just a name?
What makes you think it might be him?
Your friend's code name is "Jackal", right?
Jackal in French is...
..."chacal."
See?
Now it might just be a coincidence...
...but the first three letters
of his Christian name, Charles...
...and the first three letters
of Calthrop make up....
That's all the Charles H. Calthrop,
way back to 1958.
-How many does that make?
-23.
Will you please tell Commissioner Lebel...
...that there is a faint possibility,
very faint...
...the name is Charles Harold Calthrop.
That's right.
We've checked with the Passport Office.
23 passports were issued
to Charles H. Calthrop...
...during the past five years.
We've interviewed 12 of them so far.
Nothing at all, but I'll keep you posted.
Do you have a garage for rent?
Excuse me.
Would you happen to know
where Mr. Charles Calthrop is?
-Mr. Calthrop?
-Yes.
I think he's abroad. He often is, you know.
Thank you.
We better get a search warrant.
What's happening?
Come in.
We've been through the lot, sir.
He's away, all right.
Let's see what you've got.
-What's this?
-His passport.
We checked it. It's him.
Look. The Dominican visa.
There's no exit stamp though.
He must have got out on the sly.
You haven't grasped it yet, have you?
Yes, this is our man, all right. Definitely.
But hasn't it occurred to you
that we're holding his passport?
If he is out of the country,
what's he traveling on?
-He might be on holiday in the UK.
-Yes, he might.
Then again, he might not.
His name is Charles Harold Calthrop.
Here's his passport photo.
I'll circulate photos
to each of you after the meeting.
Excellent.
Thank you, Commissioner.
It may be Calthrop has already entered
the country and is staying at a hotel.
-Phillison.
-Minister?
I want every hotel card for the past
72 hours checked by the police.
The same for you, Pascal, with those cards
that are filed for the greater Paris area.
Circulate to your staffs
this man's name and photograph.
He must be arrested on sight,
and my office notified at once.
I want every border post...
...airport, seaport, fishing village alerted.
-General Colbert.
-Minister?
Calthrop is probably still abroad,
so get your agents working on that.
Yes, sir.
In the meantime,
complete silence must be maintained...
...until we're sure
the man's in this country.
-Thank you. Good night.
-Good night.
Commissioner Lebel's office.
Yes.
Thank you. Good-bye.
No one called Calthrop has crossed
any border point legally...
...since the start of the year.
And no hotel has taken in a guest
under that name.
Maybe he's given up and gone into hiding.
If the British found
Calthrop's passport in his flat...
...it's because he no longer needed it.
Don't count on that man
making too many errors.
He's not the type.
I'm beginning to get
a feeling about the Jackal.
He may be abroad,
traveling on a false passport.
What you're going to do now is
go down to the Passport Office.
Get every passport application
for the last three months.
-But, sir--
-I don't care who's closed.
Wake the buggers up.
Then take all those papers
down to Somerset House...
...get started on checking
the applicants' names...
...against death certificates,
not birth certificates.
If you find an application filed by someone
who died as a child...
...the one who filed it might be our man.
If you find nothing
in the first three months, go back three.
And another three if you have to.
Off you go.
Yes?
How's it going, Hughes?
How many applications?
8,041?
You'll be there a week.
How about I send you some more staff?
Bloody holiday season.
About 4,000 more to go, Mr. Thomas.
But if we work through lunch,
we should be finished tonight.
Superintendent Thomas, Special Branch.
Hughes here, sir.
Paul Oliver Duggan.
Born April 3, 1929, in Sambourne Fishley.
Applied for passport July 14 of this year.
Passport mailed July 17
to an address in Paddington.
That will probably turn out
to be an accommodation address.
Why?
Because Duggan died at the age
of two and a half on November 8, 1931.
Passport, please.