Stieg Larsson's
The Girl Who Played With Fire
Hello. Welcome.
Come here.
Yes, like that. Much better.
Will you be good to me?
Then I'll be good to you.
It's too late.
Solicitor Bjurman?
Yes?
This is regarding a police file
dated 1993. Lisbeth Salander.
My employer would like to take a look at it.
Really?
And who is your employer?
I have the case files stored at my retreat.
Do you have copies?
- No.
Is she still abroad?
- Yes, most likely.
Thank you.
Bjurman?
I will stay in touch.
You're supposed file reports about me to
the Guardianship.
I do.
- Each month. You're sloppy.
I have some reports stored at my retreat.
- Shut your mouth.
If your reports say I'm
behaving well,
I will let you go when I'm no
longer under the Guardianship.
If you can't do it, I'll send
our movie to every newspaper in the country.
If something happens to me,
or if I die, it will be made public.
And if you touch me again,
I'll kill you.
And one more thing:
If you visit that clinic in Marseille
for tattoo removal,
I'll redo my work.
On your forehead.
Do you understand?
- Yes.
Is this Zala?
Nils Bjurman.
you're interested the police file on
Lisbeth Salander.
I have it
in a safe place.
I'll let you have it, but only if you
take care of Salander first,
She has a DVD
which belongs to me,
When I have it,
you'll have the file,
She's back in Sweden,
and probably not difficult to find,
- Do you still see her?
- Who?
Lisbeth Salander.
- I haven't seen her in a year.
Why is that?
- I don't know.
One day we'll talk.
The next day she won't answer the phone.
We must go now. Dag Svensson
will show up at the editorial meeting today.
Dag who?
- He writes about human trafficking.
The girls from eastern europe.
What kind of guy is he?
- Freelance. Young and bold.
Fit.
- Fit?
For how long have you been working on it?
- About four years.
I found the subject through my girlfriend. She's
researching gender and is a criminologist.
She's pursuing a PhD.
in human trafficking.
So you work as a team?
No, Mia focuses on the
girls.
I focus more on distributors
and the span of customers.
And what have you found?
I have found
several prominent customers.
Amongst them
someone from the Justice Department,
who participated in
shaping the new sex market legislation.
Three police men,
one from vice,
one from SEK.
Five solicitors
one judge and one prosecutor
The affected girls -
are so low on the social ladder
they're irrelevant to the justice system.
Crimes against young eastern european
girls is not a priority.
A whore is a whore.
That
... is a part of the system.
How far have you progressed?
- I've completed the research.
What's missing is checking the facts...
and confronting the customers I want
to expose.
Hang on.
The last time I didn't check my facts properly,
I spent three months behind bars.
Everybody will get their
chance to comment on the allegations.
There is no need for you to worry.
The documentation is water proof.
That sounds reassuring.
- Yes.
Okay...
We don't pay any huge salary.
I suggest
a two month project position.
You can have a desk there.
Does it sound good?
- Yes, excellent.
We're poking our heads out with this
case. We have to realize that.
That is supposedly the whole point of
of Millennium?
That's why we're sitting here.
- Yes, welcome to Millennium.
Thanks.
Sandstrom?
We have a job for you.
- I don't think...
Yes, we do, actually.
Hello, Armanskij.
May I come in?
More than a year.
What do you want?
Do you need a job?
Do you work some place else?
I have been travelling.
I just recently returned to Sweden.
Where have you been?
- Here and there.
Australia, New Zealand.
The last few months in the Caribbean.
I don't know why
I didn't say goodbye.
Because you don't really
care about other people.
You treat people trying to be your
friends like shit.
It's that simple.
Blomkvist has been looking for you.
He's called at least once
a month to inquire about you.
He cares as well.
Just like Holger Palmgren.
It has been two years since he had a stroke,
and you haven't even visited him.
Is he alive?
You don't even know
if he's dead or alive.
You've been missing.
I've been travelling.
I had to run away for a while.
Have you been worried?
No. You can do anything.
That's how it is.
How are things with
the new...
...guardian?
Bjurman.
He's okay.
It's okay.
And you're still forced to be
under the supervision of a guardian?
Don't worry about me.
I'll fix it.
It's no longer your job.
No, I'm too old.
I'm just a silly,
old fool.
Yes, you are.
Truly silly,
if that's what you think.
I thought you were dead or something.
- Or something.
We didn't meet that often
before you left.
I was busy.
- It's good to have you back.
I only know one person
who dares knock on the door -
after one and a half years of silence
to ask if I want to fuck.
...then I broke up with her and
went to Paris. Mom and dad lives there.
I worked in a club
near Clichy.
A fantastic place.
But I had applied for law school,
and been accepted.
Mom found the letter and told...
- Do you want my apartment?
What?
Are you moving?
- I have already moved.
I can't afford buying anything.
The rent has been paid for a year.
Do you want it?
There's just one thing.
- I assumed that much.
I'm still registered here.
My mail is sent here.
You'll take care of it.
I can do that.
Where do you live?
Some place else.
- Can I visit?
No. Not now.
But you'll come over to fuck me
when you feel like it?
I'd like that,
but it's not a part of the contract.
You're not wired properly.
Are you serious?
Yes.
Come here.
Damn, I have something for you.
There you are.
Happy birthday.
This isn't my birthday.
- It's from last year.
If you're going to keep smoking
that crap,
you might as well do it with elegance.
You are the only one
who gives me presents.
How are you?
- I'm good. Excellent.
Or just ok. I'm trying
to get a hold of one of the customers.
A policeman from SEK.
Gunnar Bjorck.
But he's nowhere to be found.
As if swallowed by the earth.
It's hopeless.
What do you have?
- A PO Box address.
A PO Box address?
Try the lottery trick.
What?
- The lottery trick.
Write to the PO Box
and tell him he's won...
...a monster cellphone with GPS
and that he's one of 20 selected -
to win 100,000 if he'll participate
in a market research study.
Is it legal?
It can't be illegal
to give away a phone?
Say you're from
Indigo Market Research.
Hi, honey.
Sorry I'm late.
We're hitting the press next week,
so we're fucking busy.
Are you the only one
working in that paper?
Everybody's working like animals.
I need more time than the others.
Micke has begun confronting some of the
customers.
He's so experienced
they crap their pants if he just...
It's finished. Printed.
Yes.
It's already finished?
"From Russia With Love".
"Organized crime and
human trafficking".
By Mia Bergman.
- That's me.
My girlfriend.
Vi have to celebrate.
- Yes.
Give me a kiss.
- It's finished.
Lovely food.
Truly lovely, Annika.
Why do you tell her?
I did the cooking.
It's quite tasty, Annika.
Why don't you get married?
- Leave him be, aunt Angelina.
He doesn't want to.
- Why not?
He's so handsome.
Mikael, do you have a woman?
You must have a woman.
Yes, I have a woman.
So marry her.
- I'd love to, but she's already married.
Hi, am I interrupting?
No, I'm at my sister's and
half a platoon of her husbands family.
Sounds nice.
About the pictures...
They are on paper, and Mia
and I leave for Dalarna tomorrow.
I don't know if I should send
them with a messenger,
No, don't use a messenger.
I'm leaving soon.
I can give you a lift.
I'll stop by.
- Great,
And one more thing.
I want to run a name.
A criminal named Zala.
Tell him he's Anton in my
dissertation.
Did you hear that?
- Don't give me new material this late.
No, I know,
but I think it can pay off.
We'll talk about it later.
- Yes,
Two minutes.
Did something happen?
- It sounded like a gunshot.
Just now.
Dag?
Hello? Hello?
But you reported it?
Yes.
Did you see what happened?
- No. I found them.
It can't have been
more than ten minutes after...
Do you have a description?
Did you see anyone run away from the scene?
No.
Maybe the neighbors saw something.
Do you live here?
No, I was going to visit the couple
living here.
I'll be back.
Hello? Blomkvist?
We have a couple of questions.
You can't have that here!
The murdered couple
was a journalist and a criminologist.
They were found by another journalist.
Blomkvist from Millennium.
What do we know about the motive?
- Not much at this point.
The girl was about to get her PhD.
in a couple of weeks.
This case has the highest priority.
Assemble a task force.
Hans Faste, Jerker Holmberg.
- Sonja Modig.
You can pick out the team yourself.
But make it quick.
Ekstrom, prosecutors.
You described the murders
as pure executions.
Which ones on the list are capable of that?
And getting away with it?
We're about to publish the names of
several persons -
who'd prefer to stay out of the spotlight.
Some of them
had already been contacted by Dag.
This is speculation.
- Shouldn't we hand the list over to the police?
Yes I suppose we should.
- No.
They can have the names of some customers,
but we must never reveal our sources.
It's about the safety of those
girls Mia interviewed.
It can be life or death.
Back to the first question:
Are we printing this?
I think that's what Dag would've wanted.
- Agreed.
Christer?
Sure.
We have received a temporary report
about the murder weapon.
It's illegal?
- No, it's perfectly legal.
It belongs to
solicitor Nils Erik Bjurman.
Acquired in 1983.
He's got an address on Gardet.
There you go.
We could also identify
two sets of fingerprints.
A woman born in 1981.
Arrested for assault in Gamla Stan
in 1998, when the fingerprints were taken.
Do you have a name?
- Her name is Lisbeth... Salander.
Lisbeth Salander
seems quite disturbed,
She's under a legal
guardian.
Guess who the guardian is?
Solicitor Nils Bjurman.
The owner of the murder weapon in Enskede.
She was already violent
in school.
Psychiatric treatment as a teen.
We think she supports herself through prostitution.
And documented
violent tendencies.
Do we have Salander's address?
- Lundagatan in Sodermalm.
Stop! Police.
Cross the street.
- Have you arrested Salander?
- No, we're waiting for backup.
- Call me.
- I'll call when we're done.
Hookers have no class
anymore.
They look more fucked up every day.
Would you pick her up?
There has to be a simpler way.
Why call in the storm troopers
to catch one small fish?
The girl is 150 cm tall
and weighs 40 kg.
We're in
but the apartment is empty.
Affirmative.
Faste?
- Yes?
Why did it say Salander Wu
on the door?
Have no idea.
Hello, this is Bjurman. Please leave
a message and I'll get back to you.
Hello?
Snap one from that angle as well,
so we get it properly.
She's in there..
Thanks. My coffee craving was
about to kill me.
What have you found?
Bjurman, and an empty Magnum bullet box.
We're checking it for prints.
And copies of monthly reports on
Salander,
which he's been sending
to the Guardianship.
According to the reports
Salander is basically an angel.
We have turned him around.
There is something you should see.
"I am a sadistic pig and a rapist".
What do you think?
- Not a bad motive for  murder.
LISBETH 28
SOUGHT FOR THREE MURDERS
IN ENSKEDE
HUNTED FOR THREE MURDERS
JOURNALIST BLOMKVIST
FOUND THE MURDER VICTIMS
This afternoon another
victim was found.
The 56 year old socially commited
solicitor was found shot...
...in his apartment. Police is investigating
if the murders are connected.
One of the victims worked for
the newspaper Millennium,
...where Blomkvist
is editor in charge.
According to Blomkvist,
Svensson was about to write about -
- IT security and hackers.
It's a great loss
for his family and collegues...
...and the whole journalist community.
A brutal attack
on free society.
Why did you tell them that?
- Because it's true.
One of Dag's specialties
was hacking.
We had agreed that it would
be his next case.
And I want to find a certain person
before the police does.
Lisbeth reads everything I write.
No matter where she is.
And she's quite interested in the subject.
This statement might make her
contact me.
You have no doubts?
- About what?
No.
No?
- Lisbeth has not murdered anyone.
That's Dag's phone.
- I'll get it.
Indigo Market Research.
- Good morning, my name is Gunnar Bjork.
I have received an interesting offer
from you.
THIS IS WHERE POLICE FOUND IRINA
DAG SVENSSON'S RESEARCH
COPY
- Which documents were she looking for?
- The e-mail log from Svensson.
Or his research.
Can you track her?
- No. She doesn't work ilke that.
She's got a reason to
stay hidden.
Do you think she's guilty as well?
- I'm not saying anything.
I know she hasn't done anything.
Not this time.
Why do you ask, mom?
The fucking police
did it. The pigs!
This place looks fucking awful.
I don't know.
She is vanished.
Wait, somebody is at the door.
Hi, Miriam.
Tony Scala, journalist.
Your girlfriend
is suspected of three murders.
Can you confirm that you spent time
abroad with Salander?
You have to talk to the media sooner
or later. I can help you.
Go to hell you
fucking pig!
A double espresso.
Why do you think Lisbeth is innocent?
She had no reason to kill
Dag or Mia. Especially not Mia.
Mia wanted to expose human trafficking.
Sounds like something Lisbeth could've done.
Lisbeth detests men
who hates women.
We have proof she was at
the scene of the crime.
So you found fingerprints?
- Yes, she's connected to the murder weapon.
That doesn't mean she
pulled the trigger.
And Bjurman? Her gardian?
- The answer lies in Svensson's research.
This is a police matter. We do not need
private detectives and their wild theories.
I have no theories. I'm stating
that Lisbeth did not kill Dag and Mia.
I want to present evidence.
I want to point out an alternative killer,
and write an article you and your
peers won't like, at all.
- This is Bjorck.
- Hi, this is Indigo.
- Good, did you receive the travel instructions?
- Yes, that's not a problem.
This lottery and the cellphone...
You're still one of the
20 selected.
- Have we met before?
- No.
You seem familiar.
Maybe you've seen me in the paper.
What was your name again?
- Mikael Blomkvist. Journalist.
I work for Millennium.
I didn't know
you do market research.
Sure, sometimes.
Look at these three pictures
and tell me,
which model you
prefer.
First off, this is Lidia Kamarova.
She is 16 years old
and from Minsk in Belarus.
Then we have Myang So Hun.
She is 25 years old, a little older,
but it doesn't show.
She's also called Jo-Jo.
She's from Thailand.
And then we have Silvia,
her real name is Jelena Barasova.
She's 19 years old and from Tallinn.
You have paid for sex
from all these women.
So what I want to know is
which one is your favorite.
Is this a joke?
- No.
Our journalist Dag Svensson had
documentation proving...
you paid them for sex.
Did he contact you?
- Who?
Dag Svensson.
- I never heard the name.
Now I want you to leave.
- Yes, that might be so.
He did not manage to confront you with the
documentation...
before someone shot him.
Do you know solicitor Bjurman,
who was also shot and killed?
What do you want?
I want to allow the sex buyers to
comment on the facts...
in our next theme issue on
human trafficking.
You do understand that you will ruin my life
if you print this?
Yes.
Several visits with Irina
Check Anton = Zala
Come on. Get up.
Get up.
I'm going to ask you some questions,
Per Ake. If you answer, I'll let you live.
If you refuse, I'll zap you again.
100,000 volts.
If you lie or answer
confusingly, I'll zap you.
Your muscles will stop working,
and you'll hang yourself.
And I'm leaving.
Understand?
I don't want to die.
My mistake. I forgot to tell you that
you can't speak without my permission.
Is this your daughter?
- Yes. She'll be here any minute...
You'er breaking the rules again.
Do you want to die?
- No.
In january you visited Irini
in an apartment in Norsborg. Why?
I don't know...
I wanted her. She was beautiful.
Beautiful?
- Yes, she was beautiful.
And that gave you the right
to tie her up and fuck her?
You are a sadistic pig and a rapist.
Isn't that so?
Who is Zala?
I don't know.
- Don't abuse your chance.
I don't know who he is.
The journalist you shot asked about him as well.
If I knew
I would tell you.
I only spoke to some who said
his name was Zala.
One minute on the phone.
- Why?
I was supposed to import a car
with amphetamine from Tallinn.
I didn't want to.
They showed up a few days later
and told me I couldn't pull out.
Then they forced me
to come with them to...
To?
- Some storage facility.
The first thing I saw was a man
on the floor, beaten to a pulp.
And he was there...
- Who? Zala?
No, a blond fucker.
Pure muscle.
I've only seen him once before.
Damn.
What's his name?
- I don't know.
What else happened?
They said the guy on the floor was a snitch.
The blonde raised him up
on a chair in front of me.
Then he put his hands around
his neck.
I heard his neck cracking.
He died
before my eyes.
Then the blonde wrapped his
hands around my neck.
Magge held a phone to my ear
and told me Zala wanted to speak to me.
What did he say?
Zala?
I was to do as I was told.
What choice did I have?
Hello.
We have to get back.
I have a lunch meeting.
Have you been in contact with her?
Who?
Who do you think?
An old friend called
this morning.
He's also convinced
Lisbeth Salander is innocent.
Who?
- That's completely skewed.
Erika?
It's best if you meet and
discuss it yourselves.
Jab, Paolo! Come on!
Give him a jab!
Move your feet, man.
Concentrate on your foot work. Come on!
Don't give up.
From where do you know Lisbeth?
We've boxed together since
she was 17.
Not in the same weight class.
- She's quite tough.
She's in trouble, yes?
She's in deep deep trouble.
Paolo, you have to help me.
I need to get in touch with Lisbeth's
girlfriend, Miriam Wu.
Have you read about her?
- I know her. Kick boxer.
She refuses to talk to me because I'm
a journalist.
If you, as a known boxer,
talk to her...
And try to reach Lisbeth
through her?
Fuck...!
Come on!
Micke? You asked me to dig into
Gunnar Bjorck's past.
I ran into Nils Bjurman.
He was an officer in the security
department of the national police force.
What? When was that?
- From 76 until 78.
Same time as Bjorck.
- Fuck...!
Where is she?
- Who?
Lisbeth Salander.
- I told you, I don't know!
Wrong answer.
You have one more chance.
Then I'll start using this.
Run, Miriam!
Hello?
- Micke, it's Paolo,
I'm at the hospital
with Miriam Wu.
What?
- Would be nice if you could come by.
I didn't shoot Dag and Mia.
If you want to help, find Zala, Lisbeth.
I can give and receive punches,
- but he was
no ordinary human.
What did he look like?
- A blonde, armour penetrating robot.
He was pure muscle.
- And you never saw him before?
Never. He moved
exactly like a boxer.
He kept his guard up,
but at the same time seemed completely clueless.
Clueless in what way? On drugs?
- No, it was very strange.
As if he had trained,
but never listened to his coach!
And then there was something
fucking scary.
I hit him rock hard.
About 100 punches went straight in.
But nothing happened.
As if he didn't feel anything.
Hello. Ward 1B?
- Further down the hall.
Jan Bublanski.
How are you?
- Splendid.
I'll find a place where
we can talk uninterrupted.
How are Miriam Wu?
- They're still examining her.
She looks like me.
It wasn't her they were after.
It was Lisbeth Salander.
We have identified 29 customers and pimps
from Dag's list.
In theory, they all had a motive
to murder Dag.
Eight names are missing.
We've given them pseudonyms.
What are we doing about them?
- Malin is trying to identify them.
Some of the pseudonyms are
mentioned in Mia's dissertation.
We can find references there
which can lead to the names.
First I'd like to visit the
Dag wanted to expose.
They have the most to lose.
- Then we can do the following.
Sten Falstrom, done.
He's done.
Karl Pettersson, done.
Per Ake Sandstrom
He's been confronted by Dag,
so we'll expose him.
And the guy from the security police force?
Bjorck?
What about the connection between him
and Bjurman? What about this Zala?
I'm not completely finished
with Bjorck.
It's Bjorck.
- Blomkvist here. You never called.
What do you want?
You lied to me. You and Bjurman
worked together at SEPO in the 70s,
Why would I tell you who
I worked with?
Tomorrow I'm holding a press conference
regarding the murders of Dag and Mia,
I will give details about
our article series on sex trade,
and you're the only customer
I'll expose.
So you'll have the opportunity
to comment.
You want to destroy my life.
Why would I talk to you?
Since you know Bjurman,
you probably know Zala as well?
Hello?
You know who he is?
What is that information
worth to you?
His real name is Zalachenko,
but he's called Zala.
What I'm about to tell you now is
top secret.
You understand it's important to me that
you guarantee source protection.
I've already done that.
Zalachenko was born in 1940
in what was then the Soviet Union.
Both parents died during the war..
I assume you know what GRU was?
Yes, the military intelligence.
He made his career in GRU.
Speaks six languages fluently.
Expert in camouflage
and survival techniques.
Over the years he became more and more corrupt.
GRU sent a military attache...
from the embassy in Madrid
to find him...
and correct his ways.
Something went wrong
during that conversation.
Cut to the chase.
Zalachenko killed the
man from the embassy.
He realized he had burned all bridges
went to Sweden, contacted the
security police and applied for asylum.