This is automated translation only for other
translators! Only idiots can rate it!
Get up.
What?
You fell asleep again.
Give me just five more minutes, please.
No. Get out.
Hey.
Late night?
- I guess.
- Again?
- Again.
- Same guy?
- No.
- Do I know him?
Maybe.
Did he know me?
Good morning everyone.
Good morning.
Talk to me, Lawrence,
what we have for specials?
Lobster in white wine sauce.
- What else?
- Spinach and mushrooms.
Linguini in a tomato sauce.
It looks good.
More than 25kinds
food for the wedding?
Welcome back, Mr and Mrs Stevens.
- So nice to see you again.
- I am happy to see you.
You remember the Sophie?
I pray to you to lead
Your usual table. Bon appetit.
Follow me.
Sylvia, six table needs
helpful in choosing wine.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Vivi told me that you need
a recommendation on wine.
Yes. I ordered the "Petite File".
I'd recommend "Castle Chateau" in'87.
A great Bordeaux wine.
Never heard of him.
Not on the list of menus.
We reserve a special down in the cellar.
I think you appreciate it.
Thanks, would be fantastic.
Be right back.
- Table 18note demanded payment.
- Okay.
- A to ask Vivi to go ...
- Out a little, okay?
Okay.
A wonderful idea, "Chateau Castle.
It is one of my favorite wines.
What other Friday you recommend?
Depends on the food.
It's okay, you can think of that
When you invite to dinner.
Here, I meet with clients.
This burned my father
and that fucking slut.
How a fire broke out?
Police said
that they left open and the gas exploded.
So it was an accident?
Yes. That said Sheriff.
It regularly when they died.
Their bodies remained united
because of fire?
I had to cut them asunder.
Who was that bitch?
A matron of Autuma.
There they met.
Halfway between the cities.
What are you doing?
Who knows what he
Ardea dad when ...
Why did you bring on Xavier?
Because it's my friend.
Bury your father and do circus tomorrow.
There are no circus, motherfucker.
Fuck you.
Hello, mother, aunt, Rebecca ...
You fight with Cristobal?
No.
I do not want to hear to argue.
Now more than ever.
Well.
That the whiskey is my father.
It?
When the hell you drink it?
Santiago?
- Excuse me.
- Cristobal.
Your mother does not go to the funeral.
Neither Rebecca nor me.
- Bitch do not deserve.
- You did not do anything.
I'll take it. Both.
For yours is the kingdom of Heaven ...
forever ...
Amen.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Amen.
Who are they?
I do not know.
And now we say goodbye
of our brother, Nick Martinez.
I hope your father decay in hell.
That bitch took my
all I had better.
Hey. Leave the guys alone.
Alone?
Their father is fault
that have no parent my children.
I hope you rot in hell.
Maria, come on!
Maria, go!
Come on Maria, make them like your father.
Hey, Daddy, what is it?
Hey, baby, we have a job.
Can I stay with my friends?
Sorry, honey, we gotta go.
Please ...?
- No, honey.
- Come on.
Come on ...
Come on, work.
- You have the coordinates?
- Yes.
We introduced G.P.S.
Here is  farm.
- Hello.
- Santiago Martinez. My associate.
- Nice.
I need to  besprinkle land farmed.
is a shed workers.
A  those who work the land.
There . You can make a tortillas.
- You need something?
- No, thank you.
- We handle us.
- Okay.
- See you later.
- Can I use the bike?
- Sure.
Who does that? I do it
We  with money.
I come back in a minute.
Sorry I was late.
We could not get out sooner.
Do not worry.
Can I go?
Safe.
Hello.
Not there ...
Please.
Want to leave on another date?
No. No.
It's okay.
Listen ...
My cousin left me to use his trailer.
I was never there.
But it is far from everything.
Want to go?
Not "Hilton".
I want cereal, Mariana.
I want the other.
Well, very sorry,
because you have done.
Mariana, what we have for dinner?
I prepared myself
friends and cereals.
Hey, kids.
Supermarket was crowded.
I late.
He called father?
Oh come the day after tomorrow.
Has made a delivery to Aberleen.
It's okay.
I do this.
Hey.
Hey. Take the guess.
That was the office of Senator Park.
Want to eat tonight
another eight people.
Shit.
Could not call the day before?
Lawrence?
Comes a senator in two hours.
- He wants as usual.
- Two hours and expect everything to be ready?
A call to the market over
to bring something.
Where were you last night?
What?
Home.
Who?
- You promised not to put any questions.
- Who the hell?
I work.
Be right back with another bottle.
Bon appetit.
- Why is Senator empty glass?
- Sorry, Sylvia.
Senator seemed satisfied.
So tell me. He left a good tip.
I like that
to vote at the next election.
- You are incredible.
- No, no.
That I want for Christmas next year.
To remember that.
Enjoy.
Sylvia!
Who the hell is this guy?
Jesus, John.
Do not do this now. It's just a friend, okay?
Is a client.
I saw him taking lunch here yesterday.
Yes. Yesterday.
Wait. Just ...
Get laid with all ... and this is?
When you leave your wife,
you can talk.
Let's go.
- Jesus.
- I want to talk to you.
- Unlock the door.
- Hey.
- Get out and talk.
- Hey, come on, leave it alone.
Fuck you.
- Sylvia!
- What?
- What is your problem?
- I want to talk to you.
- My friend, let her go.
- I told you to go hell.
John. John!
Jesus! Are you seven years?
- What are you doing?
- I want to talk.
This is stupid.
I let you solve your problems
your friend.
- It is not my friend.
- Why do this?
Do not touch me.
Give me five minutes.
What do you think? Did you follow to hell!
- Hey, Sylvia.
- You are my master, John.
Do me a favor and disappear.
You ...
Let me go home.
Are you okay?
What do you want?
Are you okay? Are you okay?
I understand.
Hey, hey! I drive home.
What?
I drive home?
Come on. Hey, I drive home?
Home.
What is your name?
Me? Carlos.
You?
Sylvia.
Sylvia?
Yes, Sylvia.
Hello.
You know who I am?
I came here to argue.
What?
I just want to know more, much more.
Who was your mother ...
what was with my father ...
Already know what was.
No, I do not know.
Can we talk another time?
Well. I look for you.
Dad!
Hey.
Hey, baby.
I do not come back until tomorrow.
Yes, but I finished early.
Where are the kids?
They went to a baseball game.
You want to wait
to eat lunch with them?
Yes.
Go get washed.
- Excuse me, dear.
- Thanks, baby.
I will fix shortly.
I gotta go tonight.
Where?
At K-Mart in Saint Helena.
Come with you.
You should get some fabrics
and I go to the butcher.
It's okay. You ride.
I have to buy a radio.
Hey.
Hey, kids.
Now it works.
Daddy, Daddy.
I'm very glad you are here.
- Hi, Dad.
- Hey, girl ...
Get in, baby.
So.
I forgot my wallet.
I want the window.
Bobby! Monnie! Bobby!
Bobby!
It was the first. Sit down and get back.
Put your seat belt.
Children, listen to it on your sister.
I go to pee.
And I miss you.
Try. Try to escape.
I love you.
Who are you talking about?
Laetitia.
Come on, we wait.
- Where you going?
- In the bathroom.
Daddy, I want on that.
No, trying to save money
remember?
I want to find
things on the list.
Save money for a new home.
Can I get keys? Go get tissues.
I come with you.
Go to your sister and look for a jumper.
T miss much.
- Come on, baby.
- Dad, I go up here.
Hello.
Forget it.
Sorry.
Order was not ready and I had to wait.
I gotta get back to.
You can get the money
for presentation at school.
Got everything on the list?
- Open the back, dear?
- Mariana?
Sure.
- Give me the keys.
- Okay.
Are you okay?
Want to come inside?
I come in?
Yes, go.
Well.
Want a drink?
Drink?
No ... I do not want to drink.
Go get changed. It is cold.
Are you sure that you want?
No.
Why?
I do not like?
What are you doing?
If you see my dad going to kill you.
I said I have to look.
Yes, but not here.
Wait on the road to Guadalupe.
Well.
Why did you want to see me?
I do not know.
I do not think it is okay
to talk to me.
Why?
You look like your mom?
No.
- You look to your father?
- A little.
You know how he knew
mother with my father?
No, I have no idea.
Hand it over.
We got it!
You like to hunt?
Very much.
Ex-boyfriend used to take me hunting,
but I have not been since we broke up.
My father taught me how to chase.
You loved your father?
Yes.
And I loved my mother, but ...
not a pleasure.
Got a photo?
Do not look at him.
Is made. Take it.
There may be too hot.
I burn?
Here.
- No thanks.
- Come on, you must drink.
- Are you Carlos Solar?
- Yes.
create patient to talk to you
only wants to speak with him.
Come .
Maria  not have time for that.
Come down, please.
- I go a week.
- Do not go anywhere.
I do not want to know that Mrs.
And if you want
- Is your mother.
- I saw her in my life.
- You must live.
- I!
Not interested. What
you doing your father is an asshole.
Make your luggage.
You have to go whether you like it or not.
No!
Enjoying
It is cold.
I know that Ms
- I want to go back.
- Do not start, please.
Your father wanted to meet me.
And  to meet.
Hello.
Look at this place ...
Me very happy.
I'd be happier if we had
hot water so I can take a shower.
You taste better that way.
No. No, please.
Not there.
Why?
Because I like
that side of my body.
How do you know that I do not like me?
I had cancer two years ago.
Hey.
Where were you?
I went to Libbis.
Bobby has been cut to
with a piece of glass.
A must scythe doctor.
- You okay?
- It's good.
He cried continuously and I cried.
To be good.
- Bye.
I forgot my homework.
Go, you get behind.
- I expected to.
- Do not go.
- Hi.
Finally you have hot water.
- Can I help?
- It's okay.
Almost done.
- Works?
- That's
What are you doing?
What?
need to talk, Mariana.
Wrong girl, my name is Sylvia.
Okay?
Santiago  sent me to you.
What did you say?
Mariana, is your daughter.
called Maria.
Stay away from me.
Here is Mom and Dad with us
when I was small.
We did bathroom ...
This is the last photo of the mother.
For her birthday.
And this is me.
I have one to me?
Only if I make a scar.
What?
I remember this day.
Would you do me one?
Let's meet at night.
To do then.
In a desert fire bushes.
My grandfather told me
that purifies the smoke bushes at night.
- Ard as artificial.
- Yes.
I like it.
Turn up your sleeve.
Why?
Like to have a scar from me.
Shit.
Burn.
Stop. He gonna hurt.
This is for you.
Good night.
Let me sleep with you.
Are you crazy?
I swear I did not touch you.
You have to wake up my sister, Monnie.
You said that your dad is not home?
I could sleep in his room.
What you wear your mother go to bed?
A bedgown.
You can dress up with her?
Are dressed with shirt father.
Promise not to touch me?
I promise.
I burn burn you?
No.
My bite me very hard.
You promised that you will not touch me.
Want to go?
No.
Sylvia?
He called the d-Turner,
a table for eight people.
- We all tables occupied.
- I know. What do you do, Sophie?
Are you okay?
Watch it all until I get back.
You can come out later?
We need to talk.
What happened?
I like?
I mean ...
you think you love me?
I think so.
To run together.
Only two of us. Today.
What are you talking about?
Do your bags and go somewhere
in New York to take over again.
Anywhere but to go.
- I understand ...
- Yes or no?
I do not know. Do I need to consider.
Mariana!
Hello.
Hi, Mom.
Did you eat dinner?
No, I expected you.
I go to prepare.
Why did you come so late?
Baby, you scared me.
What did you do today?
I went to get some tissues,
then we went to Libbies.
I was myself at Libbies.
I have not seen there.
Maybe you were not there when I was too.
I was there at four o'clock.
Ending questions and help me.
Clean this mess.
Nick? Hey, I'm Gina.
We need to talk.
No, not the trailer.
At the supermarket?
11Hour?
Well.
Bye.
I love you, you love me.
I do not know if it is correct, but that's it.
Want to give up on this?
No, please understand.
Answer me, you want to give up on this?
I do not want to see you.
Forever?
I can meet you.
I expect you caravan.
Every day at noon.
You should back up.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hey.
- I got a surprise.
- What is this?
Well, we had a picnic
long and I thought ...
It is pretty cold in here, baby.
Is there a secret holiday?
- Can you get a cookie.
- Okay.
- Can I get a cookie?
- Do you not eat your lunch.
I do burgerii.
- Are you ready?
- Not yet.
Hey, kids. Come to stay with us.
- Hey, kids.
- Why have a party?
It is not a party, a picnic.
Fun.
I fear to do.
Come on, do not marshmallow
~ a ~ kind of marshmallows?
I am not a child, parent.
Mariana? You want a bit?
I gotta go home to Kate,
for a project at school.
- Bye, Daddy.
- Bye, baby.
I can not.
Simply can not.
Sorry.
may want to keep track of new ...
Friday!
Hey.
Are you okay?
Nor were there.
I should
to check the "Palms".
I will find them. They left.
Believe me, a Mexican with a girl
of 12years can hardly hide.
I find.
We must continue to look.
When you saw last?
I dropped it to two days
after it was born.
Why?
Not deserve.
I think I really like.
- Hi, honey
- Hey.
You seek someone.
Hello.
Hey, you never spoke
about Mariana.
It is a friend from school.
- You want to stay to lunch?
- No thanks.
No, I get lunch elsewhere.
- We get dinner at "Polus"
- Yes.
- It's a pleasure to meet you.
- Me too.
- See you later.
- Okay.
Enjoy.
Yes, son.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to see your parents room.
Here.
It is well understood mother and father?
Middling.
Come here.
You still burn?
No.
With a girl? Are you sure? Thank you.
Room 51.
- What?
- 51.
What?
Want to see my daughter.
I understand.
Her daughter ...
He wants to see his daughter.
I do not understand what you want.
Let them go!
Maria!
Do not worry.
I think something new.
Hey.
Hey!
Maria!
Please, let me talk to you.
What do you want?
What do you want
I beg you ...
Please, Carlos.
- Carlos.
- What?
Leave a .
Are you sure?
Can I sit down?
Sorry I ran yesterday.
I ...
You just ...
Mary, speak English?
You grew.
I thought about you all the time.
In particular, when was your day of birth.
Try to imagine how I look.
You are very beautiful.
You look like your father.
Dad is in hospital.
Why?
He crashed plane.
It is okay?
I do not know.
It is a pilot ...
On a utility aircraft.
You know?
Everything is okay
Let  ask if coming with us in Mexico
You think you go
Take care of us and for everyone else.
Amen.
Well. To bed.
You said you have a prayer?
Do not ask me.
Is wrong, Mariana.
Many things are wrong, Mom,
and can not be directed through prayer.
You behaved very strangely lately.
Tomorrow I want to tell me what you troubling.
Goodnight, baby.
Good night, Mom.
Good night.
The girl who came here a day ...
is her daughter?
Yes.
A rule?
Why do this?
It is your job.
Can not do that to your mother.
Stay out.
It is not enough what happened?
Has nothing to do with you.
You must stop seeing her.
You understand?
I'm happy to betray your family?
Talk to you, motherfucker.
- Do not betray anyone.
- You are worse than your father.
I had to get home?
I will burn in hell with him.
Sorry.
Get outta here!
What happened?
Tell me that's not true.
Tell me that is a lie.
Even you slept with him?
Santiago, Dad is on its way to you.
Go away and come get me.
In what class are you?
In the eighth grade.
Got a friend?
No.
You?
I have a friend.
Jose Martinez Sanchez.
I want to have my aesthetic surgery
to eradicate breast.
Do not do it. I like how you look.
Scar is very bad.
You conquered death.
You fought and won.
This scar makes you to be beautiful.
Do not remove.
Get up, Mom. Get up, Mom.
Mother!
How is she, Doctor?
Maybe  listen and daughter
is her father.
Speakers  some complications.
You will need to operate it.
If the infection is more serious than we think,
might be needed
to amputate the leg.
Can we go to him
You can go to him, but is sedated.
Hey, Daddy.
No, girl.
Will be okay, right?
Will be okay.
I love you, Daddy.
Not  ...
You can not stay here. You must go.
Go .
Maria, come on.
have to leave.
Come .
Wait. Can ...
Can I stay a bit?
I understand. What he said
It  his wife and wants to stay little.
Two minutes .
Santiago ...
I am ...
Mariana.
You have to die, is not it?
Because if you die,
I do not know what to do with it.
Only one can look into my eyes.
She needs you.
And I need you.
I'm very scared.
I'm afraid of myself and can not ...
can not run.
I killed.
I killed your father
and my mother.
I did, but ...
I can not escape the smell ...
when burning them, can not escape it.
Why did you want to come back here?
Why?
Mariana, where are you going?
Let me go!
I have to tell Dad.
Tell him what you want.
You know, you sleep in your room.
I miss you here.
No, it is okay.
What happened?
Nothing, I got burnt once.
Dad has the same scar in the same place.
He said he did this
lest you forget again.
Just me.
And I have a scar.
What happened?
I fell when I was three years.
A stay with us?
I do not know. You talk to him.
You know, a long time.
You have left, right?
I'm tired.
Good night.
Where are we?
That is my school.
What you do there?
I got quiet.
Not one to ever have peace.
I am pregnant.
- What?
- I'm pregnant and do not want the baby.
We can go to Mexico. All three.
No. I do not want. I can not have.
Can I talk to you a minute?
Maria ...
You think you can forgive me for not ...
I missed all these years?
I left because
I was afraid I would be like me.
As you become like me.
You think you can forgive me?
Please ...
I want to go to see my father now.
- Hello.
- Hello, Doctor.
How is he?
I managed to drain the infection.
Not to lose my leg?
No, not to lose my leg.
need to track how you move,
but for the moment is right.
I can see him
Yes, you can go to see.
Dad will be fine.
Live?