My dear children...
...it is now better than several years...
...since I moved to New York...
...and I haven't seen you
as much as I would like to.
I hope you will come
to this ceremony of papal honors...
given for my charitable work.
The only wealth in this world is children.
More than all the money,
power on earth you are my treasure.
Anthony and Mary...
...although I entrusted your education to
your mother for your own best interests...
...you know how I look forward to seeing you...
...and to a new period of harmony in our lives.
Perhaps you might prevail upon your mother
to come to this celebration...
...and that from time to time...
...we can all see each other at family functions.
Anyway, I remain, your loving father.
Hail Mary, full of grace...
...blessed art thou amongst women...
...and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of god
pray for us sinners...
...almighty god, bless the insignia...
...of Saint Sebastian the martyr.
That it may contribute to the sacredness of him...
...to whom it is given.
Do you, Michael...
...promise to be faithful to the noble purposes of this order...
...to have a special care for the poor,
the needy and those who are ill?
I do so promise.
May the blessing of almighty god...
...father, son, and holy spirit...
...descend upon you and remain with you forever.
Amen.
Vincent, our name's not on the list.
Write it in.
Mancini. M-A-N-C-I-N-I.
- Hey, is there a problem here?
- No problem, our name's not on the list.
Hey, you're not on the list, you'll have to leave immediately.
- There's no two ways about it!
- You want to dance with me sir?
Joe! Joe! It's Vinnie.
Vinnie, it's Okay, these are our guests.
Sorry Dave.
- It's all right.
- Hey Vinnie. Welcome to the party.
It's good to see you.
It's good to see you again.
This is my husband.
This is my son, Anthony.
The order of Saint Sebastian
is one of the highest honors...
...the Catholic Church can bestow upon a layman.
The award was first granted by Pope Gregory...
What about Mr. Corleone's connections
with las Vegas gambling?
Press kits have pictures of...
What about his involvements with the underworld?
Hey, cut the crap, huh?
The Pope, the holy father himself...
...has this very day blessed Michael Corleone.
You think you know better than the Pope?
- Do it, do it.
- Vincent!
- Yes?
- She loves you.
- What'd he say?
- I love you too.
Hi, Vincent.
I remember you.
You remember me?
From where?
- From the last time we had a party together.
- Did you come down to the club?
- No, it was a wedding.
- A wedding?
I was eight, and you were 15.
Well I, I had a lot of girlfriends when I was 15.
- Eight-year-olds?
- Especially eight-year-olds.
Where's Mary?
Would somebody please hail Mary?
Excuse me, your excellency.
You know, you haven't kissed me hello yet.
- Relatives always kiss.
- Oh, now we're related?
I'm your little cousin.
Who's your father?
I'll give you a hint.
- He's Italian.
- Mary.
Mary, we've been waiting for you.
Remember - remember now, keep your voice low, right?
And smile! Don't forget to smile.
Carissimi Amici, the honorary chairman...
...of the Vito Corleone Foundation, my daughter, Mary Corleone.
Thanks.
I don't think I inherited my father's
love for speech making, but here it goes.
The Vito Corleone Foundation helps
the impoverished of every country,...
...gives grants to artists, funds medical research,...
...and is particularly dedicated
to the resurrection of Sicily.
ArchBishop Gilday...
...here is $100 million for the poor of Sicily...
...in the name of Vito Corleone.
Don't spend it all in one place.
Mary - Mary, I'm so proud of you.
- Michael, you've done a wonderful thing for Sicily.
- ...a special surprise from Las Vegas;...
Well, let's just hope the money gets to the people who need it.
- Amen.
- ...the most important part,...
Johnny Fontane!
Thank you very much.
I'm happy to be here with you,
and I'd like you to join me...
...in honoring commendatore Michael Corleone.
And I have something special for our host and Godfather:
I just happen to know his favorite song.
Michael, where are you going?
It's your favorite song.
I'm off here to the kitchen
to hear some Tony Bennett records.
It's your favorite song.
It's "Sausage" His Own.
That's right; a Sausage Sandwich!
I'll be back.
A rose must remain
with the sun and the rain
or its lovely promise won't come true
to each his own
and my own is you
Hello, Kay.
Well congratulations, Michael, that's really quite an honor.
It's a little expensive, wouldn't you say?
Cake?
No, thank you.
- It's been a long time, hasn't it?
- Uh huh. Yeah.
- Eight years.
- Yeah.
You look wonderful.
Your son has something
he wants to talk to you about.
I came here for him.
Nice to see you.
Thank you.
If a flame is to grow
there must be a glow
to open each door
there's a key
I need you, I know
I can't let you go
- What's wrong with being a lawyer?
- Nothing, except he doesn't want it.
He loves music, he wants his life to be in music.
Well, music is great. I love music.
But he should finish what he started.
- I'm going my own way.
- Your own way?
- Professional singer?
- That's right.
And what happens -- what happens if you fail?
I won't fail.
- Men always believe that.
- I know.
If you have a law degree you're taking out insurance.
After that you can do whatever you want.
You can work for me...
I will never work for you. I have bad memories.
Every family has bad memories.
I will always be your son...
...but I will never have anything
to do with your business.
- Anthony, finish the law degree.
- No.
Well, that he got from you. That "no".
- You could have helped me to convince him, Kay.
- Oh, convince him of what?
Of what?
He throws his life away.
He throws greatness away.
This is greatness?
You know Michael, now that you're so respectable...
...I think you're more dangerous than you ever were.
In fact, I preferred you when you were just a common Mafia hood.
- Kay, now can we talk common sense here?
- All right. - Okay.
Tony knows that you killed Fredo.
- What did you come here for?
- I came here to protect my son.
I didn't come here to see you disguised by your church.
I think that was a shameful ceremony.
I spent my life protecting my son.
I spent my life protecting my family!
Let's be reasonable, Okay?
That's your big thing, isn't it, Michael?
Reason backed up by murder.
Oh, God.
- God, you hate me. You hate me.
- No, I don't hate you.
I dread you.
I did what I could, Kay, to protect...
...all of you from the horrors of this world.
But you became my horror.
The children still love you though.
Especially Mary.
That's something.
We can build on that, for their sake.
Let's try.
Only if you let Tony go free to have his own life.
Away from you.
I'll let Tony go.
Thank you.
You could hurt somebody with those.
You've been working too hard, let me show you around.
Can you get me an interview
with Michael Corleone?
Uh, no. I'm a relative but I can't do that.
What else could I do for you?
- Handsome but useless.
- Oh, yeah?
- That's okay. I'll gamble.
- You like to gamble?
Why don't we go to Atlantic City?
My town. I'll show you how to gamble.
Yeah, but I like to win.
How will I know what numbers to pick?
Do I look okay like a guy who's gonna lose?
Well...
...that's a spooky-looking guy there.
What's a guy like that doing
at Michael Corleone's house?
- That's Joey Zasa's bulldog.
- You know that guy?
Yeah, I know that guy.
That guy's name is Anthony Squigliaro.
They call him "The Ant."
He dips his bullets in Cyanide.
Don Altobello.
- I come to pay my respects.
- Grazie.
You honor my family's friendship.
- Where is my goddaughter? Constanzia...
- Don Altobello...
It was not so long ago
I held you in these old hands.
Michael...
No, no.
I stand. I stand.
Michael, I lost all the venom all the juice of youth.
I lost the lust for women and now my mind is clear.
My duty to God is clear.
I - I have a special favor to ask.
Can I attach my name...
...to the Vito Corleone Foundation
so that you and I can be joined...
...in name and spirit?
One million dollars.
- Godfather.
- Don Altobello, you have such a heart.
Come, let's go and sample some of Italy, old vino.
The Vatican knows nothing of these shareholders.
Good.
I have a tendency to worry.
We've increased our position
substantially and naturally, I worry.
Come along now.
Stop worrying.
We have an agreement.
Good. How do you think I got this grey hair?
Mr. Corleone.
- Two seconds.
- Frank, how are you?
Thank you very much for your
contribution to the Board's swimming pool,...
...and we need your help on
Sam Wallace's candidacy for judgeship.
- We always can use a good judge.
- Thank you.
Andrew.
Your Excellency, my Godson, Andrew Hagan
my brother Tom Hagen's eldest boy
He's been assistant
to Bishop Breelan three years now.
Hoping for an assignment to the Vatican.
There's always a place in Rome
for a fine young priest.
His mother, Theresa Hagen. Archbishop Gilday.
Thank you.
It's an honor to meet you.
Mr. Corleone, hi.
Grace Hamilton.
Vincent Mancini promised that he'd tell
you about me, that maybe you'd see me.
Vincent Mancini called about her?
No.
Grace, you promised me you'd stay up there.
- I know. I know.
- Twice.
Joey Zasa showed up.
We've got him waiting in the lobby.
Says he wants to personally
congratulate you and show his respect.
Do I have to see him?
He says you're his padrone
and he only wants a minute.
Hey, Vinnie.
- Who's your favorite Aunt?
- You are.
Today I'm going to talk to Michael
about your problem.
I wish you would have warned me, Con.
I could have worn a better suit.
The Meucci Association has elected you,
their Italian-American Man of the Year.
Hey, Meucci.
Who's Meucci?
He's the Italian-American
who invented the telephone.
He did it one year before
Alexander Graham Bell.
Really? Huh.
And this is the reason you've come to my home on this day?
I umm,...
...got a stone in my shoe, Mr. Corleone.
A two-bit punk who works for me.
The one who, thinks he's related to you.
A bastard.
He's here.
Vincent Mancini.
He's at the party.
Well bring him in.
I think it's good we talk.
I have a problem...
...and I want to find out if it is my problem...
...or your problem.
Joe, your business is your business.
I have no interest or percentages.
I'm out.
Good.
Then it's my problem.
Michael, you know Vincent Mancini, Sonny's boy.
How you doing, Mr. Corleone?
- How you doing?
- I'm doin' good. How you doin'?
- Good.
- Good party.
- Oh, you like it.
- Yeah. I had to sneak in.
Well, you're dressed for it.
So, what's the trouble between you and Mr. Joe Zasa?
There's trouble. I'll take care of it.
- That's foolish of you.
- Foolish of me?
It's a little foolish of this guy, don't you think?
Right?
Temper like his father.
Vincent. Mr. Joe Zasa now owns what used to be...
...the Corleone family business in New York.
Out of the kindness of his heart,
he gave you a job in his family.
Contrary to my advice, you took the job.
I offered you something better
in the legitimate world.
You turned me down.
Now you both come to me with this bad blood.
And what do you expect me to do?
Am I a gangster?
- No. You're not a gangster.
- That was papa's neighborhood.
Now it's a sewer.
Zasa runs it like a disgrace that's...
- ...what the women tell me.
- That's the past Connie.
I earned that territory with my talent.
The commission gave it to me,
and you approved it.
- Yes.
- Uncle Michael, I came to the party here.
I'm not here to ask for any kind of help.
I could just kill this bastard,...
- ...he's the one who needs the help.
- So kill him.
What has all this have to do with me?
Well, he's going around behind your back
saying fuck Michael Corleone all the time.
That's it, see, that's one thing it has to do with you.
Right?
Say it to his face,
one time say it to his face, one time!
Mr. Corleone, all bastards are liars.
- Shakespeare wrote poems about it.
- What am I gonna do with this guy?
What am I gonna do with this guy?
Joey.
If there's some guy running around
this city saying "fuck Michael Corleone",...
...what do we do, with a piece of shit like that?
He's a fucking dog?
No.
Yes, it's true.
If anyone would say such a thing...
...they would not be a friend, they would be a dog.
My interests don't confiict with Mr. Joe Zasa's.
Oh you don't know how much your interests
conflict with Mr. Joe Zasa's, Uncle Michael.
Wait.
He needs your support, Michael.
- Don't let me work for this guy no more Uncle Michael,
let me come work for you.                   - For me?
- Yeah.
- As what? Tough guy?
I don't need tough guys.
I need more lawyers.
Since we have no confiicts, no debts...
...I accept your tribute.
I wish you well.
Vincent, make your peace with Mr. Joe Zasa.
Come on.
Okay. Go on.
Bastardo.
For Christ's sakes, stop!
What the hell is the matter with you?
Get him out of here.
Oh, Jesus.
Uncle Michael, I told Connie it
wasn't the right time for this thing -
- Close it.    - Uncle Michael, listen,
I know you're into banks and Wall Street,...
...but everyone knows you're the final word,
you're like the Supreme Court.
All I want to do is protect you from these
guys and your lawyers can't do that.
- And you can?
- Yeah, I can do that.
And why should I be afraid of Joe Zasa?
Well, he knows you're stopping him from
rising up in the commission, Uncle Mike.
I say we make him dead.
You give me the order, I'll take care of it.
- You'll take care of it?
- Yeah.
Maybe you should, uhh, come with
me for a few weeks. See what happens.
- Okay.
- See if you learn.
And, umm, we'll talk about your future.
I won't let you down.
- We're just about ready.
- No, it's all right.
- So what happened?
- What happened?
They put me in a room with Joey Zasa,
what's gonna happen? I bit the guy's ear off.
Here we go.
Watch the card.
- There.
- Hold it.
I'll just change the plate here.
- Vincent.
- Yeah?
Take the picture with me.
Come on.
- Nice jacket.
- Little girl...
...closer to the center, if you would, sir.
And here we go.
Ready. Smile.
Excellent.
I'll have it for you on monday.
- Butter cake.
- Beautiful.
Godfather, this is the cake for you
and your family, from Enzo the baker.
You want to do it?
All right...
You lead.
Kathryn, you lead.
- Vincent?
- What do you want, sweetheart?
Do you love me?
- Come on. Go to bed.
- Come on. Say it.
- No. Say it.
I love you.
I love you too.
You got a cat?
Go get us some water, would you?
I'm thirsty. Come on.
Come on.
Well, I just guess I know my place.
I can't believe I'm actually getting up to do this.
"Get me a glass of water, bake me a cake."
Whatever happened to "please"?
Come on.
Good boy, sockface.
Let's go for a walk.
Hey. Come on, let her go.
Fuck it.
Cut her fucking throat, man!
- What'd you say?
- I said, cut her fucking throat.
- Okay, chief, let her go.
- Drop your gun man, or he's gonna cut her throat.
What are fucking crazy, I hardly know this broad.
Go ahead and cut her.
What the fuck do I care?
You got no choice, man.
This chick's gonna be dead.
You hurt her and I'll kill you both.
- You give up that knife, I'll let you go.
- You cut her throat man, right now!
Hey! I'm gonna do something to convince you.
Don't get frightened.
Don't do any sudden movements.
Just watch me, all right?
- You hear what I said?
- Okay.
Oh, shit!
Drop the knife.
Go ahead. Drop it!
Good boy.
Sit down.
I want to talk to you.
That was a wise choice, sit down.
Lose the mask.
Relax. Have a smoke.
You smoke?
Whose idea was this?
Who sent you?
Come on. Tell me.
- No one.
- Take a good look at this guy?
- Yeah.
- So who sent you?
It was Joey.
Joey Zasa.
You okay?
- You were going to let them kill me!
- No, I wasn't gonna let anything happen to you.
You pig!
You sick fuck!
Come on, sweetheart, that's gambling.
You wanted gambling? That's gambling. Call the police.
- You killed the other guy too?
- He went for my gun.
It's self-defense, justifiable homicide.
Go ahead. Call the police.
- Where are you going? Oh no, no, no. No pictures.
- I'm going to take some pictures first.
No pictures.
You had a gun.
They only had a knife.
You could have talked them into surrendering,
handed them over to the police.
Zasa sent these guys.
I just sent him a message, that's all.
- Now he has to send you a message back.
- Joey Zasa's gonna send me a message back?
- Joey Zasa's gonna send a message!
- He did the right thing.
- He got Zasa's name.
- What has Joey Zasa got to with anything?
Joey Zasa's a pazzo.
Joey Zasa.
All right, you are what you are.
It's your nature.
You stay close to me.
You don't do anything.
You keep your mouth shut, and your eyes open.
- And you do what I tell you. Understand?
- I understand.
I got problems with the Commission, young man.
- I know that.
- Yes. You don't make them easier.
I understand that,
it wasn't my idea that this happened, you know?
All right. Go on.
Get out of here.
- Michael...
- Yes?
Now they'll fear you.
Maybe they should fear you.
B.J., excuse me.
What's up?
Michael, the Archbishop just called back.
He's arranged some amazing things for your bidding.
The publicity is phenomenal.
You're the new Rockefeller of philanthropist.
- Sign right here, please.
- Times do change, don't they?
My father hated foundations.
He loved doing it by himself, man to man.
But we're different, huh?
It's no different than any large corporation.
We control a lot of money with very little.
Minimize taxes, with, no government control.
Yes -- Right.
Godfather?
Andrew.
- Godfather...
- Off to Rome.
I wanted to thank you for all you've done for me.
- Come on, you want to have some breakfast with us?
- No, thanks. I can't.
All right. How's your Italian.
In fare di podi practico...
- His father was a great lawyer.
- I know.
Didn't live to see him ordained.
I did.
- You ever seen one of those?
- No.
Oh, beautiful. I was so proud.
Come on let me walk you out.
Andrew, if you hear any rumors fiying
around the Vatican you let me know?
Oh no, no. Andrew has the true faith.
Don Corleone. I need your help.
And not just to light a little candle.
My, gift, was to be able to persuade people,...
...to give, to the Holy Church.
Then, Rome decides,
to put me in charge of the Vatican bank.
But I was never a true banker.
Mais á culpa, I trusted my friends.
Friendship and money - oil and water...
Indeed.
But these, friends, use the good name of the Church,...
...to feed their greed.
If money was lost, then I am to blame.
Oh, if only prayer could, pay off our $700 million deficit.
769 million.
The church owns 25%
of a large corporation... Immobiliare.
You know the one I mean.
Largest landlord on earth, real estate
all over the world worth $6 billion.
- That's true.
- And the Vatican vote is necessary for control.
No. No, no.
You're mistaken.
This isn't a question of one person deciding,
one deciding vote.
This is like any other company in the world.
We have directors. We have rules.
We have very old rules.
The Pope himself would have to approve you.
We've sold the casinos...
...all businesses having to do with gambling.
We have no interests,
or investments, in anything illegitimate.
The Corleone's are prepared to deposit
$500 million in the Vatican bank...
...at such time as Mr. Corleone receives
majority control of Immobiliare.
Immobiliare could be something new...
...a European conglomerate.
Few families have control of such a company.
It seems in today's world...
...the power to absolve debt is greater than,
the power of forgiveness.
$600 million.
Don't overestimate the power of forgiveness.
Don Corleone. This deal with Immobiliare...
...can make you one of the richest men in the world.
Your whole past history, and the history
of your family, will be washed away.
600 million.
[Keinszig] The motion and a discussion
relates to the Corleone group's proposal,...
...to acquire 100 million newly issued,
Class A, quoted shares...
Once issued, the shares will permit...
[B.J. Harrison] ...$600 million and Corleone capital
invested directly into International Immobiliare,...
...an old and respected European company...
...that Michael Corleone has an ambitious program
to expand this real estate holding company,...
...into an international conglomerate
that could meet the challenge...
...not by political ideologies, but by
Eastern techniques of efficiency,...
- ...Mr. Corleone!
- ...and focus, and unlimited...
Mr. Corleone, excuse me.
Isn't it true that you recently deposited
$200 million in the Vatican bank...
...which is affiliated with International Immobiliare?
- This is true. Why not?
- Well, wasn't there any questioning...
...about the timing on, on this particular deposit,
or wasn't there some talk...
- Mr. Chairman, if I may?
- ...about the, the fact that...
The Vito Andolini Corleone Foundation,
of which Mr. Corleone's daughter Mary is chairman,...
...has established an endowment
in the amount of $100 million.
The money comes from his own family
and will be administered by the Vatican.
Answer your question?
I have always believed...
...helping your fellow man
is profitable in every sense...
...personally and bottom-line.
My fellow shareholders,
if Europe and America can learn to cooperate...
...if we can learn to pool our wealth,
share our markets...
...we can defeat any competition anywhere in the world.
Let me thank you for the time you have given me
here today, and I hope, that you will look favorably...
...on my proposal. Thank you.
Listen, let me at this microphone here!
How can we let a criminal like that, run our company?
He's got the map of Sicily on his face,
can't you see it?
- Order! Order!   - He's either a Catholic
or a Mafiosi and I say how do you like them bananas?
The Hamilton Investor's group cannot support this proposal.
Your excellency?
Mr. Chairman, the Vatican Bank feels,...
...that international Immobiliare...
...will be safe in Mr. Corleone's hands.
Subject to audit and final ratification
which must take place in Rome,...
...please join me in welcoming Mr. Michael Corleone.
- Dad?
- Uh huh?
Tony says that I'm a front for the foundation.
That you're using me just to pull the strings.
- To get the money where you want it...
- Oh come on, please.
...to shine up your public image.
Mary. Mary, this is real this foundation, it's real.
I wanted Anthony to be a part of it.
I wanted -- I thought the two of you
would be together on this. I won't interfere.
- I'll help, only, only if you ask.
- But...
...what is this really for?
Why are you doing this?
Why am I doing this?
I'm doing this for my children.
You're doing it for your children too.
This foundation is supposed to help all people.
Of course, that's the purpose.
This is legitimate, Mary.
I swear this is legitimate.
Dad, I want this to bring me closer to you.
I would burn in hell, to keep you safe.
No no, no, you go in the other car,
I'll ride with Michael. Go, go, go.
As your family's oldest friend,
I'm always chosen to bring you messages.
Tell me, Don Altobello.
Your old partners are grateful
for the money you've made them...
...they, they worship you.
But their hearts are broken...
...because they think you abandoned them.
They want to share your deal on Immobiliare.
To be a family again.
It can purify their money.
This I cannot do.
Immobiliare must be legitimate.
I know. But they're unhappy.
And you?
I ask nothing for myself.
Only peace in my old age.
But I - I must please the world around me.
Michael, your father was a reasonable man.
Learn from him.
I learned many things from my father.
Call a meeting, my friend.
So there are no debts, or grudges.
We will make the peace. You and I.
They just had a press conference.
They said the Pope's condition was grave.
Gravisimo, they said.
Please. Our group represents...
...a consortium of Catholic businessmen,
against the Corleone control.
The Vatican has cast its vote.
The Corleone group already controls the board.
According to the lateran treaty,
the Vatican support must be ratified...
...here in Rome by the Pope.
The Pope is gravely ill.
Until he recovers, I am powerless.
What if he dies?
Then, as you Americans say, all bets are off.
Gentlemen please, this is a brief delay.
Nothing more.
Your excellency, gentlemen...
...I advise, you join us in our prayers
for the Holy Father’s recovery.
Now we had an agreement!
And this meeting was to be merely,
a formality, that's all it was.
- Please sit down.
- I'd rather stand. Could someone just give me an answer?
- We have put ourselves on the line...
- The Immobiliare has its roots in the European tradition.
Please try to understand.
I understand. Your tactics are despicable.
Well, that's quite an indictment,
coming from a Corleone.
Gentlemen - gentlemen!
Remember, you are in the Vatican, please.
What is it that you want?
Yes -- you will take control.
We'll gladly put you at the helm of our little fleet.
But our ships, must all sail in the same direction.
Otherwise, who can say how long,
your stay with us will last?
It's not personal, it's only business.
You should know, Godfather.
Very well. You want to do business with me.
I will, do business, with you.
Vipers, all of them.
- We're back with the Borgias.
- Uncle Michael.
Andrew.
I heard you were here.
It's so nice to see you.
- Vincent.
- How are you, Andrew? - You look so nice.
Listen, what is this with the Borgias?
Those days are over Uncle Michael...
- Recognize it?
- Yeah.
Genco Olive Oil.
That's where our Grandfather got his start.
Started as a delivery boy, made three bucks a week.
Three years later, he owned the company.
- Only in America.
- That's it.
Hey Vincenzo, where have you been hiding?
You deserted us, and we need your help so badly.
Well now I'm back, what can I do for you?
Get rid of Joe Zasa.
He sells drugs to children.
Listen, when I was a young girl it was different.
Now I'm an old woman...
...I'm afraid to walk the streets at night, you know?
Where are they supposed to be at?
- Lou, what's going on?
- He's going pazzo.
- We're late.
- Don't tell me that garbage.
- Have I ever let you down?
- I trust you.
- Don't worry about it.
- Thank you very much.
- Bye bye.
- Enjoy yourself.
- What was that?
- The neighborhood's in trouble.
- You keep your eye out for them?
- That's right.
- And for me?
- From now on.
I missed you all this time.
I missed you, too, cousin.
I missed growing up with all my cousins.
I didn't even know you and I missed you.
Do you remember stories about our fathers,
the old days?
Yeah. What do you want to know?
What was Sonny like?
He was the Prince of the city.
Yeah -- he died before I was born but I
heard a million stories about him, he was a legend.
What about my father?
A great man, your father.
He's a hero, he saved the family.
- Vincent.
- What?
Did he kill his own brother?
No.
So those are all lies?
Just stories, sweetheart. Okay?
Okay. I believe you.
- I'm glad you're around.
- I'm glad you're here too.
I'd like to take Joey Zasa up
for a ride in this and drop him.
Joey Zasa is nothing.
He's a small-time enforcer.
He bluffs, threats, but nothing.
We'll be able to see him coming, a mile away.
- We should kill him before he kills...
- No.
Never hate your enemies. It affects your judgment.
Good evening.
Nice to see you again, Mr. Corleone.
Okay, girls, let's go.
Come on, girls.
We entrusted you to manage our money in the casinos.
It's not even 20 years. You sold the casinos,
and you made fortunes for all of us.
Bravo, Don Corleone!
Thank you.
Friends, I have come here...
...because our business together is done.
We have prospered, and now it is time for us...
...to dissolve the business relationship between us.
That's it. But I do have a little surprise. Al?
Your shares in the casino.
I thought I'd cut through all the red tape
so you can get your money right away.
- $50 million!
- Not everybody gets the same.
- It depends how much you invested, and how long for.
- nothing for you.
Michael, this is really generous!
Oh, wonderful.
- Hey, Perisi, how much did you invest?
- I don't remember.
Michael, you're blessed.
My family has done much of the hard work;
taken many risks.
All to make money, for the rest of the families.
You all know Joey Zasa.
He is, I admit, an important man.
His picture is on the cover
of the New York Times magazine.
He gets the Esquire magazine award,...
...for the best-dressed gangster.
The newspapers praise him...
...because, he hires Blacks into his family,
which shows he has a good heart.
He is famous.
Who knows?
Maybe one day...
...he will make all of you popular.
It's true.
I make more of a bella figura.
That is my nature.
But I also want to make a move
into legitimate enterprises.
I'd like to get a little pin from the Pope.
Sure, I take the Blacks and the Spanish into my family...
...because that's America.
And you guarantee that they don't
deal drugs in those neighborhoods.
I don't guarantee that.
I guarantee I'll kill anybody who does.
Let me talk to him, let me talk to him.
Who can refuse Don Altobello?
No! I say to all of you,
I have been treated this day...
...with no respect.
I've earned you all money.
I've made you rich, and I asked for little.
Good. You will not give?
I'll take.
As for Don Corleone...
...well, he makes it very clear to me today...
...that he is my enemy.
You must choose between us.
We can reason together - no - Michael,
Michael - please, let's agreed, huh?
He doesn't know what he's...
...Uh, Michael, Michael. The news is everywhere.
Everyone is saying that, that you control Immobiliare.
Immobiliare already is laundering money in Peru,
in Nassau, we know that.
Listen to me, Michael.
We've been friends for 40 years.
We should wet our beaks a little.
- We want to do business with you, Michael.
- That's right.
- We've been together for many.
- We can wash our money clean with holy water.
What the hell is that?
- It's a hit. Let's go. Follow me.
- Let's get outta here!
- My coat! It's my lucky coat!
- Forget your coat.
It's my lucky coat!
Stay right behind me!
- Fuck!
- Mikey, this way!
Zasa! You son of a bitch!
Come on, we're outta here.
- You did good, Vincent.
- Grazie.
The old Dons were pretty much wiped out.
- The ones that survived made deals with Joey Zasa.
- Altobello?
He survived.
He's with his daughters now in Staten Island.
Says he's gonna retire to Sicily.
Joey Zasa, would never pull something
like this without backing.
He's just muscle.
He's an enforcer. He's nothing.
He doesn't have the wit for that helicopter attack.
He doesn't even have the ambition,
to wipe out, the whole commission.
- Certainly not the balls.
- I say we hit back and take Zasa out!
Never let anyone know what you're thinking.
All right, let's get a, let's get a message to Joey Zasa.
I respect what he's done.
The new overthrows the old.
It's natural.
How can you do business with this guy?
I'm a businessman, first and foremost.
I want no further conflict with anyone.
Well you tell him from me,
that he can live, or he can die.
Vincent, will you shut up!
That's it.
Joey Zasa. He can't be doing this alone.
Just when I thought I was out,
they pull me back in!
Our true enemy, has not yet, shown his face.
- Has he taken his medicine?
- I don't know what he took. Get him some water!
- I've got my wind back, I've got my wind back.
- Call a doctor.
Run, run!
Run at thunderbolt.
Thunder can't hurt.
Harmless noise!
- Get an ambulance.
- Bullshit!
You deceitful old fuck.
Altobello, you fuck!
Vitals are all steady.
Lift.
- Oh, god. Dad.
- Okay, okay.
Excuse me. Clear, please.
I'll call Kay.
- Good evening, sir. Certainly, sir.
- Can we wait here? We'll be back in a few minutes.
Mr. Harrison, you said it was urgent.
Have you come to confess your sins?
Michael Corleone suffered a diabetic stroke.
I thought you ought to know that
before you read it in the papers.
He's in a coma on the critical list.
I'm here to insist the deal goes through in any event.
The Pope has not much time left.
So, as you, I am in a difficult position.
We have to ratify this deal as soon as possible.
We have an understanding.
Good. I'm going to the hospital.
- I'll pray for Mr. Corleone.
- Thank you.
- Our thoughts are with Mr. Corleone.
- Thank you, Father John.
Everything will be out in the open if Corleone dies.
Pray for time, Keinszig.
A habit born of...
a long contemplation of eternity.
- Just forget about it, Vinnie.
- Why? Why would I forget about it? It's a simple hit.
Look, I'd love to smack Joey Zasa
and then whack the bag, Okay?
But it's impossible.
He's always mingling with people,...
...in front of TV cameras in his own neighborhood.
- It's impossible.
- It's not impossible. It'll work for us.
How?
You think he's gonna let uncle Michael survive this thing?
Would you?
He may not survive anyway.
How would you do it?
I'd do it.
I'd do it myself.
Do it!
- What would you need?
- See if you can get me a couple of guys.
Hello Michael.
It's Kay.
Kay.
- I never expected you.
- No, I know, I know.
But I'm here.
- I'm glad.
- You know...
...this is the first time
I've seen you look so helpless.
It's not so bad, really.
I feel...
I'm getting wiser now.
- Yeah?
- Oh, yeah.
The sicker you get, the wiser you get, huh?
When I'm dead, I'm gonna be really smart.
- Michael - Yeah?
- I want to thank you for Tony.
He's doing really well.
He's gotten some very good notices...
...and he's going to be making his
operatic debut in Sicily in Palermo, this Easter. So,...
...so thank you.
That's a real honor.
In Sicily.
I will be there.
I won't miss that.
Mary, Tony. Go see Dad.
- Oh, sweetheart.
- Everything's going to be all right.
- How you doing, papa?
- Come here.
Your mother told me.
She told me what happened.
About Palermo?
I really wanted you to be there, Dad.
Of course. Of course. Kiss me - kiss me.
- Cousin Vinnie?
- No, he isn't here.
Why don't, why don't you call his apartment,
leave a message on his machine?
- It's your cousin, Mary.
- Let her in.
- Thanks. Hi, cuz.
- Hi.
I just thought I'd drop by.
Is that okay?
I'm gonna go get the guys.
No, it's not okay.
You shouldn't have come Mary.
A couple minutes only, okay?
- You look beautiful, cuz.
- Thanks.
So this is your club, your hideout?
- Yeah.
- I came to check it out.
It's so strange,
just me and Aunt Connie in the house.
I feel better when I'm with you.
What's wrong, sweetheart?
- I'm really scared about my father.
- Don't be scared.
When I saw them take him out of that ambulance,
I thought he was dead.
I know.
Everybody says he's gonna be better.
Don't worry, okay?
I remember them shooting at our house
when I was little.
And Al Neri came one time
with other bodyguards...
...which just took me and Tony away.
Is it all happening again?
Not like that, sweetheart.
Then why are you hiding here?
Is something going to happen to you?
Nothing's gonna happen to me, cugina.
I'll take care of you.
- Can I stay here and hide out with you for a while?
- You can help me make gnocchi here for the boys.
You know I don't know how to cook, but I'll help.
- Okay.
- What do I do?
- I love you, cuz.
- I love you, too, cuz.
Okay, let's cook.
Hold me.
You know the people like you in the press,
the police, use words like Mafia, Cosa Nostra.
This is a fantasy.
The Italian-Americans are great people.
We laid the bricks that built this city.
We have the artists.
We have Meucci who invented the telephone.
We have Don Ameche who played the guy
who invented the telephone, eh?
So, listen, come on. Buy yourself a nice raffle ticket.
Maybe win yourself a Cadillac.
This sausage, is wonderful.
Here, have a sandwich. Let's go.
- Nice to see you, Mr. Zasa.
- Have a nice time.
Don't forget to buy your raffle tickets, huh?
- What are you doin'?
- The kid didn't mean nothing.
- He's sorry. Come here son, tell him you're sorry.
- Okay, let's go.
What's what?
How are you?
How are you, buddy boy, huh?
Hey, Joey Zasa! Joey! Up your ass!
- Who is this? I never talked to him. You know him?
- Ignore him.
Hey, Joey, who's gonna win the car, huh?
The Ant?
This is the thing that gives the Italian-Americans
a bad name, huh? A cappone like this, huh?
Hey, Joey, up your ass!
Hey, why don't you get off of the fucking car, huh?
You got a raffle ticket?
Hey Joe, take, take a good look at my raffle ticket,
here we go.
Here's what I think of you, and your raffle ticket.
I told you, get the fuck outta here before I break
your fucking jaw, you understand you son-of-a-bitch!
Now why don't you get the fuck outta here!
Get outta here! Get outta here!
Run, Joey, you piece of shit!
- Open the door! Open the door!
- Hi, Joe.
Don't ever again give that kind of order.
Not while I'm alive. Understand?
You were too sick to make a decision.
I got a go-ahead from Neri.
I got a go-ahead from Connie.
It was the right decision, Uncle Michael.
It was the wrong decision.
I command this family.
Right or wrong! It was not what I wanted!
Do you understand?
Yes.
Come on, Michael.
Yes!
Good. Vincent,...
...help me to my bed.
I wanna talk to you alone for a minute.
You know, I always felt responsible for you.
You know that.
Your father, my brother, we were, opposites.
We would fight and argue.
But I never doubted his love.
He would do anything for me.
But his temper...
...it was too much.
Clouded his reason.
And I don't want you to make that mistake.
Also, he too, had a way with women.
- Vincent...  - So I hear.
- What are you doing with my daughter?
What are you doing with her?
It's too dangerous.
You hear me?
Vincenzo.
When they come, they'll come at what you love.
Michael, you must lead another life.
You have everything a man could desire.
It's time for you to retire.
I have too much responsibility.
Too difficult now.
You should really get out.
What do you know
about those pezzonovante in Italy?
I'm too old to know anything about those new people.
I must accept my age and grow my Olives and Tomatoes.
- We're not that old.
- But you're very ill.
Let me see what can be done.
Let me work to make your path a little easier.
Your friendship does that always.
That makes me happy.
Joey Zasa -- you were wrong about him.
I trust too much.
That's always been my fault.
Michael, treachery is everywhere.
You still have your fingers on the strings,
even now.
Let's see more of each other.
- Michael -- in Sicily?
- In Sicily.
- In Sicilia.
How are you, Don?
Don Bandito, my old friend.
I wanted to bring you here...
...so that my old friend and protector,
Don Tommasino could advise us.
The bloodbath in Atlantic City
left New York a mess.
Now, Joey Zasa at least was running
a very tight ship.
But now that he's out of the picture,
we're obligated to step in.
Step back in?
If we don't,
the Chinese and Colombians will.
Our ships must all sail in the same direction.
Italian politics have had
these kind of men for centuries.
They are the true Mafia.
The Archbishop and the Vatican bank,
that's the big problem.
They're the same problem.
B.J., they're connected.
The Archbishop has very powerful friends.
They totally protect him.
Bene.
I will go see this Cardinal Lamberto and
see if we can work things out in a civilized way.
You honor your agreements.
But these people you're dealing with are crooks.
They have no honor.
My word is final.
I've invited you all here...
...to celebrate my son's
first appearance in an opera house.
- We're playing Philadelphia.
- He'll be appearing...
- ...what's Philadelphia?
- In about three weeks...
...seven cards, two down,
four up, one down...
- ...in the theatre Maximo...
- deuces and one-eyed jacks are wild.
In the opera "Cavalleria Rusticana".
- It's Cavalleria Rusticana Dad.
- Cavalleria.
I think I've got tickets to the wrong opera.
I've been in New York too long.
Anyway...
...you will all receive tickets,. So come on time.
Uh, dad, I've got a present for you.
It comes from the town of Corleone
and uh, it's authentic Sicilian.
And uh, I learned it for you.
She was, wonderful, beautiful.
I loved her.
And she died.
My trusted bodyguard...
...planted a bomb in my car.
She drove it before I did.
Why is such a beautiful country so violent?
History.
You know, mom was telling me about the old days,...
- ...when her biggest worry was just passing exams.
- Yes, it was then.
I worry about you now.
Oh Mary. Mary you're such a warm-hearted girl,
you always were.
- I love my family.
- Even your cousin Vincent?
I really love him.
- He's your first cousin.
- Then I love him first.
Mary, you can't see him.
Just don't see him anymore.
He's right.
It's too dangerous.
Mary, listen to me.
You can't see him anymore.
- Not in that fashion.
- No.
- Please, promise me.
- No!
- Obey me on this Mary!
- No, Dad!
Mary's smart, Dad.
She'll understand eventually.
- You wanted to see me?
- Yeah.
- I want you to do something for me.
- Okay.
It's dangerous.
Good, I'm in.
What do you need?
I want you to sell your soul to Don Altobello to betray me.
He'd never believe me.
Here.
- That depends.
- Sit down.
I have an idea.
See if you can learn
how high Altobello is connected.
Arrange a meeting.
You say how devoted you are to me.
Tell him your problems.
- You ask for his help.
- What problems?
That you want to run away with my daughter.
Only you know that if you do,
I will become your enemy.
You know I would never do that, Uncle Mike.
I know.
You ask Altobello to speak to me.
To further the marriage.
But you're cousins, after all.
Michael was always a little old-fashioned.
Explain to him how, you can never be part of my,
legitimate world. That you want your own family.
I could straighten out what Joey Zasa left behind.
If you could use your friendship to persuade him.
I would be indebted to you forever.
Corleone, knows the value of such a friend.
So then you would work for me?
Remember...
...if he hints that he wants you to betray me, get insulted.
Because that's his trap.
You're not telling me the whole truth, Vincenzo.
Isn't it true, with Michael gone...
...the girl controls everything?
You leave the girl out of this.
Of course, you love her, and she loves you.
I guessed it Vincenzo, huh?
You're a wise man, Don Altobello.
I'm going to be learning a lot from you.
The richest man is the one
with the most powerful friends.
It's my duty to make the introductions.
Don Lucchesi.
Don Altobello tells me you have a good character,
strong, a man of respect.
This is the hero who put Joey Zasa in his grave.
If we'd have known of his existence,
we would never have backed Joey.
No one wants another Joe.
Let me be your friend.
Even the strongest man needs friends.
I'm flattered.
But you're a man of finance and politics, Don Lucchesi,...
...these are things I don't understand.
You understand guns.
Finance is a gun.
Politics is knowing when to pull the trigger.
How can I help?
Blessed is the peacemaker,
for he can be can be called a child of God.
I trusted this business arrangement
with the Archbishop.
I trusted him.
I was sure his honesty was beyond a doubt.
But, as you see, I'm now the victim of a swindle.
They're stalling me.
Vast moneys have gone to the pezzonovante
in high political places...
...and the Vatican bank is the guarantor.
If uh, what you say is true, there will be a great scandal.
Look at this stone. It has been lying
in the water for a very long time,...
...but the water has not penetrated it.
Look. Perfectly dry.
The same thing has happened to men in Europe.
For centuries, they have been
surrounded by Christianity,...
...but Christ has not penetrated.
Christ doesn't breathe within them.
- What's happening?
- Is it possible...
...that you could get me something sweet?
Orange juice, anything, a candy.
I have a little trouble with diabetes.
Blood sugar levels must be low.
I understand.
When I'm under stress, sometimes this happens.
I come to you, on such a delicate matter...
...accusations against your Archbishop.
It was difficult for me.
The mind suffers and the body, cries out.
That's true.
Would you like, to make your confession?
Your Eminence, I'm uh - I'm uh...
...it's been so long, I wouldn't -
I wouldn't - I wouldn't know where to uh,...
...it's been 30 years.
I'd - I'd - I'd use up too much of your time, I think.
I always have time to save souls.
Well, I'm -- I'm beyond redemption.
I hear the confessions of my young priests here.
Sometimes the desire to confess is overwhelming...
...and we must seize the moment.
What is the point of confessing if I don't repent?
I hear you are a practical man.
What have you got to lose, huh?
Go on.
I uh, betrayed my wife.
Go on, my son.
I betrayed myself.
I killed men.
And I ordered men to be killed.
Go on, my son, go on.
Nah, it's useless.
Go on, my son.
I killed...
...I ordered the death of my brother.
He injured me.
I killed my mother's son.
I killed my father's son.
Your sins are terrible, and it is just that you suffer.
Your life, could be redeemed,
but I know that you don't believe that.
You will not change.
Connie,...
...all my life I, kept trying to go up in society,...
...where everything higher up was legal, straight.
But the higher I go, the crookeder it becomes.
How in the hell does it end?
Killing each other for centuries here.
For money, for pride, for family.
To keep from becoming the slaves
of the rich pezzonovante.
I made confession, Connie.
I confessed my sins.
Why Michael, that's not like you.
You don't have to confess your sins to a stranger.
It was the man.
A good man. A true priest.
He can change things.
Michael,...
...you know, sometimes I think of poor Fredo, drowned.
It was God's will.
It was a terrible accident.
But it's finished.
Michael, I love you.
I'll always help you.
It's okay.
- Welcome.
- Oh, Connie! How are you?
- Mary, I missed you.
- I've missed you too.
- Well, hello Michael.
- Hello Kay.
- Mom, look at this.
- What, let me see - oh! My - wow!
You know it's too bad that Douglas couldn't be with us.
No, no, I know. He wanted to come very much,
but he had a very important trial.
- I know he wanted to come.
- I know.
- The car is...
- Okay.
Well, your son's an artist, huh?
- Oh, yes, thanks to you.
- Oh, what for?
- For making me let him go.
- Oh, well.
After all these years,
here I am in Sicily for the first time.
- I want to get a picture of you together.
- Oh, Okay.
Hey, Dad, smile.
I see you still have Al Neri.
Why?
Well, I need him.
He helps me get in and out of the car.
Carry my briefcase.
You're still a liar, Michael.
Let me show you Sicily. The real Sicily.
Maybe you'll understand
the family history a little better.
Oh I think I understand it well enough.
Anthony, I have something you made for me...
...a very long time ago.
- It may bring you luck.
- Thanks.
You saved it, huh?
- Remember?
- I remember.
Thank you Dad.
- I'm proud of you.
- Thank you.
- Are they as good as they look?
- They're better.
They're the best.
As long as they're around, Uncle Michael is safe.
- Bye.
- Tell your father I'll be back for dinner.
- Okay.
- Have fun.
- And tell Tony to be sure to wait for me.
Okay, I will.
- Bye, mom!
- Buon giorno, Signora.
At your service.
If I see dad, I'll tell him you left.
You're the only one left in this family
with my father's strength.
If anything happens to Michael,
I want you to strike back.
I'll have everything ready.
You swear?
I swear to you.
Here it is.
The house where my father was born.
This is where they came, to take him when he was a boy.
To kill him.
Wait, listen to that.
You know, Mary's in love.
Yes, I know.
With a handsome young Italian man
with dark eyes.
I won't allow it.
It's wrong.
It's wrong, and it's dangerous.
Honor, huh?
You know, I remember the time
that you came to my parent's house.
And you took me into that room.
And you told me about the family business...
...and how you were never going to have
anything to do with it. You sounded like Tony.
I was a lot like Tony.
- I can barely see. Kay.
- What?
- You mind driving?
- No. What's wrong?
My eyes... sometimes
they're all right, and then...
- Ssure.
- Listen, I have to see Don Tommasino.
Oh! Oh, my God!
- Well there's no bodyguards today.
- I really snuck away.
- Calo, how are you?
- Hi. Nice to see you.
- How are you?
- Bene. - Hi.
- Kay, this is Calo, my old friend.
- How do you do?
One of my bodyguards in the old days.
- We can wait here.
- You want drink?
- Yes. Shall we go in?
- Sure.
I spent a lot of time in this room...
...thinking of you.
And then you got married.
I still thought of you.
What's in that room?
You know this is dangerous for you, Michael.
This is Sicily.
- I love this country.
- Why?
Well, all through history,
terrible things have happened to these people.
Terrible injustices.
But they still expect good
rather than bad will happen to them.
Sort of like me and you, huh?
- How so?
- Well I'm still here, right?
We do have a bad history.
- But I'm still here.
- Oh Yes, you are, but with dread.
Give me the order. Come on.
What is that supposed to do,
is that supposed to make me not dread you?
We're in Sicily. It's opera.
Okay.
What do we do now?
Be reasonable. Let's try not to hurt each other.
I want you to forgive me.
- For what?
- Everything.
- Like God, huh?
- Oh, I - I need something a little closer.
You couldn't understand back in those days...
I love my father.
I swore I would never be, a man like him...
...but I loved him.
And he was in danger; what could I do?
And then later you were in danger.
Our children were in danger.
What could I do?
You were all that I loved, valued, most in the world.
And now I'm losing you.
I lost you anyway.
You're gone, and it was all for nothing.
So...
...you have to understand,
I had a whole different destiny planned.
All right, I'll stop.
I really don't know what you want from me,
Michael - I really don't know.
- I mean...
- I'm not the man that you think I am?
- I don't know.
- I love you, Kay.
Don't dread me anymore.
You know, every night here in Sicily.
I dream, about my wife and my children.
And how I lost them.
I guess, if it's any consolation,
I want you to know that...
...that -- I always loved you, Michael.
And, you know...
I always - I always will.
Frederik Keinszig,
known for a decade as "God's banker,"...
...has been reported missing.
He was last seen three days ago,...
...leaving the Rome offices of the Vatican
owned corporation International Immobiliare.
Also missing was a large sum of money,
and several documents.
Come on, Keinszig, you fool.
Mr. Keinszig's absence casts further
suspicion on the dealings of the Vatican bank.
For several years, the bank
and its subsidiary companies...
...have been the object of allegations
of disreputable business practices.
Lucchesi,...
...will you please try and understand?
I have phoned him.
I have waited here by the phone.
You would do well to remember, Mr. Lucchesi...
...that this Pope has very different ideas...
...from the last one.
Good-bye, my old friend.
You could've lived a little longer.
I could be closer to my dream.
You were so loved, Don Tommasino.
Why was I so feared, and you so loved?
What was it?
I was no less honorable.
I wanted to do good.
What betrayed me?
My mind? My heart?
Why do I condemn myself so?
I swear on the lives of my children.
Give me a chance to redeem myself,...
...and I will sin no more.
You look pale. Bad news.
Tell me right away.
It's not just a bad banking deal.
These guys are butchers.
What guys?
Lucchesi. He controls all of them.
Altobello, the Archbishop,...
...other people higher up, P2, maybe.
Secret, unknown.
They're running things.
- I'm in their way.
- Yeah.
He's hired a professional assassin to kill you.
He's Sicilian.
I don't know his name.
They say he never fails.
Then no one is safe.
Even the new Pope is in danger.
No. We still have time. We can prevent this.
I tried Vincent.
I tried, to keep everything from coming to this.
But it's not possible. Not in this, world.
Give me the order.
You won't be able to go back.
- You'll be like me.
- Good.
All my life I wanted out. I wanted the family, out.
Well I don't want out.
I want the power to preserve the family.
I'm asking for the order.
- It's done.
- Because I can't do it anymore.
Well, it doesn't matter.
Vincent knows what to do. Come on outside.
Take a rest and -- and don't think about it.
- All I do is think about it.
- I'm your son. Command me in all things.
Give up my daughter.
That's the price you pay, for the life you choose.
Nephew, from this moment on,...
...call yourself Vincent Corleone.
Sit.
Et Tu, Vincenzo?
I know how you feel about Michael,
but you, you can't save him.
He's lost.
Think of yourself.
What's your answer, Vincent?
Enjoy the opera.
It's all taken care of.
You check the balcony.
I'll check the top fioor.
"Here's hoping Tony sings better at Theatre Maximo
than he does in the shower. Love, Douglas."
My darling, Constanzia.
- This is a great occasion. Yes.
- Come and sit down.
Happy birthday.
You're 80 years old, you don't look more than 60.
You're the only one who remembered.
Michael, we just got the word.
The Pope's ratifying the Immobiliare deal. We've won.
Congratulations.
How strange, the way things work.
The Pope's doing exactly what you said he'd do,
he's cleaning house.
Well, he should be careful.
It's dangerous to be an honest man.
I wanna put more muscle backstage with Tony.
- On your birthday, you used to shower me with treats.
- Tootsie Rolls!
The nuns who made these cannolis took
a vow of silence. They're the very finest.
- Hey, cuz.
- Where's your leather?
Stop it.
You're so thin.
You eat it.
It's over Mary. There are things I have to do
that you can't be a part of.
Don't look at your father,
it's not your father's decision, it's mine.
Don't hate your father.
There are things I'm going to be part of,
you can't be around.
- After tonight, you won't see me anymore.
- No.
You gotta understand,
Mary -- you gotta understand.
I'll always love you.
Love somebody else.
- To Tony.
- They won't try anything.
- Yeah, everything is fine. It's all clear I think.
I've already sent Al Neri to the Vatican.
Check out the side.
Good. You got him.
Tonight the Corleone family settles its accounts.
Keinszig -- that little Swiss banker fuck.
He's been swindling everyone from the beginning.
Fuck him.
Don Lucchesi. My friend.
Calo will pay him a visit at his home.
Neri, take a train to Rome.
Light a candle for the Archbishop.
Michael, it's serious. Our man inside the
Vatican says there's a plot against the Pope.
You mean he's going to have a heart attack in the night.
This Pope has powerful enemies.
We may not be in time to save him.
Now let's go back to the opera.
Sleep. Sleep, Godfather.
- I like this opera.
- Yeah, I figured you would.
- Bravo. Say hello.
- Thank you.
- Did you like it?
- Great.
Let's get out of here.
- Can I please talk to you now?
- Not now Mary, it's not a good time.
- You're just like my father.
- Come on, stay with the family. Go on.
- Talk to me.
- The twins are dead.
In about one minute, there's going to be
carabinieri crawling all over this place.
- Okay. Let's get everybody to the cars, nice and quiet.
- Okay.
- Got it.
- Quiet.
When they hear the name Corleone,
they're going to think of a voice.
Dad.
This is my mom.
Dad? Why are you doing this to me.
- Go on, move back. Go on, move back.
- Hey, move!
- You don't have to do this to me, Please.
- Doing what? What do you mean?
Mary, please come...
Dad?
- No! Mary!
- Oh, God!
Oh, God, No! Oh, God, no, Please!
Mom, come on.
Let her go.
Let go.