Yeah, I worked
in a barber shop,
But I never considered
myself a barber.
I stumbled into it well,
married into it, more precisely.
It wasn't my establishment.
Like the fella says, I only work here.
The dump was 200 feet square...
With three chairs,
or stations, as we call 'em,
Even though there are only
two of us working.
But this is my point.
My point is that these traders and trappers
would come to this country,
Get their pelts
and their gold "ignots"
Frank Raffo, my brother-in-law,
was the principal barber.
Man, could he talk.
Maybe if you're 11 or 12 years old,
Frank's got an interesting point of view,
But sometimes
it got on my nerves.
Not that I complained,
mind you.
Like I said, he was
the principal Barber.
Frank's father August
they called him Guzzi
Had worked the heads up
in Santa Rosa for 35 years...
Until his ticker stopped
in the middle of a junior flattop.
He left the shop to Frankie free and clear,
And that seemed to satisfy
all of Frank's ambitions
Cutting the hair
and chewing the fat.
Me, I don't talk much.
I just cut the hair.
It says here that the russians
exploded an a-bomb...
And there's not a damn thing
we can do about it.
How do you like them apples?
Being a barber is a lot like
being a bar man or a soda jerk.
There's not much to it once
you've learned the basic moves.
For the kids, there's the butch,
or the heinie,
The flattop, the ivy,
The crew, the vanguard,
The junior contour...
And occasionally
the executive contour.
lived in a little bungalow
on napa street.
The place was okay, I guess.
Had an electric icebox,
a gas hearth...
And a garbage grinde
built into the sink.
You might say I had it made.
Oh, year,
there was one other thing.
Doris kept the books
at Nirdlingers,
A small department store
on main street.
Doris liked the work,
accounting.
She liked knowing
where everything stood
And she got a ten percent employee
discount on whatever she wanted
Nylon stockings,
Makeup and perfume.
Doris and I went to church
once a week.
Usually Tuesday night.
Doris wasn't big
on divine worship,
And I doubt if she believed
in life everlasting.
She'd most likely tell you
that our reward is on this earth,
And bingo is probably
the extent of it.
B-7
Watch you card,
honey.
I wasn't crazy
about the game,
But, I don't know,
it made her happy,
And I found the setting
peaceful.
Jesus. Bingo.
Bingo!
Doris's boss,
Big Dave Brewster,
Was married to Ann Nirdlinger,
the department store heiress.
Tonight they were coming over for dinner.
As Doris said,
We were entertaining.
Me, I don't like
entertaining.
- How you doin', Ed?
- Okay.
Take your coat, Ann?
The japs had us pinned down
on Buna for somethin' like six weeks.
I gotta tell ya,
I thought we had it tough,
but we had supply.
The japs were eatin' bugs
and grubs and thistles.
Anyway, one day
we bust off the beach...
And we find Arney Bragg,
this kid missin' on recon.
the japs had eaten the son of a bitch.
If you'll pardon the, uh...
Anyway, he was a scrawny, pimply kid,
nothin' to write home about.
I mean, I never woulda,
you know.
So, what do I say, honey?
What do I say
when I don't like dinner?
Come on.
what do I say?
I say,
"Arney Bragg, again?"
Arney Bragg, again?
- Were you in the service, Ed?
- No, Dave, I wasn't.
Ed was 4-f on account
of his fallen arches.
That's tough.
That's... That's tough.
Yeah, I guess Doris liked
all that he-man stuff.
Sometimes I had the feeling that
She and Big Dave were a lot closer
than they let on.
The signs were all there,
plain enough.
Not that I was gonna
prance about it, mind you.
It's a free country.
Holdin' down the porch area, Ed?
- That's some wife you got there.
- Yeah.
She's a rare one.
So, how's business,
Dave?
Oh, uh, couldn't be better.
These are boom times
in retailin', Ed.
We're openin' another store
over there on carson,
Big Dave's annex.
Now, this is strictly haberdashery.
It's casual wear, pajamas,
ladies' undergarments and foundations,
That type of thing.
As a matter of fact,
I'm thinkin' of makin' Doris the comptroller.
Listen, when the annex opens up,
you gotta stop by.
Maybe we can update your suit
a little bit, huh?
Course, you're in
the smock all day.
Where do you get those things,
anyway?
Specialty store
down in Sacramento.
You tie your own flies.
I mean, if you're really serious,
you tie your own flies.
You do, uh...
I know. It's meticulous.
I know.
People say, hey, you can
buy flies at the store.
The point is, there's a certain art
to the process.
The point is not merely to provide.
Let me point out, these fish are not
as dumb as you might think.
Sure.
Go to the store.
Describe to the man
where you will be fishing and for what,
And then you might as well have the man
sell you the goddamned fish, Ed.
My point is,
This is a man who knows nothing,
no matter how much you tell him.
- So sell him the goddamned fish, Ed.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Who gets the privilege?
We're just closing, friend.
Oh, happy days.
I wish I was doing well enough
to turn away business.
What's the problem, friend?
this is a business establishment with posted hours.
More power to ya, brother.
The public be damned.
Hey...
I'll take care of him.
you go ahead, Frank.
Have a seat, mister.
- You sure, Eddie?
- Yeah, yeah, go ahead.
In your ear, mister.
Oh, those fiery
Mediterraneans.
Uh, say, uh,
not so fast there, brother.
Pretty good, eh?
Fools even the experts.
One hundred percent human hair.
Handcrafted by Jacques
Of San Francisco.
I'd hate to have to tell you
what I paid for it.
Yeah, it's a nice rug.
I'm payin' it down
on the installment plan.
A lot of folks live
with the pate exposed.
They say the dames
think it's sexy,
But for my money
it's just not good groomin'.
And groomin' my friend,
is probably the most important thing in business.
After personality, of course.
Creighton Tolliver.
Pleased to know ya.
Ed Crane.
So, what brings you
to Santa Rosa?
A goose, my friend.
I was chasin' a wild goose.
Ed, have you ever heard
of venture capital?
Risk money.
very speculative.
Except that in certain situations
it's not, see.
I thought I had
a prospect here
Well, I make the haul up...
And this lousy so-and-so tells me...
That the situation has changed.
All of his capital's tied up
in expansion plans of his own.
Thank you mother.
Pop goes another bubble.
It's only the biggest business opportunity
since Henry Ford,
And I can't seem
to interest a soul.
Is that right?
It's called dry cleaning.
You heard me right, brother.
dry cleaning.
Wash without water.
No suds. No tumple.
No stress on the clothes.
It's all done
with chemicals, friend.
And here's the capper...
No shrinkage.
That's right.
Dry cleaning.
All I need is $10,000
to open up the first store.
Then I use its cash flow
to finance another, and so on,
Leapfrog, bootstrap myself
to a whole chain.
Well, me and a partner.
Cleanliness, friend.
There's money in it.
there's a future.
There's room to grow.
Say, that looks pretty good.
Let's see it
with the hairpiece on.
Dry cleaning.
Was I crazy
to be thinking about it?
Was he a huckster or an opportunity,
the real Mccoy?
My first instinct was
no, no, the whole idea was nuts.
But maybe that was the instinct
that kept me locked in the barber shop,
Nose against the exit
afraid to try turning the knob.
- Honey?
- Hmm?
Shave my legs, will ya?
What if I could
get the money?
It was clean.
No water.
Chemicals.
Gimme a drag.
Love ya, honey.
What you...
uh, come in.
Okay, yeah.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Oh. I thought
you were the porter.
Can I help ya?
I'm Ed.
Ed Crane.
Um, I cut your hair today.
I'm the barber.
Jesus, yeah.
The barber.
I didn't recognize you
without the smock.
Did I leave somethin'
at the shop?
No. No,
it's nothing like that.
Um, l-I might be interested
in that business proposition.
You got the dough?
Well, I can get it.
Come in. Come in!
Sit down over there.
- Coffee?
- No.
Well, sit down,
make yourself comfortable.
So tell me...
Other than putting up the money, uh,
exactly what would you want the partner to, uh...
Do?
Hell, nothin'.
You're gonna want to keep
tabs on your investment,
The running of the business,
but I'm looking for a silent partner.
I've done the research,
I've contacted the vendors.
The deal is set.
Disappear, if you'd like.
Check in whenever you want.
I want the dough.
I don't take attendance.
And how do we share the...
Fifty-fifty,
straight down the line.
You and me.
Finance and expertise.
So you got the dough then,
do ya?
I can have it in a week.
The barber...
Well, I thought this trip
was gonna be a bust.
Just shows to go ya,
when one door slams shut,
Another one opens.
Here's to you, uh...
Was that a pass?
Maybe.
Well, you're out of line, mister
Not a problem.
Way out of line.
Right.
Strictly business.
Okay.
I sent it to Dave
the next morning.
Then I waited.
- Frank?
- Huh?
This hair.
Yeah?
You ever wonder about it?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
How it keeps on coming.
It just keeps growing.
Yeah.
Lucky for us, huh, pal?
No, I mean,
It keeps growing,
And it's part of us.
And then we cut it off
and throw it away.
Come on, Eddie.
You're gonna scare the kid.
Okay, bud, you're through.
I'm gonna take this hair
and throw it out in the dirt.
What?
I'm gonna mingle it
with common house dirt.
What the hell
are you talking about?
I don't know.
Skip it.
Ed, gimme a zip.
Where you going?
Us. The party at Nirdlingers.
I told you last week.
The Christmas push.
Come on, get ready.
It's important.
Nah, you go ahead.
I'm not big on parties.
Oh, don't be a grump.
Gimme a zip.
Hey, uh, ain't you
in ladies' wear?
Huh? Haven't I seen you
up in ladies' wear?
I don't work here.
My wife does
Uh-huh. Whew.
That's some beat, huh?
Yeah.
Lucky for us, huh, pal?
Check out the rack
on that broad in the angora.
Ed, can I talk to you?
Sure.
Come in.
Oh, sit down.
Souvenired it off a jap
in New Guinea.
Guess you're, uh, wonderin'
what Doris was so hot about.
Havanas.
My private stock.
Romeo and Juliet.
Ed, I...
What is it, Dave?
Ed, I've been weak.
I've been weak.
The, uh...
You're gonna burn yourself.
Thanks.
l, uh...
Oh, Jesus.
I've been carryin' on
with a married woman.
No one you know.
And now the, uh,
The chickens are
comin' home to roost.
I got a note.
A blackmail note, you know.
Come across,
or everybody knows.
I guess you know
what that would do to me.
I guess that would be
pretty awkward.
Awkward?
Yeah. Yeah.
Ann would throw me
right out on my keister.
I mean, it's her st...
It's her family's store, Ed.
It's her store.
I serve at the indulgence
of the goddamn ownership.
The lady's husband
would know.
- How much do they want, Dave?
- Ten thousand dollars.
I don't know what to do, Ed.
I don't know what I can do.
You know,
I know who
the son of a bitch is.
You know... who who is?
The son of a bitch.
The blackmailer.
I know who he is.
It's no one you know.
It's a businessman from Sacramento.
A goddamn pansy, Ed.
Tryin' to rope me
into some crackpot scheme.
I heard him out,
then I told him to go to hell.
The very next day
the very next day I get a note,
the blackmail note,
Asking me for the same amout of money
he asked me for.
The very next day.
Ten thousand dollars.
How did he know that
you were seein' the woman?
He stayed at the hotel
that I went to with the, uh,
lady in question.
He must've seen us.
Oh, Jesus.
I don't know what to do.
Why don't you just pay him. Dave?
Cause that's my capitalization
on the annex.
That's my operation.
Christ almighty, Ed.
That's what I just talkin'
to Doris about down there
A way to get the money from the store
that we could hide from Ann.
Doris, she was, she was pretty hot
about that, god bless her.
Embezzlin', Ed.
Embezzlin' from
my own goddamn wife.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
In a way,
I felt bad for Big Dave.
I knew that ten grand was going to
pinch him where it hurt,
But Doris was two-timing me
And I guess somewhere
that pinched a little too.
That was pretty.
Did you make that up?
Oh, no.
No, that was written
by Ludwig Van Beethoven.
Well, it was quite something.
Yeah, he wrote some
beautiful piano sonatas.
That was really something.
I'm Ed Crane.
I know who you are, Mr. Crane.
My father used to take me with him
when he went to get his hair cut.
Walter Abundas?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Walter.
Yeah, I'm Rachel Abundas.
But everyone call me Birdy.
I'm sorry.
I just didn't remember.
Oh, no, it's okay.
You can't expect to remember
every skinny girl who comes in with her dad.
So you don't, uh, like
that music out there?
Not really.
I'm not big on music, ordinarily.
Ed.
What a knucklehead.
- Who?
- Dave.
Why's that?
Money problems.
He's thinking about
canceling the annex.
So?
That means I don't run Nirdlingers.
What a knucklehead.
Big Dave did it, though.
I sent a note telling him
where to drop the money.
And he did.
He came across.
Yeah. Good!
How are ya?
Come in.
I got everything organized.
How you doin'?
You got a check?
- Cash.
- Cash?
Usually these kinds of things
are done with a bank draft,
But cash, that's fine.
It's all the same in the end.
Dough is dough, huh?
Whoa, nellie.
I got the paperwork here.
Partnership papers.
They reflect our agreement.
Fifty-fifty on the net.
I provide professional services,
you provide the capital.
I'm gonna give you a receipt
on the dough here.
Uh, pretty straightforward.
- I don't know whether you wanna show it to a lawyer
- No, that's okay.
Yeah. Screw 'em, right?
Pay them to tangle it up,
then you have to pay them to untangle them.
What's the point?
You just give me a second,
I'll give you a receipt on the...
Whoa, nellie.
Okay, one thing
we didn't talk about was,
I am thinking about,
uh, calling the place Tolliver's.
After me, you know.
I didn't think you were, uh,
much interested in, uh...
- That's fine.
- Yeah, that's good. Good, good.
Now, ready?
One second and I will...
Okay, that's it.
As per our discussion.
All right, there it is,
Writ large in legal escritoire.
- And the, uh...
- Say, Creighton.
You're not gonna screw me
on this.
Screw you?
Jesus.
Take it to a lawyer.
No, I insist!
I insist!
This is dry cleaning.
This is not some fly-by-night thing here.
Oh, I'll tell you,
I have been 13 years as an entrepreneur,
and I have never...
- It's okay.
- Nobody's ever questioned me...
Hey, you want the dough back?
Huh? Huh? Do you know
who you're talkin' to here?
Do you know who I am?
Do you have any idea who...
It's okay.
So, Tolliver's is okay, then?
The next day was Saturday.
We were going to a reception
for Doris's cousin Gina...
Who just married a wop vendor
out near Modesto.
Doris didn't much feel like going,
and I didn't either.
But like she said,
we had a commitment.
I hate wops.
What's so goddamn strange
about that?
I didn't say a word.
You didn't have to
grow up with them.
Family.
Ed! Uncle Ed!
He's riding Garibaldi!
Uncle Frankie's riding Garibaldi!
That was when
she started drinking.
Doris.
Doris!
You been okay?
Mmm. Yeah.
How you doing, Costanza?
Oh, you know.
Still got my health.
And. Uh, how you been, uh...
- Ed.
He's a barber, right?
It's a good trade.
So, how come you got no kids, huh?
No, come on, kids!
l-I just ate lunch!
I couldn't eat another thing.
Oh, n... Anthony!
Anthony, it's you!
Okay, kids. Ready? And...
Congratulations. Gina.
It's so goddamn wonderful.
Life is just so goddamn wonderful,
You almost won't believe it.
- It's just a bowl of goddamn cherries.
- Let' go.
Sure.
Congratulations on your goddamn cherries!
Let go of my goddamn elbow!
I never wanna see
another blueberry pie.
I never even wanna hear those words.
Don't say those words, Ed.
Don't say those words.
I'd met Doris blind
on a double date...
With a loudmouthed buddy of mine
who was seeing a friend of hers from work.
We went to a movie.
Doris had a flask.
Boy, she could put it away.
At the end of the night,
she said she liked that I didn't talk much.
It was only a couple weeks later
she suggested we get married.
Yeah.
Ed, it's Big Dave.
I gotta talk to you.
What?
Now?
Yeah. It's important.
But it-it's...
Please, Ed.
Your place?
I'm at the store.
Let yourself in.
Dave?
I'm ruined.
They've ruined me.
This money.
No annex.
I'm all shot to hell.
So, you paid the guy?
What kind of man are you?
What kind of man...
Are you?
I mean, I'd understand
if you came in here and...
Socked me in the nose, whatever.
I deserve it.
I'm not proud of what I did.
But you.
Yeah, I paid up.
As you well know.
But then I went and
found the pansy.
Oh, you got nothin' to say, huh?
Well, you know the story.
I didn't.
I had to beat it
out of the pansy.
I'm all shot to hell.
Well, Dave, uh...
It was only a couple weeks later
she suggested we get married.
I said, "Don't you want
to get to know me more?"
She said, "Why?
Does it get better?"
She looked at me
like I was a dope,
Which I never
really minded from her.
And she had a point,
I guess.
We knew each other
as well then as now.
Anyway, well enough.
Holy, moley,
do I got a headache.
- How are you today, Ed?
- Okay.
- You don't got a headache?
- No.
Damn, I got a headache
to beat the band.
Did you pump it? You can't pump it.
That'll just flood it.
No, no, no, you gotta pump it.
You can't just hold it down.
I mean that'll flood it.
You crazy?
You pump it.
You can't hold it down.
- Just turn the key.
- Not when it's cold.
Well, if it's cold, choke it.
And pump it.
How many time?
Ed Crane?
I'm Crane.
- Come on outside.
- Sure.
I'm officer Persky.
This is Krebs.
Well, we goin'?
Cigarette?
Right.
Pete's got some news for ya.
Look, pal, um,
It's a tough break, but, um,
Well, damn it,
your wife's been pinched.
They sent us around
to tell you.
They sent us around to tell you.
We pulled the detail.
My wife?
Yeah, they brung her down
to county jail.
Homicide.
Well, embezzlement...
And homicide.
Guy named David Brewster.
He's the guy she...
H-He's the decedent.
I don't understand.
He's the dead guy.
Yeah, it's a tough break.
Visiting ends at 5:00.
Oh, uh, missed it today,
but, uh,
You can go see her tomorrow.
Sorry, pal.
They sent us to tell ya.
Crab detail.
- Hello, Walter.
- Hello, Ed.
Thanks.
Thanks for seein' me at home.
Oh, hell.
Want a drink?
Uh, no, thanks.
You sure you don't need one?
I'm fine.
- Boy.
- Yeah.
Jesus.
So, uh,
What do l, uh...
Of course, uh, l, uh...
It's out of my league.
No, I... no, l-I do probate
and real estate...
And title search.
I'd be absolutely worthless,
somethin' like this. Absolutely worthless.
Excuse me.
I just finished dinner.
Frankly, Doris'd be better off
with the county defender.
- He a good man?
- Bert's okay.
Yeah, he...
he's a good man.
Listen. I won't kid you, Ed.
Uh, there's nobody around here
has any experience with this kind of thing.
I hear they're bringing a prosecutor up.
From, uh, Sacramento.
It's a capital offense.
They're taking it seriously.
- So...
- They're taking it seriously.
So, what-what, uh...
Do you want any more coffee, dad?
Oh, hi, Mr. Crane.
Hello, Rachel.
I was so sorry to hear.
Yeah, thanks.
- Coffee, Ed?
- No, thanks.
- Ah, no, thanks, honey. We're...
- Okay, dad.
It was good to see you again,
Mr. Crane.
Damn.
A good kid.
Jesus...
Who do you think?
Lloyd Garroway in San Francisco.
Probity.
You know, nobody ever said anything iffy
about Lloyd Garroway.
He's conservative.
Jury might like that.
Might like that here.
Probity.
So, he's, uh,
the best man for...
No.
The best, the money-is-no-object best,
any lawyer'll tell you,
is Freddy Riedenschneider from...
Sacramento.
I don't know
how you're fixed for money.
- But he's...
- The best.
The best, yeah.
Riedenschneider.
No question about it.
Honey.
I brought your makeup.
Glasses.
What happened to you?
I don't know
what's goin' on... I...
what happened to Big Dave.
I know some of it.
Irregullarities in the books, they said.
Can I explain it?
You don't have to
explain anything.
I did help him cook the books, Ed.
I did do that.
Should I...
Should I tell you
why I changed the books?
You don't have to
tell me anything.
No, no, no!
Jesus Christ!
My books used to be perfect.
Anyone could open 'em up
and make sense of the whole goddamn store.
I knew we'd pay for it.
I don't care what it costs!
This is when you come together.
Well, that's awfully
generous of you, Frank.
The hell with it.
The hell with it, Eddie.
This is when you come together.
This is family.
They're just people
like you and me, Ed.
Remember that.
Just people.
They gotta put up the big front
so that people will trust 'em with their money.
This is why the big lobby, Ed.
But they put their pants on
one leg at a time just like you and me.
They, too, use the toilet, Ed,
in spite of appearances.
And their money will be secured
by the barber shop.
A rock.
A rock, the barber shop.
Mr. Raffo.
Yes, sir?
Could you come with me,
please?
Sure.
Can Ed come too?
Mister...
Crane.
Ed Crane.
You also have an interest
in the securing porperty?
He's a barber.
- Second chair.
- Not an owner.
No, he's, uh, family.
He's my brother-in-law.
It would be best
if he waited here.
The barber shop.
Doris and Frank's father had worked
30 years to own it free and clear.
Now it got signed over to the bank,
and the bank signed some over to Frank.
And Frank signed the money
to Freddy Riedenschneider.
Who got into town
two days later...
And told me to meet him
at Da Vinci's for lunch.
Not fried, poached.
Three of 'em for two minutes.
Strip steak, medium rare,
flapjacks, potatoes, tomato juice...
And plenty of hot coffee.
- You have any Prairie Oysters?
- No, sir.
Then bring me a fruit cocktail
while I wait.
- You're Crane?
- Yeah.
Barber, right?
I'm Freddy Riedenschneider.
Hungry?
Uh, not really.
They tell me the chow's okay here.
I made some inquiries.
Look, I don't want to waste your time,
so I'll eat while we talk.
Do you mind?
You don't mind.
While I'm in town
I'm staying at the Hotel Metropole.
Turandot Suite. Yeah, it's goofy.
They named their suites after operas.
Room's okay, though.
I poked around.
I'm having 'em hold it for me.
I'll be back and forth.
So, in addition to my retainer,
you're paying hotel,
Living expenses, secretarial,
Private eye, if we need to make inquiries,
head shrinker, should we go that way.
We'll talk about appeals
if, as and when.
- For now, has she confessed?
- No, of course not. She didn't do it.
Good. That helps. Not that she didn't do it
That she didn't confess.
Course, There's ways to deal with a confession,
but that's one less thing to think about.
Now, interview. I'm seeing her tomorrow.
You sholud be there 3:00.
One more thing.
you keep your mouth shut.
I get the lay of the land,
I tell you what to say.
No talking out of school.
What's out of school?
Everything's out of school.
I do the talking.
You keep your trap shut.
I'm an attorney. You're a barber.
You don't know anything.
Okay.
Good. Any questions,
give me a ring.
Turandot suite.
If I'm out, leave a message.
Sure you don't want anything?
No? Okay.
You're okay, pal.
You're okay, she's okay,
everything's gonna be hunky...
And the...
and the flapjacks, honey.
There they were,
All going about their business.
It seem like I knew a secret,
A bigger one, even,
than what had really happened to Big Dave,
Something none of them knew.
Like I had made it to the outside somehow,
And they were all still struggling
way down below.
Ann.
Hello, Ed.
Would you like to come in, Ann?
No. No, it's very late.
I'm so sorry about your loss.
Course you know that Doris
had nothing to do with it.
Nothing at all.
I know.
Don't worry, Ed.
I came to tell you...
And you should tell Doris...
Yeah?
You know how Big Dave loved camping
and the out of doors?
Yeah.
We went camping last summer
in Eugene, Oregon.
Outside Eugene, Ed.
Yeah?
At night there were lights.
We both saw them.
We never told anyone
outside of our official report,
Our report to the government.
There was a spacecraft.
I saw the creatures.
They led Big Dave onto the craft.
He never told anyone
what they did.
Ann, would you like to...
I cannot repeat it to you,
but this thing goes deep, Ed.
It goes deep
and involves the government.
This was not your wife.
There's a great deal of fear.
You know how certain circles
would-would find it,
The knowledge, a threat.
They-they try to limit it, and...
Ann, would you like to come in,
Sit down?
Maybe have a drink.
Sometimes knowledge
is a curse, Ed.
After this happened,
Things changed.
Big Dave...
He never touched me again.
Tell Doris not to worry.
I know it wasn't her.
Perhaps this will
bring it out
Finally.
Perhaps now
it will all come out.
It stinks.
But it's true.
I don't care it's true, it's not true.
It stinks.
You say he was being blackmailed?
By who? You don't know.
For having an affair.
With who? You don't know.
Did anyone else know about it?
Probably not. You don't know.
I knew about it.
Big Dave told me about it...
And the spot he was putting himself in
by getting the money.
Terrific! Your husband backs you up.
That's terrific.