You want to tell me
what this is all about?
I mean, if you want
me to protect this,
don't you want me
to know what it is?
- No, I don't.
- Okay.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Go ahead.
In all due respect, why don't
you just hire the FedEx?
Because I'm hiring you, Jack.
You want me to pick up this bag and
bring it to you, and that's it?
I want to pay you an
exorbitant amount of money
to get the bag and bring it to me.
I don't get it. Why me?
Jesus Christ. Look.
This is me.
This is you.
This is the money.
This is the bag.
You go and get the bag.
And now, Jack,
this is vitally important.
You do not look in this bag.
You do not open this bag.
You don't even take a
little peek in this bag.
The contents of this
bag are off-limits.
Understood?
Okay, I get it.
And you bring this bag to me.
And I give you the money.
Clear?
Yeah, hello.
How'd it go?
Your man, Bishop, tried to kill me.
Regardless, we stick to the plan.
What do you mean,
"We stick to the plan"?
I'm telling you your
man tried to whack me
and you're telling me
you still want me to go
to this shitty motel in
the middle of nowhere
and sit around and wait
for you all night?
Oh, yes.
How do I know there's not somebody
else waiting for me at the motel?
Jack, calm down.
I'm calm... I'm calling
you from a payphone
because he shot the fucking
cell phone out of my hand.
He put a fucking
bullet in my hand...
You didn't look in the bag, did you?
No, I didn't look in the bag.
You stick to the plan.
Yes. We stick to the plan.
Room 13.
Bishop, let's go.
You couldn't stick to
the plan, could you?
No! You shoot a guy in the hand.
Come on.
Can I help you?
Yeah. I need a room, please.
Okay.
How long you'll be staying?
One night.
Just for one night? Okay.
Yeah.
I'll need you to fill this out.
And I need to see a credit card.
I'll be paying in cash.
Excuse me?
I said, "I'll be paying in cash."
Okay.
I need you to fill out this card
and that'll be $65 plus tax.
What happened?
- What?
- Your hand is bleeding.
Oh.
I got into a fight with my wife.
She stabbed me with a steak knife.
She lunged at me.
Maybe you should go to a
hospital and get that looked at.
No, I'm fine.
I can call 'em if you'd like.
No, it's all right.
That's not necessary.
- It could be infected.
- It's not.
Might be infected
and not even know.
I said, "It's fine."
Please.
Fill out this card.
And this one, too.
Both of them.
- You're Bob Smith.
- Yeah.
- From Pittsburgh?
- Mmm-hmm.
You're gonna be in room number 6.
I want room 13, please.
- 13?
- Yeah.
Not many people ask for room 13.
So it's available, yeah?
Was you asked to ask
for that number?
Asked to ask?
- Were you?
- I'm asking you.
Room 13.
It's my lucky number.
I'm a contrarian, you know?
You're either a
contrarian or you're a victim.
You'll be in room number 13.
That's not an interconnecting room.
Interconnecting?
You can't go from one
room to the next
without going outside of the door.
Is that all right with you?
I don't give a fuck.
All right! You'll be in room number 13.
You can drive on down there.
Park by it if you'd like.
Hey!
Excuse me.
The phone in my room is dead.
The line is dead.
Oh, that's
because it's not turned on.
Could you turn it on, please?
Well, in order for me
to turn on the phone
or any incidentals,
I'll need an impression
of a major credit card.
I'll give you cash.
I'm sorry, but I'm going to
need to see a credit card.
I just told you I'll
give you some cash.
If you want to let me charge
you for the telephone calls
I'm going to need to
get an impression
of a credit card.
Even if you wanted
to get extra towels,
I'm going to need to see that card.
I don't have a credit card.
Here's another $100.
That's $400 cash.
Here's another.
Here's another $100.
Turn the phone on for me?
I can take the cash.
Okay.
Seeing as that you don't
have a credit card.
And if you can just wait a minute,
I will write you a receipt and
then I can turn on the phone.
You let me know if there's
any trouble with the line
because we just had
some work done on it.
I don't know why.
It seemed okay to me.
They said otherwise the whole
place could go up in smoke.
That's what they said.
- Your hand feeling any better?
- Yes.
That's good.
Is there anything else that I can
do to help you this evening?
No.
Have a good night.
Hey, man.
Got a match?
No.
Why not?
Why don't you have a match?
Hello?
Yes.
That's fine.
Yeah, that's fine. I'll be waiting.
Sorry to bother you.
I was wondering
if you had a corkscrew
I could borrow.
No.
Sorry to disturb you.
I said, "Wait here,
bitch, till I get back."
How long are we going
to stay in this place?
Until I do what I got to do!
I don't wanna be a part of this.
Shut your mouth and get your ass in
there. I said I got business. Now, go!
To tell you the truth, Janet,
I'm more annoyed at
myself than I am at you.
I like to think of myself
as being a reasonably savvy
person who can appraise the
value, the fabric if you will,
of the people who work for me.
Jesus Christ!
You'd think I'd have a goddamn
notepad in this office, wouldn't ya?
Dragna, it was a mistake.
You know something?
I don't like surprises. I never did.
I never really enjoyed that
whole Pop Goes The Wease lthing.
I mean, don't get me wrong.
I appreciate the unexpected.
And, in fact, I'd say I'm a
connoisseur of the unexpected.
But I don't like surprises.
Do you understand the
distinction I'm making here?
Yes.
But I don't think you understand
what I'm saying. I don't...
Oh!
Eureka!
Dragna, I'm not a currency trader.
You asked me to sit
in front of the screen
because Melinda was
out with the flu.
Do you know how hard it is to get
a mole in the Bank of Japan?
Even the yakuza couldn't do it.
And you know why?
Because they're savages.
- I can't find a pen in this office.
- Everybody was yelling.
I got confused. I pressed the buy
button instead of the sell button.
Just before the Bank of
Japan flooded the market
with Yen to weaken their currency.
Hmm.
The name I just wrote,
go see that guy.
He's the best plastic
surgeon in New York.
And you could pick
any nose you want.
Your old one.
Audrey Hepburn,
Beyonce, Barbra Streisand.
Whatever the hell you want.
My plane's here so I'm off.
Janet, no more surprises, okay?
Hi. Could I stay here for a while?
Please! Just until they leave.
Get up.
I said, "Get up"!
Please, I can't go out there.
- Get out.
- He's crazy. He'll kill me.
Are you deaf? Get out!
They're out of their minds.
Him and that midget.
Move. Move.
Please, mister,
I can't go out there.
They're going to fucking kill me.
Please.
What if I told them
what's under your bed?
What did you say?
What if I told them
what's under your bed?
Did you look in that bag?
No, I did not.
Bullshit! What do you want?
I just want to stay here
until they leave, okay?
Who do you work for?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- You think I'm stupid?
Hello?
Hold on a minute.
Get up. Go in the bathroom.
Okay. Look, I'm going.
Hello?
So you're still in room 13?
Listen, Dragna, I just wasted
two more of your guys.
- Why do you think they were my guys?
- Feds on the payroll maybe.
They were the only wine
connoisseurs within 100 miles
and what were they doing up my ass?
Seems like you should be on Prozac.
No, I don't need Prozac.
Or AndroGel.
I need my goddamn money.
I need my goddamn
money right now.
I need what you owe me.
Hello?
You could knock, you know?
Thank you.
Could I have a shot of that?
No.
So what are you going to do?
About what?
Sounds like you're in trouble.
Maybe I can help.
Go sit down over there.
Well, anyway, I just want to thank
you for letting me stay here.
Hey. I'm not doing you
any favors, okay?
You're staying in here 'cause you
put your nose in my business
where it does not belong.
And now I don't want you leaving
until I leave this place.
Do you understand?
What the fuck were you
doing coming in here
looking through my shit anyway?
I didn't come in here to
look through your shit.
Well, what were you
doing in here, then?
I told you.
He was going to kill me.
Well, that's not my problem.
I know it's my problem. I'm sorry.
To be truthful, I did look
inside your briefcase.
What the fuck?
There was only an envelope.
Okay.
Get it out! Show me!
Did you look inside this bag?
No, I told you already.
- Did you look inside this bag?
- No.
Why the fuck should I believe you?
Are you all right?
I can help you if you want.
Get out, bitch!
Bring your ass out here!
You fucking skank!
Where are you?
I'm not playing these
games with you.
- What happened?
- I got shot.
- In the hand?
- Yeah.
Why?
Because I'm lucky like that.
Did they miss your heart
or they couldn't find it?
A little trick I learned
on the streets.
What street?
Take a deep breath.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
You must be great at
fucking parties, huh?
There's no sign of her.
This is bullshit!
I don't know what crazy
shit she gonna pull next.
I got solutions.
Cruel and permanent ones.
Don't always think
about with your dick.
I think that's them.
You think?
I'm looking for a girl. A tall girl.
You seen a girl around here?
No, I didn't see anybody.
About 6-foot walking around looking
like Wonder Woman, and shit.
You sure you haven't seen her?
I just told you.
I didn't see anybody.
You couldn't miss her.
She's so tall.
Legs so long they go up and
make an ass of themselves.
But you wouldn't know nothin'
about that, would you?
No, I wouldn't.
No, you wouldn't?
No.
Hmm.
Yo, that slut ain't anywhere.
Hold up.
Let me ask you a question.
If you could fuck one woman
in history, who would it be?
Hmm?
I'd fuck Eve and I'd
make Adam watch.
Flip his bitch over, fuck her in the
ass right in the Garden of Eden.
What's the matter?
You don't like no pussy from the Bible?
Come on, man.
So now what?
Now what, what?
What do we do now? What's our plan?
Our plan? What the fuck
are you talking about?
Maybe I should just grab my bag.
I told you. You ain't going nowhere.
Just sit down and be quiet.
In here or the bathroom?
Whatever you want.
I don't care.
How'd you get, I don't know, involved
with those two circus freaks?
I met Lizard in a strip bar.
Which one's Lizard?
The one with the eye patch.
Oh. Are you a stripper?
No.
Well, not anymore. I stopped.
It was just like, a part-time job.
What are you now?
A schoolteacher, a superhero?
You mean for work? Because I'm
kind of between jobs right now.
Of course you are.
Yeah. I'm trying to
find my true passion.
How old are you?
- How old do you want me to be?
- I don't give a fuck, sweetheart.
- Twenty.
- Bullshit!
All right, so how'd
you end up here?
I'm from Israel, originally.
I'm not asking for your entire life
history... What do you mean, "Israel"?
- You don't sound like you're from Israel.
- Yeah, but I like Israel.
But you're not from there.
Doesn't matter.
I like Israel.
I love Israel.
All right. Um...
Just do me a favor.
Tell me where you were
directly before you were here?
Florida.
And why here?
Because this is where the
motherfucker stopped.
Who's the Russian by the way?
That's Lizard's connection.
Connection for what?
Could I have a shot of that?
Sure.
Connection for what?
Can I have a glass, please?
Crystal meth.
You're dealing?
I'm not dealing anything.
- Is that what you're on right now?
- I'm not on anything.
- You seem like you're on something.
- You seem like you're on something!
Go in the bathroom.
Why can't I stay out here?
Because I want you in the bathroom.
Go in there and close the
door right now, please.
Lock the door.
Hello?
Where are you?
Where do you think I am,
Harvey? You called me.
- Room 13?
- Yeah.
Room 13.
Do you want me to ask you
what he asked me to ask you?
Yes. I want you to ask me
what he asked you to ask me.
You have a Kindle or an iPad?
No, I don't have a
Kindle or an iPad.
Have you read Hermann Hesse?
Who's Hermann Hesse?
I'm not a library, Jack.
When is he coming here?
When he shows.
Just tell me when the fuck
he's going to be here, man!
When he shows for crying out loud!
Get out here.
It would have been easy if I
had just stayed out here.
Okay, things have changed,
and you're free to go.
I won't go very far
with those two outside.
Yeah.
Okay.
Here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to take you to a bus station,
I'm gonna give you some money,
I'm gonna put you on a bus, all right?
- When?
- Right now.
Why?
What do you mean, "Why?"
You want to go or not?
Not.
You don't want to get out of here?
You don't want to go home?
I have no reason to.
Well, tough shit.
You got to go.
Why do you want me to go?
Don't ask stupid questions.
Okay.
So, is Dragna coming
to pick up the bag?
Hey!
You don't mention his name.
All right?
You don't even think his fucking name!
Forget you know anything about this shit.
Do you understand?
How can I forget something
I already know?
Listen, I'm going to drive you to that
bus station, get you on that bus.
You're gonna forget you know
anything about this shit.
- Do you understand?
- Yeah.
So what kind of trouble are you in?
Why are you so nosy?
- Why?
- I'm just curious.
No, seriously, why would you do that?
Why are you like that?
'Cause I'm just trying to have
a civilized conversation.
No, you're not.
Why are you so nosy?
I'm curious.
You know what that did to the cat.
So what's up with the
blood in your car?
All over the backseat.
It's from my hand, yeah.
It's not from your hand.
Hey, what did I just tell you?
What?
About minding your own
fucking business?
I am. There's blood all over
your car. I'm sorry, I can't...
You know what? Let me
tell you something.
Maybe there's gonna be more
fucking blood in this car
if you don't shut your hole and
mind your own fucking business.
It's none of your goddamn business.
Well, I'm sorry for trying to help.
Hey, just do me a favor, okay?
Don't help.
Can I ask you something?
You wanna ask me something,
or everything under the sun?
Why are you doing this?
Why am I doing what?
Helping me?
I'm not helping you.
I am not helping you.
I'm getting you out of the way.
However you want to look
at it, you're helping me.
Whatever makes you happy.
Stop being a dick
would make me happy.
Okay. You know what?
Get out of the car.
What the fuck is your problem?
Get out of the fucking car,
okay? Get out!
All right!
Fucking asshole.
Here.
There. Bus stop's a few miles away.
Good luck.
- Fucking asshole.
- Bye-bye.
Get in the car.
- Get in the fucking car.
- No.
Yes. Get in the fuckin...
No. No.
Come on!
Ow! Fuck!
So who is that, huh?
Is he a friend of, you know,
the person I can't say?
Is that the guy who shot you?
Why are you so curious, huh?
It's gonna get you killed one day.
Oh... Fucking...
You're pathetic.
What kind of idiot puts a body
in a trunk that can't close?
Shut up.
Shot in the head, huh?
What did he do?
Fuck.
We're fixing the tire.
Bend down. Bend down.
Bend down.
We can't just leave him in the trunk.
We have to get rid of it.
Shut up.
There's five gallons of
blood in your back seat.
Somebody's going to see
it and call the police.
Shut the fuck up.
Ahh!
What the hell is this?
What, are you deaf?
I asked you a question.
- What the hell is this?
- And you are?
That's what you get
for messing with my woman.
I'm not your woman.
You shut your hole up.
Pop him, man.
Bobby, no.
I said, "Shut up."
I was hitching a ride and he pulled over.
He was just giving me a lift.
He was giving you a lift?
Yeah, I bet he was giving you a lift.
Are you fucking crazy?
Bitch, I wanna... I swear to God!
Fuck it. I'll pop him.
And afterwards, carry his body
into the woods and hide it.
You carry him.
- No, I'll shoot him.
- I'll shoot him.
- Then you carry him.
I should shoot your
little munchkin ass, too.
Then you'd only have more to carry.
Yeah, screw this, man.
Let's get out of here, man.
Too much fucking trouble.
Get your ass up.
Get up. Get over here.
Are you crazy?
I'm not playing with you!
Ahh!
Pull up.
Come here.
I got it. I got it.
I'm gonna get the bag.
Hold still. Hell's wrong with you?
And I'm not Russian.
I'm Serbian-Roma, you fuck.
Come on, man, let's go.
I pissed on his fucking head.
Shit, man.
Where's the goddamn keys at?
Motherfuck.
Wanna be a freaking idiot?
Yeah. I got your idiom.
Hey.
Hey. Hey. Curious cat.
You all right?
God...
Ahh!
Fuck.
Oh, shit!
Thank you.
- Mr. Smith?
- Fuck.
Just hold that there.
Who is it?
It's me, Mr. Smith.
What do you want?
Have you got a woman
in there with you?
Oh.
What?
Mr. Smith.
What do you want?
'Cause if you have a
woman in there with you,
I have to charge you $20
extra for double occupancy.
I don't have a woman in here.
I'm just saying, if you do have
a woman in there with you...
Well, I don't.
I'm just saying, if there was
someone in there with you...
I don't have one in here.
Now, listen to me.
I wanna go to sleep now
because I'm very tired, okay?
Good night. Good night.
Good night.
Don't fall asleep.
Hey. Stay awake.
I am awake.
Oh, fuck.
Quick. There was a candle in
here somewhere, wasn't there?
Yeah. It's on top of the cabinet.
Are you okay to move?
Move where?
Listen, Kitty Cat. Don't ask questions.
Are you okay to move or not?
Not.
Well...
Look, even if you're not okay
to move, you're gonna go.
Can you sit up?
I mean...
I don't understand.
One minute you're all worried
about if I'm all right.
The next minute you're
kicking me out?
What are you, schizo?
You sound like my ex.
Let's go.
Is it all right if I use the
bathroom before I go, master?
Jesus Christ.
Unbelievable.
Hey.
I got this from Lizard's car.
It's the same picture
as the other one.
That much I know.
So we know as much as each other.
Perhaps you know more.
I've been thinking, perhaps
you know a lot more.
Mr. Smith. I'm Sheriff
Larson, this is Deputy Pike.
Uh...
Hi.
Is there a problem, Sheriff?
Yes, there is a problem.
Two men and a girl were
staying in room 10.
We found the two men down the road.
Very dead.
On the interstate?
No. Down the road. I was
wondering if you'd seen
anything unusual
around here tonight.
- No, I didn't.
- Mmm.
We're looking for the girl.
She's tall, attractive, in her 20s.
Didn't happen to see her
around here tonight,
did you?
No, I didn't.
No?
No.
Well, that's funny.
'Cause someone said they thought
they saw you and a girl
getting in your car
earlier tonight.
Who told you that?
Who were you speaking to before?
I was on the phone, with my wife.
I heard you got into a little
trouble tonight, Mr. Smith.
Excuse me?
With your wife.
She stabbed you.
Yes. It's nothing serious.
Where you from, Mr. Smith?
Pittsburgh.
What brings you here?
I'm just passing through.
- Passing through?
- Yeah.
You drive 300 miles
with a stab wound.
I find that odd,
Mr. Smith. Don't you?
Not if you know my wife.
You're traveling light, Mr. Smith.
No credit cards.
But you didn't forget
your cash, did you?
I carry my money separate.
In a rubber band.
What is it that you do in
Pittsburgh, Mr. Smith?
I work for the city.
What's with the third degree here?
I mean, I told you
I didn't see anybody.
When do you plan on leaving?
Ask him.
He knows everything.
- He knows everything about me.
- Ned.
How long is he staying?
Just for the night.
- See?
- Just for the night?
That's what he said.
Yeah. Gonna go back in the morning
and patch things up with my wife.
That's it.
You know, Bob's your uncle.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, good night, Mr. Smith.
All right.
Get that hand seen to.
Yeah. It's fine.
Thank you, sir.
Ned.
Hey, you.
Mr. Smith.
What the fuck do you
think you're doing?
What do you mean?
Where do you get off telling
them my life story?
It's my civic duty.
I've known the sheriff for a long time.
Listen to me, you little rodent.
You're gonna keep your mouth shut.
Now, you back to your office and you
mind your own goddamn business.
Do you understand me?
Don't touch my wheelchair.
You shouldn't have
done that, Mr. Smith.
No one touches my wheelchair.
It belongs to my dead mother.
Hey. Wake up. Wake up.
I'm okay.
Put that on your head.
Just got dizzy there for a minute.
Keep the ice on your head.
I'm fine, okay?
I said, keep it on your head.
I'm fine.
Put it up there.
God, is that why she left you?
- Who?
- Your ex?
My ex died.
I know what it's like
to lose someone.
- Do you?
- Yeah.
What's your name?
Mine is Rivka.
My name is Jack.
Were you married?
We were going to.
We were going to be married.
She got murdered.
She didn't want me to
do certain things,
and I had to do certain
things for money.
And we got into a fight about
it and she stormed out.
I had to go do this thing.
While I was away...
She got killed.
Sorry. That's awful.
You can chill out here for a little while
longer, then you gotta get up and go.
Tell me about Dragna.
Why don't you tell me about him?
I don't know anything about him.
No?
No.
You wanna talk about this?
Anything you wanna tell me?
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
I'm gonna give you a
chance to answer honestly.
Did you look in that bag?
Don't have to look
in the bag of
allegiance to know that
it's worth more than
what you're getting.
I'm gonna go out.
Lock the door behind me.
What happens if he
knocks on the door?
Believe me, Dragna
doesn't knock on doors.
Where you going?
What are you doing there,
Mr. Smith?
Oh.
He walks.
It's a remarkable recovery.
I think it's best that
you just dig that up
and you throw that over here.
I said, "Start digging"!
You see, I heard you on the phone.
I know what's going on.
It's not what you think.
No, it's not what you think!
Okay.
You see, what you don't know is
that man, he's been here before.
What man? Who?
On the phone!
It's been years,
but that voice I'll never forget
and what he done here before.
You don't know what
you're getting into, man.
Oh, that's funny,
because that's what I was
just about to say to you.
Can you stop shining that light in my
eyes? I can't see what I'm digging.
- You just keep digging.
- Okay, okay.
- I don't owe him nothing this time.
- Okay. Okay.
- You understand?
- Yeah, yeah.
You get that out of the hole.
Okay. Okay.
That's good.
Put it down right there.
Move back away.
Go on. Move away.
- Get back over there.
- Okay.
Goddamn.
Ow! Ow!
God!
Damn it.
Fuck.
Come on, Kitty.
We're going, Kitty.
What's going on?
Who is it?
Sheriff Larson.
Did I wake you, Mr. Smith?
No, I was just lying down.
Unlock the door, please.
Hmm. Did she drive all the way
out here and stab you again?
No, no, it just started
bleeding again.
You should get that checked out.
It's fine.
You haven't seen Mr. Stenson
around, have you?
Who?
The manager of the hotel.
- No.
- That's funny.
We've been looking everywhere
for him, we can't find him.
But his car's parked out front.
Oh, maybe he's skulking around,
doing wheelies or something.
I don't know.
Maybe.
When are you leaving, Mr. Smith?
Uh...
In the morning.
In the morning?
Yeah.
Back to Pittsburgh?
Gotta go patch things
up with my wife.
Mmm.
I realized I probably
brought this on myself.
It's my fault.
Well, well, well.
What do we have here?
Yours?
My wife's.
Your wife's?
And this?
I don't know, it was in
the room when I got here.
Hmm.
A Gideon Bible and a
shovel in every room.
You're under arrest, Mr. Smith.
Something's come to light
since our last meeting.
What the fuck?
Gotcha.
Now, will you give me a
reason to break your skull?
I challenge you to a battle of
wits but you'll be unarmed.
Nice, Jones.
Okay, boys, you know what to do.
Why? Why am I here?
Target practice, Mr. Smith.
Where did you bury it, Mr. Smith?
Bury what?
The bag, Mr. Smith. The bag.
What bag?
There's two ways this can work.
I can beat you to death,
or two, you can tell me
where you put it.
Just because it's inevitable doesn't
mean it's imminent, Mr. Smith.
I have all night.
My shift doesn't finish till 7:00.
We have a long, long way to go.
Chief. I got your
wife on the phone.
Why did you tell her I was here?
What was I supposed to say?
That I'm not here.
Hey.
Macadamia Chocolate crunch.
That's...
I don't like Chunky Monkey.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
Can I help you?
I think you're looking for me.
I'm the girl from the motel.
Huh.
You were with those two in the car?
Yeah, that's me.
Who you looking for?
I'm not looking for anyone.
Is that right? Mmm.
Come with me. It's okay.
You know him?
No.
Now, what have we got in here, huh?
What do we have in here?
Oh.
I don't know this bitch.
She's got nothing to do with me.
Looks like we have a bad girl.
Bad girls need to be punished.
Deputy Pike. Deputy Pike.
Check her good.
Coke whores will hide it
just about anywhere.
Get in here.
Check every spot. Every hole.
Come on, get in here.
Hey, stupid bitch. Yeah.
Yeah?
Hold her. Grab her hands.
Look what we got here.
Well, well, well.
Looks like she intended
to hurt you, Deputy Pike.
Make sure she doesn't have
a shotgun up her ass.
Oh, let's check.
Mr. Smith.
Thought these were yours,
Oh, Christ.
But we do know they're
panties, don't we?
I'll tell you what you wanna know.
Where is it?
It's at the motel.
Where at the motel?
It's too dark.
It's impossible to find.
I had to walk through the forest.
Just tell me where it is.
I'll take you right there.
I gotta walk you there.
If this is some kind
of wild goose chase
we will take liberties
with this girl.
I'll take you right to it.
Deputy Pike,
you look after Miss Pretty.
Gladly.
Jones, come with me.
Sir.
I'll grab the car.
Get up.
Do you have any idea
what I'm gonna do to you
if they don't come
back with that bag?
Hey.
Pike!
Sheriff. Get in here.
Sheriff.
- Keys.
- I can't find them.
Gun.
Ahh!
Pike!
You all right?
Yeah. It's not deep.
That's a lot of bodies
to leave lying around.
You'd rather we put
'em in the trunk?
Please, the trunk
that never closes?
Before I speak, is there anything
else in here I should know about?
What do you mean?
Guns, knives, dynamite,
uranium, nunchucks?
Amazing what a curious
kitty can find
just lying around your
average motel room.
Guns, bodies...
I wouldn't like to
be your neighbor.
Playing the TV too loud were they?
Oh, TV! You're in the
movie now, starring role.
Oh, I know.
No. I don't think you do.
We just killed three cops.
They were ready to take us God
knows where and dump our bodies.
Even if you would've dug it up,
he still would've killed you!
What do you mean, "Dug it up"?
I mean, if you would've given
him the bag, you know...
How would they know I buried it?
Well, when you walked
in with a shovel,
I didn't think you were doing some
late-night gardening behind the motel.
Well, how do you know
it was behind the motel?
Fine, you buried it
in front of the motel.
I swear to God,
if that bag isn't there,
I will dig a hole and I
will bury you in the woods.
I didn't have to come for you.
I could've taken that bag
and left you there,
and they would've killed you and
they never would've found me.
I got shot saving you!
You're an idiot, you know that?
Maybe.
Yes, you are.
I'll drive.
Look for the keys.
Okay.
All right, let's shoot
these handcuffs off.
I like hearing that.
Come on.
Here.
I got it.
Okay.
Is this how your hand got shot?
If you shoot me in the hand,
I'll fucking kill you.
You shouldn't threaten a
person pointing a gun at you.
All right. Right.
Go right to the chain.
What if I miss?
You're not gonna
shoot me from Texas.
Just come right up
to the chain, okay?
Ready?
No, no, down lower, lower.
Don't point it at my fucking hand.
Right there. You ready?
Yeah.
Count of three.
Yeah, I think you're on the chain.
Okay.
One...
That's a hit!
No, no, no. That's a miss.
Thank you.
Seems like a waste of a perfectly
good pair of handcuffs to me.
Another time, another place.
Where are you going?
I was thinking.
Yeah?
Let's get out of here.
Take that bag with us?
Yeah.
Where do you want to go?
You name it.
That's cute.
Hello.
Hello?
You're out of your mind.
Come on, you gotta go.
Where the hell am I going to go?
You... How the hell should
I know where you go?
You go home.
I don't wanna go home.
I wanna stay.
Everything is so...
Every time I try to do something...
I mean, I don't even
give a damn anymore.
But I mean...
Someone like you.
Someone like me what?
Someone like you... I mean...
I can feel you.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
You know, like I know you.
You don't know Jack.
Please.
I don't know
if he's coming to take
the bag and kill me.
I don't know if he's coming
to take the bag and pay me.
I don't know if he's
coming by himself
or he's coming with a
whole fucking army.
You gotta go.
It's impossible.
I made a deal.
Well, I guess that's that.
Maybe we'll run into
each other someday.
Yeah, maybe.
Kitty Cat's gotta go her own way.
Cats are amazing animals though.
Survive all sorts of terrible shit,
they always land up on their feet.
Not always.
Good-bye.
Quickly.
Quick, quick, quick, quick,
quick, quick, quick.
Shit.
Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on, come on.
Why are we hiding?
We're just gonna take
a minute to think.
How about that for an entrance?
Lucky there are
interconnecting rooms.
Put the pistol on the bed.
Make him comfortable.
Sit.
You too.
Tell me something, Jack,
I always thought that the number 13
had a one and then
a three right after it.
But, you know, it's been a
while since grade school,
so, you know,
I could have that wrong.
We have a problem, Jack?
No.
Because when I tell you
to wait in room 13
and I see you waiting in room 14,
it makes me ponder,
"Why would Jack go into room 14
"when I explicitly told him
to go into room 13?"
I mean that's exceedingly
specific, is it not?
I know you can count because you're
an eminently intelligent person,
so I know it can't be any
sort of cognitive issue.
So what is it?
I muse upon this and I start to think,
"Well, there must be a problem."
There's no problem.
I got the bag. I just want...
No, there is a problem, Jack.
Distrust is a disease
that kills a friendship.
When you sneak into room 14 after
I specifically told you room 13,
that's because you clearly
don't trust me, Jack.
That's a problem. When I see that you're
starting to lose your trust in me, Jack,
then I, reciprocally,
start to lose my trust in you.
I start to think,
"Maybe I can't trust this Jack."
I don't mean
disrespect or anything,
but how am I supposed to trust you?
You send Bishop out after me.
He tries to kill me.
He ends up shooting me in the hand...
Well, frankly, I never
really cared much for Bishop.
What about those two
cartoon Feds next door?
With the silencers,
they were stalking deer?
Jack, come on.
If I wanted you dead,
we wouldn't even be talking
right now. You know that.
But I have to admit, you're
a one-man demolition crew.
I've owned this motel, the Sheriff
and everything within
miles for years.
It's been the favorite place
for drop offs, you name it.
But I am impressed.
Just because you're paranoid doesn't
mean they're not after you.
You certainly raised the bar.
I hear I even lost
my Russian dwarf.
He was Serbian-Roma.
Did you ever get a
chance to take a look
at that Hermann Hesse novel I
recommended, Magister Ludi?
I just want my money,
get out of here.
Can I give you a little
bit of advice, Jack?
Yeah.
If you took one-tenth of the
time you spend on killing people
and devoted it to reading
a book now and then,
I really think you would derive
great benefit. Don't you?
I just want my goddamn money.
That's it.
Jack,
you're not gonna introduce
me to your friend here?
She's not a part of this.
Oh, yes, she is a part of it.
You have a whore sitting here
in the middle of our business,
you made her a part of it, Jack.
You know what
"Magister Ludi"means, Jack?
Master of the game.
Master of the game!
Would it surprise you
if you found out
that this hot Tic Tac
here worked for me?
Possible, right?
I mean, come on, dude.
You check into a motel in
the middle of nowhere,
and you just happen to meet this
six-foot, weapons-proficient stripper
with aspirations to teach
second-grade in Kansas.
What are the odds on that?
I mean, I guess it could happen.
I met my wife at a fucking Staples.
Listen to me.
What's really happened here, huh?
Nothing. Nothing.
It's a business transaction.
I did everything you
asked me to do.
I'm sitting here in
this goddamn motel.
I'm going out of my mind
in this goddamn motel.
And all I want to
do is get my money.
Tell me the truth.
Did you look inside the bag?
We had a deal. No.
Anybody see it?
No.
You show it to anybody?
How about your girlfriend here?
She sneak a little peek inside?
No.
Death is inside that bag.
Did Jack tell you that?
No.
We had an agreement.
I kept my end of the bargain.
You either believe me or you don't.
Trust, the foundation
of friendship.
No, I trust you.
Okay.
The bag, Jack, where's the bag?
Under the bed. That's just genius.
Huh?
On the bed.
Unbelievable.
I wish I could share this
with you, Jack. I do.
But as fate would
have it, I just can't.
I want you to know something.
All this, everything, was a
test, Jack, to test you.
To test our friendship.
I have a job.
It's more than a job,
it's a life changer.
I need one man,
just one special man.
With your cut, you can buy
your own private island
and you can fly there in your
own Boeing Business Jet.
I told you not to look in
the bag and you didn't.
You kept your word.
You passed.
I am so proud of you.
This Pavlovian loyalty of yours
is really kind of mind-boggling.
You're a total throwback.
I mean, you're like some blacksmith
in colonial Williamsburg.
You're like an aborigine
with a boomerang
hunting in the diorama of some natural
history museum. Unbelievable.
How do you know I'm not lying?
Oh, I know.
Trust me. It would be
all over your face.
There's money and very, very important
instructions in that satchel.
Goose.
- Do you believe me?
- Sure.
You wanna count it?
Of course not.
Now we have trust again,
as I would have predicted.
You know, when you're aware,
Jack, of someone's tropisms,
you can predict what
directions he'll turn in
in response to certain stimuli.
People are what they are
and they do what they do.
Does Kojak cook kasha? No.
Kojak sucks on Tootsie Pops.
People always say,
you know, if Lenny Bruce
or Miles Davis or Jimi
Hendrix didn't do drugs,
they would have done
so much better.
Actually, I don't think
they would have done shit.
Tropisms.
You know, originally, I was going
to pursue a career in academia?
I have a Master's degree in
Transnational Criminal Syndicates.
Seriously.
My thesis was about
the relationship
between the yakuza
and ultranationalist
right-wing politics
in post-war Japan.
I was gonna be a professor.
Then, one day, I was watching
an episode ofFull House,
where Jesse goes
bungee-jumping with Becky?
Changed my whole life.
I decided, "You know what?
I gotta take the plunge."
I don't want to sit on the
sidelines my whole life.
I don't want to teach,
I want to do.
Let's go.
The big one's soon.
Caveat emptor.
Jack...
I looked...
You looked in the bag.
In the bag...
Yeah.
You know we're gonna die.
God damn it!
Hey.
What, the bills
aren't crisp enough?
There's a problem.
What's that?
Cat looked in the bag.
I didn't know.
Jack, sometimes you disappoint
the hell out of me.
You got emotionally
involved with a whore?
Yeah.
She's not a whore.
All women are whores.
No, they're not.
Take care of your business,
Jack, right now.
Okay. She's not a whore.
Shut your goddamn mouth!
You're making me sick.
Can I see the bag for a minute?
What?
I want to see what's in the bag.
For what?
I want to look inside.
Who do you think
you are talking to?
You don't talk to me,
I talk to you.
You know what you have to do,
take care of business.
Jack.
Kill him.
I don't wanna leave you.
I'll be right here.
Kill him.
Here, take this.
Try and give the master
of the game a better game, Jack.
Jesus, Jack!
You passed the Lizard
and Sheriff tests,
but I'm out of your league, Jack.
I see you haven't
read Sunzi'sArt of War.
Shot ya.
What's in the bag?
It was a gift. You were
just too blind to see it.
What's in the fucking bag?
Oh, shut up.
What's gonna happen now is you're
gonna throw your gun over here.
I'm gonna throw my gun over there?
The motel, my motel,
is rigged with enough C4 to wipe
it off the face of the Earth.
And in case you were
wondering what this is.
It's a detonator. Not a coincidence.
Am I lying?
I'm gonna count to three.
Yeah, well, I'm gonna count to two.
You wanna start, or should I?
You didn't leave your girlfriend
in the room there, did you?
You know, something tells
me you might have.
You just can't keep the
women in your life
from dying horrible,
violent deaths, can you?
I don't care about her.
I think you do care
about her, Jack.
That's your whole,
tragic thing here.
And by "tragic" I mean "pathetic."
Tell me what's in the bag.
What's in the bag?
I think you have to
look for yourself.
They never recovered your fiance's
entire body, did they, Jack?
No leads, no clues.
She had no enemies.
She just had you.
I couldn't let my best man go.
In this business you are sui generis.
Absolutely unique.
Your word is your bond.
Your fiance was taking
you away from me.
I couldn't allow that.
I told you I'd find the guy who
did it and bring him to you.
It took me a little time, but
I'm also a man of my word.
Here I am.
You know,
I'm doing you a favor by putting
you out of your misery. Trust me.
Six divorces and eight kids later,
I'll tell you one thing as
sure as the day you die.
A woman will always let you down.
Was that your good hand?
What are the odds?
You could have been a
multi-multimillionaire...
- Or at least a contender.
- Drop it.
Turn around and face me,
you piece of trash.
Oh, you wouldn't shoot a man
in the back, would you?
A man, no, but you're not a man.
I know you.
Shoot him.
More important is that I know you.
What are you doing in
public without your horns?
- Shoot him!
- Horns? That's a good one.
And just what the fuck are you?
I'm the one who's dealt
with evil all my life.
That's a little dramatic.
Not...
Shoot him!
If you want me to live,
clap your hands.
I didn't hear anything.
It is time to go, Jack.
Closure.
I should just mind my
own business, huh?
If you did, I'd be dead.
It's true. It's true.
It is true.
You are one tough Hebrew.
You have no idea.
Mmm.
Maybe we should go to a hospital.
You think?
Just a thought.
You lawyers have nice offices.
Thank you very much.
Come and sit down.
You look like you've been in a war.
You could say so.
I'm lucky to have good doctors whose
specialty's not asking questions.
There's a lot of tidying up to do.
I suggest we make a start.
You mentioned something on
the phone about a motel.
A motel where?
Louisiana, the bayou.
You'll like it down there.
It's hot.
And hook up with
some guy named Jack?
You make sure that this Jack
still has what it takes.
You fuck with his head,
you understand?
You're gonna have to
have some play dates
with the local boys
to pull this off.
No one's gonna know who the hell
you are or who you work for.
You're on your own down there.
Wonderful.
What's so important about this guy?
There are people in
my life who I trust,
and there are people
in my life who can kill.
But there aren't any
killers I trust
other than Jack,
but I'm not so sure anymore.
I think the guy's gone
soft in the head.
And he's probably gone
soft in the dick too.
So I would like you
to overexert him.
I could save you a lot
of time and trouble.
Whatever you need
Jack for I can handle.
Now, if only that were true.
Unfortunately,
my six-foot chameleon,
it isn't.
Well, he better be cute then.
I think he looks like a fucking,
average chipmunk,
but what do I know?
One thing I do know,
the guy's a killing machine.
But he's a sap.
So I want you to give him the whole
Jack-I've-gotten-myself-
into-so-much-trouble
can-you-please-help-me-out routine.
That I can do.
And, baby...
And, baby, if this gets fucked up,
this goes South or something
goes wrong and I die,
I want you to snuff Jack.
Kill him?
In the unlikely event that this
guy somehow manages to kill me,
which would actually prove
that he's considerably more
capable than I suspect
he is at this point,
I would want you to kill him.
You know I'd avenge your death
just out of love, right?
But a girl's gotta make a living.
Don't worry, along with love,
you'll get $5 million.
And you'll disappear, and
you'll live a long, sweet life.
And you'll remember me when you
say your prayers at night.
Go to my lawyer with
proof of Jack's death.
He's a fucking stickler for detail.
Come to think of it,
you might wanna
consider bringing him
Jack's head in a bag.
Come on, Mr. Fucking-
stickler-for-detail.
Let's you and me go for a ride.
A ride? Where?
Do I look like the
kind of girl who would
walk around with a
human head in a bag?
It's a little hard to say.
You do look like a pretty tough
girl and you must have been
to have outlasted
both Jack and Dragna.
You have no idea.
Well, I have some idea that
you weren't a Girl Guide.
I'm gonna be your tour guide.
Are you crazy?
I've been called worse.
Come on.
Enough talk, let's go!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on, hold on.
Let's just cut to the chase.
You look like the sort of girl who
is going to be more than happy
to carry $5 million in
cash and gold bullion.
I didn't know I was
that transparent.
You got room in that bag?
Oh, yeah.
Nice doing business with you.
You might wanna take what you've
left implanted in my wall.
Keep it.
Fair exchange.
See you.