She told you that?
Did you hear that?
- Yeah, I think you're right.
How do you like this?
- He's not bad for a white kid.
It's too much, I want to fall in love!
- You got a tin ear!
I want to listen to him. He's good.
You got everything you need?
- We got it all.
He's in the Bamville.
You can't miss him.
We won't miss him.
- Blow that bughouse bastard away!
That kid can play.
Hey, girls, join us over there!
- What?
Come to a table with nice people.
Come on over and say hello to Dutch!
Bumpy is here, too.
Stop breaking my heart!
Come over here! Nice trumpet.
I thought you were black.
There's four guys, we all strike out,
am I right? - He's cute.
That trumpet duel was great,
but you beat him bad.
You ought to be put in jail.
He puts riffs in from King Oliver!
I once lost a grand
on a horse named Gideon's Trumpet.
Your name Gideon?
- No.
Abbadabba, this man's a musician.
- Hey, girls!
Forget it!
What are you all alone for?
Give me a chance to dazzle you!
I knew it! Come on!
Look at this! The kid's got
the Midas touch with the broads!
What am I going to sit on?
Don't sit on
the best part of your personality.
What a rude man!
- Let me guess. Veronica? Alice?
Am I right?
- Forget it.
I'm not close? Well, what's your name?
Would you believe Myrtle?
- You're named Myrtle?
What's your name?
- Forget it! Vera.
Cicero. Like in Latin.
Did you ever study Latin?
I was an altar boy.
He was an altar boy!
- It figures. - I believe him.
It's a lovely tie.
- Thank you.
You going with anybody? - Do you see
a ring? - Why are they here?
The little men in blue.
You wanted by the police, Miss Cicero?
We're very good tonight, fellas.
- Watch out!
You bastard!
Solly, go after them!
What the hell is this?
- Some people don't like me.
Who are you anyway?
I'm your Dutch uncle from now on.
I owe you one. Dutch Schultz owes you.
Abbadabba, you alright?
- Yeah.
I'm in heaven!
Get up!
- Pow!
Do they do that here every night?
I'm very swoozled.
Help me!
- Which room is your room?
I'm a liitle kaflooie, you know?
Should I put you in bed, too.
Oh no!
Pull your arm out!
See, that wasn't very hard.
Come on!
There!
I really like how
you play the trumpet. Like Gabriel!
It's a cornet.
Gabriel plays the sax. Are you okay?
Whatever it is, don't go home with it.
Stay with me.
Just for the night. Please.
My ears are ringing.
What a night!
I was there with the Dutchman.
It says you saw the bomb coming.
- Yeah, so I saved Dutch's ass.
You saved his ass?
Let me take care of that.
Joe, you want to pick this up?
Since when you got money?
- I did a couple of jobs.
Coffee, home fries, eggs...
Saving Dutch Schultz's ass!
The Dwyer brothers are in.
In?
- Popke, come with us.
Wait up, Vince!
You're some bigtime hero, Dixie!
The Dutchman's telling everybody.
- I got the rakes on the Dutchman!
Vinnie, what the hell is this?
You wanna work for a bootlegger?
You don't kill a fly on Ma's plate!
- Did I get it?
I didn't get him.
- Something is wrong with you.
Behave yourselves.
You ready for the contest?
- Yeah. - Let me see your set.
It's awful and I hate it.
- Oh, you love it!
That's why you'll win.
- Let me see something.
Done quietly!
- Right. - Thank you.
You're dragging!
The master must try it.
Master of what?
Look, Mama! - You gotta do it
pretty to get into the Cotton Club.
Quietly, Mother.
That's
gonna get you to the Cotton Club!
The Cotton Club...
- No new steps...
Too important today.
- Today's audition gotta be stronger!
Stronger?
- You can't fool the Cotton Club!
You start giving white people
what they want,
soon you got no blood left.
- What are we doing?
First rhythm, then social?
- No, save it till later.
I wanna get it out of the way.
- Hello, Dixie!
Where'd you get this money?
- I do business.
You do business?
- I'm like Jesse James.
You work with Jesse? Who's this kid?
Ed Popke.
- A sad case.
I got some big news
that I didn't tell you yet.
What?
- Big news!
I suddenly got married!
- What?
I got married!
You tell me you want a job with Dutch
but don't mention you got hitched?
Where are you going?
- Inside.
We want to be alone,
with just the family, alright?
This is her! Patsy, my brother.
- Congratulations!
Don't congratulate the bride,
congratulate the groom.
One, two, three...
- On your tippytoes!
One, two, three, now turn...
One, two, three...
Would you put some clothes on!
I've told her about that!
I know, but there's
a rat in the house!
Tail this big! It's behind
the curtain, wanna take a look?
It's behind the curtain.
You were in town all day yesterday
and you didn't call me once!
This one goes up, that one goes up,
around my neck in a hug!
Oh, Mom with the dancing feet!
- He saved Dutch Schultz's life, Mom!
Why?
- I didn't know who it was.
He is an absolutely awful man.
Patsy, put some clothes on!
I did!
- Leave the cat alone!
See you next week.
- Want me to take your jacket?
Thanks.
I want you to tell your mother
everything you learned.
One, two, now turn...
Tell your mother.
How did your dancing audition go?
- They loved us.
Think you'll work at the Cotton Club?
- Nah.
You're waiting till the big time, huh?
- We'll see.
He's showing off again.
- He's got a lot to show off!
Good luck, boys!
Where you going?
- Excuse me!
Excuse me, I'm having a heart attack!
You look kinda sick, I think.
- Please, Miss, I'm...
She pushed you over the cliff!
- I'm gonna climb back up!
I'll see you later, man.
- So long, Holmes.
Mr. Stark!
I'm just excited
about the audition and wanted
to find out how we did.
- Everybody liked you.
I'm gonna put you in the next show.
We're in the next show?
- You're in the next show.
Thank you! Listen,
you white folks are so smart.
Ladies and gentleman...
- Much smoother! Now, pivot.
...the Cotton Club girls!
- You're in the wrong spot!
Sorry, Miss Webb.
What's your name?
- Get out of here!
What are you doing here?
- I just spoke with Mr. Stark...
I don't care, you belong to me.
You don't use that front door,
use the back door. Don't do it again!
Are you Dixie Dwyer?
- Yeah, that's right.
The Dutchman wants to put you to work.
He says you play the piano, too?
- I play a little piano.
He wants you to play a little party.
- Party? How much?
150.
150? When?
- Right now.
What do they call ya?
- Nobody calls me nothing.
Not even your mother?
- I didn't have a mother.
They found me in a garbage pail.
How you doing?
- Sol. What's in the bugle case?
Bugle.
What kind of party is this?
- You've never been to one like this.
Maybe I don't want to go to one like
this. - You do want to go.
Wait here.
Don't screw up!
Keep an eye on the boss. Hello!
The cornet player.
I don't believe it, you made it.
What the hell is this?
- Pow! Bugle boy, meet Jesse James.
What are you doing here?
I went up to Dutch and got a job.
You saved his ass, he saved mine.
You asked him for a job?
- Yeah, I said, "I'm begging."
What about you?
- I'm with Vinnie.
I made it.
- I got your brother on my payroll.
He told me about it.
- We got too many Jews here.
We need some Irishmen.
- Since when?
Not too many!
- I love these tough micks. Wardrobe.
Did you bring your horn?
- Here is the first of the money.
My horn?
I thought you wanted my piano!
You can't work for Dutch
and walk around like this, alright?
What do you want to hear?
- Listen,
I got a lot of things to do.
I got this girl coming...
She sings. She's got her own music.
You read music, right?
- Yeah, I read it. I write it.
I play it.
I sleep with it, too.
- Play for her, don't sleep with her.
Lucky Boy, relax. I like you.
I'm looking for Mr. Schultz. Do you
know him? - Everybody knows him.
Do you work for him?
- I work for myself.
My name is Owney Madden. And you?
- You're Owney Madden?
You're very famous.
I'm Vera Cicero.
You own the Cotton Club, right?
I own a lot of things, Miss Cicero.
He's in the next room.
- Thank you.
Right this way, Mr. Flynn.
Thank you, Mr. Flynn.
Wanna lighten up a bit, doll?
Your accompaniment...
A piano player.
The little girl.
- The altar boy.
Schultzie, we gotta talk.
We're having a party time.
It's time, Dutch.
Let's get at it.
- Fine, we're set up down the hall.
What about you?
- I sing, tell a few jokes.
Tell me a joke then.
Hello, Sucker.
Dammit!
Shut the fuck up! Shut up...
You had the bomb dropped!
- What's the point?
Shut up!
- It's bullshit!
I'm telling you! You, too!
- Shit!
Now we heard it all now!
That's the end of it.
There's plenty of money in Harlem
for everybody. It's getting hotter.
You start this war here and you
got a brand new enemy... me.
And me.
You're here because you both agreed
to this truce. And it is a truce.
Tomorrow is a business day. Clear?
Is it clear?
Then shake hands!
Shake fucking hands!
In the next room, gentlemen,
is the best food, drink and pussy
available at any rice in New York.
I suggest you take a sample
of these things. And try to remember
this is why we work so hard.
To live like kings!
Get out of here!
So you finished the funny business?
I shook his hand.
I should have cut it off.
Calm down, you'll overheat.
You two getting along?
- We're making contact.
You look like a beautiful doll.
You know that tune?
"Beautiful Doll?" Yeah.
- Play it!
Go ahead.
Yeah, sure.
How you doing?
Anything you want.
Anything, just ask me for it.
I want to own my own nightclub.
We'll have a little peace and quiet.
- Come on. Hey, Monk!
Let those two kids in.
- Okay, go ahead.
Nobody else right now.
- Help yourselves!
It was good, bringing you guys
together. - We got a little
territory settled.
We ain't together.
You sound like an Irish pig!
- Alright, alright!
You wanna go right now?
Stop it!
- I'll break your fascist face!
...pretty well.
- Owney's got that diplomat...
...Guaranteed.
If Owney was in Washington,
we wouldn't have this shit in Europe.
I like keeping the fucking
Jew boys where they belong.
Them and the niggers,
then we're alright.
Jew's just a jig turned inside out.
- That's enough.
Son of a bitch!
Alright, Dutch, that's enough.
Yeah, that's enough.
Somebody ought to cut out
your brain and pickle it.
You are a crazy son of a bitch!
- I'm sorry.
Fuckin' sorry as a human being!
- Hey, kid!
Can you drive?
- Yeah. - Then take your friend
someplace quiet, away from here.
Take the lady with you. Go!
And fast!
- Get it out!
Look, I don't want you to get lost.
I need to know where you are.
Say, kid!
Come here!
Don't you worry about it.
I got the fix on stuff like this.
Whatever you say, Dutch.
- Alright.
Just right up over there.
I'll see you.
Don't go anyplace.
I wanna know where both of you are.
I need to eat something.
Did I say the wrong thing?
You don't feel for Mr. Flynn?
Mr. Flynn was a bootlegger.
That's how they live. Wise up, sap!
Why not come inside?
Not this time.
You don't belong to me.
You're Dutch's property.
Hi, Joey.
- What's new?
What'cha doing?
Call is 15 minutes to places!
Mr. Stark,
we're the Williams brothers.
The Williams!
- Oh, the Williams brothers.
Charlie, show them their
dressing rooms. - Thank you.
We're here!
- Welcome to the Cotton Club.
You come in right here with the vocal.
- All the way up...
That's Duke Ellington!
Put up the wing.
Hiya, Dixie. This your family?
- Showing the newlyweds a good time!
Some of the best musicians
in the world play here.
...all this money!
- Good thing niggers ain't allowed!
They can't get into their own club?
- Owney Madden owns this club.
May I take your coats?
- Wait till you see this!
Look at the rump on that baby!
Hey, baby, come over here!
Vinnie, come on!
These are the times
that try men's souls.
Is this the best table in the house?
- The best for you, my friend.
You ain't no friend of mine!
- Sit down, watch the show!
I know that man, Owney Madden.
- Where?
Right over there.
He backs a lot of Broadway shows.
They call him "Mr. Broadway."
I wonder if he remembers me.
Where you going?
- Hey, Ma, wait!
Mr. Madden?
Owen.
Well, well!
A pleasure to see you again.
- My son Michael. He plays cornet.
I think you should hire him.
- It's my mother, she loves me.
Don't you already have a job?
I play here and there. Nothing steady.
You gotta be careful
who you play piano for.
Alright, come around and see me.
Maybe sometime soon.
Thanks, Mr. Madden.
What do you think of this Dwyer kid?
I'm not impressed.
- Do you trust him?
Dutch seems to.
- Ahhh.
Dutch relies on fear.
It's loyalty we need.
I'm thinking about the coast.
The kid looks good. Talks pretty.
I don't trust no one with a nickname.
What about your nickname, Frenchy?
- That's different.
Why?
- I'm trustworthy.
Oh, yeah.
What would I do without ya?
I'm always watching you, Williams.
Nice place!
How come you never brought me here?
The Cotton Club?
Frances, I almost never come here.
Nice to see you again, Mr. Schultz.
- Really, I don't come here much.
Hey, Dutch!
- Do you ever tell anyone the truth?
The Dutchman just come in.
Bring him up to the coop, right?
I bet you could do that?
Do that little thing
with your tongue. Come on!
Compliments of the house!
- That Owney!
You gonna pop the cork?
50 bucks if you hit the ceiling!
Hello Dutch...
- Oh, hello! - How've you been?
Have a cigar.
- Take a walk.
They read your name in the papers,
they think they know you.
Give me a light.
- Anything you need, Dutch?
Yeah, why don't you bring me the moon!
- It's up on the roof.
Owen would like
to show you his pigeons up there.
Owney and his pigeons.
I'll be right back. Enjoy yourself!
- Could you leave somebody with me?
Yeah. Sol, come here.
Now you're gonna have
a good time, so just relax.
Follow me.
What's with the pet pigeons?
I used to catch 'em and cook 'em.
Don't tell that to Owen.
I haven't been able
to eat or sleep for days. You okay?
Oh, you shouldn't fall so soon.
All I want to do is marry you,
take you away from this. - Away?
I practically just got here.
- Me, too.
Look, let's never be separated.
- Can I do this number?
What are you doing here?
- He likes to look at me.
He says if his wife leaves early
he wants to see me.
He wants to talk to you.
- Talk to me?
I don't want to talk to him!
My family's over here tonight.
Do yourself a favor. Don't rile him.
You know how he gets.
I don't want any part of him.
- He can get you anything you need.
Beautiful one.
I was gonna leave it to you
what the restitution would be.
Then I realized, you're such a cheap
son of a bitch, you probably
wouldn't satisfy
my sense of right or wrong.
What I want is
either 25,000 in cash now,
on the table,
or 10,000 a month
for the next four months.
The first offer is a bargain.
I know you love a bargain.
That's fair. I heard.
25.
Sometimes you're a big man, Dutch.
You know how I got that big?
- How?
I ate a pigeon every day.
Did'ya see Dixie here?
300 a week.
- I thought you said 200.
I could say 50 and you'd take it.
Dutch, I appreciate it,
but guns, knives, bombs...
That's not my life. I play music.
- I'm telling you
you got a job.
You got it? All I want you to do
is to take Vera around. She can't
stand Abbadabba, but she likes you.
If I didn't like you,
you'd be dead. Do you understand that?
Sure I understand.
It's nice to be liked.
I gotta see you after the show.
- No.
Tomorrow!
You gotta!
- Alright, I'll tell you what.
I have a meeting at ten at the
Abyssinian Church. Meet me there.
I'm new. I'm trying to meet people.
- Watch your act, nigger!
You don't handle the merchandise.
There's Gloria Swanson!
You're my biggest star!
You are a very beautiful person.
You're more beautiful than I am.
- You have a chance to be in pictures.
You are gorgeous.
Well, I can't miss, can I?
- Call me at the studio. Monday.
Monday.
- Yes. Goodbye.
That was Gloria Swanson.
- Right here she said it.
Gloria Swanson says I'm gorgeous
and I should have a big future.
Hey, kid.
Good show. See you tomorrow.
Not tonight.
- I don't take "no" for an answer.
You have to this time.
I've got a private life, you know.
The only trouble with the nigger
numbers racket is the risk. I like
things you can fix,
like a horse race. Or a politician.
I think I can fix the number.
- What, you kidding me?
What have you been drinking? Dixie!
Play that Beiderbecke tune for me.
And see if the piano player knows it.
Where do the numbers come from?
- You know "Singing the Blues?"
You take that thing everywhere?
- Dutchman likes the sound of my horn.
His master's voice.
- Look who's talking.
But I'm getting my own nightclub.
Think about it for a minute.
That number comes in the 7th race.
So I look at the payoff totals
from the first six races and...
What if I don't like the number?
I place last minute bets.
And that changes
the last number to what I want.
Any number!
And you can figure it in your head?
The one and only.
They're fixing the world with math.
You ever play the horses, Sol?
- When I was a kid I raced rats.
If you can do this, we can take over
the whole Harlem numbers racket!
The service is lousy here.
Why don't you get me a gin, darling?
You can own Harlem,
lock, stock, and barrel.
Bottoms up, Dutchess.
I'm really sorry about that.
I saw you spilling that drink.
You ain't clumsy. I didn't like it.
You ever do anything like that again,
I mess up your face. You hear me?
Yeah, yeah.
I won't spill any more drinks.
I want you to pick up my laundry.
It's at the Chink's.
Yeah.
What's up?
- Three bankers.
15,000 from 113th, 20,000 from 72nd,
and 21,000 from 150th Street.
Beautiful. You'll be the next boss!
- Come on.
Come on, get over there!
- One more time!
You still mad at me?
- I was never mad at you.
I just felt you should respect my
private life. - Let's get married now.
We could have lunch anytime!
- Dalbert, no chance.
I got too many things to do.
I want to make it.
Really make it. I want to do Broadway.
You want to do white show business.
- Isn't that what it is?
Wait a minute!
I can't just run out like this!
Wait a second here.
I like that you're taller than me.
Most men are intimidated.
- We're going to the top together!
Dalbert, wait!
Sugar, marry me!
- I'm already married.
You're the president of the club.
So you can perform the ceremony.
And I can't wait no longer.
- If you take this man
for your husband,
you're crazier than he is.
Sugar, would you...
- Plus, ain't no women allowed.
Why not no women?
- 'Cause this is the Hoofers Club!
Hoofers! I'll show you.
- This is going to be something.
This is what you do.
Give me a little music.
Heelology!
Don't be so mean!
To the floor!
I'm coming through!
Look out!
No, no!
- What? My brother...
He's doing it!
This is the way it goes!
One, two, three, four... now!
What is this? Where's the Duesenberg?
Where's Dutch?
- Dutch can't make it tonight.
I'm your escort.
I'll do anything for money, too.
Where we headed? Not the theater.
- We ain't going to the theater.
What is this, a kidnapping?
Would you like that?
I think I'm up to it.
I don't know why,
but you do move me.
In unusual places.
Where? Your appendix?
We'll sit at Dutch's table.
Go ahead, will you walk?
Keep moving!
Sit down!
Thank you.
- Thanks.
I never have figured you out.
That's funny. I know all about you.
I can imitate your walk.
The way you play your cornet.
Like how?
I know a few things about you, too.
Like what you look like making love.
When did you see that? - Ever since
I put you to bed that night.
The Golem has arrived.
He follows me everywhere.
- The Golem is in love.
Don't be ridiculous.
He just keeps tabs on me for Dutch.
Why do I feel
like I'm walking the dog or something?
I want to dance.
Let's dance for Dutch.
I used to dance for a living.
- No kidding?
I worked in tearooms when I was 18.
Tell me all about it.
These old ladies would pay me
to put my arms around them.
Waltz them off their feet.
Pay two bucks
in the afternoon. Plus tips.
More for the night work.
In private. If you could stand it!
- Could you?
Sure. Look at me tonight.
Dutch likes you to dance, huh?
Dance!
You dance for me! Get up!
Come on, you dance!
You wanna dance?
I'll dance with you, come on!
What makes you think...
That's enough!
I'll dance with you next time, Sol.
I just cracked my heel.
- I didn't mean to hurt you.
Yes, you did.
- No, I'm crazy about you.
You tell that to all the girls you
beat up. - I live here.
It belongs to my brother's wife.
She's about your size.
To anything!
Is that you, Vincent?
- No, it's Michael.
It's okay, go back to bed.
- Goodnight, Michael.
Goodnight!
Michael?
Yeah, Michael.
Well, Michael, where do I change?
You feel like
you're on your honeymoon?
Honeymoons are never this dangerous.
If he came in here right now,
he'd kill us. - Forget about him.
Who?
I'm quitting the Dutchman.
I'm not running around for his
cigarettes while he strokes you.
I'm not waiting in the car...
while he does whatever he does to you.
- Whatever he does.
All I know is...
I'm getting away from that bastard!
You're a tough guy.
Some things you can't do.
You can't see a murder,
then come home,
fuck your friend, who loves you,
leave him, then go home,
and wake up
and have breakfast with a psychopath.
You can't do that, can you?
Yes.
Madden upstairs?
- Yeah, he's in.
How are ya?
- Alright, alright.
You says I should come see you.
- Oh, yeah...
You're seeing difficult times.
You noticed.
You got any ideas for me?
- If you was colored, we'd book you.
The great tragedy of my life.
- Listen...
I heard what
Gloria Swanson was saying about you.
A lot of my cash
goes to different places.
Some goes to Hollywood,
and to the studios and to movies.
You could front for us.
What do you mean?
- Be my face on the coast.
What about the Dutchman?
I'll keep him off your back.
Come and have some lunch.
Swell, Mr. Madden.
See you tonight!
- See you later!
I got a specialty act.
Remember that solo we talked about?
Can you do it tonight?
- Of course.
You're on right after the Duke.
- I'm there.
What's this about a solo?
- They asked me to do a solo.
They asked you? You didn't ask them?
- I talked to them.
Clay...
Look, it's a step up, man!
It's good for both of us.
Don't give me trouble. Shake my hand.
Shake your hand?
I ought to spit in your hand!
How could you? I'm your brother!
How could you go behind my back?
You want a solo? You got one!
On stage and off!
Your brother wants to see you.
See you later, Vinnie.
What's the urgency?
I gotta go to a doctor.
- For what? You okay?
I got a small graze.
Can't go to a hospital I know.
'Cause they'll find out.
- Jesus Christ, kid!
What?
What happened?
- It's just a graze.
A graze from what?
- I was fighting niggers.
The niggers, Harlem niggers.
Why?
Look at me. Why do you think?
I should kick the shit out of you.
What are you doing fighting coloreds?
Who do you work for?
What's the matter, Dix?
Do I look like a boss in this suit?
Keep two thugs behind you and you do.
- I want them to notice the suit!
Spill a little gravy
like you always do, they'll notice it.
You know, Dixie took a screen test.
What's a screen test?
- They shot some pictures.
Now they want me to make a movie.
- In Hollywood?
That's right.
- Forget it! - What do you mean?
It's his big chance!
- They want me to play a gangster.
You?
- In fact, I did an imitation of you.
"Hey, come here. Do what I tell
you to do or I'll plug ya!"
Owney arranged the whole thing.
He's co-financing
the movie. He said you wouldn't mind
if I left for the coast.
Playback Dixie Dwyer. Sound!
Here he comes. He's in egg-cream.
- Madden always had good judgment.
Right.
- What's the kid's name?
Dixie Dwyer. Keep an eye on him.
He's fantastic. He's coming in now.
Unbelievable. Watch him, watch him!
First kid you ever sent me
that doesn't sound like a soprano.
He's the greatest. He'll become...
Hold it, hold it, Sully!
- What? What?
This kid can't act.
- Alright, I can see it.
He has a good face, good voice,
doesn't look like a fruit.
Not at all.
- He looks like
a gangster. What's his name again?
Dixie Dwyer. A great name!
A fake name. The first thing...
I'll decide about the name.
I like the name. Keep the name.
- Put him under contract.
We'll send him to the coast. We'll
give him a shot. - Fantastic.
Anyone who moves is a dead nigger!
You! St. Clair!
The Dutchman
wants you in his numbers racket.
Madame St. Clair!
Gentlemen, we are here because
Mr. Jewett says he can
protect us from the white invaders.
Is that true?
I know how the Dutchman thinks.
I see him operate with the Flynns.
You meet a gun with a gun.
And I got all the guns you need.
Hire him!
- I don't want no parts of guns.
Or I'll leave the numbers business.
- It's not about guns, it's politics.
You connected with Jimmy Hines
in Tammany? They control the police.
Look, I come to do you people a favor.
That man is leaning on you.
You wanna lean back or no?
It seems we will pass on your offer.
We are not ready
to go to war at this time.
Then you don't know
you already lost the war.
Lila!
You can't do this to me, Lila!
- Do what?
Disappear like you do.
Where do you go all day?
I have a private life now.
I can't talk to you here.
Let's go up on the roof.
I told you that there are
other people in my life.
I want to talk.
- This is Madden's place!
I want to talk to you now.
Now just come on! Come on!
Not up here.
- We won't get into trouble.
Let's go outside.
- You moved. Got a new address.
How am I supposed to find you?
What are you doing up here?
- We're just going to talk.
Yeah! You come up here
to fornicate like two dogs.
You don't belong up here. Get down.
Why can't we...
- I'm fed up with you!
Please!
- I'll take care of you!
Wait a minute!
- Come here!