Leave the cell door open.
Let him escape.
lt's all very irregular. lt might entail
the most embarrassing repercussions.
Exactement. lt's a responsibility
of the first magnitude.
- Mr Wilson, you must see...
- Blast all this discussion.
What good are words? l'm sick of words.
Hang the repercussions.
lf l fail l am responsible.
Leave the cell door open. Let him escape.
lt's our only chance. Let them
threaten me with hell and still l insist.
This obscenity must be destroyed.
Do you hear me? Destroyed:
Todos los pasajeros desembarquen.
All passengers ready to disembark.
l am travelling for my health.
Tengan listos sus pasaportes.
Get your passports ready.
l am travelling for my health.
- ? Sus negocios en este pais, senora?
-  Je n'ai pas compris.
- l don't understand.
- Your business in this country?
l'm joining my husband.
Next, please.
Stefan Polaski.
- You take care of him.
- Your business in this country?
- l'm travelling for my health.
- How?
- l am travelling for my health.
- You are a native of what country?
- Poland.
- Oh, Poland. Grata permanencia.
Next, please.
-Que pasü?
Yo lo voy a seguir a pie, tý ve en el carro.
-Çotel Nacional? 7702.
Hello?
Yes.
You're sure you know where he's going?
My wife is following him.
He's going to the photographer's.
Probably to get a new passport
and new instructions.
Hold it.
l wish to know the whereabouts
of Franz Kindler.
Franz Kindler.
There is no Franz Kindler.
Franz Kindler is dead. And cremated.
lt's incorrect:
l have a message for Franz Kindler.
From the All Highest.
lt is... forbidden.
l command you
in the name of that authority.
You know the name he is using?
Connecticut.
ln the United States. The town of Harper.
Harper.
Oh...
Excuse me.
-
- Good afternoon.
- Have a nice trip?
- Yes, thank you.
Quite a store you have here, Mr...
- Potter.
- That's me.
We sell about everything here.
This suitcase. l could leave it here?
The bag?
l don't assume no responsibility.
Just put it up on the shelf.
lt'll be there when you want it.
- Can l buy this magazine?
- That'll be a dime.
- What's the best hotel in town?
- Best place is down at Mrs Peabody's.
lt's just down the road here a piece.
- This way, mister.
- Yes. Thank you.
l may come in?
Yes, of course.
- Does Mr Charles Rankin live here?
- Yes, but he isn't here right now.
- Are you expecting him?
- Yes, in a few minutes.
How soon?
Well... a few minutes.
A few minutes.
l may...
l may wait here?
Well, yes, if you like.
- Would you like to sit down?
- Thank you.
- Are you a friend of Mr Rankin's?
- Yes, a friend.
- l'm Mary Longstreet. How do you do?
- How do you do?
Mr Rankin ought to be here now.
Sometimes he stays after his last class,
but he'll come straight here today.
This is our wedding day.
- You are getting married?
- Yes. At six o'clock.
l know it's unconventional my being here
today, but l want to get these curtains up.
When he comes,
which way does he come?
Why, from Webster Hall.
lt's the big dome building right over there.
Thank you.
Who shall l say that...?
Franz.
lt's l, Franz.
Meinike. We mustn't
be seen talking together.
Go back to the church.
lnto the woods, you understand?
Follow the path. l'll meet you there.
- Hello, Professor Rankin.
- Hello, men. What are you up to?
- Paper chase.
- l lay the trail.
You ought to have Jerry's job.
Trim that waistline.
- You should go with us.
- Where to?
- The woods.
- Hiya, blondie.
The woods? l'd like to. l'm afraid
l have a couple of things to attend to.
- Join us later.
- All right.
We'll catch up with you.
This way, fellas.
- Meinike.
- Yes, Meinike.
- l thought...
- l had been hanged.
The others, but not l.
A dead man could not stand
face to face with you, Franz.
You're not much changed.
Put you back in your old uniform,
you'd look very much the same.
- l am a different man than before.
- l too.
l too am different, Konrad.
l destroyed every item in Germany
and Poland that might reveal my identity.
Guess what l'll be doing at six tonight?
Standing before a minister of the gospel
with the daughter of a justice
of the US Supreme Court.
The girl's even good to look at.
The camouflage is perfect.
Who would think to look for the notorious
Franz Kindler in the Harper School,
surrounded by the sons of
America's first families?
And l'll stay hidden...
till the day when we strike again.
Franz: There will be another war?
Of course.
War is an abomination, saith the Lord.
lt is to tell you this that l am here.
- He set me free that l might come here...
- Set you free? Who set you free?
The All Highest.
- You don't mean...?
- l mean God.
- God:
- Franz.
- l am a new man since l found him.
- You, Konrad. Religious:
Franz, all doors were opened to me.
All doors.
lt was one of God's miracles.
Mm-hm.
They freed you so you'd lead them to me.
Have you been followed?
Were you followed here?
- Yes.
- Who followed you?
The evil one.
He looked like any other man.
He was dressed like any other man.
He even smoked a pipe.
But l recognised him through his disguise,
and l killed him.
Struck him from on high down.
God's will be done.
You killed him, the man with the pipe?
The man who followed you?
No one else followed you?
Mm-hm.
You must be brought to salvation, Franz.
Confess your sins as l have.
Proclaim your guilt.
Only thus you can attain salvation.
- You really think so, Konrad?
- lt will take strength.
Such strength as can come
only from God.
Kneel by me, Franz.
And together we will pray to him
to give you strength.
l have sinned against heaven
and before thee.
l am not worthy to be called thy son.
Say these words after me.
l despair of my sins.
- O God of all goodness.
- O God...
- How could l ever have offended thee?
- ..of all goodness.
This way, fellas:
Don't let him get away.
Hey, fellas, there's the trail.
Hurry up.
This way, fellas.
Dearly beloved, we are gathered together
here in the sight of God
to join together this man and this woman
in holy matrimony.
..and, forsaking all others, keep thee only
unto her so long as ye both shall live?
l will.
Mary, wilt thou have this man
for thy husband,
to live together after God's ordinance
in the holy estate of matrimony?
Wilt thou love him, comfort him, honour
and keep him in sickness and in health,
and, forsaking all others, keep thee only
unto him so long as ye both shall live?
l will.
- Good afternoon.
- Afternoon.
- Wedding?
- Yep. Judge Longstreet's daughter.
He's Supreme Court justice, you know.
- Bottle of aspirin, please.
- Back there, third shelf down.
You'll see the big ones on the left,
the economy size.
Have to get it yourself, mister.
Right back there.
All your needs are on our shelves.
Just look around, help yourselves.
Right in there. That's it.
- Livin' down at Mrs Peabody's?
- Just a few days only.
Coffee too, please.
Or should l get it myself?
- Cafeteria style around here, mister.
- That's right. Self-service.
- The usual, Frank.
- That's three dollars even, Mr Todd.
- No limit on the cream?
- All the people around here take it black.
- The one on the right.
- Thank you.
- Who is Miss Longstreet marrying?
- One of the teachers.
- A stranger in town.
- l issued the licence.
Yep. l'm town clerk.
Uh...
- Checkers?
- All right.
Town clerk, huh?
That must be quite a responsibility.
Town clerk runs the town, you might say.
We usually make it for... 1 5, 20...
We often play as high as
25 cents the game.
Well, that's kinda stiff for me, but...
- Make a million, lose a million.
- That's the way it goes.
- My move?
- Hm?
All right.
You must know just about
everybody in town here.
Not just about. Know everybody.
- Here on business?
- Mm-hm.
- School business?
- Mm-mm.
- Sellin' something?
Buyin'?
Oh, antique dealer.
They all come to Harper.
Judge Longstreet's got the best collection.
l don't suppose he'd sell.
Happen to know if there are
any other out-of-town buyers here?
Let me see... Come to think of it,
there was a fella come in this morning.
Came on the same bus with you.
Left his suitcase here.
Never did come back for it.
He might have been one of them.
No. He was more the missionary type.
Wasn't in long. Looked in the phone book.
Tiny little fella, he was.
Thinnish. Unfortunate-looking.
- Hurt your head?
- No, nothing serious.
Oh, that's too bad.
lt's a game you got to
keep your mind on. Hah:
25 cents, please.
Hello, Father. Has anybody seen
my brand-new husband?
- Don't tell me he's deserted you already.
- Looks as if, the brute.
Red, have you seen Charles?
Go find him for me. Hurry up.
l've looked everywhere for him.
- l'm getting worried.
- Are you, darling? What about?
Charles... You've changed.
Don't you think you'd better?
After all, aren't we supposed to be
going on a honeymoon?
Give me five minutes.
- Hello there.
- Hello.
- Was that you working on the clock?
- No. l was just cleaning around it.
lt's a beautiful thing,
from what l can see out front.
- My name's Wilson.
- Noah Longstreet.
l'm glad to know you.
l couldn't judge too well out front,
but l'd say it was 16th century.
Probably by Haabrecht of Strassburg.
- The clock.
- l wouldn't know.
My brother-in-law's going to work on it.
- ls he up there now?
- No, he's on his honeymoon.
He plans to work on it when he gets back.
- ls he an expert?
- Yes, but it's more of a hobby with him.
Really? Well, it is with me too.
- Honeymoon?
- Yes. He and my sister.
He has to be back on Friday
because of the examinations.
He's one of the teachers at the school.
- His name is Rankin.
- Oh?
lt's nice to show it to someone who
knows what Revere silver's all about.
- Personally, my specialty is pewter.
- Oh, yes. Pewter.
The Revere workmanship,
although sometimes heavy in design,
almost invariably shows
the sign of a master craftsman.
lt is beautiful.
- Noah.
- Hello, Mary.
- Adam.
- Hello, Mary, dear.
Mr Wilson, my daughter Mary.
My son-in-law, Charles Rankin.
l hope you don't mind
my intruding on your homecoming.
- Good evening, Mary.
- Jeff, how are you?
- You're looking good.
- Welcome home, Miss Mary.
Sara:
lf you don't sit down it'll get cold.
- How were the mountains?
- Marvellous.
Mr Wilson, will you sit on my right?
Jeff, your usual place. Darling, right there.
You ought to see Charles on skis.
He's wonderful.
- l'm pretty good too, aren't l?
- Very.
- Did you keep your knees together?
- Yes, freshy, l did.
Mr Wilson here is compiling
a catalogue of Paul Revere silver.
- How nice.
- He's also an authority on clocks.
- That's Charles' hobby too.
- So your brother tells me.
You're going to fix
the one in the church tower?
- l may try.
- That's quite an undertaking.
l hope he fails.
l like Harper just the way it is,
even with a clock that doesn't run.
Have you been in Harper long, Mr Wilson?
Since... Friday, a week ago.
You lost a day.
l patched you up on Friday.
- How's the head?
- Much improved, thanks to you, Doctor.
You were hurt on Thursday.
The day of the wedding.
Yes, that's right. Wednesday l left Bangor.
- You were hurt, Mr Wilson?
- Nothing serious.
Serious enough to raise a bump
on his head the size of a billiard ball.
The usual door.
Good thing you're back.
That dog of yours has been inconsolable.
All right, Red, here you are.
This is for missing me. Good boy.
- How was your meeting, Adam?
- lrritating.
- The Foreign Policy Association.
- l read that report.
- Standish.
- l think he's full of prunes.
That's the way we used to talk
in the 1 930s, Noah.
- Standish?
- The London Times man in Berlin.
Of course he was
quoting rumours, mostly.
Men drilling by night. Underground
meeting places. Pagan rituals.
- Do you believe him?
- Well, anything's possible.
l'm sorry, sir, but l think it's ridiculous.
Besides some fanatics, no German in his
right mind can still have a taste for war.
Do you know Germany, Mr Rankin?
l'm sorry, l...
l have a way of making enemies when
l'm on that subject. l get pretty unpopular.
Well, we shall consider it the objective
opinion of an objective historian.
Historian? A psychiatrist
could explain it better.
The German sees himself as
the innocent victim of envy and hatred -
conspired against, set upon
by inferior peoples, inferior nations.
He cannot admit to error,
much less to wrongdoing.
We ignored Ethiopia and Spain,
but we learned
the price of looking the other way.
Men of truth have come to know for
whom the bell tolled, but not the German.
He still follows his warrior guards,
marching to Wagnerian strains,
his eyes still fixed upon
the fiery sword of Siegfried.
ln those meeting places you don't
believe in, his dream world comes alive.
He takes his place in armour beneath
the banners of the Teutonic knights.
Mankind is waiting for the Messiah,
but for the German
the Messiah is not the prince of peace.
He's another Barbarossa.
Another Hitler.
Then you have no faith in the reforms
being effected in Germany?
l don't know. l can't believe that people
can be reformed except from within.
The principles of equality and freedom
never have taken root there.
The will to freedom
is voiced in every other tongue.
''All men are created equal.'' ''Liberte,
egalite, fraternite. '' But in German...
There's Marx. ''Proletarians unite. You
have nothing to lose but your chains.''
But Marx wasn't a German.
Marx was a Jew.
My dear Charles, if we concede
your argument, there is no solution.
- Sir, once again, l differ.
- What is it, then?
Annihilation. To the last babe in arms.
l can't imagine you're advocating
a Carthaginian peace.
Well, the world hasn't had much trouble
from Carthage in the past 2,000 years.
There speaks our pedagogue.
- Speaking of teachers...
- Yes?
The faculty is coming for tea on Tuesday.
Would you like to join us?
l'd like to, but my work here is finished.
l'm leaving Harper tomorrow.
Extraordinary, clocks being
Mr Wilson's hobby too.
Yes. lsn't it?
- Red, how do you like your new house?
- He loves it.
- Think l'll take you for a walk.
- Just let him out. He won't run off.
l need the walk. l'm restless.
Come on, boy.
That's good. Çow are you coming along?
l'll be in Washington tomorrow afternoon.
You were right about Rankin.
He's above suspicion.
Here, Red.
Red, come here.
Give me long distance.
l want Washington, DC.
Who but a Nazi would deny that Karl Marx
was a German, because he was a Jew?
l think l'll stick around for a while.
What is it, dear?
Oh.
l'm sorry. l was dreaming.
About that little man.
What little man?
You know, dear. l told you about him.
He came here the day we were married.
Light me a cigarette, will you?
l've never had a dream like that before.
lt frightened me.
Thanks.
The little man was walking all by himself
across a deserted city square.
Wherever he moved, he threw a shadow.
But when he moved away, Charles,
his shadow stayed there behind him
and spread out just like a carpet.
- l wish you could think who he was.
- You're overtired.
Perhaps.
Here, dear. Put this out, will you?
What was that?
That sounded like Red, Charles.
- What in the world's the matter with him?
- l put him in the cellar.
No wonder he's howling.
He's never been locked up in his life.
lf Red is to live with us,
he must be trained.
At night he will sleep in the cellar.
ln the daytime he'll be kept on a leash.
l don't believe in dogs being
treated like prisoners. Red's my dog.
Please, Mary. l know what's best.
Hi, Red. Thought you'd gone
to live with your mistress.
Mary brought him home.
Said he howls all night.
- Fishing any good in these parts?
- Pretty fair. Like to come?
l've got the wrong clothes on, but
the fish probably won't mind. Thank you.
l'm just not lucky today, that's all.
- Would you like a candy bar?
- l don't mind if l do.
- All your folks like fishing?
- My dad always brings in something.
- What about Charles?
- Charles?
Oh.
l have to call him Mr Rankin at school.
l get a little mixed up sometimes.
He spends most of his time on the clock.
Why don't you like him, Noah?
- What do you mean?
- You don't like your brother-in-law.
lt's none of my business,
but l wish you'd tell me why.
Well... l like him well enough.
l don't know any reason why l shouldn't.
Don't tell me l'm butting in - l know l am -
but l can't help myself.
lt's my business.
l hate bringing you into this,
but you're the only one l can turn to.
- l need your help very badly.
- What is it?
Your sister may be in trouble. You're man
enough for what l'm asking you to do.
The truth is,
l'm not really an antique dealer.
l'm sort of a detective.
Well... what do you
want me to do, Mr Wilson?
lt would help if l knew every move
Rankin made on his wedding day.
- Right up to the ceremony.
- Well, l should be able to...
- Unless Charles realises what l'm doing.
- l'll keep him busy.
You must be wrong. Mary wouldn't
fall in love with that kind of a man.
l hope l am wrong, but that's the way it is.
People can't help
who they fall in love with.
- Evening, Mr Potter.
- Evening, Mr Wilson.
- Evening, boys.
- Evening, sir.
85 cents.
Hear you and Rankin aim to fix the clock.
That's right.
- Figure it to tell time rightly?
- Mm-hm.
And will the angel
circle around the belfry?
- ls that a man or a woman angel?
- l don't know.
Well, reckon it don't make
much of a difference amongst angels.
Well:
- Give up?
- No. We'll play it out.
That's my privilege. 25 cents.
Oh, by the way, did Mr Rankin
pick up his supper this evening?
No.
He generally gets through
up there about now.
Yes, l know.
Gets dark earlier these days.
Our man never did pick up his suitcase.
- No.
- Strange.
Ain't it, though?
l've been tempted once or twice
to look and see what's inside it.
lt ain't even locked.
- Seems to me you have a perfect right.
- You do?
- l'd need a witness.
- That's me.
lt is? That's all l wanted to know.
Let's see what's in there.
Wonder what's in it?
- Soiled linen.
- Uh-huh.
- Sweater.
Soap and a razor wrapped in a towel
with ''SS Cristobal'' written across it.
- A pair of old shoes.
- Yep.
- Nothing but religious pamphlets.
- Yep, that's all.
Evening, Mr Potter. Hello, Mr Wilson.
- Mr Wilson, hi.
- Evening, Mr Rankin.
Mr Potter and l have been poking our
noses into somebody else's business.
That suitcase. That chap left it here
and he never did call back.
- lt's been over two weeks.
- Did he say what he was doing here?
No. Looked in the phone book,
didn't telephone.
Funny-looking, he was. Scrawny with
big stary blue eyes and a queer walk.
Like any second
he might break into a run.
- Did he have a foreign accent?
- Why, yes. He did.
Not so much of an accent
as a foreign way of talking.
Do you happen to know
who he could be, Mrs Rankin?
Why... why, no.
l was just trying to
complete your mystery for you.
Don't all foreign strangers
have to have foreign accents?
- Mary, have you seen Red?
- Why, no.
Not since l took him home to you.
He's been spending all his time
out in the woods.
- Thought you told me he never ran away.
- That's why Noah's so anxious.
Come on, Mary.
Good night, Mr Wilson. Night, Noah.
Were you able to find out anything?
Meinike did go to Rankin's house.
And your sister did see him.
- Did Mary say so?
- She started to.
Your sister's a fine woman, but she must
find out the kind of man she's married to.
She wouldn't listen to anything
against him. Much less believe it.
We must arrange it so that she finds out
for herself. Do you understand?
Yes.
lt's certain she knows nothing now.
Except that he didn't want her to admit
having seen someone she did see.
l'd give something to know
what explanation he's making now.
l was a student in Geneva.
There was a girl.
The night before l was to leave
we went out on the lake together.
She told me unless l promised to
marry her she'd never return to shore.
l thought she was joking, naturally,
but... she wasn't.
Before l could stop her
she stood up in the boat, and...
Well, l dived in after her
but it was too late, she was gone.
Only one person knew we were
on the lake together. Her brother.
He knew l hadn't murdered her,
but he told me he'd be willing to
call it an accident for a compensation.
l gave him all l had and left Switzerland.
As the years went by l allowed myself
to believe the dead past really was dead.
And then... on our wedding day, Mary,
he appeared again.
Her brother. The little man.
l gave him all the money
l had in the world.
And he went away again.
Oh, darling.
You should have told me,
and not carried this awful thing
around by yourself.
You're a very wonderful person, Mary.
l love you very much.
Oh, Charles.
But... why didn't he
go back for his things?
Well...
l suppose once he had money
he could afford better.
Darling, l'm terribly nervous.
Think l'll work up in the clock alone
tonight, by myself. lt will calm me.
- You understand, don't you?
- Of course l understand.
- Shall l walk you home?
- No, dear. There's no need for that.
- lt's late.
- That's all right.
ln Harper there's nothing to be afraid of.
l love you.
Poor old Red.
He heard my whistle, l'll bet.
He couldn't bark or anything.
He just crawled this far and died.
- Why do you think he died?
- Let's go and find out.
That's young Longstreet's dog, Red.
Looks like he's dead to me.
They're taking him up to
Dr Lawrence's office.
Do you know anything about it?
What in the world's happening?
Checkers?
No. No, thank you.
That Coke's a nickel.
Thank you, Mr Rankin.
Doctor, how long could the dog
have lived with that amount of poison?
Not more than a minute or so, l'd say.
Then Red was poisoned within a few
hundred yards of where you found him.
ln the latter part of the distance, he must
have been moving slower and slower.
- Thank you very much, Doctor.
- Thanks, Jeff.
Mr Peabody, would you get that
magazine rack in and hurry up about it?
Yes, Mr Potter.
Hurry up about it. Move along.
Afternoon, Mr Wilson. Afternoon, Noah.
Bring them right in there, Mr Peabody.
What does the law say about this kind of
murder? ls it the same as killing a man?
lt ought to be. lt's just as bad.
Forepaws muddy. No mud on hind.
Dry leaves mixed with the mud.
Red must have been
digging in the woods.
Have you any idea what for, Mr Wilson?
A body, l think. Meinike's.
The little man.
Then...
- You just caught me.
- Anything wrong?
You mean closing up?
Just going on a search.
- What are you after?
- Oil. What search?
For the body. State police
deputised half the town. Fourth shelf.
One misses the news up in the tower.
What body?
My bet is, fella that left his bags here.
Scrawny little duck. Unhappy-looking.
l knew he'd come to a bad end.
That oil will be 1 5 cents.
l'll just put it on your account.
Sara told me you were up here.
Why are you packing?
Are we going somewhere?
We aren't, dearest. l am.
What?
As a rule, men leave their wives
because they don't love them.
l must leave you because l do.
You won't object once you know
the kind of man you married.
But you are the man l've married
and that's all that matters.
Darling, l meant it
when l said for better or for worse.
Even to...
to killing Red?
You couldn't have.
- lt was an accident.
- No, l meant to kill him.
Murder can be a chain, one link leading
to another until it circles your neck.
Red was digging at the grave
of the man l killed.
Yes, your little man.
- You killed him?
- With these hands.
The same hands that have held you close.
Now are you satisfied to let me go?
Why? Why did you do it?
l'd have given him all l had,
but his dreams were far grander.
He knew your father was well-to-do.
He knew he would be glad to protect you
from scandal for a few thousand dollars.
l should have gone away and lost myself
in a world where he could never find me.
But l loved you. And l was weak.
Darling...
lf one of us goes, we'll both go.
You would have shared
half my trouble if l'd had any.
Charles, what is there
to connect you with that man?
Nothing, actually. You're the only one
that knows l knew him.
Then you need have no fear.
lf l'm the only one who can speak.
But, Mary, in failing to speak,
you become part of the crime.
But l'm already a part of it,
because l'm a part of you.
But you shudder at the touch of my hands
as though it was the touch of death.
lt's nerves.
Hold me close, Charles. Hold me close.
Mr Peabody, open up the coroner's office.
l knew darn well it was the same fella.
Course he's changed some.
Being buried in the earth does it.
Evening, Mr Wilson. Evening, Noah.
- Evening, Mr Potter.
- A mess, ain't it?
What do we do about Mary? We can't
leave her with him now we know.
She realises now that whatever story
he told her about Meinike was false.
Noah, l think your sister
should be ready to hear the truth.
Charles.
Will they make me look at the body?
l shouldn't think so.
Because l couldn't do it.
l mean, l don't think l could.
See, l've never seen a dead person.
l...
- How many are you having to tea, Mary?
- 28 altogether.
- You didn't eat nothing at dinner.
- lsn't that a lot?
- 28 for just you and Sara?
- No.
We'll manage all right.
- But suppose l...
- What?
l don't know. l'm terrified of
seeing anybody or being seen.
You must get tight hold of yourself.
To go through with this, you must know
what you're going to do and say.
Perfect naturalness at all times.
Now, darling, listen to me.
- Darling...
-
l am prepared to go to the police.
- lt's your father, Miss Mary.
- Thank you, Sara.
Mary...
Hello?
Yes, l think so. Just a minute and l'll see.
- He wants me to come over.
- Did he ask me too?
He said he wanted to see me alone.
There's nothing unusual about
a father wanting to see his daughter.
- ls there?
- No.
All right. l'll be right over.
- Don't you think that's rather strange?
- Strange? No.
l'll go and work on the clock
while you're with your father.
You can come by and pick me up later.
l'm so afraid.
He was so pointed about wanting to
see me alone. He sounded different.
You know what you're
going to say, don't you?
Come in, Mary.
ls something wrong?
Mr Wilson is here on a serious matter.
We must help him every way possible.
He wants to ask a few questions of you.
What do you want to know, Mr Wilson?
You know about the body
that was discovered yesterday?
Yes.
- Did you ever meet the deceased?
- No, l never met him.
Have you seen the body?
No.
Then how can you be sure
you've never met him?
Of course l can't be certain.
Do you suspect me of something?
lf so, what?
Of shielding a murderer.
Perhaps this will refresh your memory.
Do you recognise this man?
Konrad Meinike. Commander of one of
the more efficient concentration camps.
You know him, don't you?
You have met him here in Harper.
No, l've never seen that man, Mr Wilson.
Judge, would you mind
putting out the lights?
l've been showing him some films.
l'd like you to see them too.
l'm on the Allied Commission
for the Punishment of War Criminals.
lt's my job to bring Nazis to justice.
lt's that job that brought me to Harper.
Surely you don't think that...
l've never...
- l've never even seen a Nazi.
- You might without realising it.
They look like other people and act like
other people, when it's to their benefit.
A gas chamber.
The candidates were given hot showers
so that their pores would be open
and the gas would act more quickly.
And this is a lime pit, in which men,
women and children were buried alive.
Why do you want me
to look at these horrors?
All this you're seeing...
lt's all the product of one mind.
The mind of a man named...
- Franz Kindler.
- Franz Kindler?
Yes. He was the most brilliant
of the younger Nazis.
He conceived the theory of genocide,
mass depopulation of conquered lands.
So no matter who won the war,
Germany would be the strongest nation
in Europe, biologically speaking.
Unlike Goebbels, Himmler and the rest,
Kindler had a passion for anonymity.
The newspapers carried
no picture of him.
Before he disappeared
he destroyed every evidence
that might link him with his past.
There's no clue to the identity of Kindler -
except one little thing.
He has a hobby that almost
amounts to a mania. Clocks.
So have lots of people. You yourself.
l'm not quite finished, Mrs Rankin.
ln prison in Czechoslovakia
a war criminal was awaiting execution.
This was Konrad Meinike, one-time
executive officer for Franz Kindler.
He was an obscenity
on the face of the earth.
The stench of burning flesh
was in his clothes.
But we gave him his freedom on the
chance that he might lead me to Kindler.
He led me here.
And here l lost him.
Until yesterday.
Your dog Red found him for me.
But unfortunately Meinike
was dead and buried.
Now, in all the world, there's only one
person who can identify Franz Kindler.
The one who knows - knows definitely -
who Meinike came to Harper to see.
No, he's not a Nazi.
My Charles is not a Nazi:
You were at Rankin's house
on the day you were married.
- Yes.
- Did anyone come?
- Not that l remember.
- Try hard. lt's not so long ago.
- No one came.
- Were you alone all the time?
- No.
- Who else was there?
Charles. He came after his last class and
we were together for more than an hour.
You have nothing to link him with Kindler
except a wild suspicion. lt's ridiculous.
You want to use me
to implicate him and you can't.
You can't involve me in a lie
and that's all it is, is a lie.
lt's a lie, you know. lt's a lie.
Mary:
Wait a minute. Mary:
Wait a minute, sister.
That's better.
You know that your welfare and Noah's
means more to me than anything.
Yes, yes.
We've got to face this thing
with complete honesty, sister.
Your entire happiness may well depend
on your telling me the absolute truth.
lf Mr Wilson is right and you have married
a criminal, then there is no marriage.
There's no call upon
your loyalty as a wife.
He's good.
He's good. He wouldn't hurt anybody
except to protect somebody he loved.
- He's good.
- Then the truth can't hurt him.
Charles was not with you
that afternoon, sister.
- l remember your saying so.
- You're against him too, Adam.
You've never liked him. That's why you
don't believe me now. Leave us alone.
He's not a Nazi.
He's not one of those people.
Leave us alone.
She has the facts now.
But she won't accept them.
They're too horrible
for her to acknowledge.
Not so much that Rankin
could be Kindler,
but that she could ever have
given her love to such a creature.
But we have one ally. Her subconscious.
lt knows what the truth is
and is struggling to be heard.
The will to truth within your daughter
is much too strong to be denied.
Look here. lf he's not Charles Rankin
we should be able to expose him.
l'm not interested in proving that
he isn't Rankin, only that he is Kindler.
How do you propose to do that?
Through your daughter.
She's headed for a breakdown. That's
the usual result of being inwardly divided.
Rankin will see this.
That's what l'm banking on.
He can't trust a person near hysteria.
He'll have to act.
He may try to run before she collapses,
which would be an admission of guilt.
- Or...
- Go on.
He may kill her.
You're shocked at my cold-bloodedness.
That's natural. You're her father.
lt's because you are her father
that l'm talking to you like this.
Naturally we'll try to prevent
murder being done.
But the proof that murder is his aim would
be the strongest evidence she could have.
Charles.
Listen. lt's striking. After 100 years.
lt was a trap, just like you said.
Mr Wilson was there.
He tried to tell me you were a Nazi.
And l was supposed to believe it.
lmagine you being an escaped Nazi:
He thinks he's clever, Wilson.
He wanted me to tell him
about the little man.
- Who did he say he thought l was?
- A Nazi. Franz Kindler.
He made it all up to trick me.
But l didn't tell them anything.
l outfaced both of them, Charles.
lt'll be simple enough to prove
you're not that Nazi.
We'll just find someone
who was in your class at college.
lf what you say is true
he can't touch me.
l'm quite safe if you say nothing.
l won't. l promise l won't. They can
torture me and l won't tell them anything.
Look. The chimes have awakened Harper.
We must go down and greet them.
- You must act naturally. Smile at them.
- Yes.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, l'm all right.
We'll face them, darling.
And when she struck, that angel started
marching. lt was a sight to behold.
- You knocked it off. My hat's off to you.
- Congratulations.
Won't the rector be delighted:
lf she's going to chime all night long,
how's a body going to get any sleep?
We'll face them, darling. All of them.
Them chickens of yours is going to be
on and off the roost every 1 5 minutes.
Sara, l've told you
l want these curtains drawn.
- The sunlight is bad for them.
- That's rubbish and you know it.
- At the other house we didn't close them.
- This is my house and l want them drawn.
Suit yourself, then. lt's going to look
mighty gloomy for the party.
- ls it that time already?
-
Were you able to see
when they opened the grave?
- Not the most pleasant sight.
- There's Mary. Hello, Mary.
Filling out prescriptions is something
l hate. Sleeping pills is another.
- They're for Mrs Rankin.
- Want them wrapped?
- No.
- Don't approve of them.
Man works, man gets a night's sleep.
Or he could till that clock
started bonging.
l believe Mrs Rankin
ordered some ice cream.
Already gone. Fella said he was going
past your house so l gave it to him.
Mr Wilson.
- Mrs Rankin.
-  Wouldn't leave the house alone.
He might be anywhere, the murderer.
Waiting for a new victim.
l hope you haven't forgotten
you were kind enough to invite me.
- No, of course not.
- Mr Potter asked me to deliver this.
- Good. Sara's waiting for it.
- l hope it hasn't melted.
- l won't detain you any longer.
- l have a drink for you.
- Just the medicine l need.
- You know Dr Hippard?
- Can l get you something else?
- Nothing more, thank you, dear.
- Where's Doctor Rankin?
- He'll be here soon.
- l want a word with him about that clock.
- Yes.
May l get you some more tea?
..Jack the Ripper.
And what was that Frenchman's name?
There may well be ten or a dozen graves
out there in those woods.
He was murdered just three weeks ago.
- May l get you some more tea?
- Thank you, no.
l forget what Emerson says about crime.
There's Rankin. He may know.
- Sorry to be late.
- Darling.
Hello there, Rankin.
You know the quotation. Emerson.
''Commit a crime,
and the earth is made of glass.''
No, l don't.
''Commit a crime,
and the earth is made of glass.''
Commit a crime...
''Commit a crime, and it seems as if
a coat of snow fell on the ground,
such as reveals in the woods the track of
every partridge and squirrel and mole.''
''You cannot recall the spoken word,
you cannot wipe out the foot-track,
you cannot draw up the ladder
so as to leave no inlet or clue.''
You're Mr Wilson, aren't you? You're
our No.1 suspect in our murder case.
So far you're the only suspect.
Potter fingered you.
He thinks you committed the crime
to get possession of some antique.
l wish you'd let that clock alone.
Harper was a nice quiet place.
- Mary, what's Wilson doing here?
- l don't know.
- You invited him. What's he after?
- Are you all right?
- Yes, quite all right.
- Remember Friday, Mary.
- Yes, all right.
- May l help you, dear?
- No.
No: No, no:
- Mary, Mary...
-
lt's all right, dear. lt's all right.
lt broke, and the beads
fell all over the floor.
He took her upstairs.
- When l left l could still hear her crying.
- The floodgates have opened.
Her subconscious has almost won.
From now on we must know
every move that Mrs Rankin makes.
She's never to leave the house
unless l know where she's going.
lf l can't be found she's to be detained,
no matter on what pretext.
Don't worry. She won't get by me.
When she snapped those beads
it was her death warrant.
We're carrying her life in our hands.
Every time she walks on a slippery
sidewalk, is near something that can fall,
drives an automobile - anything that
could result in an accidental death -
her life is in danger.
She won't get by me.
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, sir.
Today we will finish with
the career of Friedrich der Groâe,
Konig von Preuâen, Kurfurst
von Brandenburg, Prinz von Polen.
Frederick the Great to you.
- 862, please.
-  That'll be 85 cents.
- Hello?
-  Hello, Mary.
Mary, this is Charles.
Can you hear me, dear?
l can't speak loudly,
but l want you to understand this.
Something very important has come up.
Come to the church immediately.
- The church tower. Understand?
- Yes, l understand.
l don't want anybody to know
you're going there.
Don't tell anybody. Leave your car in the
rear and come in through the back door.
OK? All right, then.
- Peabody:
- Coming.
Stack that wood down there,
then get back to work.
Yes, sir.
Watch that, Mr Peabody.
Your move, Professor.
Going someplace?
Where to?
- l asked you where you was going.
- l heard.
Well?
You forget l am no longer a child.
l'm a married woman.
Well, you ain't been married very long.
Wait, Mrs Rankin.
- What is it? l'm in a hurry.
- No need to go biting my head off:
- What is it, Sara?
- Well, l...
- lf you've got something to say, say it.
- l don't know what's got into you.
You never was mean to me
back at the old house.
Maybe l've outworn my usefulness.
l'm not as young as l used to be.
- Maybe you don't want me around.
- Don't talk nonsense.
lt's true and you know it.
l'm going to pack my things and leave.
l'm sorry if l've hurt your feelings.
l didn't mean to, really l didn't.
Sara...
l couldn't get along without you.
You know that, don't you?
- Well, don't you?
- Honest?
- Honestly. Cross my...
- Oh, Miss Mary.
Please, wait just a minute.
Sara, you'll never leave me, will you?
- You know how l feel about you.
- Yes.
Like you was my own daughter.
My own little girl.
l've got to go now. Really.
l've promised to be somewhere.
Well, where to, Miss Mary?
Stop fussing, Sara.
lt's a secret.
Miss Mary:
What's the matter?
My heart. l can't breathe. The pain:
No, Miss Mary. Please don't leave me.
Lie right there and keep quiet.
- Maybe l'm dying.
- You're not dying.
- Stay with me.
- l won't leave you.
1 30, please.
Yes, Mary?
l was supposed to meet Charles
at the clock tower and l can't get there.
Will you go and tell him
to please wait for me?
Noah, no one's to know where
or why you're going. lt's important.
All right.
238, please.
May l speak to Mr Wilson?
- Looks like it's coming up for snow.
- Yes, that's right.
lsn't it after hours? You ladies
are working too hard at the library.
Oh, no, Mr Rankin,
we closed as usual at 3.30.
You're perfectly right.
l dismissed class ten minutes early.
lt's 3.44.
l was playing checkers with Mr Potter
and l didn't realise.
You know what you are?
You're the absent-minded professor.
- You sure are lucky today.
- l am.
- Mr Potter.
- Afternoon, Mr Hill.
- l can't find the earmuffs.
- Right over there by the mittens.
- Come on, help us look.
- l'll be right back.
Right over there by that box.
Latest thing out.
- How much?
- 85 cents.
- That's an awful lot.
- They come high this year.
- You want this thing?
- l'll keep it.
You're a bad influence. l intended
only to spend a couple of minutes.
- Look what time it is.
- Yeah. l'd like to get even.
lt's your move.
He really had the wind up. You can
still smell the glue where he joined it.
Look at that.
Like l told you, it's coming up for snow.
Look here, Professor.
Double or nothing?
- Afternoon, Mr Potter.
- Afternoon, Professor.
Charles?
- You didn't go the church.
- No. Sara...
- What about Sara?
- Sara had some kind of an attack.
She's resting now. Jeff said it wasn't very
serious, but that l should stay with her.
- What's the matter, Charles?
- Nothing's the matter.
Then why did you want me to go to
the church? You said it was important.
lt wasn't. Nothing, actually.
lt's my sense of proportion
has failed me these days.
Please, Charles. What is it?
l'm sorry.
l've just begun to feel the strain.
You see, l have my weak moments too.
l'll tell you in my own good time.
- Have they found out anything more?
- Nothing to find out. Unless you...
- l haven't seen anybody all day.
- l heard there's an arrest to be made.
My head aches. The incident with
the beads made me doubt your strength.
l thought maybe you'd gone to your father
and told him something. lf you had...
- You didn't have to be afraid.
- No?
- What did you tell Noah?
- What about?
- Didn't you see him?
- Why should l see Noah?
- Did you come from the church?
- Are we in court?
No, but l told Noah to go there
and tell you l was detained.
l told you not to call anybody.
Call him and tell him not to go.
- l can't.
- Call him, l say:
- He's gone:
- lf he dies, his blood is on your hands.
- What?
- lt's your meddling that's done this.
lt would have been all right
if it wasn't for you.
But you had to be here. On that day.
- Hanging your stupid curtains:
- Did you kill Noah?
Yes, if he goes to the church
and climbs up that ladder:
- lt was l you intended to kill, wasn't it?
- No.
Why wasn't it l?
Franz Kindler:
Kill me. Kill me, l want you to.
l couldn't face life knowing what l've been
to you and what l've done to Noah.
But when you kill me
don't put your hands on me.
Here. Use this.
Mary.
Noah:
Operator.
Get me the state police.
Yes, the roadblocks are up.
We're watching the railroad station
and he isn't hiding in the woods.
Judge Longstreet:
Get Wilson, Noah. l'll go for the police.
lf he is where l think he is,
it'll be easy.
- We'll do all we can to take him alive.
- She's gone.
- She's not in the house.
- Clock tower?
l don't know.
lf that's where he's hiding
and she gets there before us...
- What'll we do?
- Call Captain Samuels and the deputies.
Ouch:
- The church:
- What about you?
l'll get there. Hurry up.
Your sister may be still alive.
Don't move. l have a gun.
You don't need it. l'm alone.
- What are you doing here?
- Lift me up.
- You're telling the truth?
- Why should l lie?
- You were followed here?
- l came by our way.
Through the cemetery. No one saw me.
l needed the excuse.
l was afraid you wouldn't let me up.
- What do you want?
- l came to kill you.
No, Mary, it's you that's going to die.
You were meant to fall
through that ladder.
You're going to fall.
l don't mind, if l take you with me.
You are a fool.
They searched the woods.
l watched them.
Like God looking at little ants.
l'll hide in the woods.
They won't look again.
When they find me
they'll know you're still here.
You were on the verge of a breakdown.
Now you've cracked.
Why else would you leave your bed,
climb here in the dead of night?
- Any child could see you'd kill yourself.
- Killing is what led you here.
lt won't help you now.
Look out the window. Look:
That's an old trick. A very poor trick.
Tricks: That's all you know, is tricks.
l don't need any tricks. No matter what
happens to me tricks will do you no good.
You're finished, Herr Franz Kindler.
The citizens of Harper.
They've come after you.
The plain, ordinary people,
the ones you've been laughing at.
Well, you can't fool them any more.
Sure, you can kill me, Mary,
half the people down there.
But there's no escape.
The world closed in on you
till there was only Harper.
That closed in
and there was only this room.
And this room too is closing in on you.
lt's not true, the things they say l did.
l followed orders.
- You gave the orders.
- l only did my duty.
Don't send me back there.
l'm not a criminal.
You are.
Give me that gun:
All right, Mary's safe.
Let me give you a hand.
- No, thanks.
- What happened?
- V-day in Harper.
- l don't get that. Come on down.
No, not until you get me a new ladder.
l've had my ankle busted
and my head conked.
- From here on in l'm taking it easy.
- l'll get you another ladder.
You've had enough trouble.
Good night, Mary. Pleasant dreams.
Visiontext Subtitles: Paul Sofer
ENHOH