Peace! Happiness! Smile!
1, 234!
Smile! More teeth!
Don't let the camera
catch you looking bad!
Smile! 1, 2, 3, 4!
Real joy, not just pleasure!
And natural beauty!
This isn’t fake!
Okay, peace! Peace! Peace!
I'm looking for an actress...
...an actress to play a mother.
Old ladies like you...
When you see
movie stars on TV-
- you must dream of becoming one.
- No, I don't.
- Why not?
- You have nothing else to do.
- No, I'm busy.
These women won't agree
to play communists like this.
It might work if we
invite them to your house first...
But if we ask them right here,
they'll be afraid.
People might think
they really are communists.
I disagree... In my neighborhood
everybody would do it.
Then let's go there instead.
It's impossible here.
This whole area was communist.
We're looking for
women with children -
-to play communist wives.
You try to prevent us
from burning down your house.
But in the end
we burn it down.
'Mother, they burned
our house down!'
Like that.
And don't worry if you touch
her breasts. You're still a kid.
Ready?
Kill them!
No!
- Destroy their house!
- No, please don't!
Burn it!
Kill!
Cry! Weep!
Don't burn my house.
Keep crying!
Okay cut, cut!
Whether this ends up
on the big screen -
- or only on TV
it doesn't matter.
- But we have to show...
- That this is the history!
This is who we are!
So in the future
people will remember!
It doesn't have to be a big film -
- like Rank Organization,
Paramount Pictures, MGM...
We, in our simple way
step by step -
- will tell the story-
- of what we did
when we were young!
Excuse me...
There's many ghosts here, because
many people were killed here.
- They died unnatural deaths.
- Unnatural deaths.
They arrived perfectly healthy.
When they got here
they were beaten up... and died.
At first, we beat them to death...
But there was too much blood.
There was so much blood here...
So when we cleaned it up,
it smelled awful.
To avoid the blood,
I used this system.
Can I show you?
Sit there.
Face that way.
We have to re-enact this properly.
This is how to do it -
- without too much blood.
I've tried to forget all this
with good music... Dancing...
Feeling happy..
A little alcohol...
A little marijuana...
A little... what do you call it?
Ecstasy..
Once I'd get drunk,
I'd 'fly' and feel happy.
Cha cha.
He's a happy man.
Anwar Congo,
from the paramilitary group.
You've heard of him?
From the Medan Cinema.
Now that I'm governor,
I stab him if he threatens me.
Everyone was scared of him.
The only one not scared was me-
- because he looked after me
when I was a kid.
When I was in high school -
- I was the only one
not scared of him -
- because I didn't think of him
as a big gangster.
But when people heard his name,
they'd be terrified.
- Why?
- Because he's one of the killers.
Now, the communists' children
are starting to speak out -
- trying to reverse the history.
One of them wrote, 'I’m Proud to be
the Child of a Communist.'
But this won't last long -
- because the people won't accept it.
Communism will never be
accepted here, because -
- we have so many gangsters,
and that's a good thing.
The word 'gangster' comes
from English. 'Free men'.
Thugs want freedom to do things,
even if they're wrong...
But if we know
how to work with them -
- all we have to do is direct them.
We were gangsters.
We didn't have real jobs.
So we'd do anything for money..
...just to buy nice clothes.
This was the cinema -
- where I worked.
I'd stand here,
scalping tickets and showing off.
When films were popular,
we'd scalp tickets.
But when the communists
were strong -
- they demanded
a ban on American films.
They wanted fewer
American films.
- So we gangsters made less money.
- Because there was no audience.
Hollywood films were popular.
Without them the gangsters
didn't make as much money.
As we say:
'Dinner missed the belly'
When we'd watch happy movies,
like Elvis movies -
- we'd leave the cinema smiling,
dancing to the music.
Our hands...
Still dancing...
Still in the mood of the film...
if girls passed,
we'd whistle.
We loved it.
We didn't care what people thought.
Here was the paramilitary office,
where I always killed people.
I'd see the guy
being interrogated...
I'd give him a cigarette.
I'd still be dancing, laughing...
it was like we were killing...
...happily!
When my mom was alive -
- sometimes,
when I was screaming...
...my mom would rush in
and wake me up.
'Before you sleep, wash your feet!'
'Pray properly Don't just sleep.'
I know my bad dreams
come from what I did...
...killing people
who didn't want to die.
I forced them to die.
Why are you daydreaming,
my love?
Are you so uncertain?
You're a star now!
Amazing!
This guy's a star!
Joshua, film the photos!
That's the president's father-in-law,
Sarwo Edhie.
- I'll introduce them one-by-one.
- That’s the president.
That's him with the president.
Ibrahim Sinik is famous
all across the country!
We gangsters keep him
well protected.
We wish him
a long, prosperous life.
But don't forget
to share your money!
Ask Joshua for money.
After all, he’s from London!
You interrogated communists
in your newsroom?
He was always
gathering information.
When he had the information -
- he'd say: 'Guilty!' and we'd
take them away and kill them.
When you interrogated
communists in your office -
- what questions did you ask?
Whatever we asked,
we'd change their answers -
- to make them look bad.
As a newspaper man -
- my job was to make
the public hate them.
And your relationship
with the army?
- The army.
- We had no formal relationship.
But after we captured
the communist youth -
- and beat them to a pulp -
- we gave them to the army
but the army wouldn't take them.
They said,
'Just dump them in the river.'
Do you remember
exactly what the army said?
I didn't bring the victims.
I had men for that.
Why would I do such grunt work?
Why would I kill people?
I didn't have to! One wink from me
and they're dead!
Pancasila Youth!
How you doing, Anwar?
This is the real Anwar Congo!
Pancasila Youth,
servants of the nation...
Once our sails go up -
- we never turn back!
- Pancasila!
- Forever!
All Pancasila Youth members
are heroes.
From exterminating
the communists -
- to fighting neo-communists
and left-wing extremists-
- and those who want
to destroy our country..
This isn't only the duty
of the army and police.
We, Pancasila Youth,
must take a stand.
These are threats to the nation,
and we must take action.
They say Pancasila Youth
is a gangster organization.
If we're gangsters-
- I'm the biggest
gangster of all.
Oh, shit!
How did Pancasila Youth
exterminate the communists?
We killed them all.
That's what happened.
May I hit the ball now?
We have too much democracy
it's chaos.
What is this 'democracy'?
Things were better under
the military dictatorship.
Better economy More security .
Gangsters are free men.
They want to enjoy, life
in their style.
Relax and Rolex.
You definitely have a mole
on your pussy.
Definitely.
That was great.
If I get a strike,
I get a massage!
There must be many ghosts here.
They arrived perfectly healthy.
Then they were beaten up.
And died.
Sit here.
We have to re-enact this properly
I never would have
worn white pants.
I never wore white.
I always wore dark colors.
I look like I'm dressed for a picnic.
My acting has to be violent.
And maybe I should dye
my hair black.
And now he's dead.
But how do you feel
watching this?
How do I feel?
Back then I felt more free.
Older men are gentle,
but young men...
Especially me, because I watched
so many sadistic movies.
We were influenced by them.
So we...
We were more cruel
than the movies.
I know a good location
for a torture scene.
Behind the school,
in the old toilets...
- But the neighbors will hear..
- They know me.
If I look at them,
they run away.
Look, I'm laughing.
I did it wrong, didn't I?
It's my mistake.
I was influenced
by films starring -
- Marlon Brando, Al Pacino...
Those were my favorites.
And westerns with John Wayne.
I brought these clothes
from home.
Hopefully they express my vision.
Hey you have to change your shirt.
Put on a white one.
You'll look lovely in this!
Perfect!
- What the fuck is this?
- Just a little decoration.
It matches your body shape.
It's perfect!
- This one's for the 'Big Boss'.
- Yep. It's perfect for me.
And you know where I got
the inspiration for it?
I always watched gangsterfilms -
- where they always kill with wire.
It's faster with wire.
Because when you pull the wire
hard, the victim can't grab it...
He can't, because it cuts in...
it's great to be
a communist, huh?
Don't just nod. Say 'Yes sir!'
- Wanna smoke, Pang?
- No.
Try this 'neo-colonialist' cigar.
Have a puff.
Just stick it in your nose
if you don't want to smoke it.
- Look at him!
- Look at me.
Look him in the eye!
Hold on, Joshua.
It's evening prayers.
- Don't tie the blindfold so tight.
- I didn't.
The way I pull it
just looks tight.
Even by the window it's hot.
'Human rights!'
All this talk about 'human rights'
pisses me off.
'We want a little human rights!'
Back then
there was no human rights.
- Because you made a revolution.
- That's no excuse.
For example, in Argentina
some generals launch a coup d'état-
- and then they're convicted
of human rights violations.
But I'm a gangster
I'm a gangster A free man.
A movietheater gangster.
Not much education.
- A human drop out.
- A drop out.
There are people like me
everywhere in the world.
They still look great.
There were many
Chinese communists!
I got a thick book
with all their names.
I'd visit them,
'How much you gonna pay?'
They'd say
'Please, Sir don't! I'm old.'
We used them for their money
We didn't kill them.
But if they didn't pay we killed
them. They can't have it both ways.
If they didn't pay..
...we killed them.
These Chinese are diff cult.
Sometimes they piss me off.
That's it...
You sure speak good Chinese.
When I need money
there's nothing like an old friend.
With others, if it's not enough,
I won't accept it.
Hi Lung. C'mon, shake my hand.
It's been a long time.
- I need money.
- Why me?
I'm asking you nicely
I don't even ask the others.
I just punch them...
An uppercut right in the stomach.
You give this sincerely?
Then thank you very much.
Our organization is planning
a big meeting. We need money.
We need more than normal.
We need a huge amount.
Don't give the usual amount.
What’s this shit?
Give more
or I won't accept it.
- Please...
- I'd never accept so little.
Here.
That's not enough.
What's wrong with you, Cik?
We consider you our father Cik.
So throw in more, and we'll take it,
because this isn’t for just anybody.
Count it up and put it in.
The spirit of Pancasila Youth -
- which people accuse
of being gangsters...
Gangsters are people
who work outside the system -
- not for the government.
The word 'gangster'
comes from 'free men'.
This nation needs 'free men'!
If everyone worked for
the government-
- we'd be a nation of bureaucrats.
We'd get nothing done.
We need gangsters
to get things done.
Free, private men
who get things done.
Use your muscles!
Muscles aren't
for beating people up -
- although beating people up
is sometimes needed.
- Once more, Pancasila!
- Forever!
- Pancasila!
- Freedom!
While you wait for this train,
we wish to inform you -
- that the traffic laws are there
to protect you and your family.
We also inform you,
that in accordance with the law...
- This is me, Anwar Congo.
- Oh, that's you!
Look, I'm rolling a joint.
You're smoking pot.
That's me. I'm wearing a plaid shirt,
camouflage pants, saddle shoes...
See how 'elite' I am?
This is what you should wear
in the studio scene.
And for the killing scene... Jeans.
I wore jeans for killing.
When you kill people, you should
wear thick pants. Like this...
- How about a checkered pattern?
- That'd be great, but small ones.
To look cool,
I imitated movie stars.
But I didn't copy Elvis Presley
Herman, I'll make you
a gorgeous dress!
- More energy!
- We're ready boss!
Burn them all!
Finally you got it!
Cry 'What's going on, mom?'
'Leave us alone!'
Wait everybody!
Anwar show us how to kill.
You! Come here!
What's going on?
Who says I'm a communist?
Hold him down!
Torture him! Kill him!
Are you listening?
Stop denying
you're a communist!
- Okay fine!
- Leave our grandfather alone!
You take him, I'll take the kids!
- You love these kids?
- Please stop.
Sit!
- Or I'll smash this kid!
- Let me go!
If you love these kids,
you better stop lying.
It's your choice!
Cut!
Amazing!
Why do people watch James Bond?
To see action.
Why do people watch films about
Nazis? To see power and sadism!
We can do that!
We can make something
even more sadistic than...
...more sadistic than what
you see in movies about Nazis.
Sure I can!
Because there's never been a movie
where heads get chopped off-
- except in fiction,
but that’s different -
- because I did it in real life!
What's clear is no film
has ever used our method.
We can attract a huge audience!
Humor... it's a must.
- Romance?
- We've got it!
Fuck this umbrella!
Herman’s trapped.
He should scream,
'Leave me alone! Stop! Stop!'
Meanwhile, the three of us scream,
'You communist bitch!'
Keep attacking her!
I'm gonna rape you!
I'm gonna kill you!
How long have you been pregnant?
You'll give birth to a communist!
But if the audience is
tense the whole time -
- with nothing to entertain them,
it will never work!
On Saturday night,
I went to the movies.
Oh, I'm not gonna
shake my ass or anything.
I watched the movie
alone with my girlfriend.
The film was sold out -
- so I bought tickets from
the movie theater gangsters.
Oh how lovely..
- Adi! How’s the family?
- We're all fine.
Was it a good flight?
- How've you been, Anwar?
- I'm fine.
- The city has changed a lot.
- Really?
I've tried to call you many times.
But you never answer my calls.
Your nose needs more.
- Do you remember Soaduon?
- Yes, where is he?
Over there. Soaduon Siregar.
Now he takes credit for everything,
but back then he was nobody
I remember him.
- Adi, this is Soaduon Siregar.
- I remember you.
He's one of Ibrahim's Sinik's
journalists.
As they say:
'Although camels live in Arabia,
they never get to visit Mecca.'
Being close to a rich boss
didn't make him rich.
Just like me.
Have a seat.
Interrogation of Communist, Take 2
We give land to the farmers.
We give them fertilizer, seeds,
farming equipment...
In order to spread
communism, right?
Indeed, we want to show that
the Communists are the best party.
Why do you recruit people
to join an illegal party?
But back then, it wasn't illegal.
- It wasn't?
- Before 1965? Of course not!
It's easy to make the communists
look bad after we destroyed them.
So, the communists were not
more cruel than us.
We were the cruel ones!
'Cruel' is totally
different from sadistic.
- No, it isn't. They're synonyms.
- No.
Sadism is different.
- You're playing with words!
- No, I'm not.
You're playing with words.
It bumped its head.
Sometimes I think... if my dad
was a communist and was killed -
- I'd be upset. That's normal, right?
For example, if you killed my father
I'd be upset with you.
Why'd you kill my father?
Then, you don't let me go to school.
You don't let me work.
You don't even let me marry
This needs to be changed.
There's been no official apology -
- but what's so hard
about apologizing?
The government would apologize,
not us.
It would be like medicine.
It would reduce the pain.
- Forgiveness.
- Wouldn't they curse us secretly?
They curse us secretly..
Because if they cursed us openly..
They'd be arrested!
So they whisper their curses?
For me, Adi, in the end...
I'm disturbed in my sleep.
Maybe because-
- when I strangled people with wire
I watched them die...
But when you used other methods,
you also watched.
Yes, but when I'm falling asleep,
it comes back to me.
That's what gives me nightmares.
You feel haunted
because your mind is weak.
Have you ever been
to a neurologist?
If I went to a neurologist,
it would mean I'm crazy.
No! Psychiatrists are not
for crazy people.
Psychiatrists aren't for crazy
people. They're nerve experts.
Even I've been to a nerve expert...
But for a mild stroke.
See, your nightmares are just
a nerve disturbance.
Come on, give it a try!
If you see a shrink,
you talk, he talks.
Then he gives you nerve vitamins.
Remember the 'Crush
the Chinese' campaign in 1966?
All along Sudirman Street -
- I killed every Chinese
person I met. I stabbed them!
I don't remember how many
but it was dozens.
If I met them, I stabbed them.
All the way to Asia Street,
where I met my girlfriend's dad.
Remember my girlfriend
was Chinese?
'Crush the Chinese' became
'Crush my Girlfriend's Dad'!
So I stabbed him, too!
Because he was Chinese!
He fell into a ditch.
I hit him with a brick. He sank.
Killing is the worst crime
you can do.
So the key is to find a way -
- not to feel guilty
it's all about finding
the right excuse.
For example, if I'm asked
to kill someone...
If the compensation is right...
...then of course I'll do it, and
from one perspective it's not wrong.
That’s the perspective
we must make ourselves believe.
At first, I was scared...
These are top gangsters!
Like you and Anwar...
Terrifying!
And making a film! It's shocking!
But if you want a true story
I have one.
Tell us. Because everything
in this film should be true.
There was a shopkeeper.
He was the only Chinese person
in the area.
To be honest,
he was my stepfather.
He was my stepfather..
But although
he was my stepfather-
- I lived with him
since I was a baby..
At 3 AM,
someone knocked on our door.
They called my dad. Mom said,
'It's dangerous! Don't go out.'
But he went out.
We heard him shout, 'Help!'
Then, silence.
They took him away
We couldn't sleep until morning.
- How old were you?
- 11 or 12...
I remember it well.
And it's impossible to forget!
We found his body
under an oil drum.
The drum was cut in half-
- and the body was under it,
like this...
His head and feet were
covered by sacks -
- but one foot poked out like this.
That same morning,
nobody dared help us...
We buried him like a goat
next to the main road.
Just me and my grandfather
carrying the body-
- digging the grave... No one
helped us. I was so small.
Then, all the communist families
were exiled...
We were dumped in a shantytown
at the edge of the jungle.
That's why to be honest,
I've never been to school.
I had to teach myself
to read and write.
Why should I hide this from you?
I promise I'm not
criticizing what we're doing.
It's only input for the film.
I promise I'm not criticizing you.
Look, everything's
already been planned.
We can't include every story
or the film will never end.
And your story is too complicated.
It would take days to shoot.
- Maybe we can work it in...
- Or it can motivate the actors.
We believe this man's a communist.
After we decided to kill him, there
were many reactions. Some prayed.
- Come on, pray.
- 'God help me!'
How do you tell him he's going
to die? Angrily or softly?
I tried to make them accept
that they were going to die.
Anwar teach us how to torture.
'You want me to use this?'
- Should I scare him?
- Yes.
You want me to use this?
Then, beg him not to.
Now, take the cloth
and blindfold him.
Josh always asks me,
'You worked in the same office -
- how could you not have known?'
I declare: I never saw anything.
Now, seeing your re-enactment,
I realize you were so smooth -
- that even me, a journalist
with such sharp senses...
I never knew!
I'm surprised. Because we didn't
hide what we were doing.
- If you didn't know, I'd be shocked.
- I didn't.
We were in the same office...
- And we didn't hide it.
- I never knew.
You were so smooth, and I rarely
went upstairs to your office.
- Your publisher directed the torture.
- No!
- He says so himself.
- That's not true!
He and the other leaders
decided who we killed.
Look, I'm not calling you a liar,
but logically..
- Continue, Adi.
- I'm not calling him a liar Joshua.
But this man, a journalist distancing
himself from these things...
That's predictable. But logically
something we didn't hide...
How could he not know?
Even the neighbors knew!
Hundreds were killed.
It was an open secret.
- Drink!
- Have some water.
- It's not poison!
Drink! Just drink it.
- Drink it. It will refresh you.
- Give him a cigarette.
Let him smoke.
It's sadistic, Adi.
Ask him again about his activities.
Have mercy on me.
Please, sir.
Should we kill him?
Wait. Would you give a
message to my family?
Sure.
Or could I speak to them
one last time?
No way.
Okay pull.
Lower your head.
He's dead.
Wrap him up.
Listen, if we succeed
in making this film -
- it will disprove all the propaganda
about the communists being cruel.
- And show that we were cruel!
- We're the cruel ones.
If this film is a success! We must
understand every step we take here.
It's not about fear
it's 40 years ago...
...so any criminal case has expired.
It's not about fear it's about
image. The whole society will say:
'We always suspected it. They lied
about the communists being cruel.'
it's not a problem for us.
It's a problem for history.
The whole story will be reversed.
Not 180 degrees... 360 degrees!
If we succeed with this scene!
But why should we always hide
our history if that's the truth?
No, the consequence is...
...that everything Anwar
and I have always said is false.
It's not the communists
who were cruel.
- But that’s true!
- I completely agree.
But not everything true
should be made public.
I believe even God has secrets.
I'm absolutely aware
that we were cruel.
That's all I have to say
it's up to you what to do about it.
I don't mean to make you
uncomfortable, but I have to ask...
By telling yourself it was 'war',
you're not haunted like Anwar.
But the Geneva Conventions
define what you did as 'war crimes'.
I don't necessarily agree
with those international laws.
When Bush was in power
Guantanamo was right.
Saddam Hussein had
weapons of mass destruction.
That was right according to Bush,
but now it's wrong.
The Geneva Conventions may be
today's morality but tomorrow -
- we'll have the Jakarta Conventions
and dump the Geneva Conventions.
'War crimes' are defined
by the winners.
I'm a winner So I can make
my own definition.
I needn't follow
the international definitions.
And more important,
not everything true is good.
Some truths are not good.
Like re-opening this case.
Even if everything you're finding out
is true, it's not good.
But for millions of victims'
families-
- if the truth comes out, it's good.
Fine, but start with the first
murder Cain and Abel.
Why focus on killing
the communists?
Americans killed the Indians.
Has anybody been
punished for that? Punish them!
For me, re-opening this case
is a provocation to fight.
I'm ready! If the world wants
continuous war, I'm ready
if you wanna make
us fight, I'm ready!
What if you were brought to the
international court in the Hague?
- Now?
- Yes.
I'd go! I don't feel guilty
so why would I go?
Because I'd be famous.
I'm ready!
Please, get me called
to the Hague!
More hot!
I like this... Eye candy.
This is healthy for a guy like me.
Enjoy the scenery Ma'am.
Okay.
- One, two, three.
- Ah!
- Again! One, two, three.
I was asked to run for parliament.
'Why me?' 'Don't worry!
You can do it!' they said.
Then I thought,
'Why not?'.
In fact, I'm a perfect candidate
because I'm well known!
Don't clench your fist.
Be quiet!
I've almost got it!
- OK, but don't make a fist.
- You're ruining the sound!
- But...
- Stop it!
Be quiet!
You're a real pain! Just shut up!
Long live the Businessmen and
Workers Party! I am Herman...
...ready to fight
for workers' rights.
Remember to vote
for me on election day!
If I get elected and get
on the Building Commission -
- I can get money from everyone.
For example, if a building
is 10 cm too small...
I can demand
'Tear down the building!'.
They'll say, 'Please don't report us.
Here's your money'.
Even if nothing's
wrong with the building -
- if I threaten them,
they'll give me money anyway.
Not just a little money
In a block of 10 buildings...
if each pays $10000,
just do the math!
That's already $100,000.
That's only one neighborhood!
Actually parliament should
bethe most noble place in society.
But if we see
what they do there...
They're really just
robbers with ties.
What illegal businesses are
Pancasila Youth involved in?
Gambling.
Gambling, night clubs.
Supermarkets.
But that’s not illegal.
They just hire us as security.
- The illegal ones?
- Gambling.
- Any others?
- Smuggling.
Illegal fishing, illegal logging,
illegal gambling...
...and if they don't pay
we blackmail them.
Let's welcome our candidate,
Marzuki!
Long live our party!
Pancasila!
Ready!
What am I supposed to say?
How does it begin?
- What's the first sentence?
- I'm Herman.
- I'm Herman!
- Stand up, you'll look better.
Ladies and gentlemen... What
comes next? I can't remember
I'm Herman, from the Businessmen
and Workers' Party!
- Any free T-shirts?
- Nope... Ma'am, here's my card.
T-shirts! We want presents!
Don't worry about money or presents.
We'll come back with gifts.
Pray for us, hopefully he'll win.
Tell people
who ask for presents...
'We'll come back with gifts
if we win.'
Tell them, 'We're filming today'
- Don't forget.
- Just a card?
Where's 'the bonus'?
Don't we get anything else?
- 'The bonus' comes later.
- Once you're elected?
- Honey where do you think you are?
- Yes, but...
Many of the parties
bribe people to vote for them.
In fact, they all do.
And when you see thousands
of people at a rally -
- all of them
were paid to be there.
They consider it going to work.
Without money they won't come.
They'll ask each other,
'how much did you get?'.
And leaders just get paid more!
Nowadays, nobody believes
in what they're campaigning for.
We've all become
like soap opera actors.
Our souls have become
They look happy,
but inside they’re pissed off!
Fuck this shit, they're thinking.
Where's the injured one?
Where’s the crippled one?
- Which?
- The injured one.
There she is.
- Sweet little duck.
- Don't! You'll hurt her again.
She's weak
because you broke her leg.
Don't do that.
She's a baby!
Say 'I’m sorry Duck.'
- I'm sorry Duck.
- That's it.
Now say 'lt was an accident.
I was scared, so I hit you.'
Say 'lt was an accident.'
Speak loudly.
- Sorry Duck.
- And pet her a little.
Now the communist
has become a ghost.
He was killed and became a ghost.
- Haunting you.
- Haunting me.
Do you feel trauma seeing this?
If he came to me at night,
I'd be terrified.
It's like the ghosts hate me.
Because in my dreams they
have threatening voices...
- They laugh, but frighteningly!
- Try to laugh.
Anwar's nightmare, take 2.
Standby.
Record.
I thought I killed you!
- What did I do wrong?
- Just get up, surprised.
And ask, 'Why are you alive?'
What's so hard about it?
I... I thought I killed you!
Why am I coming to this place?
Because it affected me so deeply.
Because the method of killing...
...was very different.
And that's why I always
have nightmares.
Is it because I've been
telling you my story so honestly?
Or maybe
the vengeance of the dead?
I remember... I said
'Get out of the car'.
He asked,
'Where are you taking me?'.
Soon, he refused to keep walking...
I saw Roshiman bringing me
a machete.
Spontaneously I walked over to him
and cut his head off.
My friends didn't want to look.
They ran back to the car.
And I heard this sound...
His body had fallen down...
And the eyes in his head
were still...
On the way home, I kept thinking,
why didn't I close his eyes?
All I could think about was
And that is the source
of all my nightmares...
I'm always gazed at by those
eyes that I didn't close.
That's what always
disturbs me so very much.
Slit his throat!
Cut off his head!
Hooray!
Did you take it?
Is it good?
- Thank you.
- No, thank you, Sir.
No. With such a beautiful girl?
I should thank you.
Too bad she bleaches her hair...
Makes her look like a whore.
- Tell him about the car!
- What happened?
There was this girl...
She sucked off six men -
- and not a drop of cum on the floor.
- Six men?
- She swallowed it all.
And after the last guy finishes,
she's still sucking -
- like she wanted more!
Dear God, make our great
organization a pillar of this nation.
You know the price of the land?
200 million dollars.
I gave it to the birds.
So they have a happy life.
I'm also happy.
Everybody's terrified of
the paramilitaries.
So, when a businessman wants
land where people are living...
if he just pays for it,
it's expensive.
But we can solve his problem.
Because people are terrified of us,
when we show up -
- they say 'Just take the land.
Pay what you like.'
This is a rose.
Very very limited.
Elephant.
This is very very limited.
I buy these
from every country I visit.
Hungary
2,250 dollars.
You've cut off my head...
You have to be furious,
but also sad.
You have to be angry sad.
Sadistic.
Look at your blood!
Look what I found
in your stomach!
Look at this!
Your liver.
It's rotten!
Even in make-up he looks like
he's from Ethiopia!
- Tanzania. Like Idi Amin.
- Idi Amin Dada.
Camera 3 on Citra!
Close up on Citra for the opening.
Everybody ready?
Roll the leader!
Indonesian National Television
'Special Dialogue'
Welcome back to Indonesian
Television's Special Dialogue.
Today we meet movie theater
gangsters who are making a film -
-to commemorate the
crushing of the communists.
We go straight to the perpetrator
and star of the film, Anwar Congo!
Let's welcome Anwar Congo!
In those days movie theater
gangsters were very well known.
What's the origin of
the word 'gangster'?
Actually gangster comes
from 'free men'.
That's why we use
a special song in our movie.
A song called 'Born Free.'
So you brought the communists
straight to your office?
Yes, and after we interrogated them,
and decided they shouldn't be alive-
- we had to kill them.
And was your method of killing
inspired by gangsterfilms?
Sometimes!
It's like...
Amazing!
He was inspired by films!
Each genre had its own method.
Like in mafia movies...
...they strangle the guy in
the car and dump the body.
So we did that too.
Which means Anwar
and his friends developed -
- a new, more efficient system
for exterminating communists.
It was more humane, less sadistic,
and avoided excessive violence...
But you also just wiped them out!
- How many people did he kill?
- About 1000.
How can he sleep?
Isn't he haunted?
- A lot of them went crazy.
- Yeah.
- No, they got rich.
Rich from stealing.
But killing all those people
made them crazy too.
But what’s the special meaning
of this film for young people?
Young people must remember
their history.
They must never forget.
What's more...
God must be against communists.
Yes. God hates communists!
That's why he's made
this film so beautiful!
According to General Sarwo Edhie
2.5 million communists were killed.
Why haven’t the victims'
children ever tried to take revenge?
It's not that they don't want
to take revenge. They can't!
Because we'd exterminate them all!
This is the only film shoot to be
visited by a government minister.
He's coming here just for you,
to motivate and support you!
You should be proud!
The whole world will see this.
London, England!
Forget Jakarta.
Jakarta is nothing!
Wow! All the killers are here!
Just improvise
and express your anger.
Scream, 'Crush the communists!'
- Crush the communists!
- Wipe them out!
Okay let’s try it.
Attack on Kampung Kolam. Take 1.
Don't let any communists escape!
Kill! Kill!
Kill the communists!
Slaughterthem!
Are you ready to attack?
Take no prisoners!
Destroy them all!
Burn down their houses!
Kill the communists!
Chop them up!
Exterminate them to their roots!
Chop off their heads
Burn them! Kill them all!
Kill! Kill!
Cut! Cut! Cut!
Joshua and crew, now I'm speaking
as a leader of Pancasila Youth.
What we’ve just shown is not
characteristic of our organization.
We shouldn't look brutal,
like we want to drink people's blood.
That's dangerous
for our organization's image.
But we must exterminate
the communists.
We must totally
wipe them out-
- but in a more humane way.
What we just filmed,
I felt awful...
Especially with my image
right in the middle of it!
OK, Joshua?
This is the true story
That's what we all want, right?
Sure. Sure.
You know, what we just filmed...
Don't erase it! Use it to show
how ferocious we can be!
In fact, we can even be worse!
So, think of it as
a simulation of our rage -
- if anyone disturbs our country
If they're pretty I'd rape them all.
Especially back then,
when we were the law.
Fuck 'em!
Fuck the shit
out of everyone I meet.
Are you a communist woman?
What are you hiding there?
That’s the spirit!
Especially if you get one
who's only 14 years old.
Delicious!
I'd say it's gonna be hell for you
but heaven on earth for me.
Keep struggling.
No one wants to be tortured, right?
If you can save yourself,
you should.
And if you can
run away go ahead!
Attention everybody!
While you're acting,
remember the cameras!
Ladies, think positively
if you think positively -
- your acting will be great
and the scene will succeed.
Positive! Think positive!
Kill them all!
Catch him!
Cut! Cut! Cut!
Bakti! Bring water!
Let her rest.
Febby your acting was great.
But stop crying.
You're embarassing me.
Film stars only cry for a moment.
What I regret... Honestly I never
expected it would look this awful.
My friends kept telling me
to act more sadistic -
- but then I saw
the women and children.
Imagine those children's future.
They've been tortured...
Now their houses
will be burned down...
What future do they have?
They will curse us
for the rest of their lives.
This was so very very very..
When you say 'karma'...
What does it mean for you?
What are you afraid of?
Karma is like a law of nature.
A law straight from God.
Imagine, in all this darkness -
- it's like we're living
at the end of the world.
We look around...
There's only darkness.
It's so very terrifying.
Hit the table.
To frighten me.
Start by hitting the table. Hard.
Trying to ban American films
in Indonesia?
What are you trying to do?
Shut up!
- What are you trying to do?
- Please, sir..
Don't get friendly with me!
We're not friends!
Answer the questions!
Hurry up
or I'll break your legs!
Dana, ask!
Besides Titi Kuning,
where else are you active?
- Hamparan Perak.
- A real big communist.
Quick! Don't waste our time!
Lift up your hand
or I'll cut it off.
Hey look! Gold!
Take off your watch.
Put it on the table.
What else do you have?
A ring? Gold?
Talk or I cut your face.
- Talk.
- Tell us everything!
- Please, don't...
- I won't, but you talk!
Talk...
Cut.
Okay let's do it.
I place this medal
around your neck.
- Are you alright?
- I can't do that again.
Get him some water.
Have some water.
We shoved wood in their anus
until they died.
We crushed their necks
with wood. We hung them.
We strangled them with wire.
We cut off their heads.
We ran them over with cars.
We were allowed to do it.
And the proof is, we murdered
people and were never punished.
The people we killed... There's
nothing to be done about it.
They have to accept it.
Maybel Im just trying to make
myself feel better but it works:
I've never felt guilty, never been
depressed, never had nightmares.
For executing me
and sending me to heaven.
I thank you a thousand
times, for everything.
This is great, Joshua.
This is very good.
I never imagined
I could make something so great.
One thing that makes me
so proud -
- is how the waterfall
expresses such deep feelings!
You know the scene
where I'm strangled with wire?
- Do you have it here?
- Where you're strangled?
Please put it on.
Yan?
I want him to watch this...
- Yan?
- He's in bed.
Yan, watch the scene
where grandpa is tortured and killed.
Ami, come see grandpa beaten up
and bleeding.
But this is too violent.
Watch this.
Grandpa gets beaten up.
Turn up the volume.
But this is too violent, Anwar
Are you sure?
Yes, it's fine.
Will you be scared, Yan?
This is only a film...
Look at that.
Grandpa looks so sad,
doesn't he, Yan?
So scary
it's so sad, isn't it?
That's your grandpa.
That's grandpa being
beaten up by the fat guy.
Grandpa's head is smashed.
Did the people I tortured feel
the way I do here?
I can feel what the people
I tortured felt.
Because here my dignity
has been destroyed...
...and then fear comes,
right there and then.
All the terror suddenly
possessed my body
it surrounded me,
and possessed me.
Actually the people you tortured
felt far worse-
- because you know it's only a film.
They knew they were being killed.
But I can feel it, Josh.
Really I feel it.
Or have I sinned?
I did this to so many people, Josh.
Is it all coming back to me?
I really hope it won't.
I don't want it to, Josh.
This is where we tortured and
killed the people we captured.
I know it was wrong -
- but I had to do it.
This is...
This is one of the easiest
ways to take a human life.
And this...
This was used to take away..
...the human beings we killed.
Because without this...
...maybe people would know.