(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN SOBBING)
HAPPINESS: I've always wondered, when
a butterfly leaves the safety of its cocoon,
does it realize how beautiful it has become?
Or does it still just see itself
as a caterpillar?
(BELL RINGS)
When I was a kid,
I knew the secret to a happy life.
Play by the rules, work hard in school,
and if you work hard in school,
then your reward is more school.
And after more school,
then you're given the best
that life has to offer,
a job, and money, and a future,
filled with the unending singular pursuit
of more.
It's going up a quarter of a point.
Block it now.
And this is what I was living for.
My happy life.
(LAUGHING)
I envied those who never questioned it. Me?
I needed a way out.
- The usual.
- Sure.
I have...
(STUTTERING)
Here's something that I was hoping
that you might...
You might take a little... A look at.
- Is there something the matter?
- No.
Your track record is perfect.
And with your stock market luck,
we could... You could...
Maybe you should invest more.
No. Small amounts. Just keep it simple.
It's just... You just...
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
How do you do it?
Sometimes risking everything
is the only choice you have.
But you don't seem to be
taking any sort of chance.
I wasn't talking about me.
I'm sorry. You're right.
This is none of my business.
Please, don't concern yourself with me
piggybacking on any of your stocks.
I would never do that.
I'm not worried.
I know for a fact
that you would never do that.
(SCREAMS)
HAPPINESS: So, where does
change come from?
And how do we recognize it
when it happens?
...and she's whining about it, saying,
"No, please. It hurts."
- Thanks for the tip. I owe you one.
- Yeah. Back-door girl.
All right. Hey, that was my cousin.
We are on for tonight.
All right, now, listen up.
(COUGHING)
All right. This place is the real fucking deal.
Back rooms and everything,
so do not fuck around.
We go in, we make our bets,
we collect, we get the fuck out.
The fix is in,
he's got the winning horse's name.
And get this, shitheads,
odds are eight to fucking one.
- Yeah.
- BART: It's a sure thing.
All right, we meet downstairs at 7:00.
And keep your mouths fucking shut,
especially you, motherfucker.
- Jeez.
- Don't worry. We're cool.
Hey! The winning horse? What's the name?
Get this.
Butterfly.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
You want somethin'?
I want to put some money down
on Butterfly.
In the next race.
Can I use this?
Sure. How much?
10.
$10,000, please.
(PENCIL SCRATCHING)
Wait.
20. 20.
Maybe... How about 50?
You got that much scratch, huh, mister?
No, 'cause if you don't,
you can always borrow something
from the house.
Thank you.
I'm gonna have to see your driver's license.
Hey, Louie, file this, will you?
Okay, 50 Gs on Butterfly.
(CHUCKLES)
(TRUMPET PLAYING)
ANNOUNCER ON TV:
The horses are in the gate.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(BELL RINGING)
And they're off!
Jello out in front by a half a length.
Alpha and Santana right behind him,
followed by Shooting Star, Perpetrator,
Butterfly and Silky April.
On the inside, Alpha making a move.
He's neck and neck with Jello.
Wait! Here comes Butterfly
- at a surprise dash.
- Come on, baby.
This is unexpected! He's passing Alpha.
Passing Jello. Butterfly takes the lead!
- Around the turn they go. It's Butterfly...
- Yes!
... followed by Alpha and Jello.
- Oh, my goodness! He's down!
- What the fuck?
Butterfly has rolled,
and there goes Alpha with him!
- What a terrible accident...
- Fuck!
...ladies and gentlemen!
And it's Jello across the finish line.
Jello wins.
(GRUNTING)
PARKS: What do you guys want me to do?
THUG: Shut up!
How did you find this place?
How did you... I'm talking to you!
It's a simple fucking question!
Okay, here we go.
(GROANS)
- Are you working for the cops?
- No.
- I was just trying to gamble. That's all.
- You wanted to gamble?
Nobody comes to this place
because they feel like a little gambling!
Please, I'm sorry, Del. I wasn't going to run.
I was going to go...
PARKS: Fuck.
God damn.
You bet on Butterfly.
Yes, I did.
You knew about the fix.
- No. I didn't... I...
- Look,
don't lie to me. How?
Come on! Come on! Come on!
How did you know about the fix?
I overheard my coworkers, and I...
I like butterflies.
- You like what?
- Butterflies.
- I like butterflies.
He likes butterflies. The horse's name
is Butterfly, so he comes here,
and he bets on a fix.
- You know why they call me Fingers?
- No.
Well, Mr. Parks here knows
why they call me Fingers.
Because two weeks ago,
he also came by because
he also felt like gambling.
Hey, I wasn't going to run.
I was gonna get the money from my sister!
I was gonna go pick it up!
He lost. And instead of paying me
what he owes me,
what does he do?
- He tries to run.
- I wasn't trying to run.
I swear to God!
What is it with you guys?
You come here, you make a stupid mistake,
and now what?
Now I got to be the bad guy? Is that it?
That my job?
I can't enjoy the fucking opera?
I got to come here, and be a bad guy?
You think I enjoy this?
- You think I enjoy this?
- I don't... I don't... I don't know.
Well, I don't enjoy it. It's guys like you,
and you, Mr. Parks.
(SIGHS)
You know, you just leave me no choice.
No. You do have a choice.
My sister has the money! I...
No! No!
(SCREAMING)
Fucking no!
Oh, fuck! God! You son of a bitch!
(PARKS SOBBING)
You got two weeks to pay me the money.
Each day you're late, I cut a finger.
Going somewhere?
You.
- But I...
- You're packing.
No, I'm not.
Sit down.
You work for Fingers, don't you?
(GRUNTING)
You have a nice home. A good job.
You're good at it.
And you just threw it all away. Why?
- Please, I don't know.
- Why did you do this?
(PANTING)
I don't know. I was stupid. I wasn't thinking.
- Why did you do this? Why did you do this?
- Please.
Stop it!
- Why did you do this?
- I don't know!
- Yes, you do.
- No, I don't!
- You do!
- No!
- Tell me!
I... I...
(MUMBLING)
(SIGHS)
Here, take it.
Go on.
It's all I can give you.
Wait.
What am I supposed to do with this?
I don't know anymore.
Wait.
Please.
HAPPINESS: Sometimes, being totally fucked
can be a liberating experience.
Today, I see things in a new light.
I see the money move through this place
like it does every day.
I see the cameras that will monitor
my every move.
I see the panic button that the tellers
will push, alerting the police.
And when that button's pushed,
I know that the police will arrive
no earlier than four minutes,
which gives me plenty of time,
assuming I've already planned
my escape route,
which I have.
And finally, I see a strap bag
with a lead-lined pouch, filled with money.
No one else will see it.
But I'll know it's there.
(MEEKLY) Everybody, freeze.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
Freeze.
(SCREAMING)
Everybody, freeze!
(CHUCKLES)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(THUDDING)
Dude, that was crazy. Are you okay?
Are you okay?
(SIRENS WAILING)
(HORNS BLARING)
POLICEMAN: Let's go! Move, move, move!
(SIREN WAILING)
(HAPPINESS SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
(HELICOPTER ENGINE HUMMING)
POLICEMAN OVER MEGAPHONE: This is
the police. You are surrounded.
Do not attempt to run,
or make any sudden moves.
Drop your weapon, raise your hands,
and walk forward to the south end
of the roof.
Put the bag and the gun down!
This is your last warning.
Drop your weapon,
or you will be fired upon!
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
Call the... We need to get him on...
Sir, sir, can you tell me
what happened to you?
- I don't know.
- Sir,
can you remember what happened to you?
(LAUGHING) I don't know. You tell me.
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
PLEASURE: As far back as I can remember,
I've never lost a fight.
(DOOR OPENS)
- Come on, Markie, hurry up!
- I can't do it anymore! Can't run anymore!
I didn't fight well because I was
big or fast or mean.
I fought well because I could see the future.
The problem with seeing the future
is that it only comes in bits and pieces,
like a reflection in a broken mirror.
After a while, though,
it's like playing a video game in your head.
Do it enough times,
and you know all the moves.
(GRUNTING)
Look out!
(PANTING)
But no matter what, the future is written.
Markie, say something, come on!
I can't change that.
Come on. Markie. Markie! Markie! Markie!
And sometimes,
the things you can't change,
they end up changing you.
(GRUNTING)
MAN: Please, wait! Wait!
Fingers, he'll listen to you.
Talk to him! Please?
I've seen what happens to you.
Nothing could change that.
No!
(COUGHING)
Please, no!
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
- It's done.
- FINGERS: Good.
I need you to pick somebody up
at the airport.
I know.
See, my dad's got business locked tight
back home,
but you know, I want to see the world,
you know.
And my Uncle Fingers, he's all about family
and sharing the wealth, you know?
You know how he got that
nickname, Fingers?
Because people do whatever he wants,
and all he has to do is just snap his fingers.
Man, that's a great fucking nickname, man.
Just fucking snap, and snap
his fucking fingers and shit, yeah.
You know, seeing my uncle is cool and all,
but I'll tell you, I came here for one thing,
and one thing only. Pussy.
(TONY LAUGHS)
TONY: You know what the fuck I'm saying?
I'm going to fuck tonight!
(TRISTA SINGING ON STEREO)
Hey, hey, hey! I heard my favorite uncle
was here, huh? Come on!
- How you doing?
- Good.
- How are you, Tony? Good to see you.
- Great to see you...
That's the boss's nephew.
Nigga, what?
Look at this fucking thing. This is huge!
What's he like?
- Fuck, I mean, this is just like... Fuck.
- Articulate.
My men taking good care of you?
Oh, yeah, yeah. We've been chatting it up.
We're going to check this town out.
- Good.
- Yeah.
- Young man's gotta change his oil.
Listen to me.
Your dad wants me to pop your cherry,
show you the ropes.
Now, there's going to be plenty of time
for dick-waving,
but we need to make time for...
- Business.
- Exactly.
No joking around. Okay. Good.
You want to take Tony out
on your rounds tonight,
show him the city, what we do?
Start his education,
keep you company? Okay?
- Of course.
- All right, then.
Keep your ass out of trouble.
Remember the last time.
Yeah, yeah, hey, hey, no lingerie. I swear.
I promise, huh?
It's funny now, all right?
Okay, go. Get out of here. Go outside.
I got some business to discuss.
I'll see you later.
Kid's a fucking mess.
Just try to keep him out of trouble.
Maybe he'll learn a thing or two.
But, now,
it's time for business.
Listen to this.
(TRISTA SINGING ON STEREO)
(FINGERS EXCLAIMS)
- What do you think?
- It's fine.
- Excuse me?
"It's fine." It's fucking great.
What are you talking about?
I don't know much about music.
A client of mine, who paid his debt to me...
Part of the deal
was her management contract.
This is her first CD. The sales?
Through the roof. Very promising.
I'm sorry, I still don't follow you.
How long have we been doing this?
Too long. I'm tired of chasing money.
I'm tired of teaching lessons to lowlifes
who won't pay.
I've always hoped for more.
For both of us.
This girl's our way out.
I'm sure she's going to be pissed off
when she finds out I'm her new manager,
but I'll take care of that.
You just keep an eye on her.
Yeah.
What is it? What do you see?
Nothing.
You see something.
I don't see anything.
What do you mean? She has no future?
No, she has a future.
I just can't see it.
You don't talk much, do you, huh?
Busy thinking about the future, I bet.
Yeah, my uncle fucking told me.
He said you can see the future and shit.
Says you're fucking money. Casinos,
stock market... He said you know it all.
You know what it reminds me of?
You ever see that movie Krull?
All right, there's this fucking Cyclops in it,
and the way that he got that way
was he traded one of his eyes
to see the future.
Okay, but long story fucking crazy short...
...all ended up happening
was the evil warlord tricked that fucker,
and the only future he could see
was his own death.
Man, that shit would suck. Yeah.
Fuck me.
So, what's the plan tonight, my man?
Are we going to get
some fucking drinks first,
or is it just
- straight to the pussy?
- Tonight we work.
(LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He's not here. Come back next week.
He's in the hospital.
Getting a mole removed.
Come back next week!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SCREAMS)
- Hey! Stop!
- How do you like that, huh?
Bet you don't! Yeah.
I told you next week!
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
You pay up now, old bag.
Otherwise, we're going to
fuck some more shit up, huh?
Hey! Stop, little bastard! Come on!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(TONY YELPS)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
Dude! Dude!
(PANTING)
Why didn't you help me out when I was
getting fucked by Moby Dick in there, huh?
Come on, what do you think?
You want me to go back?
Stomp that bitch, man?
'Cause I'm a fucking savage,
you know what I'm saying?
Look at this fucking hat.
Look at this shit, man.
(MAN GRUNTS)
(WHEEZING)
(WHOOPING)
- Where's the money?
- Where's the fucking money, huh?
I don't have it!
(SCREAMING IN SPANISH)
(WOMAN GRUNTS)
- You bleeding?
- I don't know.
Get up.
I'm going to cut you a break.
I'm coming back next week, all right?
I need you to get that money.
I want to make sure Fingers gets it.
'Cause if he doesn't,
he's going to get one of these.
Yeah?
- You don't want that.
- No.
- Okay? I'll see you next week.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- All right? I'm sorry about the missus.
(MAN GROANS)
Let's go.
Dude!
(TONY EXCLAIMS)
Man, I've never seen anything like that, man.
Fucking cold, merciless shit back there.
I mean, you knew that crazy bitch
was coming, didn't you? You...
What's it like? I mean, what do you see?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
You enjoy this shit, man?
Fucking people up like that?
Sometimes it's part of the job.
Yeah, but do you enjoy it?
'Cause you know what I think?
I think you do, man. I think you love it.
Yeah, you do, 'cause
otherwise, you'd just predict the lottery,
and get the fuck out of here, right?
- Right, right?
- I can't.
What do you mean you can't?
A man does anything he wants.
I can't do that.
I can't do that
because I haven't been shown.
The moment I see it, then I'll move on.
So, you could, like...
You could, like, fuck any girl,
and know you ain't getting the clap
for sure, sure, huh?
(LAUGHS)
I mean, safe sex is a beautiful thing.
So I've heard.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Dude, this is just what my dream house
looks like. I want a place just like this,
with chicks, and music,
and chicks fucking each other,
while some midget chick sucks my balls.
Why didn't we come here first?
Lot of ass for an old guy.
JIYOUNG: Hello, boys.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
It's a pleasure to see you. As always.
Jiyoung, this is Tony, Fingers' nephew.
Oh!
Hi, how you doing?
Hi. I love your uncle. He's such a sweet man.
Have you had something to drink?
No, I'm actually on a bit of a schedule
right now, but you know...
- We got a room or...
- We don't have time to stay.
You always say that, but I know it's not true.
Whatever you want, just ask.
Hey, hey. Baby, baby.
Ladies, Tony's not that easy.
Let's get high and naked.
Where's the fucking room?
- That old man up there...
- He and his men are regulars.
They don't even bring their guns.
- He has a gun.
- Just him. No one else.
You pay for Fingers' protection.
It's worth every penny.
You know you're always welcome to stay.
I don't entertain anymore.
Unless I choose to.
Can you do me a favor?
Anything.
Tell Tony that
I'll be back after my rounds.
Of course.
PLEASURE: When you can see the future,
you think you're capable of changing it.
But you're just a witness
to coming moments,
unable to help, even if you wanted to.
And maybe you don't.
Sometimes you think
you're supposed to learn something...
Come on, man! Give me some!
... about patience or distance.
But in the end, it's all about discipline.
Seeing things you don't always want to.
And just moving on.
After a while, things become easier.
Routine keeps your mind from wandering.
You begin to accept things as they are.
Every man has his destiny.
You can't escape it.
Even if you can see it coming.
(TONY CHUCKLES)
(TONY MOANS)
TONY: Where you going, baby?
(SNICKERING)
Hi.
(MAN GRUNTS)
(GIRL GIGGLING)
Hey, come on, baby.
Come on, get the fuck up.
No!
- You're in the wrong room!
- No!
Don't fucking touch me!
Hey, come on, baby, come on.
You don't want to do this...
- Don't tell me what to do!
- My bad.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
We were having a very nice time,
so go away!
- Fuck! Take it easy.
- No! No!
Come on!
Petrovich!
- Petrovich.
- Drop the fucking gun.
No, no, mate, you got this all wrong, man.
This isn't my fault.
- The gun went off by itself!
- Drop the fucking gun!
It's not my fucking fault, man!
The fucking gun just went off!
Then there's nothing to worry about.
Don't fucking come
any fucking closer, dude.
I'll fucking use this, man.
I'll fucking... Don't...
Get the fuck back, man.
You're going to shoot us all?
PLEASURE: Hey!
(GRUNTING)
(CRASHING)
Let's go.
(MAN SCREAMING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
I did nothing! I did nothing!
I did nothing!
(MEN SHOUTING)
- What are we doing, man? We have the gun.
- No. No killing today.
Fuck!
(PANTING)
What the fuck you waiting for, huh?
PLEASURE: So, why all this effort when
you know what's going to happen?
Will watching a person's fate
give it purpose?
Or is it just the muted feeling of watching
a movie when you know how it ends?
(MEN SHOUTING)
And then something happens
that I will never forget.
Come on!
I'm wrong.
For the first time ever, fate takes a detour,
and I glimpse something strange and new.
(GRUNTING)
Run!
A future where anything can happen.
It's a beautiful thing.
And the feeling it gives me
is as close as I've ever felt
to pleasure.
(GROANS)
(COUGHS)
Sir, sir, can you tell me
what happened to you?
(LAUGHING) I don't know. You tell me.
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
(WOMAN CHATTERING OVER PA)
There's my boy.
I appreciate what you did for Tony.
How come you didn't see it coming?
Don't worry about it. Just get better.
We need you back.
I need you back.
The guys that did this to you,
I'm going to take care of it.
'Cause nobody treats my boy this way.
Nobody.
WOMAN OVER PA: This is a pre-boarding
call for flight 62...
Chaos, mayhem, panic in the streets.
My work here is done.
Um...
Thanks.
And don't worry, you know, pussy's...
Pussy's still going to line up for you.
Chicks love scars.
It's like a road map of the soul, you know?
Hey.
PLEASURE: It's a new day, and I have
no idea what to expect.
I can change someone's life if I feel like it,
make it worse,
or better.
It's up to me.
A girl with a future I can't see enters my life.
On the same day, my visions fail me
for the first time.
There are some people
that believe in coincidences.
I am not one of them.
INTERVIEWER: This has got to get old, huh?
Every 10 minutes,
you got another guy like me
asking you the same three questions.
TRISTA: It's part of my job.
Well, I promise you that I'm going to
try to make it interesting, okay?
I'm all about asking questions
that no one else asks.
- No one?
- No one.
You gotta trust me, okay?
It's going to be fun.
You're sweet.
- DIRECTOR: Forty seconds.
- Got you.
- Thanks, Danny.
- Frank's here.
Where?
What does he want?
He needs to change your schedule.
Some kind of meeting.
And cameras rolling!
So, Trista, thank you for sitting down
with me today.
Oh, for you, anything.
So, your debut album, it heralds you
as this fantastic new talent.
Is there pressure to try to live up
to the hype?
It's not hype.
You know, I'm not just a pretty face.
I have something to say.
I'm just so excited
that my fans want to hear it.
Okay, but what is it about you
that sets you apart from all the other acts
that are out there today?
I think it's my musical influences.
- You know, if you go back...
- Okay, what I mean, you're young,
you're pretty, you sing, you dance.
Why should we care, right?
I mean, what is it about you
that's so special?
- What makes me special?
- Yeah.
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
Do you mean, like, what makes me
better than everyone else?
No. Not better. Just...
Deserving.
Um...
Well, I...
- What is he doing?
- I have a really rare blood type.
Don't worry.
- How about that?
- What is he doing?
It's okay. She's doing fine.
It's called Kp A-B. Almost no one has it.
That's my gift from God.
Well, that, and I sing and dance well enough
to have millions of fans.
Uh-oh.
It's more like
hundreds of thousands. Right?
Whatever. Doesn't make a difference.
I have fans that chant my name
wherever I go.
Come on, Trista, I mean...
They're not even chanting
your real name, right?
What?
I mean, can't you at least tell us
your real name?
I'll never tell.
How about my name? We've met like this
now three times, three different interviews.
You say you'll do anything for me.
What's my name?
- We're done. We're done. We're done!
- Wait, wait. What, what?
Take it easy. What's the problem?
What did I do?
You.
Danny. Danny.
That son of a bitch
is going to be wiping asses
for a living by the time I'm through with him.
Just take me home.
We can't leave yet. We have a meeting.
Are you kidding me?
Don't worry. It's right on stage 10.
It'll be fast.
Okay, now, flash Papa Fingers
those beautiful blue eyes.
Randall's got nothing on you, kid.
Fingers! What do you think?
Living the dream, huh?
You ruined my shot, Frank.
It's a pleasure meeting you.
Fingers.
It's cute. I guess I'm supposed to ask
why they call you that?
I guess it's because when I talk,
I use my hands a lot.
Sorry.
- You're Trista, right?
- Yeah.
Now that we're friends,
let's get down to business.
Sure. Trista, things are going great.
Single's getting play,
the album's starting to sell,
the video is getting a lot of air time,
but there's a big difference
between having a video on MTV
and being an artist who headlines arenas.
What Frank is trying to say is that you need
someone to take you to the next level.
Someone who's going to open doors.
Someone who's strong.
- You're quitting?
- No.
No. I'm not quitting. I'm not...
I'm stepping aside.
A person of his influence
can make you a superstar.
He asks for things,
and people give them. Gladly.
I'm so excited to be working with you,
and completely committed to your success.
And all I ask is you commit to me.
And that's our deal. That's our promise
that we make to each other.
If anybody gets in our way,
- I'll take care of it.
- I don't fucking believe this.
- Get me a car.
- Trista, baby...
Oh, screw you, Frank!
That didn't go so well.
It went fine.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Tomorrow, we get to go shopping
for a new manager.
Trista, there are contracts.
Fuck contracts!
I think I should go.
(TRISTA WHOOPS)
Can you stay with her?
Sure.
Be back tomorrow.
- I'm tired.
- Yeah.
- Do you love me, Danny?
- Course I do.
I love you, too.
Leave the light on, Daddy.
I don't like the dark.
Daddy.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
My little girl's not nervous,
is she, huh? Come on.
Don't worry. After school,
I'll be right here waiting for you, okay?
Come on, let's go.
(HORN BLARING)
(GASPING) Daddy?
(TRISTA SCREAMS)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Danny!
Danny?
Your friends are not going to help you.
Nobody's going to help you.
Nobody but me.
Your manager has drained
all your accounts trying to pay me back.
And that little piece of paper that owns you
is the only thing that's keeping
his ass alive.
Now, what does that mean?
It means that you... You have nothing.
And you are nothing unless I say you are.
And you are going on the road.
And you're staying on the road
until I see profit.
And if I ever have to come back here again,
we're going to have
a totally different conversation.
You understand me?
(COUGHS)
Cheers.
Thanks.
- Don't you think you've had enough?
- No.
I don't think it's nearly enough.
It can't be as bad as you think.
You must get tired of not knowing
what the fuck you're talking about.
Where were you anyway
when Frank was fucking me over?
Were you in on it?
Did you help him?
No. Of course not. I'm your friend.
I can't remember.
How much does being my friend pay again?
Allison, wait... Wait, wait!
BARTENDER: Hey, who's paying
for the drinks?
TRISTA: I didn't mean it. Come on!
I'm sorry.
- Trista!
- Trista! Oh, my God! Trista!
Allison! Allison!
Wait! God damn it! Come on!
Oh, come on. I'm sorry.
- Are you Trista?
- What?
- No.
- Yes, you are.
- No, no, no.
- Hey, can I have an autograph?
- Sure.
- To Jake the hottie.
- Yeah, sure. Cute.
- MAN 1: Trista, my sister loves you!
- I love your sister.
- MAN 2: You looked great in your last movie.
- Thank you. Thanks.
- MAN 3: You were the best, too.
- Thank you.
- WOMAN: Trista! Trista!
- Stop!
God, that fucking hurts.
Hey, how about a picture?
- Get a picture of this.
- No! Stop!
(TRISTA SHOUTING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
I love you, Trista!
We love you!
(TRISTA SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
(HORN BLARING)
(TRISTA YELPS)
- TRISTA: So, I can leave?
- Of course.
What are you going to do?
Where you gonna go?
(SIGHS)
I don't know. I mean,
I have shows coming up.
Fingers owns you now.
He'll work you until you're used up,
and throw you away. It's just what he does.
What are you suggesting I do?
Well, if Fingers knows that you've run,
then he'll hunt you down.
But, you know, the one place
that he won't look is...
Is right here.
I could get some money together,
and you could...
You could get far enough away
that not even Fingers could touch you.
Why are you helping me?
I don't know.
I just want to.
For as long as I can remember,
I've never let myself
want anything.
Stay away from the windows,
and, you know, help yourself to anything
in the kitchen.
Otherwise, don't touch anything.
(DOOR SHUTS)
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANS)
You okay?
Yeah. I'm fine. It's just... Just work.
What did you do today?
I looked for you.
I like what you've done with the place.
I figured if I was going to be here
for a while...
Who's that in the picture with you?
It's Markie.
- Are you guys close?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
We were. He's...
He died.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
What happened?
I saw it coming,
and couldn't do anything to stop it.
I know how that feels.
Makes you feel like you never want
to feel anything
ever again.
- There.
- That's good.
It's just what I need.
More scars.
Did you know that
scars are the road map to the soul?
Yes.
PLEASURE: It's been a couple weeks, and I
was thinking that maybe we could take a trip.
Tomorrow?
- You mean we're leaving?
- Yeah.
What's in your hand?
That's nothing.
It's just something I think I saw.
- It's not what you think, really.
- What do you have to do?
Don't worry about it. It's for a friend.
(DOOR SHUTS)
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hello?
- FINGERS: Who is this?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
Piece of shit!
Three weeks we've been looking
for this tart. Three weeks!
Asking around, busting heads,
you by my side, and all this time,
she was sitting right here with you!
You'd think when that scumbag
Frank begged for death,
you would have shown some mercy
on the poor bastard,
and told me the truth, but no!
You just stood there and watched.
You're a cold piece of work, my friend.
A cold piece of fucking work.
Oh.
What's this?
You putting some aside,
take your little lady on vacation?
Huh?
Is that yours? I don't think so!
Leave me alone. Go.
What's the matter with you?
Back in the day,
you would have saw this coming.
You're losing your touch.
(WHIMPERING)
Did you say something to me?
You trying to say something to me?
You put me in this situation!
You think I'm a bad man?
I'm talking to you.
I'm not a bad man.
I want what everybody wants.
(GROANS)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(SNIFFLING)
I tried to give you everything.
And what happened?
What did you do with it?
But that wasn't enough for you!
It wasn't enough! You wanted more.
You have all the love in the world,
but that's not enough for you,
so you took my friend!
And you turned him against me!
And then what?
You're a selfish little shit!
I guess...
You don't know what you got until it's gone.
(SOBBING)
Oh, my God.
(WHISPERING) Tell me.
Tell you what?
Your
real name.
(TIRES SCREECH)
- Hi.
- Gate's closed.
- No.
- You gotta go around the front.
You gotta let me in.
- No. Cool it.
- Please, please. No, you don't understand.
- I'm a doctor.
- You gotta go around front.
Someone...
Someone is going to die.
I've got to see Trista.
This is the last time I'm going to tell you.
Cool it!
I got to see Trista!
(GRUNTING)
Come on, come on, man! I'm a doctor!
All right, she is going to fucking die,
and it's going to be your fault!
LOVE: Everyone has a purpose.
Sometimes a person lives their entire life
without knowing what theirs is.
Not me. I knew when I was 10.
My purpose is to love the right person
wholly and completely.
When I was 10,
that person was Heidi Fontel.
But when Heidi's father moved
her family away,
I was sure I would love again, and soon.
I was wrong.
I met Gina in med school.
We were best friends.
My roommate, Henry, said she was the kind
of girl you waited to marry.
But I waited too long.
She married Henry right out of college.
And I was best man.
And all these years later, I guess I still am.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
So, where were we?
Henry was trying to make a point.
Henry's trying... He's trying to make a point.
- About you joining him in plastics?
- What else?
Bob is rich. That's not right.
And Derek. Derek barely graduated,
and Derek is rich as shit!
It's not all about the money.
Hey, you put in the time, you do the work,
you ought to be compensated.
- I'm doing fine.
- A lot of folks are doing fine.
She's doing fine. Oh, that's right.
She's the waitress.
Everyone else I know?
- Rich as shit!
- I'm not.
But you're doing genius research
which one day will lead
to an amazing discovery.
- Maybe.
- And that will lead to patents,
and now we're talking stupid rich.
There's nothing wrong with her trying
to make people's lives better.
No. It's fantastic. I love her for it.
I make people's lives better.
(LAUGHING)
I do. Come on.
Okay, I admit it.
The boob jobs and the Botox,
that's what pays for my amazing car.
Okay, but consider this. A girl is born
with a nose that could kill on sight.
There's no prom day for this girl,
no shy first kiss.
She gets in an accident, sure,
you patch her up fine.
But eventually, this girl's going to write
a goodbye letter to her cat,
and throw herself off a rooftop.
The same girl, she comes to me,
I do a little of my magic,
and, my friend, that letter never gets written.
I have saved a life.
Hey, I saved a life today.
Maybe I did, too. We'll never know.
But either way, I'm going to sleep tonight
in one big motherfucking house.
I gotta pee.
(CHUCKLING)
- My husband.
- Your husband.
- So, how are the snakes?
- They're great.
My hours are killing me, though.
You feeling all right?
I'm exhausted. Been fighting a cold, too.
- You should come see me tomorrow.
- I don't want to bother you.
That's impossible. You know that, right?
Take care.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Jesus.
Think about what I said.
Oh, man, thank you.
Are you this way?
- No, I'm actually parked out back.
- I'm sorry.
- You're going to be okay?
- Yeah, I'm used to this.
- Love you.
- Love you, too.
GINA: Bring me the vial.
WESLEY: All right.
Yeah. Here we go.
You're going to cure hemophilia, little guy.
Dr. Sweet?
Mmm-hmm.
This isn't a rattler.
Maybe you want to break out the gear.
Don't worry.
(GINA SCREAMS)
- What do we got?
- Snake bite.
Let me take a look. Oh, my God.
They sent us the wrong anti-venom!
- She needs a transfusion now!
- Gina?
Hey, Gina. Gina. Can you hear me?
Gina, hi. Hi.
- Come on, wake up now.
- My blood...
What?
- What did she say?
- I'm not sure.
Something about her blood.
Get her blood type. What bit her?
- A Russell viper.
- All right, tell me about this snake.
You don't understand. It's already
in her heart. She needs a transfusion.
- Get me that blood type now!
- She's got 24 hours!
(PANTING)
- Okay.
- Doctor, I have her blood type.
What? What the hell is this?
- The lab said it's extremely rare.
- All right. Do we have any of this in stock?
- I've never even seen it come through here.
- All right. Check again.
- No, Doctor...
- Just do it!
Henry? Henry? Did Gina keep
any of her own blood in storage?
All right, look. Listen, she's...
She's been bitten.
Hello! Can you check again, please?
It's very rare. Next week is too late.
Thailand? Please don't put me on hold.
Please don't put me on hold.
Please... Damn!
We don't have it, Doctor. I checked
the computer files, but it's useless!
It's not in there.
We don't have her blood type!
Doctor! Stop it, Doctor!
We don't have the blood type. That's why...
Nick!
(ALARM RINGING)
- Damn it!
- Wait! What are you doing?
No, no, no. Wait, wait.
You don't understand.
You've got to let me go!
You don't understand! She's going to die!
All right. All right, all right! All right!
I'm fine. I'm all right. Just let me go.
Let me go.
Okay, I'm fine. I'm all right.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm here live inside Palm Hill Studios,
where Trista has begun production
on her second music video.
Now, we're not allowed to take you
inside the actual shooting,
but while we're waiting, why don't we take
another look at a clip
from a recent interview
that had everybody wondering,
"Pop superstar or pop meltdown?"
- What makes me special?
- Yeah.
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
Do you mean, like, what makes me
better than everyone else?
No. Not better. Just...
Deserving.
I have a really rare blood type.
How about that?
A blood type?
Yeah, it's called Kp A-B.
Almost no one has it.
That's my gift from God.
(TIRES SKIDDING)
(HORNS BLARING)
Okay, I talked to the director.
I told him no more
than two full run-throughs of the song.
Thank you.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
You need some air?
- No, I think I can...
- I think you need some air.
Could everyone please back off?
She needs air!
Let's go, honey.
I mean it! Back off!
Let's go.
- (WHISPERING) Put this on.
- What's going on?
Your plane ticket and passport
are in the pocket.
- Hi.
- Gate's closed.
- No.
- You gotta go around the front.
You gotta let me in.
- No.
- Wait, I...
I'm a doctor.
Don't call anyone.
Just lay low for a little while.
Give me some time, and I'll make sure
that someone gets to you.
I'm a doctor!
(THUDDING)
All right, she is going to fucking die,
and it's going to be your fault!
She's going to fucking die!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Trista?
- Trista, wait! Wait!
- No, no, don't get near her! Get in!
- (SCREAMING) No, no, Gina...
- No!
- Let go of Allison! Help!
- Sorry, I'll explain later!
Trista! Wait! Wait! Wait!
(GRUNTING)
Trista? My God, Trista?
Trista. Trista, are you okay?
Oh, God! Trista.
Trista?
I pushed back your concert dates
and canceled your video shoot.
And I'm not mad at you.
Even though I know you tried to leave.
But I'm not mad at you.
When were you going to tell me?
- Tell you what?
- About the baby.
- I'm pregnant?
- Three weeks.
You didn't know?
It's gonna be okay.
I know what you're trying to do.
You want the whole world to love you,
and that's a dangerous fucking life.
And you can't do it alone.
But I'm gonna take care of you.
I'm gonna make that happen.
All your dreams will come true.
And to put that aside
would mean that he died for no reason.
It would mean you killed him for no reason.
No. We have a deal.
He got in the way. And I did my part.
Now it's time for you to do your part.
We both lost someone special.
Now it's time to move on.
I hate you.
Until the day I die, I will hate you.
(FINGERS SIGHS)
You can't keep the baby.
- What?
- You got concert dates and TV appearances.
You can't keep the baby.
- It's my baby.
- No one gets in our way!
No one!
You got a concert date in two weeks.
Gives us plenty of time to take care of this.
I'm gonna make the arrangements.
(SOBBING)
Wait, wait, wait. Wait.
No, no. No. Stop!
(PANTING)
Stop!
(SOBBING)
You're going to have to reach for me.
Please.
I need you.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(BEEPING)
- Hi.
- Hey.
Hey.
So,
you saved a life today.
You, too.
It's funny. It's the only thing that matters.
All the rest of it...
I'm glad your baby's okay.
Me, too.
- Thanks for the loaner.
- Sure.
- I'll get it back to you as soon as I can.
- Whatever.
You okay?
(SIGHS)
Yeah. I will be.
It's hard starting over.
You'll be fine.
So will you. Thank you.
I'm sorry, sir, but you can't go in there.
Sir! Sir, you're not allowed!
(SIGHS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(THUDDING)
Dude, that was crazy!
Are you okay?
(ENGINE ROARS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(SOBBING)
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMS)
(THUD)
Subtitles by LeapinLar