Set design: Chien Hsin
Wardrobe: Chu Shen Hsi
Make-up: Hsieh Tse Ming
Property: Wang Shun Chang,
Sing Won On
Lighting: Chung Hui Jan,
Script: Chang Tung Jo
Eggs.
- Tang Lung?
- Miss Chen Ching Hua?
Yes. Why didn`t you wait for me
instead of running around?
My plane was early. I was hungry,
so I went to get a bite to eat.
How is my uncle in Hong Kong?
He`s not very well,
so I`ve come to help.
He wrote saying someone would come
but he didn`t say who.
How can you help me?
Please, as we`re family,
I`ve come specially to help you.
You`ve come specially to help me?
Do you know what the problem is?
Tell me later.
First, can you tell me
where the toilet is?
It`s a Ferrari.
Mustang?
A flying horse?
Dad died last month
and left me the restaurant.
Uncle Wang and the others
are helping me at the moment.
Business wasn`t bad at the beginning,
but there`s a huge
business syndicate here.
They`re interested in our property
and want me to sell up.
There`s no sale without agreement.
If you refuse, what can they do?
Of course you`re right...
but these bastards won`t listen
to reason.
They`ll do anything
to get my property.
They hired some gangsters
to watch the place.
If a customer approaches,
they simply drive him away.
- What am I to do?
- Why not report it?
They disappear
as soon as the police arrive.
The police can`t be there
24 hours a day.
Business is getting worse by the day.
So many mouths to feed
and wages to pay.
Expenses are so great,
I don`t know what to do.
The threats are getting worse,
they`re demanding
an immediate answer.
So that`s why I wrote to my uncle.
I thought he`d send a lawyer, but...
These are trivial matters,
he asked me personally to help you.
Don`t worry, Miss Chen.
It`s no problem,
I can take care of it.
Look, that`s their headquarters
up there.
Make yourself at home.
Here.
I rent this place.
The guys live at the restaurant.
It`s more convenient this way.
There`s a spare room,
my sick workers stay there sometimes.
There`s no room at the restaurant,
so you can stay here for now.
Since you are a friend,
make yourself at home.
Let me know
if there`s anything you need.
- Where is your toilet, please?
- It`s over there.
Chinese New Year is coming up,
it`s a joyous time in Hong Kong.
Do they celebrate it in Rome?
I haven`t been to Hong Kong
in over 10 years.
I`m sure it has changed a lot.
Has the restaurant business
changed much in Hong Kong?
I live in the country,
I don`t go to town much.
I practise martial arts every day.
Straight punch, hooked punch,
curved kick, flying kick!
Restaurants?
They haven`t changed much.
Sit down.
Here`s the key for the flat.
These are the details
of the flat and restaurant.
The restaurant is nearby.
If you get lost,
show that card and any taxi driver
will bring you back here.
Taxi? They`re far too expensive here.
Don`t they have any buses?
Do you need money?
No, I brought some with me.
You`d better put it in the bank.
It`s safer that way.
No, it`s safer and easier
to carry it.
I won`t argue.
How much did you bring?
Not much.
Really, not very much.
I still say it`s safer in the bank.
Let`s go.
How much do you have? Let`s see it.
How much do you want in lira?
20 will do.
Foreign currencies have been
depreciating drastically.
That was the bank manager,
not a pickpocket. Show some manners.
There are a lot of criminals
out there, but not everyone is bad.
Besides, I know that bank manager.
Foreigners are warm and polite,
and very welcoming.
When people smile, smile back
at them. That`s basic manners.
When someone puts their arm around
you, it`s a sign of affection,
you should reciprocate.
You should remember what I`ve said,
or you`ll be sorry.
Ah Lung?
You must be Ah Lung! Welcome to Rome!
I`m Ah Quen
from Miss Chen`s restaurant.
Ah Quen!
Miss Chen got tired of waiting
so she went back to the restaurant.
She asked me to take you there.
By the way, where were you just now?
Let`s go.
The Shanghai.
Uncle Wang, this is Ah Lung.
Ah Lung, this is Uncle Wang.
Uncle Wang.
Don`t be so formal, we are family.
Sit down.
Ah Quen, make some tea.
You`ve been flying all day,
you must be tired.
You`ve been living in Hong Kong,
you must find it strange here.
Everything has been strange,
since I got off the plane.
You`ll get used to it.
It`s been such a long time...
since I was back in Hong Kong.
- How are things there?
- In Hong Kong?
I don`t go into town very often.
But out in the country...
Have some tea.
Come, let`s have some.
Thank you.
It`s a big place,
why are there no customers?
With those gangsters hanging about,
who`d dare come in here?
Ah Lung, there are more workers
practising Karate out back.
Let`s go and meet them.
There`s no business,
so they spend their time exercising.
Come on!
Before Mr Chen passed away,
they learned Karate
to take care of those gangsters.
Why don`t you learn?
I`m not interested
in foreign martial arts.
The style isn`t important
as long as you are using your body
to its fullest extent.
Even in the midst of violent movement
you can achieve your goals
and express yourself.
I`d prefer to learn Kung-Fu.
- Can you do Kung-Fu?
- Yes.
Really?
OK, let`s take a break.
Come over here.
This is Tang Lung.
Introduce yourselves.
My name is Tony.
I`m Jimmy.
Thomas.
Robert.
I`ve got no English name.
Call me Ah Kun.
He looks like your typical
Kung-Fu expert.
Can you fight?
Ah Lung came from Hong Kong
to help us.
He`s not bad at Kung-Fu.
I`ve just studied a little.
Kung-Fu? That`s all just Tai Chi.
It lacks strength.
Whatever the style, it all lacks
strength if you don`t learn it right.
Yeah!
How do you develop strength then?
By training from the waist up,
you become one with your body.
Will you demonstrate
how to be one with the body?
I might hurt someone.
What?
Don`t worry about it, they`ve got
protective pads. They`ll be OK.
Go on, go on. It`s just a bit of fun.
Hold it tightly.
We`ve got some customers.
You`d better change and get to work.
Hurry.
Come on, let`s go.
Change and get cracking.
Ah Quen, where`s the toilet?
The toilet? It`s over there.
The sign is in English.
What have you decided?
- Uncle Wang!
- Yes?
Quick, they`re here again!
Stop, stop it!
If you don`t answer by tonight,
don`t blame us for getting rough.
Mr Ho, please help us out.
Put in a good word for us.
Give us a few more days
to think it over.
A few more days?! A few more days?!
You`ve continuously delayed things.
Are you selling or not?
Hey, don`t hit him.
Don`t fight, please.
You`ll only wreck our own things.
Remember, you must give us
your answer by tonight.
Sorry.
Watch where you`re going next time.
You can`t even speak a word
of English.
Why did my uncle send you here?
Ah Lung, they`re young
and headstrong, don`t blame them.
Everything will be all right.
That was disappointing.
It`s lucky they didn`t
bring guns with them.
In broad daylight? They wouldn`t
dare use a gun in public.
If Uncle Wang hadn`t stopped us,
I`d have given them a taste
of my Karate.
You`re full of hot air. You`re always
practising, but what good is it?
At least it`s better than Kung-Fu.
When he bumped into you,
you didn`t dare say a word.
You even apologised to him!
And he says Kung-Fu is great!
- OK, here come some customers.
- Serve the customers, quickly.
Ah Quen, get Uncle Wang
out here to help us.
Stop messing around.
Remember this is our place,
so we have to pay for breakages.
We can`t take this any more!
- Ah Lung, you...
- Let`s go!
Jimmy!
Jimmy.
You bastard! Are you blind?
This isn`t Kung-Fu.
If I knew how to do Kung-Fu,
I`d give you a taste of it!
I`ll go.
Tell him this is Kung-Fu.
The Golden Dragon, movement four -
Little Dragon Seeks the Path.
Big Dragon Shakes His Tail.
- Ah Lung! He`s really good!
- He`s got some moves.
- Magnificent!
- Excellent!
You`re really good!
Congratulations, that was great!
Ah Lung, you`re really magnificent.
Don`t get so excited,
there`ll be more trouble to come.
With skill like Ah Lung`s,
we`ve nothing to fear,
the more they come,
the more they`ll suffer!
You guys are still young,
you have no fear of death.
There`s an old Chinese saying:
"Not even the tiger can beat
the worms at the end!"
Remember, this is their territory.
One day they will get their revenge.
I told you to be careful.
We should restrain ourselves
and resolve this by peaceful means.
We`ve nothing to fear,
the dragon`s on our side.
Mark my words
or there will be trouble.
- What trouble?
- There`s no trouble.
Calm down everyone,
we`ll work this out.
Ah Lung, it`s late
and you must be tired, let`s go home.
Do you want some supper?
No, I must get up early for training.
I hear it`s easy
to buy a gun here.
Yes, any local citizen
can get a licence.
- What are you doing?
- Making darts.
Darts?
Food`s up.
Let`s have one, then.
Stop!
You want to eat? You can eat
when you`re as good as Ah Lung.
You`d better go
and practise your Karate.
So it`s for Brother Lung?
Why didn`t you say so?
Brother Lung?
Here he is.
Brother Lung!
Good morning, Brother Lung.
Out of the way.
Brother Lung, I made this breakfast
especially for you.
Eat it while it`s hot.
Please, take a seat.
Yeah, sit, sit.
Your Kung-Fu is really terrific.
Who was your teacher in Hong Kong?
Watch this.
Little Dragon Seeks the Path.
Big Dragon Shakes His Tail.
In two moves, he takes them out!
You said Kung-Fu lacks power.
I was only kidding.
Ah Lung, you were too fast yesterday.
We couldn`t see clearly.
Will you show us again?
Go on, show us!
I want to see
how magnificent you are too.
OK, Brother Lung,
show him your moves.
Let`s go! Show us!
Hold this!
You take this one.
Don`t get in his way.
Everybody says you`re fast and
powerful. I didn`t see it last night.
Didn`t you say you have to be
one with your body to gain power?
Why not show us, then?
Hey, stop yabbering on.
Let Brother Lung show you.
Get out of the way.
Are you all right?
- Are you all right?
- Are you OK?
I`m OK.
- Fantastic!
- Yeah!
You`re the greatest!
Ah Lung, will you be
my Kung-Fu master?
You said physical training
was useless. Why the sudden interest?
That`s because it was Karate.
This is Kung-Fu. Get it?
He`s stupid.
We`ll give up Karate.
Let`s ask Brother Lung
to be our master.
Is that OK?
Customers, come quick!
We`re coming!
After you, Brother Lung.
Mind your step.
Go and get changed. Be quick.
Ah Lung, no, master, I have to take
care of the customers now.
We`ll talk further when we close.
Is there anything for me to do?
Keep a look out for those gangsters.
- What was that?
- He wants us to see his boss.
See you tomorrow.
- Good morning.
Sit down.
Eat.
It`s hard to find this in Rome.
Is it good?
It`s not as good as in Hong Kong.
I cooked it.
It`s all right. Help yourself.
And you?
Would you like some more?
When you`ve finished, I`ll take you
sightseeing around Rome.
Get over there.
Where is the man called Tang
from Hong Kong?
Tell him to get out here.
Where is he? Tell us.
I don`t know.
Are you going to talk?
Don`t hit him, I`ll talk.
He`ll be here soon.
Where is he now?
Look, these are famous ancient ruins.
Over there...
What is it?
Our area has more run-down buildings
than this.
Let`s go.
A king built these gardens
for his queen.
It took a lot of time and money.
They must have been
very much in love.
Are you married?
How do you like the palaces?
Such a big place is a waste.
If I had this space in Hong Kong,
I would build a skyscraper
and collect rent.
We`d better get to the restaurant.
The boss means you`re both men
of the world. He likes your style.
He appreciates talent.
Oh, what muscles!
We don`t want to harm you.
Here`s a ticket back to Hong Kong.
No need to trouble yourself with
these small matters. Enjoy yourself.
I told you so.
Now look what you`ve done.
Miss Chen, why cause more trouble?
You might as well accept our offer.
We take our business seriously.
We`re offering you a good deal.
What do you say?
Tell him this...
If there is any more trouble...
I will retaliate.
Tell him!
Get rid of them.
Go on, get out!
Ah Lung, hold it, that`s a customer.
Please come in.
Welcome.
They`ve come to eat.
Put that away.
Come on,
tidy up and serve our customers.
See? I asked you
to restrain yourselves.
Now look what`s happened.
You lot and your pig-headedness.
What will we do now?
We`re not afraid.
We`ll fight to the end.
This is no joke. They mean business.
I know, but...
I know how you feel,
but we must think of Tang Lung.
They mean what they say.
You mean...
Keep him out of sight for a while.
Tomorrow is the Chinese New Year.
If there is trouble...
I don`t know if he`ll agree.
I know he`s stubborn,
but you must persuade him.
Without our master, we`ll be forced
to sell the restaurant.
That`s not what I mean.
We`ll cross that bridge when we come
to it. If we fail, then we`ll talk.
Whatever happens,
we mustn`t sell the restaurant.
- You decide for me.
- All right.
It`s gone eleven.
You go and talk to Ah Lung.
Tomorrow is Chinese New Year.
Is the restaurant open?
Good, we`ll go to the countryside
and practise.
Remind Ah Quen
to bring the protective padding.
Firecrackers?
They`re banned in Hong Kong.
There must be Chinese living nearby.
Don`t ask me why,
but you must leave Rome for a while.
Leave Rome?
We don`t want you to go,
especially me, but you must.
- Do you understand me?
- No, l don`t.
Ah Lung, why don`t you...
- Are you scared of firecrackers?
- I`ll take you to the airport.
- Why?
- Those white guys will...
My duty is to help you.
I know, but you must leave.
- They`re going to kill you.
- Kill me? Who?
Time`s up, let`s go!
It`s too noisy. I`ll close the...
Stay here and don`t move.
Miss Chen?
Miss Chen, don`t waste
any more of our time.
Here is the sale agreement.
- Sign it.
- No.
Why are you so stubborn?
Our boss has been so nice to you.
If I draw this knife across
your face...
that would be a shame.
Don`t keep us waiting.
Our boss is an impatient man.
Whatever you say, I won`t sign.
We`re only trying to help you.
It`s for your own good.
We`ll get the restaurant
sooner or later anyway.
Don`t be so sure. Tang Lung
and the others will be here soon.
Tang Lung?
You think he will come here?
He`s playing Mahjong
with Our Lord in Heaven.
Tang Lung.
Be careful!
The mastermind is over there.
Let me tell you...
Tang Lung,
he doesn`t understand you.
Let`s go.
Happy Chinese New Year!
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
Thank you, Uncle Wang.
- Thank you, thank you.
I didn`t expect traditional
lucky money abroad.
Uncle Wang gives us lucky money
every year.
This is my best New Year`s ever!
First, we successfully defended
our restaurant.
And second, we have Ah Lung with us
who is also our master.
Third, we finally defeated
those gangsters.
Let`s skip the violence
and enjoy the New Year.
Here comes Ching Hua.
- Happy New Year.
- This is for you.
- Thank you, Uncle Wang.
Ah Lung, a telegram for you.
It`s from my uncle.
He wants you to go
and help someone else.
Don`t be like that.
If I get the chance, I`ll be back.
Miss Chen, I won`t leave
until this whole thing is settled.
Happy New Year.
What beautiful decorations!
You`re having a little party.
What do you want?
Today is Chinese New Year,
I`ve come to wish you the best.
I must apologise,
it was all our fault.
We must all be friends.
Our boss would like to see Mr Tang.
Would he do us the honour?
OK, a new year, a new beginning.
Business will be good this year.
Tell your boss we`ll be there.
Fine! The Empress Restaurant
tomorrow morning.
You`re here. Sit down.
Sorry our boss couldn`t make it.
Are you pulling our legs?
An urgent matter came up.
He couldn`t get away.
My car is just outside.
I`ll take you to him.
What? We`re to go to him?
Never mind. Take us there.
Right. I admire people
who come straight to the point.
Let`s go.
Where is he?
He`s gone.
Forget it. He won`t get away.
It`s a trap. Be careful, everyone.
Master.
The three of us can handle him.
I`ll go first.
Are you Tang Lung?
Leave him, he`s finished.
Ah Lung, we were lucky this time
not to have fallen into their trap.
Tang Lung!
If you`ve got the balls, follow me!
Ah Lung, follow him.
Don`t let him get away.
Tony and Jimmy can
take care of the Japanese.
Tony, are you all right?
I`m tired and I`m hurting all over.
Uncle Wang, why...
Don`t blame me. If you must blame
someone, it should be Ah Lung.
Yes, Ah Lung got you into this mess.
He shouldn`t have stood in the way
of my fortune and happiness.
You...
What do you mean?
What do I mean? You know.
Working men have no future.
I`ve worked all my life and for what?
I can`t even clothe
or feed myself properly.
I have a wife and children.
I want the best for them.
If the restaurant co-operates,
they`ll pay me a big reward.
Then I can return to Hong Kong
and enjoy my family life.
I`ve worked here all my life.
I want to take it easy now.
Tang Lung, you`ve got guts!
Tang Lung, the man you just saw
will be your downfall!
Tang Lung, you`re on
the path to total destruction.
Tang Lung,
today you will meet your death.
Ho!
Wang, we`ve failed.
Hold it!
We`ve been tricked!
Tony and Jimmy... Look!
Brother Lung, don`t be angry, please.
Listen, Mr Tang.
Now it`s all over...
I must go.
I`ll see you off.
No need.
Ah Quen has a car waiting.
Take care of yourself.
Wherever he goes
in this dog-eat-dog world...
he will be admired by all.
Subtitles by
European Captioning lnstitute