(WOMAN CHATTERING ON P.A.)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You don't speak Spanish,
right?
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
Are you ready?
Everything is cool?
Yes.
(CREOLE SPEAKING SPANISH)
Good.
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
Use your imagination
and your skills.
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
Everything is subjective.
Whatever that means.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
He who think he's bigger than the rest,
must go to the cemetery.
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
There he will see what life really is.
It's a handful of dust.
La vida no vale nada.
FRENCH: Diamonds are
a girl's best friend.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
Go to the towers.
Go to the café.
Wait a couple of days...
...and watch for the violin.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(STEWARDESSES CHATTERING)
(SIRENS WAILING
IN THE DISTANCE)
(WHISPERS BUDDHIST
WORDS OF PRAISE)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Two espressos
in separate cups.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No. Two espressos
in separate cups.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No.
I said two espressos.
Dos espressos, dos espressos.
In separate cups.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING
ON STEREO)
(BELL TOLLING IN THE DISTANCE)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(BELL TOLLING)
Señor.
Dos espressos,
in separate cups.
Two espressos,
Sí.
WAITER:
Sus dos espressos...
(THANKING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No.
GUITAR: Very loud.
Are you interested in music,
by any chance?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CONTINUES SPEAKING SPANISH)
What else?
Wait with the girl.
She's a criss-cross.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No.
Yeah...
...you left your bag
unprotected.
There's nothing in it.
Oh.
NUDE: Ah.
Do you like my ass?
Yes.
So, what's wrong?
You don't like sex?
Never, while I'm working.
Really?
(MOANS)
How can you stand it?
(PATRONS CHATTERING)
(LOUD UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Hola.
Do you like my raincoat?
Yes.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SMASHING PHONE)
So, you don't like
mobiles, either.
Huh.
No guns...
...no mobiles...
...no sex...
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No.
(THANKING IN SPANISH)
Suspicion.
Hitchcock.
Are you interested in films,
by any chance?
I like really old films.
You can really see
what the world looked like...
...thirty, fifty,
a hundred years ago.
You know the clothes,
the telephones, the trains...
...the way people
smoked cigarettes...
...the little details
of life.
The best films
are like dreams
you're never sure
you've really had.
I have this image in my head
of a room full of sand.
And a bird flies towards me,
and dips its wing into the sand.
And I honestly
have no idea...
...whether this image came
from a dream, or a film.
Sometimes I like it in films
when people just sit there,
not saying anything.
Oh, yes.
Diamonds are
a girl's best friend.
Have you seen
"The Lady from Shanghai,"
Orson Welles?
That one makes no sense.
Rita Hayworth as a blonde.
I think it's the only film
she's ever a blonde in.
It's like a game.
Deception, glamour...
...a shootout with
shattered mirrors.
She dies in the end.
(SIREN WAILING
IN THE DISTANCE)
So, I finally have
what you need.
Do you have what I need?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING
ON STEREO)
Do you like Schubert,
by any chance?
I love him.
He died when he was
thirty one years old.
Something like that.
(MAN CHATTERING ON P.A.)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No.
Are you interested in
science by any chance?
I'm interested
in molecules.
The Sufis say each one of us is
a planet spinning in ecstasy.
But I say...
...each one of us is a
set of shifting molecules.
Spinning in ecstasy.
In the near future...
...worn out things will be made new
again by reconfiguring their molecules.
A pair of shoes.
A tire.
Molecular detection
will also allow...
...the determination of an
object's physical history.
This match box
for example.
Its collection of molecules could
indicate everywhere it's ever been.
They could do it
with your clothes.
Or even with your skin,
for that matter.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Wait three days until
you see the bread.
The guitar will find you.
Among us, there are those
who are not among us.
I'm among no one.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No.
(MUSIC PLAYING
FAINTLY IN THE DISTANCE)
(BELL TOLLING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(MUSIC PLAYING
FAINTLY IN THE DISTANCE)
(FLAMENCO GUITAR PLAYING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Take a seat.
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(RESUMES SINGING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MUSIC PLAYING
FAINTLY IN THE DISTANCE)
(BELL TOLLING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No. I don't speak
Spanish, either.
Except, maybe
when I'm in Spain.
Would one still call
those, "bohemians?"
My grandfather
was Bohemian.
You know,
in the Prague sense.
I strongly doubt that he would
have had any bloody sympathy...
...for those kinds
of bohemians.
And then of course, they are often
the true artists, are they not?
Are you interested
in art, by any chance?
Maybe painting,
perhaps?
(LAUGHING) Yes.
Well, as we were discussing,
the derivation of the usage of bohemian...
...in reference to artists or
artistic types, wasn't that it?
I don't know
the origin, exactly.
Of course there's Puccini's opera,
"La Bohème".
That's based on the French book,
"Scènes de la vie de bohème."
Probably published
mid-nineteenth century.
There was an oddly
beautiful Finnish film...
...some years ago
based on the book.
But where the use of
bohemian or bohème in French,
came from to
begin with...
I can only speculate.
Oh...
Yes, of course.
I imagine you have... things to do.
The Mexican will find you,
he has the driver.
Ah yes...
...the driver.
You do know...
...that this guitar was owned and
played by Manuel el Sevillano.
It was recorded on a wax cylinder
in the 1920's, believe it or not.
God only knows
whatever happened to that.
Been nice talking with you.
As they say,
la vida no vale nada.
(LAUGHS)
(CAR APPROACHING RAPIDLY)
(BLONDE EXCLAIMS)
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON P.A.)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Los Americanos!
(ROOSTER CROWING
IN THE DISTANCE)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I heard you have a very
beautiful black girlfriend.
She's asleep.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Nothing is true.
Every thing's imagined.
Do you
notice reflections?
For me, sometimes the reflection
is far more present...
...than the thing
being reflected.
(WHISPERS IN SPANISH)
Are you interested in hallucinations,
by any chance?
Have you ever
tried peyote?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
They wear mirrors
around their necks.
And they play violins.
Handmade violins.
With only one string.
I'm going to
call the driver.
LONE MAN: No mobiles.
Está bien.
Ya, ya, ya...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No mobiles.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(WHISPERS BUDDHIST
WORDS OF PRAISE)
(CHATTERING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(DOOR LOCKING)
These fucking
Spanish assholes.
Jesus Christ! Addington!
Fucking sound proof door.
How the fuck did
you get in here?
I used my imagination.
(GUN COCKING)
(GUN CLICKS)
Is this your twisted idea
of revenge for something?
No. Revenge is useless.
Addington! Security!
God damn it!
What is your
fucking agenda here?
You people
don't understand...
...a fucking thing about
how the world really works.
I understand.
But I understand
subjectively.
That's fucking nonsense.
Your sick minds have
been polluted with crap.
Your music,
movies, science.
Fucking bohemians
on hallucinogenic drugs.
All that shit has
poisoned you.
And it has nothing to
do with the real world.
And I suppose you believe
that by eliminating me...
...you will eliminate control over
some fucking artificial reality.
Reality is arbitrary.
Fuck you.
(THUDDING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(SPANISH SONG
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(ZIPPER OPENING)
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON P.A.)
(RECEIPT PRINTING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)