Do you believe in God?
No, but I enjoy
the tranquility here.
Want to check the gun?
I trust you.
Another quiet tear
Streaks down my face
Another night ofdesolation
And solitude
Just accept me
For what I am
Don't make promises
That you won't keep
Who needs dreams
When we have each other
Who needs tomorrow
When we have today
- I can't see.
- Your corneas are badly damaged.
- Will I recover?
- Your sight will never be perfect.
- My sight is so blurred!
- We can do an operation transplant.
Will I be blind?
Jenny, I'm Sergeant Chang.
Do you remember
the murderer's face?
Please, leave me alone.
I'm frightened.
Calm down.
SIX MONTHS LATE R
Help! Help!
Please help!
Just go away.
They're gone now.
Don't be afraid.
I'll take you home.
Jenny!
How do you know my name?
I've listened to you sing so often...
Who are you?
I feel as if I know you.
I know you can't see too well.
I've wanted to help,
but I never had the chance.
In this world,
not everybody is untrustworthy.
Will you let me help you
this time?
Is it all right for me to leave?
Stay calm.
Let me check it out.
It's only a cat.
It often sneaks in
and scratches my furniture.
What a pain!
- Why did you turn off the light?
- You can see?
I only see shadows.
It was better last month.
I could see images.
Turn on the light.
It makes me feel safer.
What are you doing now?
Looking at this scarf.
It's got my blood stains on it.
The man who shot me
wrapped it over my eyes.
I'll never forget that.
- Would you like some tea?
- No, thanks.
It won't take a minute.
Please, sit.
I'll put some music on.
Another quiet tear
Streaks down my face
Another night of desolation
And solitude
Just accept me
For what I am
Don't make promises
That you won't keep
Who needs dreams...
Relax! You look exactly like
what you are, an undercover agent.
Lighten up,
or it'll be an open secret.
Come on.
Smile!
Now you look like something
out of a nuthouse.
Chang, this guy Eddie's
a lunatic. Be careful.
Same to you, pal.
Watch your ass!
Eddie, sorry to keep you waiting.
- Who the hell is that?
- He's a good buddy.
- Say hello to Eddie.
- Eddie.
Search him!
Eddie, what's with the security?
It's not our filrst deal.
Maybe he looks familiar.
Here's $200,000.
We'll check the guns filrst.
What are you guys doing?
Nothing special, offilcer.
A reunion.
Open the trunk.
Open it!
Now!
Damn you!
You set me up, didn't you?
Are you a cop?
Talk!
I'm no cop!
I didn't betray you.
Then how come he's here?
He's no cop!
I stake my life on it, Eddie!
Lying bastard,
I shouldn't have trusted you!
The guy's a cop.
I recognize him!
You've got it wrong.
Chang, I'll get him!
That shithead!
Don't move!
Goddamn mess, assho--
Finish your sentence.
Ass... assho--
Inspector Li, the suspect
Eddie Hung held a hostage...
in a crowded trolley car...
Could you see him clearly?
- Could you?
- Yes.
- Why did you shoot?
- Instinct.
Did you consider the safety
of the passengers?
Did you sound any warning
before you shot?
Insuffilcient time.
The hostage had
a coronary thrombosis.
She died of a heart attack.
Her family has registered
an offilcial complaint.
- You're responsible for her death.
- That's crazy
How could I know she had
a heart condition?
I've been on Eddie Hung's case
for seven months.
The guy was a maniac.
He'd shoot anybody for any reason.
Should I have waited
until he killed her?
You forget
I'd just seen him kill a cop.
Who's responsible
for that cop's death?
Fine! Do whatever you want.
I'm used to all sorts
of complaints.
One more makes no difference.
Catch!
- How's the action hand?
- Pretty useless.
Better use it more.
It won't help.
A one-handed killer's
out of the action.
I've had my day.
His name is Tony Weng.
He works with a drug ring
in Central America.
- Who wants him dead?
- No questions. Take it or leave it.
- 1 .5 million.
- Seems high.
This is my last hatchet job.
All right, it's a deal.
Money's no object.
These guns are clean.
No serial numbers.
Untraceable.
Explosive head bullets.
Your favorite.
Easy to pick up, hard to put down.
Want to change your mind?
Why take this job?
If she doesn't have
a cornea transplant soon...
she might lose her sight forever.
There's a cornea bank
in Hong Kong...
but it's always empty.
When a donation does come in,
someone else gets it filrst.
So we're going to try abroad.
I have to leave you
for a few days.
When I return, I'll take you
overseas for surgery.
You will come back, right?
I promise.
Today is the Dragon Boat Festival.
Many VI Ps and government offilcials
will attend the opening ceremony.
You are assigned to protect them.
Their information is in your filles.
Make sure you're extra alert!
Yes, sir!
Tony Weng,
we're protecting that scum.
Attention please!
Will all the competitors please
assemble before the floating platform...
for the dotting
of the dragon's eye.
It's our pleasure to welcome...
the president ofTung Yuan
Financial Corp., Mr. Tony Weng...
the chairman of Rotary Club,
Mr. Peter Chu...
Cover him up.
Keep everything under control.
Red alert! red alert! Tony Weng's
been shot on the floating platform.
The shot came from
around the filshing junks.
The killer is probably nearby.
All units!
Prepare to seal off the area.
Mr. Weng fainted.
Everything's filne.
Please enjoy your day.
Chang!
Chang, look over there!
An explosion!
Let's check it out
Chang, we can't lose him now!
Freeze!
You'll be all right.
Don't be afraid.
Don't cry.
- He's down there! Step on it!
- Okay.
- Any hospitals nearby?
- Think he's got a conscience?
He won't let the little girl die.
Nurse, where's casualty?
Go down the hall.
What happened?
- A gunshot.
- Quickly, put her down.
Nurse, check her blood pressure.
Prepare her for surgery.
Oxygen mask.
How is she?
Blood pressure unstable.
Weak pulse.
Blood pressure low.
- Have you seen a man carrying a child?
- He went to casualty.
- Detain anyone suspicious.
- Yes, sir!
Are you related to the patient?
How was she wounded?
Sir, you can't leave now!
I have to register your name.
Where is he?
I'm an inspector.
Just continue.
- Right, nurses, ignore them.
- Yes.
Don't disturb the doctor.
Put your guns down.
- What happened?
- There was a gunshot.
- Where?
- Over there.
Get everybody out.
I'll call H.Q
- Any progress in the Weng case?
- No, none at all.
I nearly got the suspect,
but he escaped.
Where's your razor sharp
intuition?
Many people want me to fail...
so this case means a lot to me.
I don't need you letting me down.
You always were a pain in the ass.
Do me a favor and prove me wrong.
Sir, I do nothing for nobody.
I'll get the murderer.
You'll get your promotion.
I hope you don't forget
who helped you reach the top.
I want you to draw the suspect.
Try to bring him to life.
He's over 30.
He looks determined...
without being ruthless.
There's something heroic about him.
He doesn't look like a killer.
He comes across so calm...
acts like he has a dream...
eyes full of passion.
- Hello.
- It's me, Jeffrey.
Jeffrey?
Why haven't you left town?
I want my money now.
I want it tonight. Tonight!
Sure, I'll bring it tonight.
Mr. Weng.
You should let me handleJeffrey.
He's my responsibility.
- What if he squeals on me?
- He wouldn't.
I don't trust anyone,
including you!
I know the rules of the game.
I'll keep my word.
Forget the rules.
I want him dead
because he exposed his identity.
I'm the boss now,
and you'll do things my way.
Okay, you kill him for me.
Ifyou blow it,
you're dead meat.
I paid you well enough.
Eddie, this could be a lead.
Six months ago, Weng's partner, Chu,
was cut down in Club Nine.
The killer was never caught...
but he accidentally blinded a singer.
What was her name?
Jenny.
She hasn't recovered yet.
Life's cheap.
It only takes one bullet.
He's no ordinary assassin.
I hope we're just looking
for one man.
If I'm not mistaken...
this man is not
a cold-blooded murderer.
It only takes one bullet,
cold-blooded or not.
He risked his life
to save the little girl.
And if he did hurt
the singer by accident...
he's probably contacted her.
Ifwe meet again
We'll filnd out where we stand
But perhaps there will be
no tomorrow
Only time will tell
-Jeffrey?
- I'm notJeffrey.
I'm sorry.
I don't see too well.
I mistook you for my friend.
It's a beautiful song.
Could you sing it again?
I only sing for one person.
Jeffrey?
Your singing
is so fiIlled with emotion.
I feel I already know him.
I wish he was here now.
Wherever he may be,
you are in his thoughts.
Part of him will always be here.
You no longer trust me?
You know why.
Of course.
In our profession,
we shouldn't trust anyone.
How did they know
about that beach?
They might have followed me...
when I drove there.
That's my fault.
Who wants me dead?
Why do you ask?
You know the rules.
Why didn't you leave town
after the job?
I haven't got my money yet.
Who wants me dead?
Ifyou hadn't exposed your identity,
he wouldn't want you dead.
Answer me:
Who wants to kill me?
Answer me filrst:
Do you have any bullets left?
I always save the last bullet.
Either for myself,
or for my enemy.
It'sJohnny Weng,
Tony Weng's nephew.
He wants you dead.
He hired you to kill his uncle.
Do you really
have one last bullet?
Jeffrey, thank you for sparing me.
We're in the same boat now.
There's no way out for us.
Don't let me see you again.
Inspector Li!
Five dead witnesses.
- It was him.
- Are you sure?
Show his picture.
Ask the neighbors if he was here.
Okay.
No regrets
No remorse
Let bygones be bygones
No signs of melancholy
No tears of self-pity
I don't care about what's
right or wrong
I'm not sentimental about the past
Just set me free from this reverie
For the pain lingers on
It dwells deep in my heart and soul
Only time will tell
Ifwe are meant for each other
My tears and laughter
are my own indulgence
Inspector, you hit the nail on the head.
The neighbors say he lives here.
Are you nuts?
Jenny!
Jeffrey, is that you?
Why don't you come back?
I'll be back this morning.
We're moving to a new home.
Why?
I thought you loved
to live by the sea.
I do.
Beautiful sea breezes.
I can imagine the view
of the clear blue sky...
and the deep blue sea.
Great! Pack your things
and wait for me.
I'll be here.
Why didn't you leave Hong Kong
immediately?
What stopped you?
- Are you the new janitor?
- Yes.
You're doing a lousy job.
This is a filre escape.
Look, there's garbage everywhere.
What if there's a filre?
I can't fly away like a phoenix.
I pay my monthly maintenance fee.
If I filnd you goofilng off again,
I'll fille a complaint.
Don't leave any garbage here.
Move it all away. Shit!
Jeffrey, you're back.
Yes, Jenny.
Are you with a friend?
Yes, he's my old football buddy.
We grew up
in the same squatter area.
Yes. He's...
I'm Dumbo,
he's Mickey Mouse.
That's what you called
each other?
- It's good to see you again.
- The feeling isn't mutual.
- You're not pleased to see your friend?
- We're not that close.
- He's been causing me a lot of trouble.
- I'm here to sort it out.
Please sit.
I'll put on some tea.
- Don't bother.
- No need.
- Please be careful.
- Take care, Jenny.
I know how to do it.
I won't hurt myself.
Jeffrey, take care
ofyour friend, meanwhile.
Make yourself at home, Dumbo.
I am, Mickey Mouse.
Ma'am, why are you so concerned
about the garbage?
He paid me a thousand bucks
to keep you talking.
Don't leave now!
I haven't had this much fun in 20 years!
- You're going to lose this game.
- Am l? Lets wait and see.
You're always the loser.
Not this time.
I'm well prepared.
Let's put your preparations
to the test.
- Are you always so determined?
- Yes, that's my style.
Mine too.
So we have something in common.
Is that what you think?
Defilnitely.
Have some tea while you catch up
on old times.
Thanks, Jenny. Be careful.
- Here's my friend's hand.
- Here's your tea.
- Thank you.
- A pleasure.
Is he another friend ofyours?
No, he's the janitor. We don't have
a janitor in this building.
Oh, he's the plumber.
There's a burst water pipe outside.
Your voice sounds familiar.
Have we met before?
I met you in the night club.
I loved your singing, but you wouldn't
sing withoutJeffrey there.
Oh, I remember.
What a coincidence.
Dumbo, take care ofJenny for a while.
I'm going to the bathroom.
So am l.
There's a second bathroom
in the bedroom.
Jenny, there's a rat in the kitchen!
I'll catch it.
Hey! Don't shoot! It's me!
Somebody's aiming at my ass
from below!
What happened?
Where'sJeffrey?
I know you both lied to me.
Tell me the truth!
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm a cop.
Jeffrey's a professional killer.
He murdered somebody.
I've been after him for months.
- I don't believe you!
-Jenny!
- Listen to me, Jenny!
- No!
-Jenny, it's true.
- Chang!
Jenny, calm down.
Listen, please!
Sit down.
Six months ago...
Jeffrey shot your face up by accident.
Now his employer wants him dead.
I don't believe it!
I'd like to help,
but I can't, in my position.
I hope you'll cooperate with us.
Jenny, we're using you as bait.
It can bringJeffrey in this time.
I'll save his life for you.
Otherwise, the guy who hired him
will kill him.
Name your price.
I want him dead.
He was recognized doing the job.
I want him wasted,
the sooner the better.
Deposit $ 1 00,000
into my account now...
and $200,000 more upon completion.
No money, no action, Mr. Weng.
Not even if I see his filnger on
the trigger ready to blow your head off.
- Put the hundred grand in his account.
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Weng!
What do you want?
You should payJeffrey,
or he might come after you.
That's bullshit! I'm safe.
Look at these guys.
They're killers.
You're the boss.
You should keep your word.
Don't talk crap.
I won't pay him,
even ifyou beg.
Mr. Weng, let me keep my word
and pay him what I promised.
Then I'll bring him to you.
Mr. Weng, if it pleases you...
I will beg.
Go to hell!
Ifyou hadn't worked for my father
for so long...
I'd have kicked the shit out ofyou!
Who is he?
He doesn't deserve your sympathy!
Why are you doing all this forJeffrey?
He's my best friend.
Cut the crap!
Come here now!
Mr. Weng's been shot.
Kill him!
Don't let him go!
- Mr. Weng, you've been hurt!
-Just kill him!
- Let's go! You're in danger!
- Go after him!
Ifyou consider me your friend,
kill me now.
I loathe seeing you demean
yourself by begging.
Though I didn't succeed...
I risked my life trying
to get you your money!
I could have just killed you.
I didn't have to beg Weng
for your money.
I'm not completely
without honor, am l?
Our world is changing so fast.
It never used to be like this.
Perhaps we're too nostalgic.
Nostalgia is one of our saving graces.
At least when I die, I'll know
I was remembered by a friend.
Let's settle our differences
in the next life.
Let's cancel them right now.
That's what friends are for.
Right?
- A drink?
- Thank you.
Jenny always wanted
to live by the sea.
You've done so much for her.
I wonder how she feels about you.
- Hello?
-Jenny!
Jeffrey, why did you leave
without saying good-bye?
I'm sorry.
I had something to do.
We have to leave tonight.
- Tonight?
- Dr. Ho called this afternoon.
He's reserved a pair of corneas,
but they're in Singapore.
Ifwe're not there by midnight,
someone else gets them.
All right, I'll take you.
Meet me at the airport
at 7.30 tonight.
I'll wait at the information
desk, okay?
Of course.
Will he come?
Will you go?
I trust her.
Everybody's here. Let's go.
How's it going?
Right. Full alert now.
I want you to check
every inch of this place.
Everything's ready.
He'll never get away.
Don't worry.
We'll take care of everything
while you're away.
Thank you.
Have a nice trip.
While I am gone, take good care
of the company business.
Please take care.
Jeffrey!
Get away from here! Run!
She's crazy!
Jeffrey!
Jeffrey, the cops are everywhere!
Run away!
Jeffrey, the cops want you!
Don't come near me!
Jeffrey, are you there? Run!
Don't let them catch you!
Jeffrey, run!
The cops are after you!
Freeze!
Jeffrey, the cops are all around!
The cops are everywhere!
Run!
Jeffrey, run away!
It's me, Jenny.
Don't move!
Let's go.
What's wrong, offilcer?
Flirting isn't a crime.
Arrest him!
Keep clear, everyone.
Let me through.
Open those suitcases.
- What were you doing at the airport?
- Chasing a piece of ass.
What's yourjob?
I'm a casting agent
for movie companies.
- But you resisted arrest!
- I was drunk.
Stand up and walk a straight line!
- Where's your friend?
- What friend?
You know who.
He's in grave danger.
Help him.
Tell me where he is.
I want to help him solve his problem.
I have some questions to ask him.
That's none of my business.
If the guy you're talking about
is my friend...
he sure doesn't need your help.
Starting now,
you're off the Weng case.
Inspector Chan will take over.
You're getting another case.
- What's the reason?
- I don't trust you.
Siding with the suspect
is not the way to catch him.
Sir, you don't understand how I work.
You said it!
That's why you're off the case.
I won't give up the investigation.
Bullshit!
Chang, you'll be Chan's assistant.
Yes, sir.
Release the man you just arrested.
Give him 24-hour surveillance.
He'll lead us to Weng's assassin.
- Have you got that?
- Yes, sir.
Will you kill again?
I thought the people I killed
deserved to die.
Now I believe everybody has
the right to live.
No, I won't kill again.
I hope I can keep my promise.
I've been followed.
Weng's men, and the cops too.
Don't worry, I lost them.
Weng hired Paul Yau to waste you.
Don't worry,
you can use my guns and ammo.
- Where are you going?
- To get your money off Weng.
I'll meet you in the church.
- Are you going alone?
- Yes, of course.
I must keep my promise.
Weng won't hurt me.
I still deserve some respect.
Sidney, I don't need the money.
I do need your friendship.
Chang! Chang!
I followed him to 6 Horizon Drive.
I almost got him.
I know.
I could have... got him.
Don't worry, I'll filnd him.
Chang, don't worry.
Eddie.
You can't win all the time.
But you can't lose forever, either.
Chang... Chang...
Inspector Li,
did he give us anything?
Go ask him yourself!
-Jeffrey!
-Jenny, what is it?
Why is it so dark this morning?
It's just a cloudy day.
Relax, it'll be all right.
- Are we leaving today?
- Yes.
Freeze!
Who is it?
It's Mickey Mouse.
What does he want?
He's come to say good-bye.
What are you waiting for?
I'm a cop.
I don't shoot people in the back.
Another way we're the same.
No, we're not the same!
I uphold the law,
and you break it!
Chang died because ofyou.
I swore I'd get you this time.
I'm sorry, but I won't
let you lock me up.
Ifyou must take revenge
for your friend, shoot me now.
Don't force me to kill you!
- You'd really kill me?
- I won't let you go this time.
Go ahead.
You can't win all the time.
Jeffrey, where are you?
Where is he?
Right in front ofyou.
- Don't take him away.
-Jenny!
Jeffrey's promised me
he'll never kill again.
Put that gun down.
Jenny, put that gun down.
Not unless he leaves us alone.
I beg you, please, let us go.
I'll never let you arrest him!
Did I kill him? ls he dead?
I didn't mean to kill him.
I didn't mean it.
He's all right.
I didn't mean to...
He's filne.
Calm down, be brave!
- You stay there!
-Jeffrey!
Let's get out of here.
Then you can arrest me.
Let's getJenny out of here.
The car's outside.
Come on!
I won't let you put me behind bars!
Throw the gun down.
You wouldn't kill a cop.
Thank you.
You could have killed me
with one shot.
I don't kill anybody until I know
they are the real enemy.
- Do you really know me?
- Fate controls everything.
The only person who really knows me
turns out to be a cop.
You could always give yourself up.
No. I made a promise.
I keep my word.
Sometimes, I really envy you,
your freedom.
It's something I don't have.
I believe in justice,
but nobody trusts me.
I have the same problem.
You're an unusual cop.
And you're an unusual killer.
I'm sorry to drag you
into this mess.
Tell me, who's behind all this?
That's not my game.
I play by the rules.
I knew you would never tell me.
Take care ofJenny.
Weng won't stop until he kills you.
You'd better let me arrest you.
We'll stay here tonight.
Sidney will bring me my money,
and we'll leave tomorrow.
I'm scared those gangsters
will filnd us here.
Don't worry.
This place isn't easy to filnd.
Why is it so dark?
I can hardly see anything.
Jeffrey, turn on the lights.
Why don't you turn on the lights?
Jeffrey.
Please turn them on.
There's been a power failure.
Will your friend come back
with the money?
I'm sure he will.
Boss.
Here's the $ 1 00,000.
Please check it.
You think he can kill Jeffrey?
Boss, Sidney Fung is here.
What if he betrays you again?
I'd still consider him my friend.
He was so good to me.
- Where isJeffrey's money?
- Where the hell is he?
I wish that I had a friend like you.
You will, one of these days.
Drop your guns!
Your right hand still works?
Well enough.
It's still fast and accurate.
You've got no way out.
Why are you doing this?
You tell me,
what's the alternative?
- Where's the money?
- Give it to me!
I'm one step ahead.
Why didn't you shoot me in the head?
Maybe I'm no longer a professional.
I wish I could start all over again.
It's a pity...
- Give me the cash.
- Where isJeffrey?
Give me the money filrst.
We owe it to him.
Hypocrite!
Do all killers
have a sense of honor?
The world has changed.
Honor is now a dirty word.
Sidney, sometimes I think
you're not human.
You're more like a dog.
At least we have
one thing in common:
We both use guns for a living.
But our motivations are different.
Right?
In some ways
dogs are superior to men.
Ifyou don't tell me whereJeffrey is,
this is your funeral.
Throw this garbage away.
- Give me the money!
- Are you sure you still got bullets?
You wanna bet?
Jeffrey said,
always save one last slug.
Either for yourself,
or your enemy.
Hurry!
Turn around!
Goddamn it!
Get him!
Promise me one thing:
If I don't make it,
take me to a hospital.
Have them save my corneas forJenny.
If that's impossible...
organize my money
and send her abroad for surgery.
Don't think like that.
It's the filrst decent thing
I've ever done.
Will you help me?
What's that noise?
Who is it, Jeffrey?
Sidney.
Here's your money.
I fought for it like a man.
This is my last tribute to a friend.
Sidney, you didn't have to do this.
He said I was a dog.
Now I'm not sure
if I'm human or a dog.
Sidney, nobody can call you a dog.
Sidney!
Am I a dog?
No, you're not a dog.
You're a great man!
We're outmoded characters.
We're outcasts.
I don't want to die like a dog.
But you see,
I didn't keep one last bullet.
I have one.
-Jeffrey!
-Jenny, don't move!
Don't leave me alone!
- What'll you do?
- Storm my way out!
Don't kill anymore, please!
Give up your guns and come with me.
What? You saw me kill Sidney.
He was my best friend!
And you dare tell me to surrender?
When Chang died,
I swore I'd kill you.
But now I don't want you dead.
Get out of here with Jenny.
How?
They'll chase me
to the ends of the earth!
I have nowhere to go!
Get out there
and say you're a cop.
See if they give up their guns!
Jenny!
Jeffrey!
Dumbo!
Thanks, Mickey Mouse!
I owe you.
You owe me nothing.
This is a gift of friendship.
Good luck!
Jenny, take cover!
Don't move!
Jenny!
Dumbo!
- Give me a gun!
- Here!
How good a shot are you?
I'm a cop.
I have to be good!
We've been through so much,
and I don't even know your name.
Is it important?
Whether we win or lose,
you won't be around.
I'd like to have a name
to remember you by.
Would you rather see me dead
or set free?
Neither, if fate spares us.
You're a hell of a good friend.
Just remember me as Mickey Mouse.
Why not?
Leave her alone!
She's innocent!
Drop your gun!
You heard me, hurry up!
Jeffrey!
Where are you, Jeffrey?
Don't be afraid, Jenny.
I'm in front ofyou.
Drop your gun!
Jenny, don't move an inch!
Don't hurt her.
I won't hurt her.
I'll just kill her!
Release her!
- Let her go, Johnny!
- No way!
What if I don't?
Like I said, drop your guns!
Dumbo.
Will you do what you promised?
No problem.
Remember, there's always a friend
to back you up.
Drop the guns,
or I'll kill her!
Drop your gun, idiot!
Jeffrey!
-Jeffrey!
-Jenny!
Jeffrey, where are you?
Jeffrey!
- Freeze! Don't move!
- Okay, okay, I surrender.
I'll cooperate.
Arrest me, please!
You're an unusual cop.
And you're an unusual killer.
I believe in justice,
but nobody trusts me.
I have the same problem.
- Arrest him!
- Yes, sir. I'll do it.
Arrest me!
I'm asking for police custody!
I'm a criminal!
Arrest me!
Jeffrey...
my friend.