-You wanna get somethin' to eat?
-Nah.
I had somethin' last night,
ruined my appetite.
Besides, I gotta get down the road.
Okay. Thanks for the ride.
Come on, I'll buy you
a cup of tea and a bromo.
-Come on.
-Okay, but I can only stay a minute.
Good.
Okay, we open. Come in.
-Where's the john at?
-In the back.
Gimme a bromo for my friend here.
I'll take a small steak,
two eggs on top...
...some fries, juice,
and a side order of toast...
Yes, sure. Right away.
Look out for that stomach, huh?
Here we fix you up one second.
You'll feel much better.
Okay. See you, huh?
We'll have your steak
ready in a minute.
Where's my buddy?
Oh, he left.
He left?
-What are you talkin' about?
-Hey, what's a matter? You okay?
The guy drove off on me.
How are you gonna figure that?
Oh, I think your steak's ready.
Thank you.
Oh, no!
-What?
-He took my wallet.
I left the raincoat in the car and...
I can't even pay you for this.
Tell me, where you goin' anyway?
-Down to L.A.
-Why?
I was goin' down for a job.
The whole thing's in the wallet.
-What kind of job?
-Phone number...huh?
Machinist.
Eat.
-Hey, thanks a lot.
-Eat, you'll feel better.
I'll be right back.
You watch.
-Watch what?
-You watch.
I find a new guy for the cars.
How's food? Good?
Very good. Great. Really.
-Nick Papadakis.
-Frank Chambers.
Frank, huh?
You know cars, Frank?
Yeah. Some.
I need mechanic.
-Here?
-Oh, sure. Station.
I'll tell you, though, Nick...
...l got friends down in L.A.
I gotta go down in L.A. Thanks.
And the meal, really, it was delicious.
She cook the food.
The food...
...delicious.
Tell me somethin', Nick,
just a question...
What would you pay a guy?
-Cora, how much we pay last guy?
-Eight dollars.
-And you promised him...
Room, board and you say
you like my wife's cooking.
-Your wife?
-Oh, sure.
Tell you what, Nick.
I got to track my guy down in L.A.
If it don't pan out,
I take you up on it.
Well, okay. If we still got it.
And I'll send you some money
in any case for the breakfast.
-Oh, yeah. Do that.
-Okay. Thanks a lot, Nick.
Goodbye, now.
Missus.
Be right with you there.
Here's a change, 20 cents.
Thank you very much.
What you need, Mr. Papadakis,
is more coverage.
I hadda lass year.
Last year you had fire,
theft, no liability.
So what I need it now for?
Well, you should've had it then.
Suppose a customer comes in here and
there's a spot of grease on the floor?
No, I'm sorry.
There's no grease onna floor.
-No, I'm just sayin' suppose.
-No. You suppose-a something else.
-What are you doing here?
-I come lookin' for some hand soap.
I don't have any hand soap here.
You got anything in the kitchen
I could use?
Go use the station john.
I'd just get it dirty.
I'll tell him to get you some
the next time he goes in.
Sorry to bother you.
You want a cup of coffee?
Yeah, thanks.
A nice place you got here,
Mrs. Papadukis.
Papadakis.
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
What are you, Greek or somethin'?
What...do I look Greek to you?
No.
Thanks.
So...
...what do I call ya?
I guess you can call me Cora.
A man, every man,
needs to have a home.
-You travel, huh?
-Sure.
It's okay.
But you know, the time come...
The time come!
Close the door, it is windy.
Cora, give the man some wine.
-It's in the cupboard if he wants it.
-Nice coffee, Missus.
When the times comes...
I used to travel a lot, too.
I was a young idiot.
I know you...sit down.
I know you travelin' men.
I was, too.
Oh, sure. I've been everyplace.
I speak six language.
-No kiddin'.
-Oh, yes, sure.
Go get the wine, huh?
Ah, language. Watch this.
You know what that is?
What?
You know what it means, that?
No.
I know, you never make fun
of a man talk funny.
I talk English
better than she talk Greek.
You know, Frank, this-a country...
...there's no...
...there's no...ideas here.
Opportunity, oh yes.
There is no happiness.
Frank, Frank come here!
Hurry up! Quick!
Hurry up! Look!
Look at his!
Goddamn son of a bitch thief.
Here, pick 'em up. Here.
-Hold on. You got 'em?
-Where are we goin'?
We go here. Put 'em up on post.
You got it?
Push. Push.
Know what I'd do, Nick?
-I'd get a new one.
-Oh, I get new one, sure.
And that son of a bitch
hang it first time, he pay for it.
Neon. Somethin' flashy.
You know what I mean?
Bring some business in.
Neon? What's a neon?
Neon. You know...
-...them little colored tubes.
-Tubes.
Oh, it's a neon.
Yeah, neon...
Maybe.
Goddamn, they all try cheat foreigner.
Frank, clean up the place.
He say how long he's gonna be gone?
He didn't tell me.
He said he was goin' into town
to get some parts.
Smells good in here today.
Is that door locked?
I must've locked it.
That's money down the drain,
isn't it?
You could look at it that way,
if you wanted to, yeah.
It's not your money, either, is it?
No.
Open it.
Did you hear me?
Wait a minute!
Wait! Get off!
All right, come on!
Come on!
I have surprise for you.
Here.
What do you think, huh? It's new.
Let's see it.
-You like it?
-Nick, it's beautiful. Real silk?
-Yeah, silk.
-For you, huh?
-Where you go?
-I'll be right back.
How'd you get that way?
How're you feelin' tonight, Cora?
Lousy.
Yeah.
Yeah, you missed me.
Cora!
Oh, stupid, I almost forgot.
Like the sign, huh?
I see they make it the way I say.
See you tomorrow, eh?
Yeah, see you later, Nick.
Yeah?
Feel like doin' somethin'?
I'm doin' it.
Do you want some company?
Huh? Want some company?
You want to be with me, right?
Right?
Yeah.
Good.
Go pack a bag, we're goin' to Chicago.
Go pack a bag.
We're goin' to Chicago. Now.
-I used to work near here.
-Get your L.A. Times.
-You got a cigarette?
-No.
How much money you got?
$110.
Don't flash it around here. Come on.
Wait a minute. You left your suitcase.
Bus leaving for Los Angeles,
San Diego, Phoenix...
-Want something to eat?
-Sure.
-Yeah.
-I'll be right back.
The next departure will be...
...Los Angeles to Chicago.
Help you, sir?
Change, sir. Sir! Change.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
-I've got 'em all, what do you want?
-You want one?
Okay, new shooter comin' into the game.
All right, guys, four.
I got it. Who wants a hard-ways four?
-Two to one.
-Two to one on the hard ways?
Right. You got it.
What about you? Dollar here.
Okay, roll 'em. Come on.
Don't touch this money.
-Where does he think he's goin'?
-I don't know.
-Hey, buddy, we ain't got all night.
-Honey, gimme some money.
Come on, we're gettin' lucky.
These guys don't know craps
from wheat or somethin'.
Come on!
No, I'm not giving it to you.
What? No, you don't understand.
I got to cover a bet.
-I can't talk to you about it just now.
-Frank, I can't go out there broke.
What?
What're you doin' out there, anyway?
Will you, for Chrissakes,
just give me some money?
I saved that money.
Two for San Francisco.
-What are you doing?
-I'm tradin' these in.
-San Francisco.
-Wait. We're going to Chicago.
Not anymore.
You want to give me some money?
-No.
-That's $37 change for you folks.
-I appreciate that.
-Wait.
You told me your friends
were in Chicago.
Hey, I got friends in Chicago.
I got friends in Duluth.
Now I'm gonna show you somethin'.
Sit down.
What have I got?
-You got it.
-All right.
Oh, I must've skipped you.
-You destroyed me.
-I sure did get lucky.
Wait a minute.
Are you leavin' with the money?
Well, I won it.
Hey, mate.
I want a shot to get it back.
Fuck you, Commodore.
I won this money.
All right?
It's all right with me, pal.
-Good meetin' with ya.
-Come on, Jim.
Wait a minute. Let's play.
Did you see that good-looking girl
that I was talking to leave here?
No, I don't know where she went.
Okay, you can turn 'em on.
I told you we shouldn'a hooked this
up in the rain in the first place.
Finish up, already.
-You check the connections?
-Yes, I checked the connections.
-Did you check the switch?
-I checked the switch.
Well, go check the hookup.
Your boss say, "Sign work both
day and night." I wanna lights on.
-Want a cup of coffee, Nick?
-Turn 'em on.
He's checkin' the hookup.
Well, hurry up.
I wanna see lights on.
Turn on.
Where the hell is it, anyhow?
Go around there,
he said it's around to the left.
Yeah, I think I've found it.
He would have found us anyway.
You don't know him, Frank.
He would've followed us,
and he would have found us.
Don't lose sleep over it, Cora.
I'm just disappointed.
I thought we had somethin'.
You just don't know what it's like.
Bein' a woman,
trapped in this kind of...
You don't, you don't know.
There's always a way, Cora.
If we stick together.
I didn't know what to do.
Cora!
I've got to have you, Frank.
If it was just us...
If it was just you and me.
What are you talking about?
I'm getting tired
of what's right and wrong.
They hang people for that, Cora.
Cora!
Come here!
Hey, Frank, it look good
from here, uh?
Yeah. It's a hell of an idea you had.
Hey, neon, huh? Neon.
All right?
Ah, ring twice for danger.
And the door?
Locked from the inside.
And then down the ladder
and that's it.
-Yeah.
-Okay.
Do you love me, Frank?
Sure.
You know I do.
Don't worry about anything, okay?
Don't tell me that.
Evening.
You knew I had to stop here, didn't ya?
She's beautiful.
I come by here all the time.
When'd you put her up?
-Just today.
-Had to be.
What was that?
-There's a damn cat up there.
-Oh, yeah.
Hey, they sound a lot like
babies cryin' sometimes, don't they?
Yes, they do.
Well, I expect I ought to
get back to work.
Yeah, well, we all got to sometime,
that's for sure.
That's for sure. Take care now.
Yeah, I'll do that.
Frank, get over here!
Oh, my God!
What happened to the light?
I hit him! I hit him!
-What happened?
-I hit him and all the lights went out!
Get on the phone. Call an ambulance.
The cop came by and saw everything.
-The cop? What cop?
-Get on the phone!
We're gonna die for this!
Hello, Nick.
Nick, wake up.
Come on, Nick. Come on, Nick.
We'll know for sure
after we see the tests.
It'll be about a week.
All of a week.
Can I have the book, please?
Thanks.
All he knows, it went dark.
If he'd have turned around, Frank,
they'd have hanged us for it.
And something,
something put that cop there.
It's an act of God,
those lights went out.
Don't look back.
-What?
-Don't look back. It's a cop.
-His red light's on.
-Oh, God.
No, no, leave 'em on.
Bathroom upstairs?
Ah, yeah.
What's the ladder doin' there?
I don't know.
Hey, come here.
All right. Sure.
Hey.
Cover's off this fuse box up here.
I'd say that sucker stuck a paw in it.
Fried him deader than hell.
Yeah. How about that?
Must've been those guys
that were workin' on the sign today.
Yeah.
Sounds like that.
Sorry about your husband, ma'am.
Thank you.
Thanks a lot.
I'll get a flashlight.
I know it's tough...to go down
and see him.
You're sure you don't want
me to drive?
Hurry back.
Take it easy guys, there's plenty here.
Cut pie. Little portions.
John Philip Sousa.
I don't want to make love tonight.
It's our last night.
I know.
I don't want to make love.
Yeah, you're right.
Me neither.
Oh, Christ, Cora.
It's all in the feet.
You must watch the feet.
-Can I talk to you a minute?
-It is beautiful, believe me.
-You just watch your feet...
-Can I talk to you for a minute?
-And you will learn...
-Excuse me.
I can't talk about it now.
What do you mean,
you can't talk about it now?
Four days already,
you can't talk about it.
Yeah, and you don't understand.
I can't do it anymore, Frank.
You understand?
Why can't you do it anymore?
What does that mean?
You can't do it anymore?
-It's over.
-Come dance.
What? What are you talkin' about?
Bravo, Nicko.
Come here.
This man saved my life.
I'm fond this man.
Cora, my feets, you know.
My feets. They're beautiful, huh?
-Beautiful.
-You say it.
You say it Greek.
Nick, I can't say it in Greek.
Come on, you say it.
Say it.
That's it.
Come here. Now, you say it.
Is beautiful.
Tonight.
What?
What're you doing?
You're the guy's wife, Cora.
You told me that.
You were gonna leave me?
-I was writing you a note.
-Were you writing me a thank-you note?
-Is that what you were doing?
-Cora, look.
Live here.
Live with the guy.
Took a chance, we didn't make it.
Live with the man.
He wants to have a baby.
You understand?
He's changed.
He says the accident changed him
and now I'm supposed to have his kid.
How am I gonna do that, Frank?
How am I supposed to have his baby?
I can't have his baby.
The only one I could have
a baby by is you.
Okay.
Say you won't leave me. Please.
Just stall him, babe.
Just stall him.
-Going far?
-We're goin' to Ventura.
A trip. A change of scene.
-Is it much farther?
-It's a couple of hours.
-That's it.
-What do I owe ya?
$1.44.
-Okay. Here you go.
-Be right back.
-Here's your change.
-I'm gonna drive now.
You can't even walk.
What are you talkin' about, drivin'?
-Now, get in the back.
-What?
-Get in the back.
-Are you nuts? Are you nutty?
-Mister, you don't want to--
-I'm drivin' this car home.
-Come on, Frank.
-You don't want to drive tonight.
-What, do you own this car, big fella?
-Get in the back.
-Just get in the back.
That's it.
You drive safely now, okay?
Goodnight.
-Good wine.
-C'mon, Nick.
Is nothing like to have a wife.
-Cut it out, Nick.
-Don't worry. He's drunk.
-Shit!
-Don't talk like that.
It's boiling over, Nick.
I gotta pull over.
Hey, wake 'im up.
Wake up. The car's stopped.
Come on, wake up.
You gotta fix it.
Frank, get out of the car.
Shit.
I'll fix it myself.
What's a matter...with door?
There, got it...
Is he dead?
Get in!
Come on, Cora, get in.
Drive.
Put it in neutral.
Wait.