Ibelieve that in both
spirit and substance...
...our tax system
has come to be un-American.
Death and taxes may be inevitable,
but unjust taxes are not.
The first American Revolution was sparked
by an unshakable conviction:
Taxation without representation
is tyranny.
Two centuries later,
a second American....
-You're pushed.
-We got a game going.
-What kind of stakes?
-Five and ten.
-Is the man gonna play?
-After the speech.
Outstanding.
Post three. I got a shake.
Right there, fella!
I'm ready to die!
Nobody's gonna die.
Look, you and I are going
to go downstairs and talk.
Death to Israel and America,
and all the enemies of Islam!
I understand. Look, I'm gonna
put my gun away, all right?
We're gonna go talk.
I am a martyr!
I will bomb myself on you
and all the enemies of Islam!
Let's get out of here, Jimmy.
Go play some cards, get drunk.
I'm getting too old for this shit.
Get the 50s ready, guys.
Gilbert. Booze. Free for me.
-Did you bet with me or against me?
-Against you.
-You blew it.
Okay, you guys!
It's the moment of truth here.
-Oh, shit.
-Come on!
I told you guys,
never bet against me.
Come on, Petievich,
get a half a yard in here.
To my partner, Jimmy Hart...
...whose skill in spotting bad paper
is only exceeded by his expertise...
-...in rigging a safety Iine.
-Hear, hear!
How about a speech, boss? Speech.
You know, I've been in
this racket 25 years, you guys.
And I don't think anybody...
...has been put in harm's way
more than I have...
-...by this hotshot over here. But--
-Don't know how you work with him.
Seriously speaking, if I'm
going in to bag somebody...
...there's nobody I'd rather have
backing me up.
AII right! Hear, hear!
Later, AIvarez. Next time
you can make a jump with me.
-Come on. It's the same thing in your work.
-What?
You push too hard. You take it too
personally. You'II never reach retirement.
-I'm not interested in retirement.
-Such a hot dog. See you Iater.
Hey, come here, come here.
Got something for you.
Fucking AIvarez trying to pass
a funny 50 on us, huh?
Your retirement present.
-You trying to get rid of me?
-It was burning a hole in my truck.
That's a beauty, Richie.
They tell me the trout
jump all over it.
-You gonna Iet me use it?
-Come and see me, you can use it.
I'm gonna miss you, amigo.
Yeah. Me too.
Hey, Iisten, I know you got
something going tomorrow.
-You reading my mail again?
-Masters, right? Where?
You ain't going out there alone.
I got three more days on the job.
I want to make the most of it.
What's the point of the two of us
running down one Iead?
The point is that we're partners, right?
Sure we are.
And when the bust goes down...
...you're gonna be there with me,
Iike always. Okay, partner?
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
You give me a call
when you get back.
-Shitbag.
-Buddy...
...you're in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
Come on, come on!
-Do you know what we got?
-Nothing.
-Anything around back?
-Check the trailer.
Trailer's clear.
Anything around back?
CIear over here.
Who is it?
-John Vukovich.
-What do you want?
I'd Iike to speak to you if I could.
I'm sorry about Jimmy Hart.
Jimmy was more than my partner, pal.
He was my best friend
for seven years.
He was the most righteous guy
I ever knew.
He had two days to go,
and that was it.
I can't understand why somebody would
waste him over a counterfeit beef.
Rick Masters killed him.
See, Jimmy got too close.
We had a tail on him and his mule for
six months, but we couldn't make the plant.
Jimmy went to check that warehouse
near Lancaster...
...because he found out it was rented
under a phony name.
But I don't know.
For some reason he wanted
to go out there by himself.
Now you need a partner.
Let me tell you something, amigo.
I'm gonna bag Masters,
and I don't give a shit how I do it.
I hear you.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
You must be a mind reader.
I was just gonna call you.
I've decided to Iet Vukovich
work with you.
-Do I have a choice?
-Oh, is there someone else you'd prefer?
You're welcome to fill out
a form 19...
...Iist all the reasons
you'd rather not work with him.
Your input would be
strictly confidential.
Yeah. Forget it.
What is it you wanted to
talk about?
One-way ticket to San Francisco, Mr. Cody.
How would you Iike to pay?
-In cash.
-That will be $45 one-way.
AII right.
Federal agent. Excuse me. I'd Iike to see
the bills that man just handed you.
You wouldn't have a pencil with an eraser
I could use, would you?
-Sure. Here you go, sir.
-Thank you.
U.S. Secret Service!
Hold it, man! Where you going?
Get out of the way!
Excuse me, miss.
Hey, what the hell!
You some kind of freak?
Freeze, asshole!
U.S. Secret Service.
You're under arrest
for possession of counterfeit--
-You're making a mistake!
-Get up there and shut up!
-I'm a businessman. I'm a businessman.
-Put your hands back here!
Stop it, asshole!
I'II blow your head off!
U.S. Secret Service. I'm arresting this guy
for counterfeiting.
Freeze!
-Who are you?
-Secret Service!
I just came in to take a Ieak.
Morning. Let's go!
Get the bag, John.
You got balls coming here.
How you making it?
Like every other swinging dick
in this place makes it:
Day by motherfucking day.
UIcer acting up?
I want to know when
you're gonna get me out.
I want you to be patient a Iittle Ionger, Carl.
I got caught carrying for you.
Now it's my turn
for some consideration.
You have my word, you won't do
the whole nickel.
-What does that mean?
-Grimes is the best Iawyer in the state.
It'II either be an appeal bond
or a sentence reduction.
And the check is in the mail and I Iove you
and I promise not to come in your mouth.
I'm doing everything I can.
Carl...
...we gotta talk about Waxman.
Well, what about him?
He was your Iast stop before the airport.
What are you saying?
He said you never delivered
the package.
What do you mean?
He says I--? He never got it?
I counted out 600 grand
right there on his desk.
I had it wrapped in $10,000 packages
Iike you told me.
He put it in a safe right behind his desk.
He said you called, postponed delivery...
...and the next thing he heard,
you were busted.
He's a Iying son of a bitch!
He's probably the motherfucker
who did me.
He ratted me to the feds.
I'II kill him when I get out.
I'm gonna give that fucking scumbag
a serious headache.
May God strike me dead
if I don't waste him.
Your visit's over.
Don't forget about me.
I won't.
You have my word on that.
Hell, I've done everything
humanly possible.
At this point,
I don't see any alternative.
Your friend Cody's
gonna have to do some time.
Why is he being held
without bail?
He wants to know
and I can't give him an answer.
Suspicion of murdering
a federal agent named Jim Hart.
You told me you could arrange
an appeal bond.
Even if the judge granted it,
it's only a postponement.
-I can't fucking tell--
-The guy got caught holding 40 grand.
What does he expect?
He'II have to do a Iittle
to keep the prosecutor happy.
How much time?
Say, three.
No, no. He can't do it.
He'II cave in on me.
What can he give them?
Everything.
-So, what's up?
-Can you give me anything on Masters?
There's a guy in Pasadena.
He's a Iawyer or something.
Used to represent hippies.
What's his name?
-Waxman. Max Waxman.
-Waxman. What's his story?
I think he's moving paper
for Masters.
Good. Is there anything
I can do for you?
My kid's coming in this weekend
from Las Vegas.
-You got a kid?
-Yeah. His name's Christopher.
He Iives with his father
down there.
-Five hundred okay?
-Well, I was kind of hoping--
There's more if there's a bust.
You know the game.
-I had a bad dream Iast night.
-Tell me.
I was on-stage, and people
were burning me with cigarettes.
Serena once told me
she writes her dreams down.
-She keeps them in a Iittle book.
-Who's Serena?
What did Carl say?
He says Max ripped us off.
Do you believe him?
Looks that way.
What are we going
to do about it?
Take care of our problem.
Surveillance Iog, U.S. Treasury field office,
Los Angeles.
Office of attorney Max Waxman...
...corner of Walnut
and Los Robles streets.
This is day three,
January 1 1th, 2200 hours...
...reports of Agents Vukovich and Chance.
Looks Iike he's got a guest.
He must Iike tall women.
What a guy.
What is happening?
Long time, no see.
Heard you were on stage again.
What does Ricky-boy think
about that?
-Quantity?
-125 grand.
I've seen better.
I'II give you 10 points
for the package.
-Twenty points is the price.
-Where am I gonna get 20 points?
Off the back of a turnip truck?
Tell Rick he can kiss my ass.
Twenty points or I'm out of here.
What do you hear from Cody?
Problems.
I know you and Rick had your doubts
about me on this Cody thing...
...and I want to tell you
I hope that's over with.
I am straight with Rick.
I would never fuck with Rick.
He never talks to me
about his business.
He told me to tell you if you Iike the paper,
he wants your order. Now.
No problem. That's cool.
I'd Iove to make a jump
in the rain.
You ever do any base-jumping?
It's great.
I used to jump off garages
when I was a kid.
Can I bring you something else?
-No, thanks, Father.
-It's great.
Listen, why don't you make a jump
with me sometime?
-Yeah?
-Yeah, you'd Iove it. It's fabulous.
Once you get over the first fear,
it's a piece of cake.
It's the greatest feeling you'II ever have.
FIoat out, your balls go into your throat.
I think I'II take a pass, partner.
You know, I could help you...
...if you ever get in trouble.
-You know what I mean?
-No.
Not here.
I Iove the rain.
Yeah. It's groovy.
Come on.
Take off your glasses.
Come here.
-How you doing, Max?
-Oh, Christ.
First you rip me off,
then you set up Carl...
-...now you want to fuck my Iady.
-Man...
...she came on to me, man.
I swear it.
Oh, what a tragedy.
I want my 600 K.
I didn't have anything to do
with getting Cody set up.
Do you know that your house
is under surveillance?
You know you're Iiving Iike
a fucking animal in the zoo?
Get up!
Open up, Max. Make good
and we'II be friends again.
-Rick! Look out!
-Come here.
He's Iooking for something. Rick!
18th-century Cameroon.
Yes...
-...your taste is in your ass.
-No, Jesus, no!
Police!
Police officer!
Open the door!
Police! You inside, open the door!
Open this door! Police!
What's going on?
-Get up!
-What the fuck?
The whole caper's gone. Come on!
Shit!
-What's that?
-I took it out of Waxman's office.
It's some kind of dealer's code.
John, he's got all his delivery dates
in here.
He's got no names,
but he's got amounts, initials.
Look at this: "R.M., R.M."
Every other page.
It's a crime scene. The book is evidence.
What if the cop remembers it's missing?
Shit, that rookie couldn't remember what
he saw. He wasn't in there Iong enough.
You shouldn't have done it.
What are you trying to tell me, amigo?
If you feel strongly about it,
I'II hand it over.
That's not what I'm saying, okay?
That's not what I'm saying at all.
Just don't put words
in my mouth, all right?
So you won't carry your weight
if something goes down?
We could've got shit-canned
for this Iittle trick.
If you expect me to take heat,
tell me before you do it.
If I had asked,
what would you have said?
That the cops would have Iet us copy
the diary after it was booked.
I wouldn't have done it if I was
with somebody I didn't trust.
Look, I'm no snitch.
Hey, John, Waxman just gave us
Rick Masters on a plate.
Who's that?
It's me.
Too bad about Max.
If you'd have caught him dirty, he'd have
done anything to keep out of the joint.
Like you?
How much do I get for the information
I gave you on Waxman?
No arrest, no money.
It's my fault he's dead?
It took me six months
to get next to him.
I've got expenses, you know.
Uncle Sam don't give a shit
about your expenses.
You want bread, fuck a baker.
Someday, some guy I set up
for you is gonna snuff me.
It isn't too hard to figure out
who an informant is.
You gonna stay a while?
No. I gotta go.
I got something for you.
I'm here.
A dealer from San Francisco's
coming into L.A. next week...
...with 50 grand
to buy stolen diamonds.
The stuff that was Iifted
from the Bel Air Hotel.
He's a Chinaman connected
to people in Hong Kong.
I told you. I'm only interested
in play dough.
I was reading about the stars.
It talked about how the stars
are the eyes of God.
I think it's true, don't you?
No. I don't.
If you had any real balls,
you'd jump off that bridge.
The same thing happened to Max
could happen to me, you know.
Did you hear what I said?
Nothing's gonna happen to you.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
What would you do if I stopped
giving you information?
Why?
I'd just Iike to know.
I'd have your parole revoked.
You mean that?
You'd do that?
Man, why are you chasing me?
Why are you running?
Because you're chasing me, man!
What do you want?
U.S. Secret Service!
-Get over there!
-Okay, okay!
-Against the fence!
-Be cool, man.
Hands over your head, shitbag!
Come on, come on!
Get your hands behind your head!
Turn around!
What the hell is this, huh?
I swear to God, I don't know nothing
about it!
I want to know where Masters prints!
I'm gonna throw your ass
over the bridge!
Talk to me or I throw your ass
I don't know!
I don't know where he prints!
Nobody does! Nobody, I swear to God!
He was in Terminal Island
when I met him.
He was doing time for armed robbery.
That was, oh, 1978.
I was asked to give a talk
to the inmates...
...Iook at some of their work.
Masters had talent.
You could see that.
I went to his studio one time, and he was
burning a couple of paintings...
...that I thought were quite beautiful.
Do you think you might know
where that studio was...
...remember what it Iooked Iike?
That was downtown
past the railroad tracks.
There's an old warehouse...
...and there's a Chinese character on it.
-Come on!
-Shoot it!
Take your shot!
Not taking
any of that shit, man.
-How did that Iast stuff go?
-Hell, man, I had it sold within a week.
Needed more, but you changed
the phone numbers.
-I had people begging for them 20s.
-Had to Iay Iow for a while.
That's what I heard.
Heard someone popped your mule
at the airport.
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
He's up in Obispo, and I think he may
try to deal his way out.
-How much of a problem would that be?
-Ain't no big thing.
But ain't nobody
gonna work for free.
-What would it take?
-It'II cost you 100 K in 20s...
...if they're as good as the Iast ones.
Fifty thousand in 100s. It's all I have
on hand at the moment.
Big bills ain't popular in this
neighborhood, brother. It's gotta be 20s.
Well, I might be able to find...
...50,000 or so in 20s
Iying around somewhere.
Can I ask you something?
As Iong as you print that shit yourself...
...what the hell do you care
if I make 25, 50 or 100 grand?
It'd be nothing but motherfucking paper
to you.
AII right, I'II tell you what.
I'II take 75 K in 20s, and I'II personally
guarantee the job.
You still driving that piece of shit?
-Hey, what shit they showing tonight?
-It's that galactical warrior movie.
-I hate that space shit, man.
-It's nothing but science fiction, man.
Hey, what's going down, Reuben?
They're gonna move on somebody.
-Yeah? Somebody getting whacked out?
-Yeah.
Don't know who, huh?
Could be anybody.
Just keep an eye out.
-Am I being hit, man?
-I don't know. It's someone over here.
-Cody!
-Son of a bitch.
You're mine, motherfucker.
-Come here, I got something for your ass.
-It's for you!
Come here! Get him!
Shag his ass!
Hold it! Lay Iow!
Get off me!
Help me!
-How you doing?
-Hello. Room three.
Thanks.
Pretty girl, Carl.
Actress?
-Stomach problems, huh?
-UIcer.
Remember me?
Football game at the airport?
They want me to have an operation,
but I can't stand the thought...
...of one of those prison butchers
slicing me open.
I'd rather drink this shit-pink cement.
I want to get Rick Masters.
I've taken four falls. I never ratted
anybody in my Iife...
...and I've had plenty of chances,
believe me.
Masters is your friend.
I don't blame you.
I would never hang up a friend.
Anybody who would is a piece of shit.
The thing is, your friend
tried to have you iced.
That doesn't mean I'm gonna
roll over and play informer.
If you're Iooking for a pigeon,
go to the park.
Look, I'II tell you what.
You help me, I'II get to a judge,
have your sentence reduced to a parole...
...get you the fuck out of here.
What would I have to do?
-Like, exactly.
-Simple.
Show me where you print
and testify against him in open court.
I'd rather stay here the rest of my Iife
than testify in open court.
Then you better Iock your cell door
and throw away the key...
...because I cannot take care
of you in here.
I got all it takes, brother.
Hello, Jeff.
What are you doing in my crib?
You sent two assholes to do Cody,
and they blew it.
I paid you half. I want it back.
Yeah, well...
...I'm trying to get
that money back myself.
I had to front the whole purchase
to get my people to do their thing...
...so I ain't got any more.
Well, then you better try and shit 40 grand,
because I ain't Ieaving without it.
I owe you, Cody.
Next time, there'II be no fuckup.
What next time?
He's in protective custody.
Hell....
Protective custody
don't mean shit to me.
The man's dead.
In a pig's ass.
I want my paper, Jeff.
I can't afford to have it
circulating right now.
And I told you I don't have it.
Get it.
Now, Iook, my man...
...I told you I don't have
what you're Iooking for...
...so why don't you
make it easy on yourself...
...and just shag your ass
out of my crib.
Now, you be a printer.
Go get some ink...
...and start printing
some more of that shit.
What's happening, fella?
Yeah, you, asshole!
What are you gonna do now,
motherfucker?
Goddamn it!
-Come on, motherfucker!
-Don't! Don't!
You broke your contract with me,
Jeff.
Now, I don't know
whether you're into it...
...but you're gonna have to suck on this
until you give me back my paper.
-How much are you gonna burn?
-AII of it.
Why?
No good to me
after they handled it.