I can hear your heart beating.
Sounds like a little animal
in your chest trying to get out.
Sounds like blood.
Sounds like flesh.
No.
Most of all, it sounds like love.
- What's this?
- Well...
What is this?
- It's my gun.
- Your gun?
Don't hurt me.
Give me your hand, Culter.
- Get on your knees. Get up, Culter.
- I'm trying to.
- Jess, I'm here,
- I've got Culter.
Wilson, I need backup.
23 Ralston, the old Battery.
10-4, Backup units rolling,
I got your back, Jess,
- Get on your knees.
- I'm on my fucking knees.
- Get up.
- I'm up. I'm up.
- Hold him there, Jessica,
- Come on.
Come on.
Oh, yeah. One more thing.
- Hey, Shepard.
- What?
Do that thing again.
Do it! Do it! Do it! Do it! Do it!
Do it! Do it! Do it,,,
Inspector Shepard, Homicide.
Yes.
Who wants a beer?
- I do.
- I second that.
- Another round, Peter.
- You got it.
- All right, big guys.
- Pass them down, boys.
Thanks for being
on the phone, Wilson.
You and me?
You and me are like this.
You're drunk.
No, seriously, serious,
serious, serious.
Look, just because you're
moving up to Homicide,
don't take me off
your speed dial, OK?
No, no, no. I mean,
any time you press that button,
any time you push that button,
I'll be there to pick up.
OK?
- I'm gonna miss you.
- Here's to you.
OK. Don't forget about me.
Give me some.
I'll miss you too, Wilson.
Look, I'm telling you,
these Homicide guys, they're mental.
And they get turned on
by fucking corpses, remember that.
Now, that's interesting.
What the fuck is this,
the peanut gallery?
Shot of rye, please.
I was just wondering, do you mean
they're turned on by fucking corpses,
- or by fucking corpses?
- God.
- Mind your business.
- A lot of beers here.
Let's spread them around.
Another shot of Jack, please, Pete.
What?
Oh, nothing.
Oh, I was just thinking
how awkward you look...
...even though you are a cop.
What precinct?
Have it your way, stranger.
- Congratulations, inspector.
- Hey.
Hey, sexy. Come on, let's dance.
- You wanna dance?
- You gonna be cool, Jimmy?
What do you mean,
am I gonna be cool?
Like I'm here to fight with you
or something?
Hey, he made it!
- Hello, commissioner.
- Hi.
- How you doing?
- Hey, how you doing?
Back up, boys,
you're breathing my air.
- Hey, look who showed up.
- Good to see you.
- What's up, commissioner?
- Hey.
Leo, how you doing?
If my mentor were
police commissioner,
I think I'd be getting a promotion too.
You know what I mean?
- Yeah, is that right?
- Yeah.
I got ears like a cat, son.
So let's see what we can do
about getting you that promotion.
Test. There's a man sitting
at the end of the bar,
looks like he's been sitting there
for a while.
I want you to describe him.
And I want details.
Well, you know what? I'm just here
to have a good time, man. That's it.
Oh, so talking to me is not
your idea of a good time?
Or is it that you just can't do it?
- I could do it.
- OK, so go ahead,
get yourself a promotion.
Look at me.
He's a white guy.
And...
He's got, I don't know,
a dark sports jacket. I don't know.
- You know what? I'm off duty, man.
- Yeah, I know.
Shepard?
Go.
White male, late 40s, 6 foot, 200
pounds, thinning gray hair, glasses.
He's wearing two gold chains
with some sort of medallion.
He's drinking shots and paying cash.
And that's why she's an inspector,
and you're not.
The good inspector's never off duty.
My office.
Inspector Shepard.
Making an old man proud.
So...
- You pass the written?
- Yeah, of course. How could I not?
- Trained by the master.
- Really, Grasshopper?
Well, the master is amazed
at how badly you almost fucked it up.
- What?
- Well, a moment ago,
you demonstrated you still know
how to process a room.
So tell me this,
how did that psycho get
a knife to your throat?
No. Let me tell you.
You went there alone without backup.
And you didn't tell anybody.
You didn't follow procedure
and you almost got yourself killed.
You know, you're lucky you're not
being brought up in front of
a disciplinary committee
instead of being promoted.
You're right. I fucked up.
Listen, it was an honor for me
to raise you,
to raise my partner's child.
I'm just glad you made it through.
But you're Homicide now.
There's no more room for mistakes.
Copy that?
Copy.
Nice kick.
I mean, what kind of moron
tries to flush body parts down a toilet,
especially when he's got
a perfectly good furnace out back?
- I'm gonna head out.
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Where you been hiding?
This is your night.
Hey, the first female chief of police
of San Francisco right here.
- Mark my words.
- Oh, yeah.
- To the chief.
You remind me so much
of your father.
God, he would've been proud of you.
All right. I want you to go
straight home
- and get some rest.
- I will.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah. Everything's all right.
Knob Creek, neat.
Do you live around here?
What?
Any nightmares?
Insomnia?
Anxiety? Panic attacks?
Nothing.
OK, here's the deal.
This session is mandated.
It's standard procedure
for any cop
who's been through
a traumatic experience.
Plus, in this instance,
the suspect got a little roughed up.
Really?
Let's get something straight.
I do not have a dog in this fight.
I am not the enemy. Anything
you tell me goes right into the vault.
OK?
Unless I'm convinced a crime
is about to be committed
or you are a danger to yourself.
Also, you being here does not
jeopardize your promotion.
Good to know.
Anything else?
You're hoping I have
some big problems.
Frankly, I prefer to find people
in perfect mental health.
Well, then say hello
to perfect mental health, doc.
OK, then.
Hello, perfect mental health.
So you did kick Culter?
Hands break, feet don't.
You gotta get physical
every once in a while.
What's once in a while?
Yawara to the rib break.
Yawara to the groin.
Remember your distracters.
Yawara to the sternum.
Yawara to the clavicle.
Yawara to the rib break.
Yawara to the groin.
Good. Let me see how
you're holding your Yawara stick.
OK, put your thumb over here
a little bit.
OK, perfect. Let's do it again.
Yawara to the sternum.
Distracter.
Yawara to the clavicle.
Yawara to the rib break.
Yawara to the groin.
Hi. I'm looking for
Inspector Delmarco.
Delmarco!
Where the hell is Delmarco?
- Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
- Do I look like the kidding type?
- Delmarco.
- Shepard.
Follow me.
Boys, meet Inspector...
- Shepard.
- Flanagan. Dale Becker.
- Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
Shepard, here's a tip for you.
Stumbling on a suspect does not
an inspector make. Good luck, honey.
Thanks so much.
Dale was primary on the Culter thing.
Then you waltzed in with the suspect.
Congratulations.
You've made enemies already.
This job is about the fucking work.
So how come you didn't say anything
in the bar last night?
I couldn't.
I was following someone.
- Oh, yeah? Who?
- You.
Ask her.
She knows what she did.
She picked me up
and she lured me to that place, sir.
And then she got rough.
That's it. That's the simple truth of it,
Mr. Porter.
I had no idea she was a police officer.
I mean, isn't that some form
of entrapment?
Then she handcuffs me,
I'm down on my knees.
She kicks me in the face,
knocks me out cold.
Come on, isn't there some law
against police brutality, sir?
I'm going through a lot of pain
and suffering, Mr. Porter.
Yeah. Well, I'm very sorry
about that, Edmund.
But now that I'm on the case,
we will be petitioning
the judge to reconsider your bail.
We will be pursuing
many, many other options. OK?
I know your little dirty side.
I know you.
You're me.
Come on.
Ray, please tell me you are not
gonna represent that loser.
That loser's daddy
is Culter Pharmaceuticals.
I golf with him Tuesdays
at the Olympic Club.
He's asked me, as a favor,
to defend his boy.
I'm gonna do that.
Is that a problem?
When you were assistant DA,
you used to love
to nail bad guys' asses to the wall
like trophies.
Raymond Porter. I wonder whatever
happened to "crime doesn't pay"?
Gee, Delmarco, I don't know.
Whatever happened to
"innocent until proven guilty"?
I mean, do cops
ever make mistakes?
How about you, Mike?
Ever make a mistake?
Yeah, you know
what I'm talking about.
Would you excuse us?
I need to speak with Jessica
for a minute. In private.
OK, that guy, Delmarco,
tends to go off the deep end.
You be careful.
Ray, you got a client
with a string of murders in his past.
Wait a second, every defendant
has the right to his day in court.
That young man
has no prior convictions...
Ray.
He's the guy.
I nabbed him in the act.
Well, sometimes nabbing the bad guy
is the easy part.
The hard part is learning how to relax.
Yeah. Maybe you know someone
who could help you with that?
I think about that night.
I think about it all the time.
Always thought you'd come back...
...but you never did.
This fucking skell
runs around grabbing up girls,
sticking a knife into them,
murdering them.
Hell, he deserved
a piece of your mind.
Yeah, Ray will say he was cuffed,
and that you violated his civil rights
and all that bullshit, blah-blah-blah.
But the bottom line is,
it's your word against his.
He was resisting.
Remember that.
And that's your story
and you stick to it.
Don't get fancy, don't get creative.
Just stick to your story,
you'll be fine.
Hell, everything's fine.
And what's not fine can be fixed.
Right?
I guess Culter did impact my life.
He got me promoted.
So?
Do I pass?
Well, almost.
There's just one more thing
I'd like to talk about today.
Shoot. I'm an open book.
I'd like to talk about your parents.
My parents are dead.
They were killed in a car crash.
OK. So...
...now that's what you tell people.
Thought this was supposed to be
related to my job.
I don't see what my parents
have to do with my job.
Well...
...25 years ago,
your father went on a killing spree
which ended with your mother
and his own suicide.
And you've devoted your life
to tracking killers
and you don't see how it relates?
You sure?
I barely remember my parents.
I was raised by John Mills,
my father's old partner.
OK, but it...
- It could be your anger problems...
- I don't have anger problems.
I don't have any problems.
I feel fantastic.
Wow.
Aren't you lucky.
What's your secret?
Jessica, listen to me,
My job is to help you
deal with your feelings,
I deal with my feelings plenty,
Hello?
I miss you, Mom.
- Shepard.
- Shepard,
- where've you been all day?
- Mike?
Be outside, I'll pick you up
in 15 minutes,
- We got a 187,
- OK.
- Jess.
- Hey.
- How are you, Wilson?
- All right.
Wilson, Delmarco. You remember
Wilson, my old patrol partner?
- Hi.
- Hey.
OK, here we go.
Any signs of cause of death?
I don't know, man. But at first glance,
I'd say he was beaten to death.
What's the score?
We're up three, top of the fifth.
Jesus Christ.
Who'd you piss off?
OK, what have we got here?
Let's take a look.
Interesting.
OK, inspector,
let's see what you got.
- I don't think it was done here.
- Right. Good.
- So?
- We should check the tide charts.
What's that?
Hey, Lopez, my key still good?
- Yeah, Mike. Anytime.
- Tomorrow.
She'll be waiting.
Marine unit, my old unit.
Tomorrow, me and you,
we gonna go for a little boat ride.
Hey. Check it out.
- Cigarette burn.
- Nice.
- Perfectly centered. Looks fresh.
- Yeah, let's get a photo.
Get me a photo here.
Close-up of the cigarette burn.
- Nice and tight.
- OK.
One more. Good.
Thank you.
Looks like he's been hit
with a blunt instrument.
Precise. Very professional.
Something like this.
Now batting, first baseman,
J, T, Snow,
- OK, see you later.
- You all right?
Don't sweat it,
you'll get used to it.
It's not that. I think I know him.
His name's Bob, he drinks gin.
Nothing more you can tell us?
I told you, I don't really know the guy.
I met him once, about a month ago.
But you said you were intimate?
I picked up a stranger in a bar
and had sex with him.
You ever picked up a woman
in a bar, lieutenant?
Yeah, in my fantasy life.
All right, I'll give it
to Parker and Lewis then...
- Hey.
- Wait a second. Hey.
- What is she, a suspect?
- Come on, we got the call.
All right, it's yours.
Okey-dokey.
We have got Bob Sherman.
Confirmed death,
eight, nine hours prior to discovery.
The weapon is a small blunt object,
and the kill shot is a blow
to the right temple.
Although this guy was definitely beaten
postmortem as well.
And trace evidence...
,,, nada.
Look, there are no fibers, no hairs.
I tented this guy.
I even super-glued him up.
I could not raise a single latent.
Sorry.
Shepard?
We'll talk later.
- Hey, Mike.
- We'll find the current that carried
this guy here. Last night was windy.
Flood tide was about five knots.
The body could've drifted a long way.
I bet they could tell us
what happened.
They've seen all the bodies
floating on the tides.
They've seen all the smugglers.
There's hundreds of different
dumpsites, hiding places.
Heroin, cocaine,
illegal pharmaceuticals, party drugs.
You name it. I've chased a lot of guys
right down in there.
I know every nook and cranny,
every secret spot.
I'm like the sea lions.
They're my neighbors.
- See that place in there?
- You live there?
You're one big surprise
after another, stranger.
- You up for a cappuccino?
- You up for finding out who done it?
OK, inspector, back to work.
So, what exactly are we looking for?
Well, I assume you checked
the victim's cuffs last night, right?
I also assume that you would've seen
there was sand inside those cuffs,
which tells us...
Maybe he was dragged
along the beach.
Exactly.
Let's go check out the beach
at Crissy Field.
I don't think anything
would've happened here. Too risky.
Not if it were late at night.
So anyway, the ex confessed
after we shook him a little.
Great. Delmarco, Shepard,
where are you guys on yours?
Crime scene is clean.
No weapons, no prints, no witnesses.
We're going out to known associates
and neighbors.
All right. Anything else?
All right, let's break it up.
Yeah, actually,
I'd like to put word out to be on the
lookout for similar victims coming in.
Males, 20 to 30, severely beaten.
Wait a second.
You got only one body
and already you're thinking serial?
I mean, what is this?
Spotlight withdrawal?
Here's some advice I like to share
with new inspectors.
It's sort of like Homicide AA.
One body at a time. OK?
Your boyfriend.
He's not my boyfriend.
He's an ex and he's the reason
I don't get friendly
with my co-workers anymore.
Well, that's good to know.
- Let me talk to him.
- Thank you.
Shepard.
- Jessica,
- Yeah?
Bridge Patrol found another floater,
Someone pounded the shit out of him,
OK.
How much did we drink last night?
Well, maybe next time you should
go easy on the sangria.
I must have gotten wasted.
I kind of blacked out.
Too bad I wasn't there.
Big inspector now, so you don't
call me back ever, right?
I guess that's the reason.
You patrol guys wanna rustle
me up some breakfast?
A little bacon, eggs, toast,
black coffee.
Seeing as how you're not busy.
Fuck you, Delmarco.
Make that bacon crisp.
Check it out.
Yeah. There's the cigarette burn.
- It's our guy.
- OK. Let's get him out.
- Keep it level!
- OK.
Good, a little more.
- How's that?
- Right there.
All right.
We got him. The guy was
in the system. Lawrence Geber.
DOB 12-11-68.
Had a DUI a while back.
- See you later, man.
- OK, bye.
Tell me about it.
How did you know
there'd be another body?
There was that cigarette burn
on the back of the hand.
It's not a simple homicide.
Cigarette burn's intentional.
A signature.
What's up?
I can't say I'm happy
you were right about this,
but it was a good call, Shepard.
Nice going.
All right, let's get on this fast.
I want this guy stopped
before the bodies pile up.
This guy thinks he's a pro.
This guy thinks he's being careful
by covering his tracks.
Not with me, baby.
Everybody leaves something behind.
All I need is one little
speck of blood.
Just one little...
...drop.
Oh, yeah. Oh...
Like this little drop, for example.
You see the blood spatter
on the front of his body.
That matches the angle of the blows.
So, what's this little drop of blood
doing all the way back here
- behind his ear?
- Could be the killer's.
How soon will you know?
Well, I've got to extract it for DNA,
I've gotta amp it,
I gotta type it.
That'll tell us with absolute certainty
whether or not that drop
matches the victim's blood.
And, if I may say it, you are looking
a little rough around the edges.
I've been a little stressed.
You have been.
At one point, you did suffer from
some stress-related symptoms.
From when I was 6?
Is that what you've got there?
My parents had died and I was sad.
I didn't know how to handle it.
And what we have been discussing,
your parents, your childhood,
that all could be stirring up a lot.
Dr. Frank.
I am working on my first case.
Looks like it could be a big one.
Turns out I've slept
with both the victims.
That's why I brought it up. You know,
for someone who's supposed to
understand people,
you're a little slow on the uptake.
Jessica, listen to me.
You have to tell your partner about this
or your lieutenant,
or someone in the department.
And what if it isn't a coincidence?
What if you're in danger?
Fucking phone.
Shoo! Go away! Go away!
Goddamn it.
Easy does it, Jessica.
- You all right?
- Yeah...
...just a few rats under the car.
Rats. Yes, well, we live near water.
- See you next session.
- Yeah, we'll see you.
I just can't believe...
...that there was no warning.
That he just went...
...off like that.
Your father loved
your mother very much.
So much, in fact,
that it twisted him.
You know what I mean?
You know, sometimes I wonder if
maybe I hadn't told him about her.
About her affairs. Look,
you need to focus on your case.
Do your job.
That's the most important
thing right now.
Hey.
OK, here's the deal,
You all know about
serial killers taking trophies,
a behavior which often
gets them caught.
Well, in the past,
there have been killers
who tried to smarten up,
didn't take trophies. Instead...
...they "signed" the bodies.
It's been done
in different ways: cuts...
...brands...
...burns.
But signing the bodies
might not be that smart after all.
Because the signature itself...
...can be your best clue.
So cigarette burns.
We gotta think we're looking at
a smoker and the overkill...
The overkill suggests some rage.
Any questions?
Oh, me! Me!
Me.
I was wondering,
have we eliminated
Inspector Shepard as a suspect?
- That's very funny, Dale.
- No, Mike, I'm serious.
I mean, we know she slept
with victim number one, right?
- Sure.
- Yeah.
So do we know if she slept
with victim number two?
I mean, shit, Shepard,
he is kind of cute.
- Motherfucker!
- Get off me! Come on!
- Cunt!
- Take her outside, Mike.
- I'm cool. I'm cool.
- Dale! In my office!
Back off.
Bad joke. You made your point.
Now let it go.
Yeah, it is a bad joke.
You wanna know the punch line?
I did sleep with
victim number two.
Why the hell did you do
something like that?
Listen, brother, it is none of your
business who I sleep with.
Hey! Who the fuck cares
who you sleep with?
I'm talking about you
lying to me!
OK? Because partners
tell each other the truth!
Well, I'm telling you now!
She says she met
these guys in a bar.
Our killer's probably trolling
the same places,
and he was probably stalking her.
Just to consider all options,
any enemies?
Anyone got, like, a sick fixation on you,
might be stalking you?
Lately, I've...
...sort of felt like I'm being watched.
- So how do we handle it?
- Do we pull her off the case?
- No.
You need to operate as though
this is not a coincidence.
That's the smart thing to do.
From that angle, we pull her,
it might tip the killer
and we blow a good lead.
And if she is connected,
we're gonna need her help
to find out how.
- That's gonna put her at risk.
- She's a cop.
- She knows the risks.
- OK.
Hey.
Thanks a lot for
backing me up in there.
Backing you up?
I was just giving
my professional opinion.
You want my personal opinion?
Just what the hell do you
think you're doing?
- I'm not doing anything.
- Yeah?
Well, that's not what I hear.
These men you've been seeing.
And today, you attacked
a fellow inspector.
Oh, it was a...
...a disagreement.
And what's going on with you
and this Delmarco genius?
For God's sake, John.
He's my partner!
OK. Look, I know it's a new century
and people think it's OK
to just have sex with whoever.
But let me give you some advice.
Don't shit where you eat.
Keep your social life
separate from the job.
I do. John, I know
you worry about me
and I love you for it,
but I can take care of myself.
Really? Is that why people
keep dying around you?
Nice. Nice.
May I have your attention, please.
S.F.P.D.
Did I say that out loud?
Hey, I know you.
You come in here all the time.
You're a cop?
I don't believe it.
- Believe it.
- I did think you were kind of hot
for a working girl,
but I couldn't figure out
why else you'd keep taking off
with those guys.
Get it straight. We are not here
to discuss your opinion of me.
We are here to discuss a guy
who used to look like this,
and now looks like this.
So I know for a fact
he spent time in here.
Who'd you see him with?
Look, the only person I've ever seen
that guy leave the bar with,
aside from his girlfriend,
was you.
The bastard was always late
with the rent.
Played drums at night.
Serves him right.
Know what I mean?
Did Mr. Geber have many
regular visitors?
The last person I saw him with
looked a lot like you.
Seemed like he'd fuck
any skank that came on to him.
You find out anything up there?
We just wasted the entire day
tracking down me.
Good. At least we
have a suspect.
- It's a joke.
- Fuck you, Mike.
How did you get in my place?
Now, is that any kind of welcome
for a man who's seen you naked?
- What do you want?
- I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
I mean, I just... I just wanna...
I wanna see you.
- Come on, Jimmy, it's over.
- I... I do.
Don't you miss me just a little?
I miss you.
What do you want?
How many times do we have to
go over it? You know, it just...
God, Jimmy!
Come on, knock it off!
- No, no, no. Let me touch you.
- Jimmy!
- Just let me touch you.
- Jimmy, knock it off!
Just, please... Fuck.
- Jimmy!
- I need you...
Holy fuck.
Oh, my God!
- Jimmy, man, I'm sorry.
- Get off of me!
- Get off! Holy shit!
- Hey.
- Hey, here.
- Get away from me!
Goddamn it!
Get away from me!
Oh, my God. You know what?
You're a goddamn psychopath!
You know that?
You've got a screw loose, man!
Wacko!
Bitch! Holy shit!
- I'll be seeing you!
- Jim...
When did you first find out?
When did you realize...
When did you realize that
you had the capacity to kill?
To take a human life?
You know, we all have it in us.
You. Me.
It's a matter of who can control it.
Can you?
Jessica? What the hell are you
doing here with my client?
A little police work.
Following through on some hunches.
Oh, some hunches? I wanna
be here when you talk with him, OK?
Every fucking time!
You got that?
You don't have to have a hissy fit, Ray.
I'm cool with that.
Edmund, do you remember
what I told you?
OK? Only in my presence.
Jesus fucking...
I am not having a hissy fit, OK?
I am protecting my client's
interests here.
And you, you have got
a real battle on your hands here.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah. I'm coming at you
- with both guns blazing.
- At me? What did I do?
Oh, yeah. Let's just say the law
works in mysterious ways, OK?
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
Well, I will explain it
to you in detail.
But this is not the time
nor the place.
Let's say you come over
to my house Sunday morning
and we will talk about it.
You know.
Like old times.
God, I love that perfume.
See you.
Thank you.
- Sometimes I could kill that guy.
...the arresting fucking officer...
...without me present!
You got that? Never!
OK, OK. Don't have a hissy fit,
Mr. Porter.
The good news is,
I was right, as usual.
That tiny little drop of blood,
no way did it match the victim.
So we have our killer's blood?
Well, the bad news is,
he wasn't in the system.
CODIS, the convicted felon database,
it gave me zip.
So all you gotta do is bring me the
guy's blood that matches my sample.
That's all, huh?
Hey, that's why they pay you
Homicide guys the big bucks.
Surely, you have some leads.
Bring your good pal Lisa
a little blood sample, will you?
And I, one of law and order's
little people,
will burn the midnight oil,
doing the task,
making the match
that will lock that fucker up.
And you get all the glory,
and what, do you ask, do I get?
Hey, perhaps a dinner
at Chez Panisse.
Downstairs, I would hope.
Working late?
Still going over all those
unanswered questions?
The biggest question
of all still being,
why is someone who would normally
be considered a prime suspect
being allowed to participate
in this investigation?
You got something to say to me,
Becker, quit being such a pussy
and come out and say it.
I'll say it, all right.
And I'm not gonna hold back
because you're well-connected
to someone protecting you.
I'm not gonna let you drag
this department through the mud.
Are you listening to me?
I know about you.
I know about you and Bob,
and I also know about you and Larry.
Let me ask you...
...while you were sleeping with them,
were you thinking about hitting them?
Are you thinking about
hitting me right now?
Go ahead. You know you want to.
You know, I don't know
about this case,
but I do know one thing for sure.
Every bone in your body
wants to hit me right now.
Am I right?
- Yeah, who is it?
- It's Jess.
Hey, come in. It's open.
How could you?
- How could you do that to me?
- What's the matter with you?
How could you tell Dale
about the victims and me?
- What?
- I was just starting to trust you.
Hey, listen to me!
You think I'd betray our loyalty?
I would never do
something like that!
What's the matter with you?
What do I have to do...
...to show you that
you're my partner?
I'm sorry.
Where the hell do you think
you're going, partner?
We got work to do.
Are you gonna let me in
on this thing or what?
I'm starting to realize I have
more enemies than I thought.
Everybody has more enemies
than they think.
But the only reason why Dale and
the other guys give you a lot of shit
is because they're afraid
that you might be better than them.
I love the way you eat.
You know, John would never tell me
anything about my mother.
It didn't matter what I asked,
just a complete no-fly zone.
Except at dinner.
He tells me I eat just like her.
Two-fisted.
Yeah.
What can I say?
I get hungry.
Me too.
Sorry.
Sounds like a little animal
in your chest trying to get out,
Sounds like flesh,
You are in for a battle
on this one, Jess!
I'm coming at you
with both guns blazing,
Ray?
Anybody home?
Ray, I am not jumping
in there with you.
What is it?
Looks like he was beaten,
thrown in the hot tub,
and he's got the burn on the hand.
Let's just get this over with.
It'll take about five minutes.
It'll be standard form questions.
Let's go,
I still think it might be best
if we just pulled her off the case.
Do you have any physical
evidence on her?
Anything to indicate that she
might have killed these men?
- No, of course not.
- Didn't think so.
Just knowing them
is not proof of a crime.
Proof of bad judgment, yes.
But I'm not pulling her
from her first homicide case.
It would kill her career.
She'll come through this. Just watch.
And your involvement
with all these victims was,,,
Intimate?
Yes.
Do you think it's possible to do things
behind your own back?
Maybe I drink too much.
I don't know. I...
I pass out, and when I wake up
I think I've done terrible things.
- What is it you think you've done?
- There's been another murder.
And I'm my best suspect.
This third victim...
...I slept with him too.
Jessica, listen to me.
You grew up your whole life
knowing that your father
has done these horrible things.
So now you may be thinking,
"I have that in me too."
I don't think I have it in me.
I know.
Am I losing my mind?
I have violent dreams, Flashes,
- I'm hearing voices,
- When did you first find out?
When did you realize that
you had the capacity to kill?
To take a human life?
Get away from me. Go!
Hey.
I...
...need this right away.
Right away takes 24 hours.
Lisa, please. I need it.
OK.
I'll skip a couple of steps,
and I'll run it straight through
the amplification process.
You know, I always say,
you can tell a lot about a person
from a drop of their blood.
Can you tell
if they're a good person?
Give me a little time.
- Angela.
- Yes?
I need you to run this up to the lab.
Get a toxicology screening,
and I'm still gonna need to type it.
- OK.
- Thank you.
Hi, it's Lisa from the lab.
I need to see you right away.
You're a goddamn psychopath!
You know that?
- Bring me a drop of the killer's,,,
- I know about you,
Let's say you come over
to my house Sunday morning,
Are you thinking
about hitting me right now?
Killing spree, Killing spree,
Tell me something,
,,, saw him with looked a lot like you,
,,, I've ever seen that guy
leave the bar with was you,
Have we eliminated
Inspector Shepard as a suspect?
,,, keep dying around you?
What is it you think you've done?
I can hear your heart beating,
One body at a time,
Sounds like blood,
I know you, You're me,
At least we have a suspect,
So now you may be thinking,
"I have that in me,"
We all have it in us,
The capacity to kill,
Capacity to kill,
You OK?
Why wouldn't I be OK?
I tried calling you.
Something's wrong. You know
that feeling you've been having
that somebody's been following you?
I'm getting that same feeling tonight.
Something's gonna happen tonight.
Get away from me.
- Put the gun down.
- Go away.
- What are you doing, Jess?
- Mike...
Mike.
You've been drinking.
You gotta stop.
- You've gotta be strong.
- Mike...
No.
Give me the gun. Give me the gun.
Everyone who kisses me...
...turns up dead.
No, they don't.
Mike, don't go.
I ain't going anywhere, stranger.
Hello?
Mike?
You asked to see me?
Turn and face that wall.
Test. The bulletin board behind you.
Go.
Crime scene photos.
Three black and white. Two color.
Two black and white. Three color.
What is going on with you?
You know a couple of victims, so you
just let yourself fall to pieces, is that it?
- I think I'm losing it, John.
- Hey, you have a job to do.
- Hi, Jess.
- What the fuck, Jimmy?
Jimmy, just go home.
Oh, go home.
Like I'm some kind of dog.
Like I'm supposed to
obey you now?
Is that it?
We're gonna rumble?
Open the fucking door, Jessica.
Open the door.
I'm coming to get you.
I'm coming.
Jessica Shepard?
Chip Marshall, SID.
Where were you
the night of September 25th,
the night Bob Sherman was killed?
I don't know.
The night of October 1 st,
the night Lawrence Geber
was murdered?
- I don't know.
- The night of October 5th,
the night Ray Porter was killed?
I don't...
...know.
Jessica, did you kill these men?
I don't...
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know what else
there is to say.
I was raised to be a good girl,
but I was born to bad people.
It's kind of comforting, in a way.
I've been running from it all my life...
...the fear of being the bad seed.
But most of all, I feel bad for John.
It's OK, though.
It's good.
It's good that I'm in here.
It keeps other people safe.
Have you given her any medication?
- No, I've given her nothing.
- I didn't think so.
The problem's not in her head,
it's in her bloodstream.
- What's in her bloodstream?
- Report from forensics.
I had them run her blood
through a drug screen.
Rohypnol. Ever heard of it?
Yeah, of course. Roofies.
It's a date rape drug.
Completely incapacitating.
Get dressed. You're out on bail.
Thanks for all your help, doc.
We won't be needing
your services anymore.
All right, give me the headline. And
don't tell me you're not up for a test.
This is the biggest test of your life,
inspector.
Four men murdered.
Suspect slept with all of them.
Incriminating evidence found on her
person the morning after the crimes.
When she awakened
from a drug-induced blackout,
which makes it physically impossible
for her to have committed the crime.
- I didn't do it.
- Stick to business.
The crime remains the same,
only the suspects change.
- Who?
- What do they have in common?
- Just me.
- Who knows your habits?
Whose job is it to know
where you are at all times
in case he might have to call you
at any hour of the day or night?
No, you're off on that. Mike never
knew where I went at night.
Didn't this start when you got
the new job, when you met him?
It's not Mike.
All right, I need you
to tell me where to go.
Straight down Market
to the Embarcadero.
- But why would Mike drug me?
- How better to incapacitate you
while he went about the business
of doing what he had to do?
Do you think he'd let you prowl
without following you?
There were times when I felt like
I was being followed.
Suspect follows the accused.
When? Where?
The night she picked up
a man in a bar.
Followed the victim back to his place
where he watched you
do what you do through a window
or maybe a crack under the door.
Just enough to make him crazy.
Come on, inspector, I'm waiting
for you to tell me something.
Suspect had...
...intimate knowledge
of the habits of the accused.
Access not only to her place,
but to her deepest fears.
Plus, familiarity with the drug
that ultimately incapacitated her.
Remember, he's a cop.
We give him the benefit of the doubt.
No doubt. He'll get all
the benefits he deserves.
You got out.
Why didn't you come see me, Mike?
Yeah, why didn't you
come see her, Mike?
What do you mean?
I was there. They brought me in.
They questioned the hell out of me.
- I told them you were innocent.
- How could you be so sure?
Hey, Jess.
You're my partner.
- We're partners.
- Partners lie for each other?
- What are you talking about?
- Partners tell each other the truth.
- Partners tell each other everything.
- Hey.
Partners come see you
when you're in jail.
- You didn't get my message?
- Oh, God. There was no message.
- You're so fucking full of shit.
- I was there.
Somebody put me
on the "no access" list.
Excuse me, can I help you
with something over there?
Looks like you were having some
wine before we got here, Mike.
You celebrating something?
No, I'm not celebrating anything.
What the fuck is going on here?
- I'd like to propose a toast.
- What?
To Jessica. You got
a problem with that, Mike?
No. Why would I
have a problem with that?
What's going on here?
Is this some kind of joke?
You gonna toast or what?
Here's to my partner.
OK...
...somebody better
say something.
Rohypnol.
Rohypnol? Yeah, Rohypnol.
- And? What?
- Date rape drug.
- You ever heard of it?
- Of course I've heard of it. Roofies.
Roofies. That's what you
hip guys call it, right?
I seem to remember you had
a little girlfriend who OD'd and died
from this stuff. So you know
what Roofies do, don't you?
What the fuck is going on here?
Somebody has been following me
since these murders began.
Someone has been drugging me.
- How?
- Somebody who was lurking around.
- You know, who was in my place.
- Incapacitate you, don't they?
They make you feel
confused and anxious?
You...
...feeling confused, Mike?
- Any anxiety?
- You put something in my wine.
Whoa, this is quite a stash
you got here, Mike.
- Stash?
- A little of this stuff
must go a long way. You plan on date
raping a whole sorority house here?
You planting evidence?
Shit! This is not my stuff.
Listen to me, this is not my stuff.
- Party drugs.
- Whoa, lookie here what I found.
This is one of those...
What do you call it?
A Yawara.
Those little Japanese sticks
that pound your features to a pulp.
It's not mine.
They didn't have these in my day,
but I heard you're an expert
with one of these.
- That's not mine.
- This one's got some blood on it.
I wonder if that's Jimmy's blood.
You think that could be poor Jimmy's?
You didn't care too much for him,
did you?
I seem to remember you threatened
to kill the poor bastard.
You're not going for your gun,
are you, Mike?
- Mike!
- No, no, no, no!
No bruises. Just take it easy.
Take it easy.
We're in this together now. Partners.
And now you understand.
So we got a cop killer here.
A man who's committed
a very special crime
that requires a very
special form of justice.
Step one, make sure
the crime scene is clean.
Don't you touch anything, darling.
Step two, no sign of
physical restraints or struggle.
Step three...
...motive.
In this case, I'd say,
oh, remorse for what he's done.
Unlucky in love.
That always works too.
What are you doing?
Tomorrow...
...when those crime scene
boys show up...
Photos never lie.
They also save on those messy
courtroom appearances
and some asshole judge
letting him out on bail.
And now you understand,
We're in this together.
Give me the weapon.
- Step away from Mike.
- What?
Put your hands behind your head,
and get on your knees.
- Don't you understand?
- Understand what?
- I'm doing this for you!
- Get on your knees!
Put your hands behind your head!
Rule number one,
you gotta be crazy to be a cop.
You ever heard that old saying,
"Everybody runs away from a man with
a gun, but a cop runs toward him"?
Give me the gun, Jess.
You're not gonna use it.
Do it! Do it! Do it!
Your father had that same rage.
I told him about her. I had to!
He was my partner!
You tell your partner everything!
You always tell your partner the truth!
I told him she was fucking
that hippie scum!
He lost his mind, ran in the house,
I heard arguing.
Look, all my life, I wished that...
Hey!
You killed them all.
They were scum.
Don't you understand, darling?
They weren't good enough
for you and her.
You have the same
emotional problem.
You have her disease.
I've tried to cure you.
- You cured my mother by killing her?
- She was ruining my life.
She was ruining her life
and your father's life.
I loved her.
I couldn't let her keep doing those
things. There was no other way.
You killed my father.
You couldn't stop killing.
Stop?
I stopped for all those years,
and I can stop again.
Control, Jess.
It's all about control.
Give me the gun.
I kill you, I kill a fleeing felon.
You kill me, you commit murder.
We've heard everything you said,
commissioner,
You don't need the gun,
Test. Identify the voice
you are listening to.
I'm here, Jess, I got you,
Recognize the voice of Officer Wilson,
my old patrol partner?
Go along with the program, sir,
You don't want to destroy her,
Move. Come on, come on.
Let her get the capture,
commissioner,
Hold him there, Jess, I'm coming,
Maybe some asshole judge
will cut you some slack.
10-4, Backup units rolling,
Code three, We're on our way, Jess,
Well done, inspector. Well done.
You outsmarted the master.
That means I did my job well.
There's just one more test
you have to pass.
Don't!
No room for mistakes.
- Test.
- No!
- Mike.
- There she is. Let's go. Move it!
- Come on, we got one in the water.
- Officer down. Call it in.
There's no uniforms down here.
Get the paramedics.
Always got your back, Jess.
You OK?
- It's cold out here, kids.
- This is Marine One, On our way,
Copy that.
Marine One, get someone in the water
right away to retrieve the body.
Follow my light.
- See us? Right here in front of the dock.
- Mike?
Mike?
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry I thought you were the guy.
I am the guy.
I'll see you later, stranger.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH]