# Cat out green that
could deal with weez' #
# Homie quick like coupes,
'cause they feel the breeze #
# And I'm Holly Grove's hear,
the hood made me trill #
# The hottest hot boy,
baby, time reveal #
# And I'm Momma's oldest boy,
Papa's first seed #
# But Papa's not real,
he don't bleed what I bleed #
# I'm nineteen strong,
a kid with a kid #
# And ain't too many people
outdid what I did #
# I rock bricks down,
I rock ever town #
# I puff the best 'Bro,
pound for pound #
# Now say round,
the boy tough not bluff #
# Yeezy weezy,
young money squad up #
# I do this for
the penitentiar #
# I stunt for y'all while
I'm spending these dollars #
# I like cells
like four-corner blocks,,, #
Knockdown! Knockdown!
Another victory
for Sweetwater!
And now, for your
entertainment pleasure...
while we get ready
for the main event...
give it up for the Gat Boyz!
[Rap plays]
# You in the ghetto #
# We ain't got
no hustlers here #
# Get down and give me ten #
# I don't know what
you've been told #
# Motheruckin' rock 'n' roll #
# Blame it on the bullshit #
# To the north, to the south
to the east to the west #
I saw Louis the night
that he beat Braddock...
won the title. 1937.
Louis hits him
with a left and a right!
And Braddock is down!
Straight right hand to the jaw.
Christ, they could've
counted to fifty.
He was the best heavyweight...
that ever fought
under the modern rules.
No discussion, the best.
Then the fucking government
chased him about taxes.
Fucking IRS,
fucking bureaucrat assholes.
Fuck it.
# I don't know
what you've been told #
# Motheruckin' rock 'n' roll #
# Blame it on the bullshit #
# To the north, to the south,
to the east, to the west #
in the west corner,
weighing in at 230 pounds...
wearing the green trunks
with the gold trim...
he's undefeated with
eight wins and no losses.
Representing
the State Prison at Loda...
the great white hope,
Vern Van Zant!
# Let me tell you boys
who you're messing with #
Now in the east corner...
he's also undefeated
and defending champion,,,
with a record of
67 wins and no losses...
weighing in at 191 pounds...
wearing the burgundy trunks
with the black trim...
Sweetwater's own,
Monroe Hutchen!
All right now, shit birds,
y'all both know the rules.
I want a nice, clean fight,
nothing below the belt.
You understand me? Let's box.
Now remember,
brother convicts,,,
if you learned how to act...
they wouldn't have to fight
inside of a cage.
And be on your
best behavior, too...
'cause we don't want
no incidents, all right?
Now, let's see what
the pride of Loda...
has to offer against
the great Monroe.
Give Hitler's cousin
his lunch, baby.
It's all you, baby!
It's all you!
Yeah! Come on now!
Come back
from the rail--get back,
And there go the bell.
Here we go.
Monroe comes out
and peppers him,,,
with a nice left hand,
And another left hand,
Monroe's
just feeling him out,,,
popping him with
a little left hand,
He going to shine that
bald head up, for sure,
Move your feet!
Oh, yeah, that's right!
Yeah! Yeah!
Beat the teeth out of
his mouth, Monroe!
Come on, man!
A left
and a right by Monroe!
This guy hasn't
tagged Monroe yet,
How in the hell
could you be 6-6, 280,,,
and look wobbly already? Ooh!
He's down! He's down!
He's already down!
Vern Van Zant is down!
We're not even halfway
through the first round,,,
and he's already down!
Excuse me, sir,
we just got some big news.
The word is, the Iceman's
day of arrival is tomorrow.
E.T.A., 2 p.m.
Now, Vern Van Zant
said he got those...
brand-new tattoos
just for this occasion.
Well, Vern, don't look like...
the parry’s gonna last
too long for you.
This guy is a bum--
big, uncoordinated motherfucker.
Nine...
Look at me! You OK? Box!
Ah, here we go again!
Monroe's on the hunt.
Vern, swinging and a-missing,
Ooh! And another left,
right to the midsection,
Left and right
uppercuts to the head!
Right to the head!
Right to the stomach,
This guy's just
a-swinging and a-missing!
Hits him with
a left and a right!
Monroe's just
tearing his ass up,
Right in the face!
Right to the head!
Left to the midsection!
Another left and a right!
Oh, my God,
he shined his head up!
I told you,
he's shinin' it up!
One more time for Monroe,
Knockout! Knockout!
One round, motherfucker!
That's it! That's it!
It's done! This fight is over!
Monroe wins again!
Spit it.
Yeah, but I got a little
announcement for you.
Got a little
Little news bulletin.
Y'all been wondering
when that day is coming.
Well, that day is tomorrow.
He's coming to Sweetwater.
The so-called undisputed...
heavyweight champion
of the world...
George "Iceman" Chambers!
What do you say to that,
Monroe? You ready?
OK, here we go. Tape rolling.
Former world
heavyweight champion,,,
George "Iceman" Chambers,,,
now you'll be moving
to a new home...
going to live with
murderers and thieves...
in California's newly-built...
Sweetwater Prison
in the Mojave Desert.
How's all this going for you?
I'll be OK.
I got a bad break.
I just gotta
play this thing out.
Your lawyers have filed
all the expected appeals,,,
but realistically, what do
you think of your chances,,,
of getting out
before serving,,,
the full sentence
of 6 to 8 years?
I'm not supposed to talk
about that legal stuff.
My people don't want me
commenting on that.
Boxing experts tend to agree...
that even as little
as two years in a prison...
without proper training
could mean the end...
for a boxer your age.
Now, you're regarded...
as one of the greatest
offensive fighters...
in the history of the sport...
an attacker
like Dempsey, Joe Louis,,,
Rocky Marciano, Joe Frazier,
Just exactly how
damaging to your skills,,,
is this prison stint
likely to be?
No damage.
I'll stay in shape, work out...
watch what I eat. I'll be fine.
But when an athlete
is removed from competition--
That's where you're making
one big mistake right off.
I'm not an athlete.
I'm a gladiator.
How do you define that?
People play baseball.
Nobody plays boxing.
Iceman, last week after
you were convicted,,,
boxing's various
so-called governing bodies...
began stripping you of
your title belts...
stripping you--
Who they think they kidding?
Everybody knows I'm the champ.
And I'm gonna be the champ
till I quit.
This fight with
Manfredy is meant to be,,,
just a tune-up for
George "The Iceman" Chambers,,,
hopefully leading
to the unification bout,,,
with Montel Briscoe,,,
undefeated holder
of the WBC crown,
The two biggest names in boxing
on a collision course,,,
sometime next year,,,
assuming the Iceman gets by
the South American challenger,
[Club music plays]
It's round 1 and one to go,
and it's all Iceman!
He's stalking Manfredy,
chasing the big South American,
Iceman with a right,
another right,
Another right
and a left to the body!
Oh, and a right-hand uppercut,
That staggered Manfredy!
Iceman stalking him,
He knows he's got him hurt,
Oh, body shots!
Right, left to the body!
Left hook and he's down!
He's down! He's down!
That's why they call him
the Iceman!
Well, Carlos Manfredy,,,
gets a one-way ticket
back to Brazil!
George "Iceman" Chambers,,,
remains undefeated
heavyweight champion!
And the big man on the block!
Are you fighting Montel next?
Just another sucker who's
gonna get his ass whipped.
If the money's right,
bring on Montel.
Nobody's running,
nobody's ducking.
Nobody--l mean, nobody--
can stand up to what I got.
Does that include Montel?
Oh, yeah, that damn sure
includes Montel.
Mr. Lewis!
Estimates are up
to 300 million dollars...
for the pay-per-view
gate alone.
Any comment on that?
Let's make the deal first.
But my first guess is
you're a few million short.
And, Iceman,
it's nine months till summer.
What's next for you?
Well, first of all,
I'm gonna go to L.A...
you know, see some friends...
then I'm gonna do
a little partying.
Hey, hey...that's it.
I've done things in my life...
maybe I shouldn't have.
I know that.
But I did not want to,
and I told him "No."
You'll be moving
into a new home,,,
going to live with
murderers and thieves,,,
in California's newly-built,,,
Sweetwater Prison
in the Mojave Desert,
Without getting into
legal strategy,,,
let's discuss your trial.
You continue to maintain
your innocence.
I didn't rape nobody.
I done a lot of wrong shit
in my life...
but I ain't no punk-ass rapist.
Look at me.
What I gotta rape somebody for?
Psst. Monroe.
You see him through the window?
Big deal's got his own
helicopter service...
instead of coming
in here on the bus.
He's the champ.
What's this shit?
Don't think negative, man.
I don't want to hear that shit.
This is your house.
You own this place.
If this was my house,
I could get up and leave.
He's here.
Just getting out
of the helicopter.
Maybe you'd like to meet him,
Mr. Ripstein.
I could bring him over.
You two could talk boxing.
I'll tell you when
I want to talk to him.
Why couldn't your high-priced
team of lawyers...
convince a judge and a jury?
Because I put people
in body bags on TV...
and get paid
a lot of money for it.
Because I'm a big, bad,
black motherfucker--
that's why nobody believes me.
I have received
over 170 requests...
for interviews with you,
Mr. Chambers.
Networks, local TV, cable...
ever newspaper organization
in the country...
foreign press, foreign TV--
you name it,
I have turned them all down,
Mr. Chambers,
here is Sweetwater,
Maximum security, level five...
state correctional
institution...
with nearly
seven hundred prisoners.
We house only murderers,
armed robbers, rapists,,,
and those with
connections to gangs,,,
and other forms
of organized crime.
The state is trying to
spare lesser criminals...
the contaminating influence
of these more hardened types.
Now, we don't want
any incidents that might add,,,
to your already great
difficulties, Mr. Chambers,
This is Mr. Mercker.
He's the senior prison officer,
He's the head guard,
This is Ms. Early,
our administrative officer.
She can arrange
for religious counsel...
or instruction, if you wish.
Whatever.
I need a CD player and some CDs.
Now, I'll give you a list.
My people on the outside
will pay for it all.
Not possible
for the first six months.
It's a privilege,
has to be earned.
Any and all privileges,,,
will depend upon
your general conduct,
Mr. Chambers,
you have been convicted...
and sent here
for the crime of rape.
That's a very serious mater,
If you'd take advantage,,,
of this opportunity
to apologize,,,
to this woman
and to sports fans,,,
and the American public
for letting them down--
heck, even the former
president of the--
Man, fuck the president!
I ain't apologizing--
not to you, not to her,
not to nobody!
And you lucky I got this
damn gate between you and me...
or I’d rip you a new asshole,
you judgmental motherfucker!
Another strong
athlete in the joint!
Welcome to Sweetwater,
Chambers!
If you
need anything, champ,,,
I got you covered,
Hey, champ!
Seen all your fights, man!
You got a name?
Mingo.
Mingo, move your shit,
stay out of my way...
and we'll get along just fine.
Hey, listen. It's an honor
to be cellmates with you.
I don't want no trouble, champ.
No trouble. You just gonna
stay out of my way.
He just thinks he's the king.
Because he's the heavyweight
champ, he's the man.
Well, for some of us others,
we have rights, too...
and I had the right to say no
if I didn't want to.
I want everybody
to keep your distance.
I don't need to make
no new friends...
or hear no sad stories
on why they're here.
I got my own sad story for that.
I ain't loanin' nobody
no money...
so you tell 'em don't even ask.
And I don't want
nobody talking to me...
unless I talk to 'em first.
-You got that?
-Got it.
"Leave the champ alone."
I know boxing.
I seen a lot of fights.
You're a good champeen,
Who the hell are you?
This is Mendy Ripstein.
He's a very important man
in here.
Ripstein,
Yeah, my manager, Yank Lewis,
he told me to say hello.
I don't remember him.
He said you two
were friends in Miami...
about twenty-five years ago.
I didn't have
any friends in Miami.
A lot of people, they say
they knew me from the old days.
They're full of shit.
You're a good champeen...
but we got a champeen
right here...
and he can kick your ass.
Kiddin' me.
I watch all your fights.
You're not as good as you were.
You're just looking
for one big punch.
You're not
throwing combinations.
You're not using as much
head movement on defense.
Yeah, right, old man.
I'm just knocking
motherfuckers out.
Who's the punk in here
you got in mind?
Oh, did I hurt your feelings?
Fuck you.
Heh. Monroe.
Name's Monroe Hutchen.
Mr. Ripstein thinks
he can whip up on you, man...
but no offense. Not trying
to cause any trouble here.
# Hey, yo, it's real in here #
# All of these contenders know
just how it feels in here #
# When you're trin'
to be the top boss #
# Put your gloves on, then #
# This here
be the sport of men #
# Everybody
wants a shot at me #
# One word,
you get knocked out #
# Rocked out the box #
# Only men
leave a place like this #
# Hardcore,
I'm in your face like this #
# Tell your mama that
you'll never come home #
Which one of these suckers
in here is Monroe Hutchen?
He's over there in line,
wearing a white cap.
What's happening, Mo? Yeah.
Brought in
some big guys in here.
He beat 'em all.
It ain't only about being big.
You gotta have skill, son.
You Monroe Hutchen?
Yep.
I guess you know who I am.
Are you the champion in here?
Yeah.
Not the heavyweight champ.
Champion...
heavyweight or
any other kind they got.
I didn't even know they had
boxing in a place like this.
Well, it's a special program.
We only get bouts
ever six months.
Mostly we fight guys
from other prisons.
How long you been on top?
Ten years.
Ever since I got in here.
Damn. Brother, that's
a real fine record you got.
I gotta congratulate you.
Yeah! You want some of this?
Yeah! Come on!
I'm gonna win.
Come on! What?
Ain't no champ in here but me!
I'm giving you another chance.
I'm inclined to overlook
what happened this afternoon,,,
and not make it a par of
your official record,
Look, let's get something
straight, Mr. Warden.
I'm not just some convict
doing five to ten.
I'm a real big deal.
Not only am I
heavyweight champ...
I'm close to being the most
famous man in the world.
So if you think
you're gonna lean on me...
like these punks
you got in here...
you better think again...
because if anything
happens to me...
it's gonna be on
the 6:00 news worldwide.
There's gonna be
a whole lot of people...
askin' a whole lot
of questions...
and you and your little crew
here better know that.
Just my luck he got sent here.
Iceman, my ass.
He's just another goddamn thug.
One who happens
to be a world champion...
and a potential
public relations nightmare.
Mr. Hutchen.
You know the little problem...
you had with
the Iceman yesterday?
Got you in some trouble.
Heavyweight champ.
Man gave me a cheap shot.
Yeah, I know,
By the court
and the higher powers,,,
you contributed to a situation
that threatened violence.
One thing you ought
to know by now, Monroe,
Life ain't fair,
Not fair at all,
The warden understands,,,
what he's doing
is unfortunate,,,
but unless Mr. Hutchen
and the Iceman are separated,,,
there will be
enormous pressure,,,
for another
physical confrontation,
Nobody likes this...
but Mr. Hutchen's presence
is an incitement to violence...
and he will be kept in there
until such time...
as we can make arrangements for
his travel to another facility.
OK.
Hey, Monroe.
Take care of yourself
in there, Monroe.
Sergeant Marinez
to the hill tower,
New duty roster just got posted.
You're working
in the kitchen with me.
Look, since we're gonna
be stuck together...
what you in here for?
You know, champ,
I don't mean to be...
telling you what to do
or anything, but...
it's not considered polite
to ask why we're here.
Kinda violation of the ethics.
You know, the code?
Yeah.
People take it as disrespect.
Yo! You keeping in shape,
Mr. Iceman?
Who's this chump?
Call him Ratbag.
Runs with Monroe.
Shit.
Thinks he's his manager,
-Ratbag?
-Ratbag.
OK, Ratbag,
what you in here for?
-Me?
-Yeah, you.
Arson.
Nothin' up close and personal.
You hit people much?
What do you mean?
You know, punch people.
When you were a kid
or since you been in here.
Sometimes. Not much.
I never was the physical type.
You want to hit me?
What, are you kidding?
You can say you did it.
"I punched
the heavyweight champ."
You can tell people
all about it.
It might even make you...
feel good about
your little punk-ass self.
I don't want to hit you, Iceman.
Shit!
Sure you do!
You don't even like me.
Come on, man.
Go crazy. Let one go.
If I hit you just this once,
will that end it?
I won't have to hit you anymore?
All you gotta do
is hit me one time...
and I'm telling you, man,
it'll make you feel good...
and it ain't gonna hurt me none.
Aright. Just once.
Just to satisfy whatever
weird trip you're on...
and show you
that I'm a good guy...
trying to do what you want.
Right. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Unh!
Ohh! Yeah, baby!
Oh, yeah! Yeah!
I hit the Iceman!
Yo!
-Yeah!
-Thank you.
You still feel good, Ratbag?
Yeah. I guess so.
You're not mad, are you?
Ohh! Damn!
No, I'm not mad at you.
Now, you go tell Monroe
what I said.
Ain't but one champ in here!
And it ain't some
nickel-and-dime convict,,,
beating up on fools in prison!
Get that bitch outta here.
# Yo, assemble the criminals #
# With subliminal
brought to the forefront #
# Hey, ain't nobody
know I'm in here #
# Check me, you'll learn
to respect me #
# Homeboy, don't correct me #
# I'll call you out,
step on necks #
# Man, I'm better,
stand over #
# Took out them cocky,
wanna be Rocky #
# Niggers that ran up
from the outside #
# The inside my metal cell #
# Who the hell
wanna star bitching #
# Get across in the kitchen #
# End up in the infirmary #
# On close watch, talk shit #
# That ass will get muted #
# Fuckin' with the undisputed #
I ain't gotta spend my time
makin' potato salad.
Where I come from...
we didn't have
any kind of salads.
Where's that?
Indian country. Oklahoma.
Hmm.
Look, man, I know
I'm not supposed to ask...
but what you in here for?
I stole some rich guy's
Mercedes in L.A.
I got a Mercedes. Three of 'em.
Mr. Hutchen.
It's Darlene Early, the G.A.O.
General administration officer.
I need to do
the interview and paperwork...
for your transfer to Folsom.
How are your spirits?
I want you to know...
I'm not in favor
of solitary confinement.
Not for you,
not for anybody else.
It's OK in here.
You can't be serious.
It's all a prison.
I live inside my head.
So that's how
you're doing your time?
Are you really that much
in control of your emotions?
Been that way all my life.
Only time I ever lost it
is what got me in here.
Yeah. I'm familiar
with your case history.
So you prefer your own company?
Most of the time.
I am supposed to recommend
whether or not...
you seem to require a detailed
psychiatric evaluation.
Other than the incident
in the mess hall--
That wasn't me.
Why don't you
go talk to the hotshot champ?
Ask him about it.
So you deny any responsibility?
Yeah, I deny it. How does
that affect me movin' on?
This has no bearing
in your transfer to Folsom.
You know, this whole thing...
this whole thing
is about people bein' scared.
Aren't you afraid of him?
Afraid. Shit, no.
He's a fighter. I'm a fighter.
If I'm better on that day,
I win.
That's just the way it goes.
Someday, ever fighter loses.
Sooner or later,
somebody comes along...
and they got your ticket.
Too old, just wasn't your day,
whatever the reason is.
in the end,
everybody gets beaten.
The most you can hope for
is that you stay on top a while.
Be the best.
I tried to say hello
to that old gangster.
Ripstein.
He said he don't remember you.
He remembers.
He just don't want to admit it.
Standard mob procedure.
Guys like him deny
they ever had a mother.
Yeah. Right.
How you makin' out, man?
It's shit, but I can handle it.
Yeah. Rumor goin' around
you almost stared a riot.
It was all bullshit, man.
I had to let the peeps in here
know who's the boss.
Just keep
your goddamn nose clean.
You already got
enough problems.
And since they stripped
you of your title...
they're having this
elimination tournament...
to figure out a new champ.
Everybody thinks
Briscoe's a lock to win it.
Word is, Montel's fighting
Jimmy Stubbs in July.
Jimmy Stubbs's a bum.
The good news is
you get outta here...
fight the new champ,
we're looking at...
the biggest payday
of boxing history.
-Mm-hmm.
-Yeah.
The one thing I can tell you,
you lost a lot of fan base...
with this conviction thing.
Fuck the fans.
I get outta here,
I'll get 'em back.
The fans pay your bills,
and don't you ever forget it.
Yeah.
You gotta keep the pressure
on these lawyers, OK...
and get you outta here
to fight this...
big money fight with Briscoe.
Yeah.
You can't be servin'
no full sentence.
You're 35 years old.
Time is tickin'.
Everything
you ever worked for...
it's going
right out the window.
Janiro's an agile boxer,,,
who has the ability
of a champion,
Janiro is fresh off
a victor,,,
over Charlie Consario,
The Rock turns it on,
It's Le Graziano alone,
He won't give Janiro
punching room,
Stays after his man,
Hits him from all angles,
He remembers things
from a long time ago,,,
clear as a bell,,,
but ever day,
I gotta tell him who I am.
He's in another world:
Cuba, forty years ago...
or some fight he saw in 1953.
Then all of a sudden...
he's right there with you,
like everything's normal.
And mean--
he can be mean as shit.
Look, we went to the Emme.
We paid good money
for his protection...
and his personal needs.
They gave you the job.
I got him
an oversized cell--
ground level, so he don't
have to use the stairs.
Food privileges.
Relaxed dress code.
Big easy chair.
I even got him his own
little boxing library.
And he's safe. I promise.
These guys I got, they don't
let any harm come his way.
# It's hard in the yard #
# You can't be sleepin'
or caught off guard #
# When the boys get to creepin'
with sharp objects #
# I'm obsessed with putin'
heads in a permanent rest #
# When I flex
thirty-four-inch biceps #
# Getin' swell,
might put your lights out #
# Spend the night
in the hole, in here #
# Ever hear is cold #
# It's the gatherin'
of lost souls #
# No self-control #
# Connected with the gangsters
runnin' this shit #
# From the inside,
so there's nowhere to hide #
# Tell your mama that
you'll never come home #
Hey, chief.
Mmm.
How you getting along
with your new cellmate?
-He's OK.
-Mmm.
Rumor has it he took down
one of the skinheads.
A lot of rumors in prison,
you know?
Ah, probably deserved it anyway.
Maybe.
We hear you don't want to
associate with anybody here.
Maybe you got
way too much attitude, man.
Unh.
Aaron's an expert.
He's the man on appeals.
But before we talk
about your appeal...
I need to tell you about
Miss Tawnee Rawlins.
She's filed a civil lawsuit
in the amount of $75 million.
You handlin' that?
I'd recommend
an outside attorney.
Another specialist.
However, we can handle
your tax litigation.
The government has filed
an intent to audit.
We have someone in the firm
that can deal with that.
ls any of this covered...
by the $2 million
I already paid you?
We get the same deal as you get.
You get paid win or lose.
So do we.
There are a couple
of procedural areas...
that are still in question--
possible reversible error.
But I'm not gonna kid you.
I'd make us a long shot.
You're looking at
a six- to eight-year sentence...
with possible time off
for good behavior.
Now, in California,
that means...
you're eligible for parole
in four years.
What you need to focus on...
is if you become
a model prisoner...
exhibit
special circumstances...
you could be considered
for a work furlough...
as soon as eighteen months
to two years.
So it don't matter
whether I did it or not?
It doesn't work that way.
Justice and the law
are separate issues.
Let's get back to
some of your other problems.
We've done an audit.
Your financial situation
is a mess.
-No, that's bullshit.
-No bullshit.
Big financial settlements
with your ex-wives, entourage.
Bad investments
and misrepresentations...
by your ex-business manager.
I'm gonna sue that motherfucker.
And what about this IRS shit?
Where do I stand on that?
By the firm's calculations,
you could end up owing them...
$7 million in back taxes,
and that's just the feds.
Then there's the state.
The bottom line--
we need to get
your black ass outta here...
and back in the ring.
Clive Johnson
here ringside,,,
for KHIL Channel 13
in the Bay Area,
Next, round seven
of the California,,,
state heavyweight
championship fight,,,
here from the Palmer Arena
in downtown Oakland,
Challenger Monroe Hutchen's
undefeated,,,
takin' on
state champ Butch Davis,,,
in what, so far,
has been a nearly even fight,
There's the bell!
Davis has a bad cut
above his left eye,,,
and Monroe Hutchen
looks like,,,
he wants to do
something about it,
It's all Monroe,
it's all Monroe!
A big right hand,
Another right!
Davis is down,
and this fight is over!
After forty-three seconds
in the seventh round,,,
Monroe Hutchen is the new,,,
California state
heavyweight champion!
Your attorneys have
come to me and asked me,,,
to handle your response
to the plaintiff's filing,
As you know, you are now facing
a separate civil suit...
that may well go to trial...
over the criminal charges
you've been convicted of.
Briefly, "That on March 17,
you and four other men...
"took six women
via private jet...
"from Las Vegas
to Los Angeles--"
Showgirls.
"At approximately 1:30 p.m....
"you checked into
the penthouse suite...
"of the Beverly Manor hotel."
Until that point of the evening,
all parties concede...
but for minor discrepancies,
the foregoing is true.
What happened next
is in question.
No question.
I ain't no punk-ass rapist.
She wanted it.
Look. None of this makes
any difference at this point.
We're just trying
to get an over--
No. She didn't say no.
She ain't say shit.
She didn't have a problem
with any of it.
Miss Rawlins
effectively convinced...
the criminal trial jury
that she believed that...
you could break her
in two with one arm.
Yeah, uh-huh.
That's why she was makin'
all them happy sounds...
'cause I was killin' her,
right?
Some women like it rough.
You know anything about that?
That wasn't par
of your testimony.
A lawyer said don't sound
like I'm calling her a ho.
The prosecution
pegged you as a bully.
And she could explain it away
easily enough by saying...
that you mistook what were
in fact her cries for help...
for she was just in pain.
I heard pain before,
and--ha ha ha--
believe me,
she wasn't in no pain.
She's asking $75 million...
but I don't like negotiating
with your appeal pending.
No negotiatin'.
I ain't givin' that bitch shit.
And then when he finished,
he just put back on his pants...
and went back out
into the party...
and left me alone.
# Ohh #
# Man up #
# Motherfucker,
you are now in jail #
# Man up #
# Motherfucker, where
it's strange as hell #
# 'Cause you's
a no-booty and so,,, #
# Man up #
# Motherfucker, get your
manhood took #
# Man up #
Champ,,,
I'm looking to be
your friend, Champ,
I'm a gift.
Well, I don't need no gifts.
Who sent you?
Saladin.
He want to be your friend.
He kind of run things
for El Faziz Assassins.
You can check it out.
You kind of pretty for a bitch.
But I don't want to owe nobody.
You tell him I said that.
Now get outta here.
You may be the champ,
but you are only one guy.
Let me help you out.
El Faziz Assassins give you
something, you take it.
You do not refuse.
I'm looking for Saladin.
Pleased to meet a man of
your great accomplishments.
You run shit here?
There's strength in unity,
brother.
In here we need cooperation
and understanding.
We are at times
discriminated against...
even within these walls.
Now, if you wish to come
and join with us--
Oh!
Brother,
if you don't join with us...
you'll be destroying
the unity we create.
Warden wants to see you.
That's quite a show
you put on there.
Come on. Let's go.
I'm disappointed.
Three incidents already,
one a near riot...
one an assault and now
a physical confrontation...
that has sent five men
to the hospital...
for medical treatment.
You've only been here ten weeks.
It is undeniable--
you are making
a very poor record.
The whole thing is,
they got to respect you...
or you nothin'.
I believe that
you're missing the point.
The warden is trying
to explain the idea...
of acceptable behavior.
I'm trying to explain to him
how to survive.
I don't think there
are too many inmates here...
who could challenge you
physically, Mr. Chambers.
You really don't understand.
When you're the champ,
everybody wants a piece of you.
Everybody’s testing you.
My whole life, I got a problem,
I take care of it with these.
People love a guy who can fight.
Money, pussy, kiss your ass,
put you on TV...
put your picture
in papers, magazines...
anything I want, because people
love a guy who can fight...
and don't take shit.
# Murder #
# The choice I made,
so now I pay #
# Thinkin' back,
I have to ask #
# How'd it end this way? #
# You see,
it all happened so fast #
# I couldn't think twice #
# Now I'm chillin'
for killin' #
# And I'm payin' the price #
Who I'm with is none
of your business!
None of my business?
I'll deal with you--
Stop it!
You're killing him!
On the night
of December 1, 1990...
you beat a man to death
with your bare fists...
which because
of your profession,,,
and your training
are considered,,,
to be lethal weapons
in the state of California,
You've been found guilty
by a jury of your peers,,,
and you are sentenced
to life imprisonment,,,
without the possibility
of parole,
Good morning, Mr. Ripstein.
How are you today?
Don't give me no shit.
How the hell
is the fight comin'?
What fight?
We got the heavyweight
champion of the world...
and an unbeaten prospect
right here in Sweetwater.
Quit wasting time.
Set the fuckin' thing up.
I know fights.
Long prize,
Monroe kicks his ass...
we can make
a lot of money here.
Mr. Ripstein, excuse me,
but you're talking about...
the real heavyweight
champion of the world.
Are you gonna fix the fight?
Shit no. Boxing.
It's a matter of style.
They all can be beaten.
Right time, right place,
the right circumstance...
they all can be beaten.
Mr. Ripstein wants
to see the Iceman...
fight a prisoner
we got in here.
His name is Monroe Hutchen.
And a real goddamn fight. Pure.
So, what do you want us to do?
I talked to the head guard.
He's OK.
But the warden's a problem.
Mr. Ripstein said
you can take care of him.
You know the drill.
You help him or you hurt him.
Now...about Monroe Hutchen.
The warden thinks it's time...
to give him a chance
to rehabilitate himself...
by socializing
with the other prisoners.
In six weeks,
I'm going on vacation.
On the fifth,
I'll be gone for two weeks.
First week in New Orleans...
second week visiting friends
in Tucson, Arizona.
If while I am gone...
if Mr. Hutchen happens to
get into a sparring match...
with Mr. Chambers,
I don't want to hear about it.
And when I get back...
I want this whole goddamned
enterprise finished.
Yes, sir.
Leaving no evidence,
no videotape...
and never to be spoken of
in my presence.
-Anything else, sir?
-Hit the yard.
Thank you.
Had to have been somebody
in the governor's office.
Soon as he got the call...
Mr. Backbone stared
arranging his vacation.
Know what that means,
don't you?
This whole load of shit
comes down on you and me.
There is no "you and me."
I'm taking my vacation
right along with the warden.
Well, thank you
for your support.
Oh, come on.
You run the fight program here.
You want this to happen.
Here we go, Monroe.
Free at last, free at last.
-I'm not going to Folsom.
-What can I tell you?
Looks like the warden
went and changed his mind.
You get to stay home with us.
Yeah, Operator,
a collect call to Yank Lewis.
No. Yank Lewis.
From George Chambers,
the Iceman.
Yank. Yeah, man, it's me.
Who the hell you think it is?
Get your ass up here
and share the beauty.
Maybe I gotaa ticket
back on the gravy train,
What?
What are you talking about?
Remember your old buddy
from Miami, Mendy Ripstein?
Yeah,
His boy came up to me
and said...
that if I fight
some punk in here...
he could maybe
get me out quick.
If Mendy Ripstein says it,
then it's the real deal.
But you can't hear this
from some other guy.
You gotta hear this
from Mendy himself.
Then it's dope for sure.
If it's on the real,
I'll whip on this punk's ass...
and be out of here.
Who's the punk?
Don't tell me Monroe Hutchen.
He fought out of Oakland.
He was undefeated.
He was a real prospect, man.
He's a full load.
Even if he was something,
he's been in here for ten years.
I'm just saying it might not be
a walk in the park.
-I don't believe this shit.
-What?
You worried about me
being out of shape.
I've been in here
for four months.
That chump been in here
for ten years.
-You too much, man.
-What? That's concern--
Get the fuck outta here.
Yes, I want you to fight him,
In the cage, no gloves,
bare-fisted, to the finish,
I make a couple of calls,
I put down some money,,,
There's some people
on the outside,,,
that know you,
everybody knows him,,,
we'll get maybe twenty,
thirty-to-one odds,
It's easy to spread around,
maybe two hundred thousand,
You win, that's
four million bucks, maybe more.
And I think he can't wait.
What's in it for me?
Mr. Ripstein
uses his influence...
you stay out of solitar...
get the privileges
you been missing.
Privileges?
Offer me half the profit,
Oh, I don't think so.
I'm putting up all the dough
on a real long shot.
I'm taking all the risk.
What are you worried
about money for?
What are you gonna
buy in here?
You in here, too.
Probably gonna die in here.
What the money matter to you?
You're gonna get ten percent.
I know that fighters
usually get...
fifty percent, minimum,
on the outside.
Yeah, but we're not outside.
I want more.
I got a sister,
she got three kids...
no job, no skills, no husband.
Government gives her
a check once a month.
I could send her the money.
You're gonna get thirty percent
of everything we win.
It's a deal?
Forty percent.
That's it.
You wanted to see the Iceman?
Mr. Ripstein thanks you
for bringing him...
to this neutral location.
The Iceman doesn't want
any disappointments.
He expects to negotiate.
You have to understand...
that Mr. Ripstein is
a great boxing enthusiast...
a great student of the art...
a great historian
of the prize ring.
Mr. Ripstein
believes the truest,,,
purest expression
of the sport,,,
was the bare-knuckle fights
of the Nineteenth Century...
the Queensbury rules.
Oh, no, no.
The London Prize Ring rules.
Queensbury changed the rules
to the ones that we got now.
Look, let's cut through
all this bullshit.
I want out.
Otherwise, no fight.
How you gonna pull it off?
We handle that through
the Department of Corrections.
We got a guy on the committee.
I got your word on this?
You better get ready to fight.
# Train all day #
# You know I gotta feel
the pain all day #
# Work hard even if
it rain on me #
# Nothing less than
five miles in the morning #
# I'm jogging and yawning #
# Stick and move,
intense, here we go #
# One, two,
come up the ring now #
# What you gonna do? #
# Showboat when
I expose the ribs #
# Watch for the hook #
# Place bets, hey,
money on the books #
# You ain't seen a fight
till you seen what I took #
# I got precision,
the jab keep you #
# At the perfect distance,
and it can be done #
The fight is six weeks
from tomorrow night.
Y'all got that amount of time
to get your fighters in shape.
These are the rules.
Mr. Ripstein has gone
through a lot of trouble...
putting them together.
What about a foul?
Who's gonna ref this thing?
There isn't any referee.
That's one of the rules.
What kind of shit is this, huh?
Mr. Mercker can judge fouls
from outside the cage.
No kicking, butting, low blows.
If you win or lose on a foul,
all deals are off.
This is a bunch of crap, OK?
My guy's got a lot more to lose
than this other chump.
Nowhere to train properly,
First there's no gloves,
then these dumbass rules.
Truth is, we don't know shit
about fighting this way.
And that makes you even.
[Rap plays softly]
# Train all day #
# Even though I gotta feel
the pain all day #
# Work hard even if
it rain on me #
# Nothing less than
five miles in the morning #
# I'm jogging and yawning #
# Stick and move,
intense, here we go #
# One, two,
come up the ring now #
# What you gonna do? #
# Showboat when
I expose the ribs #
# It's the standard
arrangement #
# Trust me,
they'll crown me the king #
# Learn a routine
and get between #
# Because I'm still
the champeen #
Mr. Ripstein, I don't
want to cause no trouble,
I wanted to talk to you
about the rules, you know?
Actually, about the gloves.
There aren't any gloves.
It says so on page three
of the rules.
Yeah, I know,
but it'll make for a dull fight.
I mean, bare knuckles,
nobody throws a lot.
If you watch those old films...
of Jack Johnson
and Jeffries and Cornet--
Those guys were trained
in bare-knuckle style, you know?
It was like a news flash
when somebody threw a punch.
I just want to make it
clear that I agree...
but my boy?
He don't give a shit.
Gloves, no gloves,
it don't matter.
Bring him on.
We ain't backing up for nobody.
Jab, baby! That's right, jab!
Be a lot more
hitting with gloves.
I gave you a copy of
the London Prize Fight Rules...
that Mr. Ripstein typed out,
and it says "No gloves."
No. Wait a minute.
He's right.
It's a better fight
with six-ounce gloves.
Get 'em,
[Hip-hop music plays]
Monroe!
How you doing, brother?
First, there's a smile,
then comes a cheap shot, huh?
I guess nobody's dumb enough
to fall for that twice, huh?
You got that right, Mr. Iceman.
You can call me Champ.
Now see, you've been told.
In here, I'm the champ.
You believe that, you must
believe in the tooth fair.
Nobody's backing up.
Hold on, brother.
You gonna get your chance.
[Bass music plays slowly]
Good evening,
I'm Maureen O'Boyle,
Tonight on CNO X's
"The inside Story",,,
we'll be talking
with Tawnee Rawlins,,,
in an exclusive interview,,,
that will be her
first public statement...
since the sensational
trial and conviction...
of George "Iceman" Chambers...
former heavyweight
champion of the world.
Thanks for being
with us, Tawnee.
I was scared.
I didn't want
to be there anymore.
I--I didn't want
to do nothing with him...
but he wouldn't stop.
This whole thing
is just such a mess.
I've been out of work...
since this
whole thing happened...
and I had to have lots
of doctors and lawyers...
and I got stacks of mail
from people...
saying that they hate me...
because I took away
their heavyweight champ...
and that I'm a gold digger
and all that...
but I say
walk a mile in my shoes.
I did not want
to cause him any harm...
but he wouldn't listen to me,
and he wouldn't stop.
These dumb shits been watching
too many old prison movies.
You get on the horn.
Get me a situation red in here.
Central security,
this is the mess hall.
We have a situation red.
Repeat, a situation red.
We've got a situation,
Get down to the mess,
On the double, all right?
Riot's coming down,
Hey, Iceman!
Hey, Iceman.
Before you came here...
we all figured
you were some kind of dude.
Then you show up
actin' like you're the God...
and we're the sod,
Well, hey, man,
ever dog in here,,,
wanted to see you
get your ass kicked,
You're goin' down, man!
Shit.
[All chanting "Monroe"]
Kick your ass, motherfucker!
Let's go! Move!
Move! Move! Move!
Give 'em one!
Take out the ceiling!
Again!
He cancelled the fight,
Jesus fuckin' Christ,
this fuckin' state.
Who the fuck
does this fuckin' warden...
fuckin' think he is?
Doesn't anybody know how to do
business in this fuckin' state?
My fuckin' wife and her fuckin'
asthma and allergies.
We had to move
to the fuckin' desert.
Goddamn fuckin'
chickenshit doctors...
I should've known better than
listen to those shitheels.
Fuckin' Palm Springs...
Lay there in the fuckin' sun
and do nothin'.
Then this fuckin' state
grabs my ass for taxes.
Why the fuck I didn't stay
in fuckin' Florida...
where people know how
to do fuckin' business.
Fuckin' wife
and her fuckin' asthma.
Shit,
Somethin' needs
to get fuckin' done...
I gotta do it myself.
Call the fuckin' warden.
I wanna meet him.
Yes, sir, Mr. Ripstein.
I don't make it a habit
of meeting with prisoners.
I'm doing this out of deference
to Mr. Mercker here...
who thought
it'd be a good idea.
However, any attempt to have me
reinstate the fight...
between Mr. Chambers and
Monroe Hutchen will be futile.
It has been
irrevocably cancelled.
Can I tell you a story?
One of my favorites.
It's about how things get done.
This is a story that
takes place in about--
it must've been
the middle 1950s.
I was second in charge
of certain operations...
second to a Mr. Meyer Lansky.
There was this casino--
a new one--
that had been built
in a neighboring town.
But the mayor, he wanted
to close that casino...
because he did not
like gambling.
He thought it brought
the wrong kind of people.
So he ordered
the casino closed. Ohh.
I had to report this
to Mr. Lansky.
So Mr. Lansky,
he told me, he says...
"You tell that mayor...
"that the casino stays open,
no question"...
but that the mayor
had a choice.
He could choose to be killed,
or he could choose to have...
a great deal of money
deposited in his bank account.
It was his choice.
In either case,
the casino stays open.
What happened to the mayor?
He died,
He hit his ignition and his car
exploded like a fireball.
You're gonna stand there and
let this hoodlum threaten me?
Well, sir, I don't much
want my car to blow up.
We could
talk about the money...
when you come back
from your vacation.
I understand
you're leaving tomorrow?
All of us, we hope
you and your family...
have a very pleasant time.
Time!
We're gonna limo over
a few guys from Vegas--
act as witnesses.
Chuy, we've been talkin'.
We need you
to go to the Iceman.
Get a number.
We're gettin' a hell
of a price on Monroe.
We need the Iceman
to go for it.
Ask him to lie down?
I don't see it.
Offer him a million.
He made $25 million the last
time he fought somebody.
-He had to fight for that one.
-Talk to him.
You got it wrong.
You hired me
to look after Mendy.
I'm looking after him
right now.
Mendy wants a straight fight.
It's not the money.
Bullshit! In New York,
in Cuba, in Florida...
his whole life,
it's always about the money.
He's got it stashed
all over the place.
Fuckin' millions.
He's got ever fuckin'
nickel he ever made.
With Mendy,
it's always about the money.
You guys are way off
Mendy's radar on this deal...
and I don't want
to mess it up for him.
Mendy wants a straight fight
to the finish, and that's it.
You want the Iceman to dump?
You go talk to him.
But don't get your hopes up.
OK, Monroe, now that
this thing is back on...
here's the deal.
We got a guy in the dispensary.
He's gonna steal five or ten
Valiums, crush 'em up.
And I got another guy
in the commissar.
Last meal Iceman eats before
he fights, we mix it in.
Just enough to slow him down,
fuck him up.
Now, he'll still fight,
but he won't be the same.
That'll be just enough
to give you the edge.
You got it?
You do that, I'm gonna
break you up into pieces.
I can take this guy,
and I don't need no help.
You understand that?
Hey! We're just trying
to give you...
a little something extra, man.
We got a lot of money
on this table.
I may not be a real good guy...
but I ain't no chickenshit,
either. You remember that.
Take him down.
OK. We got ourselves
ninety minutes.
We just concentrate. We focus.
We mentally imagine
ourselves winning.
Just close your eyes.
We concentrate.
We see ourselves winning.
We see Iceman all beat to shit.
In twenty minutes,
we star to loosen up, OK?
Break a sweat.
We don't want this shithead
to catch you cold.
Hey, you get sloppy,
that's when mistakes happen.
All right,
cell blocks A, B, C, and D...
if all y'all
are ready over there...
let's star movin' em in
on fifteen-minute intervals.
Let's get
the fighters in here!
Tear it up, Monroe, tear it up!
Yeah.
He's shit! Iceman is shit!
He is shit! Yeah.
That's it, that's it!
That's my man! Go!
Go ahead, now!
Yeah, let it go,
let it go, let it go!
And now,
Sweetwater's the Gat Boyz...
will sing the national anthem!
[Hip-hop beat playing]
# Oh, say can you see #
# By the dawn's early light #
# What so proudly
we hail'd,,, #
You're livin'. You're hot.
Just listen to 'em. Yeah.
He is a guest,
and this is your house!
He is an unwelcome guest.
# Ever inmate wanna be free #
# Ever hustler wanna be me #
Go ahead, baby!
Yeah, let it go! Let it go!
# O'er the land
of the free,,, #
He don't look good.
He's ugly.
# And the home of the brave #
It's time! It's time!
Fighters to the ring!
Fight's on! Fight's on!
# Now the time has come #
# Time #
# No place to run #
# Might get burned up
by the sun #
# Time #
# But I'll have my fun #
Good evening, honored guests,
scumbags, and Mr. Mercker...
the time is now!
We got a first here,
my friends...
courtesy of a great man,
whose name I cannot say.
Fight fans all over the world
are gonna be wishin',,,
they's in the bottom
of the barrel with us,,,
wishin' Sweetwater Prison
was their home tonight!
Now pay close attention...
'cause I'm only
gonna say this once.
The fight you're about to see
follows a set of rules...
never been used before
around here.
London Prize Rules:
no traditional rounds
to speak of...
no regulation-size gloves...
just those bitty six-ounce
suckers gonna tear up.
A fighter steps from
the mark ready to fight.
He go down, then he got
sixty seconds to come back.
That's it!
Fight to the finish! No ref!
All we got is the timekeeper
for the mark!
Our very own Mr. Mercker,
the walkin' boss.
Now put your hands together,
my friends...
for our favorite son...
Sweetwater's
defending champion...
undefeated,
with a prison record...
of 68 wins, no losses,
weighing in at 199 pounds...
wearing the burgundy trunks
with the black trim...
Monroe...Monroe...
Monroe Hutchen!
Now give it up
for the west corner.
He's also undefeated...
on the outside.
Weighing in at 205,,,
the former heavyweight
champion of the world,,,
George "Iceman" Chambers!
Come on, motherfucker!
There's only
one thing I got to say--
put his ass
between his shoulders!
OK, brother cons,
we are ready!
Now, don't let your passion
for the great Monroe...
interfere with good judgment,
and don't do nothin' stupid!
That'll forfeit
all the money...
that you guys bet
at those big odds.
And welcome to our amigos
from Las Vegas...
here to witness this contest
and report it,,,
to various cities
all around our great country,
Whole lotta bookmakers
out there want to know...
what's comin' down.
Well, it's us against
the world, my brothers,
And just like you, I too am
for the great Monroe Hutchen!
He brought honor
to our house of pain...
but I will call
a neutral fight.
Come on, bitch.
This is the fight
for what's right,
This is the brawl for it all!
This fight ain't about money!
This is their
heavyweight champion,,,
against our
heavyweight champion!
This fight is for respeck!
R-e-s-p-e-c-k!
Respeck!
Round one! Round one!
And here we go, baby.
They move
to the center of the ring,,,
feelin' each other out,
You gotta remember something:
Monroe is
a forty-to-one underdog,,,
goin' up against the Iceman,
a great champion,
Combinations, man!
Combinations!
Monroe swings and misses,
Iceman counters,,,
with a hard right hand
to the head!
-That's it, baby, come on!
-Hit that big motherfucker!
Monroe's
backpedaling, circling,
Doesn't look
like he's too willing,,,
to trade punches
with the Iceman,
Watch it, Monroe,
watch it, now, baby!
Lookin' for a way
to get to Monroe,
Now he's tauntin' him!
He's tauntin' Monroe!
He's taunting him!
Monroe swings,
The Iceman hits him
with a hard right,,,
and a left to Monroe's head!
You ain't hurt him!
Hey, bullshit!
Oh, Monroe misses,,,
and the Iceman tags him
with a hard left hand,,,
and Monroe
is going backwards, baby,
The Iceman tauntin' him on,
Get in his face!
Monroe lands an overhand right!
Now a combination!
Monroe's getting himself
into this fight!
The Iceman counters with
a hard right to the face,
Another right to the head,
Monroe is fast, but the Iceman
is much stronger,
They hook up again! Both men
exchanging combinations!
Right hand!
Left! Right! Right!
And boom!
The Iceman drives Monroe back!
Make him bleed, man,
make him bleed!
Both men throw combinations!
Left! Right! Overhand right!
Monroe misses,
The Iceman comes back,,,
with a right-left to the head!
Get him!
They're fighting
at an incredible pace!
Can you believe it?
Nice overhand right
by Monroe!
Iceman's not hurt, but he
ties Monroe up in a clinch!
Oh, shit, baby! Go get him!
Hard right hand!
Yeah! Another one! Move!
Monroe swings and misses,,,
and the Iceman
keeps hurting' him,,,
with an overhand right,
Combination, right-left!
Big left hook!
A right and a left
to the stomach,
Another left--
oh, an uppercut!
And Monroe is down!
Sixty seconds!
And we now know why
he's the heavyweight champion...
of the world.
Huh? Huh? Huh?
Huh? What? What?
And Monroe is up!
Looks like he will continue,
Hey, Iceman, you ain't shit!
You just got robbed!
The Iceman's straight-ahead,
locomotive style,,,
may be a little too much
for Monroe,
He's never had to face
anything like this,
-Boo!
-Fuck!
-Come on, big daddy!
The Iceman's in his corner,,,
a mighty confident man,
That's what you gotta do!
Let's go!
Monroe's trademark of
occasionally switching,,,
to a southpaw
left-hand style--
ain't workin' so far, baby!
Ten seconds!
Fighters to the line!
Clear the ring!
Pucker up, motherfucker.
Round Two!
And here we go, baby!
Despite the knockdown,
Monroe looks,,,
like he's pulled himself
back together,
The Iceman misses,,,
and Monroe lands
an overhand right!
Right hand! Right hand!
A quick-hit exchange!
Now this is boxing!
Hard combinations,,,
and they clinch!
Beautiful! Beautiful!
Ooh, what a right hand
by the Iceman!
Another right to the head,
Monroe misses,,,
and pays for it dearly
to the body,,,
and he reels back
from the punishment,,,
given to him by the Iceman,
Another hard right and left,
and Monroe is on his heels!
He's up against the fence!
The Iceman
is going for the body!
Another one to the body,
and it doesn't look good,,,
for Sweetwater’s
own favorite son,
The Iceman's all over him!
He's tearin' Monroe up!
Oh, another right
to the head!
Monroe's down, and he's dizzy
as a motherfucker!
He's talkin' shit, baby!
He's talkin' shit!
Who the hell you think--
I know he ain't talkin' to me,
He's talkin' to y'all!
That's right! Yeah! Uh-huh!
Monroe's wobbly, He's shaky,
There's no question about it,
Monroe is hurt!
Come on! Come on!
Don't get careless.
Knock him on his ass!
Now take a whiff of this.
Come on.
This fight is far from over.
You're gonna get him.
We got plenty of time.
He just loves
to taunt the crowd,
He's got everything
going his way,
Oh, that Iceman is
one cocky son of a bitch,
He's already knocked
him down twice, Eddie!
I don't know how much longer
this has got to go.
You gotta fight your fight!
You're fightin' his fight.
You control the rhythm.
You gotta
turn this fight around!
You can do it, Monroe!
Come on, now!
This is your round!
The Iceman lookin'
supremely confident,
He's got it all goin' his way!
Round three!
They come out,
and it seems like the Iceman,,,
is just trin'
to find that one big shot,,,
that'll put Monroe
on his ass,,,
and give him a one-way
ticket to Bootyville.
Oh! A big right hand
by the Iceman!
And another right hand
This can't go much furher!
That's it! That's it!
Come on, Mo! Dance with him!
Both of these men
are great warriors,
Iceman has a look
of determination in his eye--
but like I said before,
brother scumbags,,,
he's lookin' for that big punch
to end it all for Monroe,
The Iceman is clearly
in control of this fight,
But Monroe
is still there, baby.
Our favorite son
is still standin',
Oh, that right hand just
keeps shakin' Monroe up!
Stay strong! Stay strong!
Big left and right
comin' from the Iceman!
He is all over Monroe!
And the Iceman is on the hunt!
He's on the prowl!
He's goin' in for the kill!
Oh, God!
What a devastating
left hook from Monroe!
The Iceman is staggering,
and he's hurt!
Oh, Monroe hits him
with another shot!
He's drivin' him
back up against the cage,,,
punishing him
with wicked combinations!
Monroe is all over him!
He's hurt! He's hurt!
Left, and right!
Oh, shit.
Can you believe it?!
Ohh! And a right hand
puts the Iceman down!
The Iceman is down,,,
for the first time
in his career!
Sixty seconds!
Shit!
This is unbelievable,
Unbelievable!
Way to go, Monroe!
I can't believe it!
The Iceman is down!
And the Iceman is up,
He's staggerin' around,
He doesn't know where he is,
Oh, my God, he's gone
plum-fuckin'-crazy in there!
The Iceman's gone
absolutely crazy,
This could be it, This could be
a disqualification,
Somebody get in there
and stop this thing!
I got a lotta damn money
ridin' on this!
Pandemonium! Out of control!
[Crowd chants "Monroe"]
Monroe has definitely
turned this fight around,
What goes on in the mind
of George "Iceman" Chambers,,,
at this moment
is anybody's guess,
This is one
for the record books, baby,
People are gonna be talking
about this,,,
for the rest of their life,
and if I knew,,,
I had to go to jail
to see a fight like this...
I'd have did a crime
a long time ago!
This is your night!
This is your house, baby!
Don't let up! Go at him!
Stick him hard!
Take him out, baby! Come on!
Ten seconds!
Fighters to the line!
You can do it!
Kick his ass!
Let's go, Monroe, let's go!
That was
the toughest round,,,
in the Iceman's whole career,
He must regain momentum,
He must come out strong,
He must get back
in this fight!
Oh! And he is back!
A left and a right to Monroe!
Monroe hits him with
a right hand, left hand,,,
and another right hand,,,
and the Iceman
is forced to clinch!
Stick him, baby! Go at him now!
Monroe switches to southpaw!
They're hookin' up!
Toe to toe!
Punch for punch!
Back and forth!
This is a war!
Oh, my god, what a fight!
And I am so happy,,,
that it's happenin' right here
at Sweetwater Prison,
Let's go, baby!
He's on the hunt!
Monroe's on the prowl!
Right hand!
A left to the stomach!
Overhand right!
Another left and a right,
and an overhand right,,,
to the head!
Monroe is punishing him,,,
with blows to the head
and the body,
Say what you want to say about
George "Iceman" Chambers,,,
but he is dead game!
It's over! It's over!
Monroe wins again! It's over!
It's over!
That's it! Monroe wins,,,
and I just won
a lot of goddamn money!
Yeah! Yeah!
You owe me money, Eddie!
You owe me money!
Monroe! Monroe!
Yeah! Yeah!
Monroe! Yeah!
But this...
this is a thing of beauty.
A great thing of beauty.
Two guys
fightin' to the finish...
but just one guy wins
because he's the better man...
and that's what
the goddamn sport is about.
Mendy Ripstein died
3 weeks after the big fight,
He kept his word,
Monroe got his money,,,
and the Iceman got out
on special parole,
I can personally
thank Mr. Ripstein,,,
for another thing,
His lawyers
contacted my family,
He left me $2 million,
free and clear,
So I guess I'm not
gonna have any excuses,,,
when I get out of here,
I read in the sports page
that Iceman and his manager,,,
both denied the fight
with Monroe ever happened,,,
and the story about him losing
was only a big rumor,,,
a fairy tale,
Once upon a time in prison,
[Rock music playing]
Our panel of experts,,,
have the fight even
at two rounds apiece,
Both fighters fighting,,,
for the heavyweight
championship of the world,,,
the greatest title
in all of sports,
One thing I can tell you
for sure,,,
life in prison hasn't changed
the Iceman's fighting style,
Both fighters feeling
each other out now,
Briscoe trying
to work the jab,
He can't get anything in,
A left to the body!
And here comes Chambers!
Another right!
A left to the body!
Right-left combination!
A left! A right!
A left hook,
and down goes Briscoe!
Down goes Briscoe!
Chambers over
to the neutral corner,,,
and referee Mathew Kerrigan
is counting it out!
Briscoe, desperately trying
to stand up,
He wants to continue,
Kerrigan has called it off!
And by knockout,,,
with one minute, 22 seconds
into the fifth round,,,
Right here!
Always was the champ!
,,,Briscoe is knocked out,
and the now-undisputed,,,
heavyweight champion
of the world,,,
is George "Iceman" Chambers!
Hey, Monroe! Iceman won!
Guess what, cat?
They say he's the heavyweight
champ of the whole world!
Undisputed! Haaaa!
Monroe!
[Chanting "Monroe"]
[Rap music playing]
# Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Uh-huh, who? #
# CMB #
# Who? Who else? #
# Who? #
# The undisputed CMB #
# We holdin' the title #
# You know why? Look #
# There ain't a cat out green
that could deal with weez #
# Homie, quick like coupes,
ah, feel the breeze #
# And I'm Holly Grove's hear,
the hood made me trill #
# The hottest hot boy,
baby, time reveal #
# And I'm Momma's oldest boy,
Papa's first seed #
# But Papa's not real,
he don't bleed what I bleed #
# I'm nineteen strong,
a kid with a kid #
# And ain't too many people
outdid what I did #
# I rock bricks down,
I rock'r town #
# I puff the best 'Bro,
pound for pound #
# Now say round,
the boy tough, not bluff #
# Eazy, weezy,
young money, squad up #
# Whoever don't like it,
mount up and down you go #
# I been a champ
like the dude Monroe #
# Not in ten years, they still
wouldn't have planned it #
# For ever one to fall,
and I still be standin' #
# We can't lose,
been through too much pain #
# Too much struggle,
and too much strain #
# This is CMR #
# Though them haters
try to lock us in #
# We got it locked
from the block to the pen #
# We can't lose,
we been through too much pain #
# Too much struggle,
and too much strain #
# This is CMR #
# Though them haters
try to lock us in #
# We got it locked
from the block to the pen #
# Undisputed #
# I'm the Iceman, whoa,
it's nothin' to ex you out #
# Put the G on the head #
# Ain't got to say it
out the mouth #
# With the beanie,
with the blue jean jacket #
# Metal packin',
walkin' up that walk #
# And I'm 'bout
that jackin' #
# I do this for
the penitentiar, holla #
# I'll stunt for y'all while
I'm spendin' these dollars #
# I lock cells
like four corner blocks #
# I'm the bird man,
I never chipped off the top #
# I'm switch-handed,
when I'm swingin, I'm landin' #
# I thug on the street,
and I thug red-banded #
# Wipe you off the land,
it's a concrete jungle #
# A tip full of gangstas,
O,Z,s, and bundles #
# The tip drops
for the clowns I put under #
# You know, I been livin'
like this for ten summers #
# I'm the boss of the ghetto,
black crow of the game #
# Third ward survivor,
ain't a damn thing changed #
# We can't lose,
we been through too much pain #
# Too much struggle,
and too much strain #
# This is CMR #
# Though them haters
try to lock us in #
# We got it locked
from the block to the pen #
# We can't lose,
we been through too much pain #
# Too much struggle,
and too much strain #
# This is CMR #
# Though them haters
try to lock us in #
# We got it locked
from the block to the pen #
# Undisputed #
# Say, hold up,
check this out #
# We 'bout to cut
the lights off, right? #
# Send me some meddum
and a Joe #
# While you're at it, send that
week down here with it #
# Boy, I done sent for ya,
so it's best you come #
# I'm Lac Saladin,
the dog of the prison #
# I'm the next best thing
to the warden #
# Plus I'm chargin',
two bits on accordin' #
# I send words
to an old blister #
# With no pistol,
the BGF still sho' getcha #
# I walk
with my pants saggin' #
# I'm a HBG for life,
now, what's happenin'? #
# Please, what you talkin',
I'm a dead man walkin' #
# If we was on the streets,
the 44 would be barkin' #
# Keep the shank
on the left side #
# The Bitch right hip,
I'm the greasy outta B,C, #
# That's runnin' the tip #
# With the black gorillas,
petty hustlers, and asses #
# Jeffrey Dahmer, son of Sam,
Aran nation, and O,J, #
# Now how you gonna
stop them? #
# Throw away the key
and lock them #
# Tell the D,A,
it's them against me #
# We can't lose,
we been through too much pain #
# Too much struggle,
and too much strain #
# This is CMR #
# Though them haters
try to lock us in #
# We got it locked
from the block to the pen #
# We can't lose,
we been through too much pain #
# Too much struggle,
and too much strain #
# This is CMR #
# Though them haters
try to lock us in #
# We got it locked
from the block to the pen #
# Undisputed #
ocr by Andante