(Speeding car)
(sirens, squealing tires)
(squealing tires, crash,
empty bottles)
(car horn, squealing tires)
(helicopter whirring)
(crash)
(truck horn)
(Angelica) You're late.
(Michael) I know, I'm sorry.
(Angelica) Is everything okay?
(Michael) No, no, there was
this, uh, mechanical issue
with the plane and we were
delayed, and then this customs,
it just, it took forever.
(Angelica) It's hard, Michael,
this history. You know I want
this to work, it's just
you coming, I don't know.
(Michael) Angie, just
listen to me. I'm here. Okay?
And it's gonna be
different this time. I promise.
(Angelica) I want to believe
that, you know, I really do.
Just please don't let me down
again, okay? I'll be waiting.
(Michael) Okay. I'll
see you in twenty minutes.
(Angelica) Okay.
(car beep)
(dials phone)
(Receptionist) Hertz Rental.
Sandy speaking. How may I help you?
Yeah, this is Michael Woods.
I was just in
there a moment ago.
Oh, yes, the American. Is
everything okay, Mister Woods?
No, actually. Uh, this
is a minivan. I ordered a sedan.
Um, well, uh, why don't
you just come back on in
and we'll see if we can find
out what the problem is.
I'm sure my manager
will be back any time-
You can't sort this out?
No, sir. I'm afraid I'm not
that good with the computers,
but my manager will
be back any time soon now.
You know what?
This is gonna be fine.
No, no no, sir.
I'm sorry to say-
Yeah, unfortunately uh, I'm
runnin' late. Somebody's waitin'
for me and we'll just sort it
out when I come back, all right?
But I'm afraid-
(Michael)
Thank you. Bye. (disconnects)
This is weird.
What?
(car horn)
They drive on the left.
♪♪
(cell phone beeps)
(car horns)
(crash)
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, man!
(Bicyclist) Better wake up!
Stay outta trouble, Michael.
Stay outta trouble.
Stay out of trouble.
(dials phone)
Hey.
(Angelica) Where are you?
I'm, I'm stuck in a traffic jam.
There must be an accident
or somethin'. And then I
ran into an issue with the
rental car company, too.
Michael, you know what
security is like here.
Just to get this
little bit of time,
I have to go through
a whole procedure.
No, I know. I know.
But, I mean, it's not my fault.
What am I supposed to do?
I can't control the airflow
or the, the, the traffic,
I mean- Can't you just wait
for a little bit? I've been
waiting for eighteen months.
I know.
All right?
And I'm here now.
When the parole board approved
your travel, I thought this
could be like a new start for
us. But now I'm scared that-
What? Wait,
why are you crying?
No more stories, Michael.
I can't get hurt again.
I can't.
What? What stories?
Did you stop at
the liquor store?
No! Come on, I told you,
I'm stuck in a traffic jam.
Okay.
Angie just give me this
one chance, all right?
I promise you I'm not
gonna screw it up.
Okay. Okay,
call me when you get here.
(cell beep)
(car horns)
Hey, you'll get there, buddy!
God!
(knocking)
(Kid) Hello, my friend.
I'm selling chargers, my friend.
Yeah, I don't need a charger.
No, my friend.
Here's a charger, my friend.
No, I just bought
one at the airport-
Oh, come on, those break
all the time, my friend.
I don't need one.
No, my friend. Look at me
I'm the cutest boy in town.
Yeah, I'm sure you are.
What phone do you use?
Hey! Hey what are you doin'?
Hey, what are you doin'?
They just stole my glasses.
(rolls up windows)
♪♪
(voices)
(cell rings)
(stops ringing)
Hello?
(Detective Smith) You were meant to
acknowledge receipt of the message.
Hello? Who is this? Can you
tell me what's goin' on here?
Hello?
How did you get this phone?
Um, it was in the glove box.
I, I, I
I picked up this car
from the rental car company,
they, they screwed up
the, the, the car and-
(disconnects)
Hello?
Hello!
Why is this gun in my car?
The hell with this.
I'm outta here.
(phone rings)
Hey-
(Detective Smith)
Hello, Michael.
Hey, I just thought you
should know, I'm not playin'
your stupid game.
I'm outta here. I left your
van, your gun, Your phone.
You can have it all, buddy.
Michael, my name is
Detective Smith. We're in the
middle of a covert operation at
the airport. There was a mix up.
That car was meant to be picked
up by one of our undercover
police officers. We appreciate
that this was just a random
mistake and that you are merely
an innocent party in this.
That's good.
That's good news.
You're not to blame here.
We know what happened.
You have no idea.
Yeah, sorry about that.
We've got another car for you.
We'll send you the address and
we can swap it over, okay?
Okay, great.
That's a relief. I gotta-
(disconnects)
(cell beep)
Guess I'm
not walkin' after all.
Uh, Smuts Street, please.
(Operator) Uh, which one? I have over
fifty-seven in the directory, sir.
Uh, I don't know. I-I'm
American, I'm not from here.
Unfortunately, I cannot help unless
you have more information. Good-bye.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, can you tell
me where Smuts Street is?
(speaks foreign)
I didn't see that one coming.
Smuts.
Excuse me.
No, it's- Never mind.
Thank you.
Now I gotta turn around.
(bang)
Crap.
(dials phone)
(Angelica) What's going
on? You're half an hour late.
Yeah, I I got, I got
lost and now I'm stuck.
Where are you?
I turned off Crane Street.
Crane Street? What are
you doing on Crane Street?
There was a mess up, there was a
mess up at the rental car and-
You have the wrong car?
I don't understand.
Michael?
Angie, do you love me?
What?
You heard me.
Michael, what's going on?
Because if
you really love me-
I need you to tell me
how to get to Smuts Street.
And then I need you to not
ask me any more questions.
And please, just give me twenty
more, twenty more minutes,
and if I'm not there
within twenty minutes,
you don't ever have to
talk to me again. Okay?
Go back.
Go back on Crane,
take a right on Gull, um,
and then the third left
at the light is Smuts.
All right.
All right, I love you.
(starts car)
I'm not gonna hurt
you, I swear to God.
I'm gonna take
this gag off, okay?
Are you all right?
(Rachel) Water.
Can you untie me?
Yeah.
(crash)
Are you crazy?
Who are you?
They wouldn't have left
this to some random guy,
so don't play the innocent man!
You just sit back, all right?
I don't know what the hell
you're talkin' about and I
don't really care. You just sit
there and you shut up. Just sit
in your seat. Just, just stay
there! Just- This is crazy!
Oh, God.
Turn the car around.
I don't wanna hear it.
Listen to what I say
and you won't get hurt.
(cocks gun)
Turn the car around.
I don't have anything to
do with this, all right?
Not a thing. I don't have
any involvement in this.
You're driving too fast.
Slow down.
I said slow down!
(gun shot)
Enough!
Okay, okay, okay! Okay,
okay, okay! Okay, okay, okay!
What are you doing?
(car horn)
Stay in the car!
You don't know
what you're doing.
Sit down!
You just don't-
(cell rings)
Hello.
(Detective Smith)
You're late, Michael Woods.
Yeah, I know, I'm sorry.
You got out of jail
only ten days ago.
I checked your record. Already
broken your parole condition
by leaving the country.
An ex-wife at the embassy.
Is that where you're going?
No, no, I'm on my
way to you right now.
Do you wanna go back
to jail, Mister Woods?
NO-
Five minutes or
we're coming for you.
I'm coming. There's a woman,
there's a woman tied up in
the back- (disconnects)
Hello?
Just, just stay in your seat!
Please just stay in
your seat, all right?
Just stay there. Don't
move. Nothin'! Just stay there.
You don't know what's
going on, do you?
I think I need to explain the
situation you find yourself in.
You're talkin' to
the wrong person.
My name is Rachel Shabangu.
I work for the National
Prosecuting Authority.
I have recently uncovered
information implicating a very
powerful man named Ben Rose in
various counts of international
sex trafficking. The last
thing I remember is going home,
opening my front door,
then waking up in this minivan
with you. I have reason to
believe I have been kidnapped
to prevent this information
from coming to light.
You know, I don't wanna
hear any of this. All right?
I don't wanna hear any of it.
You have to do the right thing.
You know what? You just
save it, all right?
You can just save it for
the police when we get there-
Ben Rose is the Chief of Police.
It's the police
that want me dead.
Look, I don't know how you got
involved in this, but you are.
No.
This is my reality, and
it's just become yours.
No, it hasn't become my reality!
You may
not like it-
This isn't my reality.
Sometimes life
doesn't give us a choice-
I gotta do what I gotta-
You're in this
situation for a reason!
I just got to stay out
of trouble right now!
You have to do the right thing.
- No, I don't! You shut up!
- Don't you care-_
Shut up!
You can't-
Argh!
(birds)
This isn't right.
(gun shot)
Go! Go! Go!
Why are they shooting at us?
Just get the hell out of here!
Just go, go, go! Go, go go!
I'm going, I'm going!
Get back onto the main road!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
(Michael) I'm goin', I'm goin'!
Give me the gun.
Give me the gun!
These people are going to
kill us! Give me the gun!
(gun shots)
Will you give me the gun?
(gun shot)
Faster!
(gun shots)
(breaking glass)
(gun shot)
Shoot 'em! Shoot 'em!
Go faster! Go!
I'm going, I'm going!
Go! Go!
Keep shooting!
Go!
Okay, hey! Hey!
What?
When I say duck inside
you duck inside!
Hear me?
There's a wall!
I know! When say duck
inside you get inside! Now!
(crash)
♪♪
(explosion)
I know someone.
Someone who can help.
Where are we?
(Rachel) Alex township.
Just keep going further down.
All right, turn right here.
This is it.
Wait here.
(knocks)
(kids squealing)
What's goin' on?
We're gonna have to
try somewhere else.
There he is.
There. Benji?
Benji?
(Michael) Hey, Benji!
Okay, go around.
(Michael) He's ignoring us.
There.
Benji!
They kidnapped me.
They tried to kill us.
(Ben/i speaks foreign)
Benji!
(Rachel speaks foreign)
(speaks foreign)
Benji!
They threatened my son.
At his school. You know
what I'm saying? At his
school. He is only eight.
Please. Leave me alone.
Threatened his son?
That means they're gonna go after
my wife. She's at the embassy.
(Rachel) Call her. Whatever
happens, she must stay where she is.
(dials phone)
(phone) Hey, it's Angie.
You know what to do. (beep)
Angie, listen, I need you
to stay put. I don't want
you to move. I want you to
stay right where you're at.
There's some guys-
Listen, just stay
where are, all right?
I'm on my way. I'm comin'
to get you right now.
You can't go there.
I have to go there.
These people are dangerous
and they will kill us.
She's safe. They can't
get to her at the embassy.
I don't care.
|'m goin'.
Give me the phone.
What department at the embassy?
Uh, diplomatic. Um-
It's on the phone.
Look on the phone.
It's gonna be okay.
She's safe there, as
long as she stays inside.
(dials phone)
(Receptionist)
American Embassy.
Yes, hi, can I have
Diplomatic Affairs, please?
Not a problem, ma'am.
And who would you
like to speak to?
I'm looking for Angelica-
Moore. Angelica Moore.
Angelica Moore, please.
I'm sorry, she just stepped out.
How long ago?
What?
She just stepped out.
There was someone to see her.
(squealing tires)
Put on your seatbelt.
It's only a block away.
(squealing tires)
It's red.
It's red!
It's just there.
There.
Those are his men!
Wait, there she is!
Angie, get back inside!
(honks horn) Get inside!
(Rachel) Michael!
(crash)
(gun shots)
She got back in!
(gasping)
Wait, you've been shot?
Where's- We gotta
get you to a hospital.
No.
No doctors.
No hospitals.
They'|| find us.
Turn, turn here.
Turn left here?
Turn left.
Follow that, that
underground parking sign.
Right there.
(Michael) We can't
just stay down here.
Okay.
Go down to the bottom level.
Find a place out of sight.
Somewhere where
they can't see us.
(Michael) Here.
Okay.
(parking brake)
All right.
Okay help me take this
off. I need, can you help
me get this off?
I need to see the wound.
Okay.
Use the sleeve.
Stop it. All right.
You gotta-
okay, you're gonna
have to push harder.
Just do it!
Push. Push harder.
I'm pushing.
It's not stopping.
Come on.
I'm not gonna to make it.
It's too much blood.
It's not gonna happen.
You're gonna be fine.
No, you're gonna
be fine. You-
No, it's too much.
It's too much.
You hang in there.
I can't.
- You hang in there.
- I can't.
You stay with me.
Come on.
Give me your phone.
Your phone.
It records?
Yeah.
Turn it on.
All right, just press
that. Hit that button.
Push it.
Push it?
Mm-hmm.
My name is Rachel Shabangu.
Today October 12th, 2011-
I have been shot.
In the event that I don't
survive this will serve
as testimony for
my prosecution.
On September 17th, 2011-
I uncovered a sex trafficking
ring out of Johannesburg.
It's okay.
And a trail
that led back to-
Chief of Police-
Ben Rose.
When I realized how
deep not only he,
but other high-ranking
officers are involved I tried,
I tried to contact
Judge James Mzuka-
but then found myself-
concludes my testimony-
witnessed by-
Michael.
Michael Woods.
Michael-
Woods.
Come on open your eyes.
Open your eyes. Hey.
Open your eyes. I want
you to stay with me, okay?
I don't want this
on my shoulders.
You're gonna stay with me.
So I want you just to breathe.
Take it to the courthouse.
No, I'm not-
To the courthouse.
I'm not gonna deal with
the police. Okay? I'm not
even supposed to be here.
You're gonna stay with me.
Find Judge Mzuka.
He's the only one you can trust.
No, I'm not-
To courthouse.
You stay with me.
Just stay, just-
Please. He's the only one
you can trust. No one else.
No, I'm not, I'm not trusting
anybody, you understand?
You're gonna stay right
here. Okay? You're gonna take it
to the judge. You're gonna
do this. You're gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine. Okay?
I just- you're gonna be fine.
I want you to say it.
Just say it.
It rests on you.
No, this doesn't
rest on me. This rests on you.
This rests on you.
Now you say it. You say-
It's up to you now.
No, it's not on me. You s-
You stay with me.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
This is yours.
This isn't on me.
This isn't on me!
I can't do this!
♪♪
(dials phone)
(Phone) Hey, it's Angie.
You know what to do. (beep)
(foreign)
(Crackhead) Give me your wallet.
I said, give me your wallet!
Get outta here.
Listen here. Your wallet
or I'll stick you, man!
Hey! Hey, now!
Are you deaf?
Get outta here.
This is your chance. Now go.
(phone rings)
(Detective Smith) We just picked
up a call to 911 about a dead
woman in a parking garage.
The caller sounded distressed.
You feeling any better now?
So how much did our
friend Rachel Shabangu
tell you before she died?
You killed her.
Hey, hey, hey,
easy there, big boy.
Look, Michael, I'm not
the one just out of jail
for a hit and run, okay?
It was an accident.
I paid my dues.
You don't know me.
You do seem to have a bit of
a knack at being in the wrong
place at the wrong time,
don't you, Mister Woods?
Anyway, here's the situation.
You've broken your parole
conditions, making you a wanted
felon. You're alone in a city
you've never been to before.
Whereas I, on the other hand,
have access to the entire police
force here. I know the
car you're in. I know its color.
Its plates. I also have
people waiting for your
ex-wife to take one
step out of that embassy.
One step and she's mine.
So what you gonna do?
Oh, there is one more thing I
thought might help you make the
right choice here. So why
don't you turn on your radio?
(Reporter) -and have released
his picture and name to the
media. American Michael Woods
is wanted for the murder of-
(Smith laughs)
So what say you make the
enlightened choice here and
just stay out of my way, okay?
(Smith laughs)
Cookie boy.
What?
That's what my father used to
always call me. "Cookie boy. "
Said I'd always
crack under pressure.
crumble like a cookie.
He was a mean bastard.
Tough life, huh?
(Smith laughs)
That chuckle of yours
it reminds me of him.
'Cause he had one just like it.
A sadistic-ass chuckle.
And you know, even though he's
dead, every time I screw up,
I can still hear it.
Are you a mean bastard,
Detective Smith?
Be very, very careful here.
'Cause you know what's more
powerful than a mean bastard
with too much power?
You're playing with fire.
A man with nothin' to
lose, Detective Smith.
I will kill you.
So you asked me to choose.
Okay. I choose.
I choose, fuck you.
(disconnects)
♪♪
(audio rewinds)
sex trafficking ring-
Judge James Mzuka.
(audio rewinds)
James Mzuka.
(Operator) Afrikom
Information. How may I help you?
Yeah, I need the phone
number for Judge James Mzuka.
Oh, here we go. Would you
like me to connect you?
Yes.
Please hold.
Hi, this is Judge James Mzuka.
Please leave a
message after the tone.
(beep)
My name is Michael Woods.
I have Rachel Shabangu's
recorded testimony.
They killed her.
And they tried to kill me.
I'm comin' in.
I'm gonna bring it
in to the courthouse.
(squealing tires)
(sirens)
(cell phone)
♪♪
(dials phone)
(phone) Hey, it's Angie.
You know what to do. (beep)
Remember that night, when
you had on that yellow dress,
the new one,
and it was rainin'?
I was runnin' around tryin'
to catch all the raindrops
so you wouldn't get wet.
We were laughin' so
hard our stomachs hurt.
You and me, we used to have
some, some good times, Angie.
Ah these people-
These people, they're
gonna tell you things.
I don't know exactly what
they're gonna tell you,
but I know they're
gonna tell you that I killed
somebody and it's not true.
And I'm gonna
prove that to you,
I'm gonna prove that to
everybody even if it kills me.
I'm just trying to make
up right now for every wrong
turn I've ever made. I'm just
tryin' to do the right thing.
And right now, unfortunately,
my only chance of gettin'
back to you, my only
chance of ever even seeing
you again, is to clear my
name. This is the only way.
That's the only way, so
just know that I'm sorry.
I hope you understand.
And I love you forever.
(hangs up)
(foreign)
(Mohawk) You lost something?
I need my car sprayed.
You've got this look- doesn't
quite fit your pretty face, huh?
That's the look
of a man on fire.
Are you on fire, Mister
American in the Minivan?
I don't have any money.
You're right
out there, huh? Just burning up.
You see, when a man
is on fire like you,
usually everything
seems perfectly clear.
But you don't have clarity, huh?
'Cause you seem to have
mistaken me for Mother Therese.
(foreign)
You know how much a
can of spray costs?
This is a knock-off, man.
You get this in a cereal box?
It's all I got, man.
I don't need a pro job,
just change the color.
Go around back.
♪♪
(whistles, speaks foreign)
All right, I gotta
get outta here.
(Mohawk) Places to go,
things to do. I get you, man.
Boys, come on, wrap it up, huh?
Man on a mission's gotta go.
I gotta go, come on.
(Mohawk) Come on, boys, come on.
H- how do I get to
the courthouse?
Just off Diagonal, third right.
You'll see the big steps.
Thank you.
(cell phone)
Hello?
(man) Hello. Am I
speaking with Michael Woods?
You called me.
Yeah, who is this?
My name is Judge Mzuka. There
was a message about Rachel.
Yeah, yeah. I have her,
uh, I have her testimony.
She recorded it before she died.
(Judge) Listen, what you
have in your possession is
the best chance we're ever
going to have of convicting him.
It's the only chance we've got.
I need that and I need that now.
Yeah, yeah, I'm, I'm on my way
to the courthouse right now.
No, no, no.
They will kill you on sight.
Well, they won't know, though,
'cause I had my van, I had the
whole thing sprayed and they
won't be able to tell. I got-
You don't understand.
There's a shoot on sight
order out on you.
There are police everywhere.
The courthouse is the worst
place you could possibly go.
That's exactly where they're
expecting you to go.
I have to.
That's suicide, Mister Woods.
I promised her.
Look, I can come to you,
just tell me where you are.
(siren)
(knocks)
(Traffic Cop) Talking on your
cell phone and operating a
vehicle is illegal.
You do realize that?
May I see your license, please?
Can I see your license, sir?
Sir, I need to see your license.
Step out of the car, sir!
Sir, step out of the car!
(car honks)
(shouting, throwing cans)
You, stay put!
(siren)
(Judge) What happened?
Oh, just-
it was a cop, but he's
gone now. He, he left.
Michael, listen to me.
It's too dangerous.
Do not go anywhere now.
I'm going to send someone.
Just tell me where you are.
Uh-
(cell beeps)
He-hello? Michael,
can, can you hear me?
Yeah. Yeah, um-
Where are you?
I'm on, uh-
I need to know where you are.
Yeah, my, my, my phone
battery's going dead.
I'm on, this is, uh-
uh, Bertha Street.
Yeah, Ber- Hello?
(cell beeps)
Hello? Can you hear me?
Hello?
Where is it?
Come on!
Please, please, please please.
NO, not now!
I can't have this!
I can't ha- I swear
to God, come on.
(cell beeps)
No! Come on!
Damn it!
Damn it all!
Come on, work!
(Bum) Burn it all away.
I don't need it.
I'm goin' in.
(siren)
♪♪
(helicopter whirring)
(crash)
Get outta the way!
(cell beep)
It's working!
Judge!
Judge, I lost 'em!
And the courthou-, the
courthouse is right here.
(crash)
(sirens)
I'm going the wrong way!
(truck horn)
(gun shots)
(cops on bull horn,
helicopter, sirens)
(Lieutenant) Hey! Hey!
Hey, drop your weapon!
- Stay back!
- Drop your weapon!
You get me Judge Mzuka
and you get him now or
I'm gonna blow his brains
out! I'm gonna shoot him!
Listen.
I'm gonna pull this trigger!
- We'll get you whatever you need.
- You listen to me!
But you have to lay
down your weapon.
You listen to me! You get me
Judge Mzuka and you get him now.
Just drop your weapon!
(gun shot)
I said get me the judge!
Are you gonna listen to me?
Huh? You gonna listen to me?
(helicopter)
Get outta here! Get
outta here! Get them outta here!
Listen, man, you have to
give me a chance here, okay?
We can work
something out-
I said get the judge!
Get the judge now!
Go get Judge Mzuka now!
(Detective Smith)
Hold it, hold it.
Hello, Mister Woods.
This man is a
fugitive from the law.
Nobody is getting him anything.
(Lieutenant)
And who the hell are you?
Detective Smith.
This is a DT matter.
I'll take it from here.
I'll blow his head off!
NO, You won't.
Yes, I will. Now you get
that judge and you get him now,
or this guy dies.
I swear to God, this guy's
gonna die if you don't
get me the judge right now.
Not gonna happen.
Don't you push me.
Don't you push me!
Haven't you screwed up enough
for one life, Mister Woods?
Right now you're dead center
in the crosshairs of at least
two Class A snipers. I give
the word and you're dead.
Don't you push me. I swear
to God, I'm gonna kill him.
I will kill him.
Now you get the judge
or somebody dies.
(audio feedback)
That thing on?
Is this thing on?
Yes. Yes. The
camera's running over there.
Make no mistake,
I will shoot you.
He's got a hostage,
you can't-
Back off. On my word,
you're a dead man.
Hey, there's protocol here!
Unless threatened, you
have no right to fire.
I need the judge.
Don't tell me how to do my job.
What's going on here?
Just stay out of this.
Tell me, man.
What's going on?
Stay out of this!
No, mister you step
back! I've got this!
Drop your weapon now!
Step back! I've got this!
I need the judge now!
- Okay, step back!
Stay out of this!
Tell me, what's
going on here man?
I need the judge!
Get me the judge!
Drop your weapon now!
I need back-up! I need
back-up! You step back!
No one fires! No one fires!
Please, I need the judge.
I have evidence, okay?
Don't you say another word!
Rachel Shabangu's death-
(Detective Smith)
He' got a bomb! (gun shot)
No! No! Stop!
No one fires!
No one fires! No
one fires! Step back!
USPS) MY
name is Rachel Shabangu. Today-
(Detective Smith)
Cut the feed!
(tape) October 12th, 2011
I have been shot. In the event
that I don't survive this
will serve as testimony.
On September 17th 2011,
I uncovered...
...a sex trafficking ring
out of Johannesburg
and a trail that led back to
Chief of Police Ben Rose.
(Reporter) Recovering in
Johannesburg's Central Hospital,
the American tourist Michael
Woods was praised as a hero
by President Jacob Zuma,
who called him a courageous
defender of justice.
At his bed side,
his ex-wife Angelica Moore
spoke with us earlier today.
(Angelica) Yes, we've had
difficult times, but somehow
I always knew that he's got it
in him. When it really mattered,
he pulled through and I will
always love him for that.
(Reporter) Rose and several
other high-ranking officers
and members of court were
arrested late last Tuesday
after a dramatic showdown
on Constitution Hill.
Shabangu's testimony and the
body of evidence found in
Justice James Mzuka's
possession ultimately led to-
(continues in
several languages)