Hello, George. Only me.
How are you today, dear?
Having a little doze,
or just resting your eyes?
I'll make you a fresh cup.
Shan't be a minute.
Couple of biscuits.
Here you are then, dear.
That better?
Yes, thank you.
- A little bit...
- A bit more?
There. Do you need anything else, dear?
You sure?
Drink your tea up
before it gets cold.
I'll be on my way.
Tell lvy I was asking after her, won't you?
And don't get up to any mischief.
Ta ta, dear.
- Hello, Reg.
- Afternoon, Mrs. Drake.
- You all right, dear?
- Can't complain.
- Going off for your tea?
- Yes.
- What you having?
- Bit of bread 'n dripping.
- That all?
- Cup of tea.
Look after yourself, Reg. I told you.
You ought to come over to our
house for tea one night.
- I don't want to put you out.
- oh, don't be daft.
What about tomorrow?
You could come over after work.
You know where we are.
Number 82.
I'll feed you up a bit.
Do you fancy that?
- You sure?
- Be no trouble, Reg.
- Go on, then.
- Oh, lovely.
See you tomorrow, then.
Now don't you forget!
- Hello, Nellie.
- All right, Vera?
- Isn't it cold?
- Yes.
That's better.
Nice cup of tea.
- That you, Ethel?
- Hello, Mom.
- Nippy today, weren't it?
- Yes.
Ooh. Hold up, Ethel.
- 'Scuse, Mom.
- What you doing?
I'm washing me hands like you told me to.
- Oh, yes. Your dad's here.
- Hello, Dad.
- Hello, Mom. You all right, Ethel?
- Yes.
- All right, Dad?
- Yes, thank you.
- Good day?
- Not bad, you?
- Can't complain.
- Oh, Ethel. Take the teapot through.
God, I'm starving.
I could eat an 'orse.
Wash your hands, Dad,
I'll put the tin on the table.
Just get me slippers on.
Well he's all on his tod, ain't he?
Seems a nice enough fellow, though.
- Oh yes. Hard worker.
- Is he the little bloke... bald?
- No.
- No. Stocky fellow.
- Lives opposite.
- Oh, yes. Does he?
I shouldn't wonder he don't have bread
and dripping every night.
There ain't nothing wrong
with bread and dripping.
Not every night.
- I wouldn't mind.
- Oh yes? Like to see your face
If I put bread and dripping on the table
every teatime.
No, I'll do him a nice stew.
- Can we have dumplings, Mom?
- Of course, we can.
- I love a dumpling.
- You are a dumpling.
- Oh, that's nice.
- What you got your work clothes on for?
It's a Tuesday, Dad.
I've got me night school.
- Oh, yes.
- That's right.
I've gotta leave in a minute.
Dumpling.
I'm meeting David this evening.
You're looking very flat-chested.
Have you lost weight?
I don't know.
That was lovely, Vera. Thank you very much.
- Very tasty.
- You're welcome, I'm sure.
Why don't you sit on the settee, Reg?
Make yourself at home.
Yeah, Reg. Sit down.
We'll have a smoke.
Make a fresh pot, Ethel.
- Here we are.
- Nah, go on.
- Sid?
- Oh, cheers, mate.
How's work going, Stan?
- Was it motors?
- Motor mechanic, yes.
Well, they bring 'em in.
We mend 'em, push 'em back out again.
It's just the two of us, see?
Me and my brother.
Oh, a family business like?
Well, it's Frank's business.
I work for him... with him.
Have you always worked on the roads,
then, Reg?
- No. I started in the war.
- Oh.
Oh, what kind of war effort
did you have, Reg?
- The pioneer corps.
- Oh, yes?
We laid tarmac on the American bases.
- Did you?
- We did.
- Went out in France... 1940.
- You was out there early?
Dunkirk. We done a running when they
broke through.
Then we went out a few days after D-day.
Same as you, Dad.
'Bout a month after D-day,
we went out there.
- Just after the battle of Caen.
- Oh, yes?
It was murder then. Mind you,
others had it worse than us.
I was in the service corps... driver.
We pushed from Normandy
into northern France, Belgium,
And I ended up in Hamburg.
I was in Hamburg and all, Reg.
- Was you?
- Not then, though.
- No, after the war. National service.
- Oh, I'm with you.
I'll tell you, they've got it worse
over there... the Germans.
We all had it bad.
- It weren't cozy for no one, was it?
- Right along, Dad.
No, but we done demolition before the war...
- Me and my brother.
- Oh, does he live around here?
Not now. He's in Australia.
- Melbourne.
- Ooh, is he?
He went out two year ago.
That's a long way away, isn't it?
Well, he was in Burma in the war.
- My brother was in Burma.
- Was he?
Well, he met a few Australian blokes,
Came back, married a Scottish girl
and went out there.
Oh, well, I never...
Was he a P.O.W., Reg?
He don't talk about it, Stan.
No, my friend won't talk about it, neither.
You lose any mates, Reg?
A few, yes.
I lost a couple of pals, and all.
I lost my best mate.
- Ah, that's right... Bill.
- Did our basic together and everything.
Out in Palestine...
he got ambushed in an orange grove.
I had to pack his kit up for him like...
Sit next to Reg.
- It's dreadful, isn't it?
- Terrible.
You warm enough, Reg?
Put the fire on, Dad.
I lost my mom in the blitz.
Did you, Reg?
Chapel Street market, 1941... March.
Well now we remember
that bomb, don't we, Dad?
- It blew all the windows out.
- Yes, it did.
It was just around the corner, Penton Street.
- Opposite the church.
- Oh, yeah.
Our flats never got touched.
She popped in to see my aunt, went shopping...
gone.
Another cup of tea, Reg?
Sorry to hear that, mate.
That was a lovely spread, Vera.
Thank you very much.
Well, enjoy your pub.
Make sure you wear a coat,
Susan, if you're traveling
- in an open top sports car.
- Yes, I am.
- Cheerio, chap
- Goodbye, sir.
Good night, Sid.
- Night, Dad.
- Night-night, Ethel.
Night-night, Dad.
Night, Ethel.
Good night.
Where are you tomorrow, Mrs. Wells'?
No, Mrs. Fowler's tomorrow.
I was at Mrs. Wells' this morning, bless her.
- Night-night, love.
- Night, dear.
Ooh, Stanley, your feet!
- Warm 'em up for us.
- Come on, then.
I reckon that Reg would make a good husband
to some nice girl.
Where's a bloke like that gonna meet anybody?
We managed to find each other.
Sure enough.
Miracles do happen.
Let me go.
Don't.
Stop.
- You're terribly beautiful, you know.
- I should get a...
- I should get a taxi. - Shh.
Come on, let's dance.
Don't be silly.
- I do apologize. - What?
I haven't got a gramophone.
It's not funny.
- It's not funny.
- It's not funny?
It's not funny...
Not funny?
Oh, morning, Mrs. Fowler.
Good morning, Mrs. Drake.
Oh, I'm in your way, here?
Lost something?
- I am in your way, aren't I?
- Oh, it's just...
I can't see for looking, sometimes.
I'm like that myself.
Among other things.
All right, Mother?
Ain't you been up today?
Leave it alone.
You getting married yourself, sir?
No, I fear.
No, it'll be a sister of mine
that's getting married.
- Oh, lovely.
- Yeah.
But to tell you the truth,
I haven't met her man yet.
He's a bit of dark horse, so l...
- Just lower your arm for me. - Yeah.
So when are you catching the boat?
A week this Saturday coming.
- Oh, doesn't give us much time, then.
- From Holyhead, I'm goin'.
Just lower your arms for me please, sir.
- Yeah, yeah. - Thank you.
So I'll be having
the waistcoat with it, then?
That's no problem whatsoever, sir.
As I said, it's, uh... we charge
10 guineas for the two-piece suit,
moving up to 13 guineas for the three-piece.
Well I have your money on me now, so...
Oh, lovely.
And I want the jacket just like the one
you have on there.
Well, you have chosen
the double-breasted jacket, sir...
- with the four buttons - Yeah.
Now, the only difference is... your lapel...
is going to fasten down
to the bottom button,
giving it a much more streamlined effect...
Oh.
And what with the light blue bariff
here, plus the stripe
to accentuate your height,
it's bold, it's sharp,
and it's certainly going
to make an impression
when you walk into the church, sir.
Well, that's exactly what I want, sir.
- Just face the mirror for me.
- Yeah.
- I'll be the lord of the manor in this?
- Oh yes, sir.
- I'll be like your man, George Raft.
- You will indeed, sir.
Me daddy won't know me, huh?
Well, if you're going
for the George Raft look, sir...
we can always supply you
with a pair of spats.
Oh, no.
No spats.
Whatever you want, sir.
I'm just going to measure
your outside leg.
Yeah.
Come on.
Seized up?
She's there.
Is Joycie all right?
She's fine.
We ain't seen her in ages.
She's started talking about moving.
Moving where?
To a bigger house.
Your house is big enough, isn't it?
Yes.
- You ain't been there a year.
- I know.
We had a bit of company last night.
- Did you?
- You know what Vera's like.
She finds a young fellow,
lives on his own, no family,
hoicks him in with us,
gives him his tea.
She's got a heart
of gold, that woman.
- She's a diamond.
- You're a lucky man.
You're a lucky man in all, Frank.
What she invite him round for, anyway?
- He lives on his own.
- A lot of people live on their own.
Don't mean you've got to invite them
all round for tea though, does it?
It's just Vera's way, ain't it?
Maybe he wants to be on his own.
She wants to mind her own business.
She's a little busybody, bless her.
She's going to get herself in trouble
one of these days.
I'm glad we moved out here, aren't you?
I seen the washing machine
I want this morning. It's ¡ê25.
Oh no, not now, Frank.
Not your accounts.
- It'll take me 10 minutes.
- I know your "10 minutes."
An hour and 10 minutes, more like.
I thought we was going
to have another early night.
I'll finish this and we can have
an early night.
All right, dear.
Frank?
Frank.
You're asleep!
Don't go to sleep on me.
Frank?
Well, you come on top of me then.
- Come on.
- Can't we leave it till tomorrow?
No, we got to do it now, ain't we?
Afternoon, dear.
Thank you.
This way.
Right then, dear.
First thing we've got to do...
is put the kettle on.
Oh. Got a bowl in here?
Now, where are...?
You got a towel, dear?
Very good. Where's your bed?
Through here.
Now, what I want you to do...
take your
knickers off for me,
lie down here.
Don't you
be upset.
Because I'm here to help you, aren't I?
And that's what I'm going to do. So...
hop your bottom on the bed
and I'll be back in a jiffy.
Here we are, then.
Hop on the bed for me.
How long is it going to take?
Not long, dear.
Open your legs.
You on your own?
Only for a bit.
Now, what I'm going to do
is have a little feel,
Make sure everything's as it should be
and then we'll get
the soapy water inside,
- so you go all floppy for me.
- What do you mean?
Just lie down, dear.
Wet my hand a bit...
and feel.
You're all right. All right...
Push this little tube in.
All right.
Here comes the water.
When you feel full,
we'll stop.
Was you at work, today?
I went in this morning.
- Weather's turned. - Yes.
Now...
- that feel full?
- Yes.
You dry yourself off.
Hold that towel there for a minute
and I'll clean out the bowl.
Now, what's going to happen
is tomorrow or the day after
you'll get a bit of a pain down below.
Take yourself to the toilet,
you'll start bleeding
- then it'll all come away.
- What do you mean, "it will come away"?
lt'll all be over, dear.
You'll be right as rain.
I won't die, will I?
No, dear.
Right. I'll be on my way.
- I'll see meself out.
- It's all right.
- Look after yourself, dear.
- Right.
I've got 200 crate a day,
and he's giving me eight pairs of nylons.
I'll have some nylons.
I'll take three pairs of nylons off you, Sid.
- What you offering?
- Five packets of Players.
What, for three pairs of nylons?
- That's right. - No, no...
These are the Italian nylons.
They ain't the Czech ones.
- Yeah, they're nice, Al.
- I don't care.
I'm offering five packets of Players
for three pairs of nylons,
take it or leave it.
To hold it up, Ron, eh?
I mean either I'm talking
in another language,
- or he's a bit Mutt and Jeff.
- I heard you.
Look. Make it 10 packets.
- I'll give you six... seven.
- Eight.
Look, take 'em out with you Saturday...
"How you doing, darling? Fancy a turn?"
Slip her a pair... happy days!
- All right, eight.
- Done. Good boy.
I'll give you two packets
of tea for a pair.
What are you two, a double act?
- Hello, Lily.
- Your bleedin' stairs.
- they'll be the death of me.
- You've must've heard the kettle boil.
No.
Just made a fresh pot.
How'd that go the other week?
Same as usual.
- Nervous little thing, wasn't she?
- I know.
I put her right.
Set her mind at rest.
- You always do, don't you?
- Don't you want a biscuit, Lily?
Won't say no.
Thank you.
- I've got another one for you.
- Oh, yes?
- Friday, is it?
- Is Friday all right?
- Mm.
- I told her 5:00.
- That's all right, yes.
- Want some tea?
- Sardines?
- I'm all right this week, Lily.
- Oh, now what sweets you got?
- Boiled sweets.
Here you are.
Don't you want some for your Ethel?
How much are them, then?
Tuppence a bag. A penny eighty to you.
Righty-oh.
- Kelp Street.
- Oh, I know.
Nora. She's got seven kids already.
Oh, can't she manage?
- No, could you?
- I've only got a thruppenny bit.
I've got change.
Ain't the husband around?
I expect so.
Can't control himself, if you ask me.
Terrible. Poor woman.
Serves her right.
Don't you want no
sardines for your mother?
No, she can't eat them no more, Lily.
Gives her heartburn.
How's she keeping anyway, your mom?
Oh, you know. Getting older.
Ain't we all?
That's Ethel.
- That you, Ethel?
- Hello, Mom.
- Lily's here.
- Oh.
Hello, Ethel.
Hello.
- You want a cuppa?
- Yes please, Mom.
- Ain't she got a boyfriend yet?
- No.
I ain't surprised.
That was a lovely spread, Vera.
Thank you very much.
- You're welcome, Reg, you know that.
- Doing a bit of mending?
Yes. You got anything that needs doing?
You've got a bit of leg poking
through your trousers.
- Yes, he has.
- I done that at work.
- I ain't got round to it yet.
- You do your own sewing?
Well, I'm all fingers
and thumbs, but I have a go.
You ought to bring 'em over here, Reg.
You need a little patch on that.
I'll get you a bit of cloth
from the shop, Reg.
What is it?
Navy serge, 19 oz.
Give it to Mom, she'll mend it for you,
no problem.
- I could do that.
- Of course, she can.
- Ethel will see you right.
- I don't want to put you out.
- I don't mind.
- Thanks very much.
It'll cost you... half a crown!
- Do you want another sweet?
- Ta.
- What are you doing, love?
- Go back to sleep.
You're ill.
It's going to have to be quick.
- Is it going to take long?
- No, dear.
I haven't told him, you see?
He's supposed to be at work.
- Yes, dear.
- What's he want to come home sick for?
Take your knickers off for me.
Can't have no more kids, see?
I've got seven already.
I ain't having no more.
- I know, dear.
- It'd kill me.
Lay the towel on the bed for me.
You sit right on the edge.
- What's that?
- Just soapy water, dear...
a bit of disinfectant.
- Do you want me to lie down?
- Stay where you are.
- I've just got to get this inside.
- All right.
All right. You all right?
Yes.
Oy, oy.
- What?
- See them, blonde, brunette?
- Oh, tidy!
- Ain't they?
How do you do?
Right, 'o mugger... bright-eyed,
bushy-tailed and look lively.
- We only just got here.
- Oh, come on, Kenny,
- let your hair down.
- Enjoy the view.
- Let's have a swap, eh?
- All right.
Do you reckon she likes him?
Well, she's gone for a walk with him.
She wouldn't go, would she,
if she didn't like him. Would she?
He should take her out dancing.
- I don't think he's that type.
- I can't see Reg dancing.
She'd come back
black and blue, wouldn't she?
- Dad.
- she'd have to give her feet a soak.
They might turn out
to be a proper Fred and Ginger,
The pair of them. You never know.
- Did you have to come far?
- Not far, dear, no.
Are you sure you
wouldn't like a drink?
No, thank you.
- Have you done this before, dear?
- Yes, as it happens.
Here we are...
One bowl, one towel.
- Kettle's on.
- Oh. Thank you.
Are you sure you wouldn't like a drink?
No, dear.
What?
You know, your hair looks really lovely.
- Do you think so?
- Yes.
Oh.
Why don't you make us all a cup of tea?
What, do you want a cup of tea as well?
Oh.
Good luck.
All right, dear.
You're gonna have
to take your knickers off.
Okey-dokey.
So, how are you?
This is rather a surprise.
- Haven't seen you for ages.
- Yes... no...
Sugar?
No, thank you.
- Thank you for coming today.
- Yeah? Not at all.
An excuse to get out
of that dreary old bank.
Would you like a fag?
No, thank you.
Thank you for...
Sorry.
What's the matter?
Oh, sorry.
Have some cake.
I had a piece before you arrived.
Can't resist... it's delicious.
I wanted to talk to you.
Fire away.
Um.
You're the first person I thought of.
Really.
Crikey, Susan. What is it?
I have this, um...
friend, who...
she needs some help.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
You've got yourself
into trouble, haven't you?
Oh, Susan. You clot.
Who told you to phone me?
All right. I'll tell you
what you have to do.
Oh, and when you see the psychiatrist,
you have to make up a fearful fib
about some potty aunt
or something or other.
Here. Have a hanky.
Thank you.
You'll be all right, you know.
Hello, George. Oh... hello, Peggy!
You off work, today?
Sit up, then
Oh, she's all right, George. Bless her.
This has slipped a bit.
Ivy taken bad again, has she?
Oh, dear. Well I'll make
a fresh pot of tea.
And you'll want a biscuit,
Peggy, I shouldn't wonder.
- Hello, lvy.
- All right, Vera?
Having one of your bad days?
- I'm sick of it.
- Oh, dear.
I'll put the kettle on.
Didn't you sleep last night, dear?
You don't sleep
when you're like this, do you?
Have you managed to kip at all today?
- No, I ain't.
- Oh, ain't you?
Still, you're in the best place, lvy.
I should be at work.
You can't go to work in this state.
Somebody's got to earn the money.
If I stay off, she wants to stay off.
I'll lose me job if this goes on.
It's not your fault, dear.
Try telling that to your boss.
They don't understand nothing, men.
Bastards.
Now...
is this your first pregnancy?
Yes.
And what does the father say?
Um...
I don't want my parents to know.
No, no, no.
I mean the father of the child.
Big as you can.
Come and sit down.
Have you considered
the possibility of having the child?
I can't.
Very well. I'll help you,
But I'm afraid we are obliged to discuss
The delicate matter of money.
It'll come to ¡ê150.00.
How much do you have available?
Um, just over ¡ê100.00.
I see.
Well...
Let's say 100 guinea, shall we?
In advance. In cash.
Now, I shall require you
to see a psychiatrist.
- I know.
- Do you?
Yes.
And I'll arrange the nursing home...
and the obstetrician.
Baxter. Terribly good man.
Any questions?
Pretty day.
Yes.
- How many weeks pregnant are you?
- Seven.
And were you a virgin?
Yes.
Miss Wells, it would be helpful
If you would give me
simple and honest answers
If you can.
What does your father do?
- My father?
- Yes.
Um, he works in the Ministry of Defense.
And are your parents happily married?
Um, I think so.
Is there any history
of mental illness in your family?
Yes...
an aunt of my mother's committed suicide.
Did she?
Yes.
And your own mental state, how would you
describe it at the moment?
- Um.
- Anxious?
Depressed?
Tell me your feelings
towards the father of the child.
- Do you love him?
- No.
- Does he love you?
Did you love him
at the point of conception?
No.
Did he force himself on you?
Miss Wells...
if you were to have the child,
would you keep it or have it adopted?
I can't have it.
I'd rather kill myself.
Well, I don't think
we can allow that to happen...
can we?
Tea's brewing.
- Miss Wells.
- Hello.
- I'm Nurse Willoughby.
- How do you do?
- Is this all your luggage?
- Uh, yes.
- If you'd like to follow me.
- Thank you.
- Have you had far to come?
- Not really, no.
- Miss Wells.
- Hello.
- Sister Beech.
- How do you do?
I hope you'll be comfortable.
Thank you.
There, dear.
I'll put this back under the bed for you.
Now... that didn't take too long, did it?
- What, you finished already?
- Yes, dear.
So when am I going to see you again?
What did you say, dear?
You have to come back, yes?
Oh no, dear.
I've done all I've got to do.
Now you've just got to wait.
What is it I'm waiting for?
For it to come away, dear.
But all you used
was a little bit of water.
Don't you worry.
What happens if something goes wrong?
Now what's going to happen is this...
tomorrow...
or Sunday, you'll have a pain down below.
Get yourself to the toilet.
You'll start bleeding, it'll all come
away, you'll be right as rain.
What you need now
is a nice hot cup of tea.
Take care, dear.
Ta ta.
- Hello, dear.
- Good morning, Mrs. Drake.
- Hello, Mommy.
- Good morning, dear.
- How was your weekend?
- Lovely, thank you.
How was Norfolk?
Oh, bearable.
Terribly sunny.
Extraordinary.
Have you got the money?
I've got the ¡ê2.00.
- ¡ê2.00?
- That's what she told me.
Well, she told you wrong.
It's two guineas.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Ain't no use being sorry.
Oh. You want payment now then, do you?
Well, I don't want payment next week, do I?
Where is your husband, anyway?
Korea, since you're asking.
- In the forces, is he?
- Yes.
- Two guineas.
- Thank you very much.
So it's not his, then?
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
Done this for a lot
of girls then, have you?
Mind your own bleedin' business.
- I'm only asking.
- And I'm only telling you.
Right.
You put your address down there.
She'll be there at 5:00.
Don't mention the money.
That's between me and you.
- Is that understood?
- Yes.
Good.
Can you do one on Friday?
- At 5:00?
- Yes.
That's all right.
- Married lady.
- Oh, yes?
- Got herself in a bit of trouble.
- How is that, then?
Having a bit of "how's your father"
on the side.
- Oh, that's not right, is it, Lily?
- Well, I don't think so.
Still, gotta help them out, ain't you?
How'd you get on with that darkie?
- Oh, I did feel sorry for her.
- Long way from home?
She was very scared.
What are they doing over here, anyways?
Trying to make a better
life for themselves, I shouldn't wonder.
- They should stay where they are.
- They're hard workers.
- You need any sugar?
- How much you charging this week, Lily?
¡ê1.80, to you.
All right, then.
- Here you are.
- Ta.
Thank you.
I'm ever so scared.
Try not to upset yourself, dear.
S- sorry...
I've got to pull myself together.
Oh, I've got to go through with this.
Oh, I know I have to... it's just that...
nobody knows...
well, my friend knows,
but she doesn't know...
I mean she doesn't know it's today.
So if anything were to happen to me...
no one would know.
You've got to get your knickers off,
dear, and lie down.
Oh. Oh, no. No, no, no.
No, no, no.
Oh, no. No...
I'm a terrible person!
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Ain't you had a nice night?
Yes.
You?
You ever thought about moving out?
What do you mean?
What do you think about getting married?
What, to you?
Yes.
I ain't never thought about it.
- I've been thinking about it.
- Have you?
About three or four weeks.
What do you reckon?
Do you wanna?
Yes.
I do.
All right, then.
Better tell your mom.
Dad...
- Dad, wake up.
- What's the matter?
I've got to go in the kitchen.
Woke me up...
- oh, hello, Reg.
- Hello, Stan.
Good kip?
Yes, all right.
Can I have a word, Stan?
What's the matter?
Can I have your permission to marry Ethel?
Have you asked her?
Yes.
What'd she say?
She said yes.
Well, of course you can.
- You sure?
- Congratulations!
- Thanks very much.
- Vera? Ethel?
- You know what he's just asked me?
- I'm ever so pleased.
- I'm delighted!
- Me too.
- What's all this chatting about?
- These two just got engaged!
- Congratulations, mate!
- Thanks very much.
I was asleep on that chair, there.
Sorry about waking you up.
Oh, don't you worry about that.
- I asked her last night.
- Oh, did you?
Well done, the both of you.
Wow, Reg, good going.
- Don't look so worried.
- You're sure?
Of course, I'm sure.
I've been to the doctors and I'm sure.
About time and all.
You have to start taking things easy.
What, you gonna look after me?
- Yes.
- Are you?
We have to tell Stan and Vera.
Yes, we'll tell Stan and Vera...
but we'll tell them together, properly.
We'll go around there...
- next weekend.
- I'll ask him in the morning.
Can I have my washing machine now, please?
- Morning, Frank.
- Morning, Stan.
Got some news for you.
What?
Here you are.
Have a guess.
Good news, or bad news?
- Bad news.
- Wrong. Try again.
All right, good news.
Come on, then. What is it?
Eh?
Spill the beans, old cock!
My little Ethel? She got engaged.
- What?
- Yesterday afternoon.
- What, to Reg?
- I couldn't believe it.
I thought they'd be courting for years.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, Frank.
You must be a very proud man.
You should've seen Vera's face.
It was a bolt from the blue.
So, on Sunday...
you and Joycie got to
come over for your tea.
We'll get some beers in...
some sherry for the girls.
We'll toast the happy couple
and Reg can meet the family.
- On Sunday.
- About 4:00.
- You tell Joycie?
- I'll tell her.
Can you feel that, dear?
Starting to fill up?
Yes.
- Does that feel peculiar, Pam?
- Yes, Mom.
That's how it's meant to feel, ain't it?
- Peculiar?
- Yes.
- You've done this before, ain't you?
- Yes, dear.
- So, it's safe.
- It's safe, isn't it?
- Yes, darling.
- And when it's full,
that's when we'll stop.
I know your face from somewhere.
- Who, me?
- Yes.
- Do you?
- I can't think where, though.
You all right?
Of course. Sunlight laundry.
- Oh, dear.
- It's Vera, ain't it?
- That's right.
- Vera Drake.
I knew your mother before the war.
- Did you?
- Was you doing this back then?
That feel full, dear?
Yes.
All right.
Just dry yourself off.
Get that down you, come on.
Cold. Cold.
Cool you down.
- Cheers.
Hello again, Pamela.
How are you feeling?
Poorly, hmm?
Now, I need to take
another look at your tummy.
Don't worry,
I'll be as gentle as I can.
Pamela, we just need you
to straighten your legs.
Good girl. Right onto the bed.
I promise you, I have very warm hands.
Bring your bottom up.
Good girl. That's it.
Now, I'm going to press gently
And I want you to tell me
what happens when I let go.
Good girl, well done.
- We'll do an internal, Sister.
- All right, doctor.
Now then, Mrs. Barnes,
I, uh... I don't have
very good news, I'm afraid.
- Why, why, what's happening?
- I'm going to have to operate.
- Pamela is a very sick girl.
- She ain't gonna die, is she?
We sincerely hope not, Mrs. Barnes,
But this is a grave situation,
as I'm sure you'll understand.
Now then...
when Pamela was admitted this evening,
you stated that she was having a miscarriage.
Yes.
But that isn't the whole truth, is it?
Mrs. Barnes...
did you do something to Pamela to try
- to bring about a termination?
- No, I didn't!
Well, somebody did.
You know that and I know that.
Mrs. Barnes, I've been a doctor
for over 25 years.
Sister and I see cases like this
every weekend,
- don't we, Sister?
- Yes, we do.
All right...
someone come to the house.
And what did they do?
She grated pink soap
into a bowl of warm water
and she had a bottle of stuff and she put...
- And she used a syringe.
- Yes.
And no doubt, she'll use her syringe again.
And again and again
and again, and Sister and I
will have to deal with dozens of cases
just like Pamela's.
Mrs. Barnes, these people must be stopped.
You're going to have to inform the police.
I ain't talking to them.
Sister Coombes.
Righty-oh. They're ready for you
in theater, Mr. Walsh.
Thank you, Sister.
Mrs. Barnes, if you don't inform
the police, I'm going to have to.
Unfortunately, it's my
legal obligation to do so.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me, nurse.
- Yes, sir?
We're police officers.
We're looking for Sister Coombes.
Oh yes, sir, just follow me.
Sister, it's police.
Good evening, sister.
I'm Detective Inspector Webster,
- this is D.S. Vickers...
- Good evening.
Oh, good evening.
We was sitting by the side of the road,
there was bodies everywhere... stink, petrol...
I'd had enough.
I couldn't do nothing.
Couldn't run away, couldn't cry,
couldn't feel nothing...
I just sat there.
And all of a sudden,
there was this old girl...
staggering past us,
muttering in French.
Guess what she was carrying under her arm?