I believed in America
I thought this country
would be my salvation
When I was seven, my dad died of cancer
so my mom and I had
to stay with my uncle
The day my mom died,
I made a resolution...
...to escape this middle class rut
and get my doctorate in the U.S.
As if on cue, Uncle
Jagannathan arranged our alliance
Conveniently, he was in the U.S., so...
I see
That's why you agreed to marry
Mr. Vishwanath, despite the age difference
Of course it was
a marriage of convenience
I don't know what Wiz expected,
but he knew what he was getting into
- Wiz?
- Yes, Wiz is my husband
- Oh, is that your pet name for him?
- No way!
Everyone called him that, so I did too
We've never been a loving couple
I told him from the start
that I came here to study
To hit the books, not the sack
He smiled and agreed
He has a great sense of humourthough
So, what is your Ph.D. On?
Nuclear oncology
I had several job offers lined up...
But I chose Deep
nuclear research and oncology
The pay was good
No complaints at all, till...
Till Deepak?
Who is Deepak? Does he
work at your company?
No, no
I work at his company
He's my boss and is very rich
That's not why I started this...
Affair!
I'm not a bad person, doctor
None of my patients are
And you're not even my patient
I agreed to see you for Bindu's sake
She said you were her
rock during her divorce
She recommended Peter Manivannan
Detective Peter Manivannan here
Quickly, tell me
He just stepped out of class
Right nowfollowing your husband madam
Okay! Just find out if there's
another woman in his life
Most likely it won't be a woman
Let me know either way, immediately
If he hasn't, I'll feel very guilty
So guilt seems to be the key here
Alright...
When do you feel guiltier?
Before or after sex?
- What sex?
- With your secret lover
How crude! Nothing like
that has happened... yet
Yet? So it's imminent?
Lmminent? Look doctor, even if
I do it, what's wrong with that?
It's nothing new in America
Didn't Bindu tell you about my husband?
He's your husband
You tell me
When did you and Vishwanath
stop living as a normal couple?
He's not normal
So!
How is he?
You are the unique king of Aninaya
Child of Gokula
You emit crores of light
In this land of sorrow
you have come as the savior
How many times
will I yearn and die?
What should I do
for you to accept me?
Vaakala who has
accepted the worn garland
The girl was tired
of yearning for him
He sent her to
Indarlok as an angel.
Will you accept
the infatuation of the lady?
Aayardham Maaya you come
Aaya Maaya
Aaya Maaya, come
Without seeing you, I am not me
No root without a seed
Krishna! Without seeing you, I am not me
Sky that seen daily is not true
Dream that gives pleasure
is not happiness
I'm not me without you
Without seeing you,
without seeing you
Without seeing you
the heart of the lady is in unrest
No root without a seed
Shaamala Ranga with lyrical love
You are the Linga
who dances to the beat
She is tired without proper sleep
Radha is the one
who is yearning for you daily
Radha is for you only
Only one Radha is for you
You have superb hearing, guruji
You are the expert, Brahmin lady
Tell me howthe chicken tastes
How do you cook meat so well
despite being a vegetarian?
Don't even ask
You know my wife
She loves chicken
And I love my wife
I'm lucky to have been
blessed with such a good wife
The story is over
Off you go now
If you see like that
how I will approach you?
I stood in front of mirror
and saw myself
To join together,
I did rehearsal for...
...Hundred dramas and I looked for you
Without expecting, he!
Oh! He came from
my behind hugged like a top...
...and he kissed lip to lip
She forgot that there
is a world near her
Like a dress on the body
will you wear me?
From now on?
From now on? Kannaa...
My eyes which don't sleep,
will sleep because of Kannan
From now on... From now on...
Without this happening
Without seeing you
With this my heart beat have ended
Without thinking that useless carving
I'll live by breathing you
Deceit thief, Kanna Kanna
Desired artist Kanna Kanna
Hold on a sec
Hello... Mrs. & Mr. Vishwanath residence
Jagannath speaking
Hello, Uncle! How's London?
I don't know
- You don't?
- I'm at JFK now
JFK? When did you land?
Just now
You didn't warn me
Fine, come on over
Dawkins is with me
Bring him too
We'll have dinner here
I can easily cook for four
Okay? Well, then...
- Should I leave?
- Eat first and then go
I haven't even showered
You smell nice only...
You can use our bathroom
Hey! Shut the door
You want your guru to catch pneumonia?
Get going, ladies
Two lives are involved here
Actually, three
Dinnerfor two then...
He's probably made dinner already
You eat at home every night
Just for a change...
Okay Mrs. Vishwanath, what if
your boss asks you to work overtime?
The matter is settled
Go to my office, cash in the safe and
then dinner, I'll take that as yes...
Sounds like Uncle and Dawkins need to
brief us about something over dinner
But how? In front of Nirupama?
Nirupama won't be home for dinner
Did you have a premonition?
Exactly
Hello, Mrs. & Mr. Vishwanath residence
I know it is Nirupama
I've cooked a fantastic dinnerfor you
Along with a special surprise
- Ask me what it is
- No
- Why?
- Don't bug me
I'm stuck with work
I'm at the office right now
Boss' orders
I'll be very late
Kill joy
I'll tell you the surprise anyway
Uncle is here from London
Oh God
You didn't even bother
to tell me beforehand?
I just found out
He landed at JFK and called me
Dawkins is with him
- Which Dawkins?
- Say hello to him
Hello...
Hello, I'm sorry, I can't talk,
got mouthful of food!
That's ok no problem, can you
give the phone to my husband please
- Of course
- Thank you
Let them eat now
They are starving
Come soon
I'll wait foryou
You don't have to wait up for me
- I don't care for leftovers
- I'll make you something
There's no need! Send my
apologies to your uncle
- Who is coughing?
- Oh, that!
Just a lab technician
I hear car horns
You said you were at work
I'm going from the lab
to the office with the lab technician...
...the Mexican,
it's quite a long walk you know?
You're being a typical husband
Bombarding me with
questions and suspicions
That's all I can do overthe phone,
since I can't see you
Are you mad at me?
No, I'm all smiles!
You just
can't see it over the phone
- Come and show me then
- Enough
Okay, bye bye I got to go
Did you see how suspicious he was?
Why wouldn't he be?
My looks, his age...
I'm also rich...
Suspicions and
jealousy are only natural
This isn't funny
What will I do?
Will put the money in safe
Enter into the computer and then we go
Shall I go outside?
No no no open the computer
password is "Moolah"
- You just told me the password
- Ya... of course babe, Partner
now pass me the money
Is it safe to keep all this money here?
Why not in a bank?
You don't trust banks?
I do
But American banks don't
trust some of my customers
What customers?
Yemen, most of the
middle east countries, Nigeria
What is wrong with them?
Can't they stop bragging?
They have to raise Obama's ratings
So? Why celebrate someone's
death as if it were a party?
People usually
celebrate a demon's death
Try telling that to the demon's family
Why are we worried forthem?
What say youjohn
You should go home Ashmita...
before Nirupama comes
Come on I'll drop you
Go
Bye Viz. Jag. Work tomorrow, lets
hope it doesn't turn out to be a wet job
Wejust have to do what we have to do
Or our respect and dignity will suffer
We have a reputation to keep
Do we! What kind?
Good night cuckold
Come on let's go
Hello, madam! What's
your husband's name?
Fantastic!
After all this time,
now you ask me his name?
I thought it was Vishwanath,
a Hindu name
If you know, why ask?
I'm confused
I have good reason to ask
Either Vishwanath is
a fake name or he has converted
Converted?
Convert to what?
- Hello, Uncle
- Yes, tell me
Nirupama's fatso is after me
- Where are you?
- Me? Near the warehouse
Why did you go there?
Why? Because of Farouk
How would I know I'd be followed?
What do I do?
Run! Just lose him
What are you looking for brother?
Brother, my name is peter,
I'm looking for a friend's house
He gave me the keys but
they don't seem to fit in
Is it door number 9? Oh 27!
2+7 is nine, total of 27 is also 9!
Ok sorry forthe trouble brother
See you bye
Brother Salim
Brother...
Brother
Brother?
Where is he now?
At the factory! The meat factory
This way
Acouple of questions,
a couple of strikes
and he dropped dead
We can make it look like suicide
I got his signature just in case
There are many details in his notes
Name, address, client name,
Dr. Nirupama, boss Deepak
Deepak of Deep Research?
Take care of it right away
Hello, Deep? What a mess!
We've opened a can of worms
You know?
Know what?
Yes, that's right
Let's talk in person
Come right away
Here? Wiz will be home any minute
What the hell have you
gone and done women?
- Deep language
- Shut up
Why did you send your
detective to Farouk's place?
How did you...
Whose place?
Don't faff around with me woman
This is dangerous
Deep, why are you talking
like that? You've changed
I don't mind changing.
I mind dying! I'm scared
Why the hell did you
send the detective there?
I did it for us
I thought it would be good for
us if he caught Wiz red handed
- He's Muslim
- Your husband is Muslim?
Mr. Deep what a surprise
Did you offer him anything, Niru?
Are you Muslim?
What?
Cut the crap! Trust me, he is Muslim
What else have you been hiding from me?
Excuse me
Let's not argue in front of others
Listen to me...
If you touch her
I'll break your hand
Hands off!
I should be saying that
She's my wife!
How dare you come to
my house and threaten me?
Please get out
Oh, really? Come on
Let's go, Deep
No, this is our house
You stay, he gets out
We'll get out so the police can come
No no no no. No!
Did you lead
the detective to that place?
Why would I lead him?
He followed me to the warehouse
Hold it right there
Did I say warehouse? Did I?
You mother f-
You knew?
Sure, I've known my mother since birth
I'll break your face!
Oh, I get it! Don't insult
my mother in front of my wife
- Show some respect, or else...
- Or else what?
Deep, he can't take all that!
You'll kill him
One murder is enough
- Murder?
- Wow, look at his acting!
Why are you acting?
This won't work
I'll let them handle it
That's right
Call the police
No not the cops you fool!
Fool? Watch your tongue
I'm not your wife yet
Thank God forthat
Come in
It's just these two?
Who are you people?
He's my friend! He's here
to ask you some questions
Questions?
- Who the hell are you?
- Shut up
No questions! Come with me
Why should we?
I'm calling 911
Why would you hit a woman like that?
Would it hurt if I hit her like this?
That's why
What's your name?
- Tawfeeq
- Vishwanath
No hurry, Tameez
Take your time
Just keep chewing on
the tape until the cops arrive
It's stuck, boss
Excuse me do you have
scissor, knife, blade
Second drawer on the counter
Second drawer
Yes, that drawer
Why do you need scissors?
Why are you cutting your
dirty tape with our scissors?
Would you like it if we cut our
dirty tape with your scissors?
It's very unhygienic
Hello
Go
Go, go
Please shut the door
Please
Quickly
Shut it
What's your husband's real name?
Hejust told me
Some Muslim name
Tell him! Oh, Farouk
What? Farouk is my name
Tameez... Tariq!
No, don'tjust guess
The thug will... Sorry
The gentleman will hit me
Mr. Farouk, my name is Tawfeeq
She just found out now
You wanted to question them
I've brought them here
Do as you please, just let me go
Deep, you creep, you are
handing us over to these pigs
He hits me and you just stand there?
What kind of a man are you?
You need a man?
How about this one
kneeling beside you? Ask him
He'll rush to your rescue
What can he do with his hands tied?
Untie him and see for yourself
No, what are you doing?
No need, sir! Keep me tied up
I will...
Correct! Spit out the truth
Yuck! Why? There are
cleaner ways to say it
But you must believe me
I swear on Allah
- Nasser is my name
- What?
Tawfeeq is also a good name
Still, my name is Nasser
Did it hurt?
I always get hit there
At this rate, we won't have children
We? Who?
Who else?
For better orfor worse,
you are my wife
Okay, okay
Don't cry
Shush
Call Salim
I'll tell him and leave
No, no one moves without
orders from Brother Omar
Omar? Who's that?
Yes, Farouk
Tell me
Who?
Hold on
Brother, it's Farouk
Can Deepak leave?
We don't know who the other guy is
Who?
Dr. Nirupama's husband
A Muslim
He's living in New York
under a Hindu name
A photo
Photo
- Does he have a photo ID?
- E-mail
- What?
Send me a picture of him
- E-mail it
- Yes, Brother
Okay, Brother
I will, in two minutes
- Ask him if I can leave
- Shut up!
Sorry! Sorry very sorry
Krishna!
Krishna? Son of a-
You said you were Muslim
I swear on Allah
I'm Muslim
But I'm also a good actor
I got into character
You didn't like that?
Allah Hu Akbar!
Enough?
Mocking me?
You haven't had enough?
What's your problem?
So, getting angry?
Any chemistry student will be able to
decipher what is written on this sheet
This is Cesium 137 and RDX,
we have readied a device...
...to explode at our command
in your city, for the unin...
Again
Any chemistry student will be able to
decipher what is written on this sheet
This is Cesium 137 and RDX,
we have readied...
...a device to explode
at our command in your city
Yep... Now Hindi, ready!
Wait, wait
Enough! I can't take any more!
Got it...
He shook his head too much
Damn...
Hey hold him
Did you get it now?
Got it
Send Salim the picture
Get me some water
Tamil
Not anywhere near
the bomb of Hiroshima
Not even 1l10th of it
But strong enough to make New York
uninhabitable for the next 30 years
I've told them to dub
it into other languages
Behroz
Send it to the antique
shops on 5th Avenue
- Yes, sir
- Munnavar
Munnavar will pick it up in the morning
Yes, sir
- Be careful
- Yes, sir
Sir, I just got
Nirupama's husband's picture
I checked her files,
nothing on him, on your screen
Yes, Brother Salim?
Is anyone near you?
- Yes
- Move away
Tell me
The man on the photo you sent us...
Shoot both his knees
Don't even talk to him
Alive! I want him alive
Make sure he doesn't bleed to death
Bandage his wounds
He should be alive
when Brother Omar arrives
And Deepak?
Deepak is here
Should I send him away?
- Brother Omar, and Deepak?
- End it
No, he said to end it
Not the knees! The head
Okay brother!
What?
- What? Can I go?
- You can
But before you go you
have to do me a small favor
Hold this
Spread it out
Can't your men do this?
They will, but
you'll also help, come on
Come stand here
- Why?
- Just like that
It's a trick to make the couple confess
Hurry up
Don't you want to leave?
Hey, both of you
Look here
No rough stuff huh...
You must be a big shot
for Brother Omar to come see you
Allah
I'll tell you everything
From one Muslim man
to another, I beg you
Before anything happens to me,
please allow me to pray
Okay, pray
Is this fair of you?
You tie up a man's hands
and tell him to pray?
Shut up!
Don't take long
Understood?
Azar! Abdul has some bandages
Get them
What?
Our Lord, give us in this
world that which is good
and in the Hereafter that which is good
and save us from
the torment of the Fire
What did you think about him?
After seeing what you laughed?
While a seed sprout
A full form will come out
He is born for fire
He grew up with eternity
On a right time, his own
form will come out
Do you understand who he is?
You can see him as fire
He created history by breaking obstacles
Can you remember?
He is not a slave for anyone
He is not a king for anyone
He passes forest without
disturbing its serenity
What did you think about him?
After seeing what you laughed?
While a seed sprout
A full form will come out
He is born for fire
He grew up with eternity
On a right time, his own
form will come out
Multiple forms with
different faces (Like God Krishna)
Take the steps and
get out when I tell you
The car is parked outside
Drive it to the front of the building
Two gun shots
Count to ten
If I don't come out then,
leave and tell Uncle "code red"
What's code red?
He will know I'm dead
It's a code
No, no!
Get back! Else we both will die now
Two gun shots
Count to ten
And go when I tell you
- Two gun shots, Count to ten
- Go
Like small, small particles
he'll reside under earth
While digging the earth
the different faces will come out
Which face he'll take?
Who'll know that?
He'll take forms alternately
from different faces
Do you understand who he is?
You can see him as fire
He created history by breaking obstacles
Can you remember?
How did he escape with
so many of our men around?
Why are you surprised?
Remember, he trained the Al-Qaeda
Wisam Ahmad Kashmiri
Afighterfor the Liberated Kashmir
Son of the late Kashmiri from Pakistan
The Indian army is offering half
a million rupees for his head
He doesn't speak Pashto,
but he speaks Tamil fluently
Half a million rupees is easy to get
But a Tamil-speaking Jihadi is rare
Wisam Ahmad Kashmiri
Thanks
Where did you learn Tamil?
In Tamil Nadu
I was in hiding for a year
Coimbatore, Madurai, Ayodhya, Ahmedabad
Nasser, sir
Wisam Ahmad Kashmiri
Late Mr. Kashmiri's son
How are you?
I, I don't know Arabic
He says...
Do you read Quran in English?
- No!
- Then you know Arabic!
Welcome to Afghanistan
Come, let's go
- Afghanistan?
- He said "welcome to Afghanistan"
We'll be going there
You must learn Pashto and Arabic
I'll teach you
You'll teach me Tamil and Kashmiri
I don't know Kashmiri
My mothertongue is Tamil
How's that?
Isn't Kashmiri yourfamily name?
My father gave me his name,
and my mother gave him a divorce
I kept his name for my mother's dignity
I understand
No, I don't think you do
No brother, I do
Fatherless kids are very smart
Like you
Just kidding
Are kids who don't even know
who theirfather is even smarter?
Like you?
Just kidding
- Did you tell him? Did you?
- Why would I?
This guy is dangerous
Mammu
Wisam, meet this
important young warrior
Mammu, Wisam Ahmad Kashmiri
A photo?
How can we say no to Mammu?
The photographer
Come
Nasser, sir
All the ground and the dirt in the heat
senses dead and going blind
When you have war on your mind
Feel the drums of battle
beating in your head
And the only song you are
singing is the song of the dead
I am not a man I am a shell
that's waiting to explode
On my shoulders got a burning overload
Guns on our shoulders,
our life is unlucky
Always death is before us
We will win this battle now
We didn't choose war
But war chose us
Weapons are not in our hand
but we are in its hand
Doing rehearsal for war
which saves world
We promise death is our life
Camel's back is not a plane surface
In dollar world, there is no justice
Without getting justice
wars doesn't end
Guns on our shoulders,
Our life is unlucky
Always death is before us
we will win this battle now
With a rifle in your hand
It's down to man to man
To live you got to let die
I'll bear the sky for a nine
You can't afford to fail
got to fight it to the nail
Got to live the warrior's code
Can't afford to look back down the road
We roam, sleeping with Gun as a pillow
We roam, carrying death in our shoulders
Camel's back is not a plane surface
In dollar world, there is no justice
Without getting justice
war's doesn't end
Father!
DOCTORS WITHOUT BORDERS
Welcome home
Khadija!
- Whose horse is this?
- The doctor is inside
- Our healer?
- Well... No, the doctor
No no no... you sit, you sit
Is that your husband?
I'm doctor Clara, your wife just got
asthma attack but she is gonna be ok
Do you speak English?
Yes I do, woman
Now coveryourfeet, cover your
face and get out of my village
Damn! I was just trying to help
I'm really sorry
Jalal
It's alright to call a doctor
when you are suffering
My mother was an asthmatic,
that's why I...
You are right, but we are holding
American prisoners at a nearby village
She is a white woman
Why invite trouble?
Yes! My wife Khadija
- Hello, father!
- Nasser! You've grown so much!
Wisam! This is my future, Nasser
Greet your uncle
Peace be with you, uncle
How are you?
I am... and how are...
Uncle does not speak Pashto
Then what language do you speak?
Wow you speak English?
It's his mother's doing
Treachery
Do you still speak to him in English?
No! Not afteryou told me not to
So Jalal is the culprit!
Come here
Did you teach Nasser English?
I didn't teach him English
He learned it at school
School?
Oh, he learned it at school
Nonsense
I shut the school down a year ago
He...
Is the English teacher
Hold this
If you teach him one
more word of English
you will be hopping for
the rest of your life
Go!
My relative! He wants to
be an engineer in England
when engineers are choosing
to be Jihadis in Afghanistan
Wisam, whatever language
Nasser speaks!
He'll become a warrior
like his father
Like mamu!
- You wanna become a warrior?
- No
Then?
I wanna become a doctor
What?
I'm not a child
Push me, push me
Push me
NATO has attacked
- When?
- Now
They thought the Americans were here
They were fooled
Weren't the American prisoners here?
You think I'm stupid?
I never keep them in one
place for more than two weeks
They were here until last week
The sin of murdering
innocent souls is on them
There is a place far away
I want to go there some day
First came the British
Then the Russians
The Taliban
The Americans... And now you all!
- Shush!
- Go shush your mother
Men are nothing but
monkeys with tails in the front
Where atom was sown
you'll reap atom only
If the sea of greed erupts,
there won't be place to live on earth
No new houses have been
built in atmosphere
The one going to war
is a mother's son
If anyone of us dies,
some mother is sure to cry... see!
Where are we going?
Where the American prisoners are
- Are they here?
- Yes
- Since when?
- It's been a while
Hey Jo! Jo! Caption
Yes you, get up
Come out
Do you now agree, what America
has done to our country is wrong?
Say it
- Say it
- Yes
Thank you, now we will
do the same with you
But if you continue...
Open your mouth, good girl
Ok
Ask her what she's suffering from
Photo photo
Where's the doctor?
She's dead
He'll have to become the next doctor
Nasser, come!
I took the picture
Go, Go
Run! Run!
Hey, Nasser
The elders are gathering
for a conference tomorrow
He will also be there
He who?
The tall guy! Our sheik
I'd be honored to meet him
Americans
He started out with two
acres and now has 2,000 acres
Any currency
Tawfeeq is ourtreasurer,
sent to us by Allah
Tawfeeq, here is Nasser
Here he comes
Tawfeeq is not a Jihadi
But he is useful
Everybody knows you here
You might know some of them too
I believe I might
- Dear Nasser
- Oh, Omar
Wisam Ahmad Kashmiri
Great warrior!
Come
Meet my mother
Mother, this is Wisam Ahmad Kashmiri
She is saying you are Allah's warrior
and many generations will...
How do you say "dua?"
- Bless
- Will bless you
Are you as good as yourfather?
- No
- Why you not good as your...
Oh! May Allah forgive me
Forgive me
Sorry! Excuse me
A humble gift from humble farmer
Just a simple gift
Opium but lot of worth in America,
London, France, Pakistan and India
Don't corrupt my warriors
It's a simple gift
Yourfriendship is worth more
than whateveryou can give me
- So forget me
- Forgive!
- Oh oh... forgive me
- You don't have to do this
Mother
Have these sweets
What was that?
Put it in the bag
The Pakistani
Omar!
Let's go, let's go!
Come
Is he...
He is
Not everyone is this fortunate
Move! Move!
- Who is this man?
- Munnavar, a Pakistani
He must have some
information from ISI
He works for ISI?
He works for money
Anyone's money
He's like a rodent
scavenging everywhere
One day in the gutter,
the next, in the kitchen
Americans
Let's go! Let's go!
What's he saying?
We are fighting forAllah
Americans are fighting for oil
If you let them lay the pipelines
they'll be saying Allah Hu Akbar with us!
Allah Hu Akbar!
Let's go
Let's go, let's go!
Where is Sheik Osama?
Shouldn't we protect him?
No! He needs time to get away
We need to hold
the Americans back until then
Americans? Is there another
escape route from the cave?
Yes
- What?
- Yes!
Father!
Go! Go!
Go inside!
Omar! Wisam!
No, no
The Americans are everywhere
We have to get away
I'll be back with two vehicles
You stay right here
Wisam!
Nasser, Khadija, Jalal...
Don't worry
They'll be alright, God willing
I'll handle it
lmtiaz, stay here
We need to protect
Sheik Osama! Let's go
- Yes, let's go to our Sheik
- No one can catch Osama now
Brother Omar, you are our leader
- Let's stand and fight
- What's going on here?
Americans will not
kill women and children
They need us alive
They need their prisoners alive
- Kill the American prisoners first
- I'll take care of that! You go
- Me too
- No!
If anything happens
to Brother Omar, we...
You scoundrel!
Take him to the hospital
Take the highway
- And you?
- I'll stay with Khadija, Nasser, and Jalal
Go go right right
Let me see
- You'll need a couple of stitches
- No time for that
- There is
- They'll be here soon
There's still time for
the colonel to come
Are there any more files?
There are three
brown covers on the table
The memory cards also
have to be destroyed Sir
Sir? Isn't he your uncle?
Everyone has a double role here, happy?
Get the small box in
your closet underyour bras
How do you know
where I keep my bras?
- Hurry
- Hey, Ashmita!
Hurry up
- I have to stitch him up
- What? Stitch?
- In your closet, under your bras...
- I already told her
- Oh so you know, go
- Ok, are you a doctor?
You're the doctor, right?
Want to do it?
- I'm not a medical doctor
- Ya ya she is just a nuclear oncologist
Something is burning!
- Asmita
- Yes sir
We leave in 10 mins
Sir please got to stitch him up
Niru, pass me
the hard drive, there there...
Just through it, and that box
It's mustard
I must get needle and
thread to stitch Wiz up
You'll find them in
your lingerie drawer
Do you wanna...
- Are you sure!
- Go go
- Nirupama, what you doing?
- Packing
What?
Tell her...
We don't need that
But I need all this
- And that's an order
- Ok sir
I'm off to the antique shop
and Jag, you to the Embassy
- Please don't get shot any of you
- Thanks
- Ashmita
- Ya, I'm ready
Sir are you done, let's go
- Good Morning
- Sir i can't have you here
Why, what's happening?
Look its none of your business...
I need you to clear out of here
- Of course
- I need you to the right
In my house?
- We have a basement
- Yes
Wisam, can't let the FBI get us
Take me to the Embassy
Alright, Sir
He rolled off the hood!
Why are we running away
from the cops?
You're a good man, right?
Good man? Says who?
- Where are you going?
- To your office
Why?
To check how your office
helped Omar make the dirty bomb
The Cesium came from your office
Who is Omar?
My company would never...
I don't know anything
We know that, honey
- Just close your eyes, relax
- Why should I do that?
What happened?
Open your eyes
Can't give you a running commentary
I know where he's headed
Inform the FBI
They'll do ourjob for us
Did you see them dead?
Sure, the Americans
didn't take them away?
There was nothing to take away
I prayed over their ashes
Salim, leave us alone
Wisam! Wait
My warriors shouldn't
see me like this
Why is Allah
Making me suffer like this?
Salim, go!
I should've sent Jalal to
London to study Engineering
If we had sent Nasser along,
he would've become a doctor
Not ash
Why?
Am I not a Jihadi fighting for Allah?
Brother Omar, the answer
lies within your question
Death is a part of war
Jihadis like us don't shed tears
Only blood
Sheik!
Leave me
What's going on here?
Tawfeeq says this Pakistani is a thief
The Pakistani says
Tawfeeq is an American spy
What?
The Pakistani has
already been thrashed before
He wants revenge!
Where's the proof?
He says the proof
is in Tawfeeq's bag
Check it yourself
Check it
There's only opium in here
He sells it for us
Tawfeeq, you're a good man
Omar, what is this?
You know what it is
No, what is it?
I really don't know
Salim, what's this?
A hi-tech locator,
made in the USA
The Americans used this
signal to find our location
Hold this
My gratitude to Allah, Lord of all
May he bless and protect all
his families and followers
Save my son!
We are carrying out Allah's
punishment of this guilty man
I'm not guilty
I'm not guilty!
Yes... yes
Tawfeeq!
Save my son!
Allah is great
Praise be to Allah
This is due to your own deeds
Allah is never unjust to His followers
The ill you intended for
others has befallen you
Let him go
He is innocent
Go away
In the name of Allah
and with His will
Praise be to Allah
Wisam! Hey, Kashmiri!
Look at them
What have they done
to your brother?
Ok, alright you are set,
have a good day sir
Sir, excuse me sir
What ever happened
Wisam was one of us?
No... no
He is the enemy
He turned my family to ashes
You don't know the full story
That's why you trust him
Abu, clear the apartment
Leave no trail
This is urgent
Let's clearthe apartment now
This project was in
planning for at least three years
Your oncology machines are used
to treat cancer patients, right?
When your international
customers sent you their machines...
...for repairs or replacement
- Make a left
- I know
Omar's men would first scrape
the Cesium from those machines...
...and only then send them to you
Get it?
Like Aladdin and his magic lamp!
Exchange old lamps for new ones...
...and the genie is in Omar's hands
No way! Cesium can't be
scraped off by hand like that
Do you know what will
happen if radioactive material
Isn't handled under
proper lab conditions?
What?
Radiation exposure
In Tamil
What? What's your problem?
Nothing at all, madam
Just clearing my throat
Please continue
- Where was I?
- Cesium
If you handle Cesium
without gloves or masks,
...the handler will die slowly,
in six or seven months,
...as if from cancer
Actually, it is cancer in a way
Correct
Remember when they
held us in the warehouse?
They had those cargo containers,
like a hospital ward,
...with men lying in them?
Oh, no!
They handled Cesium
with their bare hands?
But why?
Jihadis
They know no fear
Unlike otherJihadis who
die at the push of a button
These are suicide bombers...
In slow motion
They are prepared to die
slowly to kill their enemies
And their leader is my comrade,
Omar Qureshi
Who is Omar?
The one who tried to
overtake us in the car
The man with the...
He became like that
thanks to the Cesium
God save us
Which God?
- Now, look here...
- We'll discuss that later
I want a detailed list of Deepak's
customers, accounts and addresses
But why?
Why should we do this?
This is the police's job
It's more complicated
Besides, this is
beyond NYPDjurisdiction
But within yours?
It's no time to argue
You saw what happened, right?
Right! You killed a lot of them
You rescued me
Thank you forthat
But this is wrong
You need a code
to open the safe
We know that, honey
We bugged your entire office
You bugged our office?
Oh god see this is what I'm saying
I don't know who you are
Who are you?
Are you good or evil?
Why didn't you ask
this man that question?
- He's dead
- So what?
Does death wash away sins?
So come on,
Let's then forgive Hitler!
This money is blood soaked
The blood of innocents
I've done a lot of
good and bad in my life
Some of my sins cannot
be erased even by death
To answeryour question
I'm a mix of both
I'm hero and a villain,
I'm good and I'm bad
What's that noise?
Let's go
Let's go!
Wisam get out of there,
now now now
What's this?
It's a high-tech locator,
made in the USA
The Americans used this
signal to find our location
Hold this
You rascal!
Lmtiaz, what have you done?
I told you to get it out
of the bag and destroy it
Why do you disobey my orders?
Sir, the Pakistani saw
me opening Tawfeeq's bag
I was going to do it later...
...but he raised hell
I'm sorry
You are sorry
Tawfeeq will die because of us
- Allah will not forgive us
- Us?
You mean 'you'?
Lmtiaz is a pseudonym,
not my religion
Do I have your
permission to leave? Sir
Dismiss
My gratitude to Allah, Lord of all
May he bless and protect all
his families and followers
Kashmiri, save my son!
I have a lot of emotional baggage
I don't have time to discuss it now
We have to stop Omar and his gang
Their accounts are in your computer
So please help me
You need the password
- The password is moolah
- Moolah
- Yeah its moolah,
- Yeah moolah, but?
Abbasi your service is needed today
I thought we have more time
Why you have problem?
No no
I'm ready
- Allah is the greatest
Salaam aleikum, my name is Munnavar
You have a packet for me
You? You are Munnavar?
Yeah! I converted
Look I have no time
Call Omar or Salim
You want me to call him?
No... No
Come on in
What's that?
That's mogul original
Be with you in a moment
Excuse me
Could you tell me
where the piano rolls are?
Right over here on the table
Alright thanks
Here you go
Thanks
Hello I am Munnavar, I have come
forthe package, Omar has sent me
Hi
Looking for this Mr. Dawkins
This guy Abassi received
a large payment
The shipment came from India
There's no entry for
the source of the funds
Check the bank
The money came from Nigeria
We don't have
customers in Nigeria
May be Yemen
FBI
Ladies and Gentleman,
You are under arrest
If you let me make a call
to my Embassy?
No and if you touch your cell phone
I might have to shoot you
Yeah I know but if you talk to my Embassy
they will be able tell you that I am...
You're what? The president of India?
Look you are coming with me, so are they
Hey hey that's my wife
Take it easy, or else
Or else what?
Listen to me
Hold your fire
I am... I am sorry sir
It's alright sir
Right now?
Allah is the greatest
The time has come
for us to go to Heaven
Tom the bomb in the apartment
is a diversion it's not dirty
Look you can lock me up in
yourjail and throw away the keys
I don't care but you
have to listen to me...
Tell your superior...
Send somebody to the warehouse
You would save lot of lives
I'm sure you have a Muslim name
Where were you born
Mayavaram
Come again
You first let me go
May be I'll come again
You are smart hands aren't you?
Ya...
May be
Thank you
OK sister is that how
you are going to play it?
I am not playing
I am telling you the truth
Satyameva jeyate
(The truth will triumph)
Look, you call me names again,
I will sling your hands
Oh god
What god is that? Allah?
That is my husband's god
My God has four hands
Four hands? AGod with four hands?
How do you crucify him then?
We don't crucify our God
Then?
We dunk him in the sea
Wait... I lost it
Ok you Son of a Gun, I getting
calls about radiation all over New York
So what, so what it's a dirty bomb
So if I'm gonna die, I am gonna
make sure that I kill you first
What? Want you wanna
me to do with this guy?
These are pigeons
released by Omar
What?
Look! Look for
the Pigeons of New York
The radiation is a diversion
The dirty bomb is yet to blow
I don't know what
the hell you are talking about
You will
If you listen to me
Ok wise guy how did you
know about the pigeons?
Many years ago
we spoke about it
We... who?
Omar and I
Don't mess with me
What if we detonated
a nuclear device in New York City?
How do we take
a nuclear device there?
I have a plan
We'll need many Jihadis
Won't you ask me how?
How?
We'll tie tiny capsules of Cesium
or Plutonium to the legs of pigeons
To the pigeons of New York City
The radiation detecting
Geiger counters will go crazy
They will feel stupid for
mistaking pigeons for Jihadi bombs
And when they relax...
Tom, this is Mr. Singh
from the Indian Embassy
- You wanna help Mr. Kashmiri up here
- Yes of course
He is a spook like us
Research and Analysis Wing, India
Oh! Look... looks like
that I owe you an apology
There is no need for that Tom
He understands
These things happens,
it's not personal just business
No time for thank you or sorry
There's work to do, Wisam
Hello Mr. Wisam the nation
is proud of you...
...and your bravery in exposing
the Al-Qaeda sleeper cell
The department of homeland
security has also expressed its gratitude
Hillary called me to thank India
Wisam you are alright I guess
Yes sir I am fine
Thank you
Take your brief from Col Jagannath
and Mr Gurnihal singh
They will tell you what to do...
...and the ambassador will keep me informed
I am sure you understand Major
Will do sir
I will take the brief from them
Thank you sir
- Hail India
Jesus man! Who the hell are you?
Have you spoken to Dawkins, sir?
- I thought he was with you
- No, I thought he was with you!
The last he called he said
he sent the tape to the Embassy
Yes, we got the tapes
Where is Dawkins then?
Wisam, is the warehouse around here?
No no no... lt's... it's
somewhere around here, I think
Damn it! There is a school nearby
Freeze, this is the FBI
I said freeze
Hello! Wisam here sir
Hello Wisam!
Trouble sir?
Absolutely...
Think it could turn sticky
Seems like it Wiz
Just a moment
If Ml6 and RAW try to blow us up,
we can do better, bigger!
Any last words to your handler
I just got a traced
call from Brooklyn park
You alright Sir
What are those pills?
Nitroglycerin
Sublingual
I can't have a heart attack just
because my best friend died, right?
We have work to do
That's his apartment up there
The Nigerian
He got a name?
I am not sure... Manabi... Vasabi...
Something like that
...they will send a photo id from precinct
How can you be sure
the is the guy?
I'm not sure
His name was in the computer in
your office, and he's Nigerian
If it isn't him...
Why sorry?
He's a criminal anyway
Agents to Dyker heights address
I will be there in 10
Do not approach until the SWAT team arrives
Possible suspect sitting on a bomb
Brad are the nest guys here
Good, SWAT
Alright
These must be the NEST guys
I got confirmation that Abassi is up there
Hey Brad
What's the status?
Nirupama, these are the nest guys,
explain to them about the Cesium and stuff
Tom, can I come with you?
Here is your glock
I don't know
howthe hell you got that
Thanks
Let's go
Hello, welcome, your
friends' already arrived
- Could be a dirty bomb?
- I am not sure
It is, it has Cesium
Cesium? And what would
you know about it Mam?
Atomic number 55; melting point
28.5; atomic weight 132.905;
I am sorry
The Cesium came from
the company I used work for
And you are?
I am doctor Nirupama
She has a doctorate
in nuclear oncology
Oh! I am Bob
no Doctorate
Nirupama, take a cab or a police
car and go as far away as possible
I will, if you come with me
I have a duty here
So do I
Have you seen the phone
on top of the bomb?
If someone calls this phone,
the bomb will detonate
We need a faraday shield
Which shield, what's that?
Hey! Your wife is a Techie and probably knows
a little more about the bomb than you do
- Oh Shut up & thank you Bob
- You are welcome
What's he doing?
He is praying for you
God almighty
Basically, except
that's the Arabic version
I need to call
Can I do it inside or outside?
Can I get you anything
to drink before we take off?
- Anything foryou sir?
- No
Target down...
target down...
Yeah that's a cell phone trigger
Get her
- We got him
- Well done guys
Get Bob up here
Hey, you can't go in there
Hey hey she is with us
- Wait! Where are you going?
- He is my husband!!
What's that?
Yeah yeah send her up
Thank God! It's over
No it's not,
it's not over
Faraday... we need a Faraday shield
It will be here in 5
That's too late
Someone could have heard our
gunshots and might trigger the bomb
It might be too late,
we need a Faraday shield...
Open its door
Careful
Wow... maybe, maybe not
Eitheryou are genius
or we are all dead
The subscriber you are calling...
...is not available at this time
Please try and call again later
Ok genius
That's enough
Go now
No
I'm staying with you,
If you don't mind
I do
- Suppose it doesn't...
- It will work!
Well I don't know
If anything happens,
whatever happens...
I want you to know
that I am sorry
If we come out of this alive,
I'll tell you in detail
Abassi, detonate now
Peace and blessings upon you
Brother Omar, Abassi is dead
How can I be at service to you?
This is Wisam
Thank God!
It's over
No, it's not over
Either Omar dies,
or I die
Until then, the story continues
What did you think about him?
After seeing what you laughed?
While a seed sprout
A full form will come out
He is born for fire
He grew up with eternity
On a right time,
his own form will come out
He's our only live agent
Like small, small particles
he'll reside under earth
While digging the earth
the different faces will come out
Wisam was a loyal Indian
He is one, and will always be
Which face he'll take?
Who'll know that?
He'll take forms alternately
from different faces
Do you understand who he is?
You can see him as fire
He created history by breaking obstacles
Can you remember?
He is not a slave for anyone
Let them go, Nasser sir
These are children of the land
He passes forest
without disturbing its serenity
What did you think about him?
After seeing what you laughed?
While a seed sprout
A full form will come out
He is born for fire
He grew up with eternity
On a right time,
his own form will come out
Do you understand who he is?
You can see him as fire
He created history by breaking obstacles
Can you remember?
He is not a slave for anyone
He is not a king for anyone
He passes forest
without disturbing its serenity
What did you think about him?
After seeing what you laughed?
While a seed sprout
A full form will come out
He is born for fire
He grew up with eternity
On a right time,
his own form will come out
Multiple forms
with different faces (Like God Krishna)
Like small, small particles
he'll reside under earth
While digging the earth
the different faces will come out
Which face he'll take?
Who'll know that?
He'll take forms alternately
from different faces
Do you understand who he is?
You can see him as fire
He created history by breaking obstacles
Can you remember?
He is not a slave for anyone
He is not a king for anyone
He passes forest
without disturbing its serenity
Face, face face, faces...
form with different faces