- Jacob was a good farmer.
- But not the man to buy your horse.
Hochleitner, wasn't it your father sold
him a horse with the ruptured testicle?
- "A bee sting made him limp that way."
- That horse had one good ball.
That's all it takes.
Rachel ...
I'm sorry about Jacob.
I know he'll walk with God.
Thank you, Daniel.
- Daniel.
- Good morning.
So, first time to the big city?.
You'll see so many things.
Close your eyes.
Open.
Samuel, careful!
You come back soon.
Samuel!
Samuel ...
You be careful out among the English.
Mama, look!
Oh, he's a cute little Amish boy.
We have tickets to Baltimore.
Where is that train?
It's delayed three hours. You'll hear it
announced when it's time to board.
Just take a seat over there.
I have to wait on these people.
Mama, look. What's that thing?
Don't go far, Samuel.
Mama ...
It's over there.
Hey, man.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Washing my hands, man.
- Let's get out of here.
- Hold tight.
I already did that.
Let's check it again.
Move these people back.
Get Schaeffer down here, now.
Who found the body?.
How you doing? You found the body?.
- I just reported it. It was the kid.
- What kid?
How do I know what kid?
The kid in the funny black threads.
How's he doing?
I'm a police officer.
I have to talk to the boy.
What's your name?
Samuel.
- Samuel Lapp.
- And he's your son?
We were on our way to Baltimore.
Soon our train is leaving.
We'll get you on another train.
Sam, the man who was killed tonight -
- was a policeman.
It's my job to find out what happened.
I want you to tell me
everything you saw in the bathroom.
There were two.
I only saw one.
- Does anybody know about this?
- No, nobody's talked to him.
What did he look like,
the man that you saw?.
- He was like him.
- A black man?
- He had black skin?
- Yes, but not stumpig.
What's stumpig?
On a farm, when a pig is born small
like that, he's stumpig. A runt.
So he wasn't a runt.
- He was a big guy, like me?
- Big guy.
- Where are you taking us?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
We're looking for a suspect. I want
the little boy to take a look at him.
You have no right to keep us here.
Yes, I do. Your son's a material witness
to a homicide.
You don't understand.
We want nothing to do with your laws.
Doesn't surprise me.
A lot of people I meet are like that.
- What did he say?.
- He asked who you are. Your name.
I told him we didn't need to know
anything about you.
Book.
John Book.
Where are you going?
- Looking good, T-Bone.
- What the fuck ..?
Is this the man, Sam? ls this him?
You're sure?
- Back off!
- We want no further part of this.
Okay. Get back in the car.
Hey, honest mistake, all right?
What are we gonna do with them?
A hotel?
No, they won't be there in the morning.
We'll have to get them in Baltimore.
I got it.
This is my sister, Elaine.
This is Mrs Lapp and Samuel.
- Where do they go, the blue room?
- Sure, the blue room.
- Can I help you with something?
- No.
Right back there, Sam.
- How could you do this to me tonight?
- It's important.
Just keep going straight through.
There's a folding cot for your son.
- I told you I had company!
- Are Jason and Billy asleep?
- And you got a man in the house?
- That's none of your business.
Anyway, they like Fred.
Who are these orphans, anyway?.
They're Amish.
- Everything okay?.
- Yes, thank you.
- John says you're Amish.
- Yes.
Oh ...
- Do we have to stay here?
- No, we don't. Just for the night.
Say your prayers.
- Hey, Captain.
- Hey, Bob.
- When can we leave the city?.
- I'll try to get this over with quickly.
But Samuel will have to come back
and testify. I'm sorry.
No, you're not. You're glad.
Because now you have a witness.
I just don't like my son spending time
with a man who carries a gun -
- and goes around whacking people.
"Whacking"?
Come here, kiddo.
Big guy ...
You can see them,
but they can't see you.
I want the hats and sunglasses off.
Straighten up.
Tell me if any of these men
are the man you saw in the bathroom.
Take your time.
Look real carefully.
Make sure.
Are you sure?
Okay.
- Three dogs to stay.
- Thank you.
- These we call Wurst.
- Good, good.
Your sister said
you don't have a family.
No, I don't.
She thinks you should have
children of your own, -
- instead of trying
to be a father to hers.
Except she thinks you're afraid
of the responsibility.
- That's interesting. Anything else?
- Yeah ...
She says she thinks you like policing
because you think you're always right.
And that you're the only one
who can do anything.
And that, when you drink a lot of beer,
you say things like:
"None of the other police know a crook
from a bag of ... elbows."
I believe that's what she said.
Good appetite.
Captain, Sgt. Carter for you
on line 23.
Hey, how are you doing?
- I don't know.
- Little boy ... He's shy.
Hey, knock it off!
I'll get it.
- Hi, Kathy.
- Dad!
- Hello, Marilyn.
- Hi, John.
It's McFee, Paul. He's one of them.
Positive ID from the Amish kid.
- McFee? Lieutenant, Narcotics?
- Right.
I hope you don't have any doubt
about that.
It fits. Four years ago, Narcotics runs
a raid in which, among other things, -
- 550 gallons of this P2P stuff
is confiscated.
They put it in Police Storage.
Philadelphia supplies
all the major cities with speed.
They need this P2P stuff to make it.
They pay up to $5,000 a pint for it.
I call Police Storage ...
No record of ten 55-gallon drums
of P2P.
That's $22 million.
Guess who ran the raid four years ago.
McFee ...
Have you talked to him about it?
No. Vacation. Florida.
- What do you need to clean this up?
- People from outside the department.
Put some guys on McFee.
Watch him, wait him out.
FBl, or maybe someone from Treasury.
I'll take care of that.
I want maximum security on this.
The boy's gonna have to be moved.
- Who else knows about this?
- Just you and I.
Get back! Police!
Back in the elevator!
- That's our car!
- Get in the elevator, you idiot!
I know you, asshole!
John says you have to leave now.
He says it's urgent. Dress quickly.
John?
Put my car in the garage
and close the door.
- I don't understand any of this.
- You don't know anything, okay?.
I borrowed your car. I didn't say why.
You never heard of that woman
and her boy.
- John, please tell me why.
- Just do it.
- You said we'd be safe in Philadelphia.
- Well, I was wrong.
Did you deliver the kid's interview
to Schaeffer?.
- No.
- I want all the paperwork to disappear.
- Tonight, you understand?
- Do you know what you're asking?
Just do it. I'm gonna disappear
for a couple of days.
- John, what is happening?
- I'll call you when I can.
And, partner, watch your back.
Schaeffer's in this thing too.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Working late, man.
That's it.
Hey, Fergie ...
I told you I hit him.
He's in trouble. I want to help him.
We just need to know where he is.
- What kind of trouble?
- A police matter. Don't worry about it.
You're saying he's involved
in something illegal?
Anybody who knows John
knows that's a goddamn lie.
Of course it is. But as long as there's
any doubt, it's better he clear his name.
It's better you should get off my porch.
I don't want to have to take you in.
He left with the Amish woman, right?
- She say where he is?
- She doesn't know. What about Carter?.
Tight ... but I'm working on him.
Samuel!
You should rest.
I'll make us some coffee.
No, I can't stay.
- Will you be taking Samuel to trial?
- There isn't gonna be any trial.
Rachel, what happened?
Who was that man?
- Why didn't you go to a hospital?
- No doctor.
They have to report gunshot wounds.
If they make a report, they find me.
And if they find me, they find the boy.
- Is the English dead?
- No.
He's upstairs.
I feel burning.
The bullet entered there
and came out there.
There's danger of infection.
He's lost a great deal of blood.
I am not a doctor. This man
should be treated in a hospital.
- There is nothing I can do for him.
- No! No, he must stay here.
What if he dies? The sheriff will come.
They'll say we broke the laws.
Then we must pray that he doesn't die.
If he does, no one must know.
But this is a man's life.
We hold it in our hands.
God help me, I know that, Eli.
But if he is found, the people who
did this to him will come get Samuel.
Then make a poultice, three parts milk,
two parts linseed oil, for the infection.
I will send Mary by with some teas
I will brew myself.
Thank you.
- I'll have to speak with the elders.
- As you see fit.
You prick...
Don't do it.
I'll fucking kill you.
You asshole ...
John.
Are you saying there's no way
we can locate this woman?
We're talking about
20th-century law enforcement.
There's yourproblem. YourAmishman
doesn't live or think in the 20th century.
If the Amish have taken yourman in,
he won'tbe easy to find.
The problem is, about every third
Amishman around here is named Lapp.
And we've got 14,000 Amishmen
justin this county...
That's very interesting, Sergeant,
but this is a very important matter.
It involves the murder
of a police officer.
- There must be some sort of directory.
- Sure. Tax rolls, voter registration ...
But I don't have the manpower
to send a deputy -
- to everyLapp farm in the county.
- Maybe you could use the telephone.
- Yeah, maybe I could ...
But since the Amish don't have phones,
I wouldn't know who to call.
Thank you, Sergeant.
It's been an education.
- Who are they?.
- The leadership of our district.
They decided to come see you
for themselves.
Except Stoltzfus. He came the first day.
I think he saved your life.
No, that was not I.
- Who else knows I'm here?
- No one.
- How long have I been here?
- Two days.
Rest, Mr Book. That's the ticket.
And drink my tea.
Lots of my tea.
- Tell him his tea stinks.
- You can tell him when you're able.
We're happy you'll live. We didn't know
what we'd do with you if you died.
It's not our place
to ask how he came to us.
Don't move!
What are you doing?
Come here, Samuel.
Sit down.
This is a loaded gun.
This is very, very dangerous.
Never, ever, touch a loaded gun.
Now I'm taking the bullets out.
Now it's safe. Okay?.
- Okay, Mr Book.
- Look, you can call me John.
I just don't want you to get hurt.
I didn't mean to yell at you.
It's all right for you to look at it
now. It's unloaded. It's safe.
You wanna handle it, you can handle it,
while I'm here. But that's not right.
Samuel, wait for me downstairs.
John Book, while you are in this house,
I insist that you respect our ways.
Here, take it. Put it somewhere
where he won't find it.
This gun of the hand
is for the taking of human life.
We believe it is wrong to take life.
That is only for God.
Many times the wars have come,
and people have said to us:
"You must fight, you must kill."
"It is the only way
to preserve the good."
But Samuel ...
There is never only one way.
Remember that.
Would you kill another man?
I would only kill a bad man.
Only the bad man, I see.
And you know these bad men by sight?
You are able to look into their hearts
and see this badness?
I can see what they do.
I have seen it.
And having seen, you become
one of them. Don't you understand?
What you take into your hands ...
... you take into your heart.
"Wherefore come out from
among them, and be ye separate, -
- saith the Lord."
"And touch not the unclean thing."
- Go and finish your chores now.
- Yes, Grandfather.
- Enjoying your reading?
- Yeah, I'm learning a lot about manure.
Very interesting.
What's that?
Your clothes were stained with blood.
You can wear these.
- They're your husband's?
- Yes.
It's good that someone
can have the use of them.
Besides, in your clothes
you'd stand out to strangers.
I should tell you that
this kind of coat doesn't have buttons.
- See? Hooks and eyes.
- Something wrong with buttons?
Buttons are Hochmut.
Proud, vain. It's not plain.
Got anything against zippers?
- Are you making fun of me?
- No.
Like the tourists ...
staring all the time.
Sometimes they come into the yard.
It's very rude.
- They seem to think we're quaint.
- I can't imagine why they'd think that.
Is there a phone somewhere near?.
The Gunthers across the valley.
They're Mennonites.
- They have cars, refrigerators ...
- I mean a pay phone, a public phone.
The store at Strasburg, but you won't
be going to Strasburg for a while.
I'm going this morning.
- But Stoltzfus said ...
- Yeah, I know what he said.
You can go with Eli.
He's taking Samuel to school.
- But you'd better hurry.
- Rachel ...
Nothing.
What?
- Hurry up, John Book.
- You'd better get going.
Hurry up, John Book.
My gun. I need my gun.
Thanks.
The bullets?
It's not much good without them.
Of course.
Thank you.
How do I look?.
I mean, do I look Amish?
- You look plain.
- Okay.
- Carter.
- Partner, are you okay?
Yeah. You?
- I'm coming in. How hot am l?
- Too hot. Don't do it.
- Don't come in. They're looking for you.
- And the kid. I have to make a move.
John, don't do it. You couldn't get
within a mile of Schaeffer right now.
- Can you hear me?
- Yeah.
What are we gonna do? FBl?
- Maybe.
- What about an investigative reporter?
No, they'd want to talk to the kid.
Listen, I'll make a couple of calls,
let you know when you can come in.
- I've got to go. Take care of yourself.
- Yeah, you too.
Here ...
Don't put them in the peaches.
See this stream?
It goes to the wheel -
- and it makes the wheel turn around.
Then it goes ...
It makes this wire
pump the pump over there, -
- into the well, and the well's water
goes into the house.
This place really echoes.
Hello!
- What's up there?
- Corn.
Would you like to hold my kitten?
I'll show you how to do a back rub.
You hold them like that, push their
head back, and you rub their neck.
Book?.
Is that you, Book?.
What are you doing there?
I'm just trying to get the car started.
If you are well enough to do that,
you can do work for me.
Yeah. What can I do?
Milking, maybe ...
Cows, you know. Cows.
Yeah, I've seen pictures.
Good. You start tomorrow.
It's 4:30, time for milking.
Milking stool, milking hat.
There's the milk.
Firm grip.
Pinch the top off and squeeze.
- Didn't you hear me? Squeeze.
- I am squeezing.
You never had your hands
on a teat before.
Not one this big.
Hey, I got it!
I got it!
I think.
Samuel, help him.
- No, no, no ...
- Eat. What's wrong with your appetite?
- I'm not used to eating at this time.
- You're not used to hard work.
Rachel.
Samuel ...