( accordion playing )
Radio announcer:
And remember to join us this weekend
for the Polish
Heritage Festival
featuring a battle
of the polka bands
at the Buffalo
Civic Center.
And after that, join us
for the pierogi eating--
( clicks off )
( man singing in Spanish )
- Stef.
- Hey.
We missed you
at dinner last night.
- Pam made pierogies.
- I was tired.
I bet.
You doing all right, Frank?
How's your mood?
I'm fine.
Yeah, you know,
I've been reading
about that Seasonal
Affective Disorder.
So?
Amtrak station.
O'Leary's getting on a train
to New York late tonight.
Apparently, it's
stopping just for him.
Fancy.
This one's real
important, Frank.
Who you telling?
Listen, forget it.
Want to stick around?
The game's on.
I promised Daniel
I'd go sledding with him.
Hey.
Great.
Just make sure O'Leary
doesn't get on that train.
( door slams )
( train rattling )
Announcer on P.A. :
The Lake Shore Limited Amtrak number 49
now departing
for Cleveland, Toledo,
South Bend and Chicago.
- Track nine. All aboard.
- ( car starts )
Man on radio:... makes fun of Polish
people and that's just not funny.
Man #2: Polish jokes are funny
'cause they're about Poles.
That's-- that's
why they're funny.
Man: You know like-- you take
a joke like this, you know.
Um, how do you get
a one-armed Polack out of a tree?
- Man #2: How?
- Man: You wave to him.
- See, that's not funny.
- Man #2: I think it's funny.
Man: They're not funny.
I'm Polish...
( train rattling )
Mr. O'Leary,
the train's here.
Where'd you get
that hat, James?
I took it off a snowman.
You look like an idiot.
Yes, I do.
James:
You know, my grandfather
was killed
at Pearl Harbor.
- O'Leary: These guys are Chinese.
- James: I don't care.
O'Leary: We need their money,
so shut up and smile.
We'll bring you
back an egg roll.
( car starts )
Here.
- Uncle Roman.
- No no no. No excuses.
- He never came.
- You slept right through it!
O'Leary's been
in New York for an hour!
I told you how
important this was.
Let me go to New York.
He'll be dead 15 minutes
after I get off the train.
You know what
the Chinese money means?
- Stef: All you had to do was kill him.
- I will.
No no,
it's too late.
When Eddie O'Leary
gets back from Chinatown,
the Irish are
gonna take the...
tiny piece of this city
that the blacks
don't already have.
And when that happens,
the Poles have nothing!
- Thank you!
- ( hacking, retching )
Oh God.
We've got to do something.
Not we, Dad. Him.
Just let me go to New York.
- We're not talking about that.
- You've got a problem, Frank.
Stef:
Yeah, a substance abuse problem.
Roman:
We can't let you do this to the family.
And we can't watch you
do it to yourself.
I just need
a few days to rest.
- Stef: Not good enough!
- Every time we send you out,
I have to make
a call to find out if they're dead.
I can't trust you
anymore, Frank!
- Even if you are my nephew.
- Stef: You let us down.
I want you to get yourself
into a program.
- Like hell.
- No, I mean it.
- I want you to go to San Francisco.
- Why?
Because I said so.
Stef: Look, you need to be
in a new environment.
What, they don't
have beer there?
Frank, we're just trying
to facilitate your recovery--
All right now, Stef!
Put it to rest.
Now, this is not
advice, Frank. This is it.
You go to San Francisco...
and get into AA
and you clean yourself up!
Or you don't
work for us anymore.
And we can't let you
work for anybody else.
Even if you are family.
All right, then.
Come on.
We've got streets to plow.
Frank:
Why San Francisco?
We can look out
for you there.
Roman's got a guy.
Hey, you'll be getting
away from the snow.
I like the snow.
- ( bells chime )
- Announcer: Your attention, please.
So do you hate me now
'cause I did this?
Right now, pretty much.
It won't last.
Try me.
I got you something.
- So when do you think you'll be back?
- How the fuck do I know?
( blues music playing )
# Yesterday's mistake #
# Has made my life #
# An uphill climb #
# Now I'm wondering
which road #
# Should I take #
# Mm-hmm #
# To make up
the wasted time #
# Lonely days
and sleepless nights... #
( snoring )
# How much more #
# Can a man take? #
( phone ringing )
( groans )
- Hello!
- Man: Falenczyk?
Yeah.
Saint Margaret's,
Geary and 28th,
7:00 p.m.
Be there.
( hangs up )
Great.
( bell ringing )
Man: Okay, so I just want
to let you all know
that, uh, there
is a 12-step progress meeting
here on Sunday night.
I encourage
you all to attend,
and uh, if you want to kick in
for coffee and doughnuts,
see me after
tonight's meeting.
Uh, also,
if you're parked
in the back of the building,
uh, you're gonna have
to move your car by 9:30.
And, uh, one more thing
before I give it
back to Emily:
The Rentals Association
is meeting here on Saturday,
so I would encourage
you all to be here
unless you want to see
your rent go up.
Thanks, uh, Emily?
Thanks, Juan.
All right.
Anybody new to the meeting
or visiting from someplace else?
I'm Janet
and I'm an alcoholic,
and I just moved
up from LA.
- Emily: Hi Janet.
- All: Hi, Janet.
Emily:
Anyone else?
All right, welcome.
As I said before, my name
is Emily and I'm an alcoholic.
All:
Hi, Emily.
Last November,
I celebrated my 10th birthday.
No drinks,
no drugs for 10 years.
I thought I had it down.
I got sober
when I was 21
and I figured at 31
things were different.
So I went out
and had a drink.
Just like that,
all grown up.
And I woke up in the park
three days later.
So--
( crying )
I'm almost glad
I slipped, uh...
'cause it makes me
a grateful alcoholic.
And the more
I live with that,
the more I think it's the best way
for me to go through life--
thankful.
Thank you.
Okay. Now it's
time for Juan
to come up and give out
tonight's chips.
So I'm Juan,
addict and alcoholic.
All:
Hi, Juan.
Is there anyone here
with six months sobriety?
Hey hey!
( all applauding )
Juan:
Good for you.
Leaving kind of early,
don't you think?
Who the hell are you?
Guy with a drinking
problem like yours
probably ought
to stick around.
Where you going now?
Probably going
for a drink, I bet.
It's a problem drink...
'cause you've got a drinking problem.
( grunts )
You fuck.
- I'm watching you, Frank!
- Who are you?
Roman called me
a few days ago
to tell me you
were coming out.
I'm the one who got
you to this meeting.
Gee, thanks.
Name is Dave.
And I also got you
your apartment.
I'm really scared.
You shouldn't joke, Frank.
In a town with a 2%
vacancy rate,
a real estate agent is God.
And that's what I am--
a real estate agent.
It's a swell apartment,
Dave. Go away.
Nope, I'm on
you till you leave.
Can't stop me
from doing anything.
I don't have to stop you.
All's I have to do
is watch, wait and make
the call to Buffalo.
You gonna run
and tell Mommy?
That's right, Frank.
I'm gonna run
and tell Mommy.
Shit.
- I'll see you in the morning.
- For what?
Work.
Fuck. Fuck.
Hey, come on.
It's kind of along
your line of work.
- I don't need this.
- I don't give a shit what you need.
- Doris.
- Dave.
Where'd he live?
Oh, in Pacific Heights.
Own or rent?
Own-- upstairs apartment,
two bedroom.
Swell.
Keys are in his
pants over there.
( chuckles )
Ha ha, Doris.
Come on.
Frank Falenczyk,
meet Doris Rainford.
Doris said she'd be
willing to hire you on.
- As what?
- General help.
- You'll love it.
- No, I won't love it.
I won't love it so much
I'm not even gonna do it.
- Yes! Yes, you--
- Like hell.
You got an unorthodox way of
being interviewed for a job.
Just-- keep--
Listen, Roman said
to get you a job.
This is it.
It's yours to fuck up.
However,
if you fuck it up,
I will be on the phone
to Buffalo.
Guess what, Doris?
Frank's decided
to take the job.
Super.
Hey.
( chattering )
Hi, I'm Becky,
addict and alcoholic.
Hi.
Frank.
Hand me a plate.
Thanks.
( clicking tongue )
- I also got an eating disorder.
- Good for you.
What, that I can say it?
Yeah, it took me so long.
And then I realized...
I was never full because
I felt so empty inside.
( slams coffeepot )
No no, you're-- you're
not supposed to eat those.
They're just
for show, okay?
Oh.
I'm kidding.
- I'm Tom.
- Frank.
- Hi. This your first time?
- I've had cookies before.
Mmm.
So what do you
think so far?
It's all right.
A little talky.
Yeah, you know, um,
some people kinda
tend to wallow in it.
But me, you know,
I'll go months at a time
without saying anything.
Plus, it's a really
good place to meet guys.
Um, I'm not...
It's okay.
I'll get over it.
Hi. Brenda, alcoholic.
All:
Hi, Brenda.
Brenda:
Just a couple of things:
They're ripping up
the playground next door,
so you'll have
to park on the street
for the next few weeks;
Second, uh, I have
a new list of sponsors
if anyone
is looking or...
Iooking to switch.
Raise your hands
when I call your names.
Tom, Robin and Susan
have all volunteered.
Tom's voice:
And the thing is, at a certain point,
you just decide that
the bar is not an option.
I just decide that?
Odds are you're
gonna drink again.
You have to want to quit.
- It doesn't seem like you do.
- Part of me does.
Which part?
Some part I don't like.
- Oh, like the dark meat on the chicken?
- Yeah.
Frank...
give it up
because you want to,
not because everybody
in the room's staring at you.
The first year,
it's all about trying.
If you think it's
about solving your problem,
you'll fail... a lot.
I'm already
pretty good at that.
You wouldn't be giving up
anything that you need.
Does that mean
you're my sponsor?
you're asking?
Is this the part
where we kiss?
Let's not make this any
harder than it's got to be.
Thanks for coming.
- Have a nice time in New York?
- I'm happy.
You see any shows?
Roman...
nothing drastic
needs to happen.
I'm completely agreeable.
You can plow and I can
offer you 15c
on every dollar that we take off
the union skim at Bethlehem Steel--
You cleared this
with your Chinese daddy?
Let's get something
straight, okay?
They're just the money.
I still do all of my own--
I started this business after the war--
me and Stan Falenczyk.
- We had nothing but a plow--
- Would you please spare me
that GI Diary bullshit?
You and that other
thug started a gang
just like everybody
else around here.
You got rich, you had a good run,
and now it's time to retire.
Hey!
This isn't just about business,
you Irish asshole.
This is what I do.
If you take it, there isn't
dick left for me in Buffalo.
Well, then get
out of Buffalo.
Woman:
Hey, are you Frank?
That's me.
- Doris said you could help me.
- I'm not following.
I'm Laurel Pearson.
I'm looking
for my stepfather.
- And there he is.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
He's already dead.
What'd he do,
tie it himself?
It's not that
easy in reverse.
Mm-hmm. We need
to change his shoes.
- We do?
- Yep.
Mom wanted him buried
in his favorite shoes.
He was a big bowler.
You don't seem
too broken up.
- Even people you don't like die.
- Yeah.
I was thinking he
kind of looked like a prick.
- If you don't mind me saying.
- No.
No, not at all.
Also...
he-- he seems
to have enormous feet.
Yeah, well, those
aren't his shoes.
I couldn't find his.
I stole those
from the Chestnut Lanes.
Don't tell my mom.
Might have to
break his toes.
Whatever gets the job done.
Laurel:
You look beautiful.
( mourners murmuring )
He looks real nice.
Good job.
Thanks.
Next time you might want
to ease up on the rouge.
He's looking
a little Raggedy Andy.
I wanted to thank you.
Abe looks like a real sport.
I'm glad you're pleased.
I'm sure he appreciates
how much care you gave to--
well, to make
every-- everything--
Take it easy, Mom.
Here.
Just think, he's going out
wearing his favorite shoes.
- And they fit like a glove.
- Oh.
Doris:
Can I help you to the car, ma'am?
That'd be fine.
Thank you.
Laurel:
Hang on a second.
His lipstick was smeared.
I got the eyes down.
I'm still working on the mouth.
You like working
with makeup?
I prefer it on women, really.
Guess it's hard to meet real live ones
in your line of work.
I'm usually in the back.
Although I've heard of
some people in your position,
you know, making do.
- ( chattering )
- Man: I'll see you there.
Thank you.
You're very strong.
Think my mother
might think you're cute.
She's been through a lot.
Hey, so maybe
I'll see you soon.
Jeez, I hope not.
Mom's still pretty frisky.
And I'm perfectly healthy.
No, look, if nobody dies,
maybe we could
get coffee sometime.
Sure.
That'd be nice.
( grinding )
Dave:
It's a housewarming present.
No. Yeah, right.
I forgot, you're a killer.
What do you want?
Roman wanted to make sure
you were okay out here.
I know you know he's
got his hands full back in Buffalo.
So...
I said I'd check.
I checked.
- And?
- Mmm.
You ball your socks,
you floss.
And you don't hide booze
in the toilet tank.
- You live like a Mormon.
- You want to look up my ass, too?
Maybe later.
Cashew butter...
Mmm, it's like peanut butter,
but with cashews.
Well, what is
wrong with peanuts?
Remind me to be
nice to you, cock.
( phone ringing )
Hello?
- Frank: Hello, Laurel?
- Who's this?
Frank.
Frank Falenczyk...
from the funeral home.
Finally.
What?
Frank Falenczyk,
funeral, finally.
Just playing with the F's.
For fun.
Oh, hmm.
Uh...
fabulous.
- I'm glad you called.
- Yeah?
Yeah, I need
those shoes back.
What?
- Just kidding, Frank.
- ( laughs )
Listen...
( clears throat )
- Do you want to go out tonight?
- Out?
- Yeah, with me.
- Oh, "out."
Well, yeah.
Fucking great.
I'm there.
- Where?
- What?
Calling you is about as far
as I got planningwise.
- Well, I know places.
- Great.
- Frank.
- Yeah?
I'm glad my
stepfather died.
( dial tone )
You know,
it's a whole lot easier
fucking girls you don't like
when you're really drunk.
I realize that may
sound harsh,
but in my defense, a lot
of them were drunk too.
If anyone was being
taken advantage of,
it was me.
And that had to stop.
Because it was there...
See you tomorrow.
...but it gets
old pretty quick
in terms
of nailing chicks.
- ( snoring )
- Man: Why am I here?
( whispering )
Frank.
You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- So where are you headed?
I have a...
thing to do.
( laughs )
You know, if you're
going to drink, drink.
But please don't feel like
you need to lie to me--
I'm not gonna drink.
- Okay. See you.
- No, really.
Um, I mean--
I have a--
A what, Frank?
A date.
Is that okay?
- You think it's okay?
- I don't know.
I'm not sure I've
ever done it sober.
That's why at the beginning
there's not always room
for both the program
and women.
Or men for that matter.
And you should just
know going into it
that... there's
the possibility
it might not turn out
that well, that's all.
You're giving me
tremendous confidence here.
L-- I just mean that...
you might be more raw
than you realize.
Frank:
Do you mind if I ask what you do?
I sell time.
I thought that
was still free.
Only on PBS, and even then
you've got to buy a tote bag.
You lost me again.
Commercial time
for Channel 8.
I was the Bay Area's
top selling rep last year.
They gave me a plaque
to hang on the wall.
Hey, congratulations.
It's not like the advertisers
had any choice.
- The word "no" means nothing to me.
- ( laughs )
( koto music playing )
- I should tell you something.
- You're gay.
I'm in AA.
I just started.
I'm raw.
Oh.
Well, are--
are you okay?
I mean, you're not gonna
run out right now
and get wrecked, are you?
- No. I'm fine.
- Well, okay then.
As long as you're not gay.
Thanks for telling me.
It doesn't bother you?
- You said you just started, right?
- Right.
- How many people have you told?
- So far...
- you.
- Why me?
I don't know.
It seemed important
to start off honest.
Mmm, that doesn't
bother me at all.
Besides, if I had to deal with dead
bodies all day, I'd be drinking too.
Oh, I'm okay
with the dead bodies.
Frank:
"I came to believe
that a power
greater than myself
could restore me to sanity."
Driver:
Thank you.
- Do you believe in God?
- I went to First Communion.
Think that's
the last time I saw Him.
Well, uh,
it doesn't have to be
the guy on the cross
or a golden calf.
You know, it can be-- be anything.
It's a God of your understanding.
You know, you can
make it a mountain,
make it a bridge,
make it whatever you want.
Just make it something big,
something good and not yourself.
I generally like
to run my own show.
Yeah, you've done
a real good job of that so far.
- Thank you.
- Even if I did believe in God,
I'm not so sure he'd want to have
anything to do with me.
Oh, the alcoholic's God
is a very forgiving God, Frank.
He's got to be.
I kill people.
- Excuse me?
- It's my job.
I've been doing it
almost my whole life.
I mean, I get
paid to do it.
I don't just
pick 'em randomly.
In any case,
I don't feel much guilt about it.
My drinking was interfering
with my work.
That's why I'm here,
so I can get sober
and go back to killing
people full time.
- Did you hear what I said?
- L-- l-- I did hear you.
I'm just trying to figure out
if you're being serious or not.
- What do you think?
- I think you're being serious.
Hello, my--
I hope this
doesn't scare you off.
Driver:
Hey, I gave you a 20.
No, l--
l-- I just want to know
that it's not something
you do for recreation.
No, it's not.
Hey, you gave me
the wrong change.
Are you drunk
when you do this?
Frank:
Not always.
But sometimes
I couldn't go drinking
'cause I had
to kill somebody.
And sometimes
I'd miss killing somebody
'cause I was out drinking.
To think I was, uh,
nervous about you
going on a date.
- Hello.
- Yeah?
- My change.
- Oh, I'm sorry. Excuse me.
- What'd you give me?
- Just keep it.
( tires screech )
I don't know
how you do this.
( phone ringing )
- Hello.
- Stef: I'm just waiting for my wife.
- She's trying on bikinis in there.
- Stef.
Really, I have to tell her
if she looks good or not.
No. You have to
stay out here.
- Frank: Where are you?
- At the mall.
So why are you
calling me?
Hey, remember when you
had to go to Florida for six months
after that
Canadian thing?
- Yeah.
- How was that for kids? Did--
- did they have a pool?
- What's going on, Stef?
Pam and Daniel are going
down there for a while.
You're not
going with them?
They have to go.
I have to stay.
O'Leary's being
an asshole.
Watch your back.
They might come after you.
- You want me to come home?
- Nah, forget it.
You're out,
stay out--
Yeah, Stef,
but I should be there.
Guess I just wanted
to hear your voice.
# Dupayash! #
( chuckles )
Yeah.
You're not pregnant,
are you?
Not unless you put
something in my egg roll.
And then put my
egg roll in my--
- Did I tell you where I lived?
- No, you didn't.
I called the funeral home.
Doris didn't
want to tell me.
Then I told her I was
from the AIDS clinic
and had to get you
your test results,
you know, right away.
Oh, good.
I can't wait
to see her.
Come on,
I'll walk with you.
You should try this.
It's easier on the shins.
So you're coming
to dinner at my house.
It's 9:00 in the morning.
Can we make it later?
- Later, sure, but you'll be there.
- Okay.
- See you tonight then.
- Hey, wouldn't want
- to take me down the rest of the way?
- Maybe later.
Hi. How are
the dead this morning?
Shut up.
- I'm in a good mood, okay?
- Not on my time.
Who's this?
- Patrick Heaney.
- What happened?
Well, Mr. Heaney
had a heart attack
on top of a long
flight of stairs.
Ouch.
Yeah. Wake's tonight.
He's got to be flushed,
prepped and casketed by 4:00.
I look forward to working
with you, Dr. Rainford.
Jesus, you're annoying
when you're happy.
( cracks )
Now that is one
good-looking dead man.
- ( laughing, chattering )
- ( Irish folk music playing )
( laughing )
Ah! I'm drinking that.
Sorry.
He hasn't looked
that alive in years.
I was working
from old pictures.
- You did this?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, thank you.
Thank you very much.
God bless you.
You did good work here.
I'm Walter Fitzgerald.
Frank Falenczyk.
Patrick here
was my wife's brother.
- She's taking it pretty hard.
- ( women laughing )
- I can see that.
- Would you have a drink with us, Frank?
No, thank you.
I'm trying to quit.
I tried that once.
Didn't take.
When did you start?
- Not too long ago.
- What's the difference then?
- Have a nip.
- No, really. Thank you.
You'd refuse a dying man
his last request?
Sorry.
You dying?
( laughing ) For fuck's sake,
I'm talking about Patrick.
That's what this
party's all about--
sending him on his way.
Thank you. Really.
I can't.
I'm working.
I got to keep
an eye on things.
He's not going anywhere.
Ah, Katie!
This is Frank
from the parlor.
He's who fixed up
our Patrick all nice like this.
Oh, God bless you.
Oh, that's nice.
Margie Rose.
Margie, look.
This is the man who
fixed Patrick's cheekbones.
Aw, bless your heart.
Will you have a drink
with us, Frank, huh?
- Uh, really, I shouldn't.
- Says he's on the wagon.
Really? What is he,
some kind of Mary?
( laughing )
To Patrick!
May neighbors
respect you,
troubles neglect you,
the angels protect you
and Heaven accept you.
To Patrick, the biggest
pain in my ass!
- ( Frank laughs )
- And the best friend I could have ever
thought of having.
To Patrick!
All:
( sighs )
- Na zdorovya!
- ( all cheering )
All:
Na zdorovya!
Whoa, hey!
Get this man
another drink!
Laurel:
Douchebag.
Cocksucker.
Fuckhead.
Frank:
Who wants to give me a ride?
Kathleen:
We're taking the bus home.
Walter will come and pick up
the car in the morning...
- after Mass.
- Aw, for fuck's sake.
Come on!
I'll drive your car.
I can walk home from there.
You don't know
where we live.
Nonsense, nonsense!
The bus is for cripples
and old people.
All right, okay.
( coughing )
( Kathleen moans )
Kathleen:
Left is your brakes, right is your gas
and everything
else is the same.
- Frank: Right.
- ( van starts )
- ( revs, tires screech )
- Kathleen: It's all right.
- ( Kathleen coughing )
- Think you could pull over maybe?
I've got the bladder
of an 80-year-old man.
Walter, we're almost home.
- You can hold it.
- Would you like to hold it for me?
( Kathleen groans )
Francis, pull over.
( tires screech )
Radio:
# And they call it lonesome town... #
( unzips )
Francis, can you do
an old woman a favor?
Sure. What is it?
- Give us a kiss.
- ( laughing )
- Oh!
- Just a quick one.
- Walter won't mind.
- I don't-- I don't think--
- ( tires squealing )
- Frank: We're moving!
( screaming )
( air hissing )
- ( dog barking )
- ( thunder rumbling )
- Kathleen!
- ( Kathleen groaning )
- Are you all right?
- I'm all right.
What happened?
Uh...
Walter, he made
a pass at me.
- ( thunder rumbling )
- Why the--
# In the town #
# Of broken dreams #
# The streets are
filled with regret... #
( dogs barking )
( coughing, sniffs )
- You look like shit.
- I need to tell you something.
No, you really don't.
Hey, get the fuck out.
( groaning )
I missed dinner
last night
because I got drunk
with little Irish people.
Well, you missed
some really good chicken.
You didn't
even occur to me.
Oh, well, fuck you too.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were in AA.
I thought you were supposed
to be done with this crap.
- It's not that simple.
- I don't need simple.
I just don't
need assholes.
I like you!
You shouldn't
be in the dark.
I'm gonna tell you
everything you need to know.
I thought you
did that last time.
- There's more.
- There always is.
I don't need this.
I've heard a lot
of lies in my life--
You haven't
heard them from me.
The drinking was
messing with my work.
- At the funeral home?
- ( sniffs )
No, that's temporary.
- What do you do?
- I'm in personnel.
- Hiring?
- Firing, more like.
Anybody sitting
on a drink tonight?
Come on up.
- Emily: What's your name?
- Frank.
Everybody, here's Frank.
Hi, I'm Frank
and I'm an alcoholic.
All:
Hi, Frank.
Yeah.
( clears throat )
I didn't really know
I was an alcoholic
until recently.
I'm from Buffalo.
Drinking's a pretty
obvious thing to do there
and, you know, there's
work and then there's...
whatever you do when
you're not working.
And I was either
working or drinking.
And...
I guess I thought I kept
the two pretty well separated.
It had to be pointed out
to me that that wasn't...
really true.
I kill people.
Not with my drinking.
I actually kill people...
for a living.
I guess that makes me
fucked up, I don't know.
It's the only job
I've ever had
and I'm good at it,
at least I was.
It's like any business.
You-- you have competition,
you identify them,
you offer
to buy them out.
They don't agree,
you go to other means.
Everybody I killed
knew it was a possibility.
I've heard people here
blame a lot of stuff
on their families.
I don't know.
I like mine.
I got a choice--
drinking or them.
I don't know the exact definition
of the word "alcoholic,"
but from what
I'm hearing here,
sounds like I'm
a pretty good one.
I'm an even better killer.
I want to do it again.
I will do it again.
But I know now,
the only way I'm ever
gonna get to do it again
is if
I stop drinking...
forever.
Amen.
I know now
I can't do it alone.
Proved that to myself
last night.
I'm not even sure
I can do it here.
And I'm really scared.
Thanks.
Well, thanks
for that, Frank.
Tom: Actually, it went better
than you think. It did.
Laurel: How do you know they
won't tell the police?
Frank:
It's Alcoholics Anonymous.
Somehow I don't really feel
that's what they had in mind
when they came up with the name,
but you never know.
How do you kill them?
Well, you just
put it on a level
with everything else
and you don't
think about it.
That's deep, Frank,
but I meant literally, how do you do it?
Guns, mostly.
I need a drink.
Can you give me a moment?
Of course.
( woman screaming )
I know it's kind of
a lot to swallow.
You're right.
Why should I bother?
Because you don't want
to be alone any more than I do.
You know, it's sad,
but that's actually
good enough for right now.
Here.
Go kill something.
- ( tools buzzing )
- Well, I'll pick 'em up myself.
That's a bullshit
excuse, Bill.
No, I don't have to try
and understand anything.
Everything I need to know
I already understand
pretty goddamn well.
So stay at home, Bill,
crack a six pack, watch your TV
and make yourself
comfortable,
'cause you just
made a big mistake.
Who was that?
- Bill Kubala.
- Guy from Diecast Direct.
He says they're
out of parts.
The parts guy
is out of parts.
( chuckles )
God!
That Irish bastard
is closing his fist.
Maybe we should
call the Greeks.
- Dad?
- Yeah, all right. Fine.
Let's call the goddamn Greeks.
You know, it used to be
shit like this happened,
we could just call Frank.
Frank's not here.
Lucky fuck.
( bowling pins clattering )
President William McKinley
was assassinated in Buffalo
at the Pan-American
Exposition.
Somebody shot
a president in Buffalo
and you thought,
"Wow, that's for me"?
No, see, he was
shot on the sixth,
but he didn't die
till the 14th.
For eight days he was
lying around in some mansion
while the doctors tried
to find the bullet.
Oh, yes!
No, I still--
I don't see.
They were using
an x-ray machine,
but he was lying on a bed
with metal springs.
So they couldn't find the bullet.
He got sicker and died.
Isn't that the kind of story
that's supposed to make you
grow up and become a doctor?
I saw the point in all
that poking around and malingering.
You shoot somebody,
you should kill them.
I saw the need
for precision.
Oh!
Gutter ball.
Can I get you
anything to drink?
I've got some
great tap water.
Comes out of that
tap right there.
Coffee?
It's a little late
in the day for me.
Why are you so nervous?
Coffee.
Laurel:
I like older men.
Frank:
Why?
Laurel:
Because you're done experimenting.
You're not gonna
wake up tomorrow
and tell my you're gay.
Frank:
What about the drinking
and the other thing?
Laurel:
Nobody's perfect, Frank.
- Coffee.
- Morning.
What are you
thinking about
sitting there
all serious?
My shortcomings.
Women don't even
pay attention to that.
I'm talking about this.
Oh, what is it?
People I've harmed.
You mean killed?
Well, eventually.
That's not the point.
I mean harmed.
The people
I've killed badly
because I was drunk.
This is your whole
precision thing?
Yeah.
Like here.
Look, Rod Fitzhugh.
Took me seven bullets.
And Karen Whittier,
I was supposed to slit her throat.
She moved.
I got her in the eye.
Fuck, Frank.
It's a little early
in the morning.
Well, I'm serious.
Jack Hensley.
He saw me first. I had to chase him
two blocks before I got him
in a Dairy Queen
parking lot.
That's no way to die.
So you got sloppy.
You can't unkill them.
They're still dead.
I don't regret killing them,
just killing them badly.
So what, then?
I got to make amends.
There are many
rewards that flow...
from the practice
of making amends.
So that's what you do.
And you do
what you have to do.
Thanks.
( cash register beeping )
All right, these can be redeemed
in any of our stores nationwide.
Clerk:
That's five $25 gift certificates.
Well, I can't believe you had
the addresses of their next of kin.
Even drunk, I kept
thorough records.
So a knife in the eye
is worth 50 bucks off
your next purchase at the Sony store?
It's a start.
All:
...to accept the things I cannot change,
the courage to change
the things I can,
and the wisdom
to know the difference.
Amen.
O'Leary: Let me have a couple
of kielbasa, will you?
Hiya, Roman.
Do you know that my wife
loves your sausage?
Stef:
We're fucked.
Hardwood floors,
of course...
with a view on three sides,
five bedrooms,
three and a quarter baths,
- marble fireplaces, walk-in closets--
- Dave.
It was on the market
in '92.
It went for a mil-five.
Now it'd go
for six-- 6.5 easy.
Why'd you call me?
They're tearing it down.
Some building inspector
with a bug up his ass
did an earthquake
retrofit check.
Apparently it's unsafe.
And is it?
- It's got hardwood floors.
- What does this have to do with me?
I made a deal
with the owner.
The city's paying him off,
but he's not getting
the real value
of the property.
The market is bullish, Frank.
This is going to be worth
maybe nine mil by
the end of next year.
What's your deal, Dave?
Well, if I could get
the city off his back
he'll split the profits
with me when he sells.
That's very
exciting for you.
Yes, it is.
And it could be very
exciting for all of us...
as I thought there would be
an opportunity
for you to...
negotiate with the city.
( laughs )
Frank, it'll
give you a chance
to ease back into things.
You're doing so great
with your recovery.
- Forget it.
- Come on, Frank.
- I've been more than courteous.
- You what?
I got you your job,
got you a nice place to live.
I didn't have to do that.
I could have gotten
you a shitty walk-up in the Tenderloin
or a studio
in the Castro.
You'd be up to your
neck in dog collars and assless chaps
if it wasn't for me.
Not to mention
the cashew butter.
And asking for help should
not be such a big production.
Why are you walking
like that, anyway?
Look, no shooting,
no stabbing.
No violence at all
if you can help it.
Just strong,
clear negotiation.
- I'll let you know.
- I'd appreciate that.
Lick-dick.
Becky:
Everybody laughs at the fat girl.
But if I'm drunk,
I can't hear them.
Maybe the drinking helps me
laugh at the fat girl too.
Thanks, Becky.
I know we're...
not supposed to respond
directly to each
other's stories,
but I was hoping I could
say something to Becky.
Is that all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, go ahead.
Becky, I think I might
know how you feel.
Life for me has pretty
much been a pain in the ass.
And I always thought that
was reason enough to drink.
I mean, sure,
now and then,
I'd kill somebody
and I'd cash a check,
and that made me
feel good, but...
I'd just use the money
to drink more.
You know?
I don't like me either.
Be thankful
that something in you
had the courage to say
"Enough.
I'm not the worst
fat girl in the world."
Uh, thanks, Frank.
No problem.
Up next is, uh...
John. John?
( jazz music playing )
# I just can't keep
a smile off my face #
# I belong
to the human race #
# It's my happy day #
I just take one big
look in your eyes
# And I'm lost
in paradise #
# It's my happy day #
# It's been
a long time coming #
# I'm gonna make
the most of it #
# Dear, I've been ready #
# A brand new habit
I just can't quit #
# Stars in my eyes,
dreams in my pocket #
# My heart is beating #
# I just can't stop it #
# It's my happy day #
# Aw, happy, happy... #
You should call Dave.
I don't know.
I know you're nervous,
but you're doing so well.
You've got real talent
and a real opportunity here.
I won't let you waste it.
Now, get out there and threaten to kill
that city supervisor.
- Do we have an appointment?
- I just want to grab you for a moment.
- Really?
- Just to talk.
I assume there's a reason
I'm not calling security?
Why aren't you?
I don't know.
As disturbed as I am
to find a man
in his underwear
in my private office...
I don't exactly feel
like I'm in danger.
There you go.
Supervisor Davis,
the reason I came to you like this
is precisely so you
wouldn't feel threatened.
Do you mind if I sit?
So, why would
I feel threatened?
- Are you planning on threatening me?
- Far from it.
I'm here today as a harmless
but concerned taxpayer.
I'm aware your
time is short,
so I'll just quickly address
my three main points.
One, what I'm proposing
would allow a historic building
to be preserved
for generations to come.
Two, this project would
enhance your reputation
as a sympathetic
civic leader.
- Security, please.
- Three, I have a gun.
Now I feel threatened.
Hey, what do you say,
Rosemary?
- Oh, hi, Stef.
- Hi.
- I'm sorry, I, uh...
- ( pool balls clacking )
We already made our bets.
Hey, Czyprynski.
Here to get a bet in?
Hey, look.
Irish guys in a bar.
( chuckling )
( sighs )
( grunting, thudding )
( moans )
Your time's up already.
O'Leary wants you gone.
Stupid Polack.
Then he said,
"That house?
That house sounds
perfectly safe to me."
And that was that.
L-- I put on my clothes
and I went home.
Here's to granting others
the serenity to change
the things
you cannot accept.
And the courage to accept large amounts
of change serenely.
And the wisdom
to know the difference.
- Laurel: Hear, hear.
- Cheers.
You did this sober, Frank.
Did a really good job.
I'm proud of you.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Now all you have to do is keep it up
for the rest of your life.
So, how's it
going with her?
- She's still here.
- Yeah.
Well, it's getting late.
If I'm not on the bridge by 11:00,
got to work
the truck lane, so...
Can I, uh,
catch a ride with you?
Sure. Just got to
use the bathroom.
You're not staying?
L-- I don't think I should.
L-- it's not because
I disapprove
of what you did today.
But you don't approve
so much you want to stay.
Oh, I want to stay.
It's just I've kind of
been accused
in the past of losing
my boundaries.
Which boundaries are those?
You name 'em,
I've lost 'em.
Remember the word "no"
means nothing to me.
Am I saying no?
You're getting better,
Frank.
I need to make sure
I am too.
Baby, I know
what you mean.
Tom:
Well, all right.
Thanks, Frank.
See you later.
- Okay.
( chuckles )
- Hi, Doris.
- Oh, Jeez-- son of a bitch!
What the hell
are you doing?
Working on being alone.
Well, work on it
someplace else.
Supposed to be
a part-time job.
Come here.
If I'm gonna be
working this late,
he's not the only
one getting embalmed.
This is it, isn't it?
What is?
No matter what you do,
you know, no matter how good you are
you die.
Then there's
nobody else around.
Well, he's not
exactly gonna be
washing himself,
now is he?
Hey, get the hell
out of here.
I don't need you
getting all freaky on me
- in the middle of the night.
- Sorry.
Just go be alone
with somebody else.
- Hey, thanks for the drinks.
- No worries, man.
Feel like
getting one more?
( chattering )
( knocking )
- It's Roman.
- ( door opens )
Stef:
How'd it go?
I talked to Spiros
and his brother.
They said if they wanted to back a
losing team, they'd buy the Sabres.
- Fucking Greeks.
- Roman: Hey, they gave us democracy.
You're gonna ruin
your eyes in this light.
Stef.
We're gonna come out
on the other side of this.
I'm gonna fix it.
Okay?
Dave: Money's no good here!
I'm the King of Nob Hill!
( crowd chuckling )
And half of North Beach!
How did that happen?
Mmm. Mmm.
What do you say, Franklin?
Uh, another one
down here, hmm.
( sighs )
You did me a huge
favor today, Frank.
Maybe you ought to
come hang with us.
You know, meet some
of the guys and--
You need to shut up now.
Yeah.
You know--
you know, you're...
a loser, Frank.
It-- it's just--
what's it like to have absolutely
no self-control, hmm?
In real estate,
you learn to expect
a certain amount
of natural resistance.
That's the part I like--
breaking their wills.
But with you,
what did it take?
Me asking.
You do what
you're told, Frank.
You're a victim.
You let people fuck you.
I'm gonna drink
this drink.
And when I'm finished,
do not be in this bar.
Oh.
You're not the only guy
in town with a gun, Frank.
Hey.
Keep 'em coming.
- You got any food?
- Check the fridge.
Pam made a whole
thing of golumpki.
Henry, go get some food!
( keys jangling )
( phone ringing )
Hello?
It's him.
- Yeah.
- O'Leary: Hey hey, Roman, it's me.
L-- I just thought
I'd call and say good night.
Yeah.
Good night.
( dial tone )
All right. Stanley,
get the front door.
Stef, get the back.
( doorbell rings )
It's Henry.
Henry's got a key.
Come on in, Henry!
( whispers )
Move.
( doorbell rings )
Here, I'll get this.
Give me the shotgun.
Give it to me!
You take this.
Check the basement.
- ( thuds )
- ( grunts )
- Stanley: What was that?
- Nothing.
I'm coming.
( moans softly )
( doorbell rings )
All right.
Let 'em in.
( groans )
( gagging )
You know, Roman,
you could have
still plowed.
( sirens wailing )
Shit.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
Stef:
They're all dead.
- Stef?
- O'Leary shot Roman
in my front hallway.
Couldn't even
shoot him standing up
like a regular guy.
Stef, wait.
Go slower.
He hit me
over the head
to protect me and--
You want me
to come get you?
No.
Stay out there.
Live your life.
It's my fault, l--
I should have
killed O'Leary.
Dave's voice:
You're a loser, Frank.
Roman's voice:
I can't trust you anymore, Frank!
Tom's voice:
The alcoholic's God
is a very
forgiving God, Frank.
( slams )
God!
I could really
use a hand right now!
Dave's voice:
You do what you're told, Frank.
You're a victim.
You let people fuck you.
Hi, you've reached Laurel.
Leave a message at the beep.
( beeps )
Laurel, hi.
You're sleeping.
I guess that's
just as well.
There's no way
to tell you this
that isn't gonna make me
sound like an asshole,
but I'm leaving
for the airport
and I probably
won't come back.
I would have just hurt you.
Forget me.
I'm a joke.
Find somebody better.
There'll be
other funerals.
I'm sorry.
( jet engine roaring )
So, uh, gonna find a meeting
when you get there?
- Cross my heart.
- Okay.
Oh.
This isn't the place
for this, Frank.
I can't exactly
take it onboard with me.
What am I supposed
to do with it?
Kill bad guys.
Crack walnuts.
I don't care.
You were kind to me.
I want you to have it.
Thank you. I'll think of you
when I shoot something.
Frank. What the fuck?
What the fuck
are you thinking?
What are you doing here?
Not letting you
get away with it.
- With what?
- With being a pussy, Frank.
I told you, I'm not
any good for you.
Don't you think I have
anything to say about that?
I'm not helpless, Frank.
If I'm getting screwed over,
I'm really quite capable
of figuring it out for myself.
And the only screwing over
that I've gotten
from you so far
is that bullshit message
that you left on my machine.
Laurel, I'm a drunk
and a killer.
And I still
want to be with you.
Doesn't that spell
anything out for you, Frank?
I know what has to happen.
You can't be a part of it.
Haven't you learned anything
in that stupid program?
You don't know
what has to happen.
You don't know shit
about how to run your life.
It's not that simple.
I saw you last night.
Well, fuck my boundaries.
You know, I wanted
to see you so I came.
I almost killed you.
I pointed my gun
right at your head
and I almost killed you.
You were gonna
shoot me, Frank?
Somebody!
It turned out to be you.
I was drunk.
Don't do this, Frank.
Sorry.
Hold on.
Boarding pass?
Ma'am? I can't let you through
without a boarding pass.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
Ma'am.
Do I really look like I want to go
to fucking Buffalo?
( sighs )
( toilet flushing )
( gasps, exhales )
Boo.
I used your toothpaste.
Stef:
The Chinese think O'Leary's a genius.
He's brought three legitimate
businesses with their money
in addition to taking
all our stuff.
It-- it's like
we don't exist anymore.
We don't.
They have one last meeting--
money, routes, shares,
some serious
business talk.
It's tomorrow.
One day at a time.
Stef:
Did you find one?
"Living Sober,"
8:00 Labor Hall.
You want me to go with you?
Not to that meeting.
Not to the other one,
either.
( car starting )
( car starts )
( chattering )
Earl:
Ray, how you doing?
Looking good, buddy.
Looking good.
Earl: Jim, haven't seen you
for a couple of weeks.
He's going to a meeting.
He's a drunk.
O'Leary:
Put two in his head.
Got it.
( doorbell ringing )
( knocking )
( doorknob rattles )
- Earl, alcoholic.
- Frank: Hey, Earl.
All:
Hi, Earl.
Earl: I see some new faces
here this morning.
Let me go over
some ground rules.
We meet early
and we break early.
We don't have
guest speakers
and we don't
have time for rambling.
We're here so everybody
gets to speak his mind,
have a doughnut
and get on with his day.
( doorknob rattling )
( knocking loudly )
- Stay there!
- ( screaming )
- Get your hands up!
- ( muttering )
Don't move!
What are you doing?
I can't--
I can't breathe!
( gasping )
I can't breathe.
I'm Ray and I'm
an alcoholic.
- Frank: Hey, Ray.
- All: Hi, Ray.
Pretty big day for me.
It's Sherry
and my anniversary.
20 years.
Well, l-- l--
I guess you could say
I put her through a lot.
She's been really great.
Hey, could somebody
get the curtains there?
( clicks )
Shit.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Stef: I know you think
you know Frank pretty well,
but there's probably a few things
you're not gonna want to hear.
Like that he came back
to Buffalo to kill Edward O'Leary
so he could stop him
and the rest of the Irish
from getting into bed
with some Chinese sugar daddy
and wiping your
family off the map?
Oh, and he's
a really big drunk.
Wow.
He's really opening up.
Earl:
Well, uh, I guess that's about it then.
Unless, uh,
any of our new faces
would like
to say something.
Earl:
Come on up.
My name's Frank
and I'm an alcoholic.
All:
Hi, Frank.
I just moved back
after a few months away
sorting out my life,
that type of thing.
I've had
a rough time recently.
I don't know if...
coming home
is a good idea or not.
But...
my work
is here in Buffalo.
I'm needed.
That part's easy to figure.
I can focus on that.
But the other part,
my life, I don't know.
It's hard here.
I'm not the same guy
who learned to be a drunk
in my parents' garage.
L-- I don't see myself
the same way.
I know now that I have
people I care about,
a person I care about.
Hi.
Hey.
I have a person I want
to have care about me.
I can't run away
from that.
She won't let me.
I guess...
what I'm saying is,
Laurel...
I love you.
I'm ready to spend my life
with you, whatever happens.
( grunts )
I love you too, Frank!
- It looks like James is here.
- I hope he turned up the heat.
Come on.
Can I get you
a drink, Frank?
No, thanks.
Nuh!
Get in.
Now.
- Here to kill me, are you?
- Yes.
Well, then you won't mind
if I get myself a drink.
You know, a guy
like me, Frankie,
I can't drink
out of the bottle.
You could pull an army tank
out from behind there...
I'd still kill you.
( chuckles )
Ahhh.
- You know I got friends coming.
- Come out from around there.
Are you good at your job,
Frankie boy?
Didn't used to be.
Well, how about now?
( crying )
Don't kill me, Frank, okay?
Don't kill me.
Well, it was worth a try.
You should think about getting
yourself into a program.
( laughs )
Well, I guess that--
- ( glass clanking )
- ( thuds )
Emily:
Anybody here with one week?
One month?
Six months?
One year?
- Anybody celebrating one year?
- ( all applauding )
( hooting, cheering )
( sighs )
My name's Frank
and I'm an alcoholic.
All:
Hi, Frank.
( jazz music playing )
# If you know love #
# Like I know love #
# The sun don't
rise the same #
# When a heart sings #
# Like a moonbeam #
# It shines on everything #
# If I told you #
# I was so sure #
# I woke up and love #
# Whispered your name #
# And, baby, believe it #
# I could not lie #
# If I try #
# If you know love #
# Like I know love #
# The birds don't
sound the same #
# With your sweet smile #
# Going on for miles #
# It warms up everything #
# If you told me #
# You were so sure #
# You found out that love #
# Had come to town #
# You don't second-guess it #
# If you know love #
# Cotton candy #
# And summer nights #
# String of pearls #
# And city lights #
# I would throw them #
# All away for love #
# Oh, yes I would #
# If you know love #
# Like I know love #
# The words won't
sound the same #
# I have stumbled #
# I have wandered #
# And found
sweet happiness #
# Well, if I told you #
# I was so sure #
# I woke up and love #
# Whispered your name #
# Well, baby, believe it #
# If you know love #
# If you know #
# Like I know love. #
( guitar playing )