Zero for Conduct
Little Devils at School
Written and Directed by
Jean Vigo
Cinematography by
Boris Kaufman
Original Music by
Maurice Jaubert
After the holidays, back to school
He's dead!
No larking about this year!
Think so?
Hey, Kid Beans!
We had a dead guy with us
Behave yourself Caussat!
I shall bring Rene Tabard
in the morning: he's homesick
He was dead
No kidding, see for yourself
I'm the new master
Huguet
Rene Tabard: absent, staying with
his parents until tomorrow
Good night, housemaster
To the foot of my bed, Dupont!
Who's there?
Caussat...Bruel...Colin
Where's Dupont?
I didn't call you three but now
you can stay here until eleven
I've got to go sir!
Can he go sir?
Sir, he's got to go!
Go on, don't worry about that fool
Are you there, Caussat, Bruel
and Colin?
Go back to bed
Keep quiet, or he'll drop dead
Up! Up! Quickly now!
Bruel, Caussat, Colin...
zero forconduct, detention on Sunday
Late as usual Bruel
Hurry along there!
Do you want a black mark for conduct?
BOYS IN CONSPIRACY
Here's the plan:
the conspiracy is ready
We're in detention,
so we hide in the attic
Caussat knows where to get food
What's Tabard looking at?
Watch out, teacher!
Oh Huguet's a good guy
So, on the Day, we hoist the flag
What about ammunition?
To your places! Get a move on!
Someone's pinched my chocolate
He's been snooping again
Been snooping again has he?
Give me your glue-pots
Watch this
Give me some paper from the drawer
The ink...and a pen
Isn't she a beauty?
Give me that
To your places
Caussat and Colin, bring me
your algebra books
No, don't bother;
you're in detention on Sunday
The Headmaster is here
Please come to my study, Housemaster
Our Commemoration Day is nigh
isn't that so?
I want no trouble,
no larking about
I mean Bruel, Caussat and Colin...
isn't that so?
As for Huguet, what you tell me
is most agitating
And finally, Housemaster, you tell me...
...Tabard and Bruel
are behaving unnaturally
Do you realize the immensity of
our moral responsibility?
Huguet is back alone?
What about the boys?
It's intolerable
Together again
It's unwholesome, Housemaster
They must be watched
Sit down
I might almost be your father, child
At your age, there are things...
isn't that so?
Bruel, I mean, is older than you...
Your sensibility, and then his...
isn't that so?
Neuropaths...psychopaths...
...and who knows what else?
Come and sit beside me
Colin and Caussat to the visitors' room
Do you want to be kept in?
I have to spend Sundays
in the kitchen with mother
You can visit your tarts
SUNDAY, CAUSSAT AT HIS GUARDIAN'S
COLIN WITH MA BEANS, HIS MOTHER
Come and look, Tabard
Give Tabard the chocolate
He's no traitor
Caussat should have let him
into the plot...
...because I say so
In any case, he's got a hiding place
He'll help us. He doesn't like teachers
any more than we do
Yes, Housemaster, beans again
Always beans!
I can't give the boys beans every day
Beans again!
Down with Ma Beans!
We hate beans!
Tabard's got a hiding place
He has? Where?
Well, if you don't know, shut up!
Bruel wants him to join
Tabard's a sissy
No, the Head had him up
for something
He's a sissy, anyway.
What good is he?
How very witty
But I don't care for all that at all,
not at all
Well, my lad, aren't we taking notes
this morning?
That's better
I was only saying...
Bugger off...you shit
Tabard
My boy, the disciplinary committee
has agreed
...under pressure from your
soft-hearted teacher...
Such magnanimity, Mr Viot
...out of consideration for your
family and concern for you...
...and in view of the celebration of
our Commemoration Day tomorrow...
...to excuse your behaviour
Especially as you have, so to speak
offered your apologies
Apologies which are worthless unless
repeated before your peers
We are waiting
Come now, what do you want to say?
Sir, I say the teacher is a shit!
War is declared! Down with teachers!
Up with revolution!
Liberty or Death!|Our flag must be raised!
Stand firm tomorrow!
We'll fight with rotten old books,
tincans and smelly boots!
The ammo's in the attic!
We'll bombard the old
Commemoration Day dummies!
The next morning,
fatigue is the quartet's accomplice
The boys have barricaded themselves
in the attic. It's unprecedented
Governor, what an honour
The Governor is seated
This is terrible