[Lively jazz music plays]
Stephen King's
"Bag Of Bones" Part 1 of 2
By Mikhel for SUBTITULOS.es
==SPREAD THE WORD==
[sinister music]
[lively jazz music]
Whoo!
[Sinister music]
[somber piano music]
help!
Help, I'm drown...
[Warped screaming]
[Gun fires]
[Gasps]
[Breathes deeply]
Last night I dreamt
I went to Manderly again.
- You all right?
- Yeah?
Just a bad dream.
[Sighs]
Well...
What?
Your book?
Done.
[Sighs]
Done, done?
Done, done.
Totally done?
Well, not totally done.
We'll still need the grand gesture.
That's all.
For a second, I thought
I'd been replaced.
Replace you, my lady?
[Whispers] No, impossible.
Come.
Come, your hand in mine.
Come on.
[Giggles]
Come, come, come, come.
I don't know whose idea it was
to put my office up here, but anyway,
here we go.
Keep going.
Too many stairs in this house.
All right, your throne, madam.
Be seated.
Okay.
Right.
Ready?
- Mm-hmm.
[Taps key]
"She smiled,
"satisfied...
[Keys tapping]
"And then...
"Unwrapped the chains...
"Around her neck.
"She smiled, satisfied.
"And then...
"Unwrapped the chains...
From around her neck."
Now...
Done.
[Taps key]
- Done.
- [Sighs]
- Hmm.
Mm.
What's with
the chains around her neck?
You're just going to have
to read the book and find out.
Oh.
[With German accent]
We have ways of making you talk.
Yeah, I bet you do.
[Moaning]
Why do you always have me
write the last lines
of your books?
[Sighs]
Well, because this book...
All of these books...
I couldn't write them without you.
Ah, are you just
trying to get laid, Noonan?
Mm, oh.
Is it working?
[Moaning and laughing]
Okay.
Cheers.
Thank you.
I'm your number one fan.
Great.
I'm going to go get some lunch.
I'll see you when you're done.
See you later.
Okay.
Have fun with Annie wilkes here.
Who do I make this out to?
Your best friend, Jimmy.
Best friend.
Maybe just underline "best"?
[Horn honks]
Hi.
- Hi.
- What's your name?
Ellen.
Good.
[Sirens wail]
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Oh, my goodness.
[Sirens wailing]
[Heart beating]
[Police radio chatters]
[No audio]
[Distant sirens wail]
[Sobbing]
Get off!
Get your hands off me!
[Solemn music]
- so sorry, Mike.
- Thank you.
Listen, they all fall down
is number four
on the times list.
Great.
Another push from marketing
and the right mixture of
in-stores and readings,
scribner thinks we might
be able to hit number one.
We haven't done that since
when the bough breaks.
Now before you get
all high and mighty on me
about demanding why I'm talking to you
about this during your wife's funeral,
it's because Jo wouldn't
have had it any other way.
She supported your career
when you weren't making a dime.
She cared about your books
as much as you do,
and she would be thrilled
to know that you have written
possibly your most successful
novel to date.
You're right.
When you're right, Marty,
you're right.
She would have wanted this.
None of this would
have happened without her.
To Johanna Beverly Noonan,
the best of them all.
Hear, hear.
To my dead wife.
Easy, Mike.
Thateer's not going anywhere.
[Clears throat]
[Sighs]
This is.
Look, um...
I... I can't imagine
how hard this is for you,
but you... you really got to take
it easy, okay, Mikey?
Jo was pregnant when she died.
What?
Turns out she was eight,
nine weeks pregnant.
I thought...
I thought the doctor...
Yeah, yeah, I know.
He told me years ago
I couldn't get her pregnant.
Hmm.
Oh, come on, Mikey.
You don't really think that Jo was...
What?
She was cheating?
Hmm?
Maybe Jo didn't want you to know.
Exactly.
That's not what I meant,
and you know it.
The noonans weren't exactly
the fathering type,
and dad, God rest his soul,
wasn't exactly cuddly.
Well, dad was a prick.
He was an Irish Mick of a prick.
And Jo knew you felt that way,
knew how you felt about being
a father because of that!
Just because he was a son of a bitch
didn't mean I was going
to be a son of a bitch.
I mean, a couple of years ago,
we even decided to have kids.
Yeah, I remember.
Jo told me about it
one time at dinner.
She never looked so excited.
We both were.
If it was going to be a little boy...
[Sighs]
We were going to call him Mike junior.
[Laughs]
And if it was going
to be a little girl,
she'd be...Kya.
Kya.
Kya Jo Noonan.
That's really pretty.
We tried to get pregnant,
but then I, you know,
I went to the doctor,
and he told me it was this
low sperm count,
and that was the end of that.
That was the end.
Jo wasn't cheating on you, Mikey.
[Clears throat]
When you sold me your share
of granddad's lake house...
Yeah.
I mean, Jo spent a lot of time there.
Yeah, of course she did.
I mean, the place was a dump.
It was a total fixer.
Yeah, I know, I mean, I was
really wrapped up in the book
and everything like that.
I went there
a couple of times with her.
I haven't been there
for two, three years.
[Sighs]
You and Jo were the best couple
I ever met, Mike.
So don't beat yourself up
over the little things, okay?
I just hope she wasn't
too lonely out there
on Dark Score Lake, you know?
Hope she didn't need somebody
who might have kept her company.
That's all.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
[Cell phone ringing]
[Groans]
[Breathes deeply]
[Scraping]
[Sighs]
[Scraping continues]
Oh?
[Grunts]
[Scraping continues]
- Aah!
- [Screaming]
[Swallows]
[Melancholy music]
[grunts]
[Sobbing]
[Phone rings]
Hi, this is Jo Noonan.
Leave me a message,
and I'll call you back...
If you're very, very good.
[Voicemail beeps]
[Phone rings]
Hi, this is Jo Noonan.
Leave me a message,
and I'll call you back...
If you're very, very good.
[Voicemail beeps]
[Keypad tone]
[Phone rings]
Hi, this is Jo Noonan.
Leave me a message,
and I'll call you back...
If you're very, very good.
[Voicemail beeps]
[Ominous music]
[phone ringing]
[Rings]
Jo!
[Screams]
[Distant sirens wail]
[Groans]
"Driving home...
[Cell phone chimes]
[Clears throat] Sorry.
Shut off the phone.
So...
[Clears throat]
"Driving home, I thought
of an old saying about...
"How one person can never really
truly know another.
"It's easy to give
that idea lip service,
"but it's a jolt
as horrible and unexpected
"as severe air turbulence...
"On a previously calm
airline flight to discover
it's a literal fact
in one's own life."
And I can't do this.
It's...
I'm sorry.
[Indistinct]
[Dramatic music]
hmm.
Always said I couldn't write
without you.
Jo...
Are you there?
Can you give me a sign?
Once for "yes,"
twice for "no."
[Cell phone rings once]
Jo...
Jo, is that you?
Hey.
Once for "yes,"
twice for "no."
[Telephone rings once]
Hello?
Mike, Mike!
I'm sorry about that.
I'm going through the tunnel.
[Sighs]
Marty.
Hey.
[Laughs] What's up?
We just got our hands on the
spring fiction list.
And?
And it's...
Looking a little bit crowded.
What do you mean?
How... how crowded?
Like, with some unexpected names.
Names like who?
Patterson. Grisham.
There's even talk of a newly
discovered Bachman book.
All those authors,
they don't publish in the spring.
I mean, they...
Those are summer, fall guys.
What can I tell ya?
Maybe they got some extra ideas
this year.
Some might've stockpiled novels
like squirrels.
Hey, what did you used to call
those books you used to write
when you were young and hungry,
and were writing books faster
than they could print them?
Trunk novels.
That's right.
Maybe those guys
dug up a few trunk novels
and dusted them off.
Figured, "what the hell," right?
What are you asking me, Marty?
Scribner wants to publish
a novel late winter.
What does that mean?
Pages with your name on them
by the end of the summer.
You're asking me to write
a novel in three months, Marty?
No, no, no.
You wouldn't have
to turn in the manuscript
until end of September
or early October.
'Course that means they'd really
have to crash their production,
but they can do it.
The question is whether
or not you can do it.
So what do you say?
Can you write your next novel
on this ridiculous schedule?
I can do it, Marty.
Attaboy, Mike.
Well, you get clickety cranking
on your next Noonan blockbuster,
and I'm going to get
to gouging these guys
for every penny they have,
for breaking your balls
and making you rush
your next novel like this.
Okay, Marty, that sounds good.
All right.
Oh, and do me a favor, will ya?
Yeah?
Take it easy on the drinking, will ya?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[Phone beeps]
[Sighs]
[Breathes deeply]
You're not disappointed in me?
Hmm?
Once for "yes,"
twice for "no."
Hmm?
Last night I dreamt I went
to Dark Score Lake again.
[Heart beating]
[Shrill screaming]
[Distant child crying]
[Distant screaming]
[Phone ringing]
Oh?
[Sighs]
Yeah?
Mr. Noonan.
My name is Bill Dean,
from down on Dark Score Lake.
I was helping your wife
renovate the property
you inherited a couple years back?
Okay.
The local kids are getting
Wilder and Wilder every year.
A bunch of them snuck
into your house the other night.
At least the only thing
I can think of happening.
Why?
Why is that?
Well, it's the windows.
They're all broken
from the inside out.
Now I just wanted to make sure
you'll approve the expenses
of getting them fixed.
This goes a little beyond
the normal caretaking
your wife hired me for.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure.
Well, do whatever it takes.
Of course.
Um, listen, Mr. Dean,
how is the lake house?
I mean, apart from the windows,
of course.
She's fine.
How come?
Oh, I was just thinking
of maybe getting away
for a while, that's all.
You... you want me to get
it ready for an extended stay?
Yes.
Yes, let's... let's...
Let's do that, Bill.
That would be great.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
She'll be ready for you,
Mr. Noonan.
I think it's a good idea,
don't you, Jo?
Once for "yes,"
twice for "no."
All right, let's go.
[Groans]
Oh.
[Sighs]
[Telephone rings once]
[Kings of Leon's pyro]
single book of matches gonna burn
what's standing in the way
run down a Mountain
now they're calling
on the fire brigade
bury all the pictures and
tell the kids that I'm okay
now arriving at Dark Score Lake.
[Turns radio off]
[Sighs]
Wake up, Jo.
[Foreboding music]
[crickets chirping]
Last night I dreamt I went
to Dark Score Lake again.
[Door slams]
Hello?
Mr. Noonan.
Bill Dean.
Oh, good evening, Bill.
Yeah, please call me Mike.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I just thought you'd like
someone here to greet you
when you arrived.
Oh, thanks very much.
I appreciate it.
You look just like your
granddad, Harold.
I do?
Yup.
Can I help you with your luggage?
Yeah, sure, sure.
I don't have much, but thank you.
[Eerie music]
yeah, just put that over there, Bill.
Thanks.
Oh, Jo really did a lot of work
to the place, didn't she?
Yeah, she sure did.
[Chuckles]
Bunter.
Jo named him.
It's the first thing we bought
when we inherited the place.
Got it in a little antique store
outside of town.
[Laughs]
When we got frisky here,
she said we were ringing
Bunter's bell.
[Laughing]
Uh, look, I better be off.
Okay.
Oh, I left my number on the fridge,
along with the number
of the local cleaning lady
your wife hired...
Brenda Meserve.
- Mm-hmm.
Told her she ought
to come by tomorrow,
if that's okay with you.
Great, great.
Good night, now.
You bet.
Mr. Noonan.
Hmm?
I was awful sorry
to hear of Jo's passing.
Right.
We all were.
People around here, they...
Really liked her, didn't they?
They did.
Well, good night,
Mr. Noonan.
Good night Bill.
Good night, now.
[Keys clank]
[Sighs]
Hmm.
[Playing guitar]
[Melancholy music]
come to me.
I have so much to show you, Mike.
[Keys jingle]
[Sighs]
[Jazz music]
let's fire it up.
[Cracks knuckles]
Mm-hmm.
[Sighs]
Come on now, something,
something, anything.
Something!
Come on!
Just give it to me!
Something!
Okay, Jo.
Tell me how to write, hmm?
Just tell me how to write.
[Bell rings]
Bunter?
[Foreboding music]
[bell softly rings]
[Continues ringing]
[Clears throat]
[Scoffs]
Okay.
Okay, Bunter.
That's enough of that.
[Bell rings]
[Soft rock music]
there are clouds on the horizon
so take a breath
you're in the calm
before the storm
if only for a moment
close your eyes
and feel the thunder
we can't hide
or run for cover anymore
it's time to take a stand together
oh, oh
hold on
'cause the tide is strong
it can't erase
the fire in her eyes
[sighs]
Greetings, my dear lady.
Greetings, my green lady.
Huh.
[Sighs]
[Scraping]
Oh!
[Grunts]
Jo?
Is that you?
Once for "yes."
Twice for "no."
[Bell rings once]
[Laughs]
Oh!
[Sighs]
You're here, aren't you, Jo?
[Bell rings once]
[Laughs]
[Woman singing shrill note]
[Groans]
[Woman screams]
[Bell ringing]
[Screams]
[Panting]
We're not alone, are we, Jo?
Huh?
[Door creaks open]
Jo, are you there?
Hi.
Who are you?
I'm sorry,
Mr. Noonan.
Name's Brenda Meserve.
Your housekeeper?
I... I used the key
to let myself in.
Yes.
[Chuckles]
Oh, yes.
Of course.
Oh, good.
Nice to meet you, Brenda.
How are you?
Uh, Bill said he told you
I'd be coming by today
to clean the place up for you.
I can come back at a better time
if you'd like.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
It's all fine.
Uh, I was just going to head into town
and get something to eat.
You're sure?
Oh, absolutely.
Any, uh...
Any suggestions?
Buddy Jellison's cafe,
right there on main street.
Can't go wrong ordering
the villageburger.
Ah, good.
Thank you very much.
Thanks for coming.
Hey! Hey!
Get out of the road!
[Horn honks]
Hey, get out of here!
Come on, come on!
What are you doing?
Ky!
Ky?
Is that your name?
Like Kya?
- [Panting]
- That's my mommy.
Sweetheart, what were you thinking?
- I wanted to go swimming!
- [Sighs]
Her name's Kya?
Kyra, but sometimes I call her Ky.
Oh.
- I'm... I'm Mattie Devore.
- Hi, Mattie.
- I'm not a bad mother. I swear to God.
- No, I didn't say you were.
Please don't mention this to anybody.
We're... we're going through
a little bit of a hard time.
Yeah, well, I think
it's a little late for that.
Yeah.
Well, thanks for saving
my little girl.
I guess God sent you here
at the right time.
God's got nothing to do with it.
I was just going to Buddy
Jellison's for a hamburger.
[Both chuckle]
This is a little bit weird
for me, but, uh,
you're one of my favorite writers.
And I can't believe you just
showed up out of nowhere
and saved my little girl!
Oh, thank you.
And you know who I am?
Of course.
You, uh, inherited
that house on the lake,
but you haven't been back since...
Yeah, since my wife died.
[Quietly] Yeah.
Well, um, you take care
of yourself now, okay?
Stay out of the road.
Nice to meet you, Mattie.
Nice to meet you.
- Bye.
- Bye!
Bye, Kyra!
[Tires screech]
Hey.
Hey, uh, you want a menu?
Uh, I was told
to order a villageburger.
One villageburger coming right up.
Uh, what do you want on it?
Everything.
And a local brew.
Grab a seat.
We'll bring it to you.
Thank you.
Villageburger, aud!
And drag it through the garden.
[Sighs]
See you made a new friend
this afternoon.
Yeah, yeah.
Two, actually.
I hear that Mattie Devore can be
quite a dear in the right position.
Yeah.
You hear a lot,
old-timer?
More than you know, son.
Old don't mean dead.
Thank you.
[Sighs] You'd do well
to keep your distance
from Mattie Devore,
Mr. Noonan.
- Mm.
Uh-huh.
How do you know my name?
We don't see a celebrity
here every day.
Yes, well, I'm hardly
what you'd call a celebrity.
Well, we take what we can get.
I'm really sorry to hear about
what happened to your wife.
Hmm.
She was a doll.
So when she'd come in here
and eat, uh...
Would she be alone?
Uh, I guess so.
Or sometimes
with Bill Dean and his wife,
sometimes with Brenda Meserve,
and maybe another friend or two.
"Another friend or two,"
huh? Yeah.
Maybe. Yeah.
Why are you so interested in who
your wife was eating with,
Mr. Noonan?
Mike. Mike.
Just... just call me Mike.
I don't know, I guess
I'd just like to know
what life was like
for a year on Dark Score.
You know, all those years that
I couldn't make it up here.
So...
Hmm.
Anyway.
Mattie Devore...
She's a...
A nice enough girl,
only she can be trouble.
That ain't fair, Buddy.
Mattie Devore's in trouble
and with the wrong people.
Person.
And who's that person?
Max Devore.
He's a mean old son of a buck.
I mean, he owns that big,
uh, computer company.
Multi-millionaire.
Yeah, I think I, uh, may have
seen him yesterday afternoon
in the window
of that old resort up there.
- Mm, warrington's.
- Mm, yeah.
Yeah, that's the fella.
Mean old cuss.
He wants custody
of the little girl, Kyra.
And why would he want to take
his daughter's little girl away?
- Daughter-in-law.
Mattie married Devore's only son.
- Devore had the boy
when he was 60-something
with some Vegas showgirl
who's no longer
in the picture, of course.
- Oh, okay.
- And so about a year ago,
Lance, that's Devore's son,
he goes a little Dark Score crazy.
What does that mean?
He tried to drown the little girl.
His own flesh and blood.
And Mattie ended up killing Lance
just to protect the little girl,
and ever since then,
Devore's made it his mission
to take Kyra away from her.
And what Max Devore wants,
Max Devore gets.
[Both laugh]
[Sighs]
[Chuckles]
[Clicks tongue]
[Phone ringing]
Hello?
Mr. Noonan?
Yes?
- I understand you met
my daughter-in-law today.
Ah, this must
be Mr. Devore.
Yes, well, it's a pleasure
to meet you, sir.
I'm concerned about my granddaughter.
I was told there was
an incident in the road today.
- Uh-huh.
How did you get my number?
You were seen talking to them.
Yeah, I met a woman and a little girl
on the road this morning, yes.
I stopped to ask directions
to Buddy Jellison's cafe.
Don't lie to me,
Mr. Noonan.
Why are you protecting
my daughter-in-law?
Did she promise you something, hmm?
Listen to me,
Mr. Devore!
I don't like your tone of voice,
and I don't know how
you got my number,
but you can shove it up
your ass, you understand?
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
Sometimes I feel
like a motherless child
sometimes I feel
[door creaks open]
A long way
from home
a long way
sometimes I feel
like I'm almost gone
whew.
Sometimes I feel
like I'm almost gone
a long way
from home
what in God's name?
A long way
from home
Sara tidwell.
A long way
from home
[Frankie and Johnny plays]
[Hums]
[Sighs]
Frankie and Johnny
were sweethearts
oh what a couple in love
swore to be true to each other
true as the stars above
he was her man
but he done her wrong
Frankie went down to the corner
for a bucket of beer to buy
the bartender told her
that Johnny was makin' love
to Nellie bly
he was her man
he was doin' her wrong
Frankie went home in a hurry
she didn't go there for fun
Frankie went home just to
get a hold
of her old .44
he was her man
but he done her wrong
and Frankie peeked in on the party
she got a surprise when she saw
Nellie and Johnny were makin' love
sippin' something through a straw
he was doin' her wrong
Johnny in a panic
mounted the staircase
screaming oh Frankie
please don't do it
she pulled that trigger
and rooty toot toot
three times she did shoot
he was her man
but he done her wrong
now this story has no moral
and this story has got no end
this story just goes
to show you women
that there ain't no good in men
he was her man
but he done her wrong
[applause]
[Knocking at door]
- Mr. Michael Noonan?
- Uh-huh, that's me.
This is for you.
Just take it.
What is it?
A subpoena?
To appear in the offices
of Elmer Durgin,
attorney-at-law and guardian
Ad Litem of Kyra Devore.
And it's my duty to remind you
of the penalty
should you fail to...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll be there.
[Sighs]
Let me give you a piece of advice.
Don't mess
with Mr. Devore.
Or he'll squash me like a bug?
[Scoffs] I believe the script says,
"let me give you a piece of advice.
Don't mess with Mr. Devore,
or he'll squash you like a bug."
That's right,
you can say stuff like that
because you're the hot shot
book writer.
[Clicks tongue] That it?
[Sighs] I'll see you
at the deposition, Noonan.
Sounds good.
[Sighs]
"Help 'r.'"
help her?
Is that what you're trying to say, Jo?
Help Mattie Devore?
[Bell rings once]
[Laughs]
[Bell ringing rapidly]
[Woman screams]
What?
[Screaming continues]
Sara tidwell?
Is that you?
Sara?
I think we might have company, Jo.
[Thunder booms]
Lullaby and good night
[groans]
With roses bedight
creep into thy room
[door creaks open]
There pillow thy head
if God will thou shalt wake
when the morning doth break
when morning doth break
if God will thou shalt wake
lullaby and good night
for the sandman is coming
bright angels are near
so sleep without fear
lay thee down now
and rest
may thy slumber be blessed
lay thee down now and rest
lay thee down now
and rest
lullaby and good night
for the sandman is coming
bright angels are near
so sleep without fear
lay thee down now
and rest
may thy slumber be blessed
lay thee down now
and rest...
[suspenseful music]
You didn't think you and your wife
were alone, did you, baby?
You want me, just like all them boys.
What boys?
You'll see, baby.
You'll see.
[Cackles]
[German accent]
We have ways of making you talk.
[Gasps]
Help her.
Who?
Mattie?
And write.
You have to write.
I can't write.
I can't write without you, Jo.
I'll help you now.
I promise.
There's only death out there.
Them that's got shall get
them that's not
shall lose
I still love my wife.
Then you should do what she says.
Didn't she tell you to help me?
That's not what she meant.
[Whispers]
You have no idea what Jo meant.
No idea.
Yes the strong gets more
mm.
While the weak ones fade
aah!
All will be revealed.
[Gasps]
[Sighs]
State your name for the record.
Michael Noonan.
As you know, I'm Kyra Devore's
guardian Ad Litem.
You know what that means,
Mr. Noonan?
You've been appointed by
the judge to decide what's best
for Kyra, should a custody trial
become necessary.
Very good.
And the judge would not,
in such a case,
be required to base his decision
on my conclusions.
But that's usually what happens.
[Electric whirring]
Sorry to be late, Elmer.
George had trouble getting here.
Let's turn to your first meeting
with Mattie and Kyra Devore
on the highway, shall we?
Sure.
Kyra Devore was all alone.
Her mother wasn't with her, right?
- That's a poorly-phrased
question,
but I suppose the answer is yes.
I'm flattered to have
my grammar corrected
by a best-selling author.
Is this
a better-phrased question?
You could have run Kyra Devore over
'cause she was playing in
the middle of the road, correct?
The phrasing isn't better, no.
And my answer is absolutely not.
I was driving the speed limit.
I saw Kyra in plenty of time.
So it's your experience
that most people obey
the speed limit
on that stretch of the road?
I haven't spent that much time
on Dark Score Lake.
I can't say.
Even in your limited experience,
do you think that most people
obey the speed limit
on that road, Mr. Noonan?
I haven't done
a traffic survey. Sorry.
Okay, Mr. Noonan.
Then answer me this.
If you hadn't carried
Kyra Devore to safety,
isn't it possible that
she could've been hit
by another car?
[Whispers] Just wait.
You know what?
I left my crystal ball at home.
[Chuckles] I really can't say.
I'd like to remind you
you're under oath,
Mr. Noonan.
I'd like to remind you that
I answered your question,
leading as it was.
Under oath...
[Sighs]
Let me ask you a question,
Mr. Durgin.
If you're on Kyra Devore's side,
why does it actually seem that
you're working for Max Devore?
[Taps gavel]
This meeting is adjourned.
This isn't over yet, Noonan.
Oh, thank God, Max.
It's just starting to get fun.
I couldn't agree more.
Mike!
Hi.
Thank you!
It's...
Yeah.
It's my pleasure.
Really.
I have to pick up Kyra from day care.
Would you like to walk me to my car?
Sure.
Why not?
So are you working on a new book?
- Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my God, I'm so lame.
That must be
the most annoying question,
right up there with, "where
do you get your ideas from?"
That is an annoying question.
The one about working on a new book?
Well, that's just...
Writer's block?
Mm.
Yeah.
My next book,
the one that's coming out
this winter...
Yeah, I know about it.
Red shirt man, right?
Yeah.
I wrote that book over a decade ago.
It's a trunk novel,
a book I never thought
should see the light of day.
I passed it off to my agent
as a new novel
just to keep my little...
[Sighs]
Dilemma a secret.
Nobody knows it's an old book?
Nobody but you.
Well, your secret's safe with me, sir.
[Chuckles]
My agent, my little agent Marty,
after he read
the first couple of pages,
he called me up and, uh...
[Laughs]
You know what he...?
- You know what he said?
- What?
This is the best thing
I've written in years.
Well, call it classic Michael Noonan.
Yeah, you could do.
Marty would, you know.
But Marty lies.
All the time.
[Chuckles]
He always wants to say
the right thing,
but says the wrong thing.
Thomas Hardy said that...
Compared to the dullest human
being walking on the earth,
the most brilliantly drawn
character in any novel
is nothing more than a bag of bones.
The only problem is that
sometimes I feel like
nothing more than
a bag of bones myself.
A bag of bones without
the energy or the... the talent
to do what I thought I was born to do.
I...
I don't think I can write anymore.
You miss her a lot, don't you?
Yeah.
I saw her once.
She was very beautiful.
Where did you see her?
At warrington's.
I was, uh, a waitress there.
And I was working a shift
with my friend Laurie wilton,
and... and I saw her, and I said,
"there's Mrs. Noonan,
the writer's wife.
Isn't she pretty?"
I think Laurie was more interested
in the guy your wife was sitting with.
What guy?
He was just a guy, I guess.
- Oh.
- Did I say something wrong?
Yeah, I mean, who was the guy
having dinner with my wife?
I'm... I'm sorry.
I, um...
No, it's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's just...
I'm sorry.
[Clears throat]
After Jo died,
I found out she was pregnant.
[Sighs] Oh, my God, I'm such an idiot.
No, no.
It's not your fault.
It's just...Messy.
Complicated.
Plus the fact...
I keep thinking that Jo...
That she brought me here.
After she died, she brought you here?
For a reason.
Like what?
I don't know...
Yet.
Crazy, right?
[Laughs]
Not to me.
Yeah, well,
maybe she did bring me here
so she could finally tell me what...
She was doing here.
Or maybe it's to get you
to write again.
Yeah.
Maybe you're right.
Okay.
[Sighs]
There you are.
Look at you.
Just look at you.
Hmm.
All right.
Let's just move that there.
There you go.
[Sighs]
"She lit a cigarette
"and took a long drag.
"What I saw made me
feel like screaming."
It made me feel like screaming.
[Laughs]
Thank you, Jo.
I always said
I couldn't write without you.
I just had to find you.
[Peaceful music]
[muttering]
Yeah.
Ah.
[Sighs]
29 pages.
Holy shit.
God, I'm good.
Oh, yeah.
[Sighs] Thank you, Jo.
[Water splashes]
[Suspenseful music]
[splashing continues]
What the...?
Help!
Help, I'm drown...!
To be continued...
By Mikhel for SUBTITULOS.es
==SPREAD THE WORD==