CATHERINE: Nine years ago I witnessed
my mother's murder.
I would've been killed, too,
if it hadn't been for Vincent.
VINCENT: I was part of an experimental
Special Forces group.
Their goal was to create
the perfect super soldier.
But something went wrong.
You're him.
Being in any relationship,
it's a risk.
Dr. Forbes, it's about
something that you wrote.
That was years ago.
I have evidence that a
cross-species creature exists.
I could do with a biochemist.
I'd include you in all
aspects of the investigation.
CATHERINE:
My nurse, you might know her?
We grew up together.
We were pretty close.
They said you were dead.
You should've
just given up on me.
ALEX:
I loved you.
CATHERINE:
Maybe I've been misreading us.
(panting)
(knock on door)
Hi.
Hey.
Remind me never
to get shot again.
Never get shot again.
Come in.
Thanks.
Now put the
dumbbell down.
Why do I get
the feeling
that this is going
to hurt even worse?
Give me your hands.
Come on.
You need to work
on your flexibility.
(laughing): I don't remember
asking you
to be my personal
physical therapist.
Okay.
Slightly back, that's it.
Careful.
You know, the first time
I got shot in Afghanistan,
I couldn't sleep for months.
Yeah, it's like
I'm sleepwalking.
I can't do anything,
and they've got me
on restrictive duty
until I am physically
and emotionally up to par.
(phone ringing)
And, again.
You want to
answer that?
Uh, no, it's okay.
I'll call her back.
Ah, it's Alex.
Really, Vincent,
it's okay.
I don't mind.
Uh, okay, thanks.
Oh...
Look, uh...
Catherine,
the thing is...
You... you don't
have to explain.
She was your fiancée.
You were planning
a life together for years.
Six years
and an entire childhood.
But... you and me...
You and I are...
You know,
I don't know what were are.
We're kind of in no-man's-land.
Yeah, I mean-I mean, we've
hardly even known each other,
what, a few months.
You know,
it's really none of my business.
ALEX:
I'll be right out.
Yeah.
You know,
it's, uh, it's good you called.
There's, um, there's something
that I wanted to talk
to you about, too.
ALEX: I'll be all yours
if you just give me a sec.
Is this what
you wanted to show me?
No.
This is.
(frame clatters)
How am I supposed to compete
with six years?
Not to mention the fact
that they grew up together
and that she doesn't know all
the darker sides of him.
But, if I say, hey, pick me,
and ignore that
totally perfect, caring woman
that you planned on spending
your life with,
I am a total bitch.
Aren't I?
Are you?
Don't "are you?" me.
It's bad enough
that I am being forced
to come here just to
get back to full duty.
I could do without
the self-reflective crap.
First of all, let me say
that I am impressed
by your willingness
to open up so quickly...
Yes, I know
the mandatory routine.
The sooner I spill my heart,
the faster I get out of here.
Second, what's mandatory,
is for us to discuss the trauma
that you went through
during the shooting,
not your boyfriend issues.
Oh.
Third, yes,
you would be.
And that's okay.
Sometimes in life
we need to be a bitch
in order to get
what we need.
And you're off to a good start.
Sorry.
I had enough therapy
to last a lifetime
when my mom was killed.
I know,
that is like throwing prime rib
at a Rottweiler.
Interesting choice of dog.
They're beautiful.
And dangerous.
No offense, Doctor...
Oh, David.
But I don't need a shrink
to figure out
what my problems are.
You mean running away from
tough emotions and throwing
yourself into your work?
I read your file.
I hope it was a good read.
Mm-hmm.
And from your file,
my conjecture is
you lean on
your crutches:
work, protecting people...
Yes, I took an oath.
To serve and protect.
But who are
you really protecting?
(man speaks indistinctly
over P.A.)
(keypad beeping)
(zipper closing)
Catherine?
Alex. Hey, hi.
What are you doing here?
I was just jumping
through hoops.
Had to get a final evaluation
before they return me
to full duty.
What are you doing?
I'm just heading home.
Running late.
For... the gym?
Oh, no,
it's, uh, change of clothes.
I live a very glamorous life.
(elevator bell dings)
Well, that's my ride.
See you.
Bye.
JT:
Someone please explain to me
how a guy who's unemployed,
never goes out,
and is officially dead,
gets not one,
but two smoking hot women
fighting for his attention.
No, JT, the whole point
of going over there
was to tell her
that I can't see her anymore.
Because...
because of Catherine.
Kind of, yeah.
I mean,
Catherine's life has
never been the same since
she found out about me.
And my secret.
Neither has yours.
You and Catherine, you risk
so much to keep me safe.
And you don't want Alex
to take the same risks.
No.
Okay, but what if
I don't tell her?
Vincent.
Look, I know what you're going
to say,
okay, but, JT,
to have someone look at you
and not feel like
you've got this big secret
that they have to protect,
you know.
Like Catherine does.
Yeah.
But, JT, I... I loved Alex.
You know, we spent our whole
childhoods planning everything,
and then... ah.
I don't know,
I guess I got afraid.
And you don't think
Catherine's just backing off
because she's trying
to do the right thing?
How did I end up
on Catherine's side of this?
My side of what?
All you, my friend.
(sighs)
What's this?
I don't know how
to tell you this,
but I ran into Alex
at the hospital.
She was putting a bunch of
boxes into her duffel bag,
and, it turns out that there
are a bunch of thefts
being reported at that ward.
You've been spying on her?
I followed up
on something I saw.
Vincent,
she's stealing medicine
and supplies from the hospital.
You don't actually know that.
Okay.
You can believe me, or not,
but there is an open
narcotics investigation
into these thefts,
and someone else is going
to find out,
eventually.
Does she know?
I mean,
does she know how careful
she has to be with your secret?
No.
♪ Beauty and the Beast 1x11 ♪
On Thin Ice
Original Air Date on January 31, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Ah, reading about skydiving
is surprisingly very boring.
Hope what you're doing
is a lot more interesting.
Oh, yeah,
I have sharpened every pencil
in the precinct.
Thank you.
So, how's the case going?
Mm, sorry, partner,
you're out on this one.
Okay, if you don't tell me
about this case,
I am going to make you get
mani-pedis with Heather.
Have you ever heard
of Noah Hawkes?
No.
He's one of Forbes'
wealthiest men under 35.
He went skydiving
with his wife.
Her chute didn't open,
neither did the backup.
EVAN:
That's because the parachute
was definitely tampered with.
Hey, Cat.
Hey. I didn't hear anything.
Based on the latent bacteria
on the rip cord,
it was cut 16 to 20 hours
before the jump.
All right, I'll look
into Noah Hawkes' alibi.
You may want to check
if he's left-handed.
From the angle of the cut,
I'm 99% sure
that the doer was a lefty.
But I did hear that.
That's my cue.
Okay, Tess,
you need to let me work
on this case,
or I am going
to get myself in trouble.
Sorry, Chandler,
Joe laid down the law.
You're to know nothing,
nada, zero.
Zip.
I'm mortified.
If I'd known it was
"towel-only" option...
Oh, God, oh, God.
It just... it started to feel
like old times
and I got carried away.
You know,
when that towel dropped,
I almost got carried away,
too, so...
Look, Alex,
I'm sorry...
No, I know.
This is all so strange.
I mean,
you knew me better than anyone.
Before or since.
I used to think I knew you
better than anyone.
You did know me.
But I am a completely
different person now.
Who isn't?
Vince, I admit,
with you back, it's
all so confusing.
I'm beginning to remember
my old self,
and I want that life
back so badly.
I guess the question is,
do you?
Want to go back in time
to the way we used to be?
Yeah,
yeah, I do.
But...
a lot has changed.
And I guess we both have
a few new secrets, yeah?
She saw me, didn't she?
(quiet laugh)
You could never lie
to me, Vince.
Your handler,
Catherine,
she caught me taking stuff
from the hospital.
I told her that you...
weren't into anything like that.
Actually I am.
Kind of.
You know how you said you
wanted your old life back?
Or parts of it anyway.
I have something to show you.
And no, it's not my linen
collection this time.
(bell jingles)
(distant siren wailing)
Hi.
Hello.
Okay, I never pegged you as
a drug lord, but this...
I have my doubts.
It'll all make sense
in a moment.
(coughing nearby)
What is this place?
Like a care unit?
It's for people
who can't pay
or can't get to
another facility.
There's still a lot of people
our there without jobs,
without any insurance.
They fall through the cracks.
Okay, Mrs. Voluska?
You can take a seat in there.
I'll be right with you.
Um, Nurse Alex?
Who's he?
Um, just a...
Just a friend.
Doctor.
TESS:
Mr. Hawkes,
did anyone besides
you and your wife
have access
to her parachute?
Am I being interrogated?
No, sir, I'm just trying
to assess the facts.
The facts are that Lisa
and I pack our own chutes.
And the morning of the jump,
nothing was out of place?
No one touches them but us.
I know this is
difficult, I only have
a few more questions to ask you.
You're with Noah Hawkes, right?
I bet you're a one sugar?
Black.
Ah.
I'm on the
Neanderthal diet.
What is the Neanderthal diet?
Nothing a caveman wouldn't eat.
I'm ready to kill somebody
for a carb.
(laughs)
Catherine Chandler.
Pam Davis,
CFO of Hawkes Worldwide.
Ah.
So how is Noah taking it?
He's a wreck.
Plus we're in the middle
of an IPO
and we spent the entire day
before Lisa's death,
uh, in marathon meetings.
Wow, sounds stressful.
Yeah.
Tears me up
to see Noah like this.
Did he have a happy marriage?
Storybook.
Outside of work,
they did everything together.
Lisa and I,
we loved living on the edge.
And we knew with that
risk comes a cost.
I just never dreamed the
price would be so high.
PAM:
When somebody becomes
that integral to your life
and suddenly they're gone,
it makes you wonder
who you are without them.
Yeah, I have some personal
experience in that department.
Thanks for the coffee.
Yeah.
And if we need to talk
with you further?
I work the rest
of the afternoon,
then tonight there's
this event I have to be at.
That I obviously
don't want to be at.
But that you can't miss.
Exclusive billionaire boys' club
kind of deal at the Dylan Club.
You are more than welcome
to stop by if you need
to pull me aside
for a few minutes.
Call me whenever--
I'll track him down.
We should go to
the Dylan Club.
What, and party
with a suspect?
No, we'll go under the guise
of working on the case.
When in reality we're going...?
About the case.
And because you and I
are both attractive women
who shouldn't be wasting
our youth on available men.
So what, you want to get dressed
up, put on smoky eyes
and fall in love?
Is that it?
That's it exactly.
And, look, if we happen to
catch a break in the case,
it's two birds with one stone.
Preferably a diamond.
The big question is
what to wear.
(phone ringing)
JT:
Leave a message and if I don't
get back to you it's probably
because I don't really like you.
JT, it's Evan Marks.
I think I found another victim
of our cross-species animal.
I have clearance
to exhume the body
and in the spirit
of our partnership,
I thought you'd want to be there
to confirm if it's a match.
Call me. This could be big.
(phone beeps)
Wow.
Claire.
Someone sounds excited.
What are you doing here?
I know we were supposed
to meet at
the restaurant, but
I thought I'd surprise you.
It's a welcome surprise.
Mm.
A very welcome surprise.
I think restaurants
are overrated.
I find morgues
much more enticing.
As do I.
(laughing)
VINCENT:
Okay, buddy,
I'm not gonna lie
to you.
This is not gonna
feel good, okay,
but it's gonna
be over quickly.
(exhales loudly)
Yeah, breathe.
And... one.
And two.
(grunts)
Ow!
(sighs)
Okay?
(panting)
You didn't count to three.
Yeah.
Well, waiting
for the pain is worse...
Worse than the real thing.
...thing.
You're glowing.
Uh, I'm a guy.
Guys don't glow.
Do they, Milo? Okay.
Hey, no more
board sliding, okay?
Okay.
All right, man. All right.
See you, Milo.
Thanks.
It felt good, didn't it?
Helping?
Uh, yeah, it did.
A little more
exciting than...?
I mean, wherever
it is you live,
I keep imagining
it's some dark corner
in a place that
everyone's forgotten.
Alex, it's fine, okay?
I've made peace with it.
But do you need to?
I mean, Vince,
look at what you just did.
You were amazing,
just like you
always were.
I guess it comes naturally.
Well, the doctor part, at least.
We need that.
We need you.
Nobody needs to know.
I mean, we're so
off the grid here,
it's not like anyone's
looking over our shoulder.
Don't you want that?
To be that Vincent again?
WOMAN: Miss Salter,
can you come in here, please?
(sighs)
(brakes squeak)
Welcome to Fright Night.
Should have packed
my wooden stakes.
Want me to plug you in
a night-light?
Let's just get this over with.
(wooden creaking)
Oh, yup.
That's a dead guy.
The whole opaque
skin tone thing.
Who was he?
Bike messenger that attacked
a colleague of mine
a few months ago.
I think the creature
intervened.
Sample from the wound
here should confirm it.
Or if there truly is a creature
roaming the city,
is it possible
that it could be cogent?
I mean,
wouldn't it have to have
feelings and emotions
and a sense of justice
and morality
to only be targeting criminals?
Then why do you want
to catch it so badly?
I don't.
I want to understand it.
You want to tag its ear and
follow its migration patterns?
More like question it.
If it had a choice,
would it retain
its evolved abilities, or
would it choose
to be cured?
Cured? Where did that come from?
From your research paper.
So if it did want to be cured,
would you help it?
I can't think of
a more extraordinary challenge.
Would you take this
for me, please?
(distant siren wailing)
(bell jingles, door closes)
Freeze, buster.
Am I supposed to put
my hands in the air?
You are not going home.
Well, as tempting
as the lukewarm beer
at O'Farrells is...
So forget O'Farrells.
We'll do something else.
Oh...
But we're celebrating.
And I won't take no
for an answer, Dr. Keller.
Wow, I never thought I'd hear
you call me that again.
It's what you are.
Come on.
(Alex giggling)
I can't believe they still
haven't fixed that door
after all these years.
Maybe we were the only ones
crazy enough to sneak in here.
We shouldn't
be here.
I'm sorry, but aren't
you the same guy
that once climbed
the Unisphere on a dare?
Yeah, well, maybe
I'm older and wiser.
Or maybe you've
just been hiding
the real Vincent Keller
for too long.
What if more has changed
than you realize?
It wouldn't matter.
When I thought
you were dead,
I used to fantasize
about leaving New York
and never coming back.
I read about this
mobile medical team
that works
in remote Nigeria.
They travel from
village to village,
helping whoever
needs medical care.
We could do it, Vince.
(sighs)
We could go together.
No.
Hey...
It doesn't have
to be a fantasy.
The sooner we get
out of here,
the sooner we
can start living.
(shrieks, laughs)
I wasn't ready.
Ready? Come on.
Oh...
Hold on.
Okay.
Slip on the ice.
Come on.
Hang on!
(laughs)
(Alex whoops)
Whoa.
(laughing):
Whee...
Ah! Oh!
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Whoa... whoo.
Oh, my God.
I'm gonna fall.
(laughing)
(both laughing)
Thanks.
My pleasure.
MAN:
Don't move!
(indistinct radio transmission)
You're telling me
you don't have I.D.?
I just... need to
make a phone call.
Relax, man, I'm not taking
you two in for booking. Yet.
Just holding you.
But I need to be able
to identify you.
Come on, sir, please, just
don't-don't charge me, okay?
ALEX: It was just a silly
little thing we did.
Not a felony.
Listen to your girlfriend.
This could be very easy--
you give me
your driver's license,
I call it in, we're done.
I just need my phone call.
And I need a name.
Seems we're
at a crossroads here,
and we're not going anywhere
till I know
who you are.
(indistinct chatter)
Look, I take back
every bad thing
I've ever said
about Heather.
These dresses she pulled
from work are sick.
Okay, so we talk to Pam
and then we go, right?
What's the rush?
Are my earrings
too slutty?
Too slutty for what?
(phone rings)
Good point.
Chandler.
VINCENT: Catherine.
Meet me at the bar.
Vincent?
Look, I need your help, okay?
I think I'm getting arrested.
Okay. Hold on.
Tess.
Oh, no.
You better not bail.
I'm not bailing.
Just a friend in need.
A guy friend?
Why do I even bother?
Get your ass
back here pronto.
Will do.
(indistinct radio chatter)
OFFICER: We've been over this.
You keep stalling me, you're
forcing me to take you in.
You don't understand.
Are you showing off for your girl?
Is that what this is?
No, I just...
It's simple.
I need a name.
Just tell him your name, Vince.
It'll be okay.
OFFICER: Vince. Okay, good.
That's a good start.
Vince what?
(low growl)
VINCENT:
I can't tell you.
(growls)
OFFICER: Okay, you know what, sir? I need
you to get inside the vehicle.
Watch your head.
Hey, what are you doing
with my C.I.?
Who are you?
Narcotics. From the 98th.
OFFICER: Little out of your district,
aren't you?
He was gathering information
for me on a case.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I could be better.
Why didn't you tell me
you were a C.I.?
Why would he tell you?
All right, give me your badge.
I'll run it through.
This look official
enough to you?
Now get on your walkie
and call off the 10-12.
I don't run it through...
you don't get your C.I.
Okay, if you screw up what
I have going on tonight,
I will bring a world
of hurt down on you.
You'll be riding
your time until
retirement giving
parking tickets
to Eurotrash in SoHo.
Relax, sweetheart.
I'm just doing my job.
Just wait.
Okay, I am sorry
for putting you
in this position
and bringing you down here.
What the hell is
going on with you?
I had to lie to
a police officer.
If he had run my badge,
I would've been
kicked off the force.
And you were taped.
Every squad car
has a car-top camera on it.
Now I've got to
cover that up, too.
I know, okay? And I can
understand that you're upset.
I am beyond upset.
I-I am mystified.
Alex makes you do
reckless things
that the rest of us
have to protect you from.
It wasn't her fault, okay?
It was mine.
Well, then you know
that if that cop had booked you,
Muirfield would have been here
before the ink dried.
Don't you think I know that?
Okay, I nearly lost control
thinking about what would happen
if I was taken in.
It's not just you.
You put Alex at risk.
JT. You put me at risk, Vincent.
If you want to figure out if
you can get your old life back,
that's fine.
But it doesn't erase the life
that you have now.
You have to figure
out what you want.
Because...
if you're not gonna
protect yourself,
maybe it's time
that I rethink the risks
that I have taken
to protect you.
(sighs) Look, I'm sure this is
inappropriate for me to say,
but your boss is H-O-T.
And as hot as he is,
is as kind and generous
as he is.
Sounds like someone
has a crush.
Not anymore.
He's so smooth.
Looks like he's wrapping up
a big deal.
Those suits he's talking
to are with the SEC.
They're discussing
the initial public offering.
Shouldn't you be a part
of that conversation?
You're the chief
financial officer.
Noah likes to take
his high-level meetings alone.
The day
before Lisa Hawkes' death,
Noah was in an all-day meeting
with the SEC.
All day, all night.
Where were you?
I...
Back at the office.
Waiting for his instructions.
The dutiful work wife, right?
(gunshot)
(sighs)
You didn't show up for
your session this morning.
Only authorized personnel
are allowed on the firing range.
Well, since you're stretching
that guideline a bit,
why can't I?
I'm sorry about the other day.
I'm not usually so...
Do I get to run with that one?
(sighs)
I'm-I'm not easy.
You can ask...
any of my ex-boyfriends.
My chief, my partner,
my sister, my dad, my...
Oh, no, I'll let you
take that one. Your...?
Let's talk about why
you've been spotted
nosing around a case that you're
not approved to investigate.
Lot of eyes around
the precinct.
So, you take comfort
in your work.
You're good at it.
You have a strong purpose.
You're in control.
Yeah, you caught me.
Seriously,
wh-who doesn't do that?
What's so wrong
if I am committed
to a job that I care about?
Everything.
If you're doing it to escape
dealing with your true feelings.
The only thing I am trying
to escape right now is you.
Catherine, you're clearly
suffering from PTSD
from when Sabrina shot you
and you need to...
Post-traumatic stress?
You want to know
what PTSD is?
It's seeing my mom get gunned
down in front of my eyes.
Watching one of the few
people who really knew
and cared about me leave my life
for reasons I don't understand.
And it is happening again.
Yes. Yes, I have feelings
for the most complicated guy
on the planet, and-and he
doesn't appreciate the risks
that I take every
day to protect him.
He would rather be with someone
who doesn't even
know him anymore.
(rhythmic beeping)
It's him. It's our creature.
He killed the bike messenger.
Uh, for good reason.
The bike messenger
was a strangler.
Even so,
this is at least six cases
that the creature's
interfered with.
Not that I have proof
of all six, but...
I think this is
enough to go to Joe.
Joe? Who's Joe?
My boss.
Without the samples
that got stolen,
I needed a few new matches
before I could approach him
about forming a task force
to track down this thing.
But... I thought you didn't
want to catch it--
y-you wanted
to understand it, cure it.
I do. Once we've caught it.
JT, look around you.
I work in a
police station.
Good or bad,
this thing kills people.
It's my job
to help uphold the law.
Why do you look so worried?
Your boss.
H-He'll interfere
with our research.
He'll bog us down
with red tape.
More like give us the manpower
that we need to find this thing.
(beeping)
EVAN:
What?
Corrupted? No!
No, you've got to be kidding me.
Maybe there was contamination
in the lab equipment.
That's impossible.
I sterilized everything.
(groans) It's not like I can exhume
a buried man twice.
Pardon me, ma'am.
Oh, thank you.
Sorry I'm late.
I hear it's tough
to get a reservation here.
So...
how's it going?
With Evan?
Mm-hmm.
Couldn't be better.
(sighs)
He was getting
a little close to Vincent
for my taste,
but I managed to disrupt
one of his studies.
I snuck into his lab
and I corrupted his samples.
And he doesn't know it was you?
I know how to keep
Evan preoccupied.
Ignorance is bliss, huh?
We'll get to Vincent
before the police.
Then Muirfield will have
everything it needs
to move forward.
We need you to
sign that release
understanding your rights
in regards to questioning.
My heart goes out to you,
Pam.
Being the other woman
can drive a woman crazy.
Don't I know it.
I'm not the other woman.
Uh, did you break up with him?
It was mutual.
See, now, that's not
my understanding.
I spoke to a Ben Williams
at the party.
Cute. Married.
Aren't they all.
He tells me
your relationship with Noah
abruptly ended
after Noah met Lisa.
Said it got a little tense
at the office.
So, you're left-handed.
Yes, I am.
Pam, we know the killer
had a left hand strong enough
to cut that rip cord.
We have CSU searching
for the knife you used
to cut the cord
on the parachute.
First, they're gonna
search your office,
then they're gonna
search your apartment.
And they're very
good, our CSU team.
They'll find it.
Now, if you help us out,
and you let us call off
the scavenger hunt,
we could put in a good word
with the D.A.
(sighs)
He told me he loved me.
That what we had
was special.
Oh... epic.
Oh...
that a love like ours
only came along
once in a lifetime.
I believed him.
Then he met Lisa.
And, uh, his head snapped
in her direction...
...and never snapped back.
And I should've
fought for him then.
But I was stunned.
By the time I composed myself,
they were married.
So you killed her?
Noah's... strong-headed.
(Pam sighs)
He was never gonna
change his mind.
I had ha take action.
She was never gonna know him
the way that I do.
(distant siren wailing)
(knocks)
Do I need armor this time?
(sighs)
Sorry, my last apology
didn't come out right.
You're not here
to apologize.
You feel what you feel.
Something tells me
that there's been a lot
that you have felt that
you needed to apologize for.
Your anger towards your mom,
your feelings for guys
who don't deserve
you, apparently.
And now you've
put your heart out there again
after you've kept it
locked up for so long,
and this lug nut
can't see how unique
your connection is
if he's tempted to fall
back into a relationship
that's safe and familiar,
but not really
what he needs, or...
not really what he wants.
Wow, that was...
that was oddly good.
Well,
you're not the only one
whose life isn't perfect.
Relationships are, um...
uh, they're a pain
in the ass.
Yeah, you can't make
someone love you.
But...
you can stop trying
to escape getting hurt
by throwing all of your energy
into protecting people.
Take a chance.
Have you told him
exactly how you feel?
Exactly what you want?
I don't know, I...
think it's pretty obvious.
You can't even say it to me.
I love him.
(door opens)
(door closes)
Hey.
Hi.
I pulled some strings,
and I got the recording
from the police car.
Last time I cover for you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Catherine, I am so...
No, you... you don't
have to say anything.
No. Please, let me.
You risked your job for me.
And Alex.
And even if I was
gonna be with her,
you were willing to protect me
unconditionally, and no one...
Okay, I-I...
I wasn't honest with you.
When?
(laughs softly)
I can't compete with the life
you had with Alex.
But...
I don't want to
give up on us
before we've even begun.
I want to be with you, Vincent.
And I'm willing
to fight for you.
I...
I don't know
if my choice is...
so clear.
I need to be honest
with you.
I really miss who I used to be.
You know, Vinnie Keller,
the doctor,
the normal guy.
And I think,
I really think,
I can be that person again.
And with me...
you'd always be, what?
Not normal?
Alex is willing
to give her life up
to go with me.
And not here, just...
away somewhere from
all of this so I can be free,
you know, from...
from Muirfield.
Would you?
Would she?
If she knew the truth?
Vincent, you haven't told her.
And until you do,
isn't all of this
just a fantasy?
== sync, corrected by elderman ==