Everyone deserves a death.
I was going to die of old age.
That was the plan.
Mitchell was going to go down
in a blaze of gunfire and glory.
Not cold and alone and shit scared.
He didn't think death
would smile at him first.
Death was always a certainty, the
punch line we could all see coming.
But not for Mitchell.
For a vampire, death isn't the end,
but the beginning.
Sorry, thanks for coming.
'So here we are.
'Overlooked and forgotten.
'Unnatural and super-natural.
'Watching the dance
from the sidelines.
'At least I was surrounded by
friends and family.'
Why won't anyone look at me?!
'At least I got that bit right.'
You know the worst thing
about being a ghost? It's lonely.
You'll give anything for that...
crumb of comfort,
that feel of skin against skin
that says it's OK, I'm here.
It's a hunger.
The most basic instinct.
You might even drag others into this
world of the dead.
Even if it means turning them
into monsters, too.
Then there are the ones like George.
The ones that should have died.
But shattered and bloody,
they walk away from the train wreck.
But at what cost?
They're scarred.
Aa-aa-aa-aargh!
Transformed.
They're monsters now, too...
aberrations,
the stuff of nightmares.
The big bad wolf.
So...
What have we got left
to look forward to, us refugees...
the flotsam and jetsam of death?
I was joking. Put them back in the
sink. I'll put them back in the sink.
'Maybe, if we still deserve
such a thing as mercy...'
I needed to do that.
' ..we find each other.'
Hello! 12 inch Mess of Meats.
Oh, thank you. Great.
Keep the change. So, how long have
you been delivering pizzas?
Uh...couple of months?
Could you ride a moped or did they
teach you? They taught us.
We had to drive round a car park.
Bet you hate pizza.
When your girlfriend's like, "What
do you want for your tea?"
I bet you're like, "Not pizza!"
I live with my dad.
Madness. See ya.
He could see me. He could SO see
you.
It's happening all the time now.
Not just with you two,
but with normal people.
I was putting out the recycling
and a van drove past
and the guy shouted "Slag!"
So who wants tea?
HE GRUNTS
What? You keep making tea!
Every surface is covered
with mugs of tea and coffee!
I go to make some tea and I can't!
There's no mugs, no tea!
It's all been made!
You can't even drink it!
You can't drink it,
but you keep making it!
Oh, oh, oh, my god,
it's driving me INSANE!
Oh, well, I like my routine, it
makes me feel normal. You're a
ghost!
Yeah, OK. Are you finished
with these?
Come on. Oh, you're both off then?
Yeah, we've got work, then it's his
time of the month. Oh. Great.
Tell you what, I won't miss that.
Used to have to curl up on the sofa,
a hot water bottle,
Pride and Prejudice. Anyone said
anything, I'd bite their head off.
Gosh, I suppose in your case that...
that is actually quite a possibility
isn't it, you know, biting?
We'll see you later.
OK, I'll see you later, guys.
# We were so pretty, now this is it
# You and I are too young
for this... #
You know, you should be
pleased for her.
She can be seen by other people now.
She can step out of the house.
Other people move in somewhere.
They get damp, no, they get woodlice.
Why do we get Caspar
the friendly ghost?
We've been over this.
There must be something unresolved
about her death.
That's what's keeping her here.
It's not fair...
Exactly. Whatever happened
to her, it was unfair.
No, it's unfair her being here. The
amount of washing up she generates...
So what are you gonna do?
Oh, well, I'll work for an hour,
then say there's a family emergency
and scoot down to the isolation room
before the moon comes up. Cool.
I'll come and let you out
in the morning.
VOICE: 'Mitchell...'
Jesus, Mitchell, how are you supposed
to find anywhere in this place?
I followed the signs to Intensive
Care, I ended back where I came in!
What are you doing here, Seth?
Herrick thinks recruitment should be
more tactical.
Those with money and influence.
No more tramps or people who
fall asleep on the night bus.
You had the right idea with Lauren.
At least she's easy on the eye.
This fella, I think
he's on the council or something...
Leave him alone.
What, you want to share?
No, I've...
I've stopped.
Yeah...
We've had this conversation,
Mitchell.
What blood type is he, anyway?
A-positive. Hmm.
A bit Jacob's Creek for me, but there
you go. Move away from the bed, Seth.
Remember that student, the guy?
When was it '58, '59?
Or you and Herrick and
that girl in the hotel?
Or the couple in the park?
You can't stop, Mitchell.
This is what we are.
Now, come on.
Just a taste. A sip.
I said leave him alone.
Or what? Look at you,
when was the last time you fed?
You're shaking, sweating. Get
into character and watch the door.
I've got a job to do.
I don't care if the coolest kid in
school is suddenly your mate, Seth.
Tell Herrick
the hospital's out of bounds.
A word of warning.
One friend to another.
It's cold out there without us.
I loved it, but I just
thought if I don't get out now...
Cos mates of mine, they got
married or they've had kids,
and they've just stayed, really.
Who was she? Lauren. Worked in A&E.
When did she die?
A couple of months
before you started.
She was beautiful.
Oh. They're doing a memorial thingy.
Planting a tree. Hey, George.
Hey, Mitchell. Yeah, hi.
Shouldn't you be going?
Shit! I've got,
I've got to be somewhere erm, er...
Like now.
I've got a break in ten minutes.
I'll see you around then.
In your own time.
Hello? Uh, what are you doing?
This will be the site office when
they start building the admin wing.
Look at the state of it - furniture
all smashed up,
marks on the walls...
Have they been keeping mentals
in 'ere or what? Ha-ha-ha!
Oh, no.
..I just felt so alone,
do you know what I mean, Mitchell?
Mitchell?
Are you OK? Your hand's shaking.
Oh. Yeah, I, uh, quit...
smoking, a few weeks ago.
So are you seeing anyone or..?
OK, that was me trying to be all
sophisticated and Marie Claire,
but it just came out Special Needs,
didn't it?
Oh, God, I'm such an idiot. I
shouldn't be allowed near people.
It's fine, it's fine.
But in answer to your question, no.
My relationships have followed
a similar pattern.
They've been brief,
they...haven't ended...well.
And that has to change.
I can't keep hurting people. I
just want something good and normal.
But there are those who say I
can't do that. Well, who says that?
Can you give me one second?
The isolation room,
it's full of people!
We need to get somewhere now,
I've got 40 minutes before I change!
OK, let's go.
Here's fine, it's fine. What here!?
I can't pull over here, George!
Stop the car!
THUMP
This is... Whoa, whoa, whoa!
George, George, wait. What?
You haven't had time to find
somewhere. You can't just run.
You'll kill someone. What else
can I do? Come back to the house.
I'm not doing this in the house!
You can't keep it separate.
This is happening.
This is part of you! George,
it's safer there!
We can contain you! George!
# Start to wonder what his story
might be, what his story might be
# Cos they said he changes
when the sun goes down
# Yeah, they said he changes
# They said he changes
when the sun goes down... #
Hi, how are you?
Oh, oh, oh...
# ..Look, here comes a Ford Mondeo
# Isn't he Mr Inconspicuous?
# And he don't even have to sail... #
Oh, oh...
Sorry, sorry...
# ..when the sun goes down round here
# Round here. #
Hello, mate.
What you running from?
# They said he changes
when the sun goes down
# Round here
# They said he changes
when the sun goes down
# Over the river
going out of town... #
No, no, no, don't start the engine!
No, you're right,
let's go back to the house.
What? Well, like you said,
it's safer there.
So can we go?
Like, now?
All right, George? What's happening?
It's your time of the month. It is.
He's doing it here. I've hoovered!
George, what do you need? Close the
curtains so it can't see the windows.
And, er, put some music on. Loud.
Good idea. We'll say there's
a party going on. Annie.
Anything you don't want broken,
in your room.
Er, what are we supposed to do
while he's doing his thing?
Get the hell out.
Well, can I watch?
I just wanna see what happens.
This isn't like when you were six,
watching your cat have kittens.
It's, it's private.
Well, you've seen me
since I've died.
I think the rules of privacy
got a bit muddy.
Oh, come on. It's not like you can
hurt me. Maybe she should.
This is what I mean.
It's part of you.
OK. Erm, keep to the kitchen.
Stay out of its line of vision.
If it sees you, I don't know
what it'll do. Aargh!
It's coming.
# Change my picture
Smack my bitch up
Smack my bitch up... #
I think someone's finally moved
into number 18.
Aaargh!
Aa-aa-aa-aargh!
Aa-aargh!
Aa-aa-aa-aargh
Aa-aa-aa-aargh!
George?
He's gone.
Hey. Hi.
Oh, no...
Where's, where's all our stuff?
What did it do?
We've salvaged what we can.
But there's about ten bin bags of
crap and wreckage
stashed in my bedroom.
I'm sensing a trip to IKEA.
And you know my feelings about that.
Look, why don't you two go out.
Let me finish up here.
It's the least I can do. Owen rang.
Owen who? Owen! Your landlord!
My fiancee, EX-fiancee.
He's coming round. In about... Now.
He's coming here? Why? He's over
from Saudi and wants to meet us.
Well, you guys are his
longest staying tenants.
All the others have found it,
er, strangely unwelcoming.
Why didn't you put him off?! I tried.
But she kicked me in the shin.
The shin, George! Sorry, can we
focus?
You're not going to be here
when he arrives? Of course!
Obviously I'll hide,
he's not gonna see me.
OK. I've written a list of questions
for you to ask him.
Are you screwing Janey Harris?
She always fancied Owen. If she'd
known when I died,
she'd have been here
before the ambulance crew.
Ah-h, "Has my sister had a baby?"
Cos they've been trying for ages.
I blame her husband. Robin. Works
for the Post Office.
Oh, my God, has everyone taken Stupid
Pills? This is Annie's ex -
Annie's ex, who buried her.
She can't be here, you can't
be within ten miles of here.
Well, I can't have him
in the house and not see him.
For Christ's sake, we were engaged.
And can you imagine, if he sees you?
The effect it will have on him, the,
the, the danger it'll put us all in.
This isn't about our safety.
You've lost your lover,
and now you can't bear
the thought of me seeing mine.
That's... That's... How dare you?!
Look, if she stays upstairs,
what's the worst that can happen?
I'll remind you of that as the crowds
gather with torches and pitchforks.
No, I'm sorry,
we have to protect the household.
YOU have just smashed up
the household.
It wasn't me...
Oh, that's that settled. Annie?
OK, OK. Erm and remember...
Janey Harris.
Crazy, you're all crazy... Oh-h-h.
Ask about the clanky tap. No, I will.
Just, just just leave
all of the talking to me.
Now, remember, we're two guys renting
a house,
it's, it's the most natural thing
in the world.
We just have to be totally
and completely normal.
Yeah, good luck with that.
Hey, how you doing? Good, good. I'm
Mitchell. Nice to meet you, Owen.
This is George. Hi, how's it going?
Yes.
Where's all the furniture? Um...
Oh, um,
we wanted a more,
uh, minimalist life.
It's so easy to get seduced by all
the clutter and debris
of 21st-century living, isn't it?
Isn't it?
To think having this sofa or that,
uh, uh, uh, chair
will bring you happiness when really,
shouldn't we be striving
for something more spiritual? More...
more Zen?
Oh. I thought maybe you were going
to redecorate
and didn't want to get the furniture
all painty.
Yeah,
that would have made more sense.
George, why don't you
go and see what that was.
Yes. Thank you, Mitchell. Can I get
you a drink, Owen?
Tea, coffee, there's a couple of
beers in the fridge.
Actually I wouldn't mind a beer.
I'm still on Saudi time.
What are you doing? We can hear you!
I just wanna to see him.
Look I can sneak down, I can hide.
Are you CRAZY?
He will see you and...
and die of shock!
Annie, that is not an option.
Most of the time it's fine.
Eventually the water comes through.
But it's driving George nuts.
OK. No worries. I'll take a look.
Like I said,
it's such a relief
having you guys here.
Er, it didn't work out with
the last lot of people...
Oh, cheers. I think they heard
about what happened and let their
imaginations run away with them.
You do know? About my fiancee?
A little.
Just what the estate agent said.
Yeah, I've hardly been back since.
You can imagine, it's still kind of
weird...being here.
What happened, exactly?
If you don't mind me asking.
Erm... We'd literally just moved in,
we were still living out of boxes.
And it was dark,
I hadn't sorted out the wiring yet.
And she was at the top
of the stairs and...
I don't know,
they said she must have...
fallen awkwardly or something...
What was she like?
Annie?
Oh, she was kind, funny.
Cleverer than she thought she was...
And she was mine.
I believe people can leave an echo,
in a place where they were.
I know the tenants before us
said they could detect something.
Maybe that's what it was.
They said it was creepy.
It's not, it's not creepy.
It's good. It's happy.
We like it.
What was it? What?
Oh, um...
it was, it was a pigeon.
A pigeon?
Must have left a window open.
Well, have you got rid of it?
I killed it. You, you killed it?
With a shoe.
You know what? I should, erm...
I gotta get going.
Yeah. Really? Aw, oh...
It was lovely to meet you, Owen.
Thanks for the drink. Any problems,
phone me.
Yeah. Like I said, we're really
happy here.
Really. Thank you. Really.
How'd you do that, stay so calm?
OK, shut up. You're a spy,
aren't you?
You've clearly had training, because
the way you held it together,
it was chilling.
He loved you very much, Annie.
The way he talked about you...
You made him very happy.
Oh, Did you ask about the tap?
Is this his?
What?
This bottle. Is it his?
Yeah.
Thank you very much. You want to
see it again?
Here we go, are you watching?
Are you sure you're watching?
You're not watching. Here it comes.
Thank you very much.
Ah, There's my friend.
Sorry, guys, gotta go. One more?
No, no. Another time, I promise.
You didn't get my message?
This isn't your fucking larder,
Herrick.
This is a social call, nothing more.
We're really worried about you.
We're meant to keep a low profile.
Coming here,
attacking people in their sleep.
Attacking people in their sleep? Who
is attacking people in their sleep?
Seth said... "Seth said..."
Listen.
There's something you
need to know about Seth.
He's an idiot.
But it makes you think, doesn't it?
These rules about what
we can and cannot do.
Now for instance, here's a thought,
suppose the world
knew of our existence.
Suppose they had a choice...
Sorry, love, do you
do hot chocolate?
You do. Good.
Do you want a hot chocolate?
No. I'll have one hot chocolate,
please.
What time did you start? Uh, two.
Ooh, that's long shift.
So who do you get in here mostly,
this time of night? Staff, mainly.
Though we get parents too,
of the kids in the children's ward.
You can tell 'em a mile off.
They take it in turns
and they come in
and they order their coffee
but they don't drink it.
Well. I'm sure they very much
appreciate what you do.
Actually. It's fine. Well, you're
very kind.
Take care.
What was that? More tricks?
No. It's, er...manners.
So we declare ourselves.
And what then?
Start a mass conversion?
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
one step at a time...
But, that is exactly the kind of
left-field thinking
we need right now.
And those that refuse?
Well, as I recall,
you welcomed me with open arms.
God, that is terrible.
Taste it.
To save the lives of my men.
Yeah, how noble of you to take on
the curse of immortality
so that your friends could wither
and decay
in hospitals
and old people's homes.
I'm kidding. Just teasing you.
I'm willing to bet - you offer
people eternal life,
not just for them
but their lovers and children -
and the queues would stretch
a thousand miles!
Let's go up to the children's ward.
Those parents she was talking about,
you think a single one of them
would turn us away?
You've thought
about it, haven't you?
They had their chance.
We left them to tend this paradise,
this Eden, and look what they did.
You know what I don't understand,
this interest in me.
Look. If things were to change,
having you by my side, like it
was, back in the day, it would...
People admire you,
I admire you.
Despite your, er..
your eccentricities.
My eccentricities? Yeah.
I mean we all we all play a part.
But you... It's like you like it.
Plus now I hear everyone
tells me you're on the wagon.
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
Good. I don't. It's mental.
You're a shark, be a shark.
Besides, I suppose you've
got some fall-backs in place?
Fall-backs? Oh, just
someone you've been grooming.
So that eventually when you do fall
off the wagon,
you won't have too far to drop.
Oh, that's me.
Everything's about to change,
and nothing can stop it.
This is nature,
it's tectonic plates shifting.
And the only thing is, the only
thing you and me get to choose,
is which side
we're on when it happens.
Something to ponder.
Listen, I'm going
to that thing later.
The memorial thing, for Lauren.
You want to come? Um, I don't know...
Come on, it'll be nice.
Well, not nice so much as...
horrible.
I thought you were friends.
Not really.
A bit. Towards the end.
George? Hiya. Hi.
I need three pillow-cases, please.
Mrs Nixon's just vommed up
her fisherman's pie.
Thank you for sharing.
You've changed your shampoo.
It's minty.
Normally you're vanilla-y.
How do you know that?!
Er, I've
just got a good sense of smell.
Erm, do you like it?
Yes, you smell like a polo.
Have you got a hole?
I'll, uh, see you later, yeah?
Shit, are you interested in her? No.
I don't know. Why, are you?
Me? God, no.
I mean, she's nice, but...
if you're interested in her,
I could...
Oh, come on, it's not like you get
interested in people every day.
I don't want to discourage it.
She won't be interested in me. I'll
ask. Do you want me to ask? No, no!
Christ, this is so playground.
Well, welcome to being a bloke.
Why are you so anxious
to pair her off with me?
I'm not trying to pair you off,
that's... That's daft.
Let me talk to her. You see, I can
actually talk to women
without weeping
or setting fire to myself.
I don't know. I don't know.
Let me think about it.
Oh, yeah...have you seen my phone?
No.
'Tap in kitchen
making very odd noises.
'Could you come and repair?
'This afternoon good.
'Hope you're well.
'From George.'
Boo.
Lauren?
Surprise.
Did you enjoy my memorial service?
It's a shame Mitchell
couldn't make it.
Maybe he'll come to yours.
Aw, your face.
This must be really confusing.
Let me explain... Before I died
I had this one odd last thought.
And now I'm gonna make it yours.
You know all the things
that you were scared of as a kid?
All the monsters under the bed?
They're all real.
OK, I'm kind of new to this,
but aren't you supposed to, er,
weep or scream or wee yourself?
Mitchell did this to you?
What, you know? You know what he is?
Wait a sec.
Come here.
Oh, my God.
A werewolf.
Creepy.
Hey. Ooh, there's some bacon
in the fridge at home,
that goes off at midnight.
Guess who I just saw.
Er...Yoko Ono?
No, Lauren!
I manage my condition. I hide
in a shitty bloody cellar
or the middle of a forest. But you?
You buy a bottle of wine
and a packet of condoms!
What is the point of us trying
to build some kind of normality
when you are attacking our friends
and turning them into monsters?
For Christ's sake!
we knew her. You let me go
to her bloody memorial!
How the hell do you think I've
survived for the last 100 years?
There's no escape from it.
I'm not like you, I don't have
days off. This is what I am.
Then why are we even trying?
Hey. Oh, shit, sorry, can I walk
on that? Have you just mopped there?
It's fine.
So do you want to come out
for a drink with me?
Yep, I've made a decision,
no more procrastination.
I've been meaning to do it for ages,
but I just kept putting it off.
That sounded a lot funnier
in the ladies.
What the hell.
Cool! Right, erm,
see you later then.
Oh, God.
Owen, be not afraid.
George?
It's Owen.
Mitchell?
The TV's on.
Maybe he's popped out.
Hello?
I rang the doorbell...
Look, you don't have to do this,
Janey. You can wait in the car.
It's fine. I want to. You think
I should turn this off?
You say something?
What?
Did you say something?
You're hearing things...
You gonna look at this tap?
Er, yeah. It could take a while.
Go and wait in the car, please.
And miss you doing DIY?
It'd be like missing an eclipse.
I have no idea what I'm doing.
Oh. Hello.
What?
Ahhh! Hello, hello!
George, hi, sorry,
we rang the doorbell,
no-one answered.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, it's,
it's, it's, it's fine, it's, erm...
I got your text.
My text? About the tap.
The tap? Yeah, George. You texted me.
About the tap.
Right. The tap
But how silly of me, telling you to
come round when I wouldn't be here.
Sorry, I haven't even introduced
you. Er, this is my partner, Janey.
Janey? Harris. Hi.
Right. Hello.
I'm going to have to
come back later,
take a look at the tank
in the attic.
Erm, so when are you not in?
I don't want to disturb you.
Well, it's hard to say.
There's usually someone here.
OK, well, I'll pop by
later in the week?
It was nice to meet you.
Yes, nice to meet you too, bye.
Annie.
I just wanted a chance to explain!
Look, you don't know him! You don't
know how he'd react, but I knew!
I just, I knew that if,
if he saw me again, he'd...
But he couldn't see me,
and now he's got someone else.
And now she gets to kiss him,
and watch him shave, and laugh
and I'm still in the clothes
that I died in.
I get nothing.
She gets him and I get...
I get you.
After I got...
After I lost everything, I ran away.
I met Mitchell and we came here
and met you and...
I'd just about come to terms
with what'd happened to me,
and then I saw her.
My ex.
And she'd met someone else.
And it was so...savage.
So I know how it feels.
It feels like losing everything
all over again.
How did it happen?
We were on holiday in Scotland.
The place we were staying was on the
edge of this huge ravine,
and one night I decided
to go for a walk.
I've never been so scared.
This thing was...
Even at the time I remember
looking at it and being...
offended.
That thing in this world,
it was so, so wrong.
It attacked you?
This other guy, this, er...
another guest, he'd tagged along.
He was killed.
It literally tore his throat
and chest out.
Over there, he's there,
this way now, quickly.
I was only scratched. This way.
I survived.
Like me.
Like you. Hooray for us.
Why do you think Owen
couldn't see you?
I dunno.
Maybe the shock of it was like...
Just set me back. Like a relapse?
There's just so much of this
I don't understand.
So what did you think of her then?
Janey. She's...
orange.
She works in a tanning salon.
She thinks that looks classy.
I think she looks like Kilroy.
Well, you're much prettier.
And much nicer.
And much deader.
Does that look like
a three or a five?
A three.
That's what I thought.
That's Becca's handwriting for you.
So if she give Mr Davies
his meds at three,
then he's gonna need 'em again,
hm, now.
But if she give 'em to him at five,
oh, he ain't gonna need
'em till ten o'clock. So ask her.
She ain't answering her mobile.
Gone out for a drink with your mate.
What mate?
You know. Him with the face. Where?
Where did they go? Christ knows.
I would have asked but that would
have looked like I gives a shit.
I'm serious. If there's
another man there, I can't pee.
That's ridiculous!
I know, at my age.
OK, now you -
something embarrassing.
Uhhhh. OK. It wasn't until six
months ago that I stopped phoning
my ex every time I got drunk.
Oh, God, I probably shouldn't
have said that.
No, it's sweet. It's tenacious.
Yeah, "sweet". Me, usually with sick
in my hair, going, "Gavi-i-i-n!"
Oh, erm, I meant to ask you.
How's the not-smoking going?
Oh, not great.
But I'm thinking,
once a smoker, always a smoker.
There's no point in fighting it?
So, would you like to
come back to mine?
My flat-mate's out so we'd have
the place to ourselves.
Erm, is that a friend of yours?
Well, lookee here.
Mind if I join you?
Aren't you going to introduce us?
I should explain.
Me and Mitchell dated.
Well, just once really.
It was sort of a date.
So where are we up to? With me
he did this whole thing about
the ancient machinery of the world.
Please don't do this.
At least he brought you out.
We had to make do with a bottle
of wine from the supermarket
and a packet of Doritos at my place.
I've seen you before.
Well, I had my photo
in the paper recently.
Yeah. Yeah.
I've seen you in a photo... Get up.
I want to see her face
when she works it out. Get up.
Well, you seem nice.
Maybe afterwards
we could hang out...
Oh, I, er, saw your furry friend.
I was actually gonna feed from him,
can you imagine?
I'd probably have to
get jabs or something.
What do you want?
Did Herrick send you?
This isn't just about him.
Then what do you want? You left me.
You brought me into this
and then you left me.
I woke up surrounded by strangers.
It should have been you there!
Ever since then they've just passed
me round, I'm like this orphan!
I'm sorry...
Come away with me.
There's places we can go,
where we can be safe from them.
They're not some dopey
abusive boyfriend.
You think anywhere's safe
from them?
They stay away from the smaller
towns, anywhere that's exposed.
Wait... Oh, my God,
you actually think I want saving?
We can save each other,
this is what I'm trying...
We can save each other, OK?
You don't get it, do you?
I want to kill! I want to feel
their blood dripping down my chin!
I want to see their faces
when they realise!
I wanna kill my parents, my lovers,
I want them to know.
Herrick's talking about
offering it first.
Christ, let's just take it.
Take their world.
Tear their children to shreds.
Thank you. What for?
You can't do this, Mitchell,
you can't choose them over us,
you'll lose everything.
Whatever it takes,
we will drag you back!
You all right?
What was that all about?
Yeah, listen. I'm gonna head home.
Oh. Erm...
Oh, OK.
I just think it's for the best.
Look, was it that thing I said
about my ex?
That's not me any more. I promise.
This is about me, not you.
It's gotta be the first time
I've heard that before a shag.
That must be a record, even for me.
I'm sorry.
Can I walk you to the taxi rank?
Oh, no, there's no need. Please.
I wanna make sure you're safe.
Err, yeah, whatever.
Erm, I just need to pee.
Lauren?
It's me. It's...
It's George.
Bad dog.
No, sorry, she's not in there.
Oh, Jesus Christ...
Call an ambulance!
Becca, it's OK, it's Mitchell.
Come on, baby, that's it,
keep looking at me.
Now isn't this a touching scene?
What did you do to her?!
Easy, tiger. What's the problem? You
just need to let her drink from you.
Becca, Becca, keep looking at me.
Keep looking at me.
It's OK, honey, he'll save you.
He can make all of this go away.
Mitchell? Can you save her?
I can't... I can't...
She's losing consciousness!
You'd better hurry up.
She's about two pints away
from being an organ donor.
Mitchell, DO something!
Mitchell!
Not another one... I can't...
I can't. You did this.
You made me this, Mitchell.
This is all your fault.
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry,
I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry.
She, erm, she didn't make it.
Is this how it ends then?
They connect her to you,
you to Lauren.
Everything gets blown open.
We lose it all.
No.
They have ways of doing this.
Come on.
What do you mean?
We've been around
for thousands of years.
You think this is the first time
something like this has happened?
They've branches everywhere.
Er, you wait here.
I'll go and find us a cab.
Hey, Mitchell.
It's all about to start.
We're drawing up the lists.
Make your mind up time.
I choose them.
Pity.
Be seeing you.
And your little dog.
MUSIC: "Hurt" by Johnny Cash
# I hurt myself today
# To see if I still feel
# I focus on the pain... #
I'd forgotten what they were like.
The others.
They're predators.
Every inch of them
is just hunger and fury.
The energy it must take him,
every minute, not to be like that...
Do you think he should
have saved her?
I think he did.
We should go out. What? To the pub.
Well, anywhere. It'll do us all good.
Oh, no, I think...
I think I wanna stay in the house.
No, yes. Let, let,
let me put some clothes on and...
No, I want to stay in the house now.
Oh, look. I'm sorry.
I feel safe here.
There are monsters outside.
When it's just the three of us, it's
like none of them can touch us. OK.
# ..I will let you down
# I will make you hurt
# If I could start again
# A million miles away
# I would keep myself
# I would find a way. #
George! I know what you are.
We don't need to feed,
we can just...play.
My friends...
..will never understand you.
transcript:chocolate
sync:innuit