Littlejohn: Tech Department
have enhanced
this GPR scan, and you won't
believe what Pettigrew found.
Hildur: If it's not Jason,
then it's someone
ruthless enough to
cave a man's skull in.
Does he think I even care
about that stupid drill now?
Natalie:
Jason is really sick.
Vincent: If larvae passed
into a living host,
then that host is food.
Natalie: The trouble with larvae
is you don't know
what they are till
they pupate and hatch.
♪ The river
did come to me ♪
♪ Straight into my arms ♪
♪ I tried to caress it ♪
♪ But it ran
through my fingers ♪
♪ Water will keep running ♪
♪ Rivers will turn ♪
♪ Rivers will turn. ♪
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
( wincing )
Don't come in!
( stammers )
Don't...
don't make noise.
What the fuck
are those things?
They were
inside her...
came through her skin.
They stinging you,
Vincent?
( gurgles )
When I move,
get stung.
Wasps.
Parasitical wasps.
If they get out,
this will spread.
We have to kill
them all.
How do we kill them
without killing Vincent?
Natalie, we have
to kill them all.
( gasping )
G-Gas.
G-G-Gas.
We burn them.
Come on!
( gasping )
Okay.
This
an explosive mix?
It's oxygen and hydrogen,
very.
Okay.
The delivery valves.
Open the delivery valves.
( wincing )
( gas hissing )
Okay,
once the room's full,
how do we ignite...?
Wait.
Natalie:
Wait!
- ( gasping )
- ( alarm blaring )
( electricity crackling )
Vincent.
Help.
- Help.
- Okay, okay.
- Okay.
There you go.
( panting )
- Vincent.
- He's not breathing.
- Okay.
- Um...
- Don't you die on me.
- Have you got a knife?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Here.
It's anaphylactic shock.
His throat's closed.
Here.
Hold him down.
Don't let him move.
Okay.
- It's in.
- ( Vincent gasping )
Shh. It's okay.
We've got you.
- It's okay.
- It's okay!
- We've got you.
It's okay.
I've got you.
( glass clinks )
I'm so sorry, Margaret.
( wind blowing )
0-1-6-9!
8-3-1-5!
8-3-1-5,
0-1-6-9!
Shovel!
"X" marks the spot.
( chuckles )
Come, come, Max.
What do you think
the treasure is?
What treasure could be
buried out here?
Fix this.
Fix it?
What's wrong
with it?
Doesn't fucking work.
I don't want to die
down a fucking hole
starving
in the dark,
so fix it.
( singing in Russian )
( singing echoes )
Parasites
that lay their eggs
in a live creature,
a live host,
then they hatch and
consume the creature
from the inside out.
Margaret Allerdyce
was eaten alive
from the inside out
by insects?
I think
they're wasps.
Wasps.
Where have these things
come from?
Well,
they're prehistoric.
There's
no recorded instance
of a human ever being
parasited by an ichneumonidae.
So this is
the first time
this species has been in
contact with a human population.
Because Fortitude has only
been inhabited for 100 years.
They're way older
than that.
So where could they
have come from?
Permafrost?
They could survive
frozen in the permafrost?
If they were
in a larval state
inside something else,
something
that protected them.
So we have
to find Jason.
I'm gonna take you home,
sweetie.
Your dad'll
stay here...
do his job.
We'll go home...
you and me...
back to England.
You'll see your dad
when he visits.
( tupilaq rattling )
Just like when
he was a soldier.
That'll be best,
won't it,
everything
how it was?
That'll be best.
Come on.
Yeah.
♪ Don't know jillions ♪
♪ Don't know Renaissance ♪
- ♪ Don't know fashion laws ♪
- ( retching )
♪ Don't know violence ♪
♪ Don't know wisdom ♪
♪ I don't know rock, roll ♪
♪ Don't know gentle ♪
♪ And I don't know
the "Mad Men" show ♪
♪ I don't know impossible ♪
♪ I don't know elegance ♪
♪ And I don't know sorrow ♪
♪ I don't know sorrow. ♪
Jason never
showed you this,
never mentioned
what he found?
No. I've never seen
that thing before in me life.
You know he attacked
Natalie Yelburton?
Jason's out there,
and the whole town
is in a state
close to panic.
Where would he go?
If he was in trouble,
where would he hide?
He'd come home to me.
He's not himself.
Mummy.
Jason found the
remains of a mammoth.
Now we think
those remains
are hazardous,
infectious,
so we're all in
danger, Celia, all of us,
especially Jason.
- Governor, please.
- We must find him.
Hey, come on.
Hi.
Dan:
I'm required to ask you
if you feel safe
in Fortitude.
I'm required to ask you
if you have any plans
to leave Fortitude.
Are you seeing anybody?
( Elena chuckles )
Is that
an official question?
( winces )
( sighs )
Frank:
Elena.
Forgive me.
In my head...
the way I felt
about you...
caused
all this pain.
Please forgive me.
Perdoname,
por favor.
( whirring )
Okay, then.
Yep, seems to be
working fine now.
- ( snowmobile roaring )
- All right?
Shit.
Have you told anyone
about this place?
No.
Max.
Ah, fuck.
Put the gun down!
- And get down to your knees!
- ( speaking Russian )
You! Hey! Hey!
( speaking Russian )
Don't give me this shit!
Do as I say now!
- ( speaking Russian )
- On your knees!
Max! Max!
Motherfucker!
Why don't we settle this
like real men?
With pleasure.
We put down the guns.
My count.
One...
two...
three.
- Like real men.
- ( gun clicks )
What the fuck?
Motherfucker!
Get up!
( both grunting )
( screams )
- ( Yuri gasps )
- Oh, motherfucker!
( yelling )
( groaning )
Listen.
Okay.
Okay, listen to me.
This was brought
to me by fate.
♪ Crazy... ♪
The glacier hotel
is a shit,
a piece of shit.
It will never happen.
It is not possible!
The glacier...
moves!
You cannot build
a hotel on it.
♪ Crazy for feeling... ♪
Your wife...
is a crazy woman, man,
a crazy bitch.
♪ I knew ♪
♪ You'd love me
as long as you wanted ♪
( spits )
♪ And then someday ♪
♪ You'd leave me
for somebody new ♪
( both grunting )
- ♪ Worry ♪
- ( Yuri gasps )
( yells )
♪ Why do I let
myself worry? ♪
( gags )
♪ Wondering ♪
♪ What in the world
did I do? ♪
♪ Oh, crazy ♪
- ( coughs )
- ♪ For thinking ♪
♪ That my love ♪
- Listen.
- ♪ Could hold you... ♪
Why don't
you help me?
We dig.
Help you?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
♪ And I'm crazy
for loving you... ♪
We go down
to the treasure
and bring
the treasure
to surface.
What treasure?
What treasure?!
You know
what treasure!
Pettigrew found the
treasure under the ice!
I don't know what the fuck
you're talking about.
Don't lie.
You know.
See? See?
They killed
Pettigrew for this map.
Bill Pettigrew
found it,
and this is
the place.
Come on!
( song ends )
( yells )
( radio chirps )
Ingrid:
Eric, we found Jason.
We have him under arrest.
Right. I still need
to talk to him, so...
- Okay.
- Thanks, Ciaran.
Listen, I know
what happened to you.
The thing you found
has made you very, very ill.
And I know that
the mammoth is real.
You found it,
didn't you?
Jason, would you
look at me?
Now I need you
to tell me where it is.
Jason,
you're the only one
who can help us all now.
When you tell me where
the mammoth can be found,
all of this will stop.
Everything
will be fine again.
Listen, Jason.
I'm going
to trust you now.
I'm going to unlock
your handcuffs.
Governor,
he might be dangerous.
Give me the key.
Okay.
So, Jason,
where is it?
Where's the mammoth?
Cold store.
Behind the supermarket.
Thank you.
( monitor beeping )
( over intercom )
Poor boy.
- ( zipper unzips )
- These,
they are the reason
for all this?
The ichneumonidae.
Charles Darwin
considered
their life cycle
to be
inimical to the notion
of a benevolent creator.
I see.
A loving God
could not have created
something so wicked,
or so he thought.
"Parasitical
wasp larvae."
Frozen
inside the mammoth
30,000 years.
Permafrost thaws.
Frozen wasp thaws.
Wasp injects eggs
into human bloodstream.
This is what happened
to Shirley?
Yes, the eggs develop
inside the host,
and the host is
compelled to find a victim,
hacks open
the thoracic cavity,
vomits.
Larvae develop
inside secondary host.
Wasps erupt from
Dr. Allerdyce and attack...
attack scientist.
That's
the best hypothesis
I can give you based
on the available data,
subject to revision.
And they are
inside him now,
these
little eggs?
Don't know.
( wind blowing )
Hello?
Are you down there?!
Markus:
What if this theory...
is nonsense?
What if gentle
Shirley Allerdyce
attacked her mother
because for years
her mother
belittled her?
What if Shirley
was reacting to me
and I am the cause of
her pain and self-loathing?
No.
What?
He said, "No."
No?
We always seek excuses
for our baser selves.
We are always victims
of circumstance,
not responsible.
Well, maybe when we do
bad things for good reason,
we must still face
the consequences.
A child
is in torment.
A father takes action.
Will there be
no consequences?
You...
and you...
you cut Shirley open...
to further research.
Will there be
no consequences?
We had no choice.
Hmm.
Well...
it is not wasps
that should make one doubt
the existence of a benevolent God.
It is us,
his children.
( lock clatters )
( woman panting )
( handcuffs clinking )
( gasping )
( buzzing )
( fluttering )
( chorus vocalizing )
Jason,
they've done it.
They've set the thing
on fire. They've done it.
Ronnie's in the house.
( gunshot )
Jason?
We've identified
a pathogen,
and we've identified
a marker in the blood
which will tell us whether
or not someone's infected.
Well, that's what
I'm saying, Alstad.
We can prevent
an epidemic if you...
Listen,
I'll call you back.
- Look, I know...
- Please, let me speak.
Oh, God.
The only thing...
that I ever cared for
in my sorry life,
Hildy, is you.
I betrayed you...
my love...
my only love.
I miss you.
I miss you so much.
I got your drill back.
( chuckles )
Thought you
might need it.
( chuckles )
Eric.
( honks horn )
Elena.
Elena, I got
frozen Bolognese.
We can have spaghetti.
( gasping )
Elena?
- ( gurgling )
- Elena?
( knocks )
Elena, are you okay?
Can I come in,
please?
Who did this to you?
( gasping )
You're really hot.
Get you some water.
Elena?
Elena, where are you?
( wood clatters )
( buzzing )
( chorus singing )
Cordon off the area.
Yes, sir.
I'm so sorry, Celia.
He said that Ronnie's
in the house.
Ronnie?
( crying )
( dials cell phone )
Dan...?
( tone chimes )
( Elena grunting )
( groans )
( muttering )
( wailing )
( snorts )
( grunts )
Elena!
Don't do this.
Please...
don't do this.
Please.
No!
( screams )
( sighs )
( Dan screams )
( music playing )
( Dan panting )
- ( radio chirps )
- Dan.
Ronnie Morgan's house.
Shooting and stabbing.
( gurgling )
( panting )
( music playing )
( sirens approaching )
( raps on glass )
News?
Very few of the
60,000 known species
of ichneumonidae
achieve sexual maturity
within less
than 48 hours,
so the chances
are...
that you were
only stung.
Multiple times
in multiple places.
But there is
a chance
that there are no
eggs in your bloodstream.
- Chances?
- We'll know.
We'll know
in a day or two.
I would be dead already
if it wasn't for you.
You know what?
It was
quick thinking,
gas,
explosion.
( imitates explosion )
( chuckles )
Thank you.
I'm here.
( groans )
( buzzing )
( fluttering )
Motherfuckers!
- ( flamethrower jetting )
- ( buzzing )
( indistinct yelling
outside )
( fire crackling )
( monitor beeping )
( shallow breathing )
Dan: I think about you
all the time.
( Dan chuckles )
You're all I see...
in the darkness...
in the daylight...
all the time.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com