Now listen, yo!
People put your guns up
Mazu ore ga run dat
Hashirimawatte yatsura o gun shot
Brand new sound sou still survival
Here come the sound boy kono sekai ni ikiro
Chiryoku tairyoku to un ga mau ze! Flow
Fukuranda ataman naka wa zakkubaran nan da
Savannah de Banna ni wanpan
Kantan knockout kan kan kan
One time for your mind ikinuke
Around the world
Tsukimatou no sa itsu no itami mo
Kedakai kami no mawari mo ima karimono
Makareta tane mo hana sakeba dare no
lkite uchikomu shinnen no ya o more more more
lkisaki ni yasuragi wa nai
Tachi na sa don't give up the fight
lma sou kono shunkan mo die die die
Big shooter ikiisoide blazing
Beat you up kirihiraite break
Shot shooter ikiisoida crazy
Shoujun au shikin kyori de break
Big shooter ikiisoide blazing
Beat you up kirihiraite break
Shot shooter ikiisoida crazy
Shoujun au shikin kyori de break
It's the beginning of a brand new day
A day filled with hope
Open your heart to happiness
C'mon! What's with this dog?
And look up at the big, blue sky
C'mon! Stop it!
Listen to the voice on the radio
Hey, are you all right?
Stop it! Don't come any closer!
Listen to the voice on the radio
And fill your lungs
C'mon! I said stop it!
With the fragrant air
One! Two! Three! Let's go!
Here, put this on before I attack you myself.
I wonder if this dog was owned by
a single working girl or something?
They Aren't Human
What's this?
It's displaying some text.
Your...
"Your lives are now over, you bastards.
What you do with your new lives
is for me to decide.
So there you have it."
What the hell's THAT supposed to mean?
Don't you mess with me!
Plis go eliminate this target now, you bastards.
The things it says are so ridiculous,
but it's kinda scary if you take it seriously,
don't you think?
The Green Onion Alien
but it's kinda scary if you take it seriously,
don't you think?
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
but it's kinda scary if you take it seriously,
don't you think?
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
Catch phrase: "Green onions are enough for me!"
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
Catch phrase: "Green onions are enough for me!"
"Please go eliminate this target now,
you bastards.
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
Catch phrase: "Green onions are enough for me!"
The Green Onion Alien.
Traits: Strong, smelly.
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
Catch phrase: "Green onions are enough for me!"
Likes: Green onions, friendship.
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
Catch phrase: "Green onions are enough for me!"
Catch phrase: "Green onions
are enough for me!"
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
Catch phrase: "Green onions are enough for me!"
The Green Onion Alien
Traits: Strong, smelly
Likes: Green onions, friendship
Catch phrase: "Green onions are enough for me!"
What the hell is that?
Is this some kind of game?
Is it going to let us out?
Awesome!
These look like the real deal!
They're heavy too!
There's a man inside!
I guess you could call him a bubble boy!
Why are you clinging to him?
It's probably a fake!
For a fake, it looks pretty realistic.
Ouch.
Kurono
Kato Cha:)
That's a bad pun!
Hey, Kato! Looks like there's one for you.
Kato Cha:)
Cosplay?
Isn't this kinda cool?
Try it on.
Why, you dumbfuck?
What's with this? It doesn't fire!
Bang!
What do you think you're doing?
Get off it! Nothing happened.
What's this? It's like an X-ray!
Hey!
Hatanaka...
What do we do now? Everyone's vanished, Kei.
What? I'm vanishing too?
Wait!
I'm outside.
Damn it!
Oh, yeah! Do I still have time?
Kurono
Come on, come on!
Damn, this is tight...
I can't get it on!
It's Kei.
Not good!
Got it!
I got it just in time.
What the hell are you doing butt-naked?
Kei...
It's not what you think!
Butter Dog!
Are you all right?
Yeah...
Oh, man!
This is so embarrassing!
This really is cosplay.
Hey, which line was that again?
Well, for now, let's look for
the nearest train station.
Why is she following him?
I ran to her rescue too, you know.
Maybe now I can get back
in the political arena.
If so, I've still got a chance.
A chance to mop the floor with
that cheeky Prime Minister.
Aw, man, I need some action...
Maybe I'll hit that soap.
Too bad these aren't real guns.
I swear I'm gonna fuck that girl
before I leave here.
I'm glad we get to go home.
I've got to grade those tests tonight.
Let me let you in on a little secret.
There are criminal aliens living here on Earth,
unbeknownst to humans.
I was recruited by a secret organization
of the Japanese government.
So it's our job to get rid of these aliens.
What the fuck you talkin' about?
You're full of it!
You mean like the Lost Continent of Mu,
or something, right?
Son, the current government doesn't have
that kind of money. I should know.
You don't have to believe me, but...
I hear if you kill one, you'll get ten million yen.
Get outta here!
Kei, you believe him?
Uh, well...
Aren't you stretching things a bit?
My dad's one of the top brass at
the Cabinet's Information Bureau.
You don't mean Vice Minister Nishi?
Old man?
If I remember correctly, there's a man
named Nishi in the Information Bureau.
He's sharp as a knife.
He's unlike most bureaucrats
in that he never lies.
You're shitting me!
Ten million yen...That's enough
to buy my own soap.
It's all in here.
So this is where we are? It's nearby!
Ten million yen...
But this can't be. Something like this can't be.
Mr. Suzuki, bureaucrats don't
tell politicians the truth.
That's because politicians are just there
for show. Did you know that?
You've all been recruited for this alien hunt.
I don't buy that.
No one recruited me.
Didn't somebody come up and talk to you
just before you entered that room?
We've only got an hour!
Let's go!
This is foolishness! I'm going home!
What are you going to do, Kei?
Is he there?
Isn't this the right place?
He isn't here, you fuck!
Hey, kid! If you're fucking with us, I'll kill you!
I don't care. It appears as though
I'm already dead anyway.
The Green Onions
There you are!
Hey, is he there?
Green onions are enough for me!
There he is!
He's eating green onions.
Hey! Taxi!
None of them are stopping.
Ouch! Damn...
Oh, well. That means I'm alive.
It hurts. I bleed.
When I get back...
When I get back, I'll start over from scratch.
Ichinomiya? Where the hell is Ichinomiya?
Ichinomiya
Damn! I can't go home dressed like this.
I must say, she's definitely my type.
It'd be a shame to just go home
without doing anything about it.
What's going on?
What? What do you mean?
What do I mean? You mean you don't know?
What a cute voice!
Well, we're going home, right?
All right, all right! You can have my pants too.
That's okay!
So...what are we going to do now?
I don't even know your names.
I'm Kei Kurono!
Okay...
Excuse me...
Me? I'm Masaru Kato.
Mr. Kato? Just plain Kato?
I don't care what you call me.
Why are you cozying up to him?
I'm going to find the rest of them.
Are you really going?
Something just doesn't feel right.
Yeah, I know.
Why?
Just gimme two.
Hey, what are we gonna do about him?
Just two.
Gross! Why, you little!
Oh, I get it. You gotta do this to fire it?
Just gimme two. Just gimme green onions.
Why are you carrying two of them?
Hand one over, now!
You too, blondie!
All right, let's do it!
Hey!
Wait a sec...
What's this?
What do you mean, what's this?
No, I...
Hey! Watch where you're pointing that!
Oops, sorry!
You little runt!
Just two...
Look what you did to my clothes, you little fuck!
He went up those stairs!
Hey, you! Wait!
What an idiot!
Outta my way, you!
Hey, are you okay?
Hey! I don't think you should be
moving around like this.
Just gimme green onions.
Hey!
Hey, wait!
Get back here, you!
What was that?
Kei, what was...
So does that mean we really ARE dead?
Mr. Kato! Kato!
Why does it have to be like this?
Hey, wait!
Take my green onions! Take my green onions!
I don't want them!
Damn, you're fast!
So, like, you told me you'd buy me
that ring the other day...
Kei, take her home for me!
Wait!
Score!
It's all right! I can get home by myself!
Well...
Now I've got you!
Take my green onions! Take my green onions!
I told you I don't want them!
What the...It had a good kick to it, but...
Wait!
No way!
One blast from this, and you'd be dead!
Take my green oni...
Hey, how do you shoot one of these things?
There are two triggers.
I got it to fire when I pulled both
at the same time!
Something's coming out of his ears!
Who is this guy?
It's funny, but he pisses me off!
Especially his face!
He's got razors!
Shoot him!
Stop it!
Hey!
Take my green onions! Take my green onions!
I'll forgive you for that because you're cute.
What the hell are you doing?
I can't believe you guys. I can't!
We gotta call an ambulance!
You got a problem with this, kiddo?
This can't be right...It just can't be!
What do you mean? You're strange.
Yeah, we got caught up in the thrill of it
and bagged ourselves a weirdo.
I couldn't save him.
Damn it! I couldn't save him!
Stuff it, you hypocrite!
He wasn't even human!
What difference does that make?
But what are we going to do about this?
Shit! Someone saw us!
Hey! Call the police!
What the fuck are you saying?
Mom! The Saitos' house is all messed up!
It looks like she didn't see us.
I guess that means we really are...
Dead...
Who the fuck is this?
The Green Onion Alien's dad?
Say something, you fucking green onion man!
Stop! I'm not exactly sure,
but I don't think it's a good idea to
get him any more agitated!
Shut up, kid!
What?
What the fuck are YOU looking at?
Are we gonna die?
This might be the end for us.
What is he made of, concrete?
Shoot him! Now!
Wait!
Don't shoot!
Okay...
I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
Hey, kid!
You still going to tell us to stop
even when it comes to this?
I told you not to shoot!
I'm sorry.
Would you shoot one of your kids
if he didn't listen to you?!
Well?
I'm sorry!
WELL?!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
It won't work on me.
I will live through this!
Hajimari wa dare demo junshin muku na baby
Nigai mi kajitte mo kujikecha
dame yo walk straight
Satta koto da kedo ame no naka
zukizuki itamu yo
I'm lonely as floating ice
Yaseta yubi ni kiss o shite
Naita anata o omoidasu yo
Kore de owari da to shite mo
Saigo no kiss wa wasurenai yo
Wasurenai yo
Kare no kiss o wasurenai yo
The Kei Kurono I remember.
A running, shining, shouting friend.
But now his friend is being ravaged
by strange, ferocious claws.
What will the others do?
What will he do?
Next time: "Kei, You're Awesome!"