Previously on Hannibal.
We're just alike.
This gives you the capacity
to deceive me
and be deceived by me.
Have you been firing a gun?
I told you I was feeling
paranoid.
All I want to do is catch him.
- He's given me nothing.
- I know what to expect
from lung cancer.
And there will be a time
when there is nothing
you can do.
No.
What are you up to?
I want you to come with me.
Alana Bloom isn't harbouring any doubts. She's
convinced that he murdered Freddie Lounds.
- How was my funeral?
- We're gonna get caught.
Jack already suspects
you killed Freddie Lounds.
- That means he suspects you.
- I know. - You should give him
what he wants. Give him
the Chesapeake ripper.
Dr. Hannibal Lecter requests
the pleasure
of my company for dinner.
You sit in that chair, Will,
as you have
so many times before.
It holds among its molecules
the vibrations
of all our conversations
ever held in its presence.
All the exchanges,
the petty irritations,
deadly revelations,
flat announcements of disaster.
The grunts and poetry of life.
Everything we've ever said.
Listen.
What do you hear?
(whispering voices)
A melody.
We're orchestrations of carbon.
You and me.
And Jack.
All our destinies
flying and swimming
in blood and emptiness.
Everybody's settling
in for dinner.
I'm wearing a wire.
I have sharp shooters
on the roofs of neighbouring
houses with lines of site
to all the windows.
He'll try to kill you
in the kitchen.
For convenience.
Make it easier
to prepare the tartar.
Jack won't be easy to kill.
He'll be armed.
He's strong,
well-trained.
We can't hesitate.
Hannibal thinks
you are his man in the room.
I think you're mine.
When a fox hears a rabbit
scream, he comes running.
But not to help.
When you hear Jack scream,
why will you come running?
When the moment comes.
Will you do
what needs to be done?
Oh yes.
(dogs barking)
(growling)
Shhhh.
See?
See.
(haggard breathing)
Forgiveness is such a profound,
conscious and unconscious
state of affairs.
You can't actually choose to do it.
Mmhm.
It simply happens to you.
Does forgiveness happen to you?
I died.
I'm between deaths.
The punctuation
at the end of a sentence
gives meaning to every word,
every space that proceeded it.
They moved my punctuation
mark, Dr. Lecter.
You moved my meaning.
(coughing)
I'm not here
because I want to be here.
You saw to that.
I'm here...
because I can't abandon Jack.
Not again.
Love and death
are the great hinges
on which all
human sympathies turn.
What we do for ourselves
dies with us.
What we do for others...
That's beyond us.
You saved me for Jack.
Will you save him for me,
when I'm gone?
Hmm.
I'm going to enjoy
my resurrection.
Nothing sells better
than a survival story.
I wouldn't count us
as survivors just yet, Freddie.
Counting me as a survivor?
I started as a cancer editor
at a supermarket tabloid.
Cancer is very lucrative media.
"New Cures for Cancer,"
"Cancer Miracle Cure."
We're all desperate
for a little hope.
I want to ask you to do
something for me, Freddie.
Or rather, don't.
Don't write about Abigail.
You can write about me.
You can write about Hannibal.
But, leave Abigail alone?
You really don't know
if you're going
to survive him, do you?
Just let her rest in peace.
These are your notes on me.
So they are.
Don't your patients need these
after you're gone?
The FBI will pore over
my notes if I left them intact.
I will spare
my patients the scrutiny.
I'm dismantling who I was
and moving it brick by brick.
When we've gone from this life,
Jack Crawford
and the FBI behind us,
I will always have this place.
In your memory palace?
My palace is vast,
even by medieval standards.
The foyer is
of Norman Chapel in Palermo.
Severe, beautiful and timeless.
With a single reminder
of mortality.
A skull.
Graven in the floor.
All I need is...
a stream.
In those moments
where you can't overcome
your surroundings,
you can make it all go away.
Put my head back,
close my eyes,
wade into the quiet
of the stream.
If I'm ever apprehended,
my memory palace
will serve as more
than a mnemonic system.
I will live there.
Could you be happy there?
All the path's chambers
are not lovely,
light and bright.
In the walls of our hearts
and brains, danger waits.
There are holes
in the floor of the mind.
In the few jerky seconds
of sleep I do get,
all I see is dark,
swarming behind my eyelids.
I dream darkness comes into me.
It comes and it's insidious.
Up my nose into my ears.
I feel poisoned.
We're all poisoned.
You saw what no one else could.
All it took was the, uh,
traumatic.
We're still in the thick of it.
We're getting through
the worst of it.
You've set some sort of trap
and you're goading
Hannibal into it.
How can you be sure
he's not goading you?
I can't.
Do you know what
an imago is, Will?
It's a flying insect.
It's the last stage
of a transformation.
When you become
who you will be?
It's also a term
from the dead religion
of psychoanalysis.
An imago is an image
of a loved one,
buried in the unconscious,
carried with us all our lives.
An ideal.
The concept of an ideal...
I have a concept of you,
just as you have
a concept of me.
Neither of us ideal.
Both of us are too curious
about too many things
for any ideals.
Is it ideal that Jack die?
It's necessary.
What happens to Jack
has been preordained.
We could disappear now.
Tonight.
Feed your dogs,
leave a note for Alana
and never see her or Jack again.
Almost polite.
Then this would be
our last supper.
Of this life.
We'll serve lamb.
Sacrificial.
I don't need a sacrifice,
do you?
I need him to know.
If I confess to Jack Crawford
right now,
I would forgive you.
If Jack were to tell you
all is forgiven,
would you accept
his forgiveness?
Jack isn't offering
forgiveness.
He wants... justice.
He wants to see you,
see who you are.
See what I've become.
He wants the truth.
Tell the truth, then.
And all its consequences.
This is entrapment, Jack.
You can't entrap someone
into committing
premeditated murder.
Yes, you can.
You're doing it.
You conspired to violate
Dr. Lecter's property
and personal rights.
And for the record,
the only one involved
in this investigation
we can confirm actually having
killed someone is Will Graham.
It was self defense.
Hannibal Lecter is being
induced to commit murder
by an undercover FBI informant.
This is outrageous
government conduct.
You would never
get a conviction.
You're not thinking
clearly, Jack.
We are as close as we are
ever going to get
to catching this man.
I understand that your wife
is very ill.
You're distracted.
After an inquiry,
I'm putting you on forced
compassionate leave.
This is just staggering.
What are you going to do
about Hannibal Lecter?
What Jack should have done.
We've frozen his passport
and we're getting
a search warrant.
Hannibal already opened
his doors to the FBI,
there won't be
physical evidence.
The only way to catch him
is in the act.
Are you saying we should have
just let Jack hang himself?
And everyone else
in his department?
No. But Will and Jack
are still your best chance
to catch Hannibal.
This man that Will Graham
killed in self defense...
he was mutilated.
At a certain point,
self defense stops.
Will Graham didn't stop.
Jack Crawford sanctioned this
and then he hid it from us.
I have to believe
that Will was trying
to maintain his cover identity.
Reality doesn't go away
because you stop
believing in it.
It's stubborn like that.
The reality of this situation
is Jack Crawford misused
the power of his office.
Mrs. Prurnell,
they are desperate.
They are breaking the law.
I'm bringing these men
up on charges.
They're not going to stop.
That's why they're being
brought into custody.
Jack knows what you'll find.
He knows what you have to do.
That won't stop him
from doing what he has to do.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
[It's Alana.
Is Jack with you?]
No, why?
They've issued a warrant
for your arrest, Will.
For acting as an accessory
to entrapment
(dogs barking)
[and for the murder
of Randall Tier.]
[They're going to arrest
Jack as well.]
[Will?]
Goodbye, Alana.
(phone rings)
Hello?
They know.
Hello, Jack.
You're early.
I couldn't wait to get here.
Would you care
to sous-chef?
I want to thank you
for your friendship, Hannibal.
The most beautiful quality
of a true friendship
is to understand them.
Be understood
with absolute clarity.
And this is...
the clearest moment
of our friendship.
Argh!
I'd like to report gunshots.
Hannibal.
Hannibal!
Where's Jack?
In the pantry.
I was hoping you and I
wouldn't have to say goodbye.
Nothing seen nor said.
You may have found that rude.
STOP!
I was so blind.
In your defense,
I worked very hard to blind you.
You can stay blind.
You can hide from this.
Walk away, I'll make no plans
to call on you.
But if you stay,
I will kill you.
Be blind, Alana.
Don't be brave.
(clicks)
I took your bullets.
(Alana whimpering)
I found more bullets!
Abigail?
I'm so sorry.
(medieval music)
This is Will Graham,
I need ERT.
Jack is inside.
Go...
(choking sounds)
(footsteps)
Abigail?
I didn't know
what else to do, so...
I just did what he told me.
Where is he?
Y... you were supposed...
to leave.
We couldn't leave without you.
Ah!
Time did reverse
the teacup that I shattered
there to come together.
The place was made
for Abigail and your world.
Do you understand?
The place was made
for all of us, together.
I wanted to surprise you.
And you...
you wanted to surprise me.
(sputtering)
I have let you know me.
See me.
I gave you a rare gift.
But you didn't want it.
Didn't I?
- You would deny me my life.
- N... no. No.
Not your life, no.
My freedom then,
you would take that from me.
Come find me in a prison cell.
Do you believe
you could change me,
the way I've changed you?
I already did.
Fate and circumstance
have returned us to this moment
when the teacup shatters.
I forgive you, Will.
Will you forgive me?
Don, don't...,
No. No.
N... no. No. No.
Abigale, come to me.
(gulping)
You can make it all go away.
Put your head back.
Close your eyes.
Wade into the quiet
of the stream.
Argh! Ah!
(gasping)
(phone dialing)
Hello? Jack...
Closed Captioning by SETTE inc.
Jus d'orange? Eau? Champagne?
Je voudrais du champagne,
s'il vous plaît.
Merci.
Je vous en prie.
Madame?
Non merci.