- Mick St. John,Thank You For Joining Us Tonight.
- You're Welcome.
So,What's Your Life Being A Vampire?
Being A Vampire Sucks.
It's A Bad Joke, I Know,
But It's The Truth.
- So You Drink Blood?
- Why, You Offering?
I'm Just Kidding.
Yeah, I-i Have A Guy.
- You Mean, Like A Dealer?
- Yeah, Like A Dealer.
So You Never Bite Anybody?
No, No... Unless
They Really Ask For It.
Do You Sleep In A Coffin?
No. That's An Old Wives' Tale.
I Sleep In A Freezer.
And While We're On The Subject,
Garlic Is Tasty On Pizza.
Does It Repel You?
It Repels My Dates Sometimes.
Toss Holy Water On Me, I Get Wet.
Crucifixes? Okay, If You Like
That Kind Of Thing.
Oh, And I Definitely
Can't Turn Into A Bat.
That'd Be Cool, Though,
Wouldn't It?
What About Daylight?
Daylight's Not Good.
The Longer I'm In The Sun,
The Worse I Feel.
- But You Don't Burst Into Flames?
- Not If I Can Help It.
How Do You Kill A Vampire?
Wooden Stake, I'm Guessing?
No, A Wooden Stake
Won't Kill A Vampire
Flamethrower
Will Kill A Vampire.
Or We Can Lose Our Head.
I Mean, Literally.
Other Than That, We Heal.
You Seem Like A Very Nice Guy,
But Don't Vampires Kill People?
Most Vampires Don't Have
Boundaries Or Rules, But I Do.
I Don't Hunt Women.
I Don't Hunt Children.
I Don't Hunt Innocents,But There's Predators Out There
Who Need To Be Dealt With.
Is That Why You Became
A Private Investigator?
It's A Way To Use My Special Abilities.
- Any Advice For The Vampire Wannabes Out There?
- Yeah...
Stay Out Of My Way.
I Often Wondered What It Would Be Like
If I Had The Opportunity To Explain Myself...
But That's Just A Fantasy.
Here's The Reality.
You Sleep Alone...
You Keep Your Secrets Hidden.
Oh, Yeah, And Here's What
A Dinner Party Looks Like.
I Know, I Know.
Everyone Says They're Open-minded.
Everyone Tries To Accept People
Who Are Different From Them.
But The Truth Is People Don't React Well
When They Find Out That You're...
Undead.
And The Other Thing
You've Got To Deal With--
When You Live Forever,
The Past Always Catches Up With You.
Like All Good Detective Stories,This One Starts With A Girl...
A Promising Life Cut Tragically Short.
Tonight, A Killer Is On The Loose.
Well, Technically Two Girls,
And One Of Them's Already Dead.
This Is Beth Turner For "Buzzwire." Cut.
Really? I Was Okay?
Oh, Yeah, Total Amanpour.I Mean, No One Would
Ever Know It Was Your Very First Live Webcast.
- We Gotta Get A Shot Of The Body.
- Cops Won't Let Anyone Get Close.
I'm Not Leaving Without My Money Shot.
- Oh, My God.Did I Just Say That?
- Yes.
- I've Become A News Whore Overnight.
- Not... Overnight.
Lieutenant Carl!
Carl, What Can You Tell Me?
- Well, Let's See, Beth.
- Nothing.
Come On.I Was First On Scene.
Who Fed You The Location On
The 710 Freeway Shooter?
All Right, Fine.
We Think She Was A Hearst College Student.
She Had Their Mascot Tattooed On A
Very Discreet Part Of Her Anatomy.
- Front Or Back?
- These Guys--get These Cameras Out Of Here!
Get These Cameras Out Of Here,
Now! Move It!
When You've Been Around
As Long As I Have,
You Ink That Nothing
Can Surprise You Anymore,
But That Was Before Tonight--
Before I Saw Her
Walking Barefoot Through A Freezing
Fountain At 2:00 In The Morning.
Beth...
Step Away From The Body.
"Murder On Melrose." No.
"Southland Student Slain."
Vampire.
Something With "Vampire" In It.
Do I Know You?
You Tell Me.
You're A Cop, Right?
No.
Reporter.
Nope.
We've Met Before.
You Look Very Familiar.
Well, Maybe I've Just Got
One Of Those Faces.
Okay.
Question.
What Do You Like Better--
"Vampire Slaying Rocks L.A."--
There's No Such Thing As Vampires.
I Don't Think The Girl
In The Fountain Would Agree.
I Mean--
Come On, Beth.The Body's Gone.
Cops Packed Up Hours Ago, Okay?
What Are We Still Doing Here?
Oking For The Girl's Car.
Right, And How Do We Know
She Didn't Walk?
- Nobody Walks In L.A.
- Of Course.
Here We Go.
Hearst College Parking Permit.
I Need You To Check On That Parking Decal.
- I Can't Deal Right Now.
- No, Don't Worry About It.I'll Call 'em, I'll Call 'em.
200,000 Unique Visitors On Your Vampire Story,
And We Posted Less Than 24 Hours Ago.
The Vampire Angle Was Genius.
Did You Come Up With That?
Yeah, It Just Kinda Came To Me.
Very Nice. Get Me Some
Science On This--an Expert.
Now I Wanna Blow This Thing Up,
Make It Seem Real.
"Are There Vampires Among Us?"
I'm Letting You Run With This.
What's Your Next Move?
Steve Got The Dead Girl's
Address From A Parking Permit.
I Think I'll Take
A Look Around.
Don't Think. Go.
Mama Needs Fresh Content.
You Don't Get To Change The Rules Of The Game
After The Game Has Started,
And That Goes For Your Silent
South American Partners, Too.
My Position Is Simple, Okay?
I'm Short The Shanghai A-shares,And
That Was A Guaranteed Deal.
Guaranteed!
Hey, Buddy, Let Me Get Rid Of This Guy.
My Friend Josef Is One Of The Oldest Vampires In L.A.--
400, Going On 30. Living...
Well Unliving Prooves That Paranoea Never Goes Out Of Style
Any Default, And I Would Not Be Sleeping So Snugly If I Were You.
These People Are
Unbelievable--no Integrity.
Oh,You Don't Like Veiled Threats?
Then How About This? You Screw Me, And
Personally Come Down There And Cut Heart Out, Okay?
That's The Only Thing They Understand.
Oh, That Sounds Good.
And My Best To The Family.
Ah, You Look Good. You
Working Out? Little Bit, Huh?
Well, Have You Seen The News?
This Terrible Thing In West Hollywood?
- It's Everywhere."Vampire Slaying Rocks L.A."
- Yeah, I Know.It Doesn't Look Good For Us.
It's A Threat To Our Secrecy.
What Is This, The 1720s?
We're Discreet. We Don't
Leave Bodies Lying Around.
Now We Have To Be Extra Vigilant.
We Live In An Age Of Fingerprint Scans,
- D.N.A. Tests, Genome Mapping--
- Josef, Relax, Okay?
I Am Relaxed. This Is Relaxed.
You're Only 90. You've Never Been Chased
By A Torch-bearing Mob--hungry!
- Would You Care For A Liquid Refreshment?
- No, Thank You.
Are You Sure?She's Delicious.
'82 Was A Good Year.
Oh, We Went To The Super Bowl In '82, Right?
Lost A Million Bucks On Cincinnati That Year, Right?
- Except For That.
- Yeah.
You're Fooling Yourself
- If You Think You Can Exist On That Retail Blood Forever.
- I Do All Right.
Yeah, For Now. But You're
Fighting A Losing Battle,My Friend
Okay?Sooner Or Later,Your Inner Vampire
Is Going To Demand To Be Fed,
And Then What?
- Good-bye, Josef.
- Good-bye.
My Guy At The Morgue,Guillermo,
Deals In Information And Blood.
Tonight I Needed Both.
Hey, Mick.What Can I Do You For?
Drinking On The Job?
40 Or 6-pack?
Give Me A Sixer.
Oh-ho.Thirsty Boy, Huh?
I Don't Know Why You Like
This A-positive So Much.
The O-positive Has Got A Much Better Finish.
I Wanna See The Body Of The Girl
They Found At The Design Center.
Yeah,I Figured You Would.
There's No Smell Of Vampire On Her.
- I Noticed. The Carotid Artery's Been Severed.
- How Much Blood Loss?
She Exsanguinated At 40% Loss, The Heart Stops.
Vampire Would've Drained Her.
Those Aren't Bite Marks.
They're Too Clean.
Plus There's Impact Trauma Around The Wound,
And Her Neck Was Punctured By Something.
Call Me If You Get Anything Else.
Oh, Yeah, Yeah,'cause I Work For You, Right?
I Didn't Intend To End Up A Do-gooder.
For The Longest Time,I Was Like Most People--
Just Kind Of Looking Out For Myself.
Then 22 Years Ago,
I Took A Case That Changed My Life Forever.
Los  Angeles 1985
Mr. St. John,Please Help Me.
Someone Took My Daughter.
Some Cases Really Sucker Punch You.
You Think You Know What You're Getting Into, Then... Wham.
The Police Have Nothing.It's Been Two Days.
Whether It's A Missing Child Or A Murdered Coed,
Victims Always Leave A Trail.
You Just Have To Find It.
Cops Had Been At The Dead Girl's
Apartment Since Morning.
I'd Been Waiting Since 6:00.
Looks Like I Wasn't The Only One.
- You Were At The Crime Scene.
- Easy With The Mace, Okay?
- Stay Back!
- I'm Not Gonna Hurt You.
You're Not Gonna Hurt Me?
How Do I Know You're Not The Killer?
Well, Because I'm Not Killing You.
Okay. If You're Not The Killer--
And Let's Go With That,'cause That's Comforting--
What Are You Doing Here?
I'm A Private Investigator.
Let Me See Your Credentials.
"Mick St. John"?
Who Are You Working For?
Falls Under My Client Confidentiality Agreement.
So Don't You Wanna Know Who I Am
And What I'm Doing Here?
You're Beth Turner.You Work For "Buzzwire."
It's Entertaining.
Excuse Me.It's Not Just Entertainment.
It's Hard-hitting,Investigative--
- Okay, There's A Bit Of Sleaze.
- You're Probably The Best.
Best What?
Thing They Have.
Oh. Thanks.
Let Me See.
I Saw Something Just Like It
In The Victim's Car.
- Look. Same Exact Thing.I've Been Researching It--
- Egyptian Hieroglyphic.
The Insignia For An Ancient Blood Cult.
Right. Blood Cult.
So We're Talking Vampires?
I Know.They Don't Exist.
Something Has To Explain All The Killing
And The Goth-o-rama Around Here.I Mean...
Obviously,She Had A Thing For Vampires.
Yeah, I Guess They're Back In Style.
You Know, Some People Actually Find Them Attractive.
Really?
Yeah.
- What Is It?
- Blood.
We Should Get That To The Police.
Hey, Honey.
Josh, I'm In The Middle Of Something Right Now.
Can I Call You Back?Okay. Bye.
Stop Doing That.
Nine Out Of Ten Murders,
The Killer Is Someone The Victim Knew.
That's Why I Wasn't About
To Miss Kelly Foster's Funeral.
Too Bad Funerals Always
Take Place During The Day.
That Glance In The Grave
Always Puts Everyone On Edge,
But When It's Murder...
Keep Your Eyes Open.
You're Gonna See More
Than Just Tears.
Thanks For Ditching Me
The Other Night.
I Knew You'd Be All Right.
You're Resourceful.
Kelly Was A Bright
And Promising Student,
And We All Mourn Her Loss.
Christian Ellis--
He Was Kelly's
Social Anthropology Professor.
We Inhabit Our Physical Bodies
For What We Call A Lifetime,
But Death Holds No Dominion.
Kelly Foster Lives
As Our Sister In Blood.
I'm Guessing The Emos With The Black Roses
Are Part Of His Ancient Mythology Studies Program.
- Did Your Homework.
- Which I Am Sharing With You.
Your Turn.Where's The Blood Vial?
You Took A Vial Of Blood From Kelly's Apartment.
I Want It.
You Son Of A Bitch!
Chloe, Chloe!
Chloe, Chloe, Chloe!
Chloe, Chloe, Hey, Hey,
We Still Love You.
- Oh, Shut Up!
- You Know That.
A Whiff Of Fresh Blood On The Air
Blood I'd Smelled Before.
You Okay?
I'm Okay.
Lot Of Angry People.
Angry People Make Good Suspects.
And Dangerous Ones.
Don't Worry.
I'll Look Out For You.
We Should Divvy Them Up.
Two Can Cover More Ground.
I Work Alone.
A Girl's Dead.
I'm Not Letting This Go.
Kind Of Pushy, Aren't You?
You'll Get Used To It.
Start With The Professor.
I'll Take His Young Attacker.
Wait. What About My Vial?
We Should Get It To The Police So They Can
Analyze It,Find Out Whose Blood It Is.
It's The Professor's.
What's Going On With You
And Professor Ellis, Chloe?
What Do You Mean?
Well, You Tried Slicing The Guy
Open At The Funeral Today.
Christian's A Svengali.
He, Like, Brainwashed Kelly
With All This Literary Crap
About Vampires And Sex And Dark Desires.
He Runs A Vampire Study Group.
Study Group?
It's A Cult.
What Goes On There?
The Usual Clich?--chanting,
Candles, Blood Drinking.
They Drink Blood?
Oh, Yeah. Christian Thinks
He's A Vampire.
A Real Vampire?
A Lot Of Girls Believe Him.
He's Got A Lot Of...Disciples.
- Were You A Disciple?
- Yeah, I Was In.
In Fact, I Was The One
Who Told Kelly She Should Join.
Big Mistake That Was.
What Happened?
She Was All Over Christian,
Totally Fed Into His Crap.
And You Didn't?
Yeah, I Did.
He's Really Powerful...
Seductive...
- Makes You Feel Special.
- But You Weren't.
No.
And That Made You Jealous Of Kelly?
Yeah, And Pissed Off.
And, No,I Didn't Kill Her,
If That's What
You Want To Know.
Go Write Your Stupid Little
Vampire Story Someplace Else.
When I Was Turned Into A Vampire,
All My Senses Were Heightened To 11.
For God Sakes,
You're Giving Me A Headache.
I'm Able To Smell The Past...
Glimpse The Future...
- Not Now. I Have Class.
- Oh, When Should We Discuss This--
When Another One Of
Your Students Turns Up Dead?
And I Can Hear A Marriage Going Down The
Drain From A Hundred Yards.
I Had Nothing To Do With That.
Is That What
We're Telling People?
You Tell Them Whatever
The Hellou Want.
Hi. Is Professor Ellis Home,Please?
He's Not Here.
Oh. Uh, I'm--
I'm Sorry To Disturb You.
I Didn't Mean To Bother.
Is There Something That
I Can Help You With, Mister...
St. John. Mick St. John.
I'm A Private Investigator.
This Is About The Dead Girl.
Yes, I-i'm Looking Into The Case.
This Must Be Very Difficult For You.
How About I-i Come Back Another Time?
What Do You Want To Know?
There Was A Time When Christian
Was A Serious Academic.
He Has A Phd
In Mythological Anthropology.
He Published Every Year.
But Now He Has Other Interests.
Like Kelly Foster?
Among Others.
These Girls Are So Young
And Impressionable.
- I Used To Be That Way Myself.
- Me, Too.
Christian Can Be
Very Charming... Like A Snake.
Oh, He's A Vampire By The Way.
- I Don't Know If You Knew That.
- I Did Not.
At Least, That's What He Tells
Them When He Seduces Them
In The Basement
Of Chandler Hall.
Mrs. Ellis, Do You Think Your
Husband Killed Kelly Foster?
The Girl Had A Bite In Her Neck, Right?
- Right.
- He's The Only Vampire I Know.
We Have All Fed On Blood,
Every One Of You In This Room.
Everyone On This Earth...
In The Womb,
Our First Meal Is Blood.
We Feed In Darkness.
There Is No Time.
There's No Life.
There's No Death.
It Is A Perfect World,
Seemingly Everlasting,
Until We Are Ripped
From The Womb Into Daylight.
When We Are Born,
That Paradise Is Lost,
And We Spend The Rest
Of Our Days
Trying To Find Our Way Back--
Back To That Perfect World
Of Blood And Darkness.
That's Enough For Tonight.
But Remember To Take
This Truth With You
To Your Everyday Lives.
We Are All Vampires,
Every Last One Of Us.
I Will See You All Next Week.
That Was
An Amazing Lecture.
Thank You.
Hey, I'm Kate Nelson.
I Just Transferred Down
From Berkeley.
Welcome.
I Read Your Book,
"The Mythology Of Darkness."
Well, That's More Than I Can
Say For A Lot Of My Students.
I Think
It's Really Interesting,
The Vampire As Metaphor
For Desire.
The Thirst For Blood Is
Symbolic Of A Deeper Hunger.
A Hunger To Connect.
You Did Read My Book, Huh?
Do You Think I Could
Audit Your Class?
Well, My Lectures
Are Pretty Popular,
But I'm Sure We Could
Squeeze You In.
Thanks.
I Really Appreciate It.
Sure.
I Know I'm A Month Behind.
Is There A Syllabus
I Could Get Started On
Or Some Way To Catch Me Up?
Well, I Do Have A Study Group
For Some Of My More
Motivated Students.
I'm Really Motivated.
Daniel?
This Is Daniel, My T.A.
Daniel, This Is Kate...
Nelson.
Kate Nelson. I'm Sorry.
Would You Take Down
Her Information?
Sure.
I Have To Get Going.
Hi. Study Group, Huh?
Sounds Intriguing.
-so How Do We Get Hold Of You?
-3-1-0...
Somewhere In The City,
A Killer Is On The Loose.
Josef Wants Me To Hunt Him
To Keep Our Secret Safe.
I Just Want To Make Sure
He Doesn't Do It Again.
You Don't Have To Be A Vampire
To Get A Taste For Blood.
||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||
You Startled Me.
I'm Mick St. John.
Right. My Wife Mentioned
You Came By The House.
You're Looking
Into Kelly Foster's Death.
Uh, Murder.
Do You Mind If I Ask
Who You're Working For?
I'm Working For Kelly.
Well, Then I Want To Help
In Any Way I Can.
She Was
An Extraordinary Girl,
On
And I...
I Truly Cared For Her.
So There Was
A Relationship?
I Already Told
The Police Everything.
I Have Nothing To Hide.
If I Did, Do You Think
I'd Be Talking To You?
That Piece Is
Over 500 Years Old,
From The Reign
Of Sigismund I--
The Sign Of Vilnius,
A Lithuanian Vampire God.
Vampire God, Huh?
You Know, That's Interesting,
Because Kelly Foster
Showed Up Dead With
Two Bite Marks In Her Neck.
Well, Clearly, Someone's Trying To Make It Look
?????????
-i Am A Vampire.
-really?
Well, Not In The Way
Most Commonly Portrayed
In Dime-store Novels.
When Most People Hear
The Word "Vampire,"
They Immediately
Conjure Up An Image
Of Some Undead Monstrosity
Running Around At Night
Trying To Drink Human Blood.
Hate That.
A Real Vampire Is Simply
A Person Born With The Abili
To Absorb And Manipulate
Pranic Energy.
-"Prana" Is A Hindi Word Meaning--
-life Force.
Yes, Very Good.
Real Vampires Have
A Critical Eneicy Imbalance.
So We Must Seek Out
Pranic Energy And Absorb It.
Couldn't You Just Have
A Double Espresso Or Something?
Fresh Blood Has Oovery High
Pranic Energy Content,
Hence The Blood Link
To Vampires.
But When Done Correctly,
A Pranic Ceremony
Can Have Salutary Effects
For Both Participants.
So Tell Me Something,
Professor--
Do The Salutary Effects
Kick In
Befo Or After The Sex
With Your Students?
I Think
We're Through Talking.
All Right, Thank You.
You Know, If One
Of The Killers You Put Away
Ever Wanted To Get Even,
All They Would Have To Do
Is Wait For The Cochinita Pibil
To Go On Special.
"Vampire Slaying Rocks L.A."?
Publicity Spawns Tips, Carl.
Yeah, And Copycats.
Don't Be Mad. I Gave You
The Vial Of Blood.
It's Inadmissible.
Did You Have It Analyzed? Is It
From A Person Of Interest?
The Professor Of Darkness?
You Have His D.N.A.
On File?
- Look, He Volunteered A D.N.A.
Swab During His First Interview.
- Cooperative.
Yeah, That's What They
Always Want You To Think.
What Do You Have On Chloe Jones?
????
???
She Should Be.
We Found A Stalking
And Harassment Complaint
- Filed Against Her
With The Campus Police.
- Filed By?
- Kelly Foster.
- Chloe Said They Were
Best Friends.
They Were. We Also Found A Blood Pendant At Chloe's
Apartment.
They Were Both Sleeping With The Professor.
Well, Threesomes
Never End Well.
Huh?
Don't Ask.
It's About Time You Got Back.
Make Yourself At Home.
I Did,
And Poured Myself A Drink.
You Seriously
Drink This Stuff?
- What Is It, Like,
Nonfat Soy Vegan Blood?
- If You Don't Like It--
- I Didn't Say That.
- Are You Sure?
Get Out Of Here. Actually,
You Got Any Freshies Around?
Yeah, Of Course Not.
Am I Supposed To Know
Why You're Here, Josef?
It Is Possible
That There Is A Core Truth
Behind The Vampire Myth.
Perhaps There Are People With
Certain Genetic Predispositions
Who Actually Could Require
And Digest Blood.
Vampire Experts. Beautiful.
Now We Got The Food
Mouthing Off About The Farmer.
The Whole City Is Talking.
- You Want To Know What
They're Talking About? Us.
- So It's A Slow News Day.
Oh, That's Not It.
It's A Reporter From "Buzzwire."
She Started This Whole
Killer Vampire Thing--
- A Beth Somebody.
- Turner.
You Know Her?
Yeah, We Did Some Breaking
And Entering Together.
Hmm. Well, You, My Friend,
Must Get Her To Stop.
What Do You Mean?
Like She's Driving Along
And Suddenly Her Car Explodes?
I Was Thinking You'd Ask Her Nicely,
- But Fielder's Choice.
The Killer's
- Not A Vampire, Josef.
- There Were Bite Marks.
- Two Stab Wounds.
- And The Blood?
- Well, You Hit An Artery, You're
Bound To Get Some Of That.
Oh, So You're Telling Me
Some Possoannabe
Drinking Blood Out
Of A Snoop Dogg Chalice
- Is Behind This?
- Yeah, Something Like That.
- Why Haven't You Killed Him?
- There's More Than One Suspect.
So Kill Them All.
That's What I Would Do.
Hey, Look, I Know You Have
Morals And Scruples,
And That's Fine... Sort Of.
But You Are Not The Man I
On Occasion Pretend To Respect
If You Don't Get This
Under Control.
Hey, You Have A Soft Spot
For The Mortal Ones,
A Fascination With All
The Charming
While Listening
To The Tick, Tick, Tick
Of Their Own Looming Demise.
That's Fine. It's Good.
Everyone Needs A Hobby.
Look, People Aren't Gonna
Suddenly Believe In Vampires
- Because Of A "Buzzwire" Article.
- Are You Willing To Take That Risk?
If Everyone Have Vampires
On Their Mind
Because Of Some Reporter,
Suddenly Things Get Noticed.
- We Get Noticed.
- I Said I'm On This.
Good, 'cause If That Reporter
Actually Finds Out
Who We Are, She Gets A Pulitzer,
And We Join The List
Of Extinct Species.
We're On The Same Side.
I'm Sorry. I'm Not
Questioning Your Loyalties.
Yeah? Good.
Yeah. Vampire Solidarity.
Rah, Rah, Rah And All That.
Hey, And Don't Forget,
I'm Your Only Friend Who Doesn't
Like You Just For Your Money.
That's True. Sad But True.
We're Closed.
Oh. It's You.
It's Not Funny.
Why Are You Wearing
That Stupid Thing Anyway?
Take It Off. You're Really
Starting To Freak Me Out.
Did You Hear Me?
Relationships Are Complicated.
Vampire Or Mortal--
That's One Thing
We Have In Common.
Yeah, Yeah.
Okay, Here's What
I Don't Understand.
I'm Fine. How Are You?
How Did You Know The Blood
We Found In The Vial Was The Professor's?
You're Saying It Wasn't?
No, It Was.
He Gave The Police
A D.N.A. Sample, And It Matched.
So You Must Have A Source
In The Department, Right?
No, But Obviously You Do.
So...
What Did You Find Out
About Chloe?
She's Got A Few
Anger Management Issues.
Turns Out Our Murder Victim
Got A Restraining Order
Against Her
A Couple Months Ago.
What's Her Deal?
The Professor Toss Her Aside?
Yeah, But Murder?
Check Her Out.
Let Me Kw What You Think.
Okay.
What About The Wife?
Well, She Knows
Her Husband's A Snake.
- But The Professor...
- What?
- He Thinks He's A Vampire.
- Yeah, I Know. I Attended
His So-called Class.
You What?
I Also Managed To Wrangle
An Invite To His Study Group.
I'm Not Sure
That's A Good Idea.
What Are They Gonna Do, Kill
A Newcomer To Get Extra Credit?
I Just Think
You Should Be Careful.
- Don't Let The Professor
Get You Alone.
- I'll Be Careful.
Good.
You Look So Familiar.
Are You Sure
We Haven't Met Before?
Yeah, Twice Now.
No, Someplace Else.
I-i Guess I've Just Got--
One Of Those Faces.
I Know, You Said.
I Should Go.
Sometimes The Past Doesn't
Just Catch Up With You.
It Haunts You...
Makes You Think
About Your Choices.
On That Night 22 Years Ago...
It's All Right.
I Followed A Trail...
I'm Here. It's All Right.
Found The Girl
And Came Face-to-face
With The Woman
Who'd Made Me A Monster--
Coraline.
I Knew You Would Come.
Here We Are, Mick...
Finally One Happy Family.
Forever Is A Long Time
With An Ex-wife Like Mine.
You're Taking A Long Time
Putting That Mike On.
I'm Just Trying To Get It
Exactly Right Here.
Does That Include
Feeling Me Up?
Hey, You're Going Into
The Vampire's Lair, Okay?
I Just Want To Make Sure
This Mike Works.
I'll Be Fine.
So... Exclusive Infiltration
Of A College Sex And Blood Cult.
Man, The Story Just
Keeps Getting Better.
A Girl's Dead.
This Is An Important Story.
Yeah, It Doesn't Mean
We Can't Milk It.
?????
||
Chloe?
Beth.
Hm
Where Are We Going,
Exactly?
Don't Worry.
It's All Part Of The Ritual.
Ritual? I Thought
It Was A Study Group.
Yeah. You'll See.
Seriously?
The Ritual's In A Boiler Room?
Hi. You've Reached Beth Turner.
I'm Unable To Answer Your Call
Your Call Right Now,
So Please Leave A Message,
And I'll Get Back To You?????
||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||||
Lurks Between The Lines
Of Sanskrit Tablets.
Numerous Cultures Of Antiquity
Believed That Blood
Was The Vital Element
In The Lovemaking
And Life-giving Process.
Now All These Ancient Texts
Can Be Categorized
In A Number Of Ways,
But What's Most Important To Us
Is The Spirit Of These Texts,
Not The Letter.
Hi, Kate.
So The Ancient Tantric Practice
Of Using Sexual Intercourse
To Transform One's Sexual Energy
Intolissful Consciousness
Speaks To That Issue Perfectly.
Well, I Think That's Enough
For Tonight.
I Will See You All Next Week.
Blood Is Life, And Life Is Blood.
Born Into Light,
We Seek The Dark.
Thank You.
Kate.
I'm So Glad You Could Make It.
Seems Like I Missed It.
I Thought I Was Supposed
To Be Here At 11:00.
Well, This Is Your First Session,
And I Like To Get
- A Little One-on-one Time
With My Students.
- Okay.
So Let's Go Back And Talk.
Don't Be Shy.
Hold Out Your Hands
Above Mine.
Right Above Mine.
Just Like That.
We Are Only Now Rediscovering
What The Ancients Knew.
We Are Simply Energy.
We Both Radiate And Absorb It.
Concentrate On Your Hands.
Do You Feel That?
Uh... Maybe.
It Takes A Little Practice.
Close Your Eyes...
And Concentrate.
Feel Your Yonic Energy
Balancing Mine.
Do This Long Enough...
Our Hearts Will Synchronize.
Are You Kidding Me?
This Actually Works For You?
What Do You Have
Under There?
Huh?
What Do You Have
Under There?
Get Your Hands Off Me.
Get Off!
Are You Recording This?
Who Are You? Answer Me!
Where's The Recorder?
Kate! Hey, Kate!
You All Right? What Happened?
I Need To Call The Police!
Why? What Did He Do To You?
Do You Have A Cell Phone?
Uh, Uh, Yeah, In My Car.
Come On.
Where Is She?
Who?
Your New Student.
Where Is She?
No Idea.
What Do You Think--
I Don't Have A Lot Of Time.
I Know She Was Here, Man.
I Can Smell Her On You.
And You're Gonna Tell Me
Where She Is.
She Just Left.
But... You Can't Be Real.
That's Right, Professor,
Because There's No Such Thing
As Vampires.
Li
Why Are You Doing This?
You Wouldn't Understand.
I Might.
Christian's A Prophet.
His Teachings
Reveal The Powerful Truth
About Our Vital Pranic Energy.
We Must Absorb This Energy,
Preserve It,
Not Waste It On Women.
Without These Distractions,
- Christian Can Fulfill
His True Destiny.
- What Destiny?
Hey, Hey!
?????
Shouldn't Have Done That.
Everything's Gonna
Be All Right.
You're Not Gonna Do This.
It'll Work, Mick,
You, Me And Baby.
No. I'm Not Gonna Let You
Hurt That Girl.
I Can't Let You.
Come On.
I'm Gonna Take You Home.
The Last Time I Held Her In
My Arms, She Was Only A Child.
Over The Years,
I Tried To Stay Close,
Just Out Of Sight,
In Case She Needed Me.
And Tonight She Did.
It's All Right.
You're With Me.
You Saved Me.
From A Graduate Student
In Mythological Studies.
Didn't Exactly Take Superman.
No, That's Not What I Meant.
I Mean, When I Was Little.
When I Was Taken.
You Got A Really Nasty Bump
On Your Head Tonight.
You Probably Just Need To-
He Stabbed You.
He Sure Tried.
I Saw The Knife Come Out.
He...
You Need To Get Some Rest.
I'm Gonna Take You Home,
Okay?
60 Years Is A Long Time
To Deny Yourself
The Touch Of Another...
||
But You Do It Because You
Just Can't Bear The Thought
Of Seeing Yourself As A Monster
In Someone Else's Es.