I'm not letting you
drive six counties over
with somebody I don't even know!
...for stealing his daddy's
car, what, six damn months ago?
That's not what happened.
And he didn't mean to steal it.
Mindy, I raised you better than this
for you to be giving me
this bullshit right now.
His dad...
You are 16 years old!
Yeah, I'm older than you
were when you got pregnant!
That does not make it
okay for you to run wild!
If anything, it means the opposite!
Mindy Prairie Austin, can't you
see I'm trying to protect you?
Oh, protect me from what?
It's a concert! Six of
us are gonna be there.
What's gonna happen?
The answer is no.
Do you have any clue
what this means to me?
What this could do?
All my friends are going!
Let's not get overly dramatic, dear.
If you want to hang around
and be with your friends
some other day when you
don't have to drive
a hundred miles outside of town...
You know, I could have lied!
You will not be going out forever!
Why don't you go to your room?
I am sick of this!
Mom, you can't just yell at me
every time you feel like it.
I could've just said I was going to
Sarah's and you'd have never known.
You think about that? Don't
I get any credit for that?
Great job. I am so proud of you.
You're still not goin'.
I hate you!
Joshua, put away the chips.
You already had dinner.
Joshua.
Keep listening to WFKK
with Bobcat Joe to win your share
of the biggest free ticket
raffle in West by gosh Virginia.
Up next, we got a little
Conway Twitty coming your way.
Attention all cars.
We have a possible 503 in
progress at Main and Park.
Anyone in the area, please respond.
The boys will get it.
Where you at with the new
playground equipment?
Don't try to distract me.
It's going well.
Thanks for comin' to the potluck.
A little of that makes a
little of this okay, right?
Isn't that how it work?
Whatever your motives.
There would've been something
missing without the chief's chili.
Yeah... heartburn.
The point is,
we are almost to our fund-raising goal
and you two fine public servants are
about to put us over the top.
I'm gonna make sure
there's a little plaque
with your names on the teeter-totter
in honor of this generous contribution.
Lord willing.
Ogden, you get a read on that?
Does it mean he's got a
terrible hand and needs help
or he's got a great
hand and is bluffing?
There's your answer. Fold.
I ain't so sure.
Much as I hate to disappoint them kids,
I think I'm gonna make
you show me them cards.
All right then. Call, raise, whichever.
Just quit wasting time and
give me my damn money.
This better be life or death, Florence.
It's Mrs. Austin.
- Says it's urgent.
- I'm out.
Past time to call it a night, anyway.
Wife is going to be pissed, so...
No, come on. That...
That... that can wait.
I'm gonna hit your little
boys' room on my way out.
Fine.
Just don't forget to
open a window this time.
Shit.
What can I do for you, Betsy?
Reverend...
it's Joshua.
You have to help him.
What is it?
It's just like you've been
talking about on Sundays.
Like the Conners boy
and Miss Martindale.
You sure? I mean, there's a...
there's a lot of things...
I'm sure.
Kyle!
Kyle, come on!
Kyle, you asshole!
I can see you!
Let me in!
You know I'll stay here all
goddamn day if I have to.
Please go.
And leave your sorry ass all alone?
Not a chance.
You can't be here.
It's worse than I thought.
How long has it been since
you ate a vegetable?
Do you even remember solid poop?
This isn't healthy.
Why are you here?
I'm checking in on you, shithead.
Because I care about you.
You know people do that, right?
Care about other people?
Things are that dull with
your real family then, huh?
I'm not even going there with you.
Why didn't you call me
when you ran out of food?
Were you out of minutes or somethin'?
I lost that phone.
Is this you punishing yourself?
Take a fucking shower already.
Okay.
I appreciate your judgment,
really do,
but you can quit making me your mission.
I'm doing just fine.
You don't owe me anything.
Bullshit you're fine.
Look at this place.
Maybe your little savings
account will last forever.
You still haven't had
the water turned on.
I don't need it.
And bullshit I don't owe you anything.
You know better.
It's my home, Megan.
Please let me get you some food.
Let me get you out of here...
at least for an hour.
Maybe you'll luck out and the place
will burn down while we're gone.
One hour?
Then you'll leave me alone?
All right.
I'll meet you out front... Don't.
I'll meet you out front in five minutes.
Morning, Reverend.
It is a fine one.
Any change?
I'm afraid not.
Thank you.
I got donuts too.
But I'm afraid they didn't
survive the drive over.
Is he awake?
I brought him some food this morning,
but I don't know if he ate it.
He scares me.
The Lord would never abandon
one of his children.
And neither would I.
Now...
let's see about your boy.
They really do need to get
more organic produce here.
The selection is pathetic.
Organic shredded wheat.
High in fiber. Poops be solid.
You shouldn't have brought me here.
I don't know what I ever did
to make you hate me so much.
I don't hate you, Megan.
Then why do you avoid
me like the plague?
If I get you this,
you'll call me next time
you need something...
and not the one person on Earth
you're not supposed to call?
Do your 12-year-old students
notice your condescending tone
or is that just me?
Pretty much just you.
I don't want you to
get in trouble again.
Is that so wrong?
I won't call her.
Soup preference?
Ech.
Kyle Barnes is here.
That must be a sign, I tell you.
Kyle Barnes?
Uh, yeah.
We went to church with
your mother, Kyle.
Do you remember me? Florence Hall?
Uh... okay.
It's been a long time.
- It's good to see you.
- And you too, dear.
Haven't seen you in
church in a long time.
You really should attend a sermon.
Yeah.
I'll try.
We're asking everyone in Rome
to pray for the Austin boy.
- Hm.
- You know the family?
Uh, I don't. No.
Their son, Joshua, bright boy.
He's fallen prey to dark forces.
It's like what happened to your
poor mother all over again.
It is such a shame. So terrible.
And so soon after the Conners family.
Reverend Anderson has been visiting
little Joshua all week.
Can you keep him in your
thoughts and prayers?
Yeah.
I can do that. Sure.
You were always such a sweet boy.
We should be going, Flo.
I hope I'll see you soon at the service.
I'll try.
Great.
Thank you.
Are they kidding with
that fucking nonsense?
"Dark forces"?
Please.
Your mother was sick, and some people
in this backwards town are crazy.
Kyle?
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Come out and face me, coward!
In the name of Jesus, I command
you to release this child!
You're hurting him!
Go downstairs!
Look into my eyes
and see the power I hold over you.
The power given to me by
the Almighty God our Lord.
No... power.
You don't belong here.
In the name of Jesus,
I cast you out!
Oh my God.
Oil of the spirit
and the holy water of
the cleansing of God...
Joshua!
- Baby, wake up.
- Betsy, get out!
- Just wake up, baby.
- Get the fuck out!
Oh!
Heavenly Father, please
grant me the strength
to overcome this evil I now face!
- Allow me to drive this demon out
- Joshua!
so that his body can be
filled with the Holy Ghost
and put back upon a path to your glory!
- Appreciate this.
- The hell?
Is that gratitude?
Shut up.
Your
father was a coal miner.
Your grandfather was a coal miner.
This boy those women
are talking about...
you hear anything?
Don't go down that road again.
I remember when you first moved in,
before Mom and Dad adopted you.
You thought there were demons
hiding in every shadow.
And Anderson really filled
your head with some bullshit.
I'm just worried about that boy.
Yeah, well, not much you can do there.
Hey!
You lost?
If you're gonna backseat drive,
climb in the back fuckin' seat.
Where are you taking me?
Come on! You've never
even seen the new house!
- Oh, my...
- It's been two years!
Damn it, Megan! No!
I know you don't want me
around your daughter.
Your husband hates me.
- Please.
- A nice dinner will be good for you.
You can shower with actual hot water.
I'll give you some of
Mark's old clothes.
- Oh, God.
- Holly loves you.
You don't hate us enough
to jump from a moving car.
I'll take that as a win.
Uh, Megan brought me
over against my will.
Honest.
Look, Mark, I'm the only person
who wants me here less than you do.
Believe me, man. You know how she is.
Do I ever.
Honey, is that you?
Yep.
Nice shirt.
Hey, doodlebug.
Uncle Kyle is here.
Yeah, I know that.
I saw him with my own eyes.
Listen, sweetie, can you
go on up to your room?
Need to talk to your mama.
Go on. Scoot.
Now, Holly.
Yes, ma'am.
Megan, why?
Come on. You know how I feel about this.
It's just one goddamn dinner, okay?
Do you really think he's stable?
I mean, you can't tell me that
you feel safe around him.
You think it's a good idea to
bring him around our daughter?
Well, he's in there, she's in here.
Oh, okay.
So, he's just gonna eat in there alone?
That's not gonna be awkward?
Look...
I know what he did for you
when you were younger...
and we can never thank
him enough for that.
But he took a turn when
he got older, okay?
You can't ignore that!
How can you be okay with him
being here after what he did?
He made a mistake and he did a horrible,
unforgivable thing, and...
damn it, he's paid for that.
It's ruined his life,
and I'm gonna be here for him.
What?
You think he's gonna attack
Holly over the dinner table?
It's just dinner, just one night.
He's not gonna hurt anybody.
Please, Mark.
Please let me do something nice for him.
He's got nothin'.
Hey.
Uh...
You remember me, right?
I'm... I'm your mama's brother.
You hurt your little girl,
and now you're not her daddy anymore.
That's not...
What is it, honey?
Uncle Kyle left.
Shit. Kyle!
Why would he leave?
Why look a gift
horse in the mouth?
Asshole.
I'm sure he's fine.
We need to get a patrol
car, have 'em pick him up,
drive him home?
Let him walk.
All he ever wants is to be alone.
Hello?
Kyle, is that you?
Amber, honey, come inside!
Temperatures are
expected to drop tonight
with scattered showers throughout
the afternoon and into tomorrow.
We should see some sunshine here...
Howdy.
Offer still good to borrow your car?
Sure.
Yeah?
Uh...
I heard about your boy, and...
um...
Reverend Anderson, is he here?
Hold on.
Kyle Barnes.
This is a surprise.
Yeah, I know, Reverend.
It's, uh, been a long time.
I didn't know you were in town.
Yeah, um...
back about five months now.
I wish we were seeing each other
under different circumstances,
but I'm glad you're here.
Okay.
Uh...
Hold on, Reverend.
I didn't come to see the boy.
Not to help, at least. I came 'cause...
I don't really know.
Sure you do.
What you think I did, I
assure you, I didn't.
Uh-huh.
Doctors think you should be in therapy,
but we know what this is.
We don't know anything.
Whatever you think
happened to your mother,
it was you who stopped it.
My mother was sick.
I don't know much else about it.
I was just a kid.
These things are everywhere.
They're all around us.
Now, you've been gone a long time.
You have no idea how bad it's gotten.
And you might not believe it,
but that doesn't make it any less true.
Why don't we stick to what we know
before we start blaming
the bogeyman again?
He's showing signs of very
animal-like behavior,
which is common.
I know you.
You think so, huh?
When's the last time you
went to school, Joshua?
Pretty cool getting to skip out
on school like this, isn't it?
I like school.
I miss my friends.
Well, I'm sure they miss you too, bud.
Why don't you stop all this,
so things can go back to normal?
You're scaring your mom.
You're wasting this man's time.
Stop pretending, Joshua.
He... he hasn't been
speaking like this before.
This is new.
You're all grown up.
You barely even fit in that pantry now.
What?
Padlock on the door.
You used to draw pictures on the walls.
Don't you remember?
You're talking nonsense.
I know you, Kyle Barnes.
What do you know, huh?
Got any idea what you're
talking about with all that?
You're just a damn kid.
You don't know shit.
Kyle, just...
Sorry. I... I'm sorry.
We all know what we know.
Why don't you tell me
what you know then, huh?
Come on, kid.
Why don't you say something
that makes one goddamn bit of sense?
- Right now!
- Just keep your distance.
He's playing games with us.
Sit down.
I'll light the sage.
This... this should calm him.
Just, uh...
give it a few moments to...
to fill the room.
So long have we tried
to find you, Outcast.
Too long have you hidden
your light from us.
Now you heed this.
- In the name of the Father,
- Dull. Making us search
- the Son, and the Holy Ghost...
- through the darkness.
Here.
No.
He ever try to do that to you?
What about what he was saying in there?
Any of that make sense?
About him... knowing me?
Demons are tricksters.
They want you to be more scared
of them than you need to.
With the power of God on our
side, we got nothing to fear.
"The power of God."
You think your mother and
Joshua are the only ones?
There's a house like this one
in every town, in every country
of this whole wide world.
And you go into those houses?
- Yes, I do.
- Well, what makes you think
you can do anything about that?
You want my advice?
Run.
While you still got something left.
There was a time I might
have taken that advice.
You know, I wasn't always the, uh...
the gung-ho holy warrior
you see before you.
I served God, tended my flock...
but I questioned.
Then I went into your house...
and I saw the devil was real.
And I didn't question anymore.
My path was clear.
I don't believe it's a coincidence
that you set me upon that path,
and here you are, walkin' it yourself,
facing all this again.
And I don't believe you're gonna run.
Hey, Caleb.
- Working late?
- Yeah.
This railing was loose.
Didn't want any of our old
folks taking a tumble.
Thank you kindly.
I also noticed your screen
door is coming of its hinges.
Might want to get you a
new one before we paint.
Paint?
I think we can hold
off for another year.
Money'd be better spent on more
important things than a pretty house.
Let me just show you.
- Damn.
- Yep.
- Maybe we could put up a fence.
- No.
- No, they'd only climb it.
- Hm...
You know what? Leave it.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Yeah, let 'em have their fun.
We can turn the other cheek.
Mmm.
Visiting hours are ending, honey.
Yeah, uh...
I was just leavin'.
Aah!
No!
Thanks.
Uh, sorry, I had it all day.
I got some stew going inside
if you haven't had dinner.
Yeah, sure.
That sounds good.
Elise, I'm sure you don't
remember her, but...
she died a year ago this week.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
We were married longer than we weren't.
Alone just don't... feel right.
It gets scarier when it does.
I never spent a day away from her.
Barely got through
a conversation without her help.
Don't expect you to know
what it's like to lose that.
Uh, Allison was a...
Well, I started out just
wanting to look at her.
And then all I ever wanted
to do was listen to her.
But, um, you know, I...
I think she's the only
person who has ever...
truly known me.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Oh, she... She didn't die.
We just, uh...
It didn't work.
Elise...
she would want me to
tell you how sorry I am.
We knew what was happenin'.
Found you hiding under
our porch often enough.
We didn't realize how bad it was.
All of that racket, it sounded like...
discipline.
It haunted us both.
Uh...
It was a long time ago, you know?
Don't mean it's okay.
Kyle?
Any time you see a light on,
you come by.
I'm here...
for whatever you need.
Thanks for the ride. My
neighbor's a good guy.
I don't wanna borrow his
car two days in a row.
Sorry about the mess.
Just throw them in the back.
It's for the kids in the hospital.
Folks think being a
preacher is a Sunday job.
I spend more time in this little old
beater than I do in the pulpit.
Click it or ticket.
Oh.
That your son?
Yeah.
Matthew.
You know, I could always use
a hand delivering meals
if you got the time.
No. I'm... not good around people.
Really?
You holed up in that house
five months in town without
showing your face.
Is that because what
happened to your mother?
You think you caused it?
You weren't around Joshua.
It still happened to him.
What if you're punishing
yourself for no reason?
What if I'm right?
Then why are you coming with me?
To find answers.
Is that why you came back to Rome?
I heard you had a family.
Things were going good for you.
Maybe I just missed the house.
I read scripture to him.
It didn't do anything.
Holy water irritated him severely,
but had no long-term effect.
Will you pray with me?
You are very brave to return.
He doesn't like the light.
My mother didn't either.
That day with her, it was the same.
Why don't you like light, Joshua?
Think back on that day.
What else did you do?
I hit her.
She attacked me, and...
I'd had enough.
She'd done it many times before.
This time, I fought back.
It seemed to...
hurt her.
More than it should've.
Just help me get him into the light.
Don't touch me! Don't touch me!
Come on. Don't think about your mother!
Think about the boy! Come on!
- No!
- You're leaning on my last nerve, boy!
- No! No!
- You're unwelcome here!
You do not belong here!
In the name of God, I cast you out,
no matter how long it takes!
Stronger than Allison.
Kyle!
What do you want from me?
You gotta stop it!
Why won't you leave me alone?
The great merge... cannot be stopped.
Mama?
- You're free to go.
- What?
Chief, you can't be serious.
Nothing happened here, Officer Holter.
The mother's saying it's just
one big misunderstanding.
What?
Look, just because you're
friends with the preacher...
It doesn't matter what
we think happened.
You can drag him into town,
file all the paperwork you want.
The fact is, the mother
refuses to press charges.
There's nothing more for us to do here.
Let's wrap this up.
After everything Megan's done for you...
Come on.
Take you home.
Did you get the answers
you were looking for?
Some.
I've seen a lot.
Thought I'd seen the worst
suffering a man could imagine,
but that was...
I've never seen anything
like that before.
That what it was like with
your mother in the end?
Different with her.
It wasn't like that with my wife either.
I always thought it was
something I did to them.
Now I know it's something else.
It's still because of me.
Seems like they've been coming
after me my whole life.
Allison!
Amber!
Come on. Breathe, baby girl!
No.
Allison, no.
Come and get me.