(Ominous music)
(Woman crying)
(Whimpering)
It's... an... anagram.
__
(Man, muffled from hallway)
- God!
- Nena.
Nena.
(Tapping on door)
Nena, listen to...
Nena, please.
Open the door, Nena.
Nothing but lies!
Open the door!
You betrayed me!
(Sobs)
(Speaking French)
- You sold me!
- Open the door.
- (Woman sobbing, muttering)
- (Man shouting)
(Speaking French)
(Continues in French)
(Whimpers)
(Whispering)
My baby, my baby.
(Pounding)
Please, we have to talk.
(Shouting in French)
(Shouting, pounding)
Nena!
(Continues shouting)
No... Don't!
No!
(Thud)
Sync & corrections by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com
Wow.
So, how have you been feeling?
I'm good.
Anxious, but good.
- Has it been four months?
- Mm-hmm.
Yep.
We found out she was pregnant...
I think it was
the all-star game, right?
And now, we're through the playoffs.
- Yeah, that's four months.
- Knicks fan?
Nets.
Mm. That's too bad.
(Laughter)
But we're happy.
We've been planning this
for a long time.
A long time.
(Tapping keys)
- (Tapping)
- (Beep)
Everything okay?
Give me one second, okay?
Okay.
Hey.
Hey, it's fine.
(Inhales)
Okay.
I'm sure there's just something wrong
with the machine, that's all.
What if there's something
wrong with me?
- Hey, Rosemary, no.
- I can feel it.
Okay.
- Hi, there.
- Hi.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, we're just checking.
(Taps key)
(Suspenseful music)
I can't find a heartbeat.
I'm so sorry.
(Sobs)
I got you.
__
(Background chatter)
MAN:
Taxi!
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
You have arrived at your destination.
Excuse me, monsieur,
I'm looking for Rue de la Buch...
(Chuckles)
Thank you for confirming
the stereotype.
(Indistinct conversation)
Pardon.
- Bonjour.
Je suis perdu.
Je suis americaine, of course.
(Laughs)
Can you please help me
find this street?
(Speaking French)
No, no, no, no, no.
Pardon, pardon, pardon.
(Speaking French)
You cross the street...
- On your right.
- No, no, no.
(Laughs)
No, no, no, no, no.
(Both speaking in French)
Thank you.
- Oui, oui. (Speaks French)
- Okay.
(Laughs)
Thank you.
Julie.
Hey! (Squeals) Oh, my...
(Laughs)
Hi.
Hello. Oh.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay. It's okay.
I don't ever want to hear those words.
- All right?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- For what?
Guy would've never gotten his job
if it wasn't for you.
One year in Paris, Julie...
Oh, my God...
- At the Sorbonne too.
- (Speaking French)
Listen, all I did was put his C.V.
at the top of the pile.
He's pretty impressive all on his own.
Yes, he is.
(Laughs)
By the way, you won't be thanking me
once you see what they consider
faculty housing.
- No, we saw it. It's fine.
- Yeah?
Actually, it's perfect.
- It's exactly what we need.
- Okay.
- Yes.
- Merci.
- Do you want to walk?
- Yes!
Oh, good.
So how's Guy's novel going?
Every time I check,
he's one revision away from "the end."
There's a publisher interested,
so he's trying to finish.
- That's fantastic.
- Yeah.
And what about you?
- I'm coping.
- Yeah?
Yeah, Guy doesn't want me to work,
at least not immediately.
He's so sweet.
He says he wants to be the one
to wear the pants
in the family for a while.
Well, you've supported him
all these years as a dancer.
- That's not easy.
- Yeah.
And he should return the favor
and make the big bucks for a change.
(Laughs)
Yes.
But I encourage him because
I believe in his writing.
I'm just so happy that you're here.
(Laughs)
I want to take care of you.
Oh, you know what we should do?
What?
Take cooking classes?
- Yes.
- Yes?
Oh, my God,
I've been dreaming to do that
ever since we found out
we were coming to Paris.
- Yes! Yes!
- It's done.
- I'm making all the arrangements.
- Oh, God.
We perfect a couple of gourmet dishes,
then make it for Guy.
And get him off his obsession
with macaroni and cheese.
- Hmm.
- Hmm?
I already did that.
He's been banned from them.
- Seriously?
- Mm-hmm.
How did you do that?
- Pastrami sandwiches.
- (Laughs)
Yeah, we really need
these cooking classes.
Absolutely.
Can I?
Sure.
(Baby babbles)
- He's perfect.
- Thank you.
(Gasps)
Hey!
Stop him! Somebody stop him!
(Man shouting in foreign language)
(Shouts in French)
He has my purse!
He has my bag!
- (Clang)
- (Men shouting)
He took my bag!
(Tires screech)
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
(Whimpers)
Oh...
Hey!
- Thank God he's okay.
- (Speaks French)
You can't kill a cockroach.
Thank you, sir. I got it.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- (Man murmuring in French)
Wait a minute.
This isn't my wal...
(Panting)
Oh, my God.
Let's see.
(Panting)
"Margaux Castevet."
This is your lucky day.
(Somber music)
(Buzzer rings)
__
Madame.
(Speaking French)
Parlez-vous anglais?
- Oui. Yes.
- Great.
I have this wallet, and it belongs
to one of your tenants
by the name of Margaux Castevet.
Well, thank you.
I will make sure
it is returned to her.
I'd rather give this to her myself.
Looking for a reward.
No.
No, I'm not.
Can you please call her?
- Margaux Castevet.
- My ears are burning.
Are you looking for me, darling?
Yes.
Yes. I have your wallet.
Oh, my God.
I just spent the last hour
with the police.
A complete waste of time.
They had no hopes of returning it.
You're an absolute angel.
- No.
- American?
I love Americans.
You're so honest and open.
Everything can be seen on the face.
How did you find this?
I think we were robbed
by the same thief, actually.
Look.
I hope you beat him to a pulp.
You must take this for your efforts.
No, no. I'm so sorry.
I just... I'm happy.
I'm happy that it's returned
to its rightful owner, that's all.
What's your name?
Rosemary. Rosemary Woodhouse.
- Rosemary?
- Yes.
An old-fashioned name.
I like it. Very feminine.
Thank you.
Where are you staying in Paris?
My husband... he's teaching
at the Sorbonne.
And we're staying
at the faculty housing.
Oh, my husband is on
the Sorbonne honorary board.
You must come join us
at our party here tonight.
I won't take no for an answer.
You will come with your husband.
I insist.
Okay.
Thank you.
(Laughs)
- See you tonight.
- Yes. Au revoir.
Au revoir.
Nice to meet you.
- (Laughs)
- What?
The drawers are full,
all the drawers are full.
And I still haven't unpacked
the second bag.
What about this?
Okay, good news.
I think I found the kitchen.
- (Laughs)
- Oh, man.
Well, at least it happens to be
right next to the bedroom.
I guess that makes breakfast
in bed a cinch.
And I thought
New York apartments were small.
Hey, look at it this way.
At least it's only for an entire year.
We'll take shifts then.
Mondays, Wednesdays,
and Fridays, I get the room.
Tuesdays, Thursdays,
and Saturdays, you get it.
And what about Sundays?
We stay in bed naked
all day together.
Ooh, can we make it Sunday
every day?
(Laughter)
Oh, the lady whose wallet
I returned,
she invited us to come
to her party tonight.
Party? Wait.
I still cannot believe that you went
chasing after a purse snatcher.
That's crazy. You're crazy.
My passport was in the bag.
What did you expect?
Well, what do you think?
Can we go to the party tonight?
Wouldn't you rather just stay here
in our new palace and eat
a delicious bowl of
soupe poulet et nouilles?
Well, if you put it that way,
- how could I refuse?
- Oh, you like that?
You want to hear about
what I want to do with you later?
Yes.
(Speaking French)
What did you just say?
- Ooh.
- It sounded so sexy.
- You like it, yeah?
- Yeah.
Mm.
I said let's unpack the bags...
Mm-hmm.
And clean... the room.
That's it?
Yeah, that's it. What?
- Funny man.
- Hey, come back.
All right.
I should put in a couple
of hours on the book.
It's gotta be every day or nothing.
(Knock on door)
You expecting anybody?
Mr. and Mrs. Woodhouse?
Yes?
I'm here to take you to the party.
(Low chatter, laughter)
Um...
(Clank)
Voila.
(Laughter)
This door?
(Clears throat)
(Doorbell rings)
(Indistinct chatter)
(Classical music in background)
- What?
- MAN: You're welcome.
- (Laughs)
- What?
Are you kidding?
Look at these people.
We should put on aprons
and start serving them.
(Speaking French)
The waiters are better
dressed than we are.
Look at his suit.
(Laughter)
Oh, Rosemary.
Margaux, hi.
- And you must be the husband.
- Guy.
- Yes.
- Hello.
Mwah.
- What a gentleman.
- Roman, come.
I want you to say hello
to my savior.
- Roman, this is...
- The fabulous Rosemary.
Of course it is.
I've heard your name all day.
- Nice to meet... Oh.
- How fabulous
to meet a real superhero
in the flesh.
Hmm.
(Chuckles)
And this is the man set to shake up
our English Department,
Guy Woodhouse.
- Wait, how did you...
- Roman.
When Margaux told me
you might come, I was thrilled.
I read your brilliant submission paper
- on Fitzgerald.
- Seriously?
- Here we go.
- Now, I make no apologies
for being star-struck.
Excuse us, I'm afraid
I need to monopolize
your husband the whole evening.
I'm gonna show the French
what a real intellectual looks like.
- Yes. Okay.
- Um... Are you...
- Come on.
- Bye.
Over here is someone you must meet.
- I'm sorry, my husband...
- No, your home is beautiful.
- Margaux.
- Yes.
- Thank you for inviting us.
- I'll be right back.
Okay.
Yes?
- A petit-four?
- No thank you.
(Indistinct chatter)
(Classical music)
- (Murmurs greeting)
- Oh! Bonsoir!
Rosemary, there are no wallflowers
allowed at my parties.
You'll have to mingle.
Mm.
Everybody's just so fascinating.
I don't speak a word of French.
I feel like I...
Da, da, da, da. Come.
S'il vous plait.
In honor of my guest,
Rosemary Woodhouse,
this night of festivities
will now be conducted
in English only.
- No, no, Margaux...
- Yes.
Of course.
Americans are known
to speak just one language.
- (Laughter)
- And French are known to be
arrogant pricks.
I have been called much worse,
Madame Castevet.
- You've met wife, Sylvie.
- No.
- Enchante.
And thank you for having us.
Such a beautiful home.
The secret to a lively party
is new and interesting guests.
It's you two I have
to thank for coming.
Rosemary, this is the man to know
if you're up to any mischief.
Commissioner Fontaine is
the head of police in Paris.
Oh. Nice to meet you, sir.
- Nice to meet you.
- Enchante.
- Rosemary.
Madame Castevet told me
your story with the thief.
You were brave, but very foolish.
I wish I had a hundred more
like you on the force.
(Laughs)
Well, I promise I will
never do it again
if you can promise
that I won't ever, ever need to.
(Both laugh)
(Speaking French)
She's exceptional.
Shall we go?
(Both speaking French)
Anything you need, you call me.
Thank you, sir.
Madame Veaulieu is the chief designer
- of the House of Beauchamps.
- Hello, Rosemary.
- You look stunning.
- Thank you. You do too.
Xavier Exharos.
Exharos Shipping.
- Nice to meet you.
- Rosemary.
- Oh, Rosemary, come.
Monsieur Wees is a master
of rare manuscripts.
He's a guiding force
in the preservation
of the dead sea scrolls.
- Don't exaggerate.
- I'm not.
It's very nice to meet you, sir.
- Oh.
- (Laughs)
Behave!
Yoshiro!
Akia Technologies.
Rosemary.
(Laughs)
Can you tell me where
the ladies' room is, please?
Yes, down the hall and to the left
- next to the Goya.
- Thank you.
(Overlapping conversations)
When they uncovered the mouth,
they restored the whole piece.
Turns out, he had a rather
self-satisfied grin...
What are you doing?
Oh.
Hey. You okay?
You're red. What's wrong?
No.
Can we go home? Now?
Yeah, of course.
Can we please go home?
(Classical music in background)
(Laughter)
Roman.
Thank you so much
for a lovely evening.
- You're not going yet.
- Yes.
This is Paris.
- (Laughter)
- We're just getting started.
I know.
We really have to get going.
Come say good-bye to Margaux.
Okay.
Just two minutes. Come on.
(Indistinct chatter)
(Chatter ceases)
Making a new friend,
as we all know,
is one of the sweetest things in life.
And it happens to me
very rarely indeed.
So I hope that
you, Rosemary, and Guy,
will allow us to consider you
as new additions
to our little clan of misfits.
(Laughter)
And as a small token
of our friendship,
we'd like to present you
with a small gift.
Margaux.
Oh.
They say one life is not enough
to fully enjoy the pleasures
of this world.
We'd like to offer you nine more.
- (Cat meows)
- (Rosemary gasps)
(Cheers and applause)
What kind of people get
complete strangers
an animal for a gift?
That's not a gift. It's an obligation.
I think she's beautiful.
What should we name her?
Name? No, no, no.
No name.
We're not keeping this cat, Ro.
- Oh, Guy.
- No.
Look at her face.
Look, there's hardly enough room
in here for the two of us as it is.
And I don't think the university
is gonna allow us to have cats anyway.
Come here. Come here.
(Cat meows)
What did you think of them?
Them?
- Yes.
- What did I think of them?
Uh... I don't know.
I don't want to speak ill
of my fellow clansmen, with a "C."
- (Laughs)
- But...
Roman... I think he's maybe
one of the most
arrogant, obnoxious people
I've ever met in my entire life.
And that's just the stuff
I liked about him.
Definitely doesn't lack in confidence.
Baby, can you help me?
Yeah. Well...
He's got enough ego
for the both of us
and the cat.
Mm, mm.
He would make
a good character though.
He would, right?
- You should put him in your book.
- Yeah.
But then, I would have
to see him again, so no.
- I like Margaux.
- Hey...
What got you so hot
and bothered in there tonight?
You want to talk about it
or do you want to do something
about it?
Ooh. Um...
That's a good question.
I think...
I think I'd talk about it.
What do you think?
(Soft piano music)
- (Cat purrs)
- Oh.
We have a friend.
(Gasps)
Oh. Honey...
You're not gonna give up, are you?
She was meant for us.
(Chuckles)
You really love her.
I do. I do.
Okay.
(Cat meows)
(Coughs)
(Cat meowing)
Guy? Guy, wake up.
There's smoke.
My God. Okay. Wait here.
(Ominous music)
- Be careful.
- I got it.
(Electricity crackles)
Aah!
- Aah! Guy!
- Aah! Aah!
Shh...
(Cat meows)
(Speaking French)
Huh? I don't speak French.
No animals allowed in the hospital.
- No, I know.
- If you want to wait,
- the animal has to go outside.
- No, please.
Listen, my husband,
he's in the burn unit, okay?
And it's very cold outside.
I can't put this cat...
Then I'm going to ask
both of you to leave.
- No, please.
- Excusez-moi.
(Both speaking French)
We came as soon as we heard.
- Is he hurt badly?
- I don't know.
They haven't told me anything.
What are you doing here?
How did you find out that I was here?
Commissioner Fontaine
said the police
responded to an accident
at your residence.
We wanted to make sure
you were okay.
I'm fine.
(Sniffles)
It's Guy.
There must have been a short circuit
with our hot plate,
and everything caught on fire.
And Guy was burned.
- Oh, don't worry.
- (Crying)
We're here now.
I've already started a prayer for him.
I don't like bullies.
She's gone to get us some coffee.
- And the cat stays.
- It's okay, baby.
Thank you.
Did you hear that, baby?
No Name, she saved us.
She was the one that woke us up.
- You named her "No Name"?
- Guy did.
That's quite the imagination
for a writer.
- (Chuckles)
- Mrs. Woodhouse.
Yes, doctor. Thank you so much.
How is he?
From the description of the accident,
I expected much greater trauma.
Your husband suffered
second degree burns,
but he seems to have escaped
any permanent damage.
He should be released within the hour.
Okay. Merci.
- Oh...(Murmuring)
- (Sniffles)
It's okay. It's okay.
- Hey.
- Oh.
He's gonna be fine.
They're gonna release him
in an hour.
Oh, thank God.
These are...
these are our new friends.
- Margaux and Roman.
- Hi.
- This is Julie.
- How do you do, Julie?
Hi.
So, where are you going
to live now?
You obviously can't go back
to that place.
I haven't had a second
to think about that.
You can stay with me.
I've got a sofa and an air bed.
You'll be fine.
We have an empty apartment
at La Chimere.
- (Cat meows)
- No.
I don't think you realize how much
an English professor makes in a month.
But we couldn't even afford
your building
- for a weekend.
- We own it.
We charge whatever we want.
It's just sitting there empty
waiting to be burgled.
Really, you'd be doing us a favor.
You can pay the same rent
you pay now,
and we'd be in profit.
It's a win-win.
- That's insane.
- (Cat meows)
- Julie...
- (Laughs)
What she means is
it's very generous of you.
- (Cat meows)
- Yeah. That's what I meant.
(Cheerful music)
(Music in French)
Ahh!
(Laughs)
Closets.
- Guy!
- Yeah?
You're not gonna believe this.
- What?
- This is unexpected.
Are you...
Ro, look at this.
It's a perfect fit.
(Laughs)
(Gasps)
Look, there's more.
This... this all can't be for us.
Well, it's either that
or the last tenants
were exactly the same size.
- (Laughs)
- Guy.
These clothes are brand-new.
They all the tags on them.
Ooh.
(Clicks tongue)
That's creepy.
Well, yeah.
But, I mean, you could try it on
just once for kicks.
- I'm kidding, sort of.
- No.
- Not at all.
- Seriously.
I know.
I know that this was done
with the best of intentions,
but it's too much.
Ro, look.
It's temporary, okay?
I promise. We won't have
to take anything from them.
From now on, we eat our food,
we wear our own clothes,
and then if I sell my book...
When you sell your book.
We get our own place.
Yes.
Mwah. Okay.
- (Rosemary laughs)
- All right.
It's slick.
Don't get lost in here.
Look who's excited to see you.
- (Cat meows)
- It's great
seeing how many times
I can write the same paragraph.
- Hmm, let me see.
- No.
It's nothing.
Baby, you're putting too much
pressure on yourself.
Or not enough.
This starving artist thing
is getting old, Ro.
It's about time I started
taking care of our family.
You do take care of us.
- Us.
- Yeah.
(Cat meows)
(Distant baby crying)
Aah!
(Scream echoes)
(Ominous music)
- Hey.
- Sorry I'm late.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- Good.
- Is this where you work?
I know. Amazing.
- I'm so lucky.
- Julie, it's beautiful.
So how's it going at La Chimere?
Oh...
I hear Mick Jagger has an apartment.
- (Laughs)
- Or is it David Bowie?
I haven't seen either one of them.
Though I wouldn't mind to bump
into them in the elevator.
Did Guy tell you
I put him up for a new job?
- No.
- Yeah, the post just opened up.
What's the position?
Oh, head of the
English Literature Department.
Yeah, it'd be a lot more money,
plus the prestige.
Well, Guy doesn't care
about the money.
He just wants to finish the book.
He's had a really hard time.
I think ever since the miscarriage,
he's had writer's block.
He just needs a new muse.
Oh, don't worry, honey.
Your husband never had
a wandering eye.
Not after he met you.
You're sweet.
Ooh. That's Guy's main competition.
Professor Hildegard Bishop.
Mm. Sounds so severe.
Oh, yeah. She's an uptight prig.
Very well published though.
(Cell phone chimes)
Sorry.
Uh...
Where do you want to eat?
Cafeteria or my office?
Oh!
Back so soon?
Yes, I didn't have much
on my list today.
(Gasps)
(Both scream)
Don't be afraid, Rosemary!
This is Emile,
the handyman for the building.
- What?
- Forgive his lack of eloquence.
He was born without a tongue.
It's my fault.
I haven't called for
a handyman, Margaux.
I know.
We had an issue with our fireplace.
And I thought we should check yours
while he was engaged.
(Speaking French)
- (Groans) No, no.
- Oh, God.
C'est bizarre.
(Speaking French)
I know he's scary. Sorry.
Margaux, please.
You have to notify me before
you let anybody into my apartment.
I... This can be such a fright.
I'm sorry.
I thought my husband told
your husband yesterday.
Maybe Guy forgot to tell me.
I'm sorry.
So now we're both sorry.
Oh, God.
What's wrong?
I just have a really bad
headache after the scare.
Come.
Come with me.
Lie on the bed
with your head on that side,
- and your feet up there.
- Like this?
Mm-hmm.
Sorry.
I learned this in Tibet.
For all our hubris,
so much ignorance remains
in western healing.
Wait.
Don't move. Don't move, don't move.
Stay there.
(Eerie music)
Close your eyes.
Take a deep breath.
Hold it in your chest.
Now exhale.
Slowly.
It's gone.
Mm-hmm.
How did you...
How can I ever repay you?
Thank you.
You can wear one of
the dresses in your closet.
I spent a lot of time picking them.
Now you relax.
I'll let myself out.
There's no fireplace in this room.
Guy!
Can I offer you a ride?
Yeah, I speak like a writer.
I think like a writer,
but I just can't actually write
my own words.
Ah.
Well, maybe this
teaching job's distracting you.
Maybe if I had
a better job or more money,
then I wouldn't have
to worry about it so much.
I'm never going to be able to provide
my wife with the life
that she deserves.
Maybe we can help you.
(Taps glass)
Pierre.
The club, please.
- (Object shatters)
- Damn it.
What was he doing in here?
Come on. Come on. Uhh!
What were you hiding?
Damn it!
(Eerie music)
You want to know the secret?
- To what?
- To success.
- Yeah.
- In order to be a success,
everyone needs to find
two special people.
My first was Margaux.
She made me whole.
Yeah. That's what Rosemary does.
I know.
The other was my benefactor,
who made me who I am.
Your benefactor? Who's that?
Doesn't matter who mine was.
Yours will be a different person.
You have to find them.
You have to ask them.
They'll guide you and help you realize
all your dreams.
'Cause they are possible, Guy.
All of them.
And you deserve it, don't you?
I really do.
You really do.
(Laughter, clink glasses)
(Door closes)
(Rosemary grunts)
Come on.
(Grunts)
- Uh... Uhh!
- Ro?
(Rosemary panting)
- Are you okay?
- Can you help me with this?
- Help me move this.
- What is going on?
Look.
There's a molding.
Behind the armoire,
there's a hidden door.
- Babe, come on.
- Just help me.
(Groans)
Okay, just stop. Careful, all right?
Hey. Come here.
Okay, that's it, that's it,
that's it, that's good.
I told you.
It's just a closet
that they were hiding?
Ro?
Hey, Ro.
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
What were you talking
about with Roman yesterday?
What? When?
I saw you at the school.
I was there visiting Julie,
and I saw you and Roman.
What were you guys talking about?
Rosemary, you gotta stop.
You're acting paranoid, okay?
- Come on.
- You're right.
Come on. Help me clean this up.
What did you do?
Standing here.
Here.
It's the exact spot
when they took this picture.
Rosemary. You're obsessed.
What are you wearing?
- Guy...
- Okay, yes.
I know what I said, but I just...
I want to look good
for this interview.
That's all.
Is that what you really want?
To be the head
of the English Department?
It would almost double my salary, Ro.
I know.
I just... I thought you wanted
to finish your novel.
Those who can't do teach, right?
Besides, I don't have
a publisher anymore, so...
What are you talking about?
They called yesterday.
They cancelled my contract.
What?
What happened?
- What did they say?
- I don't know.
I don't know what's going on with me.
It's like my brain is stuck
in molasses.
It was never easy to write,
but it was always possible, you know?
No.
Every writer gets writer's block
at some point in their career.
It's temporary.
Yeah, well, the problem is
that I was counting on
selling that book
for you and me,
so now this interview
has suddenly become a white-knuckle,
balls-in-a-vice type situation.
Oh, and Ro,
I wouldn't mention that picture
to anybody.
- Why?
- (Laughs)
You just... you went
a little nuts last night.
That's all.
By the way, I like the new you.
I thought you liked the old me.
Well, I did. But this is better.
More confident. More manly.
Yeah. Hey, listen.
Do you think I really have a chance?
You'd be perfect for the job.
You're a much better teacher.
She's tedious.
Good luck.
Thanks.
(Clattering)
Sorry.
- (Cat meows)
- Hey.
Come here.
Mm. Baby.
How are you, hmm?
(Kisses)
(Muffled chanting)
(Cat meows)
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh, shh.
(Cat meows)
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
(Chanting continues)
(Laughter)
Credentials are impeccable.
Of course, your publications
are impressive.
But I wonder how they will
apply to the class?
After all,
we must engage the students,
not entertain them.
Grab their attention
and keep it, so to say.
I agree with everything you say.
Even though every student is unique,
it is my responsibility
that each student reaches
their full potential.
The position is head of the depart...
(Voice distorts)
I think you'll find the...
(voice repeating, echoing)
salary is appropriate
for the job's responsibilities.
(Static, buzzing)
(Buzzing echoes)
God!
(Buzzing continues loudly)
(Groans)
(Thud)
- (Panting)
- (Woman screams)
(Commotion, chatter)
Oh, my God.
Compress. Compress tight, okay?
- Call the police now!
- Call the police!
So, Dr. Carraro is going to be okay.
I guess the scissors didn't
reach any vital organs.
That's good news.
Do you have any idea what happened?
No.
I never thought
Professor Bishop was capable
of anything like that.
I mean, she wasn't so much fun,
but to have a psychotic break?
I guess you never really
know what's hidden
inside somebody's heart.
Listen, I probably
shouldn't be saying this,
but this is good for you.
- Julie, don't.
- I mean it.
It's sick, but now you're
the best candidate for the job.
I can't think about what I stand to gain
from something like this.
- It's...
- Guy, stop it.
It's not your fault.
You had nothing to do with it.
She was bipolar,
or on drugs or whatever.
(Crowd murmurs)
Guy, you okay?
I don't understand.
Do you know them?
Are they missing?
No, I don't know anything about them.
But you have suspicions
they were met with foul play.
Yes.
That's in our apartment.
You see, this is our bedroom.
That's where they took the picture.
It's morning.
And they do look very happy,
but every time I look at the picture
and I see her eyes, I just get
a bad feeling, you know?
You have an entire life
imagined for them
from this single snapshot.
Yes.
(Chuckles)
It's a little crazy, right?
I'm really sorry.
Did you talk to Madame Castevet?
She might know the whereabouts
of this mysterious couple.
She didn't want to talk about it.
Do you feel she was hiding something?
You don't want to disparage
anyone without evidence.
You're a kind and loyal friend.
Let's check if there might be
any police activity
reported at your address.
Just a moment.
(Speaking French)
Hmm.
- I'm sorry.
- Nothing?
The woman in the picture is dead.
Her name was Nena Pascal.
Egyptian born, no family in France.
Preliminary report indicates
she jumped from the balcony
of her bedroom to her death.
My bedroom?
Her husband, Jacques,
confirmed her suicide.
Ah.
It appears that he missed
an appointment for questioning.
He's presently missing.
Thank you for bringing this
to my attention.
You should always listen
to your feelings, Rosemary.
Guy?
__
"Put on the dress."
Guy?
- Surprise!
- (Shrieks)
(Laughter)
The belle of the ball has arrived.
The party can get started.
What a surprise.
(Laughs)
Your lovely husband is the new head
of the English Literature Department
- at the Sorbonne.
- (Crowd oohs and ahhs)
And I made the mistake
of telling Roman,
so here we all are.
This was their idea.
Life is to be celebrated, particularly
when good things happen to good people.
So, raise your glasses,
ladies and gentlemen,
to the meteoric rise
of Professor Guy Woodhouse.
ALL:
Cheers.
- Thank you.
- Cheers, baby.
(Speaking French)
Congratulations.
I hope this is everything
you wanted, baby.
Not exactly.
Come here.
(Background chatter)
When did...
Come here.
You don't know anyone at all,
do you, darling?
- No.
- Come.
(Chatter, dinner music)
What? What is it?
(Exhales)
I think we should try again.
Try what?
I want to make a baby.
I know. I know.
- I know it's scary.
- Guy...
- I know.
- It may be too soon.
Don't you feel how different
everything is here though?
I do feel different.
They feel right.
Things are happening
the way they were supposed to.
What if it's too soon?
Baby, I think we need to.
It's time.
Right?
Yeah?
(Laughs)
Okay.
What's going on?
Let me guess.
- You're pregnant.
- No.
I swear to God,
I didn't say anything to her.
It's okay.
But I'm... We're gonna try.
- (Squeals)
- (Laughs)
- No, no.
- No, no, no, no, no.
Margaux, please. No more gifts.
I can't... can't bear it.
It's not a frivolous thing,
like a dress.
- This is serious.
- What is it?
It's a family heirloom
filled with tannis root
from my greenhouse.
It's beautiful.
It's pungent.
It's actually quite powerful.
It's there to protect you
and the baby soon to be inside you.
Promise me you'll wear it.
I promise.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, Margaux.
Aah!
(Thud)
(Gasping)
What are you doing?
Writing my book.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
It's coming, Rosemary.
The words, all of it. It's coming.
It's like a spigot has opened up.
(Laughs)
So you're not just falling.
He's pushing you off the building.
Yes. And it's very disturbing.
You know, maybe you should rethink
this whole getting pregnant thing.
Hmm?
No.
What are you talking about?
I'm ready.
I've started charting my cycle.
I'm ovulating next week.
Yeah, but think about your dream.
I mean, it's so obvious.
You falling means you're anxious,
you're afraid of losing control.
And Guy pushing you
means exactly that.
I mean, what did he pressure
you into recently
at a party in front
of your new friends?
No.
I think I know what it's about.
A couple? I don't get it.
Is Guy pushing you into swinging?
Very funny.
This is Jacques and Nena.
They were the couple that lived
in our apartment
before we did.
She died three months ago.
In the apartment.
She either jumped
or she was pushed off
the balcony of our bedroom.
That's creepy.
Maybe my dream was a sign,
a message.
You think Guy is trying to kill you.
Of course not.
Well, yeah. Of course not.
I just feel like
whatever that dream meant,
she had the answer,
and I'll never know because she's dead.
Oh, well, maybe you can go
and talk to her friends.
I don't know anything about her.
How would I know to find her friends?
Okay, look. You see this?
That's a symbol for Coptic Christians.
- Coptic?
- Yeah.
There's only one Coptic church
in Paris.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
(Bells tolling)
(Solemn music and singing)
(Man whispering)
Pardon.
(Electronic voice speaks in French)
Do you know her?
(Speaking French)
Follow me, please.
- Are you a friend of Nena's?
- No.
But I want to know more about her.
She died.
Three months ago.
Father, I'm trying to find out why.
I know why.
Nena was consorting with Satanists.
She lived in an unholy place.
La Chimere.
Wait, that's where I live.
What do you know about its past?
I looked up its history online,
and it said that it was built
in the 1860s
and that it was exclusive
for the rich and famous.
Did the computer tell you
about the Trench sisters?
They lived there in 1933.
No. Were they famous?
Infamous.
They were cannibals.
(Overlapping chatter)
They slaughtered countless men
and served them to their friends
before they were caught
and hanged for their crimes.
It's a horrible story.
It's not the only one.
Terrible things
have happened ever since
La Chimere rose from the ground.
- The building is cursed.
- Father...
Steven Marcato lived there until 1986.
Who's Steven Marcato?
He was a Satanist,
maybe Satan himself.
- What is this?
- Fortune Magazine.
How do you think he's so successful?
The Devil hides behind his billions.
Why do you believe
he's this great evil?
I saw him in an alley
behind La Chimere.
He sacrificed a whore.
(Woman murmuring)
(Groans)
(Groaning)
Marcato killed her and ate her heart.
It says here he's the founder
of the Delphi Group
and he gives millions to charity.
The Devil who has many faces.
You never know what shape
it is going to take.
Steven Marcato one day,
someone else the next.
I've wasted too much of your time.
Thank you so much for...
You don't believe me!
Nena didn't believe me either,
and look what happened to her.
Take my advice.
Leave everything behind,
all your worldly possessions,
everyone you know, leave here!
Leave here and disappear
before they find you!
Well?
It's the best work you've ever done.
It's wonderful.
- Really? Really?
- No.
No, these are not tears in my eyes.
I'm not moved by the story,
or your brilliant, magical words.
It was beautiful.
Thank God.
(Laughs)
Roman really loved it too.
He said he's gonna take it
to his publisher.
You gave it to Roman?
Yeah. I mean, I had to.
If it weren't for him,
I wouldn't have written it, right?
He's practically my muse.
I've been replaced by a man.
Hey. I still think about you
in my private time.
Baby, I'm proud of you.
You finished this.
You did it all by yourself.
I'm gonna go call him.
(Whispering, indistinct voices)
(Whispering voices chanting)
Wait.
Wait!
Wait, stop!
Paul.
Did you see a man come out
of the elevator?
- No. No.
- Just now?
Really, there wasn't a man?
No. Anything wrong?
No.
(Exhales)
Okay, so you, like,
you don't write poetry?
No, I did when I was your age.
But, you know...
(Laughs, murmurs)
That was a great paper by the way.
- Yeah, great work.
- Thank you.
Keep it up.
Well, ladies, make sure to do
- the reading for tomorrow.
- We will.
- Bye.
It feels good when everything
goes your way, huh?
Yeah, sure.
But, you know, pretty soon,
it will feel quite natural to you,
to always be on top.
It's addictive.
And you'll find yourself doing
anything to stay there.
Do you make a habit out of this,
just walking next to strangers,
talking total nonsense?
It's an art.
The seduction, you know.
(Laughs)
All right, I'm sorry, man.
I don't have any money.
But nothing comes without a price.
You know that.
All right, I'm not having
this conversation
with a total stranger.
Who are you?
I am you.
(Bells tolling)
Wait.
Hey!
Professor.
Everything all right?
Who was that?
Oh, um,
a student.
Well, I have news.
They, uh, they read the book.
And, uh...
They loved it.
They'd like to meet today
if that's okay with you.
(Both laugh)
Come on.
(Doorbell rings)
- Commissioner?
- Hi.
What a surprise. Come in, come in.
Is there anything wrong?
I have something to ask you.
What did you do yesterday?
I had a class at La Toque Blanche,
and then after that,
I went to church.
Why?
Because I needed spiritual guidance.
Father Tekem was found hanged
last night.
Now why did you go see him?
I wanted to ask him about Nena.
What did he say to you?
He said a lot of crazy things.
He said that cannibals
lived in this building
as well as Devil worshippers
and that he saw
Steve Marcato commit murder.
- Oh?
- Steve Marcato...
he's a... he's a billionaire.
He said he saw him eat
the heart of a prostitute.
I thought he was
out of his mind, so I left.
Steven Marcato?
Look what comes up.
Many strange images.
Do you think it's a coincidence,
or do you think his death
has something to do with Nena?
I don't know.
But this is no purse snatcher,
Rosemary.
You need to let this go
and let the police do their jobs.
Be careful where you place
your trust.
I've never seen
what you're doing to that chicken
in any of my cooking classes.
Because I'm brewing medicine.
(Sawing sounds)
I see you're not wearing the amulet.
I didn't feel like wearing it today.
What is this medicine?
Fertility soup.
You drink it after it simmers
for 12 hours in the clay pot.
Does it taste good?
No. Terrible.
But it will make you ready
to have a baby.
I learned this from the Chinese.
I have a friend, Shui Fa,
she had to flee China
after the Communist Revolution.
She was desperate to have a child
with a man she was forced
to leave behind,
and only had three days
to conceive it.
This is the recipe she used
to make her fertile.
A recipe she still uses today.
Well, not for herself I'm assuming.
- She must be, what, in her 80s?
- Of course.
But my friends' secrets
are at your disposal.
What about your secrets, Margaux?
Why didn't you tell me about Nena?
How do you talk about
the most painful heartbreak
of your life?
I loved Nena like the daughter
I never had.
I begged her to leave her husband.
He was a dark force...
who had a stranglehold on her soul.
I tried so many ways
to help her out of the trap
I knew she was in.
I saw her the day before she died.
I still remember her smile.
She told me she was so happy.
She was walking on air.
I have no more secrets.
No. I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry
I doubted you and Roman.
It's just when I found out
about Nena,
I thought that you...
You were too good to be true.
Rosemary, our friendship is
not about replacing Nena.
I care about you.
I just want you
to be happy and healthy.
I promise I will try some
of your stinky soup.
No.
You will finish every last drop.
This is horrible.
You want some?
No?
You're such a coward.
Oh, my God.
I hope you had dinner
'cause all I have is
Margaux's fertility soup.
Yeah, I know. I'm not hungry.
- You okay?
- (Meow)
Yeah.
I just don't know
if I just made a huge mistake.
What do you mean?
Guy?
I sold my book.
(Gasps)
(Laughter)
That's amazing!
Here, wait. I gotta show you this.
You ready? Look.
Look, look, look, look, look,
look, look, look, look, look.
(Gasps)
Guy...
I don't think I've ever seen
so many zeros
in one check before.
Right? And that's just the advance.
Mwah. Go on.
Go get changed.
Put on some fancy clothes
because we are going out.
What is that taste?
That soup is bad.
I know. Okay.
- I'm gonna go brush my teeth.
- Go.
The things I won't do for you
and this baby.
- (Shrieks)
- (Laughs)
(Somber music)
What did you do about the shoes?
I had to take them off.
Yeah, well...
- At the opera?
- Yes.
(Laughs)
Look at my husband.
Does he look happy to you?
You know, sometimes success
is hard to accept.
Wait until he has a "problem" in bed.
Then you'll really have to be
a cheerleader.
(Chuckles)
Merci.
(Speaking French)
- Thank you.
- Merci.
Roman, let's walk.
I need to clear my head
from the wine.
- (Roman, indistinct)
- Thanks.
(Speaking French)
I'm a little embarrassed to admit
I was jealous of you.
Of me?
You got to do in two weeks
what I couldn't do in two years.
You got Guy to finish his book.
He told me you were his muse.
I wish I had that kind of power.
You know, inspiration's a mystery.
You know what inspired Napoleon
to propose to Josephine?
That restaurant we were just
sitting in, the very booth.
For Guy, who knows?
Maybe it was the new apartment,
maybe it's the smell of your
sweet breath on his pillow.
No, it was you.
So thank you.
But I'm still jealous.
(Laughs)
Are you cold? I can call the driver.
- No, I'm fine.
- Are you sure?
Yeah.
Margaux!
Yes?
Let's get in the car.
No, don't be ridiculous.
We're three blocks away.
You okay?
Yeah.
(Speaking French)
I want what you promised.
Look.
Call me tomorrow,
and we'll sort everything out.
Everything will be fine.
No more lies.
(Gunshot)
(Screams)
Roman!
- Hey!
- (Gunshot)
- (Screams)
- (Groans)
Call for help!
Please...
Somebody help us!
Call for help!
- Somebody help us!
- Your phone!
- Give me your phone!
- Somebody help us!
Somebody!
(All speaking French)
Roman is strong.
And it's gonna take more
than a bullet to kill him.
- Bonsoir.
- Monsieur.
I hope you're here to give me
some good news.
Please tell me the man
who shot my husband
suffered before he died.
Jacques Pascal is not dead,
Madame Castevet.
They are prepping him
for surgery now.
I'll talk to him the moment
he regains consciousness.
I would be curious to know
why he felt the need
to shoot my husband.
Jacques Pascal and his wife
lived in the same apartment
where Mr. and Mrs. Woodhouse
are living now.
(Speaking French)
Oui.
His wife died three months ago.
The police told me it was suicide.
With what happened tonight,
I think we may have to consider
another theory.
Can I ask you a few questions?
Can you tell me exactly
what Jacques Pascal said
before he fired his weapon?
Um, I don't know what he said
because he was speaking in French.
And we were standing too far away.
But then he said in English
"I want what is mine."
No. "I want what was promised."
And then he said, "No more lies."
And then he shot Roman.
What promise could
your husband have broken?
C'est impossible.
Roman would never break his promises.
Anything else you can remember?
Maybe you might have seen him
before tonight, or...
I've never seen that man in person.
No?
No. Never.
All right, if you think of anything,
let me know.
I wish your husband
a speedy recovery.
Merci, monsieur.
- Good night.
- Bonsoir.
I want to start a prayer.
Do you want us to come with you?
No, I must do this myself.
Are you sure you want to be alone?
If you have faith,
you are never alone.
(Ominous music)
(Whispering)
(Monitor beeping)
No, no, no.
It cannot be. He's waking up.
(All speaking French)
(Jacques coughing, gasping)
- Hold him, hold him!
- (Screams)
(All shouting in French)
- (Speaking French)
- I can't!
- (Shouting in French)
(Rapid beeping)
(Flatline tone)
Mm.
I can only imagine how gruesome
I must look, my darling,
because you look terrible.
(Laughs)
I was worried, mon amour,
but now I know
you're going to be fine.
Mm-hmm.
Ah.
How you feeling, Roman?
Well, I feel pretty...
pretty good.
(Laughs)
(Groans)
Oh.
Careful.
Oh, spoke... spoke too soon.
Thank you for coming.
They've been here with me all night.
Hmm. You are true friends.
Well, it's the least we can do
for my benefactor.
Hmm.
What happened to...
my attacker?
We don't know.
Do you need us to get you anything?
Yes.
I need you to go home
and take my wife with you.
And this time, no walking.
You take the car.
- (Laughs)
- We promise.
Bye.
You smell different.
Sorry.
I guess with all the excitement...
Something else.
I know what it is.
What?
You're ready.
You're ripe.
Guy, wake up.
- We have work to do.
- Oh.
(Chatter, giggling)
(Cat meows)
Margaux, are you sure
you want to do this?
I'm exhausted.
And you must be too.
Go take a shower.
When you come out,
this will be ready.
(Indistinct muttering)
I feel so warm inside.
Everywhere.
You look beautiful.
Guy, I want this to be
the most romantic,
perfect night of our lives.
No pressure, right?
I feel so strange.
I'm floating away.
(Wind whooshing)
(Birds chirping)
(Voice echoing)
Rosemary...
(Tense music building)
(Heavy breathing)
This isn't a dream.
This is real.
Sync & corrections by Elderfel
www.addic7ed.com