Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
They found Wells. They got him.
They found him.
I found you too!
I don't trust him.
Have you ever trusted anybody?
He'd be dead if it
weren't for you.
I thought maybe you were coming
out here to talk about us.
You've seen my brother?
Not for a long time.
Makes two of us.
So, what's your real name?
I never tell.
You're just gonna
leave us in here?
From now on this part of
the prison is yours.
Consider yourselves
the lucky ones.
( footsteps )
( liquid sloshing )
( clattering )
( theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by
err0001 & n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Okay, let's get
the other car in.
- We'll park 'em in the west entry of the
yard. - Good, our vehicles camped out
there look like a giant
"vacancy" sign.
Rick: After that, we need
to load up these corpses
so we can burn 'em.
T-Dog:
Gonna be a long day.
Where's Glenn and Maggie?
We could use some help.
Up in the guard tower.
Guard tower?
They were just
up there last night.
Glenn!
Maggie!
( door clicks )
Hey, what's up, guys?
( laughs )
- You coming?
- What?
( all chuckle )
Daryl: You comin'?
Daryl: Come on, we
could use a hand.
Yeah, we'll be right down.
Sickos.
Hey, Rick.
Come with me.
Rick:
That's close enough.
- We had an agreement.
- Please, mister. We know that.
We made a deal.
But you've gotta understand
we can't live in that place
another minute.
You follow me?
All the bodies--
people we knew.
- Blood, brains everywhere. There's ghosts.
- Why don't you move the bodies out?
- T-Dog: You should be burning them.
- Axel: We tried.
- We did. - The fence is down on
the far side of the prison.
Every time we drag a body out,
those things just line up.
So hump in a body and
just running back inside.
Look, we had nothing to do
with Thomas and Andrew.
Nothing.
You trying to prove a point?
You proved it, bro.
We'll do whatever it takes
to be part of your group.
Just, please, please.
Don't make us
live in that place.
Our deal is not negotiable.
You either live in your
cell block, or you leave.
( sighs ) I told you this
was a waste of time.
They ain't no different than the
pricks who shot up our boys.
You know how many
friends' corpses
we had to drag out this week?
Just threw 'em out, like.
Humph.
These were good guys.
Good guys who had our backs against
the really bad dudes in the joint,
like Thomas and Andrew.
We've all made mistakes
to get in here, chief.
And I'm not gonna
pretend to be a saint,
but believe me...
we've paid our due--
enough that we would
rather hit that road
than to go back
into that shithole.
C'mon, dude.
Rick:
Are you serious?
You want them living
in a cell next to you?
They'll just be waiting for a
chance to grab our weapons.
You want to go back to
sleeping with one eye open?
I never stopped.
Bring them into the fold.
If we send them off packing, we might
as well execute them ourselves.
I don't know.
Axel seems a little unstable.
Carol: After all
we've been through?
We fought so hard for all this,
what if they decide to take it?
It's just been us for so long.
They're strangers.
I don't--
It feels weird all of a sudden to
have these other people around.
You brought us in.
Yeah, but you turned up with
a shot boy in your arms.
- Didn't give us a choice.
- They can't even kill walkers.
They're convicts, bottom line.
Those two might actually have less
blood on their hands than we do.
I get guys like this.
Hell, I grew up with them.
They're degenerates,
but they ain't psychos.
I could have been with them just as
easy as I am out here with you, guys.
- So are you with me?
- Hell, no.
Let 'em take their
chances out on the road
- just like we did.
- What I'm saying, Daryl--
When I was a rookie,
I arrested this kid.
19 years old.
Wanted for stabbing his girlfriend.
The kid blubbered like a baby
during the interrogation,
during the trial--
suckered the jury.
He was acquitted due to insufficient
evidence, and in 2 weeks later...
shot another girl.
We've been through too much.
Our deal with them stands.
( truck engine revving,
faint digging )
( people chatting )
Pretty amazing.
If we had more ammo we could
cut down a whole pack of biters.
I hear you and Andrea
are leaving today.
That's a shame.
We could use
a soldier like you.
You seem like you're
holding your own.
Even the National Guard
was overrun.
No amount of training can prepare
you for the world today.
You'd think one soldier
would drive away--
especially against
something so slow.
Those men were heroes.
Not the kind to leave
anyone behind.
If only we'd
gotten there sooner...
and you were with us.
Lots of bullet holes.
You think biters figured
out how to use weapons?
They must have encountered
bandits weeks ago.
It's ugly out there,
but then...
you know that
better than anyone.
It's too bad what
happened to Wells.
It is.
Dr. Stevens
couldn't revive him.
Merle put a bullet
in his brain.
No funeral?
We cremated him, quietly.
These people
have been through so much,
I figured, thank God,
at least no one knew him.
Thank God.
( crackling )
Rick: Move the cars
to the upper yard...
Point them facing out.
They'll be out of the way but ready
to go if we ever need to bail.
We'll get the prisoners.
A week's worth of
supplies for the road.
It might not last a week.
It's their choice.
- Did they really have one?
- Hey, hey.
Whose blood would you
rather have on your hands--
Maggie's, Glenn's, or theirs?
Neither.
( car engine starts )
Twin cylinder.
Is that a Triumph?
Don't even look at it.
Didn't want it bored out?
( motor revs )
Sounds like it could use a tune-up.
I'm pretty handy with the grind.
Heads are leakin'.
I know my bikes!
Man, will you just stop?
Have some balls.
Just sayin'.
( creaking )
All right.
Just take your time.
Daddy, don't push yourself.
( chuckles ) What else
am I going to do?
I can't stand looking up at the
bottom of that bunk...
Whoa.
( tapping )
You know?
I can go pretty steady.
That's a good start.
Want to take a rest?
Rest? ( chuckles )
Let's go for a little stroll.
If we leave soon,
we'll got a few hours
on the road before dusk.
Where are we heading?
I'm thinking the coast.
We have the water completely
on one side,
maybe we find a boat.
Best thing we can do
is find an island.
And if the coast isn't safe?
Keep moving.
Then what do we do?
Just grow old,
live off the sea by ourselves?
I'd rather take my chances
out there than stay here.
Because your gut tells you there's
something off about this place--
About the Governor?
It's kept us alive this long.
That's true.
There's enough food in there
to last you guys a week.
Cut you loose when we get back.
Thank you, bro.
Sit tight.
Oscar:
"Thank you, bro"?
( engine starts )
- Glenn: Should I take her out?
- Rick: No.
If that armory hadn't been picked
clean, we could spare the ammo.
I'll start making runs.
The sooner the better.
We'll throw as much wood
as we can in the dog run.
Won't the fire
attract more walkers?
Maybe we should bury them.
We're behind the fence.
It's worth the one-time risk to
get rid of the bodies for good.
I don't want to be planting
crops in walker-rotted soil.
I got you here if you need it.
Just take your time
on these steps.
Carl:
Ooh, ooh.
Hershel: You cleared
all those bodies out?
It's starting to look like a place
we could really live in.
Hey, you watch your step.
Last thing we need
is you falling.
Looky here.
He is one tough son of a bitch.
( chuckles )
- All right, Hershel!
- Shh!
Keep your cheers down.
( growling )
Oh, man. Can't we just
have one good day?
You're doing great, Daddy.
Ready to race, Hershel?
Give me another day.
I'll take you on.
( Carl chuckles )
Grab the rest of the bodies...
( chuckles )
( growling )
Walkers! Look out!
No!
( walkers snarling )
( gunfire )
Rick:
Get out!
Get out of there!
No!
Lori!
( growling )
( yells ) Carl!
Come in here!
Daddy, behind you!
Come on!
The lock--
hurry up!
The lock!
Keys!
That gate is open!
Lori! Here!
Come on!
( snarling ) This way!
Get out of my way!
Daryl:
Come on, come on!
Axel: Hey, bro, what about us?
( growls )
( screams )
No!
Hurry!
[ both laugh ] I circled where you can find
that farm I was staying at with Daryl.
Ah, you were right off Route 9
right before it becomes
Dahlonega Highway.
And you're saying that the farm
is only about a day's
walk from there?
Give or take.
This is where
we looked for Sophia.
Even made it up around here.
How come we never hooked up?
You called me a whore...
and a rugmuncher.
( chuckles ) Got a way
with words, don't I?
- Yeah.
- Mmm.
Why are you doing this?
I'd want the same thing if
it was my family out there.
- Sure you don't wanna come with me?
- Mmm.
You ain't curious
about the old gang?
Oh...!
Oh yeah, you really was
cut loose, weren't you?
I'm sure they came back.
I didn't stick around to find out.
Ain't that a big ol' pig sack?
We got something
in common, blondie.
We got left behind
by the same people...
and saved by another.
Have you ever thought
about leaving this place?
( sighs )
Never had a reason to.
So the Governor is a good man?
Let me just
put it this way--
I wasn't in the best
of shape when he found me.
He should have
just kept on going.
Yeah, he's a good man.
Let's go.
Pull it!
( snarling )
- What the hell happened?
- Beth: The gate was open!
Where's Lori, Carl--
everyone else?
Maggie led Lori and
Carl into C block.
- Beth: And T was bit!
- Anyone else?
- Beth: I couldn't tell.
- Stay put.
( gurgles )
Those chains didn't
break on their own.
Someone took an ax
or cutters to 'em.
( walkers growling )
- You think they did it?
- Who else?
( alarm blaring )
What's that?
Oh-- you gotta be
kidding me!
( blaring continues ) Daryl!
( Hershel yelling ) Kill it!
( snarling )
Back up!
How the hell could
this be happening?
Whoa-whoa-whoa!
It has to be the backup generators.
Well, how do you turn those on?
There's three that's connected
to a diesel tank, okay?
Each one controls a certain
part of the prison.
The hatch shut them all off
when the prison was overrun.
Can someone open up the
main gates electronically
- with full power?
- I only went in a few days.
I guess it might be possible.
- Come with us!
- Glenn: Let's go!
There's a set of double doors
that will lead to a corridor
that will get you back
to our cell block.
- No, you should stop.
- I'm getting you there!
- Stop!
- T-Dog: Why? Sit here and wait to die?
I'll do what I have to.
You're not becoming one of those things.
- I can't ask that.
- It's the pact, remember?
This is God's plan.
He'll take care of me.
Always has.
He's gonna help me lead
you out of these tunnels.
( alarm blaring continues )
( grunts )
- Can you keep up?
- Lori: Something's not right.
- Carl: Are you bit?
- Lori: No, no, no.
I think the baby's coming.
Mom?
( zombies snarling )
No, there's no time!
( snarling continues )
( Lori grunting, coughing )
( growling )
In here!
( thumps )
( grunts ) Okay.
( alarm blaring continues )
( panting )
( alarm continues )
( growling )
( gasps )
( ball clatters )
( whistles ) Pretty good.
We should visit Augusta.
Take only the women
and let them play.
It'll be historic.
And break decades of tradition?
- Absolutely.
- I don't know.
Some things are
worth holding on to.
You know, I was thinking
of taking Tim and Martinez
out on a scouting mission
later on this week.
For what?
( faint crash ) Blondie.
She said my brother
was still alive.
Eight months ago.
You can track
with the best of 'em,
it's like a needle
in a haystack.
She told me where I could
find that farmhouse
they were holed up in.
He could be anywhere.
- I know my brother.
If he's out there,
I'll be able to find him.
What if someone gets hurt
during this search, huh?
We almost had in
the crowley last time.
Then I'll go on my own.
I get what you're
feeling, I really do,
but I can't risk it.
I need you here.
This whole place would
fall apart without you.
This is my brother.
Tell you what, huh?
You get more concrete
information, I'll go with you myself.
All right?
( alarm blaring )
Lori!
Carl!
We just took down
five of 'em in there.
They were four in here, but no
sign of Lori or anyone.
They must have been pushed
back into the prison.
Somebody is playing games!
We'll split up
and look for the others.
- Whoever gets to the generators first,
shut 'em down! - Let's go!
( grunts )
What are those alarms?
Don't worry about it.
Carl: What if it attracts them?
( Lori panting )
- Maggie: Lori, let's lay you down.
- No-- the baby's coming now.
We have to get back to our cell block
to have Hershel help.
Maggie: We can't risk
getting caught out there.
You're gonna need to give
birth to this baby here.
Great.
( panting )
What is she doing?
Can't she breathe?
She's fine.
Come here-- let's get your pants off.
Okay.
( Lori grunts ) Okay.
You're gonna need to help deliver your
brother or sister. You up for it?
*** save her doll. I did
- Okay.
- Do you know how?
Dad taught me, but trust
me, it's my first time.
( grunts )
- I can't tell.
- I gotta push.
- Okay.
( grunts, huffs )
Whew... whew...
( grunting )
Somebody!
- I'm okay, I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Okay.
- Maggie: You're doing great,
Lori. Just keep doing it.
Your body knows what to do.
Let it do all the work.
( Lori yelps )
You're doing great.
( grunts )
Lori, don't push-- stop.
Something's wrong.
( screams )
T-Dog:
We're almost there.
( snarling )
( clicking )
Oh, shit.
Go back!
- T-Dog: No. We're close. We're close!
- No!
( yells )
Go! Go!
( growling )
Go! I'm dead!
( screams )
( bottles clink )
Sorry to see you leave.
This place isn't for everybody.
Thank you...
for everything.
Where are you planning to go?
The coast.
Michonne thinks it'll be safer.
What do you think?
Her vigilance has kept you
both alive.
( stopper pops )
Oh-- I haven't had
hard liquor in a while.
My tolerance is probably
close to nil.
Lucky you.
Merle told me you provided information
about his brother's whereabouts.
What I could.
It wasn't much.
Well, it's given him hope.
If you ask me, I don't
think he'll find him.
- But he's gotta look--
- Governor: Gotta look.
What about you?
Think you'll find
what you're looking for?
- I'm sorry?
- You still got family out there?
I lost my family.
My parents, my sister.
I'm sorry.
Lost my wife--
car accident.
18 months before all this.
Just my daughter and me.
To better days.
( chuckles )
( clinks )
Ahh.
This is good.
The truth is, I don't know
what I'm looking for.
For the longest time,
it was all about survival.
Nothing else mattered.
So much so...
I don't know what matters now.
Pay off the car,
work 50 hours a week,
get married,
buy a house-- that was survival
for many not long ago.
A lot's changed.
The scenery has.
The landscape.
But the way we think...
I better go.
But I appreciate the drink.
Sure.
Merle will see you out and he'll
have your weapons waiting for you.
Remember--
if it gets tough out there,
you're always welcome here.
That's very kind.
- Thank you, Governor.
- Philip.
I thought you never
told anybody your name.
Someone recently told me
never to say never, so...
( chuckles )
Well...
take care.
Goodbye.
( zombies growling, snarling )
Rick:
Daryl, Get the door!
( alarm blaring )
How do you shut these down?!
Go help 'em.
I got it.
Right here.
( yelling )
( grunts )
Shoot him!
We can take back this prison.
What you waiting for?
Do it!
It's our house.
Shoot him!
( alarm continues )
( generator whirrs down )
( alarms stop )
Let's go.
Mom...?
Mom, look at me, look at me.
Keep your eyes open.
We have to get you back to Dad.
I'm not gonna make it.
Lori, with all this blood, I don't
even think you're fully dilated yet.
No amount of pushing
is gonna help.
I know what it means, and
I'm not losing my baby.
You've gotta cut me open.
- No. I can't.
- You don't have a choice.
- I'll go for help.
- No!
Look, Carol is the one
that practiced that.
Dad only taught me the steps, Lori.
If I--
- Please. - I have no anesthetic,
no equipment--
Carl has a knife.
You won't survive.
My baby has to survive.
Please.
My baby...
for all of us.
Please, Maggie!
Please!
( Lori gasping )
Please.
I thought we had an agreement.
We can always leave tomorrow
or the following day.
The following day?
We don't want to walk into trouble
that we can't get out of.
- Tell me about it.
- Michonne, it is just a day or two.
I heard you the first time.
( door opens, closes )
Lori: You see my old
C-section scar?
- I can't.
- You can.
You have to.
Carl?
Baby, I don't want you
to be scared, okay?
This is what I want.
This is right.
Now you-- you take care of
your daddy for me, all right?
And your little brother
or sister, you take care--
You don't have to do this.
You're gonna be fine.
You are gonna beat this world.
I know you will.
You are smart,
and you are strong,
and you are so brave,
and I love you.
I love you too.
You gotta do
what's right, baby.
You promise me, you'll
always do what's right.
It's so easy to do the
wrong thing in this world.
So don't--
so if it feels wrong,
don't do it, all right?
If it feels easy don't do it.
Don't let the world spoil you.
You're so good.
You're my sweet boy.
The best thing I ever did.
I love you.
( sobs ) I love you.
You're my sweet, sweet boy.
I love you.
Okay--
okay, now.
Okay.
( grunts )
Maggie, when this is over,
you're gonna have to--
- Shh-- - Lori: You have to do it.
It can't be Rick.
All right...
all right.
It's all right.
Whew...
Good night, love.
I'm sorry.
( screams )
What are you doing to her?
( shudders )
Carl, give me your hands.
Carl, please.
You should keep the
site clean, okay?
I cut too deep,
I'm gonna cut the baby.
Okay, come on...
I see it.
I see the ears.
I'm gonna pull it out.
I can't tell if this is
the arm or the leg.
Well, pull the baby out.
( fluid splattering )
Okay...
( squelching )
- ( infant cries )
- ( Carl gasps )
( crying )
- We have to go.
- We can't just leave her here.
She'll turn.
- No.
- Carl...
She's my mom.
( crying )
( sobbing )
No more kids stuff.
People are gonna die.
I'm gonna die...
Mom...
There's no way you can
ever be ready for it.
( sobs )
( gunshot echoes )
( growling )
( gunshot pops )
- Hershel!
- Hershel: You didn't find them?
Glenn: We thought maybe
they came back out here.
- What about T? Carol?
- They didn't make it.
That doesn't mean the others didn't.
We're going back.
Daryl and Glenn, you come with--
( infant crying )
( sobs )
Where-- where is she?
Where is she?
No...
Rick, no!
Oh, no. No!
( sobs ) No!
( sobs )
( stammers ) ( sobs ) No!
( sobbing )
Sync and corrections by
n17t01 & err0001
www.addic7ed.com