- (people yelling)
- (radio chatter)
Hey hey.
Whoa whoa whoa whoa.
Ma'am. Ma'am, please.
- Please, can you help me?
- No no no!
- (siren wailing)
- (gunshots)
Man:
Check them all. Check them all.
(helicopter passing)
(screams)
- (growling)
- (man screaming)
(gunshots)
(panting)
- Okay.
- (heart monitor beeping)
I'm gonna get you
out of here, bud.
- (gunshots)
- (grunts)
- (helicopter passing)
- Okay. Okay.
What do I do?
(door opens)
Man:
Come on, corporal. Move out!
(gunfire)
(pounds, grunts)
(helicopter passes)
Listen to me. If you're gonna wake up,
I need you to do it now.
Okay? Now.
Please, man,
you just show me a sign. Anything.
- Please, Rick.
- (explosion)
(power whirring down)
Man:
The place is coming down!
Fall back!
All units fall back.
(guns firing)
(grunts)
(crying) I'm...
I'm okay.
(people yelling)
- (gunfire)
- (woman screams)
(growling)
(theme music playing)
Shane:
Daryl, you cover the back.
Rick: Hello?
- Hello?
- Shane: Close those doors.
Watch for walkers.
- Rick: Hello?
- (gun cocks)
Anybody infected?
One of our group was.
He didn't make it.
Jenner: Why are you here?
What do you want?
A chance.
That's asking
an awful lot these days.
I know.
You all submit to a blood test.
That's the price of admission.
We can do that.
You got stuff to bring in,
you do it now.
Once this door closes,
it stays closed.
- (beeps)
- Vi, seal the main entrance.
Kill the power up here.
(rattles, clangs)
(beeps)
Rick Grimes.
Dr. Edwin Jenner.
(elevator humming)
Doctors always go around
packing heat like that?
There were plenty left lying around.
I familiarized myself.
But you look harmless enough.
Except you.
I'll have to keep my eye on you.
(chuckles)
Carol:
Are we underground?
Jenner:
Are you claustrophobic?
- A little.
- Try not to think about it.
Vi, bring up the lights
in the big room.
(humming, beeping)
Welcome to zone 5.
Where is everybody?
The other doctors, the staff?
I'm it.
It's just me here.
What about the person
you were speaking with?
Vi?
Jenner:
Vi, say hello to our guests.
Tell them... welcome.
Computer:
Hello, guests. Welcome.
I'm all that's left.
I'm sorry.
Andrea: What's the point?
If we were infected,
we'd all be running a fever.
I've already broken every rule
in the book letting you in here.
Let me just at least be thorough.
- (syringe clicks)
- Jenner: All done.
- Ooh.
- Jenner: Are you okay?
- Mmm.
- She hasn't eaten in days.
None of us have.
- (all laughing)
- Fine.
You know, in Italy,
children have a little bit
of wine with dinner.
And in France.
Well, when Carl is
in Italy or France,
- he can have some then.
- What's it gonna hurt? Come on.
- Come on.
- (Dale laughs)
- What?
- (laughing)
Dale:
There you are, young lad.
(chuckles)
- Eww.
- (adults laughing)
That's my boy. That's my boy.
- Good boy.
- Yuck.
- That tastes nasty.
- (laughing continues)
Well, just stick
to soda pop there, bud.
- Daryl: Not you, Glenn.
- What?
Keep drinking, little man. I want
to see how red your face can get.
(men laughing)
(clinks glass)
It seems to me we haven't
thanked our host properly.
He is more than just our host.
- Hear hear!
- Here's to you, doc. Booyah!
- Men: Booyah!
- Thank you. Thank you, doctor.
- T-Dog: Booyah!
- (glasses clink)
So when are you gonna tell us
what the hell happened here, doc?
All the-- the other doctors
that were supposed to be
figuring out what happened,
- where are they?
- Rick: We're celebrating, Shane.
Don't need to do this now.
Whoa, wait a second.
This is why we're here, right?
This was your move--
supposed to find all the answers.
Instead we--
(chuckles)
we found him.
Found one man. Why?
Jenner:
Well, when things got bad,
a lot of people just left,
went off to be
with their families.
And when things got worse,
when the military cordon
got overrun,
the rest bolted.
Every last one?
No, many couldn't face
walking out the door.
They... opted out.
There was a rash of suicides.
That was a bad time.
You didn't leave.
Why?
I just kept working,
hoping to do some good.
Dude, you are such a buzzkill, man.
Most of the facility is powered down
including housing,
so you'll have to make do here.
The couches are comfortable,
but there are cots
in storage if you like.
There's a rec room down the hall
that you kids might enjoy.
Just don't plug in
the video games, okay?
Or anything that draws power.
The same applies--
if you shower,
go easy on the hot water.
Hot water?
- That's what the man said.
- (both laugh)
(knob squeaks)
(laughing)
Ah!
- Dale: Hey.
- (Andrea vomiting)
(sobs)
(coughs)
- Andrea?
- (vomits)
- Andrea.
- (sobbing)
That's it.
That's it. Get it out.
There you go.
Oh... God.
(flushes)
(sobbing)
Oh.
Everything's gone.
It's always better going down
than coming up, huh?
I don't mean the wine, Dale.
You know, it's over.
There's nothing left.
Don't you see that?
Oh, I-- I see a--
a chance to make a new start.
(laughs)
Oh my God, Dale.
Dale, didn't you see
the look on Jenner's face?
Hear what I'm saying.
There's nothing left.
(knocks)
How's the blood?
No surprises.
I came to thank you.
You did.
You all-- you all right?
You don't know what it's like.
(laughs)
You don't know
what it's like out there.
You may think you do,
but you don't.
We'd have died out there.
It was only a matter of time.
There's too many of those things.
My-- my boy...
my-- my wife, I never--
I never told 'em
what I really thought.
I never even hinted, just--
just kept it in.
Kept it in and kept us
moving, you know.
Just kept it in. Kept us--
It'll all be okay.
It'll be okay.
(chuckling)
- Any good books?
- Carol: Uh-huh.
- (book closes)
- Enough to keep us busy for years.
All right.
Come on, kids, it's bedtime.
Baby, go say your prayers.
I'm gonna browse a bit.
Carol:
Come on.
This is the first night we might
actually get some real sleep.
- Lori: Hmm.
- It's a miracle, isn't it?
(slams door)
(sighs)
Jesus, you scared me.
I'm gonna tell you a few things
and you're gonna listen to me.
Now is not the time.
(chuckles)
Come on. When is it ever the time?
How can you treat me like this?
- You're kidding, right?
- No. Huh-uh.
Because you told me
my husband was dead.
Jesus, Lori. I didn't lie
to you, all right? I didn't.
Do you know
what it was like there?
Stop. Things were falling apart.
They were slaughtering
people in the hallways.
It was a massacre.
There were walkers everywhere.
- So you left him?
- Everybody else ran.
There were no doctors there.
It was just me.
He was hooked up to machines
and I did not know what to do.
I even took my ear
and I put it on his chest
and I listened for a heartbeat
and I did not hear one.
And I-I-I-I--
I don't know why.
Maybe it was gunfire.
I don't know what it was,
but there was no way
he could've survived that. No way.
- He did.
- Yeah,
but then I had y'all to think about,
didn't I? I had you and Carl,
- and I needed to think about--
- Okay. No no.
I had to get you guys
safe to Atlanta.
That's what I had to do. Just stop.
If you thought for one second
that he was still alive,
would you have come?
So I saved your life--
you and your little boy's.
That's what I did.
Right?
Okay.
And if I could've traded places
with him, I would have.
I would trade places
with him right now because--
- No no no. No.
- No no no, you--
- I love you. Shh shh.
- No. No, you're drunk.
- I love you.
- No, you're drunk.
And I know there were some things
that say that you love me too,
because there's no way that you could've
been with me the way that you were.
- Shane. Shane. Shane!
- Just-- okay, stop.
- Listen. You love me.
- Get your hands off me.
- I love you. There's nobody here.
- Please! Ah!
Stop, Lori.
It's all right. Just--
(groans)
(pounds wall)
(sobbing)
- (belt buckle rattles)
- (shoes clatter)
(switch clicks)
(crying)
(whispering)
We don't have to be afraid anymore.
We're safe here.
All right?
(sniffling)
Glenn: Hello.
- Rick: Morning.
- Are you hungover?
- Mom said you'd be.
- Mom is right.
Mom has that annoying habit.
Eggs. Powdered, but--
but I do 'em good.
- (Glenn moans)
- T-Dog: I bet you can't tell.
- Protein helps the hangover.
- (moaning)
Where'd all this come from?
- Jenner.
- Rick: Could you help me, please?
He thought we could use it.
- Rick: Thank you.
- Some of us, at least.
Don't ever ever ever
let me drink again.
- Shane: Hey.
- Hey.
Rick:
Feel as bad as I do?
Worse.
The hell happened to you?
Your neck?
I must have done it in my sleep.
Never seen you do that before.
Me neither.
Not like me at all.
- Jenner: Morning.
- Shane: Hey, doc.
Doctor, I don't mean to slam you
with questions first thing--
But you will anyway.
We didn't come here
for the eggs.
- (clicks, beeps)
- Give me playback of TS-19.
Vi:
Playback of TS-19.
(beeping)
Jenner: Few people
ever got a chance to see this.
Very few.
- Is that a brain?
- An extraordinary one.
Not that it matters in the end.
Take us in for EIV.
Vi:
Enhanced internal view.
What are those lights?
Jenner:
It's a person's life--
experiences, memories.
It's everything.
Somewhere in
all that organic wiring,
all those ripples of light,
is you--
the thing that makes you unique.
And human.
You don't make sense ever?
Those are synapses,
electric impulses in the brain
that carry all the messages.
They determine
everything a person says
does or thinks
from the moment of birth
to the moment of death.
Death? That's what
this is, a vigil?
Yes.
Or rather
the playback of the vigil.
This person died?
Who?
Jenner:
Test Subject 19.
Someone who was bitten
and infected...
and volunteered to have us
record the process.
Vi, scan forward
to the first event.
- Vi: Scanning to first event.
- (beeping)
What is that?
It invades the brain
like meningitis.
The adrenal glands hemorrhage,
the brain goes into shutdown,
then the major organs.
Then death.
Everything you ever were
or ever will be...
gone.
Is that what happened to Jim?
Yes.
Lori:
She lost somebody two days ago.
Her sister.
I lost somebody too.
I know how devastating it is.
Scan to
the second event.
Vi:
Scanning to second event.
Jenner:
The resurrection times vary wildly.
We had reports of it happening
in as little as three minutes.
The longest we heard of
was eight hours.
In the case of this patient,
it was two hours, one minute...
seven seconds.
- It restarts the brain?
- No, just the brain stem.
Basically,
it gets them up and moving.
But they're not alive?
You tell me.
It's nothing like before.
Most of that brain is dark.
Jenner:
Dark, lifeless, dead.
The frontal lobe, the neocortex,
the human part--
that doesn't come back.
The you part.
Just a shell
driven by mindless instinct.
God. What was that?
He shot his patient in the head.
Didn't you?
Jenner:
Vi, power down the main screen
and the workstations.
Vi: Powering down
main screen and workstations.
You have no idea
what it is, do you?
It could be microbial,
viral, parasitic,
- fungal.
- Or the wrath of God?
There is that.
Andrea:
Somebody must know something.
Somebody somewhere.
Carol: There are others, right?
Other facilities?
There may be some.
People like me.
But you don't know?
How can you not know?
Jenner:
Everything went down.
Communications,
directives-- all of it.
I've been in the dark
for almost a month.
So it's not just here.
There's nothing left
anywhere? Nothing?
That's what
you're really saying, right?
Jesus.
Man, I'm gonna get
shit-faced drunk again.
Dr. Jenner, I know this
has been taxing for you
and I hate to ask
one more question, but...
that clock--
it's counting down.
What happens at zero?
The basement generators--
they run out of fuel.
And then?
Vi, what happens
when the power runs out?
Vi:
When the power runs out,
facility-wide
decontamination will occur.
(beeps)
Glenn: Decontamination--
what does that mean?
Shane: I don't like
the way Jenner clammed up.
The way he just
wandered off like that.
What's wrong with him?
Seriously, man,
is he nuts, medicated or what?
In there.
- (beeps)
- (lights humming)
Check that way.
Shane.
(chugging)
It's empty.
- (sighs)
- (generator clacks)
- Vi: Emergency lighting on.
- What the hell is this?
Hey, you guys kill the lights?
- Nah, it just went out.
- Rick: Anything?
T-Dog:
Yeah, a lot of dead generators
and more empty fuel drums
than I can count.
It can't be down to just that one.
Mom? Something wrong?
Nothing. It's just...
the air conditioning stopped.
(sighs, sniffles)
I did the best I could
in the time that I had.
I hope you'd be proud of that.
We always think
there's gonna be more time...
(power whirs down)
...then it runs out.
Carol:
Why is the air off?
- And the lights in our room?
- Daryl: What's going on?
Why is everything turned off?
Energy use is being prioritized.
Dale:
Air isn't a priority? And lights?
It's not up to me.
Zone 5 is shutting itself down.
Daryl: Hey! Hey, what the hell
does that mean?
- (power whirs down)
- Hey, man, I'm talking to you.
What do you mean
it's shutting itself down?
How can a building do anything?
- Jenner: You'd be surprised.
- Rick?
Jenner, what's happening?
The system is dropping all
the nonessential uses of power.
It's designed to keep the computers
running to the last possible second.
That started as we approached
the half-hour mark.
Right on schedule.
- It was the French.
- What?
They were the last ones
to hold out as far as I know.
While our people were
bolting out the doors
and committing suicide
in the hallways,
they stayed in the labs till the end.
They thought
they were close to a solution.
What happened?
Jenner: The same thing
that's happening here.
No power grid.
Ran out of juice.
The world runs on fossil fuel.
I mean,
how stupid is that?
- Shane: Let me tell you--
- Rick: To hell with it. I don't care.
Lori, grab our things.
Everybody, get your stuff.
We're getting out of here now!
Oh, okay.
- (alarm blaring)
- What's that?
What's that?
Vi:
30 minutes to decontamination.
Daryl:
Doc, what's going on here, damn it?
Shane:
Everybody, y'all heard Rick.
Get your stuff and let's go!
Go now! Go!
- Let's go.
- Glenn: Come on!
(whirs, clangs)
No.
Did you just lock us in?
He just locked us in!
We've hit the 30-minute window.
I am recording.
- Carl.
- Carl: Mom!
- You son of a bitch.
- Shane!
- You locked us in here!
- No, stop. Don't!
- Shane: No no no no! Don't!
Wait, no!
No, don't do it.
Hey, Jenner,
open that door now.
There's no point.
Everything topside is locked down.
The emergency exits are sealed.
Dale:
Well, open the damn things.
That's not something I control.
The computers do.
I told you once
that front door closed,
it wouldn't open again.
You heard me say that.
- It's better this way.
- What is?
What happens in 28 minutes?
(keyboard clacks)
- What happens in 28 minutes?!
- Daryl: Come on!
Do you know what this place is?!
We protected the public
from very nasty stuff!
Weaponized smallpox!
Ebola strains that could
wipe out half the country!
Stuff you don't want
getting out! Ever!
In the event
of a catastrophic power failure--
in a terrorist attack,
for example--
HITs are deployed to prevent
any organisms from getting out.
HITs?
- Vi, define.
- Vi: HITs--
high-impulse thermobaric
fuel-air explosives
consist of a two-stage
aerosol ignition
that produces a blast wave
of significantly greater power
and duration than
any other known explosive
except nuclear.
The vacuum-pressure effect
ignites the oxygen
at between 5,000° and 6,000°
and is useful when
the greatest loss of life
and damage
to structures is desired.
It sets the air on fire.
No pain.
(both crying)
Jenner:
An end to sorrow, grief...
regret.
Everything.
Open the damn door!
Out of my way!
- (grunts)
- T-Dog: Daryl!
(both pounding, grunting)
(crying)
You should've
left well enough alone.
- It would've been so much easier.
- Lori: Easier for who?
All of you.
You know what's out there--
a short, brutal life
and an agonizing death.
Your-- your sister--
what was her name?
- Amy.
- Jenner: Amy.
You know what this does.
You've seen it.
Is that really what you want
for your wife and son?
(emphatically)
I don't want this.
- (axe bangs)
- Can't make a dent.
Those doors are designed
to withstand a rocket launcher.
- Well, your head ain't!
- Rick: Whoa! Whoa!
Daryl! Daryl!
Just back up! Back up!
Jenner:
You do want this.
Last night you said
you knew it was just
a matter of time
before everybody
you loved was dead.
What?
You really said that?
After all your big talk?
I had to keep
hope alive, didn't I?
Jenner:
There is no hope.
- There never was.
- There's always hope.
Maybe it won't be you,
maybe not here,
but somebody somewhere--
What part of "everything is gone"
do you not understand?
Jenner:
Listen to your friend. She gets it.
This is what takes us down.
This is
our extinction event.
(crying continues)
Carol:
This isn't right.
You can't just keep us here.
One tiny moment--
a millisecond. No pain.
My daughter doesn't deserve
to die like this.
Wouldn't it be kinder,
more compassionate
to just hold your loved ones
- and wait for the clock to run down?
- (gun cocks)
- Shane, no!
- Out of the way, Rick!
Stay out of my way!
Open that door
or I'm gonna blow your head off.
Do you hear me?!
Brother, brother,
this is not the way you do this.
- We will never get out of here.
- Shane, you listen to him.
- Shane: It's too late.
- He dies, we all--
- (yelling)
- --we all die! Shane!
Shane!
(grunts)
(panting)
Are you done now?
Are you done?
Yeah, I guess we all are.
I think you're lying.
- What?
- Rick: You're lying
about no hope.
If that were true,
you'd have bolted with the rest
or taken the easy way out.
You didn't.
You chose the hard path.
- Why?
- It doesn't matter.
It does matter.
It always matters.
You stayed when others ran.
- Why?
- Not because I wanted to.
I made a promise...
to her.
My wife.
Test subject 19
was your wife?
Jenner: She begged me
to keep going as long as I could.
- How could I say no?
- (pounding)
She was dying.
It should've been me
on that table.
I wouldn't have
mattered to anybody.
She was a loss to the world.
Hell, she ran this place.
I just worked here.
In our field, she was an Einstein.
Me? I'm just... Edwin Jenner.
She could've done
something about this.
Not me.
Your wife didn't have a choice.
You do.
That's-- that's all we want--
a choice, a chance.
(Daryl grunting)
Let us keep trying
as long as we can.
I told you topside's locked down.
I can't open those.
(beeping)
Come on!
- Let's go!
- Come on, let's go!
- Daryl: Come on!
- T-Dog: Move it! Move it!
- Daryl: Come on, let's go!
- Carol: We're gonna get out of here.
There's your chance. Take it.
I'm grateful.
- The day will come when you won't be.
- Glenn: Let's go!
(whispering)
Hey, we've got four minutes left!
Come on!
- Let's go. Let's go, Jacqui.
- No no, I'm staying.
I'm staying, sweetie.
- But that's insane!
- No, it's completely sane.
For the first time
in a long time.
I'm not ending up
like Jim and Amy.
There's no time to argue
and no point,
not if you want to get out.
Just get out. Get out.
T-Dog. Come on, man.
Come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
I'm staying too.
Andrea, no.
- Just go! Go!
- Shane: Come on.
Andrea,
this isn't what
Amy would want for you.
She's dead,
and you need to leave.
- Glenn: Get them doors open!
- T-Dog: Come on!
- Glenn: It doesn't work!
- Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
- Try it! Try it! Try it now!
- Shane: Daryl!
- Daryl: Come on! Come on!
- Stay close, sweetheart.
(grunting)
Time's almost up.
Daryl, look out!
(yelling)
Dog, get down! Get down!
- Jesus.
- Sophia: The glass won't break?
Rick, I have something
that might help.
Carol, I don't think
a nail file's gonna do it.
Your first morning at camp,
when I washed your uniform
I found this in your pocket.
Come on.
Glenn:
Look out!
Oh, sh--
- Get down! Get down!
- Shit!
(glass shatters)
Okay.
You win.
- What are you doing?
- I said okay.
- Don't pull this, Dale.
- I'm not pulling anything.
If you're staying, I stay too.
He's right. We know
what's waiting for us out there.
I don't want to face it alone.
Dale, get the hell out.
I don't want you here.
Too bad.
See, you don't get to do that,
to-- to come into somebody's life,
make them care
and then just check out.
I'm staying.
The matter is settled.
(zombies growling)
(grunts)
(panting)
Wait wait wait. Wait wait.
They're coming.
(computer beeping)
They got out.
Lori:
Come on.
- (horn honks)
- Dale, get down! Down!
Get back!
Everybody down! Down!
Get down!
(exhales)
Come on. Come on.
(folk music playing)
Get in, get in, get in.
Get in!
♪ If today was not
a crooked highway ♪
♪ If tonight was not
a crooked trail ♪
♪ If tomorrow wasn't
such a long time ♪
♪ Then lonesome would mean
nothing to you at all... ♪
(engine starts)
♪ Yes and only if my own
true love was waiting ♪
♪ If I could hear
her heart softly pounding ♪
♪ Yes and only
if she was lying by me ♪
♪ I'd lie ♪
♪ In my bed once again ♪
♪ I can't see
my reflection in the water ♪
♪ I can't speak
the sounds to show no pain ♪
♪ I can't hear the echo
of my footsteps ♪
♪ Or remember the sounds
of my own name ♪
♪ Yes and only
if my own true love was waiting ♪
♪ And if I could hear
her heart softly pounding ♪
♪ Yes, and only
if she was lying by me ♪
♪ I'd lie in my bed once again. ♪
Mmm.