Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
Now, I want to know
where your camp is!
Come on!
Hurry!
You guys, go ahead.
I'm gonna lay down some cover fire.
I'll be right behind you.
You wanted your brother.
Now you got him.
Crowd:
Kill 'em! Kill 'em!
- Let me go. Let me go.
- You can't go.
Let me go.
Philip.
- Stay out of this.
- He's my friend.
It's not up to me anymore.
- The people have spoken.
- What?
I asked you where
your loyalties lie.
You said here.
Well, prove it.
Prove it to us all.
- Brother against brother.
- Crowd: Yeah.
Winner goes free.
( crowd cheering )
Fight to the death.
( cheering )
Philip, please.
Don't do this.
- Man: Let's go, Merle!
- Man #2: Come on, Merle!
- Woman: Yeah, Merle!
- Yeah!
Y'all know me.
( crowd cheering )
I'm gonna do
whatever I got to do
to prove...
( grunts ) ( cheering )
( coughing )
that my loyalty
is to this town!
( blows landing )
( snarling )
Ah!
You really think this
asshole's gonna let you go?
Just follow my lead,
little brother.
We're getting out
of this right now.
( grunts )
Philip no, stop this!
Philip, stop this!
( crowd gasps )
( gunshot )
( people screaming )
( gunfire )
Come on, little brother.
( yelling )
Stay close!
Daryl!
Merle, come on.
Go!
( gunshot )
- ( screaming )
- ( gunshot )
( sighs )
Let's go.
- Rick: Daryl.
- Let's go. Go.
( theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
- ( gunfire )
- ( people shouting )
They're all at the arena.
This way.
You're not going
anywhere with us.
You really want to do this now?
( clanging ) ( Merle grunting )
Come on, man.
( panel opens )
Rick, come on.
We've got to go.
Go.
( thudding )
( Merle grunting )
A little help would be nice.
( snarling )
We ain't got time for this.
Let's go.
Rick: Glenn!
Rick.
Oh, thank God.
Now we got a problem here.
I need you to back up.
- What the hell is he doing here?
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Hey, put it down!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Put it down!
- He tried to kill me!
- If it wasn't for him--
- He helped us get out of there.
Yeah, right after he beat
the shit out of you.
- Hey, we both took our licks, man.
- Jackass.
- Hey, shut up.
- Enough!
- Hey, hey, relax!
- Put that down now!
Get that thing out of my face!
( laughs ) Man, look like
you've gone native, brother.
No more than you hanging out
with that psycho back there.
Oh, yeah, man.
He is a charmer, I got to tell you that.
Been putting the wood
to your girlfriend Andrea.
- Big time, baby. ( moans )
- Glenn: What?
Andrea's in Woodbury?
Right next to the Governor.
I told you to drop that!
You know Andrea?
Hey, do you know Andrea?
Merle:
Yep, she does.
Her and blondie
spent all winter
cuddling up in the forest.
Mm-mmm-mmm.
Yeah.
My Nubian queen here
had two pet walkers.
No arms, cut off the jaws,
kept them in chains.
- Kind of ironic now that
I think about it. - Shut up, bro.
Hey, man, we snagged them
out of the woods.
Andrea was close to dying.
- Is that why she's with him?
- Merle: Yeah.
Snug as two little bugs.
So what you gonna
do now, Sheriff, huh?
- Surrounded by a bunch of liars,
thugs, and cowards. - Shut up!
Oh, man, look at this.
Pathetic.
- All these guns and no bullets in them.
- Merle, shut up!
Shut up yourself!
Bunch of pussies you roll--
Asshole.
( door clangs )
You can take those stitches out
yourself in a week or so.
Thank you.
Pretty nice having
medical training.
It'll only get you so far.
You were bit?
( door opens )
How old is the baby?
Barely a week.
To be honest, we never thought
we'd see another baby.
Beautiful.
Thanks.
How are you feeling?
She's not mine.
Where's the mother?
I'm sorry.
Man, you people have
been through the mill.
Haven't we all?
It's only getting
worse out there.
Dead are everywhere.
And it's only making the living
less like the living.
You're the only decent folks
we've come across.
You've been out there
all this time?
Our neighbor Jerry, he was one
of those survivalist nuts.
Everybody on the block
thought he was crazy.
Always preparing
for the end of the world.
- Who knew?
- Jerry knew.
He had a bunker under
his shed in the backyard.
Sasha and I stayed there
until we ran out of supplies.
Allen and Ben were the first
two people we ran into
when we finally crawled
up out of that hole
around Jacksonville.
Used to be a bunch of us.
25 at one point.
Our camp was overrun
six, seven weeks ago.
Tyreese:
And-- and Donna,
she, uh...
We'll see that she has
a proper burial.
I appreciate you
taking care of us.
For a while, we didn't know
who we were dealing with.
Neither did we.
We've had our problems
with people.
I must be the first
brother in history
to break into prison.
( Hershel chuckles )
Makes me the first white boy
that didn't want to break out.
( chuckles )
Tyreese.
Like I said, we have
a much larger group.
A close-knit group.
I wouldn't get
too comfortable here.
We wouldn't be a problem.
It's not up to me.
Then who?
Please, you can see
what kind of people we are.
( lock clicks )
Rick:
It won't work.
- Daryl: It's gotta.
- It'll stir things up.
Look, the Governor is probably on
the way to the prison right now.
Merle knows how he thinks
and we could use the muscle.
I'm not having him
at the prison.
Do you really want him sleeping in the
same cell block as Carol or Beth?
- He ain't a rapist.
- Well, his buddy is.
They ain't buddies no more.
Not after last night.
There's no way
Merle's gonna live there
without putting everyone
at each other's throats.
So you're gonna cut Merle loose and
bring the last samurai home with us?
She's not coming back.
She's not in a state
to be on her own.
- She did bring you guys to us.
- And then ditched us.
- At least let my dad stitch her up.
- She's too unpredictable.
That's right.
We don't know who she is.
But Merle, Merle's blood.
No, Merle is your blood.
My blood, my family
is standing right here
and waiting for us
back at the prison.
And you're part of that family.
But he's not.
He's not.
Man, y'all don't know.
Fine.
We'll fend for ourselves.
That's not what I was saying.
No him, no me.
Daryl, you don't
have to do that.
It was always Merle
and I before this.
- Maggie: Don't.
- Glenn: You serious?
- You're just gonna leave like that?
- You'd do the same thing.
What do you want us
to tell Carol?
She'll understand.
Say good-bye
to your pop for me.
Daryl, are you serious?
Daryl!
Hey. Hey.
There's got to be another way.
Don't ask me to leave him.
I already did that once.
We started something
last night.
You realize that, huh?
No him, no me.
That's all I can say.
Take care of yourself.
Take care of
lil ass-kicker.
Carl.
He's one tough kid.
Daryl!
Come on, bro.
We patch you up
and then you are gone.
Where'd they say
we could bury her?
Back of the field
near the other graves.
Hey.
Wait a minute.
Losing my grip here.
Come on, put her down.
Okay.
Golden opportunity.
For what?
Little kid and a woman.
Ask them for a hand,
get a hold of those weapons.
- What? - We do it quick, they'll
never know what hit them.
- No. Whoa, whoa.
- We're out here to bury Donna.
And we will, after.
- Shut up.
- Look at this place.
It's secure.
- These are good people.
- This will be easy.
A little kid, a woman, a girl
and a one-legged old man.
Don't forget about the convict.
You gonna smash the
baby's head with a rock?
- What is your problem?
- How about a little common decency?
This isn't what we do.
Allen: You're living
in the past, Ty.
So are you.
This is survival
of the fittest,
plain and simple.
In here we live, out there we die.
( gate opens )
And I am not waiting around
for the rest of their group
to roll in here and throw
us out on our asses.
- Not a chance.
- How do you know that's gonna happen?
Got some tools for you.
It's much appreciated.
Yeah, we'll take it from here.
You don't need no help
with the body?
No, we'll manage.
Let us know if you
need anything else.
Thank you.
( gate shuts )
Get the brakes.
( snarling )
I got it.
( grunting )
You didn't kill him.
That's not why we went back.
No. That's right.
You went back for Daryl.
And now he's gone again
and the Governor is still alive.
- Daryl was the priority.
- I should have been there with you.
- You were in no condition.
- But my girlfriend was?
- Glenn, this isn't about us.
- I should have been there.
Hey, hey, you didn't come back with
us 'cause you could barely walk.
- What about her?
- What about me?
- Do you know what he did to her?!
- Leave it alone!
- Do you know?
- Let's go.
After all that effort,
all the risk we took,
Daryl just takes off
with Merle?
Well, he had his reasons.
Yeah, you keep
telling yourself that, Rick.
Doesn't change the fact that
we're up to our necks in shit.
You want me to turn the car
around, beg him to come back?
Throw down a welcome mat
for Merle?
This is the hand
we've been dealt!
Let's just get this out
of here and get back.
Get some rest.
We can talk it out there.
No, you guys do all the
talking you want. I'm done.
( crowd shouting )
How many injured?
Nine.
Stevens has it covered.
So where is he?
- In his apartment.
- And?
He wouldn't open the door.
Said he was in the middle of something.
It's all going to hell.
( horn honking )
( clamoring )
Open the gate!
( horn honking )
( all shouting )
Calm down, people.
- Back away.
- It's not safe here. We want to leave.
- There's biters out here, lady.
- Let us out.
Get back!
( shouting continues )
I told you to get back.
- Nobody leaves.
- Hey, Martinez, we got biters.
All right, take them out.
( gunshots )
- Everybody calm down.
- We can't stay here anymore.
This place is crazy.
Please, you have to let us go.
Karen, you don't want to go out there.
It's too dangerous.
- Yeah, well, we'll take our chances.
- Karen: Please!
( horns honking )
- Hey!
- Hey, knock off the horn.
- Knock off that horn.
- Martinez!
- Get out of the car.
- Put the gun down.
- Hey. Hey. Hey.
Don't hurt him.
Hey, I don't take
orders from you.
These people are scared.
Shoving a gun in their face won't help.
- Where's the Governor?
- He's--
- There's a riot out here.
- You're making things worse.
I am?
( people screaming )
- Andrea: What the hell?
- Martinez: Move!
( snarling )
Get back, get back!
( groaning )
( gunshots )
( clicking )
( groaning )
Oh, my God.
Help him.
Somebody, please?
( groaning )
Help.
Karen:
Do something.
( door slams )
( birds chirping )
It's so quiet.
It's easy to forget how loud
the world used to be.
( laughs )
I used to complain
about it all the time.
Traffic, construction,
car alarms, noise pollution.
Oh.
What I wouldn't give
for the sweet sound
of a jumbo jet.
It'd be even sweeter
if we were all on it.
Your mom was proud of you.
For what?
Being mean to her?
No, you can't think about that.
It's all I think about.
( car approaching )
Please be them.
It's them.
Hurry.
- Drive 'em up. I'll meet you there.
- Maggie: Okay.
Thank God.
- Where's Hershel?
- He's in the cell block.
Carol:
Where's Daryl?
It's all right.
He's alive.
We ran into his brother.
They went off.
He left?
Daryl left?
He's gone?
Is he coming back?
- Hey.
- Gone?
And Oscar?
No.
( door opens )
( footsteps approaching )
What the hell was that?
You put a round in a man's head
in front of all those people
and just take off?
- You have to talk to them.
- Why?
They're panicking. They were ready
to charge through those gates.
So let 'em.
Those people won't last a day.
Those people have had it easy.
Barbecues and picnics.
That ends now.
Don't blame them for
the mess that you created.
They're scared.
Well, I'm through
holding their hands.
We're at war.
I should have seen that.
So why was Daryl here?
Was he part of the assault?
Why?
Why would he do that?
He came for his friends.
The other people you know.
Glenn and Maggie.
Merle scooped them up
on the run.
Was holding them to find out
where his brother was.
My-- my friends are still alive
and we're shooting at each other?
You're trying to execute them?
Your friends killed
six good people.
Crowley, Tim, Gargulio,
Eisenberg, Bob Adams.
Haley.
That man out there,
Rich Foster, he makes seven.
So that's what
your friends did.
Why didn't you
tell me they were here?
You kept that from me
while we were...
You're just a visitor here.
Just passing through.
So why should I tell you?
Don't do that.
Don't drive me out.
Not now.
( knocks ) What is it?
The whole town
is out on the street.
It could get ugly again.
Take your sister inside.
Go on.
You came through, like always.
Sounds like we have
a new problem on our hands.
- Yeah.
- You get a good look at him?
He had Daryl and Merle
pitted against each other.
A crowd cheering for them
to fight to the death.
What kind of a sick mind
does that?
The kind this world creates.
What's wrong?
The baby?
No, the baby, she's healthy.
Eats like a horse,
sleeps like a rock.
So what is it?
( door opens, closes )
Not exactly
a chatterbox, is he?
Be patient.
When he's ready,
let me do the talking.
She kind of has Lori's eyes.
Don't you think?
( crying )
( crying continues )
( clamoring )
Milton:
Everyone, if I could--
if I could have your attention.
- Everyone.
- All right, everybody shut up!
Thank you.
The biters on the perimeter
have been dispatched.
- The fences have been repaired.
- For now.
Where's the Governor?
( crowd murmuring )
His-- his condition is...
unsteady.
The wound he suffered--
- Our friends were killed, man.
- He shot Richard.
I mean, we've all suffered.
We want answers.
( all shouting )
You're right, Karen.
You're right.
Every one of us has suffered.
We don't even have
funerals anymore because
the death never stops.
We're never gonna be the same.
Ever.
So what do we do?
We dig deep and we find
the strength to carry on.
We work together
and we rebuild.
Not just the fences,
the gates, the community,
but ourselves.
Our hearts, our minds.
And years from now, when
they write about this plague
in the history books,
they will write about Woodbury.
- Yeah, they will.
- Woodbury.
We persevered.
( all agreeing )
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
( Judith fussing )
You've got a knack for that.
Just trying to do my part.
Sophia used to wake
the neighbors.
3:00 AM.
Like clockwork.
Ed stayed at a friend's most
nights till she calmed down.
I always wanted a child.
She wouldn't have made it
if Daryl hadn't been here.
He couldn't stand
to lose anyone else.
Sounds like him.
I don't see why
he had to leave.
Merle sounds like a jerk.
Men like Merle
get into your head.
Make you feel like
you deserve the abuse.
Even for Daryl?
I'm hardly the woman
I was a year ago,
but if Ed walked through
that door right now
breathing and told me
to go with him,
I'd like to think
I'd tell him to go to hell.
You would.
It doesn't matter.
We're weak without him.
We'll get through this, too.
Tyreese and his friends
seem capable.
I'm pissed at him for leaving.
Don't be.
Daryl has his code.
This world needs men like that.
( Judith crying ) ( chuckles )
Oh. Hello.
- There.
- She fits perfect.
Yeah.
Wait.
You cozy in there?
Yes.
You got worked over good.
Surprised no bones were broken.
It's courtesy
of Daryl's brother.
You two all right?
Thanks for looking out for her.
If anything...
I'll go check on her.
You need something else?
Okay.
Same thing goes for you.
If anything worse than this
had happened to you...
You're like my own son, Glenn.
You got something
needs looking at?
Is Glenn all right?
Go see.
You two seem to be
holding something back.
You want to tell me
what happened?
I rest easy knowing
you can handle yourself.
You've got
your mother's spirit.
And her stubbornness.
You hungry?
No.
Hey.
Don't disappear on me.
She's out like a light.
Must be days since she slept.
You look pretty shot yourself.
How long before she can travel?
Have to keep an eye on her.
Pretty sure she has
a concussion.
Couple of days if she's up.
Whenever Tomas went off,
Oscar always stood up
for me, you know?
He was my friend.
He went out fighting.
So what now?
You think the Governor
will retaliate?
- Maggie: Yes.
- Glenn: Let him try.
Sounds like he's got
a whole town.
We're outnumbered
and outgunned.
We could use
some reinforcements.
( door opens )
I'm Tyreese.
Sasha, Allen, Ben.
How'd you get in?
Fire damage to the administrative
part of the prison.
Wall's down.
That side's completely
overrun with walkers.
How'd you get this far?
We didn't.
We lost our friend Donna.
Carl: They were lost
in the gyms.
- You brought them here?
- Hershel: He had no choice.
I'm sorry about your friend.
We know what that's like.
Hershel said you could
use some extra hands.
We're no stranger to hard work.
We'll go out and get our own
food, stay out of your hair.
You got a problem with another
group, we'll help with that, too.
Anything to contribute.
No.
Sasha:
Please.
It's like "10 Little
Indians" out there.
It's just us now.
No.
Hershel:
Let's talk about this.
- We can't just keep--
- We've been through this.
With Tomas, Andrew.
Look what happened.
- Carol: Axel and Oscar weren't like them.
- And where's Oscar now?
I can't be responsible.
You turn us out,
you are responsible.
Hershel: Rick.
You've done so much for us.
I appreciate that.
We all do.
We owe you our lives.
We've done everything you asked
without question.
And I'm telling you,
you're wrong on this.
You've got to start
giving people a chance.
( sighs )
Yeah.
No, no.
No, no, no, no.
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Why are you here?
- What do you want from me?
- Dad?
Why are you-- no.
I can't help you.
Get out!
- Tyreese: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Get-- get out!
Tyreese: Hey, come on.
Whoa, it's all good.
Sasha:
What are you doing?
Hey, easy, Rick.
There's no need to--
You don't belong here!
Get out! Please!
- Relax, brother. Relax.
- Get out! Get out!
Tyreese: We'll leave.
We're going.
Okay? Ain't nobody
got to get shot here.
- We're going.
- What are you doing here?!
- Okay, we're going.
- Just go! Go! Go!
Come on, come on.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com