Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
If you wanna kill me, you're gonna
have to do better than a wrench.
He's just a kid!
We reconvene at sunset,
then what happens, happens.
Isn't there anybody else
who's gonna stand with me?
- This is a young man's life!
- Do it.
Take him away.
Do something!
Sorry, brother.
Rick's voice: Dale could--
could get under your skin.
He sure got under mine,
because he wasn't afraid to
say exactly what he thought,
how he felt.
That kind of honesty is rare
and brave.
Whenever I'd make a decision,
I'd look at Dale.
He'd be looking back at me
with that look he had.
We've all seen it
one time or another.
I couldn't always read him,
but he could read us.
( Whistles )
Rick: He saw people
for who they were.
He knew things about us--
The truth...
Who we really are.
In the end, he was talking
about losing our humanity.
( Walkers growling )
He said this group was broken.
The best way to honor him
is to unbreak it.
Set aside our differences
and pull together,
st feeling sorry for ourselves
and take control
of our lives...
- Our safety...
- ( Grunts )
...our future.
We're not broken.
We're gonna prove him wrong.
From now on...
We're gonna do it his way.
That is how we honor Dale.
( Shane, Andrea grunt )
( All grunting )
( Theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Rick: It'll be tight,
14 people in one house.
Hershel:
Don't worry about that.
With the swamp hardening,
the creek drying up...
With 50 head of cattle
on the property,
we might as well be ringing
a damn dinner bell.
She's right.
We should've moved you
in a while ago.
All right, let's move the
vehicles near each of the doors
- facing out toward the road.
- Just leave it there.
Rick: We'll build a
lookout in the windmill,
another in the barn loft.
That should give us sightlines
both sides of the property.
T-Dog, you take the perimeter
around the house.
Keep track of everyone
coming and going.
What about standing guard?
I need you and Daryl
on double duty.
Gotcha.
I'll stock the basement
with food and water,
enough that we can all survive
there a few days if need be.
- What about patrols?
- Let's get this area locked down first.
After that,
Shane'll assign shifts
while me and Daryl take Randall
offsite and cut him loose.
We're back to that now?
It was the right plan
first time around.
Poor execution.
( Laughs ) That's a
slight understatement
you don't agree, but this
what's happening.
Swallow it--
Move on.
You know that Dale's death
and the prisoner--
that's two separate
things, right?
You wanna take Daryl
as your wingman,
be my guest.
- Thank you.
- You got it.
- ( Truck door closes )
- ( Motorcycle revving )
Hershel: I see why you're
not taking Shane with you.
Just know I've got
no more patience
where he's concerned.
He's turning over a new leaf.
Andrea.
When I'm out with Daryl,
help Hershel keep an eye
on things around here.
- Me
- Shane's got a way
of letting things
get out of hand,
especially when
he's all torqued up.
I think we're all a bit
torqued up at this point.
If you're staying here permanently,
he's got to understand
that it's what Rick and I
say, not whatever he wants.
- You've become close.
- We talk.
Then you know
he's not a bad guy.
He's just his own worst enemy.
You want me to babysit Shane?
( Sighs ) I need to make sure
every time I leave the farm
all hell doesn't break loose.
Then maybe
you should stop leaving.
- Will you keep an eye on things?
- Of course.
( Squeaking )
- Hey, Shane?
- What's up, man?
What you doing, wandering
around by yourself?
If, um--
If I tell you something,
will you promise
not to tell my parents?
I think it's probably a bad
idea for both of us, bud.
( Sighs )
Hey, Carl.
Come on back.
Go on.
- ( Gun rattles )
- I took it from Daryl's motorcycle.
If he found out I took it,
he'd kill me.
( Sighs )
What you doing with this?
Dale. It's my fault
that he died.
Carl, why would you say that, man?
He got bit by a walker.
- Why you say--
- I saw that walker.
I was gonna shoot it.
( Sighs )
When he was stuck in the mud.
I was-- I was throwing
rocks at him and stuff.
But I was gonna do it--
shoot it right in the head.
And it-- it got free,
came after me and...
I ran away. If I had killed
it, Dale would still be here.
Carl, I want you
to stop that, okay?
This ain't your fault.
But you need to hold onto this.
You need to protect yourself.
As long as I'm around you, nothing's
gonna happen to you, Carl.
But I can't keep my eyes on you 24/7.
Only you can do that.
- Carl, take it.
- I'm never touching another gun again.
That ain't no option,
Carl, okay?
Just give it back to Daryl.
( Car approaching )
( Engine stops )
( Squeaking )
( Breathing heavily)
( Grunting )
( Nails rattle )
The men are in there.
You can put your stuff
upstairs in my room.
With your dad in the house?
I just-- I'm just gonna
put my stuff over there.
( Sighs )
Whoa. Don't-- don't--
Don't strain yourself.
Thank you.
Rick and Carl and I are taking
the corner of the living room.
You can put that in my room.
You'll be
more comfortable there.
- We can't do that. - A pregnant
woman and child sleeping on the floor
- while I've got a bed to myself?
- This is still your house.
It's our home.
I'll take the couch downstairs.
On nights when I came
home reeking of bourbon,
my wife would lock
the bedroom door.
I'm sad to say that couch
and I become old friends.
Look, if you two can't
decide, I'll take it.
Thank you.
The couch is mine.
( Muttering )
It's gonna get real cozy
real fast in here.
( Distant hammering )
Wouldn't that be easier
if you waited for some help?
Ain't no use waiting for
something that ain't gonna come.
No, I'll just--
( grunts )
Just do it all myself.
Yeah, you always do,
just like that time you showed
up Rick fixing our sink.
( Laughs ) Yeah.
Just so you know, that's not the
reason your basement flooded.
You can thank Rick
for that--
Using rubber washers
with a metal pipe.
Please come down.
So after Sophia, I, uh...
I thought
"We'll figure this out."
You know, we'll heal somehow.
After Dale?
This is real.
And we can't...
Keep it at bay.
It's already got us.
And it just
keeps coming, doesn't it?
I made a mess of things.
I put you and Rick at odds.
I don't even know
whose baby this is.
I can't imagine
how hard that is on you.
You led us out of Atlanta
with no thought for yourself.
( Crying ) Do you
remember that night?
The flames, the--
And I'm sitting in our car
thinking "We're gonna
be all right.
He's gonna make it all right.
We'll get out of here."
And I never
thanked you for that.
Even though things got...
( Chuckles )
Confused between us,
you were there for me.
You were there for me.
Thank you.
You don't need
to thank me for that.
- Of course I do. Of course I do.
- No, you--
Whatever happened between us,
whatever the hell
we thought it was--
And not just you, but--
I'm sorry, Shane.
Please believe me.
I am so sorry.
Take him out to Senoia--
hour there, hour back,
give or take.
We may lose the light,
but we'll be halfway
ho by then.
This little pain in the ass
will be a distant memory.
Good riddance.
Carol's putting together
some provisions for him,
enough to last a few days.
That thing you did
last night--
Ain't no reason you should
do all the heavy lifting.
- So are you good with all this?
- ( Engine stops )
- ( Car door opens )
- I don't see you and I trading haymakers
on the side of the road.
Nobody'd win that fight.
I'm gonna take a piss.
Hey, man, you seen Carl lately?
He's inside with his mother.
Look, he came to me.
Okay, I wasn't supposed
to say anything,
but he was out
in the swamps yesterday
and he came across a walker
stuck in the mud.
He got scared, ran off.
The same walker
that killed Dale?
That's the one.
- I'll have Lori talk to him.
- Look, man, I think--
I think he wants
to talk to his father.
Well, I need this Randall
thing done already.
Man, that needs to wait, okay?
It's my call.
How about
I ride out with Daryl?
Good for us to spend
a little time together.
Nah, I need you here.
Don't think
I'll handle it right, huh?
- Didn't say that.
- What you say?
You know, your son--
He gave me this.
You should get that
back to Daryl, huh?
Freeing that prisoner...
( Chuckles )
More important to you
than Carl.
( Engine cranks )
Andrea. Hey, did you try
pumping the gas pedal?
I think it's
been parked too long.
You gotta tap it three times...
And give her a twist.
I know, know.
- ( Sighs )
- ( Engine cranks )
Let me see.
- ( Keys )
- ( Thuds )
Uh, Dale told me that
in these old vehicles
the points get corroded.
Screwdriver?
Flathead.
( Softly ) Okay.
( Rattling )
Could you hand me a file?
( Scraping )
I let him down.
He was proud of you.
Maybe not in that moment,
but overall.
Oh, that's easy for you to say.
You had his back.
I have my share of regrets,
but I think that he knew
how much we cared for him.
( Crying )
That might do it.
Glenn.
( Keys jingle )
Bet it'll work.
( Engine starts )
( Hammers pounding )
Mom said you'd be here.
( Sighs ) Told her I
would stand lookout.
I got tired of helping
around the house.
( Gun rattles ) Take it.
What happened to Dale
had nothing to do with you.
He-- he died, dad.
Yeah.
Feels like there's a lot
of that going around.
That's why I need you.
No more kid stuff.
I wish you could have
the childhood I had,
but that's not gonna happen.
People are gonna die.
I'm gonna die. Mom.
There's no way you can
ever be ready for it.
I try to be, but I can't.
The best we can do now is
avoid it as long as we can,
keep one step ahead.
I wish I had
something better to say,
something--
Something more profound.
My father was good like that.
But I'm tired, son.
Please take it.
( Lock clicks )
( Wind blowing )
- ( Thuds )
- ( Muffled yelp )
( Breathing deeply )
( Pants, inhales deeply )
( Handcuffs rattle )
( Grunts, moaning )
- ( Chuckles )
- ( Moans )
Only got so many arrows.
Is that Dale's gun?
- ( Clicks )
- Yeah.
Wish I knew where
the hell mine is.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- I'll get the package.
- Thanks.
Yo, Randy.
Governor called.
You're off the hook.
Oh, hell no.
- ( Leaves rustling )
- ( Randall panting )
Shane: Shh!
Go that way.
Go on, go on.
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
Hey-hey, come on. Come on.
I get it. I'm the last face you
probably want to see, huh?
Listen, I'm gonna take you
up out of here, okay?
I'm gonna get this off
of you so you can breathe,
but I want you to keep quiet.
- You listen good. Do you hear me? Okay.
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
- Don't do nothing stupid.
- ( Moans )
Shh-shh-shh-shh-shh-shh.
( Whimpers )
Hey-hey, keep it quiet
now your group--
you know where they're at?
- No, I don't. I really-- oh!
- Okay.
Get your little ass up here.
Now I'm the only shot
of you getting out of these woods alive.
You hear me?
Now you start talking, boy.
Where are they at?
We had a camp
set up off the highway...
- Okay.
- ...About five miles from here.
- Shh-- Okay.
- Who knows if they're still there?
Okay. So you gonna
take me to 'em?
Why?
Because, man, I--
I'm just--
I'm done with this group, man.
They doomed and I want
no part of it.
- That's all.
- So you're not gonna kill me?
Come on, man. If I was,
you'd be dead. Come on.
Hey, you ain't
gotta be so rough.
We're on the same side now.
You're gonna like it with us.
Gets a little crazy sometimes,
but it's a tough bunch of guys.
You'll fit in good.
Less talking, more walking.
Look, I run my mouth
when I get nervous.
I can't help it.
I got a lot going on, you know?
It ain't all about you.
I-- I ain't saying
it's about me.
Just trying to--
- ( Screams )
- ( Snaps )
( Thuds )
( Thuds, grunts )
( Panting )
- Lori: What's wrong?
- Glenn: Randall's missing.
Lori:
Missing? How.
Hershel:
How long's he been gone?
- Woman: What's goin' on?
- Hershel: It's hard to say.
The cuffs are still hooked.
- He must' slipped 'em.
- Is that possible?
It is if you've got
nothing to lose.
The door was secured
from the outside.
( Shouting )
Rick! Rick!
- What happened?
- He's armed!
- He's got my gun!
- Carl: Are you okay?
I'm fine. Little bastard
just snuck up on me.
- He clocked me in the face.
- All right, Hershel, T-Dog,
get everybody
back in the house.
Glenn, Daryl, come with us.
- T, I'm gonna need that gun.
- Carol: Just let him go.
That was the plan, wasn't it,
to just let him go?
The plan was to cut him
loose far away from here,
not on our front step
with a gun.
Don't go out there.
Ya'll know what can happen.
Get everybody back
in the house.
Lock all the doors
and stay put!
- Let's go, back in the house.
- Okay.
I saw him head up through the trees
that way before I blacked out.
I'm not sure how long.
He couldn't have gotten far.
He's hobbled, exhausted.
- Glenn: And armed.
- Rick: So are we.
- Can you track him?
- No, I don't see nothing.
Hey, look, there ain't no
use in tracking him, okay?
He went that way.
We need to pair up.
We spread out, we just
chase him down. That's it.
Kid weighs
a buck-25 soaking wet.
You trying to tell us
he got the jump on you?
I say a rock pretty much
evens those odds, wouldn't you?
Alright, knock it off. You and Glenn
start heading up the right flank.
Me and Shane'll take the left.
Remember, Randall's not
the only threat out there.
Keep an eye out for each other.
( Crickets chirping )
Looks like
it's busted pretty bad.
It's fine, man.
Don't worry about me.
( Sighs )
This is pointless.
You got a light?
( Irritated sigh ) Come on.
Glenn: We're just
back to square one.
If you're gonna do a thing,
you might as well do it right.
There's two sets
of tracks right here.
Shane must've followed him
a lot longer than he said.
There's fresh blood
on this tree.
There's more tracks.
Looks like they're
walking in tandem.
( Animal calls )
Sorry.
Yeah, there was
a little dust up right here.
- Glenn: What do you mean?
- I mean something went down.
It's getting weird.
Had a little trouble.
( Rustling )
( Whistles softly )
( Growling )
( Gurgles )
( Both panting )
Daryl: Oh.
Nice.
Does this way feel right?
As right as any.
- Snatched your gun, huh?
- Yeah.
It's my favorite piece too.
Gonna wish he'd--
Wish he'd killed me
when I find his sorry ass.
Go on.
He's got no bites.
Yeah, none you can see.
No, I'm telling you
he died from this.
How's that possible?
( Crickets chirping )
Rick: You say he got
you with a rock?
That's what I said.
Inside the shed?
'Cause that door was shut
when T-Dog rolled up.
I saw that too.
Must've slipped through
the rafters in the roof.
So this is where
you planned to do it?
It's a good place as any.
At least have the balls
to call this what it is--
( Gun rattles )
Murder.
You really believe if you walk
back onto that farm alone--
- No me, no Randall--
- I want you to hush up.
You really believe they're gonna buy
whatever bullshit story you cook up?
That's just it.
It ain't no story.
I saw that prisoner
shoot you down.
I ran after him.
I snapped his neck.
It ain't gonna be easy,
but Lori and Carl--
They'll get over you.
They done it before.
They just gonna have to.
( Exhales deeply )
Why?
Why now?
I thought we worked
this all out.
( Laughs ) We tried to
kill each other man.
What you think?
We just gonna forget about it all?
We gonna ride off
into the sunset together?
You're gonna kill me
in cold blood?
Screw my wife?
Have my children--
my children--
call you daddy?
Is that what you want?
That life won't
be worth a damn.
I know you.
You won't be able
to live with this.
What you know about
what I can live with?
You got no idea what I can
live with, what I live with!
You wanna talk about
what I can do, Rick?
How about what you can do?
Here I am.
( Pants ) Come on, man.
Raise your gun.
- No. No, I will not.
- What happened, Rick?
I thought you weren't the good guy
anymore. Ain't that what you said?
Even right here, right now, you
ain't gonna fight for 'em?
I'm a better father
than you, Rick.
I'm better for Lori
than you, man.
It's 'cause I'm a better
man than you, Rick.
'Cause I can be here
and I'll fight for it.
You come back here and you
just destroy everything!
You got a broken woman.
You got a weak boy.
You ain't got the first clue
on how to fix it.
Raise your gun.
You're gonna have
to kill an unarmed man.
Watch my hand.
Nice and easy.
Easy does it.
Now listen to me, Shane.
There is still
a way back from this.
Nothing has happened here.
We're gonna lay down our guns
and we're gonna walk
back to the farm...
Together.
Back to Lori.
Back to Carl.
Put this all behind us.
- ( Shane grunting )
- ( Gun fires )
Rick: Shh.
( Gurgling )
Damn you for making me
do this, Shane.
This was you, not me!
You did this to us!
This was you,
not me-- not me!
Not me!
( Exhales )
( Crying )
( Wailing )
Son of...
( Growls )
( Rick breathing heavily )
Carl: Dad?
Carl.
You know...
You should be
back home with mom.
( Gun clicks )
Just-- just put the--
Put the gun down.
( Snarts )
It's not what
it seems. Please.
( Walkers growling )
Wait-wait-wait-wait.
( Theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com