Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
*
Zenithoptera lanei.
Look at that. Just gorgeous
adaptations for flight.
The only thing I know
this blue in nature
are my wife's eyes
first thing in the morning.
There's magic out there.
There is magic out there.
Oh! There's magic out there.
You get that?
There's a finless porpoise
that swam right up to me.
Tell me you got it.
- Yes, we got it.
- Got it, dad.
Lincoln, how great was that?
Did you see it?
Yes.
Got it?
There is magic out there.
We're filming a species
that perhaps no one
has ever seen before.
Lincoln, come here.
All right, okay, cut.
Cut.
We'll see you next week, I hope.
Explorer, naturalist,
and beloved television host
Emmet Cole
has been reported missing.
He was a wonderful character.
He was
a passionate environmentalist.
Cole and his documentary crew
were last seen
on the Amazon
onboard their ship the "Magus."
Rescue teams have searched
the Amazon for weeks,
but with no sign.
And his death is tonight
being mourned around the world.
As a kid, I used to watch
my father on TV,
and the voice would come up,
"Next week, Emmet Cole
may not survive
what he finds in the cave."
I'd be terrified
he wouldn't come home.
He always did.
Well, today...
We give up hope.
Thanks for joining us
on "The Undiscovered Country."
I'm Emmet Cole.
We'll see you next week.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Let's get
that mike fixed, shall we?
We shouldn't be doing this
to him.
Yet here we are.
He's my son.
*
Tequila.
That's your dad's drink.
Yeah, it's his day.
Why are they following you?
Come on, guys.
Enough with the cameras.
I just buried my father.
You didn't bury him.
Mom, we said good-bye, okay?
We let go.
Why weren't you there?
'Cause he's not dead.
We've had this conversation,
okay? He's legally dead.
He's actually dead.
I wish he wasn't, but he is.
Lincoln--
Mom, I'm fine.
You know what? I've gotten
pretty used to him being gone.
I had a lot of practice
waiting for him to come back
from Kenya or Peru
for my birthday, my graduation.
I mean, you were there, right?
You'd bake a cake
and you'd tell me not to be sad
because dad was here in spirit.
So you know what?
To me, this just feels like
another birthday.
This is different.
They found his beacon.
4:08 P.M. yesterday.
The emergency signal--
His personal frequency.
After six months.
That doesn't mean that that--
I mean, that could be
anything, right?
Well, it could be him.
We can find his ship.
We can find him.
I need you to come with me,
Lincoln.
No, no, mom, listen to me.
Look, I'm going back to school
in a week, okay?
I start my residency
in Chicago.
They accepted my research.
I can finish my PhD.
You never know.
I might even make you proud.
Lincoln, wait. Wait.
Your father needs you.
No.
I gave enough to him,
to that show.
He missed my life
to inspire a billion people
I could give a fuck about.
There's no magic out there.
I'm not going.
I'm not getting involved.
They won't pay if you don't go.
The network says it's both of us
or no show.
That's the deal.
We pay for the expedition
for as long as it takes
to find him,
but we get full, unfettered
access to both of you.
They know dad and I
hated each other.
That's why we want you.
Clark.
Please.
Angel.
Come with me.
So, Lincoln, tell us
about your relationship
with your father.
Go fuck yourself.
He'll come around.
Hi there. I'm on the Amazon.
Not a lot of other Jews
out here, though.
There's a storm
coming out of Tefe.
Don't throw up.
100 kilometers.
We're close.
This is not
a ship. This is a boat.
The "Magus"-- She is a ship.
I sail her for Doc 23 years.
A year ago, Doc is
fueling up for the Amazonas,
and he says to me,
"Emilio, you no go on this trip.
Go home."
I say, "Doc... fuck you.
This is my home."
Now I understand.
He wanted to protect me.
But it was just
another expedition, right?
Why did he want to protect you?
Because of my daughter.
God hates me. I know.
Or he would have made her ugly.
Hello there. Hola.
So you can--
You can fix things?
Esos no son los
zapatos adecuados.
Sí. Uh, je m'apelle Sammy.
Escuelas americanas.
So we have to watch out
for the sand.
So when's high tide?
It's about 4:42.
That's four hours.
Uhh!
Oh! Uhh!
Caught him touching my guns.
Where we're headed, there may be
20 people in the world...
That can say I've seen worse
and not be lying to get laid.
People like Mrs. Cole--
They don't know how lucky
they are they hired me.
Stop the boat!
We found the beacon!
It's here!
Get in there. Get in there,
get in there, get in there.
- Here we go, here we go.
- Okay, where is it?
15 meters, right up here.
On the left.
Okay, stop it! Stop.
Where is it?
It's here.
All I got is river.
Okay. If it's here,
it's under the water.
It's here.
I know, but if it's here,
it's under the water.
His beacon. I'm sorry.
Well, we don't know
if he was in there.
We don't know he was in there.
Someone turned the signal on.
Someone-- Emmet--
wants our help.
The door-- The way it is broken,
something not try to break in.
Something... break out.
We got what we came for, mom.
We have an answer.
Come on. Let's just go home.
No.
We keep going.
We don't even have a direction.
I'll find one.
Medico.
Sí, le duele.
- Mm. ¿Te duele?
- Sí.
Espérate, ya está.
¿Bueno aquí, señor?
Very strong. It's good.
Lena, you shouldn't be here.
You shouldn't be here.
Lena...
No.
I modeled tide patterns
from the beacon's location.
I came up with six probables,
and the first five were empty,
but this was the sixth.
Here. 55 kilometers west. Look.
There's nothing there, Lena.
There's no river for the boat
to be on.
It's not on the map.
It doesn't exist.
I'm telling you,
a boat doesn't just disappear.
It's there. It has to be,
and they will be there--
My dad and Emmet.
It's the only possible place.
Then we go there.
Tell the crew.
No.
Eso es la Boiúna.
No podemos ir para allá.
Tell the crew.
Up here on the left.
I thought for sure I'd hear
from you at some point
after they went missing.
Sorry. Just school.
The lab.
That all sounds
rather boring--
I mean, compared
to your father's work.
Yeah, well,
that's the point, Clark.
Science isn't
a great, big wonder anymore.
Discoveries are made in a lab,
not the jungle.
Okay, that was pretty cool.
That's her.
Hello?
Emmet?!
Dad?!
Hello?! Is anyone here?
What the hell was...
Hello?!
That was from inside.
Someone's in the ship.
Emilio!
Hey.
Get the gennie running.
We need some lights.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hello? Is anyone here?
It's coming
from the panic room.
Go, go, go, let's go.
Come on. Move.
We made the safe
into a panic room
in case of hijackers.
Emmet, is that you?
Listen to me. I'm here!
They can be in there.
Open it.
It closes from the inside.
Yeah, well, it's welded shut
from the outside
- all the way around.
- Why would somebody do that?
Emmet.
I'm gonna get you out,
all right? Emmet?
I'm gonna get you out.
I'm here.
Okay, what have we got?
Look at the state of this place.
- Yeah, it's not pretty, is it?
- Oh, my God.
That's-- that's good.
Power's back on.
Oh, good.
Ship's cameras back up.
Can you believe it?
That's very nice.
AJ, can you stop
farting around, please?
Get the rest of it.
I want every inch of this boat
covered, all right?
And we might even get a view
into the panic room.
And get the editing bay up
live, too.
We can log it all.
We can cut as we go, all right??
Now please, excuse me.
Trying to make a TV show.
- It's working. It's working.
It's very nice. AJ. - Yeah?
We're in business.
Come on.
Lovely.
No deberían de abrirlo, papá.
Well, people always tell me that
the reason they loved
Emmet's show
was not because of the travel
or the adventure
but because
they wanted to be part
of our own perfect
little family.
I mean, yeah,
we had our problems.
Everybody does, sure.
Our secrets.
But... who doesn't?
We're in.
Go on.
Pull it.
Get it!
Ohh!
Ohh.
Hello?
Oh, my God.
Dad?
What is that?
Lincoln, no!
Aah! Uhh!
Bloody hell!
What the fuck was that?
One night, Jahel--
She come to me.
I'm upstairs playing cards
with Doc.
And she said to me,
"Papa, come.
Ghost friend--
Tell him to be quiet."
I think
it's one of the new crew
is bothering my daughter,
so I go get my gun.
I say, um, "Which man is it?"
She said, "No, no es man.
Es ghost friend.
Tell him to be quiet, papi."
So I say,
"Ghost friend, be quiet."
Couple of days go by,
and I ask her if these voices
are still bothering her,
and she say, "No. No bother.
Ghost friend
talk more quiet now."
No me gusta este
amigo fantasma.
No! No!
We need to keep pressure
on that.
- You're gonna be okay.
- Put your arm around her.
- It's okay.
Come on.
AJ, get the medkit.
She's bleeding!
Put the damn camera down
and get the kit!
Mm.
That's it. Just breathe in.
You're okay. You're okay.
One more.
How bad is it?
Well, know how you used
to think scars were sexy?
You're about to be much sexier.
Remember when we used to play
hide-and-seek on this boat?
And you could never find me.
I mean, typical, right?
I used to try and camo myself,
and that one time
I picked the wrong vine.
And I got covered in hives.
And you didn't come near me
for, like, a week.
No way.
You thought I looked like
the boogeyman.
You did.
And you know I had it
all over my face.
That was kinda funny.
You remember what my dad said?
- What'd he say?
- He said you're trouble.
Well...
There may be something to that.
Hey, AJ.
Yeah.
Thanks for the help, man.
She was hurt.
What, you think I'm a fireman?
I don't save people, man.
Hell with him. I got the shot.
No excrement.
That was no animal.
What is this?
Some kind of shrine
or something?
They left the food out.
Who's that?
- Holy cow, you scared me.
- No me gusta being scared,
little girl.
Sangre.
These mean anything to anyone?
Yeah, these are pictures
of Cam Travers,
one of our producers.
Emmet insisted on bringing him
on this one instead of me.
He was a son of a bitch.
The only decent thing about him
was his wife.
You think Travers is dead?
Before they went missing,
Emmet said that
Travers caught a fever
and that he didn't make it.
They buried him out here.
You spoke to Emmet?
From here?
He just had some questions
about how to back up files.
He was always afraid
of a server crash.
Emilio, all that time
you sailed with my father,
you ever see anything
like that?
Any idea what it could be?
Before he fired me,
your father started to spend
a lot of nights off of the ship,
all night, by himself.
No food, no gear.
I told Doc
I start to worry about him.
He said, "Don't."
He's protected.
By a gun?
By magic.
Papá, él no cree.
Cuéntale.
Mira. Sangre.
Wh--
- Cállate, niña.
- What's she saying?
You know what that thing was?
It's okay.
You can tell me.
No es un animal.
Es Corpo Seco.
It was not an animal.
It was Corpo Seco.
The dry spirit.
A soul so bitter,
the ground would not take him.
And the devil sent him back,
so he wanders, looking for blood
to make it whole.
More blood, more strength.
Well, are you talking
about some kind of ghost?
El féretro del niño.
Coffin for the child.
This is kraho,
from the chonta palm.
Full of tsarutuma. Holy.
The shamans use it
to catch the angry soul.
Your father used blood
to lure the spirit.
They caught it inside,
but we opened it.
...Sangre de Lena.
We fed it with Lena's blood.
Now it's strong enough.
To what?
Hey. We're going right now.
Pack what you need.
Everyone on the rafts.
Well, hang on a minute.
What are you talking about?
We're not safe.
Someone's out there.
I don't know if it's an animal
or a guy on drugs
or just the fucking crew's
on drugs.
But people died here,
and we could be next.
I am not leaving this close
to finding your father.
Someone welded the door shut.
Someone survived.
You're captain here.
It's your call.
I already lost my father
to this place.
I'm not losing the two of you.
Let's go home.
Out here!
Out here! The rafts!
Lincoln, I don't know
what happened.
I came out to see if
they were okay,
and someone must have
slashed them or something.
There's no way to fix that.
Where's the other one?
What?
- Over there!
- Can we get it?
No, the current's got it.
It's long gone.
- Did you do this? Huh?
- What?
- Of course I didn't.
- Then who did?
I have no--
No nos va a dejar irnos.
Hasta que no tenga la sangre suficiente.
We gotta get the hell
outta here.
We don't know
what that is, okay?
We don't know.
And we don't have any way
to leave, so...
Yes, we do.
This. The "Magus."
Emilio,
how long to get us moving?
I gotta get one
of our engines working.
I have to reattach
the rudder line.
I have to reseal the hull.
Two days.
All right, you got
two and a half hours.
Just work the engine.
Keep us alive
long enough to fix
the rest, okay?
We gotta be moving by 4:43.
- And what happens then?
- High tide.
Look, we get one
chance to shove her out.
I'll clear the propeller.
Everyone else, eyes open.
You might need this.
He's starting
to sound like his father.
Papá.
This place-- It gets to you.
You know, everything
I've ever studied tells me
we're all caught up
in group hysteria.
But what we saw,
what hurt you...
If that's anything other,
if that's something unnatural,
we need to know more,
or we're not gonna make it.
Nature's just disgusting.
Lincoln...
There's something
you need to see.
Emmet made me promise that if
anything ever happened to him,
I was supposed to find
these tapes and destroy them,
but... there might be something
on these that could help us.
This is his journal.
These are the originals.
He sent me backups, all encoded,
so I don't know what's on them,
but... what he told me.
The engine's dead.
It's killed half the crew.
There are four of us left.
Corpo Seco.
It's Cam Travers.
I know it's impossible.
We buried him.
It's this place.
It's trying to kill us.
So he thought that ghost
was one of their own crew?
This Cam Travers--
He killed them.
Now... he's coming after us?
The kraho carve
these-- these soul traps,
and Landry and I are gonna try
and just draw it in.
It's our only chance.
It's the only chance.
"There's magic out there."
He was looking for real magic.
Well, it looks like
he bloody found it.
And he didn't tell you
about any of this?
I shouldn't have let him go.
Pop another tape in,
would you, AJ?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
We're so close to the source.
And we have to keep going.
We have to.
And the further
we go off the Boiuna,
the more-- The more physics
breaks down.
Reality gets so much...
Bigger.
I have to see it.
We just got a second season.
Hey, mom.
It's dangerous, you know?
You shouldn't be out here
in the open.
All that time,
he was on some quest,
and he didn't tell me.
Come on. You two had your
secrets from each other, right?
No, Lincoln, we didn't.
Oh, enough with the act, mom.
The show is over.
We weren't a perfect family.
I mean, he wasn't perfect.
I sure as hell wasn't,
and you-- I mean, you had--
What about me?
Not even.
Lincoln, don't you walk
away from me.
You come here and you tell me
how I wasn't perfect enough
for you.
You know what?
I'm not a kid anymore.
All those years, you were
his partner, his captain.
And all of a sudden,
he goes off without you?
And you let him?
I always was curious.
Who was it anyway?
- Huh? - It's none of your business,
Lincoln. Don't even--
You made my life
the whole world's business.
You cheated on dad
with someone else,
so he cheated on you
with his work.
That is not fair, Lincoln.
Stop it.
You know, and maybe that's why
he went nuts,
looking for something
to believe in,
because he sure as hell
couldn't believe in you.
You have no idea
what our lives were.
Sure, I do.
I know why you're out here
in the middle of a jungle,
willing to get yourself killed.
No one goes that far for love.
But guilt?
Sure, that'd get you
to the Amazon,
and you know what, mom?
You should feel guilty,
because you were the magic
in his life.
And when he lost you...
Good. The engine's working.
Let's go home.
¡Somos mejor que nadie!
Come on! Let's go! Mom!
Ohh!
It's working!
Turn it hard!
We're clear!
We're gonna make it!
Hey.
Hi.
One hour till sunrise,
two hours till the Yutay.
I think we can make it.
Yeah. Listen, Tess,
I-I keep thinking,
if that thing--
If it really is Cam Travers,
it could know about Emmet.
If he's dead... or alive.
Papá.
What the hell was that?
Okay.
Oh!
Where you going?
Getting a shot of it.
Lead cameraman.
There is a reason.
Where are you? Huh?
Where are you? Come on.
Show me your face.
You know what I think?
You haven't got the balls
to come out here.
Here you go.
Aah!
Oh, my God.
It's following us.
Get inside.
Damn it.
Oh, great.
Someone grew a pair.
Suck it. I'm getting the shot.
Watch out! It's here! Oh!
Fuck, fuck, that was close.
- Watch out! It's coming back!
- Ohh!
Uhh! Fuck oh, my God. Fuck.
It's Sammy. Sammy.
Sammy's dead.
What? What do you mean,
he's dead? What?
He's out there, and he's dead.
I don't know what happened--
- What the hell are you talking about?
- He was just there, and now he's gone.
- AJ!
- I don't give a fuck!
AJ! AJ, what are you--
Ohh!
It's going for the engines!
Come on! Get it going!
I...
The engine's dead!
Come on.
Come on!
The engine-- Can you fix it?
Si prueba demasiada sangre
no tenemos a dónde correr.
Lincoln, what are you doing?
Same thing my father did.
I'm gonna trap it.
Anything?!
Can you see it?!
Lincoln, what are you doing?!
No, no, no, wait! Wait!
Lincoln...
Come on...
Aah!
Uhh!
- Aah!
- Uhh!
Uhh!
Throw it overboard!
- Mom!
- Lincoln...
Mom, are you okay?
Watch out! It's coming back!
You shouldn't have
let him up there.
He made his choice.
Well, Emmet's tapes--
Golden ticket.
Mm.
Hundred of 'em.
What are you up to, Kurt?
Mess with my camera.
You bastard.
Missed one.
Gotcha.
Emmet Cole saw more
than we thought.
He may be alive if he is.
And if he found The Source,
I'll put him down.
How you feeling?
Fine.
AJ, give us a minute,
would you?
I thought I knew your father.
Me, too.
The last dated tape
shows him headed west,
towards the mountains.
But we don't have to do this.
We can go home.
No, mom, dad's alive.
You were right
to drag us out here.
We're gonna look through
every single one of those tapes.
We're gonna follow
every move he made
until we find him.
You sure?
You wanna give up everything
to believe it's some ghost?
Dad was on to something.
And you know what?
There is magic out there.
So let's go see it.
You know there's a camera
right there.
I know.
*
for all the magic
there is out there,
there's even more magic right
here at home with your family.
So from all of us
at "The Undiscovered Country"...
Happy holidays!
Bye!
Cut!
- Presents. Ready for presents?
- All right, here we go.
Okay! Merry Christmas!
Here you go.
Hey.
Here, Lena.
Just a little something
for you.
Yeah. Merry Christmas.
♪ and down the chimney
with old Saint Nick ♪
♪
Just put Marbeley down
for a second.
Okay, he can strum.
He-- he can play with him.
Just like Christmas
back home, eh?
He wanted to give Lincoln
a little bit of normal, Clark.
¡A toda máquina!
¡Ella vive!
Claro que sí está viva.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, mate.
- Oh, bollocks.
We need a new camera operator.
Yeah? Well, the last one got
his head taken off by a ghost.
So... good luck with that.
Hey, Jahel.
Había un agujero perforado en la cabeza del
cilindro que estaba derramando el aceite.
You're really not gonna learn
English ever, are ya?
Yeah.
Emmet's journal says that
he and my dad were right there.
But when?
A month ago? A year ago?
Before or after
they went missing?
We need to know
where they were last.
We need to establish
a time line.
What about Emmet's tapes?
He shot so much footage here.
If we could tie him visually
to a location--
Yeah, I've been trying, mom,
but there's 104 tapes,
and there's s no way to put them
in any kind of order.
About a month before
he lost contact with Emmet,
he told me that he had
a bug bite on his thumb
that got infected.
He couldn't get rid of it.
He asked me to research
some sort of medical treatment.
Well, how does that help us?
We track the bite on the tapes.
The worse the infection,
the later the date.
It could give us
some sort of direction.
One of the strays swam up.
He's refusing to leave the boat.
The camera. Yeah.
Yeah.
Put the next one in.
Okay, wait.
Hey, look at the bite there.
It's fresh, so that means that
tape must be from earlier.
Put the next one in.
Look.
See how bad the infection is?
Mm-hmm.
So this tape
must be more recent.
Great, so dad's tapes-- So far
we've got eight possible sites,
but any one of them could be
his last recording.
Well, that's more than we had
this morning.
Pick one,
and we'll start there.
Could be dangerous.
We should warn the crew.
Everyone on this boat
has been to the Amazon before.
Well, they haven't been here
to the Boiuna.
I mean, hell, according to
every map ever made,
this place doesn't even exist.
Come on. Anyone who doesn't want
to stay, we should let 'em go.
Excuse me.
Here's the reality, Lincoln.
You let Kurt go,
who's gonna protect us?
Hmm? Emilio and his daughter--
They keep the ship running.
Everyone is on this boat because
we need them to find Emmet.
You let any one of them go,
you're letting your father go,
too.
Tess?
¿Qué haces aquí?
You shouldn't have come here.
Not Jahel.
It's not Jahel.
Emmet?
It can't be you.
Tess, you need to let me go.
What?
They have me, Tess.
I'm not leaving you.
Who has you?
This place--
I shouldn't have come.
Save yourselves.
Take Lincoln and go.
Emmet!
Emmet! Emmet!
Lincoln!
It was him.
Tess...
I know my husband.
Sometimes when we want something
badly enough,
we can imagine it--
I did not imagine this...
Emilio, has, uh, Jahel ever done
anything like this before?
No.
So if somehow
that was your husband,
maybe you'd should listen
to him, turn around, go home.
If it was someone you loved,
could you just
leave them alone to die?
Yes.
And I have.
Well, I'm not going to.
Emmet gave us a lead.
He said, "they have me."
Mom, who's "they"?
We don't even know who that is.
- Who has him?
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
In all of Emmet's last tapes,
it shows him alone with his crew
except for one.
In it, he's, um...
In the mountains,
talking to some kind
of local militia.
Pull up that tape.
Let's find what piece of jungle
these guys call home.
All I need is a direction.
Clark, get your cameras ready.
We're gonna rescue Emmet Cole
today.
Just so we're clear,
a little girl
who talks to ghosts
says...
"Don't go,"
And we're going.
Yeah.
Emilio?
If Emmet-- Uh, if Jahel says
anything else, you radio me.
¿Entendiste?
Actually, a better idea--
Film it.
Come on.
AJ,
grab the camera. Let's go.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So you really think
that was Emmet channeling
through Jahel?
I know it was.
You should put the camera down,
watch where you're walking,
Clark.
You forget I did start life out
as a camera operat--
Ow!
Yeah, so carry on, carry on.
Emmet's alive,
and we're gonna find him.
And if we do, what's the first
thing you're gonna say to him?
I'm gonna tell him I'm sorry.
What are you talking about?
He's the one that left you
to go on this insane quest
to find magic.
- Shouldn't he be the one to apologize?
- Hey.
It-- It's all right, Lincoln.
Clark is incapable
of asking a question
without trying to get a rise.
Yes, Emmet left me.
We've all done things
we regret.
I know I have.
Thanks.
So you and my dad--
You talked a lot, huh?
Just when he needed help.
Research, technical support.
Or medical help.
Here we go.
Is that why
you're pissed at me?
- I'm-- I'm not pissed at you. I'm--
- Yes, you are.
No, I'm not.
You're pissed
because instead of coming
to his son
who graduated medical school,
he came to me.
He had a question,
and I was there.
There's something to that,
you know--
Being there
when people need you.
Be right back.
Don't separate.
Stay with the group!
I've got business.
Don't take too well to company.
Sorry, mate.
He and I need to talk.
Hold on.
You're not jungle.
Guys!
Why would there be
a graveyard out here?
I thought the locals
didn't bury in the ground.
They don't.
Wow. What is this?
"Sir Henry Nevins.
Hero to the crown."
It seems like sir Nevins and I
are both a long way from home.
"The tree that weeps."
British colonial rubber barons
came over in the 19th century.
Devastated the rain forests,
slaughtered the natives-- If they
didn't work them to death.
Mm. Made a fortune. That's what
they called playing hero.
Shh, shh, shh.
Did you hear something?
It's coming
from this way. Go!
Wait.
Mommy.
Hey.
What's that?
- Is that...
- Whoa.
Is that a child?
Hello?
Honey?
Hola, chiquita.
¿Estás sola?
Hey.
Hi.
Oh!
Jesus fucking Christ!
How the fuck does a monkey
get a doll's head out here?!
I think I can see how.
Oh, fuck.
I've heard about
places like these.
They're called spirit trees.
When locals believe that
the woods are home to a spirit,
they sometimes leave gifts.
Why dolls?
This is a graveyard.
Mom.
What is it?
Did you find something?
Oh, my God.
That's my bear, Marbeley.
How?
Emmet.
He must've been here.
He must have put the bear
in that tree.
We picked the right trail.
He must be close.
Sun's going down. We have to
camp here for the night.
Here? With all the dolls?
Oh, yes, please.
AJ, let's set up some cameras.
Let's mine this gold, okay?
High angles from the top--
Tree shots.
Way ahead of you.
Wait. No, no,
we can't stay here.
If we press on, we could
find Emmet by morning.
At night out here,
the only thing you will find
are ways to get killed.
We'll pick up his trail
in the morning.
This is not an option.
How many have you got set up?
- One, two...
- What else? Show me?
Three, four, five, six.
Mm.
Tess?
Mm-hmm?
- You okay?
- Yes.
Think we're gonna find Emmet
tomorrow? Or at all?
You know, Clark,
you've been on me all day.
Would you just give it a rest,
all right?
- You know, I just want a-- Just--
I just want a quick-- - Yeah, you--
- Give me a quick one.
- What do you mean?
- Come on, give it to me. Give it to me.
Pass it over. - What are you talking about?
Don't handle the camera
like that.
- Hang on.
- You focused?
- Yeah, hang on. I got it. Just-- just fix
your-- - Don't fuss with it. Come on.
All right, then.
What about you?
What are you doing here
in the middle of the jungle,
looking for Emmet?
Hmm.
That's a good question.
And do you really care
if we find him?
Wow. I forget how little
you think of me sometimes.
Here's the deal.
Everybody always thought that
Emmet and I hated each other.
You know? I mean, it's probably
'cause we spent so much time
arguing over every last frame
of the show.
But...
You know.
The thing with him
is that--
What he never got was that
the show, this whole thing,
it wasn't about adventure
or magic.
It's about product.
Right?
But he was, uh...
He was incorruptible,
wasn't he?
I did love that about him.
Here, give it back to me then.
Give it back to me.
Now... back to the real job.
Good night, Clark.
Night, Tess.
Hey, Lincoln.
Hey.
Long ago, when I was hiking
in Mali,
I met a man high up
in the Bandiagara cliffs--
A shaman who was
old as the hills
and said he would never die.
And he said to me,
"Life and death are the same,
like a weight on a clock.
That swings back and forth.
"Tick to tock."
Then he said the clock
was getting very old
and was waiting for someone
strong enough
to cut the weight
and stop the swing.
And all the time
he's telling me this,
that his old wife--
Who was also as old as the hills
and would never, ever die--
Was making...
This.
And she gave it to me
and she said
that one day,
I would meet a child
who was strong enough.
To do what?
Well, that's for the child
to know.
My place in things was that...
I would know the one
when I saw him.
And when I did,
I should give him this.
What if I lose it?
We never lose
the things that matter.
I'm-- I'm sorry.
It's just-- My dad and I,
we barely spoke
the year before he went missing.
My mom had no idea what
he was up to. But you?
You knew everything
he was doing.
Not everything.
Marbeley.
I remember this guy.
You used to carry him
everywhere.
Yeah.
We'd, uh, we'd watched
"A Christmas Carol."
Jacob Marley
was my favorite part.
"Marbeley."
First ghost you ever saw.
Yeah.
I thought you lost him
years ago.
I did.
When I was, uh, 16,
I pitched him
into the Indian ocean,
swore I'd never set foot
on the the "Magus" again.
Next day,
I left for boarding school.
Bit dramatic, in retrospect.
Your dad must've
gotten him back.
Or the doll tree
has friends in Sumatra.
Well...
When I was a little kid,
my whole life was this bear.
And my dad...
You know, he made me feel
like I was the only thing in
the whole world that mattered.
You know?
Like I was the light
in his life.
You know...
One day, that light went off.
I don't know why,
but nothing I could do
could flick it back on again.
You know?
I mean, I knew he loved me,
but...
Whatever quest he was on,
I wasn't on the map.
I know that you think there's
some reason that he came to me
instead of you or your mom.
But...
I...
I think he was just trying
to protect you.
He knew what he was doing
out here,
that he'd be inviting in...
Darkness.
He wouldn't ever risk
exposing you or Tess to that.
But me?
He could risk me.
All these dolls. I can't sleep.
Ah.
Actually, you're a good one.
You're like
Jane Austen's Binkie, aren't ya?
All right, well,
it's just you and me, Bink.
So just open those eyes for me.
Do it on camera just once.
That'd be fantastic. Yeah?
Please?
For Uncle AJ?
Yeah?
Come on.
Any spirits out there?
I dare you,
open that doll's eyes.
Go ahead. Bet you can't.
God, you're boring me now.
Come on. Do it.
I'm going to bed.
Aah! Oh!
- Uhh! Aah!
- Lincoln?
Lincoln!
- Get off me! Mom!
- What did-- What happened?
- Who grabbed me?!
- Grabbed? Everyone was sleeping.
Then how the hell
did I end up over here?
Huh? Huh?
Oh, this is...
Where you going?
Anywhere but here.
We're all leaving now.
You won't survive at night
in the jungle.
Yeah? Stop us.
This way. Let's go.
- Watch that rock.
- Yeah.
It's just a stream.
Don't worry about it.
Aah! Something grabbed me!
- Aah!
- Give me a rope!
Help me! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
Tess, hold on!
Clark, grab the camera!
Quick!
Get her out of there!
AJ! AJ, camera.
Are you okay?
Okay. Hmm?
Tómate esto.
No?
Tengo que aguantar...
Mm.
They won't.
I know what's out there.
I have to protect them.
From what?
Something--
Someone was grabbing me.
Okay.
So what you're saying then...
Is that
someone is in this stream
in-- what, less than...
half a foot of water?
Are you sure?
Easy on the lady, Clark.
I saw a hand grab her.
Stay out of this please, AJ.
I see a dead hand
reaching out of the ground,
I'm damn well staying in it.
I mean, we both pulled her out.
What do you think happened?
Like I said, thank you.
Wait. I remember we used to sit
around the campfire,
and Emmet...
He'd tell stories,
legends from wherever we were.
And there's this one
from the Amazon.
La dejada--
The abandoned one.
Do you remember?
Mnh-mnh.
There's a little girl
from far away
whose mother was too busy
for her...
So she plays by herself
in the forest.
One day, her doll falls
in the river.
Her mother isn't there
to help her, so...
She goes in by herself
to try to get it,
but she falls in and drowns.
They never find her body.
They can't even bury her.
They say
her spirit gets lonely,
so... she brings people
to the river to drown.
So many people have died,
locals began leaving her gifts
so she'd leave them alone.
Maybe this tree is for her.
She must've been
from one of the old
British colonial families.
Well...
That explains the dolls.
But why is it coming after us?
I don't know.
You took this from the tree?
Come on, man.
It's hard enough to believe
there's a ghost out here,
but one that's mad
we took its toys?
Please.
Give it back.
Can't believe I'm doing this.
Lincoln.
Okay, I'm-- I'm sorry
I took my bear
There. You happy now?
I think we're all past
a good night's sleep.
The sun's coming up soon.
Let's pick up
your husband's trail.
Put it back.
Tie it carefully.
- I did.
- Do it again.
Sorry.
Give me the bear.
Aah! Aah!
What do you want from us?!
Mommy.
- This way! We can make it
to the "Magus." - Go!
- This way! - As fast as you can!
Fast as you-- Come on!
- Oh, my God!
- Hurry up, mom!
Go!
- Run! Stay together!
- Okay.
Oh, my God. Okay.
Stay together, guys!
Come on!
Aah!
We're almost
at the "Magus."
Go! Go! Come on!
Um... the doll tree?!
You...
You led us right back here?
We were going the right way.
What, so the tree brought us
back here?!
Huh? Come on!
It did this. It's trying to trap
us. What does it want from us?
I think it's pretty clear.
Where's my mom?
She was right behind me.
- She's not here.
- Tess!
Tess?
Tess!
Mom! Where is she?
- Aah!
- Mom?!
Tess!
Where is she?! Who saw her?!
Who-- What-- Mom!
- Tess!
She was right here.
She was right here. Tess!
Tess!
It's to our left.
Hold on!
- Aah! Aah!
- Mom!
Help!
- Tess! Tess!
- Where is she?!
Mom!
I can't see anything!
- She's in here somewhere!
- Aah!
We all saw her drown.
Guys, over here!
Uhh! Keep looking!
Lincoln!
- Tess!
- Mom?
- Oh, my God. Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
Lincoln.
Mom! Where the hell is she?!
Tess!
- Mom!
- Lincoln.
Where are you?!
Lincoln!
Where the hell is she?!
- Wait.
- Mom!
Wait.
Listen to her voice.
It sounds like
they're in the same place.
- Lincoln!
- Where?! Where?!
It doesn't matter.
If she can take my mom,
she can give her back.
How do we get her to do that?
We give her
what she really wants.
You've gotta be kidding me.
If she wants her mother,
we'll give her her mother.
Just keep looking, okay?
Just look!
What the hell is this?
Here.
That's Nevins.
There's one here.
- That it? - No, no, no, no.
This isn't the mother.
Hey, I've got something.
I've got something here.
Here we go. Here we go.
It's this one.
"Taken by the--
Taken by the river."
- It's her.
- That's her, isn't it?
- That's the daughter.
- Where's the mother?
Wait.
She's there.
"Her heart broke
when love drowned."
That's the mother.
Wait.
We gotta get in there, guys.
Another two or more to go.
More shovel. More shovel!
Come on!
And the side.
We got something.
There it is.
Please... give her back.
You have your mother.
I brought her to you.
Now give me mine.
Come on! Give her back!
Give her back!
I mean, how could
she just disappear like that?
She was right here.
And now she's dead.
I mean, this-- this place
is-- is taking them both.
It's a fucking nightmare.
We shouldn't be here.
We should never have come.
Now they're both gone.
You're not alone.
Lincoln!
- Mom! Mom!
- Lincoln!
Mom!
Aah! Lincoln!
Okay! Oh!
I couldn't breathe.
I thought I was...
Oh!
It's okay. You're back.
Are you hurt? Let me see.
Let me see.
Keep the light on her.
Here. You okay?
You need to talk to her.
About what?
We got lucky with her. We might
not be with your father.
It might be too late.
Jahel?
Dad?
Dad, if you're still there,
I mean, I-I know you can be,
but...
If you are, I...
I just want you to know, I...
I understand.
There's a whole world
of things out there
that... I never knew.
That's just terrifying. I...
But you knew.
You know, maybe you were
just trying to protect me
all that time.
But now it's my turn
to protect you.
We're here for you.
If you're still out there,
if there's a chance
you're still alive, then you--
Dad?
Dad, can you hear me?
If you're anywhere, you just
tell me and I will find you.
Perdón...
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
It's okay, it's okay.
...That one day I would meet
a child who was strong enough.
So how was your day?
Hey, Russ, this autofocus
is acting up again.
It's just-- I guess
it's the humidity.
Good God. These kids are gonna
end up getting married someday.
Lena.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com