Hmm...Ben...
Mmm?
What do you think
you're doing?
Mmm...
this is a dream.
It's--it's a--
a beautiful dream.
[Laughs] It doesn't
feel like a dream.
Oh, no, but--but it is.
I'm not really doing this.
Mmm.
Or this...
or this...
No, I'm not doing anything.
I'm sound asleep,
just like you.
Oh.
You're not sound asleep,
and this is not a dream.
Well, let's pretend that it is.
Ben, we agreed. No more sex
until we get married.
Right. Why did we agree
to that again?
-Hmm?
-Mmm.
Mmm!
It'll make
the wedding night special.
It'll be like starting over.
Well, let's start
over right now.
Hi. My name's Ben.
What's your name?
-Oh...Ben...
-What?
We're not doing this.
Didn't you give
Father Brendan your word?
Yeah. I--I had
my fingers crossed.
Oh. I sometimes wonder how
committed you are to all this.
-What--to all what?
-To our getting married!
I'm--I'm committed.
I--I proposed...didn't l? Hmm?
Yes, you did.
And very sweetly, too.
Maybe you could throw me a bone
once in a while, hmm?
Yeah.
OK. OK.
OK. No sex for six months. OK.
This is a test, right?
Yeah, OK.
Don't worry, Samantha.
I'll pass with flying colors.
Yeah, if I don't explode first.
-Oh, you won't explode.
-Yeah?
Mmm.
Oh. Hey. Hi.
Oh. How are you?
Hey, uh--
Oh, hi. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Oh, hey--hey there.
Hi--hi there.
Ho--ho there.
-l, uh, I work here.
-OK.
I'm the senior photo editor,
so if you have any pictures...
you'd like me to look at,
I'd be glad to, uh, to look.
[Girls laugh]
Have you seen
the women out there?
Nines, tens.
I think I even saw a twelve.
You and Samantha
still not having sex?
Is it that obvious?
I feel your pain, chief.
That was one nasty virus.
Good thing you backed up
your hard drive.
For you.
What's this?
The best sex
you're not having.
And it's absolutely guilt-free.
A virtual sex program?
Are you serious?
I don't need this.
I love my fiancée.
And you two make
a very cute couple...
but this has nothing
to do with Samantha.
"Sensuous Cindy"
is the greatest program...
Fantadyne's ever cooked up.
Fantadyne?
The--the game simulation people?
Samantha works for them.
I bet she didn't work
on this sucker.
How did you get ahold of it?
Easy. A friend
snuck me a beta copy.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Have--have you tried...this?
Hey, I don't kiss and tell.
Now, what is it, six more months
until the wedding night?
Well...
It's your decision, chief.
I like it.
Oh....wha...
What?
Ow!
Mmm!
Hi, Ben.
I've been waiting for you.
Sexual fantasies...
every one of us has them.
Harmless enough
most of the time.
On the eve of his marriage...
Benjamin Baker has decided
to indulge himself.
He's about to get
very, very lucky.
Or is he?
You're traveling
to another dimension...
a dimension not only
of sight and sound...
but of mind.
A journey
into a wondrous land...
whose boundaries are only
that of the imagination.
You're entering...
Oh, you taste great!
So do you.
How--how is this,
uh, happening?
I--I mean, how--
how does it, uh, work?
Well, I could
draw you a diagram...
but that might ruin
the mystery.
So, what did you
have in mind...
something naughty...
or something nice?
Well, l--l--I don't--
I--um...
Look at these curtains!
Amazing!
They feel just like silk!
Did you come to play
with the curtains...
or to play with me?
Uh...
Ohh!
Why don't you just lay back
and relax and let me drive?
Uh...
OK...
Ohhh...Cindy...
I don't know
if I can do this.
This all feels too real.
Gee, Ben,
I'm just a computer program.
Yeah, some program.
You know, l--
I'm engaged to be married.
You are? That's so sweet.
Yeah.
You're not married yet,
are you?
Uh...no. I am not.
Then consider this practice.
Hey, mister...
there's a speed limit
in this town.
Oh.
Just kidding.
[Music playing]
I could stay like this forever.
Most guys are just
wham-bam-thank-you-ma'am.
Well, you know guys.
You're different.
You're sweet...
considerate.
I mean,
don't get me wrong.
You were a real tiger
when it counted.
Well, you were
pretty terrific yourself.
You're so sweet.
I could really
get used to this.
Wow...
Ohh! Ha ha! It's you!
What's the occasion?
Oh, no occasion.
We're not having sex,
Benjamin.
That's fine with me.
And reverse psychology's
not gonna work.
What are you talkin' about?
No. Six months is nothing.
It's a drop in the bucket,
and, besides, like you said...
it--it'll make for--
for one hell of a wedding night.
-I love you.
-Do you?
Well, these flowers
weren't cheap.
-Oh, be serious!
-I'm being serious.
I mean, about loving you,
not about the...flowers.
You're the only man
I'll ever love.
-Yeah?
-Mmm...
Ohh...
Hello?
Yeah, he's right here.
-It's for you.
-Oh.
Hello?
-Ben?
-Yes.
It's me. Cindy.
Cindy. Cindy who?
Sensuous Cindy, silly.
I had such a great
time today with you...
and l--I can't stop
thinkin' about you.
Uh--it--Cindy?
Who--who is this really?
I told you. It's me. Cindy.
Cindy from this morning?
Just hearin' the sound
of your voice again...
gives me butterflies.
Well, no--
But-butterflies?
You're--you're
a computer program.
Who is it?
Oh, it's, uh, uh--
it's, uh, somebody...
uh, from work.
Nobody, uh, y-you know.
Uh, th-this can wait
until morning.
We'll--we'll discuss it then.
Will you promise to come see me?
First thing?
Uh, yeah, sure. Fine.
Can't wait for you to hold me
in your arms again. It was so--
Is everything all right?
What? Oh, uh, great. Yeah.
Uh, so-something came up.
Uh, no--nothing r-really.
It's--it's, uh, something,
but it's nothing.
Every--everything's
under, uh, control.
Must've been a glitch
of some sort.
Whatcha doin', Ben?
Aah!
Didn't you make a little promise
to me last night?
I'm confused. Is--is--
is--is this part of the program?
Look, all I know is I've never
felt like this before.
Uh, l--l--I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm talking
about chemistry, silly.
You know,
that mysterious attraction...
between two people
who belong together?
Pheromones
and all that good stuff?
No, no. You--you have to be
human to--to have pheromones.
Well, I was human enough
for you last night.
Yeah. Um...
w-well, why--why don't l...
come visit you,
uh, a-after work?
And afterwards will you
hold me for a while?
Well, y-yeah.
Uh, holding, uh, touching...
w-w-whatever you want.
[Telephone rings]
Hello.
Hi, Sam.
No, I had to, uh, work late.
I had a photo layout
I had to finish.
Yeah. No, I'm outta here
as soon as we hang up.
OK. I love you, too. Bye.
[Sighs]
Ben?
I've been waiting so long.
Where are you?
Ben?
[Elevator cables screech]
Hey, there, mister.
Aren't you
forgetting something?
Cindy, please.
Start the elevator.
Not until we get a few
things straightened out.
Boy, when you sweat,
you really sweat.
Yeah, well, I have a thing about
being...trapped in small spaces.
So, now, Cindy,
I'm approaching meltdown here...
and it's not gonna be pretty.
Well, how do you
think I feel?
I mean, I can't eat,
I can't sleep--
OK, you never eat.
You never sleep.
I keep dreaming about you.
Look, you just said
you can't sleep!
Ben, I want to be with you.
I want us to be together.
-We can't be together!
-Why?
Because you're a com--
You're...
Ben, I know you like me.
Yes, yes! Yes!
Yes, like you! I like you!
But l--I love Samantha!
I'm OK with that.
B-but I'm not!
OK? It was--
it was sex, Cindy.
That's all!
I'm sorry.
I meant nothing to you,
and it was--
it was just a fling,
a one-night stand?
Well, yeah--uh...
I don't--I don't want
to hurt you...
but, yes,
you meant nothing to me.
It was just a fling,
a one-night stand.
I'm so disappointed in you.
Cindy? Cindy?
Don't leave me. Cindy?
Cindy?
OK...OK, OK.
OK. The walls--the walls
are starting to close in.
OK. OK. OK. OK.
Help! Help! Help!
OK, OK, OK, I made a mistake.
A big mistake.
OK, OK, OK, OK,
I--I should have
come to see you.
I should have come to see you.
Cindy...please, please,
please, please.
I--I'll do anything you want.
Anything you want.
Forgive me...please.
I--l--l--l--
I didn't know
what I was saying.
I just want to be
with you, Ben.
Is that such a bad thing?
No, no, no.
No. No, no, no, no.
Ben? I'm waiting.
Where are you?
I--I'll be there
in a minute.
I--I have--I have
to use the men's room.
Ben?
Oh, Ben?
Where are you?
Ben!
This isn't funny anymore.
I know you're out there.
What, are you trying
to kill me?
Why couldn't I take
the elevator?
-lt isn't safe. Nowhere's safe.
-It's 25 stories!
Ben?
Who's that?
Hey, about how much longer?
Don't rush me.
I can't believe I'm doin' this.
This is a crime, a real crime.
You want to talk about a crime?
How about attempted kidnapping?
The elevator got stuck.
It happens.
I'm tellin' you,
she wasn't gonna let me out.
Would you stop talkin'
about her like she's real?
-You're weirdin' me out.
-Let me tell you something...
you know she's not real,
I know she's not real...
but Cindy sees things
a little differently.
She's a series
of ones and zeros.
Ones and zeros wrapped in
the cutest, hottest little body.
Would you stop it?
I feel guilty enough
as it is.
But not as guilty as I'd feel
if Sam ever finds out.
Sam's a software developer.
She'd probably think
Cindy was pretty damn cool.
Don't you get it?
We made a vow--
no sex until our wedding.
That means not with each other,
not with others, and not with...
some sex-happy computer program.
Your loss. Your loss.
I push this key...
and that's it.
Cindy vanishes
from your life forever.
What do you say, chief?
Terminate her.
Now.
Hi. I'm home.
In the office.
Hi.
-Tough day?
-Yeah.
Uh, I won't bore you
with the details.
Poor baby.
I know how you feel.
I'm having trouble
with my hard drive.
I can't access any of my files.
You want me to check it out?
Who's the computer expert here?
Well, a fresh set of eyes.
I'll open the wine.
Yeah...
Iet's see.
"Terminate her"?
Did I actually hear you say,
No! You can't be here.
We got rid of you.
You tried, but I was hiding...
in the computer
in the office next door.
Having any luck?
Uh--oh, look...
no, the--the damn thing
it, uh, froze up on me.
Why don't we, uh,
pop some popcorn?
-We'll watch a movie.
-Wine and popcorn?
Yeah, let's stick a bag
in the microwave.
I'll--I'll see what's on.
Sometimes you can be so cute.
Why are you trying
to hurt me, Ben?
I love you.
I'll--I'll get it.
Yeah?
Maybe it's time Samantha and l
had a little talk.
No, no, no,
don't--don't do that.
I'll--I'll--
I'll come to the office.
Don't do anything
on my account.
No, I want to come see you.
We'll talk.
And once
we're done talking...
I'm a tiger, remember?
Grrrr.
-You are so cute.
-Yeah--
-Will you stay the night?
-Uh, uh, stay the night?
Yeah. Uh, sure.
Anything you want.
OK, but hurry.
No--I'm already out the door.
Ben?
I got some--
the office called.
There's a fire
I have to put out.
I gotta go.
Hi.
What took you so long?
Oh. What can I say?
Traffic was horrendous.
I was gonna stop
for flowers, but--
Oh.
Uh, well, I hope,
uh, you like them.
They're beautiful.
What did you do to me?
Uh, well, that's--
oh, it's--it's a virus.
I--I stopped by,
uh, Garrett's.
He--he wrote it for me.
But why?
I'm sorry, Cindy,
but being with you...
made me realize how much
I really love Samantha.
That is so romantic.
You are so sweet.
Yeah, I guess, but--oh...
Cindy?
Hello?
Ben, are you OK?
Yeah, I'm OK.
Did you get the fire put out?
Yeah. Yeah, it looks that way.
I know it's late...
but could you stop by the store
on your way home?
Sure.
I e-mailed a list
of what we need.
The computer's working fine,
by the way.
Uh, great.
So, I'll see you soon?
No need to hurry.
No problem. Sam?
What?
I love you.
Me, too. Bye.
Bye.
Sorry I'm late.
I was dealing with my fiancé.
He's been acting
a little strange lately.
If I didn't know better,
I'd swear he was cheating on me.
Hmph. Men...
You can't trust them.
Benjamin Baker
narrowly escaped his fantasy...
while his fiancée
explores her own sensual nature.
A glimpse into the future
of modern romance...
for better or for worse...
courtesy of
The Twilight Zone.