Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
Sasha: He has a camp he wants
us to audition for membership.
Rick Grimes: What
is this place?
Deanna Monroe: This is the
start of sustainability.
We need people who've
lived out there.
Deanna Monroe: They're still
your guns, but inside here, we
store them for safety.
Rick: Everybody said
you gave them jobs.
Deanna Monroe: Yeah,
that's part of this place.
Carol Peletier: This place
is gonna make us weak.
Rick Grimes: We'll
make it work.
If they can't make it, then
we'll just take this place.
(crickets chirping)
(birds chirping)
No, no, it's cool.
I'm usually up.
I used to open for a coffee shop
every day for seven years.
Your brain, it gets wired
to things you don't
need anymore.
I still like carrying
around my cell phone, too.
One of these days
it's gonna ring
and freak my ass out.
Hey, if you happen to bag a boar
out there, can I have a leg?
To make a prosciutto.
I used to cure meats in my
basement even before all this.
I made some kick-ass
pickles, too.
Sure, Olivia.
Thanks.
(glass shatters)
(breathing heavily)
(crow cawing, echoes)
(glass shattering)
(walkers snarling, echoing)
-  (snarling stops)
-  (heart beating)
(sighs)
Come and get me.
(theme music playing)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
-  (leaves rustling)
-  (walker snarling)
I don't see it, but it's close.
There's just one of 'em.
We won't be here long.
So what do you think?
We can go in when it's empty.
How is that?
It's locked up at night.
The window. There's just a latch.
I can leave it open.
- A latch?
- Yeah.
What if one of those
pricks shuts it?
Wait a couple of days,
leave it open again.
-  (walker snarling)
- It's getting closer.
We need to do it
sooner than later.
Right now,
they're not watching us.
Not worrying about
meetings like this.
We may need the guns,
we may not.
We will whatever way it goes.
They're the luckiest
damn people I ever met.
And they just keep
getting luckier.
How's that?
We're here now.
They've got a couple
of footlockers
just full of 9 millimeter
autos, Rugers, Kel-Tecs.
Just tossed in there.
They don't use them.
They're never gonna know
they're gone.
Someone's got one now, right?
Mmm.
Listen, the others,
we want them to try.
You, too.
So we keep it quiet.
Just us.
-  (walker snarling)
- Here it comes.
- I got him.
- Hey, wait.
We said we were
taking me out shooting.
I couldn't go back
with a full mag.
Lucky he came by.
We should get back.
You'll pull the latch,
we'll pick our moment.
Us, we don't need to be lucky.
What the hell's that?
Is that a W?
Yeah.
(sighs)
I don't know if this
is some kind of play,
handing authority to strangers.
The authority
to break up fistfights.
If it was just that, she should
have given one of these to Daryl.
I don't know if it's
for us or for them.
Or maybe Deanna's trying
to get rid of us and them.
You put these jackets
on me and you,
have the people see it.
If that's the play,
that'd be smart.
And she seems smart.
Smart for then or smart for now?
This is now.
(leaves rustling)
Come out!
Now!
You can tell the difference between
walkers and humans by sound?
Can you tell the difference
between a good guy and a bad guy?
Rick doesn't seem
to be an expert at that.
There ain't much
of a difference no more.
That how you feel
about your people?
Why you following me?
I didn't know I was.
I came out to hunt rabbits.
I know why you're out here.
Mind if I join?
Keep up.
And keep quiet.
Deanna:
You protect and serve.
You patrol, walk the wall,
watch out for the kids.
If there's a conflict,
you solve it.
And people will listen to you.
Because we're wearing
windbreakers?
Because they believe in this.
Because I'm telling them to.
A police officer
used to live here.
So we had these jackets and I
wanted to make it official.
So it's official.
There's gonna be a
government here one day.
That's why I want
Maggie working with me.
There's gonna be a police force.
That's why I want
you two to start it.
I see a vibrant community here
with industry, commerce,
civilization.
Real lives.
It might be horses
and mills, but... what?
Does that sound like
pie in the sky?
No.
Can we talk security?
We need a constant patrol
along the walls.
Not just looking for damage,
but signs that anyone
climbed in from outside.
You can move
right up the supports.
That's what I'd do.
People are the real threat now.
Rick, I know you think that we should
all be armed within the walls.
I... I can't do that.
That's fine.
You make these changes,
we won't need to.
Sasha:
Excuse me.
I want to volunteer to be one of
the lookouts in the clock tower.
There are no lookouts
in the clock tower.
- What?
- We saw someone up there earlier.
That was an empty rifle
my son Spencer put up there.
He mans it sometimes,
but not often.
Look, there hasn't
been the need.
We need a lookout in that tower
right now, 24/7.
It's the only way we'll be able
to see if someone's coming at us.
Okay, okay, we'll make shifts.
I'll take those shifts,
as many as possible.
Why?
Sasha's one of our best shots.
She can do it.
I'm gonna put Spencer
up there today.
I'll consider you being
our primary lookout,
but I want something in return.
Tonight I'm hosting a welcome
for all of you at my home.
I want you to be there.
Why?
Come tonight.
Then we'll talk about it.
Mashed lima beans,
cocoa powder,
a little sweetener.
I would have eaten it
before all this, I swear.
It's protein
and it fills you up.
Sounds delicious.
I'll be back.
I've got to go beg Rick
for some help with tonight.
You need anything else,
you hit me, girl.
Okay, thanks.
You've heard about the party?
Everyone's gonna be there.
That's right.
So tonight, then.
Should be able to slip out.
The armory is right
next to Deanna's.
I'll back you up.
People might wonder where
their new constable is
or Carl's dad.
Okay.
We can't use Daryl.
They're watching
every move he makes.
It's fine.
You know what's great
about this place?
I get to be invisible again.
(horse nickers)
(nickers)
I've been trying
to catch him for months,
bring him inside.
His name is Buttons.
One of the kids saw him run
by the gate a while back.
Thought he looked
like a Buttons.
I haven't seen him for a while.
I was afraid it was too late.
Every time Eric or I come
close, he gets spooked.
Have you done this before?
My group did.
But they weren't
out there that long.
The longer they're out there,
the more they become
what they really are.
I ain't gonna hurt ya.
All right?
Come on, boy.
Yeah.
Just keep on eating.
(clicks tongue)
Good boy.
Yeah, you used to be
somebody's, huh?
- Now you're just yours.
-  (twig snaps)
- (nickers)
-  (walkers snarling)
Shit!
(neighs)
- Come on, they're coming!
-  (silenced gunshot)
Come on.
You really substitute
applesauce for eggs?
That could change my life.
If we can keep that
between you and me.
It's sort of the secret
to these cookies.
- Are you serious?
- I am.
A girl's got
only so many secrets.
It'll die with me.
Uh, the chocolate
is kind of a trick.
You actually have it?
I can only ration you
a quarter bar.
I'll make it work.
Hey, Olivia.
- We're gonna need to make a withdrawal.
- Late start?
Boss lady wants me to check that strut
on the east wall before the party.
Head on back.
Carol, just grab what you need.
- Chocolate's in the hall freezer.
- Okay.
You afraid of guns, ma'am?
Mm, no, I...
well, I had a handgun
and I carried a rifle
when we were on the outside,
but I'm not an expert.
Not with those, at least.
Well, my name is Tobin.
And whenever you want,
I'd be happy to teach you.
Just better to be safe
than sorry.
That'd be nice.
Thanks, Tobin.
Thank you, Olivia.
You ride horses?
I ride bikes.
I take it you don't
mean 10-speeds.
I know you're feeling
like an outsider.
It's not your fault, you know.
Eric and I,
we're still looked at as
outsiders in a lot of ways.
We've heard our fair
share of well-meaning,
but hilariously offensive things
from some otherwise really
nice men and women.
People are people.
The more afraid they get,
the more stupid they get.
Fear shrinks the brain.
They're scared of you and
me for different reasons.
They're less scared of me
because they know me.
It's less and less every day.
So let them get to know you.
You should go to
Deanna's party tonight.
I got nothing to prove.
I met a lot
of bad people out here
doing a lot of bad shit.
They weren't afraid of nothing.
Yeah, they were.
-  (music playing)
-  (people chatting, laughing)
Oh, my.
Welcome.
Hi.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Hi, Carl.
Thank you for coming.
You know, I didn't get a
chance to interview this one.
-  I envy her.
- Rick: Why?
She'll get to see what
this place will become.
Come.
Come on in.
I don't know about this.
They have beer.
I'm gonna try.
You're Rick.
Rick, this is my husband Reg.
You're a pretty remarkable guy.
How's that?
I watched the tapes.
All of them.
The things those people
said about you.
The things you did for them.
Didn't you build
that wall out there?
(chuckles)
Yeah, I did, with help.
A lot of it. And it's a damned
incredible achievement.
But it's a wall.
(Deanna chuckles)
14 lives in this world?
I think you have me beat.
Well, we're standing behind
that wall right now, dear.
So let's call it a tie.
(chuckles)
Well, I'm glad you're here.
Now, take a glass.
I'm good.
You don't have to be.
(laughs) There you go.
Go on.
Right. Welcome.
Thank you.
(walkers snarling)
Gotta move quick.
He's pinned in with them.
I got the far ones.
(groans)
Thanks.
(whinnies)
(walkers snarling)
(whinnying)
I got the ones on the right.
Go ahead.
(horse breathing heavily)
(sighs) He always ran.
You were trying to help him.
-  (music playing)
-  (people chatting)
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah. Just isn't
really my thing.
- I think I'm gonna head out.
- No, no.
You're not bailing.
We're in this together, man.
Maggie:
You're here with us now.
You're here with family.
Come on.
Daryl.
Hey.
Thought you were going to
that party over there.
Oh, I was never going to go
'cause of Eric's ankle,
thank God.
Why the hell did you
tell me to go, then?
I said try.
You did.
It's a thought
that counts thing.
- All right.
- Hey, come in.
Have some dinner.
Come on, man. It's some
pretty serious spaghetti.
Look, she's here,
which means it's empty, so...
I'll go with you.
No, remember...
- You're invisible.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey, Rick,
this is my husband Pete.
Hey, good to meet you.
I wanted to thank you for
taking on being our constable.
If we keep growing at this rate,
we're gonna need even more.
I hope so.
You want to come by
my office next week?
I'll take a look at you.
And I probably should have
said I was a doctor first.
I think it sounded nice
either way.
I'm going to get us a refill.
- Oh, I can do it.
- I'm on it.
Having fun?
Yes, I am.
That's kind of a stupid
question, right?
(chuckles) No.
Still, this place has
a pretty amazing view.
Yeah?
Yeah, take a look.
Ordinary life like before.
Well, not like before.
No.
Yeah, no.
I mean...
I mean, it's better.
Not out there, in here.
You know, everyone's been
through it somehow.
Everyone.
And a lot of things disappeared.
But a lot of bullshit
went with it.
They're all from totally
different backgrounds,
different places.
They never would have even met.
And now they're part
of each other's lives.
They are each other's lives.
I'm just saying,
we all lost things,
but we got something back.
It isn't enough,
but it's something.
Carl:
No, it was a tie, man.
You saw it, right?
(chuckles)
Yeah, yeah,
it's a pretty good view.
- Mom, there's no more cookies.
- Oh.
Well, I happen to know
the cookie maker.
She's a good friend of mine.
And I might be able
to see about her
making a whole batch
just for you.
Mom, he doesn't have a stamp.
Oh.
Do you want a stamp?
Sure.
See? Now you're
officially one of us.
Yeah.
- Ron: Hey, Sam.
- Sam, wait, don't run.
- I'll see you later.
- Yeah.
(knocking)
Trying to make a getaway, huh?
I can pretend I didn't make it.
I'm Sasha.
I'm Spencer.
Deanna's my mom.
Your mom...
she seems nice.
Well, if you want
to hang with me,
I'll make sure you don't get
stuck with Mrs. Neudermyer.
She really, really likes talking about
how much she wants a pasta maker.
It's not a conversation
you want to have.
Excuse me.
(slurping)
(grunts) Thanks.
Mmm, when you're out there,
if you happen to be
in a store or something,
Mrs. Neudermyer is really
looking for a pasta maker.
And we're all really trying to
get her to shut up about it.
I mean, we have crates
of dried pasta in here,
but she wants to make
her own or something.
I really think she just wants
something to talk about, so...
if you see one
out on your travels,
it would go a long way to...
I thought it was done.
You didn't ask him already?
Ask me what?
When I got the place,
there was that frame
and some parts and equipment.
Whoever lived here built them.
It's a lot of parts
for one bike.
Whenever I came across any parts
out there, I brought them back.
I didn't know what I'd need.
I always thought
I'd learn how to do it,
but I get the feeling you already
know what to do with it.
And the thing is,
you're going to need a bike.
Why?
I told Deanna
not to give you a job
because I think
I have one for you.
I'd like you to be
Alexandria's other recruiter.
I don't want Eric
risking his life anymore.
You want me risking mine, right?
Yeah, because you know
what you're doing.
You're good out there.
But you don't belong out there.
I know it's hard getting used
to people getting used to you.
And I understand right now you
need to be out there sometimes.
So do I.
But the main reason why I
want you to help me recruit
is because you do know
the difference
between a good person
and a bad person.
I got nothing else to do.
Thanks.
Yeah.
I'll get you some rabbits.
(laughs) Great.
(chatter)
(door opens)
You packing different
steel nowadays?
(chuckles)
Yeah.
Live by it, you die by it...
and eat potato puffs by it.
(chuckles)
Pray to God you don't
have to use it again.
Pray to God you don't get
used to not using it again.
It's on your back...
even when it's off your back.
Hmm.
How much have you had to drink?
(both laugh)
I am a large man.
And I have had many beers
to make up for that.
Uh-huh.
And you know what?
By that brave act,
I have...
I have come to realize
that things
have worked out
pretty damn well for me.
(chuckles)
How about you?
What have you done?
I put on this dress.
Try again.
Sam:
What are you doing?
Sam, what are you doing here?
I followed you.
I was hoping you were
going to make more cookies,
but then you came here.
Well, I could make more.
I could make a whole
batch just for you.
- Would you like that?
- Yes.
- I mean, yes, please.
- Okay.
But you've got to promise me you can
keep it secret that I came here.
But I'd have to tell my mom.
I mean, I tell
my mom everything.
You can never tell anyone,
especially your mom.
Because if you do...
one morning you'll wake up...
and you won't be in your bed.
Where will I be?
You'll be outside the walls
far, far away
tied to a tree.
And you'll scream and scream
because you'll be so afraid.
No one will come to help
because no one will hear you.
Well, something will hear you.
The monsters will come.
The ones out there.
And you won't be able to run
away when they come for you.
And they will tear you
apart and eat you up
all while you're still alive.
All while you can still feel it.
And then afterwards,
no one will ever know
what happened to you.
Or you can promise
not to ever tell anyone
what you saw here
and then nothing will happen.
And you'll get cookies.
Lots of cookies.
I know what I think
you should do.
-  (music playing)
-  (chatter)
That's a pretty good
view, too, isn't it?
It's been a long time
since I held one of these.
She and Carl...
they're why I'm still here.
And I get what
you've been telling me.
What's that?
Here isn't that bad.
(fusses)
Do you want to take her?
Yeah.
Sasha.
Come join us.
I promise all you
have to do is listen.
Come on.
Okay.
Bless her heart. I don't get
what takes her so long.
I mean, we only have one copy
and the point of book club
is that we all read the book.
I just keep hoping that a
dentist shows up at our gates.
- It's his teeth. - I mean, it's just
so much better when it's fresh.
-  (overlapping conversations)
-  (heart beating)
I mean, it's just so much
better when it's fresh.
(walkers snarling)
Sasha, honey,
what's your favorite meal?
I'd love to cook it
for you sometime.
I'm doing it for all
the new arrivals.
- I don't know.
- Of course you do.
Everyone has favorites.
So what's yours?
Whatever you want.
I'm just worried that I'll end up
cooking something you hate, you know?
You're worried?
That's what you worry about?!
I'm trying to figure
out what it is.
What it is exactly.
This...
it isn't real.
Sasha, you've been through a lot
and I accept that,
but what you just said...
that's bullshit.
Take your pick.
Look, I've been thinking.
Do we really need these?
I mean, things go bad,
yeah, sure.
We do what we gotta do,
but it's like you said.
We don't need these for that.
Right now we don't.
You wanted me to try, right?
I'm good.
(hammering)
(sighs)
Hey, Rick.
(music playing)
♪ Where is the sun ♪
♪ That shone
on my head? ♪
(metal rattling)
♪ The sun in my life ♪
♪ It is dead ♪
♪ Where is the light ♪
♪ That would play
in my streets? ♪
(walker snarling)
♪ And where are the friends ♪
♪ I could meet? ♪
♪ Where are the girls ♪
♪ I left far behind? ♪
♪ The spicks and the specks ♪
♪ Of the girls on my mind ♪
♪ Where is the sun ♪
♪ That shone
on my head? ♪
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com