Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
You find out who did this
and you bring them to me!
Do you understand?
You were out on your own
when Daryl found you.
- That's right.
- I just want to make sure
you know how to play on a team.
That veterinary college...
The drugs are the same we need.
I'm glad you're here.
- Where else would I be?
- Running off.
Daryl's got a group going out.
I gotta go.
Make a run for the gaps right there.
Carol, did you kill
Karen and David?
Yes.
( knock at door )
- Ma'am?
- Hi, Lizzy.
They told me to come down here.
Are you okay?
Good.
I wanted to see you because
I'm going on a run with Rick.
( faint sloshing )
Lizzy:
Do you think Daryl's dead?
Carol:
No.
He had to go far away
to get the medicines,
so it's gonna take a while.
We lost all our food
in cell block D,
so we're gonna go look for more
and whatever else we can find.
Lizzy:
Nobody's died yet.
Yet?
I think a lot of people
are going to die.
It's what always happens.
Makes me sad, but...
at least they get to come back.
Lizzy, when they come back,
they aren't--
people aren't who they were.
Yeah, but they're something.
They're someone.
I'm little now.
If I don't die, I'll get big.
I'll be me,
but I'll be different.
It's how it is.
( coughing )
( grunts )
Lizzy:
We all change.
We all don't get to stay
the same way we started.
Lizzy, it's more
complicated--
You said I was weak.
I'm not.
I'm strong, so I'm telling
you what I think.
You remember what I told you
to do when there's danger?
Run as fast as I can.
You run and run
until you're safe.
And if it's your life
or your sister's life,
you can't be afraid to kill.
Understand?
Yes.
Carol:
You are strong, Lizzy.
You're gonna live.
You, your sister,
and me--
we're gonna survive, I know it.
Where's your knife?
Put your T-shirt
behind it.
You've gotta be able
to get to it quickly.
Yes, Mom.
I mean ma'am.
Don't call me "Mom."
It was an accident.
Just don't.
Okay.
Carol:
What is it?
Lizzy:
I'm not afraid to kill.
I'm just afraid.
You can't be.
How?
You fight it.
And fight it.
You don't give up.
And then one day,
you just change.
We all change.
( theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Michonne:
This is Turner Creek,
so Barnesville must be
a few miles downstream.
Bob: Sounds like our best
chance at finding a new ride.
Daryl:
Yo, Ty.
Come on, let's go.
Vámonos.
Ty.
Ty!
There should be a town
a few miles south.
Lost a whole night.
My sister,
everybody else--
they're probably dead.
Well, it helps to keep moving.
No, it doesn't.
Maggie wanted
to come, you know.
Someone had to stay back,
watch over things.
Someone you trust, you mean.
They would have drowned
in their own blood.
They were suffering.
I made it quick.
We needed the bodies gone.
We needed to stop it
from spreading.
They were the only ones
who were sick.
They were a threat.
I was trying to save lives.
I had to try.
Somebody had to.
Maybe.
- Is that jasper?
- Mm-hmm.
It's a good color.
Brings out your eyes.
When Miss Richards went into
A block, we were leaving.
Asked me to keep a lookout.
I'm gonna use it
for her old man's marker.
You know all them back there?
You stay in one place
more than a couple hours,
you'd be surprised
what you pick up.
( crows cawing )
_
Carol:
Think they're coming back?
Windshield's clean, wiped down.
Can't have been here
more than a day, maybe two.
You mean Daryl and the others.
That's what this is, right?
In case they don't?
Until they do.
That's what this is.
Medicine cabinets,
first aid kits--
anything that
could help Hershel.
We get in, we get out.
And if we can eat it,
we take it.
( wood creaking )
You see something?
I don't know.
Maybe.
( sighs )
We gotta find us a new battery.
- ( spits )
- ( walkers snarling )
Got some friends inside.
Come on.
Let's clear a path,
see how many we got.
( grunting )
Hey, man, go easy.
We don't know
what we're dealing with.
- ( grunting )
- ( door rattling )
( door rattling )
( walker gasping )
( walker growls )
- ( growling )
- Ah!
Bob:
Tyreese!
Ty!
Ty, let him go.
( grunting )
Why the hell didn't you let go?
( door creaking )
( faint snarling )
( growling )
Carol!
( door opens )
( door creaks )
Whoa, whoa.
It's cool.
We're-- we're cool.
We have fruit.
Man: Yeah, we got
apricots, peaches.
Here, catch.
Or, you know, don't.
( chuckles )
- Carol: How'd this happen?
- Greenhouse around the corner.
We were looking
for a place to crash.
The roof's broken now and it's been
getting rain, so it's full of fruit.
We were there about a day
and the skin-eaters
showed up.
( laughs )
Killjoys, man.
Jackin' it up
for the whole world.
I thought everybody was an asshole
before this all went down.
Now I love people.
You know-- people
who are alive.
How did it happen?
When they were coming in
through the door,
I tripped crawling out
the other side.
Pulled the glass out,
but my shoulder--
it still hurts like a bitch.
It's dislocated.
Can you fix it?
Here, lay on your back.
Okay, scooch over to the edge.
Just hold your arm...
Grab ahold of this bag.
- Hold on.
- ( groaning )
- And keep holding on.
- ( crying ) No, that hurts.
Keep holding.
I can't, I can't.
- ( bone crackles )
- ( groaning )
( man gasping )
- ( bone pops )
- ( panting )
Sit up.
Woman:
Is it...
Yeah.
It's gonna be sore
for a few days.
Rick: After the greenhouse,
you came here?
Yeah. We thought
it was clear.
We missed the deadie
in the PJs,
so we dove into the bathroom.
So how long were you up
there till we showed up?
Like, two days.
There was just one.
You had guns.
We have about 12 bullets.
It usually take us
about five or six
to bring one of them down.
But you have knives.
To what, stab it in the head?
Yeah.
We got separated from
our crew about a week ago.
Been trying to play it safe
since it's just the two of us.
- I have to with my leg.
- Yeah.
We were at a refugee center
together and there was a fire.
People were just
trampling over me.
Assholes.
Sam saved my life.
We didn't know
each other before.
It didn't heal right,
but it healed.
And we found each other.
It was worth it.
Where are you two headed next?
We just keep moving.
We haven't been waiting
for places to go bad.
I mean, it's getting
a little old.
You guys look all right.
What's your setup like?
The "skin-eaters"?
We call them walkers.
How many have you killed?
( door creaks )
Come on.
Here we go.
Hmm, cells look pretty dry.
A little distilled water
will clear that right up.
You should have let him go.
The hell you know
about it, huh?
- You the damn expert?
- No.
I just don't want
to see you die.
Is that what
you're trying to do?
Do you even know
what you're trying to do?
I know you're pissed.
And you have
every reason to be.
But anger makes you stupid.
Stupid gets you killed.
Aren't you still angry
about the Governor?
What he did?
If he was here right now,
I'd cut him in two.
'Cause that's
how it needs to be.
But I'm not angry.
I was.
Then why are you still
going out looking for him?
I don't know.
( grunting )
Daryl:
That's puke.
Those douchebags in the vines
took themselves out,
holding hands--
kumbaya style.
They wanted to go out
together same as they lived.
That make them douchebags?
It does if they
could have gotten out.
Everybody makes it,
till they don't.
People nowadays are dominoes.
What they did, maybe it's about
not having to watch them fall.
Right.
( raspy breathing )
Come on.
( grunts )
We got about all
we're gonna get here.
We should move on.
So, did we pass your test?
We're in a prison
eight miles north.
If you come back with us, we
can't guarantee your safety.
There's an illness, a flu.
It's bad.
We've lost a lot.
- Kids, too.
- Yours?
No, thank God.
But one of my girls,
she's got it.
- I'm sorry.
- She's strong. She'll make it.
Sam:
You got fences and walls?
- We're in.
- Yeah, whatever you need us to do.
For now, sit tight.
The two of us will circle
back for you before dark.
Or you could help us sweep the
rest of this neighborhood.
Woman: We can do that. I
can check the greenhouse,
see if it's clear,
bring back more fruit.
And I can hit
some of the houses.
Well, it's nice
of you to offer,
but your shoulder's
barely--
Sam: As long as I don't put too
much weight on this arm, I'm good.
- And I can still move pretty fast.
- I just don't think--
We won't take any chances.
We'll look. And if it's
cake, we'll do it.
If not, we'll just roll.
I mean, you don't look
so good yourself, man.
Are you a righty or a lefty?
We'll cover more ground.
The sooner we get back...
Sam:
You can't carry us, man.
- It doesn't work that way.
- Please, we want to help.
You fire a shot,
we'll come running.
Let's meet back here
in two hours.
You'll need this.
You never told us about the
group you were with before.
Which one?
You know, when you found
me out on that road,
I almost kept walking.
Why is that?
'Cause I was done
being a witness.
Two times,
two different groups.
I was the last one standing.
Like I was supposed to see
it happen over and over,
like it's some kind of curse.
But, when it's just you
out there with the quiet...
Used to be I'd drink
a bottle of anything
just so I could
shut my eyes at night.
Figured the prison, the people,
thought it'd be easier.
The run to the big spot,
I did it for me.
You gotta keep busy.
No. I did it so I could
get me a bottle.
Of anything.
I picked it up,
I held it in my hand,
but I put it down.
I put it down so hard it took
the whole damn shelf with it.
That's what brought on
the walkers,
and that's what got
Zack killed.
That's bullshit.
Why don't you get in there
and try the engine?
It's a red and a green wire.
Go on. It ain't
rocket science.
Give it some gas.
( engine starting )
( whistles )
( car door closes )
Sasha and me picked that spot.
He took you with us.
There ain't no way
anybody could've known.
You ain't gonna be
standing alone,
not no more.
Let's go.
( engine revving )
It's all expired
by at least a year.
Better to take it. Let
Herschel decide what he needs.
Did you think it was right?
Letting those kids
come back with us?
I think it was the
humane thing to do.
But did you think it was right?
( drawer slides )
Look at us.
Digging through drawers,
hoping that...
a couple of cough drops
and some disinfectant
might be the difference
between dying and living
a couple of more hours.
( pills rattling )
If they're strong enough to
help us survive this thing,
yeah, I think you made
the right call.
Rick:
And if they're not?
Let's hope they are.
( softly )
Yeah.
Rick...
I killed two people and you
haven't said a word about it.
What do you want me to say?
It's not about what you say.
It's about facing reality.
It always comes for us
and over and over again
we face it so that we can live.
- So that we can live.
- That's right.
That's what it always
comes down to.
You can be a farmer, Rick.
You can't just be a farmer.
You're a good leader.
Better than I probably
gave you credit for.
I never murdered
two of our own.
Just one.
He was gonna kill me.
So were they.
They were gonna kill all of us.
You don't know that.
If you thought it would
save Judith or Carl,
would you have done it then or would
you have just gone back to your crops
and hoped it'd all be okay?
You don't have to like
what I did, Rick.
I don't.
You just accept it.
( wind rustling )
( distant can rattles )
Daryl: Looks like
we're getting closer.
Ty: The building we
want is just up ahead.
( creaking )
( softly )
Come on. Come on.
Move, move.
All right, let's
make this quick
There you go.
Come on.
Carol: Let's hit the
houses across the street.
Hold on.
How'd you put his
shoulder back before?
You learn that from Herschel?
Internet.
It's easier than
telling an ER nurse
I'd fallen down the
stairs a third time.
I'm sorry.
Don't be. Just fixed
what needed fixin'.
I actually convinced myself
I was happy with him.
Which wasn't
all that hard to do
considering my idea
of happiness then
was just not being alone.
Made a decent living.
He was charming
when he wanted to be,
especially those mornings after
he'd come home piss-drunk and...
Stupid.
I didn't think
I could be strong.
I didn't know I could.
I already was.
Why don't you say her name?
She's dead, Rick.
Sophia. Dead.
Somebody else's slideshow.
Some mornings I still wake up
half-expecting Lori
to be there.
Reminding me to pick
up Carl after school
or telling me
breakfast is ready.
Every Sunday she'd
make us these pancakes
that were just...
godawful.
( chuckling )
Clumps of flour
that weren't mixed in right.
Thing was...
she knew it was bad.
Why'd she keep at it?
Well...
she wanted us to be
the kind of family
that ate pancakes on Sunday.
( creaks )
( grunting, munching )
We should get back.
Sam's probably waiting.
Anything ending
with -cillin or -cin,
C-I-N, grab it.
We'll dissolve
the pills in the IVs,
put 'em right into
the bloodstream.
Dosage will be tricky but
considering the time we lost...
- How'd you do?
- Bags, tubes, clamps, connectors.
- Everything on the list.
- What about y'all?
Yeah, we got it all.
Yeah. We're good.
All right, let's roll.
( softly )
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
( snarling )
Michonne:
Up ahead.
( growling, snarling )
( door creaks, shuts )
Hey! Door's busted.
Oh. Hold up.
( walkers growling )
( snarling )
Michonne:
There.
( snarling )
( grunting )
- How many?
- I can't tell.
( rumbling )
- Ty: We can take 'em. - No! They're
infected. Same as at the prison.
We fire at 'em, get their
blood on us, breathe it in.
We didn't come all
this way to get sick.
How do we know the ones in
there aren't any different?
- We don't.
- Well, it's gotta change sometime.
( snarling )
- ( blade rings )
- Daryl: Ready?
Ty:
Do it!
( growling, snarling )
( grunts )
( snarling )
Daryl:
Come on.
( snarling )
( tapping )
It's been too long.
We should give him
a couple more.
He might be fine.
He really might be.
But it doesn't matter...
because he's not here...
and we have to go.
It was a nice watch.
( snarling, growling )
( snarls )
- ( doorknob rattles )
- Back.
Don't have an exit.
Then we make one.
Get down!
( grunts )
- Come on, move it!
- Jump down to the walkway below.
- Bob: They're here!
- Let's go! Go, go. Move.
( snarling )
Michonne:
Bob, let it go.
Let it go, man.
- ( grunting )
- Ty: Just let it go.
- ( snarling, growling )
- Daryl: Let go of the bag, man.
( snarling, growling )
You got no meds in your bag?
Just this?
You should have kept
walking that day.
Don't.
( grunting )
Just let it go, Daryl.
The man's made his choice.
Nothing you can do about it.
Just gotta let it go.
I didn't want to hurt nobody.
It was just for
when it gets quiet.
Take one sip. When those
meds get in our people,
I will beat your ass
into the ground.
You hear me?
( handle clicking )
They might have lived.
Karen and David,
they might have lived,
and now they're dead.
That wasn't your
decision to make.
When Tyreese finds out...
he'll kill you.
He damn near killed me
over nothing.
I can handle Tyreese.
When the others find out,
they won't want you there.
And if they don't make it back,
if everybody dies of this thing
and it's just the two of us,
with Judith and Carl--
with my children...
I won't have you there.
Rick, it's me.
No one else has to know.
I thought you were done making
decisions for everyone.
I'm making
this decision for me.
I could have pretended that
everything was gonna be fine.
But I didn't.
I did something.
I stepped up.
I had to do something.
No, you didn't.
If you think I'm going anywhere
without Lizzie and Mica--
If you want them to leave,
to go out there with you?
Lizzie's sick.
Mica is 10 years old.
She can't.
( sniffles )
We'll keep them safe.
You're not that woman who was too
scared to be alone, not anymore.
You're gonna start over,
find others,
people who don't know,
and you're gonna
survive out here.
You will.
Maybe.
Ty: That's where I was
traveling, Highway 100.
Michonne: Then it will take
about seven hours to get there.
We're gonna need more gas.
Ty:
But we'll get there.
- Taking Highway 100.
- I heard.
( door closes )
You were right,
what you said before.
About the trail going cold.
I don't need to go out anymore.
Good.
( engine starts )
Take it.
Ed gave this to me
on our first anniversary.
Please.
I should have given it
away a long time ago.
( engine starting )
♪ It was a close call ♪
♪ Sitting in the back
of the room ♪
♪ with a ball
I had thrown at you ♪
♪ And you didn't know ♪
♪ Closing on my black eye ♪
♪ I feel safe at times ♪
♪ Certain emblems ♪
♪ tell me it's time ♪
♪ Serpents in my mind ♪
♪ looking for your ♪
♪ crimes ♪
♪ Everything changes ♪
♪ I don't want mine ♪
♪ this time ♪
♪ Everything changes ♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com