Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
Dad!
You handcuffed my
brother to a roof?
And you let him there!
It seems to me what you really
need most here are more guns.
I dropped the bag in Atlanta
when I got swarmed.
I'm going back.
You just got here and you're
gonna turn around and leave?
Merle! Merle!
No! No!
- What?
- Nothing.
It's not nothing.
It's always something.
Didn't dad teach you
to tie nail knots?
Why would he do that?
He only ever used a fisherman's knot.
- One knot.
- No, he didn't.
No, he tied at least three.
Clinch knots?
No way.
Fine, I'm making it up.
Did dad teach you
mostly dry lures?
Yeah.
You?
- Wet.
- You're kidding.
But he was always
so adamant.
I mean, you know dad
on the fishing thing.
Gee, you think?
I only spent my entire childhood
with my ass in a boat.
But in my day it was all
about getting the hook seated.
We were fishing
for the dinner table.
Not us.
We always threw them back.
- Always.
- I guess he changed things up.
But that'd be like changing
his religion or something.
People change. It's not his fault
we were born 12 years apart.
No.
No, because the minute
you went off to college
it was my ass in that boat and he
taught me dry lures from day one.
This was not behavior
developed over time.
You think he did it for us?
Because he knew
we were so different.
He knew that you needed
to catch the fish
and I needed
to throw them back.
All right, remember his rule:
No crying in the boat.
It scares the fish.
Mom and dad...
I mean,
maybe Florida
wasn't hit so bad.
Maybe it's better there.
Do you think?
I think you have a bite.
Even with the wrong knots.
Oh God.
So much for the no crying rule.
I think that was more
for dad than the fish.
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
I won't hesitate. I don't care if
every walker in the city hears it.
You got a do-rag
or something?
I guess the saw blade was
too dull for the handcuffs.
Ain't that a bitch.
He must have used a
tourniquet... maybe his belt.
Be much more blood
if he didn't.
Merle?
You in here?
Jim?
You okay?
You keep this up, you're
gonna keel over out here.
Drink some water at least.
Had enough in him to take out
these two sumbitches.
One handed.
Toughest asshole
I ever met, my brother.
Feed him a hammer,
he'd crap out nails.
Any man can pass out
from blood loss,
no matter how tough he is.
Oh, baby.
Will you look at that?
Hey, check it out.
Ladies...
Because of you my
children will eat tonight.
- Thank you.
- Thank Dale.
It's his canoe and gear.
Mom, look.
Look at all the fish.
Thank you.
Yeah, whoa.
Where did you two learn to do that?
- Our dad.
- Can you teach me how to do that?
Sure. I'll teach you all
about nail knots and stuff.
- If that's okay.
- You won't catch me arguing.
Hey, Dale. When's the last time
you oiled those line reels?
- They are a disgrace.
- I, uh,
I don't want
to alarm anyone,
but we may have
a bit of a problem.
- Merle!
- We're not alone here.
- Remember?
- Screw that.
He could be bleeding out.
You said so yourself.
What's that burned stuff?
Skin.
He cauterized the stump.
Told you he was tough.
Nobody can kill
merle but merle.
Don't take that on faith.
He's lost a lot of blood.
Yeah?
Didn't stop him from busting
out of this death trap.
He left the building?
Why the hell would he do that?
Why wouldn't he?
He's out there alone
as far as he knows,
doing what he's got to do.
Surviving.
You call that surviving?
Just wandering out in the
streets, maybe passing out?
What are his odds out there?
No worse than being handcuffed and
left to rot by you sorry pricks.
You couldn't kill him.
Ain't so worried about
some dumb dead bastard.
What about 1,000 dead
dumb bastards?
- Different story?
- Why don't you take a tally?
Do what you want.
I'm gonna go get him.
- Daryl, wait.
- Get your hands off me!
- You can't stop me.
- I don't blame you.
He's family, I get that.
I went through hell to find mine.
I know exactly how you feel.
He can't get far
with that injury.
We could help you check
a few blocks around
but only if we keep
a level head.
I could do that.
Only if we get
those guns first.
I'm not strolling
the streets of Atlanta
with just my good
intentions, okay?
Hey, Jim.
Jim, why don't you
hold up, all right?
- Just give me a second here, please.
- What do you want?
We're all just a little
concerned, that's all,
Dale says you've been
out here for hours.
- So?
- So why are you digging?
Are you heading to China, Jim?
What does it matter?
I'm not hurting anyone.
Yeah, except maybe yourself.
It's 100â° tod.
You can't keep this up.
Sure I can.
Watch me.
Jim, they're not
gonna say it so I will.
You're scaring people.
You're scaring my son
and Carol's daughter.
They got nothing
to be scared of.
I mean, what the hell, people?
I'm out here by myself.
Why don't you all just go
and leave me the hell alone?
We think that you need
to take a break, okay?
Why don't you go and get
yourself in the shade?
Some food maybe.
I'll tell you what...
maybe in a little bit
I'll come out here
and help you myself.
Jim, just tell me
what it's about.
Why don't you just go ahead
and give me that shovel?
- Or what?
- There is no or what.
I'm asking you. I'm coming to
you and I'm asking you, please.
I don't want to have
to take it from you.
And if I don't, then what?
Then you're gonna
beat my face in
like Ed Peletier, aren't you?
Y'all seen his face, huh?
What's left of it.
See, now that's what happens
when someone crosses you.
That was different, Jim.
You weren't there. Ed was out of control.
He was hurting his wife.
That is their marriage.
That is not his.
He is not judge and jury.
Who voted you king boss, huh?
Jim, I'm not here to
argue with you, all right?
- Just give me the shovel, okay?
- No no no.
Just give me the... Jim!
- Okay, shh shh.
- You got no right!
- Stop. Shh.
Jim, just stop it.
Hey hey hey hey.
- Don't! - Jim.
Jim, nobody's gonna hurt you.
You hear me?
Shh.
Jim, nobody is gonna
hurt you, okay?
That's a lie.
That's the biggest lie there is.
I told that to my wife
and my two boys.
I said it 100 times.
It didn't matter.
They came out of nowhere.
There were dozens of 'em.
Just pulled 'em
right out of my hands.
You know, the only
reason I got away was
'cause the dead were
too busy eating my family.
You're not doing this alone.
Even I think it's a bad idea and
I don't even like you much.
It's a good idea, okay,
if you just hear me out.
If we go out there in a group,
we're slow, drawing attention.
If I'm alone, I can move fast.
Look.
That's the tank, five blocks
from where we are now.
That's the bag of guns.
Here's the alley I dragged
you into when we first met.
- That's where Daryl and I will go.
- Why me?
Your crossbow is quieter
than his gun.
While Daryl waits
here in the alley,
I run up the street,
grab the bag.
You got us elsewhere?
You and t-dog, right.
You'll be in this alley here.
Two blocks away?
Why?
I may not be able to
come back the same way.
Walkers might cut me off.
If that happens,
I won't go back to Daryl.
I'll go forward instead,
all the way around to that
alley where you guys are.
Whichever direction I go,
I got you in both places
to cover me.
Afterwards, we'll all
meet back here.
Hey, kid, what'd you do
before all this?
Delivered pizzas. Why?
You got some balls
for a chinaman.
- I'm Korean.
- Whatever.
Whoa, don't shoot me!
What do you want?
I'm looking for my brother.
He's hurt real bad. You seen him?
- Ayúdame!
- Shut up!
You're gonna bring the geeks down on us.
Answer me.
- Answer me.
- Ayúdame!
Ayúdame!
Shut up. Shut up.
Shut up.
That's it.
That's the bag, Vato.
Take it!
Get off me!
Daryl!
Come back here,
you sumbitches!
Whoa whoa whoa.
Stop it.
I'm gonna kick your nuts
up in your throat!
- Let me go.
- Chill out.
They took Glenn.
That little bastard
and his little bastard
homie friends.
I'm gonna stomp your ass!
Guys! Guys!
We're cut off!
Get to the lab. Go.
Come on.
Damn, let's go.
Jim, take some water?
- All right.
- Yeah?
All right.
Here you go, bud.
Pour some on my head?
Yeah.
Cooling you down, huh?
How long you gonna
keep me like this?
Well, yeah.
Until I don't think that
you're a danger to yourself
or others.
Sorry if I scared your boy
and your little girl.
You had sunstroke.
Nobody's blaming you.
You're not scared now, are you?
No sir.
Your mama's right.
Sun just cooked my head is all.
Jim, do you know why
you were digging?
Can you say?
I had a reason.
Don't remember.
Something I dreamt last night.
Your dad was in it.
You were too.
You were worried about him.
Can't remember the rest.
You worried about your dad?
They're not back yet.
We don't need
to talk about that.
Your dad's
a police officer, son.
He helps people.
Probably just came across some
folks needing help, that's all.
That man, he is tough as nails.
I don't know him well but...
I could see it in him.
Am I right?
Oh yeah.
There ain't nothing gonna stop
him from getting back here
to you and your mom,
I promise you that.
All right.
Who wants to help me
clean some fish, huh?
Sweet.
Come on, Sophia.
Stay with Carol, all right?
You keep your boy close.
You don't ever let him
out of your sight.
Those men you were with, we
need to know where they went.
I ain't telling you nothing.
Jesus, man.
What the hell happened back there?
I told you, this little turd
and his douche bag friends
came out of nowhere
and jumped me.
You're the one who
jumped me, puto,
screaming about trying to find his
brother like it's my damn fault.
They took Glenn.
Could have taken merle too.
Merle? What kind of
hick name is that?
I wouldn't name my dog merle.
Damn it, Daryl.
Back off.
Want to see what happened to the
last guy that pissed me off?
Start with the feet this time.
The men you were
with took our friend.
All we want to do
is talk to them,
see if we can work
something out.
You sure you're up for this?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
One wrong move,
you get an arrow in the ass.
Just so you know.
G's gonna take that
arrow out of my ass
and shove it up yours.
Just so you know.
- G?
- Guillermo.
He's the man here.
Okay then.
- Let's go see guillermo.
You okay, little man?
They're gonna cut off
my feet, carnal.
Cops do that?
Not him.
This redneck puto here.
He cut off some dude's hand, man.
He showed it to me.
- Shut up. - Hey, that's that
Vato right there, homes.
He shot me in the ass with an arrow.
What's up, homes, huh?
Chill, ese, chill.
Chill.
This true?
He wants Miguelito's feet?
That's pretty sick, man.
We were hoping more
for a calm discussion.
That hillbilly jumps
Felipe's little cousin,
beats on him, threatens
to cut off his feet,
Felipe gets an arrow in the ass
and you want a calm discussion?
You fascinate me.
Heat of the moment.
Mistakes were made
on both sides.
Who's that dude to you anyway?
You don't look related.
He's one of our group,
more or less.
I'm sure you have
a few like him.
You got my brother in there?
Sorry, we're fresh out
of white boys.
But I've got Asian.
You interested?
I have one of yours,
you have one of mine.
Sounds like an even trade.
- Don't sound even to me.
- G.
- Come on, man.
- My people got attacked.
Where's the compensation
for their pain and suffering?
More to the point,
where's my bag of guns?
- Guns? - The bag Miguel
saw in the street.
The bag Felipe and Jorge
were going back to get.
- That bag of guns.
- You're mistaken.
- I don't think so.
- About it being yours.
It's my bag of guns.
The bag was in the street.
Anybody could come around
and say it was theirs.
I'm supposed to take your word?
What's to stop my people
from unloading on you
right here and now
and I take what's mine?
You could do that.
Or not.
Come on, man.
Make the trade.
Please.
Oye.
I see two options.
You come back with Miguel
and my bag of guns,
everybody walks.
Or you come back
locked and loaded,
we'll see which side
spills more blood.
Them guns are worth
more than gold.
Gold won't protect your family
or put food on the table.
You're gonna give that up
for that kid?
If I knew we'd get
Glenn back, I might agree.
But you think that Vato across the
way is just gonna hand him over?
- You calling g a liar?
- Are you a part of this?
You want to hold
onto your teeth?
Question is, do you
trust that man's word?
No, question is what are
you willing to bet on it?
Could be more than them guns.
Could be your life.
Glenn worth that to you?
What life I have I owe to him.
I was nobody to Glenn,
just some idiot
stuck in a tank.
He could have walked away,
but he didn't.
Neither will I.
So you're gonna hand
the guns over?
I didn't say that.
There's nothing
keeping you two here.
You should get out,
head back to camp.
And tell your family what?
Come on, this is nuts.
Just do like g says.
I see my guns but they're
not all in the bag.
That's because
they're not yours.
I thought I mentioned that.
Let's just shoot these
fools right now, ese.
All right?
Unload on their asses, ese.
I don't think you fully appreciate
the gravity of the situation.
No, I'm pretty clear.
You have your man.
I want mine.
I'm gonna chop up your boy.
I'm gonna feed him to my dogs.
They're the evilest, nastiest
man-eating bitches you ever saw.
I picked them up from
Satan at a yard sale.
I told you how it has to be.
Are you woefully deaf?
No, my hearing's fine.
You said come locked and loaded.
Okay then, we're here.
Felipe! Felipe!
Abuela, go back
with the others... now.
Get that old lady out
of the line of fire!
Abuela, listen to
your mijo, okay?
This is the not the place
for you right now.
Mr. Gilbert is having
trouble breathing.
He needs his asthma stuff.
Carlitos didn't find it.
He needs his medicine.
Felipe, go take
care of it, okay?
And take your
grandmother with you.
¡Abuela! Ven
conmigo por favor.
Who are those men?
- Por favor, ven conmigo.
- Don't you take him.
- Ma'am?
- Felipe's a good boy.
He have his trouble
but he pull himself together.
We need him here.
Ma'am,
I'm not here to arrest
your grandson.
Then what do you want him for?
He's...
Helping us find
a missing person.
Fella named Glenn.
The Asian boy?
He's with Mr. Gilbert.
Come. Come, I show you.
He needs his medicine.
Let 'em pass.
Abuela, por favor.
Take me to him.
All right.
Nice and easy.
Just breathe.
Just breathe. Just let it out.
Just relax.
- What the hell is this?
- An asthma attack.
Couldn't get his breath
all of a sudden.
I thought you were being
eaten by dogs, man.
Could I have a word with you?
You're the dumbest
son of a bitch I ever met.
We walked in there ready to
kill every last one of you.
Well, I'm glad it
didn't go down that way.
If it had, that blood
would be on my hands.
Mine too.
We'd have fought back.
Wouldn't be the first
time we've had to.
Protect the food, the
medicine... what's left of it.
These people, the old ones...
the staff took off,
just left 'em here to die.
Me and Felipe were
the only ones who stayed.
What are you, doctors?
Felipe's a nurse...
a special care provider.
Me,
I'm the custodian.
What about the rest
of your crew?
The Vatos trickle in
to check on their parents,
their grandparents.
They see how things are
and most decide to stay.
It's a good thing too.
We need the muscle.
The people we've encountered
since things fell apart,
the worst kind...
plunderers,
the kind that take by force.
- That's not who we are.
- How was I to know?
My people got attacked and you
show up with Miguel hostage...
appearances.
Guess the world changed.
No.
It's the same as it ever was.
The weak get taken.
So we do what we can here.
The Vatos work on those cars,
talk about getting the old
people out of the city.
But most can't even get to
the bathroom by themselves,
still, it keeps the crew busy,
and that's worth something.
So we barred all the windows,
welded all the doors shut
except for one entrance.
The Vatos, they go out,
scavenge what they can
to keep us going.
We watch the perimeter
night and day and we wait.
The people here,
they all look to me now.
I don't even know why.
Because they can.
Admit it, you only came
back to Atlanta for the hat.
Don't tell anybody.
You've given away half
our guns and ammo.
- Not nearly half.
- For what?
Bunch of old farts who are gonna
die off momentarily anyhow?
Seriously, how long
you think they got?
How long do any of us?
- Oh my God.
- Where the hell's our van?
- We left it right there.
Who would take it? - Merle.
He's gonna be taking
some vengeance back to camp.
Wrapping paper,
color tissue, anything?
Seriously?
How can you not have any?
Had I been informed of the impending
apocalypse I'd have stocked up.
It's Amy's birthday tomorrow.
I've been marking days on the
calendar just to make sure.
You don't give
a gift unwrapped.
Deep breath.
I'm sure I'll find
something here.
I, uh, built up
the rocks all around.
See? So the flames can
be a little higher
and have 'em be hidden.
Hey, Jim.
How you feeling, man?
I'm better.
More myself now.
I hope you understand
the need for this...
this timeout.
I've got others
I've got to think about.
I just want to
make sure there's no...
there's no hard feelings.
There's not.
I do understand.
Okay.
Why don't you come
join in with the rest of us?
Big ol' fish fry.
- I'd like that very much.
- Okay.
Why don't you come outside
with everybody?
Hell with them people.
Wouldn't piss on them
if their heads were on fire.
Hey!
Why don't you stay here?
Keep your daddy company.
Ed, she wants to join in.
- Come on.
- Fine.
Hell with the both of you.
Ain't no need to be bothering me
no more the rest of the night.
- Pass the fish, please.
- Here you go.
- Man o man, that's good.
I miss this.
I've got to ask you, man.
It's been driving me crazy.
- What?
- That watch.
What's wrong with my watch?
I see you every day,
the same time,
winding that thing
like a village priest
saying mass.
I've wondered this myself.
- I'm missing the point.
- Unless I've misread the signs,
the world seems to
have come to an end.
At least hit a speed bump
for a good long while.
But there's you every day
winding that stupid watch.
Time... it's important
to keep track, isn't it?
The days at least.
Don't you think, Andrea?
Back me up here.
I like...
I like what, um,
a father said to son
when he gave him a watch
that had been handed down
through generations.
He said,
"I give you the mausoleum"
"of all hope and desire,"
"which will fit
your individual needs"
"no better than it did mine
or my father's before me;"
"I give it to you"
"not that you may remember time,"
"but that you may forget it
for a moment"
"now and then"
"and not spend all of your
breath trying to conquer it."
You are so weird.
It's not me.
It's Faulkner.
William Faulkner.
Maybe my bad paraphrasing.
- Where are you going?
- I have to pee.
Jeez, you try to be
discreet around here...
Thought I told y'all to leave
me the hell alone, didn't I?
Hey!
What'd I say?
We're out of toilet paper?
- Mom!
- Carl!
Lori, get him down!
Oh my God.
Go! Go!
I'm right here.
Shane, what do we do?
- Shane?
- Follow me!
No!
Oh God!
Oh my God!
Help me.
Oh God, I don't
know what to do.
I don't know what to do.
- Come on. Come on, stay close.
- Carol!
Stay close!
Come on, y'all!
Work your way up here!
Right in front
of you. Shane!
Get to the r.V.! Go!
- Shane! Shane!
- Stay with me.
Stay behind me.
Morales, work up here!
- Get behind me!
- Let's go!
Stay with me.
Come on, make your
way to the winnebago!
Baby! Carl!
Baby!
- Dad!
- Carl!
Amy.
I don't know what to do, Amy.
Oh, Amy.
Oh no no.
Amy!
I remember my dream now,
why I dug the holes.
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com