It's so green.
Well, hello there, folks.
Hi. We're movin' in today.
Ah. Could I see
some I.D., please?
Thank you.
Well, welcome
to Evergreen Estates...
Mr. and Mrs. Winslow.
The, uh, moving van...
delivered your things
this morning.
Thank you.
And these must be
your daughters.
Hello there, sunshine.
I have a sunflower on my ass
if you're interested.
Maple street
is your third left turn.
Meet the Winslows:
a family searching
for a way...
to control
their troubled teen.
How far
they're willing to go...
will take them
to a gated community...
whose address
can only be found...
in The Twilight Zone.
I promised myself
I wasn't gonna...
let your bad attitude
get to me...
but damn it, I am tired
of your antics.
Ed, please. You know
what the doctor said...
about getting upset.
You think she cares...
if she gives me
another heart attack?
That is mean.
You should apologize, daddy.
Did she apologize to me...
when she nearly
burned down her school?
Did she apologize to anyone?
All right. I see the geeks...
now show me some freaks.
What's that?
I don't know.
She's not the only one
who feels like crying.
Hel-lo.
Break time!
I'll have a shot of tequila...
with a lime wedge.
Or... lemonade will work.
The lemonade...
what did you guys put in it?
Honey, it's for your own good.
You're traveling
to another dimension...
a dimension not only
of sight and sound...
but of mind...
a journey
into a wondrous land...
whose boundaries are only that
of the imagination.
You're entering...
The Twilight Zone.
What?
What the?
What?! Crap!
You bastards!
Mommy, how could
you do this to me?
This is my body!
And look how you've been
treating it.
Ed.
Oh, what?
You don't like
my tattoos, huh?
I'll get bigger ones!
You don't like my hair?
I'll shave it off!
They made me take
my earrings off, too.
This is insane!
You drug me, you take my tats...
my CDs, everything!
Honey, it is
for your own good.
Your parents love you
very much, Jenna.
They've told me many times.
Who the hell are you?
Cliff Brooks...
head of the Evergreen
Homeowners Association.
So this was your idea?
Jenna, do you realize...
what your parents
had to sacrifice...
to move here?
Everything we own.
Your parents
are providing you...
a haven from
the outside world...
with its drugs, gangster
rap, violent movies.
Oh, you mean
everything I care about?
Life is full of trade-offs.
Whatever.
You're not gonna change me.
That wasn't fair, daddy.
Cigarettes gave daddy
a heart attack.
Not according to him.
He thinks I did.
How'd you sneak
'em in, anyway?
In the trunk, underneath
the jumper cables.
Listen, Jules,
I gotta get outta here.
You mean running away?
Yeah. I... I gotta get away...
while I still know who I am.
You're just gonna leave me here?
No. I'll come back for you...
just as soon as I get
a place, some money...
The hell you will.
Hey, watch your language.
But mom and dad moved here...
because of you.
Well, maybe they can
get a refund.
Mike. Wait.
How you guys doin'?
So they got you with
the lemonade, too, huh?
Yep, the same way
they stripped me clean...
my first night here.
Welcome to heavenly Evergreen.
How long have you lived here?
Long enough to know
that if there was a way out...
I'd have found it already.
How do you survive?
I got ways.
I'm Logan.
Jenna.
Winslow, I know.
16 years old.
Arrested twice for possession.
Got suspended from Holy Cross...
for sleeping with
a teacher's aide. Nice.
I... I'm assuming it was a "he."
How do you know about all this?
Well, the Homeowners
Association has files...
on all the families
living here...
and I happen to have
a key to the file room.
This place is like a prison.
Yeah. Although it's not
as bad as Arcadia.
Arcadia? What's that?
I think it's, like...
like a military school.
See, if you piss people off...
that's where they send you.
And if Brooks and the rest
of the storm troopers...
send you someplace,
you know it ain't good.
So, what do you do
to have fun around here?
Well, there's...
there's always homework.
Or I got a stash of MP3s...
a bottle of Jack,
and a little weed...
all buried not far from here.
My hero.
There's a community picnic
this Saturday...
sack races, 3-bean salad...
clay making for the kiddies.
Oh, you'll be there.
Yeah, it's mandatory.
Everyone's there.
But I say that we meet up...
grab a blanket...
sneak back up here,
and break some rules.
I'm in.
That's the way I like it.
You should
have him come over...
spend some time.
Found him yet?
Not yet, but we will.
There's no place to hide.
I'm afraid he's gone.
Jack, seriously...
Logan's had plenty of chances.
He's our only son.
His fate is in the hands
of the Community Council.
Jules, what are you doing
sneaking around?
You're supposed to be in bed.
So should you. It's past 10:00.
Oh, I'm breaking
my curfew. I'm so scared.
They're gonna send me
to Arcadia. Oh, no.
I'll be good. I promise.
That's not funny.
What are you doing reading
the Evergreen bylaws?
Huh?
This crap
will warp your brain!
I'm just doing it
to make mom and dad happy.
You coming inside?
In a minute.
Wait.
No good night?
You can be such
a butthead sometimes.
That's me.
Mom! Dad!
It's me! Let me in!
Let me in! It's me!
Logan!
Hide! Now!
Logan... surrender.
There is nowhere to run.
What took you
chuckleheads so long?
Jenna! Downstairs, right now!
Coming!
We'd like to talk
to you about Logan.
What about him?
He's in very serious trouble.
Several witnesses
saw the two of you...
together the other day.
Yeah, so? We weren't
doing anything.
Did you know about all that crap
he had buried in the woods?
Look, who's in trouble here,
me or him?
Are you aware that he had
a hunting knife out there, too?
And he attacked
one of our security guards...
quite brutally, I might add.
Logan...
I told him that he was
gonna get in trouble.
I know this has been...
a difficult transition
for you, Jenna.
In the future...
if someone approaches you
with anything off-limits...
I'd like to believe
you'll report it.
I'll keep my eyes open.
We'd appreciate it.
You know your daughter.
Can we trust her?
I'd like to think so.
What's gonna
happen to that boy?
Oh, he'll turn over
a new leaf...
one way or the another.
We'll decide at
the Community Council...
at the high school tonight,
which is mandatory, by the way.
Look, I'm tellin' you...
there is somethin' seriously
wrong with this place.
I went online and ran
all kinds of searches...
on Arcadia Military School.
There's no such thing.
There's no school
with that name.
Well, why would
they lie about that?
I don't know, but I know
that they are lying about...
Logan cutting up that guard.
There's no way.
There is just no way.
So what are you gonna do?
I'm gonna figure out
what's going on around here.
We should get back inside.
Jen, mom and dad
signed a contract.
If we get kicked out
of this place...
we lose everything.
You're gonna have to trust me.
OK, Jules?
West side, report.
7-10. All clear.
While we wait
for the official count...
I'd like to move on
to other business.
Now, in the light
of this recent incident...
I propose that we
instate random car checks...
upon reentry into Evergreen.
Obviously, this is troubling...
but unless we stop contraband...
from coming into
this community...
we're gonna find ourselves...
right back here
in the same situation.
Uh, Ron... Nell...
I want you to remember...
that Logan will always
have a place in this community.
We've already picked out
a beautiful spot for his tree.
For God's sake,
he's my only child.
A number of us have
sent kids off to Arcadia...
myself included.
But it must be done for
the good of this community.
And people, let us not forget...
that we've saved
plenty more than we've lost.
Plenty more!
And if we have to toss out
a few bad apples...
I say it's worth it.
Let's face it...
Evergreen is the good life.
Keep moving.
We got the Agar boy.
We're bringing him in.
Logan!
Get out!
The sign!
- What?
- The sign!
Get out!
Don't! Run! Run!
Run!
Looks like one
of the Winslow girls.
Jules! Jules! Jules!
Hurry up, wake up.
I need your help.
What's going on?
I gotta get out of here
before they find me.
They're gonna
be here any minute.
What'd you do this time?
I can't explain it to you.
You wouldn't even believe me
if I told you.
- It's a nightmare.
- You're scaring me.
Just listen to me, OK, Jules?
All right, when they get here,
I want you to tell them...
that you saw me,
and you spoke to me...
and I said that I was
gonna be hiding...
in the ravine
down by Willow Road.
Where will you really be?
I'm gonna be
waiting for you, OK...
at the park down the street.
As soon as they leave,
I want you to sneak out...
and come find me, OK?
We're gonna find a way
out of this together.
I promise.
Can you do this for me?
Ok?
Jules?
You scared me.
Jules, what's wrong?
Why?
Jules, why?
You were going to ruin
everything again.
No!
Mommy! Daddy!
Please don't let me...
please don't do this!
Mommy, daddy, please don't
let them do this to me!
Now, Julie...
Let this tree be a reminder...
that there's something good...
in each and every one of us.
That's my good girl.
The Winslows have finally...
taken back control
of their family...
but it cost them
one teenage daughter...
a deal brokered only
in The Twilight Zone.