Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
I'd have died. The walkie-talkie,
the one in the bag I dropped.
He's got the other one.
I'm going back.
I tell you what!
My husband is alive.
Do you think I'm
not happy about that?
You were the one that
told me that he died.
God!
Oh, my God.
Morgan,
I don't know
if you're out there.
if you can hear me.
Maybe you're
listening right now.
I hope so.
I found others... my family,
if you can believe it.
My wife and son,
they're alive.
I wanted you to know that.
There's something else
you need to know.
Atlanta isn't what we thought.
It's not what they promised.
The city is...
Do not enter the city.
It belongs to the dead now.
We're camped
a few miles northwest,
up by a big abandoned
rock quarry.
You can see it on a map.
I hope you come find us.
But be careful.
Last night walkers
came out of the woods.
We lost people.
Watch yourself, Morgan.
Take care of your boy.
I'll try you again
tomorrow at dawn.
Andrea.
I'm so sorry.
She's gone.
You got to let us take her.
We all cared about her
and I promise we'll be
as gentle as we can.
She still won't move?
She won't even talk to us.
She's been there all night.
What do we do?
Can't just leave Amy like that.
We need to deal with it
same as the others.
I'll tell her how it is.
Andrea.
I know how the safety works.
All right.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Y'all can't be serious.
Let that girl hamstring us?
The dead girl's a time bomb.
What do you suggest?
Take the shot.
Clean, in the brain from here.
Hell, I can hit a turkey between
the eyes from this distance.
No. For God's sakes,
let her be.
Wake up, Jimbo.
We've got some work to do.
Thanks.
- Thanks.
- What are you guys doing?
This is for geeks.
Our people go over there.
What's the difference?
They're all infected.
Our people go
in that row over there.
We don't burn them!
We bury them.
Understand?
Our people go
in that row over there.
You reap what you sow.
You know what?
Shut up, man.
Y'all left my brother for dead.
You had this coming.
Are you bleeding?
I just got some on me
from the bodies.
That blood is fresh.
Were you bit?
No.
I got scratched
during the attack.
- You got bit.
- I'm fine.
Then show me.
- Don't tell, please.
- A walker got him.
A walker bit Jim.
- I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Show it to us.
Show it to us.
- Easy, Jim.
- Grab him.
Jim, put it down.
Put it down.
I'm okay.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
I say we put
a pickaxe in his head
and the dead girl's
and be done with it.
Is that what you'd want
if it were you?
Yeah, and I'd thank you
while you did it.
I hate to say it...
I never thought I would...
but maybe Daryl's right.
Jim's not a monster, Dale,
or some rabid dog.
- I'm not suggesting...
- He's sick. A sick man.
We start down that road,
where do we draw the line?
The line's pretty clear.
Zero tolerance for walkers,
- or them to be.
- What if we can get him help?
I heard the C.D.C.
was working on a cure.
I heard that too. Heard a lot of
things before the world went to hell.
What if the C.D.C. is
still up and running?
- Man, that is a stretch right there.
- Why?
If there's any government
left, any structure at all,
they'd protect the C.D.C.
at all costs, wouldn't they?
I think it's our best shot.
Shelter, protection...
Okay, Rick, you want those things,
all right? I do too, okay?
Now if they exist,
they're at the army base.
- Fort Benning. - That's 100
miles in the opposite direction.
That is right.
But it's away from the hot zone.
Now listen to me.
If that place is operational,
it'll be heavily armed.
We'd be safe there.
The military were on the
front lines of this thing.
They got overrun.
We've all seen that.
The C.D.C. is our best choice
and Jim's only chance.
You go looking for aspirin,
do what you need to do.
Someone needs to have
some balls to take care
- of this damn problem!
- Hey hey hey!
We don't kill the living.
That's funny coming from a man
who just put a gun to my head.
We may disagree on some things,
not on this.
You put it down.
Go on.
- Come with me.
- Where are you taking me?
Somewhere safe.
I came to pay my respects.
Did I ever mention
how I lost my wife?
- Cancer, wasn't it?
- Yeah.
I dragged her to every doctor,
every test.
And after all the surgeries
and the chemos,
she was ready.
She accepted it, you know?
But I never could.
And I spent
the last few years
so angry.
I felt so cheated.
Since she passed,
you girls were
the first people...
That I cared anything for.
This is her birthday?
Her birthday was always like...
like a week long affair.
But I somehow always missed it.
I was away at college
or too busy for kid's parties.
She'd call all excited.
I always said
that I'd make it home
and I really always meant to,
but I never made it
past that phone call.
I know things
are hard enough for you
without adding guilt
into the mix, huh?
I'll do it.
He's my husband.
Amy.
Amy, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry
for not ever being there.
I always thought
there'd be more time.
I'm here now, Amy.
I'm here.
I love you.
Say it.
Okay.
I'm thinking if
you'd of stayed here,
if you'd have looked
after your own...
Instead you went off.
You took half our manpower with you.
I'm thinking maybe our losses
wouldn't have been so bad.
If we hadn't gone off
and brought those guns back
when we did, I think our losses
would have been a lot worse.
Maybe the entire camp.
I still think it's a mistake
not burning these bodies.
It's what we said
we'd do, right?
Burn 'em all,
wasn't that the idea?
At first.
The Chinaman gets
all emotional,
says it's not the thing to do,
we just follow him along?
These people need to know
who the hell's in charge here,
- what the rules are.
- There are no rules.
Well, that's a problem.
We haven't had one minute to hold
onto anything of our old selves.
We need time to mourn
and we need to bury our dead.
It's what people do.
Oh no.
No no no no.
No, not this, please.
No no no.
Oh, no no no.
No no.
I can do it.
I can do it!
Hey.
Burying other people
is bad enough,
- but the thought of one of us...
- Shh.
Are we safe now, dad?
Now that we're together?
I won't leave again.
I promise you that.
Not for anything.
Now give me a chance
to discuss some things
with your mom, okay?
- Yeah.
- All right.
All right.
Shane blames me
for not being here.
Do you?
We got guns now.
We're stronger.
And we have fewer people.
That makes us weaker.
You want me to say
I think you were right?
I understand that.
All I can say is that neither
one of you is entirely wrong.
It's the best
I can do right now.
What about the C.D.C.?
- Rick...
- We're at the ragged edge here.
We need relief and we got
a sick man who needs help.
I don't know why
people can't see that.
Well, look at their faces.
Look at mine.
We're all terrified.
If one of us suggested,
based on a hunch,
that we head toward that city,
you'd have no part of it.
Tell me something
with certainty.
I love you.
That's all I got.
I love you too.
His fever is worse.
You need anything?
Uh...
Water.
Could use more water.
- I'll get some.
- Okay.
Carol, you help me?
You save a grave for me?
Nobody wants that.
It's not about
what you want.
That, uh...
that sound you hear,
that's God laughing
while you make plans.
What I want, Jim, if...
if God allows,
is to get you some help.
Watch the mangroves.
Their roots will gouge
the whole boat.
You know that, right?
Amy is there swimming.
You'll watch the boat, right?
You said you would.
I'll watch the boat.
Don't worry.
Okay.
I need you to help talk
some sense into Rick.
Look, this C.D.C. thing,
Lori, it's a mistake.
So you're backing him?
What else would I do?
He's my husband.
Look, it may be time for you
to play the dutiful wife,
but you can't tell me
that fixing your marriage
is worth putting
people's lives at risk.
I think folks around here can make up their
minds without bringing my marriage into it.
It's a habit you need to break.
I guess I'll just
add it to the list
of habits that I'm breaking
whether I like it or not.
What habits?
Just talking about
my need for a plan, man.
So what is it?
Are we leaving or not?
Maybe y'all just
want to stay here.
We could hang
some more tin cans.
We can't stay here.
We both know that.
I was just telling Shane I think
we should trust your gut.
Let's go do our sweep.
Tell you what, man,
these people, man,
they're not convinced.
You know?
You head to the C.D.C.,
you might be on your own.
You gotta really consider
whether you want
to put Lori and Carl
in that kind of spot.
I got to do
what's best for my family.
Best for your family?
What's that?
- Exposing them to all kinds of risks?
- As opposed to what?
Crossing 100 miles
of hostile territory?
If we're looking for a lifeline, I
say swim toward the closest ship,
not further out to sea.
Why can't you back me up?
Look, I want to.
It's just...
I don't see it.
If it was your family,
you'd feel differently.
What did you say to me?
I kept 'em safe, man.
I looked after them
like they were my own.
- That's what I did.
- I didn't mean it that way.
Well, how'd you mean it?
Go on, man.
How'd you mean it?
You're misinterpreting me.
- All right.
- You're just hearing it wrong.
- Yeah?
- Look, you know...
You know I can never
repay that debt, okay?
Jesus.
I know.
Gonna have to start wearing
reflective vests out here.
Seriously.
Come on, man.
Come on, man, let's go.
Nothing out here.
I've been, uh...
I've been thinking
about Rick's plan.
Now look, there are no...
There are no guarantees
either way.
I'll be the first one
to admit that.
I've known this man
a long time.
I trust his instincts.
I say the most important thing
here is we need to stay together.
So those of you that agree,
we leave first thing
in the morning.
Okay?
We're moving out,
leaving the quarry.
If you heard me yesterday,
you may be coming here.
If you are, we'll be gone
by the time you arrive.
I'm leaving a note
and map behind for you
taped to a red car
so you can follow our trail.
We're heading
to the C.D.C.
If there's anything left,
it's got to be there,
don't you think?
Morgan...
I hope you were right
about that place.
I need you to be.
Everybody listen up.
Those of you with C.B.s,
we're gonna be on channel 40.
Let's keep
the chatter down, okay?
Now you got a problem,
don't have a C.B.,
can't get a signal or anything at all,
you're gonna hit your horn one time.
That'll stop the caravan.
- Any questions?
- We're, uh...
We're...
we're not going.
We have family in Birmingham.
We want to be with our people.
You go on your own, you won't
have anyone to watch your back.
We'll take the chance.
I got to do what's best
for my family.
- You sure?
- We talked about it.
We're sure.
All right.
- Shane.
- Yeah, all right.
- .357?
- Yeah.
The box is half full.
Thank you all...
For everything.
Come here.
Good luck, man.
- Appreciate it.
- Yeah.
Bye.
Thank you.
Channel 40
if you change your minds.
- All right?
- Yeah.
I know.
What makes you think
our odds are any better?
Come on.
Let's go.
Let's move out.
I told you we'd never
get far on that hose.
I said I needed the one
from the cube van.
Can you jury-rig it?
That's all it's been so far.
It's more duct tape than hose.
And I'm out of duct tape.
I see something up ahead.
A gas station if we're lucky.
Y'all, Jim...
It's bad. I don't think
he can take anymore.
Hey, Rick, you want
to hold down the fort?
I'll drive ahead,
see what I can bring back.
Yeah, I'll come along
too and I'll back you up.
Y'all keep your eyes open now.
We'll be right back.
We'll be back on the road soon.
Oh no.
Christ..
My bones...
My bones are like glass.
Every little bump...
God, this ride is killing me.
Leave me here.
I'm done.
Just leave me.
I want to be with my family.
They're all dead.
I don't think you know
what you're asking.
The fever... You've been
delirious more often than not.
I know.
Don't you think I know?
I'm clear now.
In five minutes I may not be.
Rick, I know what I'm asking.
I want this.
Leave me here.
Now that's on me.
Okay?
My decision.
Not your failure.
It's what he says he wants.
And he's lucid?
He seems to be.
I would say yes.
Back in the camp when I
said Daryl might be right
and you shut me down,
you misunderstood.
I would never go along
with callously killing a man.
I was just gonna suggest
that we ask Jim what he wants.
And I think we have an answer.
We just leave him here?
We take off?
Man, I'm not sure
I could live with that.
It's not your call,
either one of you.
Yeah. That's it.
Hey, another damn tree.
Hey, Jim...
I mean, you know
it doesn't need to be this.
No.
It's good.
The breeze feels nice.
Okay.
All right.
Just close your eyes, sweetie.
Don't fight.
Jim, do you want this?
No.
You'll need it.
I'm okay.
Oh. Hey.
Thanks for, uh,
for fighting for us.
Okay.
Wildfire MSB3417 active
begin transmission.
Jenner here.
It's day 194 since
wildfire was declared
and 63 days since the disease
abruptly went global.
There's no clinical
progress to report.
Item... I finally got the scrubbers in the
east sector shut down to save power.
Wish I could have
done it a month ago,
but it took me that long
to figure it out.
Too bad I never studied
engineering.
Could have saved a lot of amps.
Item... I'm still
not sleeping well.
Can't seem to keep
regular hours.
Living underground
doesn't help,
not knowing
if it's day or night.
I'm just feeling very
off-kilter these days.
Alert status.
Air qualifiers indicate
corrosive fumes.
All personnel
must clear the room.
Corrosive element is deemed
poisonous if inhaled.
All personnel clear.
Full decontamination
in effect.
No!
Full decontamination
complete.
The TS19 samples are gone.
The tragedy of their loss
cannot be overstat.
They were our freshest
samples by far.
None of the other samples
we gathered even came close.
Those are necrotic,
useless dead flesh.
I don't even know
why I'm talking to you.
I bet there isn't
a single son of a bitch
out there still listening,
is there?
Is there?
Fine.
Saves me the embarrassment.
I think tomorrow I'm gonna
blow my brains out.
I haven't decided.
But tonight,
I'm getting drunk.
Speaking of which,
how far do you think
I can chuck this, huh?
Pretty far I bet.
- - Oh!
It is out of the stadium!
All right, everybody.
Keep moving. Go on.
Stay quiet.
Let's go.
Okay, keep moving. Stay together.
- Keep moving. Come on.
- Shh.
- Carol.
Oh, God.
No.
Keep it together.
Come on.
We're almost there, baby.
Almost there.
Nothing?
There's nobody here.
Then why are
these shutters down?
- Walkers!
- Baby, come on.
You led us into a graveyard!
- He made a call.
- It was the wrong damn call!
Just shut up. You hear?
Shut up. Shut up!
- Rick, this is a dead end.
- Where are we gonna go?
Do you hear me?
No blame.
She's right. We can't be here,
this close to the city after dark.
Fort Benning, Rick...
Still an option.
On what? No food, no fuel.
That's 100 miles.
125.
I checked the map.
Forget Fort Benning.
We need answers tonight, now.
- Well, think of something.
- Come on, let's go.
- Let's get out of here.
- Let's go. Please.
All right,
everybody back to the cars.
- Let's go. Move.
- The camera... it moved.
- You imagined it.
- It moved.
- Rick, it is dead, man.
It's an automated device.
It's gears, okay?
They're just winding down.
Now come on.
- No, just go away.
- Man, just listen to me.
Look around this place.
It's dead, okay?
It's dead.
You need to let it go, Rick.
Rick, there's nobody here!
I know you're in there.
I know you can hear me.
- Everybody get back to the cars now!
- Please, we're desperate.
Please help us.
We have women, children,
- no food, hardly any gas left.
- Rick.
- There's nobody here.
- We have nowhere else to go.
- - Keep your eyes open.
If you don't let us in,
you're killing us!
- Please!
- Come on, buddy, let's go.
- Let's go.
- Please help us.
You're killing us!
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
www.addic7ed.Com