In this book i collected all
the prophecies of eibon,
handed down from generation to
generation over more then 4,000 years.
You ungodly warlock.
Because of you this hotel and
this town will be cursed forever.
The seven dreaded gateways are
concealed in 7 cursed places.
Woe be unto him who ventures
near without knowledge.
Be careful what you do because
this hotel was built on one of
the 7 doors of evil
and only i could save you.
Woe be unto him who opens
one of the 7 gateways to hell,
because through that gateway
evil will invade the world.
I told you martin, we can't. All i
inherited was the hotel, nothing else.
But it'd be such a pity not to.
Let me at least finish the plans.
No forget it.
I won't even charge you
for it. Look, really it's not the case.
Ljust wanted to clean up the outside
walls a bit, and maybe tidy up inside
a bit and then, well, business
starts booming we'll see.
It's better we do it now because wait
four months or six and believe me,
you are going to lay out.
You can't imagine the effect
that double digit inflation is
having on housing.
Hi larry. How's it going?
Oh, good morning. I'm gonna have
this whole wall finished by tonight.
Great.
Bye.
Outside is ok. Good old 1800th louisiana,
but the interior.
I mean, hotels just aren't...
the eyes!
The eyes!
Eyes!
Arthur. Where's that doctor?
He's on his way.
This man needs to get to a hospital.
I'll clean up the wounds first. Have
you got any water?
I'm sorry, but till the plumber comes
back i'm afraid i can't get you any.
Then we'd better move him right now.
Give me a hand, will you?
Take the legs... gently...
ok, up, right.
Thank you doctor.
It's ok.
How can i check up on him?
Ask me at the hospital. John mckay.
We're off to a great start. Let's just
hope there isn't any lasting damage.
I sure would like to know how a man
can fall off a scaffolding 6 feet wide.
Liza. Hey, look at this picture.
Weird.
I wasn't aware that you had
already scored a client.
Client? There isn't a soul here!
I guess it must have been arthur.
Yeah.
Hey, is anybody home?
Just a minute, i'm coming!
Good morning. Are you
the plumber? Joe, right?
Yes ma'm. What's the trouble?
No, thank you. I'm afraid i can't tell you.
Nothing comes out of the faucets,
and yet somehow the basement is flooded.
You tell me.
The whole basement?
And how!
Well, let's take a look.
Ok! Follow me, this way.
Off we go.
I hope it isn't too serious. Watch out,
the stairs are really slippery.
I'm an old sewer rat.
Well, here it is. How long do
you think it will take?
It'll take as long as it takes!
Martha?
I made this little pathway
to the far end just forjoe.
Thank you martha.
Well, i'll go take that look.
Where is arthur?
He is upstairs, tidying up,
we're doing our best to help
yeah, i know. Thank you.
Listen, i'll be going into town later.
Would you please make
me out a list of all the things
we'll need? Ok,
don't worry.
Arthur! What are you doing in my room?
I was looking for keys.
Which keys?
I told ma i was gonna clean up the
rooms but some of them are locked.
Well, ljust have to find those keys,
arthur, won't i? Or else we'll
simply call a locksmith.
In the meantime, could you go up on
the roof and check the chimney?
I think it is clogged.
I heard a car drive up before.
Was it joe?
Yeah. Why??
You are liza, aren't you? Yes.
My name is emily.
I've been looking foryou.
Joe!
Arthur?
I don't understand, emily.
How do you...
don't worry. I know the way by heart.
And there's always dickey here.
Come liza. I'll show you the way.
Joe?
Emily. Why did you say i must
give up the hotel?
I can't explain it to you.
Just take my word for it.
Go back to where you came from
and hurry.
What's the matter?
I don't know. He is in amazingly
good condition for a corpse
who is supposed to have been
dead for 6 years.
Well, the d.a. Said to open him up
and see what he had for breakfast.
How about we give it
a try with...
forget it.
You wanna wire this old guy into
your brain wave machine?
Why not?
Okay. Okay.
But you're on your own with this one.
I warn you though. When i get back,
i'm gonna give him an autopsy.
Harris here.
Miller want you up at 24 on the double.
I'm on my way honey.
Wait here for me jill. I won't be long.
Mommy! Mommy!
So, what did you do in the big apple?
Just about everything a girl could do
without losing her good english
breeding and reputation,
modeling, dancing, secretary.
I almost became an unsuccessful
fashion designer.
When this letter arrived
announcing the inheritance.
Big surprise, uh?
More or less. I mean, i knew i had
a rich uncle who was a bachelor
with a lot of real estate
imagined for one day to the next
but i neverthat i'd be running a hotel.
Tell me, with all those accidents,
you know, joe the plumber
and the house painter.
Do you think you'll give up now?
I couldn't do that if i wanted to.
This is my last chance.
Either i run this hotel or i go on relief.
Well i tell you what,
when you get the hotel fixed up,
i'll come and stay there
so you can book me a room now.
Sure, you've got it. The best in
the house.
Of course. How long do you think
it'll be before it's ready?
I don't know, it's driving on so much.
Arthur and martha are more of a
hindrance then a help.
They just can't seem to get it together.
Well, if you hired them,
you can fire them.
But, i can't fire them.
They came with the hotel.
Strange, i've never heard of them.
Dr. Mckay,
dr. Mckay,
you're wanted on the phone.
It's the hospital.
Thank you. Excuse me.
Oh... harris, hi.
What?
...in heaven
give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us ourtrespasses, as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
Lead us not to temptation, but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
...and as we commit the souls of
joe and mary ann, to ourfather
in heaven we pray together,
oh merciful father,
watch overjill, their daughter
whom joe and mary ann's untimely departure
has left alone in this world, as a helpless child
confort her, and guide her, and give her strenght
we ask this, o lord,
in the name of the father and of the son,
and of the holy ghost. Amen.
Courage, my child
liza!
Liza!
Emily?
Why didn't you listen to me liza?
We blind see things more clearly.
I wanted to spare you, but now
i'll have to tell you everything.
60 years ago everybody in this
hotel disappeared.
Every last person.
A painter called schweik,
who lived here closeted in his room
had found a key.
What key?
The seven gateways to hell.
This house was constructed
on one of the...
who else is here?
There's nobody here.
I can feel a presence.
Somebody else is in here.
No, emily. Nobody is here.
Yes, it's him. He is here again.
He has come back to the hotel.
Get ahold of yourself,
emily, please.
What is this?
That? A painting, just an old painting.
There's the bell.
That's the bell from room 36.
That's where he was killed, in his room!
36 was schweik's room,
the man who found the key.
He has returned, liza.
Don't ever enterthat room.
Now look emily, i've lived in ny
all my life and if there is one thing
i've learned not to believe in it's ghosts.
I was lucky to inherit this hotel.
The first good break i've had.
It'll take more than a faulty electrical
contact or some crazy story to make me
give it up.
Emily! Emily! Emily!
Liza!
John!
Hey, hey, calm down, calm down.
Take it easy, take it easy, come on.
But i saw him. There, nailed to the wall.
He...
see these nails.
Well, they certainly look old,
but this seems more like rust
than blood.
Now it seems so impossible, so absurd.
And yet... i don't know.
Now look, come and tell me
exactly what you saw, hmm?
No, never mind. It's useless.
I guess i must have a pretty wild
imagination.
Hmm?
I got carried away with that story
that emily told me about room 36.
Emily? Who's emily?
The blind girl
that lives in the old house
by the crossroads.
There's no blind girl living there.
And i know everyone around here.
The book!
The what?
The book that was on the desk. It's gone!
Open two walls and enterthe basement
and then you'll have a room
for a kitchen and maybe for a laundry.
Huh?
What do you think of that?
Martin,
i've already told you.
I don't have the money.
Do whateveryou want to as long
as it doesn't cost.
I have carte blanche?
Carte blanche, but not a blank check.
Okay? Okay. Well, the
first thing we do is bring someone
in to pump out all the water.
That i can get done real cheap.
And then... oh, and on the other side
i'll make a living room
and a game room. Have you got
the original plans of the cellar by any chance?
There was another book here.
A different one.
You wanna buy the book
no, not this one.
The one that was here before,
just a second ago.
That book has
been there fortwo years.
Nobody wants to buy it. It's very
nice though. Very, very interesting.
Liza! What's wrong?
About the book?
I was just looking
for...
what? Is anything the matter?
You look sick.
You're sure
it's nothing?
I'm just a little tired that's all.
I think i'm beginning to see things.
I get the picture. Later i'll have to
go to the town hall and dig out
the originals from the files.
Re-open that hotel? Uh, huh.
Anyway, all the turn of the century
building plans are on those upper
shelves there.
They should be under what
the cards say, m 13,012.
Well, let's get them down and look at them.
You surprised me mr. Avery.
You haven't heard about ourtown
employees latest labor victory?
It tooks three weeks strike to win.
Yeah. It was something about lunch.
An earlier break.
I'm sure you'll be ok on your own.
I'll be out until one or a quarter of.
You feel completely at home now,
you hear?
Have a happy lunch.
Thank you.
I'm gonna lock the door,
that way you won't be disturbed.
First from one to two,
and now from twelve to one.
Three weeks of picketing.
A great labor victory!
Now, then. M 13,012. manderville.
7 doors hotel. Hotel... 7 doors.
What the...?!
"The 7 dreaded gateways to hell
are concealed in 7 cursed places."
"And the day the gates of hell are opened,
on that day the dead will walk the earth."
Good boy, dicky, good boy.
Who's there? Who's there?
Answer me! I know you're there!
Where are you? Who are you? Who?
I know it's you. I can sense it.
What do you want from me now?
What is it now? Schweik, i know you're here.
No, no, schweik!
Go away! I don't want to go back!
You can't take me.
I don't want to go back.
Stop tormenting me! Don't get
any closer! Don't get any closer!
No! Go away! Leave me in peace.
Don't touch me!
You can't take me back!
I did what i've been asked,
now leave me alone! Go! Go away!
No! I never spoke. You can't
condemn me! I don't want to go back!
Attack dicky! Attack dicky! Attack!
Dicky! Dicky! Don't let them get
near me! Attack! Attack! Chase them
away! Attack! Get rid of them, dicky!
Attack! Dicky! Attack!
Good boy.
Good boy. Good boy, dicky.
You made them go away.
Martha? Arthur? Arthur?
No! No! No!
Stop it! Liza! Liza! Stop it!
Liza, come on, it's me.
Come on, calm down.
Come sit down,
i saw arthur,
come on sit down.
He was dead but...
liza, liza, stop it!
I'm sick of hearing all these stories.
What stories?? Well, like the first one.
There was a man nailed to the wall in room 36.
And the blind girl that doesn't exist.
Emily's real. She does exist. I saw her.
I spoke to her.
The girl that lives in the old house
by the crossroads?
Yes!
That house has been abandoned
forthe last 50 years.
But that's not true. It's not possible.
I was there! I mean i went there.
I was there.
Yes, i know you were there. I found
the book you left for me to read.
You found the book?
And i read it.
What did it say?
Show me where is arthur.
Here? And he tried to kill you? Huh?
Please john, you must believe me.
I swear.
So where is arthur now?
But i don't know! He attacked me!
I was trying to break free.
He was here!
The cuts on my...
there are no!
I must be going crazy.
Perhaps, or else...
who are you liza? Who are you really?
John, i don't understand you.
What a question. Why do you ask?
Because according to the book of eibon,
this hotel is one of the
7 gateways to hell.
"And you will face the sea of darkness
and all therein that may be explored."
Strange. There isn't a soul in sight.
Yea. Well, we'll be at the hospital
pretty soon.
I wanna talk to harris.
Where is everybody?
Let's try the laboratory.
But john...
no, liza, i'm a doctor,
and i won't accept irrational explanations
i want to talk to harris.
I'm gonna call the fbi.
John!
The elevator! Get the hell going!
Jill?
Jill!
Harris! What the hell is going on
around here?
I don't know. I think i'm going crazy.
Here they come!
It's jill.
She was in the autopsy theater all alone.
This way.
Come on.
No!
We're underthe hotel.
Impossible!
It's impossible!
It's crazy.
What's happened? Why are we here?
Come on.
"And you will face the sea of darkness
and all therein that may be explored."