What're you looking at?
Nothing.
Shanks, what's your status?
Yeah, I got her in the car now.
She's not going anywhere.
Listen, we hit a little traffic
on the BQE.
Running a little late,
tell Jimmy, to meet us at the house.
- Over.
- Copy.
Here we are.
Home sweet home.
Enjoy the fresh air.
Last time you'll get to.
- Now, let's go.
- I'm goin'.
Let's go.
Hasn't changed much, has it?
Hey!
- You're late.
- Yeah, traffic.
- Hi, I'm Jimmy.
- Hi.
- Let's get started.
- All right.
Yeah, it's a bit bulky.
Actually, I keep requesting
the smaller ones,
but the department won't spend
the money, so...
Just put the fucking thing on her.
I'm gonna need your leg, please.
Is that too tight?
- What, is this a date?
- No, it's fine.
There you go.
Now, it stays on your ankle
all the time.
It never comes off,
even when you shower.
Key stays with me.
You're now under house arrest,
and you'll remain on these premises
for the duration of your entire sentence.
- Understand?
- Yep.
Good. Jimmy, show her
how this thing works.
You're free to move anywhere
within 100 foot radius.
If you go past the 100 foot perimeter,
an alarm activates.
If the alarm continues
for more than 3 minutes,
a signal will automatically be sent,
and the cops will be dispatched
to the scene immediately.
That would be me.
Break house arrest,
you go back to jail.
Any violation automatically adds
10 years to your sentence, you get it?
- Do you get it?!
- Yeah, I get it!
Um, also, if you attempt to remove
the electronic ankle bracelet...
or otherwise tamper
with the base unit...
again, an alarm will automatically
alert the police.
Just try it.
Okay.
I wanna make sure that you have maximum
mobility within this restricted area.
- Thanks, Jimmy.
- You're welcome.
Now, the base unit comes
with its own power source...
so even if we get a blackout
or something, it's live.
Ms. Watson, go to
the front door, please.
Good.
What do you think you're doing?
I gotta get the mail, don't I?
Any questions?
None on my end.
How about you, Lou?
Goodbye.
You got it.
Have a nice day, now.
You'd think you guys,
would clean that up.
You made the mess,
you clean it up.
Here you got the next year to sit in
this house and think about what you did.
I hope it doesn't give you
a minute's peace.
You, son of a bitch!
If you'd have answered
just one of my 9-1-1 calls...
or taken any of my police
reports seriously...
Mike would be alive today.
You didn't have to kill my partner.
Better him than me.
Carol!
What do you mean you have no one
in the area to turn the power on?
I called Con-Ed twice today, the guy
said he'd be here between 1 and 4.
Not util Monday?
Oh, man! I gotta go the whole
weekend with no electricity?
That's just great.
No, no, that's it.
Thank you.
Hello.
Honey, your fine ass better be in front
of a color TV watching American Idol...
with a Hagen-Daz in one hand and a bottle
of Johnnie Walker in the other.
What's up, girlfriend?!
Same bitches different day, you know.
How's everything on the outside, baby?
Well, I'm home, Chandra.
But, you know, they gave me one of those
electronic bracelet thingies, you know?
So it's like I'm sort
of still in jail.
Stop feeling sorry for yourself,
go get laid.
Oh, I don't know how much action
I'm gonna see stuck in this house.
Use the phone, make a booty call.
You don't know how lucky you are.
You make damn sure,
you never come back here.
Rosey and Johnson are still in solitary
for that shit they did to you.
I could never go back inside,
I'd die first.
Listen, my time is up. I gotta go,
but I'm glad you're home.
The girls in Cell Block "C"
say hi.
- Call me.
- Come visit.
Who's there?
Oh, shit.
Oh, no...
Oh, no, no, God!
Please don't be a rat.
Oh, God!
Oh, my God, you scared
the shit out of me!
Come here.
Hey.
Come on, it's okay.
Come here.
Come on.
Hi... it's okay.
I ain't gonna hurt you!
Get back... get back,
or I'll use this! Back off!
- How did you get in?
- Don't cut me!
- How'd you get in?
- An open window in the basement.
- The basement? That's where you been staying?
- Yeah, in the basement.
- Get out! Get out! Get out!
- I'm going.
- Get out!
- I'm going!
Hi, is this Christine's?
Do you deliver?
- Who's there?
- Christine's delivery.
Oh... huh, hang on a sec.
- Hi.
- Hi, huh...
it's a long story,
oh, come in.
Huh... where'd you want these?
Kitchen... huh,
just down the hall.
Oh... huh, anywhere.
- You... huh, just moved in?
- Yeah.
Well, not exactly.
It's my house,
I... I was away for awhile.
I live just up the street.
This place was closed up
for the longest time. I thought...
the cops had...
I don't know.
- It's a nice place.
- Oh, thanks.
- I'm Marnie.
- I'm Joey, hi.
Hi, Joey, huh...
I need you to bring me groceries
regularly, is that okay with you?
The market's right around the corner.
Yeah, I know, I'm... I'm
kinda the stay-at-home type.
That's cool, I can use the tips.
Right.
- How's five?
- Yeah, thanks, that'll be cool.
So... um, what do you do?
Oh, I... I work out of the house.
Right... well, cool.
Okay, well...
Yeah, well, I guess,
I should be getting back.
- Alright, see you around, Ms. Watson.
- Marnie.
Okay! Nice to meet you, Marnie.
Robbing the cradle.
What happened?
I fell down.
No, what happened, Marnie?
- I don't remember.
- You remember prison?
How did you get a bruise
on the side of your face?
I don't know. I guess
it happened when I...
- I fell down and hit my head.
- Oh, really? No.
You don't get a bruise on the side of
your face when you fall on your head.
It looks like a person did that.
It wasn't a person.
Marnie, was there somebody
in this house with you last night?
No.
- You covering for somebody?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
I'm asking you.
Is somebody beating on you and for
some reason you're covering for them?
No! Why would I do that?
- All right.
- Thanks.
I guess living in a house where you killed
your husband must be tough on anyone, huh?
I thought you would have
cleaned that up.
There's no such thing as ghosts.
I think I found one, cat.
Yeah... huh, is this Magnum Sales?
Yeah, I'm calling about your ad saying
you're looking for phone sales people.
It says here you can work out
of your own home.
Who's there?
Who the fuck is there?
Thank you, Con-Ed.
That's what's wrong with me.
Caffeine withdrawal.
You had it coming!
You hear me?!
You beat the shit out
of me for years!
And when you were
on the juice it was worse.
It's your fault you're dead.
You, bastard!
You were gonna kill me.
This is my house.
And I'm not leaving, you hear me?!
This is my house!
You'll have to kill me first!
Hi.
Well, I see you haven't lost
your flair for the dramatics.
Oh... huh, I cut myself shaving.
I can't believe you came.
Well, I left a message, I told you
I was coming by with the papers.
I know, but, I... I thought maybe you
send your assistant or something.
Well, what you wanna do?
Do it here, or do it inside?
Oh, in here, come in.
Sit down.
So I see you're still biting your nails.
Yeah. Thanks for noticing.
I'm... I'm glad you're out,
and doing well.
Well, it's not a penthouse overlooking
Central Park, but it's home.
And now it's your home.
I'm gonna make some coffee.
Want some coffee?
No, thanks.
Look, I have no idea why it was
mom's dying wish...
that you should have this place
when you got out, but,
I couldn't talk her out of it.
I don't understand
why you're so angry at me.
Just sign the goddamned papers,
Marnie.
No. Not until you tell me.
Tell you what?
That mom drained her life
savings to defend you?
That I had to watch
as the stress killed her?
And then to top it all off, she used her
life insurance to pay for this dump for you?
Is that what this is about?
Money?
You really don't get it, do you?
This is about you.
It's always been about you.
Precious little Marnie.
I thought you worked this stuff
out in therapy.
You know, that's exactly
what I would expect from you.
You create all kinds of problems...
and then, you just assume everyone else
is gonna clean them up for you.
This is the end of the line for me.
So, what are you gonna do now?
Go back to your fabulous life
of book publishing...
and tell all your socialite pals,
you're an only child?
And to think I never thought
you caught on that quickly.
It's ironic, isn't it?
After all these years you're the
one who got all the attention.
And now you'll spend
the next year in this hole...
with no one but the rats
to fall for your shit.
Trick or treat!
Hey.
Thanks.
- Marnie, you okay?
- Yeah, never better, come in.
- What happened?
- Well, I fell down the stairs.
To bad.
My Pop had to wear one
of those for 6 months.
I don't know who it was harder on,
him or my Mom, but...
she said things were a lot easier when he
wasn't hanging around the house all the time.
- How long you gotta wear it?
- Longer than 6 months.
- Yeah. I know.
- You do?
Talk around the neighborhood is,
some cop got killed by his wife.
This place was empty for years,
then you moved back.
It's what they are.
So, people been talking about me, huh?
Yeah, I guess.
- Bad stuff?
- Those people are idiots.
Those people used
to be my friends, Joey.
Carol next door, Romeros
down the block.
We used to have 'em over
for barbecues.
I mean, I used to watch their kids,
for christ sakes.
Now they don't want anything
to do with me.
Hey, screw those jack-asses.
- You want a cup of coffee?
- Yeah, sure.
So, huh...
what's the deal?
I mean, what happened?
I don't know if...
if I should talk about it.
That's a... that's cool if you don't
wanna talk, but if you do, it's okay.
We married right out of high school.
And we were really in love.
But, as soon as Mike joined the force,
he changed.
He hated his job, hated it.
And he brought it home with him.
That's when the beatings started.
People didn't see the bruises?
He knew how, not to leave marks.
You must've reported it
to the police, right?
Yeah, I filed 6 police reports, Joey.
His buddies investigated it.
Mike denied it all.
And then he beat the crap
out of me again.
I had nobody to turn to,
nothing I could do.
So I saw a lawyer
and I filed for divorce.
I was gonna move back
to my Mom's, but...
papers got shuffled and then
he got served a day early.
- He came at me with a knife, he...
- It's okay.
- I got so scared.
Somehow, something came
outta me, you know, I...
I... I got the knife away from him
and I just... I... I went at him...
I stabbed him three times.
Side... neck... chest.
He... he died over there
in the corner.
752 days ago.
I knew, I committed a terrible crime.
A terrible, terrible crime.
But I'm not a murderer,
I'm not.
Look, I wanna be your friend, all right?
So, I figure you need
some right now.
I don't give a crap what anybody says.
- I'd like that.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Good.
All right, well...
this...
is... my house number.
And... this...
is my cell.
- Okay?
- Okay.
You call me if you need anything, all right?
This means a lot.
Like I said, anything you need.
Oh, yeah, actually, there is something.
Name it.
Could you go to the library
and get me some books?
Sure, what kind of books?
Ones about ghosts.
In order to cleanse an area
of an unhealthy spirit...
it is first required, that said
area be thoroughly...
eradicated of all the decedent's earthly
possessions, belongings and reminders.
What do you think?
You have nine lives,
what do you care?
The easiest way to get rid of a
ghost is to simply ask it to leave.
Okay.
Use a firm voice and tell the ghost
exactly what you want and why.
This is the traditional practice
of smudging a home.
To get rid of an unwanted entity, crack
a window in each room of your home...
take a dried bundle of sage
and smudge your home...
clearing out any negative
or stagnant energies.
Smudging is simply lighting the sage bundle
and walking around your entire home...
allowing the smoke to circulate
and cleanse the energy and space.
The main thing is your intent,
which is your faith.
Your intentions are to rid the home
of negative energies and spirits.
They will know this,
if they are there...
Oh, fuck!
All right...
1-1000... 2-1000... 3-1000...
4-1000... 5-1000... 6-1000...
7-1000... 8-1000... 9-1000...
10-1000... 11-1000... 12-1000...
Okay, okay... everything...
Oh, shit!
Prick!
Marnie, open the door, it's Shanks!
Marnie!
What the fuck is going on here?
- Nothing.
- Bullshit, I heard screaming.
- Now what happened to you?
- I fell out of bed.
It looks like somebody's
been beating on you.
Oh, yeah? Like who?
It's just me here, Shanks,
you should know that.
You've been staking out the place
day and night like a stalker.
Well, there's been people coming
in and out of this house.
Is there somebody in this house
right now with you, Marnie?
- Define somebody.
- Meaning what?
Look around...
let me know what you find.
This is the police!
Anybody in this house, step out
with your hands on your head!
Come out with your hands up!
He must have slipped out the back
before I got here, huh?
What the hell do you want?
You're not telling me something.
Marnie...
Marnie, did somebody else
kill Mickey?
- What are you talking about?
- I'm asking you.
Did somebody kill him
and forced you to take the rap?
No.
Has that person come back here to make
sure, that you keep your mouth shut?
Is that what's going on here?
No, that's not it.
I think that is it.
I think that is it 'cause you're not
even back in this house for a day...
before somebody starts
smacking you around.
I think they're back.
I think they're here...
I think they're threatening
you again, that's it, isn't it?
- Isn't it?!
- I wish.
Marnie, who killed Mickey?
Who killed Mike, Marnie?
- I did.
- Bullshit!
Who really killed Mickey?
It's that kid, isn't it?
Yeah, the one who's delivering
the groceries.
You don't think I do
my fucking job, Marnie?
Joseph DiCenzo, did six in Juvi
for grand theft auto.
That little mother fucker killed my partner,
I swear to God I'll kill him myself!
You leave him alone, okay?
You leave him alone,
Lou, he's just a kid, okay?
He's my friend! He hangs out
and he talks to me is all!
Why are you covering
for Mike's killer?!
Let me help you, Marnie!
Let me help you,
you don't have to be afraid.
Just tell me!
Who the fuck killed Mike?
Just tell me who did it,
we'll put him down together.
We'll put his ass in jail, and you
can go, wherever the fuck you want!
Let me help you!
Let me protect you!
You can't protect me!
Marnie, I went back
and I looked...
I looked in Mike's files.
I saw all the assault reports
you filed on him.
It was just like you said.
I should have done something,
but, Marnie, he was my partner.
And now I gotta live with that.
But I will protect you now, Marnie.
I give you my word.
But you gotta talk to me.
You wouldn't believe me.
Try me.
Mike did this to me.
Marnie, Mike's dead.
Yeah? Well, he's taking the news badly.
What?
He's a ghost.
- A ghost?
- Yeah, that's right.
You know that line,
"Till death do us part"?
Well, that's a crock of shit.
You're crazy.
You're fucking nuts,
I can see it in your eyes.
And now you're here,
you're back under Mike's roof...
and you're going nuts.
Wow! Lady, lady, lady, lady!
You can't pack your trash like that!
You gotta wrap it properly
or I just can't take it!
Come on, Mister, please,
just this one time, okay?
- I promise next time I'll do it.
- I told everybody on my route...
Lady! Lady!
Oh, fuck!
I can't get rid of you
if you left something here, Prick!
Where is it, huh?
Where the fuck is it?
Fuck!
Come on, huh?
Where is it?
God-dammit!
Oh, my God!
Oh, Mike...
you were one dirty cop.
Thank you, for coming, Father.
I wanted to give you this.
A donation,
I wanna make to the church.
It was my husband's.
It's been a long time, since you've
been to confession, Marnie.
I'm here now if there is anything
you wanna tell me.
Perhaps you could unburden
yourself of any guilt.
I understand this isn't
the ideal confessional...
but whatever you say will be
strictly between us.
Oh, please, help me, Father.
I don't know what to do.
Help me.
Did you kill your husband,
with murder in your heart, Marnie?
Search your soul.
No.
I was defending myself.
Then I pray you find peace.
Thank you, Father.
One last thing, Father.
Could you bless this house for me?
No...
I don't think I can do that.
The money's gone, Mike.
I gave it to the church.
The last thing in this house
that belonged to you, is gone.
There's nothing keeping you here.
This is my house now.
I want you to leave
and be at peace.
I want you to leave my house, Mike.
It's time for you to go.
I hope you can forgive me.
I bear you no ill will.
I want you to leave my house, Mike.
It's time for you to leave.
Oh, no!
What do you want?
I can't take this shit anymore.
Alright.
Alright Mike, huh? Do it.
Come on, huh?
What're you waiting for?
Come on, do it!
Come on, Mike!
Yeah?
- Joey, it's me, Marnie.
- Marnie? Oh, hey.
- You said I could call.
- Yeah, what's goin' on?
- Did I wake you?
- Nah.
I'm just chilling.
I didn't mean to bother you.
You're not.
It's good to hear your voice.
Is everything okay?
Look...
Can I come over?
- No! That's not a good idea.
- Why?
Huh... it just isn't, okay?
You have to trust me on this one.
I'm... I'm getting my shoes on.
No, no, no. Joey, no.
Not tonight.
- Some other night, huh?
- I promise.
Well, sweet dreams.
Hey, Marnie!
- Joey, what the hell you're doing here?
- I was in the neighborhood.
Yeah, right.
Look, I'm gonna camp out on your
doorstep, unless you let me in.
- Joey, you can't come in.
- I'm getting soaked out here.
- Joey, you gotta go home, okay?
- Please, come on, let me in.
No!
I'm gonna stand out here all night in this
rain, unless you let me in, so, come on...
Fine.
Catch.
Watch it!
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yeah, damn it.
I'm fine.
That was funny, I'm sorry...
- Hey.
- Good morning.
- I slept really good.
- Me too.
- I can't believe it.
- What?
It's a beautiful day.
No!...
No!
No Mike, no!...
Stop it! No!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it! No!
No!
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it! No!
- I'm going in.
- Copy.
Marnie!
- What do you want?
- I got a warrant for Joseph DiCenzo's arrest.
- I know he's in there.
- Nobody's here but me, and the ghost!
Marnie, I've been outside
of your house all night.
Now, cut the shit.
- I know he's in there.
- Well, let's see the warrant.
Come downstairs
and I'll show you the warrant.
You can show it to me right here.
Now quit fucking around with me
and open this door.
- I'm in the shower.
- Put some clothes on and open the door!
Just give me a few minutes, okay?
- We are at the back door.
- Hold on.
- Marnie!
- Joey isn't here.
Just hold your freaking horses
I'm...
- Shanks!
- getting dressed!
- Check the basement.
- Alright.
- Check the basement!
- Okay.
- Marnie?!
- I'm coming!
- Where is he?
- Easy.
Where is he?
I told you, he's not here.
He's not here.
What do you want from me?
Let's go.
Go by his house, check by that market
he works at, he's gonna show up.
Alright, come on.
- So you admit he was here last night.
- Yeah.
- And when did he leave?
- I don't know, around one.
- And what were you doing?
- Screwing each other's brains out.
- In your husband's house.
- In his bed.
This isn't over.
- You know the way out, detective.
- I don't know where you stashed this kid,
or I don't know where he's hiding...
but I'm gonna be out in that car
all day every day...
until he comes back, because
I know he's coming back. Marnie.
You bought yourself maybe
2 or 3 days.
I want you out of my house, Shanks.
Okay.
What the fuck?!
You?
Get out!
Put your fucking hands up!
On your head!
You, fucking bitch!
Get your fucking hands up!
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of fucking law.
Go ahead, arrest me,
I'll never be free anyway.
I got you. Alright.
This is Shanks.
I got the DiCenzo kid, dead.
In the woman's apartment.
I got her cuffed.
I got it under control.
I'm bringing her in now.
Over.
Let's go.
You win, Mike!
What the fuck?...
Mickey?
Mickey, it's me... Lou!
Mickey... what happened to you?
You stay away from her.
Mike, you stay away from her!
You stay away from her, Mike!
Stay fucking away from her!
Stay away from her, Mike!
Mike, you stay away!
Shanks...
Shanks. Shanks, wake up!
Come on. Wake up. Shanks!
Shanks! Come on! Wake up!
Oh, shit!
Come on! Shanks, wake up.
Oh, Come on!
Marnie!
Shanks!
Shanks! Shanks, can you hear me?
Marnie? Where are you?
Answer me!
Marnie!
Hang on!
Come on!
Come on.
It's over!
Marnie...
Come on.
Shanks...
Are you okay?
Come on.
You should go.