-Hello.
-Do you live here?
Nobody lives here.
-Where's Freddy?
-Heh, heh. He's not home.
[GASPS]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
CHILDREN [CHANTING]:
One, two, Freddy's coming for you
Three, four, better lock your door
Five, six, grab your crucifix
[CHILDREN SCREAMING]
Be calm, Kristen.
[SCREAMS]
[METAL SCRAPING NEARBY]
Joey! Kincaid! Help me!
[WHIMPERING]
[SHOUTING]
Oh, shit, Kristen. Not again.
-I'm sorry, Kincaid.
-Sorry?
You are one spooked chick.
[METAL SCRAPING NEARBY]
Joey.
-Thank God. I thought for a minute--
JOEY: What?
-Dragging us in here?
-Yeah. Cut it out.
You're putting one serious dent
in my beauty sleep.
It's Freddy. He's here. I heard him.
Freddy is dead, buried and consecrated.
We won, remember?
-He's coming back for us.
JOEY: Kincaid's right.
Fred Krueger's history. Come here.
The pipes are cold. The boiler is cold.
See for yourself.
I don't know.
[GASPS]
[GRUMBLES]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
How are you, Mr. Johnson?
That's nice.
Hi, Kristen.
Rick will be out any second.
-You going out dressed like that?
-What's wrong with it this time?
-I might just wait by the car.
-Me too.
[CLATTERING FROM ABOVE]
KRISTEN: Something wrong with the stairs?
-It's Avoid All Contact Day.
What?
RICK:
Whoa.
When Dad's popping aspirin like popcorn,
it's Avoid All Contact Day.
Waiting for a limo?
I'm off to the club, honey.
[GIRLS CHUCKLING]
Let's go.
[GIRL TALK'S "BAILA BAILA"
PLAYING ON CAR STEREO]
All right,
anybody have trig this semester?
-What happened?
-I had a conflict. Homework or Dynasty?
And, uh, Dynasty won.
Sad story. Soaps will kill you.
DEBBIE:
Mm. There's Dan Jordan.
Mm. We are talking
one major league hunk.
You know,
you are one major league hunk.
-Heh. Thanks, Alice.
RICK: Earth to Alice.
-Earth to Alice. Hey, you spacing again?
-Rick, please.
Well, tell you what, he's a friend of mine.
I'll introduce you.
-Rick.
-Just kidding. But I would introduce her.
All right. I think I see salvation.
How can you ride this health hazard?
It's no wonder that you have asthma.
No, you see,
asthma is an inherited condition.
Read a book now and then,
you might know something.
You know, speaking of books,
isn't trig your favorite?
Dynasty again?
Deb, do us a favor and get a VCR.
Hey, baby, you're sucking
on the wrong nozzle.
Hey, yo, needle dick.
I bet you're the only male in this school
suffering from penis envy.
[BELL RINGS]
[LAUGHING]
I owe you one.
Ew! Ew! Ew!
-So disgusting.
-Hey, super girl, it's dead.
Give a bug a break.
Hi, guys.
Hi, guys? That's all you have to say
after last night?
You better be careful.
I'm telling you, he's coming back.
Listen, you got this freak-o talent
to bring folks into your dream...
...but we don't need it anymore.
-Time to start living like regular people.
JOEY: Yeah. Let it rest. I mean...
...did it ever occur to you that if you keep
going in, you might stir him up again?
Look, we'll help you.
We all have better things
to dream about.
You got that right. Signed and sealed.
-Then what about this?
-That don't mean dick.
My dog is like me. Drag him
into your crazy dream, and he gets wild.
Here comes your boyfriend.
Can he give you a good night's sleep?
We don't kiss and tell.
How about you?
[CHUCKLES SARCASTICALLY]
[BELL RINGS]
-Look, we'll talk later, all right?
-Okay.
Those guys are kind of spooky.
-Then you must think I'm a total freak.
-I go back and forth.
Hey, lighten up. No one died.
[GRUNTING]
Hi, Dad.
Looking for something?
Shithead.
I'm late. I know.
Damn contracts.
Let's eat.
-You know, we waited a long time.
-And we gave up, as usual.
You call this vegetation a meal
after a ten-hour workday?
What the hell am I, a rabbit?
Christ, Alice, try to think a little more.
Yeah, I can think.
I can think of how sick I am...
...of watching you drink your life away
and taking it out on me.
Alice, Alice, I'm talking to you.
Are you awake or what?
-Dad, don't start.
DENNIS: Start what?
Telling the little daydreamer to wake up?
It's long overdue.
I don't need this aggravation.
Jason. Come on, boy. Come on.
Come on. That's a boy.
You almost scared me, boy.
Yo, open this sucker up!
Damn.
[GRUNTING]
This ain't my dreamland.
Kristen!
If you're here,
I'm gonna pound your ass!
Jason.
Jason?
[BARKING AND GROWLING]
[BARKING]
[GROWLING]
[WHIMPERING]
[MAN GROANING]
Fucking A.
You shouldn't have buried me.
I'm not dead.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Yeah!
Take that, motherfucker!
[SHOUTING]
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
Kristen, Freddy's back!
Freddy's back! Freddy's back!
Freddy's back!
[GRUNTS]
I'll see you in hell.
Tell them Freddy sent you.
[LAUGHING]
One down, two to go.
[GASPING]
[FREDDY CACKLING]
[BARKS]
[WIND CHIMES JINGLING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
[SIRENS WAILING ON TV]
ANNOUNCER [ON TV]:
MTV in stereo defies the mind.
Illusions of space through sound.
[BILLY IDOL'S "FATAL CHARM"
PLAYING ON TV]
There may be teardrops to shed
I'm coming in from the cold
MAN [ON TV]: I watch MTV every morning
when I get up for a couple of hours.
And then right around breakfast time,
you know, I watch a little bit more.
Then about lunch when I feed the fish,
you know, I feed the fish and watch them....
Wait.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
How's this for a wet dream?
Kristen! Help!
[JOEY GASPING]
FREDDY: Joey.
JOEY: No!
Hi, guys.
Sort of defeats the purpose, don't it?
-What?
-The mirror.
You can't see yourself in it.
I don't want to.
You know, if Mom was still alive...
...Dad wouldn't treat us like this.
Alice, you gotta learn
to stand up for yourself.
You know, fight back.
[SHOUTS]
Like that. It's all in the mind.
You see yourself doing something
and your body reacts and does it. Like so:
[SHOUTS]
-Like that. Now you do it.
-Me? No, I can't.
-Yeah, yeah, you can.
-No, I can't.
Yes, yes, yes, you can.
Just get up there and just....
[SHOUTS]
Like that. Big and strong. Do it.
Good, good.
But, Alice-san, you must have balance.
Okay. So go to it.
[SHOUTS]
[GIGGLING]
Swish. Killed a fish.
Joey.
MAN [ON TV]:
You know, I watch it for a little bit more.
Then about lunch, when I feed the fish,
you know, I feed the fish and watch....
WOMAN: Joey, I'm getting tired
of picking up your clothes.
And this crap,
I wish you'd turn it off.
Joey.
[SCREAMS]
Here you are.
Where were you this morning?
Rick's looking all over.
Have you seen Joey and Kincaid?
I can't find them anywhere.
-I'm sure they're around.
-Yeah, well, I'm not so sure.
We have matching luggage again.
-The bags under your eyes. Nightmares?
-Yeah.
God, I hate dreaming.
Mm, I love to dream.
I just hate the ones about my Dad.
How do you handle your nightmares?
My Mom taught me when I was little.
Did you ever hear of the dream master?
-Sounds like a game show host to me.
-No, it's a rhyme.
Just have to dream about someplace fun.
Remember, you're in control.
How do you know
so much about dreams?
Well, when it's all you have,
you kind of become an expert.
[BELL RINGS]
We better get going
before your brother starts a search party.
RICK: Anyway, Kafka and Goethe
have never been irreconcilable to me.
Kris, where were you?
Kincaid, Joey. No.
-Hey, what?
-He killed them!
-What? Wait. Calm down.
-No.
[STUDENTS CHATTERING]
Feeling better now?
Yeah, I guess so.
What happened?
You had quite a nasty bump.
-I gotta get out of here!
-No, no, no. You stay put.
You need your rest.
You don't get it. He's after me.
Shh, shh, shh.
It's okay, honey.
[CHUCKLING]
-I wanna draw some blood.
-No!
No!
Feeling better now?
What happened?
You had quite a nasty bump.
[JOE LAMONT'S
"PRIDE AND JOY" PLAYING]
I wanna be your pride and joy
Won't you treat me like a little toy
You seen Rick around?
-No.
-Well, you are his sister, right?
Um, Rick stayed late after school.
Kristen wasn't feeling very well.
Could you tell him I'm looking for him?
Oh, by the way, I'm Dan.
[PATRONS CHATTERING]
Sorry, Alice. Your shift's over.
My table now.
Hi, guys. Hi, Dan.
How you doing?
Hi. Um, can I get just a Coke
and some fries?
DEBBIE: Do you wanna hear our specials
or do you want any dessert?
Oh, hi, handsome. Care for some buns?
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Here. You in a hurry?
I gotta get to the library
before it closes. Killer physics test.
I know. I hardly have any time to study.
Maybe you shouldn't
be working here so much.
You don't wanna get stuck
waiting tables the rest of your life.
I know. It's my greatest fear.
You know, he is so cute.
-I wonder where he works out?
-Save it, Deb.
I mean, there is life after exercise.
One of these days,
I'm gonna set you up with a real guy...
...teach you
to get your priorities straight.
I think Sheila's more interested
in dissecting bodies...
-...than looking at the outside.
-Give her time.
Her hormones will kick in some day.
Deb, you know, later in life,
you're gonna appreciate my motto.
-What's that?
-Mind over matter.
[SCOFFS]
-Look, I'll see you later, okay? Bye.
DEBBIE: Bye.
-Bye, Alice.
-Bye.
-Alice, can you leave here?
ALICE: What's wrong?
Kincaid and Joey died last night.
-What?
-Yeah.
-Hey, Rick. Rick!
RICK: Yeah.
Stay with her.
Kristen, what happened?
Look, you're gonna hear
all kinds of stories.
And after all
we've been through together...
...how could I let him get to them?
We were a team.
-I'm gonna get that son of a bitch.
-Who?
Rick, we gotta go.
-Now.
RICK: I'm coming.
DEBBIE: I'll be right back.
-Before it's too late.
DAN: I gotta go. I guess I'll talk to you later.
-Come on.
So, uh, why the haunted house?
It's not just a house. It's his home.
And he's waiting in there
for me to dream.
Hey, it's okay. We're with you.
I told you, you can't help me.
This isn't a normal nightmare.
I'm history.
I don't get it.
RICK: Come on.
-What'd I miss?
RICK:
She told us a story about Freddy.
Fred Krueger. He's a town legend.
He was a child killer
freed on a technicality.
-So?
-So a lot of parents got pissed off.
And according to Kris...
...they hunted him down and roasted him
like a Thanksgiving turkey.
Nice neighborhood.
Yeah. Anyway, that's where it gets weird.
Um, she says
that he comes back in dreams.
And if he kills you in your dream,
you're dead for real.
ALICE:
Now I lay me down to sleep
The master of dreams, my soul I'll keep
Dream master.
I think I remember the rhyme.
[HORN HONKING]
Kristen, get the hell away
from that house!
[SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
Hey, hey, hey, you don't have to go
if you don't want to. I'll take care of you.
-I better go.
-Okay.
But I'll call you tonight,
and we'll get through this.
-Okay.
-Okay. Bye.
Bye.
RICK:
Alice.
Shotgun.
Something the matter with the cuisine?
Well, Mom, I'll tell you.
When two of your friends die
in the same day...
...let me know
what it does to your appetite.
You're tired. Don't think I haven't noticed
that you haven't been sleeping.
That has got to stop, honey.
-What's wrong with me?
-Adolescent anxiety. That'll make it better.
-Oh, God. Mom, what did you do?
-Oh, Christ!
KRISTEN:
Jesus, sleeping pills?
-Look, Kristen, I'm sorry. I'm just--
-Sorry?
Sorry that you and your tennis pals
torched this guy, and now he's after me?
In case you haven't been keeping score...
...it's his fucking banquet,
and I'm the last course!
Kristen, we went over this in therapy!
No, mother. You just murdered me.
-Take that to your goddamn therapy.
-Kristen!
Kristen.
Kristen?
[GROANING]
[DlAL TONE HUMMING]
KRISTEN:
Alice.
Alice. Alice.
Dream someplace fun.
Dream some....
Thanks, Alice.
Hi, little girl.
Hi.
-What's your name?
-Alice.
I have a friend named Alice.
[GIGGLES]
[GRUNTING]
No! No!
[CACKLING]
[INFANT CRYING NEARBY]
[PANTING]
FREDDY:
Elm Street's last brat. Farewell.
-We beat you before!
-And now you're all alone.
Kristen, why don't you, uh...
...call on one of your little friends?
Maybe they could help.
Never! I'm the last!
Why don't you reach out
and touch someone?
No!
No! No!
No.
Alice!
FREDDY:
How sweet!
Fresh meat.
Alice, wake up and get out!
Alice, I'm so sorry. It was a mistake.
I pulled you in.
Alice, come to Daddy.
Leave her alone, you son of a bitch!
Now no one sleeps.
KRISTEN:
No!
[KRISTEN MOANING]
FREDDY:
The souls of my children.
Alice!
You'll need my power.
[GROANING]
[GASPING]
[GASPS]
[FREDDY CACKLING]
-Are you okay?
ALICE: Kristen.
Kristen, we've gotta get to her house.
Kristen!
[SCREAMING]
Oh, God! Kristen! Oh, God!
RICK: Let me go.
-No. Rick.
Hi, Alice. Wish you were here.
DEBBIE: Hi, Alice.
KRISTEN: Your brother's up to his old tricks.
Rick, as long as I've known you,
I've always wanted to ask...
...what the hell this shit is
that you put in your hair?
KRISTEN: Rick, tell us about your sex life.
ALICE: Oh, no. Don't.
KRISTEN: Come on. Sorry.
ALICE: We can't.
KRISTEN: Come on.
ALICE: No. What are you doing?
-I told you. I want his body.
ALICE: Oh, that's bullshit.
-What else do you want?
-She wants my body.
ALICE:
Kristen's my only friend.
-She's my only friend.
RICK: Excuse me. I would like....
Alice, what are you doing?
I don't know.
KRISTEN:
See you later, bye.
RICK:
Come on. Come on.
It makes me feel better.
RICK: Hit it. Hit the ball,
everything will be great.
KRISTEN: I'm gonna hurt somebody.
RICK: Hit it.
KRISTEN:
What are you doing?
-Hello, baby.
-Great.
You made her so happy then.
Yeah. Until all this Freddy shit.
-Why didn't I just stay with her?
-It wouldn't have made any difference.
Sure it would have.
No.
I saw it happen in my dream.
-And there was this horrible man.
-Oh, who? Freddy?
Freddy? I don't wanna
hear about Freddy, okay?
Heard it all from Kristen.
I don't wanna hear any more.
I could smell the smoke.
I could feel the heat from the fire.
-It wasn't a dream!
-Just stop it!
She wasn't crazy and neither are you,
so just cut it out. Please.
Jeez, why are you acting this way?
I don't know, Rick.
I just feel so different.
Something happened in the dream.
And now it's like part of her is with me.
ALICE [ON TV]:
Okay.
RICK: Miss Kristen Parker. Oh, my.
KRISTEN: I love you too.
Bye, everyone.
Phew, girl, I am so dead on my feet.
We have matching luggage.
-What do you mean?
-You didn't sleep last night?
It's that obvious, huh?
Then you saw him too.
Saw who? I mean, I was up all night
cramming for that physics test.
Oh! And I put this little baby together.
You know how Deb's afraid of bugs.
Well, I made it for her.
Ultra-high soundwaves.
Make them run,
screaming their antennas off.
[ALICE CHUCKLES]
Look, I'll see you in class, okay?
I don't smoke.
[SHEILA COUGHING]
[INHALER HISSES]
All right, you've got 40 minutes.
So good luck and go for it.
[GASPING]
[SCREAMING]
-Alice. Help me. Help! Wake up! Wake up!
ALICE: Help! Help!
SHEILA:
Wake up, damn it!
[FREDDY CACKLING]
[FREDDY GRUNTS]
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
-Wanna suck face?
-No.
Sheila, wake up!
Sheila!
You flunked.
[GASPING]
Sheila.
RICK:
Sheila. Give her her thing.
[STUDENTS MURMURING]
Didn't you see it? He was here.
GIRL: Alice, what are you talking about?
-He was here!
PARAMEDIC 1 :
Out of the way, please.
-Step back please. Stand back.
PARAMEDIC 2: Step back.
Asthma attacked?
PARAMEDIC 1 :
I got it.
What 17-year-old has fatal asthma?
God, she was gonna be a doctor.
-It was Freddy.
-Enough with that crap.
I saw it. It was my dream.
I brought Sheila in.
Oh, God.
I brought Sheila in
like Kristen did with me.
No, don't. I gave Sheila to him.
And now she's dead.
Hey, Rick, I really think Kristen's story
is getting to her.
Dan, I really don't know if it's a story.
Look at us.
We're dropping off like flies here.
MAN 1 : Good to see you. Take care. Bye.
WOMAN 1 : Bye.
MAN 2:
Come on.
[BLONDIE'S "IN THE FLESH"
PLAYING ON STEREO]
I can't wait to see you
Your picture ain't enough
I can't wait to touch you
In the flesh
Excuse me, miss.
Can I get a pack of gum?
Hey. Where you been?
I haven't seen you around lately.
I've been working double shifts.
Guess you need the extra money, huh?
Look, you know why.
You just don't wanna believe me.
Don't you understand?
I can't sleep.
Someone might die.
Met you with a girlfriend
You were so divine
Alice, let's say that, uh, this is real, right?
Why, uh, all of a sudden
is this Freddy guy after you?
Kristen was the last child left
of the people who killed Freddy.
Maybe Freddy can't get to the new kids...
...unless there's someone
to bring them to him.
Danny, we're gonna be late
for the drive-in.
I have to get back.
Uh, I guess I'll see you later.
'Cause if you say hello
It'll mean you wanna see me
In the flesh
Ninety-three days
till summer vacation, man.
-What's the matter, you tired?
-No, I'm getting worried.
Let's see if we can make it until summer.
It's like open season around here.
Pretty weird stuff.
Speaking of weird,
you gotta feel for that guy.
Dead girlfriend,
basket case for a sister--
Why don't you learn to shut up, asshole?
-God, what a dick.
-I know.
-You look wasted, man.
-I've been up with Alice.
Hey, how's she doing?
I, uh, saw her last night at the diner.
She's blaming herself for Sheila.
I know how she feels.
I mean, I think about Kristen all the time.
You know, maybe I could have stopped it
if I'd have listened.
-You mean, uh, Freddy?
-What else?
You ever take a look at our town's history?
It's not a safe place to be a teenager.
Hey, bozos, let's hustle. Now.
Well, if I'm next, watch your back, man.
Where were we?
Every society
dating back to the ancients...
...has had theories regarding dreams...
...what they mean, how to control them.
Aristotle believed that during sleep,
your soul roams free.
What it sees are dreams.
The skilled dreamers, well,
they are able to control what they see.
There is a myth that there's two gates
your soul can enter.
One is a positive gate...
...the other, a negative gate.
The key element
is that there's a dream master...
...someone who guards the positive gate
and, in fact, protects the sleeping host.
Taken altogether,
they offer a fascinating perspective...
...on ancient history.
Now those of you
who don't find it fascinating...
...you better listen up,
because it's gonna be on the final.
[GIRLS GIGGLING]
Rick, make me laugh.
[CHUCKLES]
[CACKLING THEN RICK SCREAMS]
FREDDY [OVER INTERCOM]:
Going down.
[FREDDY CACKLING OVER INTERCOM]
[GRUNTING]
What?
[FREDDY CACKLES]
FREDDY:
A true warrior needs no eyes.
Come on out and fight me,
you chickenshit.
FREDDY:
Ninja warriors have calm.
Find your balance, Rick.
Too wimpy to show yourself, Krueger?
Well, how's this for balance?
[GRUNTING AND SHOUTING]
[THUD]
Yes.
[SPEAKING IN JAPANESE]
How you gonna fight me
without your weapon, Freddy?
FREDDY:
Sayonara, Rick-san!
[GASPS]
No!
[STUDENTS SCREAMING]
PRIEST: ....through the valley of the
shadow of death, I shall fear no evil...
...for thou art with me
with thy rod and thy staff....
Dearly bereaved, we gather here in remorse
for Rick Johnson.
A young man whose death
confounds and mystifies us...
...for Rick was in his prime,
beloved by all...
...exemplary of young men's ideals...
...and of strong moral fiber.
We grieve our loss,
but take comfort in knowing such a man...
...rests in the kingdom of God.
Let our faith supersede our knowledge...
...for truly the Lord works
in mysterious ways.
Hello, baby.
I love this.
They think I'm dead, don't they?
This is great.
Hey. What's with the tears?
I wouldn't leave you. Come on, don't cry.
I'm here. It was a joke.
A big joke to fool Freddy.
Come on, smile for me.
ALICE:
No more daydreams.
Well, gotta go.
Good night.
Alice. You okay?
Not really.
Is there anything we can do?
I don't think so.
I guess this is my own war.
No. No, it's not.
We all have to survive.
I mean, look,
I don't spend hours working out...
...to let some night stalker beat me.
You don't really get it.
He's not a night stalker.
And it'll take more than bench presses
to beat him.
DAN: So, what do we do?
-Let's go over to Debbie's tonight.
-We have to make a plan.
DENNIS: Alice!
I gotta go.
-How about I pick you up at the diner at 8?
-Uh, yeah.
DEBBIE:
Here. It's a good luck charm.
Brings bad luck to the creep
you flatten with it.
This is it.
Mind over matter.
Mind over matter?
Sheila used to say that.
God, every day, she changes.
No.
It's after every death.
What's happening to me?
[INAUDIBLE CHATTER ON TV]
Alice, where are you going?
Just to see Debbie.
No, you're not.
I want you to stay in.
Dad, I gotta go,
and there's nothing you can do about it.
DENNIS:
Alice.
-No.
-You have no right to stop me.
If you just knew what was going on....
I know very much what's going on
with you and your friends.
Yeah. Everybody thinks they know,
but they don't.
Look at me, Alice.
I lost Rick because I didn't watch him.
I don't wanna lose you.
We're all we have.
[SIGHS]
All the towns in America...
...and I gotta move
to the Bermuda Triangle.
That's great.
[SINEAD O'CONNOR'S
"I WANT YOUR HANDS ON ME" PLAYING]
I want your hands on me
[DOG BARKING NEARBY]
Dan?
[RAGTIME MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO]
MAN 1 : Oh, no.
MAN 2: Jimmy. Jimmy.
WOMAN:
There you are, ma'am.
MAN 1 :
Hey, he ain't no paperman.
Why, don't you know him?
That's Hot Fingers Curly.
Boy, he really swings out
hopping with a jive.
-Do you want to dance?
-Do I?
[GROANING]
[SCREAMING]
No!
[GRUNTS]
[METAL CLATTERING]
[WOMAN HUMMING]
What will it be?
Come on, honey.
I don't wanna be here forever.
If the food don't kill you, the service will.
GIRL:
Help us, Alice!
-Mm! The usual.
RICK: No!
No, Alice, don't let him do it!
My favorite.
-No! Come on, no!
-Eeney, meeney, miney...
RICK: Come on, no!
FREDDY: ...moe.
RICK:
No, Alice, don't let him do it!
Rick, you little meatball.
-I love soul food.
-No, no.
Stop!
Mm!
Bring me more.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
Your shift is over.
[GASPS]
[SINEAD O'CONNOR'S
"I WANT YOUR HANDS ON ME" CONTINUES]
I want you to come and please me
Put 'em on, put 'em on, put 'em on me
Come on. We have to hurry.
-What's going on?
-I'm driving.
He's going after Debbie.
I gotta stop him.
We gotta stop him.
I'm with you on this thing.
I wanna help you.
I'm on your side, okay?
I want you to love me
And just touch me
Put your hands
Put your hands on me
Put 'em on, put 'em on, put 'em on me
Here we are.
Come on. We have to hurry.
-What's going on?
-I'm driving.
Put 'em on, put 'em on, put 'em on me
[FREDDY CACKLES]
-I don't believe in you.
-I believe in you.
[GRUNTING AND PANTING]
No pain...
...no gain.
[SCREAMING]
He's going after Debbie.
I gotta stop him.
[DEBBIE SCREAMING AND GASPING]
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
DEBBIE:
Help me!
Here we are.
Come on. We have to hurry.
-What's going on?
-I'm driving.
He's going after Debbie.
I gotta stop him.
You know, I got the weirdest feeling
we've done this before.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[GRUNTING AND SCREAMING]
-Come on. We have to hurry. I'm driving.
-We have to hurry. I'm driving.
Oh, my God. We're both asleep.
He's got us going in circles.
We gotta go!
[SQUEALING]
[FREDDY CACKLING]
You can check in,
but you can't check out.
[GROANS]
What the hell was that?
Debbie. She's gone.
I've collected her, like the others.
All right, I'm gonna punch his ticket in.
Oh, Dan.
I'm sorry.
PARAMEDIC 1 :
Get him in there.
[SIREN WAILING]
PARAMEDIC 2:
Base, this is med seven.
We have a male Caucasian,
approximately 16 to 18 years of age.
Uh, multiple lacerations
about the head and neck area.
Possible internal injuries.
-What's that do?
-Relaxes your boyfriend.
-Put the needle down.
-Sorry, rules is rules.
He stays awake!
Those are my rules, understand?
What are you, nuts?
He's allergic, okay?
You should have said something
in the first place.
Damn kids.
Don't let them put you to sleep.
-We have to get ready for him.
-Okay.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
Dr. Schick to OR, stat.
-When does he have surgery?
-Fifteen minutes.
Let him be, Alice.
-They're gonna kill him.
-What are you talking about?
-Let me go.
-Alice.
Damn it. Get back here! Alice!
Alice!
Come on!
[EKG BEEPING]
DAN:
No. No gas.
No gas. No. Don't put--
[GROANING]
Fucking A.
-Krueger.
-Well, it ain't Dr. Seuss.
Alice! Alice!
[FREDDY CACKLING]
DAN:
Alice! Alice!
Get away from him, you son of a bitch!
-Dan.
-I saw him. He was here.
I know.
We have to get out of this place.
[CACKLING]
ALICE:
Dan.
FREDDY:
Out for a spin, lovebirds?
ALICE:
Dan, hold on.
DAN:
Alice! Alice!
[DAN & ALICE SCREAMING]
[DAN GROANING]
Alice, it's too late.
DOCTOR: He's hemorrhaging.
Bring him out of it. Hurry!
DAN:
Alice.
Alice! Alice!
You gotta put me back under now.
Relax, son.
It was rough, but we pulled you out.
You're gonna be okay.
CHILDREN [CHANTING]:
Freddy's coming for you
Three, four, better lock your door
Five, six, grab your crucifix
Seven, eight....
Welcome to Wonderland, Alice.
[CACKLING]
[GRUNTING]
You've got their power.
I've got their souls.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
[FREDDY SHOUTS]
[ALICE SPEAKING IN JAPANESE]
[GASPS]
You think you've got what it takes?
[CACKLES]
I've been guarding my gate
for a long time, bitch.
[SHOUTS]
[GROANING]
[HEART THUMPING]
[CACKLING]
I am eternal.
[GRUNTING]
[FREDDY CHUCKLES]
[CHANTING]
Now I lay me down to sleep
The master of dreams
My soul I'll keep
In the reflection of my mind's eye....
Evil will see itself, and it shall die
[CHILDREN SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
Let them out!
You're dead, Krueger.
[ALL GROANING]
CHILD 1 :
Thank you, Alice.
CHILD 2:
You saved us, Alice.
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
CHILD 1 : Goodbye.
CHILD 2: Bye.
Rest in hell.
DAN: You know, I slept through all of
last night and I haven't done that in days.
I'm still having trouble.
I can sleep two, maybe three hours
if I'm lucky.
I don't mind though.
I have more reasons to stay awake now.
Come on.
Make a wish.
Oh, come on,
you don't believe in that stuff.
Uh, yeah, I do, and I think you do too.
Here it goes.
What'd you wish for?
If I tell you, it won't come true.
[English - US - SDH]