♪ ( woman singing ) ♪
(explosion)
(gunfire)
Man: Okay.
(groans)
(grunting)
(screaming)
(groaning)
(panting)
Come on!
(grunting)
Oh!
Ah!
(groans)
(grunting)
(continues grunting) (coughing)
(gagging)
Man: Boys, look at this.
Put the cards down, you cunts.
That's it, touch her hair.
Go on.
(grunting)
Man: Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Two fuckin' beautiful faces.
(man groaning)
Man: Kiss her.
Yeah, that's it.
Yeah. Fuckin' tits.
Don't fuckin' care.
(groaning)
(panting)
(men laughing)
Man: What is that fucking smell?
♪ ( electronic dance music )
♪ Would it kill you to smile?
Fucking $6,000 a month
to rent this place,
and it stinks like shit.
(gagging)
- (gunshot)
- (woman screaming)
(gagging)
- (shell rattles)
- (woman continues screaming)
Hi, I'm Peter Toland.
Welcome to Toland's World.
This week we're in Elderberry Vale in
Nottinghamshire, a thriving stretch
of classic English countryside.
Home to literally thousands
of indigenous plants and animals
including a 400-year-old
badger sett,
which has crisscrossed this hill
for untold generations.
But in the last two years,
the badgers have disappeared because
a shadow has fallen across this hill,
a shadow in the form of this.
Are you gonna pan off me? Hello? Are you
gonna pan to the power station or--? Man:
Yeah, okay, cut. Sorry, Peter. We gotta cut.
Peter: No, no, don't cut. Do not cut.
- Peter: What's happening? - Man:
Sorry. We lost focus
- a few times earlier, so-- - Peter:
Yeah? We lost focus? - Or you lost focus?
- I could do with another crack
- at that, Peter, sorry.
- Could you? Another crack. Well,
what's going on? You lost focus.
That's the whole point. That's your job,
isn't it, Brian? Brian:
We just didn't realize you were going
to move around so much.
Of course I move around. That's my style.
There were some quite large movements.
We could whack down a sausage for you,
Peter, if that's-- I don't want a
sausage. Yeah? Shove it up your ass.
Man: No, look, all I meant was-- No, look,
Dom, let me explain how this works, okay?
- Man: It's John. - Whatever your name is,
I move around, you follow me,
that's the way it works on Toland's World.
- It's like a dance, okay? - Yeah, I get it.
- So should we cut now and go again-- - No.
I say cut, that's how it works
on the show. Okay?
I call cut and until then,
we keep filming.
You got that? Right,
that's how we roll. All right?
- John: Okay. Yeah. - Good. Prick. (laughs)
Man: Honestly, don't worry about it.
It's just a little alpha male display
and it'll all blow over,
I swear to you.
Look, he knows you worked with
Attenborough, right? So he just feels
a bit threatened. John: Ah, right.
It's all about
the Silver Leopard Awards.
Man: Yeah, he's a bit raw. Well done,
though. Good work. Really good work.
John: Yeah, cheers. So does he think
he should have won them or... Man:
He's been nominated three times,
and now he think Attenborough's rigging it.
(laughs) I know.
- (faint growling) - John: Whoa.
What was that? Man : Hang on,
let me listen, let me listen. Hang on.
- (growling)
- Oh!
- (laughing)
- Whoa!
- John: Greedy little buggers.
- Man: Whoa!
- Oh! - John: You getting this,
Brian? - (laughter) - Yeah.
- Waiting for badgers. - Having fun, are we?
Big fun. Fun times. Clue me in. Let's have a
laugh. Peter, the badgers are still here.
The badgers are... No, the badgers are dead
because of the toxins from the power
station. That's what the episode is about.
- Look, we put the-- - Put
what? - We should carry on
filming. - Who are you anyway?
You waltz in here at the last
minute, calling the shots. John:
I didn't waltz in anywhere.
I don't want to hear any more from you, okay?
- But listen, Peter. - Can you hear me?
- I mean, is this for real? - Of course it's
real. And it's gonna get more real because
someone's gonna get punched in a minute.
- Man: Look, please. - John: Listen,
Peter, - I'm just trying to help-- - I do
not wanna hear one more word from you.
John: Uh, shall I text you
or...?
Oh! Ow! Don't just stand there.
Give me a hand.
- (roaring)
- Ah! Oh!
- Man: Jeez!
- (Peter grunting)
- Man: Peter? - (Peter screaming)
- Man: Peter! - Oh, God.
- (distant growling) - John: Peter!
- (growling) - (Peter screaming)
- John: Peter! - (roaring)
- (body thudding)
- Oh, Jesus.
(gagging)
(coughing)
(screaming)
(moaning)
Cut.
- (indistinct shouting)
- Quiet!
Quiet!
People, settle, settle.
Justice will be done,
but not here.
Fletcher Powell, this court finds
you guilty - of the murder of
Lucy Wilson. - (crowd shouting)
- Child killer!
- I didn't kill her!
I did not kill her!
You need to let me go.
You need to call the police!
You need to deal with this
the right way! The only way!
All local matters
are dealt with internally.
- You know that.
- This is a matter of law!
Your authorities do not stretch
to those boundaries!
- Barclay. - (grunting) Man:
If you confess now, we shall call
the proper authorities.
Deny, and you will be executed this
afternoon. - (crowd shouting) - Very well.
- I killed Lucy.
- (all shouting)
- Bastard!
- I dumped her body
in the River Kennet beyond
Eddington. There you go.
There's my confession,
now call the police!
- You said! You promised!
- You all heard him! You all bore witness!
You shall be taken from this
court to the place of execution
with no further delay.
Female Newscaster: The main headlines this
lunchtime: Lucy Wilson, missing for over a
month and presumed dead,
has been found alive and well in East
Yorkshire. The 14-year-old had run
away with her 26-year-old boyfriend,
who has been arrested
by local authorities.
Hey, guys, she's alive! Lucy's
alive! It's all over the news!
Come on, faster!
So this it? You're just gonna
shoot me like some dumb animal?
Oh, Jesus Christ, no, please! Don't do this!
Father, don't let them do this! Please!
Dearly beloved, it hath pleased Almighty God,
in his justice,
to bring you under sentence
- and condemnation of the law.
- Hold him down. (sobbing)
You can't!
Please, you can't kill me!
- Father, please stop! - You are to suffer
death in such a manner, that others,
warned by your example,
may be the more afraid
to offend.
- Oh, fuck!
- (tires screech)
- (grunting)
- (crow cawing)
What the fuck, Tobias! You didn't hit him
hard enough! I'll hit him a fucking again
then, won't I?
Oh, fucking hell! You nearly took my
fingers off! - Well, fucking move back
then! - Decorum, boys.
- Give this man his dignity. - Father,
shut the fuck up! For the love of God,
finish this! (grunting)
(screaming)
- (bone cracking)
- Tobias: Finish him off.
And we pray, God,
that you may make such use
of your punishments in this
world, - that your soul may be
saved-- - You're blooded now.
Female Newscaster: Lucy Wilson,
missing for over a month and presumed
dead... Man: I did not kill her!
(faint panting)
(panting)
(cord unraveling)
(whirring)
(squelching)
(exhaling)
(high-pitched chittering)
(echoing laughter)
Distorted Voice:
Welcome back.
Looking good.
Life is yours.
Now you must pay me.
You pay for life.
(distorted gasping)
(garbled gasping)
(screaming)
Distorted Voice:
You pay for life.
(echoing laughter)
(high-pitched screaming)
Distorted Voice:
You pay for life.
(metal scraping)
(seagulls crying)
(farting)
(gasps)
(panting)
(tapping)
(laughing)
(screaming)
(rustling)
- (gasps)
- (grunting)
(screaming)
(metal scraping)
(gasping)
(donkey braying)
(rope cutting)
(screaming)
(gasping)
(gunshot)
Are you sure this is Cognac?
Tastes more like supermarket cooking brandy.
- Trust me, it's the good stuff.
- Yeah, I don't know, Granddad.
I've done wee-wees tastier than this.
It's the good stuff.
Ugh.
You could've got a TV in here.
I've told you, I don't like telly.
Well, just get
a small one then.
It's like being
in the 1950s in here.
- (laughs)
- Oh.
Have you heard something rotten
about the 1950s?
Look at you,
my lovely little grandson.
Not so little these days.
Uh, hello.
This is embarrassing.
Right.
I'm fucking off to bed.
(belches)
Hm...
Oh, this necklace? Yeah,
it is real gold. Would look even
better hanging off your tit, love.
Hm...
And I am absolutely
loving it.
(sighs)
My lovely little grandson.
(laughs) What a twat.
Grandfather:
You're the twat, mate.
Who called me a twat?
- Ah!
- Grandfather: Twat.
- Ah, shit!
- Grandfather: Ah, shit! Twat.
Ah! What are you
doing in there?
Oh, I'm here every night.
And you keep me awake all night,
with your wanking
and your farting. Twat!
Are you trying to look like me?
Yes. (laughs)
Is that all right?
Ooh... Ah...
What have you got on your
finger? I got this in Chad.
It's for opening mollusks.
And I'm absolutely loving it!
Hey, that my catch phrase!
What is your fucking problem,
Granddad? You are my fucking problem!
You've been staying with me
for a whole year now,
and you're cramping my style!
- (screams)
- (groaning)
(exhaling) Out!
(groaning softly)
I heard you on the phone
calling me a wanker.
Me, a wanker.
You don't know how that hurts.
- (groaning)
- Look.
Can you see anything
that I could wank with?
Can you? Can you?!
Can you?!
Can you?
Ah...
(kiss smacking)
(man moaning)
(woman gasps)
(glass shatters)
(loud rattling)
(air hissing)
(jet engine roaring)
- (low humming)
- (zapping)
- (explosion)
- (gunfire)
- (machine gunfire)
- (explosions)
(steam hissing)
- (thudding)
- (man moans)
- (squelching)
(shouting)
(camera shutter clicks)
(car alarm chirps)
(low rumbling)
(banging)
(soft thumping)
♪ ( rock music plays ) ♪
- (screaming)
- (siren blaring)
(laughs) Fuck yeah,
I'll do some bath salts.
(screaming)
Mm...
(camera shutter clicks)
Hey, I liked your movie.
Did you like mine?
Oh, I liked yours.
Huh? Oh, I was taking a nap.
I am ready.
Yeah, I am dressed.
I'm not going to be late,
all right?
(echoing laughter)
- Oh, my God. - (clock ticking) (rattling)
(loud ticking)
Excuse me,
is this the fastest route?
It's a busy night, lady.
Woman: George was there, so yeah,
I know. They haven't seen each
other since the divorce.
Right? Ah, man, I want
to be there for that.
(grunts)
Woman: I'd like to get there in
one piece, if you don't mind.
Woman: Yeah, okay, I should be there in
ten minutes. Hey, shouldn't we be avoiding
downtown with the parade and all?
I'll be honest. It would
be better if you took a walk.
Hey, I can't hear you.
I'm on the bike.
I'll be there any second.
Driver: One, two,
three, four, five.
(man laughing)
- Man: Frankie! - Hey, what's up, guys? Man:
Yo, Frankie, you're famous! Thank you, thank
you. It's impossible to get across town.
I don't think my cab driver
knows what he's doing.
(police siren wailing)
Woman: Hey there, can I take
a picture of you, scary guy?
- You can take mine.
- Boy: I like your costume.
Okay. We have to go
meet your mom.
Oh, wait, wait.
- (ticking)
- (buzzing)
Boy: Thank you.
Just get us through the light and pull
over. Driver: Whatever you want, lady.
Ah! Oh!
(gasps)
- (sobbing)
- (gasping)
- (woman screaming)
- (clock ticking)
- (electrical fizzling)
- (screaming)
(all moaning)
(growls)
Male Voice:
Does anyone have a matches?
Male Voice 2: Yeah, I got some.
(stuttering) Did anybody grab
a map before we left?
(stuttering) Shucks, Kirby,
I forgot.
(stuttering) Did you forget too,
Poppy?
Yeah, Poppy forgot too.
(stuttering) Boy, that candle
sure smells good.
What kind is it, Poppy?
It's Poppy's favorite, it's...
(stuttering) p-p-p... grapes.
- (distant shouting)
- (stuttering) What's that?
(stuttering) Only one way
to find out.
(all moaning)
(stuttering) Kirby,
I don't like it out here.
Kirby: Can't see a thing.
(moaning)
- (moaning)
- Hey, look.
It's a beautiful, muscular man
with a teeny-tiny baby.
(stuttering) Should we
wake him up?
(laughing)
Hey, hello! (laughs)
♪ ( lively music plays ) ♪
(laughs)
(all laughing)
- (sneezes)
- (music stops)
(squealing)
(man blows)
(Kirby stuttering) Poppy, do you
have any more matches?
Poppy: Yep.
(blows)
(distorted screaming)
- (high-pitched screaming)
- (blows)
- (baby crying)
- (whimpering)
(blows)
(stuttering yell)
(gasping)
(stuttering) Now,
just wait a minute here.
- (all moaning)
- (blows)
(stuttering yell)
Hey!
Say, what gives?
Hello? Hello?
Is anybody out there?
Anybody? Hello?
Where did everybody go? Oh!
Huh? (stuttering) Poppy?
(stuttering) Bart?
(heart beating rapidly)
(screaming)
(babbling)
♪ ( lively music plays ) ♪
(distorted laughter)
(screams)
- (cooing)
- (screaming)
Man: Seven days of the week.
Woman: Twelve 'S' of the 'Z'.
Man: Twelve signs
of the Zodiac.
Woman: In the United States, can you marry
your widow's sister? Man: Oh, I've heard
this before. No, because you're dead.
What relationship
is your nephew's brother
to your brother?
- That's his nephew.
- Great.
What is the missing letter
in the third
three-letter sequence?
A, B, C, B, B, D, A, E, blank.
A, B, C,
B, B, D,
(sighs) A, E, F.
- Correct. - Um, sorry. Can we wrap this
up pretty soon? I need to...
Actually,
you're doing very well.
I think it's worth your while
to stick around. Really?
Okay, 'cause I kind of feel
like I'm locked in now.
- Like I'm in a good head space. - The day
before the day before yesterday is three
days after Saturday. What day is it today?
Uh... Monday,
Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday... Friday?
Woman: Correct.
Now I'm going to show you
two flashcards.
You tell me if the images
are the same or different.
Same?
Man: Different.
Man: Different. Noticed that one
quick. Woman: All right.
One more question. True or false:
A roller-coaster has a minimum
rider height of four feet tall.
Johnny is three feet six inches tall
and Jimmy is four feet six inches tall.
Jackie is taller than Johnny and shorter than
Jimmy. Jackie can ride the roller-coaster.
True or false. Jackie can ride
the roller-coaster.
She's taller than Jimmy?
Both: Shorter than Jimmy.
Taller than Johnny.
Okay, so all these have
to be true-false, right?
Woman: This question reads
"true-false."
Man: Okay, um...
Can I say "unanswerable"
or "trick question"
or something like that?
- Woman: Under what reasoning?
- Man: Well, you don't know...
You don't know how much taller.
Like it could be, you know,
an inch, it could be two feet.
I'm, like, looking at your face
for clues. Uh... - Woman:
That's all right. - Man: So, yeah.
My final answer is the question
is unanswerable.
Woman: Excellent, that is correct.
Congratulations, that was a perfect score.
If you can come with me right
now, I'd love to talk to you
some career opportunities.
Great, um,
I love opportunities.
Woman: Great, let's go.
(glass shatters)
(banging)
(roaring)
(line ringing)
- Hey, baby. - Hey, sorry,
did I wake you? No. No, it's fine.
How are you? How's the hotel?
It's fine. Yeah, it's all right.
It's quite plush.
Um, look, I'm sorry I didn't call last
night. I just got stuck with these people,
it was... It's okay. So how was the meeting?
Good. No, it was really good. Not
everything is nailed down, but I pretty
much think we've got a done deal, so...
That's great, congratulations.
So are you coming home today?
I miss you.
Not sure, there's another meeting this
morning, but... If that goes well,
then I should be on the night flight.
How's...
Is that the door bell?
Well, are you
expecting anyone?
Woman: No.
- (doorbell rings)
- (pounding on door)
(doorbell continues ringing)
- Who is this?
- Who is it?
Hello? Sir? Who is it?
- I don't know. - (doorbell
rings) What do you want?
Who is it? What do they want?
Please go away or I'm calling the police.
(knocking on door)
- What's going on, Miriam?
- Don't know.
Don't know what...
(screams)
- What was that? - Oh, my God!
He's got a hammer, he's breaking the door!
(screams)
Oh, he's breaking in!
- What?
- He's opening the door!
- Woman on Phone: Hello?
- Give me the police. - The English
police. - (woman speaking French)
- (line ringing)
- Come on, come on.
- Man on Phone: 999, which service? - Police.
- (line rings) - Man: How can I help you?
You need to send somebody to my
home. An intruder's broken in.
Man: What's your name and address?
Robert Walters, 35 Queen Mary Road, London.
Man: Are you at the property now, sir?
No, I'm in fucking France.
I'm on the phone to my wife,
now please send someone.
Miriam? The police
are on their way, are you okay?
(whispering) Sh...
I'm in the bathroom, just...
Just don't speak, okay?
- (Miriam screaming)
- Miriam?
- Miriam, talk to me!
- (screams)
Miriam, are you okay?
Talk to me, please!
Miriam?
(Miriam gasping)
- Miriam.
- (moaning)
Help! Help!
(sobbing, moaning)
Why? Why are you doing this?
(gasps) I love you!
(baby crying)
Whoever you are,
please, I'm asking you,
- don't do this. - (baby crying)
Please, don't hurt my baby.
Please, there's
a small baby in the room.
Please don't...
Leave my baby alone, please.
(sobbing)
What have you done
to my family?
Woman: Let me talk to him.
What?
Let me talk to my husband.
It's your wife.
(police siren wailing)
All right.
Basically, why we're shooting
your audition today
is to show the producers what
you're comfortable doing,
what you're able to do,
and willing to do.
It's really like
an attitude thing.
If I told you to suck my dick,
would you do as you're told?
Or would there
be some sort of an issue?
Open your mouth for me please?
Good.
(gagging)
You a little whore?
Say it.
You know, a lot of girls would
kill for this opportunity.
So you gotta stand above
the competition.
Wow. Phew,
those are some eyes!
Are you blind?
We're gonna have to get some, uh,
sunglasses for her on the day of the shoot.
We are gonna need to see your body.
Unfortunately, producers are kind
of picky about that kind of thing.
So if you could just take off that
retarded dress that you're wearing.
Faster, please.
We do not have all day, do we?
(laughs)
Yeah. Those are okay.
I give 'em a C-minus.
Wait!
What the fuck is that?
Oh, that's a dick.
- Man: Oh, gross! - A dick?
Come on, you guys! How many fucking
times is this gonna happen
before somebody starts fucking
screening the girls?
(distorted voice) Not a dick.
I like dicks.
- (banging)
- What the fuck was that?
(distorted laughter)
- (groaning)
- (laughing)
(distorted groaning)
(distorted groaning continues)
- Holy shit!
- (distorted moaning) Oh, yes!
(distorted laughter)
(alarm blaring)
(camera shutter clicking)
(beeping)
(mechanical whirring)
(whirring sounds)
(screaming)
- (electronic beeping)
- (line ringing)
- Woman: Hi, honey! - Hey, sweetie! - Woman:
Hi! - Is this working? Woman: Yeah,
I can't believe your phone works there!
Oh, hold on, hold on.
Look at this, look at this.
- Are you seeing that? - Woman: Oh, wow,
that is so beautiful. - Tell me that's
not gorgeous, right? - Woman: Yeah!
It is so good to see your face.
- Woman: I miss you! - I miss you more.
- Woman: Where's Dylan?
- I think he's still sleeping.
Woman: Yeah? Is he glad I'm not
there? I bet he's been talking shit
about me. What? No! No, not at all.
Come on,
Dylan loves you, okay?
Woman: What'd you guys
do last night?
We literally took a walk,
uh, in the sand,
and we just had a couple beers.
Woman: Uh-huh, on your boys' trip?
It's okay, you can tell me. Okay,
three beers. But really, that was it.
Honestly, um, you know,
it's just, we're just keeping it super
low-key. Woman: Right. Oh, is that Dylan?
- Look, he's right there. - (laughs) Yeah,
he's here. Hold on, dude, I'm on the phone.
Give me one second, okay?
- I'm sorry. - Woman: Hi, Dylan. - Hi, Amber!
- Dude, I told you I'm on the phone, man.
- One second, one second. - Dylan: Okay.
Amber: Where are you guys
staying? Show me your room! Uh,
honestly, it's a mess right now,
- you wouldn't want to see it.
- You want to see our room? - Amber: Yeah,
give me the tour! - What are you doing?
- Baby, I'm going to call you back.
- Let's give her a tour, man! Yo,
what the fuck! Give me the phone! Dude!
Give me my phone! Give me... Hang up! Hey,
baby, how you doin'? Amber: Dylan,
what are you doing? Hey, shhh, don't worry!
Just want to show you
our place.
- Man: Baby, hang up! - Dylan: Oh,
look at that. What's that? - Amber:
What is that? - What's that?
- Amber: Are those hard drugs? - Yeah.
Introduce you to some of our new friends,
like this sweet little peach. Mm...
- Amber: Who is she? - Take a look at
that. - Yeah, you like that? - Amber:
Who is she? Ooh! (laughs)
Look at those
itty-bitty titties!
Remember when your titties
used to look like that? I do!
- Amber: Fuck you, Dylan. - (laughs) - Let me
show you what Curt got. - Curt: No, no, no! -
Look away! Look away! - Dylan: Sh, sh, sh!
Did you know your boyfriend
likes smelly, old pussy?
Did you know that? (sniffs) Oh!
Wow! That's strong!
Funny story, you know
you get a discount here
if you do both mother
and daughter.
- (Amber groans)
- Yeah, it's sick!
- Hold on.
- Amber: Put Curt back
on the phone! You're disgusting!
Is that a screwdriver?
Smelly mommy did a smelly trick
with this last night.
- (Amber groans) - Let me show you.
- Curt: Don't listen to him!
- (door opens) Baby, don't listen to
him! Hang up the phone right now!
- Dylan: No, man, come on! - Curt:
Give me the phone! Dylan: Hang out with us!
Come here! Here, here, here.
Do a show for Amber, okay?
(laughs) Yeah.
- Curt: Amber! - Dylan: Suck him off.
- Woman: Fuck again is extra.
- Dylan: No problem.
Stop it! Amber! This is not me, and you know
that, okay? Amber: I don't know anything
right now! I have no idea who you are!
This is all Dylan, I swear, all right?
I said stop it, you fucking whore!
- (beeping) - (Dylan laughing)
- Amber? Baby? - Dylan: Damn, dude!
Honey? Are you still there? Amber!
- Amber: You have lost it! - No, wait,
just listen to me! - Amber: You are
fucking psycho right now! - Listen to me!
Amber: No, I'm hanging up! I'm done! - No,
no! - Amber: I am hanging up right now!
But it was Dylan, all right? I should
have told you, okay? - But it was all
Dylan. - Amber: You are so full of shit.
Tell her it was all you!
Fucking tell her!
- (woman sobbing) - Dude,
tell her you fucking brought the girls
back! - I didn't do anything! - (groaning)
Curt: Stop fucking around, man,
this is serious shit!
- (groaning) - Curt: Wait a second.
Bro, turn around! Dude! Fuck!
Screwdriver, dude! Turn around! Dude!
Dude! Oh, fuck!
Curt: Oh! Oh, my... fuck!
This fucking door won't open!
Stop! Stop!
- (woman screaming)
- Curt: No! Fuck!
Fucking door won't open!
Dylan! Oh, I'm
going to fuck you up, bitch!
I'm gonna fuckin' stab that
screwdriver right in your
fucking cunt, you fucking...
(screaming)
- (body splats)
- (yelps)
(sobbing)
(woman speaks foreign language)
- (beeping)
- Amber: Tell me he's okay.
(sobbing)
Do you speak English?!
No!
Narrator: Champions of Zorb.
Harmonia is under attack.
Has the heroic Prince Casio
finally met his match?
- No!
- Narrator: Who dares challenge
the evil Mindlord Zorb?
Don't worry,
Fantasy Man will save you.
Narrator: Terrify your opponents
with the mighty Fantasy Man.
- I wish we could help Prince Casio.
- Yeah! Narrator: Now you can explore
the world of Zorb.
Where are we?
Both: Prince Casio?
We're dead! We're all
fucking dead! (grunting)
(men shouting)
(lasers zapping)
Man: Ah!
(man screams)
Help me!
(screams)
(both screaming)
(garbled electronic voice
speaks)
(man screaming)
(creature roaring)
No! No!
(moaning)
(groaning)
Man: No! No!
No!
(whimpering)
What?
(garbled electronic voice
speaks)
(groaning)
Fantasy Man: Don't
be scared, princess.
It's me...
...Fantasy Man.
(thunder rumbles)
- (Fantasy Man whistles)
- Huh?
Ah! Yah!
Sleep, Fungor,
my old friend.
Quickly,
princess, into the sack.
There's no time!
Quickly, into the sack!
(creature screeching)
Boy: Where are we going?
Almost there, princess.
- We're almost there.
- Boy: No, No, No!
(boy continues shouting) No!
♪ ( vocal music plays
on old record ) ♪
(xylophone clinking)
- ♪ ( music continues ) ♪
- (clinking continues)
(squeaking)
(low rumbling)
(clinking gets louder)
(record scratching)
(door unlocks)
♪ ( vocal music plays
on old record ) ♪
(screaming)
(match lights)
(wind howling)
Woman (sobbing): Don't leave
me. Don't leave me, Ti, please!
The midwife said chewing on
portlock root will slow down the
baby until I can get her from town.
Just take small bites.
Woman: Oh, Ti, please don't leave!
- I don't want to be alone! - You'll be fine.
There's years enough root in that jar,
and she's not even a half a day out. Woman:
Come back, Ti! I don't wanna be alone again!
Please, Ti!
(wind howling)
Woman: Ti!
(woman moaning)
Ti!
- (woman continues moaning)
- (door opens) - Ti! - (wind howling)
Ti?
(bell jingles)
Baby: Is it him, Mama?
No, it's not, sweetie.
(meowing, hissing)
Baby: What did we catch, Mama?
- (cat hissing)
- A mean, old bunny rabbit.
(cat meowing)
Baby: Mom, why don't you go out
and catch the rabbit
instead of waiting for it to get trapped?
I can't be running around looking for
rabbit with you inside of me.
Baby: You should let me come out
then. Why do you want to come out?
Don't you like spending
time with your mom?
Baby: No, it's not that.
Well, it sounds to me like you wanna
leave your mom - in this place all by
herself. - Baby: That's not what I meant.
Don't know what I'd do
if you left me here all alone.
Baby: I'm sorry, Mama,
I'm just sick of eating the same
things all the time, is all.
Well, you can come out
when your dad gets back.
And if you're a boy, he can take you out when
he goes hunting. Baby: I hope I'm a boy.
Well, he'll be back any day now,
we'll find out then. But for now,
you're just a little baby.
(screaming)
Baby: You all right, Mama?
Where is it?
There was a piece left,
I know there was some left.
- Baby: Where's what?
- Mama's medicine!
(screaming)
- (groaning) - Baby: Calm down,
Mama. You gotta let me come out now.
You promised,
you said you won't leave!
Baby: But I'm too big and it's
hurting me. Don't you leave me!
(moaning)
(sobbing)
Baby: I won't leave you, Mama. (groaning)
(screaming)
Baby: It's okay, Mama,
I'm here, just calm down.
(sobbing) You can't leave.
Baby: Don't worry, Mama,
I'm not leaving.
I don't wanna be alone again.
Baby: I won't leave you,
Mama, I just need more room,
okay? - (cracking) - (sighs)
Baby: Don't worry,
I can fix this, Mama.
Just stay calm.
Baby: See, Mama?
Now there's room for both of us.
(banging)
(rattling)
(insects chirping)
(door creaking)
- Ti, is that you?
- Do I really look
that different?
- Where have you been?
- Don't start.
I waited as long as I could,
but it didn't sit right.
I had to cut it out myself.
Then we'll just
have to try again.
I don't know if I can.
Of course you can.
(school bell rings)
♪ ( woman singing ) ♪
(distorted screaming)
(distorted laughter)
I mean, how the fuck am I meant
to wank to that? (sighs)