(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(OWL HOOTING)
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
DUKE: Do it!
Hey, maybe
we ought to wait...
Don't go pussy
on me, Otis.
I'm not, man.
I just think...
Don't!
This is the stupidest
goddamn thing
I've ever done.
Go right, Cody,
go right.
All right.
(NlGHT CREATURES CHlRPlNG)
Watch for traps.
(RUSTLlNG)
(GRUNTS)
Hey, moron!
You almost harpooned me.
Suck it up, piss pants.
Idiot.
(RUMBLlNG)
Guys?
(GRUNTlNG)
CODY: Shit!
Duke!
It's over here!
Shit.
Fuck. Fuck!
God damn it!
(GURGLlNG)
(GROWLlNG)
(SCREAMS)
(ALlEN SCREECHlNG)
(GASPS)
Shit.
(SNARLlNG)
(SNAPPlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
Fuck you!
Fellas!
I can't believe
we actually
caught one.
It's uglier
than I remember.
About to
get uglier.
(SCREECHlNG)
Those sons of bitches
following us?
I don't think so.
You don't think so?
The rest took off right after
we seen the first one.
God damn right they ran.
Little bitches.
I need more chains.
More chains.
I ain't got no more.
He ain't got no more.
Son of a bitch!
Cody!
Stop that shit.
Fuck.
OTlS: God damn it, Duke,
you're bleeding
all over the van.
I'll try to hold it in.
OTlS: It looks dead.
It's not dead.
I don't think
it's breathing.
Would you just
shut the fuck up,
please?
I need to think.
(STARTLED GASP)
Cody! Don't look
that thing in the eyes.
What do you think,
I'm retarded?
That's some dangerous
shit back there.
Oh, thanks for
the news flash, brainiac.
Duke,
what the hell is that?
It's a star.
It's a moving star.
It's an airplane, then.
Ain't no fucking airplane.
It's a fucking airplane,
Otis! Chill.
Oh, God!
What the fuck?
For protection.
Against the eyes.
Give me that shit.
Left! Turn left!
What the fuck's that?
That's not the turn.
Only thing up here
is boonies, man.
Oh, man, Duke.
We gotta
get off the road.
Fuck no, Duke.
Fuck no!
You got a better idea?
All these years we
pissed away at Nixon's farm
waiting for this?
And this is the best
you've got?
I never thought we'd catch
the damned thing.
We can't trust them,
Duke.
Wyatt's the only one
who knows about
these things.
Oh, we all know
about these fucking things.
DUKE: Not like Wyatt.
Fucking bullshit!
Not like Wyatt.
Fuck this shit.
(GASPlNG)
HOPE: Wyatt?
Baby,
go back to sleep.
There's nothing
out there, baby.
There never is.
CODY: This is fucked,
Duke.
OTlS: They're gonna
come looking.
We can't just stand
out here in the open.
Get back
in the van.
Well, the thing's
(BANGlNG)
DUKE: Wyatt.
Fuck this.
(BANGlNG)
Wyatt, I know
you're in there, Wyatt.
Look... I know
you don't wanna see us.
I understand.
But me and the boys,
we got no choice.
We've been out
to Nixon's farm, Wyatt.
They're after us.
You know that
better than I do.
And I bet my ass
you know what we got
out here in this van.
Get it!
Go get it!
Dadgommit, Wyatt,
we need a place to hide.
You don't let us in here,
we're all gonna die out here.
I know you, Wyatt.
You won't let that happen.
You can't
let that happen, Wyatt.
Not this time.
The fucking bitch.
What's up, Wyatt?
That's far enough.
What is this?
It's a chance
to make things right.
What's in the tarp?
You know damn well
what's in the
goddamned tarp.
What the fuck
did you boys do?
We took some action.
But you wouldn't know
shit about that.
Come on, Otis.
The mask was my idea.
The chains.
Did you kill it?
It wouldn't come
without a fight.
It's lost a lot
of goop, though.
Is it breathing?
Is it supposed to?
Is... God damn it!
WYATT: Shit.
This thing dies,
we are all in a world of shit.
We kicked this one's ass.
We'll kick some more.
You ignorant shit.
You kill it,
and the rest are gonna
come and put us down.
And I don't just mean us
in this fucking garage.
Get out of the way, Otis.
You ready?
Yeah.
HOPE:
What the fuck is this?
Hope.
It's 1:30 in the morning.
Yeah,
it's just business.
Christ, Wyatt.
What the fuck
kind of business?
They got guns.
One of them's bleeding.
Hey, Wyatt.
You need me
to put your woman
in her place?
Excuse me?
Well, he don't
mean nothing, ma'am.
He's just an asshole.
At this point, I'm gonna
have to ask y'all to get
the fuck out of my house.
Please, baby,
let it go.
It's okay.
Wyatt, you in
some kind of trouble?
Nothing
I can't handle.
What the hell is that?
WYATT: Please.
I'd do her.
Just give me a minute.
That's all I need.
What is that, Wyatt?
I'll explain everything.
Do I want to know?
Please, baby.
You all need to
get that thing back
where you found it.
But we think
they're coming
after us.
It ain't
my goddamn problem.
Wyatt.
It ain't
my goddamn problem!
Now, you listen to me.
The longer you keep
that thing, the more
dangerous things get.
I told you,
he ain't changed.
Wyatt,
just hear us out.
I'm not getting mixed up
in your shit, Duke.
I left this shit
in the rear view
a long time ago.
It's been 15 years, guys.
So let this shit go.
Fuck this pussy!
We'll take it back to Otis's
and carve it like a turkey.
The hell we will.
My mom would shit.
Pissing on these things
ain't gonna bring back Timmy.
I ain't gonna hide
like a pantywaist
from the sons of bitches
that murdered my brother.
You know, fuck it.
You do what you want,
but don't do it in here.
God damn right
I'm gonna do what I want,
you sack of fucking shit.
Cody?
What?
Come on.
We're all friends
here, Duke.
You gotta trust me
on this one, Cody.
Trust you?
Last time we did that,
you made us look
like ape shit.
The whole town thought
we gone retard,
you asshole!
My own fucking father
thought I killed my brother
and buried him
out in the woods.
I thought it would be
better for you.
Better?
Fucking over your friends
was better?
Telling the whole world
we were lying?
Telling everybody
we made everything up?
Guys?
I thought
if people knew the truth...
Cody! Cody.
God, that's enough, Cody.
What'd you think
about that, dipshit?
Cody.
Guys.
CODY: Huh?
You're worse than any
fucking cocksucking
piece of shit!
You got your money's worth,
now get the fuck out
of my garage.
(SHRlEKlNG)
It's awake.
That's good,
right?
Wyatt, I think
it knows you, man.
Wyatt?
(GRUNTlNG)
No. No. No.
What's it doing?
Fuck if I know.
Wyatt,
what's it doing?
(SHRlLLlNG)
DUKE: Wyatt!
Wyatt!
They're coming back.
Oh, hell!
CODY: This fucknut wants
to take care of us!
We should make it
to the van.
OTlS: I mean, if they're
coming, we probably should
make something...
Shut up! Nobody talk.
Nobody talk.
What? Oh,
fuck that shit...
Shut up! Shut up!
CODY: What the fuck?
DUKE: Shut up!
The man says shut up,
you shut up, Cody.
They're gone,
right, Wyatt?
It's sending a signal.
Hold it down.
Hold it down!
DUKE: Hold it down!
(SHRlEKlNG)
DUKE: Hold it.
Good.
(SQUlSHlNG)
(SCREECHlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
God, fuck!
Fucking God!
WYATT: Hold it!
Hold it down!
Fuck.
Fuck you, God damn it.
Fuck. Fuck.
Hold it still,
damn it.
The fucker's trying
to send code.
Cut it, Duke.
What?
Cut it! Cut it!
Cut the fucking...
Get something to cut
the fucking thing.
Come on, Duke,
cut it! Cut it!
That's it. Come on, cut it.
Cut it, cut it, cut it!
Cut it, Duke!
(CLlCKlNG)
(PANTlNG)
It was trying
to call the others.
If it's
calling its buds,
why aren't we knee deep
in these sons of bitches?
It must be damaged.
Probably because of that
goddamn ass-whooping
we put
on this motherfucker
out in them woods.
Probably.
Best not to take
no chances.
How'd you know, Wyatt,
about the implant?
Call it a hunch.
Keep the lights out
and stay quiet,
they might not find us.
Take it back to Nixon's farm
in the morning.
Be safer to travel
in the daytime.
Hey, do you think
we all got one of those
GPS clicker
thingies in us?
Wyatt would know
if we did.
Hey, that clicker went off
the second it saw you.
What the fuck
is going on, man?
Wyatt?
You think you could
check me
for one of them clickers?
HOPE: I don't know what it is
but how soon
can you get here?
Wyatt, baby, this is
a dangerous situation.
Who did you call?
Wyatt!
Tell me!
She was calling the cops,
wasn't she?
Shut up!
I'm out of here.
Give me the keys.
The hell you are,
you fucking bitch!
Shut the fuck up!
Give me the keys, Wyatt.
Baby, listen to me.
I can't let you go.
Not until morning.
Hope, I'm trying
to protect you.
By holding me hostage.
First thing in the morning,
I will take you
anywhere you want to go.
I'm on fucking parole.
Fuck off, Cody!
You fuck off, Wyatt!
I ain't going back to prison
'cause this crazy-ass
bitch is losing it.
You understand that?
If this bitch called
the cops, I swear to God,
I'll cut her up...
DUKE: Damn it!
Baby.
What's the play now?
You always got the answer.
Put the gun down, Cody.
Always thought
you were the leader.
Some leader.
Look at us.
We're all fucked up now.
I guess Timmy
was the lucky one, huh?
Lucky, my ass.
You got no idea
what happened to Timmy.
Oh, that's right,
I have no idea.
But you do.
DUKE: Look, we're all friends
here, okay? Let's not
do anything stupid.
Just take a deep breath
and calm down.
Hope!
What are you doing,
baby?
Give me that knife,
Hope.
She looked it
in the eyes,
didn't she?
Fuck!
Easy.
This ain't gonna
fly, Wyatt.
DUKE:
The thing's got her.
CODY: Don't matter.
She ain't got nothing
to do with this!
If that thing gets loose,
we're all dead.
I know
she's your girl and all,
but I don't give a shit.
No!
It's playing with us.
WYATT: Oh, don't you shoot!
CODY: See that!
I'm shooting.
No. No. No.
Cody.
Hope?
Hope. Please, baby.
This man will kill you.
She's fucking
cutting it.
Please, baby.
Concentrate on my voice.
What do you want?
He's talking to it.
You let her go!
The gun.
Put down the gun, Cody.
CODY: No fucking way.
No...
DUKE: Calm down, Cody.
Put down
the fucking gun!
Please, Cody!
Come on,
God damn it!
Jesus Christ!
Please, Cody,
put down the gun!
No fucking way.
(SCREAMlNG)
Stop!
Let go of her!
Let go!
God damn it! Let go!
Baby.
Hope.
(MUTTERlNG)
Red line's out of bounds.
Nobody crosses it.
No matter what.
(GRUNTlNG HOARSELY)
Damn,
that looks infected.
Might need
a tetanus shot.
Had one when I was seven,
remember?
Oh, fuck. It's deep.
Oh, jeez, Wyatt.
Oh.
That works?
Hell if I know.
You shouldn't be out
pulling some
cockamamie stunt, Duke.
You got a wife and kid.
Pam left me
four years ago.
That ain't shit.
I've seen worse.
How many nights have you boys
been out trying to catch
one of those things?
Nights?
Try years.
Probably seven by now.
Fuck!
Damn, Duke.
That's some shit.
It was either that
or just go out drinking.
Well, there was
some drinking
out there, too.
Actually, after a while,
it was pretty much
all about the drinking.
Got easier when Otis
started hanging out.
We could watch
in shifts.
Then numbnuts
got out of prison.
Fucking bear traps
was his idea.
Yeah, I could have
guessed that.
Going out to Nixon's farm
was just our way of coping.
You been coping, Wyatt?
What do you think, Duke?
Shit! Motherfucker!
(GROANS)
Fuck it. God damn it.
Ma'am, I'm sorry.
I'm supposed to
put this duct tape
over your mouth
because of the...
I thought... Wyatt thought
it'd be better.
Have you told Wyatt
to go fuck himself?
(SNlFFLES)
We all know how it feels.
Having one of those things
inside you like that
controlling you.
It's the worst
fucking thing ever.
It's hell.
It's worse when it's longer.
They did it to us for days.
Well, let's hold off
on the tape for now,
'cause...
God damn it.
What the fuck?
Oh.
Oh, fuck me.
God damn it.
What the fuck?
Oh, fuck!
Oh, God damn.
Oh, fuck.
Please, no.
Please.
What the fuck?
Oh, fuck!
God damn it.
Fuck! God damn.
Fuck.
Oh!
Fuck. Fuck.
CODY: Oh, shit.
Oh.
Come on, man.
I gotta drop a deuce.
Oh!
Come on,
quit playing.
Oh, fuck.
(MUFFLED BREATHlNG)
Wyatt, is this why
you gave me so much shit
when I wanted to move in?
Yeah.
Good call.
Honey,
I never wanted to
get you mixed up
in all of this.
You understand that,
right?
You're gonna have to
give me
a little bit more time
on the whole
understanding part.
CODY: Get the hell out
of my way! I'm not
fucking around here!
DUKE: Come on, Cody.
Calm down, man.
This was your
fucking plan.
No, my plan
was to catch it.
And now what?
You want out?
Oh, you sad
fucking sack.
But there's more
at stake now than just us.
Damned right.
They killed my brother.
Now, get the fuck out
of my way, Duke.
Cody. Cody,
put that thing down.
You're not calling
the fucking shots, Wyatt.
Now I'm not
playing around here.
I've got business
with this thing.
And I plan on
taking care of it
right fucking now.
Get out of my
fucking way, Duke!
DUKE: Cody!
CODY: Get the fuck out
of my way, Duke!
Fucking savages.
DUKE: Calm the fuck down.
I want answers,
motherfuckers. Now!
Cody, this is some
dangerous shit.
Dangerous?
You wanna see dangerous?
You boys still think
I'm screwing around?
It bit me.
Look at that.
It's spreading.
Okay, we can help you.
Duke. Not too close.
What?
Listen, Cody,
why don't you
turn off the torch
and lay down, man.
You seen it before.
It's bad, ain't it?
Ain't it?
It's just a rash,
right, Wyatt?
It's just a rash, Cody.
Oh, shit!
Get out
of the fucking way!
This is between me
and it.
Put the torch down, okay?
We can fix this.
We can get you to a hospital.
Yeah.
Yeah. I could be
some college boy's
thesis project.
I'm not being
a lab rat. Not again.
WYATT:
That ain't gonna happen, Cody.
Now just put the torch down.
You see, Wyatt,
that's your problem.
You always think
you got a say in the matter.
(GROANS)
You see what happens
when you try
to fuck with me?
Come on.
You see what happens,
motherfuckers?
I dare you. Come on.
Try that shit again,
you motherfucking
little pussies.
Duke,
don't touch him.
What about you, man?
Don't worry about me.
He's not dead, is he?
I mean, I didn't
hit him that hard.
No, he ain't dead.
Don't worry.
We're just gonna
let him rot away
in there?
He needs help...
Nobody can help him,
all right?
Now you stay away from him.
That shit's contagious.
But you touched him.
It won't do nothing to me.
None of this shit
ever does.
That's what Timmy had,
isn't it?
When they took us.
That's what
killed Timmy.
It won't take long.
It'll start eating him...
inside and out.
He'll watch his flesh
peel away layer by layer.
It'll hurt so bad,
it'll make him insane.
Dangerous.
A few hours from now,
he'll be begging us
to put a bullet in his head
'cause his fingers are hurt
so bad he won't be able
to pull the trigger.
Sweet Jesus Christ
on the cross.
Wyatt.
Can I talk to you
for a minute alone?
Hey, what about me?
You stay in there
and watch the girl.
Shit, Duke,
I don't want to be
alone with that chick.
She freaks me out.
Sorry, Wyatt.
DUKE: Just get your ass
in there, Otis, please.
Please.
They let us catch it,
didn't they?
What the fuck are you
talking about, Duke?
I'm saying there is
no way in Hades
we could have
caught that thing
the way that we did.
They just dropped
that fucker off
and sent him right to us.
You're crazy.
I'm sorry, Wyatt.
I'm sorry.
I'm such a
fucking idiot.
They knew our dumb asses
would bring it to you.
What the fuck
would they want with me?
I don't know.
Maybe they ain't done
fucking with you yet.
Have you ever wondered
why you were
up there the longest
and came back
with that clicker shit
inside you?
I try not to
think about that.
Well, I think it's about time
you started giving it
some thought.
Fuck me.
Oh, shit.
Oh, fuck.
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
OTlS:
What's going on?
Nothing, buddy.
I wish
you weren't lying.
Otis, you keep this door
locked and don't let
anything through.
It's loose, ain't it?
DUKE: Just do what he says
and secure the door.
Maybe it's gone.
(GASPlNG)
Holy shit!
Oh, fuck.
God damn it, Duke.
It was over here.
There's fucking blood
all over the place.
Where the hell is it?
(BANGlNG ON DOOR)
You stay down there.
(SCREAMlNG)
Help!
HOPE: Help me, please!
(BANGlNG ON DOOR)
SHERlFF: Wyatt,
it's Sheriff Henderson.
Open up
or I'm breaking in.
Get the fuck away
from me.
(SHUSHlNG)
(HOPE HOWLlNG)
(BANGlNG ON DOOR)
WYATT: Yeah,
just a minute.
Hands up.
Easy, Sheriff.
What's with the lights?
The power went out.
That happens out here
all the time.
SHERlFF: Oh, yeah?
Well, I heard voices.
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
It was the radio.
Hoping they'd say
when the electricity
would be back.
So what's this
all about, Sheriff?
911 call.
Said you were holding
a hostage.
Is that right?
Yeah.
An extraterrestrial one.
What is it?
The third time
this winter?
Fourth, I think.
What, are you
locking me in here?
No, it's wild dogs
been snooping around lately.
I guess I could take care
of some wild dogs.
I guess you're used to
this prankster shit.
Yeah.
Anyways, we gotta
check it all out.
You know the routine.
Especially since the call
came from your phone.
My phone?
Yeah.
You been drinking?
Yeah, I had a couple.
You mind if I have one?
I guess not.
(SHERlFF EXCLAlMS)
Good.
What's back there?
Nothing.
You got a key?
Yeah, I got...
I got it right here.
Shit. I stepped
in something.
What's this?
A radiator leak?
Yeah, I guess so.
WYATT: Listen, Sheriff,
there's something
I need to tell you.
I got a girl in there.
SHERlFF: You got
an alien groupie, huh?
No,
she's just a friend.
I'd like to meet
this friend.
(BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
(SCREECHlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
What the fuck?
What...
OTlS: Go away!
Wyatt!
Help me! Shit!
Hold it. On the ground.
I gotta ram it.
I said hold it!
You're gonna have to
shoot me, Sheriff.
Wyatt, help! Wyatt!
Fuck!
On the ground!
Come on, Sheriff!
God damn it!
Please, Sheriff!
The next one will be
between your ears.
(SOBBlNG)
Otis?
Don't move!
No, no, no!
Please, Wyatt, don't move.
It's come here,
Wyatt.
I want my mommy.
What the fuck?
Don't move.
No, no! Don't
point the gun at it!
Point it away,
God damn it!
Point it away!
Stay calm, Otis.
Just stay calm.
Stay calm.
(CHOKlNG)
(COUGHlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
(OTlS SHOUTlNG)
Get the tape, Duke!
Make it stop!
Oh, it hurts.
(GUNSHOT)
No, no, no, no, no!
Please make it stop!
Hold it down, Duke!
I'm gonna kill you,
you motherfucker!
You're all right.
You're okay.
I don't think
the duct tape's gonna work
this time, Wyatt.
You're gonna be fine.
Just hold it together,
all right? Don't look.
Sheriff?
Shit. There's a pulse.
All right.
I'm gonna get you
some help, okay, Sheriff?
Fuck that.
Go get me a beer.
All right.
(GROANlNG)
Easy.
How's your friend?
About as good as you.
All that shit
about you and aliens
was true, huh?
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Shit.
That's fucked up.
(GASPlNG)
You got anything harder?
Yeah. Yeah.
(CAR ENGlNE STARTlNG)
It's not safe
out here.
Is it safe
in there?
I'm not going
back there, Wyatt.
Not until it's dead.
We're taking it back
where they found it.
Otis needs help.
We're gonna
take him to County.
Kill it, Wyatt.
Can't kill it, Hope.
I'll do it, then.
Hope.
Hope?
Please don't tell me
it'll be okay, Wyatt.
If you tell me
it'll be okay,
I swear to God
I'll fucking hurt you.
Killing this thing
will only make it worse.
Worse? Fucking worse?
Did you fucking see
what it did?
Why can't you be a man?
Why don't you care?
I hate you!
Hey. Hey.
I care. I care.
(SOBBlNG)
Oh, fuck.
You had the keys.
You should have just
gotten the hell
out of here.
I've never been
so good with "should've".
Me neither.
We're losing him.
Cody.
Cody. Otis is...
Otis is bad off.
We're gonna
go for help, man.
CODY:
Always thought one day
we'd find Timmy.
Take him back to town
and have a fucking parade
or some shit.
That ain't gonna happen,
huh, Wyatt?
(CODY SOBBlNG)
I'm gonna die
with everyone thinking
I killed my brother.
WYATT: Nobody thinks
you killed Timmy, man.
The hell they don't!
My own pop.
CODY: If I had it my way...
I'd take
that fucking monster
and drive it back
to my pop's
little peach house,
walk right past
that motherfucking
white picket fence,
and drop
that piece of shit alien
right on that
cocksucker's doorstep.
Ding dong.
Oh,
that would be good.
I'm sorry, Cody.
My mom,
she thinks
I'm working overtime.
She's gonna be
all alone now.
Oh, shit.
Watch your fingers.
Yep.
Ready?
All right.
He's a heavy little
fucker, isn't he?
I doubled the chain.
Let's hope
it stays unconscious.
Yeah.
It ain't safe
out here, Duke.
DUKE: I can't leave Cody.
The boy's my responsibility.
Take care of yourself.
Bye, buddy.
(CAR ENGlNE STARTS)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
ON CAR RADIO)
What happens
if we kill it, Wyatt?
You know what happens
when an animal
kills a human?
We kill that thing
and they put us down.
They put us all down.
We kill one,
they declare war
on the human race?
Wouldn't be no war.
They want us gone
from this planet,
we are gone.
The show is over,
end of the human race.
It'd be a
goddamned massacre.
Wyatt, when this is over,
I think I'll move back
to my mama's house.
Cody?
I'm real sorry, Cody.
(KEY TURNlNG)
I'm gonna
make things right.
(HEAVY BREATHlNG)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
Why'd they come back,
Wyatt?
They let the others go
after the second night.
And they tested us all,
you know.
But Timmy and l...
I guess Timmy and l
passed the first round.
WYATT:
Timmy got sick real fast.
Like his brother.
But it didn't take with me.
So they kept doing
more and more.
They kept fucking with me.
They altered me.
Till one morning I woke up,
naked,
couple of counties away.
They'd sent me back
with some sort of
tracking device in my body.
But I knew it was there
because I could hear it
clicking away.
So I cut it out
and went into hiding.
I guess they want me back.
They're scared of you,
Wyatt.
When that thing
was fucking around
inside my head, I felt it.
That's why they came back
for you. They're scared
shitless of you.
Yeah, well,
the feeling's mutual.
(TlRES SCREECHlNG)
HOPE: What?
What the fuck,
Wyatt?
Shut up! Shut up!
They'll hear.
How do you even know...
I can feel them.
Where are they?
Everywhere.
Lots of them.
We can't just sit here.
It's not safe out there!
Well, sorry, sweetie,
but sure as fuck
ain't safer
sitting in the middle
of the road in this van
with that thing in the back.
Wyatt?
Wyatt!
Hope. Hope.
This ain't cool, Hope.
Hope, this ain't cool.
That van will be our coffin.
Otis is back there.
Otis died ten minutes ago.
That is not true!
Yeah? Then check
on him yourself.
Hope, we should
get back in the van.
I am not hiding away
for the rest
of my life, Wyatt.
That's your thing.
Hope. Hope!
WYATT: Otis?
Come on, buddy. Otis?
Come on, Otis!
Come on.
Come on, Otis.
Come on, boss.
Come on.
Come on. Come on, boss,
stick with me. Come on, man.
(GRUNTlNG)
You son of a bitch!
God damn you, motherfucker!
Why'd you pick us? Why?
Motherfucker!
You like that?
You like that shit, huh?
Fifteen years ago,
we were out
on a hunting trip.
You know all about
hunting trips, don't you?
Don't you?
It was me, Wyatt,
Otis and Cody.
And Timmy.
Yeah, you fucking remember.
You fucking remember.
You fucking remember
that shit!
We were just kids.
But Timmy.
You remember Timmy.
You killed our friend.
Now you're gonna pay for it.
You're gonna fucking die!
See what it feels like.
Feel what it feels like.
(ALlEN GRUNTS)
CODY: Duke!
Duke.
Oh, shit. Fuck.
Cody. Cody.
Holy shit.
What the fuck,
Duke?
Shit, Duke.
You're not supposed to be
holding me like this. Shit.
It's okay.
(GROWLlNG)
HOPE: We could go
get help.
You get help.
I'm going back.
Take this, okay?
Won't you need that?
No.
Okay. I'm gonna
drive you back.
No. You stay
on the road
and keep driving.
All right? You don't
turn back for nothing.
I won't leave you.
I need you to
do this for me, Hope.
No,
I won't leave you.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHlNG)
(FOOTSTEPS STOP)
(ALlENS BREATHlNG)
Duke?
Oh, no.
(COUGHlNG)
Duke. Duke. Duke.
Duke.
Hey, Wyatt.
Duke. Where is it?
Where'd it go?
It's calling the others,
Wyatt.
(COUGHlNG)
Duke.
(SHUSHlNG)
You run, Wyatt.
Go.
Duke. Duke.
(RUSTLlNG)
(GUN CLlCKS)
(CREAKlNG)
(ALlEN GROWLlNG)
Damn.
Get off him, you fuck.
Duke! No!
(GROANlNG)
(CHOKlNG)
Duke!
You motherfucker!
You fucking bastard!
Why'd you have to do that,
you son of a bitch?
You goddamned motherfuck...
(ALlEN SCREECHlNG)
(RUMBLlNG)
(SHRlLL RlNGlNG)
(GROANlNG)
How did that feel?
You ugly motherfucker.
Cody!
How does it feel
to be probed, cocksucker?
Cody?
Oh, shit, Cody.
I ain't got time for this,
man. We've got some
serious company coming.
Cody. God damn it, Cody!
You hearing me,
Cody? Please.
Oh, God, Cody.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, man.
God damn it, Cody,
listen to me!
Cody!
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
(GROANlNG)
Oh, shit.
Shit, Cody.
Oh, Jesus.
Cody, stay down there.
Please.
Cody. Cody.
Cody, please.
Cody.
He's had enough!
God damn it!
I said, that's enough!
(RUMBLlNG)
(SHRlLL RlNGlNG)
(GASPlNG)
I know what they want.
Call them off.
I'll go with you.
Call them off!
WYATT:
Just leave Cody alone.
And don't hurt anybody else.
And I'll go with you.
You'll get a ribbon
or something,
you piece of shit!
No! This is between
you and me!
Nobody else!
I said call it off
and I'll go with you!
I'll go with you!
(GUN FlRES)
(GASPlNG)
You're not going
anywhere with them.
(RUMBLlNG)
Hey, van's
down the road. Let's go.
Wyatt.
Cody?
Cody.
I got you.
You okay?
Timmy was never
really good with pain,
was he?
He was a real pussy,
wasn't he?
(SOBBlNG)
(CODY GROANlNG)
I need you to do
what you did to Timmy.
I didn't...
I didn't do...
Please, Wyatt.
You were his best friend.
(CODY SOBBlNG)
(GUN CLlCKS)
(GUN FlRES)
(THUDDlNG)
(ALlENS SQUEALlNG)
Come on.
Come on. Hurry!
Come on, Hope. Get in.
Hope, get in.
Come here.
Cover your ears.
(BlRDS CHlRPlNG)
(DOORBELL RlNGlNG)
What the fuck?
Where now?
Somewhere else.
We're all right now,
aren't we, Wyatt?
We'll see.