The tank itself...
...was unusual in that it was vertical...
...and looked like an old boiler.
Inside the tank the subject wore
a heavy glass bubble...
...and you would have thought the whole
contraption uncomfortable to say the least.
It was, however, effective.
Of the 23 students tested,
only two found the experience unpleasant.
Some even called it exhilarating.
A number of students hallucinated.
Dr. Jessup found the encephalographic
evidence especially interesting.
And one Saturday afternoon, in April 1967...
...he decided to try the experience
for himself.
Arthur. Hey, Arthur.
Are you there?
Can you hear me, Arthur?
Arthur, answer me.
Is that it? You want me
to come in and get you out?
I want to get a look at those EEG tracings.
How do you feel?
Not bad.
I hallucinated like a son of a bitch.
A variety of dream states, mystical states...
...a lot of religious allegory,
mostly out of Revelation.
You were in there close to five hours.
It felt like an hour.
I'd like to try that myself sometime.
You should. You'll like it.
Did we have any communication?
Sure. I kept checking you out
like you told me to.
How did I respond?
Very orderly.
At one point you were crying.
You mean, actually crying?
You were sobbing.
There were tears on your face.
When I asked you what was going on,
you said you were...
...re-experiencing your father's death.
Did you make notes?
It's all there.
I'd like to try this again next week. Do you
think you could make it again next week?
What are we looking for?
I don't know, yet.
There's really very little literature
on this kind of research.
There are some good people in the field:
Tart, Ornstein and Deikman...
...but most of it is radical-hip stuff,
drug-culture apologias.
Obviously, the first thing to do is
set up some sensible methodology...
...study these experiences
under controlled laboratory conditions.
It won't interfere with the work
we're doing with Hobart.
What are we getting into?
Sensory deprivation? Isolation studies?
I mean, where will we be going
with the tank stuff?
We're not writing up a grant.
Strictly bootlegging, just for kicks.
We've got the use of this tank.
Let's play with it.
Let's find out where it takes us.
It's fascinating stuff.
I think we ought to get into it.
I didn't even know they had one of those
isolation tanks at New York Hospital.
Must be some guy
in the Psychology Department...
...doing sensory deprivation studies.
What's Jessup doing with it?
You've got me. He's been taking students
out of his classes and testing them.
He's been doing this for three, four months.
Did you know...
...Jessup was into this kind of stuff?
Not until you just told me.
What do you want?
How long are you going to let it ring?
It's okay, I'll get it.
He's the last guy in the world I figured...
...to be screwing around with anything
as flaky as altered states of consciousness.
Let's face it. Jessup is pretty flaky himself.
That's him.
Arthur says you're very shy.
He wants me to draw you out.
Draw me out?
That doesn't sound like Arthur.
Well, what he actually said was
you were a high-handed, arrogant prick.
A little nuts, but brilliant...
...and that if I ever got you talking,
I would find you fascinating.
That sounds more like Arthur.
He says you're doing some work with him
and Alan Hobart at Payne-Whitney.
What sort of work?
Toxic metabolite stuff.
We're replicating Heath's
and Friedhoff's strategies...
...trying to find maverick substances
specific to schizophrenia.
I think we're chasing our tails.
What do you do?
I'm a physical anthropologist.
I'm sweating out my dissertation.
Where?
Columbia.
Holloway, and that bunch.
You're kind of young for a Ph.D.,
aren't you?
I'm 24.
That's still pretty good.
I didn't get my Ph.D. until I was 25.
I'm supposed to be a whiz kid.
I'm a whiz kid, too.
Anthropology seems to attract
good-looking women.
So you don't think schizophrenia can be
reduced to a single etiological agent?
I'm not even sure it's a disease.
You think madness is simply
another state of consciousness?
There's a body of evidence to support that.
You don't Iike to talk
about your work, do you?
As a rule, no.
I'm interested in interior experiences,
especially the religious experience.
The only reason I'm working
with schizophrenics now...
...is the religious experience is
so significant in schizophrenia.
There's only so much
you can do with animals.
I worked with monkeys...
...but they can't tell you what goes on
in their consciousness.
You need human beings for that.
You can't ablate human beings,
nor stick electrodes in their skulls...
...so I have to use
a trance-inducing technique...
...and the isolation tank seemed
the least risky.
And I'd like to go home with you tonight.
Would that be all right with you?
I've got a roommate.
We'll be confined to the living-room couch.
What's wrong with the living-room couch?
You tend to slip off a lot.
I'm sure we'll manage.
I'm sure we will.
So, whenever you want to go there,
you let me know.
How about right now?
What are you thinking about?
God...
...Jesus, crucifixions.
As a rule, do you usually think about
Christ and crucifixions under sexual stress?
When I was nine years old,
I used to see visions...
...visions of saints and angels,
even Christ himself.
Of course I don't do that anymore...
...not since I was 16.
Were your parents religious?
Anything but.
My father was an aeronautical engineer.
My mother, a clinical psychologist.
What happened?
I mean, how did a little kid who saw
visions of Christ turn into a physiologist...
...teaching at the Cornell Medical College?
I stopped believing.
It was very dramatic.
My father died a protracted
and painful death of cancer.
I was 16 years old
and very fond of my father.
I used to race to the hospital
every day after school...
...and sit in his room doing my homework.
He was very heavily sedated.
The last few weeks he was in coma.
One day I thought
I heard him say something.
I got up and leaned over him...
...my ear an inch away from his lips.
''Did you say something, Pop?''
Then I heard the word he was desperately
trying to say, a soft hiss of a word.
He was saying...
''...terrible...''
''...terrible.''
So the end was terrible,
even for the good people like my father.
So the purpose of all our suffering
was just more suffering.
By dinner time, I had dispensed with God
altogether. I never saw another vision.
I haven't told anybody
about this in 10 years.
I'm telling you now
because I want you to know...
...what sort of a nut
you might be getting mixed up with.
Arthur was right.
You are a fascinating bastard.
Well, it's settled.
Metcalfe spoke to Spencer again this
morning and it's definite. The job's mine.
I'll be in Nairobi doing
my post-doc work July and August...
...and in September,
I'll be teaching at Harvard.
Terrific.
It looks like we'll both be teaching
at Harvard in September.
Looks that way.
You can't get any tidier than that, can you?
We're going to be together in Boston
and I think we should get married.
You know, of course,
I'm supposed to be at least a little bit nuts.
A little bit?
You're an unmitigated madman!
You don't have to tell me how weird
you are. I know how weird you are!
I'm the girl in your bed
the past two months.
Even sex is a mystical experience for you.
You carry on like a flagellant,
which can be very nice...
...but I sometimes wonder
if it's me that's being made love to.
I feel like I'm being harpooned by some
raging monk in the act of receiving God.
And you are a Faust freak, Eddie.
You'd sell your soul to find the great Truth.
Well, human life doesn't have great truths.
We're born in doubt. We spend our lives
persuading ourselves we're alive.
And one way we do that is
we love each other, like I love you.
I can't imagine living without you.
So let's get married.
If it turns out to be a disaster,
it'll be a disaster.
We'll shake hands and say goodbye.
He's giving her dimethyltryptamine.
It takes effect in about a minute
and she'll trip out for about half an hour.
Do you feel different now?
Less anxious?
Much less.
Do you have any special feelings?
I feel...
...like my heart is being touched by Christ.
There's a lot of religious delusion
among acute schizophrenics.
Some guys say schizophrenics are
physically different from the rest of us.
It's almost as if they were trying
to change their physical selves to...
...adapt to their schizophrenic image
of themselves.
All right, we'll get married,
since it's that important to you.
I'm not comfortable with women...
...and I'm not likely to find anyone
half as remarkable as you again.
I think I can make
a reasonably good husband.
I don't want to lose you, you see.
I suppose that's the closest thing to
a declaration of love I'll ever get out of you.
Am I really that weird in bed?
Sometimes.
Shall I try to change?
No, I kind of like it.
-Daddy, I'm tired.
-We'll give the little lady a ride!
Hey, Mason, be careful.
How you doin', Eddie?
Hi, Mason. How about a beer?
-If I didn't see this, I wouldn't believe it!
-You were supposed to come next week!
Look at the family man!
Oh, Eddie, you look so good!
I don't believe it.
Not again? When did this happen?
Well, it's a long story.
Have you found a place yet?
We got a nice little place
near Huntington Field.
We moved to San Francisco
seven years ago.
Arthur is going to teach at Boston U.
I can't believe it's been seven years.
I hear you just got associate professor.
You guys must be loaded!
We've got a place in Maine
you can use for the summer.
I'm going to Africa again in June.
Eddie will be in Mexico.
Do you know a guy named Eccheverria,
University of Mexico?
Says he worked with you.
Sure. A very bright young guy.
He's here at the Botanical Museum.
We'll all have to get together.
I'm going back to Mexico with him in June.
What's in Mexico?
Eccheverria's got this witch doctor
down there, the Hinchi Indians.
They're an isolated tribe in Central Mexico
who still practice...
...the ancient Toltec rituals, sacred
mushroom ceremonies, that kind of thing.
Apparently they use some kind
of hallucinatory drug...
...that is supposed to evoke
a common experience in all users.
Maggie has fallen asleep on the couch.
Will you take care of her?
Did you ever get into an isolation tank
since New York?
No. Did you?
No, but I just found out
there's one here at the Medical School.
I didn't think anybody was doing
those kind of studies anymore.
We did some interesting stuff in that tank...
...in New York for the few months
we played around with it.
Maybe when I get back from Mexico
we'll get into it again.
Why not?
A terrific housekeeper she's not.
They're getting a divorce, you know.
-I don't know if they're getting--
-What are you talking about?
She and the kids are moving to Cambridge.
That's why this place is such a mess.
They're moving her stuff
into storage tomorrow.
Then she's going off to Africa
for a year with the kids.
And he's going to Mexico.
When she comes back, she's going
to live in Cambridge and he's staying here.
It's he who wants the divorce, not her.
I'm surprised they stayed together
this long.
When did all this happen?
She just told me five minutes ago.
What about the letters she kept writing us
about how happy they were?
Don't ask me. She's still crazy about him.
He's still crazy.
Sylvia just told me
you're getting a divorce.
We're getting separated.
We probably won't get around
to the divorce until next year.
I know it's none of my business, but why?
You're married to a great woman
who adores you.
My God, if anybody has it made, you have.
You're a respected and admired figure...
...a full professor on the faculty
of the Harvard Medical School.
For God's sake, is that how you imagine
me? A respected and admired figure?
A devoted father? A loving husband?
Well, I've also published nearly two papers
a year for the last seven years...
...and not a fundamental piece of work
in the lot.
I sit around the living rooms
of other young married faculty members...
...talking infantile masturbation, who's
sucking up to the head of the department...
...whose tenure is hanging by a thread.
Emily is content to go on with this life.
She insists she's in love with me,
whatever that is.
What she means is
she prefers the senseless pain...
...we inflict on each other to the pain...
...we would otherwise inflict on ourselves...
...but I'm not afraid of that solitary pain.
If I don't strip myself of all this clatter
and clutter and ridiculous ritual...
...I shall go out of my fucking mind!
Does that answer your question, Arthur?
What question was that?
You asked me why I was getting divorced.
Listen, it's your life.
I'm sorry I even asked.
Why don't I call Eccheverria
and we'll all go out and have some dinner?
As a matter of fact, Eduardo,
my year in India was disappointing.
No matter how you slice it...
...yoga's a state-specific technology
operating in the service of...
...an a piori belief system....
We scientists have a moral obligation to
the public as well as to our own research.
It just never occurred to baboons...
...that they could shorten that time
to five minutes if they used a stick.
Originally, man was just another
savanna-living primate like the baboon.
What dignifies the yogic practices is the
belief system itself is not truly religious.
There is no Buddhist god, per se.
It is the Self, the individual Mind, that
contains immortality and ultimate Truth.
What is not religious about that?
You've simply replaced God
with the original Self.
Yes, but we've localized it.
Now I know where the Self is.
It's in our own minds.
It's a form of human energy.
Our atoms are six billion years old.
We've got six billion years
of memory in our minds.
Memory is energy! It doesn't disappear!
It's still in there!
There's a physiological pathway
to our earlier consciousnesses.
There has to be.
It's in the goddamned limbic system.
Jessup, you're a whacko!
What's whacko about it?
I'm a man in search of his true Self.
How archetypically American can you get?
Everybody's looking for their true selves.
We're all trying to fulfill ourselves...
...understand ourselves,
get in touch with ourselves...
...face the reality of ourselves,
explore ourselves, expand ourselves.
Ever since we dispensed with God...
...we've got nothing but ourselves
to explain this meaningless horror of life.
You're whacko.
Well, I think that the true Self...
...that original Self, that first Self,
is a real, mensurate, quantifiable thing...
...tangible and incarnate...
...and I'm going to find the fucker.
What are their chemical properties?
Are they safe?
The mushrooms are almost
certainly amanita muscaria...
...a very powerful psychedelic
and a little dangerous.
It contains belladonna, alkaloids...
...atropine, scopolamine.
The sinicuiche plant is highly regarded...
...among a number of Indian tribes.
I've seen it as far north as Chihuahua.
The Indians say it evokes old memories...
...event ancient ones...
...and the Hinchis call it The First Flower.
The first in the sense of primordial?
Yes.
In the sense of the most ancient.
I'd like to try it.
Do you think they would
let me join in their ritual?
Well, they seem like agreeable people.
Est todo bien para ti
participar en la ceremonia.
He says it's all right for you
to participate in their ceremony.
Ask him what kind of an experience
I can expect.
Are they gathering these mushrooms
for the ritual?
No, they're being harvested for next year.
Qué clase de experiencia
puede esperar mi amigo?
Su alma regresar a su primera alma.
Your soul will return to the First Soul.
Ask him what this First Soul will look like.
_Cómo es la primera alma?
Es la Materia Increada.
It is Unborn Stuff.
Entonces, usted se lanzará en el vacío....
Then you will propel into the void.
Usted verá una mancha.
You will see a spot.
La mancha se convertiráen una grieta.
The spot will become a crack.
Esta es la Grieta Entre la Nada...
This is the Crack Between the Nothing...
De esta Nada saldr su Alma Increada.
...and out of this Nothing will come
your Unborn Soul.
Dígale que extienda la palma de la mano.
He wants you to hold the root.
Put out your hand with your palm up.
Are you all right?
We only have their word I killed a lizard.
You didn't see it
and I have no recollection of it!
This whole hideous business is
just a joke...
...the Indians have played on me
to make the gringo look like a fool!
Look, you asked me what happened
and I told you!
You drank the mixture
and you went outside.
After a while there was a scream
and some dogs were barking.
I shouted after you.
The screaming stopped.
The brujo yelled at me to come back.
Oh, bullshit!
Then why did you ask the brujo to give you
the mixture to take back to Boston?
I thought I'd like Arthur to analyze,
maybe synthesize, it.
The noise is stupefying.
The sun became black...
...as sack cloth.
The full moon became like blood.
Then a great mountain burning with fire...
...was thrown into the sea.
Then the beast ascends
from the bottomless pit.
The angel of the bottomless pit.
His name is...
...Abaddon.
He's off the wall!
Are you okay?
Get this stuff! It's new!
It's deafening! The noise is deafening!
Can you hear me above this noise?
The most unbelievable thing I've seen!
I'm watching the birth agony
of a mountain!
Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Really, I'm fine.
Do you want me to bring you down now?
What happens now?
He's blacked out.
These blackouts can get pretty freaky.
Sometimes they last as long as four hours.
When he comes out of it, he's as chipper
as a bird, but he doesn't remember a thing.
Just how dangerous is this stuff
he brought back from Mexico?
I didn't say dangerous,
just said it was weird.
It hangs around too long...
...and what's really screwy is
it heads straight for the brain.
Well, I don't believe this.
You guys are shooting up with an untested
drug that stacks up in the brain...
...and works in the nucleus of the cell
and you don't call that dangerous?
For the record, we don't actually shoot up.
-Eddie drinks a 10-milligram....
-It will stop now!
You guys are supposed to be
reputable scientists...
...not two kids in the dorm freaking out
on Mexican mushrooms!
Why do you think I called you for?
Let's see you stop him.
This ain't LSD, goddamnit!
This is no serotonin antagonist
you're drinking!
How many grams of that stuff
you think you've got in you?
Two? Three?
You could be working up
one hell of a case of cancer...
...with all the antimetabolites in you.
The Hinchis have been drinking that stuff
for centuries with no incidence of cancer.
Fuck the Hinchi Indians!
You don't know anything
about those mushrooms!
They seem to have
fantastic staying powers!
We've shot up at least 30 rats
with that stuff.
Some of them have
a whopping load in them...
...and none of them have been
noticeably affected.
Where are we going?
We were going to get something to eat.
Eddie wants to show me an isolation tank.
Isolation tank! You guys get flakier
every time I talk to you!
I thought all that isolation tank stuff
went out in the '60s...
...with Timothy Leary
and all them other gurus!
Will you shut up for a minute
and let somebody else say something?
What happens during
these blackout periods is...
...you get the feeling
of phenomenal acceleration...
...Iike you're being shot out over millions,
billions of years.
Time simply obliterates.
You sense the hallucination is going on,
but you get no images.
I want to break through
that blackout barrier.
I want to know what those images are
that I know are going on but I can't see.
We can't raise the dosage of the drug
because we're close to toxic levels now.
The only way to intensify
the experience is...
...to take the 200 milligrams
along with the tank.
There's more I'd like to do to that drug
before you take it again.
I'd like to do a half-life determination.
-That would take us a year!
-I'd like to know the transport system.
I'd like to find some analogues.
This Mexican stuff
is an extraordinary substance...
...and every instinct I have tells me
I'm onto something hot here...
...and another 200 milligrams
isn't going to kill anybody.
There it is.
Oh, it's horizontal.
It's smaller than the one
we had in New York.
If they're doing sleep studies, it must be....
I don't think anybody's used it in years,
but I checked it out yesterday and it works.
It won't take a week
to get this place cleaned.
You could get your ass in a sling...
...if it ever gets out you're using
an untested drug on human subjects.
Don't worry.
Nothing's going to happen to me.
Let's get a quick hamburger.
I'm seeing one of my students tonight.
All right!
Do what you want to do.
I think you're both irresponsible as hell!
Don't call me and tell me you're worried
about Eddie putting all this shit into him!
I'm telling you, don't you put
any more of that shit into him...
...until you know a hell of a lot more
about it!
I've offered you the use of my lab
and all the rats you can cut!
That's as much as I want to be implicated
in your dumb experiments!
Go get your own dumb hamburger.
I've already got my own date
I'm an hour late for!
I already did these first three.
You do the rest.
Couldn't resist, right?
Well, somebody's got to keep his eye
on you two sorcerers.
What have you got in there,
some kind of salt solution?
Ten percent magnesium sulfate,
for buoyancy.
Weird, man.
One, two, three, four.
Okay, you're fine.
Wednesday, January 7th, 4:28 P. M.
Hey, this is terrific!
He went into theta like a shot.
No spindling, nothing.
Grasslands, savannas.
I feel...
...I am actually alive
and inside this landscape.
A density of woodlands about a mile away.
Beyond that,
mountains that seem to be smoking.
Newly born mountains,
Cenozoic, latter Tertiary.
I'm in an edge-area.
Utter tranquility, but alive.
Life in the trees. Life in the sedge.
Oh, my God...
...the birth of man. That's got to be it!
My God! There it is...