Clara was my babysitter.
I was only 12 years old,
naive and somewhat trusting.
But all that
was about to change.
Some babysitters
take you to the movies,
or roller-blading
in the park.
Mine brought me on a date
with a serial killer.
Patrick Bateman.
Not my idea
of a romantic evening.
God, look at her.
All drugged up
and tied to a chair.
I knew we should have
gone to the movies.
At first, I was scared.
I wanted to get out of there
as fast as I could.
But then...
something came over me.
As soon as
I was free, I got really pissed.
He was about to make
a real mess of my babysitter.
So, I did what many of you
would have done,
I took matters
into my own hands.
And it changed
my life forever.
Is everything
all right in there?
- I thought I heard a crash.
- Yes, everything’s fine. Thanks.
They found Bateman
and his final victim a few days later.
The FBI quickly
uncovered a psychopath,
and a few extra
unsolved murders,
and he became an instant celebrity,
an overnight sensation.
They even
wrote a book about him.
Only in America.
As for me?
I was never tied
to the scene.
And rather
than self-destruct,
or spend the rest of my life
on some shrink’s coach,
I told no one
of what had happened.
I silently vowed
to devote my life
to stopping
other psycho killers.
I couldn’t wait
to grow up.
The next six years
of my life were a blur.
My parents
wrote me off emotionally.
My mom became
a raging alcoholic,
and my dad was busy
fucking the secretary.
Pretty cliché, huh?
So, here I am today,
attending the most renowned behavioral
studies program in the nation.
Here they focus
on profiling,
the art, craft and science
of tracking serial killers.
The subject matter itself
attracts some weirdoes.
Hey, Rachael.
But then again,
maybe it’s just me...
The problem is,
I don’t have time for games.
I’ve got to focus
on my work.
- You can do better than that.
- That’s what your mama said.
And what can I say?
Studying murder often
brings out the best in people.
Thought you quit!
Getting into
West Washington wasn’t easy.
I busted my ass
in high school
and maintained a perfect
4.0 grade point average.
All this, so I could study
with the best mind in the field,
Pr. Robert Starkman.
Possibly the most revered
hunter of serial killers
the FBI ever produced.
After solving every high profile
crime ever thrown at him,
he suddenly made a startling
life change and became a teacher.
Some say it was
his last case,
the mysterious death
of serial killer Patrick Bateman.
Good morning.
Funny how life works, isn’t it?
Starkman never discusses
the Bateman case...
Never.
Congratulations on getting through
the first half of the semester...
- alive.
-
I have here...
the official application form
for the teacher’s assistant
position for next year.
This is my golden
ticket to Quantico,
the FBI’s elite
training program.
Unfortunately, everyone else
is here for the same reason.
They know that nine out
of Starkman’s last 10 assistants,
- were accepted into the FBI.
- ...Announcing my new assistant
by the end of the week, just before
we head off for Spring Break.
And, talking about
Spring Break,
don’t forget the party
at the Dean’s mansion.
We’ll have the opportunity
to say goodbye to Miss McGuire
who’s leaving us for bigger
and better things.
Well, after weeks of grueling,
if not gruesome work,
let’s have some fun,
shall we?
Today we’ll be looking
at the unique aliases
the FBI, the press
and the general public
have nicknamed
serial killers, and why.
His present TA
is Elizabeth McGuire.
She’s already been
accepted to Quantico...
Early admissions.
I’m the front runner
to replace her.
Nobody comes close
to my rock solid GPA.
Dr. H.H. Holmes was
once vilified, in a biography,
as the „Arch Fiend.”
I’d like to say
none of them have a chance,
but grades
aren’t everything.
And I do have
some competition.
Contender number one:
Brian Leads.
A GPA as low as his
wouldn’t normally pose a threat.
But his family’s fortune,
easily numbering in hundreds
of millions, can open a lot of doors.
How do you think
he got into the school?
Can you spell „donation”?
He can’t.
Albert Fish,
AKA „The Moon Maniac”...
AKA „The Werewolf
of Wisteria.”
Contender two: Cassandra Blaire.
They say she and Starkman
have been going at it
since the beginning
of the semester.
But my guess: No way.
He’s old enough
to be her grandfather.
Nannie Doss...
„The Black Widow”
who murdered four of her husbands.
Contender three: Keith Lawson.
He poses the biggest
threat of the three.
He and I have been sparring
all year in this class.
But, I’ve yet to lose
a single round.
The fact is,
none of them have a chance.
Oh, Bobby.
Red lips, red leaves
fall on my knees like autumn
I miss cigarettes
every single day of my life
When you make love
to me
I close my eyes
and pray you say goodbye
Damn
She’s dawning on me
She’s beautiful
And I bet you don’t know
what love means
It’s just that
you do not love me.
The application is a mere formality.
Come Friday, I will be Starkman’s
new teaching assistant.
The position is mine.
I deserve it
and I’m going to get it.
Yes, there maybe a few more hoops
I have to jump through,
but I can handle them.
Besides,
failure is not an option.
Why don’t we just
start over here,
because I suggest you reconsider
your position on this.
WoI’m sorry, Mr. Leads.
I can’t make any exceptions.
our GPA is simply
not high enough.
Are you saying no to me?
Do you know who my father is?
Mr. Leads...
I am well aware
of your family’s legacy.
Heed my advice. A bird in the hand
is worth two in the bush.
That’s your fucking advice?
I have some advice for you.
Get ready to take a long vacation.
WoGo with God,
dear heart. Next!
Can you believe
this shit?
Wait till she sees my GPA after
my cousin hacks into their mainframe.
Oh!
Do they give these things up
for bitch of the month?
That hag could be
the reigning champion.
She’s lucky I don’t bash
her brains in.
Next!
Hi.
I was told to drop off
my application here.
Looks like everything’s
in order here.
Thank you.
Wait a second.
- What’s this?
- What?
It says here
that you’re a freshman.
Yeah, so what?
We don’t usually allow freshmen
or sophomores to become TAs.
You have to be
a Junior or above.
This isn’t
your usual situation.
Pr. Starkman
told me I could apply.
Shouldn’t this decision
be left up to the professor?
‘Fraid not.
I’ll run this up the flagpole
and see who salutes.
I’ll have to speak
with your teacher.
I have a schedule to keep.
It’s all worked out.
We do this
for your own good.
Freshmen can be extremely
overwhelmed, being at college,
and away from home
for the first time in their lives.
Here, take this.
„Beat common freshmen fears
in 10 easy steps.”
So many new experiences.
It’s so exciting.
Look,
the only experience I want
is to be Pr. Starkman’s
TA next semester.
‘Fraid not!
It just wouldn’t be right.
I’m sure he will put in
a good word for you,
but I don’t see how I can make
any exceptions at this point
without setting a dangerous
precedent in school policy.
I’ll be informing
the Dean of the situation.
I’m sorry, Miss Newman.
You’ll just have to wait.
Have a nice day.
-
- Hmm.
Ricky Martin?
Ricky?
Come to mama.
Ricky Martin?
Ricky?
Oh!
Ricky, you got
some explaining to do.
Ricky?
- Oh, thank God.
-
What happened to you?
Bad things
Dead things
Sad things have to happen
Bad things
Dead things
Sad things have to happen.
Hey, Miss Newman.
Wow, Brian.
Are you stalking me now?
No, Rachael. If I was
stalking you, you’d know it.
I mean-- you wouldn’t know it.
You know?
I thought we should
get together and...
discuss the state of the union
and life in general.
Get to the point, Brian.
My inside source says
he has narrowed it down.
Guess who’s still
in the running?
Keith, Cassandra
and me.
Unless you can raise
your GPA.
That problem’s
already solved.
Do you want to catch
a bite to eat tomorrow night,
maybe some dinner
and discuss it?
What’s to discuss?
It’s no big news.
We were always
the front runners.
We could get together
and form an alliance,
eliminate our competition.
That sounds
intriguing but...
- I have a paper to write.
- A paper?
We should get to know
each other better.
Is it just me or is there unspoken
sexual tension between us?
We should bring it to the surface
and stop lying to each other.
Are you on crack?
I don’t know. It was white,
it was in a pipe--
- So, what do you say?
- I have a paper to write.
No, no, no...
I won’t take no for an answer
twice in one day.
You have to eat, right?
I have to eat. We both have to eat.
Let’s just eat together.
It’s no big deal.
I was just fucking around
with this sexual tension stuff.
I just throw stuff
out there.
I’m crazy, I’m like a volcano,
just waiting to erupt--
Okay!
Okay, fine.
Pick me up at 8:00.
- Eight? Like 8:00pm?
- Yeah.
- Between 7:00 and 9:00?
- Yeah!
Okay.
‘Cause
it’s great for me--
- I’ll see you at 8:00.
- Whatever.
Maybe I’ll be there
five minutes later.
So... what are you doing
for Spring Break?
I’m just gonna hang around
and get some work done.
What do you mean "hang around?"
You mean stay on campus?
Yeah.
You’re not going home?
Why?
Because
I have work to do.
My family’s coming
for my mom’s birthday
to see how
the other half lives.
- Okay, that sounds terrible.
- I know.
What are you doing?
Bobby’s taking me up to his cabin
in the Northern Cascade--
Cassandra, please don’t call him
"Bobby" in front of me.
I’m sorry.
Pr. Starkman
is taking me up to his cabin.
When do you guys leave?
He’s got to go upstate first,
to meet Diane and Louisa.
You mean, his wife
and his baby daughter?
Whatever!
Yes, them.
He’s meeting them
at his in-laws’ for the long weekend.
I can’t stand how much
of his time they take up.
Cass,
they’re his family!
Whatever.
I’m late for a study session.
I should just go.
I can’t believe you’re
actually going out with Brian.
How did that happen?
Okay...
the other day, our eyes met
across a crowded room,
and there was this--
this spark,
the sign I’ve been waiting for
my whole life.
It was then that I knew
that Brian was my soul mate.
- Oh my God.
- I know.
- Really?
- No, not really.
It’s great
to be with you tonight.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Hi.
Hi. Can I get you
something to drink?
Yes. I’ll have a Kettle One
martini, straight up,
very dry.
Very, very dry.
And the lady will have...
- I’ll have a glass of house red.
- House red.
Good.
I’ll be right back.
- So, you look great.
- Thanks.
our hair is different.
It looks good.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
It’s great that we finally have
some „us” time.
- You and I hanging out.
- I agree.
Yeah. Listen, Rach,
before we embark
on our evening,
I have a confession
to make.
Can you wait
until we get our drinks
before you start
making your confessions?
- Oh yeah, sure.
- Thanks.
Look. Our drinks.
Thank you.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
It’s my first day.
So, ready to order?
Can you just
give us a minute here?
Sure.
Take your time.
Thank you.
Okay. What would you like
to confess?
This is difficult for me,
because I really want us
to remain friends after--
regardless of who Starkman picks
for the TA position.
Wow, I’m touched.
Brian, I really am.
You should know I’m determined
to get the position.
Over the last few months,
I’ve been doing a little research
on Cassandra Blair.
What kind of research?
Let’s just say that
if she gets the position,
the Dean’s office is going
to receive an anonymous letter
regarding her and Starkman’s
relationship,
accompanied by some
very revealing photographs.
- How Christian of you.
- Thanks.
I guess that narrows it down
to three.
Yeah.
You know
who my father is, right?
Yes, we’re all in awe
of your family’s money.
You know, you and Keith
are very smart.
So I’ve had to go
to great lengths
to ensure that my bright future
in the FBI goes without a hitch.
What are you
smiling at?
This.
That is the press release
for the new Carson-Leads
Behavioral Sciences Building.
It’s just one of my dad’s
new pet projects.
So...
I have an offer
you can’t refuse.
Drop out of the race
for the TA position,
and I’ll ensure you have seven
digits of my family’s gratitude.
Brian?
Are you bribing me now?
Bribe?
Did I say bribe?
Just think of it
as a business opportunity.
Trust me,
the alternative wouldn’t be
too pleasant.
„I’ll let you be in my dreams
if I can be in yours.”
- What?
- It’s a quote.
Bob Dylan,
maybe you’ve heard of him?
- Oh, yeah.
- You know, Brian,
you should
get out more.
Maybe I will.
The night’s young.
That it is.
Cheers.
Don’t!
-
- Shh!
We’re home, we’re home.
Wow!
This is like... a room.
Do you want
to be my girl?
to be my friend?
Do you want
to start it all?
We can stop if you want.
- No, no... I just don’t--
- What, you don’t have any?
Don’t worry, I’ll take care
of everything when the time comes.
Oh, the old
"pull out and pray" trick.
Great,
a Renaissance man.
Wait a second!
The convenience store,
down the street--
I’ll just go down there,
it’s right around the corner.
It’s really convenient
and I’ll get some, I’ll get tons.
Wait a minute,
what am I saying?
My roommate’s got tons of them,
drawers full of them.
A real
prophylactic factory.
Are we done here?
No,
we’re not done.
I’ll walk down the hall,
and get some from a friend.
- Oh, great.
- Make yourself comfortable.
Sure, great.
I’ll be here.
Jeez. A piss-sheet.
Jesus.
What the fuck.
Ribbed,
for her pleasure.
Yep, I just killed Brian.
But you’ve got to look
at the positive side...
I’m killing
for a better tomorrow.
Once I get into the FBI,
I’ll be able
to stop dozens,
maybe even hundreds
of serial killers every year.
Okay, think about it...
I’m killing the few
to save the many.
Sort of like Robin Hood,
you know?
God, I think I need
some professional help.
Rachael, have you ever been
to a psychiatrist before?
No.
- No, how does it work?
- I works like this.
You want answers,
so we get together weekly,
and we ask the questions
that will lead you to your answers.
All right?
I could tell you anything,
and you’d still never know me.
You could,
and that’s your choice.
But why would you
lie to me?
Because I don’t expose
my Achilles’ heel to anyone.
- Why do you say that?
- I just need to be on watch.
If I’m not looking out
for number one, then who is?
It’s a dog-eat-dog-world
out there,
and my future depends on
not getting eaten by the other dogs.
I have schedules,
appointments and dreams
that only I can fulfill.
No one is going
to do that for me.
Who do you think is keeping you
from achieving these goals?
- Other people.
- What people?
Anyone who gets
in my way.
If you could be anyone
in the world, except yourself,
who would that be?
Elizabeth McGuire.
Elizabeth McGuire?
Who’s she?
She’s Pr. Starkman’s
present TA.
And the next in line
to go to Quantico.
- And Quantico is?
- My goal.
- My destiny.
- I see.
Have you ever wanted
something so bad
that you’d do
anything to get it?
Sure.
Go on.
And that’s why I went
to West Washington.
I’ve always known that,
really,
there were
only three other people
who could steal the TA position
away from me.
What happens
if you don’t get the position?
I can’t even consider that.
Failure is not an option.
I’ll get the position.
- How can you be so sure?
- Because I am.
- Why don’t we stop there?
- Okay.
My secretary will get
your billing info.
Okay.
So, same time next week?
- You bet.
- Okay.
-
- Starkman.
Hey, Bobby.
It’s Eric.
Hey, Eric.
What’s up?
I just had a first time session
with one of your students.
Wow, wow, wow...
Aren’t we violating
some sort of privacy code here?
Yes and no.
I’ll tell you what...
I won’t tell you the name,
if you promise not to say it
once you’ve figured it out.
- Is that a deal?
- Okay. Fire away.
All right.
I think I’ve identified this person
as a textbook sociopath.
It’s a prerequisite for getting
into college in the first place.
Tell me about it. Still, this girl
has no concept of reality
or the difference
between right or wrong.
A girl.
Mmm, the plot thickens.
She’s obsessed with becoming
your assistant next semester.
If that’s her obsession,
it’s no big deal.
These kids think
I’m their ticket to the FBI.
Just keep
your eyes open.
This girl--
she scared me.
Jesus, if she’s that dangerous,
tell me her name
before she turns up
in class with an AK47.
I can’t do that. I’ve already broken
the law by placing this call.
Just be aware this student’s
in your class.
What exactly do you mean,
"be aware?"
25 years in the FBI...
turn your radar on.
Just make sure
she doesn’t get out of hand.
- She’s identified three of her peers--
- Dr. Daniels?
- Okay, okay, Mother.
- Mom?
I’ve got to go,
I’ve got an appointment.
I love you. I do.
Okay, I’ll see you
this weekend. Bye.
Rachael?
I am so sorry
to disturb you.
I didn’t realize
you were on the phone
- and your secretary wasn’t there.
- It’s okay.
I just left my keys here.
I am such a textbook
nut case sometimes.
I’d probably lose my head
if it wasn’t screwed on.
Oh, there they are.
It’s so nice that you stay
in touch with your mom.
- How old is she?
- 72.
Wow.
72,
that’s a great age.
So many new and exciting things,
the golden years.
Grandchildren?
No. I’m--
My wife and I
never had children.
Was she not able to?
Actually,
we’re divorced.
I have another patient
coming in soon.
I have
to prepare for him.
So I’ll have
to ask you to leave.
Which is it, Eric?
An appointment downtown
or a patient in your office?
It’s not nice to lie
to your dear old mom.
See you next week.
After my session with
Eric, I really needed some therapy.
That guy just about
drove me nuts.
So, I went back to something
my dad always said,
"Nothing like a change of scenery
to clear your head,
to ease the burden
of a busy schedule.”
Besides,
tonight’s the Behavioral Sciences
party at the Dean’s.
I have to look good.
I wanna be dressed to kill.
<Sometimes
she feels so sad>
<And other times
feels twice as bad>
<When the tears
are in her eyes>
<But I’m stranger
in the world>
- Excuse me?
- Bite me, Barbie.
The Anthony Perkins character
in Psycho was modeled on Ed Gein.
My heart rate
nearly triples when I get there
and see the vultures
have descended upon Starkman.
He broke the mold because he only
killed two people in his entire career.
I must have
lost track of time running.
I had planned
to get here early to get
as much time
with Starkman as possible.
And now I’m late.
This is a disaster.
Bitch!
...for Leatherface
in The Texas Chainsaw Massacre--
- Hello, Miss Brown.
- I’ll be right back.
It’s good to see you.
- Hey, how is it going?
- Hey!
How was your date
with Brian?
Fine. Short.
I don’t know.
Short?
How short was he?
I mean, „it.”
We didn’t get that far.
He went home after dinner.
What do you mean?
Why did you come to borrow a rubber,
- if he went home after dinner?
- What’s up with the third degree?
I’m just confused.
Did you guys get it on or not?
It’s none
of your business.
- Can we drop this, please?
- Whatever.
Sometimes
I don’t understand you.
It’s like
you’re not even here.
What did you do
last night?
- Bobby came over for--
- Cassandra!
I’m sorry. Pr. Starkman
came over for a study session.
And let me assure you,
it was definitely not short.
I’m gonna vomit.
What are you smiling at,
freak?
Come here.
Bob--
I mean the professor,
said I’m a shoe-in
for the TA position.
I wasn’t supposed
to tell anyone,
but since
we are so close...
I was gonna burst.
Now I get to spend
all this time with my sweetie.
And his wife’ll think
we’re working.
Wait, maybe
I’ll go to Quantico.
How great would that be?
Just don’t tell
anyone, okay?
- Not even Brian.
- Don’t worry.
our secret’s
safe with me.
This party’s such a dud.
Let’s blow it off
and you give me the details.
Perfect.
Let me talk to Starkman,
and we’ll go
to Jittery Joes for coffee.
No! It’s way
too crowded.
You don’t want anyone
to know about you and Bobby.
Let’s grab some wine
and go to your room.
That sounds great!
Just make sure
you don’t tell anyone, okay?
- Don’t let me down.
- Don’t worry,
I would never
let you down.
Like I said, Cassie,
student-teacher relationships
just never work out.
Hi It’s Cassandra,
I can’t get to the phone,
so leave a quickie
and I’ll get back to you.
Hello Cassandra.
Pr. Starkman here.
Listen, it’s 11:25 and
you missed your study session.
Call me back to reschedule.
Doctor Daniels?
I’m sorry to drop in
without an appointment,
but there is something
on my mind.
Sure.
Sure, Rachael.
- How are things with you?
- They couldn’t be better.
Really?
Any word
on that TA job yet?
He won’t announce it
until before Spring Break.
When does that start
for you guys?
- End of the week.
- Really?
- Two days?
- Yeah.
- And how do you feel about that?
- Pretty confident.
- You think you’ll get the job?
- I don’t think. I know.
Okay, Rachael.
Worst case scenario:
you don’t get the job.
What then?
What are you talking about,
Dr. Daniels?
It’s mine.
You want me to come up with some idea
of what’s wrong with me,
but I’ll be honest.
I came here
to tell you I’m not
coming back next week.
Don’t worry, I have every intention
to pay for your time.
However, I feel the problem we have
connecting lies mostly with you.
Look,
this is a small town.
My guess is you know
almost everyone here.
You were born here,
right?
It must be so disappointing
to see all these college kids
come in and out
of your town every year,
moving on to bigger
and better opportunities,
while you stay here, year after year,
getting older and older.
And all while taking care
of your dear old mom.
And on top of this,
you’re divorced?
God! The female population
in this town,
aside from the sexy little
college girls running around,
must be pretty weak.
This alone
would cripple any man.
our level of frustration
must be through the roof.
A dead-end job
with no love life,
all while taking care
of your sick mom.
Just the other day,
I noticed
you were judging me.
Is that fair?
I mean really, is that?
I don’t think so.
our life is very similar
to Ed Gein’s.
Ed Gein?
Yes, Ed Gein.
Very famous serial killer.
A bachelor, raised
by his domineering mother,
until she died
when he was roughly your age.
God, he went nuts!
He couldn’t handle the loss.
What would you do
without your mother?
Okay Rachael,
that’s enough.
You don’t know me,
and I don’t know you.
We were getting
to know each other.
These sessions
are a process.
So don’t go
jumping to conclusions.
No. I’m not jumping
to any conclusions here.
If you just open up your eyes,
you’d see I’m already there.
Have a good day, Doctor.
Let’s talk about Ted Bundy
for a minute, shall we?
What kind
of a killer was he?
How was he perceived?
Mr. Lawson wishes to participate.
Please, let’s hear it.
He was perceived
as a very organized killer.
- Very calculated.
- Hmphf!
You don’t agree,
Miss Newman?
Yes and no.
Come on, this guy planned
each and every detail in advance.
He chose his victims with extreme
accuracy, stalked them meticulously,
and waited for the precise
moment to attack.
All while maintaining
an air of patience
not even the FBI’s
greatest could penetrate.
- No offense, sir.
- None taken.
- But I still don’t agree.
- And he picked all his dumping sites
with the outmost
caution.
He was unquestionably
an organized killer.
- Premeditated, with a capital "P."
- Capital "P?"
- It’s a letter in the alphabet.
-
Between
"O" and "Q."
You have something to say,
Miss Newman?
He started out organized,
but spiraled down late
in his so-called career.
He began to keep bodies for days,
washing their hair
and even applying make-up
before disposing of them.
And he littered the dumping sites with
evidence, using the outmost caution.
However, his last victim,
and his youngest girl ever,
fell out of his typical
victim selection.
She was chosen out
of sheer availability.
The sheer need to kill.
He was both,
an organized killer
and off-the-charts lunatic.
- With a capital "L.”
-
You’re right.
He was both.
Very impressive,
Miss Newman.
Now, Pr. Starkman,
how would you classify a killer
whose downward spiral was actually
calculated into their grand scheme?
That’s a very interesting
hypothesis, Miss Newman.
Unfortunately, in this class,
we stick to the facts.
And there’s no known
case-study of that nature.
Keith’s
little display of brainpower
was totally unacceptable.
It’s a day before Starkman
announces his new TA.
This could be catastrophic.
I wasn’t about to watch years
of hard work go down the drain.
It was time
to pick Keith’s brain.
You know
that feeling you get
when you realize that there are
people out there just like you?
It almost makes you
feel normal.
All this time,
I thought he was taking notes.
But no. Look at his work,
his sketches.
They’re absolutely brilliant.
This may be a waste
of a rare mind.
But, a girl’s gotta do
what a girl’s gotta do.
Hi, Pr. Starkman.
- Hey!
- Miss Brown.
- How are you?
- Good.
So, the big day’s tomorrow,
right?
- What do you mean?
- For the TA position.
- You’re announcing it tomorrow?
- Yes, of course.
- At noon, in my classroom.
- I can’t wait.
My chances are much better this year
than they were last.
I would think so.
It’s a very tight race this year.
Mmm-hmm.
Were you looking for Cassandra?
She wasn’t in class.
She probably left
for Spring Break.
- Well, actually, the--
- It’s Cassandra, isn’t it?
She got the position.
Good for her, but--
I can’t say
I’m not disappointed,
but „what doesn’t kill you
makes you stronger.”
I’ll see you.
It’s Cassandra.
I can’t get to the phone,
so leave a quickie and
I’ll get back to you.
- Hello?
- Eric, for God’s sakes!
She’s dead!
- Who is?
- She is!
The „she” whose name
we agreed not to say aloud.
My patient? Dead? How?
She hung herself.
You didn’t say
she was suicidal.
She had suicidal
tendencies,
but I was more concerned
for the sociopathic
and homicidal patterns
that were emerging.
Spare me your psychobabble
bullshit.
This girl...
she may have been a little forward,
but she wasn’t crazy!
I’m sorry,
but you didn’t see what I saw.
- She was not a pretty picture.
- Listen, Eric,
I spent a lot of time
with her,
and I have to say
I don’t agree on this one.
There are tons of kids
in your classes.
How could you know her as well
as you think you did?
We’re bound
by the guidelines
of doctor-patient
privilege, right?
You didn’t, Bob?
You weren’t sleeping with her?
No wonder
she was obsessing over you.
- How could you do this to Diane?
- None of your business.
Fine. Why did you
call me, then?
‘Cause you’re
my fucking shrink!
I’m sorry. I just needed
someone to talk to.
I loved her.
Can you get me
some Valium?
Yeah. I’ll call it
in to the pharmacy.
- Can I give you some advice?
-
- Hello?
So, here we are. The big day.
In moments, I’ll be crowned
Starkman’s new TA,
and be one step closer
to the FBI.
Too bad Brian, Cassie and Keith
couldn’t be here to watch me.
But wherever they are,
I’m sure they’ll realize
they didn’t give up their lives in vain.
I will make them proud.
Guys, can I have
your attention, please?
Pr. Starkman
told me to tell you
that unfortunately he’s decided
that his sabbatical,
which was scheduled
for next year,
is now effective
immediately.
In other words, there’ll be
no TA position for next semester.
Sorry.
Have a great Spring Break.
This is an obsession
A kind of aggression
with himself
It’s the way
he’ll always be
He loves to rebel
To go against
his Ten Commandments
For him
That’s just being free
And over there
Stands my angry angel
And he’s shaking his head
In disgrace with me
Over there
Stands my angry angel
And he’s frowning
like hell
But I’m not
feeling guilty.
Pr. Starkman?
Rachael.
Why--
why haven’t you
gone home?
I’ll just hang around here
during the break.
Why?
Don’t you have family
waiting at home for you?
No.
Actually, they’ll come
visit me here.
Are you okay,
Professor?
I heard about
the change in plans.
Is that
why you’re here?
Is that all you people
ever think about?
The goddamn
teaching assistant job?
Quantico?
Don’t you kids get it?
It’s not that important.
It’s important to me.
I have a schedule,
a plan, a dream. I need it!
What makes you think
you’ll get it?
Other students
have applied too.
- Some more qualified than you.
- I beg your pardon?
I believe I am the most qualified
for this position.
Name someone who’s more
dedicated or intelligent,
that’s had more experience
than me.
You don’t know
what you’re talking about.
Go home.
- What are you doing?
- Shh.
Just relax, Bobby.
Where did you get that?
And the dress?
- What’s going on here?
- Bobby, what’s wrong?
Don’t fuck with me.
That necklace...
And Cassandra’s dress.
It was a present.
Bobby,
don’t you remember?
You gave it to me.
Stop it...
this instant!
I said, go home.
I mean it.
I have a confession
to make.
I’ve had feelings for you
for a long time,
longer than
you can imagine.
I’ve always wanted something
to happen between us.
Something beautiful.
I love you, Bobby.
- What?!
- Please, don’t be upset, Bobby.
Stop calling me Bobby!
Okay.
I’m a little confused.
You are?
How do you think I feel?
Rachael-- Ms. Newman...
- this is unacceptable.
- It is?
But it was okay
for you and Cassandra?
How did--
I don’t know what
you’re talking about. Leave.
I’ve always loved you.
Ever since
I first saw you.
Before Diane ever loved you.
Before Cassandra.
Before Clara even ever loved you.
It was always me.
Don’t you get it?
How did you know
about Clara?
That was six years ago.
I was there, Bobby.
- Clara was babysitting me that night.
- Clara.
He’s here! Do something.
I was in Bateman’s
apartment.
Clara used to baby-sit me
all the time.
She’d tell me about
your relationship with her.
She’d show me
pictures of you.
You were my first crush.
You were in Patrick Bateman’s
apartment
the night
he killed Clara?
Yeah.
I know you quit the FBI
because of what happened.
I think you blame yourself
for her death.
Bobby, all work, no play.
- You want to play?
- Uh-huh.
Okay.
She was the one who looked through
your stuff and found Bateman’s file.
She’s tracked him down.
And she went to his apartment
that night and dragged me along.
Rich and good-looking.
Why are we together again?
You shouldn’t
blame yourself.
She went over there
to cheat on you.
- She was a slut.
- Shut up!
It’s the truth.
She got what she deserved.
And so did Cassandra. She thought
you didn’t love her enough.
It’s my turn now.
I’ve waited six years.
I won’t let anyone stop me,
not even Diane and your baby.
Don’t you threaten
my family.
So now you care
about your family?
You just can’t hold
a relationship together.
- Please.
- You think you’re a catch.
But you’re just the opportunity
of a lifetime.
- Stop.
- After you can’t break anymore hearts,
you’ll still break one more...
your baby daughter’s.
Please, no more.
Goodbye, Bobby.
The sun is shining
We should be making haste
I hope you had a safe trip.
Hey, nice mop!
Sweet dreams.
We are sleeping
on our feet
We stole the songs
from birds in trees
But it’s time
on easy street
Now it’s past,
and it’s not me.
Hey!
Hey, stop!
Yeah, that’s it.
Bring it back.
Yeah,
bring it-- yeah.
Back it up.
That’s it. You got it.
Bring it in here.
Thank you very much.
Driving around
like goddamn maniacs.
That’s good. Perfect.
Thank you very much.
I sure do hope
you’ve got--
Holy shit.
- What the hell’s going on?
- Oh, that?
That’s Pr. Starkman.
He’s out of it tonight.
You’ve reached Pr. Starkman,
in the Behavioral Sciences Department.
Please, leave a message.
Hey, Bobby,
it’s Eric.
I felt bad about the other day.
I wanted to say I’m sorry.
I hope you got
that prescription filled okay.
Call me
if you need anything. Bye.
- Dr. Daniels’ office.
- Mary, if that’s Bobby Starkman,
- I’ll take it.
- He’ll take you at 3:00. All right.
It was for an appointment,
not the professor.
Okay.
I put her in at 3:00,
Rachael Newman.
She wanted
to come in today.
What?
Rachael Newman?
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Are you okay?
I can reschedule
if you want.
I’m--
no, I’m-- I’m fine.
It’s just--
it’s been a long day.
- Let me know if you need anything.
- Sure.
Bye.
Bye, Mary.
-
- Come on.
You’ve reached Pr. Starkman
in the Behavioral Sciences Department.
Please,
leave a message.
It’s Eric again.
Call me when you get this.
I’m really confused
about something.
If you don’t reach me
by 3:00,
I’ll drop by your office
between 4:00 and 4:30.
Bye.
- Hi, honey!
- Mom!
- Dad?
- We made it!
Hello, princess.
Won’t you invite us in?
Jeez, I’m sorry.
Please, come in.
Wow!
Hi, happy birthday!
Thank you, sweetie.
We’ve been
planning this for months.
Sweet Jesus! It smells
like somebody died in here.
The toilet’s clogged up and
maintenance isn’t up and running,
- so there’s nothing I can do.
- That’s wretched.
Sweetheart, you are
such a clothes-horse.
- What will I do with you?
- Don’t open the closet.
- our present’s in there.
- Oh, I’m sorry, sweetie.
Look at me,
always spoiling the surprise.
What will we eat?
I’m hungry.
Good. I made reservations
for 5:30.
I’m going out of town
later tonight.
Is this restaurant
reasonably priced?
Yes.
Is there
an early bird special?
- I don’t think so.
- That’s too bad.
- What’s it called?
- Chez Gerard’s.
Is that Italian? our father
cannot digest Italian food.
- It’s too spicy.
- Mother, it’s French.
French!
- How sophisticated!
- Yeah, okay.
I’ve got to finish packing
and finish writing some papers.
So why don’t you
go back to the motel
and we’ll meet
at the restaurant at 5:30?
Sounds good to me.
I’ve got to use the head.
Get maintenance
up here.
Daddy, I called.
How will we ever
find this place?
We’ll be back at 5:15
to pick you up.
- Okay.
- Bye, princess.
I love you, guys.
-
- You’ve reached Pr. Starkman
in the Behavioral
Sciences Department.
- Please, leave a message.
-
Bobby, it’s Eric. I know
you’re going through tough times,
but she--
the she who hung herself--
she made an appointment to see me.
I don’t know if it’s a joke,
but something’s off.
Call me, all right?
Roses are red,
violets are blue,
the Daniels will soon
be calling back you.
Mom, you’ve got to change
that message.
I’ll come by around 5:30
to pick you up for our big date.
And I’ll get you back in time
for Murder She Wrote. Bye.
- Bon appetit.
- Happy birthday, Mom.
Oh, it’s gorgeous.
This is the most
beautiful thing
I have ever received in my life.
How did you afford it?
- Stainless steel.
- It’s silver, you old lump.
Stainless steel.
Silver has...
that distinguished
look about it.
Anyway,
as I was saying before,
I said to Leora she ought
to have it looked at immediately.
So what does she do?
She waits an entire month.
And when she sees
the doctor,
he orders a biopsy
and it comes back positive.
Well,
could you just die?
If she had taken
my advice,
she could have avoided
this mess!
I know we’ll eat dinner
at some point.
- The question is, when?
- I’ll go use the restroom.
Don’t forget
to wash your hands.
Now, where is
my steak knife?
My mother drives me crazy.
That sounds cliché,
but how many people envision
carving into their mother’s neck
and yanking out her vocal cords?
Or ripping her tongue out and serving
it to her as an early-bird special?
- Bonsoir.
- Bonsoir. Daniels. Table for two.
I’ve got a table
right here for you.
After you.
Why don’t you sit
on the other side?
Get a view
of the whole thing.
Excusez-moi, garcon.
Could I have
un autre, uh...
steak knife,
s’il-vous-plait?
Oh.
- Of course. Voila, madame.
- Merci.
How about a table
closer to the window?
- That would be very nice.
- Okay, I’ll ask.
- Good evening.
I was wondering if we could get
a table closer to the window.
That section is closed
for Spring Break.
Sorry.
No problem. I understand.
This table is fine.
Good. Can I get you
something to drink?
I’ll have
a whiskey sour. Mom?
I’ll need some water
to take my pills.
As I stare at myself in the mirror,
I realize I can’t let my mother
get the best of me.
I’m Robert Starkman’s
next TA.
And that’s where
I’ll focus my energies.
I should set up a meeting with Bobby
when I get back.
Maybe we can brainstorm
at his cabin tonight.
I’ll make him my special eggs.
Sorry.
Ready to order?
Maybe you’d give us
some more time?
Sure. Of course.
I’ll be just over there.
- Take your time.
- Thank you.
- Cheers.
- Cheers, my dear.
Oh my God.
Hello, Dr. Daniels.
It’s great to see you.
And this must be
your mother.
Hello, Mrs. Daniels.
How are you doing?
I’m fine, dear.
Oh my God.
I just love that hat.
I’d kill
for a hat like that.
It is just so cute!
I have to be getting back
to my table.
- It was great meeting you.
- It was nice meeting you too.
See you later, Eric.
Who is that pretty girl?
A new girlfriend, I hope.
No.
She’s a patient.
A very sick patient.
- Excuse me for a second.
- Of course.
- I’ll be right back.
- Yes.
Excuse me. Sorry
to interrupt your dinner.
I’m a friend of your daughter’s.
Ms. Newman,
could I have a word
with you for a moment?
Sure.
Mom, Dad,
I’ll be just a minute.
Excuse me.
That’s it. I’m eating.
Didn’t he call her
a different name?
You have
some explaining to do.
First of all,
you insult me.
Then you threaten my mother.
You’re seeing a married man.
Then I hear you’ve hung yourself.
And you act like nothing happened.
- What’s going on?
- You heard I hung myself?
Yes.
Eric, why would you
say that?
Let’s say a mutual friend
told me he found you.
Dead.
- Is this some sort of sick joke?
- He never found me. He found her.
Her who?
It doesn’t even matter anymore.
It’s not important.
What’s important is my mom’s
birthday, and she’s here.
I’ll catch up with you later.
Goodbye.
Honey, why did he call you
Ms. Newman?
I don’t know.
Could we just eat?
- I have to go home and pack.
- Can’t you cancel?
We never get a chance
to see you.
I wish I could,
but I can’t.
- They’re very special plans.
- A boy?
- Yes, it’s a boy.
- What’s his name?
Bobby Starkman.
Bobby?
- Hey, Jim.
- Dr. Daniels.
A cup of
apricot-peppermint blend?
Thank. We might have
a bit of trouble.
- Is Harv in?
- He’s in the back.
If it’s not
Sigmund Freud himself!
- What’s the good word?
- Not much.
I want to file a missing person’s
report on Robert Starkman.
- You’re kidding?
- I wish I were.
His wife called 20 minutes ago
to do the same thing.
He didn’t show up at his in-laws’
upstate like he was supposed to.
- You’re kidding?
- I wish I were.
- It’s been a crazy year.
- What do you mean?
It’s the third MPR we’ve filed
this year. Right, Jimmy?
- That’s a record around here.
- Who else was there?
Let’s have a look.
I’ve got a brand new one here.
A woman, Gerty Fleck,
from Student Services.
Just up and disappeared.
And of course,
that Newman girl.
A student, Rachael Newman,
disappeared.
The first day
of the semester.
Jimmy and I toddled up
on campus to check it out.
And guess what?
I’m Sheriff Winslow,
and this is Deputy Duncan.
Just looking for a--
- Are you Rachael Newman?
- Yeah. What’s wrong?
We’re checking
on a MPR on yourself.
You’re not missing,
are you?
No, I’m okay.
She was there,
unharmed.
Are you sure
I can’t offer you some tea?
No, thanks, Jim.
I actually know
this Rachael Newman girl.
To be honest,
I don’t trust her.
Are you telling me the parents
just dropped the report?
I never said nothing
about parents.
The Newman girl,
she was an orphan.
The report was filed by
some student friends of hers.
- But it was a false alarm.
- How do you know it was her?
There’s only one Rachael Newman
registered at school.
Can I convince you guys
to come to the campus with me
to make sure
everything’s okay?
Yeah, no problem, Doc.
- Should I get in here?
- That’s fine.
You’re reached Pr. Starkman
in the Behavioral Sciences Department.
Please,
leave a message.
Hey, it’s me.
I’m almost done packing.
I’ll be there soon.
I hope you’re as excited as I am.
If you need me
to go to the store,
I’ll be here another five minutes.
Otherwise, see you soon.
I love you. Bye.
God, you stink.
Now, how did you get open?
Trying
to sneak out on me?
I just brought you up and
you’re already causing problems.
Don’t fall apart
on me now, Rach.
Wow! I like your room.
Actually,
I like your name too.
Rachael.
You don’t mind
if I borrow it?
Well, this is a wild-goose
chase, I guess.
- Have a good day.
- You too. Thank you, Officers.
Hey, Mom, I know
I’ve been out of touch,
but I got accepted
to West Washington.
I know.
Can you believe it?
It’s so sad
about your parents.
That car accident thing and all.
So tragic.
Must have been hard
growing up an orphan.
But, I’m glad
you shared it with me.
Oh, Bobby.
I told you to get
your beauty sleep.
We have a long night
ahead of us.
You’re disgusting.
So, I’m two cans of gas
and a brick away from Quantico.
I just have to dot the Is
and cross the Ts, and I’m home free.
Look out!
- Jesus!
- That was the Newman girl!
We’re on the move!
Hang on!
Not now, Bobby.
Wait till we get
to the cabin.
I’ll make you a fire.
I’ll heat you up real good.
This qualifies as breaking
the speed limit.
- Don’t you think?
- Doing?
60...
- in a 35.
- Yeah.
She’s coming up on Old Mill Bend.
She’ll slow down for the curve.
- We’ll take her there.
- Take it easy.
- We don’t want anyone getting hurt.
- It’s all under control.
That’s 275 bucks.
- Can you pull up next to her?
- Yeah, for a bit.
Jesus!
- Can you do something?
- Yeah. Take the wheel.
She’s slowing down.
That did the trick.
Doc, you stay here.
Just be careful.
She’s a loose cannon.
It’s all part
of the job, right?
Ma’am.
Ma’am, open the door.
Come on!
Come on, guys.
Don’t let her get away!
This don’t look good.
Jesus.
- What the hell?
- Don’t let it be Bobby.
Christ!
Bobby.
How the hell...
Starkman.
- Where the heck is our lady friend?
-
Come on.
Bobby.
Jesus!
A bizarre killing spree
came to an end last night
when 18-year-old West Washington student
Rachael Newman, now identified...
Rachael Newman’s killing
spree is believed to have begun
Wednesday evening with
the murder of Gertrude Fleck...
The body
of Cassandra Blair was found
- hanging in her...
- Brian Leeds’ body,
- from the Leeds family...
- Keith Lawson was...
The bodies
of a West Washington security guards
- were found within hours...
- Once a typical girl,
Rachael Newman’s death
leaves many questions unanswered.
The most burning question
of all: Why?
As a case-study,
Rachael Newman
was as rare as they come.
She was more obsessed
than Dahmer,
she was more calculating
than Bundy,
and certainly more faceless
than Bateman.
In a perfect world,
she’d still be alive.
But for her,
it all ended...
in a blaze of fire
in which she
and her final victim,
a friend of mine,
Robert Starkman--
they burned to death.
I wish I had a chance
to study her mind more,
but all we ended up
with were dental records.
All in all,
she killed eight people.
Eight people
which we know of.
Rachael Newman
is one in a billion.
One in a billion.
She’s in a league
of her own.
But she will remain
a constant and strong reminder
that people aren’t always
what they seem to be.
Thanks for taking the time
to come out.
- Thank you for coming, Doctor.
- It’s a pleasure.
- Who should I make it out to?
- Louis Okon.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Can I have a different pen?
- Here you go.
- Who should I make it out to?
- Elizabeth...
- Elizabeth McGuire.
- McGuire.
your work
is so inspiring.
It’s a huge honor
to meet you.
If you could be
anyone in the world,
- who would that be?
- Elizabeth McGuire,
Pr. Starkman’s present TA,
and the next in line for Quantico.
- You can’t be?
- What, Eric?
One in a billion?
Hello, Dr. Daniels--
- Do you know that girl?
- Who?
- Elizabeth McGuire.
- You mean, Agent McGuire.
She’s the first Quantico
student in history
to be drafted into the Bureau
in her sophomore year.
Are you all right, Doctor?
It’s like they say...
„The brightest futures
are based on forgotten pasts.”
In the end, I did put Dr. Daniels
in a bit of a pickle.
But you’ve got
to give to take.
He gets his national best-seller,
which is ever so flawed...
I wonder how he sleeps at night,
knowing I still walk the streets.
Me?
I need
for him to know.
What’s the point of pulling off
the perfect set of murders,
to realize my dream, if there isn’t
someone alive who knows?
It would be as if
I’d done nothing at all.
I remember her
The girl
that wouldn’t die
She said
it wasn’t true
I knew
it was a lie
People on the street
Would cry out
if they knew
The things
that I have done
To make the dream
come true
When she blew
my mind away
All the feelings
were betrayed
Heaven would
squeeze her
Hell would
release her
Into my brain
La la la la la
La la la la la la
And I swear
she looked surprised
When I joined
the freak show guys
Under the Big Top
I was a Cyclops
With two eyes
Morning
turned to night
And she said
it was a hoax
And when she came
with me
She said it was a joke
I still hear the beat
And it makes me
want to fly
For I cannot complete
The girl
who wouldn’t die
In a million
little years
All the waiting
to be here
Hell couldn’t crush me
Heaven would brush me
Out of the tear
La la la la la
La la la la la la
La la la la la.
SUBTITLE:BY DUQA