Camila.
Ready?
- I'm coming.
- You'll never beat me.
My God, look at this little town.
How cute is this?
Wow.
Oh, come here.
- Hola.
You know, we're close to that river
that used to be
Argentina's main trade route
into Paraguay.
Apparently it used to be
a pretty happening town.
A lot of smugglers
and rough types.
Really?
I like it already.
Pick one.
Uh...
- this one. Yeah.
- This one?
Thanks.
Here you go.
You can keep the change.
Thanks.
I mean, gracias.
De nada.
Go on, ask her.
- Go.
- Um...
Buenas tardes.
Um, donde está
El Hotel Rosarnaria?
Okay. Gracias.
Did you get all that?
Shut up.
Hello?
Hola.
- Hello?
- Hola.
- Buenas noches.
Um, me llamo es Stephanie.
Mm-hmm.
Y nosotros tenemos un, um...
You have a reservation?
- You speak English.
- Yes.
Luca.
You stay only one night, yes?
Yes.
Actually, we leave tomorrow.
Do you know what time the bus
to Posadas leaves?
At 8 o'clock.
And it's the only one of the day.
Please tell me that's 8:00 PM.
I'm sorry.
It's 8 o'clock in the morning.
Figures.
- Your passport, please.
- Oh yeah.
Ellie.
"Assport"?
That's a good one.
You are not traveling alone,
are you?
Um, well, yes and no.
We were traveling with a bike tour
but we kind of went AWOL
after the first day.
Yes, I see.
Well, please let me know
if you need anything.
- Cool.
- Thank you.
Okay.
- Ciao.
One key.
Oh, gracias.
- Ah.
- Weirdo.
Cute.
Yeah, this is cute.
Hmm.
Whoa!
First shower.
Ugh, this is gross.
Ugh.
Hey, Steph.
There's no towels.
Yeah, coming.
Here are your towels.
Danke schoen.
What did you say to those guys?
Nothing, just that you're single.
Gee, thanks, El.
Okay, I like the potential.
Yeah, it's nice.
Oh, excuse me.
Two cervezas, por favor.
Gracias.
Is that Nick?
Seriously?
He's such a dick.
I know.
But maybe I should
just talk to him.
No. No no no.
Don't even think...
it's so not worth it.
I know, but...
You know I'm not...
I'm not good
at being alone.
I know, but I'm right here.
Okay?
- We had fun.
- Yeah, absolutely.
We're about to have more fun too.
Gracias.
Um, disculpe.
We didn't order these.
Don't be rude.
Mmm!
Whoo!
All right!
- No no.
- Yeah yeah.
- Ellie, no. Seriously, I'm done.
- Just shut up and drink.
Tomorrow's gonna suck.
Yes, but that's what Advil is for.
Come on, it's our last night.
To you and me.
Salud.
- I can't...
- That was hard.
Whoo.
What about him?
I don't know.
You think he's my type?
Totally.
He looks...
Responsible.
Should I invite him over?
I can totally invite him over.
- No. El, stop. Sit down.
- I’m gonna do that for you.
Jesus, sit down! Sit down!
He's gonna look over here, Ellie.
- Stay.
- Isn't that the point?
Oh my God.
Are you hearing this?
Do you hear this? Please don't
tell me you're not hearing this.
- What are you doing?
- I'm doing us all a favor.
Oh no no,
you cannot play that song.
Ugh, Ellie.
My friend wants to know
why you don't like the song.
Well, 'cause there's a fine line
between irony and just plain bad.
Kind of like...
Your shirt.
All right.
No.
Nope.
Okay.
This one's for you, baby.
¶ I love myself ¶
¶ I want you to love me ¶
¶ When I feel down,
I want you above me ¶
¶ I search myself,
I want you to find me ¶
¶ I forget myself,
I want you to remind me ¶
¶ I don't want anybody else ¶
¶ When I think about you ¶
¶ I touch myself, ooh ¶
¶ I don't want anybody else... ¶
- Senor.
- ¶ Oh no oh no ¶
¶ Oh no... ¶
Hey hey hey.
Take it easy.
- No problem here.
- ¶ You're the one ¶
¶ Who makes me come running ¶
¶ You're the sun
who makes me shine ¶
¶ When you're around
I'm always laughing... ¶
Hey, where are you going?
Um, el peepee.
¶ I close my eyes
and see you above me ¶
¶ Think I would die
if you were to ignore me... ¶
Girl emergency.
Sorry.
¶ I'd do anything for you ¶
¶ I don't want anybody else... ¶
¶ Oh, I don't want... ¶
You're not from around
these parts, are you?
Performance anxiety?
You should stick close
to your friend.
Wow.
That backfired.
¶ I honestly do,
I touch myself ¶
¶ I touch myself. ¶
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Do you want to sit?
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Let me take your picture.
- Okay.
- Did you get it?
- Mm, I got it.
Let me take one of you.
- You think so?
- Yeah, I like it.
Now you're my prisoner.
Really?
- Does that mean I'm in trouble?
- Big trouble.
What?
What does that mean?
- It means that you...
- Yeah?
- your friend...
- My friend?
- and I...
- Uh-huh.
No way, Jose.
Not with that one.
Mmm.
Ooh!
Oh my God.
You'll wake her up.
- Shh.
Silencio, por favor.
Let's go to my place.
Your place?
No no no. We can't.
Who says?
- Me says.
- Oh, you says?
Yeah, me...
- Come on, you're gonna love it.
- I know I'll love it.
I know.
I just can't.
My friend, she's in...
she's inside.
Well, tell her to come.
Tell her to come.
I'm not gonna tell her to come.
Come on.
I live really close to here.
- I don't... we can't.
- Okay?
- I told you I can't go.
- Come on, you're coming with me.
I'm not gonna come with you.
Okay, all right.
This hurts.
Ow, stop!
What the hell?
- Hey!
- Let me go!
- Get away from me!
- Come inside!
- Hey hey!
- Steph.
Come on, we are just having...
Keep 'em closed.
He's mean. Oh!
What? Habla la bamba?
Girls, open the goddamn door!
- Ooh.
- Jesus, you trying to get us killed?
Ellie, come outside.
Ellie!
Hey, asshole.
Qué pasa?
Sorry, girls.
Maybe next time, all right?
You too.
Hey, Steph.
You saved me.
Aw shit. Ellie, get up.
We're late.
Oh, no no no no.
Oh no.
I’m not kidding, El.
- We cannot miss that bus.
- Oh no.
Wait!
Don't leave us here!
No!
Oh, we're screwed.
- We'll just take the next bus.
- There is no next bus.
Oh yeah.
Why did this have to happen
to us on the last day?
Everything was going so great
until now.
Come on, let's go back.
So that's flight 206
at 1600 hours.
Um, that's 4:00 PM, right?
Okay. No, that's fine.
Thank you.
Thank you, bye.
Are we good?
No, Ellie, we're not good.
We're both out 200 bucks.
Oh my gosh.
Wake me up never.
Come on, let's at least
do something fun.
I am doing something fun.
You have not left.
Oh no.
Actually, we missed our bus.
But we wanted to go to this place...
Villa Del Lago.
Have you heard of it?
They say the water there
can cure polio.
I don't have polio.
Villa Del Lago.
No, it's a ghost town now.
There is nothing to see.
If you must go somewhere,
go to see the waterfalls
or to see the caves.
- They are beautiful.
- That sounds like fun.
Ellie.
All right, well, thank you.
Thank you. That's great.
Rosa.
- Permiso, chicas.
- Thanks.
- Come on.
- Huh-uh.
- Come on, Ellie, let's go.
- Huh-uh, no!
Wake up.
Dude, stop!
Oh, look at that.
Wow.
Hey, let's just lay out here.
- Ellie, really?
- Come on, just relax.
We really don't have
anywhere to be.
You win.
Here, sunshine.
It will all be okay.
I promise.
Thanks, El.
All right.
¶ I'm feeling blind ¶
¶ Like the sun's in my eyes ¶
¶ Since I'm fighting in a losing war ¶
¶ Tiny little fault lines
cracking inside my soul... ¶
¶ I'm alive... ¶
You ready?
Ellie, I know you can hear me.
- Let's go.
- Huh-uh, later.
And when exactly is later?
I don't know, Steph.
When I'm ready.
Ow! What the hell?
I said I'm not ready.
Well, I am.
El, we can’t be here all day.
You really really need to learn
to have some fun.
And what,
you're gonna teach me, I suppose?
Yeah, actually.
I probably could.
Where would we start, huh?
The men's bathroom?
That sounds like fun.
Okay.
No, that's great.
I see where this is going.
- Forget it.
- No.
Forget it. No, you're right.
If you didn't care before attacking him
in the bathroom, you're certainly
not gonna care now.
Okay, Steph, I'm sorry.
If it's any consolation,
he didn't take the bait.
It's still really shitty, Ellie.
- I guess you can't help it.
- What?
You know what? I probably actually
should have done something.
Because God knows
you never would have.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
You know what?
Just... just forget about it.
No, bullshit forget it.
Say what you mean.
I mean, Steph, God forbid you take
a chance on another guy
instead of dwelling
on the same old one.
He said we’d work it out, El.
Stephanie, he cheated on you.
This is crazy to me that
you're still defending him.
You should have dumped
that guy right on the spot.
But you didn't.
And now you're hurt
and I have to pick up your pieces
of yet another disaster relationship.
What? Is this coming
from you, the expert?
You think a relationship is when
you get the guy's last name.
Wow.
You know what?
Screw you.
Nice.
Steph, wait.
Where are you going?
What do you care?
You're on vacation, Ellie.
I don't want you to have to worry
about cleaning up after me.
Have fun.
Come on, El, where are you?
Oh my...
So it's me.
Um, where are you?
I'm at the cow place now.
Um, okay.
So call me.
Bye.
Hey'
- Hi.
- Where's your friend?
Coming.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Any minute now.
Oh hey, thanks for your help
last night with that guy.
- He was a real creep.
- Yeah, he was.
You know what?
Probably got a flat or something.
I'd better go.
But see you around, uh...
- Michael.
- Stephanie.
Hey, where are you going?
I'll give you a lift.
No, I'm okay.
Thanks though.
Wait! No!
Somebody! No!
No!
Hey'
You follow me here?
Yeah. I just wanted to make sure
you were all right.
Are you?
'Cause you don't look it.
Her bike is gone.
Well...
Well, maybe she left already.
No, there's only one road.
I mean, we would have
passed each other.
Right.
I'm gonna go inside
and look for her.
Are you sure this is the place?
Yeah, I'm positive.
Do you hear that?
- It's over here somewhere.
- Ellie!
Who are you calling?
The police.
Good luck with that.
- Hola.
- Michael.
- Calvo.
- What did he say?
- We're gonna show him.
Here, give me the phone.
Calvo.
- What did he just ask?
- He asked...
Why were you and your friend
not together?
We got separated.
Separated?
How did you get separated?
It was stupid.
We got in a fight.
Oh.
Well, I am sure she will forgive you.
Wait, where are you going?
Your friend is fine.
When she realizes she has lost her
phone she will come back to find it.
Senor, please wait.
Where are you going?
Calvo.
Michael.
Do yourself a favor
and find another lover.
This one has a habit
of losing his girlfriends.
Hey. Hey!
I am very sorry, but I...
She was with a guy last night.
What did he look like?
He was tall.
He had brown hair.
Brown hair?
You just described half
of Argentina.
- Did you get his name?
- No, I didn't.
- Could you identify him?
- Yeah.
Yeah, if I saw him again
I'm sure I could.
Well, when you do see him
you can call me,
but now there is nothing I can do.
Please. Please.
Okay.
You may make a report if you want.
Yeah, that...
thank you.
Can I ride with you?
- Of course.
- Okay.
You want me to come with you?
No, Michael.
Thank you.
I think I can handle
the situation from here.
Yeah, I'll be fine.
Just because he speaks English
does not mean you should trust him.
I don't know if I trust
anybody right now.
All done.
Wait, that's it?
- That's it.
- No.
We should be out there
looking for her.
I mean, we can still make
a search party before it gets dark.
A search party?
Where do you think you are?
This is not America.
Does it look like I can
make a search party?
Then what else can we do?
Today? Nothing.
Nothing?
Please, you should not
worry so much.
Your friend is just having her fun.
My friend is not out there
having fun, okay?
I know her.
She wouldn't just leave me like this.
The way you left her alone
in a foreign country?
I'm sorry.
I will do everything in my power.
You have my word.
This is so messed up.
Is there someone else I can talk to?
You're tired.
Why don't you go back to the hotel
and take a siesta?
You want me to take a nap
while my best friend is missing?
Yes.
I think you will feel much better.
It's okay.
Look, if she's not back tomorrow,
we'll file a missing persons report
with federal police in Buenos Aires.
Okay?
Okay.
Good.
Everything will be all right.
You'll see.
Disculpe me.
Uh...
I'm looking for my friend.
Senora.
I'm just looking for my friend.
Mi amiga. Senora?
Oh, excuse me.
Can you help me?
I'm looking for my friend.
I can't find her.
Senora?
I just want to ask...
I just...
Senora, please.
Hey, wait.
Hey!
I just want to talk to you.
Wait.
Hey!
Ellie?
Hello?
Michael?
I'm sorry.
I've got to go.
Look what I found.
It was in his room.
- It's Ellie's.
- Whose room?
Michael's.
Okay.
I will question him,
but only if you go
back to the hotel and wait for me.
You let me do my job.
Is that fair?
- Okay.
- Good.
What's wrong?
Ellie's gone.
Gone?
We got in a fight
and I went on without her.
I've got to...
I've got to find her.
Come inside.
Have something to drink.
Come on.
it's okay.
Don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
Hey'
- Please don't! No!
- Just wait!
- No, let me go!
- Hey! I won't hurt you.
- Hey. Hey.
- Stop, no! Stop it!
- Get off me!
- I'm not gonna hurt you.
What's the matter with you?
Where did you get this?
You went through my things?
Look, it belongs to someone I know.
Bullshit!
This is Ellie's.
What did you do with her?
Look, I swear to God I've got nothing
to do with your friend, okay?
You have to trust me.
Look.
Look, please.
Would you just take a look at this?
Okay?
Just take a look at it.
Her name is Camila.
She disappeared
somewhere around here.
That's her bracelet.
I've been up and down these roads
100 times looking for her.
Oh God.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
You know, when we met
she was organizing
a humanitarian mission
to South America.
And I wanted to be with her
so I went too.
What happened?
About six months ago
we came to work here.
One day she took the truck
into town to get some supplies
and that's the last I saw of her.
Nobody knows what happened.
And if they do,
they're not saying anything.
I'd do anything to get her back.
And I'm not leaving this country
until I find her.
Did you call the police?
Calvo?
Yeah, he filled out a form.
Oh no.
God.
I'm gonna be sick.
Oh God.
I can't...
Look, I've been hearing things
about young women, girls,
who've been abducted
and taken across the river
into Paraguay.
I don't know if that's what's
happened to your friend.
I mean, it's rare.
it's risky to kidnap an American.
But it does happen.
That's why I tried to warn her.
Oh.
I have to find her.
I have to find Ellie.
Okay.
Well, I mean, chances are
she's probably still in the area.
It's too risky to move her
during daylight.
But we need to find her
before it gets dark.
- How?
- We need to split up.
Now I'll understand if you
don't want to do that.
But we can cover more ground
if you do.
No, you're right.
You're right.
Okay, I'll meet you back here
in an hour.
Yeah.
Ellie!
Oh shit.
Michael, you're becoming
a hard man to find.
Surely you must be lost.
You know me,
just seeing the sights.
Yes, of course you are.
Have you seen Stephanie?
No.
Because a car has been stolen
and that does not happen
very often around here.
Wow.
A stolen car.
Did you find Stephanie's friend?
I was going to ask you
the same thing.
So her friend is still missing
and you're looking for a car?
Okay.
Come with me.
Let's take a drive.
Water.
Chucho,
I know you're not a bad guy.
I can tell by the way
you kissed me.
Come here and kiss me again.
Come here.
So you want that?
I want you.
No!
Help!
Hey hey.
No!
Oh my God!
Don't! No!
Bastard!
Shh.
You fucking bastard.
Help me!
Stop it!
Fuck you!
Oh God, get me out of here, please.
Well, seems that tonight is your night.
Listen.
Don't you move, okay?
Steph. Hurry hurry.
- Ellie. Ellie, are you okay?
- Steph.
- Are you okay?
- I just want to go home.
- Let's go home.
- We're gonna go home.
Shh Shh.
- Get this off me.
- Hold still.
- You can do it, right?
- Oh, he's coming!
- Shit. Come on. Come on.
- Hey!
Hey!
Let's go!
- Ellie, come on. Hurry hurry.
- Go, go.
Lock it! Lock it!
- Oh God! Oh God!
- Go, Steph, now. Come on, go.
- Oh shit.
- Get it! Get it!
- Shit.
- Come on, come on, come on!
Okay okay okay.
Open the door.
- Steph, watch out!
- Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, come on!
Where'd he go?
Shh.
No!
Watch out!
Wait, stop!
Ellie. Ellie.
Oh my God.
Ellie, come on.
Ellie, please. Ellie!
Ellie!
Hey, get off of her!
Ellie.
Ellie, please.
She's dead!
Oh my God.
Stephanie, is this the man
you say was with your friend
the other night?
- Yes!
- Stephanie, get into the truck.
It's for your safety.
Trust me.
Now!
Oh my God.
She was very desirable.
What a waste.
"Assport"?
Clever.
That's a good one.
Michael!
it's him, Michael!
- Michael!
- But that one
will do fine in her place,
don't you think?
- Michael.
- Shut up.
Get away from the car.
Where is she?
Just put the gun down.
Where's Camila?
Michael, we can still
help each other.
- But you must put the gun down.
- On your knees.
Shut up!
On your knees.
Think for a second.
If you kill me then who will tell you
where to find Camila?
Just put the gun down
and let's talk, okay? Man to man.
I think we can work out something
that will satisfy us both.
- Where is she?
- She's safe. Trust me.
Where is she?
I swear to you no harm
has come to her.
Okay.
I can bring her to you,
but we must trade.
You piece of shit.
This is the only way.
Stephanie for Camila.
It's simple, Michael.
No.
I'm sorry.
Michael, no!
I hope you're going
to be a good girl
and play nice.
'Cause if you give me any trouble,
I swear I will cut you so bad
you will not even make $10 per day
sucking cock in the streets.
Please.
What if I told you that you
are only worth $2,000?
$6,000 if you're a virgin, but...
are you a virgin?
Get away!
Stop it!
Stop. No.
No, I don't think you're a virgin.
Please.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry, you're American,
not some brown peasant.
You're worth much more.
It's lucky for you my partner
across the river is open-minded.
You see, he is a businessman too.
And they think you could
make a nice accessory...
for one of his clients.
Night night.
Get up.
I should kill you.
Then you would owe me
a lot of money.
Pick her up.
- I don't like this.
- What's not to like?
- This is what we discussed.
- This is dangerous.
Girls like her...
people will look for her.
Then put her someplace
no one will find her.
So easy for you.
Please.
Your greed is going
to get you killed one day.
And you,
you'd better be worth the trouble.
Never!
Help! Help!
Help, somebody!
Help!
Please!
Please wake up!
Please help me.
Help me, please! Help me!
Stephanie, please.
Give me the gun.
Come on.
Be a good girl.
Just give me the gun!
It's okay.
¶ When I woke this morning ¶
¶ I saw that you were still gone ¶
¶ And just for the weekend ¶
¶ Just sayin' I think
that's way too long ¶
¶ I toss in these sweaty sheets,
no sleep ¶
¶ The clock is wailing on and on
and on and on ¶
¶ Who in the hell was I
to come here ¶
¶ All alone
on my own? ¶
¶ But you you you ¶
¶ I love you ¶
¶ More than I ever wanted to ¶
¶ It's all I am ¶
¶ All I do is sit around ¶
¶ And remember you ¶
¶ I'm on my knees now ¶
¶ Please turn around
and come home ¶
¶ I left my cold soul
on the ground ¶
¶ I can't believe I'm falling apart ¶
¶ I need your needle in my arm ¶
¶ 10cc might suit me ¶
¶ I'd rather all day
than go without ¶
¶ Your arms ¶
¶ I'm drying up
without this cocoon ¶
¶ Well, I want to be your monarch ¶
¶ Pin me up to the wall
in your bedroom ¶
¶ But you you you,
I love you ¶
¶ More than I ever wanted to ¶
¶ It's all I am ¶
¶ All I do is sit around ¶
¶ And remember you ¶
¶ I'm on my knees now ¶
¶ Please turn around
and come home ¶
¶ I left my cold soul
on the ground ¶
¶ I'm all alone ¶
¶ I'm on my knees ¶
¶ I'm begging you ¶
¶ Come back to me ¶
¶ Come back
to me ¶
¶ I'm on my knees now... ¶
¶ Please turn around
and come home ¶
¶ I left my cold soul
on the ground ¶
¶ Come home, come home ¶
¶ Come home ¶
¶ Don't leave me here ¶
¶ Please, turn around. ¶