[Growling]
Pick up, pick up, pick up,
pick up, pick up, pick up!
[Panting]
Sarah! Sarah!
- Duncan, what happened to you?
- Good. You're ok.
Go down to the basement.
Right now.
Oh, my God! What is that?
- Do it now! Hurry!
God damn it!
[Duncan screams]
[Growling]
- And there she blows.
Mr. and Mrs. hayslip,
take a look.
What is it?
- It's definitely something
the doctor should look at.
He'll be with you in a moment.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Uh-huh, uh huh.
Familial adenomatous polypsis.
- It's a polyp.
- Oh, it sounds really bad.
That sounds bad.
- You got a thing in your butt.
- Ok.
- Yeah.
You need a little trooper
in your pooper.
You don't need 'em there.
- Is it serious?
- It's, it's not that bad.
It's not that serious.
This though,
this is a weird shape.
This is concerning me a little,
but not overly.
Look, in the end,
this lump in your colon
is most likely due to psm
which is poor stress management.
Look, how long have you had
stomach issues?
- Um, for...Ever.
- Yeah. He's in
the bathroom a lot.
Not, I mean not, not a lot.
I'm in the bathroom
a decent amount of time,
but not like, it's not extreme.
- Hour. Hour and a half.
- Yeah. About 90 minutes.
- That's not, that's...
Hugely concerning.
- Over the course of the day.
Not...
- Ok. Good thing is,
we can do something about this.
It's an endoscopic polypectomy.
Basically, we insert a camera,
into the anus.
- Ok.
- Right?
There's an electrified
wire loop at the end of it,
and we (Makes popping noise)
Pop it off.
Like a plum off a tree.
Being pulled by an electrified
wire loop.
- Ok. Ok, you don't have to,
you don't have to describe it
anymore.
- Do you have a family history
of g.I. Problems?
- Uh, well, you know, my mom
would gladly tell you
that she's um, you know,
regular like clockwork.
- One of those.
What about your father?
- Uh, well, we don't speak.
I haven't spoken to him
in sometime. So...
Look, I think what you're going
to need
is some coping mechanisms,
so I can give you the name
of some professionals
that can help you out.
- Are you talking about
a therapist?
Oh, I'm not,
I'm not a therapy guy.
- We can get there.
We'll do it.
- Great. Stop by the desk
on your way out.
Talk to Nancy about scheduling
a follow-up.
Until then, you take it down.
No stress. Keep it quiet.
- Right.
- No stress.
(Whispering) Keep it cool.
No stress.
[Elevator rings]
I'm sorry.
Um, hello?
This is my office. You might be
in the wrong office.
- Hey, guys. Just take that all
down the hall and to the left.
Lucky day, dunc. New office.
Part of the new job. What?
- New job?
- Human resources.
- I'm an accountant.
I don't know the first thing
about humans.
- It's just temporary.
You're far too valuable
an accountant
to keep you in h.R.
Permanently.
- I'd love to help.
I just don't know
if I'm the right man
for the job.
- Do you believe
in this company?
- Yes.
- Do you believe in our
mission statement?
- Our clients trust us because
we put our own skin in the game.
- I'm in the game.
- I'm in the game, too.
- Yeah, your retirement
account is here. Mine is here.
We're in this together.
- Right. Right. Right.
Which is why I need you
to handle the layoffs.
- What?
- You're a nice guy, dunc.
- Thank you.
Which is exactly what we need
right now.
A nice guy, and we gotta
let some people go.
And you just said
you're a team player.
- I am a team player, it's just
that I don't...
I don't-- I've never fired
anybody before in my life.
- It's easy. You'll love it.
I'm so glad you're on board.
Um, I'd be sad to see you go.
- What?
- So. Your new office.
- This is the bathroom?
- It was a bathroom, and now
it is an office. For two.
Hey, there, cubie.
That's what I'm saying
instead of roomie.
- Dunc, you know alistair.
- Um...Yeah.
- Uh, Duncan, I need you and Al
to work on a re-org chart
and uh, I'm going to need to
see that first thing next week.
- Next week? I still have to
deal with the Darcy accounts,
I have the board of directors
asked me to make a presentation.
I have to get that done
by Monday.
- You got alistair.
Between the two of you,
- you got it covered.
- Hey, uh, cubie.
You think these toilets
are still functional?
Would save us a lot of trips
down the hall.
Really?
-Yeah.
Sarah: And don't forget
we have dinner
with your mother tonight.
At 6 P.M.
Thank you for doing this
therapy thing.
I think it's gonna help.
His name's
Dr. Oliver highsmith.
And I think you're really
gonna like him.
I know you think
all therapists are crazy,
but I think this guy
is totally legit.
I hope it goes well, doughnut.
[Laughing]
Lactose intolerant.
Just like myself.
- I am not--did I, did I write
that I was?
- You checked it yes.
I meant no, I'm not.
- I don't get it, you meant no
when you said yes?
- I think it was just
a mistake.
I am not lactose intolerant.
Ok, don't make it
a big issue.
- I'm sorry. What's happening?
- Witch doctor. Witch doctor.
- Shut up!!
Don't listen to him.
He thinks he knows everything
about everybody.
I can't stand him sometimes.
It's like--ugh. [Laughs]
All right then.
Let's get started.
I want you to come over here.
Lay down. Relax.
- Uh, what, what for?
- What you came here for.
Hypnosis. Not?
Oh...No.
- I want to bypass
your conscious mind
to access
your sub conscious mind.
- Ah...
- Where the real you might be.
The true you.
A light and consistent stroke
over the forehead...
From temple to temple...
Relaxes the patient.
Ok.
No, I act--I actually don't know
if this is right for me.
I mean, I'm only here
because of my wife.
Uh, no offense, I'm just not,
I just don't believe
in hypnosis.
How about we do this,
how about we just pretend,
I'll pay you,
and we'll pretend
that I'm making progress.
- I don't need your money.
I didn't mean to offend you.
- I'm not offended.
I'm just sad.
Uh, I'm here on earth
to help people.
- (Sighs) Well, thank you
for coming.
Would you mind if I uh...
If I took off?
-Shh.
[Bird squawks]
We're done.
I just want to thank you two
for being so supportive.
It's kind of been a rough time.
A lot of stress at work.
- It has been, it's been a crazy
couple of weeks at work.
- Well, we love seeing you guys.
And Bobby just, you know,
he loves to cook.
-Oh, I do. I do.
- Oh, mom, don't. Mom...
Mom: Mm, oh, oh...
Oh...That is not the spiciest
dish at the table.
[Duncan laughs] Yeah.
Well, thank you so much
for the food, Bobby.
- Duncan?
- Yeah?
- You can call me dad.
Or daddy.
- No. I don't need to.
- Papa.
- Bobby is good with me.
- You know what?
Don't call me daddy.
That's reserved
for somebody else.
[Doorbell rings]
[Stomach growls]
That must be our special guest.
- Special guest?
- (Whispering) I don't know
what she's talking about.
- Dunkie. I kind of imagine
what it must be like for you.
Growing up without a male
to look up to.
To know what males
should act like.
Every now and then
it's a little obvious.
- Mom: Everybody.
- Sort of...Girlie.
- This is Dr. Lawrence tip,
and he runs the tip center
for fertility.
- That's right. And we're doing
really well.
Duncan, I presume?
- Yeah. Yes.
- I've heard a lot about you.
Are--are you two planning
on having a baby?
- (Chuckles) Oh, heavens no.
- Not the way we do it.
(Duncan sighs)
- So Duncan,
your mother here tells me
that you guys are having
a little trouble conceiving.
- No. No, no, no, no, no.
- No.
- Sweetie, Sarah is ready.
So if your little guys
are slow swimmers,
maybe something can be done.
- Wow. Beatrice, I feel like
I may have mislead you
because that is not
an issue that we're having.
- Duncan, if you have a problem
with erectile dysfunction,
I can help you with that.
- Look, I just thought there
might be a problem
your father had a problem
in that department.
- I just thought...
- I don't, I don't...
Need to know about any of that.
- Honey, sometimes we have to
hear things
we don't want to hear.
- It's a common affliction,
Duncan.
A lot of men have it.
[Chuckles] Not me, of course.
I'm a very virile man.
- Me neither. Very super virile.
- I don't know you well enough
for this to feel comfortable
with me.
- Bobby, thank you so much
for this delicious food.
- If you want, Duncan, I can
set up an examination.
- I don't.
- Would you?
- In fact, maybe I can take
a look tonight while I'm here.
- That would be perfect!
- See if there's a response
to a stimulus.
- Are you the one
doing the stimulating?
- That's correct, yes.
And size has nothing
to do with it.
Don't be bashful.
- He's right. You know, I mean,
we don't have that problem.
- No.
- We have the opposite problem.
- I mean, we have to
really take it slow.
- Honey, no one cares about
the size of your Willie.
I've seen it, it's beautiful.
It's way above average.
The point is progeny.
We want grandkids.
- In other words,
there's more than one way
to choke a chicken.
- Uh, wow, that's...
- [Cell phone rings]
That's something to think about.
Oh, look at that. It's work.
I'm gonna have to take this.
Yeah, hello?
Alistair: Hey, cubie,
how's it going?
Two things, first of all,
the toilets
do not work properly.
- Uh-huh.
I've looked into the Murphy
report on your computer,
- you're using my computer?
- Yes, and the good news is,
I found it.
The bad news is,
I think I may have deleted
something important.
- You what?
[Stomach growls]
- Yeah, it was a folder called
"board of directors
presentation."
- What? Are you fucking
kidding me?
I've been working on that
for a year.
Oh, my God. This is bad.
- Honestly, I was flustered
by the toilet situation.
I called the janitor.
That's going to be better.
That will--
- whatever, whatever.
Whatever. I'll come in tonight.
I'll take care of it.
- Bye.
[Stomach growling
as Duncan groans]
Fuck, fuck, fuck...
Oh, God.
[Farting]
[Bathroom sounds]
[Bathroom sounds continue]
Duncan: Oh...
Oh...
Did you know that the leading
cause of divorce is children?
- That's not true.
That is just what children
believe in their hearts.
- Kids are a huge
responsibility.
It's just a stressful thing,
honey.
I don't know if I can do it
right now.
- Ok, look, I didn't say that
I wanted to have a kid today.
I don't need to have a kid
tomorrow.
- Ok, good because tomorrow
I have plans.
I gotta go see the doctor.
I gotta get the car washed.
Honestly, so if you're planning
on popping out a kid,
I just don't think it's an
appropriate day to do it.
[Sarah chuckles]
I'm just saying that...
I want to have a family,
and I want to have a family
with you.
- I know. I want to have
a baby, too.
I just...[Sighs]
Phil put me in charge
of layoffs.
Today.
Why did you agree to that?
(Chuckles) What am I gonna say?
- All you have to really do
is just say no.
[Chuckles] It's just,
it's not a great time
to make big changes right now.
Can we just let things
settle down a little bit?
- Ok.
- Yeah?
- All right.
- I'm sorry.
[Stomach growling
what is going on down there?
- Awful things.
God awful things.
- Oh, my God.
That is the worst smell I have
ever smelled in my life.
[Bathroom sounds]
Sarah: Honey? Is this gonna
be more of a 5 minute deal,
or a half hour deal?
- Uh,go to bed, honey.
I have to go back
to the office anyway.
Don't wait up for me.
Ok, be safe in there.
Don't rip anything.
I love you.
- Good night.
- Ok.
[Bathroom sounds]
[Duncan yelps]
[Duncan screams]
[Duncan groans loudly]
[Duncan continues groaning]
[Bathroom sounds]
[Duncan groaning and moaning]
[Duncan groaning and yelling]
[Stomach growling]
[Duncan groaning and straining]
[Stomach growls
and Duncan screaming]
[Thud and glass breaking]
[Muffled growling
and water splashing]
[Panting]
[Panting and muffled growling]
[Panting noise]
[Alistair screams]
[Muttering and chattering]
[Sputtering]
[Groans]
Hey.
[Stomach growls]
Are you ok?
- Yeah. Just uh, slept funny.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Did I tell you
what happened yesterday?
Samantha's pregnant.
Can you believe it?
And not only that,
they went down to city hall
and got married yesterday,
and they didn't even tell me
until after the fact.
- Oh.
- So crazy, she's my last friend
that I ever, ever, ever thought
would have kids,
but she has health insurance now
that she's pregnant...
Television: The body
of alistair McGee
was discovered earlier this
morning by maintenance crews.
McGee died from massive
blood loss
sometime during the evening.
that the injuries
were sustained
by what appears to be
an animal attack.
Experts say it could've
been a rabid raccoon.
- What?
- That's alistair.
- Who's alistair?
- My cubie.
Television: ...Focus of
a recent sec investigation
in response to charges
of corporate fraud.
Can you imagine
what happened in there?
It must have been terrifying.
Phil: You're late.
- What the hell happened?
- I'm not sure.
Some kind of animal
attacked alistair last night.
Animal control says it was
probably a rabid raccoon.
- Yeah, that's what they said
on the news.
- It's super freaky.
I got somebody checking out
my office right now.
Listen, at least you don't
have to fire him.
Bonus.
Here's how we're gonna play it.
I just want you to be straight
with them.
You're gonna give them
the package,
when you walk in, you're gonna
see the folder...
- You--you want me
to do this now?
You want to fire this guy today?
- You'll do fine.
- What about Jill?
Jill is great for something
like this
because she's big,
she's intimidating, she's tough.
- I don't want tough.
I want nice.
I want gentle.
- Oh.
I want you.
So clean and quick, and then
I'll send in the next guy.
And if he doesn't break out
an ak47, we all win.
Hey, hey, look what I can do?
You know, it's times like these
it...It's difficult
to bounce back.
So we're, we're giving you this,
and the severance package
is...Not much...
- I mean the meat of it
is the thank you.
- You mean like a, a note
that just says...Thanks?
- Yeah. That's bad.
- It's not much, abaloosh...
- I'll be back.
- I'm sorry?
- My name is abalash.
- It's spelled like it's
abaloosh.
- Really?
Really?
- It's dumb that we have those
in there.
Barry thought it would be a...
A laugh in a...
In a stressful situation. I...
Said at the time,
that's not a good idea.
Give those back.
I don't know why
somebody would...
That's completely...
Inappropriate.
Good job, bro.
That's it for today.
- Today? I have to do more
of this?
You gotta remember what you're
doing is a good thing.
- It's horrible.
- But...It's fulfilling.
[Duncan sighs]
[Stomach growls]
Dr. tip: Hi Duncan,
it's Dr. tip calling
from the center for fertility.
Look, I'm gonna level with you,
you've got a smoking hot wife,
and you're moping around
with a wet noodle.
You don't get her pregnant
soon, somebody else will.
- Come on.
- Be a man and ask for help.
Call me.
- How is this guy a doctor?
- All right. Let's uh...
Let's see here.
There you go.
So far...So good.
Uh...No.
That's strange.
I'm in the right...Hold on.
Huh...Huh huh huh huh.
Where are you?
Yula, can you hold the chart up
for me?
Ha! That is strange.
I'm right in the right spot,
and there's no polyp in here.
I'm right there.
I'm right in the neighborhood.
I'm knocking...
But no one's home.
Jesus!
[Demon growls]
[Nurse screams]
[Doctor and nurse screaming]
What the fuck.
[Sarah snores]
I hon--I honestly, I didn't
know where to go.
I mean, it was just
a weird night.
I mean, I had this
horrible dream.
And the guy I work with
was killed by a rabid raccoon.
- What?
I woke up in the bathroom,
and I didn't know what happened.
- What do you want me to do?
- I want you to hypnotize me.
Fantastic.
In your own time,
please tell me,
what you see.
I'm standing in front
of an office building.
It's where I work.
- Can you tell me
about your work?
- It's a financial services
company.
It's not very fulfilling.
And lately, it's been stressful.
Very...[Stomach growls]
Very stressful.
- Are you alone?
- No. I'm with my mother.
- And where is your father?
- My father's not there.
- Why?
- My parents divorced
when I was 8.
Bird: [Squawks]
Abandonment issues.
[Squawks] Abandonment issues.
- I'll clip your wings.
[Duncan's stomach growls]
Go on.
Sarah?
- And Sarah's there?
- She's...Right over there.
On the grass.
- And what does Sarah want?
- I know what she wants.
She wants a family.
And I just don't know if I...
[Stomach growls]
Know if I'll ever be a good...
Good dad.
I know, I know, I know
it will make you happy.
But I don't--I just want to wait
to have a kid.
My mother hired this asshole
fertility doctor.
Oh, my God. Aah!
[Stomach growling loudly]
[Duncan screams and moans]
[Duncan screams]
[Duncan screams
and material rips]
Hey! Just hold it right there.
Stay right there.
You hear me? Whoa!
No! No! No! No!
[Demon growls]
Mr. hayslip...
I'm going to count down from 3
down to 1.
And when I reach 1,
you're gonna wake up.
Do you understand?
3, 2, aah!!!
Get off!
1!
[Duncan screams
and demon growls]
What is that?
[Duncan screams]
[Doctor screams]
[All stop screaming]
[Car horns blare]
Oh, he's gone.
- It just went out the window.
[Car horns blare]
Wow.
How's your ass?
This might help.
And this.
I should've spotted it
when you first walked in.
- My life is over.
- It's in the eyes.
Always in the eyes. Sorry.
- What the fuck are you
talking about?
It's not in the eyes.
That thing came out of my ass.
It was ins--
- shh.
- What do we do?
- Just wait. Wait.
- Wait, what? For what?
For somebody to snap their
fingers and wake me up?
Cause my life is over. Did
I mention that my life is over?
I'm gonna just go home
to my wife.
And oh, my God, Sarah.
Hey, Sarah, I'm home.
Guess what.
I have an alien in my ass.
- There is...This ancient myth.
Surrounding...The anus.
Here it is. Look at this.
The myth of our anus.
You see, before religion became
the primary focus
of our society,
there was a beautiful time
where mythology
and legends filled our beings.
- What does this have to do
with me?
- Listen, I believe that this
very same creature
came out of your anus
and attacked your co-worker.
- Alistair?
When you're pushed into a corner
by someone,
this creature comes out
and attacks that someone.
In this case, it was me.
Look here.
My ass, I got bitten. (Laughs)
- What if I have more
inside of me?
- Well, if that's the case,
we have to kill this thing.
- No, no, no.
You're missing the point.
This thing is a part of you.
Don't you understand.
It's your sub conscious.
It's your raw desires.
No, I didn't mean
to hurt alistair.
I don't want to hurt anybody.
[Making ape sounds]
We're still apes, hayslip.
Don't you understand?
Maybe you didn't want to hurt
him in here.
But I think you wanted
to hurt him in here.
And in here.
If you kill it,
you're gonna kill
a very important part
of yourself.
You see, that fear, worry
and anger
are essential
to the human beings
as long as we can control them.
And use them to our advantage.
My mentor always told me,
stop carrying the horse
on your shoulders.
Put him between your legs,
and ride him!
- What are you--
what are you talking about?
- It's a metaphor.
- I had a monster up my ass!
This is the furthest thing
from a metaphor!
Listen! If you kill it,
it would be just like giving
yourself a lobotomy.
You will become a zombie.
This creature is a physical
manifestation of your dark side.
- What?
- You gotta accept this.
Accept it.
Take it to yourself.
Bond with it.
That's your only way
to control it.
But listen to me,
the most important thing now,
when it returns,
and it will return,
- will?
It will try to get
back inside of you.
- What? What? What?
- Yeah. It will try to get
inside of you.
- No.
- Of course.
- Before it does,
you have to bond with it.
Ok?
- All right.
Let me get this straight.
- Hmm.
- You want me to bond with it?
And if I do, you're saying
there's a very good chance
that it won't hurt anybody else?
Hopefully. (Chuckles)
So now what?
We wait.
[Woman moaning]
Oh, God. Oh, oh, God. Oh...
[Woman moans]
Oh, God...
Oh...Wow.
They teach you that
in medical school?
Sort of. So uh...
My turn now?
Oh. I don't do that.
You're being serious?
- Yes. But you got my number.
So call me.
(Sighing)
All right, Larry.
It's just us out here.
Here we go.
Focus.
[Breathing heavily]
[Glass breaks and cat hisses]
Brittany?
Change your mind?
[Crash]
Hello?
Brittany?
Don't be a little bitch.
[Doctor screams]
[Harmonica plays]
[Alien humming]
Hayslip! Hayslip, hayslip.
Hayslip. Wake up.
Wake up. Wake up!
Hey! Hey!
- What?
- There.
- There. It's back.
- W-w-what do you want me to do?
- Go over there.
- No.
- It belongs to you.
Please, please.
Remember. Bond with it.
[Alien muttering]
- Ok, ok, ok. Just give me a--
- shh...
- Time, I can't just--
- keep your voice down.
[Alien muttering]
- Doctor: Careful. Careful.
- If this thing comes at me,
I want you to hit it
with a chair.
- No, no. It won't attack you.
He's a part of you.
- Hey. Hey, boy.
- It's bleeding.
I think it might be hurt.
- Bond with it.
- Hey...Milo.
[Alien mutters]
- Doctor: Milo?
- Sarah likes that name.
- I had a much better name.
[Alien mutters]
- You scared?
You look scared.
Yeah, I'm scared, too.
Doctor: Let him back in you.
You know, he wants to come home.
- Yeah. I-I can't. I can't.
- Well, somehow, he slipped
his way out of you.
And I'm sure he knows how to
slip into you again.
Don't you think?
- It's too fucking big.
- Please don't cuss
in front of him.
- Come on. It's too big.
- Big, fat babies come out of
tiny vaginas.
Maybe your anus is just like
a vagina.
[Unzips pants
and unbuckles belt]
Come on, Milo.
[Whistling]
Come on home.
Door's open.
Ok, come on.
Aah! Nails, nails, nails, nails.
Aah! Ow!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Aah!
[Milo struggling]
[Duncan yells]
- Good.
- God! [Duncan crying]
- Duncan, breathe, breathe.
- I'm trying to breathe.
It's very difficult.
[Duncan screams]
Don't push. Don't push.
- I'm not doing anything.
Let it...Uh-uh. Yes.
Oh...
He's up there.
- It was beautiful.
- Yeah. And humiliating.
- You have to learn
one thing now.
To control Milo.
You get stressed out,
Milo comes.
And ruins somebody's day.
- Oh, yeah.
Right.
- From now on, you gotta learn
to breathe.
Relax.
Now if you feel an episode
coming on,
try some yoga or green tea.
But nothing mind altering.
No drugs. No alcohol.
And absolutely no dairy.
And you can call me anytime.
I'm there for you.
[Duncan struggling]
Breathe, breathe.
Dr. tip: This thing
is a part of you.
If you kill it,
it will be
like giving yourself
a lobotomy.
You would become a zombie.
You've gotta learn to breathe.
Relax...
Relax.
Oh, shit...
- Duncan.
- Oh, good morning.
- Any idea why Eric Paulson
would've made 6 frantic phone
calls before 9am?
- What?
- He wants to know why his
account has been zeroed out.
- Wait, back up.
Who did what to who and what?
- Zero. Gone.
- What?
- Yeah.
What? Huh...
All right. Slow down.
What happened?
- I don't know. I don't know.
and it looks like his holdings
have been sold,
and then everything was just
dumped into tectonic pipeline.
- Tectonic is junk.
- No, I know.
I haven't spoken to him
in two weeks.
I mean everything was fine
a few days ago.
- Duncan, this is your account.
It's your responsibility.
- I know. Of course. Of course.
I know. I-I--
- ok. Hold on. Just, hold on.
Let's think about this
for a second.
- Ok.
I want you to dip into
our employee pension fund.
And cover the Paulson losses.
- What?
- We gotta borrow from Peter
to pay Paulson.
Unless you got a better idea.
Right, that doesn't,
you can't, I can't...
I can't transfer accounts...
Because...
Highly illegal.
[Phil laughs]
No, this is your account,
Duncan.
It was your responsibility
to maintain it,
and uh, something happened
that happened on your watch.
[Stomach growling]
Yeah... yeah.
Ok. Keep it under your hat.
And we'll be all right.
Ok. [Stomach growls]
Hey. Team player.
(Under his breath)
Yeah. Team player.
[Cell phone rings]
- Hey.
- Doctor: Hayslip.
Have you seen the news?
It's all over the television.
Milo's making a name
for himself.
- Oh, no.
- Get over to my office quick.
We gotta take decisive action
before Milo strikes again.
Oh, boy. Oh, this is bad.
Oh, this is so bad.
This is so bad.
I mean, I don't want to hurt
anybody.
I didn't want to hurt anybody.
I mean the guy was a dick.
Yeah, sure. I wouldn't--
I didn't want him to die.
I didn't want that.
- Events are moving fast,
and we're way behind.
-Oh, this is bad.
- We usually wait until remains
are more private.
But I'm left no choice.
I have to break out
the big guns.
[Bird squawks]
We're talking about
sock puppets.
- No. No, no, no, no.
They are real people now.
Maybe you and I
are sock puppets to them.
- Right.
Hey, honey.
So what's for dinner?
[Sarah's voice]
Kung pao chicken
- but that upsets my stomach.
[Sarah's voice]
Well, we have tons of leftovers.
So take it or leave it.
[Doctor laughs]
You got her, didn't you?
- Yeah, sometimes it, sometimes
it you know because...
- You can tell her.
- She's insensitive to my
feelings.
But why do you keep it inside?
It's better to tell her.
- Ok.
- Don't turn your back.
- No.
- Keep it inside.
- Yeah. You know, honey,
it's just my stomach,
I have a very sensitive stomach.
[Sarah's voice] Oh, again with
the goddamn stomach.
- Hey, knock it off all right.
Again with your stupid,
stupid voice.
Hey, I hate you, dad.
I hate you!
Shut up and eat your
goddamn dinner, son!
- Hold it.
Oh...My...God.
Do you hear what you just said?
You said dad.
- No, no, I didn't.
- Where's your dad?
Where's your dad right now?
I-I-I have no idea.
Last I heard,
he lives in a shack.
Kind of off the grid.
- Listen to me, your fears
and all the anxiety
even this Milo,
they all share a nexus.
Rooted with your father.
[Duncan's stomach growls]
You have to find him.
Radio: She had scratches
all over her body.
And had to be rushed
to the hospital.
She spoke to Peter brookings
about her frightening
experience.
Peter, you don't hear a lot
about raccoon attacks.
In fact, I can't ever
think of one this serious.
Dad?
Hello.
[Cans crashing]
[Sitar music playing]
Man's voice:
My body is clean.
My mind is clean.
I am beautiful.
Inside and out.
My body is a temple.
And I keep my temple clean.
I sweep the pillars
of my temple.
I shower my mind.
- Dad?
[Coughing]
- Hey.
[Dad coughing]
What are you doing in there?
[Coughing]
Meditating. [Coughs]
- Dad. Wait a second. Dad? Dad!
Dad, I need to talk to you
about something.
Something that's...
Been happening.
- Uh...I don't do that.
- You don't do what?
- I don't analyze,
I don't project.
There's only the now.
- Well, what I need
to talk to you about
is happening now.
- No. You're here to lay blame.
You did it last time we talked,
but the past has no audience
with me.
This is it, son.
- No. This isn't it, dad.
This isn't it.
There's some stuff that happened
before the now.
Like the fact that you haven't
remembered my birthday
since I was 10.
- Or the fact that you don't
even remember my wife's name.
Do you remember my wife's name?
- Grace.
- No.
- Do you even think about me?
Do you wonder if I'm ok?
- I don't know. You seem ok.
I mean nobody's stabbing you in
the eye with a fork right now.
Not that I can see.
- Yeah, well, shit's fucked up
right now, dad.
- Shit is as fucked up
as you allow it to be.
Namaste.
[Duncan's stomach growls]
Oh, that's very sound advice.
Great. No, I'll take that
from my pretentious, loser,
pot head dad
who doesn't give a shit about
anybody but himself.
- I take this as prescribed.
- Yeah, why don't you go
medicate some more.
[Duncan groaning]
Just hold that thought.
Hold that thought.
[Duncan screams]
Ok. I'm letting you out,
I'm letting you out.
I'm letting you out,
but we're gonna talk.
We're gonna talk, ok?
[Duncan screams]
You're all right.
[Milo muttering]
Oh, shit. Oh, shh shh shh
shh shh shh.
Come on. I let you out.
I let you out.
So let's,
let's talk about this ok?
I don't want you to kill my dad.
I don't want that.
No, no, no, no, no.
Stop it, stop it,
stop it, stop it!
No! Don't! Bad! Bad!
Shit! Get off me!
Get off! Get off!
Stop it! I know!
I know he's a dick.
I know, I know. He's wrong.
But please, don't...
Eat my father.
No matter how I'm feeling.
[Milo growls]
Are you hungry? Huh?
Are you hungry?
I don't have anything here.
But I have something
at the office.
I have a lot of food
So why don't you crawl...
Crawl back inside me.
Crawl back inside.
[Duncan whimpers]
[Milo muttering]
Good boy. Good Milo.
[Duncan whimpers]
Wow.
Stomach flu?
Well, I hope you're not relying
on Western medicine to cure you.
- Listen, dad.
I'm sort of doing this...
Therapy thing.
And I'm seeing this guy,
and it's actually been helping.
And could, would you just
listen to me for a second?
I think that maybe if you and I
went in,
and we talked to him together,
that maybe we can
deal with this.
- I can't. I'm sorry, Duncan.
Just I can't, I...Can't.
- You can't.
- Yeah.
I can't tell you anything else.
That's, that's the size of it.
Yeah. Ok.
Maybe I expected too much.
- Yeah. I guess you did.
Woman: What's that smell?
[Elevator rings]
Oh, oh, oh, oh, food.
Food it's coming, just, aah!
Food, food.
Oh, fuck...
Yeah. I'm sorry...About this.
Here it is. A little mousey.
[Smacks lips] Come on.
It's good eats.
It's a good source of protein.
Come on, Milo. Just grab it.
- Duncan, you better
get out here.
What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Look at you. You're a mess.
What happened to you?
- [Chuckles] Oh...
- Is that poop on your shirt?
- It's a stomach flu.
- Uh-huh. Well, there's
federal agents out here.
It's looking pretty serious.
- What's that?
- We got federal agents.
Come on.
- All right, yeah.
I'll be right behind you.
I'm coming out.
- Button your pants.
[Milo growling and chewing]
Do not shut down your computer.
Do not touch anything.
These documents are now the
property of the U.S. government.
Ma'am, please step away
from your desk.
Sir, do not turn off
your computers.
Step away from your desk please.
- What's going on?
- I don't know what's going on.
Where's Phil?
Agent: Please step away
from your desk, sir.
Phil, Phil, Phil!
What the hell's going on
out there?
Uh, that uh, government seizure
of institutional assets,
freezing of accounts.
That sort of thing.
- No, no, no. I can see that.
Why?
Shit Duncan, don't worry about
it. It doesn't concern you.
- No, no. What about
our investments?
Our employee investments.
Our retirement accounts.
- God, I hate to be the one
to break it to you,
but I think those accounts
are probably all zeroed out
by now.
It sucks. I know.
- You were talking about
upper management.
You were talking
all that stuff about
employees being our clients,
that's what,
you were saying those things.
- Gee.
- What about your money?
What about your money?
- Come on, d. You don't think
I was stupid enough
to invest here. Fuck no.
I'm good. You, you got no
poker face.
You're a pussy.
In this world of ours,
pussies don't excel.
If you want to survive,
you gotta take a dump
on your enemies.
Or else, you're the one eating
the shit sandwich.
Now if you will please
remove your hand.
Hey, Phil.
[Material ripping
and Duncan groans]
What the fuck is that?
- Fuck you, Phil.
[Phil screams and Milo growls]
Operator: 911.
What's your emergency?
- H-h-hello. I'd like to
report a...
Another raccoon attack.
Sarah: Duncan?
Are you ok? What happened?
- Oh, my God, Sarah. Oh, my God.
The FBI, uh...
- What do you mean the FBI?
What are--what's going on?
- These guys came.
These FBI guys came into...
The uh, office,
and they said everything
was the property
of the government's.
- Phil said that all our
accounts are gone.
- What do you mean
all the accounts are gone?
- Everything. He stole
everything.
He stole everything.
- We have no savings.
- Oh, my God.
It's all gone [Screams]
- Oh, my God, Duncan.
- I know.
I know. I know.
- I'm pregnant.
[Duncan strains and moans]
Duncan...Duncan.
I'm pregnant.
Since when?
- Just, I just found out.
I was feeling,
I was feeling weird,
and I missed my period,
so I, I took a test.
Why, why didn't you,
why didn't you tell me this?
- I just told you. I just--
why didn't you tell me before?
- I just found out, Duncan.
I just took the test.
- No. We said we were going
to wait.
We said we were gonna wait.
Did you plan this?
I mean, did you do this on,
did you do this on purpose?
- Can you hear yourself
right now?
Did I do this on purpose?
No, I didn't do this on purpose.
I wouldn't trick you.
I don't know how it happened.
I'm on the pill.
I-I don't know,
but I'm pregnant.
[Stomach growls]
- I'm sorry, honey.
I'm just having
really, really, really
really, really bad day.
- Ok. I need you right now.
So please tell me that
everything is gonna be ok.
- Yeah, everything is gonna
be fine, baby.
Oh, my God.
- What?
[Stomach growls]
- Oh, God!
- Are you sick?
Do I need to call a doctor?
[Sputtering] I'm fine.
I'm perfectly fine.
I'm just gonna live in the now.
Right in the now.
No, I don't need anything.
I don't work,
and I don't need this house,
and I--
- Duncan.
- So um, you know,
I can just walk away and...
[Stomach growls]
In fact,
that's what I'm going to do
because it's safer for you.
- Duncan, I need you.
Don't walk away from me.
- I just, I have to rise
above it, you know,
and I can't deal with this.
I can't deal with this.
So um...
- Duncan, where are you going?
Duncan!
[Milo muttering]
Come on.
It's ok. It's ok.
It's just you and me, buddy.
It's just you and me.
[Sniffing]
[Knock on door]
Maid: Housekeeping!
No, no, we're, no, we're good.
Thank you.
[Duncan speaks spanish] Gracias.
No. Don't even think about it.
I will shove you right back
up my ass.
Milo: No!
Duncan: Yeah!
Television: Please don't
make me angry.
You wouldn't like me
when I'm angry.
Eat it.
Television:
May have entered
through the
ventilation system
and security guards have--
[Milo groans and mutters]
Television: Security guards
Mothers and daughters
have been notified.
[Milo mutters
and can crashes to floor]
Television: I don't love you
anymore.
- Look me in the eyes. Look me
in the eyes when you say that.
[Milo growling and cans
crashing to the floor]
Milo.
Dick move.
Dick move, Milo.
Sarah's voice:
Duncan where are you?
Are you coming to your parents'
party tonight?
I really wish that you would
talk to me.
I've left you so many messages.
I'll be at your parents' party
if you want to talk.
Hey. Dad.
Um, I'm in trouble.
I know. I know.
I promise
I will leave you alone.
Just do this one thing for me.
Just this one thing.
We're here today to put to rest
some of the issues that have
plagued Duncan
since you, let's say
parted from him.
- Uh-uh, I don't, I don't
agree with this.
I shouldn't be here.
I should be living in the now.
Not wasting it on the was.
- Well, Roger,
since you are here,
now...
Is it ok if Duncan can start?
Please.
- Sure.
- Why?
- Thank you. I told you
I don't do this.
- You don't do what? I mean,
why are you here
if you don't do it,
why are you here?
- I'm here because you asked me
to be here.
And if you want to,
you want to know why
things turned out like they did.
Did it for your own good.
- I was never, ever, ever
gonna be a good dad.
- You didn't even try.
You didn't even try.
- You don't know all the ways
that I might have
laid down if I'd stayed.
You don't--your mother.
She was good.
She was a good woman.
In spite of a few things.
But uh, if anyone was gonna
raise you right,
it was gonna be her.
- Yeah, but I needed a dad.
Ok? I could've used you.
I needed you.
I needed you ro-Roger.
- One step at a time.
- It's fine. I got it.
- Yeah.
- I needed you. Aah! Oh, no.
- Breathe.
- No, no, no, no.
No, no, Milo, no!
- No, Milo.
- Control it. Control it.
Hold it back.
Duncan: No!!
[Duncan screams]
Please, no.
Please, please...
- Jesus.
Oh, shit.
No!
Ralph! Ralph! No. No, Ralph.
- Ralph?
Milo, Milo, Milo, no!
- No!
[Glass crashes]
Doctor: Duncan!
Duncan, tell him to stop!
He's...He's...
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Ow!
Milo! Milo, stop it!
[Roger screams]
Dad!
Oh...I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm, I'm sorry I wasn't
there for you.
- Milo, stop it!
- I made a mistake.
- Dad. Dad, dad, dad, it's ok.
- I should've been there
to help you, and I wasn't there.
- No, no, no, no.
- I know you think your life's
falling apart, but it isn't.
No, no, no, dad. Don't worry
about it. Don't worry about it.
- Milo!
- Sarah. Sarah's pregnant.
That's good.
- Sarah's pregnant.
- Yeah.
- You believe me?
- I do.
- Dad?
Dad.
[Glass breaks]
Oh, shit.
- Sarah. He's going after Sarah.
- I'll take care of him. Go!
- Go to her. Go to her. Go.
- Go to Sarah.
I'll take care of him.
- Just go.
- Go! Go!
Milo!
Oh. Milo, you little fucker.
[Music plays]
Bobby: Be a doctor, but I always
liked cell phones, you know?
He didn't invest, and now I'm
making more than him.
Every year.
- Just don't worry about uh,
Duncan and the baby.
He'll get used to the idea.
He's gonna come around.
He's an only child. He's not
used to other kids around.
[Cell phone buzzes]
Hi, it's Sarah.
Leave me a message,
and I'll call you back.
- Shit!
[Phone beeps and rings]
Ma, pick up the phone.
Everybody's changing
and adjusting,
and it's gonna take
a little while.
[Telephone rings]
That's all. Oh, speaking
of the devil.
It's Duncan's phone.
Hi, sweetie.
- Aah--
- hello? Hello?
Help!
Fuck!
- Probably a butt call.
- What--did he say anything?
- No.
Butt call.
- You're in the middle
of the road, jackass!
[Milo growling and muttering]
Sarah? Sarah!
- Oh, my God, Duncan.
What happened to you?
- Good. You're ok.
- Oh!
- Go down to the basement.
Right now.
- What? No, you can't just
come in here
and order me around
after what you did.
- Honey, you're bleeding.
What happened?
- Please, honey.
Just do what I said.
Just go down to the basement
and lock the door.
Just lock the door.
- Uh, I, it's cluttered
down there.
I-I wouldn't go there.
[Milo panting]
- What is it?
- Shit!
- Oh, my God! What is that?
- Now! Do it!
[Mother screams]
- Do it! Go!
[Mother screams] Bobby!
Quick, everybody!
Get away from the house.
- Another raccoon attack?
- No, honey.
This isn't a raccoon.
- Sarah?
I love you.
- I love you, too.
- Hurry!
[Breathing heavily]
Oh, my God.
What is it? What is it?
Oh...
Fuck!
God damn it! Fuck!
Milo! Stop it!
[Milo screams]
Did you leave the TV on?
- No. It's not the TV.
- Should we be worried?
I'm worried.
Oh, oh, quick,
grab a tiki torch!
- Ok, ok, ok. Tiki.
[Screaming]
[Glass crashes]
Come on out here!
You just come out, you chicken!
I don't think it's a chicken.
- No!
[Glass crashes]
Milo! Milo! Stop!
She's gone. She's not here.
She's not here. She's not here.
You're not gonna find her.
[Milo muttering] Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
A lot of people
leave things behind
when, when they leave
in a hurry.
I do it all the time.
I-I leave my wallet home
all the time.
If I'm in a rush.
Sarah: Duncan,
is everything ok?
[Screams]
Stop. Ok?
Because I will jab this
in your fucking eye.
And I don't want to.
I'm not gonna let you hurt her.
All right?
No, no, Milo.
It's not gonna happen.
Do you understand?
Why don't you just, why don't
you just come back home.
I'm not gonna...
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Why don't we just go back--
why don't we go back
to the way things used to be?
Ok? What do you say, pal?
Come on.
[Milo screams]
- Milo?
No! No! Milo!
[Drain gurgles]
[Clanking in drain]
[Sarah screams]
- Sarah!
- Duncan!
- Open the door!
- Oh! Oh, my God!
- Sarah! Open the door!
- I can't!
- Stay away from her, Milo!
- Who's Milo?
- Uh, it, it's a thing that's
living up my ass.
- What?
- Never mind. It doesn't matter.
- Duncan!
- I'm coming!
Sarah: Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- No! No!
Oh, my God!
Sarah: Duncan!
- Sarah, I'm coming!
I'm coming, Sarah!
- Duncan!
Duncan! Help!
- Don't you hurt her!
Sarah! Open the door!
- I can't. [Sarah screams]
- Sarah! Sarah!
Sarah!
I'm coming, Sarah!
I'm coming, baby!
Milo, get away from her!
[Axe hacking at door]
I'm coming!
Sarah, wake up! Wake up!
Sarah, run! Sarah, run!
Sarah! Get behind me!
Get behind me! Get behind me!
Oh, honey. Look at you.
Are you ok?
Duncan is still down there.
He's fighting it.
Milo!
[Group screams]
Stay back! Stay back!
- Oh, my God. What is that?
Get it with the fire.
Put the fire in the face!
- Milo!
- Duncan!
Get away from my wife!
[Milo screams]
Get away from my baby!
Not my, I'm not my father.
[Milo screams]
I'm gonna be sick.
- Honey, honey.
Are you all right?
- I'm ok. I'm ok. I'm ok.
I'm ok. Are you ok?
- I'm fine.
- Is the baby ok?
- It's ok.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's ok. It's ok.
It's all right. You matter.
[Milo whimpers]
Oh, wow. I fucked you up.
It's ok. You're gonna be
all right.
I'm sorry.
Can-can-can I borrow that?
Your scarf?
Thank you.
Just a minute. I'm gonna
wrap you up, ok?
Is that better?
Papa.
Bobby: What the hell?
He's its father?
- It looks like him.
- It's ok.
Man: I've never seen it before.
- Yeah, yeah.
I know. You were just doing that
for me. I know.
I'll get you inside, ok?
It's all right.
It's gonna be ok now.
Hey, everybody.
How's the party?
- Honey, I'm so sorry I didn't
tell you about this.
I-I just figured it would end
with your dad.
- You knew?
- Ish. I mean,
I knew it happened to him,
but I, I didn't know
it happened to you.
It was hereditary or anything,
-That's why I gave you all the
holistic things. I thought...
You know, the stomach issues,
I don't know, honey.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
- It's ok, mom.
It's fine. We're gonna use
your bathroom.
- Probably not gonna
clean it up.
- Ok.
- Oh...
Ok. It's a very long story
of which I'm happy to tell you
all about.
Um, but first, who would like
a drink?
- Do you have any weed?
- Ok, be right back.
- Do I really have to put it
back inside you?
- Yeah. He's...
He's part of me.
- He's not gonna try
and hurt you?
- No.
He's all right now.
Ok.
- How is this gonna work?
I mean how, how is he gonna fit?
Oh, it'll, it'll work,
trust me.
There you go.
[Milo muttering]
Are you like turning him?
- I, he's kind of turning
on his own.
Ok. It's his thing. It's just...
He's probably mad.
- I just gotta get him that last
half inch.
- Ok.
- ...In there.
[Both] 1, 2, and 3.
That's it. He's up.
He's up there. Ok.
[Sighs] Thanks.
- Thank you.
- I love you.
I love you, too.
Duncan:
You know what we're gonna do?
I want to take a moment
and talk about family.
You have a wife,
you have a husband.
And you want the best for them.
You want to take a risk
with that person.
You're in it together.
Whether you're buying a car
or a house,
or starting a family.
We need to bring honesty.
We need to bring courage.
To our business
relationships,
and to our...
Personal relationships.
And not one of us
does it alone.
We draw upon our resources.
Upon our friends.
Upon our colleagues.
We're a team.
- Oh, my goodness!
I want to know what's going on
with you.
What's going on inside of you.
That's important to me.
Because we all have
difficulties, trials.
Tribulations.
Even demons we struggle with
on a daily basis.
- Oh, honey. Honey.
- No one should suffer alone.
- Blessed by the monk.
We're here for each other.
We're like family.
- One for you.
And that's what I want
for this company.
That's how I want this company
to be run.
Nobody knows what the future
has in store.
But I do know this...
Whatever problems do come up,
we'll get through it.
Together.
[Humming and muttering]
Precision creative services
www.Precision-creative.Com
ask me about my stomach
in baby talk, ok?
- No.
- [Duncan laughs]
- Ok, I'm sorry.
Director: Action.
- Dunkie, times are very
troubles [Laughs]
- Ok.
- Good, good. Very good.
- Dunkie. Having
some married troubles?
- What--are you talking
baby talk to me?
- These are standard family
dynamics.
- What is?
- These are standard
family dynamics.
- What is?
- I reserve the right to use
baby talk.
- I can't imagine that's true.
Mom, is it fair to say
that uh...
We can just make a rule,
a house rule,
no baby talk at the table?
- The patriarch is
a beautiful word.
Patriarch is beautiful.
- Let's just give him that ok?
Let--let's...I don't want to...
Married troubles.
I just wanted one more.
- You did another one.
- Just one more.
Is it the top and the bottom,
or they happen at the same time?
Is it the barf and squat?
- Oh, uh, yeah, sometimes
it's double barrel.
Really?
- Good news. Uh, a silver
lining.
On this crap cloud...
Is that this is largely...
Uh, preventable.
[Both laughing]
Accept it.
Take it to your heart.
Try to find a name for it.
- You want me to name it?
- Uh...I've got a few names
I could suggest
if you wouldn't mind.
First of all web, on a--
- no. No.
- A... no. All right.
- What was the name
that you were gonna suggest?
It started with an l?
Alamosh landau.
One of the greatest
philosophers.
I admire him.
- And that's what you wanted me
to name it?
- Well, let's go to b.
[Both laughing]
Bartholomeum.
[Laughing]
- I'm sorry.
You stay away from Thailand.
You don't go Thailand.
You stay away. Too spicy meat.
No good for you.
Hey. Don't go down. Don't go
down to Guadalajara.
Pucker. Too spicy for you there.
Fucking right?
Stay with Russian, Polish,
cabbages, potatoes.
[Snores]
But it's not going to make your
beast, your belly beast,
any bigger. It's gonna keep it
trimmed down to size.
And no booze. [Laughing]
No booze.
- He's right. You know, I mean,
we don't have that problem.
- No.
- We have the opposite problem.
We have to really take it slow.
We have to just the tip
Tuesdays.
Slowly work it in wednesdays.
Full thrust Thursdays.
- I-I...
Of course, that was in
the beginning.
But now every day.
Saturday, Monday.
Not Sunday.
That's the lord's day.
I'm joking.
Full thrust Sundays.
And now it's not a problem,
I mean...
Now you can hang up posters
in there.
Listen to me, tuna, chicken,
or meat. Organic.
- I just want to get it right.
- The green sign.
- Listen.
For me, I just don't want him
coming out again.
So I want to get it right.
- Yeah. You can
put a cork there.
A big one.
- It's gonna have to be
a pretty big cork.
- Yeah. Ok. Session's over.
Got a new patient coming in.
- Ah, great.
How you gonna explain
all of this?
- Oh, uh, they've seen it all.
- Really not my problem,
I guess.