In this world...
Is the destiny of mankind controlled
by some transcendental entity or Law?
Is it like the hand of
God hovering above?
At least it is true...
...that man has no
control, even over his own will.
Oh Prince...
Oh Prince of the eternally unforgiven...
We greet you with honor to
marvel at what you have become.
We shall meet again in another world...
We are your kinsmen...
Feel no shame about shape.
Weather changes the phrase.
Even mother will
show you another way.
So, put your glasses on.
Nothing will be wrong.
There's no blame, there's no fame.
It's up to you.
The first words should be found.
Whatever holds you back.
I...
...can...
I can get it off.
Tell me what...
Tell me what you want.
I don't know why...
I don't know why you are afraid.
Tell me what...
Tell me what you'd say.
I don't know why...
Too late...
It's too late.
Are you sure there's a secret
passage in this dismal place?
Our sources are reliable.
If this passage can be found so
easily I'll give up being a mercenary.
Found it.
Giving up, huh?
Pippin.
There's no mistake.
This is it.
Right, let's go.
Wait a minute.
I understand that Pippin and
Judeau need to come along...
...but you're the commander now,
are you sure you should come?
If something were to happen to you...
Our mission is to rescue Griffith.
We have the highest
chance of succeeding...
...in our mission if all four of our
strongest members take on the operation.
Yeah, but...
You're worried, aren't you?
Don't make me laugh!
I'm a stronger
swordsman than either of them.
Don't bring your
personal feelings into this matter.
Obey your commander's orders!
Remember...
...I can still cover your back.
Don't forget.
Yeah...
Let's go.
Griffith...
You were always
looking up to the sky...
...thinking of nothing else
but to keep climbing and soaring...
A hawk flying alone,
reaching for the highest point...
That's right...
You were always
watching us from above...
Never here on the
ground with the rest of us...
Calm, cool and never missing a beat.
Do you really need a reason...
...each time I decide to lay
my life on the line for you?
Letting nothing stand
in your path to victory...
Do you think that I am dreadful?
Griffith couldn't go on without you!
If that's true...
If that's the real truth...
Then I...
Pull yourself together.
Griffith will be back soon.
There's no way in hell I'm going to die...
...not without seeing Griffith...
Even if I have a
thousand more stitches in me...
Ricket, we need some more water.
Got it.
When Griffith returns...
It'll be the
resurrection of the Band of Hawk!
Everyone is in good spirits...
Because, Griffith will be back soon...
As long as Griffith comes back, then...
A fairy?
I saw it...
...with my very own
eyes, there's no doubt.
The enemy?
Why at this time?
Just a little more...
All we needed was a little more
time and Griffith would be back!
We can't let them destroy us, not now!
Hey...
Where is everyone?
Run...
Ricket...
It can't...
This can't be real!
What...
What's going on?
I'm amazed we learned
about this secret passage.
We have supporters inside.
Wait.
Supporters of the
resistance movement...
You must be the Band of the Hawk.
We are at your service.
I am Caska of the Band of the Hawk.
What do you mean by supporters?
They're from Princess Charlotte.
Oh...
We don't have very
much time until dawn.
We must get to where Griffith's
being kept as soon as possible.
Yes.
We'll take it from here.
In this darkness not a single
ray of light can find its way through.
How long have I been
lying here in this darkness?
For an eternity...
At times it feels like just a moment...
I feel nothing...
It's as if my body is floating in space...
Am I preserving my sanity?
Or has it already been lost long ago?
And yet...
...in this world like a hollow shell...
...one thing is clear in my mind...
Him alone...
...like lightning
splitting through the darkness...
He appears in my mind so vividly.
Over and over again
like the waves of a tsunami...
...hatred...
...friendship...
...jealousy...
...frustration...
...helplessness...
...affection...
...sadness...
They all come
together into a giant vortex...
They keep my
consciousness from fading away.
Guts, the cause of my
confinement in this darkness...
Will now...
...be the source of my life!
This man whose life
was once in my hands...
At what time did I fall under his control?
And now...
In my mind I see him radiating
so brightly it pierces my eyes.
Guts!
Griffith?
Is he in a different cell?
No, he has to be
here, on the lowest level.
Griffith?
Grif...
Gri...
Griffith...
The tendons in his arms
and legs have been slashed...
And his tongue...
Caska, the keys!
Caska!
Stay there!
Stay where you are!
This isn't possible.
This can't be Griffith...
Guts...
Griffith!
There's no escaping now...
The guards and soldiers
will be here any minute...
And in a year, you'll all
be looking just like him...
You bastard...
So you're the bastard
who destroyed his body...
That's right.
I haven't had that
much fun in a long time.
You don't come across a
specimen as splendid as him very often.
When you're as experienced as
I am in the profession of torture.
...not only do you
appreciate beauty on the surface...
...but also the beauty that lies beneath
the skin, in tendons, muscles, and veins.
He really was exquisite.
There's no use.
This door is four times
thicker than your average door.
Don't move!
Put down your weapons and surrender!
Stick with me and don't fall back!
Guts!
How dare you?
What the hell are you doing?
Shoot them!
You idiots!
Who said to retreat?
Hold your ground!
Hurry!
What's taking them so long!
There's thirty of our
soldiers after just four of them!
How can it be so difficult?
Yes, but sir...
...they're led by that
man, the hundred-man killer!
Don't be stupid!
You don't expect them to come here
just to rescue their commander, do you?
No...
Besides, myths like that
are born in times of war...
...when stories get exaggerated.
There is no man in the world who can
kill a hundred armed men with his sword.
At the very most, ten soldiers.
That is definitely him...
The ruthless commander
of the Band of the Hawk...
Guts!
It's Hundred-Man Guts himself!
Surround him,
what are you waiting for?
Seize him!
But sir...
You idiots!
He's been swinging his huge sword
around and chasing after our men...
He's out of breath.
You fools!
If your enemy sees you
hesitating, you've already lost the battle.
Taste battle, and pay for this
lesson on ruthlessness with your life.
Guts!
Advance!
Where are they?
See, it's too much
for just the four of them...
No...
You're wrong, they'll be back.
I'm sure of it.
Guts...
What a disgrace!
If we let them get away
the King will not forgive us.
Pursue them!
We'll get ahead of them
and wait for their arrival.
Yes sir!
Looking back, the morning comes.
Don't find your face in your glass.
Take the moonlight by the tail.
It's a rainy sight that you're shading.
What is that?
It's just the same.
What is trying on your crown?
I'm spending my
glass and walking back.
So wear my glass, you're fading.
I'm waiting so long.
I'm waiting...
Beloved thoughts...
The will to live...
All is lost at the end of their journey.
Their hearts bleed...
...full of regret and
sorrow as they stand idle.
In this world, will mankind survive?
Can only the wind
foretell the end of their dreams?