Subtitle created by - Aorion -
"Blair Witch (2016)" ^ (Run time 01:22:14)
Do you see her?
What do you mean?
I missed it the first time too.
Hang on.
Okay.
What is that?
Lisa, I think that
might be my sister.
Wait, wait
Okay uh...
How did you even find this?
Did you have like a search alert set up?
Yeah, yeah exactly.
And usually it's nothing,
but the guy who uploaded
this video said it was
from a tape he found in
the Black Hills woods.
But those woods have been searched, right?
They never found the house.
Yeah, but the
Black Hills forest is huge,
so maybe they weren't looking
in the right place, you know.
That's why I want us to start
where the tape was found
and camp the night...
- Lisa.
- Hi.
- Hey.
What are you guys doing?
We're doing Lisa's documentary
class project, starring me.
Boring.
Okay.
So try on the earpiece camera.
- Uh, which is... Is it this one?
- Yeah.
And then, press the button
at the side.
- Okay.
- And then it should be recording.
The cool thing about these
is they've got built-in GPS.
How's that?
You're getting one of these
for Peter and Ashley, right?
Yeah.
We just have to make sure you remember
- ... to switch out the cards.
- Okay.
Iteration, take 1...
take 2... 3...
When James was 4 years old,
his older sister disappeared
while making a documentary
near the town of
Burkittsville, Maryland.
Some of the footage shot
by James' sister was later found.
The final moments of it
showed her going into a house,
seemingly within the
Black Hills forest.
That area was extensively searched
by police and FBI
but they could find no evidence
of an existing house in those woods.
Investigators concluded that James' sister
might have vanished else where
despite her crew's equipment
and footage being found nearby.
For as long as I have been
friends with James,
he's wondered what happened to her.
His continue search to find closure and
answers to his sister's disappearance
is the subject of this documentary.
How long have you
and James been friends?
Our parents were friends,
so I guess we grew up together.
So you knew him when
his sister disappeared.
Yeah.
I don't really remember Heather
all the well, to be honest.
But after she ran off into those woods
she didn't come back.
Yeah, I remember all that.
- I got one.
- That's me.
Nice shooting.
Peter.
Can you give us an idea what
we're going to be doing out there.
The four of us,
we're going to go out there
and we're going to
try to find this house.
James, he's been messaging with
the guy who uploaded that video.
He's going to show us exactly where
in the woods he found the DV tape.
And James, you think
you're going to find the house?
Maybe, I hope so.
So you really think your sister
could still be out there
after all these years.
All I know is...
If there is
any chance at all
that I could find out
what happened to her
I need to at least try.
And what about the legends?
Legends?
Yeah. Do you believe at all in
the stories about the Blair Witch?
Hey Lisa, I can't tell if
this thing is recording or not.
- Yeah, it should be. Did you...
- Yeah?
Did you press and hold
the button when you did it?
Yeah.
These things are so small,
where are you going to put it?
Okay, it's recording.
We are recording.
Just, and make sure it's always
facing forward
and make sure you
press the button down.
- And you hold it down.
- Got it. Got it.
- Are you pressing and holding?
- Yeah, I got it.
- Did you hold it down?
- Holding down, holding down, holding down.
- Hey, Peter!
- Yeah.
- How do I look?
- Yeah, that's sexy.
The thing is, he's going back out to
those woods to look for his sister, Lisa.
Because he thinks
she could still be there
because of some blur footage
that some weirdo put online.
- So like, how's that gonna look?
- I don't want to exploit anyone.
Alright then, don't tell anyone about it.
Okay, how about that?
Who's that? There's an option.
Don't tell anyone.
Just come out there
with us and film it
like he wants you
to as his friend.
Don't use the footage
for your movie.
- I can't promise that.
- Right.
- No, I can't
- I know. I know you can.
I can't promise that, Peter.
Because it's like,
- what if something actually happened out there.
- I see you, Lisa. Yeah, right.
- No, no, no.
- Okay, I'm gonna get a beer.
What if we find something
that no one ever found.
I'm so sorry. He and James
have been since friends forever.
Because I haven't been
friends with him
for as long as you guys
doesn't mean I don't care.
- I know that.
- I have a responsibility to James...
Oh.
Oh, baby.
How are you feeling?
You're asking if
I regret getting drunk
the night before going
camping in the woods?
I do not.
Okay.
Let's just move back
a little bit.
How far does it go?
Like a 100 meters,
it's the max I think.
Ashley and I have used
this in class before.
It's just like cheap helicopter shots,
you know.
It could be useful in terms of finding
our way around the forest.
Yeah, we're going
to have GPS with us, right?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's built into the earpiece camera.
But it only works if you put on those,
just
keep an eye on the battery
in case we got separated.
Comm check, over.
Comm check?
Yeah. That's like what people say
in the military, over.
Okay.
Anyway, it's working.
Over.
Copy that, over and out.
- Hey, the walkie-talkies worked.
- Yeah, we know.
You got the faces, boys.
Somebody wasn't upgraded.
Whoa.
- Okay, which one is you guys'?
- This one.
Okay!
- Whoa!
- Who made the bed?
- I don't know.
- Let me get through.
- James. James. James.
Goodnight, folks.
Oh yeah.
Enhance it a little.
When you...
- And this used to be called Blair.
- Sort of.
There was a town called Blair
back in the 1700s
but it is was discovered abandoned.
So they built up a new town,
called it Burkittsville.
They're here.
- Hey.
Hey, come in.
- Hey...
- Hey.
Can I...
Can we have like water or anything?
I'm okay, thank you.
Feel free to make
yourself at home.
It's just through there.
Yeah, have a seat in there.
And uh,
Lane will be right with you.
Hey, I'm glad you all
are recording this.
Not everyday we get like
minded investigators
coming out here and
discuss the Blair Witch.
Hey, I may need to get you guys to sign
some release forms later, if that's okay.
Yeah, sure, that's cool.
I probably need you to sign one too.
So, you're Darknet666.
Yeah. Well, we both are,
but you can call me Lane.
- This is-This is Talia.
- Hi.
So, okay.
Well, first off,
I was hoping you could show us
where you found the tape.
We're going to make
that our starting point.
Are you guys really gonna go
camping out in those woods?
Yep, that's the plan.
Why?
Uh, we want to go
out there with you.
I mean if you're going to be looking around,
we want to be a part of that.
It's not... you know.
- I'm not going to be a burden or anything
we go camping all the time.
- Yeah.
Hey, that's the deal if you want us
to show you where we found it.
Is it okay if we talk
a little in private real quick?
Well, yeah. Oh, yeah, yeah.
Sure, go ahead.
- What do you think?
- No.
Well, don't we need them to show us
exactly where they found the tape?
Yeah.
Yeah, but I didn't think they'd
want to stick around after that.
Well, they didn't exactly make it
sound like we have an option.
What are you bragging about?
This guy really crack me up.
We made it.
- Yeah.
- Alright, Lisa.
Babe, what the hell
do you have in here?
It's heavy.
Lisa.
And Ash, I'm going to
give you the headlamp.
Okay.
It's cool if we leave
our cars here?
Yeah.
It's fine, they're safe.
No one comes out this way.
I'm already hungry.
Yeah.
I can eat.
Eat all these granola bars,
you'll like that.
Hey, what do you thing
they're smoking up there?
Definitely bath salts.
- You know what?
I'm going to go ask.
- Wait.
Hey, yo.
Darknet666, wait up.
I saw some of your other videos.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, before we came out here.
Saw this one, it was really
interesting where you guys
like found this
little pile of rocks.
Would you stop it.
Symbols.
Symbols, oh they were symbols.
No, no, no, seriously.
So, do you guys really believe
all these old stories?
I mean, someone died everywhere
at some point, right?
It doesn't mean every square foot
of this planet is haunted.
Did you grow up here?
- No.
- See, I did.
Talia did.
We both-we both grew up here.
And older folks in town used to talk a lot
about these woods when I was little.
And after his sister and her crew
went missing and her stuff got found,
suddenly everyone I noticed
wanted to forget it.
This area has a history of things happening
that no one really likes to talk about.
Rustin Parr.
Coffin rock.
The list goes on and on.
- Watch yourself.
- Okay.
- Watch your step.
- It goes down here.
Back in the 1940s,
Rustin Parr brought 8 kids
up to his house
in these woods.
He killed 7 of them.
But Parr claimed that he
heard the voice of an old woman
telling him to kill the children.
He would take them up to his attic
and make one stand in the corner
while he killed the other one.
There's been some debate on that
actually where...
whether it was the attic
or the basement.
So he thought he heard the
Blair Witch telling him to kill people.
Well, he never said who its was.
He just said that it sounded
like this voice of an old woman.
They hanged him out in
these woods near his house.
Wait, he got a house out here?
Yeah, but that's not the one
we're looking for though.
Parr's house was burned down
after he was hanged.
Supposedly they found a bunch of
old tunnels and stuff underneath
that didn't go anywhere.
Some kind of...
underground railroad thing I think.
Oh, my back.
Okay.
So, this is uh...
This is technically where
the Black Hills woods start
back when this was private land.
Uh, who owns it now?
No one.
It's the States' I guess.
So, we're not trespassing
or anything, right?
No.
No one cares.
No one living that is.
If we have to go camping
with the locals,
could you please
don't piss them off.
Babe, I didn't say anything,
I didn't say anything.
You don't have to say anything,
Peter, you know that.
Sick.
Sorry.
NO ENTERING AFTER
NIGHTFALL
This is where we found
the DV tape.
There was nothing else
on the tape?
Like I said, it was all static except
for that bit when we upload it.
Why does that tree
look like that?
Lightning.
Sometimes when it hits the tree,
the electricity goes into the ground
and burns the tree
from the roots up.
.
A girl drown in this creek.
It was around when
Burkittsville was founded.
Her family was doing the washing
and the mother said she saw
a hand reached out of the water
and pulled her daughter in.
Probably the only reason we still
know about this because there are
newspaper articles said
the girl's body was never found.
Are we crossing this?
Oh yah.
- That's not how it is.
- Cool, dude.
- I'm walking across the water.
- That's right.
- Oh.
- That's cold.
Leeches are fine.
What do you mean?
Wait, wait, you said there are leeches?
No, I'm just asking.
Are you coming?
Did you get a pedicure
before you came here?
Yes.
I know.
You sure this is a good idea?
Would you hold the
camera for me first.
One second, my shoe.
- Oh.
- You alright?
Becareful there.
Ah, that's cold.
- Yeah. I got it. I got it.
- Yeah? Alright.
Careful.
You alright?
Ashley!
Hey, hey, hey.
Come on, come on.
I cut my foot on a rock.
You could see blood.
You will be alright.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
You're alright.
Let me see that foot.
That's better.
You're alright. You're alright. You're alright.
- Is it bad because it looks like it's pretty deep?
- No, it's not bad at all.
I just got to clean it.
Lisa, do you mind getting my first aid kit,
it's in my bag over there.
- Lisa, first aid kit bag, please.
- Oh shit, sorry.
- Thank you very much.
- Yep, sorry.
- Lane. Jesus.
- Hey! Hey! Back up!
Back up! Back up!
Back it up! Back it up!
- Get back over there.
- I'll be one more second.
- I swear...
- Alright. Alright.
There you go.
Oh. Oh.
It's okay,
try not to move too much.
It looks like
it's really bad.
No, it feels a lot worse
than that, Ashley, I promise.
- Pressure.
- Ahh.
It's okay. It's alright.
Now I just got to wrap it up
and you could get
to walk on it.
Just bring it around.
There you go.
- Thank you, James.
- No problem, man.
- Okay. Want to try standing up?
- Yeah.
Okay, alright.
Don't put too much pressure on it.
- You ready?
- Two. Three.
There you go.
- You alright?
- Yeah.
- Not so bad.
Oh.
Ow.
You okay?
Come to my palace
in the woods.
That's how we roll.
In style and out.
No, that's what I'm trying
to say is um...
Is it...
Fuck.
- Babe, I got it. I got...
- Babe.
Please let me just put
the tent together, okay!
- I'm just saying that.
- I just need to put the tent together right.
I...
It's not supposed to be bent, I know.
So, you just bend...
Is this supposed to be bent.
This is not the entrance.
That's not.
Well, that's not either.
Fuck.
Fuck. Fuck. Fuck.
Fuck you.
Fucking tent.
Okay.
I think it's good.
Hey.
I'm going to get some firewood
before it gets totally dark, okay.
Looks like the sun's coming
down pretty quick.
Uh. Well, hold up.
Let's finish this and I'll come with you.
No, man.
I'm not going to far, okay.
I'll keep my camera on.
You can see me on the GPS, alright?
Okay.
Well, take a walkie-talkie with you please.
Man.
Brother, already got one.
- Thank you.
- Yep.
What exactly should
we be looking for?
We're looking for the house
from Heather's footage.
Did you see the...
Do you see any clearing
or anything like that?
I shouldn't take this thing
too much further up, but...
I mean, I don't see anything yet.
- Yeah, that was a good movie.
- Oh my god.
- Oh boy.
- Oh Lane.
- Yeah.
- Ehh.
- Eww.
- I'm really uncomfortable with this.
- Ew, I don't want it!
- Why do you have to eat it like that?
- I didn't think...
You could eat a little bit quicker,
you don't have to go all slow like that.
- Oh god.
- Oh.
Okay, so...
The Blair Witch.
Who is she really?
Elly Kedward.
That's what most people say.
She was accused of witchcraft
after some of the children in town
said that she's taking
blood from them.
There wasn't much of
a trial system back then.
The townspeople took her
out into these woods.
Tied her to a tree and
left her to die of exposure.
In the spring, they went back
to look for her body
but there was no trace of it.
They assumed she was eaten
by animals or something, but...
Then people in town
started disappearing.
First the children who accused her
and their families, then others.
Eventually everyone who was left just
abandoned their homes, fled the town.
- Whoa.
- What?
- Alright, I was just going to add.
According to this book
I read, published in 1809,
they didn't just tied
Elly Kedward to a tree.
I mean they did tie her to a tree,
but they tied her up really high
and they strung these
heavy rocks to her arms and legs
as weights stretching her.
They left her to die
on a makeshift rack.
Okay.
Thanks.
Ever since there's been
a curse on these woods.
The legend says if you
look directly at the witch
you'll die just from
the fright of it.
That's why Rustin Parr
stood in that corner.
They say no one has ever seen her
and live to talk about it.
Or alternately, no one
has ever seen her appear yet.
These are just stories, okay.
I've been to these woods before.
When I was a kid with about
a hundred other people.
You were a part of those
search teams?
I remembered that.
Yeah.
So, how come I'm okay?
Nothing got me then.
Maybe it did.
You're back, right?
Alright, real theory, real theory.
The one I put online.
Whatever spell the witch
put on these woods,
you have to be out here at night
for her to get you.
You have to spend the night.
Wait, then how come
you're still alive?
That's a good point.
Maybe she's using us
to lure you all out here.
- Okay, I had enough of that crap.
- Yeah, me too.
Let's get some rest.
We got a lot of ground to cover tomorrow.
- Night, dudes.
- Yeah, goodnight.
- Goodnight, James.
- Goodnight.
I just heard something
moving outside.
Shit.
Shit!
Hey, Lisa.
Lisa, what the hell
are you doing?
- Did you hear that out there?
- Yeah, I heard.
There is something out there
out in the woods like a bear or...
Shhh.
Shhhh.
What the fuck was that?
- It's okay. It's my walkie-talkie.
- Oh. Shhhit.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Peter, is that you?
Comm check.
Hey, man.
What the hell was that?
Fuck.
I don't know, man.
I don't know.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
We're okay. We're okay.
Lisa's here too, we're okay.
I mean, she just came like
just now and we're okay.
- Like 30 seconds ago.
- Hey, is everyone okay out there?
Yeah, we're fine.
You two, good?
No.
Lane's not here.
- Where is he?
- Well, he went off to pee.
But he always goes
far off for privacy.
Oh god.
Hey, Lane!
Lane!
Oh, god damn it.
We should probably
go look for him right?
- Make sure he's okay.
- No.
No, I'm not going out there.
- That is definitely not a good idea.
- Well, I'm gonna go and look for a while.
Okay, I'll come with you.
Uh. Shit.
He might be... lost, okay.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
I guess I'll... I should probably
go back to my tent then.
You can stay here
if you want.
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- Alright.
- I'll be right back soon.
- Hey.
- Good luck, man.
- Careful. Over there.
- Thanks.
Lane!
God, where is he?
Did you see the tree
that fell?
It sounded like
it landed nearby.
Yeah, but...
Sounds can travel
pretty far out here.
Shit!
Lane!
- Lane, what the fuck?
- I'm sorry, man. I'm sorry.
- Tell me you recorded those sounds.
Did you get those sounds?
- Uh, no.
Yeah, yeah.
Lisa and I are recording.
I went to see if I could find
what was making those noises.
I couldn't find anything.
Did you guys find anything?
- No, dude. Just...
- No.
... get back to the camp, okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Okay.
You guys, get out here.
No.
I'm getting out of here.
I'm unpacking and leaving.
This is fuck up.
Holy shit.
I want to go home, okay.
Where'd this stuff come from?
Someone must have put these things up
while we were asleep.
What's going on?
What's wrong?
We should film this.
Talia, get the camera.
- You guys should be taking pictures.
- What is it?
- What?
- You guys, seriously.
I want to go home now.
We need to get out of here.
Hey James, that's not
a bad idea, okay?
- We are not prepared for this.
- Okay.
I've seen this stuff before.
It was in Heather's footage, guys.
Shit.
There's another one back here.
- That's my tent!
- Fuck.
Does anybody know what time it is?
My watch is saying 2 PM.
What? How is it even possible?
We just woke up.
- But how did we sleep
till 2 in the afternoon.
- Yeah.
- Okay. Okay, yeah.
- Please, you know.
You know what? Ashley's right.
Let's just...
pack up our stuff and
get back to my car, okay.
No, no, no.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Yeah.
This is too weird.
- I don't know.
We found something, right?
- Yeah.
Like, we can show the footage to the police.
Maybe they'll reopen Heather's case.
Wait.
I want to get that on camera.
I'll get this free.
Let me just...
Just rip it off the tree,
for Christ's sake.
Holy shit.
Let me give this a shot,
just a shot.
I have an idea. Why don't you stay here
and get all the footage you want.
Alright, that's it. Come on.
Turn it off. Turn it off.
I want to get a shot
at it, okay?
Fuck this.
So.
Hey, what kind of
a camera is that, man?
Oh.
It's a DV camera.
- Oh yeah?
- It's old.
Good in low light.
It's better than modern cameras.
Mm-mm, okay.
Does it use tapes,
like the one you found or is it...
You know, there are not too
many brands of it anymore.  Why?
- Oh nothing, I'm just curious.
- Oh, I recommend it.
Everything is cards now but...
Some ways, you know, tapes are
more reliable and cheaper.
You still have to carry
a lot of batteries though.
Oh yeah.
Ow!
Ahh.
- Ashley.
- Babe.
- You, alright? You, okay?
- What's wrong?
I'm fine.
It's just my foot.
- You want to take the boot off.
- No, it just hurt for a second.
But, it feels fine now.
-  Can you feel that?
- Yeah.
- Does that hurt?
- It's fine.
Hey, Lane.
Lane. Stop it.
Stop it!
- What the fuck are you doing?
- What is this?
- This looks familiar, doesn't it, guys?
- Yeah, that's a rope.
I'm carrying that because
it's used for camping.
- Give back to me.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Hey. Hey. Hey.
- Give it back.
- Get back, man.
You have the samples from
the camp, don't you, Talia?
So, can I see one?
- Because this rope looks exactly the same.
- What the hell.
Definitely it does not look the same.
Rope is rope.
- Open your eyes.
- Okay, let her see it then.
She doesn't need to see it!
- Come on.
- Hey! Hey. Hey.
- Get the fuck off, big man!
- Listen, stop it!
Listen, we weren't trying to
scare you or anything. We just...
We weren't lying about the things
that were going on in these woods.
We just...
We needed...
- ... somebody to see what was happening.
- No. No, no, no.
Did you...
You fake this?
Yeah. Yeah.
We faked it.
Alright, look.
We faked it because it's real, okay.
There really is something happening here,
guys, in these woods.
- And that make sense to you?
- Everyone would.
Hey, we didn't fake
those noises last night.
And, sleeping until 2 o'clock.
How could we fake that?
There is something really
going on out here.
Right. For all we know, you guys put
sleeping pills in our water or something.
- What?
- Did you?
- No.
You know what?
Okay.
Fuck this.
I'm out.
You guys-You guys want this.
This is on you.
Hey, get a shot of this.
Lane.
The guys are fucking assholes.
Guys.
We don't-
We don't have the GPS thing.
There's no cell reception out here.
So, I mean...
- That's not our problem.
- Just hear me out.
- What if-What if we get lost, okay?
What if we get lost?
I thought you guys camp
right here all the time.
- We've been following you.
- My god!
- No.
- What the fuck is wrong with you, man!
We have gone as far as
the creek when nobody has.
- Nobody's been here for years.
- Shit.
We don't know where we are!
Okay, just calm down.
We meant to, we meant to.
- We want to stay in numbers, okay?
- Jesus Christ!
- There's more of us so the odds are better.
- Okay, is there anything that you two
told us that is not a lie.
And I guess it's just a coincidence
that your camera uses
the exact same kind
of tape that you found.
No.
- Okay.
- It wasn't...
I think you two got
all the footage you need.
You walk that way for about 2 miles,
you'll hit the fence.
Look. Can we just calm down
and we just talk about it.
- NO! Get out of here!
- Come on.
- Please. Please, just come on.
- Okay. Okay. Okay. Go.
- Cut the camera off.
- Guys, you don't understand, okay.
- Just go!
- GET OUT OF HERE!
Go!
- Come on, please.
- Time up, it's time to go! Just go!
Please, man!
- Take him, go.
- Come on!
Guys, are you sure?
Does this...
Does this have to happen?
We can talk about this.
We can talk about it.
I have like...
Lane, I swear...
Fuck.
- I'm... God, no.
- Fuck.
Fuck!
James, man.
I'm so sorry.
I actually thought that...
Heather could still be out here.
They're pathetic, man.
I should have known then.
I guess I just...
Oh god.
Well.
I don't know about you guys,
but I feel a little bit ...
You know, less scared of
being in the woods now.
- Yeah.
Are you going to be okay?
I'm alright, man.
- I'm okay.
- I'm giving you a hug.
- Don't give me a hug.
I'm giving you a hug, my son.
Aw.
Look at that.
You're welcome to stay here.
- Oh, sorry.
- That's okay.
You got it.
Lisa, come on.
Let's go.
Hey, James.
Are we anywhere
close to the fence yet?
Yep, should be.
This looks familiar.
That's a good thing, right?
How could you even tell?
I don't know.
I just...
I thought we...
- Wait, wait.
- What?
- No. No.
No way.
No way!
We've been walking in a circle!
That doesn't make sense.
I've been following the GPS.
Then we should have reached
the fence hours ago!
We shouldn't be back at the same
fucking campsite we just left!
- Can I see the GPS, James.
- I don't know, it must be broken.
- We're lost.
- No, we're not lost.
- We got turned around. We got...
- Got turned around.
Let's look around with the drone.
- Better get start hiking for the road.
- Okay, let's do that.
- Whoa, whoa.
- Hey. Hey.
- Hey, you okay?
- Yeah.
- I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine.
- You sure?
- I'm fine.
- You can't...
- You can't keep walking.
- We got to camp here tonight, you'all.
- Oh, no no no...
- No, no, no, babe. You got to...
- I'm not...! Ah, ah.
Hey. Hey.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
I can't stay here another night, Peter.
I can't stay here another night, okay.
Hey, you need a rest.
Okay, you got to let that foot heal.
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay?
Look, we'll just set up the tents.
We'll be okay.
This is fine. We...
We'll figure it out.
Can you please... at least
take down those creepy sticks, babe.
- I can't look at those things anymore.
- I got it. I got it.
Hey, can I see your camera?
I just want to charge the batteries
and change the cards out.
Yeah.
Did you hear that?
What?
Nothing.
My ears are playing tricks on me.
You know what?
I thought I heard a voice earlier...
Hey.
Hey, how are you doing?
I'm fine.
I'm just freezing.
Can you tell James
to start a fire?
Oh babe.
We should check out
this cut on your foot.
Yeah, okay.
Okay.
I'll just take that off.
- Ah!
- Okay.
- Becareful, it hurts.
- I got you. Alright.
Looks like you...
It's a bit irritated.
Is it bad?
No, uh-uh.
Uh-uh.
No, it's fine.
I mean, we should just...
You know...
put some ointment on it.
I'll go get James.
- Ah!
- Whoa whoa whoa...
Don't do that now!
What was that?
What just happened?
Okay.
It's fine now.
Just...
Becareful where you touch, okay.
That's how I felt
when I fell earlier today.
Okay.
Uh.
I'm gonna set your foot down, okay.
And uh...
You should just stay lying down.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
I'm just gonna rest my eyes.
Hey, I need to talk to you.
That cut, on Ashley's foot,
it's gotten worse.
But.
No, no.
Whatever it was,
it was really fucking weird, man.
Okay.
You said it looked like a muscle spasm.
Yeah, or something like it.
I-I don't know.
Whatever.
There's something inside of her cut.
Now she's cold and
I think she has a fever.
- So, I just...
- Okay.
- Okay, I'll go take a look at her right now.
- Thank you.
Yep.
I want to keep a fire going
for her tonight. So...
I'm going to gather some woods
if you guys think you could get it started.
- Yeah, it's a good idea.
- Hey, keep your walkie-talkie on.
Of course.
Hey, will you look at this?
What is it?
Well.
I don't see a road
or a creek or anything.
Should I take it further out?
Maybe it's the angle
or something.
- What?
- Oh.
What's happened?
I don't know.
Like it...
Oh shit!
Fuck.
God damn it.
Lisa, if you are watching this footage,
I think you'll want to delete it.
How is she?
It's infected.
She has a fever.
Did you see anything like... moving
like Peter said?
Nothing like that.
Look, we should take her straight
to the closest ER tomorrow.
Okay.
Damn it.
Hey James, is that you?
Hey, genius,
I think you're sitting on your walkie.
Okay.
Shit.
Oh shit.
Come on. Fuck.
Hello?
Hey.
Is someone out there?
Oh shit!
Oh. No.
No, no, no!
No! No, no!
No, no!
Come on!
Okay.
Hopefully the batteries last.
What was that?
It sounded like another treefall.
I think that's...
James.
Peter!
- Wait, James.
- Peter!
James!
Peter, can you hear me?
Peter!
Peter?
(Peter's flashlight.)
Peter!
Peter, can you hear me?
Peter, if you're hurt or you can't
speak or something, just...
Press the button on your
walkie-talkie twice, 2 clicks.
Peter, if can you hear me, just press
the button on your walkie-talkie.
Peter!
Fuck.
Oh.
What?
I don't feel so good.
Where's Peter?
He went to get some firewood
but he'll be back soon, okay.
Come on,
let's get you back to bed.
Lisa!
Hey.
- Can everyone stop doing that?
- Come here.
Fuck.
I found Peter's flashlight out there.
Shit.
That was him screaming
out there, right?
- I think so.
- Oh god.
Okay, James.
Look.
It will be okay.
We need to stay together.
You're right.
Let's just keep the fire going.
If he sees it, he can find his way back.
Okay.
You know, I actually thought that...
Heather could still be out
in these woods somehow.
But now...
Peter's lost
and Ashley's hurt.
It will be okay.
Did you hear that?
Yeah.
- Do you think they're coming in here?
- I don't know.
Peter!
Peter?
Lane, Talia?
- What are you guys doing here?
- No no no...
It's not-Its not real.
Don't go close.
It's a trick.
When was the last time
you saw us?
Uh.
Earlier this afternoon.
No.
Lane.
It's been 5 days
since we saw you.
Maybe 6. What the fuck
is going on with the sun?
The sun is not coming up!
The sun is not fucking coming up!
What are you talking about?
Hey, where are the other two?
Peter and, what's her name?
Ashley is sleeping
She's not feeling well.
And we don't know
where Peter is.
Fuck.
It's starting for them.
- We have to go. Come on, we have to go.
- No.
Guys, we're not going to fall
for your stupid shit again.
Could you just tell us
what's going on?
Do I look like
I'm messing with you?
- You got any food.
- No! No, get back.
Get back, please. Talia.
- Get back here, please.
- I want it!
Get back.
We're alive, don't you see that?
Are you crazy?
Look at them.
They are doing better than us, aren't they?
Are they?
- What the fuck is going on?
- I don't know.
- No, no, no, no.
- Please.
You want to stay
here, you go ahead.
- Go ahead!
- Please. Don't! Just...
These people are going to die!
They're going to be here forever.
Not me!
Lane!
Talia.
We're just gonna go
sit by the fire and...
we'll set up a tent for you, okay?
I don't think I can sleep.
Me neither.
What?
It makes no sense.
I set the alarm for 7 o'clock,
it's still dark outside.
- Okay, we should pack up.
- Okay.
What the hell?
Oh my god.
Lisa.
Lisa, get out here.
What the fuck is that?
Oh my god.
Oh.
How could we not hear this?
Holy shit.
Oh, fuck.
They're everywhere
Who could have done this?
My god.
I'll rewind the camera.
Shit, the battery is dead.
We have to go.
We...
We have to go now.
Yeah, okay.
Let's pack up our things.
No, no, no...!!!
- Ashley.
What is this shit?
Okay, okay.
What is going on?
What is she doing here?
Where is Peter?
Talia came back a few hours ago.
- she got lost okay.
- You're safe. You're okay.
Peter.
I'm not sure.
Ashley.
- Ashley.
- I feel... I feel sick.
Okay. Okay.
What...
What about the...
What about the drone camera?
Can you send the drone camera up?
- Can you look for him like
you were looking for the house!
- It crashed.
No! No!
No.
Hair.
Mine.
My hair.
- It's bullshit she was here.
- This is my hair.
- You did this!
- Ashley. Ashley.
You just shut up!
This is all your fault!
Ashley, don't!
Oh my god.
God!
No!
Talia. Talia. Talia...
No, oh my god!
Ashley.
Ashley, Ashley, Ashley.
- It's going to be okay.
- Okay.
Oh my god!
James!
Ashley!
Lisa, I'm here!
James.
- Lisa, here I am. You okay?
- Yeah.
You alright?
Where's Ashley?
I don't know.
I don't know. We got split up.
- We have to go find her.
- We have to go back. Let's backtrack.
- Okay.
- Alright, stay close.
Stay close.
It's alright.
You're alright.
Lisa!
James!
Peter!
Okay.
- She couldn't have gone far, right?
- I don't know.
Ashley!
Holy shit.
We'll find her.
Hello?
Ashley, is that you?
Comm check.
That's Peter, he's okay.
Peter, is that you?
Help me...
Hey. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Lisa, come on.
It's okay.
You're okay.
It's alright.
You're safe.
It's okay.
You're okay.
I promise.
Yeah.
Okay.
- We got to go.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- You alright? You sure?
Yeah.
We got to go.
Okay.
This way.
Easy.
Slowly. Slowly.
That's it. That's it.
- - Okay.
That's it.
Alright, the drone.
Okay. I can send help.
I can send help.
Come on.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
It's stuck.
Shit.
Okay.
I can... I can...
Shit.
Ashley!
It's okay, keep going.
It's alright.
Ashley!
- Is that her?
- Where's it coming from?
This way.
Come on!
Ashley!
Oh my god!
We found it!
This is it!
- Lisa, come on.
- No, no, no, James.
I don't want to go in there.
I don't think we should go, let's not go.
(James.)
- Heather!
- Stop!
That's my sister!
I don't know what happened
to your sister, James.
But that's not her.
That can't be her.
(No!)
Let's go.
- Oh god, I have to go in there.
- Please!
My sister is in the house!
It has to be her!
- James, please. Please.
- Lisa.
You know this is
what I came here for.
James, please!
Heather!
James!
Heather?
Hello?
Peter?
Peter!
Heather!
Heather?
No!
Oh shit.
Heather?
Hello?
Heather!
Heather.
Oh, fuck this.
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Ashley!
James!
James?
Fuck.
James!
Hello?
James?
Who is that?
You look exactly
how I remembered.
Oh my god.
Lane?
I guess she couldn't
have let you go.
She had to find
people who remember.
Draw us apart, you understood?
You have to do
what she tells you!
Get out!
Lane!
Fuck.
Okay.
It's got to lead outside.
Breathe.
Everything's okay.
Fuck.
- Lisa?
- James.
Oh my god.
The attic.
We're in the attic?
Wait! Wait!
She's right behind me.
Oh shit.
What the fuck was that?
Oh god.
What do we do?
The corner.
Get in the corner, come on.
- James, what are you doing?
- I said, corner now! Come on!
Don't turn around!
Don't look.
Shh. Shhh.
Quiet.
Just keep your eyes close.
She only takes sacrifices.
We can't look direct at her.
Close your eyes.
Lisa, I'm so sorry.
This is all my fault.
Heather?
(... ....)
Is that really you?
Who are you talking to?
James!
James, where are you?
If you don't look at her,
She can't hurt you.
Lisa, I'm so sorry.
James?
Subtitle created by - Aorion -