- Hello?
- It's me.
Oh, am I bothering you, Francesco?
No, don't worry, I had to get
out of the shower some time.
Hold on a minute, Franco...
You were saying, Franco?
No, no, nothing. Just
calling to see how you doing.
You know how things are...
...life goes on.
Gnaghi!
I've been shouting at
you for hours. Gnaghi!
He's Ghigini, the surveyor.
- 12th row, 3rd grave, right?
- Gna.
Grave three.
Here we go.
I know you've heard this before,
but this time,
my dear Ghigini,
it is forever.
Rest in peace!
Oh, my back...
What a waste of good marble.
Never looks right when you fix it.
All this fancy packaging.
I don' know why they don't
just cover the graves with dirt.
The gun! I forgot the fucking gun!
- Ea...t!
- Gnaghi,
give me the spade! Gnaghi!
give me the fucking spade!
There we go.
You handle the rest Gnaghi.
My name is Francesco Dellamorte.
Weird name, isn't it?
Francis Of Death.
Saint Francis Of Death.
I often thought of having it changed.
Andrea Dellamorte would
be nicer, for example.
I'm the watchman of
the Buffalora cemetery,
I don't know how the epidemic started,
All I know is that some people,
on the 7th night after their death
come back to life.
I call them "Returners",
but frankly I can't understand
why they're so anxious to return.
The only way to get rid
of them once and for all,
is to split their heads open.
A spade'll do it, but a
Dum-Dum bullet is best.
Come and have a glass of wine.
Is this the beginning of an invasion?
Does it happen in all cemeteries,
or is Buffalora just an exception?
Who knows? And in the end, who cares?
I'm just doing my job.
Good morning engineer.
How are you doing today?
Fine, Miss Chiaromondo. And you?
The cemetery is open, isn't it?
For you, any time.
Hello cutie. Here...
How are you?
He's happy. He likes
it when the sun shines.
I'm not an engineer...
...and you are no cutie.
Poor Gnaghi, on his ID card it reads:
"Distinctive physical marks: all".
He has a real passion for dead leaves,
can't stand it when the
wind blows them away...
Oh well,
we all do what we can
not to think about life.
The most beautiful living
woman I have ever seen!
Will I see her again?
I just came to water the flowers
on your poor father's grave.
Husband.
How long has he been dead?
Two weeks.
- Thank goodness.
- What?
- I mean, I'm very sorry.
- Have you no respect for pain?
Well, you know how these
things are... You see:
- in time, pain heals.
- It's not healing a bit.
He was wonderful,
he was a wonderful lover, incredible,
tireless.
He was fantastic!
I messed it all up,
I've lost her.
Will I see her again?
Hey, Franco!
Franco is the only living person
who even calls me. Now and
then I stop by his office
to remind myself what he looks like.
You can't live on memories alone.
It's for you. Sign as usual.
- Have you got a pen?
- No.
Hold on a sec, here we are.
Have you had any visits last nights?
A couple, yes.
All this extra work! It's
much if the pay me any more.
Tell the Mayor...
Oh, tell the Mayor then what?
They'd close the cemetery.
Good-bye job and
good-bye house!
Come on, who do you
think would believe you?
Listen, I don't care if
you don't believe me Franco,
you're not the one who pays me!
I believe you,
I believe you, and you're right...
- At least have him pay the overtime.
- Good.
Well, let's go to the Mayor, then!
It's not that easy.
First you have to fill out an M3 form,
report with an M3 form...
Forms...
I could speed things up there for you...
It's easier just to shoot them.
One M3 form!
Going to get our willies wet tonight?
Some of us, yeah.
Hell, at a certain point
in life, you realize
you know more dead people than living.
Sorry about the other day, I was
a bit crass. I didn't mean to be.
My name's Francesco Dellamorte.
You know, this is the
only job I could get
even with a degree in biology.
Anyway we all end up here
sooner or later, don't we?
I've got a great little
house... Want to see it?
I don't live alone, I've
got a helper, Gnaghi.
He's a real conversationist!
The cemetery's small, but
it's got a marvellous ossuary!
An ossuary...
I have never seen anything so...
exciting!
Neither have I.
It's like in my dreams!
This is my dream.
I couldn't ask for anything more.
Me neither.
You know, you've got
a real nice ossuary.
Thanks.
You will allow me to return, won't you?
You will allow me to kiss
you just once, won't you?
No.
Not like this.
Like this.
I must be faithful to
the memory of my husband!
I can't. I can't!
It's not my fault... It's this place.
I feel strange tremors.
It's not the cold...
I'm not afraid...
This place wants me to...
It's forcing me to...
I don't want to!
I can't! I can't!
Don't be afraid, it's just ignis fatuus.
Why here?
Why on your poor husband's grave?
I've never kept anything from him...
We trusted each other implicitly.
He would have liked to know.
Well, if that's the case...
All these lights!
Let them watch.
What's better than watching
two lovers making love, hey?
Just to have a bit of privacy.
Sorry, but the lady wants stars only.
It's never been like
this before, with anybody.
Only you.
No one will ever make us part.
Gnaghi! The gun!
I can explain! Listen to me,
you've always been so understanding!
That's life!
It's nothing my love,
you're fine.
Great,
just when I don't need it anymore.
Well don't just stand there!
Go call doctor Vercesi!
Go on, get the doctor!
Go on! Move!
Nothing can separate us.
I swear, nothing.
Nothing will separate us, will it?
Nothing, my love. Nothing.
Not even death?
Not even death.
Dellamorte, are you
in there? Dellamorte!
Jesus! You scared me to death!
Were you looking for
me, Chief Straniero?
Yes, Dr. Vercesi called.
What happened last night?
Well you know. Why are
you asking me? She's dead.
I know she's dead,
but how did that happen?
Her husband.
Sure! He came back from
the dead, he raped her,
then bit her to death.
Is that what he did?
No, he didn't rape her.
Oh, you always crack me up, you know!
Dr. Vercesi, are you spying on us?
No, I dropped this certificate.
Her heart stopped from fear, it
wasn't the bite that killed her.
She died while making...
well you know... doing it.
You know what that means, my boy?
I'll have to look somewhere else
for the creep who killed her!
- You are no longer a suspect.
- Why not?
Well, you know what I mean.
Look, don't make me say it!
Go on, you can say it. I
don't mind, I'm impotent!
Don't use that word! A young
man like you, at your age...
Did she have any relatives?
No, no relatives, no friends.
Well, I have to say that...
Shit! This is definitely not my style!
- Can I keep her here?
- If you pay for the funeral, of course
you can do whatever
the hell you want with her.
- Does that wrap it up, then?
- Yeah, except for a killer on the loose.
Care to join me for a cup of tea?
The weather's changing at last!
I can't forgive myself
for having lied to you:
I don't have a degree in biology,
I didn't even finish high school.
I haven't read more than
two books in my whole life:
one,
never finished,
and the other is the phone book.
I don't want her to become a Returner.
I don't want to see her again.
No!
Yes, my love!
No, don't make me do it!
But if you do it so well... so well!
Not to you!
It will be better with
me than with the others!
Gna!
You do it!
Well go on! If you finish
fast I'll buy you an ice-cream.
Gna!
- Here comes the Unforgiven.
- Who?
The Tombstone Mayor.
The man whose dick's so
small he pees with tweezers.
He could become a
woman. That'd solve it!
They are sewing them
back on in the States now.
Yeah, they can stitch it right on,
if you've got one to start with.
Forget it, I started that rumour.
The more they laugh, the
further away they seem.
You can never be too different, Gnaghi.
Maybe you can.
Engineer!
Engineer, engineer, come! Have a seat!
Well well well, what a surprise!
Yes! It's a miracle
seeing you here, engineer!
It's a miracle seeing
you here, Mr. Mayor.
So, how are things down at
our cemetery? How are things?
Well how do you think things are?
Population's shrinking.
You're lucky, my dear engineer!
You just can't imagine how
things are at the Town Hall.
Now that the elections are upon us,
it is chaos, right, inspector?
Yeah, it's a thrill for all,
nobody wants to lose their job.
I was hoping for a New Deal...
Daddy, what's this?
This is my assistant Gnaghi.
He's sweet!
Will you buy him, daddy?
That's great, it even knows how to cry!
Gnaghi, don't stay so close to her.
Could you move over, darling?
Would you tell your
daughter to move over please?
Yes of course.
Sometimes Gnaghi gets a little bit excited...
Oh, I'm sure he's
charming. Now, where was I?
What's he doing? Dancing?
No, no, he's just about to...
What the hell are you doing Valentina?
He threw up on me, Claudio!
Oh, a new fact!
Would you like to go for a ride?
I knew you'd understand!
Take off!
By the way, one of these days
I have to talk to you
about the cemetery.
The youth of today...
They're so... emotional.
Come on, Gnaghi! Get in, for God's sake!
Don't do this, just get in the car!
It's not the end of the world,
It didn't even bother her!
She understood it was just a
demonstration of your affection.
Anyway, it's not the first time
you threw up over a woman, is it?
Come on, Gnaghi, get in!
Look, first love doesn't count.
It's last love that counts!
Nobody came today.
I was a bit bored,
not even the admiral...
he's just disappeared!
Let's hope tomorrow, okay?
Yeah, come again and stay a while.
Oh, he was such a
distinguished man, the admiral!
Always used to bring me, always,
a touch of Sambuca.
Oh, come on Gnaghi!
You'll get over, you'll see!
Time passes,
nothing seems the same...
It just gets worse.
God, is it ever difficult
trying to make you feel better!
What were you doing with the Mayor's
daughter anyway? She's only a child!
Gna!
Oh yeah, that's not true,
you are not a child, Gnaghi.
You're a year older than I am. Anyway...
One day,
you'll settle down with some...
poor creature like yourself.
In the meanwhile, why do you care?
They all end up here
sooner or later, Gnaghi.
Often sooner than later.
Faster, open it up!
- If daddy could see us now!
- He'd kill me!
Claudio!
- Off we go!
- Go!
Go! Go!
Go!
- Hang on!
- Eat our dust!
Four motorcycles racing...
The Mayor's daughter is on one of them.
Her head was sliced right off.
They had to sew it back on the body.
The bikes crashed into
a bus loaded with scouts
on their way back from
a church-sponsored rally.
Slaughter of the innocents!
And they were all so young.
They felt their life was ahead of them,
but in fact they were already passing by.
Well, you've got your hands full!
Oh, more than you know!
Gnaghi, we're going to
need a lot of bullets.
# Never should have gone
out on the Boy Scout picnic,
# never should have, never
should have gone just then.
# Never should have gone
out on the Boy Scout picnic,
# Never should have, now
I'll never go again! #
Claudio! Take me with you!
Don't leave me all alone, Claudio!
Take me with you, my love!
Nasty tart!
My son wasn't with you!
He was promised to the Mayor's daughter!
- But he loved me!
- Liar!
He was mine, he loved me!
- Only me!
- Have you no respect for a mother's pain?
We're born to die,
born merely to die.
Do you remember?
Just yesterday,
she was alive, happy.
Do you remember?
Dear Gnaghi even threw up on her,
and she took it so well!
And now, she's gone...
and right on the eve of the elections!
I better get the pickaxe and shovel.
Pumpkin, how could you do this to me?
Is it true as they say, that the
dead come back to life here at night?
Tell me the truth!
Hey! Who told you that?
Is it true or not? Is it true or not?
What if it is?
I've got to see Claudio again!
I have to know whether
he loved me or her!
If I hear anything, I'll let you know.
No, wait...
Go away! I haven't got
time for the living!
Gnaghi?
Gnaghi!
Gnaghi, they came back
sooner than we thought!
Gnaghi wake up!
Gnaghi, watch out!
Gnaghi,
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.
Well, that's it, time's up and
I want you upstairs and
ready in five minutes! Okay?
Oh no, what's she doing here?
Visiting hours are over!
No one is going to
take me away from him!
Quick, get the fuck over here! Quick!
No, Claudio!
Claudio, take me with
you! Don't leave me!
Stupid cow!
Come on!
Wait! Wait!
Claudio please, take me with you!
Tell me you only love me!
Please...
Claudio!
You only love me, right?
Damn! It always shoots to
the right when it's cold.
Gnaghi!
No, please don't! He's only eating me!
Move aside.
Mind your business! I shall
be eaten by whoever I please!
This is my business. They pay me for it.
The living dead
and the dying living are all the same.
Cut from the same cloth.
But disposing of dead
people is a public service,
whereas you're in all sorts of trouble
if you kill someone
while they're still alive.
Wait!
This way they'll be together forever.
I'm sentimental.
Patience, Gnaghi.
In love, it's the waiting
that's the best part.
You have to learn how to wait.
- What's your name again?
- Gna!
Gnaghi.
I'm Valentina.
Haven't I seen you before?
Oh yeah. Now I remember.
You threw up on me. How sweet!
But I like shy boys.
And you never say no to a kiss.
Take advantage.
I'm certainly in no position
to refuse. Besides,
I don't think I'd refuse anyway.
False alarm!
It was only a cat.
No use you trying
to help me, little thing!
If I can't do it, imagine you...
Putting this skull together,
is one of the most difficult
things in the world.
You know, you really are
disgusting when you eat, Gnaghi.