In related news,
local woman Becky Roberts...
has been missing now
for more than 24 hours...
Is anyone there?
Hi.
Where is everyone?
In the assembly.
So why aren't you?
Why aren't you?
I'm a transfer,
I just got here.
I know.
Is it that obvious?
It's a small school.
Word travels fast.
So what's the assembly for?
Major drama.
Some townie
was screwing the wrong guy
and she's gone missing.
So the police are here
to teach us
about personal safety.
Like, don't talk
to strangers.
I'm Owen.
Dodger.
That's unique.
Blame my mom,
she's a Dickens scholar.
And your dad?
Let's just say
he's not a scholar.
So where'd you come from?
England.
I meant
what was your last school?
Bradford.
Before that, Collegiate.
Webster before that.
So what'd you do?
I was dating this girl
who happened to be
the dean's daughter.
Miss Allen.
Miss McNally.
Since you seem
to have skipped the assembly,
perhaps detention...
I'm sorry,
Miss McNally, is it?
Uh-huh.
I'm Owen Matthews
and this is my fault.
It's my first day
and I asked Miss Allen here...
if she could show me
the way to my dorm.
Not that I would ever set foot
in the boys' dorm.
No, just to the dorm's
front entrance.
Fine, but as soon
as you finish
showing Mr. Matthews around...
make sure you contact
your RA and he'll help you...
I'll do just that.
Thank you for your help.
I guess
you're stuck with me.
Mr. Matthews,
your son is on line 1.
Send him to voicemail,
Cynthia.
You've reached
Charles Matthews...
I'm away from my desk
right now.
Please leave a message
and I will return
as soon as possible.
Hey, Dad, just wanted
to let you know
that I'm all settled in.
The bus worked out fine...
though it would have been nice
to have seen you
before I left.
I got a great
work-study shift...
as a teaching assistant
in the Physics Department.
And I signed up for classes.
Mostly hard sciences,
per your request.
And I just met my roommate,
Tom.
I just beat off.
Great guy.
Well, I guess that's it, so...
you know, give me a call
if you have some time.
I hope
you washed that hand.
We're sneaking out.
Good for you.
Do you want to come?
Why would I want to do that?
Dodger asked me to bring you.
Where are we going?
The old chapel,
Westlake tradition.
To do what? Bible study?
To play a game.
What up!
Party's here.
Over here in the locker room.
No, I'm glad they're here.
What's going on, man?
I thought you were missing,
like that townie.
Tom, who's your
new boyfriend?
You'll have to excuse
Randall here.
He doesn't know the difference
between a roommate
and a cellmate.
Everybody, this is Owen.
Owen, this is everybody.
Jungle Fever,
you guys want to join us?
What's wrong, Graham?
Bad mood 'cause
you blew the physics test?
I don't know, Lewis.
Bad mood because
Mercedes blew
the lacrosse team?
Blow this.
I hate to be the bitch here,
but are we going
to play or what?
Come on, Regina,
you love to be the bitch.
All right,
everyone put your money in.
Is someone gonna tell me
how to play?
It's a lying game.
The object:
Avoid suspicion.
Manipulate your friends.
Eliminate your enemies.
Have a seat.
I'm going to secretly pick
one person in the group
to be a liar.
The wolf.
And everyone else
is a sheep.
If you can find the wolf...
and convince
the rest of the group
to vote him out...
then the money is yours.
The wolf survives,
the cash is theirs.
So how do we find the wolf?
Figure out who's lying.
Who's Dodger looking at?
I'm thinking Texas T!
What?
Dude, you will never borrow
my car again.
Then as much as I'm sure
I'm going to miss
the PT ragtop...
I thought that I heard
Tom move when Dodger...
was walking around
to mark the wolf.
All right, Randall,
that an official accusation?
And if it is?
Then you can only send home
the accused or the accuser...
but you can't win
if you don't play.
So let's vote.
That's right.
And the defense?
No, I'm not the wolf.
No, I swear to God
I'm not the wolf.
I swear on the Gold Star State
Come on,
are you gonna listen to me...
or are you gonna listen
to this chump here...
whose buddy list reads
like a sex-offenders registry?
What?
Come on!
Show of hands,
who thinks Tom's the wolf?
No!
You guys, come on.
No.
And Randall, our accuser?
Yes!
All right.
Come on, we need one more
for the majority, guys.
One more for the majority.
O- Dog, help a brother out.
Listen, just 'cause
you're Tom's new bunk-buddy...
doesn't mean
you got to be his bitch.
You don't really think
the angry homophobe thing...
is fooling anyone, do you?
Come on, Randall,
you know the rules.
Show the group
if you've got the mark.
Tell me I'm rich.
No mark.
I guess
Randall's not the wolf.
Watch your back,
pretty boy.
Dude, you know
how gay you sound?
Blow me, Tom.
Have a nice walk.
Bye.
Nighty-night, sheep boy.
You guys all suck!
Poor baby.
The wolf has survived.
Who wants to start round two?
Dodger felt up
the new guy.
She did ask me
to bring him here.
What a whore. Let's vote.
Hey, I believe
I'm allowed a defense.
Whenever someone lies,
they normally have a tell.
Like my new friend,
Graham, over here.
That's the most retarded thing
I've ever heard.
And there it is.
Haven't you guys realized
he can't open his mouth...
without taking a swig?
So?
It's empty.
Graham, you can't convince us
if you can't
convince yourself.
You would've noticed it
if you didn't know
each other so well.
Are we voting or what?
One vote for Owen.
And the accuser?
The new guy gets to stay
and I have to go?
I cannot wait
to go to college.
Bare it and share it,
Graham.
Have fun
with your new recruit.
He's just pissed
'cause he's fat.
I can still hear you!
So was he the wolf?
Money's still on the floor.
Who wants to start
round three?
All right, this is it.
It's one vote for Owen.
Who's it going to be, Lewis?
Say good night, Mercedes.
Congratulations, baby.
Tonight, you could've
gotten laid. But instead...
you got fucked.
Not bad
for your first day.
Yeah, I guess it's one way
to pay for college.
You think
you're that good?
No, it's just bored rich kids
make it so easy.
They're like
bickering siblings.
They turn on each other
for no good reason.
Graham's tell, come on.
You're awfully quick
to judge.
No, it's just that...
Those bored rich kids
are my friends.
...over 38...
Is this journalism class?
Are you Owen Matthews?
Yeah, I'm sorry, I was...
Sleeping in.
No, my alarm clock...
Relax, Owen.
If being late
is the worst thing...
that happens to you
in the first week,
you got off lucky.
Take a seat.
As I was saying...
does a reporter
just go for the story?
Or can we, as the media,
cover a tragedy like this...
with both sensitivity
and respect?
Morning, Randall.
Laura?
What does that mean?
That means, if I may...
that if you upon some
nasty pictures of the victim
on the Internet...
don't forward them
to the whole school.
A resounding no to sensitivity
and respect from Mr. Hodge.
Feet down.
You just now discovering
the Internet, Owen? Match. com?
Mr. Matthews...
you're making it very hard
for me to pretend
that I can't tell...
you're not paying attention.
I'm going to need
these articles by this Friday,
at the latest.
Now if any of you
are having a hard time...
thinking of something
to write about other than...
the most recent development
in this local tragedy...
I'd be willing
to meet with you privately.
And they only just found
that girl this morning...
because her body was dragged
through the woods by a wolf.
Yeah. Listen, the guy
blew her head off...
then let the wildlife
just go to town.
Why does it have to be
a guy?
Please.
Serial killers
are always men.
Just the ones
that get caught, baby.
Serial means
more than one, jackass.
You're not taking
your SAT book to my lake house
this weekend, are you?
Right, Owen, my dad...
The senator.
The senile drunk,
is sending a limo
to take us all...
to the lake house
on Friday.
Nobody ever stays here
on the weekends.
You in?
Yeah, sure.
I'm not going to be able
to make it, I got plans.
What?
By plans you mean
herpes, right?
Actually, by plans,
I mean I'm going...
to State tomorrow
to see the sweet Jenny Ryder.
It's Wednesday.
I know.
And I'm declaring my own
"Randall Gets Laid"
Holiday Weekend.
And I'm going to punch
Miss Ryder's v card...
Nice.
Thank you.
Can I borrow your car?
Yeah, man.
Yeah, just, you know,
leave the keys
on the tire and...
don't get any blood
on the back seat.
I wouldn't dream of it.
Actually, I would like this
to be special, you know.
Like, in the middle
of the woods,
up against a tree.
You're a pig.
You're a dyke.
Die a violent death.
Yeah well,
if that's your technique...
I weep for Jenny Ryder.
I bet you do.
So are we going
to play the game
before the weekend?
Not sure I want to.
Well, what else
are we going to do
around here, study?
Owen had a decent point
last night.
About us knowing each other
too well.
It's so incestuous.
So you just want to stop?
Because of the new guy.
Thank you.
Not necessarily.
Well then, what?
We'll play
with the whole school.
They're the sheep,
and we're the wolves.
I don't think they'll all fit
in the chapel.
Let me ask you a question.
What's the best way
to play the game?
Lie your ass off.
Defend your honor.
Accuse your neighbor.
Exactly.
Nobody knows
who killed that girl.
So why don't we
make an accusation?
So what are you suggesting?
Let's convince them
the murderer is on campus.
And he's just getting
started.
All right.
But how do we do that?
You guys
have no imagination.
It's like
you're playing checkers.
And I'm playing chess.
I had fun last night,
thanks for the invite.
Who said I invited you?
I thought Tom said.
Relax, I'm kidding.
I wanted to apologize, too.
I didn't mean to piss
on you guys with that bit
about the tells.
Sure, you were just trying
to impress me.
What makes you say that?
Well, I just...
Relax, I'm kidding.
So, I had an idea
on how to convince
the rest of the school...
there's a murderer on campus.
I'm listening.
What if this
isn't a random murder,
but a serial killer.
You already lost me.
Let's just say
someone forwarded us
an e-mail.
About not one,
but a series of murders
that happened before.
Go on.
And the first victim died
in identical fashion
to our townie.
So it's happening again.
Why else would the police
be investigating Westlake?
They're not.
Telling the student body.
It would be our duty
to warn them.
Meet me in the library.
We're going to create
a killer.
He needs a name.
The Wolf?
That works.
Okay. What else does every
good mass murderer have?
Something that he wears.
Something
that covers his face
but anyone can buy.
Pantyhose?
What? Is he robbing a bank?
My old roommate,
he used to go hunting.
He had one of those
neon ski masks.
Orange doesn't exactly
inspire fear.
Come on, it's the new black.
Okay.
There are plenty of
deer hunters around here.
Give him a camo jacket, too.
What's his weapon
of choice?
Well, the girl was shot.
Yeah, but a knife
would be scarier.
Don't get me wrong,
I love
the phallic imagery...
but serial killers
rarely change their M.O.
But don't you see?
This is his pattern.
Remember this is not
the first time
our boy has struck.
Of course, he goes
from campus to campus.
Following the exact
same plan.
The first death
is always a townie.
Which is just a warning shot.
Before he attacks
the school.
And the massacre begins.
On the full moon.
That's this weekend, right?
It's Halloween.
It's so obvious.
It's perfect.
So who were
the original victims?
So the first person killed
was obviously the town slut...
shot in the face
while lost in the woods.
Okay. Who's next?
What if the Wolf
waited for his prey
in the back seat of a car?
What if you were
any more cliché?
Like you can do better.
Dark hair, brown eyes.
Killed while
looking in the mirror.
A victim of
her own narcissism.
That means conceited.
Anyone else?
Self-mutilating de-virginizer,
eviscerated in the chapel.
No, it should be special
for him.
Lock up the misogynist pig
and let him bleed to death.
Right after castrating him.
Very slowly.
Can the Wolf do
microscopic surgery?
Laugh it up, drama boy.
You're next.
Prima donna wannabe actor
trying to play
the big balcony scene...
gets his intestines
ripped out.
Who else?
Let's not forget
the campus queen.
Her sharp wit was dulled
when she choked...
on her own severed tongue.
You people
are deeply unwell.
Four years in the same place
with the same people.
What do you expect?
Last but not least.
The good guy that fell
for the bad girl.
Died of a broken heart.
I didn't know you were
such a romantic, Randall.
I'm not.
But I do love the irony.
We'll get this out tonight,
leaving plenty of time...
for the rumors to spread.
Lights out.
If I get caught
in the boys' dorm again...
Yeah, that hasn't happened
since we hooked up, huh?
By hooking up,
you mean jerking off...
to my yearbook photo, right?
Dude, don't you want
to use an anonymous account?
Why? I'm just
forwarding it along.
With sensitivity and respect.
Owen, Tom,
I said lights out!
Hey, did you guys hear
what I said? Go to bed.
Do you think anyone
will believe it?
I'm telling you,
I read the e-mail.
It's happening.
Just like it did
at that other school.
The first girl,
she was shot
in the face.
I forwarded it...
To my brother.
He sent it to everyone
he knows.
He told me to get off-campus
this weekend
if I didn't wanna get gutted.
He said the second girl...
Owen, just the man
I want to see.
You got a minute?
Sure.
What's in the box?
Antique chess set.
Got to love eBay.
Just now
discovering the Internet?
So I read your e-mail.
Someone forwarded that to you?
Sure did.
Someone also sent it
to the victim's mother.
Who forwarded it
to her attorney.
He called
the Headmaster's office
this morning.
She assumes it originated
off-campus. Don't worry.
I'm not inclined
to inform her otherwise.
Why would I worry?
I glanced at your records
this afternoon.
I see your father
pulled some strings
to get you in here.
Dear old dad.
I also saw that your status
here is probationary.
So you end up
in the Headmaster's office...
you might as well
pack your bags.
Bringing the bitch out early.
Just keeping you
on the defensive.
Speak for yourself.
The arrogance of youth.
Don't you mean
the confidence?
Actually,
I meant the ignorance.
You know, it was just for fun.
Yeah, I do.
But you've got to know
it had some real consequences.
No offense, Mr. Walker.
This is high school.
Nothing's for real.
To buy as many properties...
Sorry. Just a second.
Sorry. Just my son.
Go ahead.
Hello, this is
Charles Matthews.
I'm away from my phone
right now...
but if you leave
your name and number...
I will get back to you.
Thank you.
What up, O-Dog! Sorry.
When I bend it like Beckham,
I usually lock the door.
I got your message.
What?
Text messaging
come in handy?
Dude, I didn't send this.
Yeah, right.
If it was me,
why would I deny it?
Dude, it's Dodger.
Doesn't really seem
like her style.
You kidding? It was her idea
to change the game
in the first place.
She's just taking it
a step further
by coming after you.
Watch and learn.
She usually does laps
after field hockey.
I bet she's on the computer
in the swim team office.
Dude, Dodger's been waiting
for a guy who'll bite back.
If you get laid after this,
you got me to thank,
all right.
Relax, man.
Whoever it is
knows your screen name.
It's got to be someone
on campus.
Hello?
Who's there?
Aim for the shallow end.
We want to scare her,
not kill her.
Yeah, okay.
One, two...
Did you hit her?
What?
I think she's faking it.
Isn't she?
She's not coming up.
Owen Matthews,
you're my hero.
You bitch.
Twice in one day, not bad.
What's that supposed
to mean?
"Be careful what
you wish for"?
Talk sense, boys,
you're losing me.
Someone sent Owen
some IM's
claiming to be the Wolf.
Said they were going
to pick our bones clean.
That's a little
over the top.
Yeah, and pretending
to drown isn't?
Look, I was with Regina
all afternoon,
studying AP Chem.
You can ask her.
No, I believe you.
Someone's just trying
to scare you.
I'm late for the team run,
I got to go.
Okay, so if you were
with Regina
and Randall's at State...
that leaves Mercedes
and Lewis.
And Graham.
You did make him look
like a chump the other night.
You think he's trying
to get me back?
And get back in the game.
The sum total
would be about 51.
Very funny, Graham.
I'm glad you think so.
Do I look like I'm laughing?
Well, I had to do something.
Sure, I understand.
You had to send me
threatening IM's pretending
to be a serial killer.
I have no idea what you could
possibly be talking about.
You didn't just IM as the Wolf
about an hour ago?
No, I've been here
since sixth period.
Owen, you can't convince me...
if you can't
convince yourself.
What were you
just talking about, then,
the thing you had to do?
I filed a noise complaint.
For what?
Are you kidding? Your room
is directly above us...
it sounds like you're having
WWF tryouts up there.
Jesus, Tom.
What happened?
Did you do this?
Of course not.
Somebody else must've...
Why didn't they
touch your stuff?
Tom,
I didn't touch your stuff.
Then who did?
That's Randall's.
I know.
That's disgusting.
Do you think
something happened to Randall?
Like what?
Like he died a violent death?
It's Regina.
She has a recipe
for fake blood
she got off the Internet.
It's just corn syrup.
It used to be sweeter.
Hey, Re-genius,
I can't believe...
you got Randall
to let you borrow
his tongue stud.
You know
you're going to buy me
a new computer, right?
What is it?
Hey, what's up?
I told Tom...
I've been on
an AP Bio field trip
all afternoon.
I thought you were in AP Chem.
No. I took AP Chem
junior year.
Who told you that?
Why are you doing this?
Not here.
Look, I was in town.
Yeah? Doing what?
I was visiting my mom.
What was she doing in town?
She lives here, all right.
This is my home.
Go ahead, laugh all you want.
The Dickens scholar.
Sixth grade English teacher.
I'm not even going to tell you
what my dad does.
So how can you afford...
Scholarship.
You think
people would really care?
I'm a town.
Around here,
town means trash.
You don't have to rub it in.
What?
It's not that.
It's just...
You know, I wish my dad
taught school, lived in town.
I mean, the guy sent me here
just so he wouldn't
have to deal with me.
I'm sorry
I flipped out earlier.
After what happened
at my last school and...
Yeah, you told me.
The vengeful dean
and his darling daughter.
What I didn't tell you
was that I was charged
with possession.
She got busted, was freaked
about her dad's job.
So I took the fall.
I'm not surprised.
Why is that?
You may not have a tell,
Mr. Matthews.
But you do have a weakness.
Yeah?
You're a good guy.
Makes you predictable.
Yeah, if it gets me
kicked out of Westlake...
I might as well sign up
for community college.
Then why did you play the game
to begin with?
The sneaking out.
The hoax e-mail.
At the pool.
You saved me.
You were faking.
I'm not now.
What?
Someone's here.
So?
They're wearing
an orange ski mask.
You're kidding.
If the light's gone off,
it means he's gone, right?
Or standing very still.
Who do you think it is?
It has to be someone we know,
he's wearing a ski mask.
Indoors.
How in the hell
did he get over there?
He's coming this way.
Okay, don't move.
The light will go off
and then we can jump him.
Try German Philosophy.
No one will bother you there.
So I don't get it.
Okay, not to get
all fortune cookie on you...
but the most obvious answer
is usually the right one.
My gut, when I got the IM,
was that it was the real guy.
Why not?
No, I said the most obvious,
not the most ridiculous.
I don't know, I mean,
someone murdered that girl
in the woods.
Maybe he read our e-mail.
Maybe he didn't get the joke.
Maybe he's pissed.
Maybe it's Randall?
It was his tongue ring, right?
It's hard to believe
he'd give up bragging rights
to Jenny Ryder...
just to play killer
in the stacks.
Like he could ever
actually seal the deal.
I bet you $20
he didn't even go to State.
How about dinner?
As long
as it's not over $20.
Damn, I left my book bag
in the stacks.
I'll be right back.
You know what,
I've got something
I should go do.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Sorry. Not a fan of the PDA.
It was a black
Jansport backpack.
I left it on the lower level.
I'm sorry, I didn't see it.
If one of the staff
had picked it up they would've
turned it in by now.
Did you see
any other students?
Maybe they picked it up.
Student information.
Hi, can you give me
Jenny Ryder's phone number?
I believe
she's in the freshman class.
I'll connect you.
Hello?
Hi, Jenny.
Can I speak to Randall?
Who is this?
I'm a friend of his
from school.
I just wanted to tell him...
Tell him yourself.
He's not here.
Well...
Do you know
how I can reach him, or...
I told you, he's not here.
He never showed up.
Did he say where he...
No. He didn't say anything.
He stood me up
for my own formal.
Half my sorority doesn't think
he even exists.
He didn't call?
No.
There has to be something
really wrong with the guy...
to just not show up like that.
I couldn't agree more.
Hey, Mercedes!
You know
where I can find Dodger?
Why?
I have something of hers.
Well, she's
on the floor below me.
I'm sure I'll see her
before lights out.
Actually, I was kind of hoping
to give it to her myself.
I bet you were.
I saw her heading toward
the faculty building.
I think Mr. Walker
is going over her article
with her.
Thank you.
Obi-Wan, what's up,
man?
Hey, you seen
my shoulder pads
around here?
By the way...
librarian dropped
your bag off.
Said someone turned it in,
or something like that.
O- Dog...
what do you think
a murder victim looks like?
Owen!
Tom.
What do you want?
Chill, buddy.
I'm just trying
to figure out...
what I'm going to be
for the Halloween dance.
You figured out
what you're doing
for a costume yet?
Yeah, I'm not sure I'm going.
I've got to work
that night anyway.
What? Dude, we could both
be murder victims.
I mean, Regina is a pro
with effects makeup.
And that's the night the Wolf
is supposed to strike.
Come on, O-Dog, don't make me
chase you to this thing.
Look...
I need to focus
on this article.
It's due tomorrow.
What? Really?
On the Friday
of Halloween?
What heartless bastard
assigned that?
Nice job, ladies.
All right.
Thank you.
Owen, you have
your assignment?
Sure do.
Can I have it, please?
I e-mailed it to you.
And the rest of the school.
Very funny.
All right, let's get down
to business.
Pop quiz. Everybody take out
a pen and a piece of paper.
Owen?
No, wait!
Put the knife back
on the ground.
This isn't mine.
You don't understand.
Someone is trying to play
a joke on me here.
Put it down, Owen! Now!
Can I explain? Please?
Save it for the Headmaster.
Someone trashed my room, too.
Did you report it?
I think it was Randall.
He wasn't even in class
this morning.
That's what I'm trying
to tell you.
I think he's trying
to make me think
the e-mail's coming true.
Look, Owen, it's over.
You brought a weapon
to my class.
My hands are tied.
By the morning
you'll be onto your next
missed opportunity.
I know.
Good.
No. I know about you...
and Dodger.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You're really going to
make me say it?
She's a student.
Exactly.
No.
She's a student.
In my class.
Anything you may have heard
about our relationship
is strictly...
What? Strictly what?
I saw you two last night.
You have proof?
No.
But I won't need it.
If word gets out
about you and a student...
the administration
will invent a reason
to fire you.
You know what, Owen?
What?
I like you.
But you think you're smarter
than you are.
Hey! There you are.
I've been looking
all over for you.
You okay?
Good, 'cause if you're lucky,
later on...
I'll let you go
over the river...
and through the woods.
Sorry.
Not a fan of the PDA.
Funny.
You gonna come
to the dance?
The Wolf is supposed
to strike tonight.
That's not funny.
Besides, I have to work.
Come on.
We're all going to
Tom's lake house right after.
I'm not going.
Why not?
Because I'm not playing
anymore.
And I'm through
with your friends.
Look, I'm really sorry about
what happened in Rich's class.
Randall sucks.
Good news is, I was right.
You owe me dinner.
I don't owe you anything.
Can I help you?
Yeah.
No. I work here.
Not all the time.
I guess I better
watch my back.
Randall?
Boo!
Someone just attacked me.
You sure
it wasn't Tom?
He said he was going
to give you a scare...
for skipping out
on the dance.
Yeah, he tried
to chase me here.
Hey, if you talk to him,
let him know Randall's back.
You saw Randall?
No, but Tom's car
is in the parking lot.
Keys just sitting on the tire
and everything.
See if you can find your car
tomorrow, T-Dog.
Officer!
Get on the ground!
Drop the weapon!
Drop it!
It's not real!
I was just joking.
I'm sorry.
What's going on?
That's what we're trying
to figure out.
What was that?
Punch line.
Dead man walking.
I'm going to keep you all here
for the remainder
of the weekend...
while I determine
the best course
of action to take.
I'm at a loss to explain
how or why this happened.
We thought that...
Please, Mr. Matthews.
Mercedes has already told us
all we need to know.
I doubt if you are
any better able to explain
how a juvenile prank...
led to the police
almost shooting
two of my students.
No, ma'am.
Let me be clear, Mr. Matthews.
Given your history...
you are in
far more serious trouble
than your friends.
I don't care
who your father knows.
I'm inclined
to send you packing now.
Mr. Walker, however,
has spoken up in your defense.
He seems to feel that...
Trick or treat.
Adam!
Please, Mommy has to work.
Come on.
Yesterday wasn't Halloween.
It was just
the Halloween dance.
Today's the 31st.
The full moon's tonight.
I'll be sure to set
my tide charts accordingly.
What's your point?
I think our original hoax...
the mass e-mail...
was read by the person
who murdered that girl.
Owen, please.
No.
I got another IM today.
I think
something's going to happen.
Are you sure it's not just
another one of your friends?
Where's Mercedes?
She just spent the whole day
talking to the cops.
No way is she sneaking out.
Whenever you do see her,
make sure you thank her...
for getting us all stuck
on campus, all right?
I mean, what the hell was
she doing in my car, anyway?
Trying to convince you
the killer could be a girl.
Yeah, well, all I'm convinced
is that Randall's
a dead man...
for letting her
touch my ride.
I mean, where the hell is he,
anyway?
Merce gave him a ride
to the bus station...
so we could keep
your car around.
Randall never went
to State.
I think something
happened to him.
The IM said, "Be careful
what you wish for. "
Good job, Scoob.
You figure that one all out
by yourself...
or did you get some help
from Shaggy?
I don't think
this is a joke.
You're the only one,
then, man.
Mercedes pulled the stunt
with Tom's car, right?
She hid in the back,
I put the fake blood
in the front.
Okay.
So who was following
me and Dodger in the library?
Sorry.
I was really trying
to scare Dodger.
You're always
the shepherd.
I figured it was time
you felt like a sheep.
She took my bag.
Yeah, I saw you left it there,
bumped it to Tom...
and figured he would
give it to you.
You put a knife in my bag?
Only because
you trashed my stuff.
Why would I trash our room?
You didn't trash
our room, man.
You trashed my side.
It was all my stuff.
Look. Mercedes had
an earring...
that looked
like Randall's tongue stud.
She figured it'd be
a good setup for the car.
You smashed my laptop?
I got a little carried away.
I was in character.
In...
Dude! If I would have known
what you and the Vocab Ho
were up to...
I would have
gone after you guys...
instead of Owen
in the dining hall.
Jesus, why do you make it
so easy for us to hate you
sometimes?
Same reason your girlfriend
makes it so easy.
Who sent the IM's
from the Wolf?
It's not us, man,
it's got to be Randall,
all right.
If Randall was behind this,
don't you think...
he would have shown up by now
to gloat?
Are you sure
he got on that bus?
I told you, I wasn't with him.
Merce took him
to the bus station.
Then call her.
Jesus, for what I paid
for this thing...
you'd think I get better
than one bar of service.
Wait a second.
How do we know
Owen's telling us the truth?
Excuse me?
I mean...
he could be making
this whole thing up.
To get back at us
for the other stuff.
Why would I do that?
I'm the one
they're about to expel.
Exactly.
This is it.
This is the new game.
Owen knows
he's going to take the fall.
Brought us all here
to confess.
Surprise, surprise.
You all fell for it.
Victims of your own lies.
Is that what you're going to
tell Mr. Walker?
I saw you two.
In his office.
Is that why you've been
such a prick?
You're the one
who's screwing a teacher.
I was.
It's over.
After the library...
I went to Rich's office
to end it.
But I saw you...
you kissed him back.
What else could I do?
He tried a lot more
before I pushed him off.
Then he told me
I was too mature
for guys my own age.
He did what?
I guess he was right.
I don't believe it.
I do.
You should really get
some sleep, baby.
I'm all congested
from crying.
I think I'm going to
take a shower.
The steam might help.
Did your RA take off?
The whole dorm's empty
except for the incarcerated.
You okay?
Yeah, just...
still a little spooked.
So what are you guys
talking about?
We're just trying
to figure out
who the wanna-be-Wolf is.
Well, who is it?
They think it's Randall.
I told them you dropped
him off at the bus station.
I didn't.
Not really.
I left him in town.
He said had some time to kill.
It was, like, an hour
till the next bus.
He probably just needed
to go buy condoms.
You taking your clothes off?
Yes.
Tell me about it.
I'm in my underwear.
Which ones?
I'm wearing your favorites.
Take a picture.
Are you kidding?
Come on,
it's like Phone Sex 2.0.
What's taking so long?
Relax, I just sent it.
Merce, someone's there.
What are you
talking about?
You okay?
Tom just scared
the crap out of me.
Still pissed about your car,
Tommy-boy?
What's going on, man?
We heard you shout.
Merce, Tom's here.
In the chapel.
Merce was attacked!
She was getting in the shower!
Call for help!
Dude, it was
just another joke.
He probably wasn't
even on the phone with her.
It was the guy
that shot the girl.
Are you listening
to yourself?
The first murder happened
in a bathroom, remember?
We wrote it.
The victims are us!
Campus Security.
How can I help you?
I think someone's
being attacked. Please send
the police right away.
Look, we're tired
of the practical jokes.
If you put a member
of the staff on,
I'll be happy...
But there's no one here!
Once I speak to your RA...
Wait, where are you going?
I'm going back to my dorm.
Look, maybe Owen's right,
maybe we should just take off.
No, we're not taking off!
Tom, she's right,
we have to get out of here!
You're not going anywhere.
You keep out of this.
All she's trying to do
is make a bad situation worse.
Said the self-centered
loudmouth
to no one in particular.
Do you ever shut up?
What?
What's on your face?
It's on my sweatshirt.
Oh, my God!
Randall!
We have to get out of here!
What about Dodger?
What about her, man?
I'm going to find her.
Will you wait for me?
You have 20 minutes.
All right?
At 2:15 we are out of here.
With or without you.
Hello?
Lewis!
Are you okay?
Merce, she's gone.
I surprised him.
I think I hurt him, but...
Hold on, I'll be right there!
No! Get help!
Tom and Regina are waiting,
we have to get...
Lewis!
Dodger?
Tom, stop!
Tom!
Mr. Walker.
Mr. Walker!
Hello?
Owen?
Dodger?
What are you doing
in Rich's office?
I'm trying to get help.
Where are you?
I just found Mercedes.
She's dead.
What do we do?
Tom and Regina
already left.
We have to find
a way off-campus.
Where's Rich?
I don't know.
I think he keeps
a set of car keys there.
Look in his desk.
Good.
I'll meet you
in your room.
No, I'm on my way
to you.
Be careful.
I will.
Owen, I'm sorry.
Me, too.
Just get here, okay.
I can see you in the window.
I can't see you.
I'm right here.
Run!
No!
Oh, my God.
Keys. Keys. Keys.
I have a gun.
I've called the police.
They're on their way.
Owen, is that you?
Mr. Walker?
Look, I'm coming in.
Don't do anything.
Where'd you get that?
Your desk.
What?
It's yours.
Why don't you give it to me?
Not a chance.
Relax, Owen.
No one's going to hurt you.
Look.
Where did you get those?
I found them
in the stairwell.
Oh, God.
You did this, didn't you?
Look, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Dodger called me...
That's why
you stood up for me...
with the Headmaster.
You wanted me here for this!
Why don't you give me
the gun, son?
You killed them!
Mercedes! Randall! Lewis!
Dodger!
I don't know
what's going on.
Yes, you do.
No, listen to me.
Don't lie to me.
Your friends are probably
just screwing with you.
Give me the gun.
Is this the gun that killed
that girl in the woods?
Becky?
Were you screwing her, too?
Dodger tell you that?
She didn't have to.
Oh, my God!
Owen.
Are you okay? We...
It was...
I don't know what to say.
It was just for fun,
we had...
We had been playing this game,
and we decided that...
We decided to
work together tonight.
We were trying to scare
Owen and Mercedes...
because they got everyone
in trouble before.
Listen, we didn't think that
anything was going to happen.
How could you let Graham
do that to me?
Baby, I didn't even know
about it
till I left the chapel.
Dodger wasn't supposed
to hit me that hard.
Why did you hide
when Mr. Walker showed up?
Why didn't you
say something?
No, thanks, Dad.
My attorney tells me
the news is good.
They're going to drop
the charges. Self-defense.
It'll be a few years
probation, if that.
Dad...
how's that possible?
They ran ballistics
on the handgun. It turned out
to be the weapon...
the police were looking for
in the shooting
of that local girl.
Really?
It appears you shot
a wanted murderer.
How do they know
it was him?
It seems he was involved
with the victim at some point.
They checked
his credit card bill...
and found out that he'd
purchased two airline tickets
last month.
One in his name,
the other in the girl's.
Do they know
why he killed her?
My attorney says
they're calling it
a crime of passion.
No one ever really knows
the truth with these things.
Sorry to interrupt,
Mr. Matthews...
but one of your son's friends
is here to see him.
Go ahead, Owen.
It's going to be okay, son.
I promise.
Right over there.
I'm so sorry.
For everything.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
You have to believe me.
It's okay.
I wish I could
make it up to you.
I know.
If I had known Rich
was involved with that girl...
I wouldn't have played
this stupid joke.
What did you say?
If I had known Rich
was screwing that girl...
I wouldn't have talked
the others into this.
You're right.
You're absolutely right.
I don't understand.
You wouldn't play some game...
if you knew
Rich was cheating on you.
That's what I just said.
You would get him back.
Owen, I'm confused.
I don't...
No, you're not.
That's what
you want me to believe.
Just like...
you wanted me to believe
that you were off-campus...
when the first IM went out.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Yes, you do.
In the chapel.
You said you had ended it
with Rich.
I don't think
that's what happened.
I think you were still
in love with him.
I think you knew that girl.
This is my home.
And you knew she was
still sleeping with Rich.
Some townie was screwing
the wrong guy.
Dodger tell you that?
You murdered her.
Well, the girl was shot.
Then you planted the gun.
I've got something
I should go do.
And told me where to find it.
Look in his desk.
I was your guy.
Someone's just trying
to scare you.
From the moment we met...
It's a small school.
Word spreads fast.
...you planned it.
It was her idea
to change the game
in the first place.
We're going to create
a killer.
The whole thing.
It's like you're playing
checkers.
And I'm playing chess.
Makes you predictable.
You knew I'd shoot him.
Owen, that's crazy.
Really?
I thought it was the object
of the game.
Avoid suspicion.
Manipulate your friends.
Eliminate your enemies.
Honestly, Owen,
even if that were true...
who would believe you?
Ripped by:
SkyFury