Ma'am.
Stop.
All right, that's enough.
That's enough.
Next. Come on.
I said stop!
Yeah! Yeah!
Aloha, kids.
Don't forget
to buy your tickets
for the Hawaiian
Hula Prom tonight.
Tickets are on sale
outside the main office
or at the door. Aloha!
Get your prom tickets,
only 50 bucks.
- What a rip-off.
- It's gonna be a very special night...
That's okay.
Get your prom tickets.
Greetings
and welcome
to the 59th official
Sci-Fi Club meeting.
Hold on, isn't this supposed to be
the Amnesty International meeting?
They're here at 3:00.
Guys, guys, stay.
- We got food coming.
- Dork.
Scalpel cam.
Mm, oh, yeah.
Nasty.
Looks great
on the macro lens.
I'm just gonna have to
take your word for it.
I cannot wait to take you
to the prom tonight.
Okay, Jimmy, we gotta get to work.
Come on.
Don't tell me.
Tell the frog.
You can have all of me,
Lindsey, my love,
cut me open, take my heart.
It is yours.
I feel the same way, froggy.
And so do I, froggy.
Jimmy, quit acting like an idiot
and dissect your frog.
And you... how many times have I told you
shut that camera off before I break it.
You, cheerleader, take your scalpel
and cut open your frog.
I can't. I like frogs.
There's the stomach.
There's the liver.
There's the pancreas.
There's the brain.
Look at it.
What a dick.
What was that?
I was just saying what an inspiration
you are to all of us, sir.
I mean, it's teachers like you
that really make a difference.
Stand up.
Seeing as we're dissecting
animals today, class,
I'd like everyone
to take a look at this one...
James Dunn,
Jimmy Dunn Dunn
Dumb Dumb Dumb Dumb Dumb.
Notice the brain
devoid of all
intelligent thought;
capable of only C-minus average,
barely passing high school;
the mouth, big and loud,
always running
with nothing to say.
Note the hands,
only worthy of working
at a drive-though;
a loser, a nothing,
a nobody.
You may be seated.
Um, Mr. Hammond,
you forgot one organ.
And I think you know
what you can do with that.
See you in detention.
Man, why did I get in trouble?
Guilty by association.
Sorry.
Man, fuck this school.
Kyle. Kyle.
Do not make me
call the police again.
Sit down.
Relax.
Shh.
Please.
Are you recording?
Hey, this is Kyle Grubbin.
This is a screen test.
Yeah!
- You faggots looking at something?
- No.
I wonder which one of his sisters
he's taking to the prom.
Dude, shut up.
I heard he carries a gun in his truck.
Dunn, you're up.
Just relax.
He can't even hear me.
Yo.
That was amazing.
Okay.
It looks really good
on camera.
So I heard your date
to the prom got sick.
Yeah.
Still going?
I wanted to talk to you about that.
Really? Wow.
You can do it, Steven!
Are those the...?
Yeah, the sci-fi guys.
Total geeks.
Do you know them?
No.
Come on, Steven,
ask her!
- Use the force, Steven the force!
- Come on!
Will you guys shut up?
I'm trying to talk to Gwen.
So should I ask him?
Him?
Him...
Nash Rambler.
Nash, the band guy?
He's, like, 30.
I mean, you're a guy, Steve.
What would you say?
Yeah, I'd say yes.
Really?
Okay.
I'm gonna go ask him.
- Oh, right now?
- Wish me luck, okay?
Yeah.
Good luck.
Hey, listen, listen.
Forget her.
We have got a serious
Sci-Fi Club meeting tonight.
Yes, we do, baby.
Bring your camera.
Bring your camera, all right?
Jules, I'm not going to another
robotics convention.
Ha ha, funny.
Child's play, my friend.
Listen, I want you to focus.
Great secrets will be revealed tonight,
my young Gandalf.
You got that?
Steven, I know it hurts, okay?
Let it out.
Steven, Steven,
your destiny awaits.
- Your destiny.
- Destiny, Steven, destiny.
Destiny.
My destiny was back there.
Come on, dude.
There are three As in "Hawaiian."
And we have 10 hours
until this dance starts.
Okay, so either you
work with me, people,
or you get the eff out of here.
Sorry. Sorry.
I'm just super stressed.
Hey hey hey,
don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
Hey, can we get someone
to take that down, please?
Thanks.
So I heard
Jimmy got kicked out
of Hammond's class again.
Yeah.
Are you seriously
going to prom with him?
Mitch, we've talked
about this.
I am going to prom
with Jimmy.
In the pizza wagon?
Please.
You want to smell like pepperoni
or vanilla bean air freshener?
Do you smell that?
Something's in the air.
This town always
smells like ass, man.
No no, this is... this is bad.
Between global warming
and smog
and that freakin'
power plant down the block,
we're killing
ourselves, bro.
Am I interrupting?
No.
I'm Gwen from third hour.
You do good flips.
Thanks.
Um, I was wondering,
are you taking anyone
to the prom tonight?
I mean, I was gonna go,
but then my date
ate bad spinach.
So now I'm going solo.
Yep, solo.
Are you taking anyone?
I'd rather chew my tongue off
with a mouthful of gasoline
than go to that fucking dance.
May I ask why?
Because we refuse to listen
to the Piñata Heads play.
That's why.
If Quarter Punks don't play,
Quarter Punks don't go.
Tell you what... go ahead
and skip that prom,
come over
and watch us play,
and afterwards
you can give me head.
Shut up and stare, goofball.
- This is detention, not dreamland.
- Yes, sir.
I thought I told you
to say nothing.
So what do you say
when I say to say nothing?
Nothing.
You must think I'm a real idiot,
don't you?
Oh, so you do think
I'm an idiot then?
Answer me, boy!
Sir, you told me not to talk.
What the hell are you talking to me
right now then for, sissy boy?
It's 30 more minutes of watching
the Brick Channel for you...
all brick all the time.
You may not believe this, Dunn,
but I'm trying to help you.
You do want to do something
with your life, don't you?
Yes, you do.
You don't want
to wind up alone, Dunn,
credit card debt
up the wazoo,
nobody to talk to
but your dog,
ex-wife won't return
your phone calls
'cause she's a bitter, fat,
stinking piece of hog meat.
What are you looking at?
Drop and give me 50
and count them off!
Everyone thinks
prom is this big event
that they're gonna remember
for the rest of their life,
but really it's just
an excuse for kids
to get together and get freaky
on the dance floor.
You'll forget it in 10 years.
No, I won't.
Yeah, you will.
Will you forget us in 10 years?
Maybe, if I have Alzheimer's.
Oh, gee, how sweet.
Jimmy, did you even
get me a corsage?
No.
I got us a motel room, though.
You know, Jimmy,
it would be really nice
if you were romantic
for once, you know?
I'm romantic.
That thing this morning
with the frog...
that got a huge laugh.
Is everything a joke to you?
Yes, it is.
Well, I'm not a joke.
I'm a woman.
And I'd like a corsage
instead of a dead frog.
Wow, I'm sorry.
You called yourself a woman.
That's it.
That's it. I am not going
to prom with you.
What? Are you serious?
Yes, unlike you, I am serious.
I'm not going to prom with you.
You can't do that.
Yeah, I can. I just did.
Why?
Jimmy,
you spend more time
in detention
than you do in class.
And everything
is a joke to you.
It's just not funny anymore.
Prom.
I'll never ask for anything else again.
That's all I want.
I just want to be prom queen, please.
I'm gonna be prom queen.
This is gonna be awesome.
I'm so glad we're not
going to the prom.
Hey guys, you ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's lock and load.
Prom, baby, yeah!
Stupid spinach.
Smell that?
Vanilla bean, baby.
Have fun.
Don't hit your crust.
Dunn, I got a delivery for you.
No can do, boss.
I'm going to the prom.
It's my car you're
driving, shitball.
You do what I tell you.
Aye aye, Captain.
Freakin' boss.
I know it's kind of strange,
but it's the best view in town.
Mitch, I thought we were
going to the dance.
We are. I just thought,
since you've been
working so hard,
we just take a breather,
you know, loosen up a bit.
Oh.
Yeah, so I was thinking
about running for student council
again next year,
but I think I might
just take a year off...
you know, give other people
a chance to win.
But then I remembered
what my dad always said...
"Never never never
let other people win."
We went to the cemetery
last month, Jules.
Yes, well, we did,
but not with this.
I got it from my brother
who works at MIT.
As an accountant.
Whatever.
He snuck it out of R&D.
He said it was developed
as some sort of prototype
to handle
ultra-high-frequency levels
of extrasensory activity
within a 10' radius.
- Nice.
- Stop.
- What does it say?
- I don't know.
It didn't come with
an instruction manual.
Whoa!
Y'all boys
shouldn't be here.
Oh, we're doing
research
of a family tree.
My uncle's buried...
in the Civil War
he was shot.
And we're looking
for the, uh, grave.
- Right, guys? Yeah.
- Yeah.
Stick to the path right here.
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
What was that?
I don't know, man,
but I got the willies bad right now.
Yeah, in your pants.
Come on, let's go.
You're the vice president.
I'm the president.
He's... he's a joke.
I just mean
you deserve to be
with somebody
who respects you.
I really like you, Lindsey.
I just want you
to be happy, that's all.
Don't mess up my hair.
Hey, shut up.
There's people
making out in there.
Come on.
- George.
- Get off me.
- George, come on.
- Just leave me.
This is it.
- Are you getting it?
- Yeah.
This is definitely it.
Oh, this thing is going crazy.
- Come on.
- Jules, what are you doing?
Okay, we saw it, Jules.
It's very pretty. Let's go back.
Dude, it's open.
Come on.
Dude, we're not
going in there.
You came all this way
to turn around and go home?
Fine, go home, little girl,
go home.
I'm going in.
Come on.
Oh, guys,
you gotta see this.
- Steven.
- Shut up.
Holy crap.
Why is it on the floor?
Is that even sanitary?
Rod, open it.
I'm not even coming in there, man.
You open it.
- George.
- I'm not gonna touch that thing.
Damn it, guys,
somebody's gotta open it.
Since, Jules, you're the president
of the Sci-Fi Club
maybe you want
to be our leader
and jump in there
and try to...
All right, fine.
I'll do it.
Pussies.
Still rolling, Jules.
All right.
It's empty.
Christ.
You all right, Rod?
Come on.
There it is again.
It's just the seats.
No, it's moaning.
Sorry, my fault.
I can't move my legs that way.
Got it.
Mitch, I don't think you should...
It's okay.
No, Mitch, really.
No, Mitch, stop.
- Shut up.
- Stop it.
Mitch?
Aw, hell.
Come on, come on!
I said...
Stay on the path.
What, you knew about this?
Why didn't you tell us?
Hey, man, I'm just
trying to keep my job.
Hit 'em in the brain.
It's the only way to kill 'em.
Come on.
Come on, come on,
come on.
- Oh, God.
- Open the door! Open the door!
I just killed those people.
No, you didn't.
Open the door.
Get in.
Hey, no eating in store.
Pizza Wagon.
Yum-yum, come get some.
Come on, people.
I got a prom to go to
without my girlfriend.
Ma'am, I see you.
Whoa.
Are you okay?
Okay, all right.
I'm gonna call 911,
or not.
Uh, someone help, anyone.
Ma'am, ma'am, I'm not gonna
be able to help you
if you don't stop
biting at me like that.
Okay?
Uh, sorry to interrupt.
Here comes
the neighborhood.
Smoking out of
the devil bong, man.
Devil bong!
Close the door,
Jensen.
All right, that's what
I'm talking about!
Hey, you kids.
Principal Castlemoody.
- Is that beer?
- No.
Give me that.
Yeah, you too, smart guy.
You're lucky I don't
call your mamas.
Get back in there.
Get!
Punk-ass kids.
Oh, God.
Mr. Hammond, you scared
the crap out of me.
What happened
to your face, Frank?
Don't move
or I'll scorch you.
Kyle?
Yeah.
They gone?
I don't know,
but are you okay?
Get your hands off me.
You're lucky I'm not kicking
your ass right now.
Drop it, Kyle.
It's tired.
What?
Your friends are dead and those things
are coming back this way
and I'd rather not be
here when they do.
Man, piss off!
I ain't scared
of nothing... nothing.
Are you serious?
I just heard you crying over there
like a bitch
a second ago.
How do I know you are not
one of them, huh?
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't
pop your head off right now.
Yo, man, they're jacking your car.
You assholes!
Wait up!
Damn it. My boss
is gonna kill me.
Whoa.
Do you have
a license for that?
No carnivorous cocksucker
is gonna mess with me.
Who are you calling?
Who do you think?
The cops.
No, no cops.
My daddy's a cop.
Great.
No, I hate my daddy.
No cops.
Don't be ridiculous.
We need them.
Who is the man
with the gun?
Kyle, I'm on your side.
Those are the guys
you want to shoot.
Waste 'em.
What is taking you
so long?
I have got to load it.
All right?
Come on, come on.
Wow.
That was disturbing.
- Hey, watch this.
- No!
Sorry, Gwen,
it was a mistake.
Jimmy, are you crazy?
Jimmy!
I gotta
get out of here.
Come on, man, wait up.
- Just go, just drive!
- I'm driving.
- Stop arguing, just drive.
- I'm not arguing.
We're all gonna die
because of you.
- Jules, shut up.
- Listen, don't tell me to shut up.
I brought the shotgun.
I got the second-most power in this car.
I keep dialing 911,
but the number's busy.
- How can it be busy?
- I don't know.
- Just keep dialing then.
- I have been.
Just dial the number.
Now, it's 911. 411's information.
Thanks, Jules, thanks,
Aren't you Jimmy Dunn's
girlfriend?
Uh-huh.
Then whose car is this?
Go go go go.
What are you...?
- Don't stop the car.
- Why are you stopping?
I didn't do anything.
It just stopped.
- They ripped through the engine?
- Apparently so.
What are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do, guys?
Does anyone have
a plan or something?
Why don't you shut up and try thinking
of one yourself, princess, okay?
Hey, easy.
Let's not bite
each other's heads off.
That's kind of funny.
It is kind of funny.
I didn't think of it like that.
It works kind of both ways.
It's funny but it's not.
Guys, if you don't
straighten up
you're gonna end up
like Rod.
That's not cool, man.
What is she doing?
Lindsey, let's go.
Come on.
It's chicks like that
that make me glad
I don't have a girlfriend.
- Right.
- What's that supposed to mean?
Pick up, Jimmy.
Please pick up.
Jimmy?
It's Jimmy.
Hey, guys, it's Jimmy.
Jimmy! Jimmy!
Thank God he's alive.
Jimmy?
It's not Jimmy.
Run!
My dress.
You made me
rip my dress.
- Guys, it's locked.
- Open it.
Shut the door.
Don't. Shut up, Jules.
She's coming.
She's not gonna make it.
Shut the door.
- Lindsey, come on.
- Let's go, hurry up.
He's right
behind you.
- There's more coming.
- Guys, we need to board up this door.
Find whatever you can
and use it.
We need to board up these windows
and that door too. Let's go.
Whoa whoa whoa,
who put you in charge?
I am vice president
of the student council.
Oh, yeah? Well, I'm the president
of the Sci-Fi Club.
And you're the genius who brought us
here tonight. I'm with her.
Okay, come on. Let's get this couch,
move it in front of the door.
Here, George over here.
Steven, right there.
Go, come on, faster.
You hold this.
Wait a second.
No no no, we're not staying.
Jules, either help out or get
the eff out of the way, okay?
Why is this happening?
End of the world.
God's flushing the toilet.
It's his way of saying,
"Y'all couldn't work it out,
so adios."
I didn't take you
for a religious man, Kyle.
I just tell it
like the Bible does.
I'm gonna need
years of therapy after this.
Gwen, it's gonna be okay.
Liar.
Shut up, Kyle.
Dude, watch the window.
Oh, thank God it's Jimmy.
Hey, Lindsey,
are you all right?
Tell her I say hi.
Where are you?
Where are we?
Guys, where are we?
- I don't know.
- I think we're at a corner of Oak,
in the house
near Millpond.
Oak and Millpond?
Yeah, Oak and Millpond.
We can get there from here.
Just stay right where you are.
I'll come and get you.
Really?
Of course.
I'll be there.
Okay.
Whoa whoa whoa, hey,
who said you get to go
get your girl?
She's with other people, Kyle.
It's better protection.
She'd better be worth it.
She is.
We can crawl
across town down here
without them
ever seeing us.
I used to play down here
when I was a little kid.
You was one messed up
little kid, huh?
- Yeah.
- Me too.
Hurry.
Go on.
Go on, girl.
Come on, this way.
Oh my God.
It stinks.
Whoa.
What is that?
Is that poop?
That shit ain't shit.
Something's wrong
with that shit.
Must you curse so much?
Looks like the power plant's
been dumping
something fierce
down here.
This town's, like,
marinating in it.
It must have finally reached
its boiling point.
Ugh, I shouldn't
be here right now.
I should be at prom
in a beautiful dress,
slow-dancing
with Nash or somebody.
Hey, I'm somebody.
So what we got is,
"I slept with my
third-grade teacher."
Teacher... what rhymes
with "teacher"?
- She was a sexual creature.
- Preacher. Preacher.
- Sexual creature.
- "Creature" is the way to go.
"She was
a sexual creature.
She always made me
feel all right."
- She kept me up at night.
- She flew my kite.
Dude, chill out, man.
Seriously, stay in the circle.
Okay, like it.
I like it.
"She made me feel all right.
- She kept me up all night."
- Kept me up all night.
"She taught me the ways
of multiplication."
Multiplication...
that's what she taught.
And led to my first
masturbation.
God damn, no,
Jensen, man.
You've hotboxed
the entire garage.
I swear, you've smoked
us all stupid.
- Go open the door.
- Open the door, go.
- "Masturbation."
- I can't even hear myself think.
How do you expect me to get
to the next level with this song?
One of you jokers laced my joint
with formaldehyde again?
Whoa.
Want to touch
my Mohawk?
- Kyle, would you stop?
- You smell good.
I think this is it.
I am not going in there.
Okay, go go go.
It's dark.
Come on.
Come on,
let's go.
Hello?
Lindsey?
- Creepy.
- There's a light.
A door.
Come on.
Yeah yeah,
this is it.
Jimmy!
You've found us.
I'm so glad
you're okay.
Steven, I'm okay.
You've got your tux.
You look nice.
You look wonderful,
baby.
You can let go now.
Sorry. Yeah.
Awkward, dude.
Oh, shit. Hey, Kyle Grubbin,
what are you doing here?
Bashing heads, turning shit up...
you know, the usual.
Kyle couldn't get
a date to the prom.
All the farm animals
were busy.
Man, I screw college girls.
So how did you end up
with these guys?
We were at the cemetery
and these things... they just came out
and they pulled Mitch
and they took...
Wait, Mitch? What were you doing
at the cemetery with Mitch?
We were just parked,
you know, by the bluff.
Mitch Cutter?
You were with him?
Yeah, but nothing happened.
Mitch Cutter.
At least have the decency to dump me
for someone cool.
The guy's a tool,
and you're a tool
by association.
Why him?
Because he took
life seriously
and I thought he liked me.
He liked you on the back seat
of his car.
Wonderful.
Move that chair.
No, give it to me.
Give it to Kyle.
Looks good, Kyle.
That should do it, yeah.
You chew?
Yeah, I'm Jewish.
Why?
I'll try some of that.
Mm, that's good.
You don't know
how weird this is, man.
Remember last year we were in gym
and you tripped over me
and started to hit me
in the face for no reason,
I started bleeding and everybody
started laughing
and I started to cry?
Remember that?
Nuh-uh.
Hey, you remember
junior year when you...
oh, okay.
You remember
junior year when
you broke my arm
'cause you said
I looked at you funny?
Remember that?
Man, that was you?
Yeah.
Man.
Good times.
Yeah.
How's your arm?
Not good, actually.
Um, but Kyle,
I hate to admit it,
but I'm actually glad
you're here.
You're the biggest
badass I know.
Hoorah!
Too bad we didn't
go to prom together.
Then we wouldn't be
in this mess.
We were supposed to go
to the prom together?
That was kind of my plan.
But you never asked me.
Eh, you would have
said no.
Steven, if I had a choice
between this place
and going to prom
with you,
I would have
chosen you.
You guys...
we're in a funeral home.
Yo, who farted?
Go!
- Is she dead?
- I don't know, George.
- Why don't you check her pulse?
- Is everybody okay?
There's got to be
a light somewhere.
Someone find the light switch.
Come on.
I can't see anything.
Feel along the walls.
Jules, is that you?
Steven, get off me.
Sorry, Gwen.
I think I got it.
Ugh.
Crazy old bitch.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Where did he go?
Make yourself useful.
Load it.
Now!
- George, get out of the way.
- Hey!
It hurts.
Am I dying?
No, man, you're fine.
Liar.
Jim, I'm sorry I whacked you
at school today.
Shh, don't talk.
I'm sorry I was a dick.
It's okay.
I deserved it.
Jim, do me a favor.
Anything.
Kill 'em all.
Kyle.
What are we gonna do?
Um, Jimmy,
he just got bit.
So shouldn't we, like, leave?
Hey.
Are you okay?
This is
such a tragedy.
I really really just wanted everything
to be perfect.
Oh, gosh, the prom.
Every teenager in town
is at that prom.
Oh, man.
Guys, all that noise,
all the fresh meat...
every zombie in town
will be there.
It will be
a feeding frenzy.
Our entire high school
class will be gone.
- History.
- All of 'em.
No one's picking up.
We have to warn
everyone.
What, you're going
to the prom?
Are you crazy?
It's, like, 1000 to six.
We just got to stay here. I'm sure
the government knows about this.
They have to. They should be
sending somebody.
Look...
if we die two weeks from now
or two hours,
I'd like to go out fighting.
If we don't stop those things
from getting to the prom,
then our world is over.
I'm tired of being a lower.
Okay.
So how do we get there?
We fight our way.
With what?
- With this.
- And with this.
- Don't be stupid. The gun's empty.
- No, it's not.
Now it is.
Guys, there's a hearse
out front...
a hearse big enough for six.
So who's the fastest runner?
I don't have
my sneakers on today.
And I don't have any shoes.
I have asthma.
And I have a wooden leg.
Come on, guys,
if you can run fast, you say so.
Um...
I can move pretty fast.
Yeah, send the cheerleader.
That's a great idea.
Guys, I can see the hearse.
It's by the curb.
You don't have
to do this, Gwen.
You're right.
You do it.
Me? I'm not really athletic.
See what I mean?
All right,
is everybody ready?
Jules, on three.
One...
- two...
- Dear God, be with Gwen.
She runs for her life
into hell.
I don't like it.
I don't want to go.
Three!
Come on.
Go!
All clear.
Run, Gwen.
Go go go go!
God, I love that girl.
I'm sorry.
Guys, come on,
get in the car!
Come on,
Steven, quick!
Let's go, let's go,
let's go!
I'm going as fast as I can!
This is a hearse!
- Is everybody okay?
- Yes.
I'm good.
We're good.
- George, did you find a map?
- Yeah, I got one in my pants.
It's a big map.
Where am I gonna get a map from?
Guys, what the hell was that?
That was a tire.
It blew out.
Someone shot it.
I think someone shot at us.
Who would be shooting at us?
I'll take you first, monsters!
Don't shoot, Coach!
- Who's that?
- Coach Keel, don't shoot.
Jimmy Dunn, fourth period.
You had me in detention today.
Dunn?
Them sons of bitches
ate my dog.
They ate my dog,
my German shepherd,
the best bitch I've ever had.
I was able to keep them green boys
away from the neighbors for a bit,
but they got to one,
then they got to another and another,
so I had to kill
the whole block.
Yeah, it's been a rough one
for all of us.
- Hey.
Ooh, boy,
looks like you got
yourself a platoon.
Where are y'all going?
To the prom,
to kick some zombie ass.
The prom...
it'll be a regular Thanksgiving-day
supper for them green boys.
All right, we'd better
get suited up then.
Suited up?
You don't win wars with toothpicks
and cheddar cheese, missy.
You gotta be prepared.
Ain't that right, Dunn?
Yes, sir.
All right, let's get in gear.
We got us a war to win.
I wish it was a corsage.
Little lady,
you'll get the machete.
But I don't know
how to shoot a machete.
What the hell is wrong
with you, son?
Whoa, is this what
I think it is, Coach?
Don't move, kid!
Don't move!
Don't move.
Don't you move.
You can take out
the whole city block with this.
Whoosh!
No eyebrows, man,
a mushroom cloud,
the whole deal.
I got this off craigslist
for emergencies only.
Everyone gets a walkie.
Tune to channel 22.
Let's sync
those watches, people.
Come on,
move move move!
Do we have any more
helmets, Jules?
No, man.
Well, can I have
that one, please?
Sorry, it's the last one.
Stop.
Dude, come on, you're taller
than me, Jules.
- Please?
- No.
This is so cool.
No guns for you kids.
Guns are mine, all mine.
I don't want to repeat
history, man,
like Rod did.
Please?
Rod?
Jules...
Thanks.
Um, can we say a prayer?
I know it sounds super dorky,
but we really need it.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Make it quick, okay?
Okay, everyone hold hands.
Gay.
Shut up, Jules.
Continue, Lindsey.
Okay, um,
dear God,
we don't know why you've brought
the dead back to life,
but you have.
So we pray that you help us
through tonight...
Mm-hmm.
...help us to help others
through tonight.
Lord, we know this is
not a perfect world
and we are
far from perfect,
but could you please
lend us a hand here?
Protect us.
In Jesus's name...
For the love of Buddha,
are we done?
...amen.
Let's rock.
Bitchin' ride, Coach.
It took me three years
to save up for her,
but she's worth it.
Why aren't they attacking?
Who cares?
They're sitting ducks.
Wait a second...
Oh!
Ew, is he done yet?
Not yet.
Okay, I think he's done.
Oh, not yet.
Yes. No.
Oh, that did it.
Yeah, he's done.
Now do you jerkoffs believe me
about the power plant?
- Nash!
- Spinach!
Oh, great, it's Nash.
What's up, guys?
Why weren't they attacking you?
They dig our sound, man.
What?
We were just in the garage,
jamming out.
And then all of a sudden
they came after us.
And at first we were freaked,
but then we realized
they were listening
to our music.
The more I watched them,
the more I realized
they're communicating
with each other like bugs, like...
- Bees, dude. They're like bees.
- Yes.
And we're like the queen bee.
And then they hear us
and they tune in
and then they check out.
The more we started playing,
the more they started coming.
That was, like,
five hours ago.
You guys have been playing
for five hours straight?
Hey, we needed
the practice.
That's amazing.
It's okay.
Oh, no, thanks.
I'm high on life.
Hoorah!
Queers, make a hole.
- Whew.
- Good job, Coach.
Dude.
- That was amazing.
- 10 years of training.
- God bless America.
- Amen.
We gotta shut that
power plant down.
It's too late.
What's done is done.
The only thing we can do now is
kill what it created.
Yeah, so take these
and follow us.
Thanks, babe,
but we got our weapons.
Apocalypse.
Where did they all go?
Where do you think?
Jimmy, look,
it's the sign-in book.
Oh.
Dude, that's Miss Raines,
my English teacher.
Aw, I liked her.
We're too late.
Every zombie in town
is here.
That's the guy from
the comic book store.
That's my mailman.
You give me two minutes,
I'll have this school wired
like a crackhead
drinking a Red Bull.
Listen up. Here's what
we're gonna do.
All right,
here's the entrance.
Here's the gymnasium.
I'm gonna drop
some firecrackers
right here, here and here.
Now you kids, you're gonna have to
board up the entrances
right here, here and here.
We got one shot at this.
So let's do it right.
You got it?
- Yeah.
- All right, let's go.
Adios, amigos.
We'll see you on the other side.
That should hold it.
Okay, good.
Did you guys
hear that?
Stop pushing me.
Please, don't hit us.
We're not one of them.
It's okay. I'm Jules Ryder.
I'm here to rescue you.
They ate the prom king.
It's okay.
I'm here to help.
Thank you.
It's okay.
You'll be all right.
All right, everybody,
we're gonna get you out of here.
I need you to stay together.
You got me?
Stay together
if you want to live.
All right, Dunn,
I just gotta set
the roof explosives.
Of course this shit
was a lot easier
when I was
20 lbs lighter.
All right, Jimmy,
it's Hiroshima time.
I just gotta
shimmy to safety
and we'll turn this bitch
into Baghdad.
Oh, no!
Shit!
Dunn, are you there?
Over.
Go for Jimmy.
I dropped the damn remote.
The remote?
The remote to set off
the explosives.
It landed right in the damn plate
of potato chips.
Son of a bitch.
Dunn, you listen to me.
You've got to get that remote.
I'd go myself, but I got
one other charge I got to set
and we got no time.
It's a one-way ticket, son,
but you gotta buy it.
Over.
I'm going in the gym.
Are you nuts?
Somebody's got to get
that remote.
They're not gonna see me
if I stick to the shadows and move fast.
Jules, get everybody
out of here
and as far away from the school
as possible.
- You got it.
- Jimmy, no.
I'll be right back.
Jimmy, please.
All right, come on, let's go.
Move it, move it.
This place is gonna blow.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go, come on.
Gwen!
Gwen, are you okay?
I'm fine.
My helmet, Jules.
My helmet. I love you.
I love you too, man,
but we gotta go.
We gotta go.
Come on.
It's all clear.
Let's go.
- Hey.
- Lindsey, no.
What are you doing?
Jimmy, I'm not
leaving you again.
Besides, I planned this prom.
I'm not gonna miss it.
You did a real good job
with this stuff, babe.
Really?
Thanks.
There it is.
Hold on.
Let's go.
- Jimmy.
- I'm here.
Very slowly follow my lead.
We have to find that remote.
Not bad for a couple of queers.
Do you see it?
No. Do you?
Jimmy, I'm sorry.
You don't ever have to
tell me you're sorry.
Let's go, come on.
Steven, I need to talk to you.
Gwen, the school
is about to explode.
Steven, I need you.
Please.
Oh, Jeez.
Steven, please don't tell them.
They'll kill me.
Gwen...
Please, Steven.
I'm just so cold.
- Gwen.
- Just hold me, okay?
Just hold me.
It's okay.
I'm not gonna
let them kill you.
I won't let you die.
I promise.
You're the best.
Please, Steven.
There it is.
Jensen, Jensen, plug it in.
Plug it in, man, plug it in!
Mitch?
Here we go again.
No no, Jimmy, Jimmy,
Mitch, Mitch!
Whoa whoa.
Jimmy!
Come on, come on, come on.
Take this.
Shit, it's the band.
We got the detonator.
Let's go.
No way, man.
This is the best set of our lives.
If you don't hurry up this is gonna be
the last set of your life.
Now come on.
Thank you, Cosa High School.
Good night.
Come on, come on,
come on.
Go go go!
Coach, is everybody out?
Everybody but me.
Count to 10.
Let's drop
those nukes.
- We locked those doors.
- That shit's not cool.
We're not gonna make it.
Get out of the way.
Safety glass.
- Jensen, come on, come on.
- Jimmy.
Jensen!
Oh!
- Go! Go!
- Go go go.
Push!
I'm slipping.
Hammond.
Jimmy.
Jimmy!
Come on.
- Come on.
- Everybody down!
Lindsey.
I love you.
Yes!
Hot damn, Dunn.
I was wrong about you.
You are a good soldier.
- Kick ass!
- Yeah!
Bring any marshmallows?
No, sir.
Steven.
Hey, congratulations
on winning prom queen.
Yeah.
Like it matters.
Tell me about it.
Who are you guys?
We're the Sci-Fi Club.
Really?
Do you believe in UFOs?
Yeah.
I saw one once.
Me too.
Wow, this is, you know...
Wow.
George...
no.
How are you?
I want to give you this.
It will protect you, just in case.
Okay.
You know what?
Actually, no.
We've got to shut down that power plant
before it spreads.
It's the way Jensen
would have wanted it.
Rock 'n' roll, brother.
Sounds like a plan,
pretty boy.
You in, ace?
Yes, sir.
Lindsey?
You go, I go.
All right, first things first...
the coach wants to go
to the pancake house.
There we'll all have
breakfast and juice on the coach.
Then we'll discuss
stage two of this op.
Sound good?
Pancakes
are cool.
Roger that.
Subtitles by LeapinLar