Now, I want you to try and
tell us everything that happened
Anything you can remember
I can't, I can't remember
We need your help so we
can find the other children
A house
- What?
- They took us to a house
- Who?
- I don't know... people
Do you think the other
children are still there?
Do you think they've been hurt?
Yes
You're doing just fine
We're going to find them
But We need you to tell us more
You've got to try and remember
I can't, I can't remember anything
Shit!
- Drink it
- But...
No complaints. Drink
- Did you get 'em?
- Get what?
The pencils
Yeah
Has he had breakfast?
- We're on it. How did it go?
- I'm brushed...
I think it's going to take
me a while to get used to it...
...and on top of that, night shifts
Don't worry, you're just starting
Anyhow I'm going to my father
about getting your shift changed
We'll see
Do you know where the toaster is?
I have no idea
We still have tons of boxes left to open
Unless you give me a hand, I give up
Hey, big guy
Hi
- Today's your first day, isn't it?
- Yeah
- You nervous?
- A little
You'll see that you'll like it
You'll make lots of friends soon
Come on, Paul
You're gonna be late, come on
Bye
It's about time
I was just about to get you up
We've got to do
It's too early
And I have swim practice
That's not for two hours
And travel
This is the sticks, I have
to take the bus everywhere
I'm not waiting any longer for this
to start looking like a real house
We've been here almost three weeks,
and with the notable
exception of myself,
one has unpacked one single box
And don't forget, you promised
you were going to paint your room
Mom, I don't I don't know if I'm staying
I thought we discussed this, Reggie
You know how your father and I feel
When have you ever listened to me?
I just want to finish school
in the States with my friends
Is that so abnormal?
- Hi
What are you doing here?
You're crazy
I'm not doing anything wrong
I'm just here to pick
up my American friend
Well, you got here too
late 'cause I got to go
Just tell me if you're gonna stay
I'm not
- Come on, you got to go
- Why not?
Go, please
They saw you
- We'll talk about it later
- Promise?
I promise
I'm warning you,
it's not going to be easy for your
family to live in another country
Especially for the kids
Oh, I know It's a big move I'm
sure hoping they'll get used to it
It's a great place
Think so?
It needs work
Yeah, That's true
A hammer and nails and a
bit of paint, you'll see
Plus I got one month
before semester starts
Good luck
Did you meet?
- No Hi
- How ya doing?
I was just saying, it's
like a dream come true
You know what? He's lying
You don't want to play anymore?
Oh, thanks
Everybody seems to be
having a good time, right?
Paul reminds me of Mark
when he was that age
Before he...
...left
Now you'll have your
grandchildren all to yourself
and you're gonna get sick of them
Yes
It must be strange for them
Poor Paul
He'll end up crazy about you... you'll see
I'm gonna get jealous
It's good to see you, dad
That's it, it's over
Finally I thought it would never end
Way to close a party
Not again
...experts suggest to be cautious.
Never look directly at the sun...
...nor the optical device...
...so take care, but make sure not to miss
it. Don't forget it's a unique event,
...a very special eclipse...
...that takes place only every 40
years and there are just 5 days to go...
- You lived here with grandpa?
- Yeah, when I was your age
That's when you left for the States?
Why did you have to?
Well, your grandparents
decided to split up and
I didn't have a choice, I had to go
With your mom?
That's right
Are you and mom going
- To split up?
- No
Only families that
don't get along split up
We get along, don't we?
Yeah
It's the second day and I
bet I'm the only one late
Don't worry, you'll make it
"We're like the lonely wildebeest
bleating his plaintive
poetry to the infinite herd"
Hey dad, do you even
know what a wildebeest is?
Sure it's
It's like a cow
And what's your cow saying?
"Get your ass
out of my face"
Dad look, it worked
Dad?
Hey, shithead, what
are you doing? Move it!
Fuck!
Help me!
Please!
- When Was his last attack?
- More than ten years ago
Haughtington is unpredictable,
but it doesn't have to be serious
As quickly as it has come, it can go
I don't know
I'm going to give him Haloperidol
But if he does have an attack,
you know about the risk of choking
Just keep a close eye on him
This couldn't come at a worse time
Don't worry, everything will be fine
Trust me
Dad
I'm okay sweetie, nothing's happened
Come on, let's go inside
We've still got a lot
of work ahead of us
This is going to be the
best house in the whole world
Mom?
What happened?
Your father had a small attack,
but it's nothing, don't worry
I've been talking to your grandfather
He's got to go back on medication
for a while and that's all
Mom
It's starting again
Nothing is starting again
This is an isolated incident
Don't blow it out of proportion
You remember what happened
You know exactly what this is
And just now
Just now what?
We're completely isolated, what
if something were to happen?
We're ten minutes away from
downtown and I already told you,
nothing's going to happen
- Mom
- What?
If you don't like this
house or your family,
then get your things and go
Isn't that what you wanted, to go?
Well, go on then!
I think we'll survive
Since the beginning of time...
...people considered this
phenomenon in different ways...
...but how do eclipses exactly work?...
- Feeling better?
- No
Come on, I fight with
my Mom all the time
It's normal
No it's not
She's never been this cruel before
I bet she didn't even notice
- Sometimes people say things that...
- I don't care
I'm not comfortable
I don't feel happy in that house
- Hey there, Tiger
- Hi
What are you doing?
Drawing
You don't play with this anymore
You used to like it
Are you going to die?
No
Listen buddy, what
happened is that your dad...
I got a little too tense
this morning
Forget about it
You're not going to let
that worry you, are you?
Come on...
...time for bed
Dad?
don't...
Come on...
...lights out
- You okay?
- Yeah
What are you doing up?
I couldn't sleep
Dad said I couldn't leave a light on
- Since when are you afraid of the dark?
- I'm not
So?
It's different here... the dark
What do you mean?
It eats my pencils
Come on, I'll tell you what, how’ bout
we make a deal? I'll lie down with you
- Until you fall asleep
- Promise?
Of course
Just give me a minute
Okay
- I can't find anything wrong
- There's definitely something wrong
Maybe you should check again
I don't know what it could be
Look, I'll check the sockets
Where's my drawing pad?
I left it here last night
- These are kind of weird drawings
- They're not weird
They're just drawings
Yeah, but you keep on
doing the same thing
They're not the same, they're different
They look the same to me
That's because they're all children
But they're different children
Paul?
What's this? Did you hurt yourself?
I don't know
Has mommy seen it?
Yeah, she says I probably
did it in my sleep
When it was dark
I'm going
If you go outside, don't
go near the road Okay?
Okay
What are you doing here?
I need to use up the last few frames
on this roll and you will be my model
I like you as a photographer, but I
think I like you better as a painter
Oh, Dad, this is Carlos
- Hi
- Hi Nice to meet you
Do you know anything about electricity?
No
Come on
It doesn't look like mold...
...it's more like rust
I don't understand
They painted the whole
house before we moved in
Trust me, baby...
...this is going to look great
It better
And I'm gonna go get some
paint thinner, just in case
If you want, phone the electric company
The hell with that, there's
something here that doesn't work
We've been here for three weeks
now, and every day the lights go out
They flicker, like the voltage
dropped Do you understand?
Look, if I were you,
I'd talk to the neighbors
If it's a supply thing, they'll
have noticed something too
What neighbors? We don't have neighbors
This is a fucking nightmare
Calm down, okay? I've done all I can
In other words, fuck you, right?
In my own house, and in my face Fuck you!
Well, you're not getting a
penny from me. Not a goddamn penny
The insurance company will pay
me either way. Tell it to them
Not now
What's wrong?
I'm staying
I can't leave now
I'm not going to ask you why
That's probably a good idea
What are you doing up? It's late
I was waiting up for you
I'm bushed
I hope you painted that room
I need to talk to you
Tomorrow I'm wrecked
You can't imagine how
busy it's been today
Why can't we just talk?
There’s something I need to tell you
You say not to worry but...
Dad is a bundle of nerves
You should have seen the way he blew
up at the electrician this morning
Oh, he's just...
- And like, Paul's not well. I mean...
- Paul's okay
Look at the drawings
I mean, does this look like the kind
of thing normal kids do? I mean
He's a kid You should have seen
the ones you used to make. Come on
Don't touch it!
Sorry
These old things can be pretty delicate
What's that?
A room. Hidden behind the wall
How did you know it was there?
Paul told me
Hey, check it out
What about hanging it here?
Fuck!
It works
That's the beauty of old things...
...no electricity required
I'll stop it
No
And you, little psychic. How
did you know that room was there?
What are you talking about?
- Dad said you told him it was there
- I didn't say anything. That's a lie
You want to be a martyr, fine
If you keep this up, I
don't know what we'll do
What's going on?
Nothing. Your brother's gone and
bruised himself again. That's all
Clumsy
Who did this to you?
Oh, Reggie don't start
Please, don't get paranoid
Don't get paranoid?
This has happened twice
Are you trying to tell me
there's nothing going on?
That's not what I'm saying.
All I'm saying is these things happen
He's got to be more careful, that's all
Mom, why do you refuse to see what
is staring you clearly in the face?
This is not normal
We'll talk to your grandpa.
Maybe he can talk to Paul, I don't know
What more do you want me to do?
I need to get the rust off the floor
Where did you guys put the matt knife?
I was opening boxes yesterday
It's gotta be in there somewhere
I don't understand you
- Honestly, I don't
- What's going on here?
Everything's fine. Great
Couldn't be better, right mom? Fantastic!
Maybe I'll go unpack something
What's up?
You said you weren't going to ask me why
What?
Why I'm staying
And?
I wanted you to ask me
My dad's kind of sick
He has this disease
It's called "Haughtington's Syndrome"
Just before Paul was
born it got really bad
He was having attacks
But you can't imagine...
...what it must be like to be
afraid of your own father
But he's okay now
The treatment took
He's been fine for years until now
Until now?
He's not doing so good
And there's definitely
something wrong with Paul
He's woken up with bruises twice now
Hold on
- You don't think?
- I don't think anything
He's acting weird and he barely speaks
Sometimes I think it's that house
You know, this thing is much
more complicated than it looks
Where's Paul?
Grandfather came to talk to him
They're upstairs
- I'm a Mothers worry
- Don't worry
Regina
I was beginning to think
I wouldn't get to see you
Hi, grandpa
- You're going to catch a cold
- Dry off, hon
Try and get him to stay for dinner
Thanks again
How are you?
I'm good. And Paul?
He's fine
I'm sure this is no big deal
The change of houses,
habits, environment
But he's never been
afraid of the dark before
I don't think that Paul's fear of
darkness is your biggest concern
Why would he hurt himself?
He's just trying to call attention
But Dad's been strange too
He's worse
He's aggressive
- Like he used to be
- That's nonsense, Regina
I know what you all went through
And I know it wasn't easy
But your father
is under control now
You need to stop worrying
Nothing is going to happen
- All right, dear?
- Thanks, grandpa
And now, I'm off
He says we shouldn't worry
Kids do strange things sometimes
We have to find a place
to hang that picture
I don't know
Mark, please... we're talking
about our children
They're going through a rough time
Reggie...
...she's at a difficult age
Maybe we're not being
understanding enough with her
And what about me?
Who's being understanding with me?
- What are you talking about?
- Come on, please
You don't think
I hear the little secret conversations
that go on behind my back?
You're losing it
Right! Exactly! That's exactly
the attitude I'm talking about
Thank you
I know where they get it from now
Mark, please, calm down
Did you take your medication?
Mark!
Mark?
Regina!
Mom?
Reggie, quickly!
Come over here
I'm feeling kinda woozy
Slow breaths, okay?
Hold it I have to get the alcohol
Not now!
Mom!
Where's the fuse box?
In the laundry room
Reggie!
Paul?
Paul, what's the matter? Let me in
They won't let me
- There's someone here
- Paul, let me in
I can't
- Paul!
- Dad!
Shut up!
You're scaring him!
I said, stop it! Dad!
Open this door right now!
Mom!
- Stop it!
- Shut up!
Let me go!
Stop!
Paul, honey, come here. It's okay
It's okay
I don't know
I got scared
We couldn't open the door
Baby,
- Are you all right?
- What's wrong with you?
I'm here now. It's okay. It's all over
It's not all over
They never go away. They only hide
Who? What are you talking about?
The kids...
What kids?
The ones in my room
They wouldn't let me out
They hate me. They say I'm an impostor
Paul...
...there's no one else here
Just you and me...
...and mom and dad
Those kids don't exist
You're imagining them
Yes they do. They come out when it's dark
They live in the dark
Didn't you hear them?
Didn't you?
- Hello
- Carlos?
- Reggie, is it late?
- I know, I know. I'm sorry
I need your help
What's wrong?
It's this house
Nobody has ever lived
in your house before
The guy who sold the
house to your father...
...doesn't even exist
Neither does the real
estate agent, or the lawyer
And the phone number that's on the
contract, has never been in service
So there's nothing We can check?
Maybe... I found some
information about the architect
Excellent
Wanna help me?
Where's Regina?
She left at the crack of dawn
I don't know
There's no one here
Hey, I've seen that guy before
He was standing outside my house...
...the other night, when it was raining
I'm sure it's him
Come on
You shouldn't have come
- You designed the house, right?
- I just drew the plans according...
...to the measurements they gave me
They?
They who?
I never saw anyone
Everything was taken care
of through an intermediary
All I had to do was draw...
...and keep quiet
That was the one thing they insisted on
But that wasn't the strange part
We've got to talk
Oh, yes. We've got to talk, about
that thing you hung up there
It's hideous
What are you talking about?
You told me to hang it there
What?
Last night
Right here
Honey,
- That is not the problem
- Oh, no?
Then what is the problem?
The larvae...
The what?
The larvae
They're everywhere
In the walls
I hear them whisper
They talk about us
We've got to do something
It was the design
The shape of the house
In some parts of the world,
a similar form is used
in the design and
construction of the temples,
or other types of occult architecture
Something about giving
birth to spiritual energy,
or entities
It's been so many years
But I didn't like it
- Reggie, I think we'd better get going
- No, just wait
And then...
...the thing with the kids happened
What are you planning to do?
Find them
They must have their nest
underneath this house somewhere
And I'm going to find it
Seven children
They never found them
Except one
When the police questioned him,
what he told them didn't make any sense...
...it was some crazy story about a round house
Just dark
So dark
I've spent years
obsessed with this story
Prowling
around the house
It's always been empty
And then suddenly,
one day, I find that a family's
living there
With a kid. For the first time
in 40 years
Why now?
So why haven't you called the police?
And tell them what?
You think they'll listen
to the crazy ramblings
of some old fart with
one foot in the grave?
- You could have told somebody
- Oh, yes...
I could have
But I didn't...
...you want to know why?
Because I was scared
What are you talking about?
Please go
That's all I know
Thank you for sharing your theories...
...Mr. Villalobos
My phone number
In case you remember something
Get your brother
- Out of the house
- Why?
Get him out
Mom!
It's okay
It's okay He had another
fit, but it's okay now
- Let's go
- No You're not driving like this
Carlos, can you take them
to the hospital, please?
Well, what about you?
I'm staying. There's
something I have to do here
Reggie
Carlos, please
Just go
Hello?
Hello
We're watching you, bitch
What the fuck do you want?
Well, I just wanted to tell
you your father will be fine...
...if that's all right with you
Mom...
I'm sorry I thought
you were someone else
Well, I guess we've
all been through a lot
Seems the problem was the tranquilizer
I gave him after he cut himself
It reacted badly with the Haloperidol
I'm a nurse...I should have known...
I don't think that's the problem
We need to talk
They're keeping him under
observation for a couple of days...
Mom?
"Ouroboros"
It's an old occult symbol
It means darkness...
...the return to the beginning...
- ...chaos
- What's going on in my house?
What the hell is this?
It's a ritual
"Take the breath
and the love out of seven children
And close the circle with their blood
when morning turns to night"
The old man was right
Seven children's throats cut
by someone who loves them
When morning turns to night
The eclipse
It's tomorrow
It only happens every 40 years
The last time they tried
it, something went wrong
One of the kids escaped
They had to be seven,
but they only got six
It's going to happen again
With Paul
Reggie,
no one's going to do anything to Paul
My dad is sick
Sometimes he doesn't
even know what he's doing
- Reggie, you should hear yourself?
- Mom,
- It's the house
- You're not!
Dad would never hurt us
What you're saying is
terrible... it's obscene
Is that too hard for you to
accept that your father and I?
Mom! Please!
Dad is sick!
And the stuff that's
been going on, it all fits
The eclipse is tomorrow
Just don't go back to that house, please
We'll do whatever your grandfather says,
since he's your father's doctor, not you
- Hello
- Grandpa,
- It's Regina
- Regina, come up
It's Villalobos
Listen, I've found one of the
papers the guy sent me, you know...
...the intermediary
There was a letterhead...
...an address
And I'm going over
there and you should too
Here, this will make you feel better
You have to believe me
I don't know what to do
I believe you, Regina
It's just that this
is all too strange
I don't know
I don't understand a lot of
what you've been telling me
You have to help me
- You're a doctor, they'll listen to you
- Okay
I don't want you to worry
I'm going to call the hospital
Please!
Don't let them go back to the house
They won't go back, trust me
- Reggie, listen... it's the old man, Villalobos
He found the address of the guy
who was sending him instructions
He said he was going over there
Wait I want to come with you
It's one of those buildings
behind the park... number 17
- What?
- Reggie...
...number 17...
Number 17?
I'll wait for you out in front...
- But I'm here
- Reggie, wait...
Grandpa
Regina
You should have been
in your house
With your family because
they are in the house
What are you doing in the dark?
Where's Reggie?
I don't know
She hasn't called
I expected her to call
Let her be
You know how she's been lately
In the beginning it was just science
You begin studying minds
of children
How their fears work
A fear shared by all children
In all times and in all cultures
An irrational fear:
The fear of the dark
I think I might take a nap
I'm exhausted
Sounds like a good idea
And now, we are almost ready
After so many years
What are you talking about?
About darkness, my dear,
the true darkness
A kind of evil in its greatest form
Pure...
...and alive
And now,
the moment has arrived
Finally...
...it will be born
Dirty...
...and perverted
Don't try so hard,
Regina
The game has already begun
The countdown has already begun
We're getting closer to the moment
When the sun and the moon aligned
submerges for a few moments in darkness
Why?
Because it's a question
of faith
We are our origin
And our origin is that
Evil, disorder
We discovered the spell
to get it back
The egg temple
and seven children's throats cut
by loving hands
And the eclipse of course
It's just an experiment
I'm a doctor
Do you know what the ancients called it?
"The great liar"
- Where's Regina?
- She's here. Come in
Thank goodness you came
I didn't know what to do
Hey what's going on here?
Do you know what's going on here?
What's going on is
that you have fucked up
I don't know why everyone is
trying to ruin this moment for me
Once begun no one can stop it
There is no way back
Everything was perfect
We were seven
We had built the temple
And waited for the eclipse
Each one with his child
But at the last minute it fell apart
I'm the only one left
The only one who has
survived all these years
Ironic, isn't it?
Because it was my fault
I had to let my son escape
I couldn't do it
Mom!
Yes, Paul
Can I have a glass of water?
Mom
Please, just go away
You loved him
Let me go
We can still stop it
The rules of the game are very clear
Seven children's throats cut
by hands which love them
Go away?
You want me to go away
What the hell are you talking about?
This is my house
Open the fucking door!
Now!
The last minute
I realized it wouldn't work,
because, honestly,
I didn't love him
Mark?
Please, just go away
Paul doesn't have anything to do with this
You haven't understood
anything, have you?
It's not Paul,
you idiot
It's your father
What?
It has to be the same child
Mark, just leave us alone
Open this fucking door!
Mark!
Mark, you're sick
You're not taking your
medicine, that's why you're sick
No!
Liar! That's a lie!
Please, Mark, go
- Can't you see you're sick?
- Mom
It wasn't Dad
He didn't hit me
It's impossible
It'll never happen
Darkness is very wise
Knows very well what a mother...
...is capable of doing to protect her young
Mark, enough!
This is my toy
A snake,
and something about to be born
It sounds familiar, doesn't it?
It'll never happen
I saw it in the book
The throat has
to be cut
and my mother wouldn't
do that. It's impossible
Have faith, Regina
Darkness knows a great deal
Okay Here's my medication
Mark
What are you doing?
Here are the goddamn pills
Daddy
I'm so sorry
I love you
So much
Run
You don't have much time
Run!
It's your turn
Answer me!
Pills! Freak pills
You want me to take pills
What's going on?
Paul,
go get a pen I've got to open
him up or he's going to die
Go!
Paul, hurry!
Paul, you should just go up
to your room and don't look
Just go, now!
Mom, no!
What are you doing?
He needs air I gotta open his throat
Get out of my way! Don't you
understand that's what it wants?
Your father is dying!
I gotta open his throat, let him breathe
I can't do it
Give it to me I'll do it
Just tell me what to do
A clean cut just under the Adam's apple
Quickly!
Mom!
Now get the tube
Put it in his throat
What tube? What tube?
- It's here
- Mom!
Where is it?
Mom!
Where?
It's too late
Mom!
It's over
The seventh child...
...is dead
Where's
Regina?
In her house
In hell
Where's the flashlight?
Where is it?
Mom, we have to get out
of here. Where's Paul?
- Where is he? Where is he?
- Upstairs
- Regina!
- Paul!
I'm scared!
Paul, I'm coming
Regina!
Come with me
It's tricking us It's trying to fool us
It's a liar
We're gonna get out of here right now
Mom?
Don't be afraid
We can end this
It's just a question of not being afraid
- He's dead
- No, he's not
I want Daddy back, Mommy
We can save him
You just have to turn off the burners
It's the only way to fight the darkness
We don't have much time left
You have to trust me, Regina
What are you saying?
For once in your life,
you'll just have to trust me
No
Turn the light off
Turn them off
You can save him
- Please, Mom
- I don't understand
You're a liar
Turn it off
You're not my mother
Turn them off
Do it for Dad
Mom?
Mom!
Where is Mom?
She's not here
Don't look. We gotta get out of here
Come on. We gotta get out of here
Try the window
We'll try the window
Come on. Stand back
Come on, we have to get
out right now! Come on, jump!
Come on!
- Come on
- Get in the car right now, honey
It's gonna be okay
Are we going back to the States?
Yeah
Come on up. I want you to see something
You're gonna love it
It's tricking us
It's a liar
It's over, Paul
No