(Footsteps)
(Sighs heavily)
(Footsteps and metallic rattling)
Ah!
(Sighs)
Ah...can I have another one?
It's for a friend of mine.
She's waiting for me.
Thank you.
Er...are you dressed like this
for the promotion of the film?
Kathy! Kathy!
Sorry I'm late.
You usually are. Mrs Buckles is
just gonna blow her stack again.
She'd scream at us
even if we were early.
Look what I was given.
- Doesn't the movie have a title?
- No. Maybe it's a sneak preview.
You know, they show a brand-new
movie in a theatre
just to see the reaction
of the public.
Where is the Metropol?
I've never heard of it.
Me, neither. Maybe it's new.
What do you say we go
and forget about Mrs Buckles?
Sometimes you really worry me, Cheryl.
You're leading us astray!
It was just an idea.
(Heavy breathing sound)
(Laughter)
Hey, look, Kathy. There it is.
Hey, you don't think it's gonna be
a horror movie, do you?
- You know I just hate them.
- And I hate missing the start. Come on.
(Heavy breathing)
- Are you sure you want to cut class?
- Hm. I'll hold your hand if it's scary.
(Heavy breathing)
That's strange. I didn't know
there was a movie house on this street.
Closed down a couple of years ago.
Looks like they spent some money on it.
- How come I never noticed it?
- You never notice anything, darling.
Please, Frank, don't start.
This is our anniversary.
So what?
I'm taking you to a show.
- What else do you want?
- Straight ahead, sir.
Straight ahead, please.
- Great bike, huh?
- It's fantastic! Absolutely fantastic.
Oh, rats! Come on,
give us back the money!
- God, I hate these machines.
- Hey, Ken, forget the bike.
- What are you doing?
- Hitting the coin return.
Oh, forget it. It's ripped us off.
- These things only happen to you.
- It's not my fault if the machine...
Looks like you're having problems.
Thanks.
Sometimes all it takes
is the right touch.
I thought you said you just hate
to miss the start of a movie.
Liz?
- Liz!
- Yes, Werner?
- Don't touch it.
- Touch what?
This.
No, I never go. There are too many
people on the beach.
Hey!
(Laughs)
How do I look?
- Terrific.
- Do you like it, Bobby?
- Sexy, huh?
- I think you look silly.
- Just a sec...
- Hey, cut it, baby!
Ow! What was that?
- You cut yourself.
- Oh, shit!
That'll teach you to touch things.
What is he getting so mad for?
It was just...
Why don't we sit next to this guy?
He's cute.
Sit here and shut up!
Jesus, this is what you call
enjoying yourself?
I bet they're gonna come and sit here.
Come on.
- Hi.
Charlie, love, did you bring the popcorn?
Shut up, you stupid bitch!
The sleep of reason
gives birth to monsters.
J' Black angels laughing
in the city streets
J' Street toys scream in pain
and clench their teeth
J' The moonlight spotlights
all the city's crime
J' Got no religion
J' Laugh while they fight
J' Save our souls for the heavens
J' For a life so good
it sure feels bad
J' Save our souls for the heavens
J' Save our souls
for the promised land... J'
Hey, stop! Look!
There's something written on this.
- It's an inscription or something.
- What's it say?
"They will make cemeteries
their cathedrals,
"and tombs your cities."
Eugh!!
According to an old legend,
Nostradamus was buried here.
Nostradamus?
Sounds like a rock group to me.
Yeah, Top of The Pops in 1500.
- They had rock groups then?
- Edith!
- So tell me, computer brain.
- He was kind of a fortune teller.
A prophet from the 16th century.
He predicted a whole mess of things
that have come true.
Such as?
Such as, for example, the discovery
of Neptune and Uranus,
Hitler, world wars,
the coming of the demons.
Big deal, that hasn't happened.
Not yet. There's still time.
A horror movie. I knew it!
I told you this was a great place.
Come on...
If you get scared, you can always
hold my hand. I won't mind.
But I thought you said he was gay...
Shut up!
- It was this way, right?
- Yeah.
Watch your step.
- What's that?
- More tombs.
Aargm
It was only a bat!
What's happening, Liz?
Yeah, so why didn't he die
of a heart attack?
They're going down into a crypt,
Werner. It's dark.
Hey, here's the way down.
Come on, Nancy, you're next.
And now it's one of the girls.
Aren't they scared?
Yes, they are.
No! I can't do it.
Pull me back up, somebody!
Just let yourself go.
- Come on.
- I can '1'.
- Smoking is not allowed in here.
- Excuse us.
We're nearly there, for God's sake,
just close your eyes, Jerry'll catch you.
Hey, Tony...
(Giggling)
Hookers...fucking everywhere.
What do you care?
Let's try down there.
This way, girls.
These cobwebs! Yuck!
I'm scared.
' Liz?
' Yes?
- Are you scared?
- Yes, I am.
Watch where you put your feet, girls.
See those cracks in the floor?
Under one of those you might
find yourself side by side
with Nostradamus' skull or ribcage.
(Laughter)
Cut it out. I came for a ride
on your new bike, not for this.
It's not fair.
Besides, I told my parents
I'd be home early tonight.
What do you say, Jerry?
Shall we tell them the truth?
- What are you talking about?
- Tell them.
We're the first people to set foot
in this crypt in centuries.
That hole we came through
only fell in this morning.
- How do you know?
- Me and Bob heard the crash.
We decided to come back tonight
so you could enjoy the discovery.
- Thanks a lot!
- Look, nothing's gonna hurt you
Vampires and all that stuff
only exist in movies.
Hey, more tombs. Must've been
a real big-shot with a fancy one.
- Let's get out of here, please.
- Just a second.
Hey, look, it's got
some kind of seal on it.
Bob, give me some light down here.
Wait a second. It's gotta be a name.
N...O...S...
It's Nostradamus!
Come on, open it.
Come on, let's get out of here.
This place is giving me the creeps.
Hey, use this iron bar.
Agh!
What are you screaming for?
You knocked it over!
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- It's OK.
My name's George.
Mine's Cheryl.
Cheryl, if I have a heart attack,
it's your fault.
Hi. Great movie, huh?
- Hey, no bones.
- Just an old book.
And something wrapped in cloth.
Let me see it.
(Coughs)
Well, what's it say?
It's in Latin. I can't figure it out...
Yes, loan, wait a second.
It's written by Nostradamus.
It's something about demons.
Look, bring it with you,
but can we go now?
No, just a second.
It says here that
demons are instruments of evil.
Trick or treat?
- Don't do that!
- How do I look?
- Whoever wears it becomes a demon.
- How do you know?
It says here whoever wears it
becomes a demon
and an instrument of evil.
Yeah, sure.
Now we know
why you looked so good in it!
Thanks a lot, Tony.
He will spread pestilence
and contaminate the world.
Remember that inscription outside?
"They will make cemeteries
their cathedrals,
"and tombs your cities."
Hey, your cheek's bleeding.
You must've scratched yourself
when you took the mask off.
- It's nothing.
- Oh, shit!
- What's the matter?
- It started bleeding again.
I'll be right back, huh?
That's funny, the bleeding won't stop.
It doesn't matter.
Just leave me alone, huh?
- Tony?
- Yeah?
You see that?
The same thing happened in the movie.
Ah, it's a bunch of shit, baby.
If we only had something
to disinfect it with.
Nancy, stop mothering me.
It's just a scratch.
But you can't leave it like that.
Come on, let's go.
- I'm all right, I tell you.
- You're white as a sheet.
- Jerry, are you sure you're OK?
- Just leave me alone!
Look, I don't know about you guys,
but I'm leaving...
Ugh! Ah...
Ugh!
Oh!
Agh!
No! Aargh!
Aargh! No-0-0!
No, don't do it! No!
(Screaming)
Is it over yet?
Yes, you can look now.
Don't tease me, Tom.
Is it really over?
Yes, silly.
Aargh!
(She sobs)
What the hell happened to Rosemary?
Maybe I should go check
and see if she's OK.
Don't you disappear too!
Aargh!
- It's too bloody of a movie.
- Ruth, shut up!
Aargh!
Somebody!
Rosemary?
Rosemary? Are you OK?
Aargh!
Somebody help me!
Help! Somebody help me, please!
Somebody!
(Screams)
(Growls)
(Sighs)
We must go see what happened.
- Liz? Liz, where are you?
- What were those shouts?
Seems to come from the abbey.
You must be wrong.
Nobody goes near those ruins.
- Well, I saw some kids on bikes.
- When?
About half an hour ago.
The bikes are still there.
They were there this morning, too.
Liz! Liz!
Liz, where are you?
He's calling me.
I better get back to him.
Let's call the police.
Answer me!
Liz! Liz!
I gotta go. He knows we're here.
Pa trick!
(Screaming)
Agh! Somebody!
Aargh! Aargh...
Somebody help me! Aargh!
(Screaming continues)
Somebody help me!
There's somebody behind the screen.
(Screaming)
- Those screams sound real.
- Come on, it's the Dolby system.
I'm telling you,
those screams sound real!
Aargh!
What happened?
(Anxious shouts)
(She sobs and screams)
Ugh! Aargh!
Will you get out of my way?
Holy shit! She's a friend of mine.
Hey, baby, what happened?
Shit, baby, what happened?
Ah... Aargh!
(Screaming)
There's some kind of madman
loose in here.
What the hell's going on here?
- Cheryl!
- I'm sorry, it's my fault.
I should have never suggested
we come here.
The movie...
It's happening just like in the movie!
Son of a bitch! Shit!
Hey, George, look at her fingernails.
(Heavy breathing)
My God, what's happening?
It can't be true.
(Screams)
Shit!
We gotta get out of here.
Get out! Everybody, get away!
Get out!
What are you waiting for? Run!
(Screaming)
Aargh!
Aargh! Aargh!
Liz?
Liz!
Liz...
Agh! Uh...
Help!
No! No!
No!
Aargh!
(Shouting and screaming)
J' Running through the darkness
like a fire in the night
J' Looking for some action,
don't know what's in sight
J' Racing with the devil
in the middle of the row
J' If you're gonna lose, the devil's
gonna take you down there below...
J' The darkness has the power
and it has come to rule
J' You better pray for your life
J' An evil circle, you better beware
J' You better take care
J' Or you're gonna die... J'
- We're trapped in here!
- That wall, it wasn't there before.
- There has to be an explanation!
- There has to be another way out!
I want to get out!
I want to go home!
Quiet! Quiet! Quiet!
Quiet! Be quiet! Listen to me!
Let's find the emergency exit.
J' Fighting to survive
in the dark and empty cold
J' You better beware
J' You're losing control... J'
Hey, there are no other exits...
There aren't any more exits!
- Help! Help!
- Find some way out of here!
Aargh! Aargh!
(Screaming continues)
Jesus!
J' You can't stand the pressure
Shock Waves rollin' through your brain
J' Your body starts to shiver,
you're going insane... J'
Aargh!
Push! Push for Christ's sake!
Come on, we'll use that.
J' You better pray for your life
J' An evil circle, you better beware,
you better take care... J'
Come on! Come on!
Get out of the way!
Push! Push!
All together now, push!
(Sobbing)
You know, I didn't think
we were gonna make it.
- It's the movie!
- What about the movie?
I don't know how to explain it,
it's just a feeling.
The movie's to blame for all this.
She's right.
She put on that mask
and scratched herself. Get it?
Because of that scratch,
she became a demon,
an instrument of evil.
Like they said in the damn movie,
you heard them!
- Right?
- Yes.
We gotta stop it.
Believe me, we gotta stop the movie.
He's right, yes, it's the movie!
Stop the movie!
Hey, George, you believe that shit?
What are you waiting for?
Stop the movie!
- Where's the projection booth?
- Upstairs next to the gallery.
Right, we'll all go up there together.
If we stick together, no one gets hurt.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
OK, let's go.
Hannah? Hannah? I lost my girl!
Get out of the way!
Hannah! Where are you?
There he is, behind the wall.
Careful, he has a knife.
- Did I;he get:1' you?
Ah, it's nothing.
Get back!
God! It's Harold!
(Growls)
There.
Hey, open UP!
Open the door and let us in!
I said open the door!
Wait a second, man.
Maybe something happened
in the room and...
The window of the projection room,
I can get in through there.
- Yes, I'll come with you, Cheryl.
- There's no need.
Shit! Another door!
Give me a hand.
We gotta keep together.
There he is!
Gel' him!
Empty. No one's here.
These things are automatic.
They work on their own.
Oh, God, then that means
no one's ever been here.
Smash everything! Smash everything!
Smash everything!
(J' Music on radio:
"We Close Our Eyes" - Go West)
J' Inside
J' Everyone hides one desire
J' Outside
J' No one would know
J' Danger
J' Close to the edge of a knife
J' Safer
J' Not to let go
J' And while we miss chances,
you can almost... J'
Hey, Hot Dog,
next time let's rip off a Ferrari.
- This heap's got no class.
- It's like you, airhead.
- It's been putting out too long.
- You asshole!
Shut up!
J' Imagination never lets us
take the blame
J' We close our eyes
to see the final frame
to time slipping away... J'
Now the damn film isn't
gonna hurt us anymore.
It's not the movie.
It's the theatre.
It's this theatre that kills.
It has killed my Liz.
My little girl...
The whole place is cursed!
(Faint sobbing)
They're still here, goddamn them!
They ain't gonna get me,
that's for sure!
Hey, look, there's a body here.
Give me a hand to throw her
into the stalls.
- No, no, leave her alone, she's dead.
- Get out of the way.
She can't hurt anyone.
How the hell do you know
she's really dead
and ain't been transformed
into a demon?
- She's scratched. And you, too.
- No, no!
Come on, give me a hand,
before it's too late.
No, don't go, I'm scared.
- No, no, no! Please!
- Give me a hand!
One of you take her legs and
help me throw her over the edge.
What are you waiting for,
you son of a bitch?
I won't give you a hand!
Christ, she's dead, leave her alone!
You ain't worth shit!
Come on, take her legs.
Ready?
(Screaming)
My God! My husband!
Aaaiee!
Aargh!
(Retches)
Aaaiee! Aaaiee!
(Radio)
J' I wipe the tears from your eyes
J' Say nothing
and still you seem so surprised
J' Though tears fall like rain... J'
Take the wheel.
This shit would wake up the dead.
Rip out the seats to make a barricade.
We have to block off the way in.
The cord! We have to undo the cord.
That's how that guy got up here.
Hey, kid...
Don't undo it, cut it.
Something wrong?
No, no.
Faster!
You look like you're scared
of breaking them.
Watch! Like this...
Aargh! Give me the knife!
Give me the knife!
Aargh!
(Screams)
Hannah!
Shh!
- Tommy?
- Yeah, it's OK now. It's me.
Hey, you're hurt. You're bleeding.
Oh, no. Don't worry.
- It's not my blood.
- Are you sure?
You're bleeding.
It's nothing, it's just a scratch.
(Radio) J' Hey, little sister
What have you done... J'
Hey, slow it down.
Leave some of that stuff for us.
My turn.
- Why? It's my can, shithead!
- Give me the can, jerk.
I said it was my turn.
It's too fucking good
for assholes like you!
Yeah?
What the fuck?
What's the matter with you guys?
It's not my fault, Ripper.
Fuck you! Pick it up, every gram!
Take it away!
Come on, come on!
Carry it away, come on.
I got it, let's go here.
Come on.
Come on! Move!
J' Hey, little sister
Who's the only one?
J' I've been away for so long
So long
J' I let you go for so long
J' It's a nice day
To start again... J'
Oh, it's even in my panties.
All of it! I said all of it!
You got trouble getting
your dope back now, Ripper.
Shut up! Unless you want me
to break your head?
Oh, that's Rambo talking, baby.
Ooh, yeah, tough Ripper.
Don't make me laugh, Baby Pig.
This takes concentration.
Come on!
Ken, you think this'll stop them?
I doubt it, but don't tell the others.
How many do you think
there are of them?
I don't know,
but I tell you one thing,
it's the last complimentary ticket
I'll ever accept from anybody ever again.
- Me, too.
- That makes three of us.
What the hell are you all doing there?
Watch the railings!
Make sure they don't get us from there.
Wait. Come on.
If you see anyone start climbing, shout!
The rest of us start
pounding on the wall.
Maybe the cavalry will hear us
and come to the rescue.
Let's hope.
I've finished.
This is me. I was one year old.
- Already selling your twat, huh?
- Fuck you!
Oh, lookee here.
There's snow in the valley.
Well, maybe there's some more
further down.
(Radio) J' Start again
J' Come on, it's a nice day
for a white wedding
J' It's a nice day
to start again
J' It's a nice day to... J'
Aargh!
You're a prick, Piggy!
Must be all the shit in the air
that's making you so nice.
Shh! Do you hear that?
(Dull thuds)
It's coming from the theatre.
It's a movie.
- No, that's not a movie.
- OK, so what is it, then?
It's Count Dracula!
Stop! I hear something.
Stop! Stop a minute!
I heard something! Listen! Listen!
What is it? Are they coming?
No, it's nothing.
Just the seats settling into place.
Relax, they can't get through there.
Come on, keep pounding!
- Tommy, someone's coming.
- Shit, let's get out of it.
Hey, it's like there's a room
behind the wall.
Come on, let's break it down!
We've got to get up to the gallery.
No one knows we're here.
- We're better off on our own.
- I want to join the others.
No, come on.
Let's try to find a way out.
Come on.
Nothing doing in there.
No way out.
- This is another zero.
- It's just walls!
Cut it out, Cheryl,
you're not helping.
Look... Hey, wait!
Calm down! Get a hold of yourself!
(Cheryl) We're all gonna die!
(Hysterical screams)
Hey, kids!
We're parked illegally?
Sorry, officer.
We're on our way.
Just give me a second...
Everybody out of the car!
Put your hands on the trunk.
Let's go.
- Hey, I said put your hands...
- Fuck off, pig!
- Freeze, punk!
- Stop or I'll shoot!
Hold it, hold it. It's a blind alley.
Shit, dead-end!
Come on!
- We're trapped, damn it!
- No!
What the fuck? This way, come on!
- Where the hell did they go?
- Come on!
- Shh! Do you hear that?
- Yeah, I heard it.
Behind the car.
Hey, buddy.
Buddy, are you all right?
What are you waiting for?
Shoot him! Shoot him!
There should be enough room to crawl.
With luck, it'll lead outside.
What did I tell you?
I'll go first.
Give me your hand.
Where the fuck are we?
We're gonna make it.
This was a great idea.
Wait. What was that noise?
What noise? Keep moving.
We're in the movie theatre.
- Deserted. That's weird.
- Where was the noise coming from?
Who gives a shit? Let's go.
Come on!
You hear it'? Like something
scratching its nails inside of the shaft.
Behind you! Hurry, Hannah!
Faster!
You go first.
Christ! Now it's in front of us!
That's impossible. It can't be!
(Fierce growl)
- What kind of fucking place is this?
- What happened in here?
Find a way out!
Hey!
There's a door here. Come on!
Hey, come on,
move the machine.
There's a door right behind it.
Asshole!
This place goes nowhere. Let's go.
- Where's Nina?
- She's probably in the can.
Aargh!
Nina!
(Growls)
Oh, shit!
(Distant screams)
I can hear someone.
(Heavy thudding)
You're right. Help's coming.
We've been rescued!
Thank God. Help's arrived!
Don't you understand?
We've been saved!
Come on, get a move on.
Give me a hand!
Stop! Downstairs is full of them!
What are you doing?
Stop tearing down the barricades!
No! No! What are you doing?
Don't unblock the exits!
They're gonna get us!
Shit! Shit!
(Growls)
- What are they after?
- I don't know, Baby Pig. You ask them.
It's us they want, asshole.
See you in hell!
Cheryl, Kathy, let's go!
Ken, come on, let's go. Come on!
Aargh!
(Panicked screams)
(Gasps)
Ungh...ungh...
Ah! Ah!
Aaaiee!
Hurry!
Aargh! No!
(LOW growl)
- I can hear them
- Easy.
George!
Help me! She fainted.
Kathy.
Oh, no! Kathy! Kathy?
Come on! Let's go!
(Growls)
Hey. Hey!
Come here!
There's an air-conditioning vent here.
We could crawl inside.
At least they won't see us in there.
Shall I go first?
No, we'd better get Kathy in there first.
I don't think she's capable
of fending for herself.
Yeah, you're right. Kathy, hey.
Kathy. Kathy!
Stand up, please!
This place. Where am I?
Kathy!
Maybe she's in shock.
(Growls) Who are you?
Oh, my God!
Make it stop!
Kathy!
No!
No, stop! No! Don't do it!
- Kathy! Oh, my God!
- It wasn't Kathy!
Not the Kathy you knew!
Understand?
It wasn't her.
It wasn't her!
Look!
Look at her back!
It got me.
- It's nothing, Ken.
- I'll turn into one of them.
It's nothing, Ken.
Stay away from me!
- Stay away from me!
- It's nothing, Ken!
Leave me alone!
Try and save yourself!
- We can't leave him alone like that.
- Come on.
Fight it, Ken. Fight it!
You can do it!
You're still here? Go away!
I don't want you to see me like this.
Please, go away!
OK, OK!
OK.
No, George. Wait.
Do me a favour.
A last favour as a friend.
Sure, Ken.
Kill me with this!
No, I can't do that, Ken!
Do it, George!
It's them!
They're coming up the stairs!
- Take it!
- No.
They're coming!
Take it, George! Kill me!
Don't let me become like them!
Come on! Kill me!
They're coming!
Aargh!
George!
Cheryl!
J' Fog in the streets
A church clock beats
J' Midnight darkness all around
J' You better beware
You better take care
J' Be prepared for the shock
J' The time has come
And he's the one
J' Breathing down your neck
J' Coming from behind
Now it's your time
J' The loser will die
J' Fast as a shark
He'll cut out of the dark
J' He's a killer
He'll rip out your heart
J' On a one-way track
and you're not coming back
J' Cos the killer's on the attack
J' Surprise attack
Coming from the back
J' An expert of the deadly knack
J' Just take care
J' Just beware
Be prepared for the fight... J'
Aargh!
J' He's a killer
He'll rip out your heart
J' On a one-way track
And you're not coming back
J' Cos the killer's on the attack... J'
Uh...oh...
Uh...
(Rumbling overhead)
- What's going on?
- My God, that noise!
(Growls)
Come on, Cheryl!
Hurry!
George, they're coming! Help!
They're coming! Come on!
Come on!
Up there!
That's where we have to go.
It's all right, Cheryl.
We're gonna make it!
Come on. Take this. This, too.
Give it here.
- See that winch at your feet?
- Yeah.
Give me the end of the wire.
Quick, give me the starter.
Come on! Give me your hand!
Pull yourself up! Come on!
- I can't anymore.
- Push! Don't let go!
(Yells and gunfire)
(Creak)
George! George!
No! No!
Run, Cheryl!
Run!
Ungh...oh...
Urgh...
Come on!
This way!
J' On your feet
I wanna see the whole place jumpin'
J' Yeah, come on, baby
Can you feel the heat?
J' Move up close
The boys are out to get you
J' Cos we don't care
Just what you got in mind
J' I said everybody up
Everybody, everybody up
J' Everybody, everybody up
J' Stand in line
We're about to rock you
J' Cos we all know
Just what you came here for
J' Stamp your feet
This place is really rockin'
J' I said everybody up
Everybody, everybody up
Everybody, everybody up... J'
(Growls)
Come on, Cheryl! Come on!
I can't! I can't!
I can't!
They're right behind us. Hurry!
Over here! Hurry up!
Jump in, hurry up! Jump in!
Come on!
Go!
On the right, June.
Good shot!
Welcome aboard.
There are more weapons on the floor.
Kurt.
- Where are we going?
- Out in the country.
Just a second. Hey, dad!
Dad, they want to know
where we're going.
As far from here as possible.
West. We saw some lights in the sky.
Maybe not everything's lost.
Maybe there's still some place
where we can start a new life.
Aargh!