...is not the only
such affliction.
And so we come
to that condition
which most often afflicts
the more nervous sex.
Hysteria.
Derived from the Greek
for "uterus".
Much studied
by the French,
it has of late
come under the scrutiny
of our Austrian colleagues.
Tonight, we'll endeavor
to add a British accent
to this chorus.
Bring in
the patient, please.
As you can see,
the patient
is a comely woman
of five and thirty years
who has been under my care
at Bethlehem Hospital.
Of impeccable breeding,
she has suffered much
of her life
from the classic symptoms
of the chronic hysteric.
Who can tell me
what these are?
Lassitude?
Correct.
Another.
The tingling
of the extremities.
Yes.
Another.
Convulsions.
Sometimes called
"hysteric fits",
during which the patient
may become violent,
dangerously unmanageable.
Which is why,
as a precautionary measure,
I've had her injected
with four grains
of heroin.
One cannot be too careful
when attempting to trigger
a fit in a clinical setting.
As I shall now
endeavor to do.
Please.
I beseech you, sir,
do not.
Shh, shh, shh.
The trigger point...
Help me.
One of you, please.
Look at me.
I am not mad.
The trigger point
may be hidden anywhere
in the female anatomy.
Most often
upon the breasts.
Do not touch me.
The inner thighs.
Or the ovaries.
Note the clenched fists,
the arched back,
the tonic
and clonic spasms.
Concluding finally
in a profound
contracture.
Watch yourself.
She's started
her monthly bleeding.
Next patient, please.
Bring in the patient.
Any questions?
What of the woman's insistence
that she is not mad?
Just as every criminal
maintains he's innocent,
so does every mad woman
insist she is sane.
But she seemed so...
Reasonable?
Perhaps.
Well bred?
Beautiful?
She is all these things.
And quite mad.
And therein lies
the paradox of insanity
and the great peril
of our profession.
Thus, I caution
you all, gentlemen,
as you embark
on your careers
as alienists,
believe nothing
that you hear
and only one half
of what you see.
Bloody hell.
Hey!
Wait!
Hello there.
Excuse me.
I beg you, stop.
At first,
Da didn't want to stop
on account you may be
a lunatic who escaped,
but I convinced him
you couldn't be
since you're headed
toward the madhouse
and not away from it.
Ah, clever deduction.
And you look like a man
who's only lost his way,
not his mind.
Well, I'm grateful.
Thank you.
Are you visiting
someone at Stonehearst?
Actually, going there
to complete my training
as an alienist.
That's a doctor
who specializes
in asylum medicine.
Well, I can tell
you'll be a good one.
You have kind eyes.
Aw, thank you.
The madhouse
is just up that hill.
You're certain?
Oh, yes.
Look!
I don't see anything.
Merry Christmas.
Hello?
Hello!
And who the feck
might you be?
Ah, good God.
Good afternoon, sir.
I'm-I'm Edward Newgate.
Dr. Edward Newgate,
from Oxford.
Might-Might you let me in?
Well, now, that depends.
Were we expecting you?
Well, I hope so.
I did send a letter
to the superintendent here.
Must have been
weeks ago now.
Well, the post
isn't regular
this time of the year.
Oh, really? I...
I'm just acting the maggot.
Of course you can
come in, Ted.
What kind of Christian would
I be to leave another outside
to freeze his onions off?
And on Christmas Eve
no less.
Well, thank you so much.
I-I do appreciate it.
My name's Finn.
I'm the chief steward.
Welcome to our
little madhouse
in the wilderness.
Presently we have
200 residents
at Stonehearst.
Sons and daughters
of some of the finest
families in the realm.
We have lords, dukes.
We even have a cousin
of the Queen.
Now, she likes
to finger paint
with her own shite.
There you go, Rosie.
We have a viscount
who's convinced
he has two heads,
and an earl
who thinks
he's a teapot.
Seriously.
Wait-Wait here.
The doctor
will be along shortly.
Right, yes.
Trephination.
An arcane
medical procedure
performed by savages
upon those possessed
of evil spirits.
By boring a hole
in the skull,
they believed
it would allow
the demons to escape.
Let us be thankful we live
in more enlightened times,
don't you agree,
doctor...?
Newgate.
Edward Newgate,
from Oxford.
Forgive me
for turning up
unannounced.
I did write a letter.
It's just your Mr. Finn
tells me it never arrived.
An Oxford man
is always welcome here.
So,
what brings you
to Stonehearst?
Well, as I wrote
in my letter,
I had hoped
I would observe
your methods in or...
Oh, no, thank you.
Nonsense.
You've had
an arduous voyage.
From the backwaters
of blissful ignorance
across vast oceans
of academic blather
until at last
you've arrived here,
on the shores
of my little kingdom.
And at the dawn
of a new century,
no less.
So,
it's asylum medicine
you wish to practice.
Uh, yes, since as long
as I can remember.
Why?
I'm sorry?
Why not some specialty
that's held in higher regard?
Surgery, for instance.
I don't much care
for blood, I suppose.
Tropical medicine then.
Or problems of the female
anatomy.
Both offer better pay.
Well, I've always
been fascinated
by the troubled mind.
So is a priest
but he at least
is guaranteed heaven.
What do you hope
to gain?
The satisfaction
of helping those
in hell.
See, of all the afflictions,
I can think of none more,
more cruel
than madness, sir.
See, it robs a man
of his reason,
his dignity,
his very soul.
And it does so,
so slowly,
without the remorse
of death.
Please, sir.
I have the desire
and the training.
All I lack
is the clinical
experience.
Time for afternoon rounds.
Of course.
I didn't wish
to keep you...
Join me, Doctor.
Thank you.
Mr. Finn,
help the doctor off
with his coat, would you?
Thank you.
You'll find us well-stocked
with the usual cases.
Neurasthenia,
dementia praecox,
incurable homosexuality,
epilepsy, melancholia.
But where we differ
from other asylums
is in the social station
of our patients.
All hail
from the finest
families in Europe.
For instance,
Terrance here
is heir to one
of the largest railroad
fortunes in the continent.
And what is the nature
of his disorder?
He suffers
from an utter lack
of interest in trains.
So his family
had him committed?
Interesting case
this one.
Signore Balzoni was thrown
from his horse during a polo
match in Milan
and ever since
he's believed himself
to be an Arabian stallion.
He gets a tad agitated
at feeding times.
Please go ahead.
You'll find most
of our patients are here
because they are
embarrassments
to their families.
Outcasts.
Signore,
give the gentleman
his arm back
or I shall be forced
to withhold grooming
for a week.
You-You groom him?
Small price to pay
to keep him contented.
Isn't that reinforcing
his delusion?
Yes.
What, you don't attempt
to cure your patients?
Cure them?
To what purpose?
Well, to bring them back
to their senses, of course.
And make a miserable man
out of a perfectly happy
horse.
Madame.
Your Eminence.
Is it always
this lively?
Here we do not believe
in sedating our patients
into a stupor
with bromides
and the like.
We prefer to celebrate them
in their natural unadulterated
state.
Check.
Mm.
Good afternoon, my lovely.
Nurse.
Nurse?
Has she eaten today?
She refuses to eat
until her son returns
from the war.
He was killed in action
in Peshawar, '85.
Have you tried
a feeding tube?
We do not use such
medieval methods here.
I'd hardly
call it "medieval".
What would you
call it then?
Well, a necessary means
of preventing death.
Death cannot be
prevented, Doctor,
any more
than madness cured.
There's no cure
for the human condition.
And it's a foolish
physician who tries.
Suppose I were
to present you
with the following case.
A woman who suffers
from violent fits
triggered by physical
or emotional contact
that she perceives
to be of too intimate
a nature.
Ah, sounds
like hysteria.
What treatment
would you prescribe?
Ah, mustard packs,
I should think.
Is she a patient
or a pickled herring?
Pelvic massage?
Potassium bromide?
I'm interested
in your opinion, Doctor,
not some textbook's.
Forget bromides.
Open your eyes.
Look at her.
So, I ask you again,
presented with a woman
of utmost grace
and refinement
within whose breast
roils passion so great
she fears
they will destroy her,
what treatment
would you prescribe?
Music.
Three times
a day, no less.
Bravo, Doctor.
I concur.
There are few therapies
better at restoring
the soul than music.
Her name
is Lady Charles Graves.
Eliza. Mrs. Graves to us.
I presume you know
her husband?
No.
Repugnant chap.
Possesses
a tremendous fortune.
Not to mention
many unnatural
appetites.
As one would expect,
her hysterical episodes
worsened
following the engagement,
until one night she bit off
his ear
and gouged out
his eye with a comb.
So her husband
had her committed.
No, her father.
If it had been up
to the Baronet,
she'd still be at home
in his loving embrace.
In fact, not a week goes by
that I don't receive a letter
from him
threatening me
and demanding
I declare her cured
so she might be remanded
into his custody.
So, you refuse?
For her own safety.
Come, Doctor.
Yes, of course.
We have much to see
before dinner.
May I just say
that your playing
is sublime.
Oh.
Oh, your playing
is sublime.
It's quite sublime.
I'm Newgate.
Dr. Edward Newgate.
My name is Edward Newgate.
Doc...
Nurse.
May I have
a glass of water?
Yes, ma'am.
Your playing
is sublime.
What was that,
Mozart, Beethoven?
No, I wrote it.
Of course.
Let me introduce myself.
My name is...
Dr. Newgate.
I know.
We don't receive
many visitors here.
We're rather
like a leper colony.
Well, I doubt lepers
are so charming.
I wish you would stop
complimenting me.
It makes me
uncomfortable.
Forgive me, Mrs. Graves.
The last thing
I wish to do
is offend you.
Are you quite certain
you're a doctor?
Yeah, well,
of course I am.
Because I've never known
one to apologize.
Or, for that matter,
give a damn who
he offended.
Well, I-I'm not like
other doctors.
I mean, to be honest,
I still haven't gotten
used to being one.
Whenever someone
calls "doctor",
I still turn to see
if they're talking
to the chap behind me.
Here you go, ma'am.
Thank you, nurse.
Right.
Remarkable, isn't she?
She should be
on a stage,
not languishing
in some asylum.
Forgive me,
I'm Dr. Newgate.
Edward Newgate.
And you are?
Let Jael rejoice
with the Plover.
Pardon me?
And Hobab rejoice
with Heraclitus.
That is Greek
for the grub.
Ah, Newgate.
Tuxedo fits, I see.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you.
I'm sorry,
but what's
he doing here?
Oh, Jeremiah.
He killed his wife
with a hammer.
Not without
provocation, mind you.
But what's he doing here
in the staff parlor?
When I was
a medical officer
in the war,
we would on occasion
invite the enlisted men
to dine with us.
It strengthened the bond
between the men and... kept
morale high.
And I believe
the same principal
applies here.
It's therapeutic
for the patients
to mix with polite society,
and, I might add,
for polite society
to mix with them.
Dinner is served.
Good boy.
Tell me, doctor,
what do you think
of our little asylum?
Why, it's quite... unlike
anything I've ever known.
Newgate recently took
his medical degree
at Oxford.
But why come
all the way here
when there are
other asylums
far closer to London?
Well, I've always longed
to return to the countryside,
I suppose.
You know, I-I grew up
in a farm in Yorkshire,
and, uh, some
of my fondest memories
are of the cows
and chickens that
were my playmates.
You don't have
the Yorkshire man's accent.
Why's that, Ted?
Well, my, my,
my parents died
when I was six
so I was sent
to an orphanage
in London.
Appalling place.
But, I mean, you know,
fascinating if one was curious
about human nature as I was.
In a funny way,
I was quite grateful
to them.
How so?
Well, misery has a way
of clarifying one's
convictions.
See, it was in the orphanage
that I realized what my life's
work would be.
To labor
amongst the wretched
and the friendless.
And to give
these poor souls
some small measure
of hope and kindness
in a world
that knows too little.
Forgive me, I-I seem
to have turned dinner
into a Dickens' novel.
Bon appetite.
What is this tonight, Finn?
Squirrel?
At present
we find ourselves
somewhat modestly provisioned.
A toast to Mr. Finn
for providing
such fine victuals
for our Christmas repast.
Mickey Finn.
I'm-I'm sorry.
Is that really your name?
'Tis. Why?
Well, you know,
to slip someone
a Mickey Finn,
you know,
with knock-out drops.
It's quite, quite, uh...
Well, quite.
That never occurred to me.
"Slip someone a Mickey."
That must be
how me da got
me dear old ma
to lie still
while he ah, ah,
ah, ah, ah, ah.
You'll forgive me
if I don't find that
at all amusing.
No?
What would bring
a smile to that puckered-ass
of a mouth of yours?
That will be
enough, Finn.
My apologies.
I meant no offense.
Yeah, well, none taken.
That's the Christmas spirit.
Come now.
Let me offer you
a little drink
of friendship.
No, no, no.
I've had quite enough.
Come on,
we're celebrating.
Honestly, Finn.
I'm sure he doesn't mind
raising a glass to our Lord
and Savior.
Do you now, Doctor?
I-I'd be delighted.
Oh, dear.
I'm afraid
that will stain.
Soda water
will save it.
Follow me.
You must leave here
immediately.
But I've only
just arrived.
You do not belong here.
Why, I was going to say
the same thing about you.
There's time before
they get suspicious.
They'll assume you went
to your room to change
your shirt, but don't.
Leave your things.
Go straight to the stable.
The roan is the most
sure-footed on the moor.
She'll see you
safely back to town.
You want me
to steal a horse?
Lower your voice.
No, not until you tell me
what's going on.
Do as I say.
Leave.
Now.
Eliza.
Eliza, please...
Mrs. Graves,
I'm... I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean
to upset you.
Mrs. Graves, indeed,
then listen to me.
There's-There's something
I need to tell you.
Help us.
Please.
Get off me.
Help us!
Help us.
We need food.
Please.
Please, help us.
Who are you, boy?
I-I'm a doctor.
Liar.
I've never
set eyes on you.
Where are you from?
Upstairs.
Before that, you fool.
I'm from Oxford.
You listen to me,
and listen
carefully, boy.
You have got to help us
escape from these cages.
We're not mad.
Please.
Please help us.
Of course you're not.
You've got to help us.
I will, I will.
First thing in the morning,
I'll consult with Dr. Lamb.
Dr. Lamb?
Are you daft?
If he learns that
you found us, he'll slit
your throat and ours.
You must get the keys.
Let us out.
Please, we're not mad.
All right.
You've got to help us.
I'll see to it
in the morning.
Let us out.
Newgate.
Edward Newgate.
How do you know
my name?
Your letter.
You remember, Benjamin?
It was weeks ago.
The young man
who wrote to us
from Oxford.
I remember.
Newgate.
Your letter came
with the last mail delivery
before Lamb
overthrew us.
Overthrew you?
Yes.
Overthrew?
What is going on?
I am Marion Pike.
Matron.
Charles Swanwick.
Chief medical officer.
Nurse.
William Paxton,
groundskeeper.
Dr. Benjamin Salt,
rightful Superintendent
of Stonehearst asylum.
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
If you really are
the superintendent,
then that means
that Dr. Lamb is...
A lunatic demon
of the worst kind.
Oh, good God.
God.
What happened?
They put something
in our drink, Doc.
Chloral hydrate.
It's-It's a surgical
anesthetic.
It's colorless
and odorless,
but lethal
in imprecise doses.
I lost four
doctors that night.
Three of my nurses died.
Poor creatures.
They'd been
planning this for months.
Treacherous bastards.
Just biding their time
to slip us...
A Mickey Finn.
I don't believe...
They give us water,
a pittance of food.
But make
no mistake, Doctor,
we are dying.
We are dying.
You could steal
the keys from Finn.
Ah?
Set us free.
They'd tear us apart
before we'd gone
a hundred yards.
We'll take
our chances fighting.
In our condition,
against their numbers?
There are homicidal
maniacs upstairs
with guns, Charles.
Look around you.
None of us are fit
to fight.
Some of us are
too far gone already.
There's only
one solution.
It's you, Doctor.
You're our only chance.
Please.
Run, boy.
The keys.
Get to town.
Bring help.
Run.
The keys.
Run, boy.
Who is it, Eliza?
I'm frightened.
It's no one, dearest.
Just the Sandman.
Mrs. Graves.
Is he going to try
and make love to us?
Back to sleep.
Mrs. Graves, we must
leave here immediately.
You had your chance
to leave before.
I have found Salt
and the others,
Mrs. Graves.
Do you realize
what would've happened
if you'd been caught?
I have some idea.
You have no idea.
We can argue
about this later.
Right now I need you
to fetch your warmest coat
and meet me in the gazebo
in ten minutes.
We can steal a horse,
and if we're lucky
we can make it
to town and summon help.
Why would you presume
I would go anywhere
with you?
Because I cannot...
I will not leave
without you.
I must go back to bed.
Listen to me.
The lunatics
are running
this asylum.
Yes, and I am one of them.
What's this I see?
Evening rounds
are finished, Doctor.
I was just giving
Dr. Newgate directions
back to his room.
Lost, is he?
Ah, yes,
embarrassingly so.
I was looking
for the staff library.
I must have made
a wrong turn.
Well, any event,
I know where
I'm headed now,
so I'll bid you all
good night.
Thank you, Mrs. Graves.
Finn, see
the young doctor
to his room.
My pleasure.
No, no.
Won't be necessary.
Oh, I insist.
And I shall expect you
for morning rounds.
Half past eight.
Right.
Of course.
This way, Ted.
Does he suspect anything?
No.
We must endeavor
to make sure
it stays that way.
Something is
troubling you,
my dear.
This cannot last, Silas.
Eventually
we will be discovered.
The spring is coming.
People will come.
Visitors.
We cannot just
lock them out.
The only reason
any of us are here
is because the world
wanted to be rid of us.
We're embarrassments
to our family,
exiles to the human race.
We will not be discovered
for the simple reason
that no one cares.
My husband does.
I promise you
you will always be safe
within these walls.
I'm afraid this
is all I could find.
Supplies upstairs
are running low.
I'll bring more
next time.
And some laudanum
for that cough of yours.
Bless you, Doctor.
It's men
with guns we need,
not medicine.
That's not an option
anymore, Doctor.
After last night,
Finn and his goons
are watching me like hawks.
I barely made it
here undetected.
Come back here.
Please mate, come on.
I could be wrong,
but Lamb strikes me
as a man
who would rather
see the ship sink
with everyone in it
than give up the helm.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
So, even
if we did steal away
and find help,
God knows
what would await us
when we returned.
We?
Well, me-me
and Mrs. Graves.
Eliza Graves?
Don't be a fool, man.
She's as mad as the lot
of them.
No, no, I...
I don't believe she is.
Tell that
to her husband.
But make sure you speak
into his good ear, the one
she didn't bite off.
The man is a monster.
She was right
to defend herself.
Mrs. Pike, may I remind you
on which side of the bars
you sit?
So, you cannot flee,
you cannot steal
Finn's keys.
What do you
propose to do?
Huh?
Look, I came here
to study his methods.
Now, Lamb sees me
as his protégé.
If I could just
maintain that-that trust,
you know, understand
the workings
of his mind,
maybe I could
bring him to reason.
He killed
five soldiers
in cold blood.
And do you think
you can outfox him, boy?
If you could just
give me his case file.
Long gone.
It's the first thing
he'd have destroyed.
Well then... well then,
I'd best be back
before I'm missed.
In the medicine cabinet.
Behind the Scotch.
In his...
In-in my office.
He escaped once before
and he stole it, briefly.
I didn't want
to give him that
pleasure again,
so I hid his casebook.
Right.
Doctor?
I want to warn you.
I do not know
what Lamb's plan
is for us,
but I do know
that if he believes
you could jeopardize it,
he will not hesitate
to slit your throat.
Deplorable conditions these,
but soon I mean to make
a change.
And what better way
to bring in the new century
than by doing away
with this godforsaken ward
and all the backward
thinking it represents.
Right, Finn?
Right, then.
So, what do you hope
to do with the current
residents?
Introduce them
to the general population.
You're not serious.
Keep a man in a cage
and he'll behave like
an animal.
Give him his freedom
and he'll remember
his humanity.
And that's your plan,
is it, to create
an enlightened society?
Do I sense skepticism
in your question, Doctor?
No, not at all.
I suppose I'm just
curious to know
if you think there are
any individuals whose crimes
are so heinous
they justify imprisonment.
Sadists... who find
gratification
in the debasement
of others.
And those cowards who
would send younger men
to their deaths
in battles
they themselves
would avoid.
Except for these,
I believe all men can
be rehabilitated
often by the simple act
of having their dignity
restored.
Who-who's down there?
The Ogre of Oxbridge.
The Ogre of what?
Stage name.
His family sold him off
to a side show when he was
a child.
He injured his hand
a few days ago whilst
attacking a nurse.
Would you be so kind
as to change the dressing,
Doctor?
You expect me
to go down there?
You came here
for clinical experience,
did you not?
Yes, of course.
Well, two grains of opium,
I should think, will do
the trick.
Don't need that.
What do you
expect me to do,
sing him a lullaby?
Use these.
The asylum doctor's
greatest ally.
Look out
for the piss bucket.
Hello?
Now listen here.
I don't mean
to harm you,
Mr. Ogre.
I just want
to see your hand.
Oh, good God.
It's all right.
Lamb, please help.
Eyes, Newgate.
Eyes.
Arthur.
Arthur, please.
P-Please, Arthur.
Arthur.
Forgive me, Arthur.
May I call you Arthur?
Can I?
I-I didn't mean to enter
without permission.
I meant no offense.
I'm Dr. Newgate.
But you
can call me Edward.
It's all right.
Eddard?
That's right, Edward.
Eddard.
Now, Arthur,
let's, let's have
a look at that hand,
shall we?
It's okay.
All right.
That's it, Arthur.
Bravo, Doctor.
Bravo.
Can you take
your trousers off,
please?
No, no.
It's, uh,
it's my shoulder.
Please?
I will do that, Millie.
You may return
to your duties.
But I want to.
Leave us.
Sit down.
Bare your shoulder.
Stubborn fool.
Why didn't you listen?
You could've left
when you had the chance.
I didn't know then
what I do now, Eliza.
Don't call me that.
Mrs. Graves,
you have to understand,
you are
in danger here.
I can assure you
I am not.
Give me your hand.
And what of those
down below?
What about them?
Mrs. Pike
and the women,
are they suffering
terribly?
Yes, all of them are.
You could go down
there yourself.
Or are you afraid that
what you'll see will weaken
your loyalty to Lamb?
You have no idea
what it was like here
before.
What monsters Salt
and his men were.
How we were stripped bare
and subjected to examinations
of the most disgusting,
intimate nature.
Strapped to tables,
given drugs to dull
our senses, and doused
with ice-cold water
and made to suffer
a thousand other indignities
too horrible to mention.
But you couldn't
possibly understand.
I can.
I-I can.
I know what
cruelty is,
Mrs. Graves.
I-I know.
And I give you my word
that you will never again
have to suffer the way
that you have.
Never.
Why do you care so much
what happens to me?
Because
the very thought
of you locked away
in this madhouse
is abhorrent
to everything
that I believe,
as a doctor
and... and as a man.
Excuse me.
For Christ's sake, Swanwick,
will you give it up?
We have as much chance
of escaping that way
as a man
clawing his way
out of his own grave.
Maybe so, but at least
it won't say on my gravestone
what it'll say on yours.
"He died like a dog
in the dark."
You done it.
Get to town.
Quick. Hurry.
Get help.
Hurry.
I still don't get
why he's walking around.
He should be down
in a cage with the others.
I cannot continue to run
this bloody asylum
on my own.
I need an assistant.
I thought that was me.
With medical training.
How hard can it be
to play a doctor?
"Turn your head
and cough."
"Bend over, young lady,
while I take a little
look at you."
Your talents
are better suited
to other duties.
Like making sure
the dipsomaniacs keep
the bloody boilers stoked.
Bloody icebox in here.
What's he got on you?
What are you
talking about?
You haven't been the same
since he showed up.
I suppose I feel
a certain sense
of duty towards him.
He has the makings
of a fine asylum doctor.
Reminds me of myself,
a... headstrong, idealistic.
Ah.
Fetch another,
would you?
I sense a kindred
spirit in him.
I believe he may understand
what I'm trying to accomplish
here.
Yeah, well,
how understanding
is he going to be
if he discovers Salt
and all them others?
Come the New Year,
that won't matter
any longer.
There'll be nothing
to discover.
I tell you,
I don't trust
that little gutterfuck.
He's up to something.
Perhaps I'm wrong
about him,
but he's taken
a keen interest
in our Lady Graves.
He won't be raising
any alarms
unless he has her
on his side.
And that I can assure you
will never happen.
Someone's escaped.
Oi.
Hai!
Here.
If they reach town,
it's the end of us.
They won't.
Come on.
Oh, Lord, no.
No.
Now, now, gentlemen.
You get back.
You bastards.
Back.
Get back.
There's no need
for tears.
You have my word
you won't be harmed.
Is that what you said
to your mother and sister
before you slashed
their throats? Hm?
Aye, Mr. Swan.
But your methods
have cured my madness.
I'm a peaceful man now.
I am.
A veritable... lamb.
No!
It's a sad
and shameful thing that.
Come now, Mr. Swanwick.
Let's get inside
before we all catch
our deaths.
Oh, dear.
One of them
threw themselves
from Stag's Leap.
And this one came
at me like a banshee.
The horse spooked,
reared up and kicked
the old pecker in the nut.
Fell down stone dead.
Suicidal tendencies
are not uncommon amongst
the seriously deranged.
As we know.
Finn.
See that the body
is buried.
Aye.
Dr. Lamb.
Did he stab himself
in the back as well?
He must have landed
on something when he fell.
Something sharp.
Pity.
No, you can't just
walk away from this.
From what, dear boy?
Sir, if you would only
just examine the body
yourself.
I am not a coroner.
Nor are you.
Dr. Lamb, this man
has clearly been...
Killed by a horse.
I have an asylum to run.
And you I believe, Doctor,
have patients to attend to.
This is madness.
What did you say?
I said
this is madness.
Madness.
Madness, you say?
How dare you accuse me
of madness in front
of my own staff?
I didn't accuse you
of anything.
Two patients
are dead, Newgate,
because you
were not doing your duty
and watching over them.
Silas.
Where were you, Newgate,
when these two
fellows escaped?
How many more must die
because of your negligence?
Silas!
Nurse, I think
we'd better get
ourselves inside.
March 1st, 1891.
This enigma
called Silas Lamb
continues to mystify me.
Silas remains mute
about his years
as a military surgeon,
the war,
and most of all,
the horrific incident
that had him committed
to this asylum.
No! No!
And yet he has
no such reservations
when it comes
to protesting
what he calls
my "barbaric" methods.
How ironic
to be called cruel
by a man such as this,
a man accused
of such atrocities.
No! No!
When you have found
the thing a man fears most,
you will have discovered
the key to his madness
and the means
to control it.
Silas appears
to fear very little.
But all men have
their breaking points.
And I am bound by my oath
as his doctor to find his.
To cure him
and to make him whole.
I believe Silas enjoys
what he mistakenly believes
is his control over me.
In his tormented mind,
his stay at Stonehearst
is merely a chess match.
And I am his pawn
to move as he sees fit
for his pleasure.
But like most children,
Silas seems to forget
all games must end.
And there is only
one victor.
October 3rd., 1899.
Over the past
nine years now
I have struggled
to determine
what it is that haunts
the soul of Silas Lamb.
A cruel mother?
A sadistic father?
Indifferent God?
I don't claim
to know the answer.
I only know
that animals
like Silas Lamb
must be broken
to be made men again.
That's one
of my suits
you are wearing.
Fits me well,
don't you think?
Of course,
I had to have it
taken in a bit.
But then,
you're a stouter
fellow than I am.
Or were.
I suppose
I shouldn't be surprised
that killing
unarmed men
in cold blood
hasn't affected
your appetite.
On the contrary.
Their deaths
were most distressing
to myself
and my staff.
Staff?
A bunch of inebriates
and chronic masturbators
more like it.
Funny I've never seen
the harm in chronic
masturbation.
Nevertheless,
I bring condolences
and a recommendation
that no one else repeat
their error.
And as a show
of good faith,
I'll increase
your rations
and send down
more fresh water.
You see,
old friend,
unlike you,
I'm not a cruel man.
Whilst, uh,
whilst I'm here,
I thought you might like
a report on the condition
of the patients.
I don't give a damn.
They're not
my responsibility
any more.
The melancholiacs
are less lethargic
since being weaned off
the large doses of opium
you had them on.
The hysterics
are less listless
now that they don't have
you poking around their
private parts.
Even the mongoloids
are thriving since being
taken out of their restraints
and put to meaningful
work in the kitchens.
A pity it's all
for naught
when they starve
to death.
We are sufficiently
provisioned.
I'll tell you
what I think,
old friend.
I think that
you haven't taken
anything for that cough
because you neglected
to lock the medical cabinet
and the opium addicts
got into the laudanum.
And I suspect that
you're wearing that suit
because it's the warmest
suit in my closet,
which comes in very handy
when you have imbeciles
looking after
the boilers.
I hope
you've enjoyed
pretending
to be sane, Silas.
Has this masquerade
helped you to forget
what it was like
blowing those poor
boys' brains through
their skulls?
Mr. Finn.
Dr. Lamb.
Find Dr. Newgate.
Have him meet me
in the surgery.
Fine.
Don't eat.
See if I care.
Silly old cow.
Millie.
I'm tired.
I'm tired
of being a nurse.
Can't things
go back to the way
they were before?
May I try?
Thank you.
Now,
will you try one
for me?
He doesn't like
the taste of it.
No.
Your son, right?
And he tastes
what you taste,
does he?
But how?
Right through the cord.
Do you not see
how it stretches from me
out the window to him?
He's off fighting
the Afghans, he is.
You don't want me
to starve, do you,
Mother?
Daniel?
Yes.
Blessed Lord.
Is it really you, Daniel?
Yes, it's me.
Listen, no matter
how great the distance
between us,
you will always be
on my mind.
My dearest boy.
Listen, Mother,
I'm afraid I have
to go abroad again
on a secret
diplomatic mission
for Her Majesty the Queen.
Where?
I'm not
at liberty to say.
But food
is very scarce there
so I need you
to eat for the both of us.
Can you do that for me?
For Daniel?
I will.
That's it.
Well done.
Very good.
No, no, no.
Go off to bed.
Get some rest.
I still have
the bedpans to do.
No, doctor's orders.
Fine.
Go.
Millie, lock the door.
A couple more.
Very good.
That's it.
Thank you so much.
Millie really
needs the rest.
Lamb has her
running herself ragged
doing the work of four nurses.
On an empty stomach,
in a ward with no heat.
Well, in a few months
it'll be spring.
In a few months
we may all be dead.
Pneumonia. Typhus.
Starvation.
Finn, even.
Look, Lamb's experiment
is crumbling, Eliza.
Look, he cannot see it
because he's blinded
by madness.
But you're not.
When I first arrived here,
Millie could barely speak.
Salt had put her
in a morphine coma
to control her.
Lamb took her off
all sorts of medication.
Had her work
on the wards.
It was good for her.
She's grown
into a capable
young woman.
Yes, with the mind
of a child, but she's
alive, Edward.
You love her
like your own sister.
Yes.
That's why
I can never
leave her.
Well, you don't have to.
Really,
you don't have to.
We can go together
all three of us.
Together.
Start a new life
away from here.
Where?
Spain, Italy.
Someplace where the sun
is always shining
and the sky is blue,
and... and you can be free
to do whatever
you want to do.
Somewhere you can be
truly, truly alive.
I can make
that happen.
I can.
Nothing can get
in our way.
Nothing.
My husband can.
If he does,
then I would kill him.
Be careful, Edward.
When you speak like that,
you don't sound like a doctor.
When I'm with you, I...
I forget that I am.
I wouldn't get
too close to that one.
Bit of a biter, she is.
Dr. Lamb requests
your presence.
Where?
Follow me.
Ah, Newgate,
just in time.
For what?
To assist me
in an experimental procedure
of my own devising
which, when perfected,
I expect to usher
in a new era
in the humane treatment
of lunacy.
An unfortunate case.
Believes himself to be
the rightful superintendent
of Stonehearst.
It's a common delusion.
Ranks right behind
Napoleon and Jesus Christ.
What are you going
do to him?
Treat him, of course.
With Edison's miracle
of our age,
we shall banish to history
the straitjackets,
the cold baths,
the nausea machines,
the floggings.
Finn, we will start
with three seconds.
I call it
"electrotherapy".
And I think you'll be
fascinated to see
what happens
when it is applied
to the subject's brain.
You'll need
a stronger stomach
if you expect
to practice
asylum medicine.
It may look painful,
but I can assure you
he feels nothing.
Yeah, but his heart.
A tenth of that could
stop his heart.
You may do the honors
this time, Doctor.
What? No.
A dose of five seconds
should clinch it.
But, Dr. Lamb, you can't
possibly imagine that I...
Do it!
Do it.
And now
you will see
the miraculous effects
of this remarkable
new therapy.
What is your name, sir?
I don't know.
Are you
the superintendent here?
I don't know.
As you can see,
a mind that was not
moments ago tormented
by delusion
is now pacified.
I... Am I in hospital?
You are a patient
at Stonehearst Asylum.
Who are you people?
Tell him, Doctor.
Tell him.
We are your keepers.
I'm afraid
that's the last
of the laudanum.
Thank you, Doctor.
Now listen.
You must rest
if you can.
You need
your strength.
For what?
Tonight I intend
to set you free.
All of you.
Tonight?
Why?
Because I-I fear
Lamb's procedure
on Salt
was merely
a rehearsal.
I fear he means
to do it to all
of you.
Tonight.
I never did approve
of Dr. Salt's methods.
Of course,
it wasn't my place
to criticize.
You know,
Eliza said you were
always very kind to her
and the other patients.
I loved them
like my own children.
Even Lamb?
There is some good
even in poor Silas.
Though I fear
it has become
deranged by madness.
How do I understand him?
Your first instinct
was the right one.
Think of him
as your patient.
Shine the light
of your sympathy
into the darkest
corners of his mind,
and maybe then you'll find
what he so desperately wants
to keep hidden from you
and from himself.
Only then will you have
what you need.
To defeat him?
No.
To heal him.
It is difficult
imagining Lamb
as a patient.
Perhaps you should spend
some time where he spent
so much of his.
Why won't you let me go?
I want to go.
Because it's not appropriate
for a girl your age.
But I'm not a girl.
I'm a lady.
Quite beautiful one,
mind you.
You should see
how the boys stare at me.
Listen to me, Millie.
You must stay in this room
with the door locked
until I return,
do you understand?
You just want to leave me here
so you can run away with him,
don't you?
Who?
Dr. Newgate.
Millie, that's absurd.
You're going to run away
with him and you're going
to leave me here
to wipe bums
and empty bedpans,
and it's not fair.
Oh, no.
Sh.
There, there.
I'm not going anywhere.
Eliza?
Yes, darling.
What's it like?
What's what like?
To be in love?
You're the belle
of the ball.
You look beautiful.
I suppose
you've come
to ask me to dance.
Believe me,
nothing would
please me more.
But there isn't time.
Look, I need you
to do me a favor.
There's something
I must do, and if Lamb
asks you,
tell him I've gone outside
for some fresh air.
Now tell him.
Where are you going?
To find a way
to put an end
to all of this.
Wait.
Edward, wait.
Dinner is served.
Oh.
Eliza.
How do you do?
Who? Me?
Why, I'd be delighted.
May I butt in?
Well, well.
What a beautiful dress.
And lovely shoes.
Think of him
as a patient.
Shine the light
of your sympathy
into the darkest
corners of his mind,
and maybe then you'll find
what he so desperately wants
to keep hidden from you
and from himself.
No.
Pleurisy, I suspect.
Brought on by catarrh.
The...
The poor
child's heart
gave out.
Take the body
upstairs, would you?
No.
Do not touch her.
She's gone
to a better place.
No.
This was supposed to be
a better place.
It is nearly midnight.
Someone.
You.
Fetch the champagne.
Bring it here, quickly.
All of my friends.
Join me outside.
The new century
is nearly upon us.
Peter!
Where's Peter?
Peter, my pyromaniac friend.
You may do the honors.
Tonight
we shall warm
ourselves
by the fire
of our ignominious past.
Are you quite
finished there, Ted?
Spiking the bubbly,
I mean.
You're slipping
them all a Mickey Finn.
Not if Mickey Finn
slips you one first.
Well, I wasn't
expecting that.
Ah!
Jesus,
Mary and Joseph.
That's the other one!
Come on.
Now, now, Ted.
Doctor.
You're just in time.
Indeed.
Ah, there you are.
There we are.
Won't you be
joining us, Doctor?
Of course.
Allow me.
Ten,
nine,
eight,
seven, six,
five, four,
three, two,
one.
Stop!
Don't drink
the fecking champagne!
Believe nothing
that you hear
and only one half
of what you see.
Welcome back, Ted.
There, have a little rest
while we set the stage.
I'll be back
in two shakes
of a whore's tail.
Come on.
Dear friends.
A few hours ago
we celebrated
the arrival
of a new century,
and in a few hours more,
we shall celebrate
the dawning of a new day
in this,
the grand experiment
we have been
conducting together.
Oh, Eliza.
Oh, thank God.
Please help me
undo these straps.
Please.
Eliza.
It was found
on your person.
Why did you come here?
You know why I came here,
to study asylum medicine.
You're a liar.
He sent you.
Who?
My husband.
To take me
back to him.
No.
I don't believe you.
Why did you come here?
I...
I came here for you.
For me?
Why?
I-I saw you
six months ago
at a medical lecture.
I saw you.
You were there?
Help me.
One of you.
Please, I'm not mad.
You looked so lost
and so beautiful.
It sickened me
to see you exhibited
like a sideshow freak.
Look at me.
I would have stopped it
if I could, but I couldn't.
I-I couldn't.
So, I vowed
there and then
that I would find you
and that nothing would
stop me.
Did you even know
my name?
It didn't matter.
No, it does matter.
Saying otherwise
proves you're no better
than any of them.
Than who?
My family,
my doctors,
my husband.
You act like
I'm some precious
thing to be bartered
or put on display
or possessed.
It-It's not like that
with me, Eliza.
No?
How is it different?
It's you
who possesses me.
Excuse us, your Ladyship.
You must
get out of here.
Go, please.
Ride to the village.
Please.
Time for Ted's
big debut.
Eliza, promise me.
Promise me.
Eliza.
Eliza!
Tonight
we will show mercy
to a man
who has betrayed us,
and through the miracle
of medical science
we make him
in our image.
And when we are done,
he'll not need to be locked
below in a dungeon
like the criminal he was,
but will join us
up above in the light,
fully rehabilitated.
And we shall embrace him
as one of our own.
Pity.
You would have made
a fine asylum doctor.
You showed
a rare talent for it.
You're mad.
We're all mad,
Dr. Newgate.
Some are simply
not mad enough
to admit it.
Crank it up, Finn.
Now.
We will start
with a dose
of ten seconds.
Wait, wait, wait.
Before you start,
I'd like a final request.
In my vest pocket
there's a picture
of Eliza Graves.
I'd like her
to have it.
Very well.
Silas.
Silas!
Keep going.
Faster.
Faster!
Feck, I don't need you.
I'll do it me self.
Eliza.
Eliza, my feet.
Hurry.
Eliza!
Eliza.
Look at me.
Hit the switch.
Quick, my hands.
Eliza.
Untie me.
Quick, my hands.
Everybody out!
Evacuate the building!
Evacuate!
Take these keys
and set them free.
Where are you going?
To find Lamb.
Everybody outside!
Go that way.
Keep going.
Quickly.
Please help, Dr. Lamb.
Dr. Lamb.
They were suffering, so...
And I...
It's over, Silas.
I saved them.
I know.
I saved them all.
The war,
it's over, Silas.
There you go.
Ladies.
Let's start
putting the patients
in the far wing.
William.
William, you may come
with me now.
Yes, Mrs. Pike.
Come.
Inside.
Eliza.
Down here.
Silas.
Can you hear me?
Eliza, he's gone.
Eliza.
We could leave now.
Edward, I can't.
You can't what?
I can't imagine
being anywhere
but here.
You can't...
I'm quite sure
you don't mean that.
Yes.
Because you are sane
and I am not.
I'm not sane.
I'm madly in love
with you.
Eliza, listen to me.
Listen to me.
There's something
I need to tell you.
I should've told you
right from the beginning,
but I was too afraid.
Eliza...
Inexcusable this.
No way to run
an asylum.
Dear God.
You realize
we've been ringing for over
a quarter of an hour.
We need to speak
with your superintendent
at once
on a matter
of utmost urgency.
No.
What?
We can't speak with him?
Well, why the devil not?
There you are, dear.
Tea, Benjamin.
Sodomite.
Am I to understand
it is you who is
in charge here, Madam?
It is.
Highly irregular.
No mind.
And what is this, sir?
Release papers
instructing you to discharge
a former patient of mine
named Eliza Graves
and remit her to our
custody.
I'm afraid
I cannot, sir.
What?
Why not?
Because she was discharged
three weeks ago.
On whose orders?
Dr. Newgate's.
I beg your pardon?
Dr. Edward Newgate,
from Oxford.
That's impossible.
Why?
Because, my good woman,
I am Dr. Edward Newgate.
It's as I feared.
We're too late.
Would someone please tell
me what's going on?
The young man
you knew as Dr. Newgate
is neither
a Newgate
nor a doctor.
How silly.
Of course he was a doctor.
I can assure you, madame,
he is not.
Well, who is he then?
A very cunning
and disturbed patient
who until two months ago
was under my care
at Bethlehem
Royal Hospital
in London.
Forgive me,
but that makes
no sense, Doctor.
Why would he go to the trouble
of escaping from one asylum
only to enter another?
To find my wife.
Next patient.
Any questions?
It seems he became
unduly infatuated
with Lady Graves
at a medical demonstration
I gave at Oxford.
Some time after that,
he managed to escape
his room,
elude two orderlies, and flee
via a laundry chute,
in the process
stealing my pocket watch,
my Derringer, and my, uh...
Identity.
In any event,
suffice it to say,
he's a very disturbed
young man.
He suffers
from Pseudologia fantastica,
one of the most severe
cases I've ever encountered.
In all the years
I've known him,
I've never uncovered
his true identity.
It could very well be
that he's an empty shell
incapable
of true feeling
beyond a cure.
Check
mate.
You'll excuse me
if I disagree, Doctor.
No one is beyond cure.
In fact, I believe
your young man
has found his.
What precisely
might that be?
Not what.
Who.
Shall we, Mrs. Lamb?
With pleasure, Dr. Lamb.