EXistenZ.
Written like this. One word.
Small "E," capital "X,"
capital "Z."
"EXistenZ."
It's new, it's from
Antenna Research and it's here,
right now.
We encourage consumer loyalty,
and want you to help our testing.
We're a team, Antenna and you.
Those of you who have come
to our invited seminars before
will know that I normally lead
the groups through new games.
But tonight it won't be me. No.
For our test launch
of eXistenZ by Antenna,
we have brought you
a special seminar leader.
(Audience chattering)
Yes, it is.
The world's greatest game designer
is here, in person,
to lead you, our first test enclave,
through her newest creation,
eXistenZ by Antenna.
I give you the game-pod
goddess herself, Allegra Geller.
(Audience cheering)
Allegra! Allegra! Yeah! Allegra!
The world of games
is in a kind of trance.
People are programmed
to accept so little,
but the possibilities
are so great.
EXistenZ is not just... a game.
It's an entirely new game system.
And, uh...
(Sighs)
It involves a lot of new toys,
which you are going
to be the first to try.
So...
(Cheering)
We have 12 prototype
MetaFlesh game-pods,
and that means for our first test
enclave we need 12 volunteers
to port into these slave units
with the game-pod goddess herself.
- OK, if I pick you...
- Hold it! Not so fast.
Oh, jeez. Right.
I'm not late, am I?
You can be part of the second wave.
You, and the guy with the grey hair.
You, sir. This lady here.
Just come up. Thank you.
- Noel Dichter?
- Yes?
- I have to scan you.
- It's a weapons check?
More for recording devices. Lot
of money invested in these games.
We'll help you to port your pod
into your bio-ports
using Antenna Research's new...
- What's in this case?
- I brought my game-pod.
It's, uh, got original
Marway tissue architecture.
Even though I couldn't afford
the Antenna 15 upgrade,
- I figured out this method...
- You won't need it tonight.
Everything's provided for.
- How are you doin'?
- Two hours, tops?
Oh, two, three hours.
- So, three?
- Yeah.
(Geller) OK.
(Host) Everything's in order.
Ready, Allegra?
Sure, this is my favourite part.
Take it away.
All right.
I'm ready to download eXistenZ
by Antenna Research into all of you.
Now, I'm warning you.
It's going to be a wild ride.
But don't panic...
No matter what happens, OK?
See ya back here in no time at all.
(Squealing)
She seems to be very shy.
Never occurred to me
that a big star would be shy.
She spends most of her time
alone designing her games.
She'd prefer it
if she never had to show them.
Death to the demoness
Allegra Geller!
- No!
- Aah!
(Confused shouts and screams)
Death to Antenna Research!
Aah!
(Gunshot)
(Gunshots)
Get her out of here.
Save her. There might be more.
- Go!
- Me take her?
We have enemies in our own house.
Trust no one! Trust no one.
Miss Geller, you're coming with me.
(Moaning)
I'm responsible for you.
You're supposed to come with me.
What are we gonna do out here?
Do you know your way around?
Know any country people?
Not country people, games people.
Countryside's full of
games development people:
Project coordinators,
little factories, you name it.
OK, you know your way around.
We can hide out.
Maybe.
It seems I have some enemies
I didn't know I had.
"Death to Allegra Geller."
Would you like hearing
someone with a gun screaming
"Death to Ted Pikul"?
Wow.
Hey, how'd you know my name?
You're labelled.
Yeah.
(Electronic beeping)
What's that?
It's my pink-fone.
Ted Pikul.
What happen... What?
Hey!
What did you do that for?
- That was our lifeline.
- That was a range finder.
- With that they know where we are.
- "They?"
- You mean head office.
- I mean anybody.
Pikul, why don't you have a gun?
- What?
- You're not armed.
You're my security,
but you have no weaponry.
Who told you that?
I'm just a marketing trainee.
Fucking hell.
I'm marked for death, and they
send me out with a PR nerd!
Marked for death.
Marked for death. Oh, jeez.
OK, don't sweat it, Pikul.
Don't sweat it. I'll handle it.
And, uh, right now we need to stop.
We do? Why?
So we can have
an intimate moment together.
If you're gonna do it, do it.
OK. OK?
Mm-hmm.
Ahh!
- Did somebody bite you?
- What?
(Thunder rumbling)
What I just dug out of you...
It's a tooth.
A human...
tooth.
Let me see that weirdo pistol.
Yep.
The bullets are human teeth.
This one's got a cavity.
That thing can get past any kind
of metal or synthetics detector.
It's all flesh and bone.
I suppose smaller calibre pistols
would have to fire baby teeth.
The tooth fairy could go
into the arms business.
- Where were you just now?
- I was wandering through eXistenZ.
The new system, I mean.
I like it in there.
'Course, without another player,
you're only a tourist.
It's frustrating.
Why won't you
let me contact Antenna?
(Groans)
They'll be going crazy
wondering what's happened.
I mean, it's not like
we've done something wrong.
We ran because we didn't know how
many of them there were, right?
We owe it to Antenna
to let them know you're all right,
and get them to send somebody to
help who knows what he's doing.
Besides, I can't...
I can't just keep doing this,
whatever it is,
you know, forever.
Not having any idea
when it's going... Hey!
- What are you doing?
- Where's your bio-port?
You've never been fitted?
I can't believe it.
No, I was never fitted.
What do you care?
You wanna get into the biz
and never played my games?
You've never played any game.
Look...
I've been dying to play your games,
but I have this phobia
about having my body
penetrated... surgically.
You know what I mean.
No. I'm not sure I do.
Getting a bio-port fitted.
I don't know. I can't do it.
It's too freaky.
Makes my skin crawl.
They just pop your spine
with a hydro-gun.
They shoot the plug into it.
It's like getting your ears pierced.
With only an infinitesimal chance
of permanent spinal paralysis.
- I've read about it.
- Hey, it's your chosen profession.
Besides,
once you're ported, zzzt,
there's no end
to the games you can play.
You can't seriously
wanna play games now?
Not while we're being hunted down
by crazy people.
My baby here
took a huge hit in the church.
One of those UmbyCords
got ripped out of her.
Ripped out of her,
just as the game architecture
was being downloaded from her
to all those slave-pods.
That's a very vulnerable
time for her.
She could be crying out for help
right here, right now.
The only way I can tell
if the game's not been contaminated,
if the pod is not about to be
crippled because of my negligence,
is to play eXistenZ
with somebody friendly.
Are you friendly,
or are you not?
Sure.
All right.
Let's do it.
Let's do it now.
Let me see. To get...
an illegal, unregistered
bio-port installed,
at about midnight,
we just drive up to your
local country gas station, right?
(Attendant humming)
Anything else I can do for you?
Well, Gas, you could check
your bio-port plugs.
The what? Sparkplugs?
You heard me.
My friend here
has a bio-port problem.
(Gas) A bio-port?
Now, that's a sorta hole
in your spine, isn't it?
Lots of assholes here,
but that's generally it.
I don't know why
you'd be talkin' to me, lady.
Sure you do.
Oh.
Ohh.
Allegra Geller,
you've changed my life.
What was your life like before?
Before?
Before it was changed
by Allegra Geller.
I operated a gas station.
You still operate a gas station.
Only on the most pathetic
level of reality.
Geller's work liberated me.
- Liberated?
- Did you ever play ArtGod?
- Capital "A," capital "G."
- I don't have a bio-port.
Thou, the player of the game ArtGod.
Very spiritual.
Funny too.
God, the artist,
the mechanic. Funny.
Here.
Those are sterilised, aren't they?
Don't worry.
The way they set things up
you could fire in a bio-port
in a slaughterhouse
and never generate an infection.
Then why the clean overalls?
It's a mental thing. Helps me focus.
The one thing you don't wanna do
is miss with the stud finder.
- Oh, God.
- God, the mechanic.
Step into my office.
(Clang)
(Squeaking)
(Hissing and crying)
(Beeping)
(Gas humming)
See? That didn't hurt, did it?
I didn't expect that to hurt.
I expect the next part to hurt.
Yeah, that's what I expect to hurt.
I haven't crippled anyone yet.
- How many have you done?
- Three.
Well, you'll be my third.
(Squealing)
Hey! Easy.
(Gas) Easy.
What's goin' on, Gas?
Hell, he's actin' like
I'm attackin' him.
People usually pay me to do this.
Yeah? All two of 'em!
As you can see, I've decided
not to have a bio-port installed.
This is it, you see?
This is the cage of your own making
which keeps you trapped
and pacing about in the smallest
possible space forever.
Break outta your cage, Pikul.
Break out now.
(Explosive hiss)
Unh!
(Groaning)
The swelling doesn't last long.
Tomorrow, you won't even notice it.
(Moaning) I love it.
Great.
What's going on?!
I can't move my legs!
The procedure comes
with its own epidural.
Just like when you have a baby.
Kinda like instant paralysis
from the waist down.
That's why it didn't hurt.
It'll wear off in no time.
I'm gonna go wash up.
You two, make yourselves at home.
You don't have to wait
for the swelling to go down.
You're gonna port into me...
while I'm paralysed?
You wanted to play my game,
didn't you?
Yeah, I did. I do, but...
Here? Now?
It's an instant-on world, isn't it?
What's that for? Feels... cold.
New ports are sometimes a bit tight.
Wouldn't wanna hurt ya.
How come...
bio-ports don't get infected?
I mean,
they open right into your body.
Listen to what
you're saying, Pikul.
Don't be ludicrous.
Don't you think
you could call me Ted?
Maybe afterwards.
Shit!
Pikul! I can't believe it.
You blew my pod!
- You must have neural-surged!
- What?
I jacked you in and you panicked.
Now it's totally fucked!
This is a disaster.
I was nervous, but I didn't panic.
I was forced to trust you and you
panicked and you neural-surged
and you blew my pod.
You can get a new pod.
Pikul,
in this pod is the only,
the original version of eXistenZ,
an entire game system
that cost 38 million to develop,
not including pre-release
marketing costs,
and I'm locked outside my own game.
I can't get me in or it out!
Are you serious?
That's the only version that exists?
It's the only one and it's stuck
inside and it's your fault.
I've devoted five passionate years
to this strange little creature.
And I've never regretted it, Pikul,
'cause it was the only thing
that could give my life any meaning.
Allegra,
why is it my fault?
I'm telling you I didn't...
I did not neural-surge. I didn't.
I didn't feel any surging.
(Gas) It's not your fault.
It's my fault.
Oh, no, Gas. Not you.
I wouldn't try to use
that bio-port again.
'Cept maybe
for a toaster or somethin'.
What's going on?
You're worth a lot of money...
if you're dead.
- What are you talking about?
- You know what.
It's all over the countryside.
$5 million for her dead body.
No questions asked.
But, she changed your life.
Yep. And now I'm gonna change hers.
Wait! Why did you install
a bad port into me?
There's a big bonus for killing
Allegra Geller's latest game
or whatever it is.
I think I just did that, didn't I?
But can you kill me, Gas?
Can you kill a person?
Can you do that?
Hide my body?
Contact the crazies?
Trust them to pay up?
Hand over my now decaying,
fucking grotesque corpse?
Really expect them to
hand over five mil cash?
Don't you ever go
to the fucking movies?
I like your script.
I wanna be in it.
(Explosive hiss)
(Hissing)
Oh, God, I think he's dead.
- He wanted to kill you.
- Yep.
That's two people in one day...
who wanted to actually kill you.
I've never been more popular.
Allegra, we need help.
You're right.
I've gotta get this pod fixed.
(Pikul) We're going skiing?
(Squealing)
Hey. Hey.
Look at that huge bug.
It's got two heads.
It's not a bug.
It's a mutated amphibian.
It's a frog-salamander-lizard thing.
Sign of the times.
What happens if somebody
here wants to ski?
Come on, Pikul. Nobody actually
skis anymore. You know that.
No, don't use that!
And bring me the sterile wash.
(Knocking)
My darling.
Allegra Geller.
I'm so pleased and...
s-so astonished to see you here.
- Kiri Vinokur, Ted Pikul.
- Hello.
Sterile wash.
Um, I hear this ridiculous story
about some fatwa against you.
The company are desperately
trying to find you.
Is this really serious?
Are you in danger?
There have been a couple
of attempts on my life.
This is unbearable.
The company must stop this.
They owe you protection.
But I don't know
if they can do anything.
It's open season on me.
Well, you will be safe here.
I assure you.
I will contact Antenna right away
and have them come to collect you.
No, Kiri, don't. You mustn't
let anybody know that we're here.
I can't be sure that Antenna
is completely safe for me.
(Kiri) I understand. Yes.
You know,
you can hide out
in one of the guest chalets
as long as you like.
And I'll make sure
you get fresh towels.
And make sure I don't lose
everything in here.
You bet.
(Kiri speaking foreign language)
Take that.
Good.
Pull this back.
- What did you port into?
- Pikul's bio-port.
Really? That's what caused
all the damage.
It was, uh,
a flawed installation. My first.
(Kiri) Well...
it fried a lot
of very expensive neural webbing.
- You see?
- Looks like an animal.
Feels like you're operating
on somebody's pet dog.
I told you, Landry, we have
become glorified veterinarians.
Put a little in there, please.
The eXistenZ game-pod
is basically an animal, Mr Pikul.
It's grown from fertilised
amphibian eggs
stuffed with synthetic DNA.
Only Antenna Research has this.
Wow. Where do the batteries go?
Very funny.
He's not kidding.
He's a total PR nerd.
It ports into you.
You're the power source.
Your body, your nervous system,
your metabolism, your energy.
You get tired, run down,
it won't run properly.
(Kiri) OK.
Landry here
will finish up the pod work.
Now, let's, uh, get that
nasty bio-port out of you,
put a fresh one in.
Oww! It hurts.
I think it's infected.
No. It's not infected.
It's just excited.
It wants action.
But I don't want action -
me, I mean -
the bearer of the excited bio-port.
My baby here has now taken
three major hits, Pikul.
In the church, in the gas
station and on the operating table.
The only way I can tell
if everything's OK...
is to play eXistenZ
with somebody friendly.
Are you friendly,
or are you not?
You're telling me this thing
will run off my body's energy?
That's how they work.
See?
You're hummin' along already.
OK. EXistenZ.
Only from Antenna.
- Here we go.
- You...
You've got an unfair
advantage, don't you?
How can I possibly compete
with the designer of the system?
Well, you could beat the guy
that invented poker, couldn't you?
(Squealing)
(Electronic beeping)
(1st Man) That one?
(2nd Man) Yes.
(1st Man) Are you sure?
(1st Man) I wouldn't recommend it.
The graphics on this one are better.
(1st Man) This is the one you want.
(2nd Man) That one?
That was beautiful.
(Electronic beeping)
I feel just like me.
Is that kind of transition normal?
That kinda...
smooth interlacing
from place to place?
It depends on the style of the game.
You can get jagged,
brutal cuts, slow fades,
shimmering little morphs.
This is amazing.
I had no idea.
Look at this.
Games I've never heard of.
Wait a minute. That reminds me.
What precisely is the goal
of the game that we're playing now?
You have to play the game
to find out why you're playing.
It's the future, Pikul.
You'll see how natural it feels.
Look at this.
Can this be the future?
Ever see anything like this?
These are delicate.
You got to be careful.
Yes, I can imagine.
Cortical Systematics
is the latest and the hottest.
Not just a new game,
but a new system.
Will it work with
an industry-standard bio-port?
I'm D'arcy Nader.
Welcome to D'arcy Nader's
Game Emporium.
Is there anything I can be,
oh, uh, helpin' you with?
We're just looking.
I have what you're lookin' for.
Who sent you?
It's none of your business.
We're here. That's all that matters.
God. What happened?
I-I didn't mean to say that.
It's your character who said it.
Kind of a schizophrenic feeling,
isn't it? You'll get used to it.
Things need saying to advance
the plot and establish characters,
they get said
whether you wanna say them or not.
Don't fight it. Just go with it.
Should you say this in front of him?
Look at him.
- What's he doing?
- He's in a game loop.
He won't come out of it until you
give him some proper game dialogue.
Uh, this is tricky.
Repeat your last line.
Include his name
so he knows you're talking to him.
We're here, D'arcy Nader,
and that's all that matters.
Yes, you're right.
That is all that matters.
Now, you said you have what we want.
We're waiting.
You're going to need
these micro-pods
to download your new identities.
I assume that you both
have had these
industry-standard bio-ports
that you mentioned installed.
Yes, of course.
We both have bio-ports.
- We do, don't we?
- I assumed we did.
In the game we might not.
We better check.
Yeah, it's there. Looks
a little different, but it's there.
Yeah, I see what you mean.
Yes, we both have bio-ports.
Good.
Port in, a-and this will tell ya
all you need to know...
for now.
I'm-I'm gonna leave
while you two, uh,
finish up here, because, uh,
it wouldn't be good
for us all to be seen together.
(Door closes)
I assume that Nader
is our entry point into the game.
- Yeah. Kinda disappointing.
- Nader?
Yeah. He's not very well-drawn.
His dialogue was just so-so,
his accent...
Yeah.
OK.
Pods are so small.
They plug directly
into the bio-port.
OK.
(Squishing)
- Oh God!
- What?
The whole pod
just disappeared into your back.
It disappeared into my back?
It's in my spine?!
It's around my spinal cord?!
It's just a game.
Do you feel anything yet?
No, I don't.
I don't feel a thing.
- Want me to do you?
- Yeah.
What the hell was that?
That wasn't me.
It was my game character.
I wouldn't have done that.
Not here, anyway.
Our characters are obviously
supposed to jump on each other.
It's most probably a...
pathetically mechanical attempt...
to heighten the emotional tension
of the next game sequence.
- No use fighting it, huh?
- What about... our new identities?
Do you feel yours yet?
They'll take care of themselves.
(Moaning)
I'm very worried about my body.
(Gasping) Your what?
Where are our real bodies?
Are they all right? What if they're
hungry? What if there's danger?
They're just where we left them.
They're sitting quietly.
Eyes closed.
It's, um, just like meditating.
I feel really vulnerable.
- Disembodied.
- OK.
Don't sweat it.