(MUSIC PLAYING)
(NO AUDIO)
(LAUGHING QUIETLY)
- You're gonna burn him. Be careful.
- Shut up.
Oh, my God...
- (GIGGLING)
- MATT: Holy...
(WHISPERS) You girls are cruel.
(WOMAN GIGGLES)
MATT: Guys, quit. You're going...
Seriously just stop.
- You're going to burn...
- (LOUD THUD)
- TODD: What was that?!
- Oh!
- Matt, stop.
- Wha...
- Matt, stop the car. You hit something.
- What?
Wait, let me get my camera.
Something's burning.
The engine's burning.
Fucked up the front end.
Everyone, chill. Everyone, chill.
You gonna give the deer
mouth-to-mouth resuscitation?
Hit a fucking deer or something.
I mean, you good, man.
The car's still running.
- I'm good?!
- There's nothing leaking...
- 700 bucks!
- Look, there's nothing leaking
at the bottom, bro.
You're straight. It sounded fine.
- We can get there. Let's go.
- I know, but it's just...
(ANIMAL HOWLS)
That wasn't no deer, bro.
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
(CAMERA BEEPS)
(ANIMAL HOWLING)
MATT: It's here.
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
TODD: Fuck what is that? Over there.
Look at the leaves.
MAN: Holy shit.
Guys, something's moving out there.
- (CAR HORN HONKING)
- ELIZABETH: Let's go!
- MATT: Jesus.
- Okay, okay. We're coming. Chill.
- (CAMERA BEEPING)
- WOMAN: Matt, maybe we should just go home.
MATT:
Babe, I've driven, like, eight hours.
- I'm not just going to turn around.
- MAN: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Really? Really? My beard?
- Shut up, Brian.
- You shut up. You burnt my fucking beard.
Yo, did anybody see what that was?
- WOMAN: Maybe it was a bear.
- BRIAN: Wait, wait, wait.
- I got something.
- MAN: I don't know if it was a fucking bear.
- MATT: It's probably a deer or something.
- BRIAN: What is that?
Yo, what the fuck is that?
BRIAN: It looks like it's walking.
- (BRAKES SCREECH)
- Fucking shit!
- MATT: I think I missed the road.
- WOMAN: What the hell?
MATT: There we go. This is it.
- Riverfront.
- BRIAN: Oh, that shit is overgrown.
- Is this for real it?
- BRIAN: Oh, my God.
MATT: Trust me, it's better
on the other side, guys.
Dude, I don't remember it being this...
- Do you remember where we stop?
- No.
Bro, your uncle has a cabin out here?
- Yeah, dude.
- (LAUGHS)
MATT: Um...
- MAN: What the fuck bro?
- BRIAN: We're not getting past that.
MATT: It's seriously just up here.
We've got to walk from here.
What do you mean you can't...
- What? Where do you want to go around?
- I don't know!
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
- What are you getting out for?
- She's right. We have to walk from here.
- Are you serious?
- I'm not walking.
Black people don't do this shit, man.
All right, guys.
It's just up here to the right.
- (ANIMAL GROANING)
- Let's go.
Anybody hear that?
Hear what?
TODD: I heard something, man.
There it is.
- ELIZABETH: Is that it?
- MATT: Yeah.
Home, sweet home.
Seriously?
Trust me, guys.
It looks a lot better in the daylight.
BRIAN: Oh, shit. Jesus.
Watch out on the right.
There's a loose board.
Uh, whoa.
Guess we didn't need
to steal the keys, huh?
Shut up.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Man.
I mean, yeah, we just gotta brush off some
of these leaves and stuff, but... this is it.
Ew!
When's the last time he was here?
Kind of looks like somebody
left in a hurry.
BRIAN: It's like a lovemaking
palace up in here.
DORA: Sweat stains on it.
BRIAN: Usually they got rose petals
and shit on the ground but we got leaves.
We got leaves. This is...
you can make tons of magic up in here.
I mean, you just hop on, you know?
(COUGHS) Oh, baby!
- MATT: All right, Brian.
- Yeah! (YELLING)
- ELIZABETH: So lame.
- MATT: Brian, quit it.
You're making it all fucking dusty.
- Fucking job!
- (ANIMAL GRUNTING)
- ELIZABETH: What the hell was that?
- MATT: What was that?
Hello?
Matt, hold on. Matt. Wait up.
- (LOW GROWLING)
- Don't go over there.
- (SQUEALING)
- (SCREAMING)
Seriously, there's a fucking pig
in your cabin?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- TODD: Oh, hell, no, man.
- MATT: We'll get it out and we'll just...
- I'm not touching it! It's your cabin.
- And I'm not staying in this motherfucker.
- It's a fucking hog. We're out in the woods.
- I'm not staying here.
- Me neither.
Come on, babe. Fuck that.
(LOW HOWLING)
BRIAN: Matt.
What?
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
BRIAN: What is that?
(CAR BEEPING)
BRIAN: You see anything?
MATT: No.
Just go to sleep.
- (WINDOW WHIRRING)
- (HOWLING CONTINUES)
BRIAN: It sounds like it's crying.
MATT: Close the window dude.
- BRIAN: Do you hear that?
- Close the window.
Dude, you don't hear... come on.
- (WINDOW WHIRS)
- BRIAN: Oh, you're a dick.
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
Dude, do you think it was that shit
that Uncle Bob saw back in the day?
- Shut up about that.
- Why?
Not a word about any of that
stupid shit. I'm serious.
I'm serious.
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
BRIAN: Maybe it's that thing we hit.
(CAMERA BEEPS)
Oh, my God.
What do we got here?
(CAMERA BEEPS)
- (CAMERA BEEPS)
- So... this is pretty sweet.
Usually when you put a GoPro
camera inside of this casing,
it doesn't focus very well underwater.
So, I went out and I bought
one of these bad boys.
That's going to help me focus underwater
because it's got a flat lens.
So, we're pretty much going to get
some pimp shots underwater today.
- (CHATTER)
- What's going on? Hey.
- Brian.
- What's up?
- Come swimming with us.
- Oh, I'll be right there.
Mm. What's up? How you doing?
- What is this?
- It's called a little GoPro camera.
- You're an obsessed freak.
- What's going to happen is
I'm going to make you guys
look like super pimps
because we're going to have
the best YouTube video ever.
- You're lame. Let's go.
- Hold up, hold up.
- I got to get this shit together.
- (SHOUTING)
Die, motherfuckers!
(YELLING)
BRIAN: Good shit! That's great shit!
- Shit, dude, nice!
- (CHEERING)
- What you got? What you got?
- Want to see what I got?
- I'd love to see what you got.
- I'm going to show y'all what I got.
- Hold up, this is how I'm about to do it.
- Make me proud.
BRIAN:
YouTube ain't got shit on us, man!
Oh! Damn!
I don't know. Todd may have just
shown up Matt for sure.
(YELLING)
BRIAN: Uh-oh.
What do we got here?
Looks like a little love walk going on.
God, I am so going to hell for this.
Todd you son of a bitch.
I hate you, you lucky bastard.
I shouldn't be shooting this.
(BRANCHES CRACKING, LEAVES RUSTLING)
Oh, shit! What the fuck is that?!
What the sh... what the hell was that?
TODD: I know that's not Brian.
BRIAN: Dude, be careful man.
There's something over there.
It just ran up the ridge.
- I know what's over here, bro.
- BRIAN: I know. I'm serious, man.
There's something fucking
over there, all right?
Brian, you're a fucking asshole!
- I didn't get anything!
- What the fuck is wrong with you?!
- Give me the fucking camera, man.
- You're going to break the fucking camera, man!
- What the fuck dude?!
- ELIZABETH: God you are such an...
Seriously, I need that
fucking memory card.
You're recording your little brother's
friends in the woods?
- What is wrong with you?
- I got your memory card. Come get it.
- Yeah, whatever dude.
- What's going on, man? What's going on?
Your brother's recording us
messing around in the woods.
Now you talking shit!
I will fuck you up!
What's wrong with you?!
BRIAN: Because of that fucking memory card!
There was a fucking beast on the memory card!
- Okay, no need to name Todd's dick.
- BRIAN: Oh, that's really fucking cute.
- You're fucking cute!
- I'm being fucking serious, man.
Serious?
You're acting like an eight-year-old.
Come on, bro.
We're about to go shoot some paintballs.
Film us doing that or something, man.
BRIAN: That sounds like
a fun fucking time. You dicks.
MATT: What'd you say?!
- BRIAN: I said I'll be in the woods.
- (CAMERA BEEPS)
This is definitely where I was shooting.
He ran across that ridge. Right there.
This is definitely the spot.
I hear something.
See, years ago,
my uncle saw something out here.
Something that freaked him the fuck out.
Bad enough that he never came back
to his beloved hunting cabin.
(BRANCHES SNAP)
BRIAN: He never used the word Bigfoot
but man, if it's out here,
Brian Tover's going to get it on video.
'Cause that's what I do, man.
That's my thing.
Hey.
Hey, big man.
We can be cool, man.
We can be... we can be friends.
'Cause, like, I'm hairy too, man.
Chicks dig it, man.
Holy fucking shit.
Look at the size of this print.
Look at that thing.
There's some toe marks in here.
Holy shit.
(CREATURE GRUNTS)
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
There's definitely something moving.
Hello?
Holy shit.
- (CREATURE GRUNTING)
- BRIAN: Holy shit.
I think I see something.
Hey.
We can be friends, man.
(LOW GROWLING)
BRIAN: Holy shit.
I'm backing off.
It's your house.
You know where I'll be.
Yeah, you know where I'll be.
- (BRIAN COUGHING)
- (DISTANT SHOUTING)
BRIAN: It's 1:37 a.m.
I think the noise from up there
at the cabin is probably...
scaring anything off.
It'll come, but...
man, as soon as those lights go off...
then we're going to have something.
Should be...
coming from right over here.
Until then,
I'm just going to wait.
(ROARING)
Trying to get some...
creatures out of the woods here. (ROARS)
Just got to mimic their sounds.
(ROARS) It's got to be very delicate.
(ROARING)
(COUGHING)
- What are you doing?
- BRIAN: Huh? Oh, sorry.
Um...
I'm...
just recording some stuff.
I got some GoPros set up
all over the forest.
If anything moves up in here,
Brian Tover's going to catch it.
- Why?
- BRIAN: Why? (CHUCKLES)
Why? 'Cause I'm making a video.
Because it's going to be huge.
This is going to be like
"Alien Autopsy" huge, you know?
Like... like YouTube top fucking ten.
Okay, whatever. Can you please
just be quiet? We're trying to sleep.
- I'm sorry.
- Good night.
I'll be quiet.
I'm just letting you know.
- (LAUGHS) Good night.
- All right?
Shit's going to be like...
like "Daily Show" huge.
(LOW ROAR)
I think those calls did the trick.
And now we motherfucking wait.
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
(BRANCHES SNAP)
(GRUNTS)
Damn it!
(GRUNTING)
There's a noise.
I definitely heard some sounds.
Just out here.
Sounds like what I heard yesterday.
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
BRIAN: Looks like it found me.
- (BRANCH SNAPS)
- Fuck.
Holy shit.
Hey, man.
(LEAVES RUSTLE)
BRIAN: Hello?
Mr. Sasquatch?
I just want to be friends.
- (YELLING)
- (POPPING)
Ow, ow, ow! Shit! Ow! Motherfucker!
What the fuck, dude?! Ow!
- (LAUGHING)
- Ow!
Man, that's fucked up, dude.
You guys are fucking assholes.
You should have seen your face, man.
Ow! Shit, dude! You fucking dick, man.
(TODD MIMICKING BRIAN) Mr. Sasquatch,
can I suck your hairy cock?
(LOUD GROWL)
MATT: Holy fuck.
- We should get inside. Go, go.
- MATT: Holy shit.
Let's go.
(LOUD GROWLING)
- Go, go, go. Go, go, go, go.
- What the fuck?
Turn off the lights.
Get the lights. Get the lights.
Get the lights.
Todd, what is that?
- TODD: I don't fucking know.
- There's something out there.
That ain't no fucking animal, man.
What the fuck is that?
- BRIAN: I know what it is.
- Shut up. Shut up.
Okay, we'll just stay close
and stay quiet.
(LOUD HOWL)
BRIAN: Shh.
(WHISPERING)
- MATT: Guys, get back, get back, get back.
- ELIZABETH: Do you see anything?
- (WHISPERING)
- (LOUD HOWL)
- I want to go. I want to go now.
- Okay, listen. I know, baby. Listen.
- Now might not be the best time, okay?
- We're safe in the cabin.
- TODD: You need to calm down.
- Guys, we're safe in the cabin.
We have to stay calm, okay?
BRIAN: We're going to be fine
as long as we don't provoke it okay?
There's no credible documented cases
of a Sasquatch attack.
Shut up about a Sasquatch.
- BRIAN: I'm serious.
- Shut up.
(HUFFING, FOOTSTEPS)
We're in fucking East Texas, okay?
The big fucking thicket.
- There's a new sighting every goddamn week.
- Okay, guys. Whatever it is,
we'll just leave in the morning, okay?
- When the sun comes up.
- All right.
- Okay?
- Okay.
(BANGS)
MATT: Turn the fucking flashlight off.
- (FLOORBOARD CREAKING)
- (HUFFING)
(FOOTSTEPS, HUFFING CONTINUES)
(METALLIC CLANGING)
- (WOMAN WHIMPERING)
- Okay, okay, okay.
(FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE)
Is it gone?
MATT:
Brian, get your crazy ass back here.
BRIAN: It's okay.
Brian.
BRIAN: It's gone. It's okay.
There's nothing out here.
- (CAMERA BEEPS)
- (GROWLS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
- DORA: What was that?!
- TODD: What the fuck is that?
What was it? What'd you see?
- BRIAN: I think I got it on film.
- Got what?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- MATT: You scared it off. You scared it off.
- BRIAN: It ran off. It ran off.
- Okay.
- I think I got it.
- DORA: Shut up!
- TODD: Bri, what was it?
- BRIAN: It was fucking Bigfoot dude.
- (LOUD HOWL)
What was that?
- TODD: Oh, shit.
- DORA: Shut up, shut up.
- TODD: What the fuck?!
- (SCRAPING)
MATT: What is it?
- You guys, what is it doing?
- (HOWLS)
TODD: Don't open... don't open
the window. Are you crazy?!
(LOUD HOWL)
- (HOWLS)
- (BANGING)
(GLASS SHATTERING, CRASHING)
- BRIAN: Oh, shit.
- MATT: Fuck.
Fuck. What the fuck?
Shit.
- What the... oh, shit.
- Motherfuck.
TODD:
See if it starts, man. Maybe it starts.
Fucking nothing.
- No? Come on, bro.
- Nothing!
Brian, let's go back.
TODD: I thought Brian said
they were peaceful.
- Brian, I thought you said...
- I thought you said it was peaceful.
BRIAN: That's what the fucking book
said, all right?
Let's get the fuck back.
We just wait.
We have plenty of food and we'll just wait
until his uncle gets here.
My uncle's not coming.
Well, he's going to figure out
that we're not back eventually.
I stole the key.
- From Uncle Bob.
- DORA: Are you kidding?
What does he mean he stole the key?
Because he doesn't let anyone
come out here.
So no one knows we're here?
No.
Are you fucking kidding me?!
- Why the hell, Matt?!
- It's not his fault.
No, it's not just his fault. It's your fucking
fault, too, because you knew, too!
MATT: Dora, come on. I'm sorry.
Calm down, okay?
Matt,
nobody knows we're out here.
What the fuck are we going to do, bro?
Dude, hold up.
Matt, I'll go. I'll go. I'll go.
I'm faster than you.
No offense, but I'm faster, dude.
I know these woods, okay?
Just take care of the girls, okay?
Matt, wait.
I'll be back, okay, babe?
- Baby, you don't have to do this.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Matt, you don't have to do this, please.
BRIAN: Hey, listen, bro.
You get cell phone reception,
you make that call,
you get your ass back here, all right?
- Later, man.
- ELIZABETH: Good luck, Matt.
- BRIAN: Ride fast bro.
- Like a demon.
TODD: Don't stop.
(PANTING)
Damn it.
I know this isn't the weekend
you girls expected,
but this shit is serious.
I don't know how long it's going to be
before Matt gets back
and whatever the fuck's out there is big
and if it gets in here, we're fucked.
Okay, we're going to take
all the furniture,
we're going to put it
against the windows and doors.
And Brian, what you're going to do
is put down the fucking camera.
- For real, bro.
- All right. Okay.
BRIAN: Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What do we got here?
Come check this out guys.
Oh, shit.
Thank you.
Hello?
- Check that out.
- Let me see what's going on.
- Babe, be careful.
- Yeah.
What you got?
Let me see if I can find
a light. Hold up.
Oh, shit! Hey, guys! Hey, we got a gun!
Hell, yeah. You know what I'm saying?
Dude. Dude, be careful
where you point that fucking thing.
Do you even know how to use that?
- Todd, you just pointed the gun at my face.
- Todd, watch it!
Hold on, dude. What the...
Will you check to see if it's loaded?
It's probably not even loaded.
Calm down and shit.
- ELIZABETH: Do you even know how to open it?
- Calm down, calm down. I'm about to check.
- BRIAN: Dude, really?
- It's loaded. Y'all going to be trippin...
- ELIZABETH: Do you even know how to use a gun?
- I play paintball.
How different can it be?
Come on.
(MUTTERING)
Thank God. Okay.
(PHONE RINGING)
OPERATOR: 9-1-1. What's your emergency?
Yeah, we're trapped in a cabin
outside Route 212.
- Hello? 9-1...
- (STATIC HISSING)
- 9-1-1. What's your emergency?
- Yeah, my name's Matt Tover.
- Hello? Is anyone there?
- We're outside Route 212 in a cabin.
- Hello? 9-1-1.
- Hello?
- (PHONE BEEPS)
- Fuck! Come on.
- Come on.
- (PHONE RINGING)
- UNCLE BOB: Hello? Hello?
- Please.
Hey, Uncle Bob. It's... (GASPS)
- (LOW GROWLING)
- Oh, God.
Matt is that you? Matt? Can you hear me?
- Uncle Bob, it's Matt!
- I'm having a bad connection.
- I'm at the cabin!
- Hello?
Cabin?
- Uncle Bob, it's Matt. We're at the cabin!
- Matt did you say the cabin?
(LOUD GROWLING)
- What the fuck?!
- (LOUD GROWLING)
Come on!
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHING)
(MUTTERING)
Holy... (GRUNTING)
- (GROWLING)
- (PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
Help!
Somebody!
(GRUNTING, SCREAMING)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
Fuck!
(GROWLS)
- (HOWLING)
- (MATT WHIMPERING)
Maybe he found somebody on the road.
They're probably
on their way back right now.
BRIAN: We knew why my uncle
never let anyone come out to this place.
We just didn't believe him.
We should have never come out here.
I'm sorry.
(DOOR OPENS)
TODD: We should probably get inside.
It will be dark soon.
Matt's the man, guys.
He's bringing back help.
- All right?
- (CREATURE ROARING)
TODD: Oh, shit!
BRIAN: Holy fucking shit man.
(ROARING CONTINUES)
TODD: Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Come on, Brian, come on!
Oh, shit. Move something.
Move something.
- DORA: That's Matt's bike.
- Fuck.
Help me with this, man.
Help me with this.
I'm trying, man.
Move it!
Fuck. Fuck.
- Come on. Grab that shit.
- ELIZABETH: Wait guys. Where is it?
- BRIAN: I don't fucking know man.
- DORA: That's Matt's bike.
- BRIAN: Oh, shit.
- ELIZABETH: Do you see it?
- BRIAN: I can't see shit.
- TODD: Check the other window.
- Can you see it?
- BRIAN: I can't see shit out there.
It's waiting for it to get dark.
It's waiting for the night.
(DORA CRYING)
(LOUD THUD FOOTSTEPS)
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
It's at the generator.
- (BANGING CONTINUES)
- (GROWLING)
- BRIAN: Oh, shit.
- TODD: It got the generator.
He's fucking with us.
Okay, okay. He's fucking with us.
- BRIAN: Oh, shit.
- (FOOTSTEPS)
ELIZABETH: Todd shoot it.
- I don't want to waste a shot.
- Fuck that! Shoot it!
- (BANGING)
- (GRUNTING)
- BRIAN: Be careful man.
- Fuck.
BRIAN: Be careful... oh, shit.
- Where'd it go?
- BRIAN: It's okay.
Shh. It's gone, okay? It can't get in.
Fucker can't get in, okay?
- He can't get in.
- (LOUD CRASH)
(SCREAMING)
- (CREATURE YELPS)
- BRIAN: Get in the room! Get in the room!
Go, go, go, go!
- Help me!
- Go, man.
ELIZABETH: What do we do now?
BRIAN: Okay.
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
Okay, guys. Okay.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Let's go. Let's go.
(HUFFING)
ELIZABETH: Shit.
(LOUD GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
I can't hold it!
- (CREATURE GROWLING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GUNSHOT BLAST)
- (CREATURE ROARS)
(ITEMS CLATTER)
- (SILENCE)
- (PANTING)
Where did it go?
It ran off.
- It's gone.
- BRIAN: I think you got it.
Yeah.
- (LOUD CRASH)
- (SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
Help me! (SCREAMING)
- Guys, help her! Help her!
- Help me! Help me!
TODD:
Get off her! Get off her, motherfucker!
(CREATURE ROARS)
- Beth!
- (ROARING CONTINUES)
Shit, come on. Oh, shit.
Brian, help me! Help me, man!
BRIAN: Go, go! Get to the cellar!
- Got to get the gun. Come on.
- TODD: Get it.
(WOOD SPLINTERING)
(CREATURE ROARS)
(CREATURE PANTING)
(ROARING CONTINUES)
It thinks we're outside.
He doesn't know we're down here.
(DRAGGING, SCRAPING)
(CRASH)
(CREATURE ROARING)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
(ELIZABETH COUGHING, GASPING)
- Shh.
- (WHEEZING, GASPING)
TODD: Be quiet okay baby? Please.
Is it gone?
BRIAN: Oh, shit! Oh, shit! Oh, God!
He looked at me! He looked right at me.
Shh.
- He knows we're in here.
- Shut up, shut up, shut up.
- BRIAN: He knows.
- Quiet. Be quiet. Shut up.
He doesn't know. He doesn't know.
(LOUD BANG)
- (BANGING CONTINUES)
- BRIAN: Oh, my God.
He knows.
He fucking knows that we're here.
Shoot him!
(YELPING)
(DORA WHIMPERING)
Motherfucker.
Let's go. Let's go.
Are you okay?
DORA: Lizzy.
Lizzy.
Is she breathing?
- BRIAN: Is she okay?
- DORA: Wake up.
(CAMERA BEEPS)
BRIAN: Holy shit.
Hey, guys.
It's all clear up here.
(KISSES)
BRIAN: We got it.
Oh, my God.
Jesus.
It's his fucking bike.
We have to go. We can't stay here.
(SNIFFLES)
See you soon, man.
DORA: What about Liz?
We'll come back for her body.
Brian, your cell phone working?
BRIAN: No.
- Yours?
- Fuck, no.
BRIAN: Hey.
Hey.
It's over this way.
- What?
- It's the trail.
If we take the trail, it's going to take us
half the time to get to 212.
Look at that shit, man.
There's no road out there.
BRIAN: I've been out here before.
Sure?
BRIAN: Ow.
It's straight down there.
Ah. Fuck.
Some fucking shortcut you got, man.
TODD: Dora. Dora. Over this way.
- What?
- TODD: Over this way.
No, no, no. We keep going right up here.
I'm serious.
We keep just walking right up here.
- Dude, I know these fucking woods.
- Todd, he's been here before. Come on.
TODD: Yeah, whatever.
It better be over this way. Come on.
- (LOW HOWLING)
- BRIAN: Holy shit.
I think we did something to it.
What the fuck did we do?
We didn't do shit.
We didn't do anything.
BRIAN: Holy shit.
TODD: It's Matt's bag.
- BRIAN: Oh, shit.
- DORA: Matt?
- Matt?
- Wait, Dora.
DORA: Matt?
- Matt?
- TODD: Dora, slow down. Slow down, Dora.
I see more blood.
BRIAN: Oh, God.
(CRYING)
- No. No, no, no, no.
- (DORA SOBBING)
Shit.
- Hey. Hey, baby. Watch out, watch out.
- (DORA SCREAMING)
Leave me here.
Slow down, slow down. I can't see shit.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
- You all right man?
- We got to rest, bro.
Cut the light off.
Don't keep it on too long.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) All right.
We got to find some cover,
somewhere not out...
- somewhere not out in the open.
- (CAMERA BEEPS)
Where the...
where the hell's the 212, man?
BRIAN: We're getting close.
I remember this little bridge
and this road.
Hey, man.
I'm sorry about Liz, bro.
- (BRANCHES SNAPPING)
- (CREATURE GRUNTS)
(HAMMER CLICKS)
BRIAN: (WHISPERING) I think it found us.
(GROWLING)
Jesus.
Chill out, chill out.
(LOUD GROWL)
- Fuck that. That thing killed Liz.
- BRIAN: Todd! Todd!
- Brian, stay here. Stay here.
- TODD: I'm right here! Let's go!
- BRIAN: Get under that.
- TODD: Where this fucker at?!
- I can do this all night, motherfucker!
- BRIAN: What are you doing? Shut up!
- TODD: How you going to kill my friends?!
- BRIAN: Shut up, Todd. Todd!
I'm killing this motherfucker right now!
Where you at?!
- Where you at, huh?!
- (LOUD GROWL)
BRIAN: You can't even see it.
What are you shooting at?
- What's up?! I'm right...
- (LOUD HOWL)
- (ROCK THUDS)
- (TODD GROANS)
- What the fuck? Oh, shit!
- BRIAN: Okay, okay.
BRIAN: Fucking save the shell.
Save the shell, bro.
Fuck it.
- BRIAN: Dude, don't waste the shells.
- The shell's not coming out, man.
The shell's not coming out, man.
Yo, we can't stay here.
We got to move. We got to move.
Dora, come on. Dora, let's go.
Let's go, let's go.
- (YELLS)
- TODD: Watch out, watch out!
- BRIAN: Go, go, go, go, go, go.
- TODD: Come on, y'all!
- Fuck that shit, nigga!
- (DORA YELLS)
TODD:
Come on, man. We got to fucking go.
- Brian, come on.
- BRIAN: Careful. Coming.
- You guys see it?
- BRIAN: No.
- Do you see it?
- BRIAN: Fucking be careful dude.
All right, man. Where the fuck are we, bro?
Where the fuck are we, bro?
- (CAMERA BEEPS)
- DORA: What is that?
Guys, guys. There's people here.
There's people here. They can help us.
TODD: That looks deserted.
That looks deserted Brian.
- Where the fuck are we, bro?
- BRIAN: Must be close to the 212.
Okay, let's get the fuck
out of here, man. Where...
(MAN YELLING IN DISTANCE)
- DORA: Matt?
- BRIAN: It's Matt! It's Matt!
- TODD: Yo, Matt!
- BRIAN: That's Matt.
- TODD: Matt!
- DORA: Matt!
- BRIAN: Matt!
- TODD: Brian.
- Brian, hold on a second.
- Shut up. I can hear him.
BRIAN: Oh...
What the hell is that?
- (YELLING CONTINUES)
- BRIAN: Matt?
- Where is he?
- Matt.
TODD: I don't hear him. Matt?
Whoa, whoa. Yo.
(YELLING LOUDER)
- TODD: Matt.
- DORA: He sounds hurt. Matt.
BRIAN: Come on. Let's go in here.
Slow down.
BRIAN: Holy fuck.
BRIAN: (WHISPERING) Matt?
DORA: Matt?
BRIAN: It's some sort of a tunnel.
- Or a nest or something.
- (YELLING CONTINUES)
DORA:
Matt. He's down there. He's down there.
- BRIAN: Hold this.
- TODD: Whoa. What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- I'm going in to get him.
TODD: Come on, dude.
You can't be going in there.
I don't have a choice.
That's my bro down there.
I've got this.
I'll be able to see in the dark.
- Brian, it's all we got left.
- All right.
(CAMERA BEEPS)
- TODD: He'll be all right, Dora.
- (CRYING)
TODD: You're all right?
BRIAN: Matt?
Fuck. Which way?
Which way?
- Matt?
- MATT: Huh?
- Huh?
- Matt?
MATT: Brian? Brian?!
Matt.
- Brian.
- Matt.
Brian, Brian, over here. Over here.
BRIAN: Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
- Matt, how you doing, buddy?
- (CRYING)
It's in here, man. You got to go.
- You got to get out of here, man.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Let's go. Let's go.
- You got to get out of here.
- Why?
- (SCREAMS)
- What, what, what?
- He smashed my legs.
- BRIAN: Shit.
- He smashed...
- He smashed my legs.
- I'm going to get you out of here, bro.
I'm going to get you out of here.
Grab on to me.
Where are you? I need you
to grab onto me. Grab on to me!
- Grab on to me. Grab on to my arm.
- (GROWLING)
MATT: It's still in here.
- It's still here.
- Shh.
- He's here. I see him.
- Do you see it?
- (GROWLING CONTINUES)
- Shoot it! Shoot it, Brian! Shoot it!
- Shoot it!
- (CREATURE ROARS)
- (GUNSHOT)
(SCREAMS, GROANING)
- Did you get it? Did you get it?
- (CREATURE WAILING)
BRIAN: I don't know.
I think so. I think so.
Come on. Grab on to me.
Grab on to me. Grab on to me.
(GRUNTS)
Come on.
(GROANING)
- Motherfucker!
- Okay, okay, okay.
- (SCREAMING)
- I can't see it.
Come on. Hold on.
Hold on to my hand, bro.
Hold on to my hand.
Keep holding on. Keep holding on.
- Keep on holding.
- Holding.
Come on.
- DORA: Oh, my God.
- TODD: Oh, shit.
- DORA: Matt. Matt!
- TODD: You got him.
- You made it bro.
- DORA: Todd, help me.
TODD: You got him. You fucking got him.
That's what I'm talking about.
All right, we're clear, we're clear.
We got to get him.
- All right.
- (GROANING CONTINUES)
- Did you fucking kill that thing?
- BRIAN: Yeah, I shot it, man.
- I shot it.
- Okay. Is it dead?
- I think so.
- DORA: Move out of the way.
This is fucked up.
This is going to hurt man.
Come on.
DORA: Guys, let's get him
back to the camper. Come on.
Come on, follow me. Look out, look out.
Here. There's a path, there's a path.
- DORA: Follow me.
- MATT: Fuck.
Here we go. Come on.
Ready?
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
- BRIAN: Be careful, be careful.
- (SCREAMING)
- (INDISTINCT)
I got you.
- Okay, buddy.
- I got you.
Here. Give him some water.
Guys, we should have just gone
to the fucking beach.
- (LAUGHS)
- (CELLPHONE VIBRATING)
That's my phone.
That's my phone. Holy shit.
- Uncle Bob. Uncle Bob.
- Brian? Where the heck are you? Where's Matt?
Matt's with us. He's hurt.
We're out at the woods. We're at the cabin.
I'm at the cabin. I can't hear you.
You're at the cabin?
- We're in a camper that's near the 212.
- Brian, can you hear me?
- Hello? Hello?
- (DIAL TONE BEEPS)
- I fucking lost it again. All right...
- Fuck!
All right,
I'm going to try to fucking redial.
- TODD: Come on, come on, come on.
- (PHONE RINGING)
You got it? You get him?
- BRIAN: No, no. It's out again.
- (DIAL TONE BEEPS)
BRIAN: He says he's at the cabin.
He's close.
- Fuck.
- Ow! Fuck!
- Jesus fucking Christ, dude.
- My bad man.
Okay, so, he's coming, right?
- He's on the way, right?
- He's... I don't know. It cut off.
- I told him we were in a trailer by the 212.
- Give me your phone. I'll keep calling it.
All right, guys. All right, I got it.
Okay, okay. Fireworks.
Check it out, check it out.
I can light off fireworks.
- It's fucking daylight out there, dude.
- So the fuck what? It's better than nothing.
If he hears them or he sees them,
he'll know where we are.
Okay, okay.
- Okay.
- BRIAN: Yeah?
Yeah. I'm going.
Let's go, let's go!
BRIAN: Come on, buddy.
TODD: This better fucking work.
I'm going to fucking light these fireworks,
signal Uncle Bob, save Matt, the end.
Here we go, guys. Here we go.
This is a good spot. Come on.
Fuck, fuck, fuck. Ready? Ready?
Hey, boy, this is for you.
Buy you a whole lot of shit. Come on.
What the fuck?
- (FIREWORKS SCREECHING)
- Oh, shit!
- (FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
- BRIAN: Shit. Holy cow.
- Is that them?
- Yeah.
- You can actually see them.
- I told you this would work.
DORA: (LAUGHING) He did it. He did it.
TODD:
We got help coming for you, Matty boy.
- (ROARING)
- Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck!
Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck!
BRIAN: Come on, Todd.
There he is. Oh, fuck!
TODD: Yo, he's coming!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Oh, my god!
Get off me, man!
Get off me, motherfucker!
- Get off me, bitch!
- (GROWLING)
Get off me!
No, no, no, no, no!
(GROWLS)
DORA: We have to help him!
Get this motherfucker off me, man!
Get him off me! Help!
(SCREAMS)
(CRACK)
Okay, okay, okay.
Shh.
Holy shit.
I can't see him.
He took him into the woods.
DORA: What are we going to do with Matt?
- (DORA SCREAMS)
- Oh, shit. Oh, fuck.
Shh.
(CREATURE HUFFING)
Stop crying, stop crying.
- Shh.
- (FOOTSTEPS)
- (SCRAPING)
- (CREATURE GROWLING)
BRIAN: Shh.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay. Shh.
(CREATURE GROWLS, BANGS)
BRIAN: Shut up, shut up.
Be quiet.
Oh, fuck. Oh, shit.
Matt, wake up!
BRIAN: He's pushing us towards the edge!
He's pushing us.
He's trying to push us over.
- Come on, Matt. Come on, buddy.
- (SCRAPING)
(BOTH SCREAM)
Come on, Matt.
Oh, shit.
- (CREATURE ROARS)
- BRIAN: Shit!
(CRASHING)
(ROCKS THUDDING)
(GASPS)
Matt. Matt, wake up.
Wake up, Matt. We got to go home.
- Matt!
- (DORA WHIMPERING)
Dora.
Hey, hey.
(GROANING, GASPING)
BRIAN: Dora, Dora.
(GURGLING)
BRIAN: Oh, shit.
- No! No!
- (LOUD GROWL)
- (ROARING)
- (YELLING)
Oh, shit.
(ROARING)
(GRUNTING, TUMBLING)
- (GASPS)
- (RUSTLING)
(ROARS)
(GROWLING)
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDE)
(GROANS)
(FOOTSTEPS, CREATURE HUFFING)
(LOW GROWL)
- (CREATURE PANTING)
- (BODY SCRAPING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(GASPING)
(COUGHING)
(YELLS)
- (CAMERA BEEPS)
- BRIAN: Guys...
Dora. Dora.
Wake up.
- Guys?
- (FLIES CONTINUE BUZZING)
(BRIAN CRYING)
No.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
I'm sorry, guys.
We gotta go. We gotta go.
It's gonna come back. Come on.
Please, come on, guys. Come on, guys.
Oh, shit.
Holy shit.
Oh...
That's it.
- (GROWLING)
- (BRIAN GRUNTS)
(CREATURE GROWLING)
BRIAN: I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It was an accident.
- (GROWLS)
- Ah!
- (CREATURE ROARS)
- (FLIES CONTINUE BUZZING)
BRIAN: We didn't mean to.
We didn't mean to kill your baby.
- We didn't mean to kill your baby!
- (ROARING CONTINUES)
(BRIAN COUGHING)
- (GUNSHOT)
- (BRIAN SCREAMS)
- UNCLE BOB: Brian?!
- Uncle Bob! Uncle Bob!
- Brian!
- Uncle Bob, help!
- Help me!
- Oh, my God.
- BRIAN: Come on. I know I know.
- Brian, what'd you boys do?
BRIAN: We have to get 'em!
We have to take them all.
UNCLE BOB: Come on.
Come on, we got to get out of here.
- BRIAN: No, we can't leave them.
- Come on, Brian!
- BRIAN: I don't want to leave them.
- Let's get to the truck.
BRIAN: Okay.
We didn't listen to you, Uncle Bob.
(DISTANT HOWLING)
BRIAN: It's my fault. It's all my fault.
Shut up. We'll deal with it
when we get to the truck.
Come on.
(ROARS)
- Uncle Bob!
- (GRUNTING, GROWLING)
BRIAN: Just stop! Stop!
Please, stop! Please!
- Please.
- (HUFFING)
BRIAN: It was an accident.
(LOW GROWLING)
BRIAN: I'm sorry.
I'm done.
This is Brian Tover.
And this is my last video.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SOBBING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)