¶
[heavy metal music
in background]
[thunder]
[panicking]
[pounding]
Hello?!
Is anyone in there?
Oh, thank God!
Let me in!
Please let me in!
Sorry lady, we just closed.
No, No!
Please!
[pounding]
[thunder]
[phone ringing]
(Operator): 911,
state your emergency.
You've got to help me!
They took them!
Took who?
My boys! Oh God.
[sobbing] We were just here,
and they took them!
Ma'am? Ma'am?
I need you to calm down
and give me your location.
Can you look around
and tell me what you see?
There's a gas station,
on the highway...
[phone goes dead]
[thunder]
[electrifying noise]
[shrill scream]
What the fuck?
[phone booth crashes
to the ground]
Woah!
[police radio communications]
What the hell's going on?
Well, we're not sure, boss.
This here is a uh...
weird one.
Store clerk here said a woman,
brunette, like 30,
shows up around midnight,
she's acting irate,
banging on the door here
and wants to use the phone.
And then...
Then what?
I think I'll let the boy
tell you himself.
Now, sheriff, I'm
not gonna lie to you,
I've done a lot of hallucinogens
in my day, but...
what I saw last night, that
shit was out of this world.
Straight up.
Nancy McPherson.
Where did you go?
I know, yeah,
I won't forget.
In the garage.
Don't worry, I'm using
a wide angle lens.
Never mind.
Mom?
Ok.
Mom, I gotta go.
I'm packing.
Mom, I'm getting off
the phone now.
I love you, too.
Bye.
Mom busting your balls again?
Yeah, she's driving me
fucking nuts.
Are you sure you want
to come with me?
I could just take the photos
and come home tonight.
No, I'm coming with you
and it's gonna be great.
It's been a brutal semester,
God knows we both deserve
some R and R.
If you say so.
It's gonna be fun.
We can go on a hike,
little small campfire,
look up at the stars.
And then...
I will make you my bitch.
[laughs]
Or I can be your bitch,
I can be your bitch, too,
if you want.
You're already my bitch.
[computer rings]
Ugh, dad, what do you want?
Hey, April!
You actually see me
over there?
Hey, dad.
Yeah, I can see you.
I can't talk for long, ok?
We're just getting ready
to leave.
I still can't believe your
mother's making you go
all the way out there.
Couldn't she just have gotten
the real estate agent
to take the damn photos?
I don't know, she said it was
gonna cost too much.
You know mom.
Cheapest woman I ever met.
She's just selling it
to spite me,
you know that right?
As if getting the goddamn house
wasn't enough.
Dad, are you drinking?
It's like eleven in the morning.
You know what they say,
the only cure for a hangover is
to keep it coming.
Dad, seriously.
Slow down.
I worry about you.
Did you catch the game
last night?
Dad, I really can't talk
for long, we're, like,
almost out the door.
Well, wait, wait.
I uh...
need you to grab some things
for me while you're out there.
Um, two fishing rods in
the garage, and a tackle box.
You'll find it behind
the work bench.
Ok, fishing rods, tackle box.
Got it.
Oh...
and my shotgun.
The double barrel.
It's in the basement.
If your mother wants that,
she's gonna have to pry it out
of my cold, dead hands.
Got it.
One shotgun, dead hands.
Ok, dad, I'm gonna go
now, ok?
I love you, I'll talk
to you later.
Bye.
Ok, how do I turn off...
I feel like I'm seventeen
all over again.
Did your dad find a new
job yet?
He's been looking, but
he's not in very good shape.
[door buzzer]
Jesus, what now?
Hello?
Yo, bitch!
Are we doing this shit,
or what?
We'll be down in a sec,
chill.
Well, it's hot as fuck down
here, Kyle,
my balls are sweating like
a motherfucker.
Let's go!
Who is that, is that Seth?
Ok, I probably should have
told you this earlier,
but I might have invited
a few people to come
with us to the cabin.
Kyle, seriously?
[yelling outside]
April!
Hey, Mel.
Come on, April,
let's do this shit!
Time is money.
I got places to go,
people to see.
It's gonna be fun,
I promise.
Oh yeah, hey April, can I come
upstairs real quick?
I gotta take a fat shit.
I so hate you right now.
[rock music]
Come on, come on!
Seth, watch it!
[laughs]
Watch this shit!
Don't fucking do that again.
Don't be such a fuckin'
pussy, man.
There's nobody
on the road!
[sirens]
Oh, fuck.
If he searches us, we're fucked.
I gotta tell you, that is pretty
high on the list
of stupidest things I've ever
seen in my life.
Yeah, I'm really sorry, officer.
I'm an idiot.
I'm glad you're aware of it.
License and registration.
Yeah, um...
Where you kids headed?
My mom owns a cabin out here.
We're just staying at it
for the weekend.
Well, we've had some
disturbances around here...
some break-ins, vandalism,
animals being killed.
Obviously, you kids wouldn't
know anything about that,
would you?
No, nothing.
We just got here.
You're just visiting.
Yeah.
See, we get a lot of that.
Kids coming down for
the weekend, getting drunk,
thinking they can do whatever
they want.
I'm here to tell you
that's not the case.
While you're in my town
you best behave,
or you're gonna have
to deal with me
and you don't want to do that.
Are we clear?
Yes, sir.
I'm gonna give you a warning.
Thank you.
No more fuckin' around.
Got it?
Yes, thank you.
We're not gonna be a problem.
Yep.
Remind me to punch you
in the dick, Seth.
Wow, this is amazing!
It's beautiful out here.
Yeah, April, when you
said cabin in the woods
I thought this was gonna be
a total shithole.
Oh, yeah!
Fuckin' A!
This is what I'm talkin' about!
This is such a trip.
Last time I was here,
we were in middle school.
Yeah, we used to come out
here every summer.
I'm gonna go grab my camera,
hopefully I can get all the
rooms before it gets dark out.
Do you need help?
No, it's ok baby, I got it.
Alright.
Hey, think fast, fuckhead!
Bottoms up, motherfuckers!
[dance music]
I figured it was coyotes, so I
replaced the whole damn fence.
Now I don't know what to think.
Well, it doesn't look like
coyotes, Rick.
It's too perfect,
too clean.
If this keeps up, I'm not
gonna survive the season.
I'm gonna get animal control
down here,
get things cleared up, ok?
You take care.
I'm over here at
the Riseman farm,
got another animal mutilation
same as the others.
Copy that, sheriff.
What the hell is going on
in this town, huh?
No.
Yeah.
Oh my God, I can't believe you
slept with that guy.
Yeah.
No!
Yeah!
He was, like, forty
and so guido!
Oh, whatever.
He was hot.
So um...
NYU probably has a pretty
good writing program.
You know, it would probably
be easy to transfer there.
What?
For Kyle.
If he wanted to go with you.
Melanie, I put a lot of thought
into this, ok?
I just don't see it happening.
I don't know,
it's just that there are a lot
of douchebag guys out there,
and Kyle isn't one of them.
You guys are great together.
I know we are, I just...
I don't want to be one of
those girls that marries
her high school sweetheart and
then pops out three kids
and wonders what could
have been.
Look, all I'm saying is
that, you know,
maybe you should just think
about it a little bit more.
[dog barking]
What?
What is it?
What the fuck?
What the fuck's your problem?
[dog barking]
Rusty, stop
being so aggro.
[leash snaps]
Fucking Rusty!
Come back here!
Rusty!
Fucking dumb dog.
Fuck.
I think he's back there.
Rusty!
Really, Mel?
Don't be a square.
Come on.
Wow.
What a shithole.
Fuck, I think he's back there.
[dog barking in distance]
Holy shit, Melanie, look.
Oh. My.
God.
Score!
Thank you, God, thank you, God.
Ok, remember, we're here to
find the dog.
What dog?
Oh.
[sniffs bag]
Mmm, sweet Jesus,
it's a miracle!
Melanie, put it down.
Come on.
This is sketch.
It's probably some drug
dealer's stash.
Can I just take one bag?
No!
I don't wanna get killed!
Ok, fine.
Fine.
There you are!
Don't do that again.
Come on, let's go ok?
Oh my God!
[muffled] What are you
doing on my property?
We weren't trying to steal
anything, I promise!
You're trespassing!
No, no, no, my dog just
ran back here
and we came back to get him!
Who sent you?
My parents own a cabin right
down the road!
April?
I know you?
Hell, I haven't seen you
since you were knee high
to a bait pail.
Remember?
Your dad and I used to take
you fishing out on the lake!
Travis?
Yeah!
[old school rock music]
Sorry for spookin'
you guys back there,
I don't get many visitors.
I see somebody on my property,
they're usually here lookin'
for trouble.
Is this you?
Oh yeah, a little green
behind the ears in that one.
So uh, were you in, like,
Vietnam or whatever?
Uh huh.
'67 through '71.
Brave as shit.
I've seen things...
things your generation
just wouldn't understand.
Hey, what's that thing?
Ah.
My motion activated thermal
cameras picked this one up
last week.
What is it?
What do you think it is?
Secret military air craft!
They've been using this
whole area for test flying
ever since the end of
the Cold War.
Maybe things have been
heating up.
Just last night I tracked
one of these babies going
about 2400 clicks an hour,
it stopped right on
a goddamn dime,
did a 180 quicker than
any aircraft known to man.
You had to see it.
No way!
Way.
Oh, you guys are so young,
you have no idea what's going
on out there.
Why should you?
When I was your age,
I thought the world was a good
and fair place.
I've seen some shit since then.
People nowadays live
in their naive,
comfortable bubble worlds, and
the people behind the curtain
want to keep them that way.
The last thing they want
is an informed,
public cable free-thought.
Free.
Yeah.
People out there, they think
they're free,
but they couldn't be further
from the truth.
That's why you gotta stay
off the radar.
Keep off the grid.
'Cause they're out there,
and they're watching.
So, um, can I buy some weed?
Of course you can.
So then, I was like
Oh.
My.
God.
And I was, like, freaking
out and I felt super dizzy
and out of it,
and I mean,
I was having a full on
panic attack
in the middle
of the club!
All of my friends were
totally like TTYL,
I didn't know what to do.
So anyway, out of nowhere,
he comes over
and he's all like
hey, are you alright?
He takes me to his dorm and he
takes care of me all night
and he gives me water
and I just knew he was
the right guy for me.
So yeah, that's how we met.
Wow, that sounds amazing.
I know, right?
Hey, um...
can I talk to you for a second?
Just, like, upstairs?
Yeah, ok, sure.
Actually, could you close
the door?
Are you ok?
You're acting really weird.
Yeah, no, I'm fine.
Um, so I uh...
I don't know how
to say this, really.
Um...
Say what?
You know that I care
about you a lot, right?
Yeah, of course I do.
What is it?
Ok, here goes.
Um...
April, we know each other
inside and out,
and the last three years
have been
the best three
years of my life.
I love waking up next to you,
and I want to keep waking
up next to you
for the rest of my life.
So...
What are you doing, Kyle?
April, what do you say?
You want to keep waking up
next to me, too?
Kyle, are you serious?
Is that a yes?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Oh, fuck.
You can't leave me
hanging here.
Kyle, I...
I can't.
But why?
Fuck, I haven't told you
this yet.
I... I didn't want it to be
like this.
I got a job offer in New York.
New York?
Yeah.
When does it start?
The middle of May.
That's like a month away!
When the hell were you
gonna tell me this?
This weekend, but
then you ended up
inviting a bunch of people
over here.
That's right in the middle
of the semester,
I can't transfer that quickly.
What, did you not
want me to go with you?
No, Kyle, I didn't say that.
I just...
I...
Oh my God.
You're breaking up with me.
No, no Kyle, I just...
I don't know if I'm ever
gonna get another opportunity
like this again.
Oh, I'm such an idiot.
I'm such a fucking idiot.
Kyle...
Kyle, don't walk away.
(All): SURPRISE!
Let's get this motherfucking
party start...
Fuck off, Seth.
You said no?
Seth!
That is some cold ass shit.
Welcome to the gayest
surprise party ever!
Not only did the surprise
completely backfire,
but there's no TV, there's no
cell phone service,
and I just got the worst news
that my chick is on the rag.
In this corner we have Kyle,
who has just taken a merciless
beating from April
and could be out for the count.
Hey!
Say something for the camera,
champ!
Come here, you fuckin'
dumb dog.
Oh yeah, gimme this shit.
What are these dirty sluts
up to?
Fuck, I just wish it didn't
have to go down like that.
I fucking care about him.
Are you filming this?
That is some fucked up shit.
I mean really, who says
no to a guy on one knee?
Seth, fuck off.
I just, I'm trying to understand
the situation.
So am I.
Seth.
I thought we were
happy together.
I'm Kyle, remember?
We're in it for the long haul.
Where you go, I go.
He fuckin' loves you, April.
Enough.
Seth, get the fuck out of here.
I care about you, but...
But what?
I fucking love you
and you love me.
I don't even think I believe in
the concept of marriage, Kyle.
Look how well it turned out
for my parents,
they can't stand each other!
But you are the one for me.
Kyle, that is just something
we are raised to believe
that we're supposed to want, ok?
The one, you know?
Like it's some magical
fucking thing
that is going to complete us
and it's crap!
Are you listening to me?
What are you talking about?
I'm saying that at the end
of the day,
we're all just alone
in the universe.
April, that is the worst
fucking logic...
What the fuck is that?
[rumbling]
[explosion]
What the fuck?
Holy shit!
What was that?
Holy fuck!
[more explosions]
Oh my God!
We gotta go!
Leave this shit! Let's go!
No way, man!
What the fuck, April?
Melanie!
Shit!
What the hell is that?
Are we really fucking
doing this shit?
Fuck sakes man, I'm too fucking
drunk for this shit, man.
Come on, hurry the fuck up.
Fuck.
Oh my God.
What the hell is that?
It's an airplane, right?
I don't know, maybe man,
but what's with the red light?
I don't fuckin' know, man.
Seth!
Is that what I think it is?
Oh my God, this is fucked up!
What is this?
I know one thing for sure
it's not,
this is definitely
not an airplane!
No way.
This is so light,
it's like tinfoil.
Do you think it's a military
thing like Travis was saying?
It has to be.
Ok, seriously, fuck this!
This is not fucking happening!
I'm going back to the car.
Yeah, yeah, yeah baby,
I'm with you.
Yo, yo guys, let's go.
Come on, let's go!
Seth?
Look at this!
Yo, yo, yo!
Come check this out!
Get over here!
Come on.
Holy shit.
Are those footprints?
[thunder]
Seriously?
Fuck.
Hey, you got the video?
I want to see the video.
[on video] I know one thing
for sure it's not,
this is definitely not
an airplane!
This is so fucked!
I knew this shit was real,
man.
That fuckin' Roswell Area 51
shit is true.
No, it's gotta be
something else.
Look at it, for Christ's sake!
It's a UFO!
It's a fucking crashed UFO!
I think we should pack our shit
and get the hell out of here,
you guys.
Let's just drive
until we get reception
and then call someone.
Who the fuck are we gonna call?
911?
They'll think it's
a fucking joke.
I don't know, but we can't
just stay here!
You guys!
She's right.
Those footprints...
they were headed
in this direction.
Alright, calm down.
Everything is gonna be fine.
You've got to be kidding me!
[dog barking]
[panicked voices]
Ok guys, it's ok.
The power's gone out here before
when the weather was this bad.
It's probably just the breaker.
Well, where's the breaker?
[whispering] Come on,
hurry the fuck up.
Alright, where is it?
It's over there.
Where?
Here.
I think it's the ground line.
[electric shock]
Are you ok?!
Yeah, yeah.
Oh my God.
[dog barking]
Oh shit.
[dog continues to bark]
What the fuck is
he barking at?
Shhh.
[loud crash]
[gasps]
[whispers] There's
someone in the house!
Yeah, or something.
There's a gun.
There's a gun down here.
It's unloaded.
Oh my God, let me do it.
Who taught you how
to do that?
My dad and I used to hunt.
[cocks gun]
[noises above]
Oh my God.
Oh my God, Rusty!
Come on.
Oh my God.
[thunder]
Quick, shut it!
Do you see anything?
No.
Is it still in the house?
[thunder]
Oh, shit.
Watch out, watch out,
watch out.
Anything up there?
Come on.
[thunder]
You see anything
out there?
No.
Whatever was in here,
it's definitely gone now.
[thunder]
[gunshot]
[shattering glass]
Oh my God.
Hello?
Did I just hear a gunshot?
[thunder and lightning]
Is that blood?
What the fuck is that?
[thunder and lightning]
Jesus.
Dude, that's a dead
fuckin' alien.
[thunder and lightning]
[tires screech]
Kyle, it's cold!
Drive faster!
Do you guys realize
what we just saw?
I mean, do you realize
what this means?
I don't care, I don't care.
I just wanna get home.
No, no, no, we gotta come back
in the morning
and take pictures!
Oh my God, are you fucking
kidding me?
Think about it!
We're gonna be rich!
We're gonna be on TV
and shit!
We have proof that life
on another planet exists.
Give it a rest, babe.
Fuck!
Kyle, slow down.
Great. Perfect.
Just drive over it, man.
It's too big to drive over.
Can't you just, like,
move it or something?
Move it?
Look at it.
This thing probably
weighs two tons.
Kyle, look at this!
What did this?
Was it lightening?
This is the only road back
into town.
What're we gonna do?
Well, at least it
stopped raining.
[wipers going]
What the hell?
[thunder]
Oh my God!
Jesus Christ, what the
fuck is that?
Get in the car!
[panicked voices]
[car electronics explode]
What the fuck are you doing?
Come back to the car!
What is she doing?
Let's go!
[sinister music]
Oh my God!
Get in the fucking car!
Go!
Oh my God, no!
[frantic screaming]
Oh, my God, no!
[knocking]
Sheriff's department.
Open up!
Hello?
[on video] We're finally
here, at Echo Lake,
it is unbelievably gorgeous,
and it's Matty's
first time fishing.
One, two, three, go!
I'm gonna catch a fish that's
even bigger than this!
Say hi to grandma!
Hi, grandma!
[playing guitar]
¶ Livin' up, I want to live
that dream... ¶
Oh my God,
what is that?
Are you filming this?
Honey, is that a plane?
Matty, what are you doing?
Get back in the camper!
Mom, I can see
something up there.
Oh my God, MATTY!
Jesus! Matty!
[panicking]
Oh God.
[noise]
Anybody there?
[bursts out of closet screaming]
Don't hurt me!
Ma'am, I am not going
to hurt you.
I'm here to protect you.
8732, I'm over here
at Dudney Trunk,
I am requesting immediate
medical assistance.
[on radio] 10-4
sheriff, we're on our way.
[gasping]
Ma'am, what happened?
Who did this to you?
They took Jeffrey!
They took my Matty!
[sobbing]
Took them where?
Who took them?
Who do you think?
[gasping]
They do tests, experiments.
They want to know
everything about us.
They'll show you things.
Put things in your mind.
Terrible things.
Ma'am.
You're safe now.
They held me down!
[sobbing]
I couldn't stop them.
They held me down.
Oh, God.
Oh, shit.
What the fuck?
What the fuck is happening?
What the fuck was that?
They just fucking took her,
man!
They just fucking took her!
We are fucking fucked!
We're in the middle of
fucking nowhere...
Seth, calm down.
Don't!
Just don't touch me, ok?
I said get the fuck off me!
What the hell
is your problem?
Guys, guys, guys!
Stop!
Look!
It's Travis's place.
Come on.
Let's go.
Yo, you sure this guy's cool?
Yeah, he's totally on the
level.
Nobody move!
Or this one will be dead
before he hits the floor!
Travis, please don't hurt him!
It's just me!
April?
What the hell are you doing,
sneaking up on me?!
We thought you were dead!
No, no.
I've been sleeping with one
eye open for years.
Yeah? You want to let go of me
then, please!
Oh, I'm sorry, son.
Old habits die hard.
I was watching the dolphins
and niner's Super Bowl game
and uh...
must have dozed off.
We didn't mean to scare you,
we just...
didn't know where else
to go.
We're in trouble and need help.
Trouble?
Seth, show him the video.
Video?
What video?
You're gonna want to add
this one to your collection.
[on video] This is
definitely not an airplane!
Aliens.
I should have known.
See, everyone within the inner
circle knows that
the US government has had
a treaty
with the extraterrestrials
after since Roswell.
We don't have time for this
conspiracy theory bullshit!
We need to get help!
Now!
Seth!
Let him talk.
What kind of treaty?
Well, the powers that be
turn a blind eye to them
abducting civilians
and doing whatever
the hell it is they
do with them.
And, in turn, we get to run
around down here
as if we own the place.
It's a basic simple agreement
with one cardinal rule:
Do not engage.
And you, you engaged.
What do you mean?
Sweetheart, you shot
one of them.
Broke the treaty.
Now they're out for blood.
You guys, what does this mean?
[sonar beeping]
It's them.
It's gone, right?
Did it fly over us?
No, they landed.
What?
Landed, what do you
mean landed, man?
[electrical explosion]
Oh my God.
It's time to move.
Where are we going?
If you guys go that way,
you'll find a path
back to your place.
Wait, aren't you coming
with us?
Look, nobody invades my property
without expecting a fight.
I'm American.
It's my right to defend
what's mine, and nobody,
not even little green men,
are gonna take that
right away from me.
Now you go, go on.
Go on.
Come and kiss my ass.
What the hell?
Where are you,
you son of a bitch?
[gunshots]
Shit.
So we want to play hide
and seek, do we?
Yeah.
[growls]
[gunshots]
[laughs]
Got you.
Time to get your friends.
[sirens]
You have to help
the others.
What do you mean?
They bring most people back.
Like they did with me.
But not everyone.
There's hundreds of people
still alive up there.
Some of them have been up
there for years.
Maybe even their
whole lives.
You've gotta do something.
[police radio]
It can't be.
[rock music]
I hope the boards hold.
I think we're gonna
be alright.
[footsteps]
[pounding]
What was that?
Shh.
[whispers] Ok,
woah, woah, woah.
[whispers]
What do you see?
I can't see anything.
What?
I'm telling you,
I can't see shit.
Move, let me see.
[gasps]
What, what!
What is it?
Oh my God, it's right
outside the door!
It's going to get inside!
Oh my God, they're coming!
[banging on door]
[gunshot]
Down!
Get down!
Get on your knees!
Don't shoot!
Put it down!
Back up!
Officer, we need your help!
Shut up, both of you!
Hands against the wall!
Now!
You need to help us!
We didn't do anything,
alright?
This is fucking bullshit!
Whoo!
This one's breath smells
like whiskey, sheriff,
and he's belligerent!
You, face me.
We found your car abandoned
on the side of the road,
do you mind telling me what
the hell is going on
and why your friend
just tried to kill us?
We were attacked.
We are not safe here!
Quiet!
He isn't talkin' to you!
Cool it, Mitchell.
You said you were attacked.
What happened?
Look, I know that this is
gonna sound crazy, ok,
but we saw something crash
in the woods.
We thought it was a plane,
but it was, like,
this disc shaped craft...
It took our fucking friend.
It was a UFO!
I mean...
it abducted our friend!
And it was a fucking UFO!
It's the truth, I swear!
Listen to me for a second,
listen to me.
There are fucking aliens
everywhere, man!
It was right outside the cabin,
we thought you were one of them!
That's why we shot at you,
you dumb pig.
Why do you think we boarded
up all the windows?
Put your hands against
the wall!
[laughs]
Come on!
Aliens?
UFOs?
Are you fucking listening
to this shit, sheriff?
I mean, take a look around.
There's booze and narcotics
everywhere!
You cannot possibly believe
this load of shit.
Sheriff, I bet we search
the basement,
we'll find us a full-on meth
lab, won't we, you little shit?
We can prove it!
One of them was
in the house.
I shot it.
It's in the pool.
Show me.
Both of you.
You stay put.
Go on.
Ok.
Get up, kid.
Oh my God.
It was right here, I swear.
It wasn't dead.
[glass breaking]
You guys have another
friend hiding back there?
No.
It's just us.
I swear.
Get back in the house.
Now.
Sheriff's department.
If someone's in there, come
out where I can see you.
[thud]
[gooey sounds]
[dog whining]
[startling sounds]
[gunshots]
[unearthly growls]
Oh my God.
So, when they took you on
board their space ship,
did they give you one of them...
you know, anal probes?
Oh yeah, very original
you fucking idiot,
I already told you it was
my girlfriend who got taken,
not me!
Hey!
You know, you ain't got to go
into outer space to get probed.
You'll be getting plenty of
that in the shower every day
from a big guy named Mootombo.
[laughs]
Sheriff, you have got to get
a load of this kid's story.
The boys back at the station,
they're gonna love this!
[laughs]
Sheriff?
Hey, you with me?
They're tellin' the truth.
[laughs]
You see? I fucking told you!
You can't be serious.
I mean, come on man, these kids
are obviously high as kites,
makin' this shit up!
UFOs?
Alien abductions?
I mean, this is horseshit!
It's because of this,
isn't it?
It's been ten years, Alan.
Now look.
I mean no disrespect, but it
is time to face reality.
She left you.
People have been trying
to convince me
that she just split town, just
took off with another guy.
People have been
saying it so long
I almost believed it myself
but now I know
what happened.
What the hell are
you talkin' about?
She would have never done
that to me.
We were in love with each other.
That night I went to bed
sleeping next to her
and I woke up and she was...
she was gone.
She didn't take any of her
clothes, didn't leave a note.
How could she lock the front
door without taking her keys?
I don't know, but I think
you need to accept the fact
that she ain't never
coming back.
If it had been her choice,
Mitchell, then I would.
But I don't think she had one,
she was taken from me!
Kidnapped, abducted,
whatever you want to call it,
but goddammit, what happened
to her is what's happening
to these kids right now!
And we gotta get 'em
outta here.
Woah, what the hell is that?
What the hell is that!?
[muffled]
Oh, shit!
Start the damn car!
Woah, woah!
[gunshot]
[cocks gun]
Don't do it!
[gunshot]
[muffled]
Fuck!
Fuck! Shit! Shit!
Are you ok?
Get me out of this fucking car!
Get these things off me,
man!
Get 'em off, get 'em off!
What the fuck happened?
Shit!
They made him do it!
They got inside his
fucking head,
and they made him blow his own
fucking brains out!
Oh shit.
Shit, they're gonna take
control of all of us!
Just stay away from me!
Seth. Calm down, ok?
We can't stay here, ok?
We can't stay here
'cause this shit,
this shit
is not gonna do
anything, alright?
We are gonna die in here.
Give me that cop's gun.
What?
I said give me the fucking gun!
Shut the fuck up, Melanie.
Put the fucking gun down.
[punched in the face]
Oh my God!
I'm the one with the gun,
so you listen to me, ok?
Do you understand that,
tough guy?
Seth!
Back the fuck off!
Ok everyone, just calm
down, alright?
Ok, just let me think.
Just let me think.
Those fuckers are not gonna
get inside my head.
Just give me a second,
alright?
Just, everyone just fucking
calm down.
These fuckers are not gonna
get inside my head, alright?
So this is what we're gonna do.
We're gonna make a break for
town, you're coming with me,
you get up, you're coming
with me.
You stay put, because this
is your fault.
They want you!
So if they want you,
they can fucking have you!
You're out of your fucking
mind, Seth!
We're not leaving
without her.
Is that right?
Well to HELL with you.
You can all stay here and rot.
Have fun on your fucking
honeymoon!
Oh my God, are you ok?
Yeah.
Yeah?
I can see why you didn't
want him to come.
[dishware rattling]
You guys?
[bottle breaks]
What the fuck was that?
[glass breaking]
[screaming]
What do you want from us?!
Get away from the window!
Oh God.
[painful white noise]
Oh my God.
[screaming]
[exploding]
[thunderous sounds]
We gotta get to the basement!
Go, go, go!
Kyle, let's go!
Kyle, what're you doing?
I'm not letting them get
you, babe.
No, Kyle!
Open the fucking door!
No, I'm gonna be ok!
No, Kyle, please
don't do this!
Babe, there's no
other choice.
I have to, I'm sorry.
You are gonna get
out of here,
and you're gonna survive.
No!
What about you?
I'm full of surprises!
[sobbing]
Kyle?
Kyle, No!
Kyle!
[thunderous sounds]
Ok.
Hey!
I'm up here,
you motherfuckers!
Up here!
Come on!
[panting]
Shit! Shit!
Fuck.
Shit.
Fuck!
Shit!
[snaps stick]
[out of breath]
Ok, alright. Fuck.
[twig snaps]
Who's there?
Who's out there!?
Fuck, who's out there?!
Huh?
[growling]
Fuck you!
[gunshots]
You motherfuckers!
Good luck taking me!
You fuck!
Shit! Shit!
[laughs]
[screams]
[gasping]
Fuck!
No!
Noooo!
No, no, please,
you can't take me!
You can't...
[rumbling sounds]
You remember when
we came out here
that summer before
high school started?
Yeah, it was right before
my parents broke up.
We raided your parents'
liquor cabinet
and got so drunk.
[laughs]
And your dad took us fishing
the next day
and I threw up all over
the boat.
[laughs]
And you covered for me,
you said I was just sea sick.
We were only on the lake.
That was the best
summer ever.
I think I took too many.
No Mel.
No, Mel, why did
you do that?
I'm so sorry.
I don't want to go up there.
I don't want them to take me.
[crying]
No, it's ok.
I'm really tired.
I think I'm gonna close
my eyes for a little while.
No.
No, Mel, no, no!
Please, no!
Mel!
Wake up!
Mel, wake up!
Don't do this to me!
[crying]
[thunderous crash]
[footsteps]
[thump]
[smashes glass]
[foreboding music]
[clanking sound]
[electrical shorts]
[music playing]
Kyle?
No.
No!
No, don't go!
[rummaging sounds]
Come back.
Please, come back!
Come back!
[explosion]
No, please!
Come back!
Come get me!
I'm right here, please!
[crying]
No, please.
[sobbing]
I'm sorry, Kyle.
[foreboding music]
[shallow breathing]
[vomiting]
[gasping]
[screaming]
[vomiting]
[epic music]
[struggling]
Oh, oh shit!
Ahhhhh!
Help!
Somebody, help!
[mechanical sounds]
Fuck!
[screams]
[mechanical noises]
[squishy gooey sounds]
Oh my God.
Kyle!
Oh my God, Kyle!
I'm gonna get you out
of here!
It's ok.
No.
No!
[crying]
Kyle!
Oh God, I'm so sorry.
Oh God.
When you proposed, I should
have said yes,
I was just scared.
Well, I'm not scared anymore.
Because what I said about us
being alone,
I know that's not true.
So wake up.
Wake up!
You're not dying!
Wake up, Kyle!
No, wake up, Kyle!
Kyle, wake up!
Wake up!
Kyle!
Kyle, wake up!
Wake up!
[coughing]
Oh my God, it's ok!
Just breathe!
April!
What're you doing here?
It's you and me Kyle,
remember?
Where you go, I go.
I didn't mean outer space.
[growling]
[foreboding music]
[birds chirping]
What happened?
I don't know.
You came back for me.
You're fucking crazy, April.
[laughs]
You just realized
that now?
[laughs]
¶
¶ The book of love is long
and boring, ¶
¶ no one can lift
the damn thing. ¶
¶ It's full of charts and facts
and figures ¶
¶ and instructions
for dancing. ¶
¶ But I, ¶
¶ I love it when you read
to me. ¶
¶ You ¶
¶ can read me anything ¶
¶
¶ The book of love
has music in it. ¶
¶ In fact that's where... ¶
Wait, wait, wait.
Do you hear that?
What is that?
It's over there!
¶
¶ I love it when you sing
to me. ¶
Hey! Over here!
¶ You ¶
Help us!
¶
[gunshot]
No!
No, wait!
Wait, wait!
[gunshots]
[epic music]
That's the last of them.
Good.
Do we know anything yet?
Intel is still coming in,
but it looks like
the storm caused the crash,
like the one last year
in Portugal.
Fatalities?
Fairly minimal.
Stories are already
being prepared.
What should we do
with the bodies?
Same thing we always do.
¶
¶ When I die and they
lay me to rest, ¶
¶ gonna go to the place
that's the best. ¶
¶ When I lay me down
to die, ¶
¶ goin' up to the spirit
in the sky. ¶
¶ Goin' up to the spirit
in the sky, ¶
¶ that's where I'm gonna
go when I die. ¶
¶ When I die and they
lay me to rest, ¶
¶ gonna go to the place
that's the best. ¶
¶
¶ Prepare yourself,
you know it's a must, ¶
¶ gotta have a friend
in Jesus, ¶
¶ so you know that
when you die, ¶
¶ he's gonna recommend you
to the spirit in the sky. ¶
¶ Gonna recommend you to
the spirit in the sky, ¶
¶ that's where you're gonna
go when you die. ¶
¶ When you die and
they lay you to rest, ¶
¶ you're gonna go ¶
¶ to the place
that's the best. ¶
¶