Sandy?
- What's the matter, princess?
Honey, Sandy, what happened?
I don't remember.
Come in.
What is this ridiculous thing? Come here.
- It's called the Windsor knot.
It's like a noose.
- I got it at a Playboy's Guide to Style.
Oh my gosh, stick with the encyclopedia.
Got you where you are.
I mean, don't get me wrong, Sandy's a cool
chick but it's not like you're gonna marry her.
You're not gonna marry her, are you?
I don't have any thought of what I'm doing
next week. Never mind, the rest of my life.
Well, you could figure it out because I'm sure as shit Sandy has.
And you can bet your ass that her parents have some pretty
strong opinions on the subject.
And what's that suppose to mean?
Just think how they don't like their perfect
little princess banging big bad wolf.
I'm not banging her, Lex.
I'm dating her, faithfully.
Alright, next year when she's at Stanford
and you're slumming in at State...
I'll give you two months before she finds some
pre-med and you meet the entire cheering squad.
Oh, yeah? What about you and TJ?
- I wanna show you something.
Subtle.
- Gotta love it, right?
Is that wash off?
Chad, what is it?
- You gotta go.
Layla's here.
Wait, what? I thought you
said you broke up.
I lied.
You asshole. How could you...?
- Have you seen your body?
But I thought you said...
- You thought I said what..?
You never were a match for thinking.
Hey, pass.
- Nice arm...
For a girl.
Maybe I'll play college football too, huh.
- I got three words for you, TJ. Random drug test..
Too early for beer, ain't it?
You put all the others?
- Scholarships don't come on line everyday, Jake.
True, dude. Well, like every other day.
- One day they'll just stop coming, believe me.
Hey, daddy.
Going to the graduation party tonight?
- God, I hope not. TJ, do me a favor. Keep things under control, will you?
You're really embarrassing to bust my whole family.
- Rated G, PG at the worst.
It's rare to find students so qualified in the
same school and they belong in the same family.
-- Thank you, sir.
May your future be as bright as your past.
- Hear, hear.
Well, after college I'd like to become a doctor just like you.
- Then we'll be colleague someday.
Eli wants to be a doctor too, don't you Eli?
- Oh well, no actually, I was looking...
Actually my little brother wants to become a pirate.
I don't wanna become a pirate.
That's such fictional, I mean...
Well anyone that becomes valedictorian after
skipping a grade can do whatever he wants.
- Well thank you. Thank you very much.
You must be very proud.
- We are.
Then you'll even be more proud to learn that I'm
recommending both Sandy and Eli for full academic scholarship.
Just consider it a graduation
present for your parents.
We're going to Stanford.
- We are.
Well, enough of that boring stuff.
What are you two gonna get into this summer?
Just a little charity work, sir.
Ladies.
You're an asshole.
- I love you too.
Let's do some fucking shots.
New king in town, bitches.
All bow down before my lengthy lance.
You're so wet, good.
Have you ever wonder what I'd be like
to live in another time and place?
Like to exist in a completely formed reality
where societal conventions don't apply.
Like in France or something?
No, like, like...
I really wish I was a pirate.
Eli, you're so random.
- No seriously, think about it.
Like think about it. I can be a pirate
just like, sail over the world.
Have a parrot.
Crunches a sword and then rips a bodice.
What's a bodice?
Hey, there's my girl.
- Hey, baby.
Wasn't sure what you wanted? So I got vodka or rhum.
- How about both?
Whoa, easy. Whoa, whoa. What are you Irish?
- My mom thinks I'm staying at Hannah's tonight.
Then I'm gonna get a second round.
- Hey, come here.
I love you.
- I love you too.
You're so goddamn hot.
- Yeah, don't you forget it.
Oh if you ever cheat on me
I swear to God I'd kill the guy.
Don't worry baby. I don't want
anybody else. Not now, not ever.
Yeah, you hear that? This ass belongs to me.
Cheers.
I'm done here. I'm fucking wasted.
Hold it.
Jennifer Atkins back in my jeep,
driver's at the glass, summer school.
Ride that stick, baby.
You're a whore.
Alright, alright, alright. Dominic Sperduto...
9th grade, 50-yard line
at the football field.
Sperduto?
- What, he was good.
He was hairy, but it's good.
Shut up.
- What about you, Eli?
A gentleman doesn't kiss and tell.
- And what's that gotta do with you. Spill it, fish fag.
Fine. Your mom. Last night.
You don't know why it's always about my mother.
Eli, I wanna make fun of Chad just ask
him about the training in Tijuana.
I wanna hear about Sandy.
You know, sometimes some memory
lane should never be discussed.
But my first kiss, now that was pretty hot.
Boring.
- Wait, wait. I wanna hear it.
Okay. Well, it was in the graveyard. You remember it?
- I remember it.
We were playing the game.
- I was there.
We were all there.
- Oh yeah, the game.
That was so fun.
- I was so scared.
Surrounded by all those dead bodies, so quiet.
I was the last one left.
And you were all out there looking
for me. Hunting me.
My heart was pounding, knowing that any second
someone was gonna jump out and grab me.
I didn't know whether I was gonna
have a heart attack or an orgasm.
Oh God, that sounds so hot.
- I'm hot.
And wet.
Grab the beers.
- Grab the beers.
Who wins? Who wins?
The Chad wins.
You cut through the fucking... You went the complete
wrong way. That's not even the course bro.
We gotta to have a complete rematch.
There's no fucking way that that is gonna be the result.
Oh whoa, careful kids. God's watching.
Okay, while we're here are we gonna
play or we're just gonna make out?
I vote play.
- Me too.
Alright dipshits, huddle up.
- Okay, everybody hold a hand.
Dude, this is so gayish.
- Oh, go back, wash mop head.
Okay, who's the ghost?
- Can I play?
You scared the crap out of me, little momma.
- I'd really like to play.
It's my favorite game.
- I bet it is, baby.
I know all the best hiding spots.
- That's what I'm talking about.
I don't know, it's kinda weird.
- You got it bro, girls are so weird.
Come on, let her play.
You might get lucky, Eli.
Oh come on Eli, I'll protect you.
- You're in.
Come here.
Alright, spread it out.
- Wait, wait. What are the rules again?
One person's the ghost. Everybody else hides,
once you're caught you turn into a ghost.
Last one alive wins.
Alright, who's the ghost?
- I am. I am the ghost.
Okay, come on.
- Here we go.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven
release the one ignored by heaven.
eight, nine, ten, now run and hide
or join her at the devil's side.
eleven comes, the clock will chime
forgotten souls erased by time.
midnight comes, it's not too late
so kill the ghost or seal your fate!
Midnight.
Layla's a ghost.
Lex is a ghost.
Chad's a ghost.
And Mitchell's sacked and lost.
This is so stupid.
Hannah's a ghost.
Fucking ghost, yeah.
Sandy's a ghost.
- You go that way. We'll get her.
You're the only one left. You won.
What are you doing?
- Do you remember me?
Do you remember me?
Hey, be careful.
You will.
Hey, where did she go?
Sandy, what happened?
The girl just jumped.
- What happened?
What happened?
- The girl she just jumped off the cliff.
We've been over every inch ground
down there and I'm telling you there's no girl.
It's gotta be something.
People are just disappearing.
I hate to say this boss but,
maybe she's just making it up.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Everything okay, daddy?
- Yeah, baby.
Look, ah, there's nothing down there.
- Wait, wait, but Sandy saw her jumped.
I know, I know. That's why we're here,
that's why we're gonna stay here until I make sure everybody's safe.
So what do we do?
- Keep looking for her.
You, you take her home.
Don't worry, if she's here, we're gonna find her.
She's dead, isn't she?
- Sandy, nobody's dead.
I saw her jumped.
- Maybe she's hiding.
Maybe planning a joke or something.
- Dude, why don't we just get home?
There's nothing we can do tonight, you guys.
Let's call it a night.
Are you okay?
I know what I saw.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven
release the one ignored by heaven.
eight, nine, ten, now run and hide
or join her at the devil's side.
eleven comes, the clock will chime
forgotten souls erased by time
midnight comes, it's not too late
so kill the ghost or seal your fate!
Sister Dolores says
it's my magic breath.
That's a pretty flower.
- They're called forget-me-nots.
You put them over the graves.
How come?
- So you don't forget the dead.
But I don't know any dead people.
I do.
Oh, sad.
- That's okay.
Sister Dolores says that if my faith is strong
enough, I can have all the friends I want.
But I only want you.
Bestfriends?
Friends forever.
Good morning.
We should leave.
- Do we have to?
Stop it.
- Doesn't feel like you want me to stop.
What's wrong with you? Are you okay, baby?
I wished we break up.
What? Why?
- I'm over it.
Why did I not do it right?
I'm just not feeling it.
It's Hannah, isn't it?
I knew it, I know you're into her.
Look, I just don't wanna be
tied down to anybody.
Don't you fucking dare.
Fine. It's yours.
Swim for it.
Are you okay?
Wait.
Do you have anything smaller?
- Here.
Perfect. Let Chad see what he's missing.
Wait, I thought you were over him.
- I am. - So what happened?
Let's just say, I wasn't wearing panties at the party.
- Hannah, you didn't.
Oh, I most definitely did.
- What about Layla?
Who?
- If she finds out, it's gonna be major drama.
Hold on. Chad is seeing someone else?
What a dick. Of course, if it wasn't for his massive...
It's kinda hot .
Hey, take it easy with my brother, okay. He likes you.
- Really?
I didn't see anything. Not that there's
anything to see, of course, there's something to see.
There's a lot to see.
I just, I didn't, I didn't see it.
- Turn around, goofball.
Will this make me look like a slut?
You look...
pretty.
Don't you have something to pack?
- No, actually I'm good to go.
Eli, go pack again.
Got you
- You got me, Pete.
You always get me, man.
- That's 'coz you smoke too much.
You know, you better lay off that shit if you wanna
make babies with that lovely little woman here.
Do you got something for me?
- I sure do.
Absolutely.
How about that? Ain't that a beaut?
All of the check, huh.
What the hell if she's worth it, right.
- Don't come calling me Monday saying you're hangover now.
Hangover? I'd probably still be drunk.
- Oh shit, wait a minute? Do me a favor, will you?
Check one, two and three
the safety guards.
Where can I put these?
- Hey, you guys.
What's up?
- Hey, Cecilia.
What's up with the stripes?
- I have to work.
Are you serious?
- Yeah, I know it sucks, I need to get rid of my tan lines.
Sure, you do.
Unbelievable.
Have you no shame?
- Of course not, you know that.
Where is Layla?
Hi, Jake.
- Hey, CC.
How is it? You'll have a drink from me, okay.
- Yes, ma'am. I'll have two.
TJ's gonna be here at seven,
the beer's gonna be chilled on ice.
Don't mind if I do.
Hey, Suzie Q. You missed me?
You want some?
Sweet.
You're good.
What up, sweet Melissa? Looking sexy.
You're so in shape baby, huh?
Mary Jane, we meet again?
What's up, baby?
Feeling a little tight today, huh.
You need a little lube?
Is that you, Pete?
Note to self:
Drugs are bad.
Out here to scream, baby.
Hey, who is there?
Don't make me kick your ass, man.
Are you okay?
First thing I wanna do when we get there,
is take a long nap in the sand.
Think back with Pina Colada
just forget about everything for a while.
If you need company let me know...
We forgot about the beer.
Wait, isn't TJ bringing the beer?
Who?
- TJ.
I'll call him.
What's with her?
- I don't know.
She's been acting weird all day.
Who wants some?
Come on, I'll not let them right here.
- I mean, what a lovely day to go to the beach.
Hey, any word?
- No, nothing.
But don't worry I gonna sort the whole
mess out when you guys are gone.
Well, if you find her, will you call me?
- When I find her, you will be the first person I'll call.
Thanks, Zack.
Alright, you kids have fun.
- We always do.
Well, not too much fun okay.  And for Christ's
sake, keep a leash on my daughter, will you?
Only if it's leather.
Sure you can't come?
- Miss me okay.
Hey, let's see what you got?
Oh Eli-e, let us see what you got.
- Loser buys beer.
Come on, Eli. Don't be a pussy.
Be a tiger.
Please, Jake. Not now.
- I'm not a tiger.
I'm a pirate.
Where is he?
- Wait, wait, wait, where is he?
You're winning.
Watch out.
No way.
Oh shit, I always had you.
Yeah well, now you
have beer to go.
Sandy?
- What the hell?
This is our game.
- This is my friend. Jake.
- I was gonna get you, I just forgot.
What are they doing here?
- It's okay, they're cool. They're my friends.
You're ruining this.
What's wrong with her?
It's nothing. She's cool.
- Come on, guys. Let's go.
Hey Sandy, you coming or what?
- Sandy, are you okay?
Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
It's fun, huh?
What's wrong?
- A new clerk.
Hannah, you have an advantage here.
Two rounds.
No way, they always card me.
- Don't look at me, I can't even grow a mustache.
Oh you can't even grow a pube, Eli.
What's going on?
- Strategy.
I told you that we should wait for TJ.
- Guys, I got this under control.
Wait, no no wait...  -- Yeah, she is.
- She isn't gonna...
Can I help you?
- I sure hope so.
You have something hot for me?
- We have hotdogs.
I'm starving.
How much?
- $1.50 for the regular, $2 for the footlong.
I'll take the biggest one you got.
Forgot my wallet. See.
- I guess, I can lend you some change.
Well, aren't you sweet?
Wait, let me help you.
What are you doing?
- What's this?
Oh my...
Holy shit, she's gonna screw that dude.
- So what? He's hot.
I don't need to see that.
- Wait, is nobody bothered by this?
Why would this bother us?
She's getting naked.
How can she do this to TJ?
- What's with you? You're talking crazy.
Me?
Who the hell is TJ?
Is somebody out there?
Screw this.
You, dude, hadn't come up yet.
Let's go.
Are you okay, man?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Alright. Move your ass right at the market.
- Sure, I'm there.
Somebody fucking help me.
Are you ready?
Where is your bike?
- I left it at the house, remember?
Come on, get in.
Oh my God, just hit me.
We're done, we're graduating.
I'm graduating.
Dude, that was awesome.
- That was awesome.
Get back in the car. What the hell is going on?
- What do you mean?
Yeah, Sandy, what're you talking about?
- Where's my stuff?
I mean, where are the beach chairs?
Where's your bogey board?
Why would you bring a freaking bogey board to the mountains?
- I have nothing to say to you.
Excuse me?
- How about TJ?
Who the heck is TJ?
- I don't wanna be with anybody else.
Not now. Not ever. You're thrash.
- Fuck you, Sandy.
Just because you're Cin"the fucking"rella doesn't
give you the right to judge the rest of us.
Do me a favor, Lex and shut the fuck up.
- Jesus, Jake, wake up!
You think it's just me? She thinks you're thrash too,
she thinks our whole family's garbage.
Stop the car.
Sandy, what the hell is going on? You're acting like a lunatic.
- You know, this is Chad's car.
Who's Chad?
Pretty boy asshole. The guy who drives this car.
Oh yeah, you fucked him yesterday, how about that?
Sandy, come on. You're freaking me out, alright.
- She's out of her goddamn mind.
Shut up.
Sandy, what the fuck is going on?
What is this, Jake? Is this some kind of joke.
- I don't know, Sandy. You tell me.
Whatever it is, it's not very funny.
Get in the car.
No, wait. Dad said that I wasn't gonna let you drive.
- Eli, get in the goddamn car.
This can't be possible.
- Wait, Sandy.
Eli, stay here.
- Wait, maybe I should go...
I said, stay here!
Can you like turn the
music or something?
What's wrong with her?
- She's fucked up.
What are you talking about? Sandy's the smartest girl I know.
She's class president. She's going to Stanford.
Well, the more perfect someone life's seems
the more fucked up they probably are.
I don't know what that makes you, Mother Teresa?
- Nope, just honest.
Well, at least I can figure out
what I'm worth to fucking fuck first.
You're a bitch, Lex.
What the fuck do you mean?
- Jesus, Hannah, chill out.
Guys?
It was like he was never here.
Oh my God, Eli. What happened?
What are you doing?
Dude, I didn't mean it.
Oh shit.
- Where's Lex?
Alexis?
Help me.
Where are you?
I'm gonna need a shovel.
To dig with anything.
Sandy, are you hurt or what? What happened?
- She was right here, I swear. She was right here.
Don't just stare there, help me.
- Stop it. Stop it.
This can't be happening.
- Jake, what is going on?
I swear, she was right here.
- Stop, stop. You're not making any sense.
She was right there.
You saw it, didn't you?
You were right here.
Eli, you saw it, didn't you?
Saw what?
- That thing, that fucking thing who
dragged her to the goddamn ground.
Dragged who?
- Lex.
How can you not remember them?
Don't look at me like that.
I'm not crazy.
I don't wanna do this.
- Jake, you were dumber than I thought you were.
What the fuck do you want?
- Nothing, sir.
Nothing. Get the fuck out of my office
- But, I...
Sandy's just worried
about that girl.
And I told you I'd call.
- Zack, you don't understand.
Shut up.
Her name is Angela Smith.
See, I told you I'd call.
I've been talking to the school but the girl she was
looking for, yeah she dropped down, the seventh grade.
This was some fucking nuns out there at the old convent.
Which if memory serves it right next to your graveyard.
Case closed.
- What do you mean, case closed?
I mean, the goddamn case is closed.
- People are disappearing.
Jake, let's just get out of here.
- People are dying.
Sandy, come on please. Let's just go.
- You have to believe me.
Is she on drugs? She's on fucking drugs, isn't she?
- Nobody's on drugs, this was a bad idea. Let's go
Hey, get back here.
Where are you going now?
- We have to hurry.
And go where?
- You heard, she lives at the convent.
Yeah, not exactly what I had in mind for a Saturday night, see ya.
- You can't leave we have to stay together.
And do what? Breaking to
a freaking convent? No, thanks.
Are you trying to get arrested? Coz then, we should just go back inside.
- We have bigger problems than being arrested.
Yeah, you got that right.
- I'm talking about Angela Smith, okay.
That's it. I'm going home, bye.
- You're gonna die.
It's not cool.
Which is it, Sandy? You wanna help with the time
or you're gonna act like a crazy person? Coz I'm not going.
Please, Hannah. I'm begging you.
Maybe we should just go home.
- Can't do that.
Coz this asshole is gonna
be there waiting for me.
What about our house?
- Right. With her like this?
Who's gonna get the blame for that?
Not you, guys.
Jake, you don't understand.
- I don't understand? I don't understand what's going on.
I don't understand what you want from me?
or what the hell is going on
with this convent or this goddamn girl?
I don't understand any of it.
But if it's that important to you...
I'll go.
We'll all go.
Not tonight.
But tomorrow morning.
We have to stay together, then.
- Then we'll stay together.
All of us.
Anybody out there?
Now, coz if there is...
I'm ready, I'll take him.
But seriously, though.
Whatever it is, I got your back.
You know what I mean?
Do you believe me, Eli?
I believe that you believed it.
And that's good enough for me.
I didn't really wanna go to the mountains, anyway.
- I did.
Actually, I was really looking forward to it.
Really? Eli?
Want no dirtbags around?
Oh Jake, just you.
And your ticket.
Here, give this to Sandy.
- I don't know, Hannah?
Oh, come on. She needs to sleep.
Come here a second.
Not exactly how we planned to
spend the night, is it?
You remember last fall when the scouts
were all over me and I was just out of my mind.
I thought I was going crazy.
But the night before state you showed up
with all the wine and blankets and what did we do?
We laid up in the roof and...
- fell asleep watching the stars.
You showed me the best thing I could do
was just forget about everything.
You were right.
- You lost the game, Jake.
But I played great.
Is it me?
Did I do something wrong?
I know I'm not what
your parents want.
But I need to know
if I'm what you want.
You are what I want, Jake.
I love you.
I love you too.
She's really out.
My God. Who needs beer?
- Me.
I'm gonna check out the pool.
Eli?
Oh come on, walk me. Make sure I'm safe.
I mean, we're all suppose to stay together.
- I can handle her. It's okay.
Are you sure?
Absolutely.
Okay, just a sec.
I'm sure you know what you're doing .
- Doing, doing. What do you mean?
Someone showed me this once.
What are you doing?
Is that a vagina?
Consider this...
the keys to the kingdom.
Looks like a treasure map.
- Well, sailor.
You follow the arrows,
the glorious bounty awaits.
That'll work?
-Only one way to find out.
Ready?
He's ready.
It's cold.
- That's coz you're all the way over there.
What if she's right?
What if we're on some kind of
physical or metaphysical danger?
Then we don't have any time to waste.
I'm serious.
- So am I.
I'm gonna move a little bit closer, okay.
How come you never
asked me out, Eli?
You always have a boyfriend.
I would've said yes.
You seem to always be with a
guy that look different from me.
Can you forgive me?
I forgive you.
It's gonna be awesome, man.
- Here, put this in your pocket.
And don't let her see it.
- What's wrong?
Maybe she's a big loser like her friend.
- I'm not a loser.
Sandy, I don't feel so good.
- Come on, Sandy. This was your idea.
Yeah, I mean, what's the big deal?
- We're gonna be late for dinner.
Yeah, whuzz.
- Everybody shut up. We're doing this, got it.
Give me the paint.
Easy, easy.
Where did you learn that?
Whatever "that" was.
A gentleman never tells..
Well, a gentleman could never do that either.
Where are you going?
- To get us some drinks.
Give you a chance to recharge.
Let me guess. This is where you disappear
and leave me cold and alone.
Cold? Yes.
Alone? Not a chance.
Oh, just so you don't forget...
It's okay.
Jesus Christ, Sandy.
Sorry, you scared me.
- You see that sign?
You break your neck,
we're ain't accountable.
Oh, creep.
Eli, come here, help me up.
She's gonna hurt herself, hold her up.
Pull her legs.
I saw that mister.
I know you're there, asshole.
Listen perv, don't make me call the...
This isn't real.
Please, get away.
There's my girl. I wasn't sure if
you wanted vodka or rhum.
Where is my brother?
Sandy, where the hell are you?
- Eli, are you okay?
No, look, mom and dad are all over me.
I can't cover for you anymore.
Is Hannah with you?
Meet me at the convent, okay.
- Sandy, just come home. Sheriff Mitchell stopped by the house.
Please meet me there.
I thought we're on a hurry.
May I help?
- Sorry to bother you...
I'm Sandy Channing and this is my friend...
- Jake Mitchell.
The quarterback?
- Yes ma'am.
Father Michael and I, we listen
to all the games on the Hi-Fi.
I'm Sister Dolores. Please come in.
I'm sorry sister, I know it's late.
- What can I do for you?
We're here because of Angela Smith.
How do you know her?
- I used to know her when I was little.
Of course.
- Sister, Sandy is just concerned...
Is Angela her?
- Oh, I wish she was...
but it's just not practical,
I'm sure you understand.
Do you know where she might be?
- At St. Mary's hospital.
They're quite wonderful there.
- Is she hurt?
Angela is in coma.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I assumed you knew.
A coma?
Thank you for your time.
- Well, I could show you her room.
I've kept her room just as she's left it.
Her doctors say that her condition
is permanent but well one hopes...
Oh well, the girls' floor...
- Mr. Mitchell can wait down here on the boys' floor.
Can he come with me?
- I'll be fine. I'll stay here on the boys' floor.
Please, come in.
Come in. Come in.
Girls, girls, game time is over.
Ride along.
Say your prayers.
I'll be there and I'll tuck you in a moment.
A little rhyme I teach the children.
It helps to keep the nightmares at bay.
Do you believe in the devil, Mr. Mitchell?
- No, not really.
Well, spend some time with these
little monsters, you'll believe.
So this is Angela's room?
This is a week before
it happened.
Six years ago this June.
How was that possible?
- Oh, I ask the Lord that every day.
Doctors blamed genetics but I don't
know. She was small...
and weaker than
the other children.
But I had faith that
God would protect her.
Angela believed in her own
kind of protection.
An angel?
- Faith is all-powerful.
If one truly believes in something,
one will make it come true.
Of course, we have to be careful
what we choose to believe in.
Duty calls. Forgive me.
I'll be right back.
Hey, you play any football?
- Do I play football?
Toss here, kid.
You see this arm? In Jefferson County,
it's worth more than your life.
Nice arm. For a girl.
Kid, hey kid.
You gotta be kidding me?
Hey kid, I've got your ball.
Speak, you little bastard.
What are you doing?
Did you know about these?
- What are they?
Why would she draw these?
Those can't be Angela's.
Just in case.
Hey kid, is that you?
What is this thing?
- I don't know.
Whatever it is...
it's real.
What in God's name?
Who are you?
He's gone.
What happened? Are you okay?
- It's too late. It's too late.
Look at this.
- I don't understand. What's going on?
It is the ghost.
- Ghost? What ghost?
From the game.
- Who are you?
You're not Angela's friend.
What do you want from her?
She's suffered enough.
- You get out of here.
Leave the poor girl in peace.
- God sees you, Ms. Channing.
God sees everything.
Who was that lady? And what the hell were you doing
out here in the middle of the freaking night?
It doesn't matter anymore.
They're all gone, it's over.
Sandy, nobody knows where you've been.
If you're in some kind of trouble,
you can talk to me.
It doesn't matter anymore, Eli. It doesn't matter.
- Stop saying that.
It matters to me.
You're my sister, okay.
If something is going on, please tell me.
So I can help you.
You can trust me.
You know that, right?
- I want you to listen to me, okay.
You do know that I love you and
I would never lie to you ever.
But what I'm about tell you is gonna sound
like the craziest thing in the world, because it is.
And I know you're not gonna believe me, because
nobody believes me. But I need you to believe, Eli.
I'm listening.
When we're little, we used to
play games, you remember?
In the graveyard?
- There was a girl, an orphan. Her name was Angela.
Last night we played the game again, but we
weren't alone. Six people are with us, Eli.
Six of our friends, and I know you don't remember them,
but they were there and now they're gone.
Gone? What do you mean gone?
- Something...
This thing took them.
This thing is connected to
Angela and the game?
It has to be.
I knew you wouldn't believe me.
- I believe you.
I believe you.
Why would you make it up?
I wouldn't.
Let's figure this out. The game.
What are the rules of the game?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven
- Release the one ignored by heaven.
That's Angela, right?
eight, nine, ten, now run and hide
or join her at the devil's side.
That's obvious.
eleven comes, the clock will chime
forgotten souls erased by time.
That's it. Erased. Okay, that's it.
Erased by time. That makes sense now.
Okay, it doesn't make any sense at all,
but I think I know why.
People are gone.
People I knew?
You didn't just know them Eli they were your
best friends and now one by one they've been...
Erased.
Alright, so how does it end? Midnight comes...
It's not too late.
- So kill the ghost or seal your fate.
God, she's still alive. Angela's still alive.
What does that mean?
- It means she has to die.
Who has to die?
What's going on?
- Dad...
We've been really worried about you.
- Step aside, son.
Wait.
- You're sick, honey.
She didn't do anything wrong.
- No, sweetheart. She just needs some help.
No, no. You're not going anywhere, alright. Sit down.
- Let go.
You don't understand, please.
It's gonna be okay, honey.
- You'll get back to normal in no time.
We're gonna take very good
care of you, Ms. Channing.
Sandy, I'm here. I'm right here.
- Step aside.
For Christ's sake. Somebody hold him down.
- Sandy, tell me what to do?
Kill the ghost or seal your fate.
- What is she saying?
Kill her?
- Kill her.
You can't go any further.
I'll do it, Sandy. I'll do it.
Midnight.
Stop. Let me go.
Let me go.
Eli? Where is Eli?
- What is she saying?
Who's Eli, honey?
- Is Eli one of her friends?
Sandy doesn't have any friends.
- Go to sleep, honey. We'll be here when you wake up.
Angela Smith.
That's strange.
Angela Smith is a patient here.
I thought we could play the game?
Who's playing?
- Just us.
I'm sorry about last time.
It's getting late. We should play.
Maybe we shouldn't play.
- No, I want to play.
Wait. Who's the ghost?
You are.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven
release the one ignored by heaven.
Run.
Help me.
Midnight.
Look at that shit.
Who did this?
I know what I've done...
but I also know what you've done.
You wanna play a game?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven
release the one ignored by heaven.
eight, nine, ten, now run and hide
or join her at the devil's side.
I remember you. I remember everything.
- Eleven comes, the clock will chime
forgotten souls erased by time.
I'm so sorry.
- Midnight comes, it's not too late
so kill the ghost or seal your fate!
Please. I was your bestfriend.
All I wanted was you.
- I'll never forget you. I promise.
Friends forever. Is that it?
Well look at you.
It's a miracle.