My name is Yasmine.
I'm three months pregnant.
One day, someone said
"Men are born free
with equal rights."
The world in which I live
is the opposite.
Who would want to be born
to grow in the chaos
and the hate?
I've decided
to spare him the worst.
[static]
[inaudible dialogue
over static]
[shouting]
To vote.
[Man] Second round
of presidential elections.
[crowd chanting]
The criminal court...
Unknown to the police
services...
The riots start...
...election of the extreme
right government.
To vote.
[shouting]
[marching]
[screaming]
[gunfire]
Nothing to see.
Go back home.
[alarm blares]
[gunshot, glass breaks]
Come on!
It's clear. Go.
Run! Come on.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Come on.
Stop, stop.
Come on, stay strong.
[panting]
Are you okay?
- Easy, easy.
[grunting]
Freeze!
Alex, come on, don't screw up.
What are you doing, Alex?
- Stop that, God damn it!
Don't move!
- Stop that, Alex!
[men shouting]
You don't play rough anymore,
huh? Son of a bitch!
Huh? You don't play rough
anymore? Asshole!
Aah!
[grunting]
Leave him alone
so we can hit the road!
Alex, come on, go!
Hurry, hurry!
[shouting]
[Man]
Hello?
Sami got shot!
He's pissing blood!
What can I do?
Damn it!
He's going to die, you hear?
My brother is dying!
Take him to the hospital
right away.
Give me that.
Hey Yas, it's Tom.
Calm down. We're on our way.
Sure, I'll wait for you.
I won't budge.
Shut the fuck up and you do
what I say, damn it!
Damn it, you idiot,
he's been shot.
So what?
It's not my fault!
He shouldn't have been.
We did that for you.
- Are you kidding me?
It's because
you bang his sister
It's over with Yas.
[siren]
Shit! They're here! Go!
Oh, shit.
No time for that.
He didn't miss you,
that bastard.
Get lost.
What were you doing?
It's a mess, cops everywhere.
We have to take him
to the hospital.
He looks like a Tampax.
It's too risky.
Oh, Oh, easy.
Don't talk about
my brother like that.
You take your
responsibility here!
Assume yours. You know
exactly what you did.
Stop it, stop it.
- You twat!
Let's be smart. Let's try
to find a solution, all right?
I'm taking him
to the hospital.
You guys can run away
if you want.
No hospital. You're
going to get busted.
Who knows he's not
going to rat on us?
Who you callin' a rat?
Bastard.
Shut the fuck up!
Asshole!
- Whoa!
Damn, guys, he needs
to see a medic.
I've a solution.
Tom, you go with Farid.
You find a room
close to the frontier,
In the meantime, I'm taking
madame and her tampon to the ER.
We'll catch up with you guys
when we're out of this mess.
There you go, okay?
All right.
I won't go with that bastard.
I'd rather die.
Shut the fuck up!
You want to die here?
Fuck you! Come on, Farid, take
me to the ER please, come on.
I can't, damn it.
- Come on.
What do you want?
You're okay?
I've had better days.
That's the baby?
You're not concerned anymore.
Don't pretend to be concerned.
Keep on taking care of yourself.
That's what you do the best.
Yasmine.
Forget it.
When I get rid of it,
it'll belong to the past.
Yas, I did it for us.
I did it for me.
[car alarm blares]
Farid, are you stupid?
You want us to get caught?
[alarm stops]
Shut up. Chill out.
How much so far?
125,000.
Plus that and that.
Don't try to screw us.
I see I've got your trust.
What do we do with Sami's cut?
Why are you saying that?
Just to know.
You think I'm
already dead, asshole.
Okay, Tom,
you're over the top.
He'll get his cut
like everyone else.
[Yasmine]
Calm down.
Okay, Boss, can we go?
Do we
have the green light?
So let's go.
Good luck, Sami.
[Announcer] Because of the riots
brought about
by the results of the first
round of the election,
the former government
has put in place
drastic measures
establishing a curfew,
each person taken in
for questioning after...
# [mellow rock]
Shit, we really have
to get away from here,
or I don't know
how this will end.
Shut up! Shut the fuck up!
Tell him to shut the hell up.
No, you shut up!
Don't touch me!
Come on, God damn it, move on.
We're there in five,
so get out of my face.
[groaning]
Shut up, don't screw up, okay?
[speaking incoherently]
Come on, Sami.
What's going on here?
Please, help us.
He's losing a lot of blood.
How did he do that?
I don't know if you're aware,
but there's a big mess outside.
Wait here,
I'll be right back.
Please hurry.
There you go.
Yas...keep it.
The baby, keep it.
I didn't want it to be known.
If Mom knows that--
We don't give a damn
about the family.
It's your life,
not theirs.
I love you, Sami.
I love you, my Sami.
I love you, Yas.
I love you.
They're coming.
Go away.
No, I won't let you down.
Go away, I said.
That son of a bitch
ratted on us.
I can't leave you.
No! No!
Yes. Go away.
Miss?
We have a few questions
to ask you.
No!
Miss, stop! Stop!
Shit!
Hit the gas!
What did you do,
God damn it?
He's dead!
Damn it!
Great, now your brother's
gonna rat on us.
He won't rat on us.
He's dead!
Please, I want
to go back home!
I'm done.
Please, I'll say nothing,
I swear.
We're gonna go
right to the end.
Things
are different now.
# Ooh #
# When you talk to me,
I'm liking it #
Okay,
that's my last joint.
Liar.
Okay, my second to last.
Third to last, maximum.
We're still in France here?
We're in the Middle Ages.
Seriously, we're better
in our high rises.
Have you ever been
out of the slum?
Yeah.
For my parents'
funerals in Blida.
But since then,
I kept to myself.
But I told myself,
next time I leave the slum,
that'll be it.
No one's waiting for me.
Not even a small slut?
You idiot.
Not even a small slut.
Why are you stopping?
Get out!
What?
Get out.
Why?
Get out!
Sorry, man, but I keep
the cash. Get out!
What?
Why are you
doing this to me?
I said get out.
I told you to get out,
okay? Get out!
You want me
to fuck you or what?
Damn it, you're hurting me.
I never betrayed you.
What did I say?
I told you to get out!
Last time I'm saying it
or I'll fuck you! Okay?
Okay, I'm getting out.
Leave me alone.
Hey, dude, I'm kidding.
Stop being such a wimp.
You bastard.
Man,
you really got scared?
Hey, you're a man.
[phone rings]
I pushed you a little,
and you're
acting like a wimp.
Hello.
Tom, it's me.
We're on the road.
No, no, it's okay. They said
he's gonna be all right.
You're together there?
We'll be
there in three hours.
See you then.
Why didn't you tell them?
It's going to be messy.
You're
not alone in this fuss.
We're all concerned,
so please make an effort.
Come on, load the joint well.
Make me a heavy one.
Don't worry, you bugger.
After that, I quit.
You quit?
Yeah, to please my mom.
It's time for me
to become a man.
I'm starting
to get tired.
Yeah, me, too.
What does the sign say?
There you go.
Great! There's always rooms
here. That's perfect.
[yawn]
You take the cash?
Hello?
Huh?
Hey, cool, man.
You're not in Paris here.
Okay, but take the cash.
Don't leave it here.
[laughing]
We're gonna do fine here.
Good evening, ladies.
Can we get a room?
Everything
is possible here.
All the rooms
are available.
Well,
it's our lucky day.
I don't know.
You have a lucky number?
2. We can do so many
things in twos.
You two?
Us three.
Huh?
I'll have to ask
for permission.
Goetz, we've got customers.
Are you insane?
She's hot, she's hot.
Goetz! Are you asleep
or what?
Goetz!
What's going on?
Do you know
if 2 is ready?
For how long?
For one night.
Go get a seat. Come on,
girls, take care of them.
Thanks.
Can I
offer you a drink?
With pleasure.
In all honesty, ladies,
I didn't know
that in coming here,
we would come upon
beauties like you.
You are really superb.
That's nice. Isn't it?
What do you think?
Drop it, Tom.
They're prick teases.
It's true.
It's a change.
Guys like you,
it's not every day.
Well, yeah, don't you
want a guy like me?
A real man.
You probably don't
see many in here.
Usually we have
truck drivers here.
You, you look sensitive.
He bangs anything
that moves.
Hey Farid, you're crazy.
Don't make me
look bad like that.
No, you're right, Gilberte.
I'm a sensitive guy.
Look, my sensitivity
is right here.
And it's there, too.
You look embarrassed.
Are you shy?
No, no,
I've got a girlfriend.
Hey, don't stop!
Go till the end.
Tom, take it easy because
tomorrow we have a long
Hey, virgin,
leave the adult working.
Well, well, well you're not
doing badly for yourselves!
At least you're not gay.
Gilberte, show them the room.
You'll be more comfortable.
Are you coming?
- Me?
You asked me to go
till the end, right?
Claudia,
take care of him.
You're not
going to stay alone?
No, no, I'm finishing
my drink peacefully,
then I'm gonna
call my girlfriend
because
she's probably worried.
You don't know
what you're missing.
Shit!
Small boobs. That's good.
I think I'm going to like it.
Come here, come here.
I'll take care of you.
Stop that. I've got
a girlfriend, damn it.
Hey, stop that.
I'm tired of that.
Hey, Tom, I'm gonna punch her.
You have a problem
or what?
Something wrong?
Let's say that I didn't think
we'd eat like a family,
but I'm all right.
- It's more cozy.
Give me your plates.
You'll tell me how it is.
It's going to perk you up!
That's good.
What is it exactly?
It's cooked in pork fat.
You won't be cold tonight!
It'll make you feel good.
You're a skinny guy, huh?
Yeah, but I don't eat pork.
It's not allowed
in my religion.
What do you mean?
Are you Jewish?
No, no, I'm Muslim,
but it's just that I don't
like pork, that's all.
Well, girls, give me a hand.
Open her mouth.
Make an effort!
Come on, Mom,
make an effort!
Come on!
Come on,
open your mouth!
Doing it on purpose or what?
Open your mouth!
I'm not doing it for you.
Oh come on!
Chew it! Bitch! Are you
doing it on purpose or what?
He's not hungry
anymore?
Neither of us is.
What the hell is that?
Come on Gil, let's go.
That's over the top.
Forget it. I have to
take care of Mom.
Plus, I'm not
in the mood anymore.
All right! Fine.
What's wrong?
You're not happy?
Family dinners
aren't my thing anyway.
But thanks, though,
and enjoy your meal.
Tom, don't go.
What's going on?
You were right, Farid.
They are whores.
No, no, sorry.
This is not what he meant.
He was kidding.
Damn it, are you nuts or what?
See how you talk?
What a bitch, damn it.
Especially after
how I banged her,
and then she's not
in the mood anymore.
I told you
they were whores.
It was too good
to be true.
I'm pissed off.
I'm so pissed off.
[phone rings]
Damn it, it's Yas.
She's going to kill me.
Answer, please,
because I can't.
Yeah!
Tom? Damn it,
what were you doing?
We've been trying to
find you for two hours.
Don't get mad.
What's up with you guys?
Tom, it's a mess.
It didn't go well
at the hospital.
Okay, okay.
Where are you guys?
We're in a hostel as planned.
I'll text you the address.
Don't say a word
to Farid, okay?
Okay, don't worry.
Hurry. Bye.
Dude, you look awful.
Is it because of that bitch?
No, I don't give a shit
about that whore.
I don't care, plus her pussy
doesn't smell good.
It's them.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Hello to all.
The interior minister
and future candidate
in the presidential election
spoke about the rioting
and decided to use security
as the major theme
of his campaign.
Meanwhile, the police stepped in
to contain the riots.
Look at this faggot.
What a piece of shit.
If I had him
in front of me,
I'd kill him
with my bare hands.
He's a murderer.
Fascist country.
I told you that France was
10 years behind the USA.
[knock on door]
Finally now we have
our George Bush.
You came to apologize?
No, someone wants
to see you.
Hi, good evening.
Good evening.
I think you know
why I'm here.
No, not at all.
Where do you come from?
From the Paris suburbs.
Gangsters? Car burners?
What are you doing here?
Integrating yourselves?
We're going to Holland
I'm not talking
to you, rag head.
So?
Well, he's telling the truth.
We're going to Amsterdam
to visit some friends,
that's it.
Right.
Getting stoned,
banging some whores.
And you started it here.
Maybe it looks like a brothel.
Hold on, sir.
First, they hit on us.
Second, we're human--
You're saying that
my sisters are whores?
No, no.
Did you enjoy it,
at least?
What?
I asked you if you enjoyed it.
- Ohh!
It's not complicated,
damn it.
Did you enjoy it?
Yeah, yeah.
Hands on your head!
Come on!
What did we do?
Gil told me you have
a bag full of cash.
That's bullshit.
Yeah, bullshit.
Yes, it's here.
Gilberte, what are you
talking about?
It's just
some dirty laundry.
You can check it yourself.
Goetz! Goetz! Goetz!
Go away! Hurry!
Don't move or I'll kill you!
Stop it! Stop it, damn it!
Stop it!
- Aah!
I'm getting ready!
Hurry up!
Tom, my brother.
Don't move, I said!
Tom.
Goetz! You didn't kill him.
Go catch them! Hurry!
Raah!
Hurry! Move, damn it!
Start it!
Start it, damn it!
Bastard!
Faster, damn it! Faster!
Damn it! Hit the gas!
Go straight!
I'll get you little faggots!
Come on!
We're going to die!
We're going to die, damn it!
No!
[Alex]
Which road?
[Yasmine]
Turn left.
So?
They fell in the pit
of the old mine.
Take this. I found that.
Klaudia!
Farid, help me.
Farid, come help me.
Farid, please, I'm in pain.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Careful.
Where are we?
You're all right?
Good evening.
- Good evening.
We're here to see
some friends who came here.
You are the friends
of Tom and Farid.
You know them?
Yeah, they're very nice.
They went to the cottage
not too far from here.
Why didn't they
stay here?
The hostel is full.
Can you tell us
which road to take?
I can take you.
I was going to go there.
Klaudia, you come with us.
We need you.
Come this way.
Did you see
how she talks to me?
I can't take her
anymore.
Klaudia,
do what Gilberte says.
I'm not her dog!
Well, make an effort!
You're going to
replace her soon.
Karl? Karl! Damn it!
Goetz.
Yeah.
I'm closing the road.
Come back quickly.
Father doesn't like to wait.
Damn! It smells like death.
Did you shit on yourself?
It's here. That smell
is coming from here.
You know what to do.
We have to get out of here.
What the hell is that?
You think we can fit?
You go first.
I'll push you, okay?
Let's go.
1, 2, 3! Come on.
Is it okay?
Damn it!
What's in there?
I see some light.
Be careful, I'm coming.
Do you hear me?
Come on! Come on!
Come on! Push!
Come on! Let's go.
Go on, push.
I can't breathe.
Me, neither.
I can't breathe, but keep going.
I can't breathe!
Tom! Come on!
Tom, come on! Keep moving.
Come on, dude.
I'm blocked!
Come on,
you're almost there.
I'm blocked!
I can't do it anymore.
Me, neither, but come on,
God damn it, move!
I'm blocked, I said!
I'm blocked, damn it!
[sobbing]
Asshole.
Come on!
We're dead.
I'm going to die, Mama. Mama.
Come on, Tom, dude,
you're almost there.
Push!
No!
[sobbing]
I can't!
Come on, you're a man,
damn it!
But I'm blocked, damn it!
You're a faggot!
Come on, move it!
Shut up!
Move!
- Shut the fuck up!
Move, you damn bastard!
Shut the fuck up, damn it!
Come on!
Move, move, move, come on!
Move your ass!
Come on, come on!
Come on, Tom!
Turn right. It's
at the end of the road.
Where are we?
We're on an old mine site,
closed since the beginning
of the century.
Take your time.
I'm going to warn them
you're here.
Stop it!
Be careful,
she's very shy.
Good evening.
Have a seat.
Thank you very much.
Klaudia, go boil
some water, please.
It's for hunting. There's
a lot of game around here.
Where are you going?
We're going to Holland.
Some business
to take care of there.
Excuse me, can I go
the bathroom, please?
Well, sure.
Follow me.
Are you guys married?
No, we're not together
anymore.
It's the small door
right there.
Are you hungry?
Want something?
No, thank you, I'm fine.
Shut your mouth!
He's coming.
Klaudia, come with me.
Who's coming?
Father.
Sit up straight. He doesn't
like when we're slumped.
Welcome to our place,
young lady.
What's your name?
Yasmine.
Your hand.
Leave.
Tom.
Alex, get out of here.
Go away.
Get out of here.
Something's wrong?
- We're getting out of here.
What?
- Get up! We're getting out of here!
Stop it!
- Get up. We're leaving.
What's going on?
Everything's okay.
Stop lying to us!
Our friend is dying!
[Yasmine]
Stop it!
- Come!
Karl!
Hang them up!
And skim the fat off of them!
Listen to me.
We need to renew
the family's blood.
But I'm hesitating.
They're young.
Look at her skin...
[Yasmine wailing]
Her hair...
Aah!
her eyes.
She's not pure...
but we don't have
any choice.
You need a wife
to take over for me.
She'll be yours.
Remember, faithfulness.
Gut him.
I'll come carve him later.
I'm going to see
what's going on.
It's the children.
The children
are in the storeroom.
They probably
smelled the meat.
We already asked you
to take care of that.
I'm coming with you.
Klaudia, it's all right.
Hold it!
Freeze!
Stop! Stop!
Keep going towards
the steam rooms!
Are you here,
my little rag head?
Son of a bitch! He's here,
the little rag head!
Die! You bastard!
I can't do it, Alex.
Yas.
Go get the cops.
Go get the cops!
- No!
Come on!
Don't stop!
Hey! Open it!
Open the door, damn it!
What are you doing?
Go away!
Come on! Go!
I love you. I love you.
Go. Go!
Get out of here! Go away!
I said get out of here!
Go away!
Come on! Hurry!
It's clear.
You can go. Hurry up!
Come on! Come on!
Move! Get out of here!
Come on!
No! Open it!
Damn it, open the door!
Open it! Open it, God damn it!
Open it! Open it! Open it!
Get lost! Get lost! Damn it!
Where is she?
In your ass,
you dirty Nazi!
The tongs!
Go get me the tongs!
No! What are going to do?
Small precaution to be sure
you won't run away.
[groaning]
No, no!
- Hold him.
In Africa--
Aah!
...the owners of diamond mines
use this method
to keep the workers
from running away.
Aah!
Ha ha!
They cut their Achilles tendon
just like that.
Just like that.
Aah!
Like that.
[wailing]
Then the slaves could
keep working in peace.
The workers!
Stop, Stop!
Please,
help me get the police.
Get in. I'll help you.
You're making a U-Turn?
No. I'm taking you
back home.
No! No! No!
Quiet!
Aah! Aah!
Are you going
to shut the fuck up?
Aah!
Shut the fuck up!
No.
One last wish?
Just one.
Kill me!
You son of a bitch!
Garbage can.
Spirit is a bone.
Come on! Hans,
to the preserving room.
Uncuff her!
She's pregnant.
That's wonderful.
Just few days to wait.
Soon you'll be family.
You'll
sleep in my bedroom
while we're
preparing one for you.
Okay?
You're so cold. Hold on.
I have a little secret
to warm you up.
We are the same,
you and I.
Father is really happy
since I told him
Drink.
It'll make you
feel better.
Drink.
It helps me
to make babies.
One more.
It's strong,
isn't it?
Here.
One more, quickly.
No. In your condition,
it's not good.
It's beautiful.
I'm gonna
have to cut it.
Father doesn't like
black hair.
Father says we belong
to the perfect race.
He came to live here
after the big war.
Me? They took me from my
parents when I was a child.
They raised me here,
telling me that one day
my parents would
come looking for me
if I was smart
and did what they said.
Father wanted to me
to grow up quick
so I could give him an heir.
Then came providence,
but our children
were born with problems.
They're not normal.
I'm expecting my fourth.
Father says it's because
of the blood.
Why are you staying here?
Because I'm waiting for my
parents to come get me.
They promised. I know one day
they will come to get me.
We can't abandon
our children like that.
I know what I'm talking about.
I love mine.
When they were born,
Father wanted
to get rid of them.
So Hans and I, we hide them.
Now they live in the mine.
When I have time,
I try to go see them.
Without them, I think
I'd be dead in here.
Here's our guest.
Please, have a seat.
Sit down!
In tribute
to the new mother
of our beloved
and beautiful family,
and to the coming
of future events:
A birth.
If it's a girl,
we'll call her Lili.
If it's a boy, we'll call
him Karl, like his father.
We'll unite and bind him
to our dear and beautiful
guest, Yasmina...
so that this year will be
bountiful and propitious
of great new developments.
We can already hear
the wind of victory.
Also, I want to tell you
that I have decided
to turn over the leadership
of the family...
to the only son I'm proud of:
Karl Von Geisler.
Stand up, please.
Thank you, Father.
You honor me.
From now on,
you'll have to obey,
in word and deed,
the sole authority
of your brother.
My son, Karl,
with the support of
my beloved daughter...
Gilberte.
That goes for you too,
Hans Vonflaak.
I think you knew
each other, didn't you?
You're insane.
Maybe,
but probably you as well.
Gilberte,
my beloved daughter,
should have
explained to you
what am I expecting
from you, right?
When they told me
you were
expecting a baby,
I took it as an omen.
So he will
be the missing link
of a pure race.
He'll be nothing.
What?
You've got to be more
respectful.
You've got to be
obedient to Father.
I'm not obedient!
I never will be!
Well, he has
a lot of authority,
our new little boss.
Goetz!
Karl!
Make her stand next to you.
Stand up!
Now,
Kiss each other to seal your
union to our new family...
and put an end
to useless quarrels.
To pure blood!
Get off me!
Let him go!
- Let him go!
If someone moves,
I'll cut his throat!
You! Open the door!
Hurry! Drop it!
Let him go! I won't hesitate
to kill you, little sister!
Come over here and I'll
bleed him like a pig!
Hans! Drop your gun!
Listen to me!
What are you doing, Hans?
Hans! Move your ass!
Hans! You bastard!
Drop your gun!
Drop it! I swear
I'm going to kill him!
Hans!
Listen to them for once!
That's an order!
I won't miss the bitch,
or you, either!
Stop, Hans!
Hans!
Hans, no, no, no!
Kill her!
Karl! Follow me!
No! Hans, no, no!
You get her from the rear!
You take the main entrance!
Hey. Get out of here.
I said get lost!
You belong to me, little slut.
You belong to me,
little bitch.
Little bitch,
you deserve this.
You want to punch me?
You want to kick my ass?
Come here!
Why do you want to hit me?
Is it because you're afraid
of the little boss, huh?
Is that why? You decide now?
Here's your little boss.
Are you in pain?
That hurts, huh?
No!
You like that, huh?
Want more?
Look at your little face.
Your little slutty face.
Where are you going?
People listen to me
when I speak!
What's Father thinking?
What's he gonna do, huh?
What's he gonna do?
I'm the one in charge!
I'm the boss!
I'm the one in charge here!
Do you understand?
What's Father thinking?
He's the one who decides?
My ass! I'm the boss!
I'm the boss! People have
to explain themselves to me!
Look at me when I'm talking
to you, you little slut!
Look at me!
Dirty slut!
Drop that! Do you understand?
I said drop it!
Farewell!
I came to help you!
Come with me.
No, I can't abandon
my children.
Come on! Hurry up!
They're looking for you
I'll tell them
I didn't see you. Go!
Come on! Go!
Klaudia! She's right here.
Klaudia! Together!
Stop it! Stop it!
It's over?
Is it over?
Don't move!
Gil! I'm begging you,
stop it!
Get lost!
Stop it! Stop it!
Move away!
Get lost, damn it!
Stop it!
Come here, bitch!
On your knees!
Gilberte! Stop it!
You're dead!
No!
Come with me!
No, I've got my children.
[crying]
[Man on radio] ...after the riot
protesting the results
of the second round
of the presidential election,
an attack against
the elected candidate
of the extreme right
was foiled.
Last night, after the
announcement of the results,
riots broke out...
Aah!
[Female singer]
# Loving your dream #
# Carrying your pain #
# Watching me slowly
going to my grave #
# Didn't know you #
# Sipping a drug
in a glass of milk #
# Injecting fears
in my pretty little veins #
# Didn't know you #
# Talking nonsense to me #
# Wish I could believe #
# Leaving me unattended #
# So little love to give #
[Male singer]
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You make me cruel,
but I'm not a failure #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# I beg you now
'cause I'm not a killer #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# Just spill my blood
'cause I'm just a dreamer #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You make me cry,
it will soon be over #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You make me cruel,
but I'm not a failure #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You make me cry,
it will soon be over #
# Farting in your dreams #
# Driven by your head #
# Faking to be him #
# Laughing at my bed #
# We have just arrived #
# With the love we've made #
# Sifting
through your light #
# Dear, it feels strange #
# What's come into my head #
# Oh-uh, oh-uh, oh-uh, oh #
# Ayeh, ai, ah, ow #
# Ayeh, ayeh, ah, ow #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You make me cruel,
but I'm not a failure #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# I beg you now
'cause I'm not a killer #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You spill my blood
'cause I'm just a dreamer #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You make me cry,
it will soon be over #
# Be over #
[Female singer]
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# I beg you now
'cause I'm not a killer #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You spill my blood
'cause I'm just a dreamer #
# Kill me, I'm a monster #
# You make me cry,
it will soon be over #
Subtitles by LeapinLar