[PIETRO MASCAGNI'S "TU QUI SANTUZZl"
PLAYS ON CAR STEREO]
WOMAN:
Björling.
Suliotis?
MAN:
Close.
Björling is easy.
WOMAN:
Tebaldi.
MAN: You win.
WOMAN: My turn.
[MUSIC STOPS]
- No looking.
GEORGE: I'm not.
ANN:
Did Daddy look?
GEORGIE:
No.
ANN:
You sure?
GEORGIE: Yes.
ANN: Okay.
[HANDEL'S "CARE SELVE,
OMBRE BEATE" PLAYS]
GEORGE:
Oh, God.
Gigli?
ANN:
Of course, but what?
Well? Darling?
GEORGE:
I'd say Handel.
ANN:
Right. But what is it?
GEORGE:
Not a clue.
ANN: Well?
GEORGE: I give up. What is it?
ANN:
Three-two to me.
Hey, hands off.
Hey, no. Just... Just listen.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[HORN HONKING]
Hey! That's not fair.
FRED:
What?
ANN:
Practicing's not fair.
You're still on for 10 tomorrow, right?
You're still coming?
FRED:
Uh, yeah, sure.
We have to launch the boat.
Can you give us a hand,
in about 20 minutes?
FRED: Yeah, sure. Yeah, I'll be there.
I'll come over in 20 minutes.
Okay, great. See you then.
Bye!
[MOZART'S "QUINTETTE FOR CLARINETTE,
VIOLINS, VIOLA & VIOLINCELLO" PLAYS]
What was up with him?
Don't know.
Seems weird.
She didn't say a word.
Who did you talk to
about the game tomorrow?
With her.
- When?
- Day before yesterday.
- And?
- Nothing, she was fine.
GEORGIE:
Where's Jenny?
ANN: I don't know, sweetheart.
Maybe she's at the beach or inside.
- Who were those guys?
- Don't know.
Maybe relatives.
Doesn't her brother have a son that age?
[DOOR OPENING]
ANN: Don't put that there.
Take your stuff upstairs, please.
GEORGIE:
Yeah.
ANN: Keep the doorway clear
or someone's gonna trip.
We have a lot more in the car.
Hey, are you listening to me?
GEORGIE:
I'm going, already.
ANN: Open the windows, please.
We need to let some air in.
GEORGIE:
Yeah, Mom.
[LUCKY BARKING]
Get out, Lucky. Out.
Come on, get down.
Come on.
ANN: George?
GEORGE: Yeah?
ANN:
Where are the other groceries?
GEORGE:
I'll get it.
Golf clubs were in the way.
ANN:
Hurry up, everything's getting warm.
This cooler's a piece of shit.
GEORGE:
Stop it, buddy.
You'll knock me over.
Go to Mommy, go on, go to Mommy.
She'll give you a treat.
ANN: The meat's in the other box.
Will you grab it for me?
GEORGE:
I'm just opening the windows.
ANN: Leave the shutters in the front,
it'll get too hot.
Lucky, come on. Honey, get out.
Will you...? Come on,
I'll get you something in a minute.
Lucky, please.
Will you call the dog, honey?
Lucky, get out of here.
- Call the dog.
GEORGE: Lucky.
ANN:
Go on, honey.
GEORGE:
Come here, come to Daddy.
[LUCKY BARKING]
GEORGE:
Stop it, Lucky. Be quiet.
I'm sorry. He's...
He's nuts. Come in.
Hey there, Fred. Good to see you.
Thanks for helping.
It'd be pretty hard on my own.
No problem. This is Paul.
- Pleasure to meet you.
- Pleasure.
Paul's father
is a business associate of mine.
Thanks for helping.
No, the pleasure's all mine.
Not so much his.
ANN: Lucky, come on.
- Sorry, he's crazy.
Stop it!
ANN: Hey! Come over here!
- Thank you, honey.
So when did you get here?
- Last week.
- You too?
- No.
- Yes.
Well, they didn't get here till
the weekend. We got here on Friday.
ANN:
Hi, Fred. Thanks for coming right over.
It's good to see you. How's Eve?
Fine.
- Hello.
- Pleasure to meet you, ma'am.
GEORGIE: And where are the Keys?
GEORGE: Got it?
GEORGE:
On the southern coast of Florida.
GEORGIE: Isn't it hotter down there?
GEORGE: No.
GEORGE:
Push.
It ain't all the time.
Last year when I was in Miami
it rained cats and dogs the whole time.
And you were up here and you were
swimming every day, remember?
Still, it sucks that Jenny isn't here.
It's boring without...
Careful.
I am being careful.
That was an expensive overhaul.
GEORGIE:
See? Not a single scratch.
Well, now you can help me
put up the boom.
You got it?
Yeah.
- Put it down over there.
- Okay.
But she told me
she'd be here the whole time.
GEORGE: Yeah, well, I don't know either.
I don't know why she told you that.
Maybe she went out with a friend.
We'll ask her mother tomorrow
when we see her.
Anyway,
forecast for tomorrow is wind.
Why was Uncle Fred
behaving so strangely?
ANN:
Well, I'm not surprised.
She got pretty worked up about it
last time.
Come on, just forget about it.
She's not gonna change.
Yeah, well,
you're only gonna upset yourself.
Exactly. That's what I'm saying.
Oh, they're great.
They're outside playing on the boat.
Uh...
I don't know, 5, 5:30.
My kitchen clock's not working,
so I have to get that fixed on Monday.
Yeah, exactly,
that's what I'm doing right now.
We're having steak.
It all defrosted,
so now I have to get rid of it.
You should come on out.
Yeah, that was stupid of me.
I froze 4 pounds of steak...
...now I'm standing here
looking at half a cow.
I'm not joking. Come on out, please,
just for the weekend.
Well, tell him not to be so difficult.
Hold on a second.
- What is it, honey?
- We need a sharp knife.
Okay.
- I'd like to see it again.
- Okay.
- Tell your father.
So, what do you think?
Well, tell your sweetheart
to bring his laptop with him.
Jump in the car,
and you'll be here in an hour.
Well, he shouldn't be so antisocial.
Come on, we've got enough steak
for the whole week.
What is it? Hold on. Okay.
All right. Well, listen, just call me
and let me know, all right?
Okay, all right, Nancy.
NANCY [OVER PHONE]: Bye.
- Bye.
What now, honey?
- There's someone here.
- Where?
At the door.
ANN: Hello.
- Hello.
Sorry to disturb you, I'm staying
next door. I saw you earlier at the gate.
Oh, yeah, of course.
Please, come in.
So how can I help you?
Tell your dad we're eating
in 10 minutes.
GEORGIE:
Okay.
PETER:
Well, Eve s...
I mean, Mrs. Thompson sent me.
She's cooking and she ran out of eggs
and asked if you could help her out.
Of course. How many does she need?
Four.
ANN:
Four?
What for?
- Excuse me?
- What for?
What does she need the eggs for?
I mean, what's she cooking?
I have no idea.
So are they okay just like this
or do you need the carton?
Whatever you want.
How did you get in here?
Down there.
I mean, down by the water.
But you're not wet.
There's a hole in the fence.
By the water, not in the water.
Fred sh... I mean, Mr. Thompson,
knows about it. He showed it to me.
Oh, I see.
So you sure they're okay like this?
Yeah, yeah. That's okay. No problem.
- Thank you very much. Thank you.
- All right.
Say hello to Eve. Tell her we're
looking forward to the game tomorrow.
I'll tell her. Thanks again.
ANN:
Thanks to Fred and your friend for help...
PETER: Shit.
- What happened?
It's not a disaster.
We have to go grocery shopping
on Monday anyway.
PETER:
I'm really sorry.
ANN: It's not so bad. None of us eat eggs
for breakfast anyway.
So the disaster's under control.
PETER: Well, thank you. I'm sorry,
I should have paid more attention.
ANN: Well, you shouldn't cry
over spilt milk, right?
PETER:
You're really nice.
ANN:
You do what you can.
I really am sorry.
I'm very clumsy, you know?
I think I have two left hands.
- Then you're the man for carrying eggs.
- Yes, you could say that.
So, what are we going to do now?
Well, we have a lot of steak,
but we might be expecting guests...
...and they definitely eat eggs
for breakfast.
You'll still have four left.
It's a box with a dozen, isn't it?
Or am I mistaken?
No, you're not mistaken.
So would you like the carton this time?
- It's not necessary.
- Are you sure?
But if you insist.
If I insist?
Well, it might be better, I guess.
- Oh, God.
- What?
Oh, no.
I'm sorry.
Before you destroy
the rest of the kitchen...
...maybe you should take the eggs
and leave. All right?
Yes.
No carton?
[LUCKY BARKING]
I'm really sorry. Honestly.
Me too.
Here you go.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
I'll tell Mrs. Thompson
how nice you were.
ANN:
Do what you have to do.
PETER:
Have a nice day.
[LAUGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO]
[LUCKY BARKING]
PAUL:
Excuse me?
ANN: Lucky. Lucky. Get down.
Come on, come on, stop that.
Get out of here. Go on, get lost.
I'm sorry. He's completely harmless.
He just wants to play.
That's a strange way to play.
- Did he hurt you?
- Peter is afraid of dogs.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Me too. He jumped on me.
- I'm really sorry.
- Yeah.
- Should I lock him up so you can leave?
- That won't be necessary.
- I can call my husband.
- It's not gonna be necessary.
It's my fault.
I completely forgot about the dog.
I should've come myself and...
Wow.
That's a really great set of clubs.
It's Callaway, right?
Awesome.
These are wonderful. May I?
I guess we don't
stand a chance tomorrow, do we?
The club doesn't make the player.
That's true.
Would you mind if I tried this?
Just once, please? Real quick.
Outside. Please? Yes?
I'll hit it towards the bay. Yes?
If it makes you happy.
Thank you.
Thanks a lot. Really.
Excuse me.
He loves golf. We both do.
- Excuse me?
- We both do. We both love golf.
[LUCKY BARKING]
Lucky!
Lucky. Be quiet.
- What's the matter with him?
GEORGE: I don't know.
It's probably too hot for him too.
[LUCKY BARKING HOARSELY]
[BARKING STOPS]
I'll take a look.
PAUL: It's wonderful. It really
makes a difference, like night and day.
Thanks a lot.
Sure.
GEORGE:
Lucky!
PAUL: Where's Tom?
- Who?
PAUL:
Did you give him the eggs?
Excuse me?
Driver's really first class.
You have to try it.
Listen, young man, I don't know
what kind of game you're playing...
...but I don't wanna be a part of it.
Would you please leave now?
What game?
I'm sorry, ma'am, but I don't understand
why you're suddenly being so unfriendly.
- Did Tom or I do anything to upset you?
ANN: Please leave.
Did you misbehave while I was outside?
Was he rude?
- Did he say something that...?
- Stop it.
I've asked you nicely to leave.
Now I'd like you to go.
Well...
I don't understand what's upset you,
but if you insist.
Just give Tom the eggs,
and we won't bother you anymore.
Excuse me?
We'll have to tell Eve and Fred. Nothing
like this has happened to me before.
What about you?
- Can you just give us the eggs, please?
- No.
How dare you.
Please just go. Right now.
Did I do something wrong?
I asked you to leave. I want you to go.
GEORGE:
Have you seen the dog? Is he with you?
- Will you throw them out?
- It's good you're here, Mr. Farber.
- That's your name, isn't it? Farber?
- Yes.
Yeah, Fre... Mr. Thompson told us.
- What's going on?
- I want them to leave.
Your wife's under the wrong impression.
I'm happy you're here.
I'm certain you can
figure out this misunderstanding.
- George, please.
- Dad, I can't...
Just go. Please, go.
Hey, Ann.
This is ridiculous. I can't believe this.
- Honey, do you mind?
- No, he's fine.
- May I please explain what happened?
- Please do.
Mrs. Thompson sent me over
to ask for some eggs, and then...
Your wife gave Peter the eggs,
but, unfortunately, they broke.
And then she gave me
another four eggs...
...but the dog jumped on me,
and now...
You had a dozen and you're going
shopping on Monday anyway.
We just want the eggs, that's all.
Ann, can you tell me
what's going on here?
Honey, can you just tell
me what's going on?
Just give them to them.
- Can I have them now?
- Hold on a moment.
Ann, if it's just about some eggs,
why are you so angry?
ANN: Look, I'm not going
to justify myself in front...
I asked you to throw them out.
Maybe I have my reasons.
Do what you want. I've had enough.
Ann.
I'm sorry.
My wife's not feeling well, so...
Yeah.
Could you please leave?
I can hardly play the mediator
if I don't know the facts, now, can I?
So could you just leave, please?
Please, the...
- What?
- Just give them to him.
- What the hell is going on here?
- Nothing's going on, sir.
He asked for the eggs,
the dog attacked him, they broke.
Now he would like some more.
What is so difficult to understand?
You better watch your tone,
young man.
You better be careful, old man,
or I'll break your eggs.
Now, please leave, right now.
PAUL: Mr. Farber?
- What?
[YELLS]
GEORGIE:
Dad!
PETER:
Is it broken?
Hey, hey, come on, come on,
come on.
Hey. Come on. Behave yourself.
Behave yourself, okay?
Okay? I don't want to hurt you...
...so you have to behave yourself.
GEORGIE: Mom.
- What is it, baby?
PETER: Please, just, ma'am,
stay where you are, okay?
Please, stay.
- He slapped me in the face.
- Yeah, he started it.
PETER: You can help him,
just don't do anything stupid. Help him.
- You should bring him a chair.
ANN: What happened?
It's my knee.
PETER: You should take off his pants.
He should sit. Bring him a chair.
Go get him a chair, honey.
Be careful.
PAUL: Peter is a... He's a medical student.
He can help you with it.
PETER:
Can you please take off your pants?
If you don't let me see
your wound, I can't help you.
I'm sorry I hurt you,
but you forced me to, you must admit.
PAUL: Come on, Mr. Farber,
be reasonable. Let him look at your leg.
He can help you with it.
Would you please...
...leave?
Please.
PETER:
We won't get anywhere like this.
PAUL: You have to let him help you,
you don't really have a choice.
You're the ship's captain, sir.
You're aware that onboard,
the captain's word is law, aren't you?
So, what do you want to do?
You want to call someone?
An ambulance or the police?
I won't stop you.
Neither will Tom. Right, Tom?
Well, what are you waiting for?
He dropped the cell phone in the sink.
- Why are you doing this?
PETER: Why not?
Okay, let's play another game.
It's a guessing game.
What is this?
Sir?
It's a golf ball.
Correct. It's a golf ball.
But why do I have it in my pocket?
Hm? The lady knows why.
Because?
Well?
Because you didn't hit it.
Correct. Because I didn't hit it.
And why didn't I hit it?
Because something stopped you.
Correct. Because I had
to test the club in another way.
Where is he?
PAUL:
Cold.
Even colder.
Ice cold.
Warmer.
Little cold.
Cold.
Warmer.
Warm, cold.
Really warm.
Would you please go to the kitchen
and get me something to eat?
That be possible?
Maybe there's some bananas or...
Please don't think about bringing back
a knife or anything like that...
...or I'd be sorry.
For you, I mean.
It's getting cloudy.
That's very nice of you, thank you.
MAN:
Hello?
WOMAN:
MAN:
Hello?
ANN:
Yeah!
Hello!
WOMAN:
Hi, sweetie.
Where are you?
Come on down to the water.
We're both thinking the same thing,
aren't we?
Hm?
We saw your boat.
ANN:
Hi, Betsy.
Hi, Robert.
When did you get here?
ANN:
Today.
We're still unpacking.
How long you staying?
ANN: Probably a week or two.
We're not sure yet.
Oh, wonderful. So nice to see you.
ANN: Let me help you.
BETSY: Thank you.
- Have you ever met my sister-in-law?
ANN: No.
Pleased to meet you.
Hello, nice to meet you too.
Hello. Hi, Robert.
ROBERT: Hi, how are you?
ANN: Fine.
This is Paul. He's staying
with the Thompsons next door.
- Hi, pleased to meet you.
- Hi, Paul. You cold?
- Oh, no, I have... I have eczema.
- Oh.
You should go swimming,
the water works wonders for that here.
Thank you, that's good advice.
- Hello, pleased to meet you.
- Hello.
How's George?
Fine, thanks.
Where is he?
He pulled a muscle putting up the mast,
so he's lying down, resting.
BETSY: So sorry to hear that. That's what
happens when you try to do too much.
Robert, on the other hand,
would never dream of launching a boat.
Right, Robert?
Tell your hubby to get better,
we're grilling every night.
ANN:
I'll tell him.
I mean it, as soon as he's better,
swing by. Robert's son is here.
He brought his little girlfriend.
He'd like her for sure.
All right. Well, listen,
it's great to see you, darling.
Listen, if the weather stays like this,
you'll probably have to take the car.
- It's supposed to be windy.
- For tomorrow...
PAUL: Where's your dock?
- Excuse me?
PAUL:
Your dock?
Oh, it's just around the peninsula,
but on the other side.
The old cottage, with the red dock?
BETSY:
Right.
It's very beautiful.
Well, thank you, we enjoy it.
Well, anyway, it's good to see you.
All right, goodbye.
So you're here all week?
BETSY:
Well, this week for sure.
Maybe we'll come by tonight.
BETSY:
Oh, do, you know we love seeing you.
ANN: All right.
We'll see how George is doing.
Yeah, see how he is.
Bye-bye.
- Bye.
They'll be here in two hours...
...and then this little charade of yours
will be over.
PETER:
Sorry, but that's not exactly true.
Didn't you ask your friends to call
and confirm...
...or did I misunderstand something?
They'll come,
even if they can't reach us.
PAUL:
Is lying allowed?
Just a second.
Wait, let me move this out of the way.
PETER: Why don't you have a landline?
Don't you find it convenient?
Or is it
that you aren't out here that much?
Please, have a seat.
You know you can be completely
open with us. You'd feel better.
We're being completely open with you.
ANN:
Right there.
PETER:
You should put a pillow under him.
PAUL: You know, if you'd let Peter
help you, it would hurt less.
PETER: I'm happy to help, really,
I just don't want to impose.
PAUL:
Careful with...
That's a good idea, put it up.
That should be more comfortable.
PETER:
So there we are.
- You sure you don't wanna put a pillow...?
- Could you please stop this?
You're asking?
ANN:
What?
You said, "Please."
I'm very happy about this.
It's easier when things are polite.
I'd like to apologize for before.
But you have to admit, George,
the slap in the face?
It really wasn't
the most appropriate reaction.
I'm Paul.
This is Peter.
Come here, Tom. Where are
your manners? Shake the man's hand.
ANN:
Here, take this for the pain.
PAUL: What's this now?
What, are we shit to you?
[GEORGE YELLING]
What, didn't we just agree that?
Jesus Christ!
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
It's okay. It's okay.
[CLATTERING]
PETER: Stop it now,
otherwise your mother will get hurt.
Stop it! Do you understand?
Do you understand?!
[GEORGIE CRYING]
Calm down.
So much stress for politeness' sake.
[CLEARS THROAT]