Some people say, this world is ugly
yet, it is beautiful at the same time
I don't know if they are right
But
I'm about to see the world with fresh eyes
Wong Kar Mun
I'm giving you a local anesthetic now
The operation will take about 2 hours
Are you ready?
Who's that?
Quiet! We don't want to alarm the nurses
I am in the bed next to yours
I heard that you just had an eye operation
I've had many operations here
I know the whole hospital. They are all nice to me
How old are you?
Why so many operations?
I'm 11. l should have been in junior high by now
but my mother says I have a brain tumor
which affects my nerves
That's why l pass out all the time
They have to remove it
But it's so large and dangerous
they have to operate many times
So l skipped school last year
and stayed here ever since
You're so young, yet so brave!
Once you can see again
l'll take you out to play
The world is really beautiful.
Wong Kar Mun
when l remove the bandages from your eyes
it might hurt a little at first
lf it hurts too much, let me know
We can always do it tomorrow
Now, let's try.
Open your eyes slowly
Hey, don't force yourself if it hurts
lt hurts!
ls it too painful?
Dr Lo, she must be in a lot of pain!
She hasn't cried out
in pain ever since she was a kid!
Grandma, let Dr Lo do his job
Please don't worry about it.
Very few patients experience immediate success
lt takes time...
...for the eye and brain to worktogether
Come on
Ying Ying
Hi, can you see now?
I'm Ying Ying
Can you really see me?
l think l can see. I'm not sure
Great! You can see!
Nurse, she can see!
Nurse
her eyes are working!
She sees me! Come quick
Grandma!
The hospital called!
What?
Mun can see!
Really?
Let's go to the hospital now
Are you going to discharge me now?
Not so soon
Every cornea recipient starts off near-sighted...
by as much as 1,000 degrees
Only when your eye muscles are able to adapt
will this falls to about 200 degrees
When will she have perfect eyesight then?
No one has perfect eyesight,
most people are near-sighted by about 100 degrees
Does that mean...
...she will need to wear glasses?
That won't be necessary
All she needs
for the moment is a pair of sunglasses.
Mun, get some rest
lf everything goes well, you can be released early
You can take off your sunglasses now
Try to get used to the light gradually
lf you feel pain
or if your eyes start watering
then you should close your eyes
and let your eyes rest
Here, l'll help you onto bed
Nurse
ls there a mirror in every washroom?
l'll take you there
Here
Slowly
Take your time and call me if you need anything
Who's that?
Ying Ying, is that you?
Why are you so quiet?
I'm having another operation tomorrow
You promised to take me out once l can see
You promised to take me out...
...once l can see
We'll go out and have fun...
...after your operation
Did they say you can leave the hospital already?
Not yet!
But even if l do, l can always drop by for a visit
Let's take a picture together.
Let's do it outside! Alright
Let's go... But where?
Let's go that way!
What's this?
A camera
Camera?
Now, look this way
Ok
Ready...1, 2, 3!
Madam, are you alright?
Hello...
I'm freezing...
Send this one to Block C
We have a full house in Block B
Nurse...
did the old lady pass away?
Yes, we've taken her away
But last night...
l saw someone drop by to visit her
They even went out together
Are you sure?
We don't allow any visitors here at night
Where's Ying Ying?
She went for an operation this morning
Dr. Lo preferred that
you stay for two more days...
but because
l'll be away on flight duty for two weeks
No one will be able to pick you up then
lt was easier to have you discharged now.
This way
you and grandma can spend more time together.
My...it's already 3 p.m.!
Hope this place is easy to find...
...hope we won't be too late
We're only 10 minutes late for our appointment
I have to leave for work soon
I'm sorry.
Dr Lo just stepped out for a few minutes
Ok
There he is
Is my 3 o'clock here?
Yes, they are
Mun, let's go
Let me introduce you to the nature of my work.
From now on
I am Ms Wong Kar Mun's psychotherapist
Since Ms Wong lost her sight at the age of two
Her visual vocabulary
is extremely limited
and she has probably forgotten most of that
Lets' say
Ms Wong, could you please remove your glasses?
and let your eyes get used to the light
Can you tell me what's in my hand?
You'll recognize that it's a stapler...
...once you touch it
because all your previous knowledge of objects
were based on touch, not on sight
Now you are no longer blind
My job is
help you re-establish
howto use your eyes
and understand what you see
Actually, I'm not too worried about that aspect
What concerns me is your psychological state
After regaining sight...
many patients end up feeling alienated and fearful
Dr. Lo
ls the other Dr Lo a relative of yours?
You mean Dr C.T.Lo?
Yes, he's my uncle
So...what time do you finish worktoday?
Ms Wong is my last patient for the day
Well...you see, l need to catch my flight
Can l trouble you to send Mun home after this?
l see, of course
AnyAfter all, starting from today...
l need to take
Ms Wong outdoors for her training anyway.
OK
You can go ahead
I'm fine by myself
I'm used to it
That's you as a little girl
Your father filmed this a long time ago...
so that you could see it if your eyes ever healed
He stopped filming after he divorced your mother
That was 7 or 8 years ago
Grandma...
ls it true when Dad comes back
he'll take us to Vancouver?
l know you don't want to go,
but life in Vancouver moves at a slower pace
lt will be better for you
l can't even read Chinese
how will l learn English?
Grandma
l don't want to rely on others forever
l want to learn to write
and find a job in Hong Kong
l want to be independent
Your father would worry about you going to work.
I have to do the dishes
l'll leave you to watch this alone
Can l help you?
Have you seen my report card?
No
Do your live around here?
Mun, who's that?
lt's a little boy, Grandma
Did a report card ever turn up on our balcony?
That kid is teasing you
Just ignore him
Kid, what are you eating?
I'm very hungry
What's your problem?
Everyone
we have two pieces of good news today
First...
Ms. Tone Deaf had a successful operation!
And second, for our Christmas charity concert...
We'll be performing with Vanessa Mae!
Mr. Cheng
why haven't l received the practice schedule?
Mun, you know, after all...
we're an organization for the blind
You're always welcome to come to practice...
but perhaps you should do something else
for the performance
such as coordination
or taking care of our members
l can even arrange for you
to help out at the centre
Mr. Cheng
l really want to take part in this performance
I've practiced so long
was just because of this concert!
l understand, but...
Excuse me, Mr. Cheng
Vanessa Mae's agent
wants us to fax over her schedule
l'll be with you right away.
Mun, Mun?
Let's finish our discussion again. I have to go.
Let's finish our discussion again. I have to go
Grandma!
Are you leaving?
Yes, to class
Come back early for dinner
I've prepared some special turnip soup
Bye!
Have you seen my report card?
Didn't you find it yet?
l really haven't seen it
Perhaps you should ask someone else
Ying Ying!
Excuse me, l'd like to talkto her
Look what I've brought for you?
Sis, I've just had chemo-therapy,
l'll throw up if l eat
lt's OK
Then we'll save it for when you get better.
lf only we had believed him just that once
or given him a chance to explain
he might still be here playing video games
Who would have expected
him to jump off just like that?
Suicide is a dreadful sin
The souls of those who commit suicide...
are obliged to repeat their painful deaths everyda
To help him break out of this vicious cycle of pai
we need to tackle the cause of his suicide
Only then can his soul leave this world in peace
Have you ever considered
he might be telling the truth?
Perhaps he really did lose his report card.
Have you been teaching calligraphy long?
Yes, many years indeed
l'll teach you howto hold the brush
Use your big thumb and middle finger
and form a circle just like this
Like this, try
Very few want to learn calligraphy nowadays
l used to teach 3 lessons a week
Now, it's down to only one
l'll let you try writing by yourself
Try it yourself
Why are you sitting in my chair?
Why are you sitting in my chair?!
What is this? What is going on?
What are you looking for? Are you okay?
What happened?
Are you feeling unwell?
ls Dr. Lo here?
Ms. Wong, you are early
Your next appointment isn't until Friday
He won't be back from his meeting until 5 p.m.
Will he definitely be here at 5 p.m.?
lf it's urgent
l can page him for you now
l'll be back at 5
You can see them, too?
They don't usually want to be seen
But you'll get used to it
All the stores nearby have been bought up
only my boss refuses to sell
He seems to be
expecting his wife and child to visit
Actually, he can't see them at all
...there was a car accident over there...
Mun!
My secretary said you were asking for me
What's the matter?
Will you help me?
Of course l will
Your eyes hurt?
Will you believe me?
Yes...
What is it?
The shadows...they come to bring the dead
What shadow?
When l was at the hospital...
l saw a man
He...he took an old lady with him
The next morning, the old lady was dead...
My room keeps changing
suddenly into a different room...
l even saw a person missing her lower body...
When he rushed over, it was like an electric shock
my whole body went numb...
Calm down
And tell me slowly
When l was little...
Granny told me...
l was not an ordinary child.
God had given me some obstacles...
so that l would grow up
to be an extraordinary person
Now l understand
what it means to be extraordinary
An extraordinary person
can see things others can't...
and feel pain that others won't feel
Maybe, l was never meant to see this world
l don't want to terrified in bed every night...
then awaken horrors every morning
l just want to be an ordinary person
Dr. Lo, can you help me?
Yes, of course l will
One of my psychology professors...
from the States...
has just come to Hong Kong to visit
Let's meet him tomorrow
He might be able to help
How can you help me when you don't believe me?
What's going on?
Excuse me, I have to go
Call me if you need anything
Goodbye
Who's that?
A friend
He asked your sister to take something to States
Yes, that's right
You are home early
Aren't you supposed to be back next week?
Well...
a co-worker switched her shift with mine.
So l come back a bit earlier
lt's smoky here
Why don't you go up?
14th floor, unit-C
Have you seen my report card?
Stop asking me?!
I've already told you l haven't seen it!
Have you seen my report card?
15th floor, unit-C
Uncle, listen to me...
No way!
Only you can help us with this!
I've already said no!
lf you still respect me as your uncle
and respect yourself as my nephew
you should have never approached me with this!
First of all
You should know only too well...
what medical ethics are regarding organ transplant
And you should also knowthat...
the identity of the cornea donor
is concealed from me
What shadow?
One cornea transplant and she starts seeing ghosts
You actually believe that?
What if l do?
Then we have even less to talk about!
Uncle...
Don't tell me you fell for your own patient
Hello?
Dr. Lo, is that you?
Mun is in trouble!
Can you come over immediately?
Yes, right away
Yes, l admit
she's more than a patient to me
Mun!
How long do you plan on hiding in this little room
Five years? Seven? Or ten?
You have to confront your problem sooner or later
You want to play violin? Go play with the troupe!
l can accept you pretending to be blind
But even then
then you didn't isolate yourself here
l just want to help
Mun!
Sis.
Ying Ying, what are you doing here?
l can leave the hospital now
You can?
Yes, l don't need any more operations
l can go to school now
So...
hen once I am out of here
we can go out...
we can take pictures, we can even...
I'm so happy that you can see now,
because this world is really beautiful
Ying Ying...
lt's alright! Cheer up.
Be strong and things will work out for the best
I have to go now
Ying Ying!
Wong Kar Mun, l want to tell you...
Ying Ying has already...
l know... l just saw her
l know she's dead
What are you looking at?
Ying Ying
Can you see her?
lt wasn't her
Don't know why she didn't show up today
Are you not afraid anymore?
I don't think I have a choice
I see all these things anyway.
At least, I get to see the people l care about
What's this?
Ying Ying made this for you
What's written on it?
Don't forget me
She put in the wrong photo though
Who's this?
It's you!
Don't you recognize yourself yet?
What is going on?
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?!
We believe that
the very last consciousness of a mortal
carries over to the afterlife
That is
the very thought of a person in his final moment..
would become the eternal consciousness of his soul
Those who die a sudden death
have no recollection of the instance of death
Their souls remain in
this world as if they're still alive
But there are others
who intentionally refuse to leave
mostly due to unresolved
problems during their lifetime
These souls can't be consoled
while their problems remain
There is only one way to help them,
and that is to resolve what they left unsettled.
The woman whom
Ms Wong keeps seeing after resuming her sight.
We have to resolve her problems
so that she can move on
l hope l haven't done anything wrong
Even if it's wrong, it'd be my fault
And l won't regret it
Were you reincarnated into the wrong body?
Why are you so different from...
...the rest of the family?
Be careful
Bangkok, Thailand
Dr. Lo believed you in the end?
Let's just say Dr Lo is not involved
He's a professional after all
you know what l mean?
Yes
Are we close?
I'm not sure
lt says here that her
Chinese name was Chiu Wai Ling
A Thai born Chinese
Here are her hospital records
This is Siam-Rach Hospital
Sl-AM-LA?
This is probably the place
Let's get off to take a look
Hi
This is Siam-Rach Hospital?
Yes. Right
l want to meet a doctor, his name is Eak
Please come help
Can l help you?
l want to meet a doctor
his name is Eak
You know him?
No
lt's there a Doctor name Eak here?
lt mentioned here
lt's this hospital, his name is Eak
He's not here now
Not here?
Wah!
What is it?
This is the place
What place?
The place I've been having nightmaes about
Nightmares?
This has to be it!
Doctor Eak!
What's the matter?
You have two visitors.
Mister, this is Dr Eak
You're Dr. Eak
Yes
My name is Wah
Hello Nice to meet you
lt's her
After the Cornea operation
We come over here
To thankthe donator's family
Hope you can give us some detail
Here is the file
Are you two from Hong Kong?
You speak Mandarin?
Can you help us?
Sorry
Sorry, l can't disclose our hospital records
This is our hospital policy
Please understand
Wait!
We need to see the donor's family urgently
Could you perhaps askthem
if they are willing to meet us?
Her family will not be willing to meet with you
Who are you to Ling?
Please leave
Wait!
After l got Ling's corneas
l started to see things that she saw!
Ling was a sad and lonely girl
All of the villagers stayed away from her
Why?
From time to time
she would weep outside someone's door
Afterwards
a person in that house would pass away
So everyone took her to be a witch...
and always chased her away when they saw she
The children treated her like a monster
even l threw stones at her when l was a kid...
Because none of you
could believe that she foresaw death?
Maybe it was because of fear.
So, do you believe it now?
This is it
Mrs. Chui, these two friends are from Hong Kong
Nobody welcomed Ling
so she hardly ever set foot in the village
Yet, on the night of the fire
many saw her running around
shouting hysterically...
as if talking to herself
Since everyone detested Ling
no one paid any attention to her
Some villagers threw water on her
to drive her away
Around midnight, a big fire erupted
and kept burning till noon the next day
Among the deceased
300 were burnt beyond recognition
How exactly did Ling die?
She hanged herself
Ling killed herself the day after the big fire
ls Mrs. Chui alright?
She's fine
So you too believed that she wasn't insane,
but that she only sawthings no one else could
She foresaw a big disaster
and tried to warn everyone
but no one listened to her
l don't understand any of this spiritual stuff
l just want you two to knowthat
Ling was a very kind person...
and she had a tough life
Can l take a look at Ling's room?
Tonight...
...l want to stay here
l'll take you to Ling's grave tomorrow morning
You've been very kind to us, thank you
You should go to bed now
Alright, l'll stay next door
Shout if anything happens
l know
you've wanted me to come here all this time
Well, here I am now
What do you want to tell me?
...ill-fated...ill-fated...
Hurry...take her to the hospital!
Get lost...
You should be ashamed of yourself...
You are a curse!
Told you not to come here!
She's evil! Don't ever play with her!
Go save him! Save my boy...
Help him... Make him breathe...
What have you done to my boy...
You little bitch! Go to hell...
She's evil!
Stay away from my house! Get lost!
Be reasonable!
My daughter is only trying to help...
Go away!
Mrs. Chui, l know howto help Ling
let's go upstairs to see her
Her most painful time was not in the past
it's right now!
Since she killed herself,
she's been trapped in a time warp...
constantly repeating her suicide
She was dead
How can someone who's dead die again?
Listen to me
very soon she'll appear upstairs
Let's go up to see her!
l won't see her!
l spent my whole life protecting her
l never once gave up on her,
but she gave up on herself!
For that l can never forgive her!
Just listen,
I'm sure you hear this sound every night
Ling died at 3'o clock, didn't she?
Mrs. Chui, come with me and you'll understand!
I'm not going upstairs!
Mom...
Help me...
Ling?
Help me!
Help me...help me...
ls it Ling?
ls it really Ling?
Mom...
Help me...
Ling, you were the one who left me...
you were the one who left me...
Mom...
Help me...
Ling, Mommy is coming!
Ling! Ling!
My girl, mommy's right here
Don't be afraid
No one can bully you anymore
Mom, I'm so sorry
I was wrong
Please forgive me!
I've already forgiven you
Mun!
What happened?
Are you alright?
Go that way! Move over...
Hurry! Pull him out!
Careful! Come on keep pulling...
Over there! Move!
Get out!
Something's happening, get out, quick!
Granny, leave your house now!
Leave your house now!
Brother, run for your life!
Get out! Quick! Run!
Get out! Run...
Run! Run for your life!
Run! A disaster is coming!
Run! Run now!
What's she saying?
Run! Get out!
Mun!
Go, go, go...Move over...
...Listen to me...
Mun...
Ever since that day, Ling never appears again
I hold no resentment towards her...
Since l saw
and experienced the same pain that she did.
But aside from pain
I saw beauty
I no longer question why am l blind
lt is becasue
I've already seen
the most beautiful things in this world
Things l'll never forget