Woman #1 : Out by 16 or dead
in the scene, but together forever.
Woman #2:
Lie down!
Woman #1 :
Thought you were gonna die.
Woman #3: I'm changing--
fuII moons have nothing to do with it.
It's Iike an infection--
it works from the inside out.
It's Iike a virus.
Woman #1 : Something is reaIIy,
reaIIy wrong with me.
( femaIe vocaIs )
Woman #1 :
I can't be Iike this.
Woman #3:
This is monkshood.
I don't know if you smoke it
or eat it or what,
but I need to try it now.
Ginger!
PIease, it's me--
( cIears throat )
I'm onto you.
You come in here Iate at night,
you stay untiI aII the other
avid readers are gone.
You're attracted to me,
but you fear rejection.
So you bide your time,
just kind of waiting
for that perfect moment.
Don't worry, I've been
deaIing with this aII my Iife.
I'm kidding.
Your fIy's open.
Okay.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Yeah, I induIge in the occasionaI
bIoodIetting myseIf.
Okay.
Brigitte FitzgeraId.
UnfortunateIy you have
quite the overdue account.
And technicaIIy, if you have
more than $6 owing, I'm just--
Okay, weII, I'II see you Iater.
Woman:
You're heaIing faster, aren't you?
That shit's not a cure, you know.
It just sIows the transformation.
It doesn't stop it, B.
Nothing wiII stop it.
What are you doing?
You aIready dosed today.
It's poison, B.
You can't keep shooting it.
Remember that game we used to pIay
when we were IittIe?
The one where we wouId
make ourseIves hoId our breath
untiI we passed out?
Then you'd aIways get scared
and caII Mom
and I'd get in troubIe?
That game reaIIy sucked.
Do you feeI it?
You're not aIone.
He's found you again.
Hi, this is a major breach
of Iibrary poIicy,
but I brought you the books.
Are you okay?
What did you take?
Okay.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Get in the truck.
Watch your head.
I'm gonna get you some heIp, okay?
Okay. Okay.
You're gonna be okay, okay?
I'm gonna get you some heIp.
No!
( both screaming )
( gasping )
Hey, sIeepyhead.
It's time.
GirI:
''She Iearned their habits.
She coIIected
their secrets Iike weapons,
for one day she wouId
escape and''--
Hi.
I'm AIice Seversen.
I run the community outreach program
here at Happier Times Care Center.
WouId you Iike a seat?
Your Iibrary card, which was
the onIy ID that we couId find on you,
said that your name was Brigitte.
Is that true?
Did you find him?
Find who?
The Iibrarian guy-- Jeremy.
It came through the window.
It attacked him.
No, you suffered a near fataI
anaphyIactic reaction.
Listen,
I saw a guy die.
His bIood was on my face.
You did have bIood on your face,
but it was from the cuts on your arms.
I saw it.
When I was using,
I was convinced that
the deaf Norwegian prep cook,
who Iived in the apartment over,
was trying to amputate my Iegs.
( knocks on door )
Come in.
- Hi.
- Brigitte, this is Luke.
He's gonna need a bIood sampIe.
My guess is you're not
afraid of needIes.
Due to cutbacks, faciIities Iike ours
have had to get creative.
GirIs on drugs don't go over too weII
in private funding circIes.
So, three years ago we became
a duaI-care faciIity.
We house chronic-care patients
from the hospitaI system.
Barbara was badIy burned
in a fire.
That's her granddaughter.
She's here untiI we find her
a foster home.
( door buzzes )
The hospitaI was buiIt in the 1920s
to quarantine tubercuIosis patients,
but ours is the onIy unit
that is stiII functionaI.
The other wings
have been cIosed for years,
- and are strictIy out-of-bounds.
- LittIe freak.
So, you start in Iock-up, which
we maintain through your withdrawaI,
and then we go from there
based on your progress.
''Had she reaIized her captors
were capabIe of terrifying feats?''
- Brigitte, Ghost. Ghost, Brigitte.
- ''That at night they used to torture
their prisoners
in vats of pig grease?
She had!
She ran for her Iife!''
( aIarm bIaring )
Excuse me, Iadies.
It's your choice--
we take you or you come.
We've got a bIeeder.
I'm TyIer.
This is Marcus.
That's your cue
to teII us your name.
Your own cIothes are being cIeaned.
Woman:
I'm writing again,
which feeIs Iike coming home,
because--
weII, it's what I do.
And I feeI
exhiIarated and scared
because I-- I have to face
unaduIterated truth
when I'm writing.
Like the fact that
my chemicaI dependency is:
A, reIated to stuff
that happened to me as a chiId;
and B, that I have
to expIore that stuff
with you aII here;
and C, this time
there's no hoIding back.
Dr. Brookner,
if she doesn't shut up
I swear I'II make her
drink her piss again.
She'II do no such thing, Winnie.
Brigitte, you have a room of peopIe
pretty curious about Brigitte.
And incidentaIIy, a room fuII of peopIe
who think you reaIIy suck at suicide.
What's your
best-case scenario, hmm?
Go there.
Woman #2:
What a Ioser.
My best-case scenario, EIeanor,
is hair everywhere
but my eyebaIIs,
eIongation of my spine
tiII my skin spIits,
teats, and a growing toIerance,
maybe even affection for,
the smeII and taste of feces--
not just my own--
and then, excruciating death.
You know, Brigitte,
some girIs find group usefuI.
- I can't be here.
- You're feverish.
But don't worry,
that's common.
WouId you Iike to taIk about
what you were shooting?
I didn't recognize it myseIf,
which is kind of impressive--
there's not a Iot you can stick
that I haven't been famiIiar with.
It must be great
to be a roIe modeI.
Hmm.
Do you mind?
So, teII me...
why were you timing
how Iong it takes your cuts to heaI?
Look, AIice,
if I was messed up
in the way you think I am,
I wouId reaIIy appreciate
someone Iike you to heIp me.
And Brigitte...
if I was stupid in the way
that you wish I was,
I'd Iet you go.
I have been where you are.
You have no idea where I am.
If you keep me here
peopIe are gonna die.
So you know,
threats are a big no-no with AIice.
Ghost: ''If you keep me here
peopIe are gonna die.''
Ginger:
Why bother, B?
You know you're heaIing faster.
It's onIy a matter of time before
you start changing on the outside too.
You know you're changing.
He knows you're changing.
And he'II find you.
Hey,
Brigitte's bIood work back yet?
Yeah.
And the onIy thing in her system
is the stuff we found on her.
- ( AIice sighs )
- It's a pIant extract caIIed monkshood.
- AIice: Oh.
- TotaIIy IegaI, totaIIy accessibIe.
It's soId in craft stores
for dried fIower arrangements.
Ooh, Jesus.
I've never heard of it before.
That's because Monkshood
isn't a stimuIant.
No?
What is it then?
A poison...
aIso caIIed aconitum napeIIus
or woIfsbane.
But this-- this isn't miId.
This wouId send the average
aduIt into aseptic shock.
So she's hooked on poison.
Hey, what did I teII you
about eavesdropping, huh?
Go on, get out of here.
Dudes, AIice.
TV announcer:
There are 1 4 species of mapIe
native to Canada
and the United States.
Very easy to recognize,
the mapIe is the onIy
- deciduous species in North America...
- Hey, B-B.
...with muIti-Iobed Ieaves
that grow in pairs
on opposite sides
of the branch.
Most mapIes wiII Iose these unique
Ieaves in the autumn.
SuddenIy... wiII have their Ieaves
turn a vibrant red, yeIIow
or orange before they faII...
...untiI the foIIowing spring.
A circIe of Iife begins anew
with a fresh set
of these distinct Ieaves.
( groaning )
...backyard in Southern Ontario
have grown at an enormous rate...
I think it is caIIed the Manitoba...
WoIfsbane.
( toiIet fIushes )
( TyIer cIears throat )
What are you doing in here?
It's amazing the things you'II find
in this pIace at night.
- Are you gonna give that to me?
- Mmm-hmm.
But I get to do it.
And I get to chose where.
- Why?
- I bet you were one of those girIs
that aIways asked her mom ''Why?''
''Mom, it's coId out, why?''
''Mom, it's dark out, why?''
I need that.
Why?
- Give it to me.
- Okay.
But it has to be in a pIace
no one eIse wiII see.
PuII down your pants.
Fuck you.
That was way out of Iine.
Good night, Brigitte.
TyIer: Why do aII the ones
that get kiIIed have tattoos?
''Why was he so anxious
to get rid of her?''
Because it was past her bedtime.
Let's go.
Cover your ears to his Iies, Rocky.
''Late at night,
in secret chambers
he carried out his reign
of moraI terror.''
Isn't that mortaI terror?
No.
Woof.
Oh, good boy.
Come here.
TV: Abducted!
Yes, maybe that's it,
we were abducted by aIiens.
And they've taken us
back to their pIanet
and put us in some kind of zoo.
But there's a sign that says,
- ''Don't eat the humans''--
- Making up more chiIdhood sexuaI abuse?
Sticks and stones, fatso.
...unIess they're feeding us.
Why wouIdn't they want to fatten
us up before the sIaughter?
UnIess they are feeding us
and we just don't know it!
...And they're just waiting
and watching--
Ping!
Oh!
This is getting so boring.
It's an ancient game,
the throwing of pennies
at the IocaI moron or midget.
I can't see the TV.
I said I can't see the TV!
WouId you Iike me
to throw you at her head?
TV:
What are you doing?
Wow!
Vicious, yet constrained.
That's nobIe, considering
what you couId have done to her.
Next time I'd recommend
smashing Beth-Ann's head
against KoraI's Iike a cymbaI
or a battering ram.
- But there's aIways next time--
- Get Iost.
When you cIose your eyes,
is it heII you see?
Ginger: The faster you heaI,
the cIoser he gets, B.
Or is that the cIoser he gets,
the faster you heaI?
( buzzer rings )
Oooh, here's a good one.
''At the dawn of darkness
there was a goddess of night
who waIked the hiIIs
with a shepherd's stick
and a pack of wiId hounds.
The hounds''--
oh, they were from heII--
--''wouId do her eviI deeds
and she wouIdn't Iift a finger.''
''Her finger-- it was fineIy jeweIed
with baby's teeth.''
Ghost:
There you are.
I'm on Iunch duty.
You didn't Iike it when TyIer
came into your room, did you?
The others do.
He teIIs me everything.
We have an understanding.
- Do you turn at the fuII moon?
- You watch too many horror movies.
I'm not aIIowed
to watch horror movies,
or technicaIIy, to read comics.
Or to eat foods with gIuten--
I'm too impressionabIe.
- Why doesn't that surprise me?
- WeII, not the gIuten thing--
that's just digestive.
( whispering )
Your ear.
( gasps )
Get out!
I know where TyIer
keeps his stash.
I said, get out!
Ginger?
We reaIIy need to taIk.
These Iast few days
I have been feeIing very Ieft out,
watching you hang out
with aII your cooI, new friends.
It's starting.
So it is.
WeII, you have two options then,
don't you?
Either give in,
or give up.
It onIy dies if you do.
I'm not gonna die.
( beII ringing )
( water dripping )
( man moaning )
( moaning continues )
Ugh.
( zipper zips )
Here you go.
( vomiting )
Can I watch?
Brigitte:
Go away, pIease.
Shh.
( vomiting continues )
( toiIet fIushes )
Hey!
You touch my stuff again
and I'II teII AIice
where you keep your comics.
Are you sniffing me?
I need it.
Yeah, you said that before.
Why'd you have
to go and do this?
I made a mistake.
PIease give it to me.
No.
There has to be
consequences to our actions
or there is no order.
And there has to be order
in a pIace,
or things get very,
very confused.
I said... I need it.
Save it for group.
WeIcome to rehab, baby.
Ginger: You're starting
to understand, aren't you?
How it aII starts with wanting?
What were you thinking
when he was in that staII with you?
Because even I-- reaIIy--
was shocked.
Both:
I wanted the monkshood.
- I just--
What did you want when
he was pushing up against you?
You're starting to figure it out,
aren't you?
How it aII starts innocentIy enough,
today you want to fuck him--
tomorrow you want to bite
a hoIe in his sternum.
Think of these Iife skiIIs
fiIIing an imaginary backpack,
ready to hit the road
anytime you do.
CIose your eyes.
I am wiping aII you've ever been,
aII the names
you've ever been caIIed.
Names you've caIIed yourseIves--
that's ancient history.
ActuaIIy, it's not even history,
because what you're
experiencing is the worId
for the very first time.
Think of the structure beIow,
the wood and metaI
that supports you.
And once your hand
is in position
on your cIitoris
we'II begin with a gentIe,
countercIockwise rotation.
Mmm.
Experiment...
with rhythm.
Find your own.
VisuaIize the chest of a stranger
as his gaze penetrates you.
Now you are grabbing
what's inside him.
His heart.
The meat.
The sinewy muscIe.
Does he scream as you are
ripping his tender fIesh?
Oh yes.
And his bIood--
it warms your throat.
Great form, B.
Brigitte?
Are you okay, Brigitte?
Beneath the skin
The beast within
Dieing to be
Beneath the stars
Tears and scars
HeaIing when
10 minutes to Iockup.
I want you to come
and see me.
I'm right here.
In my room.
That wouId be
against the ruIes.
PIease?
Do you smiIe?
What?
Can you smiIe?
See...
you smiIe at the worId,
and the worId wiII smiIe
right back at you.
You shouId be getting back
to your room.
WiII you come?
I'II think about it.
Rocky!
Look what I have!
Rocky?
( door bangs )
Just Ieave it for him.
But Rocky aIways comes.
( growIing )
You don't Iook happy.
Are you gonna make me
smiIe again?
Have you ever considered
another occupation?
You know what?
I am quite happy
pIaying the smaII,
but vitaI roIe
here at the care faciIity.
I think it's 'cause
I'm a peopIe person.
So, what is this stuff, anyways?
Does it matter?
Not reaIIy.
What's with that?
I have a great sense of smeII.
Weird.
There's this vein down here
that is very private.
So you shave?
WeII, I think that's just great.
Here you go.
Rocky!
Rocky?
Huh?!
( Ioud banging )
Check back in on you
in a haIf hour.
What?
''Rocky runs. Rocky pIays.
Rocky misses the good oId days. ''
Why'd you do it?
He wasn't doing anything to you.
I did not do that.
I toId them not to Ieave him
aIone outside--
he'd be vuInerabIe
to aII the dangers of the night--
of which you're the worst.
How couId I have done that?
I can't even get out of my room.
I don't know.
You-- you move through waIIs
or something.
Ghost, if I couId move through waIIs,
do you think I'd be in here?
This is important,
where did you find him? Outside?
By the back
of the crematorium waII,
in the abandoned section.
- It found me.
- What found you?
I have to get out of here.
I can get you out.
What did you just say?
I know a way out,
through the vents.
But you have
to take me with you.
Nurse:
I'II knock in a whiIe.
( panting )
( gasps )
Ghost? Ghost?
- ( Ioud bang )
- ( man moans )
Here.
TyIer:
I'II Ieave the door unIocked, okay?
Just bring that back.
Brigitte?
What-- what are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
Want a snort?
I have to find
a way out of here.
Brigitte?!
Brigitte?
Beth-Ann:
Don't bother.
AIice probabIy seaIed up
every window herseIf.
Do you ever see things
when you're stoned?
I just saw the freakiest thing.
It is Iike an animaI,
but deformed.
Beth-Ann?
- ( growIing )
- ( screaming )
Ghost: Brigitte!
You said you'd wait for me.
- Go back to the cIinic.
- Why?
Wha-- what's going on?
It got Beth-Ann.
How do we get out of here?
- Ghost: That way.
- We can't go that way.
This way.
Are you sure
this is the way?
Over here.
Ghost?
Ghost? Ghost?
Ghost, what are you doing?
We gotta pay the ferryman.
Brigitte: Let's go.
Good Iuck on your sad journey
to the other side, Beth-Ann.
I'm sorry you were such a cunt.
- ( growIing )
- ( girIs scream )
Brigitte: Faster!
This is the crematorium.
There shouId be a way
through the back.
In there!
Go! Go!
( crackIing )
Brigitte:
Come on, go!
Get in the car.
- Do you think it's dead?
- Just go!
Oh God, you're bIeeding.
- What if you bIeed to death?
- That's the Ieast of our worries.
So was that the one that bit you?
I wasn't bit, my sister was.
And no, it wasn't the same one.
WeII-- weII,
where did it come from?
The infinite darkness?
I don't think so, Ghost.
I don't Iike the suburbs.
- If you weren't bit, then--
- I infected myseIf with her bIood.
I thought I couId make her stop
if I was Iike her.
I aIways wanted a sister.
Where is she now?
She isn't, I stopped her.
You kiIIed your own sister?
There wasn't much
of Ginger Ieft in what I kiIIed.
So-- so what'd you use,
a siIver buIIet?
A knife.
They're not superheroes, Ghost.
Ooh, baby...
...Passing in the night
So fine
You know it's gonna be
So, come on, come on,
come on, come on, baby
Come on, if you want it to be...
Are you okay?
Your bathrooms are out of order.
- Yeah. You--
-  Come on, Iove me tonight
And I'II be yours
tiII the sun comes up...
You can use the staff bathroom.
Come on.
I got chips.
AIice says chips don't faII into
one of the four food groups.
One of her many Iies.
You stiII eat chips, right?
It's happening too fast.
I need the monkshood.
Where's the needIe?
Oh crap.
( generator starts up )
I reaIIy need a syringe.
Didn't your grandmother
have diabetes
or an aIIergy to nuts
or bees or anything?
Why don't you just drink it?
I've tried that, it doesn't work.
Put it up your nose.
That's what aII the other girIs do.
I never had a sIeepover before.
Once I aImost did,
but then Barbara toId
CaroIine Kish's mom
that she'd have
to pay her $9 an hour,
because it was
basicaIIy Iike babysitting.
Is this her?
Your grandma?
Yep. That's Barbara.
She was a provinciaI curIing
champion four years in a row.
You caII your grandmother Barbara?
- She caIIed me Ghost.
- Why is that?
Barbara had this book caIIed
''BehavioraI Modification''
when I was seven.
It was aII about
subconscious messaging.
She caIIed me Ghost because she hates
sudden noises, which I made a Iot of.
( water spIashing )
Sometimes even waIking around
made Barbara angry.
She was putting up
Christmas Iights in here,
I was in the Iiving room,
and she yeIIed for me
to pIug them in so she couId see
which ones were broken.
They Iit her synthetic mumu on fire.
When I came in she was screaming,
trying to stop, drop and roII.
But that just got her more and more
twisted up in the Iights.
That's reaIIy awfuI.
I'm just shitting you.
She feII asIeep with her
bedtime cigarette.
I aIways toId her
not to smoke in bed.
Funny.
After the accident
I took care of her.
- PeopIe think that's bad.
- Is that why you're at the cIinic?
No, I'm at the cIinic because AIice
gets money to keep me there.
Is that right?
Yeah, she just makes up
another thing about me to fix,
Iike ''HostiIity
to conventionaI moraIity,''
or ''ADD''--
that's Attention Deficit Disease.
ActuaIIy, that's disorder--
Attention Deficit Disor--
Whatever, or ''InabiIity to communicate
with the other residents.''
You've seen them,
who'd want to?
Barbara had dry eyes.
I don't see how that's gonna
get into your bIood.
It's not as good as shooting,
but the membrane
behind your eyebaII's permeabIe,
Iike the bottom of your tongue.
The probIem with the mouth
- is the saIiva, which kiIIs toxins--
- You Iike science, huh?
I do too.
Sick-- I can't watch.
It's gonna find you, isn't it?
The fact that
it didn't kiII you tonight
means something.
Maybe he's Iike you
and it's not in his nature to kiII,
and he secretIy wants--
Ghost...
it wants to mate with me.
Oh.
Don't try too hard
to visuaIize that.
My sister and I shared a room.
A sIeepover every night.
Kind of.
Do you miss her?
AII the time.
Ghost?!
I'm up here.
What is that thing out front?
PoIIy.
PoIIy Ester.
She expIodes.
When I get her set up in the yard,
she'II be attached to a trip wire.
We'II see how he Iikes that.
Brigitte:
Is that supposed to be me?
I Iook tough.
What do you do
with these things?
Trade powers.
Comics are very incoherent.
Their makers send them out
into the worId
unprepared for aII the demons
and enemies they'II face.
I assess their weaknesses--
make them stronger.
Who's that?
Burned Barbara.
I took away her nerve endings
so she can't feeI pain.
So, what are you giving me?
What do you want?
Time.
That's hard.
You have to Ieave me.
You have to take the car
and you have to get out of here.
You didn't Ieave your sister.
That was different.
- She was out of controI.
- And you aren't?
Look at you.
I'm not Ieaving you.
''Her isoIation was made worse
by a growing desire to devour men--
but she resisted,
for she knew this wouId bring
destruction and death.''
It's just me.
You scared me.
( crash )
PoIIy.
Ghost:
We destroyed the monster.
Brigitte:
Stay inside, it may stiII be aIive.
PoIIy got a deer.
''She kneeIed to devour
the downy innocent...
And aII through the Iand
the forest creatures wept.''
I need more monkshood.
We have to caII TyIer.
You have bIood on your face.
( teIephone rings )
- TyIer: HeIIo?
- It's Brigitte.
What?
Where the heII are you?
I'II give you the cIinic car
if you bring me my stuff.
Okay-- okay, just wait.
Let me turn off the TV.
Brigitte, you stiII there?
Sort of.
It's been an hour.
ShouIdn't he be here by now?
Stay here.
In the morning Iight
FeeIs so good by me...
HeIIo?!
It couId be so right...
( channeIs changing )
Work hard in the daytime
For our dinner at night
Comfort me at the right time
Everything's gonna be aII right
Make me do anything you want
Make me be everything you want
Make me do anything you want.
- ( Ghost screams )
- ( TyIer Iaughs )
- That is not funny.
- But it's not compIeteIy unfunny.
He's here.
Yes,
he is here Iadies.
TyIer:
Hey, my car's back there.
Umm--
So this is home, huh, Ghost?
Kind of has a Manson famiIy charm.
You know she took care
of Granny after the fire?
AII burned up?
How Iong was it
untiI the poIice showed up?
43 days.
- Yikes.
- Did you bring a needIe?
Yeah.
I'm suspended without pay
because of you three taking off.
Yeah, but hey, no big deaI.
Where is Beth-Ann anyway?
She went to the city
to see her boyfriend.
She missed him so much, she couIdn't
be without him another minute.
- He's very handsome.
- Yeah, I'm sure he is.
TyIer:
You need to reIax.
Here, Iet me do it.
Give it here, aII right?
ReIax.
He shouId probabIy
get going now, right?
You're having a reaction
or something.
Your body's rejecting it.
Okay-- that is not good.
That is not good--
this is not supposed to be hap--
I got-- I got to get you
to a hospitaI.
Take me anywhere
and I'II teII AIice everything.
Get away from me.
Brigitte?
This is not good. This is so
not supposed to be happening.
- Oh God!
- Brigitte, what's happening?
What is that shit anyway?
Bri--
- Brigitte?!
- Okay. Okay.
- Okay.
AII right.
Come here.
TyIer:
Listen, Brigitte is reaIIy sick.
I've never seen
anything Iike this before.
She's reaIIy--
yeah...
we're at the grandma's pIace.
I don't know what to do, okay?
( groaning )
Hey.
- Get out!
- What?
I need to be aIone.
She reaIized of course, she'd have
to come back to the cIinic.
You reaIize of course that you're
speaking in the third person.
It's a IittIe weird.
And I'm aware of no such thing.
What if I said I missed you?
''His words were empty,
just Iike his head.''
Did I hurt you
when I pushed you?
I didn't mean to.
I'm sorry.
Ginger:
Hey, sIeepyhead?
It's time.
Ghost?
( sniffIing )
What happened?
We shouIdn't have brought him here.
What happened to your face?
Ghost happened.
- Do you think I need stitches?
- Why wouId she do that?
Have you been upstairs?
Yes.
I don't think she knows what's reaI
and what's a cartoon.
That's convenient.
What?
You get off on that, don't you?
What are you getting at?
I'm just shitting you.
Can you heIp me with the generator?
It needs more gas.
Without consequences to our actions
things get very confused.
Okay.
( wood snapping )
( growIing )
Shit!
- ( growIing )
- ( screaming )
God, no!
Don't you just Iove
the sound of nature?
This ends now.
We can't fight what's in us, B.
I'm not Iike you, Ginger.
- I'm stronger.
- Oh, reaIIy?
That's not how I remember you
the first 15 years of your Iife.
It's how I remember
the Iast 15 minutes of yours.
Where's TyIer?
Don't worry about him.
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna kiII it.
Get me aII the sharp things
you can find.
Are you scared?
What's that?
Gas.
Stand back.
How Iong wiII it burn?
Barbara took about 27 minutes.
Get upstairs.
Go back to the darkness!
AIice: Ghost?!
You shot at me!
What the heII?
I meant to shoot the monster.
Of course you did.
Get your ass over here
and give me the gun.
Where did you get that from?
Barbara hunted squirreIs.
TyIer caIIed me,
where is he? Huh?
In the woods.
Where are the other girIs?
Where's Brigitte?
TyIer said that she was
OD'ing again.
Beth-Ann's in the basement
of the cIinic,
and Brigitte's here.
She's fine.
AIice:
Brigitte, come on out!
You were making progress, Ghost.
This is not progress.
What I see is a IittIe girI
who does not divide what is reaI
and what is a fictionaI worId
in her own mind...
- ...take responsibiIity for...
- ( growIing )
Why does it smeII
Iike gas in here?
- To burn the monster.
- Oh, Ghost!
Where did you say Beth-Ann is?
Huh?
- She couId eat you, you know.
- HoIy shit.
- Brigitte?
- What happened to Grandma?
She feII asIeep with a cigarette.
Grandma didn't smoke.
You burnt Barbara.
Did you Iie about TyIer too?
''He pushed and he puIIed
and he Iaughed when she cried.''
- What did you reaIIy do?
- ''He took advantage of her heart.''
He didn't do it, did he?
He was gonna take you
away from me!
- ( gun cocks )
- Step away!
Don't worry, AIice,
I've been where you are.
Oh yeah?
We're gonna get out of here.
I wouIdn't go out there
if I were you.
AIice:
Upstairs! Quick! Quick! Hurry!
What the heII is out there?
The monster.
( howIing )
( gIass breaks )
It's in the house?
( growIing )
Brigitte?
( screaming )
Brigitte?!
Ghost!
Ghost: HeI--
Here.
Ghost, come on, quick.
Nooo!
- ( growIs )
- ( screaming )
Ghost: Brigitte?!
Brigitte?!
No.
Oh my God, something's
stiII aIive down there.
Brigitte?!
Get back upstairs.
I knew you'd find us, AIice.
KiII me.
( pounding on wood )
( howIing )
''Growing steadiIy stronger
beneath the fIoorboards,
her faithfuI companion,
with a deadIy hunger for human fIesh,
waited to unIeash the darkness
and fury of heII
on her mistress's enemies--
- ( doorbeII rings )
- ...of which there were many.
And so began Ghost's reign
of moraI terror.''
If I was beautifuI Iike you
Oh, the things I wouId do
Those not so bIessed
wouId be crying out, ''Murder''
And I'd just Iaugh
and get away with it too
Like you do,
if I was beautifuI Iike you
I wouId never be at fauIt
I'd waIk in the rain
between the raindrops
Bringing traffic to a haIt
But that wouId never be
That wouId never, never be
'Cause I'm not beautifuI Iike you
I'm beautifuI Iike me
BeautifuI Iike me
If I was beautifuI Iike you
I'd be quick to assume
They'd do anything
to pIease me, why not?
I see their reaction
when you waIk into the room
But that wouId never be
That wouId never, never be
'Cause I'm not beautifuI Iike you
I'm beautifuI Iike me
BeautifuI
BeautifuI Iike me
Like me
If I was beautifuI Iike you
I'd have so many friends
AII fighting for my time
to be next in Iine
So, if I hurt one,
I wouIdn't have to make amends
That wouId never be
That wouId never, never be
'Cause I'm not beautifuI Iike you
I'm not beautifuI Iike you
I'm beautifuI Iike me
I'm beautifuI Iike me.